[ Elvis Presley ]
A ROSE GROWS WILD
IN THE COUNTRY
A TREE GROWS TALL
AS THE SKY
[ Chorus ]
THE WIND BLOWS WILD
IN THE COUNTRY
AND PART OF THE
WILD, WILD COUNTRY
AM I
WILD, WILD LIKE THE DEER
AND THE DOVE
WILD AND FREE
IS THIS LAND THAT I LOVE
A DREAM GROWS WILD
IN THE COUNTRY
A LOVE GROWS TALL
AS THE SKY
[ Chorus ]
A HEART BEATS WILD
IN THE COUNTRY
AND HERE WITH A DREAM
IN MY HEART
PART OF THE
WILD, WILD COUNTRY
AM I
PART OF THE
WILD, WILD COUNTRY
AM I 떰
[ Rooster Crows ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Blows Landing ]
[ Man ]  COME ON, GLENN.
IT DON'T HURT, DOES IT, HUH ?
COME ON, GET UP,
FIGHT BACK !
GET UP, GLENN.
COME ON, BOY.
COME ON, GET UP, GLENN !
GET UP.
[ Bleating ]
MOST FORTUNATE
THE BROTHER WAS NOT KILLED.
FORTUNATE, MOST FORTUNATE.
BUT, OF COURSE,
THERE WAS INTENTION
ON THE PRISONER'S PART.
DELIBERATE
AND MALICIOUS INTENTION.
WHAT HAPPENED, TYLER,
OVERSLEEP ?
WELL, I WEREN'T SURE TODAY
WAS THE DAY, JUDGE.
I WEREN'T SURE.
THE PAROLE BOARD'S ON THE VERGE
OF COMING TO SOME DECISION
ABOUT THIS BOY OF YOURS.
YOUR WIFE'S COUSIN,
BRAXTON HERE,
SAYS HE'LL TAKE HIM IN,
GIVE HIM A JOB AND TRY
TO SET HIM STRAIGHT.
YOU GOT ANY OPINION
ABOUT THAT ?
IT WON'T HELP NONE.
I SEEN A MIGHT OF TROUBLE
WITH THIS BOY.  HE'S AS
MEAN-TEMPERED AS THEY COME.
HE'LL DRINK, FISH
AND READ BOOKS.
COMICS ?
- BEG PARDON ?
- DOES HE READ COMIC BOOKS ?
UM, BOOKS, MA'AM.
BUT THERE NEVER WAS
A HOE OR PLOW MADE
THAT WOULD FIT HIS HAND.
YOU'RE A DAMN LIAR, PA.
[ Judge ]
I SUGGEST YOU DON'T SAY
TOO MUCH, BOY.
YOUR RECORD'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH
FOR YOU TO MAKE
THESE RAMBUNCTIOUS REMARKS.
STOLE A CAR ONCE, DIDN'T YOU ?
GOT PICKED UP TWICE
ON A DRUNK CHARGE.
I DON'T CARE, HE'S STILL LYING.
I KNOW WHY HIM AND HANK
RAISE THAT CORN.
BOTH OF 'EM DRANK MY MA
INTO AN EARLY GRAVE
WITH THAT CORN.
GLENN, HOW OLD WERE YOU
WHEN YOUR MOTHER DIED ?
MA'AM ?
SHE ASKED HOW OLD YOU WERE
WHEN YOUR MA DIED.
ALMOST NINE.
LET'S GET ON WITH THIS.
WHAT'S YOUR RECOMMENDATION,
PHIL ?
I'D GIVE HIM
ANOTHER CHANCE, TOM.
SO WOULD I, JUDGE.
ON PAROLE, OF COURSE.
HAVE HIM REPORT
ONCE A WEEK.
AND I'D SEE TO IT
HE STAYED DECENTLY AT WORK
WITH A LIVING WAGE AND BOARD.
I OWE IT TO HIS MOM,
MY OWN COUSIN, THAT MUCH.
HE'LL NEVER DO IT, ROLFE.
WHAT HE NEEDS IS CORRECTION.
MR. TYLER, WHAT DO YOU THINK
NEEDS IMPROVING IN YOUR SON ?
WELL, BEGGING YOUR PARDON,
WHAT DO YOU THINK DON'T ?
[ Laughing ]
YOUR PICTURE'S
A MIGHTY BLACK ONE, SAM.
THERE WAS NOTHING WRONG
WITH THIS BOY BACK A WAY.
THERE WAS NEVER A WEEK
COME SNOW OR RAIN...
THIS BOY AND HIS MOTHER
DIDN'T ATTEND MY CHURCH.
GLENN, TURN AROUND,
TELL JUDGE PARKER
AND THE PAROLE BOARD...
WHAT WAS THE MASTER'S CRY
FROM THE CROSS ?
"ELI, ELI,
LAMA SABACHTHANI ?"
AND WHERE IN SCRIPTURE
IS THAT NOTED ?
IN MATTHEW 27:46,
AND SORT OF TURNED AROUND
IN MARK 15:34.
AND WHAT DOES, "ELI, ELI,
LAMA SABACHTHANI" MEAN ?
IT MEANS, "MY GOD, MY GOD,
WHY HAST THOU FORSAKEN ME ?"
GOOD LUCK, GLENN.
THANK YOU, SIR.
[ Whimpering ]
HELLO, ROSIE.
I'M GLAD THE BOY
WAS PAROLED
IN HIS UNCLE'S CUSTODY.
THAT WAY,
HE'LL HAVE A CHANCE.
TELL ME, WAS YOUR SYMPATHY
FOR HIM REAL ?
YOU'RE THE EXPERT.
YOU TELL ME.
I KNOW YOU BOTH SHARE
THE SAME KIND OF BACKGROUND.
I IDENTIFIED WITH HIM.
ISN'T THAT THE WORD ?
YOU'RE NOT IN A HURRY,
I'LL BUY YOU A DRINK.
OR BETTER STILL,
MAKE YOU ONE.
NOT TODAY, PHIL.
IRENE, IS IT REALLY NEVER ?
NEVER AGAIN ?
WE BOTH AGREED TO THAT.
NO, YOU AGREED.
I MERELY WENT ALONG UNWILLINGLY.
I'M SORRY NOW I DID.
THERE AREN'T MANY TIMES
WHEN A MAN'S LIFE
IS GIVEN REAL DISTINCTION.
BACK TO YOUR LAW OFFICE,
MR. MACY.
ALL RIGHT, MRS. SPEERY.
[ Train Passing ]
WELL, HERE WE ARE.
IT DON'T LOOK LIKE MUCH,
BUT WE SERVE
A COMMUNITY NEED.
HERE'S YOUR NEW HOME, BOY.
THESE BOTTLES ARE ALL READY
FOR LABELIN'.
HERE'S ONE
THAT'S A LITTLE SHORT.
WATCH THIS, BOY.
[ Spits ]
MMM, GOOD STUFF.
YOU GOTTA GIVE 'EM ALL
A SQUARE MEASURE.
THERE.  NOW.
ALL SET TO GO.
SUPPOSE IT'S JOHNSON AND TERRY.
THEY'LL ORDER
UNDER THEIR OWN LABEL.
THAT'S SHENANDOAH ELIXIR.
THAT'S THIS ONE RIGHT HERE.
MINE'S OLD SEMINOLE TONIC.
SOLD IN EVERY STATE IN DIXIE.
SALEM DRUGS, THEY'LL ORDER
UNDER THEIR OWN LABEL TOO.
THAT'S ON THE END.
IT'S ALL THE SAME STUFF ?
YEAH, ALL THE SAME,
'CEPT FOR THE LABELS AND COLOR.
EIGHTY-SEVEN PERCENT AQUA PURE,
THIRTEEN PERCENT GRAIN ALCOHOL.
SOME FOLKS WON'T WANT A LABEL
AT ALL.  JUST WALK IN OFF
THE STREET, BUY A FEW AT A TIME.
[ Laughing ]
WELL, THAT'S IT, BOY.
ARE THESE THE ONES
TO BE SHIPPED ?
YEP, FIRST THING TOMORROW.
HERE'S THE KEYS
TO THE PICKUP TRUCK.
YOU'LL BE COMFORTABLE
IN HERE, GLENN.
HAD IT FIXED UP SPECIAL.
CLEAN, DRY, HEALTHY.
YOU EVEN GOT YOUR OWN
PRIVATE ENTRANCE.
BETTER THAN I EVER HAD
WHEN I WAS A BOY YOUR AGE.
I PLAN TO PUT YOU IN
A SHOWER RIGHT OVER YONDER.
[ Inhales ]
I DO LOVE THE SMELL
OF THIS PLACE.
DRY CARDBOARD,
ALCOHOL, HERBS.
ALSO MONEY.
IT JUST ROLLS IN.
THAT'S A GOOD SMELL TOO.
ABOUT MY PAY, UNCLE ROLFE.
OKAY TO ASK ?
PA, SUPPER'S READY.
FINE, NORRIE.
HOPE YOU MADE PLENTY.
GOT A GOOD YOUNG APPETITE
IN THE HOUSE NOW.
COME AND GET IT, GLENN,
BEFORE SHE THROWS IT OUT.
EXCUSE ME.
MIGHTY NICE CHANDELIER.
SET ME BACK A PRETTY PENNY TOO.
[ Baby Crying ]
BUT CHEAP AT THE PRICE.
SIT DOWN, GLENN.
ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, MIGHTY NICE CHANDELIER.
BOUGHT IT OFF
THE OLD JOHNSON PLACE.
RENAISSANCE STYLE,
THEY CALL IT.
YES, MIGHTY NICE.
ALWAYS SPEND YOUR MONEY
WITH A PURPOSE, BOY.
YOU'LL USUALLY FIND MY ADVICE
IS WORTH THE HEEDIN'.
YOU GOT GOOD BRAXTON BLOOD
IN YA.
I AIM TO SEE YOU GET AHEAD.
ABOUT MY PAY,
UNCLE ROLFE.
FOR WHAT WE ARE ABOUT
TO RECEIVE,
MAY THE LORD MAKE US
TRULY GRATEFUL.
UH... MY PAY ?
PAY ?
TEN A WEEK AND KEEPS.
DID I SAY TEN ?
WELL, 12.50'S MORE LIKE IT.
I WANT YOU HAPPY, BOY.
WE GOT A RIGHT PLEASANT
LITTLE FAMILY HERE,
AND I WANT TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
YEAH.
[ Woman ]
GLENN ?
BETTY LEE.
HELLO.
DIDN'T EXPECT
TO SEE YOU AROUND.
I DROVE IN WITH MA
FOR THE HOSPITAL FUND MEETING.
WE'D HOPED YOU'D BE OUT
FOR SUPPER.
NAH, YOUR KIN DON'T LIKE ME.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
MY MA THINKS--
YEAH, YOUR MA !  IT'S YOUR PA.
[ Baby Crying ]
IS THAT NORRIE'S BABY ?
WELL, IT AIN'T A CAT.
DID YOU SEE HIM, GLENN ?
WHAT'S HE LIKE ?
WHAT'S A BABY LIKE ?
DON'T BE MEAN.
WHAT DO YOU WANNA ASK
SO MANY QUESTIONS FOR ?
THEY BEEN AT ME ALL WEEK
WITH QUESTIONS
AND MORE QUESTIONS.
I'M SORRY.
I HADN'T THOUGHT.
THEY GOT ME ON PAROLE.
I GOTTA GO UP AND SEE THIS
PAROLE OFFICER ONCE A WEEK.
THEN I GOTTA GET EXAMINED
BY THIS MISS SPEERY--
CASE WORKER, PSYCHIATRY,
WHATEVER SHE IS.
SHE THINKS SHE'S GOT
A LUNATIC ON HER HANDS.
IRENE SPEERY ?  SHE SPOKE
AT SCHOOL ABOUT HER WORK
DOWN AT THE STATE PRISON ?
THAT'S THE ONE.
HER MOTHER LEFT HER
THAT BIG HOUSE.
SHE THINKS I'M
LAME IN THE HEAD.  YOU KNOW
WHAT I THINK ABOUT HER ?
SHE LOOKS LIKE THE OTHER SIDE
OF A WALNUT, AND IF SHE DON'T
WATCH OUT, SHE'LL GET CRACKED.
MY MOTHER KNOWS HER SLIGHTLY,
AND SHE THINKS
SHE'S VERY NICE.
DIG THAT.  YOUR MOTHER
THINKS SHE'S NICE.
YES !
GLENN, DON'T LOOK FOR TROUBLE.
AND BY THE WAY,
MY MA THINKS YOU'RE NICE TOO.
YOU DIDN'T SHOW HER
MY LETTERS, DID YOU ?
NO.
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHER STUFF
I WROTE ?  I WANT ALL THAT
JUNK BACK, MAYBE BURN IT.
GLENN, SOMETIMES
I THINK YOU'RE TOUCHED MYSELF.
DON'T YOU TRUST ANYBODY ?
떰 [ Guitar ]
SHE'S PRETTY.
PRETTY AND SAD.
WHEN'S HER HUSBAND
COMING BACK ?
THEY DON'T KNOW.  HE'S IN
GOVERNMENT WORK OVERSEAS.
SO UNCLE ROLFE SAYS.
WHEN AND WHERE
DID SHE MARRY HIM ?
NO ONE IN TOWN SEEMS TO KNOW.
THEY DON'T SAY,
I DON'T ASK.
YES, BUT--
DON'T WORRY YOUR HEART.
JUST LET IT BE.
떰 [ Humming ]
[ Dog Barking ]
DON'T WORRY,
SHE WON'T BITE.
[ Glenn ]
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE IN TOWN
THAT WON'T.
ROSABELLE, COME ON.
WHERE WOULD YOU
WANT ME, MA'AM ?
IN HERE, PLEASE.
ANYPLACE IN PARTICULAR
YOU WANT ME TO SIT ?
ANYWHERE YOU LIKE.
WHAT ABOUT RIGHT THERE ?
ALL RIGHT,
NOW WHAT ?
I THINK WE SHOULD GET
ONE THING STRAIGHT
BEFORE WE START.
I'M NOT A POLICEMAN, GLENN.
NO.  YOU WERE JUST
APPOINTED BY THE COURT...
TO FIND OUT IF I'M...
TOUCHED OR NOT.
WHERE DID YOU PICK UP THAT ?
AT THE HEARING.
YOU WERE TAKING ALL THOSE NOTES.
COUNTIN' EVERY FLEA ON ME.
THOSE NOTES MIGHT'VE BEEN ABOUT
YOUR FATHER OR YOUR BROTHER
OR EVEN YOUR MOTHER.
YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT MY MOTHER, MA'AM.
NO, BUT I'D LIKE TO KNOW
IF YOU'D CARE TO TELL ME.
I DON'T CARE TO TELL YOU.
YOUR MOTHER SEEMS
TO HAVE MEANT
A GREAT DEAL TO YOU.
YOU HEARD ME, DIDN'T YOU ?
YOU CAN LEAVE.
THERE ARE NO BARS
ON THESE WINDOWS.
YOU SMOKE ?
NO.  THIS ROUTINE OF YOURS
WOULD STAGGER A BILLY GOAT.
WHAT'S FUNNY ?
WHAT YOU SAID
WAS FUNNY.
IT WASN'T MEANT TO BE FUNNY.
YOU WANNA FIND OUT WHAT
MAKES ME TICK, DON'T YOU ?
NO.  YOU'RE A COMPLICATED
HUMAN BEING,
NOT A CHEAP TIN CLOCK.
YOU CAN STAY OR LEAVE
AS YOU CHOOSE.
WELL ?
THAT'S TWICE
YOU INVITED ME TO LEAVE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND IF YOU KEEP ON PRETENDING
THAT YOU'RE A SLOW-WITTED
COUNTRY BOY, I'LL PUT YOU OUT !
YOU'RE PRETTY TOUGH, HUH ?
WELL, I CAN BE.
NOW WHY DON'T WE
GET DOWN TO BUSINESS ?
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP YOU
IF YOU'LL LET ME.
I'M NOT EXACTLY DROWNING.
WHAT KIND OF HELP ?
HOW DO I KNOW ?
ALL I KNOW ABOUT YOU IS WHAT
I HAVE IN THIS REPORT.
AND THAT ISN'T VERY MUCH.
NO, THAT'S MINE !
WHAT DOES IT SAY ?
CAN I SEE IT ?
NO.
WHAT IS SAYS...
WOULD STAGGER A BILLY GOAT.
I SEE YOU CAN SMILE TOO.
I'D LIKE TO APOLOGIZE
FOR BEING SO... HOSTILE.
THAT'S THE WORD, ISN'T IT ?
OH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU DIDN'T INVENT HOSTILITY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME
TO TALK ABOUT ?
ANYTHING AT ALL.
JUST TALK.
WHAT YOU SAY
WILL NEVER LEAVE THIS ROOM.
DO YOU BELIEVE ME ?
I THINK I DO.
YES, MA'AM.
IT'S LIKE I'M--
I'M ALWAYS WALKING AROUND
WITH A FULL CUP OF ANGER
TRYING NOT TO SPILL IT.
WHEN SOMEBODY HURTS ME,
I CAN'T HELP IT.  I WANNA
HURT 'EM RIGHT BACK.
I'VE LAID AWAKE MANY NIGHTS
WISHING MY PA WAS DEAD,
WISHING MY BROTHER
WAS DEAD.
HANK DIDN'T DIE, MA'AM,
BUT I TRIED TO KILL HIM.
I GOT THE MARK OF CAIN
ON ME, MA'AM.
I KNOW WHERE I'M GONNA
END UP AND NOT YOU NOR
ANYBODY ELSE CAN STOP IT.
[ Scoffs ]
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING, GLENN ?
ABOUT THE DREAMS
I USED TO HAVE.
OF MONEY, FAME.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU WANT ?
I COULD'VE BOUGHT MY MA
HER FREEDOM
WITH MONEY AND FAME.
"BOUGHT" ?
I DON'T QUITE FOLLOW THAT.
LISTEN, MA'AM,
MY MA WAS ENSLAVED
ON OUR FARM.
I DO MEAN ENSLAVED.
MANY TIMES
I'VE SEEN HER...
OUT IN THE HOT SUN
CHOPPING COTTON...
WHILE THEM TWO MEN
LAID UP DRUNK AND WASTED.
SHE DONE THE MEALS,
SHE DONE THE CHORES...
THAT HANK WOULDN'T DO
AND I COULDN'T.
AND THEN, THAT LADY--
AND SHE WAS A LADY, MA'AM--
SHE'D SOAK HER OLD STOCKINGS
IN BUTTERMILK...
AND PUT 'EM ON HER ARMS,
NOT TO BURN,
AND GO WORK IN THE SUN...
WHILE PA'S FISHING
THE RIVER
WITH A JUG BY HIS RUMP.
MY POINT, MA'AM--
MY POINT IS I'D HAVE
BOUGHT MA AWAY FROM THERE
IF I'D HAD THE CASH.
I'D HAVE BROUGHT HER
INTO TOWN,
GIVE HER A HOUSE LIKE THIS
ON A QUIET STREET,
AND SET HER ON THE PORCH
IN A ROCKING CHAIR...
AND LET HER WATCH
THE SEASONS COME AND GO.
FROM SPRINGTIME TILL SNOW,
SHE COULD RELISH IT ALL.
WHITE LILACS,
RHUBARB.
THAT'S THE QUIET
SORT OF THING SHE LIKED.
SHE COULD READ TOO.
READ FINE BOOKS.
BUT THERE WAS NEVER
THE TIME.
"OH, DEAR, THIS IS UNDONE
AND THAT'S UNDONE."
AND, "GLENN, WHERE'S
MY MIND GONE NOWADAYS ?"
SHE SAID I'D GO
TO COLLEGE TOO.
NOW THERE'S A LAUGH.
SHE WAS BUGGED ON LEARNING,
MA'AM.
AND THEN, JUST BEFORE
MY NINTH BIRTHDAY,
SHE DIED AND LEFT ME.
HER DEATH WAS A QUICK ONE.
DID YOU WANT
TO GO TO COLLEGE, GLENN ?
IF YOU DON'T MIND, MA'AM,
THE HEART'S OUT OF IT,
AND I'LL LEAVE.
COULD I COME BACK
ANOTHER TIME ?
OH, OF COURSE.
MONDAY, AROUND NOON ?
YES, MA'AM.
QUITTIN' TIME, GLENN.
SATURDAY NIGHT.
HERE'S YOUR PAY.
THERE YOU ARE.
WELL, WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND--
HIGH JINKS ?
TOO TIRED.  UNSEASONABLE
WEATHER.  WHEN YOU GONNA
PUT THAT SHOWER IN ?
UNTIL I DO, WHY DON'T YOU USE
THE BATH UPSTAIRS ?
COULD I ?
I SHOULD SAY YOU CAN.
ANY BOY WORKS THE WAY YOU DO
DESERVES THE BEST.
YOU KNOW, GLENN,
I KNOWED YOU WASN'T LAZY.
TOO MUCH SNAP IN THE EYES.
WHAT'S TO EAT ?
FRIED CHICKEN
LIKE YOU ASKED.
I DO AIM TO PLEASE.
GOOD.  ONE OF THESE DAYS
YOU'LL FIND YOURSELF A MAN
AND HE'LL SAY,
"YOUR PA SURE
TRAINED YOU RIGHT."
YEAH ?
WHAT'S THIS ?
I TOLD GLENN TO USE THE TUB
JUST TILL I GET THE SHOWER IN.
DOES IT GET TO USE
MY TOOTHBRUSH TOO ?
JUST MAKE SURE
YOU DON'T LEAVE NO RINGS
AROUND THAT TUB.
I GOT ENOUGH CHORES TO DO.
WHAT'S EATIN' ON YOU ?
YOU ASKIN'
TO BE CHASTISED AGAIN ?
IT'S TOO HOT.
STOP PICKIN' ON ME.
DON'T YOU
SEE HE'S A GODSEND TO YOU ?
HE'S A CLEAN DECENT BOY--
WHAT'S DECENT
ABOUT A TYLER ?
NEVER SEEN YOU SNUGGLING
UP TO HIS FOLKS ANY.
BE THAT AS IT MAY.
HE'S A GOOD DECENT BOY--
THAT GOOD DECENT BOY'S
BEEN HAYLOFTING
WITH BETTY LEE PARSONS.
THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE SAY.
YOU'RE GONNA LISTEN TO ME !
LAY OFF !  I'LL BE GONE
LIKE MA IF YOU DON'T QUIT.
THAT IS AN EVENTUALITY
WHICH WILL NOT EVENTUATE,
NORRIE.
YOU AIN'T GOT THE GUTS.
[ Baby Crying ]
YOU JUST WAIT AND SEE.
[ Crying ]
SHH.
BEER'S GOOD.
ENOUGH HOT WATER
IN THERE, GLENN ?
YEAH, THANKS, UNCLE ROLFE.
THANKS.
THERE'S A BOY
FULL OF THANKS.
HA !  STUPID
AND FULL OF THANKS.
ONLY I'M NOT STUPID !
NO, YOU'RE A BRAXTON.
YOU'RE NOT.
[ Crying Continues ]
STOP BITING YOUR NAILS.
I WASN'T.
WHAT TIME IS IT, PA ?
TIME ?
TEN TO 10:00.
NO NEED TO FRET, BETTY LEE.
HE'LL BE HERE.
THERE HE IS !
GOT A TRUCK, HUH ?
MORE THAN YOU HAD
AT HIS AGE AND TIME.
LISTEN, BETTY LEE--
EVENING, GLENN.
EVENING.  I'M SORRY I'M LATE.
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW TO GET SHED
OF UNCLE ROLFE.
HE LENT ME HIS PICKUP--
IT'S TOO LATE
FOR THE MOVIE SHOW NOW.
THE DRUGSTORE'S CLOSED TOO,
BUT THEY'LL BE OPEN
AT HI TENSION GROVE--
YOU YOUNGSTERS FIGHT IT OUT.
MAYBE JUST SIT.  LOVE'S
AN ENTERTAINMENT ALL BY ITSELF.
IT IS LOVE, ISN'T IT ?
MOTHER !
DON'T JUST SIT !
WE'LL NEVER GET AWAY.
DON'T BE MAD, BETTY LEE.
10:00 !
WANT TO HEAR SOME MUSIC ?
YOU'RE GONNA HEAR MUSIC
WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT.
IT WAS UNCLE ROLFE.
HE WANTED ME TO TAKE NORRIE
TO THE PICTURE SHOW.
HE KEPT WINKIN'
AND SWEATIN'.
I WAS EMBARRASSED.
THEN I HAD TO ASK HIM
TO LEND ME THIS TRUCK.
IT WAS AWKWARD.
THERE'S NO REASON TO SHOUT.
떰 [ Rock ]
떰
I LOOK AT YOU AND WHAM
I'M HEAD OVER HEELS
I GUESS THAT LOVE
IS A BANANA PEEL
I FEEL SO BAD AND YET
I'M FEELING SO WELL
I SLIPPED
I STUMBLED, I FELL
ONE CRAZY KISS AND BAM
I HEAD FOR THE SKIES
I GUESS THAT LOVE
IS LIKE A CAKE OF ICE
YOU SKATE ALONG BUT THEN
YOU NEVER CAN TELL
I SLIPPED
I STUMBLED, I FELL
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D GET KICKED BY
YOUR SWEET-TALKIN' LIES
YOU GOT A BAG OF TRICKS
AND WHEN YOU GOT BUSY
I GOT DAZZLED AND DIZZY
I FELL LIKE
A TON OF BRICKS
MY KNEES ARE WEAK
MY HEAD
IS SPINNIN' AROUND
I GUESS THAT LOVE HAS
TURNED ME UPSIDE DOWN
THOUGHT I'D GET HURT
BUT GEE
IT'S TURNING OUT SWELL
I SLIPPED
I STUMBLED, I FELL 떰
I DON'T LIKE THIS PLACE, CLIFF.
IT'S SO COMMON.
THE ONLY PLACE OPEN
THIS TIME OF NIGHT.
GO ASK THEM TO JOIN US
FOR A DRINK.
BETTY LEE, CLIFF MACY
WANTS YOU AND GLENN
TO HAVE A DRINK WITH HIM.
TELL HIM WE GOT A DRINK.
I'VE ALWAYS HATED CLIFF MACY
AFTER WHAT HE DID TO YOU.
AH, HATE'S LIKE A SNAKE
BITIN' ITS OWN TAIL.
WHAT'S HE GOT AGAINST YOU
ANYWAY ?
YOU FOR ONE.
IT SEEMS HIS FATHER'S MONEY
COULDN'T HELP HIM THERE.
BUT I NEVER THOUGHT HE'D
GO SO FAR AS TO LEND A CAR
AND THEN SAY I STOLE IT.
BUT IT FIGURES.
I ACTUALLY FEEL SORRY
FOR HIM SOMETIMES.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF WASTING SYMPATHY ON HIM.
SYMPATHY'S NEVER WASTED,
BETTY LEE.  ONE WAY
OR ANOTHER, YOU GET IT BACK.
OR SO IT SAYS
IN THE BOOK.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT'S THAT ?
THE WAY IT SAYS WE
OUGHTA BE, IN THE GOSPELS.
THE WAY WE ARE, IN FACT.
TURN THIS CHEEK, THAT CHEEK.
DON'T CAST THE FIRST STONE.
THAT'S FOR TALL ANGELS,
NOT FOR MEN.
NO, I DON'T SEE ANY WINGS
ON YOU.
THAT IS A FACT.
THERE IS A FACT.
HELLO, BETTY LEE,
GLENN TYLER.
HOW YOU ALL DOIN' ?
WE ALL DOIN' FINE
TILL YOU CRAWLED IN.
CRAWLED, DEAR BOY ?
YEAH, CRAWLED...
AS IN INSECT.
DON'T YOU GO CALLIN' US
NO INSECTS !
SHUT UP.
TYLER, I INVITED YOU
AND YOUR LADY COMPANION
TO JOIN US FOR A DRINK.
MY DATE, MISS MONICA GEORGE,
EXPRESSED A DESIRE
TO MEET YOU BOTH.
YOU'RE STONED
OUT OF YOUR MIND.
DON'T, YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE--
HEY, THE LADY'S REMINDING YOU
YOU'RE ON PAROLE.
AND MY REVERED,
DISTINGUISHED FATHER'S
A MEMBER OF THAT BOARD.
NOW LET'S ALL CALM DOWN
AND HAVE A DRINK.
SET 'EM UP, DACE.
DON'T YOU THINK I'M
FORGETTIN' CHRISTMAS NIGHT.
LET'S GO, BETTY LEE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF !
LADIES, I WANNA CONTINUE
MY CONFIDENTIAL CONVERSATION...
WITH MR. TYLER,
THE OL' AUTO THIEF.
LOOK HERE, BOY.
YOU PUT A BLACK MARK ON ME
I DIDN'T DESERVE.
I'M GIVIN' YOU A WARNING.
THE NEXT TIME YOU AND YOUR
FRIENDS COME LOOKIN' FOR ME,
I'M GONNA USE BOTH
YOUR HEADS,
ONE TO CRACK THE OTHER WITH.
WE GONNA HAVE
TO MESS HIM UP.
HAVE TO MESS HIM UP GOOD.
HEY, TYLER,
HOW'S YOUR COUSIN NORRIE
AND HER FAMILY INCREASE ?
HEY, TYLER !
THANK YOU, SARAH.
SO GO ON.
HE YELLED SOMETHING AT ME
AS I WAS LEAVING, BUT I DIDN'T
PAY ANY ATTENTION TO HIM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK'S WRONG
WITH HIM ?
HE LIKES TO TELL THE WORLD
HE'S HAD HIS TAIL KICKED.
NOBODY WANTS HIM, I GUESS.
MAYBE HIS FOLKS
DONE IT TO HIM.
BUT THE MACYS ARE
PRETTY WELL-OFF, YOU KNOW.
YES, I KNOW.
MONEY'S NO GUARANTEE
OF A HAPPY, NORMAL CHILDHOOD.
YOU TELL THAT TO
SOMEONE ELSE, MISS SPEERY.
IT'S MRS. SPEERY.
EXCUSE ME.
I'M TELLING IT TO YOU.
DON'T YOU THINK
THE TWO OF YOU MIGHT
HAVE SOMETHING IN COMMON ?
NOT AS I CAN SEE.
YOU'VE KINDA HAD
YOUR TAIL KICKED TOO.
[ Chuckles ]
I'LL HAVE TO CHEW
ON THAT A WHILE.
YOU KNOW,
A COUPLE YEARS BACK
I DECIDED TO KEEP A DIARY...
JUST LIKE A GIRL.
DIARY'S CAN BE
VERY PRODUCTIVE.
DID YOU EVER THINK OF WRITING
IN A SERIOUS WAY ?
WHAT MAKES YOU ASK THAT,
MA'AM ?
YOU TURN A PHRASE
A CERTAIN WAY.
AN IMAGE.
YOU COULD WRITE,
YOU KNOW.
I'D RATHER READ.
WHAT DO YOU READ ?
COMICS !
[ Laughing ]  I'D LIKE TO HAVE
PASSED OUT WHEN YOU ASKED MY PA
IF I READ COMICS.
I GOT SO MAD,
I COULD'VE THROWN YOU
RIGHT THROUGH THE DOOR.
PENCIL, PAD AND EVERYTHING.
THEY COULD'VE PUT ME
IN JAIL FOR 20 YEARS.
"WHO'S HE ?"
"AH, NOBODY, JUST READS COMICS
AND SUCKS A JUG."
YOU'RE NOT BEING FAIR.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU THEN.
YOU MADE ME SMALL THAT DAY.
DO YOU READ VERY MUCH ?
SOME.
DON'T YOU WANNA TALK ABOUT IT ?
IT MAKES ME VERY NERVOUS
TO TALK ABOUT IT, MA'AM.
SEE, I WAS HELPING AT HOME,
AND I WAS LATE
GETTIN' OUT OF HIGH SCHOOL.
SO BEING A YEAR BEHIND,
AND A HEAD TALLER
DIDN'T HELP ANY EITHER.
HMPH, EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE
I'D MENTION ABOUT...
HOW I WANTED TO WRITE.
YOU'D THINK I'D SET
A BLOW TORCH
TO THE AMERICAN FLAG.
WHAT'S A MAN FOR
IF HE CAN'T AIM HIGH ?
BUT--
BUT YOU GAVE UP.
I GUESS.
WELL, I GUESS
I'D BETTER BE ON MY WAY,
MA'AM.
I'VE GOT SOME MORE
DELIVERIES TO MAKE.
GLENN, WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THIS IDEA ?
THE THING THAT HAPPENED
AT HI TENSION GROVE LAST WEEK--
WRITE IT ALL DOWN
IN YOUR OWN WORDS
JUST AS YOU TOLD IT TO ME.
I CAN TRY.
YES.
ANY CERTAIN TIME
YOU'D LIKE TO HAVE IT ?
NO CERTAIN TIME.
WHENEVER IT'S FINISHED.
I HAVE TO THANK YOU, MA'AM,
FOR AN AWFUL LOT.
NO, YOU DON'T, GLENN.
NOT YET.
ROSE ?  COME ON, GIRL.
TIME FOR YOUR WALK.
HELLO, FLOSSIE.
HELLO, MRS. SPEERY.
ADMIRING YOUR HANDIWORK,
ARE YOU ?
SOMETHING NEW, AND VERY NICE.
HELLO, DAVIS.
A DISTINCT PLEASURE
TO SEE YOU, MRS. SPEERY.
THANK YOU, DAVIS, IT'S MUTUAL.
HAVE YOU TAKEN
YOUR BAR EXAM YET ?
NO, NOT UNTIL THE FALL.
YOU MUST COME MORE OFTEN.
I'VE BEEN NOTICING MR. MACY
WORKS TOO HARD.
YOU NOTICE TOO MUCH,
DAVIS.
I THINK HE'S RIGHT.
I DO WORK TOO HARD.
LET'S RELAX.
I'LL TRY A MARTINI.
I'LL TRY ONE TOO.
I DON'T THINK
I EVER MAKE A MARTINI
WITHOUT THINKING ABOUT US.
YOU DIDN'T ASK ME HERE
TO DISCUSS US, DID YOU ?
NO, BUT MAKE HAY
WHILE THE SUN SHINES.
THAT'S WHAT MY OLD DAD
USED TO SAY.
VERY DRY ?
VERY DRY.
OOH !
IRENE, I THINK
YOU'RE JUST AS LONELY
AS YOU EVER WERE.
I KNOW I AM.
HERE'S TO LONELINESS.
IF I LET MY WIFE DIVORCE ME,
I'D LOSE ALL THIS.
I'M JUST THE STEWARD
OF THE PLANTS AND MILLS
HER FATHER LEFT HER.
BUT I'D GLADLY GIVE IT ALL UP
IF YOU'LL MARRY ME.
NOT THAT WE'D EXACTLY STARVE,
YOU UNDERSTAND.
I WONDER IF YOU REALIZE
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
OF COURSE I DO !
I'LL GET A DIVORCE IF YOU SAY
YOU'LL MARRY ME.
I CAN'T BE ANY CLEARER.
YOU'RE SAYING
IF I MAKE THE DECISION,
YOU'LL GET A DIVORCE.
YOU WON'T MAKE THE DECISION,
BUT YOU'LL LEAVE IT UP TO ME,
AND I DON'T THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S AS THOUGH
YOU WERE USING ME.
USING YOU ?
THAT'S WHAT
IT BOILS DOWN TO.
LIKE A LEVER TO
PRY YOURSELF OUT OF
AN IMPOSSIBLE SITUATION.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE BEING
QUITE HONEST WITH YOURSELF.
I THINK YOU'RE JUST AFRAID.
YOUR OWN FIRST MARRIAGE
WAS SUCH AN IMPOSSIBLE--
I DON'T WANT
TO DISCUSS THAT.
WELL, THINK ABOUT IT,
WILL YOU ?
BRING THAT FINE ANALYTICAL
MIND OF YOURS TO BEAR
ON YOUR OWN PROBLEMS TOO.
PHYSICIAN,
HEAL THYSELF ?
THAT'S THE GENERAL IDEA.
YOU'RE ASKING THE IMPOSSIBLE.
PHIL, WHY DID YOU
INVITE ME HERE ?
I WANTED TO TALK ABOUT
MY SON CLIFF.
MAY WE DISCUSS HIM
FOR A MOMENT ?
OF COURSE.
IT'S HIS MOTHER.
YOU KNOW SHE'S
AS LOOSE-FOOTED AS EVER.
SHE SPOILED THE BOY ROTTEN.
SHE'S GOT HIM HEADIN' DOWN
THE SAME ROAD AS HERSELF.
ONLY IN HIS CASE,
IT MIGHT BE A FATAL ROAD.
FATAL ?  HOW ?
WELL, NO ONE KNOWS THIS,
BUT HIS MOTHER AND ME.
CLIFF HAS WHAT'S KNOWN
AS AN "ATHLETIC HEART."
TOO MUCH OF EVERYTHING
TOO FAST.
I'VE TAKEN HIM TWICE
TO THE SPECIALIST
IN WASHINGTON,
BUT IN SPITE OF IT,
HE'S DRINKING LIKE A FISH,
RUNNING WILD, IN FACT.
WOULD YOU TRY
TO STRAIGHTEN HIM OUT ?
I DON'T THINK
THAT WOULD BE WISE.
BECAUSE OF US, YOU MEAN ?
EXACTLY !  I'D HAVE
TO TALK ABOUT HIS MOTHER
AND HIS FATHER.
HOW OBJECTIVE AND HONEST
DO YOU THINK I COULD BE ?
NOT VERY, I GUESS.
I WILL LOOK INTO IT,
AND I'LL SEE IF I CAN FIND
SOMEONE GOOD.
THANKS.
HELL, I SUPPOSE I'M JUST
LOOKIN' FOR SOME WAY...
TO TRY TO BRING YOU AND ME
TOGETHER AGAIN.
I'M SORRY, PHIL.
I REALLY AM.
THAT'S ABOUT THE SIZE OF IT.
I SNAPPED MY FINGERS
THIS AFTERNOON,
AND UP GOES A NEW FACTORY...
AND IT DOESN'T MEAN A THING.
GOOD-BYE, IRENE.
BYE.
WHERE HAS IT BEEN
THIS LATE ?
IT TOOK UNCLE ROLFE TO
THE BOWLING ALLEY.  YOU KNOW
VERY WELL WHERE I'VE BEEN.
PLAN TO DRAW
YOUR OWN BATH ?
OLD SEMINOLE.
YOUR PA'S GONNA WHIP YOUR TAIL.
THAT STUFF WOULD PICKLE
A SNAKE.
WHAT EVER HAPPENED
TO THAT OLD MEXICAN GUITAR
THAT YOUR MOTHER HAD ?
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE SHE GAVE US BOTH LESSONS.
YEAH.  SHE WAS
A REAL GOOD SINGER TOO.
HANK STEPPED ON THAT GUITAR
ON PURPOSE.
HE'S A MEAN ONE.
ALMOST AS MEAN AS YOU ARE.
ALL YOU THINK'S ABOUT YOURSELF.
I JUST LIKE TO MIND
MY OWN BUSINESS.
WELL THEN, GO ON, GO TO BED
AND MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
MOVE YOUR FAT LEGS.
I WISH YOUR PA'D PUT
THAT SHOWER IN.
IT'S HOT.
HE WON'T PUT THAT SHOWER IN.
WHY WON'T HE PUT
THAT SHOWER IN ?
PA HOPES TO CATCH US
ONE OF THESE NIGHTS.
US-- YOU AND ME,
TOGETHER IN SIN.
THAT'S HIS PLANS.
THEN YOU'LL HAVE TO MARRY ME.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR HUSBAND ?
YOU ARE STUPID.
COST PA TWO BUCKS,
THAT DID.
떰 [ Strumming ]
I MAY NOT BE HERE
TOMORROW
BUT I'M CLOSE BESIDE YOU
TODAY
SO LIE TO ME A LITTLE
SAY YOU LOVE ME A LOT
AND I'LL BE TRUE TO YOU
IN MY WAY
LOVE NEVER GOES ON
FOREVER
AT LEAST THAT'S WHAT
WISE MEN ALL SAY
SO SMILE
WHEN YOU KISS ME
TOMORROW YOU MAY CRY
BUT I'LL BE TRUE TO YOU
IN MY WAY
YES, I'LL BE TRUE TO YOU
IN MY WAY 떰
I'M GOING TO BED.
OH, NO, DON'T GO.
PA WON'T BE BACK TILL 1:00.
DON'T BAIT ME.  MIGHT
GET YOURSELF IN TROUBLE.
I WON'T TELL A WORD,
I PROMISE.
I WANNA GET OUTTA HERE.
I'M YOUNG.
I WANT A GOOD TIME OUT OF LIFE.
THEN PAINT YOUR TOENAILS
RED AND RUN AWAY.
IT NEEDS A MAN
TO GO TO HELL WITH,
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
HOURS AND HOURS OF HEAVEN
THAT JUST SLIDES
ON DOWN TO HELL,
AND WE DON'T CARE HOW
OR WHEN IT ENDS.
YOU'RE WILD, GLENN,
JUST LIKE ME.
UNHAPPY WILD !
PA'S GOT SOME MONEY STASHED,
AND HE HIDES IT LIKE
A HOPPITY LITTLE SQUIRREL.
WE COULD TAKE A SLICE
OF THAT MONEY AND RUN AWAY.
NOBODY WOULD KNOW.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T RUN AWAY
RIGHT NOW.  I GOT PLANS.
I WANT YOU, GLENN !
AND I MEAN WANT,
EVER SINCE WE WENT WADIN'
IN FELTCHER'S CREEK.
I KNOW I WAS ONLY 12--
YOU'VE DONE A LOT OF WADIN'
SINCE THEN.
I WANTED YOU EVEN THEN !
THERE'S NOTHING
I WOULDN'T DO FOR YOU.
JUST ASK AND SEE.
IS THAT WHY YOU TREATED ME
LIKE DIRT ALL THESE YEARS ?
YOU THINK I'M NO GOOD,
DON'T YOU ?
NO.
WHO'S THAT ?
IT'S DACE.
TURN THOSE LIGHTS OFF.
[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
THE LIQUOR STORE'S CLOSED.
CLIFF WANTS TO GET A COUPLE
BOTTLES OF BRAXTON'S STUFF.
SELL THAT.  PA USUALLY DOES.
WHY DON'T YOUR BOSS MAN
COME GET IT HIMSELF ?
I'M RIGHT HERE, TYLER.
SORRY TO INTERRUPT SUCH
A CHARMING DOMESTIC SCENE.
TWO BOTTLES, DEAR BOY.
[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
WHEN YOU COMIN' OUT
OF DEEP FREEZE, NORRIE ?
I'M A MARRIED LADY NOW.
CALL ME MRS. MARTIN.
[ Chuckling ]
WELL, BLESS YOUR BLACK
LITTLE HEART.
DON'T MARRIED FOLKS
GET LONELY TOO ?
YOU OFFEND OLD FRIENDS
BY YOUR PROTRACTED ABSENCE.
DON'T RUSTICATE TOO LONG,
MY DEAR.
I CAN'T MAKE CHANGE.
YOU KEEP YOURSELF
THAT CHANGE.
MAYBE BUY YOURSELF
SOME CUFF LINKS OR SUCH.
SOMEDAY YOU MAY EVEN
OWN A SHIRT.
[ Laughing ]
SOMEDAY I MAY STUFF IT
DOWN YOUR THROAT... DEAR BOY.
[ Laughing ]
GIVE THAT TO YOUR PA.
GOOD NIGHT...
MRS. MARTIN.
GOOD NIGHT.
SHH, SHH, SHH.
UH, MA'AM ?
SHH !
WELL.
I GUESS THE GRAMMAR
AND SPELLING ARE PRETTY BAD.
PRETTY BAD.
ARE THE CHARACTERS HERE
REAL PEOPLE ?
YES, MA'AM.
I DO KINDA MIX 'EM UP THOUGH,
DON'T I ?
I MEAN, I GUESS YOU SHOULD
KNOW RIGHT AWAY IF PEOPLE...
BELONG UP WITH THE ANGELS
OR DOWN IN THE
FIRE AND BRIMSTONE, HUH ?
SHOULD YOU ?
TAKE FOR INSTANCE BETTY LEE.
AT TIMES I LOOK AT HER
AND I THINK... SHE'S FLAT
AND DRIED UP...
AND SELFISH.
AND THEN AGAIN I THINK
SHE'S WARM AND UNSELFISH.
WHAT ABOUT THIS CHARACTER,
NORRIE ?
SHE WASN'T AT THE GROVE.
I JUST WROTE HER IN.
THAT'S A WRITER'S PRIVILEGE.
I EVEN GET MIXED UP
ABOUT NORRIE TOO.
SHE SAYS
SHE'LL HAVE ME ANY WAY--
PLAIN, FRIED OR SCRAMBLED.
AND I ADMIT THAT
I AM TEMPTED AT TIMES,
LIKE AT NIGHT WHEN
UNCLE ROLFE'S OFF
AT THE POKER GAMES.
BUT I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT NORRIE.
IN FACT, PROPER FOLKS
WOULD SAY SHE'S
JUST DOWNRIGHT NO GOOD.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY ?
YOU KNOW ME, MA'AM.
I'M NOT PROPER FOLKS.
NORRIE NEVER HAD A CHANCE.
HER MA RAN OUT ON UNCLE ROLFE
ABOUT FIVE OR SIX YEARS AGO.
HE'S TAKEN IT OUT ON NORRIE
EVER SINCE.
BUT SHE GOT AROUND HIM...
ONE TIME.
SHE GOT LOST OVER THE WEEKEND
WITH THIS FIFTH AVENUE
NEW YORK-TYPE SALESMAN.
HE CAME THROUGH
IN THIS BIG, NEW, SHINY CAR.
I PRETEND
LIKE I DON'T KNOW.
BUT I KNOW.
THAT BABY'S FATHER HAS
A BIG, GREEN CONVERTIBLE.
[ Chuckling ]
THAT'S THE WAY IT IS.
I DON'T LIKE TO SOUND
LIKE I'M BRAGGIN', BUT...
IT'S LIKE I GOT TWO GIRLS
WITH TWO ROADS TO GO.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN ?
YES, I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
GLENN, HAVE YOU EVER THOUGHT
THERE MIGHT BE A THIRD ROAD ?
WHAT'S THAT, MA'AM ?
WHAT YOUR MOTHER WANTED
FOR YOU-- COLLEGE.
WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT ?
THIS DOES, YOUR STORY.
GLENN, HAVE YOU ANY IDEA
HOW GOOD THIS IS ?
HOW MUCH PROMISE IT SHOWS ?
DO YOU REALLY MEAN THAT ?
I MEAN, YOU YOURSELF SAID
THE GRAMMAR AND SPELLING...
WAS PRETTY BAD.
SPELLING AND GRAMMAR--
THAT CAN BE TAUGHT,
BUT THIS HAS SOMETHING
THAT CAN'T BE TAUGHT.
IT HAS SUCH BEAUTY AND POWER
AND EXCITEMENT !
IT JUMPS RIGHT OFF THE PAGE !
ALL YOU NEED IS DISCIPLINE,
FORMAL EDUCATION.
NO MATTER HOW OR WHAT,
YOU'VE GOT TO GO TO COLLEGE.
IT'S NOT THAT EASY.
IT TAKES MONEY TO GO TO COLLEGE.
YOU KNOW THAT.
THERE'S SUCH THINGS
AS SCHOLARSHIPS.
LOOK, WHAT I'LL DO--
LET ME MAKE A SUGGESTION.
TAKE THIS HOME AND REWRITE IT,
POLISH IT UP A BIT.
THEN I'LL SHOW IT TO A FRIEND
AT THE STATE UNIVERSITY.
HE'LL TAKE IT--
LET A LOT OF PEOPLE READ IT,
STRANGERS ?
OF COURSE.  SOONER OR--
I DIDN'T WRITE THAT
FOR ANYBODY ELSE TO READ,
JUST YOU.
YOU AND ME.
THEN YOU WANNA BE AN ERRAND BOY
ALL YOUR LIFE ?
OR SLOP HOGS ON SOME FARM ?
YOU TOLD ME YOU WANTED
TO BE A WRITER,
NOW BE ONE !
SUPPOSE YOU'RE WRONG.
SUPPOSE THEY START
LAUGHING AT ME AGAIN.
YOU TAKE THAT CHANCE.
WHERE ARE YOUR GUTS, GLENN ?
I'M AN IGNORANT COUNTRY BOY,
REMEMBER ?
OH, STOP BOASTING !
ALL OF A SUDDEN ALL
THAT STUFF ABOUT MY BEING
A WRITER, GOING TO COLLEGE.
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING
TO DO TO ME ?
TO WAKE YOU UP, OPEN YOUR EYES.
IS THAT WHAT THE PAROLE BOARD
TOLD YOU TO DO ?
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO HELP ME,
NOT RILE ME UP
LIKE A MUDDY CREEK,
TAKE MY LIFE AND TWIST IT
INTO SOMETHING YOU WANT.
NOT ME, MA'AM, NOT ME.
IT SEEMS TO ME
YOU'RE OVERSTEPPING.
I HAD NO IDEA.
I'M SORRY, MA'AM.
I HAD NO RIGHT
TO PUT HARSH WORDS ON YA.
WILL YOU AT LEAST CONSIDER
WHAT I'VE SAID
UNTIL WE MEET NEXT FRIDAY ?
YES, MA'AM.
SOMETHING'S BURNING.
IT SMELLS.
I HOPE THAT GIRL'S
WATCHING DINNER.
YOU EVER WANNA FLY ?
NO.
KINDA BREEZY UP THERE.
YES.
HERE, HOLD THIS.
[ Glenn ]
FEEL THAT PULL.
WHOOP !
LIKE ME ?
L-O-V-E YOU.
BACK TO THE HOUSE,
BETTY LEE.
YOU GET OFF THIS PROPERTY,
SON, KITE AND ALL !
DADDY, DON'T BE MAD.
I'M SORRY, SIR,
IF YOU THINK--
I'VE NOT THE SLIGHTEST
CONCERN WHAT YOU THINK.
GET BACK TO YOUR FOLKS
IN THEIR WALLOW.
YOU'RE ALL A LOT OF PIGS.
DADDY, STOP !
IF YOU HAVE SOMETHING TO SAY--
YOU DIDN'T COME TO CHURCH.
GET TO THE HOUSE, AND HELP
YOUR MA PUT DINNER ON.
NO CHILD OF MINE
GETS TAUGHT UNGODLY THINGS
ON THE SABBATH OR ANY OTHER DAY.
YOU COULD FIND MORE GODLINESS
HERE IN THIS SUN AND AIR
THAN IN THAT CHURCH OF YOURS.
DON'T YOU COME
AROUND HERE AGAIN.
I'LL NOT HAVE IT.
WHERE'S GOD ?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE TAKES A BOY LIKE MY SON
OFF IN THE WAR,
AND LEAVES A LOAFER
AND BRAGGART LIKE YOU ALIVE.
GLENN--
[ Gasps ]
GLENN !
NORRIE, YOU BEEN
TOUCHING MY STOCK
IN ANY SHAPE OR WAY ?
YOU THINK I NEED A TONIC ?
THINK IT MIGHT BE GLENN ?
I DON'T KNOW.
HOW ARE THINGS COMIN'
BETWEEN YOU AND HIM ?
PA, IT TAKES TWO TO WALTZ.
BESIDES, HE DON'T MEAN DUST
TO ME.
YOU GET IT FIXED ?
I GIVE UP THE IDEA.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GONNA TRY AND FIX IT.
I GIVE IT UP !
GLENN, ACCORDING
TO MY COUNT, THERE'S
CONSIDERABLE STOCK MISSING.
YOU KNOW ANYTHING
OF ITS WHEREABOUTS ?
NO, EXCEPT FOR THE TWO BOTTLES
CLIFF MACY BOUGHT
SOME WEEKS AGO.
SUPPOSE NORRIE'S
BEEN TIPPLIN' ?
WOULDN'T KNOW, UNCLE ROLFE.
WELL, ON MY WAY.
WHY DO YOU LEAVE THAT
SAFE DOOR OPEN EVERY NIGHT ?
SO IF ANYONE WANTS TO THIEVE,
HE'LL SEE THERE'S NOTHING THERE
TO BE THIEVED !
[ Laughing ]
CUTE, AIN'T IT ?
OH, I'LL BE HOME AROUND
1:00 OR 2:00.  POKER NIGHT.
LOCK ME OUT, SON.
THANKS...
FOR NOT TELLIN' PA.
WHAT'S IN THAT STUFF
THAT MAKES IT SMELL
LIKE THAT ?
BANANA OIL.
THAT'S A JOKE.
IT'S NO JOKE.
BANANA OIL.
IS THERE ENOUGH HOT WATER ?
MM-HMM.
WILL YOU SHUT THAT DOOR ?
I WANT IT OPEN.
I SAID I WANT
THAT DOOR SHUT !
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Barking ]
MISS IRENE ?
TURN OFF THE LIGHT.
[ Glenn ]
OH, MRS. SPEERY ?
MRS. SPEERY ?
I WANT MY STORY BACK,
PLEASE.
MRS. SPEERY !
DIDN'T THAT LIGHT GO OFF ?
HMM ?
I DID-- I DID SEE
A LIGHT, DIDN'T I ?
NO, YOU DREAMED IT, HON.
NO, I DIDN'T DREAMED IT,
HON.
YES, YOU DID.
I, I WANT IT BACK.
I WANT MY STORY BACK,
MRS. SPEERY.
IT'S THAT TYLER BOY,
STONED.
STONED IS AN UNDERSTATEMENT.
MRS. SPEERY ?
MRS. SPEERY !
WELL, WHAT DO YOU KNOW.
I WANT YOU, I WANT YOU,
I WANT YOU TO MEET
MRS. SPEERY.
I DON'T WANNA MEET
COME ON,
WE'RE GONNA WAKE UP
THE WHOLE NEIGHBORHOOD.
WAIT A MINUTE.
COME ON !
IT'S TOO HOT ANYWAY.
IS IT TOO HOT ?
YES.
WELL, WE'LL COOL IT OFF
A LITTLE BIT.
[ Water Running ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN', GLENN ?
I'M GONNA, I'M GONNA,
I'M GONNA HOSE AWAY
THE HEAT.
MRS. SPEERY ?
WHAT ABOUT IT,
IRENE... SPEERY-EERIE-EERIE ?
[ Noreen ]
GIVE ME THE HOSE.
I WONDER IF THIS PORCH STUFF
IS RAINPROOF.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
WHAT'S HE DOING NOW ?
HOSING DOWN THE PORCH.
COME ON !
ALL RIGHT.
NO DESIRE TO MONOPOLIZE
YOUR TIME, MA'AM.
SHE DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT ME ANYWAY.
[ Glenn ]  LET HER
SNOOZE HER LIFE AWAY.
I DON'T CARE.
COME ON !
GOOD-BYE,
MRS. SPEERY-EERIE-EERIE.
BYE.
NO, NO, NO, WAIT.
I WANNA COOL OFF.
WAIT A MINUTE.
LET'S COOL--
GIMME SOME.
[ Squeals ]
SURE !
NO !  NO, NO, NO, NO !
OH, YOU !
GLENN !
- HELLO, GLENN.
- MA'AM.
HAVE YOU BEEN WORKING HARD ?
WHAT DOES IT LOOK LIKE ?
YOU SAID YOU WANTED
YOUR STORY BACK.
HERE IT IS.
I'M SORRY ABOUT LAST NIGHT,
MA'AM.
BUT I DON'T WANNA COME
TO THOSE MEETINGS ANYMORE.
THAT'S YOUR PRIVILEGE.
BUT I'D LIKE TO KNOW WHY.
LET'S JUST SAY
I'M NOT WORTH IT.
YOU'RE WHAT ?
I SAID
I'M NOT WORTH IT !
I DISAGREE WITH YOU.
DIDN'T YOU HEAR ME ?
WHAT AM I TALKING TO--
THE DOOR ?
ALL THAT STUFF YOU TELL ME
GOES IN ONE EAR
AND OUT THE OTHER.
YOU MEAN, THERE'S NO BRAIN
IN YOUR HEAD TO STOP IT ?
SURELY, GLENN,
YOU REALIZE YOU'RE GIFTED.
I DON'T CARE TO BE GIFTED.
IT'S TOO HARD,
IT'S TOO MUCH WORK.
A PERSON WHO'S GIFTED
GETS KNOCKED AROUND AND
I'VE BEEN KNOCKED AROUND ENOUGH.
IF WE WERE ALL AFRAID
TO BE KNOCKED AROUND,
THERE'D BE NO GREAT MEN.
WE'D HAVE NO SCHOLARS,
NO SCIENTISTS, NO ARTISTS,
NO MOVERS AND SHAKERS.
[ Scoffs ]
GET THIS, NORRIE.
THIS OUGHTA BE GOOD.
WHAT'S THAT MOVERS
AND SHAKERS ROUTINE, MA'AM ?
THOSE WHO
OVERCOME HANDICAPS,
WHO LIVE TO MOVE
AND SHAKE THE WORLD.
SHAKE IT OUT OF ITS
ALLIGATOR SLEEP AND MOVE
PEOPLE OUT OF THE SWAMPS !
SHE MEANS LIKE JESUS, GLENN.
YES... I MEAN LIKE JESUS,
GLENN.
[ Whistles ]
FLINGS THEM WORDS AROUND
LIKE HASH.
WHAT DID
SHE COME HERE FOR ?
WHERE'S YOUR EARS ?
I DON'T NEED EARS TO KNOW
WHAT SHE WANTS FROM YOU.
NO, I DON'T !
WOULD YOU GET YOUR MIND
OUT OF THE GUTTER ONCE ?
IT DON'T DO NO GOOD.
JUST GOES RIGHT BACK DOWN AGAIN.
SURE A BEAUTY.
LEAST THING A MAN CAN DO FOR
HIS ONLY CHILD ON HER BIRTHDAY.
WHY, NORRIE,
YOU LOOK PRETTY AS A BRIDE.
THANK YOU, PA.
BEING AS PA GOT ME
THAT NEW GUITAR,
I THOUGHT YOU'D LIKE MY OLD ONE.
COME ON, YOU KIDS.
IT'S A BIG NIGHT,
AND IT'S ALL ON ME.
NORRIE.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
THANK YOU.
FOLKS BORN IN JULY,
THEY'RE HOME-LOVIN', THEY SAY.
COME ON NOW.
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU,
MR. BRAXTON.
EVENIN', REVEREND.
GLENN, YOUNG LADY.
[ Excited Chattering ]
A DOLLAR'S WORTH FOR ME.
A DOLLAR ?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU GO ENJOY YOURSELVES.
I'LL CATCH UP.
TWO FOR A NICKEL, SIR.
THANK YOU.OLKS.
COME ON.  OH, TOO BAD.
DON'T GO AWAY MATHERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE.
SUPPOSED TO KNOCK IT
OFF THE BARREL.
NEXT TIME.
STICK AROUND.
OKAY.
TOO BAD.
LET'S GO.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Squeals ]  THANK YOU.
YOU WIN A BIG DOG,
A BIG DOGGIE.
STEP RIGHT UP.
STEP RIGHT UP, FOLKS.
IT'S FIXED.
HOW 'BOUT YOU, LADIES ?
JUST ONE BALL ?
[ Balloon Pops ]
CAN I, PLEASE ?
SURE.
THE LORD IS GOOD TO GIVE US
AN OCCASIONAL EVENING LIKE THIS.
EVENING, MR. MASON.
EVENING, MR. BRAXTON.
NOW, THERE'S A THING.
HE SAVED HIMSELF
USED POSTAGE STAMPS ALL THE WAY
BACK TO CONFEDERATE DAYS.
A COUPLE OF THOSE
GRAPE DRINKS, PLEASE.
YES, SIR.
POOR KID.
BEIN' HER BIRTHDAY,
I BEEN HOLDING IT BACK ALL DAY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO BREAK IT TO HER NEITHER.
HOLDIN' BACK WHAT ?
WELL, THE NEWS ABOUT
NORRIE'S HUSBAND PASSIN' AWAY.
WHAT'S YOUR PLANS, GLENN ?
IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY SAYIN' SO, UNCLE ROLFE,
YOU'RE JUMPIN' LIKE A CRICKET.
NO, I'M AS CONTINUOUS
AS BEADS ON A STRING.
AND IF YOU AND NORRIE--
YOU CAME TOGETHER--
I'D MAKE YOU A PARTNER
IN MY PLACE.
YOU KNOW THE BUSINESS NOW,
AND, WELL--
IF I WAS YOU, I'D GIVE THIS
THING A DECENT TIME OF GRIEF.
WELL, THAT'S A POINT.
BUT IF I COULD SOFTEN THE BLOW,
WHICH IT'S SURE TO BE TO NORRIE,
BY JUST TELLING HER TONIGHT
THAT YOU'VE GOT MATRIMONY
ON YOUR MIND--
HOW'D HER HUSBAND DIE ?
THAT'S THE FUNNY PART.
THE TELEGRAM DON'T SAY.
ALL THAT HUSH-HUSH
GOVERNMENT STUFF THESE DAYS.
YEAH, I'VE SEEN
A LOT OF IT ON TV.
YOU'RE NOT HINTIN'
THAT THIS IS FICTION, ARE YOU ?
I'M SAYIN', DON'T BOX ME IN,
UNCLE ROLFE.
YOU LISTEN TO ME, BOY.
YOU ARE BOXED IN, AND THAT'S
GOSPEL, BUT NOT BY ME.
YOU TOOK NORRIE
LIKE A CHEAP POSTAGE STAMP.
YOU GOT HER DRUNK,
LICKED, SMACKED AND CANCELLED
HER ALL OVER THE PLACE.
YOU DENY MY ALLEGATIONS ?
I WASN'T EXACTLY ALONE,
YOU KNOW.
ARE YOU SAYING YOU DIDN'T--
LOOK, UNCLE ROLFE,
YOU WASN'T KIDDIN' ME.
YOU HAD THIS
IN YOUR MIND ALL ALONG.
YOU'RE A RATTY LITTLE LIAR !
DON'T SAY IT !  THAT MAKES ME--
WHEN THE PAROLE BOARD
HEARS ABOUT THIS--
[ All Gasp, Exclaim ]
WHERE'S THAT BOY ?
GET THAT TYLER BOY !
YOU ALL RIGHT ?  WHAT HAPPENED ?
HE DELIBERATELY SHOVED
AND PUSHED ME DOWN.
CALL THE POLICE !
ARE YOU HURT, MR. BRAXTON ?
OH, I-- I ACHE BAD.
I ACHE VERY BAD.
HAD A BAD FIGHT
WITH UNCLE ROLFE,
BROKE MY PAROLE.
THEY'LL PROBABLY SAY
I STOLE HIS PICKUP TRUCK TOO.
THEY'LL TAKE HIS WORD FOR IT,
AND I'LL GO TO JAIL
FOR TWO OR THREE YEARS.
THE ONLY THING I CAN SEE NOW
IS TO RUN, GET OUT OF STATE.
BELIEVE ME, I'D JUST AS SOON
GET OUT OF THE WORLD TOO--
I-I-I'M THAT ANGUISHED.
TAKE A TRIP TO THE MOON,
YOU MEAN, OR HANG YOURSELF--
WHICH ?
HOW YOU EXAGGERATE THINGS,
GLENN.
LOOK, DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND ?
SYMPATHY IS WHAT I NEED,
NOT SERMONS.
YOU CAN'T BUILD ON SYMPATHY.
THERE'S NO BONES TO IT.
NOW, INSTEAD OF SPLUTTERING
LIKE A WET FIRECRACKER,
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO ?
WELL, BETTY LEE,
I DON'T HAVE THE RIGHT TO ASK.
IT'S ABOUT NORRIE.
IT'S A TRICK.
HER PA SAYS I GOT TO MARRY HER.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR THAT.
BE HONEST SOME OTHER TIME.
I'M SORRY FOR NORRIE,
FOR YOU TOO.
I'M SORRY FOR MYSELF
THAT I LOVE YOU, GLENN.
IT WON'T STOP.
AND YOU'RE WILD AND UNSETTLED,
LIKE A PORCUPINE
THAT CAN'T BE HELD.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'LL NEVER MAKE A PET.
YOU THINK YOU COULD
SCRAPE UP 20 OR 30 DOLLARS
TO GET ME OUT OF HERE ?
I CAN, BUT THEY'LL
CATCH YOU ANYWAY.
WELL, THAT'S MY RISK.
I'D GO SOMEWHERES FAR AWAY
AND NEVER HURT
OR BOTHER YOU AGAIN.
I NEVER SAID YOU HURT ME.
LISTEN, WILL YOU
GET ME THE MONEY ?
DON'T YOU THINK IT MIGHT BE
BETTER TO STAY RIGHT HERE
AND FIGHT--
FIGHT FOR
YOUR REAL-BORN RIGHTS ?
HOW ?
COME IN THE HOUSE,
AND WE'LL PHONE.
WHO WILL WE PHONE ?
MRS. SPEERY, FOR A START.
COME ON.
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
NOT ONLY MYSELF, BUT TWO OTHERS
ON THE BOARD FEEL YOU'RE BEING
UNDULY HARSH WITH THE BOY.
DR. UNDERWOOD AND--
YEAH ?
WHO'S THE OTHER ?
MRS. SPEERY'S WORKING
WITH GLENN IN HER OWN FIELD.
THAT'S NEITHER HERE NOR THERE.
THAT BOY'S MORALS
MAKE MY BLOOD RUN COLD.
ON TOP OF THAT, HE STEALS
MY PICKUP TRUCK, AND I'M GONNA
HAVE TO HAVE X RAYS.
THEN YOU MEAN
TO PRESS CHARGES ?
I DO.
I'D RATHER YOU DIDN'T,
MR. BRAXTON.
NOW, YOU LOOK HERE.
DON'T YOU COME IN HERE
HIGH AND MIGHTY,
TRYING TO BLACKMAIL ME.
BLACKMAIL'S AN UGLY WORD,
BUT LET'S EXPLORE
THE POSSIBILITIES.
A RECENTLY WIDOWED CLIENT
OF MINE-- I ADVISED HER
TO DROP THE CASE.
YOU SOLD HER SEVERAL HUNDRED
DOLLARS WORTH OF BOTTLED TOBACCO
JUICE CALLED BERMUDA BALM.
YOU CLAIMED IT WAS
A CURE FOR CANCER.
YOU CAN'T PROVE THAT.
CAN'T I ?
CROOKED TRANSACTIONS
SHOULD ALWAYS BE IN CASH.
SHE'S GOT HER CANCELLED CHECKS
AND A WITNESS-- HER COOK.
LIFE'S GOT
ITS SHADOWS ENOUGH, BRAXTON.
LIVE AND LET LIVE.
YOUR TRUCK'LL BE
RETURNED TOMORROW.
I'M GLAD YOU GOT BEAT, PA.
YOU DON'T PEDDLE ME
LIKE YOUR NO-ACCOUNT BELLY WASH.
[ Sobbing ]
GLENN !
OH, I WAS JUST TYPING UP
THE BILL, MR. LONGSTREET.
GREASE ME UP, GLENN.
I'M GOIN' OVER TO THE ACME
FOR A BITE.
[ Giggles ]
[ Chuckles ]
OH, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T SEE YA.
I-I BROUGHT YOUR GUITAR.
IS YOUR PA STILL MAD AT ME ?
"MAD" IS A KIND WORD
FOR WHAT HE FEELS.
YOU DON'T HOLD IT
AGAINST ME, DO YOU ?
OF COURSE NOT, NORRIE.
AND YOU WARNED ME.
YOU ALWAYS TELL ME THE TRUTH.
I CAN'T LIE TO YOU,
AND I CAN'T PRETEND.
GLENN, I MISSED YOU
SOMETHIN' AWFUL !
DON'T I GET TO SEE YOU
ANYMORE ?
I DON'T THINK IT WOULD
DO EITHER OF US ANY GOOD.
IT'D DO ME GOOD
FOR SURE.
YOU REMEMBER WHAT YOU SAID
ABOUT US BEING WILD--
UNHAPPY AND WILD ?
UH-HUH.
WELL, YOU NEED SOMEBODY
WHO'S MORE SETTLED, SOMEONE
WITH THEIR FEET ON THE GROUND.
ME-- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I NEED.
BUT--
BUT IT AIN'T ME.
I DIDN'T SAY THAT, NORRIE.
I CAN GET ALONG
NOT BEING NEEDED.
I JUST NEED YOU, GLENN.
I DON'T MEAN MARRIAGE.
I KNOW I'M NOT THAT GOOD.
AW, STOP TALKIN' LIKE THAT.
THAT'S YOUR PA'S WORDS.
IT'S NOT MY PA'S WORDS !
DON'T LET HIM
BEAT YOUR WINGS DOWN.
YOU AIM TO FLY
WAY UP ABOVE ME.
BUT IF YOU EVER COME
TUMBLIN' DOWN,
I CAN WAIT.
GOOD-BYE, GLENN.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
UH, IS MRS. SPEERY HOME ?
SHE'LL BE HERE IN A MINUTE.
YOU CAN SIT AND WAIT
IF YOU LIKE.
NOT IN THERE.
IN THE LIVING ROOM.
I'M WAXING THE STUDY FLOOR.
DON'T BREAK ANYTHING.
HELLO, MRS. SPEERY.
GLENN.
HOW NICE TO SEE YOU.
THANK YOU.
YOU BEEN OUT
TO THE PENITENTIARY AGAIN ?
YES.
IT'S BEEN ONE OF THOSE
LONG MORNINGS.
HOW'S YOUR NEW JOB
WORKING OUT ?
JUST FINE.
I WROTE MR. MACY A LETTER
AND THANKED HIM FOR THE JOB.
OH, GOOD.
LUNCH ?
HAD IT, THANKS.
SARAH DOESN'T APPROVE OF YOU.
YEAH, I KNOW.
SHE LIKES TO HOSE DOWN
THE PORCH HERSELF.
WHAT'S THIS ?
UH, THAT'S THE STORY, MA'AM.
I REWROTE IT
LIKE YOU ASKED ME TO.
OH, I'M VERY PLEASED.
ALL THESE THINGS
THAT ARE YOURS--
I CAN SEE
A WHOLE LIFE IN THEM.
YOU READ FRENCH, MA'AM ?
YES, I READ FRENCH.
AND WHAT ARE THESE-- YOUR
FATHER'S OLD MEDICAL BOOKS ?
MM-HMM.
- DO YOU THINK THIS IS ART ?
- YES, I THINK THAT'S ART.
IF YOU SAY SO.
THIS PLAY PROGRAM--
WHO IS PAUL SPEERY, MA'AM ?
HE WAS MY HUSBAND.
- "WAS" ?
- HE DIED.
OH, I'M SORRY.
YOU'VE NEVER
SPOKEN ABOUT HIM.
NO, I NEVER DO.
IS THAT GOOD--
I MEAN, KEEPING SOMETHING
INSIDE THAT SHOULD BE
LET OUT IN THE AIR ?
OH, YOU LEARN VERY FAST,
DON'T YOU, GLENN ?
YOU DON'T NEED BOOKS
TO UNDERSTAND YOU SHOULD
NEVER LOCK UP A HEART, MA'AM.
I'D LIKE TO HAVE KNOWN HIM,
THE KIND OF MAN YOU'D MARRY.
WELL, HE WAS JUST A BOY--
VERY TALENTED,
VERY EMOTIONAL,
LIKE YOU.
WERE YOU HAPPY ?
WELL, YOU'LL LEARN,
IN SPITE OF THE FAIRY TALES,
THERE ARE OTHER THINGS TO LIFE
BESIDES LI
LIKE WHAT ?
LIKE WORK,
ONE'S SELF-RESPECT.
I GUESS EVERYONE
WHO KNOWS YOU RESPECTS YOU,
MRS. SPEERY.
WELL, THANK YOU, GLENN.
COME BACK ON FRIDAY,
LIKE WE USED TO ?
YES, OF COURSE.
WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
YOU EXCITED ?
A LITTLE.  YOU ?
YES.
[ Bell Tolling ]
COME ON, GLENN.
[ Whispering ]
AMERICAN LITERATURE.
[ Loudly ]  ALL THIS ?
SHH !  YES.
THREE STACKS OVER.
SHH.
THERE'S HEMINGWAY,
TWAIN, MELVILLE.
YOU JUST TAKE YOUR PICK.
NOW, AFTER MY CLASS, I'LL BE
IN PROFESSOR LARSON'S OFFICE
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
GLENN, ARE YOU LISTENING TO ME ?
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
OKAY.
"DACE SNIFFS IN TWOS--
SNIFF-SNIFF--
"BUT SOMETIMES SNIFFS
IN THREES AND FOURS--
SNIFF-SNIFF-SNIFF.
"RUNNING OR WALKING,
WET OR DRY, HEAD COCKED
LIKE A SPANIEL...
"WHO AIMS TO PLEASE,
LITTLE DACE SNIFFS.
"DOES A RABBIT KNOW
ABOUT ITS TWITCHY NOSE ?
"CAN WE SAY THE CRICKET HEARS
ITS CHIRP ?
"WELL, JUST LIKE THAT,
DACE DOESN'T EVEN KNOW
HE SNIFFS.  DACE IS DEAD.
"HE'S BROWN AND LEATHER DEAD
LIKE THE MEAT
FROM THE SMOKEHOUSE.
"AND SNIFFS ?
WELL, SMOKE AND ALL,
MAY GOD HANG HIM HIGH...
LIKE A FLITCH OF BACON
IN THE WINTER WIND."
I WISH I'D WRITTEN THAT.
YOU'VE GOT SOME SORT OF REAL
NATURAL ON YOUR HANDS, IRENE.
THEN YOU AGREE WITH ME ?
OH-HO, I'D SAY.
GIVEN TIME AND SEASONING,
ANYTHING MIGHT HAPPEN.
HIS CONTACT WITH THE PAPER'S
IMMEDIATE AND INSTANT.
HE WRITES EXACTLY
AS HE FEELS AND THINKS.
I'LL TRY AND WRITE
A SCHOLARSHIP FOR HIM.
SEND HIM IN.
GLENN.  YOU'LL NEVER
REGRET THIS, JOE.
I HOPE NOT.
BUT DON'T GET
TOO INVOLVED, IRENE.
GREAT EXPECTATIONS,
GREAT DISAPPOINTMENTS.
GLENN, THIS IS PROFESSOR LARSON.
GLENN TYLER.
HOW DO YOU DO, SIR ?
HOW DO YOU DO ?
I WANT TO SAY JUST ONE THING,
MR. TYLER.  MAY I ?
YES, SIR.
FOR MAN TO DISCOVER FIRE
WAS NOTHING.
TO LEARN TO USE AND CONTROL IT
WAS EVERYTHING.
- WILL YOU THINK ABOUT THAT
AND WHAT IT MEANS ?
- YES, SIR, I WILL.
IF YOU WERE TAKING MY COURSE,
I'D BE TEMPTED TO GIVE
THIS PIECE OF YOURS AN "A."
THAT'S ALL.
RUN ALONG NOW.
I HAVE TO BONE UP
ON A LECTURE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, JOE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
BYE-BYE.
GOOD-BYE.
WE'RE MARCHING
ACROSS THE GREEN GRASS
GREEN GRASS, GREEN GRASS
WE'RE MARCHING
ACROSS THE GREEN GRASS
IN THE HUSKY, DUSTY DAY
WE'RE MARCHING OFF TO GET
MARRIED, MARRIED, MARRIED
WE'RE MARCHING OFF
TO GET MARRIED
THIS HUSKY, DUSTY DAY
YOU'RE AWFUL DIRTY
AND RAGGED, RAGGED, RAGGED
AND RAGGED
THIS HUSKY, DUSTY DAY
I'M JUST AS GOOD AS YOU ARE
YOU ARE, YOU ARE
THIS HUSKY, DUSTY DAY
I CLIMBED THROUGH YOUR WINDOW
WINDOW, WINDOW
THIS HUSKY, DUSTY DAY
I'LL LOCK AND BAR THE WINDOW
WINDOW, WINDOW
I THINK YOU'RE OFF THE KEY
I KNOW, AND I JUST
CAN'T HELP IT 떰
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
[ Tires Screech ]
YOU NEED SOME NEW TIRES,
MRS. SPEERY.
YOU'RE RIDING
ON YOUR NERVES NOW.
MAYBE I SHOULD TAKE HER
FOR A WHILE.
ALL RIGHT.  FINE.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO STOP SOMEWHERE
TILL IT BLOWS OVER ?
THAT'S-THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
[ Thunderclap ]
WELL, WHERE DID
YOU FOLKS COME FROM ?
WE DROPPED OUT OF THE SKY.
GOT ANY COFFEE ?
NEVER TOUCH THE STUFF.
WELL, WHAT HAVE YOU GOT
THAT YOU LIKE ?
I GOT LEMON AND CHERRY POP
AND ICE CREAM ON A STICK.
I'LL HAVE CHERRY POP,
PLEASE.
YEAH, ME TOO.
YOU THINK THIS RAIN WILL LAST ?
[ Chuckling ]
WELL, LADY, WHERE'S YOUR EARS ?
IT'S COMIN' DOWN
MIGHTY STEADY.
LOOKS TO ME LIKE
IT'S GONNA RAIN ALL NIGHT.
THERE YA ARE.
OH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANKS.
THE OLD MAN'S
PROBABLY RIGHT.
WANNA WAIT IN THE OFFICE ?
IT'LL PROBABLY BE WARMER.
LET'S.
YOU TWO WANT A ROOM ?
UH, NO, THANKS.
GOT ANYTHING GOOD TO READ ?
ZANE GREY.
CAN'T NONE OF 'EM
BEAT OLD ZANE.
YOU KNOW, HE CAME BY HERE ONCE,
RIGHT AFTER THE FIRST WORLD WAR.
AUTOGRAPHED ME TWO OF HIS BOOKS.
GLENN, WHY DON'T WE TAKE ROOMS
UNTIL THE RAIN STOPS ?
I'M TIRED AND A LITTLE JUMPY.
SURE, MA'AM,
IF YOU'D LIKE.
YOU REGISTER
RIGHT HERE, MA'AM.
SHALL I SIGN FOR YOU, GLENN ?
- IF YOU DON'T MIND.
- TWO ROOMS, PLEASE.
TWO ROOMS.
ARE THE ROOMS HEATED ?
YES, MA'AM.
HEATER IN EVERY ROOM.
FIFTEEN AND SIXTEEN ADJOINING.
THIS WAY.
OKAY TO TAKE THESE ?
OH, YES.  JUST HELP YOURSELF.
THIS WAY, MA'AM.
[ Thunderclap ]
FOR THE LADY.
OKAY.
THANK YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU
WHEN THE RAIN'S OVER,
MRS. SPEERY.
HERE YOU ARE.
HOW MUCH YOU GET
FOR THIS PLACE ?
SIX DOLLARS, SINGLE.
FOR ONE NIGHT, EACH ?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THAT ?
IN SUMMER YOU PAY EIGHT.
[ Glenn ]
YOU BETTER DO SOME THINKING.
I'LL GO SLEEP IN THE CAR.
HOLD IT NOW.
WHAT DID YOU FIGURE ON PAYING ?
NO MORE THAN THREE OR FOUR.
THEN WHY DON'T YOU DO IT NOW ?
YOU'RE GONNA DO IT LATER
FOR SURE.
DO WHAT ?
DOUBLE UP.
IT'LL ONLY COST YOU EIGHT.
WAIT A MINUTE--
ALL RIGHT !
TWO SINGLES FOR EIGHT.
[ Footsteps Receding ]
GLENN ?
COME IN.
GLENN, I THINK WE OUGHT
TO TRY TO DRIVE HOME.
IT WOULDN'T BE A GOOD IDEA
ON THOSE TIRES OF YOURS MA'AM.
WOULDN'T BE SAFE
EVEN IN THE DAYLIGHT.
IS SOMETHIN' WRONG ?
IT'S JUST THE RAIN.
I--
I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO SLEEP.
ANY OF THESE ANY GOOD ?
GIDEON BIBLE.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
TRY GENESIS,
SEVENTH CHAPTER.
WHAT'S THAT ?
"AND IT CAME TO PASS
AFTER SEVEN DAYS...
THE WATERS OF THE FLOOD
WERE UPON THE EARTH."
WELL, MAYBE WE SHOULD
BUILD OURSELVES AN ARK.
YOU GO ON.
I'LL WAIT FOR YOU HERE.
DON'T WORRY, MRS. SMITH,
THEY KNOW ME HERE.
EVERYTHING WITH A KISS.
OH, WELL, MR. SMITH.
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
- GOT A ROOM ?
- YES, SIR.
HEY, NOW.
I SEE YOU GOT A COUPLE
OTHER CUSTOMERS TONIGHT, HUH ?
[ Chuckles ]
YES, WE HAVE.
NUMBER 11.
YOUR OLD ROOM,
FOR LUCK.
THANKS.
[ Laughing ]
WHAT'S SO FUNNY ?
IT'S A SMALL WORLD,
YES, INDEED.
A VERY SMALL WORLD.
I'LL BORROW THIS,
IF I MAY.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.  MA'AM ?
IT WASN'T THE RAIN
THAT KEPT ME AWAKE.
IT WAS YOU.
THESE WALLS ARE THIN,
YOU KNOW.
I'LL TRY TO BE MORE QUIET.
NO, IT'S NOT THAT.
I GUESS YOU KNOW
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME.
GLENN, IN A RELATIONSHIP
LIKE OURS,
THIS KIND OF THING
OFTEN HAPPENS.
IN PSYCHIATRY,
THEY CALL IT TRANSFERENCE.
THAT'S BOOK TALK.
I DON'T MEAN TO BE
DISRESPECTFUL TO YOU,
BUT I'M IN LOVE WITH YOU,
IRENE.
I'M IN LOVE WITH YOU.
[ Door Opens ]
YOU WANT ME TO LEAVE ?
PLEASE.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
WELL, NO MATTER
HOW MANY TIMES--
WELL, I CAN'T HELP IT
IF SHE'S NOT HOME
WHEN YOU CALL.
[ Whispering ]
IT'S THE TYLER BOY.
ALL RIGHT.  WOULD YOU
TELL HER ONCE AGAIN, PLEASE,
THAT I'VE GOT TO SEE HER ?
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
YES,
I'LL LEAVE THE MESSAGE.
MISS IRENE, THAT BOY SOUNDS
VERY TROUBLED.
IT'S THE THIRD TIME
HE'S CALLED.
HERE'S TO US.
OF COURSE, I'M ASSUMING
THAT YOUR WIFE IS STILL WILLING
TO GIVE YOU A DIVORCE.
OH, HONEY, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT THAT.  YOU KNOW
SHE'D JUMP AT THE CHANCE.
IN ONE STROKE,
YOU'VE GIVEN MY LIFE
REAL MEANIN'.
PHIL, THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
I HAVE TO SAY TO YOU.
WHAT ELSE IS THERE TO SAY ?
YOU'RE GOING TO MARRY ME.
I DON'T--
I DON'T QUITE KNOW HOW
TO PUT THIS.
I'M MARRYING YOU
FOR MIXED REASONS.
[ Chuckles ]
WELL,
WE'RE NEITHER OF US
SCHOOLKIDS.
I'M RUNNING AWAY
FROM SOMETHING--
SOMETHING I'M AFRAID OF.
ANOTHER MAN.
ANYONE-- ANYONE I KNOW ?
THAT-THAT'S UNIMPORTANT.
IT'S JUST THAT...
I WANTED YOU TO KNOW, AND
I'VE BEEN TERRIBLY FRIGHTENED.
IN FACT, I'VE FELT MYSELF
ON THE BRINK--
DARLING, EVERYTHING YOU'RE
SAYING IS UNIMPORTANT.
I KNOW YOU'LL BE
A WONDERFUL WIFE.
WE'LL BE HAPPY.
I GUARANTEE IT.
[ Intercom Buzzes ]
WE'LL HAVE TO CELEBRATE.
LET'S HAVE DINNER TONIGHT.
[ Woman ]
IT'S MR. LEWIS AGAIN,
CALLING FROM CHICAGO.
HE SAYS IT'S URGENT.
I'LL TAKE IT.
I'LL MAKE YOU A MARTINI.
YES, SPEAKING.
OH, VERY DRY.
NO, NO.
NOT YOU, MR. LEWIS.
I'M SORRY.
AFTERNOON, MR. LONGSTREET.
HELLO, MR. BRAXTON.
YOUNG TYLER ANYWHERE AROUND ?
I JUST SENT HIM OVER
TO THE HARDWARE STORE.
IS IT SOMETHING YOU WANTED ?
HE STOLE
MY NORRIE'S GUITAR.
WELL, HE DON'T IMPRESS ME AT ALL
AS A BOY WITH ITCHY FINGERS.
BUT FROM WHAT I HEARD YESTERDAY,
I'D CHECK HIM ELSEWHERE
ALONG THE LINE.
WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN ?
[ Engine Revs ]
[ Inaudible ]
WHO TOLD YOU THAT ?
MY NEPHEW, WILLIE DACE.
A LAUGH, AIN'T IT ?
HEY, HONEY,
IT'S HALF PAST 7:00.
HOW LONG'S HE GONNA BE ?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'D LIKE TO GO HOME MYSELF.
NICE TO SEE YOU, SON,
MA'AM.
YOU CAN GO IN NOW, CLIFF.
EVENING, DAD.
I'M CRAVIN' A BOON,
I WONDER IF YOU'RE
IN A GOOD MOOD OR BAD.
WHERE WERE YOU
FRIDAY NIGHT ?
OH, STUCK SOMEWHERE
IN THE RAIN.  WHY ?
HAVE YOU AND WILLIE DACE
BEEN SPREADIN' A STORY ABOUT...
MRS. SPEERY UP AT SOME MOTEL ?
WELL, MAYBE TOLD A FRIEND
OR TWO, BUT--
I WONDER IF YOU'VE
ENOUGH DECENCY LEFT
TO REALIZE WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
WHAT HAVE I DONE ?
THEY WERE THERE TOGETHER
ALL NIGHT.
NOW, DON'T GET EXCITED.
SURE, YOU'RE HOT
FOR THE LADY YOURSELF.
YOU'D EVEN THROW MY MOTHER
IN THE ASHCAN TO MARRY HER.
WELL, IT'S ABOUT TIME YOU FOUND
OUT YOU'RE NOT THE ONLY ONE
WHO CARRIES A KEY TO THAT DOOR.
[ Ringing ]
WOULD YOU TELL MRS. SPEERY
I'D LIKE TO SEE HER ?
OR IS HER CAR HOME
AND SHE ISN'T ?
WELL, SHE'S HOME,
BUT SHE'S EXPECTING SOMEBODY.
NEVER MIND, SARAH.
ASK HIM TO COME IN.
WOULD YOU SIT DOWN ?
I'M SORRY, GLENN.
I WAS PLANNING
TO CALL YOU TOMORROW.
I OWE YOU AN EXPLANATION--
I HAVEN'T SLEPT
FOR TWO NIGHTS, MA'AM.
I'VE BEEN PUTTING IT OFF
BECAUSE IT'S BEEN COMPLICATED.
I LOVE YOU, IRENE.
WHAT'S COMPLICATED ABOUT THAT ?
GLENN, IT ISN'T THAT SIMPLE !
I WANT TO MARRY YOU.  ARE YOU
WORRIED WHAT PEOPLE WILL SAY ?
IT'S MORE IMPORTANT THAN THAT.
I DON'T CARE WHAT PEOPLE SAY.
GLENN, LISTEN, PLEASE.
SIT DOWN.
ALL RIGHT.  I'LL LISTEN.
Y-YOU'RE AT THE START
OF WHAT COULD BE
A BRILLIANT CAREER.
YOU MUSTN'T GET TIED DOWN.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE YOUR HANDS
FREE AND YOUR MIND FREE AND,
ABOVE ALL, YOUR EMOTIONS FREE.
WHAT'S THAT GOT TO DO WITH US ?
YOU'RE SIMPLY NOT READY
FOR A MARRIAGE, GLENN.
THIS IS ALL ABOUT ME.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, IRENE ?
IT-IT WOULDN'T WORK
FOR ME EITHER.
FOR ONCE,
WHAT ABOUT YOUR LIFE ?
I LOVE YOU.
I GOT THE IDEA
THAT YOU LOVE ME TOO.
CAN WE TALK ABOUT THAT ?
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THAT.
I KNOW A LOT ABOUT LOVE.
I MARRIED FOR LOVE.
AND YOU KNOW HOW IT ENDED ?
IT ENDED BY MY HUSBAND
GETTING IN THE CAR
ONE RAINY NIGHT...
AND GOING OUT AND HITTING
A CURVE AT 90 MILES AN HOUR.
AND YOU KNOW
WHAT KILLED HIM ?  LOVE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
A MARRIAGE
HE WASN'T READY FOR.
AND YOU BLAME YOURSELF ?
YES !  I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
HE COULDN'T CARRY
THE RESPONSIBILITY.
GLENN, DO YOU SEE
I'M LETTING THE SAME THING
HAPPEN ALL OVER AGAIN ?
I WANTED SO MUCH FOR YOU,
AND NOW I'VE NEARLY RUINED IT
BECAUSE I'VE LET--
I'VE LET MY HOPES FOR YOU...
GET MIXED UP IN SOMETHING ELSE
THAT DOESN'T BELONG-- SOMETHING
THAT DOESN'T BELONG AT ALL !
IT COULD BELONG, IRENE,
IF YOU LET IT.  IT COULD.
OH, GLENN, PLEASE !
IRENE, ARE YOU TELLING ME
YOU DON'T LOVE ME ?
ANSWER ME.
[ Door Opens ]
ANSWER ME, PLEASE,
IRENE.
[ Door Closes ]
HIS UNCLE'S BEEN SPREADING
THE STORY YOU SPENT FRIDAY NIGHT
TOGETHER IN A MOTEL ROOM.
WHO SAID THAT ?
WHO TOLD MY UNCLE THAT ?
IT ISN'T TRUE, IS IT ?
MY SON.  HE'S AN EXPERT
IN SHADY MOTELS, IT SEEMS.
AN EXPERT IN TELLING LIES.
I'M NOT SO SURE ABOUT THAT NOW.
IS THIS-- IS HE WHAT
YOU'RE RUNNIN' AWAY FROM ?
YOU'VE GOT NO RIGHT TO TALK
TO HER LIKE THAT, MR. MACY.
HAVEN'T I ?
MRS. SPEERY AS DONE ME THE HONOR
OF SAYIN' SHE WOULD BE MY WIFE.
PHIL, DON'T !
IRENE, MY SON--
WHAT HE SAID-- IS IT TRUE ?
IF I FIND YOUR SON AROUND,
HE'LL GET SHIPPED HOME IN A BOX.
DON'T SAY I DIDN'T WARN YOU.
- GLENN--
- YOU WERE RIGHT.  I DON'T
WANT TO EVER SEE YOU AGAIN.
GLENN.
GLENN !
IRENE, I HAVE TO KNOW.
IS IT TRUE ?
NO.
ARE YOU IN LOVE
WITH THIS BOY ?
YES.
NOW MAYBE
I'VE DESTROYED HIM.
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
[ Screeches ]
떰 [ Rock ]
NORRIE ?
GLENN, WHAT ARE YOU
DOIN' HERE ?
WHERE'S YOUR PA ?
HE WENT BOWLING TONIGHT.
DO YOU REALLY WANT TO
SHAKE THIS TOWN FOR GOOD ?
Y-YOU WOULDN'T FOOL AROUND
WITH ME, WOULD YOU ?
UH-UH.
NOW, WHERE'S THE MONEY
YOUR PA'S GOT STASHED AWAY ?
HERE IT IS.
NOW, IT'S GOT A FAKE BOTTOM.
JUST BUST IT OPEN !
GO PACK
AND GET YOUR BABY.
I'LL BE READY IN A SHAKE.
WELL, HOW DO I LOOK ?
KINDA FRISKY FOR A WIDOW.
GLENN, IT'S A DREAM.
IT'S A REAL DREAM.
[ Baby Fusses ]
MAYBE IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW ?
SHH.  YES, BABY.
WE BETTER TAKE THE BACK ROADS.
THEY'LL BE AFTER US BEFORE LONG.
NO, THEY WON'T.
PA CAN'T DO A THING.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, THEY WON'T ?
[ Gibberish To Baby ]
THAT'S THE OLD TAX-DODGE MONEY
WE TOOK.
IT IS ?
I WOULD GIVE MY EYETEETH
TO SEE HIS FACE
WHEN HE READS THAT NOTE.
[ Laughs ]
[ Gurgles ]
떰 [ Rock ]
WHAT ARE WE
STOPPIN' HERE FOR, GLENN ?
I'LL BE BACK IN A MINUTE.
JUST HANG ON.
YOU SEEN CLIFF MACY ?
SURE.  HE'S INSIDE.
I WANNA TALK TO YOU.
WELL, IF IT ISN'T TYLER,
THE GREAT LOVER.
WHO YOU GOT IN THE TRUCK--
LADY SPEERY ?
DON'T YOU TALK ABOUT HER.
I SAID I DON'T WANT YOU
TALKIN' ABOUT HER !
SHE'S A PUSHOVER.
ASK MY FATHER.
ASK ANYBODY !
COME ON, DACE.
[ Girls Giggling ]
WHAT IS IT ?
DRUNK ?
GET SOME WATER, QUICK !
IT WAS A FIGHT.
WHAT DID CLIFF MACY DO ?
IT DOESN'T MATTER ANYMORE.
IT'S ALL OVER NOW.
[ Police Siren
Approaching ]
STATE POLICE.  LOOKS LIKE
YOUR PA CALLED 'EM AFTER ALL.
YOU GLENN TYLER ?
YES, SIR.
I'M TAKIN' YOU IN
FOR MANSLAUGHTER.
LOOK AT THEM--
CROWDIN' IN FOR THE FREE SHOW.
YOU'D THINK IT WAS A CIRCUS,
NOT A CORONER'S INQUEST.
WHAT WAS A BOY LIKE THAT
DOING WITH A $500 WATCH ?
YOU HAVE NOTHING TO BLAME
YOURSELF FOR, MR. MACY.
A 20-YEAR-OLD BOY.
I SHOULD BE--
MR. MACY,
IT'S NEARLY 2:00.
PHIL ?  PHIL,
CAN I SPEAK TO YOU
FOR A MOMENT ?
WHY DON'T YOU GO HOME
AND PULL DOWN YOUR BLINDS ?
PLEASE, PHIL,
YOU MUST LISTEN.
GLENN HAD NO INTENTION--
YOU BETTER GET HIM A GOOD
LAWYER, 'CAUSE MY INTENTION
IS TO HANG HIM IF I CAN.
PHIL ?
[ Chattering ]
MRS. SPEERY ?
MY NAME'S HANK TYLER,
GLENN'S BROTHER.
ME AND SOME OF THE BOYS HERE
WAS WONDERING IF, UH--
SEE, WE GOT A JUG IN THE CAR,
AND IF YOU KNOWED A GOOD MOTEL,
WE FIGURED WE MIGHT ALL
GET TOGETHER--
[ Boys Laughing ]
- [ Woman ]
THERE SHE IS.
- [ Crowd Chattering ]
ANY MORE QUESTIONS
OF THIS WITNESS ?
[ Attorney ]
WAS THERE ANY WEAPON USED ?
[ Witness ]  MIGHT HAVE BEEN.
IT WAS GETTIN' KINDA DARK.
I COULDN'T SEE.
WELL, THERE WAS
NO MEDICAL EVIDENCE OF THAT.
THANK YOU.  YOU CAN GO.
[ Crowd Murmurs ]
QUIET, PLEASE.  QUIET.
IT'S BEEN SUGGESTED,
AND SHE'S AGREED.
WILL MRS. SPEERY
COME FORWARD TO TESTIFY ?
[ Crowd Gasps, Exclaims ]
SHE'S GOT A LOT OF NERVE !
QUIET !
WE MUST HAVE QUIET HERE !
RAISE YOUR RIGHT HAND.
DO YOU SOLEMNLY SWEAR
TO TELL THE TRUTH,
THE WHOLE TRUTH,
AND NOTHING BUT THE TRUTH,
SO HELP YOU GOD ?
I DO.
STATE YOUR NAME,
PLEASE.
IRENE SPEERY.
MRS. SPEERY, WE'RE SIMPLY
TRYING TO DETERMINE
IF YOUNG TYLER--
IF THERE ARE GROUNDS
FOR A CRIMINAL PROSECUTION HERE.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
KILLS A BOY, AND WONDERS IF
THERE'S GROUNDS FOR PROSECUTION.
[ Crowd Laughs ]
I WISH TO REMIND
EVERYONE HERE...
THAT THIS IS AN INQUEST
AND NOT A MURDER TRIAL !
[ Crowd Murmurs, Quiets ]
NOW, MRS. SPEERY,
WAS TYLER PRESENT AT YOUR HOUSE
ON THURSDAY NIGHT AROUND 8:00 ?
HE WAS.
- [ Man ]
WHAT WAS HE DOIN' THERE ?
- SOCIAL WORK.
PHIL MACY WAS PRESENT
AT THAT TIME TOO, WAS HE NOT ?
HE WAS.
DID TYLER AT THAT TIME...
UTTER SOME KIND OF THREAT
AGAINST MR. MACY'S SON ?
WELL--
WHAT DID HE SAY ?
I DON'T REMEMBER
THE EXACT WORDS, DR. CRESTEN.
WAS HIS REMARK
SOMETHING ALONG THE LINE...
HE WOULD SEND YOUNG MACY HOME
IN A BOX ?
[ Crowd Murmurs ]
YES, MRS. SPEERY ?
MR. TYLER HAD EVERY REASON
TO BE ANGRY.
AS I'M SURE YOU ALL KNOW,
THERE WAS A SLANDER
BEING SPREAD, A LIE !
IT'S TRUE, WASN'T IT ?
YOU'RE DENYING IT ?
YES, A LIE !
GLENN DID NOTHING TO BE
ASHAMED OF-- NOTHING !
IF THERE'S ANYONE TO BE BLAMED,
IT'S ME.  I LOST SIGHT
OF CERTAIN REALITIES,
AND I FORGOT
MY RESPONSIBILITIES !
OH, GLENN, I'M SORRY.
I'M SO SORRY.
MRS. SPEERY,
THIS IS OFF THE POINT.
WE'RE MERELY TRYING
TO DETERMINE IF THERE'S
BEEN FELONY COMMITTED HERE.
WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY IS THAT
THERE WAS NO FELONY COMMITTED.
CLIFF MACY'S DEATH WAS
AN ACCIDENT.
[ All Murmur ]
ORDER !  ORDER !
GLENN WAS ANGRY
OVER WHAT HAD BEEN SAID,
AND HE HIT HIM.
HE DIDN'T INTEND TO KILL HIM.
HE HAD NO WAY OF KNOWING
CLIFF HAD A BAD HEART.
[ All Murmur ]
A BAD HEART, MRS. SPEERY ?
YES.  ISN'T THAT
IN THE AUTOPSY REPORT ?
WELL, THERE WAS
POSTMORTEM EVIDENCE
THAT HE'D SUFFERED A CORONARY.
WE ASSUMED IT WAS CAUSED
BY THE BLOW.
ARE YOU SAYING THE BOY HAD
A CHRONIC HEART CONDITION ?
YES.
WELL, IF SO, THE FAMILY
PHYSICIAN, DR. McLAWS,
KNEW NOTHING ABOUT IT.
WELL, ASK HIS FATHER,
MR. MACY.
HE TOLD ME ABOUT
CLIFF'S HEART WEEKS AGO.
WELL, PHIL,
DO YOU WISH TO MAKE
A STATEMENT ?
NOW, YOU NEEDN'T, OF COURSE.
WE REALIZE IT'S PAINFUL FOR YOU,
BUT--
THERE WAS NOTHING WRONG
WITH MY SON'S HEART.
[ Crowd Gasps ]
HE WAS IN PERFECT HEALTH.
[ Man ]
WE'LL HEAR THE NEXT WITNESS,
HANK TYLER.
RAISE YOUR RIGHT HAND.
DO YOU SOLEMNLY SWEAR
TO TELL THE TRUTH,
THE WHOLE TRUTH
AND NOTHING BUT THE TRUTH,
SO HELP YOU GOD ?
I DO.
STATE YOUR NAME.
HANK TYLER.
SARAH ?
YES, MISS IRENE ?
HERE IT IS.  MAKE SURE IT GOES
FIRST CLASS, SPECIAL DELIVERY.
I HOPE THEY DON'T GET
TOO DRASTIC WITH THAT BOY.
DO I TAKE THE CAR ?
CAR ?  JUST DOWN TO
THE POST OFFICE ?
SARAH, YOU'LL GROW FAT.
[ Chuckles ]
S'POSE.
NO, ROSIE.
NO WALK TODAY.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Engine Running ]
[ Whimpers, Barks ]
ONE MORE QUESTION.
WERE YOU PRESENT
AT MRS. SPEERY'S HOME...
WHEN TYLER IS ALLEGED TO HAVE
MADE A THREAT AGAINST YOUR SON ?
I WAS.
CAN YOU REPEAT WHAT HE SAID ?
HE SAID,
"IF I FIND YOUR SON,
HE'LL BE SHIPPED HOME IN A BOX,
DON'T SAY I DIDN'T WARN YOU."
[ All Gasp, Murmur ]
[ Crowd Murmurs Loudly ]
NO !
I THINK WE'D BETTER
ADJOURN NOW.
JIM, WAIT.
GIVE ME A MINUTE, PLEASE.
I WANT TO-- GOD HELP ME--
CORRECT A STATEMENT OF MINE.
- WHAT HAPPENED, MR. MACY ?
- I LIED TO YOU
ABOUT CLIFF'S HEART.
IT WAS BAD-- VERY BAD.
IT WASN'T TYLER'S FAULT AT ALL.
I STRUCK CLIFF MYSELF THE SAME
NIGHT FOR THE SAME REASON.
STOP THAT MAN !
LET HIM GO, LET HIM GO !
[ Machinery Whirring
Rhythmically ]
[ Irene Moans ]
IRENE ?
[ Moans ]
YOU CAN SWITCH OVER.
IRENE.
THAT'S THE IDEA.
KEEP BREATHING.
BREATHE DEEP.
[ Glenn ]
IRENE, THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAID OF ANYMORE.
MR. MACY TOLD 'EM
THE TRUTH.
I'M FREE.
BUT I NEED YOU, IRENE.
DON'T LEAVE ME.
DON'T YOU LEAVE ME TOO.
OH.
I'M SO ASHAMED.
DON'T BE ASHAMED.
I'LL HELP YOU.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU.  I WON'T
LET ANYTHING HURT YOU AGAIN.
WELL, GLENN--
I'M NOT SAYING GOOD-BYE.
I KNOW.
BUT FIND OUT FIRST.
BE SURE.
THAT'S WHAT COLLEGE IS FOR,
IS TO FIND OUT.
WILL YOU WRITE ?
[ Whistle Blows ]
ALL ABOARD !
THE ROSE GROWS WILD
IN THE COUNTRY
A TREE GROWS TALL
AS THE SKY
[ Chorus ]
THE WIND BLOWS WILD
IN THE COUNTRY
AND PART OF
THE WILD, WILD COUNTRY
AM I 떰