First who makes 10, okay?
- Show me.
- Look me.
One, two...
Ready?
I'm the best! Champion! Winner.
Where are we going?
We don't know, anywhere you want.
Where do you want to go?
What do you want? Let's go.
- Wherever you want!
- Fuck, I'm always deciding.
Let's go.
Get the phone!
Hello.
You got the wrong number. No problem.
- Who was it?
- Some guy asking for a Pierre.
Pierre something-or-other. A wrong number.
- Shit.
- Leave it.
Hello. Yes.
Yes, it's me.
Pierre, come inside!
Pierre, come here.
We won't be seeing Daddy
and Caroline anymore.
Thank you.
- Will this be okay?
- Yes.
- Are you comfortable?
Jesus. You who know where my sister is...
please tell me where she is.
Please, I miss her so much.
I want to see her
at least one more in my life.
Please.
Here, Cesar!
That's a good dog.
He wants to lick you.
Go on, let him lick you.
He likes you.
I think he really likes you! Come on, let's go.
Caroline?
I'm sorry.
Do want me to do it like when we were kids?
Here we go. One for Daddy.
One for Mommy.
- It's not too hot?
- No.
It has carrots.
- Yes. You like it?
- Yes, but I don't want any more.
Come on, just a little more.
- One for Caro.
- I can't.
- Did it go down?
- Yes.
The last one is for Pierre.
Look how skinny you are.
You'll never get better if you don't eat.
You've got to make an effort.
What for?
Bless us, Lord, bless this food,
give bread to those who have none.
In the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Pierre, pass me the bread.
Thanks.
Bring it closer.
- More?
- Yes.
Talk.
Speak.
I kiss you.
What is this?
Mouth.
- Mouth.
- Yes, mouth.
I like your mouth.
Face.
Yes, face.
Hand.
I like hand.
- Stéphanie.
- I know.
- Mikhail.
Mikhail.
- 50 euros.
- What?
What do you mean, "what"? It's 50 euros.
I owe you 50 euros?
You think I fuck for free?
Is 20 euros all right?
Suck me.
Can't we kiss first?
Suck me, I said.
Go on.
Look at me. Look at me!
Does he make you happy?
Yes.
- Have you known him long?
- No, just a few months.
That's nice.
- What does he do?
- Works in a restaurant, he's a waiter.
- Is that where you met him?
- No, in a nightclub.
Oh, right.
- Can you tell me his name again?
- Mikhail.
- He seems solid, anyway.
- Why "anyway"?
I don't know, just a manner of speaking.
Why won't you look at me?
Look at me.
Still so stubborn, it never got you anywhere.
My little boy.
- Ancel, Jean-François.
- Here.
- Albert, Thierry.
- Benasseur, Didier.
- Here.
- Bono, Céline.
- Carpentier, Françoise.
- Here.
- Charlemagne, Bastien.
- Caumon, Pierre.
- Here.
- Decroix, Sylvie.
You don't understand?
- Russian?
- Yes.
Russkiy.
Can I see your hands?
You strong.
Yes?
My husband.
Do you understand?
My husband. My husband.
Understand? No?
He was strong, too.
You seem like a good man,
I'm glad Pierre found you.
- You don't understand.
- Pierre?
Pierre.
You...
Yes?
...can you sing?
Sing? Kalinka?
- Kalinka!
- Yes.
Yes.
Juniper, Juniper, Juniper
Juniper, Juniper, my Juniper
Louder.
In the garden there's the raspberry,
my raspberry
Hello!
Excuse me, I'm looking for Marat Babinsky.
Do you know where I can find him?
There's no Babinsky here.
He's my uncle.
I just arrived from Odessa.
Your uncle.
I guess he doesn't like his nephew much.
Why?
Babinsky's been gone for a year now.
You know where he is?
I have no idea.
In this place, people come and go.
No one stays around.
I think he wanted to go to Germany.
He talked about Hamburg.
Do you have an address or phone number?
Sorry, I can't help you.
Hello?
Hello. I can't hear you. Who is this?
- Good evening.
- Hi.
- I'm so happy to see you.
- How are you?
- Fine.
It's so cool!
Shit, there's no one around.
It's mort, dead.
- Dead.
- Yes.
- Yeah, it's quiet.
- What?
- Quiet.
- "Quite"?
No, quiet, it's quiet.
- What's that mean?
- No noise.
No people, there are no people.
No people around.
It's Deadsville.
And Stéphanie? Good?
- Stéphanie.
- Is she okay?
- She's okay.
- And you?
- You.
- Me. I'm good.
Djamel, is it good, my job?
Your job? Don't worry, I took care of it.
No problem, I told them.
And you? Your job?
My job? Sure, everything's great.
- Really?
- Yeah, sure.
I don't believe you.
- "I don't believe you"?
- Yes, I don't believe you.
Yeah, cool, everyone's cool.
Why you talk: "blah, blah, blah"?
What "blah"?
You should change your life, you know?
- My life?
- Yes.
You want to change my life?
- You change life for me?
- No, I don't want to change your life.
- You change your life.
- You want me to change my life?
- Yes.
- Why?
'Cause it's not normal.
You think your life is normal?
I have normal life.
- I'm working.
- Yeah, right.
Leave me alone.
I'm free, Mikhail, understand? Free.
Free.
Do you understand that? Free!
I want we happy, you and me and Stéphanie.
I want we are happy.
Come on.
Are you okay?
l, The Golden Knight, Lord of the Somme...
hereby promise you, my beloved Queen,
love and loyalty.
Before God, I promise to protect you
from all dangers till death do us part.
Noble Knight of the North,
your Queen blesses you...
and promises in return...
the same Loyalty and love.
Let us seal it with a kiss.
Come in, don't be shy.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello, sir.
Mom, this is Djamel.
- Did you have a nice trip?
- Yes.
It was fine.
Have you eaten?
No.
- I'll fix you something.
- Okay.
- Can I put my bag down?
- Of course.
I'm glad your father never saw you like this.
Why do you say that?
You know he wouldn't have liked it.
How do you know?
I thought you wouldn't either,
but I was wrong.
Yes, but he's a man.
He was so happy to have a son.
He told everybody right away.
Thank God, he never saw you like this.
- It would have hurt him.
- Don't say that.
Maybe he just would've wanted me
to be happy.
Men don't think that way.
- Did he love me?
- Yes.
Am I hurting your feelings?
It's fucking freezing!
- You'll sleep here. All right?
- And you?
I sleep upstairs.
- And Mikhail?
- Here.
- You mean not together?
- Not here, Djamel.
We could push the beds together.
No.
- Why not?
- Take a wild guess.
- She won't hear anything.
- Yes, she will.
Wait a sec, I didn't come 200 kilometers
to sleep alone.
You'll live, it's only a few days.
Djamel, don't worry.
Okay, show me where I'm supposed
to throw the ball.
Okay.
Go for it, Stella!
- Should I throw it hard?
- Go, champion!
Give it some wrist action.
Shift into high gear.
Very good.
Good, but not far enough.
I'm a girl, I'm weak! The ball is too heavy!
Too far!
Try again, miss.
Okay, she's ready.
She didn't get it.
It's my turn again? What about her?
- Everyone has their own role.
- Okay.
- One person points, like you.
- I see.
- The middle person shoots and points.
- I get it.
The middle one points and shoots.
- Okay, thanks.
- Try to throw it straight.
Thanks, sugar.
Now she gets it! There you go.
You did it!
Moussa, it's Natasha.
Yes, I got your message. Where do you live?
Okay. Within half an hour.
The time it takes to get there.
Okay.
- Good evening. This way.
- Thank you.
- Can I take your coat?
- No, I'll keep it.
I'm still a bit cold, thanks.
- Would you like something to drink?
- Sure, water would be nice.
- Nothing stronger?
- Just a glass of water, thanks.
Thank you.
No!
We won.
It's crazy!
Leva attacks the other phase
with a hightyfide!
Are you okay?
No, I'm not.
What's the matter?
Can I help?
- No, you can't.
- Why can't I?
Because...
I'm just tired, Djamel.
- Tired, you understand?
- No.
It's the way it is, I'm tired.
Do you love me?
Of course I love you.
I mean besides my body, do you love me?
Of course I love you. You know I do.
Then why don't you ask me to stop?
Who is it in the picture?
I love my mother here. She's beautiful.
You know, I miss them. My parents.
- He miss them?
- Miss. I miss them.
- "Miss"?
- Manquer.
Oh, he misses his parents.
But you've got us.
Want me to ask you about your life?
About my life? No, why?
- Are you mad at me?
- Mad at you for what?
For...
- all these years, I never...
- Hold still!
Sorry.
You know, if I never called...
it was because I thought
it was better that way.
That you...
That it was better.
That you wouldn't want to know.
It's been hard all these years...
without your father, without Caroline.
And with you in Paris.
It's been hard on everyone.
- Yes.
- Tip your head back.
But you have your whole life in front of you.
- Hello.
Can I help you?
Hello, Nicolas.
Settle down, I'll be right there.
- You don't recognize me?
- No.
Take a good look.
I've no idea.
It's me, Pierre. Pierre Caumon.
It's been a long time. How long?
- Fifteen, sixteen years?
- Seventeen.
I left when I was 15. Add it up.
What brought you back?
I had to come, for my family.
- I didn't think you'd still be here.
- Yeah, I know.
I got out for a while,
spent five years in Brussels.
Then I came back. I had to.
I'm okay with it. And now I've got my kids.
What are their names?
- Pierre and Daniel.
- Pierre?
That's funny.
I'm glad you came by.
- You really mean it?
- Yeah, I'm happy to see you.
Thanks.
It's strange, but you haven't changed.
- It still seems like you.
- It still is me.
It'll take some getting used to.
Do you live with someone?
- Does he mind?
- No.
- Do you love him?
- Of course, why?
No reason.
Did you think I'd love you forever, Nicolas?
Teach me...
boxing punches and all that.
- The box, you and me.
- Okay.
- Gently.
This is...
Okay, you try. Okay?
- One...
- Go ahead.
One. Oh, yeah! Good! Ducking.
- "Ducking"?
- Yeah. Up.
Yes, ducking.
Aim there, not there. One, two, three.
Yeah, no, you shouldn't turn your head.
It's very important.
Like this?
Oh, yeah, good. Very good.
- I turn this.
- Go. Bang!
He's the... 63 kilos, Djamel!
This is Mikhail Gorbachev, 120 kilos.
- It's no good, not evenly matched.
- Okay, weave.
- Okay, duck.
- Duck.
- Yeah.
- Look, huh?
Gently. Gently.
Let's go. Gently! Mikhail.
There you go. Yeah, good.
Let's go. One... Let's go again.
It hurts!
Come here, you.
Get lost.
He's better looking than me.
- Don't say that.
- That's what you said.
- I didn't.
- You did.
I said you're both handsome.
- So what do you think?
- About what?
I don't know. You, me, him.
- Us three, together.
- Could be nice.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Come on, get up.
Come on. Come on.
You must've eaten something bad.
Because of the food.
Maybe.
Maybe not, too.
Maybe not.
Have I shown you my scars?
Have you seen this one?
Do you look, I am accident.
True.
Serious.
- Look.
- I see.
Cicatrice.
Scar. Scar.
- Scar?
- Scar, in English.
This is... I'm...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11... Two and ten.
Two and ten.
Twelve years old. Me, I was very little.
Me, little, little.
Moped.
"Douze ans" in English
is "two and ten," yeah?
Two and ten?
- How do you say "années"?
- Honey.
Yeah, honey. Two and ten honey.
- No, 1 2 years.
- I mean, it's the first number.
No, I mean, first time.
First time. I am this moped.
Speak mobylette?
- Bicycle.
- Yes, two wheels.
With my friends.
Accident, you speak?
This is because, this is the veine.
Vein. Le sang. Single.
There was single everywhere. All over.
I was in shorts.
I am in shorts.
Maillot.
You speak? Maillot. Maillot.
Maillot. Maillot.
Like in volleyball.
You speak? Maillot. Football.
- To play football.
- T-shirt.
T-shirt, yes. T-shirt covered.
Single everywhere. Just like my pullover.
Same color, the single, the T-shirt,
the pull and me.
Why did you guys leave the party?
Mikhail wanted to.
I don't think it was his scene.
What did he say?
Nothing.
- Just that he wanted to leave.
- I mean afterwards.
We talked about tons of stuff.
Did you know he was a soldier?
He used to be a soldier.
Did you fuck after?
- Why do you say that?
- Oh, come on.
- Any hot water left?
- Yeah.
- There's no heat?
- No, it doesn't work. It broke down.
- A problem with the wiring.
- It's freezing in here.
Today, yeah.
Yesterday was warmer.
Misha, hold it.
Careful, it's hot.
Fill the glasses.
Olga, the ladle.
- Looks good.
- Where's the meat?
I'm not hungry.
No meat for the boss today.
Everyone's working on
the second building?
Hello?
Who is this? Answer me!
What do you want?
Who's calling?
What is it all about?
Hello? Listen to me.
Mikhail?
Misha.
I'm sure, it's you.
Please, let me know if it's you, say
something. Who is this? What's going on?
Mom, it's me.
- Hello?
- Mishenka. Misha.
- Don't cry, mom.
- Thank God, you're alive!
- Mishenka, where are you?
- Don't cry, mom. Okay?
Don't tell anyone, Mom. Not even Dad.
All right, I won't. We're so tired.
Your dad and I think about you all the time.
Is everything all right?
Don't cry, Mom. I love you.
I'm fine, Mom.
Why did you wait so long to call us?
I'm far away. I'm sorry.
- You got a girl, right?
- Yeah.
Little Samia?
You're still with Samia? Here.
She still lives in the projects?
We do the best we can.
- You take her to the movies?
- Yes.
- You know, Mom's been asking about you.
- Really?
She wants me to stop by the house.
She wants me to stop by.
Keep it. I don't know
where you get your money.
You think I buy your story about the job?
If I lie, it has nothing to do with you.
Do you understand?
The problem between Mom and me
has nothing to do with you.
I know. So why do you lie to me?
I'm sorry.
You've got white hair everywhere.
It's cool.
Do you have kids?
You have to go. My wife will be home soon.
You want to see me again?
I shouldn't get into bad habits.
Come in, if you're so interested.
Take it.
Go on.
I told you. I look awful in this.
Put it on.
Go.
I don't.
Please.
Don't be so formal.
I look horrible.
Now, speak with you male voice.
- Male voice?
- Yes.
This is my real voice.
No, you have another one.
Hello.
I've been watching you,
you're really beautiful.
Thanks, that's sweet.
- Come here often?
- Yeah, do you?
First time. I usually go to Kat's.
Actually, I want to ask you something.
Fire away.
I'd like to...
Fuck me, is that it?
Not exactly.
That guy over there with the brown coat.
I'd do it with him.
- Go talk to him.
- No, that's your job.
Better hurry, he's leaving.
Dja, it's me.
I need the apartment. Can you split?
No, a customer. Okay, me, too.
I'd rather you pay now,
that way it's taken care of.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
Don't worry.
Suck his dick.
No kissing. Keep going.
Not like that. Faster.
Like this.
Now, fuck her.
You, get on all fours.
Go, go. Don't be afraid.
She's used to it.
Jerk her off.
Careful, don't come too fast.
Now.
Dominique?
What should I do with these?
Throw it all away. I'm not keeping anything.
Is this you?
For me.
Don't play with the door, Lucas.
Leave it alone. Leave it.
You're bothering people, cut it out.