Improved & Synced by BanglarBagh
(MUSIC PLAYING)
JOHN: (NARRATING)
Ah, Venice Beach... a city built on contrast.
Decade old concrete buildings layered
between million dollar homes.
Worn out beach bums litter the same
streets your cousins from Oklahoma...
...visit every summer.
Every weird dive bar you love is being
pushed out by some shitbag tech company.
And somewhere between the ruckus,
you'll find this guy...
...Venice's only licensed detective.
You just gotta live your life.
It goes by so fast. It's like a whisper.
JOHN: That's my boss, Steve Ford...
...a self-appointed figurehead
in the community.
Takes that job very seriously.
Before you know it, you're 12 years old,
and then where are you?
I don't want you to make
the same mistakes that I made.
It starts like this, a little bit of weed,
and then a little bit of blow, okay?
And then a couple bottles
of tequila every week.
And hookers three times a week.
And, yeah, it's fun, in the moment,
it's fun, but let me tell you something.
Those moments always end up
when your head feels like this big...
...like a bus ran over it.
You happy about that?
No, you're not happy about that.
Then not too long after that,
you're sitting on your kitchen floor...
...buck naked, you got a gun in your mouth...
...and all you're thinking
about is, is today the day?
Is today the day I pull the trigger? Bang!
But you got a right to live...
...and you gotta fuckin' live right,
you get me?
All right.
Let's go. This is a skate park,
come on. Let's go skate.
JOHN: I always wanted to be
a private detective...
...and with Steve being the only outfit
in town, I really had no other choice...
...but to work with him.
Which is good... I think.
And seeing as he was busy mentoring
the local youth of today...
...I was left to finally get a shot
at cracking my first case...
...and it has led me here,
to Nola Tuiasosopo...
...at least, I believe I'm pronouncing
that right, I don't know, she's Samoan.
Not that there's anything wrong with that...
...some of them have tricky
last names, some of them.
Well, I'll edit that later. Uh...
Missing since July. I just spotted her
at the corner of sixth and Oakwood.
And, let me tell you, Steve was not
exaggerating, Nola is very attractive.
Scratch that, she is very, very insanely...
...why isn't she a professional
model-attractive.
Anyway, by the looks of it, she's going
into a support group of some kind.
- I'm guessing Alcoholics Anonymous, just...
- (PHONE BEEPS)
- Shit. Dammit.
- (HORN HONKING)
JOHN: And my name's John,
Steve's partner.
Uh, well, soon to be partner,
just waiting for some paperwork.
Who'd like to go first?
Hello, my name's Rick and I'm a sex addict.
MEDIATOR: Hi, Rick.
My poison's pornography.
It started back in Catholic school
and got progressively worse.
I'm currently logging about 40 hours a week.
That's a full-time job.
I've got premium subscriptions
to the big four...
...PornHub, RedTube,
Reality Kings and Brazzers.
Not to mention, EskimoTube...
...JizzHut...
Oh, God, I'm a monster!
Jesus, right?
Would you like to share with the group?
Hm?
- Would you like to share with the group?
- The group? Uh...
...no! No, I'm good. I'm good to just listen.
That's not really how it works.
Everyone is required to participate
on their first night, please.
Well, if it's required.
Okay.
I'm John...
- ...and I'm a sex addict.
- GROUP: Hi, John.
Hello. Uh, yeah, I just love sex.
I love getting it,
I love giving it.
I love it too much and I get it too much,
that's my main problem.
On that sex road, I've got my thumb out,
waiting to get on one of the sex cars.
I am also logging about 40 hours a week...
...but on sex, not just
jacking off like this guy, right?
Full-blown sex. And, actually,
come to think of it...
...it's more than 40 hours.
So, I'm doing time and a half.
I should get paid my overtime. I mean,
obviously I'm not condoning sex for money.
That's bad, right?
We all agree, would you? Good.
I really just have sex with...
any old thang that comes my way.
There's some limits, obviously, age...
...18 and below is no... no bueno, no good.
Upwards, though, is where I really shine...
...50, 60, 80, 90, centennials...
- Okay! Uh, thank you for sharing, John.
- All right, you got it.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Nola? Hey, Nola?
- Are you following me?
No, no, no, I'm not following you.
No, no, don't mace me!
I'm not a stalker. I...
...I am technically following you,
but not in a stalker way...
...just as a professional...
strictly professional.
Look, your brothers
hired my boss to find you...
...and that's where I come in.
They want you to come home,
okay, they miss you.
I could drive you,
at least to my boss' house.
In a professional way...
...not as a maniac or a pervert,
on either parts.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
JOHN: Yeah, uh, I'll let her know.
All right, so you'll be
safe there till tomorrow...
...and then in the morning we can figure out
how best to deal with your brothers.
Well, how about that Rick guy?
40 hours a week?
I mean, that's a serious
commitment to masturbation.
Yeah, hopefully he's changing
hands every once in a while.
I mean, if you don't,
that's carpal tunnel syndrome...
- And the blistering, and chafing.
- Ugh. Yeah.
Let's just hope he's got
a little tub of like, Neosporin.
- Ew!
- Well, I'm just saying.
Sorry.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Okay, well, this is it.
- Great.
As you can see,
it's a very nice establishment.
- And, uh, you'll be home in no time.
- (CALL BOX BUZZING)
STEVE: (OVER SPEAKER) Send her up.
- There he is.
- (CHUCKLES)
Steve's a great guy.
All right, well, pleasure to meet you.
- You, too.
- Yeah.
- Thanks for the ride.
- No problem, just doing my job.
- Goodbye.
- See ya.
(SIGHS)
She'll be fine.
Steve's a good guy.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(MUSIC FADES UP)
Stay down! You're gonna wish
you never touched her!
- Stop it, you're gonna kill him!
- Nola, take your ass in the goddamn room...
...and don't you come out of there!
STEVE: Listen, listen,
let's talk about this.
You're about to go through a Samoan storm.
- Paid you to find her, Steve.
- I did find her!
We told you to find her, not fuck her.
- She's our sister, you son of a bitch.
- Yeah.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
You're dead, Steve!
(MUSIC CHANGES)
NOLA: Run, Steve, run!
(SIREN CHIRPING)
Okay, hands, pal! Let me see your hands!
I said hands, now, get them up!
Aw, Jesus.
Oh, Bill, it's you. Jesus,
how you doing, man?
Steve, what the hell are you doing out here?
Aren't you tired of this Peter Pan bullshit?
This is no kind of life, you're an old man.
Why don't you just meet somebody your
own age and make a life, for God sakes?
- I will.
- You know, someday, Steve...
...one of these guys is gonna catch you
and what are you gonna do then?
Call 9-1-1, come find you,
we're gonna eat a lot of donuts.
- Fuck you, Steve. Go home.
- Take care of yourself.
- Be careful.
- This is not normal, okay?
They hook electrodes up
to people when they do this.
Well, that's what that feels like.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
There he is, get him!
Turn, turn, hurry up! Hurry up!
Go, go, go!
- Oh, yeah, we got him now.
- Faster.
Go, go, go, go, go! Look at this asshole!
- Shit!
- Come on, let's go, let's go.
Excuse me.
Steve, you can't have a gun in the bar!
You motherfucker!
(CROWD CHEERS)
TUI: Let's go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go!
Tino, Tino. Let me in!
Where'd he go?
- Yo, open up, man. Come on.
- You're naked.
- What? Yeah, naked. Please let me in.
- I can't take another heart break, Steve.
- The car? That's what this is about?
- I loved that car, Steve.
- Oh, man, come on, Tino.
- It was stolen and I asked for your help.
- I'm sorry, all right?
- I got feelings and I'm sensitive.
I know you're sensitive. I understand!
Alright, I'll get the car,
I'll get the car for you.
- Say you promise.
- I promise.
- You're not saying it. No!
- I promise you I'll get it. I promise.
- Fingers up.
- Let me in, man, all right!
- Cover that dick, I got pizza here.
- All right, yeah.
Fuck.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Orale.
- Pull, fucker!
I'm not going in there.
That's Spyder's place.
My car's in that guy's garage, Steve,
you gotta get it for me.
I'm not a repo man, okay,
I'm a fucking detective.
You promised, Steve. I saved your ass,
Steve. Your word is your bond.
- Okay, all right.
- Your word is your bond!
- All right, just relax. Give me the keys.
Thank you, Steve.
STEVE: I got this.
Hell yeah, fool.
Hey. Two large pepperoni pizzas.
You ordered them, right?
Hey, Spyder, pizza dude's here.
JOHN: Carlos Manuel Ochoa...
...goes by the name of Spyder, with a "y,"
with links to the Sinaloa Cartel.
Rumor has it he once killed a barista
at Starbucks for misspelling his name.
Which is tricky, it's with a "y."
Not the point.
If there's drugs being sold in Venice,
they're coming from Spyder.
Two pepperoni pizzas. Didn't you order that?
No one ordered pizza, man.
2-0-0-4, this is your pizza, right?
Kinda old to be delivering pizzas, aye?
You're telling me, man, my old lady
gives me shit all the time about it.
How much?
$25.00.
Thanks, man, thank you, that's plenty.
Hey, man, can I use your restroom?
I've been in the car a long time.
- One or two?
- One.
- All right, bro.
- Where is it?
To the left. Don't piss on the seat, huh?
All right.
Who the fuck are you,
are you a cop? Huh? Huh?
- No.
- Huh? Who are you?
- Steve.
- Is that right?
- I'm Spyder's friend.
- Yeah?
That's the lavatory, right?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(LATINO MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoa.
(CUSTOM HORN HONKING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
Hey, Spyder...
...I think someone's stealing your car.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Motherfucker.
You killed my car.
Aw, you can't kill a car like this,
man, look at it. You know...
...a little hammer, a little glass.
Tires still look fantastic.
Sorry.
Fuck!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
JOHN: Dave Jones, and no,
not the lead singer of The Monkees.
This guy's a local legend
and Steve's longtime best pal.
His claim to fame was surfing
the pier naked for 12 hours straight...
...on acid. Nowadays
he's lost a lot of that mojo...
...mainly due to a pretty nasty divorce.
STEVE: Hey, Dave.
Did you start working at Tino's Pizza?
Yeah. You want my take on all of this?
Yeah.
Never buy a surf shop,
look at this inventory.
She wants full assets and alimony, too.
Sorry, man.
You're gonna be all right.
We'll figure something out.
- Sun's gonna be up soon.
- Yeah, it is.
- Should probably get some sleep.
- I just finished your new board.
(REGGAE MUSIC PLAYING)
This has been fun,
but I gotta go pick up my dog.
Why don't you just let her have Buddy?
She likes that I come by to pick him up.
Makes her feel better...
...safer I think.
Her?
JOHN: Steve's sister has fallen on hard
times after her husband took off...
...and emptied their bank account.
He's really been there for her.
- Steve.
- JOHN: Helping out as much as he can.
- Hey, Katey.
- Thanks for the coffee.
JOHN:
It's pretty selfless of him, actually.
- See? What a guy.
- Taylor!
Taylor!
Uncle Steve's here to pick up Buddy.
Have you heard from him?
Still somewhere in Australia
and finding himself.
We can't afford to stay here.
He thinks there's something more out there.
I mean, what the fuck is out there?
Honey, I don't know.
You're gonna be all right.
JOHN: Buddy Ford,
49 years old in dog years...
...and 100 percent Parson Russell Terrier.
Man, does Steve love that dog.
Uncle Steve.
Hi, Taylor. What are you studying?
- TAYLOR: Chemistry.
- Want some help with that?
A.P. Chemistry.
Will you bring Buddy back later tonight?
How about if I bring him back every night
and pick him up first thing in the morning...
...until you tell me to stop?
- Really?
- Yeah.
- That would be cool.
- He gets a little gassy.
I don't mind it.
Come on, Buddy, here we go.
Come on, here you go, right out here.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Sorry, no dogs.
- Oh, no, he's all right.
- What does that mean?
That's just something I say
when I try to circumvent the rules.
- Sometimes it works.
- Mm-mm.
No? All right. Get out, pal.
Large coffee.
You're not in your office.
- Lew the Jew.
- JOHN: Whoa, whoa, okay...
...I know how that sounds.
It's not offensive, everyone calls him that.
I mean, he calls himself, "Lew the Jew."
- No, I'm not in my office.
- I went by your office.
- And you didn't find me there?
- Steve, I want to hire you.
JOHN: He's a savvy businessman,
and a little miserly...
- ...but not in a Jewish way, in a normal way.
- ...girl in the picture...
Hey, hey, Steve, that's a lot of money
for just a few pictures, you know?
Yeah. Could've cost you a lot more money.
Why are we arguing? Let's talk business.
Thank you. I'll see you later, Lew.
Let's go, Buddy.
Some son of a bitch graffiti punk...
...has been spray-painting
the walls of my apartment buildings.
I could certainly help you with that.
I know many of the taggers...
...in the neighborhood, the only
problem is, you still owe me money.
Aw, Steve, I can't pay you for that. You
understand, it's the principle of the thing.
Steve! We're getting the band
back together, bro!
- Great! Yeah!
- My man!
Taylor Swift saved the music industry!
- Who the hell is that?
- No clue.
I'll sell you the house back.
- My parent's house?
- Yeah.
You'll sell it back to me?
At the same price they sold it to you for?
Come on, Stevie, you're killing me, man.
I mean, this is Silicon Beach now.
You realize what I could get for that house?
No deal.
Ten percent more.
I can see this is
really important to you, Lew.
What gave it away?
- I want it in writing.
- You're killin' me.
Fine, let's go. I gotta show it to you.
Holy Christ.
LEW: See what I mean?
- I like it.
- You could see how I might not.
STEVE: He's really captured your essence.
- Why don't you just paint over it?
- I painted over it four times.
You should have seen the other shit,
it was filthier than this.
- I can't imagine anything filthier than this.
- Just get it done, Steve...
...if you want your parent's house back.
Just pay me.
Don't look at that, come here,
don't look at that.
(SURF ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
- How about this?
- Cash only, no checks.
And that's on sale.
Great, thanks.
She can take my shop,
but I'm not leaving her anything.
- Yeah.
- I'm letting it go.
You do that, pal, let it all go.
JOHN: Now, normally by this time, Steve's
already had about eight cups of coffee...
and he doesn't really handle
the caffeine all that well.
So, a little secret between you and I
is I switched the brew in our office...
...with decaf, you know,
to take the edge off.
STEVE: John. Have you seen a picture
around here, a picture of my house?
- Wow, this is good coffee.
- Uh...
...the Samoans called looking for you.
I said that you were very sorry.
Good. You didn't give them
the address to the office, right?
- No.
- Good.
Although, I'm sure if they...
...were to do any type
of light investigating...
...they could find out where it is.
What about the picture?
It's a picture of my family's house.
No. Look, the insurance company
said they won't pay...
...until you get a couple things sorted out.
A picture of my parent's house.
- Yeah, I haven't seen it.
- It was on my desk.
Okay, still, no house. The insurance
company said that we won't get paid...
- ...until we, you know, file them.
- Mm-hm.
- We're on a new case now.
- Great.
Lew the Jew, all his apartment buildings,
you're getting graffiti all over the place.
- There's a month of my life down the drain.
- The house, it was on my... it was right...
- Sorry, this is it right here.
- Oh.
Oh, well, let's see
what this photo is all about.
This is me as a kid. Look, seven years
old right there. I'm holding the dog.
- JOHN: That's you?
- Yeah.
You're such a fat kid.
You know, my parent's fed me
all the wrong food, but...
Yeah, a lot of it, too. Looks like you
might've had a third brother that you ate.
Surprised you didn't eat the dog.
Just because of how big you are.
But you're good now, so...
Do you know any graffiti artists around here?
- No, not personally...
- Then you should find some, how about that?
Yeah, sure, definitely,
I'll find some graffiti artists.
- You should get more of this coffee, too.
- Yep, definitely.
- DAVE: Steve... I need you.
- (CAR HORN HONKING)
I lost a lot of this weight right away.
Come on, Buddy.
You also lost a lot
of that hair right away, too.
- Steve.
- Hey.
I need your help.
- All right, when?
- Right now.
- Right now?
You know why.
I'm desperate.
Okay. All right, Buddy,
in the back, up we go.
- Right now, huh?
- Yep.
STEVE: Stay low, Buddy.
Put this in your ear, you'll be able to
hear me talking to you the whole time.
Okay.
- You sure you want to go through with this?
- I have to, Steve.
The first sign of trouble,
you get the fuck out of there.
- I know, I will.
- I'm not kidding.
Wish me luck.
- DAVE: (OVER SPEAKER) May I?
- ANNE: (OVER SPEAKER) Hi, Dave.
DAVE: Anne.
You need to sign the divorce papers, Dave.
STEVE: Don't sign anything.
Repeat, do not sign anything, Dave.
(INAUDIBLE)
Dave!
I'll give you the surf shop, you can have it.
STEVE: Don't do it.
Get up and walk away.
You won't reconsider?
It's done.
Dave, it's done!
STEVE: Careful, buddy.
I'm going to sign these papers
because I've learned how to let go.
STEVE: Oh, no.
And if you think you deserve everything
I've ever worked for...
...then I want you to have it,
including the surf shop.
STEVE: No, no, Dave.
Don't sign anything, stop, stop.
I told him.
I think I fucked up.
It'll be okay.
Come on, Buddy.
You're gonna be spending
some time with Taylor.
Not forever. Come on.
That a boy. Go knock on the door.
How ya doin'?
I'm okay. How are you?
You know that I think of you as a son.
I did not know that, but thank you.
I guess I feel like, sometimes
I think of you as a father...
...in a way...
- ...a very intimidating father.
- I'm gonna need your help, John.
Okay, what, like out in the field?
You're gonna go out there and you're gonna
find out whoever's painting these murals...
- ...on Lew the Jew's walls.
- I checked out all the taggers in the city.
I got nothing.
The guy doesn't leave a signature.
Maybe he's not a tagger,
maybe this guy's a trained artist.
- Okay, yeah, sure, yeah, that fits.
- And, John...
...wear extra underpants.
Why?
Why do I have to wear extra underpants?
That's the discipline.
I'm sorry, sorry,
it's part of being a detective...
...to wear multiple pairs of underwear?
Do you have multiple pairs
of underwear on right now?
That's my secret.
Cool.
- Get yourself ready.
- Classic father figure.
Jesus Christ, Nola.
No, this has gotta stop, okay?
It really does.
It's over. I cannot see you anymore.
I just had to see you.
NOLA: Baby, oh...
(MOANING)
- (PHONE RINGING)
- NOLA: Steve, don't answer that.
- This is Taylor.
- Who's Taylor?
Hold on. Hey, honey, hi, how are you doing?
- TAYLOR: Uncle Steve.
- NOLA: I want you right now.
- Who's that?
- Oh, that's the maid, she slipped and fell.
TAYLOR:
We've been robbed, they took everything!
You got what?
They took everything, the TV,
the stereo, Taylor's Xbox.
I can't believe it, they took Buddy!
STEVE: Try to stay calm
and wait for the cops.
- Well, where are you going?
- I'm gonna go and get my dog.
- Our dog.
- Our dog! Don't leave!
- Rajeesh.
- I didn't see anything.
- See what?
- Anything.
- What the fuck you talking...
- No.
Doesn't matter what it is. I'm not trying
to get into any more trouble, Steve.
- Well, can I...
- No!
Your security camera is pointing
right down my street.
- They hate me in this neighborhood.
- Who hates you? You are beloved.
Not all of them, okay, but I'm the outsider.
They stole my dog, Buddy.
- A delicacy in my country, right?
- I never said that.
- You thought it. $200.
- $200?
That's how much it costs
to betray my neighbor.
What is it coming to?
- How about $80?
- Fine. Loser.
Two guys, druggies, they tried
to trade their stuff for some beer.
They had your dog. I've seen them
hanging out down by the boardwalk.
- You're a good neighbor.
- Fuck you, Steve.
(MUSIC FADES UP)
Hey, dickhead, can I hit that?
What'd you call us?
Actually, what I meant to say was
dickheads. Dickhead one, dickhead two.
- Hey, fuck you, man!
- How's that?
- Hey, what's your problem, bro!
- You're my problem.
- You broke my nose, fag!
- Oh, shut up, who cares?
- Where's my fucking dog?
- He ran away.
- Yeah, he ran away. He ran away.
- What do you mean, he ran away?
We gave him to our dealer,
our dealer has him.
- What's his name?
- I don't know the dog's name!
Not the dog's name, idiot!
What's your dealer's name?
Spyder, his name is Spyder!
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Buddy's collar?
Never fuck with a man's dog.
Fuck me sideways.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Hey, guys.
Spyder? Hey, Spyder, it's me,
Steve, you remember?
I felt really bad about crashing the car
through your garage door.
Brought you this delicious basket of muf...
(FORCED STRUGGLE)
You got some grande fucking cojones
showing your face around here again, bro.
- What time is it?
- Time to fuck you up again, yo.
That fucker knocked himself out.
Mmm.
Hey, what is this?
Banana walnut.
It's got a hint of cinnamon, yo.
So, why you here, loco?
There's this girl.
It's my niece, Taylor, just turned 15.
She's a sweet girl. Does good in school,
she's smart, she's happy, she's funny.
Out of nowhere,
her dad picks up and takes off.
Just goes to try and find himself,
whatever that means.
So now, I just... I look after
Taylor and her mom, Katey.
- What the fuck this gotta do with anything?
- Let him finish.
Go, bro.
Last night, their house got robbed.
They took that TV,
that stereo system and that Xbox.
But the most important thing
that they took was my dog.
Buddy.
- This dog?
- That is my dog.
I didn't steal this dog, okay?
I didn't steal this dog.
Shut up.
Yo, we didn't steal no dog.
- The dog was a gift.
- Uh-huh.
Nevertheless, this dog
is the only thing that my niece...
...gets any comfort from.
- So, you want the dog back?
- I'm not giving you the dog back!
- Shut up.
- It's the only thing I want.
Okay then, ese. You can have the dog back.
- No!
- Yes. (SHUSHING)
It's only gonna cost you $3,000.
- $3,000?
- $4,000.
- You just said, $3,000.
- You just fucked up my window.
- You gave that dog to me.
- Cállate.
You give me four grand for the car,
the window and the garage...
...and I'll throw the dog in because
the story of the little niña...
...touched my heart, bro.
- I don't have that kind of money.
- Then I'll fucking kill you.
- Then I can get it.
- You got 24 hours, Holmes.
That's my dog, Spyder.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
JOHN: Ah, Yuri, Venice's local loan
shark and ruthless son of a bitch.
Everybody knows, he is the last person
you want to borrow money from.
He's also the last person you want
to see on a beach wearing a bikini.
I love this country.
JOHN: He only gives you a day
to pay him back.
What kind of person borrows money from a guy
who only gives you a day to pay him back?
- How's it going, Yuri?
- (JOHN SIGHS)
Eh, it takes patience.
So, how much money you looking for?
- $5,000.
- On the phone you said, $4,000.
I figured if I ask for four,
I should probably ask for five. Right?
So, how you figure
on paying this monies back?
Yuri, it's me, Steve,
you know I'm good for it.
- (METAL DETECTOR BEEPS)
- Whoa, oh, oh! Wait, wait, wait.
(LAUGHS)
- Huh!
- A Casio!
I need this, I'm awful with time.
Listen, you ever heard
of the, uh, Belarus Bowtie?
First you cut off the testicles...
...then you shove them down throat.
Then you have incision here and here.
You pop the balls out and it looks like a...
- Bowtie?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Very formal.
Listen, Stevie, I like you, you're funny.
I loan you money...
...but you pay me back
or you have scrotum bowtie.
"Ponimayu?"
Da.
- Scrotum Bowtie.
- Mm-hm.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
See you soon.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
LEW: So, Steve...
...I just got off the phone with my brokers
and it turns out that the Chinese group...
...that's interested in buying my apartment
complex is getting a little skittish...
- ...about the graffiti situation.
- Yeah...
...the graffiti situation
is getting skittishy.
They're cutting their offer by half, Steve.
So, here's the thing, okay? You find
this graffiti kid in the next two days...
...and you guarantee me no graffiti
through the end of escrow...
...and I will sell you this house
for what I paid for it.
- That's really generous, Lew.
- Mm-hm, it is.
Look, the way I see it, you're probably
looking at a loss of eight figures...
...if I don't find this guy. But if you
don't want my help, I understand.
- I'm sure you...
- Okay, okay, yeah, I get it, okay.
Find the guy and I'll give you
the fuckin' house!
You see? Give, take, and everybody's happy.
I'm not happy. This is not happy.
Catch the fucker.
Steve? Hi, it's John,
sorry to leave this on your voicemail...
...but I'm just looking at a picture of
one of the murals from Lew's building...
...and, okay, yes...
...I give the piece as a whole,
seven out of ten.
The scrotum shading, the veins...
...and it's like the whole thing
just follows you.
So, here's what I'm gonna do.
JOHN: (NARRATING) I'm gonna go
to all the local art galleries...
...show them the picture,
just try to absorb as much cock as I can.
In, uh...
...ocularly, through my eyes, not...
All right, well... I'm gonna go hop on
this and I'll check in with you later.
Jesus, man, that was bad.
Hey, uh... I'm wondering
if I can ask you about an artist.
- Sure.
- Okay.
I gotta warn you, it's a little racy.
Ah, yes! Salvatore Lopez, that's the artist.
- Salvatore Lopez, are you sure?
- I'm positive.
- You sure?
- Yes.
Look, you see how the veins follow you?
- Yes, I do.
- It's him.
And the, uh, scrotal shading, it's...
I mean, it's classic Salvatore. Perfect.
- Classic Salvatore?
- Absolutely, yes.
Classic Salvatore... where can I find him?
- Hm, why?
- Just 'cause I'm a big fan...
...and I'm actually looking
to commission a mural.
Okay, well, leave me your number,
I'll see what I can do.
STEVE: Hey, Spyder, got it, four grand.
Four grand. Where's my dog?
Bad news, fucker. Your dog's gone.
Gone? How gone?
All the way gone.
Lupe, that bitch, took him.
What are you talking about.
You just took my money!
This was for the car,
the window and the garage.
I was gonna throw the little dog in for free.
You think I'm some kind of fucking idiot?
Get me my dog or I'm gonna go crazy!
- The dog's just gone, is that it!
- Hey, bro? Bro?
Don't think I don't have
fucking nice people in my house!
- You really are crazy.
- They've been to places that you've never been to!
- I can see that, fucker.
- A lot of mental illness!
- Hey, that's Taylor's TV, bro.
- What about Taylor?
- What about Taylor!
- Yo. That's your little niece's TV, bro.
Take a breath, bro.
Listen, that bitch Lupe took your dog, hm?
And a briefcase filled with my cocaine.
You find her, you get my shit,
I'll give you your money back.
How about this?
How about I find your girl...
...and your briefcase full of cocaine...
...and you pay me triple the money.
Pfft!
Deal, fucker. But you better do it now,
before my drugs find a new distributor.
- I'll get right on it.
- Listen...
...wherever this bitch is,
your dog's there, too.
What? She likes Knott's Berry Farms, Holmes.
Knott's Berry Farm's been closed
for a long time, hasn't it?
No, it's still open. That other bitch
in that picture is her sister, Consuela...
...she sometimes hangs out
at my cousin's bar, La Patronca.
Got an address on that?
Fuckin' Google it, Holmes.
(MACHINE BEEPS)
JOHN: (OVER PHONE) I need you
to run some recon for me. Okay, pal?
The bar is La Patronca,
we're looking for a girl named Consuela.
We find out where's she's staying,
and that will lead us to Lupe and the coke.
And, John, try not to stand out, okay?
(RECORD NEEDLE SCRATCHING)
(WHISTLING)
Hector! Goddammit, what'd I tell you,
you're not a fucking DJ!
Hey there, amigo.
Uh, quite a place you got here.
Really nice. Um...
...to start, I would like one of
your finest cervezas, por favor.
I believe $2.00 should do it.
I don't want no gringo prices.
Oh, my.
Nice boots.
Oh, thank you, thank you so much.
Ah, you can keep the change.
I'm also, uh...
...I'm hoping you know something
about this girl right here.
- Jesus.
- Why you asking? You a cop?
No, no, I'm not a cop. No, no, no,
I'm just a friend, I'm just looking for her.
She messing with you, too?
No, not that I know of. No, it's nothing
personal, I just wanna talk to her.
Okay... just had to check.
Her name's Consuela.
She lives at the Hollywood Premiere Motel
with her sister, Lupe.
Oh, oh, wow, okay, uh...
...great, that was a lot easier
than I thought it would be.
Thank you, uh, gracias.
Oh, he spit that pit on your floor.
Uh, you know what...
...that is legitimately
all I needed to know, so...
...all right, I'm gonna let you keep that
and thank you so much for your time.
You can actually have the beer,
that's for you, my tip.
- Thanks.
- Be careful!
- She plays mind games.
- Okay.
- Takes hours to respond to texts.
- Oh, hello.
One of the most annoying things
is that she'll make plans...
...and then cancel them, day of.
She'll invite you over to watch a movie
and then just wanna watch a movie!
- Okay. Okay, I really, I gotta get going.
- Oh, and she's a Capricorn.
Yo, if you find her...
...tell her Rigaberto is thinking about her.
I will. Good day, gentlemen.
JOHN: So, after my stellar detective work,
I pointed Steve in the direction...
...of the Hollywood Premiere Motel
where Consuela was known to frequent.
Damn! Oh, my God.
Hey, baby, I'm Mocha. You looking for a date?
I... uh... I don't think so.
What... you some kind of fag
or something, sweetie?
No! What would... how...
Mocha...
...maybe you could help me.
Have you seen this girl right here?
What kind of Annie Oakley bullshit is that?
Some kind of bullshit Knott's
Berry Farm picture. I don't know.
Well, that one's Lupe, I've seen her.
- Room 216.
- You didn't see a little dog, too, did you?
Oh, that dog's got some bowel problems.
- He doesn't have any bowel problems.
- He shits fuckin' everywhere!
- It's a nervous disorder.
- Whatever.
Now, if you change your mind...
Mocha will turn you out.
I will noodle on that.
Oh, I'm gonna noodle on you. Trust me.
You cute.
Okay, so, it is 8:36 p.m.
I've got my stakeout provisions acquired.
- I am headed to the lookout spot right now.
- Time to kick the tires and light the fire.
- Hey.
- John, right? Hi.
- Yeah, hi.
- I'm John, my name's John. Hello.
- I know, we've met. I just said your name.
Yeah, I'm sorry, I remember you, I'm just...
I'm not used to people remembering me.
Well, how could I forget a guy
who followed me down a dark alley?
I should have finished the job,
killed you there.
Sorry, I wouldn't kill you.
By the way,
were you just talking to yourself?
Yeah... no... no, I was talking
into my phone here.
- I take field notes.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
- So are you following someone tonight?
Actually, yes. I probably
shouldn't be mentioning this...
...but, yeah, I got
a pretty sweet case going on.
I'm following a graffiti artist
by the name of Salvatore Lopez.
- Salvatore Lopez?
- Could be "Salvatoré", I don't really know.
- I love him.
- You do? You know him?
Yeah, of course,
he's like the Banksy of Venice.
- Right.
- I would love to see what he looks like.
- You and me both.
- Do you want some company?
Yes, but you know it's just...
...I mean, it's a stakeout,
it's sitting in a car.
I don't mind.
Okay.
You have a very low bar for a fun evening.
NOLA: Okay, my turn.
Fuck, marry, kill, Ellen DeGeneres...
...Oprah or Kelly Ripa?
Okay, uh, well, I'd fuck Oprah...
...because she's beautiful,
she's a national treasure...
...and if I do it right, I'll get a car!
Look under your seats!
Then I guess I'd marry Ellen...
...just because of the sense of humor,
you gotta want that in a wife.
And she's got an endless supply
of sneakers and suits.
- That's true.
- And will dance the day away.
And then, I guess, I'd have to kill Kelly.
Sweet, sweet Ripa. Only because...
...that's the nature of the game,
and someone's gotta die.
It would probably scar me for life,
it would ruin my marriage with Ellen, so...
That's fair.
(BOTH SIGH)
It's so crazy to me that you, uh,
that you know Salvatore Lopez, that's...
Yeah, he's great, I mean,
I love the way he combines...
...the Japanese theory of Shuko
with a street-style aesthetic.
Yes, yes.
Plus, his intimate knowledge with
the male anatomy. It's very sensual.
- And the way the veins follow your eyes.
- Yeah, yeah.
- And the scrotal shading.
- Shut up.
You know, you're kind of cute.
Well, I've been told I'm a bit
of a young Roger Daltrey...
...if he spent a lot of time with computers.
NOLA: Oh, John.
(JOHN MOANING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Ooh, it's my little noodle.
- Hey. Mm-mm. Ladies.
I like watching you walk away.
(WOMAN MOANING)
(SCRATCHING ON DOOR)
Buddy! Aw, man, come on.
There you go. Did you miss me?
Aw, come here, pal... take a little rest.
What do you think you're doing
in my girl Lupe's room?
Dog walker... they didn't tell you?
You don't look like no dog walker to me.
Really?
That's all you got, baby?
(WHINES)
GIGI:
See, I came to this town with a dream...
...make-up artist to all the stars and shit.
Then I got side-tracked when I met Henry.
He was sweet as molasses.
He took good care of me.
Loved me for what I was.
Good man like that's hard to find.
Don't I know it, girl.
What happened to him?
Oh, I killed him.
There... what do you think, sugar?
- I feel really special.
- Yeah, I knew you would.
Whew!
You know what I think is next?
A ride home?
We gonna have to give you a shave, baby.
I'll be right back.
Come on, sweetness, let's move
little doggie to the bathroom...
...before it shits all over the bed.
Gonna have some fun... mm-mm-mm.
Now, don't be wiggling around on me
'cause I'd hate to cut off what...
...little you got down there, baby.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Here you go, Buddy. Here boy,
here you go, pal, come here.
Come on, let's go. Here we go.
Get your ass back here now!
You broke my nose!
(GROANS)
GIGI: Girls!
STEVE: Run, Buddy, I'll find you!
Come back here! Come back here, motherfucker!
Let's get him!
Get that motherfucker!
Come on, girls! Let's get him! Get him!
We're gonna kick your ass! Open that car!
Get out of that car right now!
(ENGINE STARTING)
He was kinda cute.
Hey.
- Hello.
- Hey, fellas, how you doing?
You borrow money, you pay money back.
- Yeah, of course I do.
- So?
- STEVE: You gave me a week.
- No, it's a day.
- Yeah, but it's a week though, right?
- It's always a day.
- It's one day, no?
- It's always been a day.
Mm... nice lipstick.
Oh, yeah, it's my girlfriend's lipstick.
YURI: Brings out the color in your eyes.
- So, a day?
- One day.
All right.
Remind him of the due date, huh?
STEVE: I'm pretty sure that's you, Lew,
I just don't know what happened to you.
I'm running out of time, okay? The Chinese
are coming to visit the building tomorrow.
It's a Lucha Libre wrestler...
...and I think he's tea-bagging you, Lew.
I'm gonna lose the sale, okay?
Everything I worked for, for fuck's sake!
You said you were gonna take care of this!
- I got it, I got it. I'll take care of it.
- Okay? All right?
- Jesus Christ.
Hey...
...Lew, you think you could...
loan me $5,000?
You want me to lend you... fuck you! Steve!
And what happened to you?
You were supposed to take care of this.
Yeah, I know, I'm sorry,
I got, uh... distracted.
- Just go find the graffiti artist.
- It's very creative.
I've never even imagined
tea-bagging someone like that.
I'll...
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, Dave.
You're drinking alone and the sun's still up.
I've been evicted from my own house.
Ah, I'm sorry to hear that.
You know I'm there for you.
I know.
Promise me that you'll let me be there.
Fine.
I'll let you be there.
Listen, I count on you
to be the ballast in my life.
I need you to turn this thing around.
I'm there for you.
So, about that five grand plus interest
I need, so Yuri doesn't kill me.
From the closing sale at the shop.
- Oh, wow.
- Mi dinero es su dinero.
Thanks, man. Thank you.
Really, thank you.
- So, you are learning to let go?
- I'm letting go, all right.
Here...
...crash at my place.
Yeah. Thanks.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
- Hey, Yuri.
- Hey.
Thank you very much, very much.
You're welcome.
You're a man of your word, huh?
You, too. I appreciate it.
Listen, don't borrow any money from me, huh?
- It's dangerous.
- Right.
- Thank you.
- All right, thanks again.
- Come on, ladies.
- (PHONE RINGING)
JOHN: Hey, Steve? Hey, hold on.
Hold on. Wait for it.
Yes, I got him! I got Salvatore.
- What?
- Yeah, I was looking right at him.
Uh... and... just... I don't know if this
changes anything, but he's not Latino.
Well, 'cause Salvatore Lopez, right?
- But he's not, he's black.
- All right, I'll see you in a little bit.
No, that doesn't make me a racist,
I just thought you might...
...I'll be here. Jesus.
You must be Salvatore.
Yeah. So?
How much does this one go for?
$10,000.
I'll tell you what, I'll give you five dollars
for this and keep you from going to jail.
Jail? Man, I think you
should get the fuck out of here.
What's that? What's that?
Hold still, jerkoff.
You painted the top of my head blue.
You remember?
Now you're gonna tell me everything you know.
Hey, fuck you, man.
This paint don't come off.
What... what... what'd you write on his face?
- Or did you just stomp him?
- Dude, what is with you and all the violence?
JOHN: Aw, shit.
Hey, look who it is.
What's up, cholos?
- Where's my shit?
- Yeah, where's his shit?
Dude, I'm standing right here.
- I can hear every word he says.
- Shut the fuck up!
- Hey, hey, don't talk to him like that.
- You shut the fuck up!
I'm cool. We're all good.
- You and your dog's time is running out.
- You didn't find Lupe yet, did you?
You're the one that's supposed
to be looking. I want my shit back!
I want my dog back.
Whoa, jeez.
- Great.
- You got 24 hours, Holmes.
- I'm gonna come find you.
- JOHN: Have fun.
You probably don't care but, um...
...you're saying, "24," but your hands
are actually saying, "42."
I know when I do my gang gestures,
I like to practice in the mirror.
See this watch? This watch is shit.
Fuck your watch!
What's the matter with you?
You might want to get out
of the house once in a while.
I know.
What are you doing?
I gotta go steal back some drugs for these
gang guys, so I can get my dog back.
But first I gotta go shake up
these real estate assholes.
Cool.
- Wanna come?
- Yeah! Sounds like fun.
Could be dangerous.
Maybe I'll die.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Hi, we're here to see Mr. Carter.
- Do you have an appointment?
No, just tell him we represent Lew the Jew.
- Lew the Jew?
- Lew the Jew.
- Hurry up.
- Just a moment.
- Hurry up?
- No more patience.
STEVE: Have a mint.
- How can I help you, gentlemen?
- You are so fucked.
I'm sorry, excuse me?
This about money? It's always about money.
It's Lew the Jew, come on,
you need a few bucks?
No, don't need money.
But here is the deal we are gonna make you.
You are gonna make Lew the Jew...
...a very generous offer for all the shit
that you've done to his apartment building.
We were thinking $22 million.
22... $22 million?
And you are gonna give
Dave here a brand new condo.
DAVE: One bedroom and a den.
Right on the beach, for free.
Okay, this, uh... is a moment for
me to call the police. Excuse me.
Oh, good, well, you can show them this...
...because right there, that is a signed...
- DAVE: Notarized.
- Sworn affidavit...
...by a Salvatore Lopez...
...the graffiti artist that you hired to
paint all over Lew the Jew's buildings...
...so the Chinese would drop
their offer and you could buy for less.
So, we have a deal, right?
Or am I gonna have to put your head
through that fucking wall?
There, there you go, fellas.
You have a good day, all right?
Bye, bye.
(BUDDY BARKS)
(WOMAN MOANING)
You're short.
- What?
- You're short.
That's all Prince gave me for that stuff.
I swear.
Oscar, I would never lie to you.
I gotta get back to Spyder's
before he suspects anything.
What happens if Spyder finds out?
Fuck Spyder.
- Where are you taking my dog?
- I found him out back. He's my dog now.
- What?
- OSCAR: Just stay here.
Pinche loco.
Time to go.
Fuck Oscar and fuck Spyder.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Bonus!
- DAVE: What gives?
- Some "just in case" stuff.
I guess.
Wow, where'd you get this? Some drug lord?
Nah. You remember Dana Kaminski?
- Yeah.
- Well, her old man was a cop.
DAVE: Sweet.
- Grenade?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
- Thank you.
- Knuckle duster?
- Yep.
- Ninja throwing star?
- Yeah.
You sure you want to do this?
What else have I got to do? I'm with you.
To the hounds. Nice.
(ENGINE STARTING)
- GIGI: You got a flat tire.
- What?
Are you kidding me?
- Well, fix the fucking thing.
- Gigi don't fix no tires. Shit.
Fix the fucking thing or we're gonna be late.
- Fine.
- Hurry up, okay?
Hurry up. Bitch.
- LUPE: What?
- GIGI: You heard me.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Awesome.
What the hell's taking so long, girl?
- STEVE: I'll take that.
- Okay.
Where's my dog?
Spyder has him.
I swear.
Hi, I'm Dave. I just electrocuted
the shit out of your friend.
He's taking a little nap in the trunk.
I want you to try these bracelets on.
They're free.
- Where's the rest of the coke?
- That's all there was.
Ooh, a shot to the knee cap,
that's... that's gonna hurt.
Okay, okay, okay, okay,
I sold it to this guy, black dude, Prince.
Where can I find him?
He's always at this bar called Bird Cage.
You're very cute.
Where are you going? You can't leave me here!
Oh, don't worry...
...we're gonna call the 9-1-1 for you
as soon as we scamper off.
Enjoy prison.
What? Pinches gringos!
- Hey!
- (HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
STEVE: Okay, you ready?
I've got a boner
for the first time in a year.
I have no... real response to that statement.
- Hey, man, how you doing?
- Fuck you.
- Is there a cover?
Prince is expecting us.
- What's in the case?
- A lot of money to buy cocaine.
I was planning on using that later.
Is there a back door to this place?
Man, fuck you.
- Thanks very much.
- You're really good.
Fuck you.
Manhattan, neat.
Vodka tonic.
Do you need me to walk you through that?
Whoa... not so fast.
We're here to see Prince.
Spyder sent us.
BARTENDER: Spyder? But Oscar
sent some girl over yesterday.
Hang on.
He said they'd see you, but they
hope you know what you're doing.
- It's that door down at the end of the hall.
- Thanks.
JOHN: Prince is a modern-day entrepreneur...
...money laundering, prostitution,
drug dealing, what doesn't this guy do?
These two look the fuck out of place.
What the hell are these cats...
Yo, yo, yo, who the fuck are you?
- I'm Steve.
- I'm Dave.
Okay, okay, first thing, you gotta
give me the card for that DJ, man.
He is playing some great music out there.
Came here to talk to me
about the motherfucking DJ?
You a crazy motherfucker.
All right, well, so enough with
the talking and shit, open the case.
- Yeah, just show me the stuff.
- Uh, just open the case.
- Show me the stuff.
- Just open the case.
- Show us the stuff.
- Open the case.
- Show us the fucking stuff!
- Motherfucker, open the motherfucking case.
- Show us the motherfucking stuff!
- Open the motherfucking case, Steve!
- What are... what are you doing?
- Kill these motherfuckers.
Shit!
Now the thing you need to do is
sit there real quiet and just sit back.
I'm just gonna hold this up to your neck.
Okay, be very cool.
We're gonna stand up, you ready?
Come on. There you go. Come on.
Shit just got real. You, put
your gun down, put your gun down.
Take that cocaine,
put it in our case and shut it.
Tick, tick, tick, tick...
Oh, here we go, nice and easy.
- Nice and easy, watch your step.
- You're in control, boss.
- Fuck you.
- Dave, you got this?
- I got it.
- STEVE: Good.
Easy, don't move,
don't fucking move, you hear me?
It was nice meeting you, all of you!
- (ENGINE STARTING)
- Hold on to this.
Shit! Oh! Oh, shit!
Oh, fuck.
(HEART BEATING)
The fuck y'all running to?
You motherfuckers fired!
All of y'all are fired.
- STEVE: That's right, it's the Muffin Man.
- OSCAR: You find that cocaine?
- Just put Spyder on the phone!
- Go fuck yourself!
No, I will not go fuck myself, Oscar.
Just tell Spyder that I got his coke...
...and I want my dog and my money, all right?
So I'll be over there tonight.
All right, goodbye.
Well, that was easy.
Yeah, easy getting in,
not so easy getting out.
- It sure smells like a set-up.
- You got a plan?
Of course, I got a plan.
You see what's happening here, don't you?
For the first time in your life,
Katey and Taylor...
...you're putting them
and their needs before your own.
Now me, I'm doing the totally opposite thing.
I'm putting my needs before anyone else's
for the first time in my life.
I've become you, and you've become me.
- It's a little right on the nose, isn't it?
- Sure, but I didn't have much time with it.
(LOUD KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Great news! Jesus! It's me, it's okay.
What the fuck are you doing here, John?
I have something for you guys.
STEVE: Hi, guys.
Fellas, you're a day early,
the luau has been changed 'til tomorrow.
- Fuck you!
- Hey, Manu? Just... please.
- Sorry. Sorry.
- Okay? It's okay.
Listen, we are here...
...to apologize to you, Steve
for kicking the shit out of you.
Yeah, little dude says we should.
Why are you listening to the little dude?
He's dating our sister.
How many sisters do you have?
Only one.
Yeah, yeah, it just happened,
just crazy chemistry...
...just right off the bat.
Just very... very heated...
...in a respectable way, just modest...
- ...modests, hot modests.
- Why didn't you just beat the shit out of him?
- Momma likes him.
- You met Nola's mom?
Yeah, yeah, uh, just yesterday,
actually... a very lovely lunch.
Joan... is a wonderful cook.
And it turns out, we both have
a passion for vintage cinema, so...
- So we're all good here?
- Yeah, we're cool.
- And?
- Oh.
We owe you, Steve...
...and if there's anything you need,
you could come see us.
What are you guys doing right now?
JOHN: I know I'm in the minority here,
but I don't love gun battles...
...at creepy, drug-cartel trap houses.
If anything, I'm more of an "au natural,"
hand-to-hand combat kind of guy.
So, I just sat this one out and headed
back to the office. You know...
...to do office stuff.
Here you go, buddy.
Hold tight, okay, come on.
- Ssh, let's get out of here.
- (PHONE RINGS)
(DOG BARKING)
(DOG WHIMPERS)
Right?
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoa!
Not much of a plan, if I can say that.
Stay here with the coke.
I'm gonna try and get Buddy.
Keep your head down.
Picked the right man for the job.
Get some!
Fuck you.
- What the fuck, Holmes?
- It's that Muffin motherfucker, man!
He's back, took a shot at me!
Watch the windows,
I'll find that muffinfucker!
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
MAN: Drop the gun.
Does Spyder know you and Lupe
stole all the drugs?
And you've been fucking her?
MAN: Where's my coke, bitch?
You lying motherfucker.
Now what?
We had a deal... your doggie
and the money for my cocaine.
- Yeah.
- You got my coke?
It's on it's way.
It's okay.
Bring it on, motherfucker!
- Dave, Dave!
- What the fuck are you doing?
I'm completely out of control.
All right, that's our guy.
Is that for me?
Yes, here we go. I got it, I got it.
Dude... okay. Thank you.
Mm.
- Hang on to that.
- (BUDDY BARKS)
There he is, come here.
Buddy! I missed you so much!
You been feeding my dog?
Pedigree, lamb and rice blend,
he loves that shit.
Yeah, he does. Thanks for looking after him.
No problem.
- We cool?
- Cool.
- See you down the road, Holmes.
- All right, okay.
Not a bad fella, that Spyder.
JOHN: So, Steve got the job done.
Was it unorthodox in execution? Sure.
Should he see someone about multiple
concussions in a span of 24 hours?
Definitely. Could he benefit from
maybe a therapist to help him...
...sort out some of his many issues?
That's not for me to say.
The main thing is...
...Steve got his dog back.
Lew the Jew made good on his deal...
...and me, I got the girl.
Never thought I'd get to say that.
She's all yours.
You, uh, take good care of her, huh?
- I will, Lew.
- Okay.
- Thank you very much.
- Yeah.
You did the right thing.
(CHUCKLES)
LEW: Nah.
- Hey.
Hi, baby.
Do you like your new room?
My new room is...
...pretty amazing. Thanks, Uncle Steve.
STEVE: You're welcome.
Have a good time today.
Thought you might want that.
Thank you.
Hot moo! Moo!
STEVE: I'll take a steak.
JOHN: Either way, everyone is happy.
Case closed.
(PHONE VIBRATES)
- Hello.
- JOHN: Steve, it's me, it's John.
(DIALOGUE BREAKING UP)
- I can't hear you very well. Who is this?
- Here, I got you. It's John.
Yeah, uh, look, I know everyone
is probably looking forward...
...to my world-famous pasta salad...
...but I won't be able to make it.
STEVE: So I invite you to my party,
and you're not gonna bring anything?
I won't be able to attend the barbeque...
pasta salad's already made.
Okay, no worries, pal, I'll see you tomorrow.
- Well, yeah...
- (HANGS PHONE)
Hello?
Steve?
I believe he hung up.
That's terrible, because if he's not gonna
come to us, now we gotta go to him...
...which means you need
to tell us where he is.
No.
No, I won't. So, you're just
gonna have to find him...
...and you won't be able to find Steve.
Not in Venice.
He knows every nook and cranny
in this neighborhood. He'll disappear...
...he's got friends in high places,
and got friends in low places.
I didn't mean to quote
that country song right now but...
...the point is, if he even gets a whiff
of trouble, he'll turn into a ghost.
Not literally, obviously, but...
Hold on. Clancy...
...rewind that shit back
like... like a minute.
What's the address of that house
we scored from Lew the Jew?
JOHN'S VOICE: I'm standing in Steve's
parents' house at 845 Holland Canal...
...the one with the white picket fence.
I think it's mid-century.
Really? And you know,
it's perfect timing because I'm starving...
...and I really love pasta salad.
I hear yours is world-renowned.
You guys hungry?
Y'all ready to go eat? Yeah, okay?
We're going to a party, white boy.
Oh, God. Please don't.
Actually... let's go.
Thank you... thank you
for not shooting my balls.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Okay, well, I'll just be here.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
No.
(MUSIC CHANGES)
Improved & Synced by BanglarBagh