-[Emily] Night.
-[woman] Night.
-[man] Night, Em.
-[Emily] Night.
-[man] See you tomorrow.
-[Emily] Good night.
-Emily?
-Good night, Steven.
-Aren't you leaving early?
-If anything, it's late.
Incidentally, Emily, I think
the windmill is taking
too much time
for the tour, so...
Steven, the windmill is fine.
No, no, I like the windmill--
Can we talk about it tomorrow?
Emily, this is important.
Why are you avoiding me?
David, how can I avoid you?
We work in the same place.
Now listen, Emily,
I'm having difficulty with--
[exhales]
Steven, we're getting a divorce.
[woman] Good night, Emily.
[cash drawer opens]
[weather news on radio]
[music playing]
[car door opening]
Good night.
[knocking on door]
[door opening]
You almost missed me.
Almost. Thanks, Ira.
See you tomorrow.
[Emily humming a tune]
[dog barking]
[cat meowing]
Shit.
Hi, Jenny.
[Emily screams]
[cat screaming]
[glass breaking]
[Emily struggling]
[Emily screams]
[knife opening]
[man breathing heavily]
You yell,
the knife goes down your throat.
You understand?
Now I wanna hear you say,
"Yeah, I understand."
Speak up. I can't hear you.
Yes, I... I understand.
[breathing nervously]
You got underwear on?
Don't hurt me please.
What you got on?
Top and bottom, or what?
Please.
Show me, show me,
come on, lift your sweater.
I can't.
That's bullshit. You're crazy.
Sure, you can. You better do it.
[Emily crying]
Now, pull it down, sweetheart.
Hey, pull it down.
No, no.
Hey!
Oh yeah.
Pure tit.
Now open your mouth.
Say, "Ah."
-Ah.
-[man grunting]
[grunting]
You move. I cut.
Please.
Shut up and move it.
Gonna make it sound
like you're having a ball.
Now say, "Ah."
Ah.
[birds chirping]
[chatter on police radio]
[police radio] Frank investigate
a 10-10, 20 Plaza Street,
Lincoln place
on Vanderbilt Avenue,
it's in the street.
[chatter on police radio]
[dog barking]
[birds chirping]
[engine starting]
[car door closing]
If there’s something you can
remember about the incident?
Or... any sort of description.
Anything?
We know how difficult this is.
And you don't have to say
anything you don't wanna say.
[knock on door]
Emily? It's Andrea.
[footsteps]
Who are you?
I'm looking for Emily.
A police officer.
What's happening? Emily?
[door closing]
[Bob]
You're a friend? Miss...
[Andrea] Glassen.
-[Bob] Glassen.
-What's happening here?
Someone broke in.
She was assaulted.
[policewoman]
Sit down, Miss Glassen.
Sometimes a friend can help
make these things easier.
[policewoman] Emily?
If he's done
this kind of thing before,
-and he's been--
-Just give her a chance.
She used to have
some difficulty with--
[Emily]
I can... speak for myself.
I told you... it was dark.
I... couldn't see.
He wanted to hurt me.
He was very cruel.
Miss Hollander,
I know that you're at
a disadvantage.
And I realize,
it's not gonna be easy for you
to give us a description.
To describe what he did.
[Andrea] You're making her
nervous.
Would you like to try
and write it down?
Might be easier.
He's gonna be real hard
to catch, you know.
Unless you help me.
You understand?
You are.
You're making her nervous.
Look...
I just don't want this
to happen to anyone else.
So what I really need here is...
you know,
just some small detail.
A piece of his clothing...
if you can remember his voice...
or his face.
Whenever you can.
You can call that number there,
or you can just stop by.
And I'll be there
to listen to you.
Okay?
[floor creaking]
[door closing]
[dog barking]
You don't have to tell him
anything, you know.
He's never gonna catch
who did it.
I'll make some coffee.
We'll talk.
[water running]
I've been thinking,
after what's happened,
you shouldn't stay here alone,
you know.
-[Emily] A... Andrea?
-Yes?
I'm... sorry.
Would you... please leave now?
Sure, if you like.
I... wanna work this,
this out, by myself.
[door closing]
[Emily sighs]
[cat meows]
[Emily cries]
Oh, Jenny.
[phone ringing]
[man] Alright,
if you just sign at the X.
I suppose you realize how lucky
you are to catch one available.
[Emily] Yes. Thank you.
Now we need the check, huh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
[Emily clears throat]
[phone ringing]
And remember, no pets.
-[ship horn]
-[whistle blowing]
[door bell ringing]
[woman] Who is it?
[Emily] Hi, it's your
new neighbor from 6-G.
[woman] Yes?
My phone isn't in yet,
and I was wondering if I--
-Come in.
-[Emily] Thank you.
It's over there.
[phone ringing]
-Hello.
-[Emily] Steven?
Emily. I was just working late.
We are adding a piece
of equipment here.
[Emily] Uh...
Hey, what happened
to you by the way?
You weren't at work today.
I called, but...
Steven,
I can't talk right now. I...
I...
Something came up
and I need your help.
[Steven] Really?
I have to move right away,
tomorrow morning.
What about work?
Steven, I need your help.
I don’t know.
Steven, can't you drive over or
send one of the guys and a car?
Um... Well...
I...
Okay, yeah,
I'll send somebody over.
Great.
What time?
Um... Eight o'clock.
Yeah, okay, I'll try.
Thanks a million, Steven.
Really.
Thank you.
You know, young lady,
there is a telephone,
a pay telephone in the lobby.
Oh, I... I'm terribly sorry,
I didn't realize.
Don't be sorry, you didn't know.
Right. Thanks again.
You're welcome.
[man on tape]
Two rubber baby buggy bumpers.
[Emily] Two rubber
baby buggy bumpers.
[man on tape]
Three Swiss wristwatches.
Four thick thistle sticks.
[Emily]
[man on tape] Five buckets of
blue bats and black bug's blood.
[Emily] Five buckets of
[man on tape] Six sheik’s
with the sixth sheik's
six sheep sick.
[Emily] Six sheik's
with the sixth sheik's... shit.
[man on tape] Seven lemmings
lapping lemon liniment.
[Emily] Seven lemmings
[man on tape] Eight witches
and which witch wished
the wicked wish?
[somber music playing]
[Emily on recording, sighing]
[man on recording] Now pull it
down, sweetheart.
Hey... pull it down.
[Emily] No, no.
[man] Now open your mouth.
[man] Say, 'Ah.'
[Emily gasping]
[man] Say, "Ah."
-[man] Ah.
-[Emily] Ah.
[footsteps]
[knocking on door]
Miss Hollander.
[cat meowing]
[cab driver] Number three
Granbury you said, huh?
Yes.
[train horn honking]
[Emily] Thanks.
[dog barking in distance]
[cat meowing]
[keys clanking]
[phone ringing]
-Hello.
-[Steven] Emily?
What's the matter, Steven?
-Emily, you better come to work.
-What?
Now look, I have a staff
to think about,
and the maze
still isn’t finished.
Oh, my God, no one
is coming for me, right?
[knock on door]
I just can't go sending people
all over the place.
Never mind, it's my fault.
Goodbye, Steven.
Emily!
Who is it?
[Andrea] It's me.
-Andrea, hi.
-Hi, I called you last night.
Are you alright?
-I'm moving.
-Oh.
-Where?
-Across the river.
Have a doorman...
clean paint... view.
Shouldn't you think this out?
I have...
Can't live here anymore.
I can't, I can't!
Besides, I signed a lease.
[Andrea] Have you told Steven
what happened?
[Emily] What for?
Seems I... seems I don't
choose men very well.
[Andrea] No, huh.
What does the Shrink
have to say?
[Emily] Marin? He says,
"Hmm, what do you think."
A lot of that.
I was never very comfortable
with Dr. Marin anyway,
and besides it doesn't matter
from here on in,
my money goes for rent.
Money? I can lend you
all the money that you need.
Oh, thanks. No.
[knock on door]
Who is it?
-[Emily] Hello?
-[knock on door]
Oh Jesus, listen--
-[man yells]
-[Emily screams]
[man] Sweetheart.
[man grunting]
[screams]
[man screaming]
[man grunting]
[man screams]
[man groans]
[man grunts]
[Emily gasping]
[Andrea]
It's okay, it's okay.
He's gone, he's gone. Okay?
[car door closing]
[chatter on police radio]
[policeman] Bob,
there is a young lady
down here to see you,
a Miss...
[Emily] Hollander, Emily.
[policeman]
Emily Hollander.
Take the stairs, one flight up,
first door on your left.
[distant chatter]
Emily?
I'm sorry,
I should've left the door open.
Come on in.
Would you like to have a seat?
[Jim]
I'll be with Persky, Bob.
[door closing]
He came back.
When?
[Emily sighs]
This morning.
He tried to break in,
but Andrea stopped him.
And the other night?
He had a...
He had a knife.
He kept putting it at my throat,
and... my mouth.
I couldn't breathe and I...
He tore open my coat...
Made me pull... my bra down.
He had a tape recorder and...
I had to make sounds.
It was awful.
He scared the hell out of me.
Did you see his face?
[sighs]
Today I... real quick and...
Well, he was a creep.
Look, how about
if I give you a ride home?
Oh, no, no.
It's not necessary.
[stammering]
I can take a cab,
I really like cabs.
[telephone buzzing]
-Yeah?
-[man] That you, Jim?
-No, It's Luffrono.
-Where's Jim?
He's next door with Person.
-Bye.
-[phone dialing]
-Jackie, it's Luffrono.
Look, there's an Emily Hollander
coming by the desk.
-Flag her a cab, will you?
-[Jackie] Sure.
[doorman] Hollander?
We put your stuff upstairs.
My stuff?
A girl. A girl in a sports car,
made two trips.
Thank... thank you.
[doorman] She has the cat.
Thanks.
[door lock opens]
[Andrea] Mmm.
You haven't touched your drink.
[Emily I'm...
I'm not much of a drinker.
Well, a toast to...
To good friends.
This is such a beautiful room.
Stay awhile, have dinner.
Oh, Andrea I...
No, I can't.
I really... I have to go.
But I'd love to have lunch
with you this week.
Absolutely.
Umm, where is Jenny anyway?
She's around.
By the way,
what happened with the police?
[sighs]
Well, they were very nice.
-Really?
-Mhmm.
But they don't know
who did it, of course.
No, not yet.
Jenny.
Jenny, time to go home.
[Andrea]
Are you sure you won't stay?
No, I can't, really.
-Jenny!
-[cat meowing]
There she is.
Let me.
-[cat hisses]
-[Andrea] Damn!
Jenny. Jenny.
Oh, the house is new to her.
She...
You didn't mean
to hurt Andrea, did you?
[Andrea] Doesn't matter.
-Here.
-I'm sorry about the scratch.
Forget it.
How're you getting home?
Taxi.
[Andrea]
Uh-uh. I'll drive you.
I insist.
[cat meowing]
How long have you been here?
Oh, couple of minutes.
You, uh, you did
a little disappearing act.
How did you find me?
That's a trade secret.
You called "Missing Persons."
It's a terrific view.
[laughs] This is official.
Oh, there's this little bakery.
Well, actually,
it's a restaurant too,
and once a week, I, uh...
I drive over the bridge and I...
I get these little cakes
they make.
[gentle music playing]
So I thought I'd stop by
and see how you were doing.
Thank... thank you.
You know the restaurant bar...
It's terrific.
I'll have to try it sometime.
Would you like
to get a bite tonight?
I, um... I can't. I'm sorry
Anyway, this place, you know,
it's gonna look great...
when you fix it up.
I better get going.
Thanks for stopping by.
Um...
-Bob.
I'll be in touch.
You can let the cat
out of the bag now.
Oh...
Bye.
-Taxi!
-[hurried footsteps]
Aren't you out early?
-God, no.
-[car honks]
-Gonna have a cup of coffee--
-I've gotta run.
I'm through with Dr. Marin.
I'll call you later.
Great day, isn't it, Larry?
[Lawrence]
Lawrence... where to?
Um, Brooklyn Children's Museum
at the 80th Street entrance.
-Okay?
-[Lawrence] Yeah.
[Dr. Marin] Andrea,
how are you this morning?
-Andrea.
-[Andrea] What?
[Dr. Marin] Troubling you?
I mean, something right now?
[Andrea] No.
Nothing.
[Dr. Marin]
You seem preoccupied.
[Andrea exhales]
[Andrea]
And you want to know why.
If you wish to tell me.
[Andrea]
I'm working on a poem.
It's a new one.
Would you like to hear about it?
Alright.
It's about love.
You know, Larry,
it's all in your attitude.
[Lawrence]
That's bullshit.
Are you crazy?
What do you know
about driving a cab?
Speak up, I can't hear you.
[suspenseful music playing]
Listen, Larry...
Stop at the corner. I...
I wanna call someone.
Flag stays down.
I... I don't mind.
That's bullshit.
Bullshit.
[suspenseful music continues]
[suspenseful music builds]
Forgot I had to meet a friend.
[ominous music playing]
[Lawrence] Hey, you live in
Brooklyn Heights?
No.
I think I've seen you before.
I don't think so, Larry.
Why do you keep
calling me Larry?
Lawrence is my name.
Larry is bullshit.
Sorry, Lawrence.
[Lawrence] I bet.
I'm sure I've seen you before.
[stutters]
Just pull over here, Lawrence.
-[dramatic music playing]
-[brakes squeal]
-Hey!
-[gun clicks]
Alright, shit-face,
out of the cab.
What did I do?
-[policeman] Get out of the cab.
-[Lawrence] What did I do?
-[Bob] You scumbag!
-[policeman] Get over there!
[Lawrence]
Hey, what's going on?
[Bob] Aw, come on!
You got the right
to remain silent.
[Lawrence] Crazy!
[clamoring]
-[policeman] Get him up!
-[Lawrence] Are you crazy?
[clamoring continues]
[ship horn honking]
-[phone ringing]
-[typing]
Bobby, just got a call about
that cab driver, Obecny.
[Bob] Yeah?
He's got a partner.
[Bob] He's got a partner?
-What do you mean?
-[phone ringing]
He said someone paid him
to assault Emily Hollander.
Oh who, for Christ's sake?
He won't say unless
the charges are dropped.
Could be bullshit.
-I'll see you tomorrow, Jimmy.
-Okay.
[car horns honking]
[Bob]
There are questions about sex.
In these kinds of cases,
I have seen Defense Attorneys
tear up witnesses all the time.
I suppose it never occurred
to you that I might...
help by handling myself well
in the witness stand.
Well, I didn't mean
you couldn't handle yourself.
I know what you mean, Luffrono.
You got it wrong.
Absolutely wrong.
Emily?
You okay?
You're the detective,
you figure me out.
[Bob] I'll try.
[ship horn honking]
May I sometimes come here?
Whenever you like,
it's your home too.
There are people here
who love you.
[man on TV]
Look at you and Tina,
share with you peace,
contentment.
[woman on TV] Of course.
And just think it won't be
for this time only.
That is, if you will help me
keep what we have.
If we both try hard to...
to protect that little
strip of territory that's ours.
-We can talk about your child...
-[man on TV] Our child.
Thank you.
And will you be happy,
Charlotte?
Oh Jerry,
don’t let’s ask for the moon.
We have the stars.
[romantic music
playing on TV]
[crying]
[sighs]
I'm proud of myself,
I only cried once.
[Bob]
I really love old movies.
[jazz music playing on TV]
I haven't gotten
my curtains up yet.
[man on TV] You've just seen
Now, Voyager...
starring Bette Davis
and Paul Henreid.
Don't miss
the special weekly broadcast...
[TV turns off]
I... hope you enjoyed
the chicken.
Oh, the chicken was terrific.
You have to go?
Yeah, I have to go.
-I have to get my other coat.
-Oh, sure.
[Bob I'll give you a call.
Will you?
[Bob] Mhmm.
Good night.
[Bob] Good night.
[sighs]
You should keep
your door locked.
[slow music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[Dr. Marin] Andrea,
it’s very important
that you make
a clear distinction
between what should happen
and what is truly happening.
Now is this in reference
to one of your poems?
Does it make a difference?
Don't you think it does?
No.
Is something actually happening?
Yes.
What is this something
you wished to have happened?
I know what I want.
[Dr. Marin]
You mean in a poetic sense.
And I know how to get it.
Have you said how you feel?
I will. I...
Maybe I...
I can't yet, but I will.
[Dr. Marin]
You're certain you will?
Yes!
Yes.
Why do you insist that I won't?
[Emily] The dinner was great.
[Bob] Yeah, I liked it a lot.
You still wanna
walk over the bridge?
[Emily] It's so beautiful.
[Bob] Yeah, it sure is.
[Emily] I bet you can see
my apartment from up there.
[man on recording]
Open your mouth...
Say, "Ah."
[Emily on recording
breathing heavily]
[man] Say, "Ah."
[Emily] Ah.
[man] Ah...
[man] You move, I cut.
Now say, "Ah."
[Emily] Ah...
[Emily] Oh yes, ah.
[ship horn honks]
I'm all out of coffee.
[Bob] It... doesn't matter.
Uh...
Look, Bob...
I don't feel very well.
What's the problem?
[Emily] I don't know I...
I have a slight fever...
headache and...
I'm coming down
with something.
Touch of the bridge.
Yeah.
We better make an early evening.
You think?
[phone buttons beeping]
[phone ringing]
[Emily] Hello.
Hello?
Who is it?
I think someone...
[Andrea whispering]
You son of a bitch.
Don't touch her.
[Emily] Who was it?
[Bob] Oh, it's nobody.
[Andrea coughing]
[solemn music playing]
Today's a complete
waste of time.
Sorry.
It's your time, not mine.
This is of no help
to you at all.
I don't know why
you make me come here.
I don't wanna talk to you.
Why did you get drunk?
[sighs]
Because it hurts.
Do you understand
anything at all?
"It was winter with love tide.
Fire we shared went out.
Unwanted, unneeded, untended."
Trouble.
[door closing]
[Andrea coughing]
[phone ringing]
-Luffrono.
-[Emily] Bob?
I knew it was you,
I was just thinking about you.
Did you get those drapes up yet?
Bob, my neighbor Ida Marx,
her husband is missing.
Well, how long has he been gone?
About 2 hours.
Well, do you know where he went?
-Well--
-[phone ringing]
[Emily] Sam and Ida thought they
heard noises in my apartment.
Probably Jenny.
So Sam went in to check.
[Bob] And?
He never came back.
[Ida] It's not unusual.
-Where are you now?
-In my apartment.
Is everything in place?
[Emily]
Yes, but I can’t find Jenny.
Oh, she just probably
slipped out.
Maybe so.
Look, I'll come over
as soon as I can.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Bye.
[Emily]
Ida, why don't you sit down?
I'll fix you some tea.
No, I'm looking
for those little bottles
that they gave us
on the flight from Miami.
You know, once he went
to Philadelphia, just like that.
His brother lives in Philly.
That time,
he was gone for 13 days.
So, what's two hours
and 20 minutes, huh?
Won't you go in the kitchen
and see if there’s some ice?
[crash]
Sam's gonna kill me
for getting sick.
Break the news to him gentle.
Huh?
I'm so sorry, Ida.
Don't be sorry.
Tell him to call me
at the hospital.
[Andrea breathing]
[car horns honking]
[Dr. Marin] I think
it would be advisable
at this point, Andrea,
for you to think this out
in a safe environment.
In a hospital atmosphere.
I made arrangements for you
to be admitted this evening.
I'll go with you and...
We can have a short session
when you get settled.
Of course, we'll...
we'll get a second opinion.
But for now...
for your own piece of mind...
I think we should go ahead.
Andrea.
[chatter on police radio]
[Bob] You better check
all the refrigerators,
stoves, any trunks, you know.
And rest of the junk down here.
What, another stiff?
[Bob] No.
What the hell am I looking for?
An orange cat.
[distant chatter]
[chatter on police radio]
[woman] Come on kids, move.
Emily, it's Sam Marx.
Kids playing in the basement
found the body.
-I have to call Ida.
-Wait.
Look, I want you to stay home.
And don't let anyone in.
Jimmy.
I've got work to do.
I'll be back. Okay?
Take her upstairs.
I'll see you back at the car.
Okay.
Nick.
I want the names of anyone
with a Brooklyn Heights address,
who bought a telescope
in the last eight or nine days.
A biggie. Expensive one.
I want it tonight.
Luffrono, the stores
will be closed soon.
-Tonight, Nick.
-Alright.
[Andrea]
Have a drink if you like.
[Dr. Marin]
No, no, no, thank you.
It's not necessary.
I'm glad you understand
about the hospital.
[Andrea]
Of course, I understand.
I'm pleased.
We're not talking about
a long time, you realize that.
[Andrea] How long?
[Dr. Marin]
Difficult to say at the moment.
How long do you think?
Andrea?
Where are you?
I'm right here.
Yes. I'm,
I'm still trying to find a...
patient by the name of Ida Marx.
[suspenseful music playing]
[engine revving]
[stammering] Operator,
I've been waiting
for five minutes.
[operator]
I just don't have a Mrs. Marx.
Are you sure she was admitted?
Yes, she... yes...
yesterday evening, late.
Well, I can’t find
her card in the file.
Just a minute.
I see. Here itis.
I'm sorry dear,we do have
a Mrs. Marx.
She's been taken
to emergency surgery.
[stammering] Thank you.
[tires screeching]
A selfish shellfish.
Two rubber baby buggy bumpers.
Three Swiss wristwatches.
Four thistle sticks.
Five... Shit.
[dramatic music plays]
[breathing frantically]
[phone ringing]
Paul Freeson.
[Emily] Bob Luffrono, please.
Luffrono is not here now, Miss.
Can I take a message?
[Emily] Where is he?
He's out on duty now.
Would you like
to leave a message?
Have him... call me back,
as soon as possible.
[phone ringing]
[stammering] Bob.
[Andrea] It’s Andrea.
[Emily] Andrea, thank God.
Somebody killed... Jenny.
[Andrea]
Oh... you shouldn’t be alone.
Can you come over here, please?
[Andrea]
I would, but I’m not dressed.
Why don’t you come over here?
It’ll be faster.
I can't... I can't.
I'm not supposed to.
[breath stammers]
I... okay, I'll come there.
[Andrea] But don’t hang up.
I've taken a loft on the river
and you'll need the address.
Just a second.
[Andrea] Just over the bridge.
17 River Street,
fifth floor.
I'll leave the door open.
[Emily] Thank you, Andrea.
[suspenseful music playing]
Taxi!
[suspenseful music continues]
[doorbell ringing]
[Bob] Emily?
Emily?
Jesus Christ.
Did you see
Emily Hollander go out?
Yeah, she did.
Just before you came in.
-She took a cab.
-What kind of cab?
It was a checker.
She didn't happen to mention
where she was going, did she?
No. But he made
an uptown U-turn.
It was a terrible thing, what
happened to Mr. Marx, huh?
Yeah.
[Emily] Andrea?
[water running]
[stammering] It's Emily.
[stammering] Hello.
I'm... I'm here.
[Andrea]
Make yourself at home.
[door closing]
[gasps]
[Andrea whispering] It's quite
wonderful sometimes.
What's wrong?
[stammering] I... have...
[Andrea] Have to go?
[Andrea whispering]
No, you don't.
[Mr. Hollander] Hello.
-Hello, Mr. Hollander.
-[Mr. Hollander] Yes?
This is Detective Luffrono
of 12th precinct.
[Mr. Hollander] Uh,
I'm not sure, I understand.
We're trying to contact
Emily Hollander.
She's not at home.
We thought you might know
where she is.
[Mr. Hollander] No, no.
She's seeing someone, you know.
I don’t know who,
but she’s with him I imagine.
What's wrong?
Has she done something?
No. Nothing at all. Thank you.
[Mr. Hollander] No, I--
[water running]
[faucet squeaking]
[water dripping]
[whispering]
I don't look all the time.
Just every so often...
to make sure you're alright.
[floor squeaking]
I'm glad you know.
I don't want it to be a secret.
I want you to know how I feel.
[Emily whispering]
Please.
[Andrea] Don't be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
[whispering] I love you.
-Elio.
-[Elio] Who's this?
-Hey it's me, Luffrono.
-Yeah?
Look, I need
the pick-ups that were made
at the bridge tower apartments,
in the last half hour.
-[Elio] Bridge tower?
-On pearl.
[Elio] Look, Igot46 cabs
out tonight.
Elio, please get it.
[Elio] It won’t be quick.
Give me a number.
Yeah, I'm 517-2110.
-[Elio] Okay, as soon as I can.
-Alright.
[whispering]
Why don't you ever smile?
You almost never do.
I've seen you laugh.
Cop makes you laugh.
Sometimes.
[Andrea] Go ahead.
-[whispering] What?
-Take a look.
I, uh...
I don't want to.
Oh...
I think you do.
[gently gasps]
Bob.
[sighs]
Is he still there?
[Emily] Yes.
[glass breaking]
[Emily gasping frantically]
[breathing heavily]
[Bob]
Harry, let me speak to Swid.
Jimmy, find Nick, will ya?
I need a name.
Just got on those scopes.
Yeah, I'm at Emily's.
Yeah, quick as you can.
Okay.
You could never love me.
Yes, I could love you.
Don't lie to me.
I couldn't bear it
if you lied to me.
[Andrea sighs]
1215 Riverside.
32 Carmen.
17 Howard.
126 Jensen.
1341 Logan.
115 Crescent.
[Bob] No good.
29 Brook side.
[Bob] No.
132 Hunter.
That's all he's got?
That's all.
Williams, Rollins,
Henderson, Gibson.
[Bob]
Well, none of those have views.
Are you sure
about this telescope thing?
Yeah, I'm sure.
There's no "G" page.
[telephone ringing]
-Elio?
-Yeah. Man two pick-ups.
329 Park and 17 River Street,
Brooklyn Heights.
-17 River Street?
-Yeah.
-Hey, listen--
-It's right there.
Glassen.
Andrea Glassen.
[Andrea] Are you cold?
[Emily] No.
Yes, you are.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Oh!
We just spent
the night together.
I could've hurt you,
but I didn't.
I kept it from happening.
No!
Why are you running away?
You said you could love me.
You did.
You said it.
Stand still!
He could've killed you.
That cab driver.
It's him.
Him, in your apartment.
God!
I told him exactly what you do.
Exactly.
Did he hurt you?
[stammering]
Yes!
No! Because I wouldn't let him.
You're lying.
-[door slams]
-[Emily gasps]
[crying]
Come on, show it.
Lift up the sweater.
Come on.
Show me.
Lift up your sweater.
Show me what you showed him.
I wanna see.
You have to. Understand?
I want to hear it.
I want to hear you say,
"Yes, I understand."
Now...
Open your mouth...
and say, "Ah."
Say it.
Say, "Ah."
[Emily's breath stammers]
Speak up.
I can't hear you.
Please.
Understand.
I understand.
What you got on?
Top, bottom, what?
[wheezing]
...is it...
Show it, come on.
Take off the sweater.
I can't?
[Andrea breathes heavily]
Sure, you can.
[Emily cries]
And you better.
Pull it down.
No... no... no.
Open your mouth...
say, "Ah."
[exhales]
[Andrea moaning]
Stop it... please.
Please, please,
oh, please, please.
[shuddered breathing]
Ah...
[moaning]
Please!
Stop it.
-[slap]
-[Andrea grunts]
Please, don't hurt me.
[quiet music playing]
Don't hurt me.
-Please, please don't hurt me.
-[chatter on police radio]
Please, don't hurt me.
[chatter on police radio]
[Bob] You know, you shouldn't
have left the apartment.
The last thing I said to you
was to stay home, I'll be back.
I know.
You were lucky, you know that?
She never would've done
anything to me.
Yes, she would've.
Come on.
Luffrono, let's walk.
I'd like to walk.
Emily.
I feel fine.
I feel very good.
She said she loved me.
She kept telling me all night
that she loved me.
[Bob] Yeah, well,
in her own way, she...
she probably did.
Say, are you still
out of coffee?
[Emily laughs]
[Emily] I never was.
[slow orchestral music playing]