You bad guy, you are here.
Give me my cloth!
- What's going on?
- There's something going on.
Give me back my cloth!
Aren't you going to? Give me my cloth!
Why are you doing this.
- He stole my clothes.
- What do you mean?
Move.
Is that tru?
Here, here!
You strange fellow!
How dare you harass women!
Aren't you embarrased as a man?
Original work / Lee Jung Myung
Scenario / Lee Eun Yeong
My wife is
Producer / Jang Tae Yoo, Jin Hyuk
very weak
and she wanted to come out and draw
and I was trying to protect her, is that a problem?
Is it?
No!
He stole my clothes.
He's a man.
It's a she, you might be misunderstading.
Take her cloth off! Then you will know!
Why are you doing this to my weak wife.
Are you alright my darling?
- I am feeling dizzy.
- Oh my, oh my.
I told you not to move too much.
I said I don't need this.
Let's go.
Look at that!
Run, run!
Artist! I will keep this!!
Stop there!!
Oh my god!!
My cloth! My cloth! What shall I do!
That's my new one.
Hey, this is my new cloth too.
Stand up.
You, you are that guy just now.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
- Let's go together, together!
- Hurry up.
Episode 5 Women on swing
Don't look.
I won't, I won't.
Why are you being so shy?
I won't see even if you beg me.
Ah, sir!
You said you won't look!
Why do you think I would look!
Hurry up, the sun will rise soon.
Anyway why are your...
What?
bones so thin?
You look like a woman.
No, no way!
I meant...that you could have got me
when you said you were a woman!
Who will marry a woman like you?
Ah, really?
Who will even look at you
when you are a woman?
What about me?
Hey, what's wrong with me!
I am very curious.
Finish up fast and show me.
The main chracter is not here.
It's until five o'clock tomorrow.
Can you finish it?
Where are you going to draw it?
I have somewhere to go.
Okay! Then go there and fill it
in with what you want.
Yes, sir.
Alright! Good!
Well done.
Keep concentrating!
Don't even try to be lazy because all those papers,
brushes, ink, and colors are made from
the citizens' hard work. Alright?
Yes!
Sir.
Are you here, Yoo choon?
Yes, you can leave now.
Okay, take care of the exam.
I can see some details there.
Good job.
Yes.
Hyo Won, hasn't Yoon Bok arrived yet?
If he doesn't come, you will be the artist, right?
What do you mean?
Aren't I right? Yoon Bok looks like a woman but
still he's the only guy who can compete with you...
Shut your mouth!
Alright, I will, shh, shh...
You were alive! Sir Dan Won!
I told you he is...
Duk Bong! Duk Bong! Stand up.
Duk Bong!
He was such a coward and I had a hard time
bringing him here.
Sit down, sit.
You stay out for a while.
Sit, sit, sit.
Why do you look so bad?
How did you stay?
I wandered around.
You must have had a hard time.
Did you hear about lL Wol party?
Are you going to send him back to Pyeongyang?
It will take time to prepare a horse...
Hey! Stay outside!
I said you need to tell me earlier!
It takes time to get a horse.
Did you hear about lL Wol party?
He is alive.
Alive, who is alive?
I've gathered informations after
the teacher died, and...
What? His kid is alive?
Yes, but I couldn't find where he is.
You mean, the kid is alive?
Are you sure?
Yes, he is.
Sir, I'm afraid.
I am still so afraid.
Don't worry, don't worry.
I will solve this, don't worry.
Myo' is for cat and 'Mo' is for a 70 year old man
and it is pronounced as 'Mao'.
A cat which means 70 years old is looking at
the butterfly which means 80 years old
and this must mean long life.
High official / Kim Si Up
Yes! It is!
Yes it is.
Kim Gwee Joo / Brother of Queen Jung Soon
How is it?
Would you give that picture to Sir Si Up?
I know that you have good taste
but you still couldn't find out who drew it.
It's not important to know the artist's name!
Don't you think so?
Then, cheers for everyhing!
- Yes.
Can I find out the meaning?
Can you?
Kim Jo Nyun / The head of the market
This is a China pink flower.
And it means 'youth'.
And here, at the bottom, it's a violet.
Why would have the artist drawn this
two flowers at once
when the China pink blooms at early spring,
and violet at early summer?
That's because there is a special meaning.
The old people called the violet a 'wish flower'.
And so this picture means that he wants you to
Iive long and be healthy as young people
and also he wants all your dream to come true.
Lastly...
The slanting line of the flower, the cat on the right,
and the butterfly is also acting in concert.
They seem to be drawn
Hwamyorongjupdo/Kim Hong Do
without plans but it's a very skillful work
and the lively picture is for sure
Dan Won's work!
- What?
- Dan Won?
Tear the paper out.
Dan Won? This is Dan Won's picture?
Dan Won?
Then would I give any work to you
as a birthday present
infront of all the high officials?
You have a great taste.
Thank you.
You've allowed me to show my talent today
so would you allow me to pay for tonight's meal?
You speak only beautiful words now.
Don't you think so?
The head of the market...
Is he Kim Jo Nyun, the head of the market.
He's the seller who payed sir Woo Sang.
You look quite like a upper class.
I've prepared this dinner in order to thank you
for ruling the country peacefully and helping me
to sell things well.
So, please enjoy.
Let's enjoy.
Mak Nyun, where's Jung Hyang?
Where is she when all the high officials are here!
Er...special guests are here.
Special guests?
Please come inside this picture.
What do I have to do?
To go in to that picture.
Show me everyhing.
Everyhing that's hidden inside you.
Your heart, spirit, firmness, and the music.
Why do you look absent minded?
I've lost my way for a while.
I'm quite sure that you've seen
something that you desire.
How dare you speak like that?
Then I should apologize.
But, you and I have the eye that others don't have,
don't we?
What is it?
The eye that notices something most valuable.
Inform me anytime.
If you get to have that girl inside the room,
it will be your most flourescent possession.
Now do I get to live...
inside your picture?
Then...if you pass the exam, can l...
Live only inside your heart?
In my heart...
What kind of a man can reject you?
And, what kind of a man act harsh on you?
Jung Jo/22nd King of Josun
My father the King.
Grandfather, please save my father.
Move aside!
Grandfather! Grandfather!
Please, please wait a little more.
The sleeves look like bended bows
since those feet are rolling in the air.
You must be the artist that was chased out
from the art department.
Shin Yeong Bok / Shin Yoon Bok's elder brother.
Who are you?
Huh Ok / Niece of the senior in color department.
What can we do!
Someone who breaks the mortar will not be able to
come to the color mixing room.
What's wrong with you?
I can fill in a mortar without anyone knowing.
Who are you and why do you have that key?
You are under sir Baek Baek right?
Then didn't you hear from him that
he has a beautiful niece?
I didn't.
That's bad.
Wait.
Why?
How can you fill in the mortar I broke?
I saw a secret and I think I should make one.
A secret?
What are you doing?
We now share a secret.
Let's go.
How come I can't see a dust?
Does someone really live here?
Aren't you abusing Myung too much?
Suh Jing / Kim Hong Do's friend
Do you envy?
If you do, go find a girl.
Don't fuss around here.
Are you making a joke again?
Yoon, you are here.
- Uncle!
- Yes, yes, yes, here!
Did you pluck some flowers?
Are you giving it to me?
- Do you want some radish?
- Is it delicious?
Yes, yes, here.
- It's nice right?
- Yes.
Suh Yoon / Suh Jing's daughter
Do you want more?
Where are you?
Yoon.
Where's this place?
My picture!
Hello! Anyone there!
Hello! Help me!
Help me! Hello!
Hello! It's inside the well!
Help me!
Hello! I'm inside the well!
Help me! Hello!
Is it true that there's a ghost in the well?
No way.
Let's go...
Inside the well! Look inside the well!
Help me!
What do you want?
I just remembered myself taking the
artist exam...
Goodbye.
Sir, sir Dan Won?
Where have you been this late?
I've ran an errand.
I have a job to complete...
Good job.
Now Dan Won can no longer stay here.
When did he leave?
It's been hours since he left, and he still didn't
arrive at the art department?
Don't you really know?
I don't know.
Would you tell me if I pay for some drinks?
I am really worried too.
Wow, I feel...
I feel so happy because of Soon Shim.
There's not much time left.
Yoon Bok!
Yoon Bok! Yoon Bok!
Sir, sir, sir.
Sir! Here, sir!
Yoon Bok!
Sir, Yoon Bok's here, sir!
Sir, sir.
What are you doing here this late?
Haven't you seen a little student passing by?
I didn't.
You almost surprised me to death.
It's late in the night.
Go to your house!
Here! The well, sir!
It's the well, sir!
Sir!
- lnside the well.
- Is it Yoon Bok?
Sir!!
Hey! Hey!
I found him! Come here!
Sir!
Yoon Bok!
- Pass me that.
- Oh my.
Yoon Bok! Are you alright?
Sir.
Yoon Bok! What are you doing here?
Are you okay?
Where are you going?
Don't do it, don't do it.
Please pass me that bucket.
- Yes.
- Bring it.
Are you alright?
What are you doing here?
Sir.
Yoon Bok, Yoon Bok are you alright?
Yes.
There's no time, hurry up.
Let me see.
It's quite bad, get on my back.
- Sir.
- Now.
- Hurry up.
Sir.
- Get on my back.
- Sir.
- Now.
Now, pull.
Hold on tight.
- Thank you.
- Are you alright?
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
There's no time.
Let's go now.
There's no need.
What?
It's all over.
What do you mean?
Everyhing's gone.
The picture is gone.
Thank you.
- Okay.
- Why did he go in there...
What shall I do? Sir.
Let's do this,
Yoon Bok, let's do this.
Everyhing's gone.
The picture is gone.
What do you see? Huh? Just tell me.
Imagine anything!
A swing, a woman on the swing, the fall.
The sound of the wind, water, rock, tree, smell
Anything's fine, anything.
Now, close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Anything's fine.
Imagine anything.
What you see, what you hear, taste, smell.
Everyhing's connected so if you can remember one,
all the others will follow.
Think of one thing.
Can you see?
Can you?
Concentrate.
Can you see something? Can you?
Yes.
Good.
Yoon Bok is still not here.
It's a pleasant morning.
Can you do it?
Can you finish it in time?
If he is late, we won't wait even for a second.
Look at that inordinate...
He's a bad fellow!
You there!
Sir!
Your brother was chased out
for a obscene picture
and you are drawing a group of women!
Are you brothers trying contempt the department!
Get out!
Sir! No, sir.
That's not an obscene picture!
Then what is it!
That's women breathing, talking and shouting!
That's women on Dano Day and it's not an
obscene picture!
Talk about it to someone else.
Sir! Sir.
Sir!
If you chase him out,
he won't be able to take the exam.
The King is watching this exam.
It won't be late to judge his picture later!
Don't you think so?
There's only one time bell left.
Afterthat, his fate will be on strict judging!
Do you get it?
Finish it.
The nipples!
What are you doing?
End the picture.
Hurry! Hurry!
- Did you finish?
- Not yet.
Time's up!
Sir, I finished it!
Well done!
Why did you make me so nervous?
I payed foryourfood!
You've worked hard.
Well done.
Yes...he did.
But don't forget that this is the art department.
You must know what this means right?
This is quite disturbing.
The women are calm while they are naked
and the look on theirface are dirty.
And the impression of the men watching fits
with sundry goods at the market.
And, look at that color.
What about the color?
There's too much color.
Is there any reason that we
can't use too much color?
How come you are interferring?
You should resist and control the colors,
and if it's too much like this,
don't you think it becomes into a shallow picture?
Why?
A good picture doesn't show
too much of it's existence.
But how's this?
It shows custom and it is trying to attract people
with naked women, and it is also trying to
attract people's attention with many colors.
Don't you think?
This is a shallow and a rude work.
Sir!
Didn't you mean that this picture
moves the heart of people
and pulls out one's soul?
Do you think there's a student who can
move one's heart with a picture?
This work neglects the art department.
Sir!
Don't you remember you can't judge?
Why do you keep talking?
Sir! Aren't you an artist too?
Shin Yoon Bok chose one out of two topics.
Is there anything wrong?
Whatever you say, this picture won't work!
- Doesn't it?
- I'm sorry.
That's a shallow picture...
Dan Won! What do you think you are doing?
Get out!
It's now a real goodbye.
What do I have to do when I miss you?
The art department has gone crazy.
Totally crazy!
It's crazy!
- That, that, that temper!
- It's crazy!
He doesn't fit with the art department.
We have to thank him for leaving.
Don't worry.
They are here.
We will announce the result of the exam.
First, student Jang Hyo Won.
All the 1 1 judges passed him and he has 55, the
highest score.
55/means a perfect score.
Congratulations.
And!
Special entrance! Student, Shin Yoon Bok.
Yoon Bok!
Special entrance?
What des this mean?
This student got judged by 12 judges
and he got one pass in order
to qualifyforthe exam.
Am I again?
How come did he get to be judged by 12 judges?
Who is it?
Who's the 12th judge?
How can he pass Yoon Bok?
He is...
He is the King!
The...King?
Inscrutable are the king's favors.