hello, this is
yvette malone speaking.
I'm not home just now,
but if you'll be kind enough...
To leave your name
and telephone number,
I'll call you when I return.
Please begin at the tone.
Yvette, nick here.
Uh, I just thought
I'd let you know that...
I'm still on pa's ship
off the coast of malaysia
thinking about you.
And, uh, sure is nice
to hear your voice.
Even if it is recorded.
well, we're getting some
rough weather here, honey.
So, uh,
I guess I-
they want you
to go up, sir.
Okay, let's go.
All right,
now move your asses.
Get him to sick bay,
and do it now.
Ha!
Well, if it isn't
mr. Keifitz.
Lookin' more like
your father every day.
You came all the way
out here to tell me that?
No, no, sir.
I brought you an assassin.
- A what?
- Yeah, well, that man
that they're moving there.
He says he shot your brother.
He was second rifle
at city hall.
It's an outrage
to bring this man here.
You prefer the native hospital
in brunei where a man can die
of athlete's foot.
I don't have the facilities.
This man fell off an oil rig.
Doctor,
will you leave us?
Then I take
no responsibility.
That's right.
And you, out.
And you, stay.
Now, can you write?
Sir?
English. Can you
write english?
I think so, sir.
Do your best.
Be our witness.
Just write down
whatever he says.
Fletcher!
You hear me?
Nick kegan is here.
You understand?
I think he wants
to shake your hand.
Now, what's
your full name?
Arthur turkus fletcher.
How old are you?
Fifty-eight years.
We will hear your testimony.
I shot president kegan.
Jesus.
How?
I was second rifle in city hall,
February 22, 1960.
I hit with both shots.
Where was
the number one rifle?
Behind the wall.
I shot on the line with him.
Who hired you?
Junior. Casper jr.
They remembered me
from shooting demonstrations
for the rifle association.
Said he'd push me into history.
Twenty-five thousand dollars
for a morning's work.
A morning's work.
Please,
Mr. Kegan,
The rifle's in the steam pipe
under the middle window
in the engleson building.
Room 903.
I left my fingerprints
and all with my name
taped to it...
For when the time came to prove
that I killed the president.
What about willy arnold?
The pickering commission proved
willie arnold shot my brother.
Nick, he's dead.
You can't run away
from this.
get a hold of
miles garner in philly,
Have him meet me
at the airport with
some long underwear.
It'll be
freezing there.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna look
for his rifle.
Mm.
whether this guy
is real or not, pa'll understand
I had to leave the ship.
- I'm sure he will.
- I hope so.
You get that down?
I'll look at it.
Jesus, you print
like an ape.
I'm a high school graduate.
But I've never been involved
in anything like this.
Now,
You were just a little boy
when president kegan...
Was gunned down
in philadelphia.
But in the subsequent
19 years,
More than 16 people,
Who seemingly
had nothing to do
with that awful event,
Have died under
mysterious conditions.
If what you say is true,
nick, it's gonna shake up
a lot of people.
President, congress,
everyone.
Especially pa.
Does he know?
No, not yet.
I guess this assassin thought
nobody'd look for him, working
for the president's father, huh?
We're gonna need a wrench
for the steam pipe.
We'll get it
from the building supervisor.
Captain heller, this way.
Captain heller,
that's the wrong building!
Is he reliable, miles?
Captain heller,
philadelphia's finest.
He drinks a bit, but if
there's a rifle up there,
he'll know how to handle it.
Captain heller, nick kegan.
We have no time
to lose, captain.
You say you're
nicholas kegan?
That's right.
Got any identification?
Come on. I've known
nick since he was a boy.
He's tom kegan's son.
Our late president's
half-brother, okay?
You'll vouch for him?
Of course, yes.
Good enough. Now, uh,
what's the problem here,
fellas?
It's this way, captain.
Oh. Kegan,
We did everything possible
to protect your brother here.
But you can't protect
anyone against a nut.
Nine-oh-three.
Damn shame.
Police, open up.
Open up in there.
Police.
You john kullers?
- We'd like to have a look
at your steam pipe.
- My steam pipe?
We'll get a search warrant
if necessary.
Search warrant
for a steam pipe?
how long have you
occupied these premises?
cops. Why me?
Answer the question.
Four years, I don't know.
Where were you
on February 22, 1960.
1960? What is this?
You don't remember the date
president kegan was shot?
Long island. In school.
Mrs. Sayers' eighth grade
english class.
Oh, yeah?
Look, hey, I got
a legitimate
operation here.
All right, miles.
I'll check it.
Stand back.
I'm sorry.
Sorry? What for?
Now you'll have to
live it all over again.
I could put it back.
You'll always
know where it was.
Oh, the hell with it.
What's that?
What is that?
That's not mine.
You make one sound
about what you saw
here today,
And you'll be
the sorriest little man
in the sticks.
Boy, this'll stink
right up to heaven.
Yeah, this is the kind
of thing that rises.
Hey, take this. I don't
like the way it feels.
- Where to, captain?
- Bring it to the f.B.I.,
wouldn't you say?
Oh, why not?
They probably built it.
"they probably built it."
Miles! Miles.
Help!
Phone? Do you have-
Mr. Kegan's office.
Who's calling, operator?
Yes, we will.
Hello, mr. Kegan?
No, I'm sorry.
Your father left for
rockrimmon last night.
I'm not sure.
I'll give you rosemary.
Yes, nick.
How nice to hear from you.
Your father's left the house
already for his golf.
May I help you?
In the desert, yes.
Well, how urgent?
I see.
Oh, dear.
I'd better connect you
with john cerruti. Hold on.
Nick. Surprise, surprise.
How are you? Where are you?
You left the boat, nick.
Left the ship.
That's naughty of you.
Very bad not telling
headquarters. Your father-
What? What rifle?
Uh-huh. In philadelphia?
Well, that's astonishing.
Well, it's startling.
Shocking about miles.
Listen,
now where are you now?
Exactly where?
Okay, follow me carefully.
Do nothing. I'll handle
the police. You wait for a car.
We'll pick you up and
you can discuss this with
your father in rockrimmon.
And nick, don't panic.
Panic is counterproductive.
How are you, keith?
The same. Always the same.
And you,
you're looking good.
where's pa?
He's playing golf.
But he should be
back any time now.
I've got to see him right away.
Hey, shogun. Shogun. Shogun.
You've been gone
a long time, nick.
Shogun forget.
Have you had dinner?
No, not yet.
First, I'd like to take
a look at pa's copy
of the full pickering report.
That will only make you sad.
Sad? Now, you once told me
all knowledge was good.
I don't recall.
Actually, that not
something I would say.
I'll go find pa.
I'm freezing.
Sun's going down.
The desert's
supposed to be hot.
Quit bitching. You've
been bitching all day.
I don't like it.
What am I gonna do
with these girls,
mr. Secretary?
First they're hot,
then they're cold.
When she's hot again,
send her over.
I'm always hot.
Hello, pa.
Y'all know my son,
nicholas.
Hi, nick.
all grown up, nick.
He ain't a global figure,
like his brother was.
No interest.
He's a seafaring man
like yourself, admiral.
Good boy.
Right, nick?
If you say so, pa.
- You didn't tell me you were
leaving the boat, son.
- I had to.
What do you think
these girls are doing
under this blanket, son?
I don't know, pa.
Think they're
playing with my nuts?
you're awful.
I gotta talk to you, pa.
You better believe it, boy.
"clair de lune" ]
Am I disturbing you?
mother, what are
you doing here?
Oh, shh! I'm supposed
to be a secret.
I thought you
were in nantucket.
Oh, it was freezing there.
And nobody came to visit.
I met this real nice man.
Pa said he just
wanted my money.
So he sent for me.
It's a big secret.
The newspapers, you know.
Oh, nicholas, cocoa's sick.
she's sick.
Aw, let me see.
No, no.
No, she's not well.
Look.
See, she's sick.
Don't be sick on me, honey.
Please don't.
It's just her paw, mom.
She'll be all right.
Keith will take her
to the vet tomorrow.
They'll know what to do.
She's never been
like this before.
It frightens me.
You frighten mommy.
I'll speak to keith
before I leave.
He'll take care of it
for you.
You look real handsome.
thank you, mom.
Listen, I got a great idea.
Let's have an easter egg hunt
on the lawn.
We'll get all dressed up.
Everybody will come.
We'll make it black-tie.
Wouldn't that be wonderful
to have a formal easter egg hunt
on the lawn with our friends?
You can stay for that.
It's winter.
The middle of winter, mom.
But isn't it
a lovely idea?
Yes, mom, it is.
C-cocoa's sick.
You didn't tell me
nick was here.
- I didn't know
he was coming, emma.
- You're always mad...
Just because
nick doesn't wanna be
president like tim did.
He's different,
that's all.
He's my son
and he's-
He's sensitive.
Different wives
have different sons.
Yes, emma.
Come on, honey.
Let's go up to our room.
I'm flying dr. Marshall
in from washington.
He's got some new cure
thinks maybe will help her.
Some kind of vitamins.
- I hope it works.
- It won't.
You abandoned my ship.
Pa-
I got 60 million bucks floating
there and you take off like
she's Friday night's hooker.
- If you'll let me,
I'll tell you why.
- Make it snappy.
I got people outside.
What the hell were you
doing in philly?
- I called you.
You don't take my calls.
- Didn't cerruti tell you?
Cerruti? I gotta hear
from cerruti? What's
he gotta do with this?
It concerns tim, pa.
Tim?
What about tim?
I was on the teekay
when a man named fletcher
confessed on his deathbed...
That he'd been
one of the two riflemen.
- Bullshit.
- He told us where
he'd hidden the rifle.
And this morning I found it with
miles garner and captain heller
of the philadelphia police.
Where is
this historic weapon?
- I dunno.
- You don't know?
everybody was killed
as we were leaving the building.
I was trying to reach you when
the car was driven away with
their bodies. And the rifle.
And this is the tale
you come home with?
Keifitz heard
the confession on the ship.
An orderly wrote it down.
Wrote it down?
Pa?
You all right, pa?
Just wanted
to say good night.
Oh, would you please
have a veterinarian
check out mother's dog?
Something's wrong
with its leg.
I'll have it attended to.
Don't turn out
the light, please.
All right.
Good night.
hope I don't
sound too depressed,
But so much
has been happening
in the past few days.
I got a lot to tell you.
Most of all,
I wanna tell you that
the more I hear your voice,
the more I feel I do love you.
Maybe I'll come to new york
and make an honest woman
out of you, huh?
Bye-bye.
Hello? Hello?
Hello, nick.
Come on, boy.
Wake up.
Got to get our ass
in gear.
What time is it?
Time for action.
I've been up all night.
Talked to keifitz in brunei.
Um, looks like
you were telling the truth.
The truth?
Pa, I'm your son.
Yeah, you always had
an excitable imagination.
For a while, as a boy,
I was afraid you might
turn out to be a fag.
You're a real winner, pa.
Keifitz is on his way here
with that killer's confession.
Then we go the limit
to bust this thing
wide open.
You're bringing
the confession
to the president?
Hell, no.
That moron can't read
to find the men's room.
We gotta picture it for him.
Evidence. Find the rifle.
The men behind this fletcher.
And the man behind those men.
Then we go to the president.
This is bigger
than we are, pa.
What the president
will do is resurrect
the pickering commission.
Fucking corpses to begin with.
Well, you accepted that
willy arnold acted alone.
Sure as hell I did.
If I had pointed a finger
at the russians, the cubans,
Some goddamn hoodlums
or industrialists-
Maybe throw us
in a world war, civil war.
Sure I accepted it.
I got interests in this country.
Interests in this country?
Yeah, interests. But don't think
I fell for the arnold theory.
I've been a hunter all my life.
I know the best of them.
And the best
have trouble with one shot
of the kind that killed tim.
Let alone three.
And then arnold
getting it from joe diamond,
the plump saloon keeper,
While arnold's handcuffed
to detectives surrounded
by 75 rookies.
That's what I mean, pa.
We need help in this.
Help? Like who?
The c.I.A.? They smuggle
my cigars from havana,
that's what they do.
Import, export.
And the f.B.I.'s good
for chasing runaways.
Fucking f.B.I. Gave
the commission its information
in the first place, remember?
This ain't the forties anymore.
It's a whole new ball game.
We gotta be pioneers, son.
We gotta face that
we're alone in the wilderness.
We got what the pioneers had,
all they had.
- The family.
- The family unit.
God blessed you, goddamn it,
with the best of families.
My international vice president,
john cerruti,
Has files on the high and mighty
and the low and ornery...
That make the c.I.A. Record
look like the corner newsstand.
Information's power. And now
we're gonna use it to get
to the bottom of this thing.
Then we go to the president
and congress, as a family unit.
And rub their fucking noses
in the dirt that killed my son.
Now, get your ass out of bed.
Oh, and by the way,
you won't need the vet.
The vet?
Yeah, the vet for cocoa.
Your mother passed out
last night and smothered
the mutt in her sleep.
- Oh, no.
- Yeah.
Sleeps with the goddamn dog.
Crazy woman. Now move!
I'm sorry, mom.
You stink, pa!
You stink!
Captain heller
died two years ago...
In the virgin islands
of a heart attack.
So miles was either duped
or duped you with a phony.
And your wig-maker friend
jumped out the window.
Police say suicide,
'cause vandals
wrecked his business.
Sit down.
No, thanks.
Now, where do we start?
looks like
we've already started.
We got three names at the top.
Fletcher, casper jr.,
and z.K. Dawson.
Dawson's the big one.
One of the richest cocksuckers
in the u.S.A.
Christ. This takes me back.
Yeah, there it is.
Tim and me in the primaries.
Dawson was up against us,
pushing us hard.
You were just a kid.
Spent a lot of money
in that state.
I mean, over-the-counter,
under-the-table, tucked-into-
a-box-of-cigars money.
Shit, put out 9,700
primary-day workers alone.
Most gorgeous tv commercial
you ever saw.
Tim leading tanks to liberate
the hess sector in germany.
Geez, he looked great.
Ah, made a big noise
in that shitty little state.
Got 53 movie stars
to turn out.
And, uh,
all that time and...
After and...
Before and during.
Everything I did,
every dime I spent,
Every threat I made,
I was just leading tim
further along the road...
To meet that bullet.
- It sounds like that's
just what you were doing, pa.
- What?
Leading tim along.
Listen, kid. We find the killers
of your brother and you'll be
a hero like he was.
A fucking legend.
- I don't wanna be a legend.
- What the hell do you wanna be,
a goddamned piano player?
maybe, but I'm not very good.
- You stink. You're lousy.
- I know that.
You know that?
You ain't a piano player,
you ain't an artist.
You got no business sense,
no political sense.
What the hell
do you want anyway?
Where are your values in life?
I honestly don't know.
Do you get laid?
- I ask you, do you get laid?
- Yeah.
You know how many times
your brother got laid
in office?
- What are you,
the national inquirer?
- One thousand seventy-two.
And with a schedule like his.
Maybe politics
don't turn me on.
Your brother was a giant.
You'll be the same. You watch.
Now, I set up a meeting
with you and z.K. Dawson.
He'll lie of course.
But you'll get something
from the meeting.
- No, pa.
- What?
I said no.
What no? Here's a map
on how to get there.
He's south of tulsa.
It's all arranged. Take it.
Take it!
- Okay, pa. For the family.
- You bet your ass.
Good luck, boy.
I'll be with ya.
I know you will, pa!
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Can I help you?
Yes, I'm here
to see mr. Dawson.
Your name, please.
Nicholas kegan.
You go right ahead.
Z.K.'s on the playing field.
Take the turn to your right...
Before you reach the house
and that's where
you'll find him.
Thank you.
Yeah, I'm z.K. Dawson.
Who the hell are you?
I'm nicholas kegan!
Get out of the vehicle.
I said,
get out of the vehicle.
Uh, speak up.
I'm, uh, nick kegan.
Tom kegan's son.
I know that. But what are you
doing here on my playing field,
messing up our games?
Oh, the guard said, well-
I don't care what the guard
told you, I wanna know
what you're doing here.
We had an appointment,
mr. Dawson.
I'm aware of that fact.
Now you're wasting my time.
- Well, look here, uh-
- watch your tone.
- Mr. Dawson-
- that's better.
Mr. Dawson,
we've discovered a rifle.
We have every reason to believe
it's the weapon that killed
my brother in philadelphia.
Your brother was
a miserable, cold-assed,
arrogant son of a bitch.
And not a good friend of mine,
as I guess is well known to you.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
But the assassin was hired
by a man named casper jr.
And as you know everyone
of importance in the area,
we thought-
What I ought to do
is run right over you,
flatten you like a waffle.
Sir?
I know
why you're here.
You're here because you think
I had some part of a conspiracy
killed your brother.
You and all the other
conspiracy lovers in this
conspiracy-loving country.
Actually, mr. Dawson-
Why should I kill your brother
when I'm getting rich off him?
Off his military spendin',
his space spendin'.
His tax reduction
a-and h-his crisis spendin'.
Hell, you know if your old man
didn't own him already,
I might have bought him myself.
Except for
his snotty personality.
I didn't come here
to listen to slander,
mr. Dawson.
slander?
You think before you speak,
young man.
Hell, they didn't
teach you kids nothing
since 1944.
Hey, I didn't kill your brother.
That's a vile, cruel,
mythological invention.
But it is also a-
an infectious invention.
And when it reached the ears
of my daughter, I thought,
maybe I'll make...
A couple of phone calls
and really find out
who did the deed.
Who might that be?
The philadelphia police
killed your brother.
The man in charge
of the operation
was a captain heller.
So if I was you,
I'd just go and have
a talk with that man.
- Uh, he's dead.
- Well, then I'd track down
a sidekick of his.
A man named ray doty.
Thank you.
Yeah, well,
you're welcome.
Now, I'm gonna
tell you one more thing.
I'm gonna give you
a head start of 30 seconds.
And then me and my boys here,
we're coming after you.
Sir?
You heard me.
We still got some
private property
in this country.
Ten... Nine... Eight... Seven...
I'm looking for a passenger
named nicholas kegan.
Mr. Kegan?
Yes?
Telephone call for you.
Please hurry.
We're beginning our descent.
You have a telephone call
for me here?
Please.
I have a telephone call
up here.
where the hell is he?
Pa?
You didn't call me
when you left dawson.
Pa, there are hundreds
of people on board.
Uh, we're about to land.
Maybe, but I'm still
losing money on this airline.
Now, what'd dawson say?
He says it's heller
in the philadelphia police.
Says I should talk to a cop
named ray doty. He also
fired on my car with tanks.
The old coot.
Ray doty. I'll arrange it.
That why you going to new york?
come on. Come on.
No, I'm gonna see my girl.
Girl? What girl?
Just a girl, pa.
Look, I gotta go.
Forget the girl.
You go see doty.
By the way, keifitz is dead.
Keifitz?
Died in brunei.
What about the confession?
Orderly's dead too. Fell off
the toilet and broke his neck.
What?
4-14, 4-14, where are you?
4-14 approaching runway 6.
It's safe to talk in here.
These lights
stay on all the time?
Day and night.
All year round.
They never know
what time it is.
Just keep laying those eggs.
And they never hatch.
Never do.
Give 'em hormones, of course.
And amphetamines.
Keeps 'em going.
They're all on speed.
Jittery as hell.
My father's information
agency has paid you.
Is this, uh-
I took the cash.
Just like in the old days.
Once a cop,
always a cop.
Wish I was back
on the force sometimes.
So how did, uh,
casper jr. Get to you?
Oh, he didn't get to us.
He got to joe diamond.
¶
You do that very well.
I think-
now you gotta understand...
That joe diamond
was a notorious cop lover.
I mean, a real cop lover.
He always kept this nightclub
full of rookies.
Drinking beer, getting high.
Anyway,
the meeting was set up...
Between diamond
and an old pal of his.
It took place in tucson.
How you been, gameboy?
Oh, older and fatter.
Uglier. Like you.
I don't know.
- Did you eat?
- Yeah.
What'd you eat?
Pastrami on whole wheat
with celery tonic.
Any good?
Lousy.
Tucson.
Don't ever order the
wild west pastrami.
Sit down.
it's like old times.
Y-you remember us
in atlantic city?
Maybe. Maybe not.
But I got
a contract for you.
One of the biggest contracts
ever handed out anywheres.
Me? I-I'm a restaurant man.
You're also a thief
who is crazy enough to steal...
From moey and sam
and morris and uncle louie.
I wanna pay back.
you are fucking right.
I-I can pay back?
When you handle this hit,
you'll be paying back.
A hit?
Why me? There must be 200
mechanics around here can
make any hit better than me.
I told 'em. No good.
Those guys aren't political.
I'm political?
You were in cuba.
Very good friends
with a certain minister.
I thought about you a lot,
gameboy.
You have a commie background
in the f.B.I. Files.
Commie? I was out of cuba
ten years before castro.
Joe, what do you
want from me?
You were in cuba.
This is crazy.
Anyways,
youse gotta make the hit.
- Who's the contract?
- There are two.
We've already taken care
of the first one.
You make the second hit.
A kid named willie arnold.
I don't know him.
A-and who's the first?
President kegan.
so diamond went back to philly
to get ahold of captain heller.
Heller was my superior officer
at the time.
He was a great family man.
Seven daughters
and a big house.
Daughters are expensive.
¶
After the assignation,
diamond's job was
to shoot the phony assassin,
Willie arnold,
in the police station.
Heller was paid to get an in.
Heller was terrific
at organization.
Our last meeting took place
right here at this farm.
Here's two sets of keys
to the engleson building.
Get them to the texan
when he arrives tomorrow.
Right, captain.
Willie arnold should be
planted in the tv center
warehouse by half past 9:00.
The motorcade will pass
towards city hall at 12:30.
Ray will give you your rifle
and some shells to have arnold
throw on the floor as evidence.
Tell willie arnold to go home
after the real hit. If we need
him, we'll send a patrol car.
Ray will give you
the rest of the details.
And when we arrest arnold
after the hit, you know
what you have to do. Right, joe?
Yeah, I know.
There are a lot of things
we gotta consider here.
All right, cut it out,
will you? Come on.
how did they find diamond?
Who?
Casper jr.
And his people.
Figures to me
the mob found him.
Diamond was with the boys
in cleveland, chicago, detroit.
Why would the mob wanna
kill the president?
Business reasons.
Heard a very big man
in the syndicate
say one day that...
Kegan took $2 million
in campaign contributions
from the boys and then...
Didn't do anything
about it.
Nonsense. Tim didn't
need the money.
Who knows.
Anyway,
whoever did it still has
a terrific amount of clout...
19 years
after it happened.
Yeah.
Hello?
you're home!
Nick?
Oh, wonderful.
I've been trying
to reach you for days.
Where are you?
Grand central.
I'm, uh-
I'm on my way over, okay?
Okay. I can't wait.
yvette-
Oh, I got something to tell you.
I can't believe you're real!
Yeah, well, I'm not real.
I'm just a more complicated
new machine.
You're what?
You come on over
and see what this
new machine can do.
I'm on my way.
I can't wait.
I love you.
Then come and get me.
oh, shh! Somebody's
gonna call the police!
Shh. Shh.
Shh!
Marry me.
Marry me!
Shh. Shh. Shh.
Oh, marry me.
Marry me!
Yes! Yes! Oh, god, yes!
Oh, you make me so happy.
Shh. Come on.
Somebody's gonna
call the police.
Shh.
hi.
Hi.
- When should we do it?
- Let me rest a minute first.
No, I mean get married.
Get married?
You just said yes.
Oh, I always say yes
at those times.
You know I can't marry you.
What?
Come on. Up.
Ah, be right back.
- Why won't you marry me?
- You hardly know me.
We see each other.
I talk to you all the time.
You talk to my machine.
- Oh, so what.
I can tell the difference.
- That's a beginning.
I'm making an honest
proposal of marriage.
Tell you what.
I'll give you a copy
of my answering machine tape.
You can take it with you.
Come on.
Don't toy with me.
I'm serious.
We'll have this huge wedding
in saint patrick's cathedral.
Saint patrick's?
What if I'm jewish?
That doesn't matter.
Pa knows the cardinal.
You see, darling.
You know nothing about me.
I know all I need to know.
You know what?
That you're in love
with my answering machine.
Well, I'll know you
better later on.
Do you know
what I do for a living?
- That doesn't matter. You will
never have to work again.
- But I wanna work.
I'm assistant editor
at national magazine.
Maybe pa owns it.
Do you want a promotion?
I want my own life
too, nick.
- Well, I'll buy you
whatever you want.
- No.
You just said no.
I said no.
How can you say
a thing like that?
Why complicate things?
We have great sex, freedom,
no kids, no responsibilities.
Why duplicate
the messes others make?
- But we don't have to.
- We can make a mess
of our own?
- Who knows what will happen?
- Don't ask me anymore, nick.
I adore you. I really do.
But the answer's
gonna stay the same.
I'd tell you why
if I could but I can't.
Don't say you can't.
Say you don't want.
I don't want.
Then forget it.
All right.
I think
I'd better leave.
If you want to.
I have a friend coming over
if you'd like to meet her.
A friend? Who?
Patty. She's from
the magazine. You'd dig her.
- Dig her? What does that mean?
- Whatever you want it to mean.
God, you're just
like the others.
Others?
How many are there?
Fewer and fewer.
Oh, I get it.
You're into women.
- I am a woman.
- You know what
I'm talking about.
Nope. And I won't marry
a person I can't understand.
Good night.
Call the machine
whenever you want, darling.
It only goes one way.
Mr. Wilson?
Good evening.
Mr. Kegan. This is
a pleasant surprise.
Can I have my key,
please?
Certainly.
My, you're looking...
Worse than I've
ever seen you, sir.
I've been traveling.
It certainly doesn't
agree with you.
Good night.
I'll alert the staff
that you're in residence.
And get some sleep.
Welcome home, nick.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you too,
raymond.
The maid is freshening
your room, sir.
Get me a double,
please, raymond.
A double what, sir?
Uh, on second thought,
make it triple.
A triple what, sir?
Hello.
This is yvette malone speaking.
I'm not home just now.
I hate this machine!
Leave your name
and telephone number,
I'll call you when I return.
Please begin at the tone.
Hello, yvette, listen,
I'm sorry I was so, uh, rude.
I didn't, you know,
listen to you or anything.
I want you to know
that I still care about you
and I wanna see you.
Why don't we have lunch tomorrow
at the lorraine, huh? 12:30.
Nicholas?
Help! Help! Help!
Raymond!
I brought your drink, sir.
Hello. This is nick kegan.
A maid just left my room.
Have security stop her, please.
She tried to kill me.
Sorry I'm late.
I'm glad you came.
Well, me too. I hate saying
good-bye to a naked man.
Excuse me.
Yes, sir.
Can I help you?
We'd like a table, please.
For the two of you?
Yeah, someplace we can talk.
Well, I'm sorry, sir.
We don't allow ladies
in trousers in the dining area.
You what?
Uh, it's no problem.
You know what happened
to me this morning?
I go out of the taxi,
and the cabdriver followed
me on the sidewalk,
Swearing at me because
he didn't think
I tipped him enough.
Madam, we will
have to ask you to leave.
We're staying, my friend.
She's got you.
impossible.
My name is nicholas kegan.
My father owns this place.
Oh, I'm awfully sorry, sir.
I didn't recognize you.
Please, right this way.
Right this way.
Thank you.
Listen, I'm, uh-
I'm sorry about last night.
No, I'm sorry.
I got about six different
kinds of jet lag.
No, I understand.
Tell me, where were you
one week ago today?
Uh, brisbane, australia.
Oh, brisbane.
The coral sea, stonefish,
Captain cook
sweeping north through
that treacherous channel.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Yeah. Look, yvette-
I still wanna marry you.
Is that why this lunch?
No.
I need
your magazine's help.
Maybe
it's your magazine.
I need to contact
someone in the mob-
someone big.
What for?
It is not to be
talked about.
I cross my heart.
I also need everything
in your files on joe diamond.
Joe diamond?
Who he knew in the mob.
Who knew him.
What for? Does it
concern your brother?
We have reason to believe
that we're on the track
of uncovering a conspiracy.
A conspiracy?
Three days ago,
I met the true assassin
of my brother.
Is this on the level?
Now I want to find out
who actually hired diamond.
Not the go-between.
I wanna find the man
who is responsible for this.
Well, sure.
It'll cost.
It cost to have
my brother killed. I think
we can pay whatever it cost...
To find those who-
who did it to him.
And I don't want
any press until I say so.
Are you offering us
the exclusive?
Thank you.
If you come up
with the contacts.
Wow. This is big.
I mean, really big.
Hey, wow!
you know,
When I'm with you, the-
- Wow!
- Yvette?
Yvette-
You know, tim-
He had thousands of women,
and I've, uh-
I've actually
only had twelve.
And I know that may
seem conservative to you.
Oh, listen, honey.
You get me this story,
I'll get you all you want.
Are you listening to me?
I sure am.
And if you want this story,
I gotta get my tail in gear.
I call you
from the magazine.
Thanks for lunch.
Lunch?
This news makes my day.
It's wonderful.
Excuse me.
What the hell were you
doing with that broad
at lunch today?
She's a friend of mine.
Are you screwing her?
Oh, I forgot.
You're the boy scout
of the family.
Tim always shared
information
on his broads.
I'm not tim.
Where'd you meet her?
Keifitz introduced us
in paris one weekend.
She's the press.
I said no press.
I need contacts
with the mob.
I'm in business,
for christ's sake. Been dealing
with the mob for years.
But you go to some dame
you got the hots for
and spill everything.
That's wrong.
Like hell.
Cerruti played the whole lunch
to me ten minutes ago.
- You had us bugged?
- It's my restaurant, son.
A lot of people
more important than you
make deals there.
Of course
I have it bugged.
Telephone for you,
sir.
I'll take it in my room.
Take it here.
Cerruti's
recording it
anyhow.
Hello.
Hello, yvette.
You what?
Already?
Yeah, you sure do.
how much?
Who is it?
Uh-huh.
Cleveland.
All right.
I'll catch the next plane.
And thanks.
Who are you meeting?
Someone named
irving mentor.
Yvette says
he's the magazine's
direct line to the mob.
I'll check on him.
I got something for you.
Whatcha scared of?
I don't want you in any more
situations you can't handle.
- I don't want a gun.
- Look,
Somebody tried
to kill you last night.
This ain't
no treasure hunt
you're on.
Pa, I'm not
gonna carry a gun.
I admire the way
you fought off
that killer, boy.
Single-handedly.
It was only the maid.
Ah, trained killer.
We got her, by the way.
We got her?
Yeah.
Working her over now.
My people are on this
all the way.
All right. If you won't
carry a gun, take this.
For my peace of mind
if nothing else.
You're amazing.
Take these, uh,
brass knuckles too.
Uh, don't lose them.
They have
a sentimental value.
Thanks.
Uh, I'll see you
in cleveland.
I'll be in the hospital.
Oh, nothing's wrong.
Six-months' blood change is all.
- Blood change?
- Yeah.
I take it from the kids
at amherst. Got a deal
with the red cross.
Uh, for the circulation.
I'll see you, pa.
Call me from cleveland.
I'm looking
for irving mentor.
Never heard of him.
Uh, my name
is nick kegan.
I bought you
coffee.
Cream?
No, thanks.
You got the cash?
Better count it.
Humph.
You bet your ass.
Okay.
The contract for the hit
came from gameboy baker.
- Gameboy baker.
- You got it.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait a minute.
Sorry.
This ain't
a social visit.
Oh, yeah?
It's not worth 15 grand,
either. Now sit down.
Sit down
or give me my money back.
Watch your language.
These are my boys, you know.
get out of here.
Tell me about this, uh,
gameboy baker.
Joe diamond is from
the old neighborhood.
Small-time thief.
No sense.
¶
it was gameboy baker...
Who helped set joe up
in his nightclub.
Only joe wasn't paying back.
He was too busy supporting
some of the local rookies.
I was the one
who delivered the message.
That moey and sam
and morris and uncle louie
wanted a conversation with him.
so joe skipped to cuba.
And by the time
the boys found him,
He was in bed
with every faigelah
politician in havana.
joe took protection
from his cuban friend...
And went back
to his club in philly.
But he still owed the boys
an obligation,
Which he paid back on that day
he shot willy arnold.
Open that door.
The smoke's
getting to me.
That could be a signal
or something.
Open the door
or I'll shove the cigar
down your throat.
Eighty-five cents,
wholesale.
Now, who is casper jr.?
A hollywood agent.
What?
Deals for harry small,
head of federal studios.
Why would people like that
wanna kill a president?
That particular president
cost that studio...
$50 million...
When he stopped
screwing ellamae irving
and she killed herself.
I give you $15,000
and you tell me gossip.
Where there's smoke,
there's fire.
What can I tell you?
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Just a moment.
What the hell?
What are you feeding us?
The cat's dead. What is this?
calling dr. Rogers.
Telephone call, dr. Rogers.
My father's
a patient here.
Your name?
Nicholas kegan.
Thank you, doctor.
Federal studios? Hell,
you couldn't spot a nigger
in a snowbank.
I'm telling you what he said.
I got interlocking companies
controlling federal.
Her last two pictures
lost money. Harry small was glad
to get out of her contract.
You gotta stop
chasing mare tails, boy.
I fixed up
a meeting for you
with frank mayo.
- Mayo?
- Heard of him, huh?
Grand vizier
of the underworld.
I thought he was in jail.
Upstate,
maximum security.
I got him out
to meet you
this afternoon.
What can he tell me
that mentor didn't know?
What did mentor know? Nothing.
You tell that broad of yours
she owes you 15 grand.
- Have a pastry?
- Think that sugar's
good for you?
It's my hospital.
Own what you use.
Nothing competes today
with owning a hospital.
No customer credit.
Pay in advance or get out.
Unique product- pain.
Laundry alone throws off enough
to pay the orderlies and lab.
And what the lab turns over-
- When is the meeting with mayo?
- I'm talking business here.
You should see the net
on what the lab throws off.
I own 27 hospitals
in 15 major cities.
Wish I had more.
Where is the meeting
with frank mayo, pa?
Grant's tomb, 4:00.
Hey, nick.
Uh, would you
like a little?
No, thanks, pa.
Please, sit down.
Uh, pa says that you
have some information
on joe diamond.
Oh, yeah, but...
Before we get into that,
I, uh-
I wanna tell you
that I'm apologetic
about-
About what happened
to your brother,
even at this late date.
But, uh, unfortunately,
mr. Kegan,
You always hear
about these things
too late.
I was on key biscayne
at the time.
But I could have done nothing,
anyway, because, uh,
it wasn't our business, see?
They, uh-
they did it on their own.
Mr. Mayo,
Who actually made the contract
to kill the president?
see what I mean?
That, for me,
has always been a mystery.
I don't know.
What about diamond's
connections in cuba?
Diamond had no connections
in cuba.
Well, irving mentor
says he did.
Irving mentor.
Mm-mmm.
I never heard of him.
Who send you to this, uh,
to this mentor man?
A friend.
Mm.
That's funny.
No, no, no.
No, diamond was
never in cuba.
I'm told he was out of-
out of chicago.
Mr. Kegan, uh,
You're getting
the runaround here.
I'm sorry, sir.
Personnel has no record
of any yvette malone.
She works here.
Apparently not.
Could you check again?
I mean, you must
have a record of her.
Sir, this is
national magazine.
Everything we must have,
we have.
Thank you.
It's no good, mister.
The lady in 12-g
is 62 years old.
Drinks like a fish.
But yvette lived here.
I visited her here.
Why don't you try number 86?
Maybe you got
the wrong building.
You have nobody
of that description?
Buddy, we haven't
had a good-looking woman
in this building in four years.
Floor upon floor
of ugly people
is all we got.
Here's 50 bucks.
I gotta find her.
Make it a hundred.
I'll tell you
everything I know.
Okay.
Here's a hundred.
I already told you
everything I know.
No such person
ever occupied these premises!
- Look here, mister.
- Now, hold on, cocksucker.
You can't buy me, huh?
You don't accept my word for it,
you deserve to pay. Now,
get the hell out of my si-
Come on! Come on!
I'll bop your skull open,
you bastard, you!
Your money can't buy me, huh?
You give me the creeps.
Get out of here!
Go on!
Filthy bastard, you.
You give me the creeps,
all of you! Go on!
Then I'll say
good night, sir.
Oh, uh, raymond.
Sir?
Do we have any ovaltine?
Ovaltine?
I think I'd like some
before I go to sleep
tonight.
I seem to remember when
I was a kid I had this cup
with a borden's cow on it.
Cow, sir?
Oh, just give me
a glass of milk.
Very good, sir.
Boy! I have
come back for you!
Now, wait!
Wait! Hey!
Hey! Wakey, wakey, wakey!
It's me!
- You're a dead ghost!
- Like hell I am.
Pa said you're dead.
Do I look dead?
I need some sleep, but...
They're still
dredging for my body
and I've still got it.
- Then you're not dead.
- No. I got an obit
in the times...
But I am not dead.
Now, when they
got the medic,
I figured
it was healthier
not to be alive.
yeah.
Ain't you
glad to see me?
It's a conundrum-
Riddles within riddles.
Now yvette's gone.
That broad we met in paris?
The one you kept calling?
- I wanna marry her.
- You're gonna give
the whole thing up?
Someone is trying to teach me
a lesson in futility. Why am I
the only one who wasn't killed?
They will run you dizzy.
They will pile falsehood
on top of falsehood...
Until you can't
tell a lie from the truth
and you won't even want to.
That's how the powerful
keep their power.
Don't you read the papers?
You've got to accept
that there is a world
outside of you...
And that
you affect that world.
- Your dad knows it.
- Pa thinks, uh,
Moses lied about
the ten commandments,
because what god really said...
Was, "do what you want,
but don't get caught."
- Pa's awareness is global.
- Yeah, so is mud.
Nick, use him.
Use the organization.
He's got more clout
than the common market,
And you're taking
the advice of a broad
who's probably a plant.
Now, you could've
been killed in that diner.
- I thought you liked
staying alive.
- come on.
I'm gonna find her.
Go to cerruti.
He works for you, remember?
- What about you?
- I'm gonna stay dead
for awhile.
I feel healthier that way.
Where are you going?
Gonna order cerruti
to produce yvette.
This is the contract silo, nick.
Contracts, contracts,
contracts.
Agreements kept.
Agreements broken.
Papers, papers, papers.
Signatures. Your father's
holograph signature...
On his interlocking companies
going back, oh, 30 years.
Also those of diplomats,
authors and inventors.
Tax deals.
Foundation deals.
Signatures of presidents
and sheiks.
Signatures to put men away
for, oh, decades.
Destroy careers, public lives,
marriages, estates.
Love affairs. Letters
of passion, indiscretion
and conspiracy...
Acquired by your father's
intelligence network.
Letters to persuade a man
to close a deal or leave a job
or sell out on his brother.
Data necessary to sustain
a financial empire.
and here-
Here are the spoken words.
Shh. Voices and sounds.
And visuals.
Pictures on microfilm.
Movies. Video.
Marvelous little gadgets
that document verbatim...
All your father's conversations
with all his people.
And his people's
conversations with others.
From our satellite,
we can watch everything.
Nasty little wars in africa.
Troop movements. Ship movements.
Nuclear tests.
The sinai.
The panama canal.
Every little thing
to check an investment,
buy us in or out.
Even tonight,
while most of
our workers sleep,
It goes on.
take a coffee break,
gentlemen.
I have a rare visitor
and we'd like to be alone.
Information.
Black holes
of information.
Galaxies within galaxies.
Multiple expanding universes
of information.
Aren't you glad
you came?
Pa never allowed the family
here in his office.
Ah. Misjudgment.
You'll run all this
someday.
You'll need to know.
All this and you couldn't
find my brother's killer?
I'm so glad you're here.
I receive so few outsiders.
Who to trust?
All the nerves
but none of the flesh.
End of our social.
Why did you come here
without an appointment?
What do you want?
I want to find
yvette malone.
Impossible.
She's been kidnapped.
Kidnapped?
Yeah. Abducted, swept away,
taken off, snatched-
kidnapped.
- By whom?
- The kidnappers.
Bad guys. Casper jr.
where are you going?
To find my father.
I just realized.
He's been keeping me alive.
He's protecting me.
She's... Involved, nick.
Miss malone's involved.
It wasn't the tubesters
who got to diamond.
We have new information.
- While you sleep, we continue.
- Who was it?
You met the man this afternoon.
Frank mayo.
And it was lola comante
who got to mayo
and had the president killed.
¶
Miss lola comante!
thrice married by 23,
movie queen at 30,
Lola entered middle age
as friend of the shady
and legit alike...
With the special power
of a president's procuress.
Lola got tim his girls,
and he blessed her
with fame and fortune.
Tim enjoyed her favors
and the favors of her friends...
In the privacy of rockrimmon.
Sanctioned and abetted
by your father,
Who occasionally
indulged in lola himself...
And who also had some
business connections with her.
Until it all ended one day when
lola tried to collect on a deal.
Enchanted by ambition
as she was,
Lola had arranged a $2 million
campaign contribution...
From the family of frank mayo.
Mayo wanted the president
to kick out castro...
And restore the casinos
to havana.
But the president was aware
of no such contribution
and no such deal.
It was your father
who had accepted
the money from lola.
When did you get
so lily-white, son?
Been reading
your own press?
This thing's
gone to your head.
Sure, I took that cash.
You think
you got those votes
on your good looks?
I bought 'em and I paid
for 'em. And when
I needed cash, I got it.
Now, uh,
you remember your debts.
You want out of this
cuban thing, you gotta
pay back another way.
And, uh, be nice to lola.
She's on your side.
Where you going?
Hey. Where you going?
Come back here!
I'm your father!
Goddamn it!
Why do you think
I got you this job?
To review the fucking fleet?
the president broke contact with
your father on this matter...
And with lola as well.
He never spoke
to either one again.
so tim turned against pa?
Mm. It hurt your father
a great deal,
Both personally
and... Financially.
Then it was mayo
who killed my brother and
you've known it all along.
A qualified no
on both counts.
- Z.K. Dawson.
- The guy in the tank?
No, no, no. Not that asshole.
The real dawson who hasn't left
venezuela since 1956.
Your oklahoma adventure
was a little something
I cooked up.
You cooked up?
Yes. A scene. A skit.
Rather humorous, I thought,
with a point.
And what can the point be,
mr. Cerruti?
You see, it wasn't
dawson himself who plotted
your brother's assassination.
It was his only daughter-
formerly maggie dawson,
then mrs. Luigi bellini...
And lately-
Yvette?
The attraction between you two
becomes romeo-and-julietish, no?
Opposing families.
- That is ridiculous!
- Don't snap at me, you.
She plotted the whole thing.
She was your brother's mistress
too. Bet you didn't know that.
- Where is she now?
- Yvette? I told you.
Kidnapped.
- By whom?
- By whom? By the kidnappers.
Bad guys. Casper jr.
you are lying, cerruti.
No one's allowed up here,
nick.
Tell me where she is
or I'm gonna blow this
whole thing open.
No way. You're not
to be believed.
What have you got?
A half a dozen
different scenarios all going
in opposite directions.
Fantasies. They'd lock you
away in the booby bin.
You're no threat to me.
You give me this information
or I'm gonna get it
the old-fashioned way.
The ol- oh.
The old-fashioned way.
I see. What are you gonna do,
break my arms?
God, it's painful
to see you like this, nick.
It's painful to see you
suffering under a delusion
so intense,
So aggravating
that you actually believe
that you have the nerve...
To come in here
and threaten me like this.
You're just not the type.
Did you hear that?
Did you hear that,
you clown?
You've broken my arm.
Is it him?
Huh? Huh?
Is it pa?
Is it him?
Please tell me.
Is it pa?
ow!
Is it pa, cerruti?
Your legs are next.
Cerruti, is it pa?
Your father spent $11 million
to raise your brother up...
From a skirt-chasing
college boy to president
of the United States.
For 20 years,
he told him what to do
and how and why...
And what would happen
when it was done.
Your father put tim
in the white house. Why?
Because that's where you
can generate the most cash.
A cold-ass business proposition
like everything else in society.
But your brother decided
to stir up the population,
Began to think we were
all living in a democracy.
He started believing it.
Lunch with de gaulle,
dinner with kruschev.
The whole razzle-dazzle
went to his head.
Yet in spite of the fact that
everybody in this country...
Lives in the same
dog-eat-dog way,
Grabbing any angle
to make a buck,
If you were to inform them
that your father had tim killed,
They'd wanna
tear the old man
apart limb from limb.
Pa had-
pa had him killed?
What the hell?
That's the system
you wanted, nick,
And that's the system
you've got.
The whole secret,
as your father says,
is not to get caught.
I want to find yvette.
Yvette malone...
Was a professional actress
named jenny o'brien,
But I don't think she wants
to see you today, nick.
She's the guest of a freshman
anatomy class over at kegan
university medical school...
And she's
kinda tied up right now,
if you get the picture.
You get the picture, nick?
You get the picture?
Don't touch.
What the hell?
He was caught
trying to enter.
That's my son!
He refused to tell us
his name, mr. Kegan.
Rosemary will call dr. Grokest
when she comes in.
You sure
made a night of it, boy.
You should have called first.
Ought to know that by now.
I'll get you some whiskey.
You want those fellas fired,
I'll have 'em fired.
Good men, though.
Ah. You gonna
pass out on me?
Pa, cerruti
told me everything.
- You saw cerruti?
- You killed him.
Your own son.
Was it really
for money?
Rosemary, where the hell
are my cigars?
Rosemary!
a wise man
fools the doctors.
Was it for money?
Where did you get the balls
to suggest to me...
That I'd have
your brother murdered
for some additional cash?
The president
of my country.
Is this an attack, son?
A conspiracy? Have you
gone over to the enemy?
Or are you mad?
for money.
Shame.
For shame on you.
Somewhere deep
in your soul, pa,
You wanna get caught
and punished.
Like a petty thief
back to the scene
of a crime.
Petty thief? Hell,
I'm the king of thieves,
The jupiter of thieves.
But I'm not a killer.
There he is...
And there and there.
My guardian angel.
My unseen listener.
John cerruti.
Somewhere in the air,
Recording, peeking in.
John cerruti killed tim.
Cerruti.
Did it with my men
and my money.
And the profits
went into my companies.
When he told me he'd killed
my son, there was nothing
I could do against him,
'cause every finger
in the country
would point to me.
Tim's own pa.
And you too.
And our family.
- No, pa.
- You think I'm in control here?
I'm nothing
but a goddamn front.
Cerruti has run everything
since the day tim was shot.
Darndest part-
Don't even
give himself a raise.
Lives in brooklyn
in a rabbit hole.
Whatcha doing?
I'm calling the police.
You begging to die?
You got eyes
in that empty head?
Look, I'm an old man-
skin sagging, false teeth,
eyes milking over.
But I've been
holding this thing together
with the minutes ticking by...
'cause when this old clock
comes undone, you watch
where the wheels will fly.
- I won't buy it, pa.
- I'm standing between you
and darkest night, son.
The other side of me
is chaos.
Hold it, keifitz.
We won't need the gun.
Won't need the gun?
God, son, it must've been
the milkman after all,
'cause you sure as hell
ain't no part of me.
That man damn well
needs his gun...
'cause he's gonna
shoot you with it.
Pa!
Pa, take my hand!
Stupid!
You wanna go with me?
Take my hand, pa!
You get out of this alive, son-
You get out of this alive.
Take our money
out of the western world
and put it in south america.
- Oh!
- Brazil. Ah!
- Aah!
- Brazil! They're
the next ones up!
Pa's dead.
I'll connect you
with john cerruti.
Call the police, rosemary.
Yes, mr. Kegan.
Are you coming back?
I'm part of the family.
Hello. This is
yvette malone speaking.
I'm not home just now,
But if you'll be kind enough
to leave your name
and telephone number,
I'll call you when I return.
Please begin
at the tone.
Hello, honey.
This is nick.
I just wanted to hear
your voice once more.
And I wanted to tell you
that I love you...
And I'll miss you.
Bye.