-
OCTOBER
STRONGEST TIGER
Game one of the Korean Series
between Kia Tigers and Nexen Heroes.
I think they're going to change pitchers.
JE-HYEOK KIM
Finally, he's coming in.
Je-hyeok.
JE-HYEOK KIM
Did you put in the coins?
Oh, right...
15 BALLS FOR 1,000 WON
God, that moron...
500 WON COINS ONLY
-Seriously.
-Hey.
Smart in baseball knowledge,
but apparently stupid in life.
#Je-hyeokKim #BaseballPlayerJe-hyeokKim
#StupidJe-hyeokKim
She's not a kid.
She'll take care of herself.
How could you not visit
your sister once, after she moved?
Are you almost there?
I can't hear you.
Yes, I'm almost there.
Send me pictures.
Check her fridge to see if it's full too.
I wonder if she even does
her laundry regularly.
Next on the news.
You must remember the Je-hyeok Kim case,
which was the center of attention
for a while.
The pro baseball player Je-hyeok Kim
was arrested for excessive violence
against Choi,
who was attempting
to sexually assault his sister.
His trial begins this afternoon
at Seoul Western District Court.
They'll likely agree it was self-defense
and let him off with probation.
The victim is in critical condition,
and thus the public is waiting
to see how the court decides.
According to the result of the trial...
JE-HYEOK KIM
I'm almost at the entrance.
Oh, no. This won't do.
There are too many reporters.
Let's take my car. I parked it
in the next complex over.
Okay.
Are you ready? Hurry up and come down.
Okay?
-Okay.
-Those punks.
Baseball Player Je-hyeok Kim
Most Likely to Get Probation
You have a delivery, Mr. Kim.
I'll pick it up later.
This is abalone,
so you need to eat it soon.
I'll be back before dinner.
I'll pick it up soon.
MR. RYU
Hurry up, you slow turtle.
Day of the verdict
Meeting with the club owner
Je-hyeok, give the station a call.
What?
Why?
To report a 300-million-won garbage car.
What is this? Seriously.
Aren't you cold?
How can you eat ice cream in the winter?
I can. It tastes good.
You dense little thing.
Is winter here? "No."
Is it cold? "No."
You're so frustrating.
Hey. When will you take me here?
You said we'll get a table right away
if I go with you.
Good. Let's go today after the trial.
I'm meeting with the club owner later.
Let's go tomorrow, okay?
Look out the window, will you?
How can a person lack all sentimentality?
It's supposed to snow a lot today. Look.
It's nice out, though.
You're right.
Do you have any sunglasses?
Something cool looking?
What's this?
He's so quick at times like these.
By the way...
Are you sure this isn't you?
Gocheok Gunman.
Am I nuts? Why would I stalk you?
He isn't a stalker. He's a fan.
That's a stalker.
There's a rumor that
he's a pro baseball scorekeeper.
There are so many freaks out there now.
It's dangerous.
Charge your phone.
You'll get a lot of calls today.
It's okay. 15% is plenty.
Do whatever you want.
It's so nice out.
Snow?
No way.
Nothing is impossible.
2015 JE-HYEOK KIM PERFORMANCE
JE-HYEOK KIM FORMS BY SEASON
JE-HYEOK KIM NAMED NO. 1
500 STRIKE OUTS
The verdict on Je-hyeok Kim's first trial
will be out today.
I'm not sure that's the reason,
but many have requested this song.
It's his entrance song,
selected by the fans.
Here's Sarah Brightman.
"Time to say goodbye."
NEXEN INTERVIEWS
JE-HYEOK KIM MAJOR LEAGUE DOCS
GOCHEOK GUNMAN
This song is everywhere today.
-Are we almost there?
-Yes, almost.
Once we pass the tunnel.
We're almost there then.
Hey, that tunnel is long.
I bet it's the longest in Seoul.
It takes over an hour to go through it.
For real?
No, I'm kidding.
How long could a tunnel be?
What are you doing?
They say if you can hold your breath
in a tunnel, your wish will come true.
What are you, an eight?
Plus, you breathed.
You're right.
What are you worried about?
The stars are all aligned for you already.
Okay, shall we go in?
Okay. Let's go.
Case number 2016GO1178.
The defendant Je-hyeok Kim
chased the victim who was running away,
and assaulted him.
The defendant used a trophy,
a dangerous item, to assault him,
and critically injured him.
This was excessive and
exceeded justified self-defense.
Therefore, the defendant Je-hyeok Kim
is sentenced to one year in prison.
LITTLE SISTER JE-HEE
Excuse me. You're Je-hyeok Kim, right?
Do you know me?
Who in here doesn't know you?
Nexen Heroes' star lefty closer.
Korea's save record holder.
The monster closer.
Save king. ERA king.
Two-time Korean Series MVP.
Three-time Gold Glove winner.
Scouted by the Red Sox
for the highest salary in history...
But I see you here.
But actually, I'm Hyeon-jong Yang's fan.
He's just better looking.
This is odd. Why are you
going to Seobu Detention Center?
The hot shot criminals usually go
to Seoul or Nambu Detention Center.
If Nambu is like a first-class hotel,
Seobu is like
camping in a tent.
I like being prisonmates with a superstar,
but you must be annoyed.
Are you okay?
Are we going to a hotel?
Goodness. You're a druggie.
You can't keep that up.
Is this your first time?
No. I've been to many hotels.
You must be rich.
These are Cartier-style.
-I have two at home.
-Goodness. This man is in trouble.
He'll get beat up like crazy inside.
They'll smash your head in.
A close friend was also a druggie.
He couldn't get drugs in the slammer,
so he whined like a sick dog, and...
Mr. Driver. Mister?
Heater, please.
Please turn on the heater.
We're almost there.
This is Seobu Detention Center.
It faces north,
so we don't get much sunlight.
It has hardwood floors
and radiators for heat.
The auditorium is over 20 years old.
The platform is high,
so when the pastor preaches,
it feels like God is speaking,
so that's nice.
WE WILL TAKE GOOD CARE OF YOUR FAMILY.
REFORM THAT PROVIDES DREAMS AND HOPES.
WE ARE BY YOUR SIDE.
WE WILL TAKE GOOD CARE OF YOUR FAMILY.
SEOBU DETENTION CENTER
The shower heads were broken last time.
I wonder if they've fixed them.
OPEN REFORM, FUTURE FULL OF HOPE
My goodness.
Gosh, it's hard to get a cab.
Where would you like to go?
Please take me to Seobu Detention Center.
Why are you going there?
-To see my son.
-Goodness.
How long has he been inside?
It doesn't feel like long,
but time really flies.
It must be hard with the cold weather.
It's not like it isn't hard
when the weather is nice.
It's such a terrible place.
Do they feed them well?
Is it still just rice and beans?
He says they give them three meals a day,
but it can't be compared to food outside.
I'm bringing him some home-made food.
SEOBU DETENTION CENTER
We're here.
-Here.
-No. Just keep it.
-What?
-It's okay. I don't need it.
I have a child too.
Take it, son.
Are you looking down on me now?
Ma'am. Put it in your son's
commissary account.
Please do it for me.
What?
How may I help you?
I'd like to see my son.
Fill out the visitation form.
What form? He never said that.
I need to feed my son
before the food gets cold.
You can't bring in food,
only commissary money.
What? Why is everyone talking
about commissary today?
You're saying I can't see my own son?
You can't do this here.
Mom!
I said to come home.
I wanted to see where you work.
Plus, I need to go back right away.
Why? I said to stay the night.
Your dad will starve to death.
Hello?
They came through the gate already?
Yes. They came early today.
Okay. I'll be right there.
Mom, I need to go work. Sorry.
Okay, okay. You must be busy. Go.
Eat well, and be careful of people, okay?
This place is crawling with crooks.
Don't worry, okay?
This place isn't
as dangerous as you think.
Hello.
MORALITY
Where are you going?
Je-hyeok Kim is here.
We need to do cell inspections.
Why?
You didn't get the call?
It's the captain's orders.
We need to hurry.
You go alone. That's fine.
-Sorry?
-You must not know since you're new,
but you can do it alone.
-Really?
-No.
Do you really think you can? Do you?
No, sir.
When can I see Je-hyeok Kim?
TOOTHPASTE, LAUNDRY SOAP
WELCOME. WE'LL HELP YOU LIKE FAMILY.
It's so cold.
Hey. Look at me.
Sit here, Boss.
Let's speed it up.
The two of you.
-Yes?
-That way.
What is this? It's a size 110.
SUPPLIES
I asked for a 105.
What do you take me for?
-You little fuck.
-Eyes down.
I'll gouge out your eyes.
You're with the Honey gang, right?
Do you know that your boss
sends my boss spam every holiday season?
I'll rip you to shreds.
Spam? What spam?
No. Stop.
Hey, mister. This isn't your bedroom.
Wake up.
What are you doing? Stop.
-What are you doing?
-Let's go singing.
-Go where?
-Karaoke.
Karaoke?
You were driving in this state?
Stop crying, and fill this out.
I understand.
Hey. Let go of my hair.
Don't pull my hair.
-Spam...
-Please leave.
You people...
Why are you fighting?
What's wrong with you?
-I'm a fan.
-Let's go, Nexen.
This is insane.
Mister. Do you have this
with elastic along the hem?
No, we don't.
Then give me one a size bigger.
I'm going to roll it up.
Okay.
They say green brings you
peace in your heart,
so many of the items in the prison
are green.
Yes. That's bullshit.
The clothes, cell phone, wallet,
watch that you have on you
will be kept safely
and returned to you when you're released.
How much do you have in your wallet?
About 500,000 won.
All of that will be converted
into commissary money.
You can keep up to 3 million won
in your commissary account.
Your family or friends can send you
commissary money online or at the prison.
Am I done?
No. They need to examine you.
They already did.
They measured my height and weight.
Measuring height and weight is
just a beginning.
The special exam is still left.
Anus check.
Some people hide razors, money,
messages in there. Especially...
druggies like this hide drugs.
Many people hide illegal objects in there.
In the past, the guards checked
your butthole themselves.
It sucks being a prison guard.
Now, they use a camera
to protect inmate's human rights.
If you squat on the platform,
the camera automatically takes a picture
of your anus.
It's my turn now.
The guard who does the anus check
is here to take me in.
I'll see you again, so I won't say bye.
We're in the same cell. 7A5.
I'm also in 7A5.
Wing 7, first floor, cell 5.
See you later, Mr. Superstar.
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION
Who is he, by the way?
He's a know-it-all.
Isn't it obvious? He's a know-it-all.
ELECTRONIC VIDEO
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION DEVICE
Step on and take off your pants.
Remove your underwear as well.
Okay, good.
ANUS EXAMINATION
Yu. Have you seen my walkie-talkie?
I think I left it in this office.
Where... Now where could I have put it?
I don't know. Where could it be?
Do you think it's in here?
Take a good look.
Hey, Lieutenant Yu.
You know about the dinner tonight, right?
In case you didn't get the call.
Oh, my gosh. We do?
I didn't hear anything.
Would you jot down
the time and place for me?
Sure. I will. Hello.
-Hello.
Okay, Mr. Je-hyeok Kim. Please squat down.
Please say, "Ah," as you squat.
Okay. Ah.
What are you people doing in there?
Please help.
There's an emergency in wing 5!
Red alert! Get over there!
And Lieutenant Yu. Hurry it up.
The newbies are waiting outside. Hurry.
-Yes, Chief.
-Okay.
What are you doing? I said to go.
You people...
-Hurry.
-Je-hyeok Kim. I'm a fan.
Hang in there until your appeal.
Please give me an autograph later.
Okay, I will.
REFORM THAT PROVIDES DREAMS AND HOPES.
WE ARE BY YOUR SIDE.
It's okay. They'll get it out
at the hospital.
What did you say he swallowed?
A baduk stone,
-a janggi piece, a spoon head...
-Yes. Spoon head.
And?
A nail clipper.
What?
WING 5
Then this may take two to three days.
Lieutenant. Lighten up.
If Je-hyeok Kim appeals,
he'll be here for another few weeks.
Today isn't your only chance.
-You saw him in person, didn't you?
-Sure.
How was he?
It was my first time
to see a baseball player in person.
His physique...
His frame itself is different
from regular people.
Come with me.
CELL 7A5
Je-hyeok Kim won't be able
to sleep tonight.
They don't have cell bosses anymore,
do they?
Not in these days.
I'm the cell boss.
We have a new family member.
If you introduce yourselves,
we'll introduce ourselves as well.
Hello. My name is Young...
Didn't you
and I meet two years ago in Daejeon?
I have a vague recollection of seeing you
in Daejeon Detention Center.
That's right. Professor Myung, right?
We met in Jeongseon, right?
Long time no see.
We were at Kimcheon Juvy together.
This punk is a total jailbird.
JAILBIRD: Someone who frequently goes
in and out of prison
-Next, the baseball player Je-hyeok Kim.
-The verdict on Je-hyeok Kim's case
came out for assaulting Choi, who
attempted to sexually assault his sister.
Je-hyeok Kim, who was on the brink
of entering the Major Leagues,
was sentenced to a year in prison
by the Seoul Western District Court.
His attorney stated that it is a travesty,
and that they will appeal.
Seobu Detention Center,
where Je-hyeok Kim will be detained,
stated that they will not give him
any special treatment
for being a celebrity, and that
they will follow all rules.
Seobu Detention Center
has received ministers, prosecutors,
conglomerate family members, and now,
pro baseball star Je-hyeok Kim.
You can say they hit a grand slam
when it comes to prisons.
Next on the news.
Assemblyman Seung-gook Myung
announced he will run for office.
Since the election...
Welcome to the family, Je-hyeok Kim.
-Je-hyeok Kim!
CELL 7A3
Baseball is the manliest sport.
Sure.
But there is a guy in that cell
who's bad news.
-Dae-bong Gal.
-Yes, I know.
Incheon Osung Gang's commander.
-A.k.a. Seagull.
-Yes. That one.
I need to protect my boy Je-hyeok.
Call me Seagull.
I mean, please.
You're a superstar. I should be polite.
I'm powerless.
Crony here also did sports.
Hello, Je-hyeok Kim.
It's nice to meet you.
Even our old man is greeting him.
I didn't know that even you go crazy
for superstars.
Is it my turn now?
I'm Professor Myung.
Of course, I have another name,
but I have such great knowledge,
that everyone calls me "Professor Myung."
Okay. It's late. Shall we go to sleep now?
Says who? There are rules here.
You mean the ritual? Okay, go ahead.
Not you. We need to do it
for our superstar.
We may have come to this blessed place
on different days
and for different reasons,
but today, by drinking this glorious
and great blood together,
we wish to become brothers.
What are you doing? Hey.
Hey, guys.
Lift the arm.
-Do we need more plastic?
-Hey. This is not right.
Je-hyeok Kim is a lefty pitcher.
Put it under his right arm.
Seriously!
Hold on.
Your body temperature may drop
from excessive loss of blood,
so if you feel cold or dizzy,
you just have to raise your right foot
high into the sky.
Okay, let's begin.
Excuse me.
Seriously! Just a minute.
Excuse me. Just a minute.
Excuse me. Hello? Hello.
Just a minute. Just...
Just a minute. Please?
Just a minute. Professor?
Professor.
Professor. Just a minute.
Right foot.
Just a minute. Now I'm cold!
Professor, I'm freezing!
My... My body temperature is dropping.
Please don't do this.
Professor, please don't.
Fine.
I'll help you this one time.
Why? Because we're brothers now.
Thank you.
Je-hyeok. Your foot is free now.
You may put it down.
Hey, Mr. Superstar.
Turn off the light, will you?
What are you doing? You're such a nitwit.
Are you going to do that all night?
Hey. Je-hyeok Kim.
Why are you doing?
Well... I'm looking for the switch.
Did you ever see someone turn off
the lights in prison?
There's no light switch in prison.
Don't pick on him so much, will you?
Seriously.
Go to sleep.
A broadcast shared with 50,000 inmates.
I am Min-joo Lee, your host
of the Borami Broadcast.
How was your day, everyone?
Now, lie still and close your eyes.
It is time to close out this day.
The Talmud says
not to regret the things you've done,
but to regret the things you did not do
that you wanted to.
OPEN REFORM, FUTURE FULL OF HOPE
This is the last song of today.
We received a high number
of requests for this song today.
It must mean your way
of welcoming a new family member.
Here's Sarah Brightman.
"Time to say goodbye."
That's enough already. Enough.
Hey. Do you have a humidifier
or anything like that around here?
A Xiaomi is fine too.
Help me!
I was just dry, that's all!
Help!
Shit. Let go of me, you jerks!
Let go! My feet aren't touching the floor!
Oh no!
Help me!
Kim. Here, use this.
It's nothing much.
You can't find this in here.
Just let me know,
and I'll get you anything you want.
Thanks.
The law isn't difficult
The law isn't uncomfortable
The law helps us
The law protects us
A convenient world that's alive
It's time to eat, Kim.
I've ordered room service.
Meal time!
WING 7
DANGER
It's winter, so we get
beef and radish soup often.
-Right, gramps?
-Yes.
Korean food in Seobu is pretty good.
I'll probably gain weight.
Here's your soup.
Great.
Hey! Errand Boy!
-Yes?
-The omelet rolls.
Are you kidding? Give us more.
I'm so sorry.
I may run out, so let me finish the floor
and then give you more.
Chief Jo said he'll kill me
if I run out of rations.
-Hey, compatriot. You may go now.
-Thanks.
It doesn't look good to fight
first thing in the morning.
Will someone get me my pouch?
SESAME OIL
SOY SAUCE
SPICY ANCHOVY SAUCE
There are so many things in this cell.
Everyone must have money.
Professor Myung, get me some too, later.
As long as you pay.
Okay, everyone. Enjoy.
Thank you.
There's no beef in the beef soup here.
It's like a cow dipped its feet briefly.
This punk eats so damn quickly.
It's because he hasn't had
home cooking in a while.
Kim. You should eat too.
Hey, Jailbird.
What did you come in for this time?
I got a loan from a bank
to pay for my mom's surgery,
but I couldn't pay it back.
You came in
for a very humane reason this time.
I don't know if the food here
will be to your liking, Kim.
-It's fine.
-That's a great relief.
The head cook here came in
for murder and mutilation of the body,
but he's a great cook.
Je-hyeok.
Are you okay?
Did you sleep well last night?
How much longer must I stay here?
At most a month.
ATTORNEY VISITATION ROOM 3
I'll schedule an appeal
as soon as possible.
I think the judge did this
because of all the media attention.
But the public sentiment is on your side,
so you'll win the appeal for sure.
Hey. I got a new number.
The reporters won't leave me alone.
I have a favor to ask.
A private cell?
Two ministers and the Chief Secretary
will be sent here today.
The private cells are completely booked.
These punks.
Don't worry. Wait a little bit.
I'm making a deal with the warden here.
I got you your own separate time
to exercise.
I'll request a private cell too.
This is ridiculous.
How could they put you in the same cell
as thieves?
No.
Please take care of my credit card bills
and deliveries.
What?
The abalone must've thawed out by now.
That too.
Okay.
I came in so suddenly.
Okay. Don't worry.
I left the boiler on too.
Okay, I'll turn it off.
And I'm supposed
to send gloves and baseballs
to Jung-min's baseball team.
You send them for me.
He's your son, so you should know
what brand he likes, right?
Don't be late.
Don't worry about my son.
And he has no talent for baseball.
Sports are meant for gifted people.
You need to be born with it, like you.
Hey.
Don't slack off on your workouts.
I'm sure you'll take care of it,
but still.
How's the gym here? Is it big?
Why don't you give us a suggestion too?
This guy is from the next wing over.
He just became a dad today.
It's a girl, but they don't have
a name yet, so he wants advice.
How about Mal-shim Kim?
That sounds retarded.
It's my mom's name.
Very stupid.
A big moron.
Don't stay together like that. Separate.
You want a baseball?
Yes. Will it be hard?
I think it'll be quicker
to get a bat and speed gun.
I guess so.
Then, how about an apple...
An apple...
That should be doable.
If you hold an apple,
it's similar to a baseball.
So it should be of great help
with your training.
Yes. Thank you.
-How much...
-It's 50,000 won.
Just deposit it
into my commissary account.
Of course, you can take your time.
Hey! Jailbird! You. You have a visitor.
Me? I'm not expecting anyone.
Yes, you have. And, Je-hyeok Kim!
You have a visitor. Sun-ja Park plus one.
Come out.
WAITING ROOM FOR VISITATION
Visitation is for ten minutes.
Okay.
I know.
It'll be very short
if you speak so slowly like that.
Okay.
Who's here to visit you?
My mom.
Why did you think for so long? Who else?
Who else?
It's your mom plus one.
The visitation has begun.
Why did you come?
Did you eat?
I'm eating well. It's nice here.
Are you sleeping well?
Yes. You don't need to worry.
Isn't it cold?
How's the heater? Is it warm enough?
Yes.
It's fine.
-Je-hee...
Don't bring her.
I'm sure she's just crying anyway.
Don't bother bringing her.
Mom, I'm really okay.
Oh, my.
I almost used up all the time.
Ji-ho. You must have much more to say.
I'll let you talk.
What? You still didn't tell her
that we broke up?
I was going to.
Stop. Nails.
Are you okay?
No.
- How's the food?
- It tastes like crap.
Did you sleep well?
No. I didn't sleep a wink.
- Isn't it cold?
- It is.
I think I caught a cold.
Your shirt looks very low-cut.
What's it to you? We broke up.
How can you laugh right now?
You're right.
Be careful of people.
You be careful.
I'm always careful.
- Should we fight again?
- Should we?
You have one minute remaining.
What was that?
We have one minute left.
Ji-ho.
I'm fine.
So you don't need
to come here anymore. Okay?
Who said I would?
You're right.
You did nothing wrong.
So don't be discouraged.
We're all on your side.
Your visitation has ended.
Please exit
for the next visitation to begin.
And if you need anything...
That son of a...
Hey, gramps.
It still stinks.
-Clean the toilet again.
-Okay.
Okay. I will.
Do it right the first time.
Don't make me tell you to redo it.
How was your visit?
Was it your girlfriend?
What's this?
Mr. Superstar has a girlfriend?
This is breaking news.
No.
What?
He says he doesn't have one.
Shit. I need to pee.
Hey. Move.
Excuse me.
-What?
-Don't do that.
What's it to you?
Look.
Mr. Superstar.
Just mind your own business
until you get out.
Don't mind yourself here.
But he's an elderly man.
You're being too mean.
Shit!
There are no kids or adults
in the slammer.
Everyone is a thief in here. Got it?
I'm back.
Look, Mr. Superstar.
Just stay out of it, you fucking asshole.
Apologize.
What?
I said to apologize.
I don't want to.
I said I don't want to, you fuck.
Shit. That little...
Who does he think he is?
-You little...
-Stop it, you rat!
Shut up, you rat.
Stay out of my life, okay?
Got it, you asshole?
Delivery!
Everyone, let's sit down.
Let's check the goods.
What are you doing, Kim? Sit down.
Let me confirm your order.
Six milks, three cartons of orange juice.
Black tea, ginger tea, barley tea.
Six chicken legs, sesame oil,
foam cleanser.
Electric razor.
It's full again today.
Professor Myung, it's your turn, right?
Please sign here.
COMMISSARY ACCOUNT ACTIVITIES
That's right. Professor,
why did you order an apple?
The uncles here don't eat apples
because they don't taste good.
You should order something
that's in season.
Oh. Mr. Je-hyeok Kim. Hello.
If you need anything, place an order.
It's much nicer than a department store.
Get lost.
Okay.
Gramps.
One milk and one juice, right?
Yes. Thanks. Thank you.
Hey, Kim.
Nice catch.
It was just a practical joke we play.
CAUTION: SLIPPERY
SILENCE
You're really fit.
You're an athlete after all.
But you have to wash very quickly.
Okay.
You're really in trouble.
-Me?
-Yes.
-Why?
-Gramps has no money.
We place orders all together
under one person's name,
and take turns paying.
Gramps has no money,
so he works it off instead.
That's how he survives in here. Why did
you get involved? You messed up, right?
How was your visitation?
Your mom cried a lot, didn't she?
Me? My sister.
I wondered what made her come.
My mom's surgery didn't go well.
She's in the ICU at Shinchon Hospital.
She's in critical condition.
She needs another surgery today,
but she can't get it
because we don't have the money.
What?
Oh, I'm fine.
There's nothing we can do.
When my dad died in a car accident
when I was seven,
I bawled my head off.
But my uncle took
the insurance money and fled.
I lived in a shack with
my maternal grandma, mom, and sister.
It caught on fire, and my grandma died.
My sister got a bad burn scar
on her face and became ugly.
My poor sister.
My mom did all sorts of work
at restaurants.
She was hit by a hit-and-run driver
on her way from work.
He was drunk and speeding,
but they still haven't caught him.
My mom damaged her brain
pretty badly back then
and got several rounds of surgery.
I thought the last surgery
would be the last one,
so I lied and got a loan from the bank.
She probably won't make it this time.
I think she'll pass away.
Hey. It's our turn. Let's go.
We don't get hot showers that often.
CAUTION: SLIPPERY
USE WATER SPARINGLY
You don't have shampoo. Here, use this.
Buy me some shampoo too, next time.
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
There isn't much left, but here.
-Thank you.
-Not at all.
The hot water will cut off soon.
It doesn't come out for
the entire ten minutes. You should hurry.
Okay. Thank you.
It's cold.
Yes. Quitting time.
Aren't you leaving?
I should.
JOON-HO LEE
Je-hyeok Kim Had a First Visitor
in the Detention Center
First visitor?
Even this is news?
It must be such a pain for him.
I know.
My poor Je-hyeok. It must be such a pain.
So cold.
You're back. Good job.
You too.
He's fine. Don't worry.
He probably isn't asleep yet.
You can go look.
How long
Can a person live
This dog poop like world
Round
Couldn't they play Sex and Zen instead?
They have no taste.
But you know, Je-hyeok Kim is so clueless.
I feel like he'll cry
and ask for a private cell.
He's a bit dumb.
I don't know if he can survive in here.
He looks like the perfect idiot
that people pick on.
Je-hyeok Kim
has a bad temper.
-What?
-Je-hyeok Kim has a bad temper.
His fans all know.
Hey, gramps.
You love that, right?
-Thank you.
-Sure.
Eat it all right now.
What are you waiting for? Eat.
Hey, Kim. Stop glaring at me.
You look like a fish.
I was just kidding.
I'm so scared.
I'm too scared of the superstar
to live here.
Je-hyeok Kim is usually slow
and seems easy,
but once he loses it, it's crazy.
He's frightening.
That's why his nickname is
Mok-dong Psycho.
Isn't he the Mok-dong Idol?
Idol? As if.
Get up.
Hey. I said to get up.
What is it?
Are you nuts?
-Speak nicely.
-What?
I said to speak nicely, you asshole!
Aren't you guys leaving?
I should go. Go ahead.
I'll change and go too.
Okay. I'll go then.
See you tomorrow.
HOUSEMATE
Hey. You left work already?
Let go! Get over here, you jerk!
Get over here! Come here.
You come to me, jerk. You stupid ass.
Hey! Let go. You're lost your marbles!
You stupid asshole. You don't have
the guts to beat up a superstar, do you?
Damn it!
What are you doing?
Chief Jo!
This jerk is a complete psycho!
He's a mad dog! Look at me!
This jerk beat me up!
Je-hyeok. Did you do that to Seagull?
Yes. I beat him up.
This crazy psycho shit!
Blood!
-Bring Seagull to the infirmary.
-Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Come out.
You're headed straight to
the segregation unit. You'll die.
-Je-hyeok, come out.
-It was an accident.
Rather than the segregation unit,
maybe he can wait in another...
Drop the bull.
Kim. I think you'll have to go.
Hey. I'll take him.
You will?
Go have some coffee.
That jerk messed with you again.
Hey, Kim.
Cigarette?
No thank you. I quit.
This is very valuable in here.
Okay. I guess athletes
need to take care of their bodies.
Then do you want one of these?
Glass products like these
are nearly impossible to get in here.
Thank you.
Sure. You know,
you check age and pride at the door
when you come in here.
Those who were nobodies outside
fight to become the boss
when they come in here.
How ridiculous, right?
But still, there are rules
even in a place like this.
If you cause trouble as you did,
you're supposed to be segregated,
but that could be held against you
when you appeal.
That's why I'm making an exception
and looking the other way
because I like you.
Thank you. I owe you one.
I'll repay you for this.
Yes, of course you must.
Well, you can just repay me now
for what you owe.
With money.
You have an appointment
with your lawyer tomorrow.
Ask your lawyer to send money
to this account.
Here you go.
Oh, right. This would be better.
You can just call.
Call your family or close friend
and ask for 30 million won.
Have them deposit it
into that account now.
Go on.
What are you doing? Hurry.
Someone will come in.
Chief Jo.
Hi, Lee. What is it?
Why didn't you go home?
You need to go to 2023. It's flipping out.
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
Get it done by tomorrow, please.
God, what a nuisance.
Seagull, that jerk.
That's right. Please escort Kim
to his cell for me.
While you're at it,
take advantage of the situation,
and have a fan meeting with him.
Your wish has come true.
Joon-ho.
What are you doing here?
Hey, Superstar.
-It's been a while.
-Shut it.
-What are you doing here?
-What else? I'm a corrections officer.
You punk. And you come to see me now?
That's not it.
Some jerk swallowed a nail clipper,
so I was at the hospital
for the past two days.
I wanted to come right away.
What about you? You caused trouble
already, in that short time?
How's your arm? Is it okay?
Of course. That was so long ago.
What about you?
Me too.
I'm good.
FALL 2015
Only one out remains.
Pitching is the Gwangju Jeil HS' ace,
the gifted teen pitcher.
Will Gwangju Jeil win
or will it be a big upset?
Out!
GWANGJU
Uncle, me too.
Don't do that to a kid.
Is it good?
Come here.
Here.
Where's Coach?
I don't know.
Sit straight. Straighten your back.
Instant noodles again?
How can you eat noodles
after having barbecues?
They're still growing.
And kids prefer instant noodles
over barbecues.
I brought beer.
May we have some, Coach?
It's a gift for winning.
And there's no practice tomorrow.
Of course not. What's the point?
They'll be graduating soon.
Did you decide where to go?
Doosan? LG?
Bears or Twins?
Whoever pays more.
Nice. I like your attitude.
Okay, then. Excuse us.
Let's go.
How will you live without them?
Just keep them here.
They can keep living here with us
even after they go to the pros.
They can't commute from Gwangju to Seoul.
Gosh. One has clubs knocking down doors,
but the other doesn't have a single offer.
But in the long run,
he'll do better.
In whose lifetime?
I guess even you can't beat alcohol.
Are you up already?
I guess habits are a scary thing
after all.
I'm going back to sleep.
Go ahead.
I guess he's still human, though.
Who would've thought we'd see the day?
He already did.
He worked out already,
washed up and went to sleep again.
What a devoted coach.
You should just move in with them
in Seoul.
I'll be back soon.
Don't come back soon. Drive safely.
Thank you for everything.
I will never forget
all you've done for us.
I'll buy you the most expensive thing
in Seoul.
Thank you.
What are you doing? Say bye to Daddy.
-Is he going far away?
-Yes.
He's going very far away.
Next, a car accident.
There was a three-car collision
near the rest area in Jeongeup
on the north-bound side
of the Honam Expressway.
The driver of the sedan,
Hyuk-kwon Kim, the coach
of the Gwangju Jeil High School's
baseball team died on the spot.
Passengers, baseball players Kim and Lee,
were critically injured.
They were transported to a hospital
and are being treated,
but they are still in critical condition.
Due to the accident,
there is massive congestion
near the rest area in Jeongeup.
The police state that...
JOON-HO LEE
JE-HYEOK KIM
Thank goodness it wasn't worse.
There's a 50% chance of success
for elbow surgeries.
You are very muscular,
so I think you'll be able to return
after a year of rehab.
It's quite serious.
Your shoulder popped out from the impact
and broke.
The left shoulder was
dislocated and fractured.
We need to look more closely,
but surgery seems to be the only option
at this time. However,
there's only a 10% chance of success.
It won't hinder your daily life,
but if you're a pitcher,
it looks pretty bad.
If you don't get surgery,
it'll probably take
two to three years more
to rehabilitate it.
And... Well...
JOON-HO LEE
JE-HYEOK KIM
We tried to stop him,
but he was certain he wanted to leave.
He said he won't continue
playing baseball,
and that he'll return home to his family.
His mother came today and took him home.
It's a shame. He had a good chance
with surgery.
Je-hyeok.
Thank you.
No. I have nothing else to do anyway.
If you said you'd quit as well,
He may have broken down in heaven.
Thank you.
It's nothing.
Je-hyeok.
It'll be very hard.
It may take a very long time, too.
It's okay.
I know it may take long,
but you know I'm slow.
No club scouted me anyway.
I'm late anyway, so I'll fix everything
here and there, and start over.
What did you and Chief Jo talk about?
Nothing much.
Joon-ho.
May I make a phone call?
Make it quick.
If we get caught,
I'll be wearing that too.
Hello? Hey.
I have a favor to ask.
There's a certain excitement
that the word "first" gives you.
Like first love.
What about first imprisonment?
Hey. Joon-dol. This isn't a house.
It's a pigsty.
I need to submit this today.
What's Je-hyeok Kim's cell number?
And why won't they give my bro a single?
"My bro"? Is Je-hyeok your brother?
I'm your brother.
What's your problem?
You can finally be useful
to your little brother!
You should thank Je-hyeok Kim.
Your friend is a superstar.
You're so lucky. That's super cool.
Hey. I played a little baseball too,
back in the day.
And honestly,
I was slightly better than Je-hyeok.
No. You're different.
You and my bro Je-hyeok are way different.
How are we different? We're the same.
You're like crystal.
You're light and fragile, but...
But?
My bro Je-hyeok...
Je-hyeok will overcome it
because he never gives up.
He's the man who never gives up.
So? What's his cell number?
I want to start with that this week.
Okay? Tell me.
Please, tell me.
Please?
Money isn't hard
Money isn't uncomfortable
Money helps us
Money protects us
The law protects and helps us?
What a freaking joke.
Whatever. What a crappy world.
Famous and rich punks
don't get punished in this crappy world.
Come out, Je-hyeok Kim.
Come out, you jerk.
9A2
SEGREGATION CELL
At least it's a private cell.
Great.
SEGREGATION UNIT
Meal time!
The food tastes super sweet today.
Justice really does prevail.
It is so very strange.
What is?
Kim caused trouble yesterday.
Why was he segregated today?
Chief Jo is a psycho.
You should know that by now.
Please select the desired transaction.
Please enter your PIN number.
PIN NUMBER
Processing. Please wait a moment.
Please confirm the transaction
and select the desired transaction.
BALANCE: 15,000 WON
This fucker.
Please feed me.
Meal time!
Don't do that.
I haven't got used to things here yet.
-You okay?
-Sure.
You should've told me.
How did you find out?
Cho told me.
Chief Jo is a sly bastard.
You should've told me last night.
It's okay.
I can cover that much on my own.
Whatever.
That's why you're in there?
And you have money to burn, don't you?
Then give me some.
I wish Je-hyeok would rot in there
for just one week. That would rock.
What?
Are you that touched
that they served us mackerel?
Why are you crying out of the blue?
Hello?
Hey.
I have a favor to ask.
What is it? Is something wrong?
There's a patient named Mal-shim Kim
at Shinchon Hospital.
Yes.
Mal-shim Kim.
OPERATING ROOM
PATIENT STATUS
MAL-SHIM KIM: OPERATION IN PROGRESS
Je-hyeok.
That's enough, okay? That's enough.
Everyone here committed crimes.
They're bad people.
Okay.
It's because he said
he's a Hyeon-jong Yang's fan.
I wanted to steal his fan.
That old man isn't worth it either.
He has nine priors.
He came in for murder this time.
He stabbed someone walking by 20 times.
There.
He must've stabbed him with that.
Murderer!
Murderer! You evil bastard!
You evil bastard!
You evil bastard! Murderer!
He stabbed a person who was breathing
20 times
for looking at him for no reason.
Don't trust anyone.
Everyone here is a crook.
What are we going to do with you?
Can't you control your temper, you psycho?
Later.
SEGREGATION UNIT
SEOBU DETENTION CENTER
Seeing the snow makes me want ice cream.
You can have it once you win your appeal.
You just need to hang on
for one more week.
You have one week left.
Hang in there for one more week.
Hey! Seriously.
What a crappy world this is.
Some people can beat a person to a pulp
and walk out scot-free.
You never know. Life is so unpredictable.
Why aren't you ratting Je-hyeok out?
How is there no news about him
beating up a person?
This is such a strange place.
It isn't a place for people to live.
Give me a knife, you shit. A knife.
I can't get you a knife.
I'll end up getting segregated
if I'm caught just holding it.
I will board the Ark of Salvation
Dong-ho, what's wrong? Breathe.
Chief Jo.
Please call an ambulance.
Wing 7! Inspection!
When you get out,
you'll never see these people again.
That Errand Boy is a total thug too.
He's a real punk.
Pro baseball player Je-hyeok Kim's appeal
begins today at 11 a.m.
It's the most important day of your life,
so hang on for one more day.
Good luck, Je-hyeok.