And on tuesday evening you poured yourself some
brandy, drank the whole glass in one gulp,
closed the cupboard and turned the light off in the living
room, went to the bathroom and brushed your teeth
and in the bedroom you skimmed through your
newspaper and fell asleep
- So?
So what do you mean? I drank my brandy,
turned off the light
brushed my teeth and eventually
fell asleep. So?
Nothing. Only that I was still
sitting in the living room.
Listen, Katja, let's take our time in
the evening and discuss about this.
Now I'm on my way to the client, let us later
have dinner together.
- You are oblivious to me.
You know that this is not true. I was
probably lost in thoughts. I'm sorry.
One may be lost in thoughts but not
completely forget there's another person
living in the same appartement.
I'm really sorry.
And that's not all. On Wednesday,
when Lobenstein enquired about my job,
you couldn't stand it.
You immediately started talking about you.
Every time when it's about me ...
- Damn it, Katja, have you compiled a list of this ...
What have you said?
Katja, let's ...
- What have you just said?
I asked yo if you made a complete list of this.
That's what I've asked you.
Yes, I did. And that's the end of our conversation.
Shit.
So, what do we have here?
Revlon 17 Vixen.
What's so funny about it?
Do you know what BDS stands for?
No, but i'm really anxious to hear it.
Brigade of the dim-witted.
And what does the S stand for?
Ok
Have a nice evening. Bye.
Laura... Excuse me ...
Could I talk to you for a moment?
Alone.
Sorry...  This was not my idea.
Don't you believe me?
I believe you. But I've finished for today.
What did he want?
- He invited me to a meal.
Lunch or dinner?
- Dinner
And after that to dance .... tango.
Laura!
Are you Laura Reiser?
Would you please come with me. Your son
had an accident. He's in the hospital.
You were right.
I did make a list.
Only because I knew I would cry.
And when I cry, I get mixed up.
Katja!
Do you think he'll die?
Rubbish, how do you come up with this idea?
You didn't bring any of his things.
I don't need anything here.
Good morning I'd like a car,
17 Nordhoftraße, Gerber
All right. Thank you.
Why don't you drive with your car?
It's broken down.
- Serious damage?
The apex seal of the rotary piston.
Then I can drive you.
- You don't need to.
... Apex seal of the rotary piston
- What about it?
Nothing ... it sounds beautiful.
I would like to cancel the taxi for Gerber.
Thank you.
Shall I pick you up.
- No, you don't need to. I'll take a demonstration car.
What's with your car?
- It's broken down.
The apex seal of the rotary piston
- I understand ...
Shall I tell someone to pick it up?
- No, I'll do it myself.
See you later.
So?
- Well ...
What do you think? Are those people clients?
No idea.
Well, don't look at us ... look down there.
The children's seat, for example ...
is more expensive than the entire car.
Really.
Yeah, really. You can believe me ...
Now they have a child and somewhere someone rich
has become a granny or a grandpa ...
and buys a car for them.
And you shall go downstairs and sell them one.
And please don't start talking about
resales or the engine torque.
They want something that's safe and
healthy for their child.
Do you understand what I mean?
All right, then give it to them.
Good luck!
Do you think he'll manage it?
Yes, I suppose ... we'll see.
And you ... do you manage it?
What?
To be faithful and honest.
It's been a terrible week for Katja. I hope I won't
see my sister suffering like that again.
If you cheat on her, I'll sack you.
Did you understand?
I always understand you, Klaus.
You prefer the combi because you think of
all the things you have to take with you:
Buggy, trike, bobbycar ..
... but I assure you  that you can put all these
trouble-free in a limousine too.
...  I've told you that there are
two essential reasons for ....
Driver flees after running down a child
Hello, could you please put out
your cigarette.
Yes, it's you I mean.
Good afternoon. My name is Philipp Gerber.
Yesterday afternoon I have run down a child
on the L322  between Wolfsburg and Norsteimke.
I commited a hit-and-run.
I should have stopped and check for the boy,
call an ambulance or drive
the boy to the hospital.
... but I didn't do that.
I don't know why ...
... I don't know why ...
Maybe I was thinking of my girlfriend, who was
about to pack her things and leave me.
But I don't know it for sure.
I hope ... I hope that the boy is OK
... I hope that the boy is alright.
I hope that the boy gets well.
Good afternoon. My name is Philipp Gerber.
Yesterday afternoon I have run down a child
on the L322 between Wolfsburg and Norsteimke.
Is that coffee?
- There's a machine up front.
Do you have a cigarette?
- I've quit smoking.
Excuse me, that's my coffee.
- Please.
Do you have a cigarette?
Yes.
Light?
Excuse me, my name is Philipp Gerber ...
Ms. Reiser, come quickly, Paul woke up.
Please hold this.
Is my bicycle broken?
We'll buy another one.
Can I chose one?
Can you drive a bicycle at the seaside?
Yes, on the spots where the sand is moist.
Red car. Ford.
What type. Ask him what type the car was.
-Later.
... the boy has woken up.
The nurse says he'll make it.
... yes he has. A red Ford.
No, he shortly felt asleep.
Shall I stay here?
It's me. I just wanted to hear your voice.
Bye.
For how long have you been staying here?
Why didn't you call me?
You wanted to hear my voice
and I wanted to see you.
Let's go away
Where.
Simply go away. Maybe to an island.
For how long?
- For as long as you want.
Let's get married.
Has something happened?
I can't believe it.
I'm sorry. And when should it happen?
Philipp, could you come for a moment?
Could you please come ...
Why did you do that?
What for?
Do you want a part of the car dealership?
Don't you earn enough money?
Is the commission too low?
Is it the position?
You don't even love her.
You only take advantage of her.
Right. And when the situation becomes dire,
you simply bugger off.
Listen to me! Did you understand it?
Francoise! Philipp, may I introduce to you...
Francoise.
Philipp, sales manager and future brother-in-law.
Enchanted. I have to go.
You look fine.
Why didn't you let someone
from the garage do it?
I think I wanted to prove to myself
that I'm still able to do it.
And are you?
- Yes, I believe ...
I thought it was all about the
apex seal of the rotary piston.
You don't get very far ....
Could you prepare a bath?
- I could use one too.
Excuse me
I'm leaving shortly to bring a few things for Paul.
- Allright.
Could you call me a cab?
- The taxi rank is next to the hospital.
If he wakes up, tell him I'll be right back.
- Of course.
I tried to call you.
I only reached the voice mail.
The battery is empty.
I'm so sorry ...
The gentle swell rinses the bare, gleaming cliffs,
and the mild wind smoothly strikes the skin.
A sunset on Cuba is short,
but so intense and breathtaking,
that one lingers in the darkness,
oddly relaxed, almost overwhelmed.
That's not a travel guide, that's sex.
Can I see?
That's very beautiful.
When you cannot bear the suffering caused
by losing a beloved person
you may want to depart this life too
There are people who jump from a bridge,
people who throw themselves in front of a car
or of a train, people who plunge into water.
They want to disappear and follow
their beloved into the other world.
But someone like you, who stabs himself four times
with a knife doesn't want to follow anyone.
He wants to punish himself.
You feel guilty and we want to relieve you
from this sense of guilt.
Does jumping into water mean
that you're free of any guilt?
Laura, I have talked to all of them: to his
colleagues, to their mothers, to the teachers,
you are a great mother and don't have
any reason to feel guilty.
On 11. 3. 1996 you are at the councelling center
of the Departement of Social Services
and you want to give your son up for adoption.
He is currently six month old, you specify that
you're unable to mamage it anymore,
you are a single mother and
have no perspective.
Laura, you know well you
can take everything you want.
If you need another blanket,
you can find one in the closet.
Thanks.
Sleep well.
We'll find that bastard.
Sure!
Vera!
Can I sleep here?
Of course.
A clown, bears, a bottle, a dog,
a glove, a dice, a car,
a frog, another car.
I am here!
And whereto now?
To the sea.
Where's the sea?
I'ts a long, long way ... you have to drive
through five cities,
through three forests.
Shall I bring for you something from there?
A starfish.
And bring one for Laura too.
- I will.
Here it is.
Where you've this one?
- It lay there.
Totally broken.
- We'll get it right.
No you can't, forget it.
Was it in an accident?
Looks like.
But you're looking for a Ford.
This one is an NSU Ro 80.
Throw it back from where
you took it.
Do you think it helps if you'll find him?
Probably not.
Have to go again to work.
Have to take care of Antonia,
cannot take her for weeks with me.
I'll go again home.
That's not what I've meant.
- I know.
That's silly.
I think it's cute.
Phillip!?
Urgent: Seeking witnesses ....
Something has happened ...
it dates back before our
voyage to Cuba.
I thought I've gotten over it ...
Did you wait until
I lay in the tub?
What?
I've read that most men break it off
when their girlfriend is lying in the bathtub.
You cannot answer back as you're naked,
wet and defenseless.
You remain in the bathtub and all seems
more calm, more tolerable, easier.
But it doesn't have anything to do with that.
Philipp, I don't want any confessions.
I don't want to be a rubbish dump.
I'm not interested in what happened.
I'll let some air in.
I think you should start working again.
Believe me, it's better this way.
A great car!
New TÜV vehicle inspection certificate,
84.000 km, ATP
moonroof, 4 doors, shipshape
except some small injuries,
What exactly?
- Back bumper needs some bending, some painting..
And the car fender?
- Is all right.
Has it ever been replaced?
- Put your hand inside it.
What do you feel?
It's quite rough.
- You see ...
It's the underbody protection. Had it been
replaced, the surface would have been even.
It's yours for 1200, guarantees included.
Thank you very much.
1100, maybe?
Red, red, red, red, red, red, red ...
- Again
Again? Red, red, red, red, red, red, red ...
What do vampyres drink?
- Red.
What do you donate to the red cross?
When are you allowed to cross the street?
- Red.
So you cross the street when the red light is on?
- Oh, shit!
At this moment I would have
sold you a car, Françoise.
What did she want?
- She's looking for some red Ford.
Do you come in?
- I'll come in a moment.
Do you have one for me?
What's wrong with you?
I'll come in soon.
I want to go home.
Let's drive.
I only wanted to say that
I've kept your job ...
and I thought that maybe you'll like
to supervise the shelf maintenance.
That's a good position. I believe you're
the right person for this.
I'll  be very glad if
you'd come back.
January is evident. We'll take
the picture from the Web-catalogue.
For february we'll do something
completely different.
Simple, clear, still life.
I find it great.
- Yeah. Continue!
For march I thought we'll
go right into the summer.
Sun, wind, cabriolet,
but no clumsy Cote d'Azur.
With a woman's close-up.  Her hair in the
wind, a fresh face, say goodbye to the winter!
What's wrong with you?
Don't you like it?
I'll be right back.
Did you take dance lessons?
- No.
... and Argentinian tango ...
Of course! Anyone can dance tango.
I can't do it!
I can drive you home.
The bycicle goes into the trunk.
I can flip over the back seat.
I'll drive you to a hospital.
No. no hospital.
I'll drive you home.
Urgent: Seeking witnesses!
What are you doing?
I was looking for some dry things.
You've fainted. I've driven you home.
I made some hot tea.
Please leave.
Of course.
Everything is all right. I only want to be alone.
- Good bye.
Did I wake you up?
I'm sorry.
What's happened to you?
A flat tyre.
There's always something wrong with your cars.
And, how's the calendar?
- Shitty.
Then it was worth it.
Good morning.
I brought your bicycle. Didn't want
to leave it unlocked downstairs.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
- Yes.
You can leave that there,
noone's going to steal it
Good coffee.
I'm glad that nothing bad has happened
to you last night.
I'm glad too.
Do you know what BDS stands for?
Brigade of the dim-witted.
And what does the S stand for?
I have to go.
- I'll drive you.
I'd like to get off here.
Thank you.
When do you finish work?
- At 7. Why?
I'd like to invite you to dinner,
if that's all right to you.
I could come by at 8.
I'm sorry, but I'd rather not go out.
You polished your fingernails.
Right.
How did you enter
the brigade of the dim-witted?
I's a job.
What job did you learn to do?
Typography.
And why don't you work
as a typographer?
There's hardly any work
for a typographer.
For how long haven't you
worked this?
For eight years.
Could you drive me home?
- Sure.
I could find you a job. A good one.
I'd like to help you.
I'd really like to go home.
Nice to see you!
What are you doing here?
Business ... discussions.
I have to ... have a nice evening.
Do you want to drive along for a while?
Simply drive.
Good morning.
I got us breakfast.
Would you like some coffee?
Where are we?
- Near Braunschweig.
What's the time?
- One second ...
Almost 8.
- Shit! I have to go to work!
We'll eat as we drive.
I can't go like this to work.
Then we'll first drive to your place.
In case you're hungry ...
there are some sandwiches in the bag.
They only had chicken.
I hope you like it.
No, thanks, I'm not hungry.
Does it taste good?
How late is it now?
- Shortly after half past.
I have to hurry.
When can I see you again?
- I don't know.
I have to go.
A little late, huh?
I felt asleep in the car.
I've lost a shoe.
Laura, could you please come to my office.
Now.
I was only 20 minutes late.
It's not going to happen again, really.
- No, Laura.
Oh, please.
It's too late.
I'll get it all under control, really.
Yes, I've seen that.
So that's really ...
Please leave now.
And what are the deduction from salary for?
Because I didn't want to kiss you?
We've made an error and paid you
family allowance for 3 extra months.
I can't employ a typographer.
Noone can pay for it.
You'd do me a great favor, that's all.
And the social security contributions,
the protection against dismissal and all that?
I'll pay all that to you.
- Philipp, you're a friend, I'm not happy to take money from you.
Simply tell me how much.
Is all this a coming to terms with the past
or investment in the future?
How much?
- She's beautiful ....?
Please, simply tell me how much.
30.000
- 30.000? For sure, for one year.
Shall I transfer it to a company?
- Cash. You know, the books ...
But she won't know anything, right?
- You look exhausted.
Switch it off!
It was a business dinner.
She's a graphic artist from Oliver's firm
and we discussed some details about the calendar.
Did she drop this detail in your car?
Who is she?
Cinderella.
You're a dirty pig.
I met her before Cuba.
I thought it was nothing serious.
I'm thinking of her night and day.
Philipp!
Klaus would like the car keys back.
... At Audi in Wolfsburg and before that
at BMW in Forchheim.
We can discuss it then.
I'll call you when I arrive.
To you too. Thank you. Good bye.
Good morning.
Did I wake you up?
I'm sorry.
You forgot your shoe in the car.
- Right.
Would you like some coffee?
For how long are you still on probation?
For three weeks.
You'll make it.
I still have to get acquainted with all the software,
but I think it will work out all right.
I would have thanked you ....
- What for?
... but I didn't have your address.
And then I thought there ought to have been
a reason for you not giving it to me.
I've just split up with my wife.
Actually I've come to say good-bye.
I'll leave.
And your work?
- I've handed my notice.
But that's terrible!
- No. Not really.
And where do you want to go to?
To Forchheim. My parents live there.
I also have an offer nearby.
Is that far away?
It's close to Nürnberg.
I'll go then ...
- What's the time?
Three quarters past eight.
- Damn it, how can I ... I'm late again.
I can drive you.
What's wrong?
- No idea.
Also closed.
Holiday.
Would you like to drive somewhere?
Don't you have to leave?
There's time enough.
Laura ...
You did it.
There's been an accident.
Someone severely injured.
Where are we?
On the B 248
close to Salzwedel.
B 248, close to Salzwedel.