Dedée of Antwerp
Rita Hayworth! Hi, red.
- Hello honey, cigarette américaine?
- No, thank you.
- A walk, miss?
- No walk, boys, no time.
- She's nice.
- Oh, let her go, she's in a hurry.
- So long, red.
- So long.
You know her?
She's one of the broads
from Big Moon.
Expensive?
She'll cost you a week's salary!
Oh what a life!
Hey, Dedée! How's life?
I don't get your language.
- Can I come and see you tonight?
- If it makes you happy.
Bon appetit, guys.
- Hello!
- Where are you coming from?
- A walk.
At this hour!
You'd better sleep.
Else you'll ruin your complexion!
Here's your food.
I kept it warm.
No thanks,
I'll just have a bit of that.
If you don't eat, Dedée,
you'll lose weight.
- Where have you been?
- Walking, I told you.
- Where?
- Over there!
Dedée, I'm asking where you were!
At the basin.
- What were you doing there?
- Walking, are you deaf?
A walk at the basin?
You kidding me?
- Germaine, pass me...
- There's a lawn?
Germaine, when I talk to Dedée,
don't butt in.
Oh my, cheap pimps really scare me!
- What did you say?
- I said cheap pimps!
- Will you shut up?
- Enough!
Will you shut up?
I'd like to eat calmly.
You can sort out your stories
in your room.
Now that one's getting angry...
I bet he didn't get his seeds!
At least tell Dedée to be on time
for meals. We're not her slaves.
If she's late, it's my business.
And I don't care. See?
Take your authority somewhere else.
Here.
Were there some boats?
Always the same ones. Those from the
Radoux and the old ones.
No arrivals?
Yes, at the Rojerslass
a small cargo coming in.
A cargo? Did you see its name?
I didn't pay attention.
You waiting for someone?
Maybe. Was there a big white X
on the chimney?
I think so. Maybe.
- Some more, anybody?
- No.
A little more.
Germaine, you'll get fat.
Men love that.
You hear? Men love fat women in Antwerp.
Eat.
Maybe they love planks in your country,
but not here.
I don't understand.
Leave her alone, Marco,
and get some beer.
- Hello...
[Flem] Aren't you gonna eat? Are you sick?
I don't know.
[Flem] Aren't you going to eat?
[Flem] No, I don't want to.
- [Flem] What's wrong?
- Hangover.
Ah, now she's speaking French.
Who has a cigarette for me?
- Here.
- Thanks.
[Flem] [Antwerp dialect]
Bring some up this afternoon,
there's none left.
[Flem] Give me a glass too.
You're right, it will
put you back together.
[Flem] Give me a glass.
[Flem] Germaine, who's making
that noise in your room?
- Oh, the negro!
- What negro?
My negro, I forgot about him. He must
have fallen asleep when I came down.
Germaine, I told you,
no one sleeps here.
A litte while, OK,
but not the night.
The poor fellow was tired.
He's very sweet, eh?
- Shall I go?
- Get him downstairs.
- Nice.
- We'll see about that.
Marco...
Be nice, OK?
Hurry up! Where do you think you are?
- You're in a decent home.
- Where is the lady?
- Lady, lady she's eating!
- Her name is Germaine!
Yes, the beautiful lady is
Germaine. You'll see her tonight.
No more lady, come for lady tonight.
- Tonight? I want to see her just now!
- Not now, tonight.
- Tonight! - I want!
- The beautiful lady tonight!
I said nice, should I repeat it?
- But that guy doesn't want it.
- Guy? My Freddy...
Off you go.
Leave him alone, brute!
He'll go away like a good little boy,
won't you?
Come on, Marco.
They should be kicked out.
- Germaine.
- Yes, it's me.
Go away...
- Come see me tonight.
- We are going today to Hamburg.
Hamburg! What a pity!
We got along so well!
I'm sad that you're going.
They all go to Hamburg. If this
goes on, no more ships will come here.
How will we eat?
Beautiful port, Hamburg...
[German] A pretty port and a big port...
[German] with many pretty ladies.
I cannot accept!
[Flem] I'm going back to bed.
- What did she say?
- Upstairs and sleep.
Good night.
You're right, that's the place.
Dedée, get my cigarettes
in my jacket.
Thank you darling,
you are a wonderful boy.
Have a nice trip, see you soon.
- Germaine...
- So long my darkie.
He's a very nice boy.
But I don't want him
to spend the night here, got it?
- I promise.
- He gave you his watch, let's see.
Don't sit down, we're going upstairs.
- We won't smoke a cigarette?
- We'll smoke it upstairs.
- Alright.
- Hurry up!
He can't wait.
Time to cuddle!
He needs it to digest.
Dedée... I'm waiting!
Yes.
Marco...
Go to Julien's and tell him to come.
I need to talk to him.
- He won't be there now.
- Then look for him! It's urgent.
Alright.
Tell him to get a move on.
- Thank you.
- It was a pleasure.
Come on girls!
Help Paul clear the table.
No need, I can do it alone.
They need to learn
how to be a housewife.
For when we get married!
It stinks.
It stinks? You think so,
at that price?
As if you paid for it!
- That's not a reason.
- [German] Smells like a rose.
You going into town?
I'm having dinner
with the diamond merchant.
- You're lucky.
- That's easy to say.
Your marabou is still pretty nice!
It's not marabou, it's swan.
If you think of it,
bring back some lipstick.
- "Young Girl No. 2"
- Tube or refill?
Refill, I got the tube.
- See you later.
Bon appétit!
You're telling me!
Leaving?
- Yes, it's Monday.
- Oh... right.
- See you.
- See you, don't come back too late.
- Is she yours?
- Yes, I brought her from France.
- French?
- Yes, from Toulon.
- Good. Are you happy with her?
- She's alright.
- But she's hard-headed.
- The only way is to dent her.
That's what I do.
- Dough?
- Hang on til tomorrow.
I'll fix it. I'll see someone.
Alright, but hurry up.
If you don't take it,
it's easy to get rid of.
Tomorrow I'll have it.
OK, see you tomorrow.
2.30 pm at Karel's.
- Bye.
Come in.
Sit down. You took your time.
Did you see Julien?
He wasn't there, I left the message.
Alright.
What do you want?
I'd like to talk to you about a deal.
I'm listening.
At Julien's, I met a friend from France.
Actually Germany...
but the French area.
Complicated story. So?
- He brought back some goods.
- I'm full.
- It's not a woman.
- Ah?
- It's...
- It's?
- Look at that.
He has a lot of it and cheap...
- Did you get the gin?
- Huh?
I said, did you take care of the gin?
- No, not yet.
- I told you yesterday.
You have to do your job, man.
- You hear me?
- Careful with that.
You're right, it fires easily.
Very easily... the catch is sanded.
And it's silent.
Come on! I'm just kidding.
You've done nothing wrong, eh?
Anyway it's not loaded.
Looks like I'm scaring you. I am!
Looks like I'm always scaring you.
Funny, you don't like kidding.
Look, it's light.
Take it.
- It's a great weapon.
- Yes, a great weapon.
- One feels strong holding it, eh?
- Yes.
With it you feel like a man.
Better than fists, right?
And it looks good.
Look in the mirror.
- You almost look like a tough guy.
- Why are you saying this?
Joking... you like to play
the bad guy in front of mirrors.
But you should close the door.
It's ridiculous to see you.
I saw you the other day
with your little gun, striking a pose.
You were so funny, you have no idea.
I forgive you.
It doesn't matter, I know you.
But suppose Dedée saw you.
Dedée... Picture the downfall
of your prestige!
- Don't make fun of me.
- I'm not, I'm speaking as a friend.
But be careful, always
close your door. Always.
Give it back, you've played enough.
Listen to me.
Your little traffic
is not my business.
Outside the club,
do whatever you want.
But if one gram
of your shit gets in here,
I'll kick you out like scum.
And I won't miss you.
I can find plenty of porters like you.
I keep you here
in order to keep Dedée,
but I wouldn't think twice.
If she follows you, too bad.
- Got it?
- Yes, got it.
Well, you're very smart...
I have a beautiful little Dedée
in my car.
What is it?
Nothing, it's a fight.
Are you afraid?
There might be people
who know me.
You don't want to be seen with me?
Me? People talk.
That happens when you're not serious.
He has a guilty conscience,
the little one.
Wait... they're getting closer.
What's that?
- Go away, quick!
- OK, sweetheart!
- Hurry up, go!
- One second!
I don't even have time to get out.
That's clever... Hey!
- I think you forgot something.
- What?
Yes, wait.
It was good, huh?
Great...
Nobody ever did that to me before.
Monday, same time.
Go back to your wife, bastard!
You OK?
You scared?
I like to see men fight.
They never hurt themselves enough.
You don't like them?
No... or I love them too much,
it's the same thing.
Was it you I saw arriving this morning?
- Yes... Why?
- Oh... nothing.
They're beating them up...
Even worse than last time.
I wouldn't have missed it
for a million.
Cops.
You really want to see them?
- Not especially.
- Me neither... let's go.
This way!
- You don't seem to like them.
- Not much.
Where are we going?
- Walk, don't fuss.
- I am!
I don't have time to lose.
- What are you doing?
- What I'm doing.
During the day and evening?
This is no place to walk alone.
I sell candles in the cathedral,
can't you tell?
I was on my way there when we met...
Night service.
And what are you doing
around here?
I was visiting.
- Tourist, huh?
- That's it, tourist...
That's what I thought.
- Say...
- Yes?
Don't you think
that's enough walking?
- Tired?
- No, someone's waiting.
- Who?
- My fiancé.
- What's his name?
- I don't know yet.
- I know.
- Really? So tell me.
It will save me searching.
His name is Francesco.
- Italian?
- Yes, can't you hear it?
Ah, that's it.
I was wondering about your accent.
No kidding, I must go back.
- Why?
- "Perché" someone's waiting, I told you.
- Another fiancé?
- No, the boss, and I'm late,
What club do you work in?
The Big Moon.
Do you know the Big Moon?
A little.
- I'm off. The cops are gone.
- Wait.
- I don't have time.
- I said wait.
Let go, you're hurting me.
And if I pay for the walk?
If I pay for the walk, can you wait?
If it's work, that's different.
Is it enough?
- It's not enough?
- Yes, it's alright.
For that price, can I sit down?
- You hurt me.
- You should have obeyed.
- This is a man's watch?
- You can see that.
What's your name?
Dedée.
- You're Belgian?
- No, I'm not from here.
And do you like it here?
If I didn't, I'd leave.
Sure... in life
we always do what we want.
Don't ask questions.
You got a cigarette?
Look at the clouds, they move fast!
Lie down, you'll see them better.
Lie down near me, there's room.
You don't want to?
OK... as you like.
The sky must be beautiful in Italy.
- Where do you come from?
- From Napoli.
- That's where Vesuvius is?
- Yes, it's there.
Is Vesuvius big?
Is it big?
OK, don't answer if you don't want to.
- Another cigarette?
- No, not right now.
Hey, have you decided?
Decided?
Yeah, are you waiting for the rain?
No, I'm waiting for 2 AM.
You're waiting for what?
I'm waiting for 2 AM.
I have to see someone.
You brought me here to wait for 2 AM?
Yeah, what did you think?
OK, we'll wait.
Give me the cigarette.
By the way, it's time.
You sure you're not early?
We could wait a little longer.
In Naples, do you watch the moon
as brother and sister?
Sometimes.
Here we don't. Too many clouds,
you can't see the moon.
You don't need my company
if it's out of your way.
I know the way.
As you like.
Goodbye, Dedée.
You played a joke on me, huh?
You think so?
I don't know.
Tonight I just wanted
to hear a woman.
It happens, doesn't it?
I don't know.
You didn't lose anything,
for you it's the same.
Yes, it's the same.
Funny, eh?
Usually I have to fight not to...
For once, it's just my luck...
Why did you smile at me when you
entered the basin this morning?
I don't know...
because you were beautiful.
Come on, go now.
- Good night.
- Buona notte.
Dedée?
Can you say something to René for me?
Do you know Mr. René?
Yes, tell him that Francesco,
it's me...
will you remember my name?
Francesco. Yes.
Tell him Francesco can't come tonight,
or tomorrow,
because he goes to Ostend,
but tomorrow night
he'll come to the Big Moon.
Tomorrow night at the Big Moon... OK.
You won't forget?
I don't think I will.
- Goodbye, Dedée...
- Goodbye.
You're just coming back?
We've been waiting for hours.
Don't tell me the old guy
kept you so long!
- No, I won't say that.
- Where are you coming from?
- Always the same song.
- Is this a song?
Tame her, Marco. That's it.
Go now, you've hung out enough.
Wait a minute.
You've got nothing for me?
But there's more than usual...
That's for the delay.
Sentimental walk.
- You deserve a kiss.
- No hurry.
Come here Dedée, come.
You're late.
Did you have trouble with the fight?
No, I was kept back.
- What's that?
- Nothing, I bumped into something.
Into Marco's hand?
Dedée, come here?
- Someone's calling you.
- Right away!
I have a message for you,
from a guy named Francesco.
Did you see Francesco? Where?
We met during the fight.
- What do you want?
- To dance with this girl.
- Come on baby.
- She is coming in a minute.
Go and get yourself a drink.
Don't forget, baby, don't forget.
So?
He can't come tonight or tomorrow
because he'll be in Ostend,
but he'll come tomorrow night.
It's funny, I saw his boat
arriving this morning.
Remember I told you?
I don't remember.
Hey girl! I'm alone.
Yes, yes, wait a minute.
I'm coming.
René, who is Francesco?
A sailor. An old friend of mine.
He's Italian.
Yes, I know...
Well, you know enough.
Come on, make the sailor dance.
Did you met him in the Congo?
Yes, the Congo and other places.
Go, or he'll fall asleep.
Hello... sleepy?
No, I'm not sleepy.
Come on, let's dance!
Julien, that was Francesco's boat
she saw entering.
- Some news?
- She just saw him.
He'll be here tomorrow. We
have to gather things quick.
For where?
Spain, Palestine, South America... You
never know with him... He'll tell us.
You're here! I was afraid
the cops picked you up.
- Hello!
You look happy!
Yes, that happens!
- Mr. René?
- Yes.
Give me a glass of water, please.
Here, girl.
Will they go away soon,
so we can turn in?
Here, they're paying.
- Good night. Good night, chief.
- Goodbye, gentlemen.
One more behind us.
I'll have some fresh air.
Me too.
Good night, gentlemen.
- Can we close?
- Go ahead, turn off the sign.
It's good!
Some air.
The weather will be fine.
The wind is from the river.
What's up with you, you're strange?
No, nothing.
Hey, the dockers.
- It must be about 7 AM.
- Come on girls, we're closing.
- Aren't you coming to bed?
- Yes, soon.
- Haven't you got enough air?
- I have a headache.
You always hurt somewhere.
Shut the window and come to bed,
I'm tired.
I'm not stopping you from sleeping.
Close the window and come here!
I need to talk to you.
So, we're no longer in love?
We're home now.
Come on, kiss me.
Better than that.
Tell me if I disgust you.
Don't be stupid,
I've told you I have a headache.
Enough for now.
Talk to Mr. René. I need money.
He refused, the bastard.
It won't be different with me.
You tell him
it's for you, an advance.
It's true, an advance,
you'll give it back.
I still owe him for the other time.
He'll be happy
to give it to you.
For his little Dedée,
what wouldn't he do?
He likes his little Dedée.
Ask him nicely.
That won't be too difficult,
you like him too.
- It's not true.
- Do you think I'm a sucker?
Not my business, he's
the boss, don't upset him.
Don't say that!
Don't shout, you'll wake everyone.
What's wrong with you,
are you getting crazy?
Don't say that, it disgusts me.
I won't say it again.
So you'll ask him.
- No, I can't.
- You will!
He won't accept.
No, Marco, don't do that!
- Will you ask him?
- You'll leave marks again.
- Yes... I'll ask him.
- Will you obey?
Yes.
At last!
You'll ask him for 100,000.
And I'll give you half
when my deal is done.
For the rest of it, you'll manage.
It's too much, Marco. I can't.
You just have to work.
It's nice to make customers drink,
but it's not enough.
You have to do like the others.
Look at Germaine, she never stops.
Enough. Enough about business.
You're a good girl.
You're a bit hard-headed,
but you're a good girl.
OK, you'll sort things out.
It's for your own good
that I'm tough.
What would you do without me?
Dedée, what would you do
without your Marco?
Come on, kiss me!
Dédée, did you talk to Mr. René?
- Yes and he doesn't want it.
- Why?
He knew it wasn't for me,
and said he couldn't lend so much.
- When did you see him?
- Right now, after dinner.
- In his office?
- Yes, in his office.
You bitch, he wasn't there
after dinner. He just returned.
- Don't let him!
- Shut up!
You didn't ask him anything?
Answer me!
No, I didn't, and I won't.
Here you go again.
- You know the price.
- Leave her alone.
If someone came in,
how would it look!
- You'll do it tonight, you hear?
- Sir!
If you don't,
you'll see what I can do.
- Sir!
- What's going on?
Shall I ask him now?
You again? I already told you
I don't want any fuss in here.
Leave her alone, understand?
- What is it?
- Nothing.
We had words, eh, Dedée?
You're supposed
to be at the door now.
- Did you forget it?
- I was on my way.
What did he want?
Always the same stories.
When he gets nervous, tell me.
I know how to calm him.
I'm sick of it.
My dear, when you have a man,
beautiful or ugly,
you always catch hell.
Do like me, work for yourself.
It's too late now.
Felice also had a man.
She sorted it out, he's caged
for 20 years, now she's at peace.
Here you are at last.
In the house, you're the only one
not to have customers.
It's not like you have to be here.
A single woman can live.
What are you looking at?
Ah, but I know that one.
Before the war he used to come here.
If I were you, I'd kick
Marco out straight away.
I'm more experienced,
I'm talking to you like a mother.
Fred, take care of the bar.
Yes, sir.
- I think you've already met?
- Yes.
I'll see you later.
You keep secrets from me.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Off to work!
Get down here, people are coming.
Authorization, registration,
all in order, all true.
You start sailing under protection?
In the Mediterranean,
they are all patrolling.
We are no longer in '36, it's over.
Now it's cruising.
How much did you pay
for your small images?
A pittance.
Since the war, we don't buy people.
It's charity now.
They're all for sale,
you just buy the cheapest.
Nothing unnecessary.
- You're almost official.
- Almost.
Coal. We sell coal.
The only risk is a raid
at loading or delivery.
It felt strange to get your letter.
I thought you were dead.
Several times, it was close.
What about the club?
Alright, thanks to Dedée.
But if a man came along, a real one,
who'd take her away,
though I like her
and she makes a lot of money,
if she came and told me:
"Mr. René, I met someone," but a good
man, not a little louse like Marco,
I'd be the first
to tell her to leave.
And if she hesitated, I'd kick
her out to make her go faster.
Why are you telling me all this?
Nothing...
René, you're doing funny jobs
in your old age.
Don't waste your time. Dedée won't
tie me up, even if you interfere.
I'm turning senile with that girl.
Won't you see her?
I said I'd go. I can't do otherwise.
Sure. Always be polite to ladies.
You spent a long time with Mr. René.
We hadn't seen each other
in six years. We had a lot to say.
I gave him your message last night.
I know, he told me.
Nice of you to think of it.
There are some things we remember.
You hold me the wrong way.
Yes, like that.
- Not better?
- Yes, much better.
You dance well.
No sweet-talk.
You smell good.
You smell of tobacco.
Already?
Wait, it'll start again.
- You don't talk more than this?
- Sometimes.
It's a bit crowded here,
don't you think?
Are you suggesting another walk?
No.
- Shall we go?
- Yes.
- No, somewhere else.
- I prefer that.
Let's go.
He won't say anything.
Where are you going? Oh, sorry!
Good evening, sir!
- Is it far?
- It's on the dock.
Let's walk faster.
- What's wrong?
- I don't like to come here.
- Is it because of them?
- Yes, it scares me for the future.
Come.
It's here.
Are you sleeping?
I didn't think
that I could feel so good.
Is it daytime?
I think so.
Don't move.
[Ital] I'm falling, Dedée.
[Ital] I'm falling like a little boy.
[Ital] I am like you.
[Ital] I didn't think it could happen.
It's nice.
What did you just say?
It's not your concern. It's for me.
Speak again.
What do you want me to say?
I don't know...
Things.
[Ital] It's dangerous to say things.
[Ital] Especially what I want to say.
[Ital] And what I want to say
is what you want to hear.
[Ital] I won't tell it to you,
but I'll think it.
[Ital] That's what scares me,
[Ital] that you know
what I'm thinking.
[Ital] Do you understand?
[French] Understood?
No. It should be true.
The other night, in the harbour,
I really wanted it to be like that.
I would have liked that also,
but not there, not in that way.
Do you have regrets?
No.
You're sweet.
[Ital] You are too sweet.
Francesco.
Huh?
Nothing, I'm saying your name.
Francesco. I love your name.
I'd like everything to stop,
so we could stay like this forever.
There would be no more outside.
Nothing but us.
I didn't imagine it could be possible.
What are you thinking of?
Do you want to know?
Yes.
Then you'll be happy.
I don't know what will happen
tomorrow, or a moment from now,
but this night I think that l...
I can't say those words.
It doesn't matter.
I understood.
Cold?
- A little, yes.
- The wind is shifting.
It smells of you.
I saw you arriving there.
What were you doing here at that hour?
I was watching the old harbour.
That's what they asked me
when I came back.
Because I always have to go back.
I almost forgot.
What if you stayed with me today?
It's not possible.
Stay. I'll fix it with René.
It's not Mr. René.
- It's someone else.
- Ah, yes.
You know?
René told me about him.
I'll fix it with him another way.
No.
Do you love him?
Don't use that word to describe it.
No, you don't know what it is,
he scares me.
He scares me, do you understand?
That's why I have to go back.
Stay, I told you I'll sort it out.
He doesn't scare me.
Yes, but in a few days
you'll be gone.
I'll still be there
and it will go on.
That's not for me.
Come tonight, if you want.
Look at me.
Was it true earlier in the room?
- Are you asking me?
- It was also true for me.
So you think I can leave you
with that bastard?
And now I'm here, you hear?
I must go back this morning.
If you think that's better.
Tonight I'll come and we'll see.
Will he ask where you were?
He saw us leaving.
At night he is the gatekeeper.
What a life to have a job here.
Here, that will keep him silent.
Thank you.
Was that the reason
on the first night?
Don't cry... It will stop.
Take your jacket.
I'll keep it.
- See you tonight?
- Tonight.
Francesco!
Kiss me.
- Ha, what is it?
- Dedée.
I was afraid you wouldn't be alone.
- Can I sleep here?
- No.
Some trouble with Marco?
I'll tell you. Sleep.
Has anyone seen Dedée?
Look at the sweetheart, he's all lost.
Dedée is in my room, she's sleeping.
What's on her mind?
She didn't want to bother you,
she's thoughtful.
We'll see, I don't like those ways.
It's 2 PM, she should be up.
When you sleep,
you stay away from trouble.
Leave her alone, she came back late,
she has to rest.
Did you hear me?
Going out? Lunch's almost ready.
I have an appointment.
Good news, then I feel hungry.
Hi! Is Mr. Charles here?
Yes, Mr. Marco. He is over there
with these gentlemen.
- Hello.
- Wait, let me finish up here.
- Is Mrs. Dedée alright?
- When she isn't, she cries.
What else?
- What can I get you?
- Give me a Spa.
- You drinking anything?
- No need.
So, are you set?
Not completely,
but I have some of it.
You think I'll wait for weeks?
No way, I won't lose money.
Until tomorrow, you...
Tomorrow then another tomorrow.
Then I go back to Paris.
You have no money, fine, others do...
Robert!
Wait, someone promised
I'll have the rest tomorrow.
- What do you want?
- Nothing.
I'll see you later.
- Where will you find it?
- My luck.
- Here, I'll give you a deposit.
- What for, to buy sweets?
Leave it here, thank you. Thank you!
I know it's not much, but...
Tomorrow I'll have the rest.
The guy I wanted to ask is away.
My girl will find a way.
You can't do that to me.
I always took everything from you.
Wait until tomorrow and then
it's set, you have my word.
I pay cash.
Don't talk about it to others.
My girl will get the money.
Yesterday she got a client who's loaded.
Say you'll wait, I'm a pal.
And the goods get stolen, tough?
- You risk nothing because tomorrow...
- Tomorrow...!
You're a carpet dealer,
you make me puke.
- Don't start sobbing.
- So you'll wait till tomorrow?
Deadline. I'm staying til tomorrow.
I have some business to do.
- Just call.
- Count on me, I'll get it.
You should change trades, buddy,
you don't have enough blow.
Hey you, hurry up,
you're not here for fun.
What, you got something to say?
OK, just do your job.
[Germ] How about a punch on the nose!
Hey shorty, is this the first time
you visit the princesses?
Whoa, stop, hold up!
Nice of you to come and see me now.
I was nearby.
- Can I talk to you frankly?
- Yes, what is it?
Don't perfume yourself like that for
me. It's not worth it and a bit weird.
- What's the word?
- It's good you came, Julien called.
- The delivery will be tomorrow.
- What time?
We'll talk. First go in,
then you do what you want.
- Is he her pimp?
- Yes, he's far from brilliant.
Hey girls, isn't it over?
- What has fallen down?
- Her mirror.
Funny way to welcome the visitors.
Your residents are dangerous.
- Let me go. - My feet!
- Let me go!
It's seven years of bad luck,
we don't need that.
Dedée.
Dedée. Wake up.
Quick, wake up.
Christ, that's serious business.
Wake up, he's downstairs,
he just came in with Mr. René.
Help yourself to my powder.
No, the other one,
that one is too bright.
Put your hair up like the last time
you went to the hairdresser's.
You know, with the curls in front.
And put on your marabou.
You're not saying anything.
Are you angry because I woke you up?
I had to do it.
Don't blame me, dear,
I don't feel like talking.
I'm in the fog.
I'm so happy.
I feel like it was always this way.
You don't know how good it is.
Ah, you finally got up!
- Couldn't you knock, it's my room.
- Forget it, leave us alone.
The customer from last night
is downstairs to see you.
Good job. You can do it
when you want to. It's not so hard.
Yesterday was good,
but it's not enough.
I told you how much I need,
otherwise my deal is gone.
If he comes in the afternoon, he's
yours, he'll give what you want.
But even that won't be enough. Listen.
You remember in Toulon?
You had no trouble then,
do it again now.
For me, you'll do it again,
for your Marco.
You'll be safe, I heard
he's leaving tomorrow.
So do it on the quiet.
You'll probably stay with him,
so tomorrow morning,
just before leaving...
Got it? Come on, you'll do it?
Dedée! Dedée!
I was so angry with myself
for letting you come back here.
I imagined you here.
That's why you came to get me?
A little.
And also to have you near me.
You had to come here.
You had to be here.
For me to have your hand like that.
Oh, stupid words.
I hadn't noticed
that your eyes were so blue.
I haven't had a good look at you yet...
let me look.
Don't look too much,
I'm not handsome.
It's funny, your hair is almost fair.
- Were you fair when you were a kid?
- Yes.
- Did you live in Naples?
- In Genoa.
I went to Naples later.
I would have liked to see you as a kid.
You're all white compared to me.
Stay with me.
I knew you were leaving tomorrow,
I wasn't afraid.
It couldn't end so quickly.
We set sail tomorrow at 3 am,
but you shouldn't be there tonight.
It can be dangerous. You'll
come only at departure time.
I'll call you at the Big Moon
as soon as it's finished.
Once we're gone,
there's no more risk.
- Where are we going?
- To many countries.
I'm offering you
a strange life, Dedée...
But after this trip,
you mustn't stay on the ship.
Women shouldn't be on a boat,
especially in this business.
You'll stay where you feel good,
and I'll know you're there.
Don't think that far ahead.
We leave tomorrow, then we'll see.
Come in.
Ah, it's you!
Come close, don't stay there.
Nothing broken, right?
No, it's fine.
Then don't make that face.
You have something to ask me,
don't you?
- Something serious?
- Yes.
And you can't let it out?
Is it so hard to say?
A little.
Then, I'll help you, Dedée.
It's about...
I feel there's a trip brewing...
He's finally made up his mind,
the gentleman.
He was stronger than everyone,
no one could have him.
So much for René... in the end,
he's like everyone, your pirate.
So, what are you doing here?
Why didn't you stay with him?
I hope you didn't come
to get my blessing?
He doesn't want me on board
before departure.
Because?
Ah yes, of course. He's right.
He'll call here after loading.
- You don't mind if I go?
- You're of age.
It has nothing to do with my will...
I knew you wouldn't spend
your whole life here.
That wouldn't be fair.
- Will you find someone else?
- I'll have to.
- We'll miss you.
- Me too, you...
Goodbye, eh? You want me
to teach you how to lie?
Now get out of here,
I have things to do.
Tonight I'll drive you there.
Mr. René, is it really dangerous?
What are you talking about?
No, it's just not for women.
Don't worry about that,
go to your room and rest.
I'll pick you up at 2 AM.
Home delivery.
Tonight I'd like to be downstairs.
For the last time.
As you wish.
And Marco, is he upstairs?
Right, I forgot about that one.
Yes, he should be upstairs.
Wait, I'll go there.
- I'd rather tell him myself.
- No, stay here.
I've been waiting for it
for a long time.
Get up.
- Is Dedée back?
- Yes, Dedée's back.
- Where are you going?
- I have to see her, is she in her room?
No, she's in my office. No hurry,
you have something to do first.
- Is this your suitcase?
- Yes.
- Then pack up.
- Pack up?
- And fast... you have 5 minutes.
- Tell me what's wrong?
We've seen enough of you
in this house.
If Dedée failed you, I'll beat her.
You can't fire us like that!
She makes people come.
Better not to talk, Marco.
Pack up... that's my advice.
The cops?
If she swiped his purse,
it's not my fault, I swear.
Yesterday she said she'd sting him.
I forbade her, it's not my fault.
I'll tell them I'm not guilty.
If Dedée is jailed...
What will I do?
You can't do that to me...
What will I live on?
- Two minutes left.
- You were always defending her.
It's your fault, you see what she is.
She isn't worth it.
Not very clean.
It had to end like that.
I'll get you another one.
Don't fire me like that!
One minute left, Marco.
You won't give me to the cops, right?
What will I do? What will I do?
A porter... keep me as a porter
until I get a woman.
Don't touch me! No, don't touch me...
My stuff! Let me get my stuff!
We'll send your stuff, get out!
- Get the hell out of here.
- You can't keep them. Dedée!
Don't bother to call her.
No cops, no wallet.
- She's fed up and leaving.
- She hasn't been arrested?
No, she's found a real man.
Know what that means?
- That Italian?
- Yes. My advice: Stay away.
- She's my wife. She's mine.
- I've had enough of you. Go!
Dedée! Dedée!
You can't stop me from saying goodbye!
- Here.
- I like Dedée!
- Here's the door!
- I must see her!
You're lucky I'm patient!
I've seen enough of you!
A page has been turned, Dedée.
I wish it was already tonight.
- Aren't you taking your perfume?
- No.
It's yours, if you want it.
It's not for my type,
but I'll still take it.
What time is it?
9:30 PM, I have to go downstairs.
It's taking so long!
Patience. You have
your whole life ahead of you.
Germaine!
No way to be alone for a minute!
Yes!
Germaine!
Coming!
I'll say goodbye to you now,
my Germaine,
because later on I'll leave quietly.
Say goodbye to them all for me.
I don't want to see them,
I'm too sorry to leave you here.
I've been so lucky.
Don't cry, my Germaine.
You'll see, your day will come.
Why? They are all so nice.
No, when I've saved enough, I'll retire.
- You'll write me?
- I promise, I'll write to you.
And if it's a nice place,
I'll join you there.
We'll be close one another.
A gin.
[indistinct]
Leave me the bottle...
[Ital] Hurry up, guys!
There's still one to unload!
Don't let yourself become downhearted.
You should have left,
I told you last time.
You shouldn't stay here.
They are hunting you,
you'll end up being caught.
Where are your two friends?
Your two pals?
Military Police.
If you stay here, it'll be the same.
Bought...
Identity papers...
Good papers, bought...
Put it away. So you're ready.
- What did you say?
- You're in order, you're OK.
I want to go home.
- I know.
- I want to go home.
You'll go back to your country.
Believe me.
You think everything is blocked,
nothing left to do, then...
one day it happens.
Come on, no more. Don't drink!
You'll go home, I'm telling you.
You'll see again America.
It happens, I can assure you,
it happens.
For me too, it was over.
Washed up.
Now I'm leaving.
It's never lost. Never.
I want to go home.
If only I could speak English well.
You don't even understand
what I'm telling you.
Wait a minute.
- Is it him?
- Not yet, soon, don't be afraid.
Who's he?
A deserter.
He comes here sometimes.
He's drunk and blue.
- Are you cheering him up?
- I've often wanted to.
Tonight it's not work
any more so I do it.
- Do you think it's OK there?
- Why not?
A little late, that's normal.
Just wait. Go comfort your guy.
- Any more?
- The last two.
[Ital] Close up and be ready
to leave at 4.
[Ital] Go have a drink at the square.
- [Ital] You coming, captain?
- I have things to do, maybe later.
Have a safe journey, guys!
You can't leave, can you?
- I had one last look.
- Come on.
- Mr. René...
- Yes?
- Do you think I'll forget?
- What? The Big Moon? I hope not.
No, Marco and the others.
It's as if I came to him with a disease.
Don't think about that.
It's no time for literature. Come on.
- Mr. René!
- What now?
Here's the little one
I told you about.
- You want to work?
- I'd like to.
- How old are you?
- 21.
I'm not asking you.
How old are you?
- 21.
- That's what they always say.
Old enough, I guarantee.
I don't have time tonight.
Come tomorrow afternoon.
Alright, Mr. René.
She's your replacement.
He brought me in the morning.
I'm not a man, eh?
I'm not a man?
[Ital] Captain! Captain!
Police!
[Ital] What happened?
[Ital] Is that our captain?
Yes. Police?
No, everything was fine.
He left the ship...
We heard shooting.
[Ital] Is he dead?
Yes.
- I'm closing, Mr. Marco.
- Where's Mr. Charles?
He left this evening.
I think he was waiting for you.
Left?
He shouldn't have left until tomorrow.
Take him to the boat.
[Ital] Take his feet.
- Marco's?
- Yes.
- Where are you going?
- Looking for him.
He was here early evening,
half drunk, you know other places?
- Karel's.
- Let's go.
He was here 15 min ago, asking for
Rotterdam train times.
You won't make it, Mr. René.
We have one hour
before the first train.
What?
Come.
- No.
- Come.
If you move too fast,
I'll drop you.
Get out... get out.
- Come on.
- No... no.
No, you have no right.
It's not possible. Dedée!
I didn't want to kill him. I swear.
- Get up.
- No!
No, I beg you.
No, I don't want to...!
I don't want to...
- Wait.
- Yes!
- Yes, Dedée, stop him.
- Not like that.
- It's too sweet.
- You'll be arrested.
You can't kill me...
The car...
It'll look like an accident.
Dedée, I don't want to die...
I don't want to...
I didn't want to leave,
it was for that.
Make him shut up.
No, I don't want to...! Dedée!
You knocked him too hard.
Too bad, he won't know.
On the road.
The gun's gone.
Go.
Slowly...