A SHOCHIKU production
WOMEN OF THE NIGHT
Script: Y. YODA
Photography: K. SUGIYAMA
With: Kinuyo TANAKA...
Sanae TAKASUGI
Tomie TSUNODA...
Mitsuo NAGATA
Directed by Kenji MIZOGUCHI
THE POLICE WILL ARREST WOMEN
WHO ARE OUT AT NIGHT.
It's so cold.
No news from your husband?
Your parents and your sister
are in Korea?
They must be back by now.
They don't know my new address.
It's a shame.
There's nobody to protect you.
And my son suffers from tuberculosis.
I'm in a big mess.
I want to sell all this.
Summer clothes.
It's not worth much.
I'll take them for 600 yen.
A little more, please.
It's already too much,
summer clothes are hard to sell.
Business isn't getting any better.
Taxes are increasing.
I'll soon have to hang myself
with those old clothes.
Give me another 50 yen.
No way!
Help me.
Just to buy eggs
for the little one.
Try somewhere else.
You won't get more.
Here, 600 yen.
I have a proposition
if you want to make some money.
What proposition?
A well paid job.
I'd do anything.
There are people
with a lot of money.
I could introduce you to them.
Will I earn some money?
It depends on you.
You can bewitch them.
Don't make fun of me.
It's not much.
Many women do it.
Don't propose this kind of things
to everybody...
How much did she give you?
600 yen.
It's not much.
You're mad at me.
I'd help you if I could.
But I don't earn enough money.
That's enough. I'll manage on my
own for the little one.
I bought you some apples.
I'll grate them.
I have eggs too.
It's your son,
you must take care of him.
You're blaming me
for drinking too much.
The house was burned when
I came back from war.
I'm moonlighting,
I can get caught.
Despite that...
I still bring 6000 yen a month.
It's great.
Tuberculosis isn't so bad.
No need for so many injections.
The doctor pushes you to spend money.
It's not true.
They all do that.
We had an X-ray taken.
If anything happens to the baby
my husband will never forgive me.
Any news from my brother?
Is he still alive?
May he come back soon!
Your brother-in-law does his best.
Forgive him.
I know.
If the baby was fine
I could work somewhere.
Let's stop talking about it.
Did you listen to the radio?
We don't have one.
They talked about your husband.
My husband?
I was listening to the radio earlier.
I heard:
"Kensaku Owada's family
"must contact Mr. Hirata
about their son. "
Thank you for telling us.
Let's go see him now.
Kumiko, can you look after the baby?
I hope he'll be well.
He was so sick at the hospital.
He regretted dying after
so many efforts to survive.
This way.
I' really sorry to tell you
these sad news.
Excuse us.
- What's going on?
- It's the parents.
Good.
It's my boss.
We're sorry to bother you.
It must be disheartening.
Sorry.
We're...
deeply affected by this misfortune.
You can come and see me if
you have any problem.
Take heart!
Thank you.
My brother is dead.
Our last hope is gone.
Don't think about it, mom.
We have to take care of the funeral.
Mom, he's suffocating. Look.
What's going on?
I'll get the doctor.
Please.
Hurry!
It's time.
I'm leaving.
Fusako!
Here, Natsuko!
Sister!
Finally!
I've been looking for you everywhere.
You're very stylish.
I'm glad.
It's Kumiko from Owada.
You're a big girl!
Do you remember, Kumiko?
She's my sister who was in Korea.
You changed a lot.
I didn't recognize you.
When did you come back?
In september 45.
Your house had burned.
Nobody could tell me
where you were.
How are our parents doing?
Are they fine?
They're dead.
Dead?
Mother died in Korea.
Father came back with me.
Malnutrition.
It has been very hard. Painful.
I lost my husband and my child.
Your husband too!
What are you doing now?
I'm a dancer.
It's great.
And you?
I didn't want to cause my
husband's family anymore troubles.
So I left them and I'm working
in a company.
She's an executive secretary.
I'd like to leave the factory
to work somewhere else.
Where do you live?
In a flat near Tengejaya.
Can I live with you?
I'm living with friends.
We're four in one room.
We never thought we would
meet like that.
It's true.
But you, you're still luckier.
Why?
You had a happy youth.
You were married.
We, the youth,
won't be able to be happy anymore.
It's necessarily true.
Your clothes are very nice.
Where do they come from?
I had them made here.
It must be expensive.
Very.
I haven't finished
paying for them yet.
What if I became a dancer?
Don't be ridiculous.
Welcome.
A visit?
Come in.
He's our boss.
She's my sister I was looking for.
We met by chance.
Like in a dream.
I'm happy for you.
Your sister talked to me about you.
I was worried.
Thank you.
It must have been hard.
If only I could dance...
My clothes aren't so nice.
It's time to go back.
I want to stay.
Your mother won't be happy
if you come back late.
It's wonderful.
Hello.
Don't use my cosmetics.
Skinflint!
Skinflint yourself!
Why don't you buy some?
I need of this to work.
I don't earn a lot of money.
You?
An executive secretary?
Do you have another
contract with him?
Don't be ridiculous.
You should take advantage of it.
It's not my boss' type.
The boat arrives tonight.
We must prepare 3 million.
I'm counting on you.
We'll get caught.
You're my secretary.
Sir!
Do you want me to buy you something?
Do you really care about me?
Of course.
Is it true?
What question!
I'm worried.
It's useless.
I'm treating you well.
What else do you want?
I'll be even nicer.
Miss!
Where is the director?
I don't know.
- It worries me.
- Why?
I just got a phone call.
The police is coming.
- What?
- A search!
Damn!
We must not keep that here.
I have to stay here.
What do you want to do?
Can I help you?
Can you hide it somewhere?
I'll take it home.
Thansk a lot.
It's heavy.
I'll manage.
Miss,
Your coat is trailing on the ground.
Did Natsuko go out?
No, she should be here.
Open! Quick!
You? At this hour?
What's going on?
There's a police search.
I took it to hide it.
Put it somewhere.
Take care of it.
What were you doing, Natsuko?
Nothing special.
Don't lie.
Watch what you're doing.
I must take care of you
without her parents.
You know it very well.
Some men took advantage
of me on the boat.
I often considered killing myself.
It's the hope of living happily
here that stopped me.
It would have been better
if I had been sold.
I could be his mistress.
The director talked to you?
Yes. I'm not a kid anymore,
I can do whatever I want.
Think carefully.
Leave me alone.
Hello.
I was wondering how you were doing.
Did your husband come back?
Unfortunately, no.
I'm sorry.
I'm free to do whatever I want.
It's about what you proposed me.
Are you ready?
She's still not back yet?
I'll check at Owada's.
Maybe she's still there.
Where is she hiding?
You never had sex with my sister?
No, never.
So why did she run away?
I don't know.
Maybe it's her.
Hello.
I wanted to check your place.
Is my sister here?
No.
Didn't she come?
What's happening to her?
She doesn't come back home lately.
How do you do?
Make yourself comfortable.
Good bye.
What's going on, Kumiko?
I ran away from home.
I quarelled with my brother.
I can manage on my own.
You shouldn't have done that.
I stole some money at home.
I'd like to stay here.
It troubles me.
What will I say to your family?
Fine,
I'll find another way.
Where are you going, Kumiko?
Leave me alone!
A hostel?
I know a very good hostel.
I'm from Osaka.
I didn't know that.
You're leaving?
I have tickets.
I still don't know where to go.
Are you a real student?
Yes...
I must earn money to
pay for my studies.
It must be hard.
You're from Osaka...
You don't know where to go...
Did you run away from home?
More or less.
It's not good.
Tell me everything.
I'm worried.
Forget my job.
Let's have a drink.
I know this place.
Ask anything you want.
All right.
But I don't have money.
I'll pay.
You're inviting me?
Two meals of the day!
Good booty?
- Promising?
- Not much.
She ran away. She has some cash.
I'll test her later.
It's not quiet here.
Come over here.
Just a slut to him.
That's all she is.
Sit down.
It's quiet here.
Something to drink...
I'll taste it.
Do you want some?
The meals are ready.
How much?
200 yens.
- We took a beer too.
- Thank you.
I'll keep that for you.
A young stranger and
a lady on the run...
meet near the station.
That's romantic.
It's true.
Take.
Drink. I'll help you.
Don't worry.
One more.
I can't.
I feel dizzy.
Hey!
Kiyoshi!
It's over. Get lost!
Wait! Kiyoshi!
He won't come back.
It's our turn.
Take everything off.
Who are you?
Robbers, isn't it obvious?
Hurry up or we'll hurt you.
Take everything off.
Give her the clogs.
Take that.
Remind yourself that
it's an accident.
I can't go back like that.
Give me my clothes back!
Don't be too demanding.
Stay with us if you want.
You'll have enough to eat.
You'll see Kiyoshi.
Are you coming? Hurry up.
Miss Natsuko.
I was wondering if
I should warn you.
- About what?
- Well...
Go on! Talk!
I saw your sister.
- Where?
- In Abeno.
In this disreputable district.
How is your business doing?
Safe return!
Don't look at us like that.
Cops!
You're wrong! Let go of me!
Where do you work?
At the Hollywood.
The Hollywood night-club?
Do you have a boss?
No, I'm looking for my sister.
- A colleague?
- No, my real sister.
Really?
Anyway, you were walking
in the district.
Such a sudden police raid!
I saw the security patrol go by.
I asked for a light.
They said that I'd find some at the
police station and I got picked up.
You're inattentive.
We don't see you often.
You must salute us.
If you don't...
You won't find customers outside.
I'm not like you.
You're hurting me.
My name is Natsuko.
I'm sorry.
You should have said it sooner.
Your bed is here.
Fusako!
Why are you here?
It's a mistake.
As soon as I learned what
you were doing,
I went looking for you.
Why did you do that?
If it was for money
I could have helped you.
You should have talked to me.
You're my only sister.
Shut up.
You know very well why.
How dare you talk to me like that
after making love with my lover?
I hate you,
but I hate this man even more.
I'll get revenge by
contaminating all men.
Is it true that you've been
brought here by mistake?
Nothing I can do. You can't leave
until you've taken the test.
You probably didn't sleep
during the whole night.
Rest a little.
So, what did they say?
You're fine, aren't you?
Doctor!
A white flower
can bloom inside a coal mine.
If those girls had a pure spirit
they wouldn't deteriorate like that.
We blame society for
anything wrong,
but the problem is within
each individual.
We must put an end to this trade
to stop this spirit from spreading.
Our association will carry
on with its goal everywhere.
Sorry, Madam.
Doctor, it's about
Natsuko Kimishima.
I'm listening.
She's my sister.
She told me.
Good.
Is she sick?
She has syphilis.
Also, she's pregnant.
Pregnant?
Take good care of her.
I understand your principle.
But we can't solve everything
with principles.
Like this girl's case.
Yes, she's Kuriyama's child.
I didn't realize.
My periods aren't regular,
I thought my sickness
was due to alcohol.
My situation doesn't allow
me to have a baby.
But I've changed since I'm pregnant.
The doctor said that
I could be cured.
I'm carrying a child.
Stupid! Why do you want to have
a child from such a scumbag?
The child is innocent.
I could leave if someone
would vouch for me.
I'll call Kuriyama.
Let's leave together.
He'll vouch for you too.
Go back alone if you want.
- Fusako!
- Are you here?
- Are you all right?
- As usual.
Cigarettes?
No, give them to the others.
- Do you want to shoot up?
- No.
Tell me what you want.
Thank you.
I don't need anything.
How is it going?
Not good at all.
I'll starve if it
doesn't get better.
Do you have children?
I lost them during the war.
My dear... You too!
Why are you talking like that?
You have black thoughts.
Not at all. Idiot!
Don't worry.
Take care. I'll be back.
Thank you.
Kimi Yamada.
Fusako Owada.
She's not here.
She's lucky!
Are you coming?
At this hour?
You don't have the money!
Poor bum!
The cops got up my nose.
Say something.
Ask for my forgiveness at least!
I'm not talking to you anymore.
Why?
I saw my sister.
I know everything.
Aren't you ashamed?
You're kidding!
I took care of her.
I did her a favor.
She should thank me instead.
I took care of two sisters.
You'll never find such a good man.
It's all your fault!
I was ready to support her.
She would have become a whore
without me anyway.
We're not animals.
I can't stand you anymore.
Then go away. It's not like
there's a shortage of girls.
I won't leave.
Why?
I must get better.
And...
What?
Speak.
I'm going to have a baby.
You're pregnant?
Are you happy?
Have an abortion!
Are you serious?
Of course.
It's better to do it fast.
- No.
- Do it.
No way!
Mr. Kuriyama,
we have the proof
that you're involved
in opium trafficking.
It's not true.
- Here's the warrant.
- There's no proof.
The smartest one
is sometimes wrong.
You'll take at least two years.
Come.
I'm with you.
Is it your wife?
She doesn't know anything.
You'll have to testify.
HOUSE OF LIGHT:
OPEN TO ALL WRETCHED WOMEN
Don't let those words tempt you.
What do you know about it?
I have a friend
who ran away from the house.
She lived there,
the owner was nice.
She was properly fed.
It's great.
But her job was supervised...
Do you want to go?
I was just looking.
It's worth it when we're very sick.
It's free.
You can leave if you've had enough.
You don't look so good.
I heard that you don't stop.
Don't destroy your health.
Mind your own business.
I'm ready to die.
Oh, it's you.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
Is Natsuko here?
Yes, but...
What's wrong?
Mr. Kuriyama has been arrested.
She's broke. She can't work
in her current condition.
So what?
She's desperate. She spends most
of her time drinking with men.
Fusako, Do you feel well?
I learned everything.
I can't bear it any longer.
Teach me your job.
Don't be ridiculous.
Do you want to drink?
Prepare your stuff.
You'll have your child.
- Where are you taking me?
- To a house for women.
I don't like it.
Come with me. Get up!
No, I don't want.
When will I be able to get married?
Get up.
The director is coming.
Hello.
How is the work going?
Everything is fine?
Yes, thank you.
I brought you this present.
Thank you, it's nice.
What is it?
Potatoes.
You like potatoes.
It's very good.
Do you feel good? Isn't it better
than in the hospital?
It's boring here.
Don't say that.
A respectable life seems
boring at first.
But it becomes interesting
once you get into it.
You! How do you do?
Much better...
Thanks to you!
Continue with the consultations.
- Give me a cigarette.
- All right.
Take heart!
You must never let yourself go.
Oh, you're here?
Hello, Mr the Director.
You caused us a lot of troubles.
Forgive me.
- Since when are you here?
- I just arrived.
- I'm happy for you.
- I'm bringing my sister.
- I want her to have her baby here.
- Good idea.
she had some labour pains.
Will she give birth?
Please, I'm counting on you.
Natsuko, pull yourself together.
A bowl! Hot water!
Help me.
She's only 8 months pregnant.
Will it be all right?
The baby wants to get out.
You, stay outside.
Not yet?
You had a child?
How was it?
A great hardship!
You must be happy when it's over...
Yes, when the baby is crying.
Quiet!
Think carefully.
A child is innocent
when he's born.
No matter who the parents are!
Must we degrade such a pure life?
No. Make sure that
it doesn't happen.
Men take advantage of sincere women.
I only think about vengeance.
What did you get out of it?
What's left in you?
A wounded and humiliated woman.
It's done. The mother is fine.
And the baby?
She wasn't fully recovered.
Unfortunately!
I'm sorry, Natsuko.
Maybe it's better this way.
A premature child rarely survives.
I'll have a child.
Next time I'll get married
and I'll have a child.
I'll have one.
You're right.
You'll stay here for a while.
You must not give up hope
even tho you've suffered.
You must become new women.
Not only must you
preserve your body,
but you must also help
to build a better world
where everybody will be happy.
Fusako!
Come spend some time with
a nice girl.
Sir, you look happy.
Sir...
Come quickly.
There's a new girl
- Where is she?
- Near the waste ground.
Fusako! Come quickly!
- Where to?
- To the waste ground over there.
What are you doing?
Where do you come from?
Show yourself.
You!
What's going on?
Nothing. Leave me.
I learned that you ran away
from the house.
It's not good.
I'll go with you.
What about you?
You're the leader
of the whores now?
Leave me!
I'm enjoying my youth.
I've suffered enough already
to be accepted
in your clan.
I spent days at the police station.
Then come!
Do you want to live in this hell?
Come, come over here.
Get sick, lose your sight.
Have your heart and bones rot!
Give birth to a monster.
Destroy all men and women of Japan.
Stupid! Imbecile!
Let's go!
Where are you going Fusako?
You want to leave us?
We'll give you a farewell present.
All right!
Hit me, beat me up.
I've had enough.
Aren't you tired of it?
My dear!
Women must not be like that anymore.
What?
Let's go, help me!
Stop! That's enough!
What's the use of torturing her?
What she said makes us sick.
Let her go.
Go away Fusako.
Don't ever come back.
Have a respectable life.
I don't know what to do...
Fusako!
Let's go.