The person who saved you...
is going to be the deity
that takes away your soul.
That means you're going to die.
What?
Oh, hello.
What are you guys talking about?
- It's nothing.
- I'm not done yet.
- I said there's a surprising turn.
- Yeom Mi.
It's not your boyfriend.
At first, I also thought it'd be him.
But the man in the wet running
shoes finally revealed himself.
It was an older man.
- An older man?
- Yes.
I'm so glad that it's not
your boyfriend here, but...
This man.
It's him.
What?
This man. Who is he?
Why do you have a picture of him?
(The Bride of Habaek)
(Final Episode)
Hey.
- Have you been well?
- Where have you been?
I thought I'd be able to take care
of the business sooner, but...
What business?
Hello.
There's no need to greet. You, over there.
So Ah's friend, Jo Yeom Mi.
How about you get going now?
This woman and I don't have much time.
Who is that?
Just go home. Knowing too much
isn't good for your sake.
By the way, what should
we do about my dream?
- The death deity is your dad...
- Stop spewing nonsense.
You just had a bad dream.
Hey, I clearly saw your dad.
It was that man in the photo.
- This is...
- What you said doesn't make sense.
- Why not?
- You said the one who saved me...
will take away my soul.
But my dad has never saved me.
Get going. And just
forget that stupid dream.
Go on.
Why is this...
Why did he do something so pointless?
You went to look for the tablet?
We don't have to find it, but I kept
getting a bad feeling about it.
- It took longer than I thought.
- Did you find it?
No, not exactly.
I just found its remnants.
Now, I need to put the pieces together.
Whatever it is, do it at Moo Ra's place.
I'm busy, so don't bother me.
The messenger must've come.
How much time do you have?
Six days.
I heard you went back, then came back.
Are you thinking about not going back?
You know that's the worst
move you can make, right?
That much I know.
It's not like I can stay here
if I choose not to go back.
Right.
- I should say goodbye to her.
- Hey.
This way.
He's leaving.
Goodbye.
You're two peas in a pod. Neither
of you is asking me to stay.
Is that your father?
Yes.
Did he make his daughter carry his burden?
- Still no word from him?
- Pardon me?
Do you want to find him?
Get going. Stop saying useless things.
Have a good time!
Gosh, I'm leaving.
Make sure you shut the door properly.
Do this.
Who knows when you'll do
this yourself after I leave?
Saying you've forgotten
someone means the opposite.
Saying you hate someone means that
you don't actually hate that person.
A part of your heart stays intact
even when everything falls apart.
When you lie, it's so obvious.
That's you.
You said...
your wish was to meet your
father and tell him everything.
I'm sorry I never got to realize your wish.
I'm a deity.
I'm sorry I couldn't even
do that much as a deity.
So...
find him after I leave.
Do your best to find him.
Even if your father turns out to
be the worst man in the world,
find him.
As you said, you're now a
grown-up who can handle it.
Find him, get the answer,
lift the weight off your mind,
and get out of that darkness.
To think...
that you will still be in
that darkness after I leave,
I'd go crazy.
Go check on him.
See if he is ready to leave.
He will leave.
- I don't have a good feeling.
- He will leave.
He knows what will happen otherwise.
He knows better than that.
Joo Dong is here.
Where have you been?
If you block your signals
again, we'll cut you off.
Ha Baek kicked me out.
You met him?
So the message came?
He's not thinking of
something stupid, is he?
Not really.
You've been looking for the tablet?
Yes, I thought I'd find it
where I fell, but I couldn't.
I realized I could have
lost it somewhere else,
so I've been looking
everywhere I've ever been.
That's why it took so long.
- But you couldn't find it?
- No.
But I at least know who took it.
Who took it? Humans couldn't see it.
Some humans can.
Can I sleep here tonight?
I'll be visiting some places from tomorrow.
- No!
Love is the problem.
- Soo Ri.
- Lord Joo Dong.
Where are you?
I'm on the street.
Why? Did you meet Ha Baek?
He kicked me out. Where are you?
Can't you let me in?
I'm working.
I can't come home tonight.
You're leaving anyway. Why
would you work so hard?
Ha Baek wants me to make a lot of money.
Fine. Hang up.
Gosh, money is the problem.
- What are you doing here?
- It's an emergency.
Someone will take her soul away?
You mean Ms. Descendant is going to die?
Yes.
Do you hate her so much that
you wish she would die?
You said your dreams are
your unconscious desires.
I thought it was precognition.
But my ability to foretell
the future is weak.
I need to complement it...
with your help.
And you're leaving soon.
Sorry?
Hello. 50 chickens? Okay.
It's not like him to sleep in.
I waited for you to come wake me up.
Why?
Just because.
I have a present for you.
I would have wanted to get you
the fanciest one there is,
but I couldn't find anything nicer
than what the female deity gave you.
So I found one that would suit you best.
I've been meaning to get you some clothes.
Wear this on our date today.
- Date?
- Yes.
Like we wanted to last time.
We'll get some good food, do
fun things, and buy clothes.
Today, tomorrow, and the
day after tomorrow.
Let's leave the car here.
Let's walk and take the bus and subway.
- Just because.
Here.
Rock-paper-scissors.
Yes!
Here you go.
Rock-paper-scissors.
Why do you lose every time?
- One more round.
- The bus is here.
Or maybe not.
It's nice to be outside, right?
- Especially with me, right?
- Yes.
I'm thirsty too.
Their specialty is cold noodles.
But you don't eat cold food.
I want to try.
Wouldn't it be nice if at
least one problem is solved?
I want to show you.
All right. Let me try.
It wasn't that bad.
I didn't have to be so scared.
What a shame.
Why are you laughing?
Ha Baek.
What? Because I called your name?
It's okay with everyone else,
but with you, I was afraid...
my feelings would be shown
if I called your name.
I didn't want you to see them.
Ha Baek.
We had noodles today.
You can play rock-paper-scissors, right?
If you win, he will draw a portrait of us.
Only if you win.
If you lose, you get nothing.
Rock-paper-scissors.
One more time. Rock-paper-scissors.
You're quite good.
Rock-paper-scissors.
You won!
Good job.
Give me a second.
Please sit down. She'll be back soon.
You're very good at rock-paper-scissors.
What's your secret?
Secret? How crude. Such word
can't explain my excellence.
I never lose.
You're very impressive.
It looks like your bride asked my
wife to prepare something for her.
My bride?
There. There she is.
Do I look pretty?
Ha Baek?
Yes.
Photographs...
fade with time, you know.
I heard that pencil lead
is made with a material...
that never fades away no
matter how much time passes.
Your face will be...
remembered more vividly than
it looks in photographs,
so I thought it'd be better to leave
a portrait that won't fade away.
You have to face this
way for me to draw you.
The groom, please.
Hold on a second!
I forgot this.
You two look picturesquely beautiful.
All right.
My gosh.
What a nice office.
You don't need to feel bad.
It is true that you put
me through a lot though.
I'm sorry.
That's how life goes. Don't worry about it.
Actually, there's something
I want to ask you.
- What is it?
- I'm looking for someone,
and I think that person is in your life.
Whom are you looking for?
Shall I say it's the person who saved you?
The person who saved me?
I lost the tablet that day.
So in backtracking my steps from that spot,
I ended up tracing your steps too.
I found out that your
stepmother, Shin Mi Jung,
found you wandering around
the Gate of Deities...
and took you home that day...
as well as the fact that
there was one more person.
Yes, that's right.
That night,
hours after you left,
a man found me.
He took me to a hospital and left,
but I found out who he is through
the traces that he left.
It was the man you met.
Why are you looking for him though?
It looks like he found it and took it.
Did he tell you where he was headed?
He said in passing that he
was going to meet someone.
I was in a critical condition,
so my mother and I left first that day.
After that day, my mother told me...
that he was on his way to his
wife's grave which was nearby.
He returned from abroad after
being away for a year,
and he didn't know about his wife's death.
We never heard from him after that day.
My mother tried very hard to find him,
but she couldn't.
His wife's grave.
But I remember him saying that day...
that there's someone he really has to meet.
Who?
- His daughter.
- His daughter?
- Is his name Yoon...
- Yes.
My mother said his name is Yoon Seong Joon.
The night of December 20, 2004?
Yes, that night.
Do you happen to remember
where you were that night?
The human brain doesn't
even remember yesterday.
How can you expect her to
remember that long ago?
- You should leave.
- Tell me. Where were you?
Don't you keep journals?
Can you try to find your journal?
What's this ruse now?
Why are you here again? And
why did you ask her that?
That's the day I went missing, you know.
What does that have to do with her?
Her father,
Yoon Seong Joon, must've taken my tablet.
- What?
- I retraced everywhere I've been.
Then I suddenly remembered something.
The man who took me to the hospital...
and the cell phone number he left.
I tracked that number.
It belongs to Yoon Seong Joon,
our servant's father. In other
words, another servant of ours.
What was that about?
Why does he want to know
what I did that day?
It answered all the questions I had.
He must've noticed it because
it's the servants' tablet.
Divine objects aren't visible to humans,
but servants can see the servants' tablet.
He probably picked it up
thinking that it belongs to me,
and I'm sure he was going to
give it to me when I woke up.
I didn't give it to him myself,
so he wouldn't have been awoken.
But...
Why did you ask So Ah
where she was that night?
Even without him being awoken,
the tablet must've recognized the servant.
Do you get what I'm trying to say?
Before Yoon Seong Joon found me that night,
he met that halfie.
He saved him first.
That guy told me...
that Yoon Seong Joon said...
he wants to go meet his daughter.
The tablet has...
the power to grant a
servant's earnest wish.
Exactly!
Yoon Seong Joon's earnest wish...
must've reached the tablet that night,
and the tablet must've
taken him to his daughter.
Now, where was she that night?
Come back and see me just once, Dad.
Then I'll forgive you for everything.
Welcome.
Gosh, you seem much more at ease.
So? Why did you want to see me?
What's the tablet that
deities carry around?
That's actually for their servants.
It reminds them that they're...
descendants of the family that
has served as deities' servants.
It is a divine object,
so it's not even visible to other humans.
Only the descendants of
the family can see it.
Why do you ask?
The daughter.
Is his name Yoon...
Yes. My mother said his
name is Yoon Seong Joon.
I was right.
(Undying connection between
parents and children)
There he is.
Ha Baek.
I found him.
An amusement park. We've been to one.
A claw-crane game... No.
Yong Yong would be jealous.
Right?
And having street food.
Street food.
Visiting a video arcade. He would love it.
I'll also ask him to get me a flower.
Will he be okay with it?
What if he doesn't want to?
Sharing a bowl of shaved ice.
Taking a nap near Han River.
I shouldn't forget to bring a mat.
Sharing earphones while listening to music.
We have so many things to do.
We should have started early.
So Ah.
Hey. Let's get moving.
We have so much to do.
By the way, you were right.
I'll look for my dad.
I'm not a kid anymore.
I'll find him and make him apologize to me.
I'll be brave.
So Ah.
- I have to go out for a moment.
- What?
Where are you going?
We don't have much time.
I'll be quick.
All right. I'll get dressed
while you're away.
I'll dress up every day.
It's important.
I should underline it.
It sounded like...
he had to meet someone.
His daughter.
I can't ask my father's
opinion for a certain reason.
My mom...
My mom is dead. So I can't
ask her opinion either.
Let me ask you a favor.
Even if you find out who Yoon
Seong Joon is, don't do anything.
That knot has to be untied by someone else.
In this life, there is
nothing prepared for you.
- Ms. Yoon.
- Hi.
- I'd like to meet you right now.
- Sorry?
It won't take long.
He is in there, Yoon Seong Joon.
So is my tablet.
You said she survived in the river.
It must have been thanks to her father.
Have you tried to look for him?
No, I haven't.
What if I do and find him here in Korea?
If he never visited us even though
he's been here the whole time...
Then what should I do?
How do you feel now?
Is that really your wish?
Meeting your dad and telling him
what you've wanted to say to him.
I think so.
I'll...
get him out.
What's the matter?
I think...
- this will be our last session.
- Sorry?
I'll tell you about the rest...
of my past.
That night,
I chased a light.
Are you okay?
It's okay.
Stay still. Calm down.
It was the first time I felt...
the warmth of a human body.
It was also the first time I learned...
the power of someone telling you...
it's okay.
I said I was lucky.
If he hadn't been the first
person I met that night...
If I had met someone who
couldn't tell me it was okay...
and hug me...
What would I have become?
I have met three deities so far.
That man, my stepmother, and...
you.
Would you allow me to thank
you with a handshake?
You're back.
I hung our portrait.
Is it raining outside?
What's wrong?
You look like you're about to cry.
What is it?
What happened?
Tell me.
Did your friends refuse
to lend you money again?
We don't need it.
I found...
your father.
I...
found him.
Where? Where is he right now?
Come on.
Where is he?
Under the river...
you jumped into that night.
What did you say?
What are you talking about?
What is that supposed to mean?
He came back...
to Korea that day.
On his way to your mother's grave,
he picked up Joo Dong's tablet.
The servants' tablet...
has a power to realize servants' wishes.
Your father's wish that night...
must have been to meet you.
That night,
right before you jumped into the river,
the power of the tablet...
led him there.
No.
He must have...
seen you jumping into the water.
No...
(Undying connection between
parents and children)
So Ah.
So Ah! No!
So Ah!
(Undying connection between
parents and children)
My dad...
can't swim.
He can't swim at all.
Why...
Why?
Why does he have to do this to me?
Dad...
Dad, Dad...
Dad, come out of there, please.
Dad.
Please save my dad.
This doesn't make any sense.
My dad...
My dad can't die like this.
Ha Baek.
Please save my dad.
You're a deity.
Save my dad's life, please.
I can't...
make the dead come back to life.
I had no idea.
I thought I got out of the water on my own.
I feel so horrible for my dad.
My dad... Because of me...
- No.
- It's all my fault.
It happened because of me. I...
- I killed my dad. I did it.
- That's not true.
I killed him! After doing that,
I spent all those years...
resenting and hating him.
I killed my dad. It was my doing!
No.
That's why he's not coming out.
He doesn't want to see me.
No. That's not true, So Ah.
No.
I should go there.
Dad must be waiting for me.
I'll go bring him.
- No.
- Let go!
I can do it.
I used to be a good swimmer.
My dad knows that.
That's why he's waiting for me.
Please. Please...
- No, you can't go.
- Let go of me.
No. No, I can't let you do that. Please.
The body doesn't move?
Ha Baek tried his best,
but it didn't even budge.
Because of the tablet,
the body is kept intact though.
He just left the tablet there as
removing it might ruin the body.
What's Ms. Descendant going to do now?
Why wouldn't it budge?
That's... Nobody knows.
Well, what do you think a deity is?
A superior being that grants
humans' earnest wishes.
That's what a true deity is.
You said...
your wish was to meet your
father and tell him everything.
I'm sorry I never got to realize your wish.
I'm a deity.
I'm sorry I couldn't even
do that much as a deity.
Excuse me, Lord Ha Baek.
- How's So Ah?
- She's not doing well.
Moo Ra and I also went inside.
We couldn't take him out either.
Then what should we do?
Ms. Descendant has been waiting for
her father for such a long time.
She says...
she'll go inside herself.
It's too deep for her. She can't go.
But it's not like we can
just leave him there either.
Why not?
Just stay still and don't do anything.
- Just like the before.
- Moo Ra.
Do you think I don't know
what you're trying to do?
I'm Moo Ra.
I've been able to read your
mind for the past 2,800 years.
I even know how you feel by
just listening to your sigh.
- Moo Ra.
- What are you saying?
I know that you've decided
to use the power you need...
to return to our realm...
on her.
- Is she right?
- Lord Ha Baek.
You... You can't do that.
If you fail to go back, you'll
fail to become the king.
If you fail to become the king...
If that happens...
You'll die.
You already know that.
I can't forgive you for even thinking that.
I won't allow it.
You can't do that, Ha Baek.
- Don't do that, Lord Ha Baek.
- You can't do that, Ha Baek.
I need to keep my promise.
Stop with the nonsense.
How is anything more
important than your death?
She said it's the deity's
duty to protect humans.
How can I call myself a king...
if I can't even protect that woman?
Stop with that rubbish.
Do you think she'd really want that?
If you die, you'll disappear
from the memories of humans.
She won't be able to remember you at all.
She'll forget all about your existence.
What... What does this all mean?
- Listen to me.
- No.
I don't want to listen to anything.
Please don't say anything.
How...
How could you think about
doing such a thing?
How could you think about doing
such a cruel thing to me?
You're going to die?
You're going to disappear from my memory?
I'm going to forget about you
for the rest of my life?
How can you...
- Listen to me.
- No...
It's because I did nothing for you.
I'm your deity.
You said deities are supposed to fulfill...
the desperate wishes of humans.
So please give me a chance.
I never said anything like that.
I don't have any wishes.
And...
I promised that I'll protect you.
I never asked you to
sacrifice your life for me.
Why are you so selfish?
What should we do?
What should we do? Let's
just send him back.
Isn't there a way to force him to go back?
Then what should we do?
He really might do it.
Let's lock him up. Yes, let's do that.
No, we can't force anything to a king.
Then use your power on her.
You can protect her. You
said you guys are friends.
You already know that I can't.
It's something that's way beyond...
the three of our powers.
Then what do you suggest we do?
It's all your fault.
Why did you have to look into the past?
If Ha Baek dies, I'm going to kill you too.
I heard Moo Ra told you
that Ha Baek is nothing...
if he doesn't become the king.
Ha Baek was born to become the king...
because that's the reason of his existence.
If he doesn't become the king,
there's no reason for him to exist.
That naturally means that he'll die.
That's the law of nature.
That's also why humans fail to remember...
all the deities that had
existed in the past.
So please do this for Ha Baek.
Tell him that...
you're willing to just
leave your father there.
Tell him that you're not
going to look for him.
That's the only way you'll both live.
Lord Bi Ryeom told me that Ms.
Descendant decided to give up.
So Ah.
You're right.
I only thought about myself
because I was scared to lose you.
I promised to help you live
with the memory you have of me.
But I had forgotten about that.
So...
please promise me one thing.
Promise me that...
you'll cherish your life.
Promise me that you'll do that...
even after I leave.
Your father will be at peace there.
I'll always look after him.
Don't forget that...
I'm the Deity of Water...
and the king of the Land of Water.
Let's go see...
your father.
I'm sorry,
Dad.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Dad.
What?
Where did he go?
Why is it so quiet?
Don't worry.
You're the one who should
leave without any worries.
That was our initial plan anyway.
Let's keep doing what we had planned to do.
Where should we go first?
I love you.
What was that?
I give you my grace.
No, stop.
Therefore, you shall live no matter what.
You shall never be unhappy.
And you shall live a full life.
No!
Therefore,
I want you to meet someone you love,
and live your remaining life in happiness.
Happiness.
That's what you've always wanted the most.
No, you can't do this.
Is this what you had in mind?
Did you fool me from the beginning?
Is that why you brought me here?
I can't just leave you
without doing anything.
I know that you're going
to go to your father...
after I leave.
How can I leave when I already know that?
I can do it. I can take him out.
What is this? How can you...
How can you be so foolish?
How?
What am I going to do now?
This is what you have to do.
Get ahold of yourself,
and go meet your father right now.
No, I don't want to.
Hurry up.
Your father's waiting for you.
Hurry.
So Ah.
Go.
Let me do something I can...
while I'm still here.
No way.
I can't believe this.
Ha Baek, how can you do this to us?
Ha Baek.
Go.
- Your father's waiting for you.
- Ha Baek.
Let him do what he's going to do.
I can't believe this.
Go.
Your father's waiting for you.
Dad.
Why are you here all alone?
You must've been so scared.
You must've been so lonely...
and cold.
Why didn't you call me earlier?
Let's go home now, Dad.
Let's go home.
(Undying connection between
parents and children)
(Yoon Seong Joon)
Just wait a little bit, Dad.
I'll soon bring Mom here too.
I'm not...
going to forgive you.
Okay.
I'm going to hate you...
and resent you.
Okay.
I'm going to regret...
meeting you.
Okay.
I'm going to put things back to normal...
before any of that happens.
I'm going to...
put things back to where
they were no matter what.
What are you saying?
I thought she was stupid.
But I guess she was smart
enough to think of this.
But I'm not going to forgive you
just because you thought of this.
What's going on?
Ms. Descendant has come up with a solution.
She's going to use my tablet that was
inside Yoon Seong Joon's pocket.
I heard that...
the servant's tablet fulfills
a servant's earnest wish.
I'm going to help you return.
- So Ah.
- Make it quick.
I'm desperate to kill you both, but
I'm trying hard to hold it in.
Hurry up. Moo Ra might cause a flood soon.
Your hand, please.
Now,
everything will go back to normal.
- With the deity's grace...
- So this is where you were.
What?
Is that the High Priest?
What are you doing here?
I come here often.
Didn't Joo Dong tell you?
What? Oh, I completely forgot.
I came to catch a servant...
that secretly ran away
after causing trouble.
I also had a few people to meet here.
You must be the one who got
to live longer by meeting...
a competent taxi driver.
Sorry?
By any chance...
I heard you did a part-time
job, Lord Ha Baek.
You didn't have any parents to
give any red long johns to.
So I wonder what you did
with your first paycheck.
High Priest, were you...
What are you doing? Why
are you disturbing us?
- Hurry up.
- With the deity's grace...
What are you doing?
My gosh.
Listen to me carefully. I'm
not going to repeat myself.
This fool used his remaining
power on this woman,
so he's having trouble going back.
Wait a second.
So you're going to use
that tablet's power...
on just helping Lord Ha Baek return?
Why would you waste that precious
power on such a useless thing?
What do you mean, High Priest?
If he fails to go back, he'll die.
Why would he fail to go back?
Lord Ha Baek has completed his mission.
That means he'll be able to return.
That's why he's a fool.
He could've just stayed there
when he first returned.
Wait.
My new mission was to find out...
the reason behind hiding the
sacred stone in the human world.
Oh, right.
That's correct. From what I know,
you've already found that reason.
How can...
a deity save the world...
if he or she can't even
save just one human being?
What... What was that?
I knew this would happen.
The universe favors Ha Baek so much.
Ms. Yoon.
I advise you to use the tablet's
power on something more valuable.
I have a guest coming over,
so I have to go now.
Lord Ha Baek, don't forget that you
still must return to Land of Water.
Yes, he's right.
Let's continue with what we were doing.
Make the best wish...
so that I can leave you at ease.
Ask for more money than Mansour.
With the deity's grace,
you shall be awakened.
You are the last descendant of the
family of servants for deities.
And you shall now speak of
your most earnest wish.
Don't hesitate. Just say it.
This is your chance to become
happy for the rest of your life.
My wish is...
I...
I wish that...
you'd...
leave a little later.
Please stay by my side...
until I die.
Please live with me until then.
You can go back...
and become a good king after I die.
Let's live together.
I'm going to go now. I'm getting too angry.
I should leave.
You had the chance to
become richer than Mansour.
It must be because you're young.
I love you.
You did a good deed, so you'll
be fine in your next life.
I didn't do anything.
Ms. Yoon came to me and asked me
about the power of the tablet.
I only told her what I knew.
You took your risk and revealed
to her the secrets of nature.
I heard that's your strongest skill.
Gosh, I've only just met you.
Nice to meet you. I am High Priest.
My name is Shin Hu Ye.
I used to be the Deity of Fire.
Can you teach me how to use fire?
If I master that, I'll
be able to control...
water, fire, air, earth, and humans.
You should come see me soon.
Lord Ha Baek, let's go now.
That sly old man.
He knew everything all along.
I still need to return to Land of Water.
I'll go there to make sure
your wish will come true.
You'll be back, right?
I promise I'll be back.
You won't take long, right?
No.
See you soon.
I organized them into categories.
There's no need for that.
I've figured out...
how to become a better person.
As you know, I used to get
such good grades in school.
I'm saying I've finally figured out
what you've been trying to tell me.
So what is it?
How will you become a better person?
Go through this.
It's a proposal. I'll pester Grandpa
to start this new foundation.
This one is for single moms.
This is for the elderly who live alone,
and this is for children without parents.
Noblesse oblige.
That's how I'll become a better person.
It's not a bad idea,
but you should do this first.
Please write down names
of the people here...
and get them to sign before
you do anything else.
"I'm sorry." That's what
you should start with.
- What people?
- Those whom you owe an apology.
List all of them here, apologize
to them, and get their signatures.
Start with your grandfather.
Then I'll preach at you again.
- What?
- When you become a better person,
- I might become your friend.
- What?
(Undying connection between
parents and children)
No, no. Don't even think about it.
Even if you jump in there,
Ha Baek won't be able to
show up and save you.
That's not what I was thinking.
Your dad is in the forest. Why
are you looking all sad here?
And don't throw things
like that in the river.
You'll pollute the water.
I have news for you.
Ha Baek won't be able to come back.
What do you mean?
Did a messenger come?
A messenger isn't necessary.
I'm a deity.
That's the feeling I'm getting.
Let's go.
We haven't heard a word from him.
That means he's not coming back.
Stop worrying. Let's
just mind our business.
You really didn't like any of the rings?
- Goodbye.
- Take care.
Do you want to tell me something?
I've been meaning to tell you this.
Well...
I think I should marry Hyung Sik.
- What?
- We should just get married.
Love isn't about anything special.
It makes you want to care and
look after the one you love.
For me, that's enough.
Hey, try to think rationally.
You can't marry your friend.
We've known for a long time,
so we know each other's flaws.
Do you dislike Hyung Sik?
No, that's not what I'm saying.
- Hyung Sik is here...
- What?
- To meet you in person.
- Hey, wait. Hey!
- Hey, wait!
- Hyung Sik.
It's been a long time, So Ah.
Yes, it's been a long time indeed.
Why have you never come by?
Because you scare me.
What did I do?
Sang Yu is getting married?
Yes. He doesn't even
have anything saved up.
I wanted to give him...
enough money for rent deposit as a
wedding gift when he gets married.
This is too sudden.
Gosh, I told him not to rush it,
but he's not listening to me.
He just keeps saying...
that people used to get married with
nothing but two spoons and a pot.
Things are so different nowadays, you know.
Hello? Did she hang up on me again?
Goodness.
- I'm back.
- Yes.
I told you not to stay out late.
You never listen to me.
What took you so long?
The process for deferring the
enthronement was so complicated.
They're so inflexible.
Let's go eat something.
Okay.
- Will you keep feeling hunger?
- Yes.
What about the magic wand?
They said I can't take it.
Then... Did you bring nothing
but a driver's license again?
They told me to get it here.
Gosh, you have a lot to do.
Where's Mr. Nam?
He's sick of the part-time jobs...
and scared of your friend,
so he didn't come.
(Ha Baek, Yoon So Ah)
Nothing has changed, right?
(Thank you for watching
The Bride of Habaek.)
People can survive anything...
with the strength they have.
But life would be better with love.
(Ha Baek, Yoon So Ah)
(The Bride of Habaek)