Fly.
You're beautiful, are you? Yes, you are.
- That's my boy.
- Is that a smile? Is it?
Found it on the beach, walking by.
- Did ya?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Many years in the family.
- How long have you had it?
Since I was five.
It's amazing.
You're joking!
My lads said...they do a beautiful dance,
fertility dance. And they had babies.
Here you go. I was told to keep it warm.
Well, we should have the results in a couple of weeks.
Brilliant.
Hi.
Eh, sorry, my husband is not here. He's...
Trying to build it, eh?
Are you one of his students?
Think the right look, huh?
- Oh, you're Nick! Oh, hi.
- So I exist.
Yeah, I know, of course. I just
wasn't expecting you, I'm Dawn.
I thought I'd drop by.
Oh, I'll let him know.
Hey, let's make it a surprise.
Oh no, I think I should.
Oh, go on then.
Thanks.
Oh. No, he's gone into a class.
Do you want to...bring your stuff in? Come in.
- It's a bit of a bomb site.
- I feel like I'm home
I'll take down my things, shall I?
We had no idea you were coming.
We're not really...set up for guests yet.
Oh, don't bring her too close to
the hen hutch. She's not trained yet.
She's a-a reject dog. She was abandoned by her owners.
Reject...
Yeah.
You wanna put up some tar in there.
Hi!
Fucking hell.
Been on a sunbed, then?
I tried to call.
- How the fuck did you know I'd be here?
- Dog returns to his shit.
He's not very refined.
So, what do you think?
It's lovely.
- Yeah.
- It's lovely.
- It'll be beautiful.
- Beautiful, yeah.
Got all you want then?
This is from my family.
It must be hard out there.
You must miss home.
Oh, fuck those glasses.
I know they're here somewhere. We
haven't really had the time to...
Shame I was away..
- Oh. It-It was kind of low-key.
- Yeah?
- It was only a register office.
- How did he behave?
Oh, well. He wasn't found shagging one
of my bridemaids in the toilet, were you?
Get back to the chopping, missus.
She's changed you.
- Huh!
- You got all posh.
Marriage is a constant process of negotiation.
Yeah-Yeah. We sing in our chains.
How's Sam?
Grand. She's-she's grand.
- And the kid?
- Dylan?
Yeah, he-he's a bundle of fun.
Not mine, by a previous.
God, how do they cope with all the coming and going?
They don't.
Thank you.
- Well...cheers.
- Cheers.
- Hmm.
- Lovely to have you.
So you didn't buy the farm, then?
Ah, it's a wreck.
Tell me.
Your brother's a joke, huh?
Why haven't we seen him?
He's been in the army.
And?
He pushed our Mum down the stairs when he was a teenager.
My God.
Why?
Well, she could be a bit...
a bit verbal.
Still.
I burned my Mum with curling tongs when I was sixteen.
And it wasn't entirely an accident.
She took me to a psychiatrist.
Yeah, well. Our Mum ended up in the hospital.
- David!
- Yes.
You hungry?
Yeah? Huh.
Eggs. Orange, then.
Something...
Morels.
You wanna take that back to bed, yeah?
What?
I want a baby.
Be patient.
What's this all about?
- You buggered it in your sleep.
- You were sleepwalking.
Oh, shit.
Shit, I haven't done that for a while.
What, bugger a lettuce?
Oh, thanks.
Maybe it's because you're able to relax..
Maybe. Do feel relaxed.
Yeah, don't relax too much.
When we were little...David and his mates,
they made me a little obstacle course.
How'd you know? You were asleep! Dawn, what you have to do
- is talk really quietly, don't alarm...
- So I sleepwalked into the pond.
Get some breakfast.
I'm all right in here, thanks.
I don't know whether we should've
gotten that claim...what we're doin'.
- Carefully, that still has life in it.
- What sort of life?
David! My God! David! David!
You...
I can't believe you did that!
It's not funny! It's not funny...
So how long is it since you've...been back home?
Well, about six years since I've been back in these parts.
How come you and David haven't been in touch?
Davy was making his way in London...
and he got kind of lost, didn't he?
Oh I love this sound. God. Fucking hell!
- Hello, mate!
- Hi!
- Back from the dead, eh?
- I can fucking sort you out, mate, I'm bigger now.
Now watch out for this one, Dawn.
So you've grafted for Sharon's dad now?
Married her. He's dead...thank Christ.
Don't tell her I said that, eh, Dawn?
- You want one, Nick?
- No, I'm good, thanks.
Thank you.
- Here you go.
Thanks. All right, Miss Grate?
These are for you.
- Ohh, ah-ah.
- Ah, what
It's not bad. I'll tell you about being bad.
Number two, The Hastings.
Cathy Histen hang herself...
nobody found her for a week...
nobody gave a fuck about Cathy Histen.
Number 3, The Hastings. Jacky Gross,
beat his wife for twenty years.
But he wasn't a bad boy because he did all the
football scores on the radio when he was driving the buses.
Oh, goody, the old Forge! Now that's come up in the world.
They used to have all...cobwebby windows
and have, like, a horses hoof, right down there.
He was having sex with his daughter.
He was. Everybody knew about it.
Homely. Ha-ha, Homely.
She had three kids and she drown herself
and two of them in the quarry pond.
Don't know what happened to the other, poor little sod.
I met an evil spirit in this church, aye, when I was seven.
- You did not.
- I did.
Made me what I am.
That and the army.
That'll ward 'em off...the spirits.
Sweet to the sweet. Hm-hm.
Go on.
Have a good day.
We all know the first line, OK?
So when I count to one, two, three,
I want you all to come in together.
I want the front line and the
back line to come in together, OK?
Tell me.
He's so full-on, he's funny.
You tell me.
One of my students is cutting herself.
How do you know?
She told me.
It's a shame, she's a bright kid.
You have to report it.
I don't want to get her into trouble. With her family, I mean.
- You have to tell someone, David, it's a law.
- Yeah.
Social services. Bit of a mixed bag.
She trusts me.
- I can't believe he hasn't brought you here.
- We did pass by, once.
- When did David leave?
- When he was seventeen.
God, it's a wreck.
- Which one was yours?
- The one just around the front.
- How often have you dreamt about it?
- I've dreamt about it, all right.
Watch out.
I left some...old tobacco just...here.
Will you look at that. Oh my God,
it's been there since I was fifteen.
- Aw, you can tell.
- Hmm.
So what was it like...
you and David down on the farm?
Mixed bag.
My grandpa, he had these big shire horses,
they were fucking huge! But really gentle. Hm.
Yeah.
Thanks for, um, for looking after.
I appreciate it.
- Obliged.
- No worries.
It's-It's Nick. And Dawn, here.
I'm not blind.
You got a big old star for geography. You know that.
- Hey, stranger!
- Wow! Fancy that! How you doin'?
- All right.
- Hey, Dawn.
- Hi!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Hi, Miss Hedges!
- Say, you won any medals yet?
- Yeah, the Purple Heart.
Ohh. I just gotta...
They spit in the food.
- I'm sure they don't.
- You'll see.
So how were they? When you were teaching them.
The Johnson boys!
Flamey brats.
Poor little chaps.
Sometimes you can't help them even if you want to.
Their father beat them.
Flack-fleck-giddley-geck.
Not that you could see anything.
David never told me.
Where is he?
I like clever boys!
- But you have been torturing her.
- What?! I...she used to torture us!
Oh, the poor old pretty, she hasn't
got any kids to look after her.
Oh, that's what kids are for!
- Remember Mister Dixon?
- Sure!
He used to beat the crap out of us. Well,the lads, that is.
- Out of you, you mean.
- Yeah, because I took the rap for Davy.
Why?
What did you do?
He was always the one there when everyone else turned and ran.
It was always him standing, saying, "What?!
It wasn't me! It wasn't me! I didn't do it!"
'Till they sent you away.
He had his spell in Bostle.
- Ten years ago, Dawn.
- Oh, give or take.
Far from the prying eyes of the state.
Banged his head against the wall.
Yeah, that's why I work looking after troubled kids.
Ahh! That's why I joined the fucking army.
Hey, remember that time you...held my head in
the water trough? I tell you, I almost choked.
- Oh, no!
- Yeah.
- Where was David?
- I remember that..
I don't know, elsewhere.
- Huh!
- You nicked my girlfriend.
I...nicked your girlfriend? I was thirteen,
how could I nick your girlfriend?!
You looked at her.
I looked at her?! Fuckin' hell, they taught me all I know.
On that same day, I was dancing around my handbag,
and somebody all scrawny, little scruffy...
- Me?
- Feller comes up to me, i.e. you, Nick...
and starts giving it the big-in coming on to me and then
Mister Trustworthy here,
older lad, comes up and saves me, i.e. Gary.
You know they forced me to do that?
You Johnson boys! Oh, nothing but problems.
Yeah, well, that's all over now.
Marriage is just so restful, isn't it,
Dawn? You don't have to choose anymore.
- Hello.
- Well, if you didn't laugh, you'd cry, eh?
Miss Hedges told me about your dad. That he beat you.
Who's that, Dad? He used to fuck us up the ass, eh?
He's too much.
- Well, you wanted him to stay.
- Did I?!
Why didn't you tell me?
Not here, Dawn. All right, mate, can
I have, eh, one more gin and tonic, please?
Oh, my God!
Shhh, come in.
- What are you doing?
- Come on!
- You go on!
- No, I can't, cause Gary won't like it.
Oh, my God!
Blimey, love!
Here.
Be careful, don't rip it.
- She lent me this, Davy boy!
- Right. Ahh.
Come on, guys, out of the way.
...must go and you must bide.
But come ye back when summer's in the meadow...
Shocking!
And we'll come back before...the valley's...with snow...
And be you here in sunshine or in shadow...
Wah-wah!
Oh, Danny boy, oh, Danny boy, I love you so.
Painful!
- Dave, I hear someone in there.
- Hmm?
Think there's someone in there.
- There is! There is, David, look!
- All right, all right.
Look! Dave, there's somebody in here!
- There's somebody in there, Dave, look!
- All right.
Come out! Come out!
Nick?
It's over, my mate, I know what was in there!
When-when he got out of tank, he was all on fire, Dave!
- He was burning!!!
- Nick?
I pulled away, but then I tried to save
him. I was like, "Where's the fire brigade?"
"Where are they?", I was saying.
But it...there was nobody there!
I tried to put it down, I jumped on top of it, like that.
Burnt right through, I couldn't save him!
- You're all right.
- Look!
- Look at me, look at me.
- Look, no!
It's all right. It's all right. Look at me.
Don't.
Is he all right?
Poor Nick.
Why didn't you tell me about your dad?
Because I don't want to think about it. Because...
he was full of hate, self-hate.
Because I hate him.
Why did we come here?
Because I wanna do some good in
the place that my dad was a tosser.
- Do you really like the country side?
- You're the one with the chickens.
- David...
- I love you.
Why has he come back?
I used to hold him.
That's all, I mean, you saw!
He likes it.
He needs help.
You can't help Nick,
can't save him.
Hello?
Nick.
Have you thought about talking to someone?
You know, about your experiences.
We think you need professional help.
We?!
There's no shame in going off on one,
you know.  Well, I could talk to someone.
- We all need help.
- You may do.
And you.
"I opened the door and I was suddenly in a-a ruined city."
"It looked as it-as it was bombed.
"The ground was hot ash with dead
bodys scattered everywhere..."
Take a break, have a look at this.
If it's one body, it is "the body" without the "S".
And if it's plural, you put "ies" in
there, and that makes "the bodies".
But that's brilliant, you've done that really,
really well. Want to read on from there.
"The building-the buildings were all smashed to pieces..."
So what do you know about professional help?
I was mugged, in London.
David weighed in, that's how we met.
- I had some counselling after that.
- Hmm.
Well, he likes a barney.
- Really?
- Um-hmm.
I've no seen him fight except that one time.
What was it like? Really?
Better than sex.
It's...um...um...
it's like there's one of me...out there, fightin'
and one of me here, um...and I can't ...
quite, um, make the two, um...
I know.
I can't have on record, see, that's-that's-that's the trouble.
OK. Eh, can we just do guys,
just the beginning. Actually, I
just wanna hear them first of all.
- Dawn! All right?
- Yeah.
- You walking?
- Yeah!
How you finding it?
Well...it's a big old church.
- It's beautiful.
- Yes, it is.
Those angels are famous.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Churches make me feel sad somehow.
- Yeah?
- Huh.
Why?
Wait for me to come and save you, do you remember?!
You frightened me earlier.
Sorry.
He gets to me sometimes.
I hardly know you, do I?
- We're trying for a baby.
- Nice.
Yeah, well, it's taking its sweet time.
Nick one. I'll do it for you.
I was stolen, well, adopted.
- Really?
- Hmm.
Well, worked out well, as far as I can see.
They're dead now. They were older.
I miss them. Like you never really, eh...
We got shot up, my mistake.
In the dark.
I couldn't see.
- Ha!
- David!
How'd you know we were here?
Dog returns to its shit.
I should've called down, he just...turned up.
- You seen enough?
- It's a wreck, innit?
- Nick. Nick. Nick, Nick! It's a dream.
- I'll hold you.
It's all right. It's all right.
- It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
- Nick!
- Nick.
- It's all right...it's all right, Nick.
- Huh? Why?
What's happened?
That was wide open. He must've left it open in his sleep.
You did that!
Why would I open the hen hutch?
You know, it's just like when you killed your rabbit!
He left the hutch opened in the middle of the night,
let the dogs out, all in his sleep, when he was a kid!
You did that, you opened the hutch
door and you blamed it on me,
- you killed her!
- You bed-wetter!
- You little shit!
- Stop it!
Dawn.
Dawn!
Dawn!!
Dawn!!!
You Johnson boys.
Bring 'em here.
Thanks.
Should we get rid of him?
Where to?
Got mates?
What about an ex?
David...
Did you let the dog into the hen hutch?
Sorry.
I was only joking.
Oh, So. Can you stand, please?
You awake now?!!
Dave, I'm sorry. Dave! I'm sorry!
- Don't.
- Dave!
Don't!
Get up. Get up!
You want it, do you? You want
her, do you? Do you? You want it!
I'll pay for that.
Why did you leave me the house?
Sorry about last night.
That looks good. Mind if I have a slice of that?.
- You made it, you cut it.
- Oww.
- Who wears the trousers in that house?
- She does.
This one's the one that, eh, his
brother had competition. Well...
he just made those, right?
Is it-Is it like like Robin Hood? Can we, eh...
- Light in his hand, like by Robin Hood.
- Just shut up.
- Do you think we should go away end of term?
- Yeah, we could.
We got a house in Spain.
Come there to us.
- It's an idea.
- I'll come to Spain.
Yeah, it's a shame you're leaving, Nick.
We have farewell party on Saturday.
Don't have much of a house, we got a hell of a barbecue.
Ohh. Gonna miss you, Nick.
Know when your time's up.
Yeah, Gary wants another kid.
Well, I just feel too young, and-and I love all this.
You know, having a laugh and just being able to have a drink.
You know, 'cause my Mum's not gonna be around forever.
And she can handle one, but hav-having to have two, I...
And I-I don't want my tits sagging to the ground. Ohhh!
- And here's the biggest one of them all.
- Biggest one of whom all, who's that?
Kids!
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, you.
Me, going to battle.
Must have your flak jacket.
I wish you were coming to hear me..
Sod's law.
No.
- No!
- Bit funerial?
Yeah.
- What about this one?
- No!
- Dazzle, Bobbie Dazzle.
- No, none of them.
You're lovely as you are.
- Where was Sharon tonight?
- Not her thing.
- David?
- PTA.
- I'll take this.
- Oh, thank you.
Oh, sorry.
- All right.
- Thank you.
- OK?
- Hmm.
No!
Stupid. Sorry.
It's all right. Uh, thanks for walking me home.
Dawn!
I think you need a wash, anyway.
You need to have a wash?
What'd you say, eh?
It's a hard thing being a teacher but
it's a hell of a lot harder being pupil.
It's not  a closed book by any means.
In the first instance, you need to
come back here for a second test to
- make sure it isn't just a-a blip.
- It's not a blip.
I'm sorry?
It's a...it's...
it's not a blip, um...I-I had a previous girlfriend who was...
trying for a baby and, eh...
Stop crying.
It's my fault, stop crying.
Why didn't you just say?
You kept pushing it, your-your little project,
I mean, why couldn't we just waited for a couple of years?!
- I was afraid it was me!
- Well it's me, happy now?
Christ!!!
I could've guessed.
I'm gonna walk home.
Dawn, please.
Please don't leave me. I wouldn't
be much without you, but...Ow!
Hello?
Dawn!
It's Gary.
Oh, God.
So...so sorry!
Oops.
- I'll take the dog for a walk.
- Go on, then.
Come on, Judy.
Well, thanks for making the bed.
Less of the chatter, please.
Right. Make sure you get into a line.
Thomas, Ann, will you stop talking, please. Thank you.
Nadir and Sinead, will you please be quiet!
You've got to do this in a week and none of you prepared, OK?
You need to start paying attention.
David.
I want to get through this.
- We can have everything, have a whole life.
- Yeah, but you really want a child.
How do you know what I want?
It was years, so we should go to the doctor.
You lied about how long we've been trying.
You lied.
Oh God, I'm so ashamed.
David...I love you.
I want you to be happy.
- David.
- You go.
I don't wanna. You go, Dawn.
You go try.
I'm awake.
I was just admiring them...
Nick.
Hi, honey, how are you?
Hi, little one, how are you?
She's sad, that's all. She can't have kids.
- What?!
- Yeah. David told me.
Ah, Dawn.
Oh. I'm sorry.
It's him who can't.
Oh, come here. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
Hello?
I know, it was a Sunday.
Yeah.
We're trying to help you daughter, so...
So you looking forward to going back?
Say hello to the Taliban?
Blow up a few more childs, eh?
Here, catch.
Oh! Oh, my God!
- Come here, come here.
- Is she allright?
- Someone, show me. Somebody get me some ice.
- April, don't go now.
She all right?
A hot coal on me, David, you should get this fucking nut...
All right, Dawn? Need some help?
- Thank you.
- Who you gonna fuck next, then?
You all right, darling? Do you want some help?
- Daisy?
- Yes, please.
- David! Give us the ball.
Watch this.
Hey, soldier boy! Catch!
He used to pay me to beat you up, did you know that?
What? What you gonna do?
Stop it!
Remember when you did this to me, eh?
- Do you remember when you did this to me?! EH?!
- David, stop it!
Baby, come here.
I fucked your wife.
Gary!
- Gary, please.
- Get off me.
Don't look at me like that, Dawn.
I'm the sane one!
He pushed our Mum down stairs!
- Nicki.
- Fuck me!
Old Mum, eh. Gave her something to think about.
David! David!!! No! David!!!
Oh yeah, sure, we'll be in...
that's fine, thank you.
He's gone AWOL.
- Did he tell you he was gonna run away?
- No.
- Has he been in touch, David?
- He dropped by this summer but we
weren't that close since our parents died.
Well...
we, eh...We think he might have mental health problems.
- Think he'll come back?
- How should I know?
- You would tell me.
- He'll come to you.
Why did you lie to me about him
pushing your Mum down the stairs?
She was hurting him.
I was protecting him.
Missed you. Yeah, I did, I missed you.
No, don't go. Don't go, don't go.
Don't go, don't go. Don't go.
Please don't go.
All right, I stink.
I went to London but I couldn't...hack it.
Do you want a biscuit?
Eh?
Go on. Go on, have one.
They come from the back of the service station.
I've let all my mates down.
I just can't...sleep.
I just can't.
How's Davy?
I have to know...
about you two.
Well, he loves me.
Davey...looked after me, yeah?
'Cause of Dad...
but he, kind of...
owned me.
That's not love.
He fucks you...but he loves ME!
He hates you!
You have to go.
I'll bring you money.
Where could I go?!
If you love him, you'll leave us!
- Where you going?
- To choir.
Drop you if you like.
Nick?
Where were you?
I was worried about you.
Where is he?
- Where is he?
- Dawn?
She'll need to get plenty of rest.
- So, we'll keep her for now.
- Thank you.
Dawn...
They say the baby is safe.
I didn't want to hurt you.
I want this child.
I want you to be happy.
Nick came back.
I saw him.
I know.
- This is little Ben.
- Little Ben.
- I know.
- Ben.
- Well...
- Hello.
- Ohh.
- Oh, he's lovely.
You must be proud.
Yeah.