(music)A faithless lover's kiss
(music)Is written on the wind
(music)A night of stolen bliss
(music)Is written
(music) On the wind
(music)Just like the dying leaves
(music) Our dreams we've calmly
(music) Thrown away
(music)Now they've blown away
(music)Softly flown away
(music) The promises we made
(music) Our whispers in the breeze
(music) They echo and they fade
(music)Just like our memories
(music) Though you are gone
(music)From me
(music) We never can really be
(music)Apart
(music) What's written on the wind
(music)Is written in my heart
[Wind Howling]
[Gunshot]
Hello
- What happened to Mrs. Black?
- My predecessor? She was paroled
So you're the new
executive secretary, huh?
Don't let that title deceive you
I do everything but wipe windshields
- I'm Mitch Wayne
- Yes, I recognized you
- I'm Lucy Moore
- Recognized me? From where?
Oh, come now
Surely you realize
how often your photograph
has graced our tabloids?
But the captions usually read,
"Kyle Hadley, Prince Charming
of the oil empire, and friend"
The dashing Kyle Hadley
I saw him dash through
the office recently
Seems he misplaced
his money belt
- Again?
- A hat was passed,
and I contributed $1647
Well, for that, you ought to get
an oil well named after you
- Your boss in?
- No, Mr. Ryan's out of town
- I guess you'll have
to pinch-hit for him
- What can I do for you?
Kyle Hadley's at 21,
in the mood for a conference
- Business, of course
- Look, I'm only Mr. Ryan's secretary
- I don't think it'd be proper to...
- Would you rather wipe windshields?
All right
Kyle and I flew in
from Texas this afternoon
- Sounds urgent
- Very
- Kyle said he felt
like a steak sandwich
- Steak sandwich?
And who serves the best
steak sandwich in the world?
- 21?
- Simple, isn't it?
Or should I say
simpleminded?
1,380 miles for a...
- Then you were fooling me
about a business conference
- No, that was my idea,
you know, in case
Mr. Jasper Hadley should ask
why we came to town
Oh, the big boss Well...
Cheer up You might
get your picture in the paper
Is that all you live for?
- Guess again, Miss Moore
- I'm sorry
I just wanted you to understand
how I feel about such things
- Know something?
- What?
Maybe we're two of a kind
Harry, put it on my tab
- Of course, Mr. Hadley
- Who's this friend we're waiting for?
Mitch Wayne, my sidekick
Mmm, where do his millions
come from?
He's eccentric...
he's poor
- [Chuckles] I'll bet
- Honey, you would lose
Mitch is just a country boy
The kind of assets he's got
you can't buy with money
Sorry, kids
I'll have to make this
some other time
- He's not eccentric
- No, he's as rich as Rockefeller
- Hello, I'm Kyle Hadley
- I'm Lucy Moore
Lucy Moore
Your taste is improving
Miss Moore is Bill Ryan's
new executive secretary
A member of the happy, happy
Hadley Industrial family
This is sure cozy
There are rare moments
when only champagne will do
This is one of them
Like the lyrics say,
"Are you from Dixie or where?"
Indiana Small town
you probably never heard of
Anytime you ask me,
I'll put it on the map
What shows
in your crystal ball?
Oh, I'll probably walk down an aisle
and wind up in a suburb
- with a husband,
mortgage and children
- That's not for you
- Why not?
- Got too much beauty and brains
to fall into a trap like that
Just what sort of trap
do you suggest?
How would you like to join
the Kyle Hadley Society
for the Prevention of Boredom?
- [Chuckles]
What would my duties be?
- Not duties
Pleasures, such as Kyle Hadley's
guided tour through the gossip columns,
around the world
in 80 headlines
- I'm afraid that'd bore me
- What wouldn't bore you?
My career... advertising
Bravo...
as they say in Texas
- Where did you learn
the advertising game?
- With the Sheraton Agency
- Top drawer?
- One of Madison Avenue's finest
Good enough
I'll buy you the agency
What if I took you up on that?
[Snaps Fingers]
A phone, please
[Man]
Yes, Mr. Hadley
- You're really serious, aren't you?
- Sure I am
- What's the number?
- The agency or my apartment?
- Seriously...
- Very seriously, forget it
I'm only following the advice
of a Texas philosopher who said,
"Give the little girl a big..."
I think it's time we heard from
another county What do you do
for the Hadley Oil Company?
We're troubleshooters
Wherever they want trouble,
they send for us
I, uh, have a sheepskin
that says I'm a geologist
- That adds up
- I was kicked out
of the same school
They found rocks
in my head
Shouldn't you be going back
to the office?
Apparently,
I never should have left
- We haven't finished
our champagne
- Remarkable, isn't it?
I think we need cigarettes
Get a carton
We'll get a cab, meanwhile
Thank you, Mr. Hadley
Carton of Mullhall, please
Thank you
[Taxi Departs]
Don't look now,
but you've dropped your friend
You advertising people...
so clever with words
Guess I've fallen
from your grace
Does it really matter?
Change your course
Teterborough Airport
Look, if you don't mind,
I'd like to get off
the merry-go-round
I can't quit now
I want you to meet
another fellow... a real one
- Some other time, perhaps
- Some times, like now,
I can get you
in the terminal
I want us to be friends
when we say good-bye
Well, then let me
give you a tip
- Drop me at the office
- And if I do, I lose you
Look, Lucy, once we're up in the blue,
I'm a different fellow...
a lot different
from this character
All right
Maybe I should meet him
No stunts now, like buzzing
the Empire State Building
The only stunts I do
are in nightclubs
May I ask why?
I wouldn't admit this
to anyone but you,
but I drink too much
- Here's your change
- Can't shake you, can I?
Goes both ways
Am I safe in this crate?
I guess so
The tanks are loaded, and
the pilot isn't, for a change
Lucy
You know, I've seen you before
at the office
- A fleeting glance, wasn't it?
- How much did you contribute?
Enough
How long have you known Mitch?
My dad introduced us
when we started the first grade
- That must have been
before your father struck oil
- Dad was worth 100 million then
He had no use for private
schools, and he wanted me
to grow up with Mitch
Why Mitch in particular?
Mitch's old man
is my dad's boyhood pal...
his idol, I guess
A small rancher...
kind of a legend in our county
Great hunter, sort of
a throwback to Daniel Boone
I used to wish
he was my father
Is your father aware of this?
Dad's a big man... so big
that he and I know I can't fit
his shoes, or even come close
- Can anybody?
- Yes
Mitch
When I was kicked out of college,
Dad gave up hoping
Mitch's qualities
might rub off on me
It's easy to talk like this
when you're 6,000 feet above
the big poker table
- Poker table?
- Sure The big one...
from Maine to California
Down there, I'm a guy
with too many chips
I throw 'em up in the air,
and a few land on my shoulders
They'd be disappointed if
I didn't behave like a playboy...
didn't end up like my uncle
- How did he end up?
- Joe Hadley?
Lived hard and he died hard
He survived a few duels
over some European duchesses
and countesses,
only to be done in by a jealous
Turk who hired assassins
to cut out his heart
- He was only 30
- Black sheep?
- One of three
- Well, I take it
you include yourself,
but who's the third?
My kid sister Marylee
She's got enough devil in her
to put Uncle Joe and me
in the shade
What's the matter?
Your ears burning?
Just came to tell you
we're off the Carolina coast
- North Carolina?
- Uh-huh Are we turning back?
Can't Automatic pilot's
set for Miami
- And then what?
- I feel like a swim
How does Miami Beach sound?
Better ask your guest
Just say the word, and
I'll make a 180-degree turn
Reluctantly?
Uh-huh Something
is happening to me
I find myself talking to you like
I never talked to anyone before...
not even Mitch
Please, Lucy I think we're past
the point of no return
[Woman On PA]
Flight 498
now arriving from Havana
at Cubana concourse
Kyle's probably arranging
to buy you the hotel,
a stretch of the beach
and a slice of the Gulf strip
Why are you so sarcastic?
Do you resent our being here,
or are you just disappointed that
I didn't ask Kyle to turn back?
The first surprise
came at Teterborough
I underestimated Kyle's charm
Perhaps you've always
underestimated Kyle
Or maybe you're
overestimating me
- Could be
- Nothing like this has ever
happened to me before
It's an adventure
It's exciting
Are you looking for laughs?
Or are you soul searching?
The latter, I guess
I think I'm beginning
to know Kyle
and to like him
Well, in that case, I'm glad
I really am
Tell me something
This hooky-playing...
when does it end?
I don't know
For me,
it never seems to end
Okay, kids
Let's beat it to Miami Beach
Found us a boarding house with
built-in black-eyed peas and grits
This way, please
I'm certain, Mr. Hadley,
you'll find everything
to your satisfaction
- Everything?
- Yes, sir
Nice little boarding house
you have here
- [Door Opens]
- This is Miss Moore's suite
- And we're right across the hall?
- Yes, sir
How do you like it?
What's not to like, huh?
Come on
I'll show you around
Anything missing?
Open the closet
Look over here
Great invention,
the telephone, hmm?
See you in an hour, okay?
[Door Closes]
Sure floored her, didn't it?
- Me too
- Sounds like a crack
No, just a dent in my armor
- What does that mean?
- Nothing much
Except I had Lucy
figured wrong
What did you expect?
I figured she'd be different
than all the rest
- She is
- No, she's not
If she were, she'd have spit
right in your eye
[Laughing]
Lucy?
Lucy, you decent?
Lucy, are you dec...
Guess she was
- Yes, Mr. Hadley?
- Did you see Miss Moore leave?
Yes, sir, I did...
about, uh, 30 minutes ago
Yes, sir
- Remember the girl who arrived
with me an hour ago?
- Yes, she left alone
Took a cab to the airport
The airport
Please step on it
[Woman On PA]
Last call
National Airlines,
flight 46 to New York,
gate number five
- All aboard
- Hello, Lucy
Hello
Please let me talk to you
I left, didn't I?
Didn't that say enough?
Yes, more than you know
Please give me an hour...
just till the next plane leaves
[Sighs]
All right
[Woman On PA]
Pan American World Airways Clipper,
flight 701
for Buenos Aires
and intermediate cities
now boarding
at Pan American concourse
- Cream?
- Never use it
Shows how little I know you
Why'd you run out?
I took a sudden dislike
to the suite
Did I overdo it?
Oh, it was beautiful
at first glance
Then I thought how ugly
it would be in the morning
You mean, the idea of
having fun?
Wasn't that your intention?
Guilty as charged
I was tempted
Was it easy to overcome?
Yes You made it easy
How, by throwing
my money at you?
- No No, it wasn't that
- What, then?
It was the ride
"Up in the blue,"
as you call it
Talked too much,
didn't I?
No It was good talk
Only something happened
to me...
something unexpected
as the things you told me
I tried to tell myself
it was, I don't know,
sympathy, compassion
But it was more
Let's
let's get out of here
Cigarette?
We'll put you on the next plane
to New York
Thank you
I'm sorry, Lucy...
sorrier than I've even been
in my whole sorry life
I hope you believe me
- Is it important that I do?
- Very,
because I
I want to start
all over again with you
How?
Suppose...
Just suppose I came
to New York again
Not to play,
but to work, to behave like...
like Tom, Dick and Harry
l-I'd ask you for dates,
take you to lunches,
to the movies
I'd be happy
with a good night kiss
[Sighs]
I'd think seriously about all
the things I used to laugh at,
like having a wife
and a home
and kids
Right now there's one thing
you don't have to suppose
I'm in love with you
So much so that
I want to marry you
- Mitch Wayne?
- Yeah
Jack Williams, Miami Press
- Uh, care to say a few words
about the wedding?
- What wedding?
We know that judge Ross issued
a marriage license this morning
to Kyle Hadley
and, uh, Lucy Moore
- So what?
- Who is Lucy Moore?
- That's a good question
- You don't know her?
- Not very well
- What is she?
A showgirl, model, what?
Just a girl... a lady
- A beautiful lady
- I got news for you, Mr. Wayne
Your torch is burnin'
- Wedding took place
two hours ago
- Yeah? Where?
- Right under my nose
St Mark's Church
- Oh
Uh, Mr. Wayne
Hey, now wait up, Mr. Wayne
- Pull up a chair
- Thank you, sir
- How does it look to you?
- Promising
How much
would you gamble on it?
I think we ought to go
15,000 feet
What do you hear from Kyle?
The gossip columns say
they're in Acapulco
When do you think I'm going to
get a chance to kiss the bride?
- Six months from now? A year?
- [Chuckles]
- It's only been five weeks
- Is that all?
It's about time you got hitched,
isn't it?
No, l... I have trouble enough
finding oil
[Chuckles]
I sure wish you felt different
about Marylee
We grew up together,
like brother and sister
I just can't see it
any other way
Yeah
It's a shame, though,
in a way
It's a real shame
- All right 5,000 feet No more
- Okay
- Hi
- Hi!
Mitch Mr. Hadley,
meet Mrs. Hadley
Welcome to Hadley...
the town and the family
Thank you
Well, son, l...
I just couldn't be happier
- Did all right, didn't I?
- You sure did
Now you vamoose for a few
minutes I want to talk
to my daughter-in-law alone
Sure, Dad
I'll be in Mitch's office
- Would you like a soft drink?
- No, thanks
Just had one
in the drugstore
- Have you been out
to the house?
- Yes, it's beautiful!
And it's home
- Did you meet Marylee?
- No, she was out
Oh, that's too bad
l-I know she's gonna like you
just as much as I do
I was afraid you might
be wary of me...
that, perhaps, you'd regard me
as a gold digger
[Laughs] Now, look
I'm gonna be honest with you
That's just what I figured,
until I talked to Mitch
Mitch? Interesting
Yeah I wasn't easy
to convince,
but Mitch sold me
In other words,
you trust Mitch's judgment
more than Kyle's
Well, I wouldn't put it
that way
- May I ask you a favor?
- Anything at all
Please give Kyle a chance
You may have to change
your opinion of him
How much liquor
has he been puttin' away?
I haven't seen him drunk yet
Does he still...
Well,
I better not ask about that
You mean, about the pistol
he keeps under his pillow
- You know
- Yes
I know all about his anxieties
and fears
You can forget
about the pistol
Kyle threw it in the ocean
- I tell you,
I'm still up on cloud seven
- And sober too
Yep, even in Mexico
Remember how I used to go
on those Tequila jags?
- How could I forget?
- [Intercom Buzzes]
- Yeah?
- A Mr. Willis calling
He says it's urgent
Okay, put him on
Dan Willis
- Mitch
- What is it, Dan?
The Hadley gal's here
with Roy Carter
Thanks, Dan
I'll be right over
- You got a gun here?
- Stay here I'll handle it
Dan said the Hadley gal
I'm the Hadley boy, remember?
[Laughing]
That's a hot one, ain't it?
Not very
I've heard better
What's the matter, honey?
Are you insulted?
Not yet
Just bored
The afternoon's wasting away
I'll be right back
How's the chances
of some privacy?
Are you crazy, Roy?
If old man Hadley
ever found out,
he'd have you sent so far away,
it'd take ten years
for a telegram to reach you
- Give me the key
- Forget it You're stepping
out of your class
You wouldn't like to have
this joint of yours catch fire
some night, would you?
Give me a couple of minutes
to clean up
Don't overdo it
[Car Approaching]
(music)(music) [Big Band]
If I ever catch you
with my sister again, I'll...
- Where do you want her
to play, in a sandbox?
- Honeymoon over?
Are you forgetting where you are
and who you're with?
Oh, be polite
Answer the lady
Tell us all about...
[Music Stops]
Marylee, come on
We're getting out of here
- Wait outside, Marylee
- [Gasps]
- Step aside, Wayne,
before I cut you
- I would like to see that
Hold it, Roy
You bigmouth beer slinger
You phoned Wayne, didn't you?
This gun's got a hair trigger
Okay
So I'm persuaded
- Some other time, huh?
- You've had it
- You take Kyle
and get out of here
- Thank you, Sir Galahad
You do care about me,
don't you?
- Let me have the gun, Dan
- Forget it
Forget it
I'll kill him
A whiskey bottle's
about all you'd ever kill
Sorry, Dan
[Engine Idling]
Mitch, let's go down to the river,
to our old haunt
We used to be happy there
Our own private world...
mine and yours
and Kyle's
Then you grew up and left me...
you and Kyle...
the rover boys
I guess that's why
I hate him so...
for taking you away
from me
I love you, Mitch
I'm desperate for you
So desperate, I run
to the likes of Roy Carter
All right, blame me
I'm not talking about blame
About love
Do you love me, Mitch?
Like a brother
I don't want you
as a brother
Can't be any other way,
Marylee
Don't... Please don't waste your life
waiting for me
I'll wait,
and I'll have you,
marriage
or no marriage
I'm Marylee
Welcome to Hadley, Sister-In-Law
Thank you
Nice of you to come in and greet me
Oh, please
I'm allergic to politeness
By the way, your darling
husband should be taught
to mind his own business
Should I apologize for him?
[Chuckles]
You should have seen him...
on the wrong end of every punch
And on the wrong end of town
It isn't 21, but
it can be exciting
What do you think of Mitch?
You changed the subject
Oh, there's a man for you...
or for me, rather
Kyle starts something,
Mitch finishes it for him
Kyle falls on his face,
Mitch picks him up
Kyle steals,
Mitch takes the blame
And there you have
the secret story of Kyle Hadley
and his electric personality
I've heard it
from Kyle himself
Anyway, about your marriage,
you have my condolences
Pardon me if, uh, I seem to be
brushing you out of my hair
Darling, I'll send you some
of my towels I believe you're
still wet behind the ears
[Door Slams]
[Dogs Panting]
What was the matter
with you today, son?
You were supposed to be
huntin', not broodin'
- I'm sorry, Dad
- [Dogs Whimpering]
[Dog Barking]
Sit Sit!
Anything we can talk about?
- Did you ever hear of Iran?
- Africa? Asia? Asia, I guess
- What about it?
- I'm thinking of going there
- For Hadley?
- No
Trans American Oil
- Got a bellyful of the Hadleys?
- I guess so
I sometimes wonder
if I did right by you...
puttin' you with jasper
and his kids
Meant it all for the best...
wanted you to have the chance
I had and didn't take
I better level with you, Dad,
about why I'm leavin'
I'm in love with a woman
that happens to be Kyle's wife
- Is she in love with you?
- No
Strictly one-sided
[Young Kyle's Voice]
Bet you can't throw that far, Mitch
[Young Marylee's Voice]
Mitch can do everything
better than you, Kyle
- [Kyle]
Shut up, Marylee
- Throw it, Mitch
- [Water Splashes]
- You did it, Mitch!
[Kyle]
Last one across is a rotten egg
[Water Splashing]
[Kids Panting]
[Young Mitch]
Hey, what's that purple stuff
on your lips?
Mulberry juice
Looks like lipstick, doesn't it?
Yeah, sure does
Mitch, am I beautiful?
- Uh-huh
- Do you love me?
Sure You're my girl
When we grow up,
you'll marry me, won't you, Mitch?
I love you so much
[Sobbing]
(music)(music) [Big Band]
[Chattering, Laughing]
It's gonna be a great football game
Could put us in the Cotton Bowl
Putting me in Dallas
is what I like about it
- I never know who's got the ball
- [Laughs]
(music)(music) [Plucking Ukulele]
(music)(music) [Strums]
A drink
for your thoughts
Congratulate me
I've just been voted
the life of the party
[Chuckles]
Your old room
- All those wonderful afternoons
we used to spend here
- (music)(music) [Playing Softly]
And it rained
Well, it was too cold for us
to go down to the river haunt
Yes, those wonderful
lost afternoons
That's a nice dress...
real flattering
I've changed since we
last swam in the raw, haven't I?
A long, long time ago
I was an idiot boy then
Yes, you were
The other idiot boy's downstairs
having himself a big party
It's a happy occasion, isn't it?
Unbelievable
Married a whole year
and still sober
and still faithful
It can't last much longer
Don't sell Lucy short
[Scoffs] There's only so much
a woman can do, and no more
I speak from
personal experience
with you
You know,
you're remarkable
You've got your axe buried
in Kyle's head, and you're
grinding it at the same time
- I can think of much better
things than making small talk
- Oh
All right Let's dance
[Sighs]
Still the idiot boy
Oh, thank you, Dad!
Oh, it's beautiful
Thank you, Lucy
What about the poor
struggling husband?
Don't I get anything?
- Well, what more
do you want, son?
- Another big party
Only next time,
we'll invite the stork
[Nervous Chuckle]
(music)[Waltz]
- Beats prescription liquor,
doesn't it, Doc?
- It sure does
Just a second, Doc, please
- Do me a favor
- just name it
Ask Lucy to pay you a visit
- She's been visiting me regularly
- She has?
Look, why don't we have
a powwow in my office
about 10:00 in the morning?
It won't keep
Tell me, is, is Lucy all right?
Well, what I mean is
can she have children?
- Tomorrow we'll sit down and...
- Now, Doc
Please
There's nothing wrong with Lucy
Well, your wife's
a wonderful dancer
Kyle, what's the matter?
- Come on Dance with me
- Can't
Somebody just stole my
magic dancing slippers
Anyone for lunch?
Don't tell me where
I'll find my way
Glory be Maybe you finally
see the light in my eyes
[Engine Starts]
Oh, there's nothing
like a picnic,
and I've brought everything
but rain and ants
Oh, correction
Everything but rain
[Blows]
Anything happen at the house
after I left the party?
[Chuckles]
Didn't miss a thing,
except the sight of me
sleeping in your old room
Did Kyle have a spat
with Lucy?
That's why you gave in
and came here with me...
to play 20 questions
Well, did he or didn't he?
I don't know
All I know is he bit
my head off this morning
Why?
What'd you say to him?
That he looked sick
All I said was, "I trust
it's nothing trivial"
- Do you...
- Oh, please
No more questions
Let's eat,
drink and be merry
We'll eat, drink and run
If Lucy were here with you,
I bet you wouldn't say that
I once washed your mouth out
with soap I can do it again
[Chuckles]
I know you, Mitch
No one will ever know you
as I know you
[Chuckles]
[Both Women]
Good morning, Doctor
- What's the story?
- I believe we'll have to make
some further tests...
What is it?
Yes or no?
Kyle, it's not that simple
No apologies Facts
- What'll you have, Doctor?
- Oh, just a limeade, Sherry
No ice
Yes, Doctor
The tests we took show a...
Well, let's call it a weakness
Believe me,
you're not sterile
And there is hope, real hope,
that, in time,
we'll be able to correct
that weakness
[Phone Ringing]
- Hello?
- Marylee, it's Mitch
Oh, yes Brother Mitch
Kyle just phoned me
He wants us, you and me,
to join him and Lucy
at the country club for dinner
Look, I'll pick you up
at 6:00, okay?
Don't bother, Mitch,
not unless you have
an exciting evening in mind
And you know exactly what I mean
by an exciting evening
[Grunts]
- Good evenin' Fill her up?
- Yes
You're Biff Miley, aren't you?
Nice of you to recognize me
without my shoulder pads
Your number's
in my program
I recognized you too,
Miss Hadley
You do?
What do we do now?
Break into a chorus
of"Hail, Alma Mater"?
I close up
in half an hour
You mean, usually
All right
Just keep the motor running
- (music)[Jazz]
- [Chattering, Laughing]
- Good evening, jack
Is Mr. Hadley here yet?
- Oh, yes, ma'am
Hello, Lucy
What's up?
I was hoping
you could tell me
I haven't seen Kyle since
he left the house this morning
He phoned me about an hour ago
and said we were having dinner
at the club
Well, he phoned me too
Kyle
Howdy
Good evening, Mrs. Hadley,
Mr. Wayne
Good evening
- Set 'em up, Ben
- Yes, sir
- Where's little sister?
- Couldn't locate her
She'll never, never be missed
- Will she, honey?
- Will she what?
Be missed
Haven't you learned to hate
Marylee as much as I do?
A toast to...
to beauty
and the truth,
which is anything but beautiful
Come on
Let's have some dinner
Honey, this is an occasion
We must proceed with,
with quiet dignity
What, um...
what are we celebrating?
The end of a drought...
a yearlong drought
We drank a toast to truth
- So?
- You ought to let us in on what
you're really celebrating
or mourning
[Laughing]
- Ben, quick The potions
- Yes, sir
So you'd like to know
my secret
The secret is
not to pour the vermouth, just
to pretend you're pouring it
[Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
Those lousy cops again
I'm sorry, Ralph
I didn't mean to blow up like that,
but I'm getting a little sick and tired
of your efficiency experts
They ought to get off
their chairs and out in
the field for a change
All right, Ralph
I'll see you in New York
Thursday morning Bye
I thought I'd seen
the last of this
I wish I could,
but I can't explain it
- Where have you been?
- The country club
- Did you have a spat?
- [Sighs] No
Nothing as simple as that
We let him drink,
hoping he'd talk and tell us
what was on his mind
But we learned nothing,
except that
he's terribly tormented
What are you
going to do now?
Go to him and try to help him
[Moaning]
Kid Kid stuff, Mitch
I want to buy a new car,
the first flashy car
To hell with college
I wanna have fun
with some girls
Nice over in Dallas
To hell with college
Wanna make some money, Mitch?
Over at the bottling plant
Old man Daley's place
[Chuckles]
No, I haven't got any bottles
Old man Daley has
[Moaning Continues]
Don't touch me
Touch me, I'll tell my father
That's what I'll do
My father
We weren't stealing,
were we, Mitch?
We were just stacking
some bottles up for you
That's all we were doing,
wasn't it, Mitch?
Mitch? Mitch
Wait for me
Wait for me!
I remember
I stopped the surgeon just
before he went in to operate
I said, " Doctor, I'll write
a check for a million dollars,
but just don't let my wife die"
But I failed
[Mutters]
I failed them all...
my wife
and my brother Joe
Both my children
I think you're being
too hard on yourself
[Car Approaching]
Where did you first meet
my daughter?
I never met her before, not till
she picked me up tonight
- She picked you up?
- Sure
- That's how she operates
- What do you mean, "operates"?
I never heard of anybody
pickin' her up That's all
It's always
the other way around
How would you know?
Why don't you just walk
up and down Main Street
and ask somebody?
I'm asking you!
Look, I don't like
to shoot my mouth off
I also don't like
being on the carpet
I didn't take her to the motel
She took me
Your daughter's a tramp, mister
If that ain't plain enough,
I could put...
- Get him out of here
- Should we hold him?
No Let him go
Keep it quiet, if you can
Thanks
Thanks a lot
[Engine Starts]
[Car Departs]
(music)(music) [jazz]
(music)[Continues]
- Kyle?
- Hmm?
When is it going to end?
You never know
Things have a way
of happening so suddenly,
unexpectedly
- What's wrong?
- What isn't?
Me and my darling sister...
we pushed Dad
down the stairs
You started drinking
before your father died
Yeah,
I was 14 years old
- Kyle
- Hmm?
Do you love me?
Love you?
I don't even love myself
Kyle, what is it?
Is it something I've said
or something I've done
or should have done?
I can't tell you
I'm afraid
It's like I was deep
in a mountain pass,
snowcaps hanging
over my head
If I make a sound,
snow might all come
tumbling down
Bury me alive
- Good morning
- Good morning, Lucy
- Would you like some coffee?
- Yes, thanks
You look ill
It's been a long week
Yeah
About time for me
to clear out
Bored?
Disgusted
Mostly with myself
But l...
I need you here
That's the only reason
I stayed... to help you
Not Kyle?
I made a resolution last week
It goes like this:
To hell with the Hadleys
[Sighs]
I'm a Hadley
Not to me, you're not
- I respect my marriage
- Haven't I?
Where are you going?
Going to see my dad Why?
Would you drop me off
in town?
What's the matter
with your car?
Nothing
All right
[Car Door Closes,
Engine Starts]
[Car Departs]
That was no lady
That was your wife
Where are they going?
I don't know
Where would you take
your best friend's wife?
You're a real sweet kid
Now be nice to me, brother
One morning we'll wake up,
and we'll be all alone together
Go on, sister
Tell me another pretty story
- Once upon a time, there was
a poor little rich boy
- Kyle Hadley, by name
- Who pickled his tiny brain
with gin and bourbon
- Not so Scotch
Till he got so stinking blind,
he couldn't see what was going
on right under his big red nose
But his charming, righteous
little sister did
Yes
She saw the end
of a marriage
and the beginning
of a love affair
You're a filthy liar
I'm filthy period
But you don't have to take
my word for anything
Just try keeping your head clear
and your eyes open
Why should you care?
You've never cared about me
- Or your wife
- Why are you putting
your two cents in?
Only because of Mitch
Because I've never had him,
and your wife has
Will you pick me up at the drugstore
in about an hour, please?
Better take a taxi
Am I that much trouble to you?
You don't know how much
I'll be waiting for you
When you figurin' on leavin'?
Monday morning
Flying all the way to Iran?
No, I'm gonna take a tanker
out of Baltimore
Places don't seem so far away
if you take a plane
Used to feel that way
about motor cars
What'd Kyle have to say?
Nothin'
Haven't told him yet
I'm waiting for him
to sober up
How's Kyle's wife?
Goin' through hell
Did she ever find out
just how you feel about her?
Yeah I about told her
this morning
How strong does she feel
about you?
I don't know
In about another hour or so,
I'm gonna find out
[Gun Clicks]
The car's over here
Stopped at the gun shop
Picked out a rifle
for my dad
for Christmas
What's the matter?
Well, I'll tell you
what's the matter with me
I'm leaving for Iran
next week
Trans American Oil
I can't keep holding back
how I feel about you, Lucy...
how I've felt ever since
the first day we met
I'm in love with you
No l-I have
to tell you something
- I've found out why Kyle's
been drinking so heavily
- Forget Kyle
- I'm talking about you and me
- Mitch, you've got
to listen to me, please
You know how much Kyle's always
talked about having children...
how badly he's wanted them
Dr Cochrane told him
he might never have any
Poor guy
Mitch, it was a medical opinion,
not a fact
I'm going to have a baby
That was for good-bye
Well, it's a beautiful day
for something or other,
isn't it?
- What's Kyle doing?
- You mean, right this minute?
- Yes
- Well, right this minute,
Kyle's out
Did he say
where he was going?
All I know is he hopped
into his car and he flew
- And I mean flew
- Was he drunk?
If he wasn't,
he was well on his way
(music)[Big Band]
You ought to take it
with you
Well, with you chasing me...
Can I level with you, Kyle?
Mr. Hadley to you
Well, it seems to me,
Mr. Hadley,
if I were one of the richest
men in the world,
I wouldn't be sitting
in a place like this
drinking raw corn
- What would you be doing?
- I'd be at the country club,
drinking bonded bourbon
- Nothin' but
- I like bootlegged corn better
It's full of memories
Each swig takes me back,
far back
You know, good ol' days,
when a fellow knew nothing
and cared less
[Phone Ringing]
Hello It's Mitch
No, sir He ain't here
I haven't seen him since
that last time You remember
Yeah Well, buzz me at home
if he drops in, will you?
Yeah, Mitch
Sure will Bye
[Wind Howling]
Excuse me, sir
Dinner is served
Thank you, Sam
It's rather pleasant here
without Kyle, isn't it?
Well, if it isn't
Smiling jack himself
[Car Approaching]
[Tires Screeching,
Engine Revving]
Hark, l-I think I hear
the master's kiddie car
I hope the drawbridge is down
[Car Door Closes]
[Front Door Closes]
My, you're a dandy group
[Laughing]
Bring me a cocktail
I can drink
Yes, sir
- I don't mean tomato juice
- Yes, sir
I suppose you're wondering why
I brought you all here tonight
[Laughing]
Now if his lights
would only go out
Kyle, would you please
come upstairs?
- You wish to confess?
- Please, Kyle
- Don't leave the country
- Please
Amusing, isn't he?
Very
Let's throw a party
Call up everybody we know
No party, huh?
What do you say to a plane ride?
We'll go to Acapulco
What do you say to Palm Beach?
- We'll decide about it
in the morning
- It'll be fun,
like turning back the clock
Palm Beach
I like that
It's got meaning
It's got signif...
[Laughs]
It's got meaning
Are you sure
your husband's out of town?
Sit down, Kyle
You said, "Sit down, Kyle"
That means bad news,
doesn't it?
No, it doesn't
The news couldn't be better
You know how you look now?
Like you did that night
at the Miami Airport,
when I took you
off the plane
Kyle, I went to see
Dr Cochrane this morning
He told you about me,
didn't he?
I said the news was good
What's good about it?
We're
we're going to have a baby
[Laughing]
You mean, adopt one
No No, our baby...
yours and mine
No No
No
Kyle, it's true
You shouldn't
have done that to me
You shouldn't have
What are you talking about?
Mitch
You and Mitch
Don't say that, Kyle
Don't even think it
What did you think?
You think I was just
a drunken idiot?
That I'd believe you?
That I'd let you use
my name? Take my money?
You all can rot in hell!
- You, Mitch and your little...
- Kyle, I've had nothing
to do with Mitch
- You dirty tramp!
- [Screams]
[Lucy Screaming]
Mitch
Get out
Get out before I kill you!
[Whimpers]
He hit me
Dr Cochrane, please
It's very urgent
She's asleep now
Give her one of these
when she wakes up
- How bad is she?
- She's weak, too weak to move
to the hospital till morning
She's had a miscarriage
- Good night, Marylee
- Good night, Doctor
- Your coat, Doctor
- Thank you
Mind if I ask you
an impertinent question?
Kyle had no cause
- Thanks Where is he now?
- I don't know
[Mitch]
He'd better not come back here
tonight I'll tell you that
- [Door Opens]
- [Doctor]
Call me if you need me
[Door Closes]
(music)[Jukebox: Big Band]
- You been in an accident?
- Get me a bottle of corn
- Maybe you ought to go
see a doctor
- I said a bottle!
You know who that is?
Kyle Hadley
The oil family
Well, what do ya know?
I thought he was a bum
That's five bucks
- I said five
- I'm buying something else
- Like what?
- That gun you keep
Put it in another sack
No sale
What's with you?
- Somebody tried to kill me
- Who?
My best friend
- What are you doing?
- The liquor's on the house
I'll give you 100
for the gun
I got business
to attend to
Take your courage
and leave me be
Oh, don't go!
- I'm just gonna
get you some water
- Oh, not yet, please
I don't wanna go to sleep yet
I just want to talk to you
Take me away, Mitch
Take me out of this house
- I will, in the morning
- No!
No, now I'm afraid
I won't leave you
[Whimpering]
Where is he?
I don't know, but wherever he is,
he'd better stay there
because if he comes back here,
I'll settle with him
Oh, no, Mitch Please
[Crying]
[Tires Screeching]
[Brakes Screech]
[Bottle Shatters]
[Whispering]
Shut up, woman!
[Gasps]
There's gonna be a killin'!
- I heard talk! I heard him!
- You heard nothin'
[Shuffling]
[Object Crashing]
[Dishware Shattering]
You lousy white trash
You no-account,
two-faced dog
I'm gonna watch you cringe
- Then I'm gonna put a bullet
in your belly
- For what, Kyle?
My best friend,
my lifelong pal
[Laughing]
What a laugh!
You crawlin' snake
You crept in here,
sponged off us Hadleys,
stole everything I ever wanted,
everything I ever had
Like what?
You made me small
in my father's eyes
You made my sister
spit at me
Then
you stole my wife
- I didn't take anything from you
- Lousy white trash, say a prayer
You know who you sound like?
Old man Daley
Remember old man Daley
and the bottles?
It was your idea
to steal them
I couldn't talk you out of it,
so I went along
But when he caught us, he didn't
blame you, he blamed me
And he grabbed me and he
kicked the tar out of me
I remember him saying,
"This is what Hadley gets
for letting his boy
play with trash like you"
He had you pegged right
You are trash!
I took the blame for stealing
those bottles, just like
I've always taken the blame,
but I'm not gonna take it
for this
Kyle, we've never lied
to each other
And I'm telling you now,
I never touched Lucy,
only because she's your wife
Get this straight
The child would have been yours
Not mine
Yours
- Lousy white trash!
- Kyle!
- [Gunshot]
Mitch?
Yeah?
What are we doing here, Mitch?
What are we doing?
Let's go down to the river
where we belong
[Mitch]
Operator, rush an ambulance
to the Hadley estate
I'll be down at the river,
waiting
Waiting
I was just thinking
You know,
you threatened to kill Kyle
The servants heard you
Also Dr Cochrane
and Yours Truly
So what?
I could tell the police
that I saw you kill
my dear brother
You could
On the other hand,
a wife wouldn't
and couldn't testify
against her own husband
You know, for a beautiful girl,
you can look real ugly sometimes
Ask yourself this:
Would I ever be enough for you?
I can talk you right into
the state penitentiary
You're sick, Marylee
Your sickness won't be cured
by marrying me
Before it's too late,
you'd better face up to yourself
Look how far we've come
from the river
Raise your right hand, please
Do you swear the testimony
you're about to give in this inquest
is the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
- I do
- [Judge]
Dr Cochrane,
would you tell this inquest
about the threat, please?
When I asked Mr. Wayne
where Kyle Hadley was,
he said, "I don't know,
but he'd better not
come back here tonight"
Thank you, Doctor
Next witness
My wife She said to me,
"There's gonna be a killin'
I heard talk Mr. Mitch said
he's gonna kill Mr. Kyle"
Thank you
Next witness
That's what I heard...
Mr. Mitch yellin'
and sayin' to Mr. Kyle,
"Get out of here!
Get out
be-before I kill you!"
- [Crying]
- Thank you Thank you
very much Next witness
Well, Kyle looked all beat up
I said, "What's with you?"
He said,
"Somebody tried to kill me"
I asked who, and he said,
"My best friend"
Did he mention a name?
No, he didn't have to
Why not?
Well, everybody knows
that Kyle's best friend
was Mitch Wayne
- Thank you, Mr. Willis
That'll be all Next witness
- [Murmuring]
Can you tell us if, at any time,
you heard Mitch Wayne threaten
to kill your husband?
Mitch Wayne did not kill
my husband
That wasn't my question
I asked you if, at any time,
you heard Mitch Wayne threaten
to kill your husband
- Yes, but...
- Thank you That will be all
Will Miss Hadley
step forward, please?
[Crowd Murmuring]
- [Man]
State your name, please
- Marylee Hadley
Do you swear the testimony
you're about to give
is the truth
and nothing but the truth?
- I do
- Be seated
You can refuse to answer
any question you may regard
as incriminating
What was your relation
to the deceased?
He was my brother
Exactly where were you at
the time Kyle Hadley was shot?
I repeat, Miss Hadley,
exactly where were you at
the time Kyle Hadley was shot?
You refuse to answer
the question?
Can you tell us anything
about the shooting?
Yes My brother,
he was killed
By whom, Miss Hadley?
By whom
was your brother killed?
- Mitch Wayne
- [Indistinct Chatter]
Stop those men!
No one will leave this chamber
till after this inquest is closed
[Chattering Continues]
Miss Hadley,
you named Mitch Wayne
Are you here and now
testifying
that Mitch Wayne shot
and killed Kyle Hadley?
Mitch Wayne was there
in the study
with my brother
Kyle had a gun in his hand
He was raving mad...
raving about things
that weren't so
Mitch tried
to talk to him,
to make him understand
how wrong he was,
to stop him
from using the gun
Afraid he might even use it
on himself
I made a grab for the gun
Kyle and I struggled
The gun went off
Miss Hadley,
five persons under oath
have testified that Mitch Wayne
threatened to kill Kyle Hadley
They don't know Mitch Wayne
as I know him
Whatever he may have said
means nothing
Except he was worried
about Kyle
as a brother for a brother
Why would Kyle Hadley
want to kill himself?
He was depressed
by Father's sudden death,
and he'd been drinking
Heavily?
[Sighs]
Yes
My brother always drank
too much
He was sad...
the saddest of us all
He needed so much
and had so little