Paola! Paola!
Here you go.
Thank you very much.
Good evening.
- Salaamun aleykum.
- Aleykum salaam.
Mustafa, candy?
Excuse me, which way is
Tophane?
Follow the right hand side.
It is 500 meters away.
- Salaamun aleykum.
- Aleykum salaam.
Salaamun aleykum.
Is lmam Ibrahim around?
What is it you want from
lmam Ibrahim?
I am the new muezzin.
Welcome brother!
Lmam Ibrahim is not here.
Come, take a sit. I will call him.
- Do you want some tea?
- Yes, I'll have some.
What is it, Sefik?
Salaamun aleykum.
I am the new muezzin.
Aleykum salaam and rahmetullah.
Welcome. Welcome.
Well, you are very young.
- Is this your first service?
- Yes.
Where are you from?
Ankara, Beypazary.
There was lmam Ebubekir
in Sincan.
We are friends from the religious
high school.
Both the mosque and the community
are very good here.
You will be pleased and
comfortable.
Here is your calendar and...
...these are the keys to
the mosque.
Which religous school
have you attend?
Beypazari.
- And university?
- Yes, theology.
Very good. Masallah.
Have you memorized the Koran?
No. Only the last sections
I don't have the rest.
We started working on it with
my father when I was a kid...
...but then we could not keep up.
- Your father?
- My father is an imam too.
Unsalaried though, not designated.
Imam Niyazi was staying here
before you.
He was from Tokat.
He asked to be reassigned
in his home town.
The furniture he left behind is clean.
There is a television too.
Do not waste too much time with it.
You may watch it from time to time.
I brought this from home. Lokum.
- I'll see you at morning prayer.
- Alright.
- Salaamun aleykum.
- Aleykum salaam.
Can you move there?
I've just moved in to your next door.
I need a screwdriver,
if you have one.
Thank you.
Come on, Musa.
You'll finish it later.
Let me introduce.
Musa is the new muezzin.
Welcome.
Imam Davut is an old member
of our community.
Will you have some?
There is cheese, there is simit.
There is everything.
Anybody there?
I am stuck in elevator.
The elevatorjust stopped.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Here is your screwdriver.
Thank you for yesterday.
If it was not for you, I would stay
stuck in the elevator.
I am grateful.
How may I help you?
Good day.
The church is closed right now.
The afternoon service will be
at one o'clock.
All right, thank you.
Menakibül Arifin
(Legends of the Sages)
Excuse me?
The book. Menakibül Arifin.
Looks like you know each other.
Yes. She is my neighbor.
How come you speak Ottoman?
From school.
Which school?
The religious school.
I am serving as a muezzin
in a nearby mosque.
Is that so?
Do you have an interest for books?
Yes, a little.
Then you should certainly
pay me a visit?
- Thank you.
- You are welcome.
You must have dropped it.
- Salaamun aleykum.
- Alaykum Salaam.
Do you remember me?
We met yesterday.
- At the church.
- Yes.
Please come in.
Sorry to trouble you.
Trouble? No! Please enjoy your tea.
- Do you have sugar?
- Sugar?
- Alright, I got it.
- It is in the kitchen.
There are lots of books.
Well, it makes a living.
To whom are you selling these?
To whoever is interested.
Not an easy job.
Actually I am looking for
an assistant.
For the Ottoman texts.
I would be very glad if
you are interested.
Well you know, I am a muezzin.
I would like to come between
prayer times, if it will be enough.
It won't be a problem for me.
- Also the pay will help you as well.
- Well, okay.
What's up bro?
What are u doing here?
- I have been assigned to Istanbul.
- Assigned?
I became a muezzin.
Very good bro, I hope it's best for you.
Thank you.
My dad told me to stop by
Hadji Müfit sometime.
- So I brought his greetings.
- Very nice of you.
He is around,
he should be here soon.
What about you? Have you finished
memorizing Koran?
- Yes, I have.
- Good.
You rascal!
I should get going.
You make yourself comfortable,
have something to eat.
Tevfik! Help my guest.
There is no need brother.
I should drop by a couple of places.
I have some things
to be taken care of.
Which mosque you said?
Karabas Mustafa Pasha Mosque,
in Tophane.
I hang around there a lot
to smoke narghile.
- I will find you there.
- Anytime, brother.
Write down your mobile number.
I haven't got a phone yet.
You call me then.
If you will need anything
I am around.
I am in a rush now.
Please excuse me.
Yes, sure.
You take care of your business.
Tevfik, look after here!
- See you brother.
- I'll see you.
I am waiting!
Hello Mr. Suha.
The books have not arrived yet.
Sure.
I'll bring it myself, sir.
I am on it.
No problem.
Have a good day.
- Hello dear Lütfi.
- Hello dear Yakup.
Let me introduce.
Musa, Mr. Lütfi.
Nice to meet you.
- The books have arrived.
- Great.
Come, have a seat.
- Here is the delivery.
- Thank you.
Musa is my new assistant.
Is that so? How nice...
- His Ottoman is very good.
- Great.
These books are sold out.
They are very difficult to find,
you know.
You are right.
Bukowski, Women.
Be careful!
Musa is a muezzin.
Is that so? Very nice.
Please tell my greetings
to Miss. Anna.
There is this bookseller
I sometimes visit.
What bookseller bro?
He buys and sells second hand books.
So...
So I work with him.
Do you make some money?
Why is Hadji Müfit get mad at you?
I do not give a fuck.
He was the same
when we were at the course.
Don't you remember?
- You aren't married, are you?
- No.
- Hi.
What if it gets broken again?
Here you go.
Why are they handing
the shop ever?
Maybe the owner went bankrupt.
All these books will be under priced.
Yakup, this is thorn.
- Come on have some simit?
- Thanks. I had breakfast.
Will you excuse me, may I go?
We expect you to dinner,
don't make plans.
Ok, hopefully.
Can you show some stuff
to your bookseller.
Okay. I will make some tea.
There is a good looking chick
in your apartment.
What chick?
I saw her when I was waiting for you.
She's a blonde.
- She's my neighbor.
- Nice.
- She's a Christian.
- Really?
- Nun.
- No shit man!
Her clothes were regular.
Well, I wouldn't know.
I just saw her at the church.
What were you doing
at the church?
Is this the book?
You are a complicated man.
Well, honestly she is beautiful.
Anyway you can
make her convert to Islam.
You would acquire merit
at God's sight.
Let him take a look at those.
Okay. I will show them
to brother Yakup.
I couldn't have finished
even one book.
So finish it.
- What about this Yakup?
- What about him?
- Is he trustable?
- Yes of course he is.
Everywhere is full of swindlers.
That's why I asked.
We are coming.
The prayer is just over.
He is with me, we are coming.
Women! As if we run away.
So, have are you getting along with
the community at the mosque?
Very good. Thankfully,
there has not been any problem.
- They also liked you very much.
- I am glad.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
- Make yourself comfortable.
- I am, thanks.
- Are you engaged?
- I am not.
I guess it will be my duty
to help you get married.
As fortune wills.
- Any candidate?
- How do you mean?
I mean candidate.
No.
You say no in a way as if
there is a candidate.
No, really there isn't.
Come on know.
I got it!
Who is she?
What is she like?
Come on tell me.
It is a fortunate affair Musa,
you shouldn't be ashamed.
Is she religious?
Yes.
Masallah.
You won't get hurt by a believer.
- As fortune wills.
Good morning.
Wellcome Musa.
How is it going?
Thank you.
I wanted to drop by
after the prayer.
Good...
I have some things to show you.
Will you have a look at them?
Put them on the table.
I'm coming.
Are they worth anything?
Where did you get these?
I have a relative, he gave them to me.
Take them back immediately.
What is it?
Do as I tell you.
Alright, but I didn't get why?
These pieces belong to the museum.
Don't ever bring these kinds of
things to me without asking.
Alright, I'll give them back tomorrow.
Give them back today.
Alright I will give them after
the noon prayer.
Salamun aleykum.
This is Musa.
I am fine.
Look, I showed the papers
you gave me to brother Yakup.
He is not interested.
Yes, since he said that
I couldn't insist.
When shall I give these back to you?
Could it any be sooner?
Alright.
I'll see you then.
- How much?
- 2.25
- Hi.
Are yo headed home?
Yes. No, I have things to do.
I will come later.
- Have a good day.
Police. Hands up!
Keep silent!
- Are you Musa?
- Yes.
Handcuffs!
Wear these.
Why didn't you sell
the mosque too?
Swindler!
Brother!
Shut up!
Yakup.
I swear I didn't know anything.
God is my witness, I swear
I am innocent, I swear.
Okay, okay I know.
You told me to take them back.
So I called Ayhan, I told him
to come and take them.
He was also stealing cars.
They found one of those pages
in its truck.
I swear this is the first time
I am hearing these.
I haven't been seeing him
for years.
We are going to my place.
No, I would better go to
my own place.
No, I can't accept that.
I will make you some soup,
it will be good for you.
You don't look well.
Each day of old age is like this.
We are going to my place brother,
I don't accept any objection.
Musa, let me go to my place.
Besides I can't make myself
comfortable anywhere else.
I will be offended if you keep
saying anywhere brother.
I spoke to lmam Ibrahim...
...I will be at home anyway.
Okay then, so be it.
I couldn't even call you.
I didn't know what to do.
I was too afraid and baffled.
Allah allah!
What kind of a man he was?
I was curious.
I asked you to the neighbors,
they told me.
Who told you?
That non-Muslim woman living
in your next door.
She said police was there.
God protected me.
Well, it is over now.
Yakup, meal is ready.
Yakup?
Quick quick, something happened
to brother Yakup.
Water!
A glass of water.
There is nothing to worry
about for the time being.
Good. Thank God.
We opened the blocked vessel
with a stent.
But in order to prevent
future complications...
...he should take his medicines
and stay under cardiologic inspection.
- So we will be here for a while.
- Yes for another day.
The sand bags should stay
two more hours.
Okay. Thank you very much.
I shall go. I hope he'll
get better soon.
Thank you.
Thank you. What can I say,
thank you.
- Clara.
- Clara. Musa.
Clara.
I brought it here when I went to
get your clothes.
- Are you alright?
- I am fine.
I am going to prayer,
do you need anything?
Thank you.
I will come back quickly.
Hi.
She is paralyzed but at least
she is alive.
What was she doing for a living?
- Nun.
- You said, my mother.
She is not my real mother but
she is like a mother to me.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
You are welcome too Musa.
Clara made some soup for me.
- Lf you could excuse me.
- But you've just came.
- I would better go.
- At least have some coffee.
- Alright.
- I'll make the coffee.
Thanks to Yakup, I learned
how to make coffee too.
If only I could drink it...
That night, I don't know what
would I do if you weren't here.
- Thank you for the coffee.
- You're welcome.
I was so surprised to see her here.
I thought I was at the wrong house.
Yakup, if you love your God don't!
I'm not saying anything Musa.
When did she come?
The place was quite a mess.
Right before you came.
I couldn't make it to? Ile.
I still have an unfinished
business there.
Don't worry about that business.
We'll take care of it.
I guess I missed that opportunity.
It was a good job though.
- Salaamun aleykum.
- Aleykum salaam.
Musa, I will go to my own place,
I have a lot to do.
No, I won't let you go before
you are fully recovered.
I should also go to Sile.
Mr. Süha's books are at home.
I can take whatever you need,
don't worry.
Clara is my daughter.
We were together with
her mother in Italy.
Anita followed me back here.
I found about that much later.
Clara was born in a church
in Istanbul.
Her mother died after she gave birth.
I have been looking for
my daughter for a long time.
Where were you back then?
In the prison.
Political.
She is dead.
You will be staying at Bianca's.
They should call you soon.
If you will have an emergent need
call me.
- I should get going.
- Alright.
Wait wait!
There are some clothes there,
have a look at them.
Ok.
- Musa.
- Yes.
- Shall we invite Clara to breakfast?
- Ok.
- Is she coming?
- She is not at home.
Her lights were off last night too.
Clara is still not around.
- May it be easy brother.
- Welcome.
I am making some coffee.
Why don't you play some music?
I don't have a player.
Then you take care of the coffee,
I will go shuffle the radio.
Coffee is ready.
It is really bitter.
Drink, you'll get used to it.
Yakup, are you going to tell Clara?
I am scared.
What if I tell her?
- No.
- Why?
I'm waiting for the right time.
- What shall I fix for the dinner?
- I invited Clara this evening.
Really?
- Here you go sir.
- Thank you.
Who wants cola?
- I'll have some.
- I'll have some too.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Do want some more.
What time we are leaving
tomorrow morning?
We'll see.
I say we should go early
in the morning.
Ok.
It will be my first time in Sile.
- You have never been there?
- No.
Me neither.
I believe you'll tell Clara today.
- No, I can't.
- Why?
I am scared.
I will tell her then.
No.
Why?
I'm waiting for the right time.
Do you want some tea?
I will pick you up from here
in two hours.
Welcome. Do you want
your picture taken?
No, thanks.
Only one picture, as a souvenir.
Ok, then.
Can you move there?
Can you get closer?
A little more closer.
Closer brother!
- Alright come on now, take it.
- Ok. One, two...
You are half of the frame.
Let me take another one?
It's okay. No problem.
Let me take another one.
Alright, it is okay, thank you.
The color of the sea will be
different in fall.
We will come back in fall then.
I can't.
Why?
I will not be here.
I will go to Italy, to become a nun.
Good night.
- I will not be coming Musa.
- Why?
That's the way...
Good bye.
Clara...