Subtitles by DramaFever
[The Princess Weiyoung]
[Episode 44]
Convey my decree.
Behead Li Wei Young for the murder
of Princess An Le in three days.
- Your Highness.
Open the door.
- Yes.
You are all dismissed.
Yes.
What brings you here?
What exactly happened?
Why would you be accused
of Princess An Le's murder?
I've reminded you so many times
to act cautiously.
Why would you get involved
with Princess An Le?
How does that concern Your Highness?
The envoy of Rouran is using this matter
to cause a fuss.
He kept pressing Grandfather
for a verdict.
Grandfather is furious about it
and will vent his frustration on you.
So?
It is but a life that he takes.
Moreover, wouldn't you be pleased
that I get killed for it?
You can get rid of your impediment now.
You can live happily ever after
with Li Chang Le.
Wei Young, what nonsense is that?
Have I said anything false?
To you, I'm the murderer
who killed your mother.
I'm a despicable and heinous villain.
Li Chang Le is beautiful,
gentle, and virtuous!
What are you doing here
instead of with her?
Are you here to bade me farewell?
- Wei Young, listen to me...
- Don't!
I don't want to hear a word!
Wei Young.
Have you no trust in me anymore?
Am I that unbearable to you?
Have you trusted me?
I kept telling myself again and again
that you have every reason
not to trust me.
I can't blame you. I shouldn't hate you.
But I wanted so much for you to trust me.
Trust in who I am.
There's no need for witnesses
or evidence. Just believe me.
Just believe in what I am!
Believe every word I say!
But you didn't! You didn't at all!
You still married Li Chang Le.
Wei Young... I'm sorry.
I truly never wanted to hurt you.
Please believe me.
I'm really here to help you.
How could you
when you don't believe me at all?
I don't wish to place my hopes
on a man who doesn't trust me!
You may leave now, Your Highness.
I never want to see you again.
We'll just pretend that nothing
ever happened between us.
You...
Are you never ever going to see me again?
What are you doing?
Let go of me!
No matter what you say,
I won't leave you.
- Let go of me.
- I already did that once.
I don't ever want to
go through that agony again.
Li Wei Young, listen.
I will never let you go again.
Do you know what you're saying?
Listen to me, Li Wei Young!
You have me wrong.
You're the most precious person to me.
How could I not believe you?
I know that you're innocent.
I knew it all along.
I never stopped loving you.
I know that... you didn't kill my mother.
And I was forced into
marrying Li Chang Le.
This is the truth.
I used Li Chang Le to lure out Tuoba Yu.
They are the real culprits
who had my mother killed.
Why didn't you tell me this sooner?
Tuoba Yu is one shrewd man.
He is very powerful.
Once he senses anything suspicious
he might do anything to take me down
just to get the throne.
If so, hundreds of people in
my household would be in peril.
As for you, it's likely that
you'd be in danger again.
Hence, I opted to act powerless
and slowly built up my power
away from the limelight so as
to pounce at the right time.
However, I have no other choice
but to tell you the truth now.
I can only save you
if you believe me.
You actually believed me all this time.
But in the beginning...
My mother's death dealt
a huge blow to my heart.
But then when I went over the case,
I spotted many questionable factors.
Grandfather wanted you dead.
I really had no other choice
but to make a pact with Tuoba Yu
and ended up marrying Li Chang Le.
Wei Young, do you know how upset I was
when I saw you at the wedding?
When I had to hurt you
in order to win Li Chang Le's trust
I was in such agony.
But what pained me the most
was that I was so helpless.
I could only watch you suffer
without doing anything to help you.
Before I'm capable of protecting you
distancing myself from you was
the best protection I could offer.
It really was you who has been
protecting me in secret.
I was framed for poisoning the empress
and I was really puzzled
about how swiftly
Ninth Princess discovered the evidence
to prove Madam Lin framed me.
And the other time when
I was nearly killed near the well
you didn't happen to just pass by.
You came over especially to rescue me.
I guessed that Prince of Dongping
would try to kill you.
But I still didn't make it in time
to save Bai Zhi.
After Bai Zhi was killed, I heard someone
playing the zither for me all night.
It really was you.
I should have stayed by your side
to comfort you when you were upset.
But that was all I could do then.
I'm sorry, Wei Young.
I made you suffer so badly.
Will you forgive me?
You have thought of me so much.
How could I possibly blame you?
I was the one who kept
holding a grudge.
I hated you.
I even said such hurtful words to you.
Do you blame me?
Silly woman.
Only when there is love
could there be hate.
Doesn't that mean you still love me?
In this lifetime, how could I
love anyone else but you?
What about Li Chang Le?
Despite everything,
she is already your wife.
I've never loved Li Chang Le.
Nothing ever happened between us.
Since I discovered that
she was behind my mother's death
how could I still treat her as my wife?
Once I have the evidence
I will report to Grandfather
to punish her as she deserves.
What matters the most now
is proving your innocence.
I believe that you would never
kill Princess An Le.
Wei Young, we've pulled through
so many obstacles together.
I'm sure that we will
get through this safely too.
Try to recall some details from
the time you met Li Chang Ru.
Perhaps we might find some evidence.
Young Mistress!
What's the matter?
I'm fine.
It was just a prick.
Young Mistress,
after Li Wei Young is killed
will Prince of Nan-An really
bury you alive with her?
Prince of Nan-An is a man
of great ambitions.
Li Wei Young just bewitched him.
Once she is dead,
he will come to his senses.
He will then know
whom he should truly care about.
Forgive me for speaking out of turn.
Prince of Nan-An is a cold-blooded man.
He's not the right spouse for you.
Young Mistress, shouldn't you
plan a way out of this?
Once I've made my choice,
how is there any way out of it?
The prime of my youth...
All of my affection...
Every effort I made...
They were all devoted to this man.
How is there any way out for me?
I'd like to see how Li Wei Young
could make it out of this alive.
If you hadn't testified for me
it wouldn't have gone so well.
You're right.
Li Wei Young is our mutual enemy.
I felt such joy in seeing
my enemy defeated.
What is it? You don't seem well.
Li Wei Young will soon be executed.
Aren't you happy about it?
Since the outcome is as expected,
it's no pleasant surprise.
You're getting better every time.
I'm just curious.
How did you kill Princess An Le?
I didn't kill her.
Why would you lie to me?
How could it not be you?
Everything is closely connected
and you're even her alibi.
As long as you're pleased
with the outcome
why would the process
be any concern of yours?
[Imperial Dungeon]
- Your Highness.
Wei Young.
Don't worry.
Listen to me.
You'll be executed in two days.
I couldn't think of any way to save you.
You're going to save me?
Of course.
If you die, I...
Whom am I to marry?
I'm already in this predicament.
I'm in no mood for your jokes.
All right.
I'll cut to the chase.
The only way to save you is
to get you a substitute.
You're going to swap prisoners?
This is no trivial matter.
Compared to your life,
nothing else matters as much.
I have already chosen
the suitable prisoner.
She will be sent in tomorrow.
By then, it will all be arranged.
Don't tell anyone.
Just follow my orders.
Your Highness need not worry.
I will be fine.
You're in the Imperial Dungeon.
You're still so confident?
Yes.
I still have much left to do.
Interesting.
Once we take out Li Wei Young
it's about time to tackle Li Chang Ru.
Unfortunately, that woman
is as cunning as a fox.
She refused to tell me the details
of Princess An Le's murder.
Otherwise, I would then
have something on her.
Isn't Miss Chang Ru on your side?
She will marry Prince of Nan-An.
If I still collaborate with her
am I to assist her
in going against my own husband
to help Prince of Nan-An
seize the throne?
That won't do.
His Majesty thinks highly
of His Highness.
The throne should surely be
passed down to His Highness.
Your Highness, that will make you
the empress, mother of the nation.
Madam Chiyun had your destiny foretold
as the future empress.
It's now coming true.
However, Li Chang Ru
is no ordinary woman.
If we are to tackle Prince of Nan-An...
we will have to get rid of her first.
Li Wei Young.
His Majesty wishes to see you.
Greetings to Your Majesty.
This woman is to be executed tomorrow.
Why is she summoned to the palace today?
Don't be so anxious.
I shall clear your doubts soon.
Li Chang Ru, do you still
adhere to your testimony?
At noon on the day of the murder
you didn't see Li Wei Young.
Yes, Your Majesty.
At that time, you were out
with Princess Consort of Gaoyang?
Yes.
Your Majesty, what are you trying to say?
Nothing.
It's just that I've found a witness
to prove Li Wei Young innocent.
A witness?
Where is that witness?
Summon the witness!
Greetings to Your Majesty.
Princess!
You... You're not dead?
Prince Yuan Lie.
Tell him what exactly happened.
Here's the story, Your Majesty.
I'm ashamed of it.
My sister wanted to sneak out
of the palace
but she was discovered by my guards.
Then she was brought to me.
Princess, what happened?
Did someone try to harm you?
Princess An Le.
If you still won't tell us the truth
I'll send a letter to
your father right away.
Let's see how he will punish you.
Please don't, Your Majesty.
I'll just be honest with you!
I never wanted to be a part
of this marital treaty.
Before I came to Great Wei,
I already had a sweetheart.
We made a plan to escape
when I got out of the palace.
I caused trouble quite a few times
in order to break the treaty.
Your Highness! How could you do so?
What about that corpse in the well?
I found the corpse of
a maid who had recently passed away.
I put her in my clothes
and dumped her in the well.
Then I had my maid announce
my disappearance.
I changed into the maid's outfit
that I prepared in the morning.
I fled to Cold Palace
(where concubines are banished).
I pretended to be ill
and avoided the search.
I heard that a batch of maids
were to be released today.
I had wanted to blend in with them
and sneak out.
Who knew that I would still get caught?
Security is airtight in the palace.
How is it just some place
you could come and go at will?
Your Majesty, please have mercy
on me and let me out of here!
I don't wish to be married off to Wei.
I believe that your princess doesn't
want to be married off to Rouran either.
There are many ways to establish
bonds between nations.
Why must women's happiness
always be sacrificed for it?
Please have mercy on me!
Your Highness, how could you say that?
Envoy.
You should now know
what really happened.
The people of Wei
didn't murder your princess.
Your princess caused this
huge disturbance because of her escape.
She nearly caused
an innocent person to be killed.
But all sorts of evidence pointed
to Li Wei Young as the murderer.
Li Wei Young murdered me?
Of course not!
At that time, I saw Li Wei Young...
She was with her!
They were talking by East Corridor.
I saw them when I passed it.
Your Majesty, I...
Envoy.
In order to prevent Princess An Le
from escaping again
she will be under
our surveillance for now.
As for the marital treaty,
we shall leave it until later.
Yes, Your Majesty.
After all, we are to be blamed
for this accident.
I apologize to Your Majesty
on behalf of Rouran.
Your Majesty is very forgiving.
Please don't hold it against An Le.
Anyone there?
Take Princess An Le away
and attend to her.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I will take my leave now.
I will take my leave.
Li Chang Ru.
How dare you!
You dared to deceive the emperor?
It isn't so, Your Majesty!
It isn't so!
Summon Princess Consort of Gaoyang!
Greetings to Your Majesty.
Princess Consort of Gaoyang.
Answer me.
When Princess An Le went missing
when did you meet with Li Chang Ru?
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.
Although I did chat with my cousin
in the Imperial Garden that day
I couldn't be certain
that it was noon.
But you sounded so positive.
You confirmed that
you met Li Chang Ru at noon.
It was because
I asked my cousin for the time.
Her maid misled me
by saying that it was noon.
Now that I think about it, my cousin
must have wanted to use me.
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.
I was too quick to believe others.
I nearly got Wei Young killed.
Please punish me, Your Majesty.
All right.
You may leave.
No...
Li Chang Ru.
We were at least cousins once.
Why did you have to frame me?
Your Majesty!
This is a misunderstanding!
I wouldn't dare deceive Your Majesty!
A misunderstanding?
Do you take me for a fool?
Can you toy with me as you wish?
I...
Anyone there? Drag her out!
Please spare my life, Your Majesty!
For the sake of the Li family's
loyalty to Your Majesty
- please spare me!
- Drag her out!
Please spare me! Your Majesty!
- Go!
- Please spare me, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty!
You can't kill me because I'm carrying
Prince of Nan-An's child!
Your Majesty, Miss Li is indeed pregnant.
- Step out.
- Yes.
Prince of Nan-An...
Is Li Chang Ru telling the truth?
Is it really your child that she carries?
Father, the child Li Chang Ru carries...
It's truly mine.
It was a moment's folly.
Please forgive me, Father.
Li Chang Ru, since you're carrying
the offspring of the imperial family
I will spare your life.
However, I would never accept
a daughter-in-law of such misconduct.
I shall decide on my verdict
after you have given birth to the child.
Thank you for sparing my life,
Your Majesty.
Anyone there?
Take her away to be
settled in the palace.
Attend to her carefully.
Thank you, Your Majesty!
Li Wei Young.
You have been greatly wronged.
Don't worry. I will seek revenge for you.
Now that Rouran has made
such a huge error
I have to use
this opportunity to punish them.
Otherwise, how could I face
the ancestors of Great Wei?
You mustn't, Your Majesty!
Why not?
Should this incident
be made known to the people
they will surely mock
Rouran and Princess An Le.
But then after all the jesting,
people would think that
the mighty emperor was actually fooled
by a young princess of Rouran.
Grandfather, we mustn't let
Great Wei become a laughingstock.
That is for certain.
Why don't we just act
as if nothing has happened
and then whoever was marrying
will proceed as planned?
No!
Father... I already learned that
Princess An Le has a sweetheart.
She would even feign her death
to elope with him.
How could I marry someone like her?
Are we not to uphold the dignity
of Great Wei anymore?
Exactly.
We mustn't be humiliated by them.
Father!
Will Father really send me away
to suffer in that place?
Princess An Le was right.
Why must peace between nations
be attained by
the sacrifice of a woman's happiness?
Father, please!
Don't marry me off to that place!
Father!
Please reconsider carefully, Grandfather.
Such a marriage alliance is meaningless.
Rouran isn't strong enough
to invade us now
but what happens
when their army is powerful?
Would they still care about
this marriage alliance?
Grandfather, please don't sacrifice
Aunt Di's happiness for nothing.
I don't want to be married off.
Father.
Your Majesty.
Since neither of the princesses
consent to this marital treaty
why doesn't Your Highness
just allow Ninth Princess
to stay with you
and keep you company?
Father.
I don't want to be married.
Thank you, Father!
All right now, stop crying.
His Majesty isn't watching anymore.
I'm really sad!
My good nephew!
What you just said is fantastic!
I haven't doted on you in vain.
I'm lucky enough not
to have been scared to death
by participating in your daring plan!
I am grateful to
Sister Wei Young for saving me.
If it hadn't been for you
I'd surely have fallen for
Li Chang Ru's tricks!
Do you think that I don't understand
why you're deliberately acting up?
If you dare
hurt Wei Young again
don't blame me for
disregarding our kinship!
I just want to be with the man I love!
What wrong have I done?
Min De?
Wei Young!
Wei Young.
Here, slowly.
Take a seat first.
Slowly...
What brings you here?
I came over here to tell you
that I suspect Li Chang Ru of
plotting against Princess An Le.
What nonsense are you talking about?
An Le, shut up!
Hear Wei Young out first.
Min De, how is
the favor I asked of you going?
I've looked up the entry and exit records
for the day of Bai Zhi's death
as you requested.
Li Chang Ru was indeed in the palace.
Judging from her entry and exit hours
there's indeed a possibility
that she murdered Bai Zhi.
That timid and gentle Li Chang Ru?
How could she be Bai Zhi's murderer?
How I wish it wasn't so.
I've always treated her like a sister.
However, during this period of time,
so much evidence has been laid before me
that I have no choice but to believe it.
Also, I've noticed eunuchs
spying on Princess An Le.
Therefore, I'm worried that
Li Chang Ru's next target is you.
But... There's no animosity
between me and her.
It isn't exactly so.
I heard that before the marriage alliance
Li Chang Ru was also a candidate
for Prince of Nan-An's consort.
Hence, I suspect that
Li Chang Ru spread rumors
to make Your Highness misunderstand me.
Do you mean that she's using me
to get rid of you?
It was no secret that we had an argument.
If you now meet with a mishap
I will surely be the prime suspect.
By then, Princess An Le will be dead
and you'll be executed for murder.
Kill two birds with one stone.
It's going to be easy for her to become
Princess Consort of Nan-An
with her craftiness.
Isn't she simply too scary?
Now that I'm already on my guard,
we will have to react cautiously.
It's just that Chang Ru was once
my closest sibling in Li Manor.
I wish that it all turns out
to be nothing more than my imagination.
Judging by Li Chang Ru's personality
she will surely make the next move.
Therefore, Min De, you must be sure
to protect Princess An Le in secret
to prevent her from being harmed.
Let's go.
Quickly!
Fortunately, it was nothing
more than a scare this time.
You are all way too daring.
If anything went wrong,
Princess An Le would be dead.
As long as the marital treaty could be
annulled, I'm willing to take the risk.
Wei Young.
Don't attempt anything risky
with them again.
I still have work to attend to.
You've been tired these days as well,
so go and get some rest.
Aunt Di.
Princess An Le.
I will take my leave now.
Yuan Lie, can I go sightseeing?
Go on!
I'll take my leave now.
Be careful.
I've been meaning to ask you.
What now? Have you made up?
You don't blame him anymore?
I've misunderstood him all this time.
He has been secretly protecting me.
He has his own reasons.
I knew it.
How could he possibly
be so ruthless to you?
So it was indeed a misunderstanding.
Anyway, it makes me happy to
see both of you reconciled.
As of now, so much has changed.
We still have a long way to go.
Wei Young, thank you for
what you did this time.
We are family.
Why are you so polite?
If anyone is to be grateful
it should be me.
If you hadn't been around to help me
I would never have been able
to expose Li Chang Ru.
I thought that she could
get a taste of her own medicine
but who knew
she and my brother are actually...
That even saved her life.
I'm so annoyed about it.
I've always trusted her so deeply.
Who knew that my trust in her
would get Bai Zhi killed?
So many other people were also harmed.
Wei Young, don't be too upset.
Moreover, I don't think that
she will just call it quits.
His Majesty might have
punished her
but no one can say for sure
what the future holds.
Besides, she is also one crafty woman.
Wei Young, you must be careful
from now on.
I already see her for who she really is.
Therefore, I won't allow her a chance
to hurt anyone else again.
Wei Young, are you all right?
I'm fine.
I seem to have been stung by something.
Stop right there!
What did you do to Wei Young?
Your Highness seems to have forgotten
about the promise you made to our Khan.
If you can't attain Wei's
"Chart of Six Elements in Army Defense"
you won't be able to
save Li Wei Young's life.
- Just now...
- Fret not, Your Highness.
Li Wei Young was but slightly stung.
If you put off the mission any longer
I will carry out our Khan's orders
to use fatal hidden weapons on her.
Don't act recklessly!
"Chart of Six Elements in Army Defense"
is a confidential document.
How could I attain it easily?
I need some time.
It isn't that you don't have
enough time to do it.
You've wasted all your time
on Li Wei Young.
You...
If I didn't take your feelings
into consideration
why would I work with you to
put on an act before the emperor?
In my opinion,
you never intended to steal
"Chart of Six Elements in Army Defense"
for Rouran.
You're right.
I don't.
The six elements are the key
to defending Great Wei against Rouran.
Once the strategy is deciphered
Rouran would come barging right in!
By then, it would be a catastrophe
for the people of Great Wei!
You are of Rouran descent, not Wei!
You dumped me here!
You allowed me to be raised in Wei!
Yet now you're telling me that
I don't belong to Wei?
Why did you come looking for me?
Why would you force me to harm
those who raised me?
Our Khan had made plans!
He wanted you to take his throne!
Once you attain "Chart of
Six Elements in Army Defense"
you can win over the support
of the officials with it!
My prince, why can't you understand
the great pains our Khan took?
I never wanted the throne!
Rouran is a foreign land to me.
Those brothers who are always
wary of me don't see me as their kin!
If I could, I'd stay
in Great Wei forever!
I wish to stay with those
who truly care about me.
All in all, it's still because of
that Li Wei Young!
If you truly wish the best for her
you should obey our Khan.
Attain "Chart of Six Elements
in Army Defense."
Or else
it will be Li Wei Young's corpse
that awaits you.
Are you going against me?
I'm willing to risk my life for you.
However, I must also carry out
our Khan's strict orders!
You can tell Li Wei Young
to be wary of us
but how long could she keep
watching out for herself?
You could also report this
to the emperor.
Give the army of Wei an excuse to
trample the meadows of Rouran
and massacre our people!
Your Highness!
Master, the room is ready.
[Snow Yard]
By His Majesty's oral decree
you are to stay in this place
until the child is delivered.
You can enter and leave
the premises as you please.
But you're not to leave the palace.
Should you cause any trouble again
His Majesty surely wouldn't
let you off easily.
I hope that you can
conduct yourself well.
Thank His Majesty for his graciousness.
I will leave you to get some rest.
Young Mistress, what should we do now?
Judging by His Majesty's orders,
he won't give you any title.
The efforts you made
all these years are in vain.
Where there is a will, there is a way.
Now that I'm pregnant,
I can still slowly plan for the future.
It's already so late.
Why aren't you in bed yet?
You're already sewing clothes
for the baby now?
I might be carrying a child, but others
just see it as a bit of added flesh.
I want them, particularly
Prince of Nan-An, to see these clothes.
I want them to feel
the existence of this child.
Young Mistress.
He hasn't even visited me once.
Should this go on any longer,
he will forget me.
He will also forget this child.
Young Mistress, don't think too much.
Prince of Nan-An might just
be too busy with work.
Could he be so busy that he can't even
write a letter or send a message?
Rong Er, run an errand for me.
Give these clothes to
Prince of Nan-An.
He will know what I mean
when he sees them.
[Snow Yard]
You didn't get to see him?
I did.
What did he say?
He didn't say a word.
He didn't say a word?
How did he react?
Was he happy or angry?
Neither.
He glanced at it and left.
It seems that he really
has forgotten about me.
Where is His Highness?
He isn't here?
His Highness won't be coming.
His Highness told me to tell Miss Li
to nourish the child
and give birth smoothly.
If so, you can both be safe.
Should you cause any more trouble
His Highness will forego
all past sentiments.
He can disregard our past relationship
but would he also ignore his own child?
Miss Li, you're on your own now.
Hold on!
Please tell Prince of Nan-An.
I'm carrying his flesh and blood.
If he could abandon his own child
I and his child
would never live in humiliation.
You are dismissed.
Yes, Young Mistress.
Li Wei Young?
What are you doing here?
What are you up to?
Subtitles by DramaFever