- Female.
- They're on their way.
You go. I'll pick up Alex
and meet you at home.
- Hello.
You haven't changed.
Hello Ramiro.
Hello.
Look at you, all grown up.
- Okay. Did you get everything?
- Yes, Ramiro's reading the book.
- I haven't spoken with Kraken.
- Why not?
I'll find the time today.
Ramiro didn't tell anybody, did he?
No, he didn't. Don't worry.
He's discreet.
Look at this place. It's paradise!
Álvaro!
See how big he is.
- Hello.
- Hi.
You don't remember me.
- He was too young. Come on.
Hello, how are you?
Welcome.
- Let me get that.
- Thanks.
Álvaro, come, it's here.
Alex likes to take a nap
on this couch. It's cool here.
You'll share the bathroom.
To give your parents some privacy.
- What's this?
- Homeopathy.
That one is for people
who're afraid of being hurt...
The fear of getting hurt.
Hi.
- You just had a wank.
- What?
- There in your room.
- How do you know?
- I can tell.
- Do you jerk off too?
Every day.
I'd never been to Uruguay.
We're talking about jerking off,
not Uruguay?
- How old are you?
- Fifteen.
I've never fucked anybody.
Would you like too?
- With whom?
- With me.
With you?
- Alvaro, you want some?
- No, I'm vegetarian.
- Are you serious?
- He won't touch a thing.
I don't like trying anything new.
Hi honey!
Hi.
This is Alex. Erica...
Hello?
- Ramiro.
- Hello.
- You two have met, right?
- No.
Álvaro, Alex.
Your mum used to say
she'd have four daughters.
We'd call her a
'Desperate Housewife'.
So the desperate housewife
got scared along the way..
- Do you go to school?
- I used to.
- What do you mean 'used to'?
- I'm getting expelled on Monday.
- What happened?
- I punched Vando. I broke his nose.
Why what happened?
- Who is Vando?
- Her best friend.
Friend or boyfriend?
You don't do that to a friend.
- When will she speak to him?
- She said tomorrow.
"In all vertebrates,
including the human being...
the female sex is dominant in an
evolutionary and embryological sense."
We should arrange to meet
Vando's parents.
To apologize.
To apologize? Us?
For breaking that asshole's nose?
It's them who should apologize.
- He's Alex best friend.
- Was.
Why didn't you tell me
he's a surgeon?
- He's the best.
- Says who? him?
- No, I did some research.
- Research?
Since when?
- I'm not the enemy.
- No?
No.
She's not taking them anymore.
Did you know?
No, I didn't.
- Do you like it?
- What?
My house.
Yes.
Don't lie to me.
Do you like cutting people up?
It's my job.
Alex.
Hurry up!
Do you read me, Kraken
They're taking the turtles to the port.
- Where are they?
- 10 miles offshore.
I'm on my way.
- Can I come?
- Climb in.
One of them lost a front flipper.
- Where did they show up?
- 10 miles offshore.
They were following
a shoal of sprats.
They were in the water
for 20 hours...
caught in a net.
Poor things.
- Can you identify them??
- Yes.
- Where are the others?
- My son said there were.
Where are they?
You have something for me, Esteban?
Nothing.
- Are you sure?
- Are you a biologist or a cop?
You should come with an apology
rather than an attitude.
My son was spitting blood.
She broke his nose..
My wife wants to report it.
She'd better not come round here again.
Wait, Alex.
Alex.
What are you looking at?
Enough already.
That's it, take her away.
Too many endagered species as it is.
Your son is afraid of my daughter?
- Your son is a traitor.
- Dad.
- I won't allow...
- You won't allow what?
She's capable of breaking
his nose again!
She's just like me!
She's capable of doing it!
- Who did you tell?
- Just Vando.
If I'm so special
why can't I talk about it?
In the end, our fathers
are in the same business.
- Will it live?
- Yes, but it'll never go back to ocean.
- How many boob-jobs has your dad done?
- I don't know.
- You're a freak.
- So are you.
- I bet he's done thousands.
- yes.
- Have you ever been?
- Where?
To surgery. To see
the butchering.
He doesn't butcher people,
he fixes them.
He does tits and noses for money
but he prefers the other stuff.
- Such as?
- I don't know, deformities...
Guys born with eleven fingers.
- My dad takes off the extra one.
- And eats it.
I'm serious. It's not a joke.
You said he didn't butcher bodies.
Nevermind. You don't get it.
Do you like your parents?
They're my parents.
So? Do you like them?
I guess so.
Thanks.
I feel sorry for mine.
They're always waiting.
- Why did you hit him?
- He had it coming.
- Do you take Argentine pesos?
- Yes.
- How much is it?
- 7 pesos.
He pays.
Here you are.
- Enjoy it.
- Thanks.
When you listen to music in the street..
What?
Everyone seems to be listening
to the same tune.
- Whats up?
- Here's a present.
- For me?
- Yes.
Look. It's a tag they put
on the turtles.
- I've got one too.
- What is it for?
To follow their migratory routes.
These two are from the same family.
- Where's this one from?
- África.
Cool. It's cool. Thanks.
- You're not wearing it?
- Maybe later.
You don't like it?
Well, I'm not sure. I'll see.
- Careful with that.
- What is it?
Corticoid.
So I don't grow a beard.
- Good morning.
- Perhaps I can help you.
- With what?
To speak with him.
To explain what we'do to her..
- Shall we go?
We'll be right back.
- What is it?
- A rare species. Don't touch it.
What do you know about
the species in my house?
Stop the car.
I'm sure this was the spot.
This is where I got pregnant
with Alex.
We still lived in Buenos Aires.
I was afraid
somebody would see us.
I was worried somebody
would drive by and see us.
- It's ridiculous.
- What is?
Being worried about
what other people think.
They'd ask:
'Is it a boy or a girl'.
It's the first thing
they ask in the clinic.
When did she stop
the corticoid?
Two weeks ago.
You know what will happen?
- What?
- She'll masculinize.
Everything will change.
Her body, her cycles.
She'll stop developing as a woman.
That's enough.
- Have you thought about what I said?
- I'm not having sex with you.
- Why not?
- Because you're too young.
- So what?
- And we've only just met.
That's why I'll never fell
for somebody like you.
Not I for you.
You say you're older than me
but you repeat every word I say...
You're not normal.
You're different and you know it.
Why do people stare at you?
Why? What's wrong with you?
Stay.
Come here.
- I don't have anything.
- I like it.
Sex Change For Boy Authorised
At 18, Scherer Starts the Journey
From Woman to Man
We can start if you want.
What about the children?
Álvaro?
He must be with Alex.
Alex.
Sweetheart.
- Here he is. What happened?
- It's pouring.
Poor darling.
Get changed and come eat.
- What's wrong?
- Nothin'.
Give me your plate?
Nothin'? What's nothin'?
- Leave him alone.
- I want to know what's wrong.
Sorry I'm late.
- Alex?
- She's not feeling well.
- Anything wrong?
- Nothing.
- Can I see?
- Yes.
- See how well my son drows.
I don't drink.
Tonight you will. You're old enough.
Ramiro!
It wont hurt him
Drink up
Don't drink, if you don't want to.
- It's not a big deal.
- Yes, it is a big deal.
- It's not.
- Yes it is.
We moved to be away from
certain kinds of people.
And now we're all sitting
round the same table.
O yes... Give it to me baby.
Take this and this.
Again, again.
- You've done it already.
- How d'you know?
I can tell.
With my cousin.
Five times.
I didn't want to at first.
I didn't like it.
He said we weren't going all the way.
Just half way.
We ended up going all the way
It didn't hurt much.
Put this on Alex.
I'll put the spare matress here.
On the floor.
Or Alex goes home.
Go to sleep, it's late.
Give it to me baby...
I have a special bottle of liquor.
I'm going to bed.
We're all going to bed.
Don't. I'll be right back.
- What's the matter?
- I found them together.
- Who?
- Alex and Álvaro.
- What do you mean?
- Together.
- Doing what?
- Don't know, I walked away... On top
- What?
- She was on top.
I don't understand.
She was fucking the boy up the ass.
Clear enough?
It was bound to happen.
That's enough, Kraken.
We knew this would happen.
She can't stay a woman.
What do you mean 'normal'?
- What?
- You said normal.
I didn't say anything.
Don't build your hopes up.
She'll never be a woman,
even if a surgeon cuts off
what she doesn't need.
When did you tell them?
That's why they're here?
I just wanted them to meet her.
I'm not crazy.
You talk to him.
What if she wants to?
Sorry.
- What do you want? Are you a doctor?
- No.
A journalist?
I have a daughter. A son...
I've seen you before.
You've been here before, right?
Yes.
I don't usually drink but
it will do us both good.
Your son?
Adopted.
We're doing the paperwork
to adopt a girl.
The perfect family.
- How old is Alex?
- 15.
Want to see me at her age?
If you don't mind...
That's me at 12.
Keep it.
Give it to Alex.
- Did you always know?
- That I wasn't a woman?
I still wonder how my life
would've been without the operation.
How was your transformation
from man to woman ?
When I was 16 I started
taking testosterone
At 17 I had surgery.
That same year I changed my name...
I met my wife six months later.
The rest of my life
is sleeping in that bed.
What if I got it all wrong?
By letting her choose?
Do you know what my
earliest memories are?
Medical examinations.
I thought I was so horrible
when I was born
that I had to have five operations
before my first birthday.
That's what they call 'normalization'.
It's not surgery. It's castration.
Making her afraid of her own body..
is the worst thing
you can do to your child.
What are you doing?
- You're looking at me differently.
- You're older.
Then you could've told me
why these people came to visit.
I didn't know.
- Are you coming with me?
- No, I want to walk for a while.
Alex!
Alex.
I don't understand.
- You're not?
- I'm both.
But that's impossible.
You tell me what is and isn't possible?
But do you like boys or girls?
I don't know.
Sorry about what I did to you.
You didn't do anything.
I'm not upset... I liked it.
- Really?
- Yes.
- So did I.
- You did?
- Then let's finish it.
- Never with you!
- Why?
- I want something else.
- I want something else too.
- Oh, yeah? What do you want?
What do you want?
- Alex, it'll be our secret.
- Liar.
- I wont tell anybody.
- Get off.
Go tell everybody I'm a monster!
Alex!
Where's Alex?
What are you doing here?
I told you not to come here.
- Where is she?
- Beat it, Vando.
Your father's in real trouble.
Alex!
Wait up
Wait, wait.
Come on
Come on over here.
Don't worry.
Calm down.
We're not going to hurt you.
Take it easy.
Please!
Quiet. We're not gonna hurt you.
Calm down
Let me go! Please!
Bitch!
Take it easy, stay still!
Take it easy.
- Please let me go.
- It's alright, I just want to see.
Let me see.
Let me see what you've got
down there
What have you got?
We're not hurting you
It's a prick.
- No way.
- She's got both!
She's got both.
- It's gross.
- No way, it's great.
Do you get hard?
Let me see.
Answer him. Do you get hard?
I want to see if it works.
Let go of her!
Get out of here, asshole!
- We didn't do anything.
- Beat it!
Beat it!
- Does it hurt?
- No.
- Did they hurt you elsewhere?
- No!
- I'll take her to the hospital.
- I don't want anyone to touch her.
- Calm down. It'll be alright.
- It won't be alright?
Come here.
Let me go!
Stay away from my daughter?
- Enough. You'll kill him.
- Enough? You say it's enough?
You're just like them. Worse!
Stay away from my son...
Just agree to the surgery.
It's not too late.
You can't hide her
for the rest of her life.
Hide her?
- You think she's a freak?
- No!
We came here to stop hearing
every idiot's opinion.
I've had enough.
I've had enough pills...
enough operations.
I want things to stay the same.
She was diagnosed 2 months
before being born.
They wanted to film the birth.
For 'medical interest', and to present
the case to the ethics council.
We said no, to all of it.
Alex was born blue...
She took 40 seconds to start breathing.
Then, they wanted to operate.
they said the only after-effect...
would be the scar.
Suli was scarred.
I convinced her not to do anything.
She was perfect...
From the moment I set eyes on her.
Perfect.
Forget her.
She's too much for you.
I can't leave yet.
I want to speak to him.
We have to leave.
Go fetch your son.
You'll catch a cold.
- May I?
- Yes.
- I thought you didn't drink?
- You told me I have to drink.
- Do you like me?
- You're my son.
Let's cut the crap
and talk seriously.
Kind of.
What about me? Do you like me?
Do you like what I do?
I'd give anything
to have your talent.
And.. Me.. am I talented?
No.
Maybe...
Do you think one day?
Do you think that I...
No, I don't.
I don't get it.
It wasn't always this way.
- What way?
- When did I stop interesting you?
It was a bad idea to come.
Your mother is right.
We're leaving
- When?
- Now. At dawn.
- No. I can't leave yet.
- Why not?
Do you like Alex?
Finally good news.
I was afraid you were a fag.
What are you doing?
Looking after you.
You can't look after me for ever.
Until you can choose.
- What?
- Whatever you want.
What if there isn't
a decision to make?
I've finished it.
- Did they hurt you?
- No.
Did you go to the police?
No, that's your decision.
We'll press charges if you want,
but it's your decision.
Everybody'll find out.
Let them.
- Have a good trip.
- Thanks.
I'll be right back.
Will I see you again?
I don't think so.
Look.
I never imagined I'd fall
for someone like you.
But it happened.
- Me too.
- No.
No?
You're after something else.
No.
What do you regret the most?
Not seeing me again
or not having seen it?
Álvaro!
Do you want to see?
Hurry up, we'll miss the boat.