There was a time when
being a man meant being a yakuza.
You shitty bastard.
You monster!
It's me.
YAKUZA APOCALYPSE
I...
lived a life
that resembled lukewarm water.
And then
I met him.
I became a yakuza.
The townspeople revere the boss.
He takes care of them.
Morning.
- Good morning.
- Beautiful day, isn't it?
What do you want?
Brother!
Shut up.
It's not as you think!
But...
even a city like ours is not immune to the recession.
Times are merciless for small factories.
Masaru.
Papa.
Take this and kill me.
I wish I had never been born.
I will
go with you, my son.
Boss!
Boss...
Boss did everything
to protect his city.
One day, maybe
I will be a man like him.
Welcome back.
Come in.
Thank you.
This is Kageyama.
I can't remember
having ever seen that young man.
You know.
Sure.
Wait here.
Yes.
Hello.
Everyone, stretch out your right leg.
Bastard!
I'll make mincemeat of you!
It's wrong to threaten people!
Sensei.
Yes.
Like this?
Yes, you did well.
Thank you.
If someone stamps on your right foot,
offer him the left one too.
Good.
Very good.
You become better every day.
Good work.
As a gift, take a cigarette.
I've stopped smoking.
You've stoped smoking?
That's great.
Well then, shall we go?
Give your best, guys.
Where did they go?
To the land of toys.
See?
Still standing?
Sit down.
- After you.
- Just sit down.
My chair is over there.
It looks good.
Want a drink?
Yes.
That stuff.
Sure.
Drink.
Cheers.
Well, perhaps it's a bit early.
Boss, is that okay?
Yeah, sure.
He seems to be in a hurry.
No, I don't mean that.
I think it's time for you to try something better.
It's not good for your health.
Just for this one time.
I won't touch civilians.
Can I have another one?
See?
Thank you.
Drink it.
Thank you!
How is it?
Are you really okay?
It was delicious.
Goddamn.
Hey.
You half-assed idiot still don't have a tattoo!
Yakuza is about this.
Don't talk nonsense.
It's no nonsense!
Yakuza is about endurance. Endurance.
We tattoo ourselves to prove our endurance.
My skin is sensitive!
You can't imagine how much.
Don't tell me to treat it like a piece of leather please!
Who cares?
Rub cream on it, bastard!
I'm sick of your attitude.
I don't need things
like cream and tattoos.
The boss is back!
Boss.
What happened?
The Karatani gang caught him at the bridge.
They beat him up because of a gambling debt.
You had told them not to touch civilians,
so I had to teach them a lesson.
Who will protect you now?
Sensei, you too.
Gambling at your age
will just hurt the people around you.
Take it as a lesson and change your life, okay?
Yes.
Okay, go.
Well, I'll try to talk with them.
Do you think that's necessary?
Yes.
Well, that's how it is.
Once you're cured,
how about we have dinner.
Just the two of us?
No, no.
With the boss, of course.
Say...
If you had one wish for free, what would you wish?
A tattoo, of course.
A tattoo such as the boss has.
And you, what would you wish?
Ask me next time.
Well, we'll talk about it when you're out.
Are you okay so far?
See you.
Hello.
What are you doing here?
Sorry.
Why are you not with the boss?
He told me to look after you.
Why?
How should I know?
He wants you to stay in touch with Kyoko-san.
She will never get involved with a yakuza.
Boss!
See you soon.
What's wrong with you?
Boss?
He's coming.
He's finally coming.
The boss is great, huh? He saved us.
We owe him our life.
Let's work hard until the recession is over.
Masaru-kun, you may have some problems.
But we all have a lot of problems.
Yes.
The shopping area will somehow make it thanks to the boss.
He keeps chain-stores and supermarkets out, doesn't he?
Well, seems I don't fit into the modern era.
You're not a child of our time, right?
You two, get lost!
Go!
Don't come back here ever again.
That's what I told you.
This is the last time I ask.
Are you coming back to the syndicate or not?
I am the happiest man in the world.
I broke away from you to live my way.
As yakuza.
Then it's best to die.
At one's happiest point.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Is here Akihabara?
Huh?
This should be Akihabara.
Boss!
Masaru.
Asshole!
Boss!
Bastard!
He wasn't so tough after all.
Boss...
Take my blood
and walk the streets
as a vampire yakuza!
Where's the owner?
He's not here.
But there is a knitting class in the basement.
Huh?
What are you doing?
Who are you?
It's food.
Food?
They are using this as food for Kamiura.
What's this?
A Sushi tun.
I guess it's a very Japanese vampire sleeping place.
Boss was a vampire?
We entrusted our life to a vampire.
I guess now everything is settled, right?
It's too early to say that.
I'll be there in a moment.
How's it going?
It's a bit confusing.
I see.
You stink!
Ah, welcome!
Ah, I see your surprised reaction.
It's indeed true.
Yes, I'm in fact a real kappa.
Pleased to meet you.
Well, anyway,
we're here to discuss the further development.
I'm your senior in the organization.
Show more respect when you speak to me.
Besides, something great has happened.
What do you mean?
He will come.
He?
No way!
Who will... come?
To put it clearly,
a modern monster.
The world's most formidable terrorist.
Are you sure?
I know Kyoken, so we don't have to...
You are strong too, that's right.
But in his presence
you'd be stiff with fear.
What are you talking? The boss is dead.
That's all I'll say.
My mouth is sealed.
But,
if we don't have a plan before that guy appears,
we yakuza will pay dearly.
Which guy?
What's this?
I am...
Alive?
What happened to me?
I'm hungry.
I'm thirsty.
Why did you run away, you bastard?
Get down.
I'm begging you.
Forgive him please.
I will teach you a lesson!
Dear! Dear!
Kageyama!
You bastard!
Civilians
must not be touched.
That was boss's rule.
Wait a moment.
Where have you been to protect the boss? Huh?
Me?
Yes.
For that you have to pay.
With your life!
Hot, hot.
Hot. Hot. I'm burning.
Do not touch civilians!
Kageyama?
Are you...
Dear!
Civilians must not be touched.
You monster! What have you done?
I'm sorry.
What have I done?
You!
Die! Die! Just kill yourself and die!
Yes.
Die!
Nobuko.
There is...
no need to apologize... for Kageyama.
It's great...
I feel so alive.
Nobuko.
No! Stop!
Not in such a place.
We just can't do it here.
Honey!
Hasegawa-san, what's wrong?
Nobuko!
Honey!
Everyone,
I'm truly sorry.
I'm happy that I became a yakuza.
I don't regret it.
Wait.
"Good-bye."
No.
"For personal reasons..."
"Due to urgent family matters..."
No!
It's all wrong.
"Despite my feelings..."
What am I talking about feelings?
Which words could express my feelings?
First, I have to hold her tightly... and then...
Kageyama-san?
What are you doing here?
Are you okay?
Why are you still bandaged?
You're cured, aren't you?
I cried all day.
The boss has been killed.
I can't believe it.
By the way,
last time I asked you what you would wish.
My eyes have seen really terrible things.
I wouldn't mind if I lost my sight.
But that's kind of ungrateful.
After all the boss did for me.
He paid for the surgery.
Still, only for this moment,
I want to see a smile.
I want to see your smile.
Kageyama-san?
No, don't do it. Don't do it.
It hurts.
It was wrong.
It's wrong... I'm hopeless.
A dream?
How do you feel?
I had a terrible dream.
What dream?
You eat soba noodles
but it turns out you eat frog eggs.
In your mouth they grow into tadpoles.
That kind of dream?
Yes.
I see. You're the real deal.
Blood...
Please limit your intake to 250ml per session.
About the size of a soda can.
And, any person you bite to drink blood
will become a vampire yakuza.
Blood of civilians tastes good.
That's why it can make you addicted.
Yakuza blood has a bad taste and is low in nutrients.
You have to drink blood.
But too much of this will lead to disaster.
However, if you only drink yakuza blood,
you will end up malnourished.
That's the reason why
the boss couldn't show his real strength.
The boss,
did he leave any message?
Right. He did.
He told me to give this to you some day.
Ah! Now I understand.
Understand what?
That's quite obvious, isn't it?
No, I don't understand at all.
What does it mean?
It means you don't know anything right now.
When will I know?
It's not something people could tell you!
For now, you're empty like this piece of paper.
You have to find out yourself, with your own body.
Myself?
Right. There is a reason for it.
He chose you!
The boss pumped his blood into you.
His blood is flowing in your veins.
His blood!
Make use of it!
Use it! Use it!
- Are you asleep?
- Sorry!
- Fools, go and find Kageyama!
- Yes.
Stupid idiots.
Is it you, Tetsu?
Yes.
Say...
Are you
hearing a kind of trickling sound?
What?
No, I don't hear anything.
I hear it clearly.
What?
Maybe your ears are ringing?
I'm absolutely certain.
You're right.
I hear something.
It's strange.
It's inside your head.
So it is, isn't it?
It's me,
Kageyama.
What do you want?
Masaru.
Don't you want to take revenge?
I can't.
You can't?
You must be holding terrible feelings inside your heart.
Don't bury them inside you, let them out.
When you let your anger out, you'll feel great.
Close your eyes.
Stand up.
Stand up, Masaru.
You're no longer a weakling like before.
Place your bet.
- Even.
Odd.
All bets are closed.
What are you doing?
Even.
Five plus Two. Odd.
We're gambling.
Hey!
Don't you know this is our territory, bitch?
Hey, hey, you're still a student.
From which school?
Minato Machi Highschool.
Level 2. Class 3.
I'm here for a little company.
You should be in class now.
But I won't go back there.
And now, get lost!
I am a realtor, you see.
We real estate guys like high school girls like her.
What are you talking about, idiot?
Don't laugh, asshole.
We all belong to the yakuza.
With heart and soul.
Don't set yourself up as if you could become a yakuza.
Then...
how do you become a yakuza?
That's true.
You can't take an official exam for it.
Or are you saying the yakuza is an incorporated company?
Here is no room
for thugs like you.
What have you said?
Shall I give you an advice?
If you want to get your neck broken,
just go on like this.
You don't obey the boss's rules,
you don't take revenge for him...
What kind of yakuza are you?
Hey, you!
Sister,
let me handle this nuisance.
You are a yakuza, right?
A real yakuza, right?
Who is this woman?
I am a realtor, you see.
We real estate guys like nurses like her.
Are you kidding me?
Do you think this is funny?
Let me introduce myself.
My name is Mikiko.
I'm here to take care of everyone's well-being.
Sister, you'd better go home before you get hurt.
You guys, go home now.
What are you talking?
Chief Zenba!
If you absolutely insist on having a fight,
this Mikiko will pump a few bullets into you, okay?
Life is a struggle for survival.
Chief.
You understand, don't you?
Huh?
Seems somewhere water is dripping.
Chief.
Chief! Chief!
Chief?
Take care, jerk!
Hey, wait!
Oi, why are you walking like that?
Can't you walk normally?
What's wrong with all these fake yakuza?
And where is the chief?
Excuse me. Sorry.
Wait! One moment, chief!
Mama, mama!
You're a civilian, right?
What are you talking about? Of course I am.
There are strange yakuza at our place.
Do something about it!
Hey!
Here's someone in trouble.
Do something!
Hey!
What?
Do you think we'd work for free?
Get lost!
But you are a public-sector worker.
And you are a public-sector yakuza.
Don't disturb the police when they drink and play.
Listen, I've always paid you.
Do something.
A civilian in trouble.
We have to take care of it.
Chief, are you okay?
Let's go.
Now let's try this.
Hey, you!
What are you doing?
I bought this woman.
Doing this to her! Don't you have feelings?
Aren't you that school teacher?
Your name is Sawada, right?
Shut up.
Sensei,
you can't behave like this.
Don't you see she's crying?
I'll give you the money back.
Let her go and...
Bastard!
Hey! What are you doing, Sensei? Oi!
What's wrong?
Wonna mess with me?
I'm a yakuza.
I'm ready to fight.
Wait, Sensei! Okay?
Do you want me to end your life?
You only have to tell me.
What do you want?
Oi!
You mustn't do that.
Just take no notice of it.
Furthermore,
I'm also a yakuza now.
Your protection,
go to Hell with it!
No, no, that's...
What's with you?
Are you going to bite us too?
Come on!
Try it, motherfucker.
I will kill you!
Uah. You stink!
They stink.
These guys must taste bad.
Get out of here!
What are you saying?
Chief?
What are you doing?
There is someone.
A boy?
Huh?
Isn't it the kid of that dead man?
Masaru?
Time to die.
Hey!
Quickly!
Hurry up! Step on on the gas!
Stop the car!
Stop it!
Kageyama?
Turn the car and drive back!
Wait!
What is it?
Again,
inside my head it's dripping and dripping.
Chief,
don't we have a worse problem?
We need civilians.
Without civilians we're in the deepest trouble.
Well, you could say we live on their blood.
What shall we do now?
They turn into yakuza and suck blood themselves.
We must protect the civilians.
Right?
Chief.
What is this?
No way.
Is her brain liquefying?
Kageyama!
Protect the chief!
Bring her inside!
Chief!
Chief.
I'm here to revenge the boss.
Chief, get into the car.
You guys, go!
Kageyama!
Relax.
Relax, asshole!
Stop wasting our time.
Come back into the organization already.
I'm a yakuza.
Join us,
or die!
Shut up with that nonsense!
What a shame.
Like Kamiura,
you're just a piece of garbage.
Bastard!
Fuck!
No way, bastard!
Jesus Christ, he's waking up.
Dynamite?
Your hot bath is ready.
Hey, let's get out of here.
Hey!
Why did you interfere?
I wanted to revenge the boss.
What are you talking?
You were in serious trouble.
You're lucky I came.
You should thank me.
What was that?
I suddenly felt an incredible power in me.
That is not all.
Heal your wounds first.
Very soon the full power of the boss will have passed over to you.
Then, you will be in complete control.
How did he...
Take my blood
and walk the streets
as a vampire yakuza!
Boss...
It smells of oranges.
A smell of oranges?
Maybe...
Maybe it contains a hidden message.
Heat it.
[ Play the fool ]
Play the fool?
Ah! Now I understand!
I knew it.
It's something you can do!
You can do it!
And once you've done it, you will surely beat them.
You want blood?
Well, yeah...
You want to suck my blood?
To tell the truth, I'm scared.
Can I do this?
Don't give up.
After all,
you want to become the greatest, right?
A man like the boss.
He's coming.
Finally he's coming.
Hey, is here a festival somewhere?
Shit!
That motherfucker...
I'll fucking kill him.
Oi! I didn't come here just to have a look at that.
I can join your organization, can't I?
It's already a bit late for that.
Besides, for a kappa like me,
can you imagine what a pain it is when my plate gets dry?
What does that mean, bastard?
It's about time you understand.
My plate is a little dry.
Damn!
What's that?
This way.
Watch your step.
Careful. Careful!
Long time no see, huh?
Wait a moment.
There's a guy inside of this, right?
It's a modern monster. The world's most formidable terrorist.
Here. Look at this.
This is Kamiura's blood.
Actually, I...
killed him before you got here.
I was told to hurry up.
What's that?
This is his paralyzing stare!
The power of these eyes is incredible.
Can you feel it, you idiots?
These eyes can kill if he wants to.
So great is the power of our Kaeru-kun.
I told them to wait,
but they didn't.
Well, well, won't you let off a little steam?
Come on.
Kaeru-kun,
you hate yakuza, don't you?
But that trembling guy just happens to be here.
Let him go.
The yakuza blood we had
has all been distributed to other guys.
What shall we do now about Kaeru-kun?
Then he must take it from Kyoken
whom we'll offer Kamiura's.
Kaeru-kun,
you will take it from here.
It's just enough.
Damn!
What the hell does that guy think he is?
So arrogant.
Don't mess with me!
This is just too humiliating.
Don't lick a Japanese yakuza!
This way.
"Breeding Farm"?
Chief?
What are you doing?
Don't step on it!
On what?
The field.
Why?
Move your feet!
That's how I grow them.
First,
I sprinkle them with milk.
Just some skim milk, you see?
And then...
Look!
It's sprouting... it's sprouting.
Quickly, quickly...
They are healthy and strong.
We cultivate the civilians we need.
What a harvest!
What large plants!
And then,
we can live on their blood.
Without civilians
yakuza cannot survive.
Do you wonna know what I think?
Yeah.
This here is no longer my business.
Boss.
Look at me now.
Damned.
Where did those guys go at a busy time like this?
Chief!
Bastards!
This is a farm where we grow civilians.
You are not needed here!
Die!
Who is this guy?
Hey... Stop!
That's dangerous...
This is bad!
This is really bad!
Is it you?
Not so fast.
That kid
has something urgent to do.
Masaru, you can handle it, right?
You...
What do you want from me?
Thanks for waiting.
But I guess it won't bring back his dad.
Angus!
Yes!
- Angus! Hit it! Hit it!
- Yes.
Quickly! Crush him!
Angus, we've got him!
Die, monster!
Oi! Angus!
Oi! Angus. Are you okay?
Didn't I tell you?
You can't beat the yakuza.
Right!
Kageyama! Yakuza are the greatest.
Do you know why?
We don't care about winning or losing.
We just enjoy fighting!
Kageyama, I'll take care of that guy.
Don't worry, I won't bungle it.
See you later.
Okay.
I see.
Angus, go and help Tetsu.
Yes.
Damn! Not good!
You motherfucker.
You don't know fright.
You're all stupid.
If you take away a yakuza's stupidity, nothing is left, you idiot!
I will rip off your head and apologize to the boss with it.
That hurts.
Damn bastard.
Brother!
Brother...
Angus!
What's happening?
What the hell is happening to the world?
The world is coming to an end anyway.
Before this,
I want to make it clear
who the winner is.
Man to man battle.
You are down for it.
Right?
Very good.
Just you know...
I will take your life,
if need be with my own.
It makes my blood boil.
Wait a moment.
Kyoko?
You can't win in this condition.
Watch and see.
I'm going to win.
You know why I'm here, don't you?
Drink my blood.
And save the world.