Servando Gonsalez presents.
"Yanco."
Here's the little jerk again!
Juan!
Demon, leave this boy.
Juanito Kuitlauak.
Present, teacher.
Irene Medina.
Present, professor.
Esteban San Migel.
Present, prof!
Refugio Pena.
Present, teacher.
Concepcion Jimenez.
Manuel Rodriguez.
Present, professor.
Teodoro Feria.
Present.
Justo Medina.
Present, teacher.
Hey, all right! Ah!
Stand up.
♪ In each encounter I find a brother... ♪
♪ Who shares my love of my country. ♪
I want some chocolate!
Did you see where my son went?
♪ The viper, from the sea, the sea... ♪
♪ How could it happen? ♪
♪ Some stay behind and some run ahead. ♪
- Have you seen my son?
- Sorry, no.
- Have you seen a boy about this tall go by?
- No.
No?
He's there with the old grandfather.
Excuse me, friend, have you seen Juanito?
No, sir.
We've tried aromatic herbs, dead chickens.
It's not possible in front of boy.
Let's go, doctor.
Right now.
Come on.
- Right here, doctor. Go on, go on.
- Well, let's see.
And you, old ladies...
Go cure some dogs.
Push off.
He's the devil, girls!
Lamb of God, who takest
away the sins of the world...
Forgive us our sins, Lord.
Lamb of God, who takest
away the sins of the world...
Hear us, Lord!
Lamb of God, who takest
away the sins of the world...
Have mercy on him and on us.
Our Father, who art in heaven...
- In the name of the Father.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee...
blessed are you among women...
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee...
blessed are you among women...
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners...
Mama!
Juancito!
Butter, I have good butter.
Sir, sir!
No. I'd like the violin instead.
No, no.
No.
Already taken? Why should
I remove the round?
Well, all right... thanks, marshal.
I'm going, because I have
to go to my father's house.
Don Arcadio, good night.
Good night, sir. Take care, eh?
Sure, Don Arcadio.
Sign: "Shop".
Open up, it's already too late!
Come on, Don Arcadio.
It's very late.
Let's see. What do you want? Sugar?
What do you want?
I picked up the basket...
and looked for it...
but the violin wasn't there.
The violin appears and disappears.
Devilish!
Right, guys!
What we need is oil.
Welcome.
What's going on?
He nicked the violin!
Don't leave me alone...
Wait for me!
You call yourselves men!
Help! Help!
Just look.
Pedro, Pedro!
Where are you?
Pedro!
No need to fret, just calm down.
Ricardo Ancona as Juanito
Jesus Medina as Old Man
Maria Bustamante as Maria.
Idea and essay by
Servando Gonzalez.
Totally filmed in Mixquic village
Nahuatl vernacular.
Cinematography by
Alex Phillips Jr.
Film Editing by
Fernando Martinez.
Original Music by
Gustavo Cesar Carrion.
Screenplay by Jesus Marin.
Executive producer
Miguel Gonzalez.
Sound editor - Raul Portillo Re-recording mixer - Galdino Samperio
Special Effects by Juan Munoz Ravelo Titles by Nicolas Rueda Jr.
Production company: Producciones
Yanco (Mexico) 1961