Subtitles provided by MBC
[Episode 34]
I brought her to introduce her
to you formally.
What?
Mom, what's wrong with you?
How could he bring her here if he didn't
think of us as a bunch of morons?
Please stop.
Please don't feel offended.
I believe you'd understand me
as a parent.
Of course.
We have no excuse for this.
Our apologies.
Seyoon didn't know you were
invited here tonight. That's why...
Excuse us unwelcomed guests
for leaving first.
Have a great time.
Juri, let's go.
Are you in your right mind?
How dare you bring her here?
And how thoughtless she is
to come with you.
She didn't know about the occasion.
To tell you the truth,
I lied to her to bring her here.
Darn it.
I can't even have dinner in peace?
Let's talk at home.
I don't think we can have dinner here.
Let's go.
Why are you doing this to me?
Why do you make me feel
this miserable?
Don't feel miserable.
I'm by your side.
I'm sorry I surprised you.
I know it's hard for you,
but we have to go through with this.
Let's win them through together.
All you have to do is hold onto me.
It won't take long.
Just be patient.
Okay?
Even though you're upset,
how could you slap his face
before his parents?
What would they think of me?
I don't care what they'll think of me.
I feel much better after slapping him!
You're really of no help.
Enough. From now on,
I will not dance to your tune.
You better get over him now,
completely.
You think I don't want
to forget about him?
But I just can't!
My. This is nuts.
She's driving me nuts.
Hongju.
Yes, Mother.
What's going on with your family?
Your mother promised our inroad
into Taesan homeshopping,
but she never followed up.
Yes or no?
She should respond whatsoever.
I'll call my mom.
You always say that.
Come on, make a call to her
in my presence.
Don't you think you're too much?
Well, I'm sorry
if you're offended but...
Can you make a call to her tomorrow?
No, no.
Can you arrange a lunch meeting
during this week?
Okay.
Darn it.
No one pleases me, not a single one.
Yes.
I see, Mr. Kim.
Please let me know
if there's any news.
Lady Hongju is anxious.
What did he say?
They signed the paper after all?
Yes.
This is no good.
What are you doing?
You sleep here. I'll sleep in the study.
Am I that disgusting?
It's not that. How can I put it...
There's no room in my heart.
What do you mean?
All the rooms in my heart
are filled with Chaewon,
so there's no room for you.
How sad.
Sorry.
Good night.
I hate to go home.
Can you let me sleep
in one of the rooms tonight?
What?
I can't dare face my parents at home.
That's why you shouldn't
have done that.
Then should I have hid you
in fear of my parents?
You don't want that, do you?
I'm not sure if I'm doing right.
If I were your parents,
I would also oppose you
dating a divorcee.
I feel I'm so shameless
to just listen to you.
What you have to do is to encourage me,
not to blame yourself.
We can make it up
to my parents later. Alright?
In that sense, let's charge up.
Excuse me?
I saw you charge up your father
the other day and I really envied him.
What?
Come on, I'm low in battery.
Ready? Click.
Charged up.
No way. I'm only half charged.
Thanks for charging me up.
Good night.
Wait.
Take the dress and the shoes.
You're supposed
to return them tonight.
Wait here a moment.
I'll get changed quickly.
I already paid for them.
What?
You really have slow wits.
Can't believe I fell for
such an untactful woman.
What?
They say you shouldn't buy
your love a pair of shoes,
but I bought them for you
since I trust you.
Don't run away.
What are you looking at?
You're all smiles.
Father, it's very windy today.
Make sure to wear a safety suit.
Cheer up!
Seyoon texted this to me
this afternoon.
Didn't you say you didn't like him?
He's quite good.
I told you.
I liked him at first sight. Maybe I knew
he'd become my son-in-law.
We'll see. I'm worried Chaewon
might end up getting hurt again.
I dread to think of that.
How are you feeling?
Good.
Why don't you go to the hospital?
I can survive at least 10 more years.
Don't worry.
Aren't you sad to have
to quit your job?
No.
Actually, I've been thinking
about learning more about noodles.
That's reassuring.
I'm sure you'll become
a great artisan of noodles.
Yes. I will work hard.
Good.
Keeok, get up.
Leave me alone.
We met Mr. Khang.
Why do you have to give him
such a hard time?
What is this?
The pledge in his blood
that he'll stay away from you.
He kept avoiding us
but we finally got this from him.
My. You're so cruel.
Whatever. This is the least
safety device to protect you.
Now that the old gigolo
wrote a pledge in his blood,
all you have to do
is make up your mind.
He's not an old gigolo.
Look, he approached you for money.
That's a gigolo.
What did you say?
He isn't that kind of a person.
It wasn't for money.
Come on, he admitted it.
Did he say he approached me
for the $10 million?
Then do you think he's fallen for you?
If that's the case,
heaven will punish him.
You got him wrong.
He isn't that kind of a person.
Get a grip.
Otherwise, he would've refused
to write this.
You're so naive.
How could you be fooled by him?
Can't believe you have no eye for men.
It's no use crying over spilt milk.
Let's put an end to this matter.
Think of your parents.
What will happen to them
if they find out?
They'll collapse from shock
and cross the bar.
Why are you whispering all day?
Something's fishy. What's going on?
Nothing.
I'm so upset.
Keeok.
What's wrong with her?
Well. She's a bit stressed out.
Don't ask anymore.
She bailed on a date partner.
There's something fishy about her.
What's fishy?
Her mind wanders in spring.
What brings you here at this hour?
Are you okay?
This is nothing. I'm okay.
How sore it must be.
Don't worry. I'm okay.
I heard you were sick.
Are you alright?
Is this your earnest pledge?
Is it true you approached me
for the money?
I'm sorry.
I harbored evil thoughts for awhile.
As you see, I'm living in need.
Your heart towards me was pure
but mine was not.
That's a lie.
It's not.
I thought my life will turn around
if you become an heiress to $10 million.
So I tried to hit on you.
But your sister-in-laws caught on.
You're lying to detach me.
You have feelings for me too.
Even before I brought up $10 million,
you had feelings for me.
What feelings?
I'm too old to feel love.
I'm sorry I had evil thoughts.
After the competition tomorrow,
I'll get out of your sight.
I thought we were of the same mind.
I didn't know you had such intent.
I'm so disappointed.
Goodbye.
I'm too old and poor...
to confess my love to you.
I'll keep you deep in my heart.
Schumann's Dedication?
Why did you bring her?
Is that a declaration of war
against us?
Should I fight with you again?
Seyoon!
Wasn't three years ago enough?
If she's an average woman,
I won't oppose you.
I'd say okay if she wasn't
worse than Eunseol.
But she's a divorcee!
I love her.
Seyoon.
What else do I need?
She restored my heart to feelings of love
that I've once given up.
There are plenty of nice women
whom you can fall in love with.
That's what you think.
She is the only right woman for me.
What blinded your eyes
and closed your ears?
Don't just think ill of her.
Accept her as she is. Please.
Any interesting news?
Give me the newspaper.
There's nothing special.
Hey. You're being presumptuous.
Why aren't you giving it to me?
Just give me the newspaper!
Huh?
What the heck is this?
Taesan CEO Youngchol Ma
Agrees to Divorce?
Hyesook Oh, the wife of Youngchol Ma,
the Taesan CEO,
filed a suit for divorce and division
of property on the 10th of this month
and then withdrew a suit.
A close Ma source revealed
that Oh was not paid alimony.
The suspicion around the causes and
process of divorce is becoming amplified.
What the heck is going on?
Hongju! Hongju!
Gosh! Can't you knock?
Shut up. Hongju, get up.
Talk to her later.
She's in a deep sleep.
Just get up!
I fell asleep using sleeping pills.
What's the matter?
Why did you hide
your parents' divorce?
They got divorced?
Take a look.
It bannered the newspaper!
Is this why she kept putting off
the home shopping thing?
No. That's not important now.
They say your mother
wasn't paid a single alimony and...
Plastic bag.
One, two, three, inhale.
One, two, three, exhale.
Then what?
The home-shopping deal is off?
Is this Ms. Chaewon Minn's residence?
Yes, it is.
This is from Mr. Seyoon Yi.
Congratulations on the first step
of the noodle artisan, Chaewon Minn.
Had I known you'd be this moved,
I would've sent a truck of flowers.
Don't work too hard.
Take it easy, okay?
I'll call you after a meeting.
This is unacceptable!
You promised not to get in on the race,
but now even Chaewon joins the race?
This is absurd!
She's right.
Hyodong, this is too much.
I'm entering the competition to learn,
not to win $10 million.
Oh, come on.
You think we are fools?
By the way, you're strange.
Are you mute?
Why don't you say anything?
We'll follow your decision.
Yes. We'd like to take a step back
and look at the big picture.
Why take a step back?
It's strange that you guys
are taking it without rebelling.
Did they get something on you?
What are you talking about? No!
Well, let's do this.
If my team wins the competition,
we'll give you $10 million,
the prize money.
You divide it into three equal parts.
Really?
Yes. We're not competing for money.
We'll do that.
How can we trust you?
We'll write a promise
and get it notarized, okay?
Are you sure?
We promise.
Don't take it too serious.
Pick the nearest taste
to what you tasted in the old days.
It's been a long time.
I'm not sure if I can recall it.
I'm sure you can.
Well, let's begin.
Okay.
Let me hear what made you
make that plate.
Starting from you, Keemoon.
Yes. We made noodles
in tofu residue.
What's the reason?
I remember there was
a tofu manufacturer near our factory.
Right, there was.
The owner used to give away
tofu residue for free.
Her mother might've scrounged them
and made noodles in tofu residue soup.
Soy is rich in protein.
We assume that she often made this kind
of noodles for Myongsoon.
- Tasty, huh?
- It is!
Good.
Yum, tastes good.
It tastes really delicious.
Makes sense.
Next, Keechoon.
Yes. We made noodles
in fermented soybean soup.
In fermented soybean soup?
Jangdan Soybean
is a specialty of Paju, right?
The noodles Myongsoon tasted
must've been made of Jangdan soybean.
Right. Mother said there're patches
of Jangdan beans all around.
You have a point there.
Next, Keeok.
I made vinegar chicken noodles.
The reason?
My parents were from Pyongahn
Province, and so was her mother.
Pyongahn people love these noodles.
I ate it often when I was little.
You can never forget the taste
of homecooked food.
So we thought her mother might've made
these noodles of her hometown.
I didn't know my mom
fled from North Korea.
She suffered all sorts of hardships
since she fled at a young age.
Now, Choonhee.
Wait, it looks like...
Right. I made flake noodles.
Flake noodles?
I heard that Father gave offcut noodles
to his needy employees.
I could've mixed water to them
and made noodles,
but since my employees struggled,
I gave them away to them.
Her mother must've mixed it with water
and made flake noodles.
Right. She didn't have
a noodle machine at home.
The soup looks tasty.
Yes. We made noodles in perilla soup,
which is a temple food.
Grandma told me that Auntie Myongsoon
was ill when she was younger...
so her mother took her
to the temple...
and prayed to Buddha
since she had no money.
Smells delicious!
Since she had little to offer
to Buddha,
she might've brought flour dough
made of offcut noodles.
So we drew a conclusion
that the noodles in her memory...
must be flake noodles in perilla soup.
I can vaguely remember mom and I
used to eat noodles at the temple.
I didn't know she was that poor...
and led such a hard life.
They're gonna get cold.
Why don't you try some?
Yes. This is it.
This is the taste of the noodles
my mom made for me.
Poor girl....
Thank you.
Thank you for reminding me
of my memory with my mom.
A bowl of noodles
recalled her childhood memory.
Noodles are so valuable.
Noodles aren't food
to stuff the stomach.
They contain memories and comfort.
Extramarital affair?
So you mean Mrs. Ma
had an affair with another man?
Yes.
My.
That's why she wasn't paid alimony.
That's not the only reason but...
Mr. and Mrs. Ma have had bitter feelings
about it and now they exploded.
That's no news
to their close associates.
Ha. She always talked
as if she were some elegant lady.
So, who is her love child?
Who's the illegitimate child?
Isn't it the first son in charge
of Taesan Home Shopping?
It's a daughter.
Daughter? Who?
My daughter-in-law?
Yes.
Yes?
Why didn't you tell me that earlier?
Because it's not a pleasant topic,
so I didn't tell you.
What the.
What's wrong with you?
This is a fraudulent marriage!
Please calm down.
Why are you doing this?
That's why they married her off
to your son.
Otherwise, why would she let her
marry your divored son?
You're shooting off your mouth!
Ms. Bhang, please calm down.
Calm down.
Calm down, please. Calm down.
What the heck is this?
What should I do? Oh no.
How are you feeling?
Did you speak with your mother?
Let's take a spin and dine out.
Come on, get up.
Stop bugging me.
When you feel down, you should go out.
Staying home will make you feel worse.
Are you commiserating me now?
What?
You hated to look at me
or come near me.
Why did you become so nice?
Are you taking a pity on me
for my situation?
Why would I?
I don't need your darn sympathy!
So don't mind me!
Where are you going? Hey.
Hey!
That foul temper.
I came back.
You came back already?
She insisted she'd take a bus.
She's just like her mother and doesn't like
causing an inconvenience to others.
I'm glad we treated her
with noodle soup.
You guys did a good job.
Well, Mr. Uhm...
Because of a personal reason,
I can't continue to compete.
Guess you have an emergency.
Yes. I'm sorry.
Thank you for all your teachings.
Let me bow to you.
You don't have to...
Keeok.
Goodbye, Keeok.
Why did you like to me?
It wasn't for the $10 million.
What are you talking about?
I told you enough yesterday.
Schumann's Dedication.
What?
Why did you play
Schumann's Dedication after I left?
Well...
It's the music Schumann
dedicated to his love, Clara.
Ms. Uhm.
Don't try to deceive me anymore.
You love me too.
What's this crap I'm hearing?
Keechoon.
He is an old, useless man...
How dare you.
How dare you covet my sister?
Did you lose your head?
Yeah, beat me up.
Beat me up to the pulp
so that I can come to my senses.
No problem. Follow me.
Stop there. Stop there!
He's gone off his head.
What should we do?
This is a big problem.
Keemoon! Keemoon!
Keechoon, don't.
Last time you went into her room
and slept there. It was planned, eh?
Why don't you answer?
Are you ignoring me?
- Bastard!
- Please don't.
He is innocent.
If you want to hit him, hit me.
Step aside, silly girl!
Honey, calm down!
Ms. Uhm, are you okay?
- Get off of her!
- Stop!
- Just get off of her!
- Dang!
Are you okay?
Where's Mr. Khang?
Can't believe this.
She's looking for him
as soon as she woke up.
Are you out of mind?
What do you lack that you...
Honey.
This isn't good for education.
Chaewon, take Boreum out.
Okay. Boreum, let's go out.
Go take a walk.
What do you lack
that you like that old man?
I'm mistaken, right?
I really can't understand you.
Didn't you hear me?
I clearly heard her saying "I love you"
to that old gigolo.
Watch your mouth. Old gigolo?
Stop beating my husband.
She's really crazy.
You're done.
Thanks, Hyodong. Thanks, Ms. Yang.
I knew you'd be on my side.
Well, since I helped you two
get married,
now it's your turn to support me.
Let's keep this friendship everlasting.
I have no intention to support you.
How about you?
No one but a madman
would support him.
Act your age.
How could you act this dirty?
What? Dirty?
If my parents-in-law find out,
the whole family
will be turned upside down.
How quick to smell money.
You shouldn't act this way.
Why are they fighting again?
They're not fighting.
They only disagree with each other.
Sorry I didn't play with you often
these days.
Instead, I'll buy you a toy.
It's a Children's Day gift in advance.
Yeah!
Go ahead.
You want this?
I thought you liked robots.
Yes, Seyoon.
Where are you?
I'm at the mart. What about you?
I'm coming back
from a business trip.
Let's have dinner together.
Okay.
How can I help you?
Did you come to buy noodles?
Isn't this Ms. Chaewon Minn's house?
Yes. May I ask what this is regarding?
Are you her father?
I am.
I am Seyoon Yi's mother.
How do you do?
Please go in.
No.
Could I talk to you about something
at a nearby coffee shop?
Sure.
I apologize for my abrupt visit.
That's okay.
I think you can guess
why I came to see you.
Yes.
Both your daughter and my son
do not listen to me at all.
So I took the liberty
of coming to see you.
Say they are blinded by love.
Then we must guide them
onto the right path.
Seyoon broke off his engagement
after he met your daughter.
He's wild and out of control.
He is the 5th-generation son
and the heir of the company.
He needs a helpmate suitable
for his social status.
The world has changed, but still,
how dare a divorcee...
I'm sorry.
That's okay.
I can understand you.
However,
although Chaewon has
a poor background, she is upright.
Whatever she does,
it is always perfect.
I'm proud of my daughter and...
It's embarrassing
that you talk so naively.
If you were in my shoes,
would you want to have
a faulty daughter-in-law?
Where's Hongju?
She is in her room.
When we came back
from working our tails off,
she didn't even greet us
when she's loafing around?
Aren't we used to that?
What's the big deal?
Mom! Mom!
You think nothing of me
and your husband?
All you care about
is that darn puppy.
Way to screw things up!
You're scaring Coco. Stop yelling.
"You're scaring Coco."
How dare you interrupt
your mother-in-law?
Are you brain-dead or what?
Mom, stop.
Try to understand.
It's a terrible day for her.
Hey! Why didn't you tell me?
You and your mom
committed a fraud!
Fraud?
I know you're born out of wedlock.
Don't say that!
What would I fear in this situation?
All the newspapers bannered it.
You're just an illegitimate child but
how dare you act like you're high class?
Watch your language!
What?
Why should I when you cheated us?
She didn't cheat.
I already knew about it.
Shut up.
Don't try to cover up her crime.
Look at the way she behaves.
Please stop!
Calm down.
Calm down, Hongju.
Let go!
Don't stop her. Let her leave.
You wished to make a stake
using my background.
Sorry I threw a wet blanket.
Are you mocking me now?
How could I dare to mock you?
Next time when you need
a daughter-in-law, be more thorough.
So that you won't
pick out trash like me!
What?
Hongju, Hongju!
Seyoon.
You came back now?
Can we talk?
- Let me fill your glass.
- Yes.
I met your mother this afternoon.
My mother?
I don't need to tell you
what she said to me.
I don't wish for honor or riches.
I wish Chaewon would marry
an average Joe and live an ordinary life.
You are too good for her.
If she marries you,
she'll lead a difficult married life.
I can't let her go through with it again.
That will never happen.
Meeting with your mother...
...reminded me of the same situation
from three years ago.
Chaewon's ex-husband
said the same thing you just said.
Your feelings for her
will change some day.
When you have differences
and clashes,
your married life can end up in scars.
Forget about her at this point in time.
I'm not a fickle-minded man.
No one says he is fickle-minded.
We all say we'll never change.
What should I do
to make you believe me?
Will you believe me if I leave home
and everything I have?
Are you threatening me?
Father.
Till your parents approve,
don't try to see her.
I'll be honest with you.
I had a girlfriend three years ago.
I was in the same situation
as I am now.
On our way to win
my parents' approval,
my girlfriend died in a car accident.
I lost my love because of my parents.
And I'll never let that happen again.
You reek of booze.
Why did you drink so much?
I had a drink with him.
Him? Who? Seyoon?
Where are you going?
I need to make honey water for him.
Hey.
I'm your hubby you should take care of,
not Seyoon.
He isn't a stranger.
He's my son-in-law-to-be.
Do you like him that much?
Yes.
Though not as much as you,
I really like him.
I like his upright
and sincere personality,
but his parents
will strongly oppose them.
His mother came here this afternoon.
Mrs. Yi came to our house?
Seyoon.
Stay still.
Let's stay still for a minute.
You smell of liquor.
Did you drink soju thinking
it was water like last time?
No.
Then why did you drink so much?
I had a drink with your father.
With my dad?
He told me not to see you unless
I have my parents' approval,
so I begged him not to keep me
from seeing you.
I did well, right?
Why don't you answer?
Say I did well.
I did well, right?
Yes, you did.
Thanks.
Now that I heard you say that,
I feel better.
I really did well, right?
Why is it so quiet?
Mrs. Park!
Mrs. Park?
Where is she?
Good morning, Cholgyu.
Why hit the bottle from the morning?
You kicked out a daughter-in-law
for the second time. Are you satisfied?
I didn't kick her out.
You saw her leaving the house
on her own.
You promised to be
the kindest mother-in-law.
How could you break your promise?
Look, I didn't know
Hongju was that awful.
I shouldn't have divorced Chaewon.
I shouldn't have let her go.
There you go again.
When will you ever get over her?
Never. I can never get over her.
You really can't live without her?
No. I cannot live without Chaewon!
This is a living hell.
I'm living in hell.
Juri, what are you doing?
You know Eunyoung?
I'll go stay with her.
Your friend who studies in Boston?
Yes.
I'll stay with her for some time.
Why would you go there?
And what about your work?
I'd rather die than see Seyoon
going out with Chaewon.
I won't come back till I get over him.
You really can't live without him?
How many times must I tell you? No!
Cholgyu can't live with Chaewon,
Juri can't live without Seyoon,
and Seyoon stands by Chaewon...
If I put her back to where she was...
both Cholgyu and Juri will be happy.
Like killing two birds with one stone.
Sweetie.
What brings you here?
I'm sorry, sweetie.
Excuse me?
I've done so many bad things
to you until now.
I apologize from the bottom of my heart.
Please forgive me.
Please?
Subtitles provided by MBC.