Episode 30
Take care, daughter.
Brother Gou, take care!
Take care.
Take care my patrons.Take care.
With the livelihood you gave us
we can obtain about 20,000 a year from those greedy rich officials.
Then we split it with the commoners in Jiang Dong.
In recent years, the name of your Bao Zi clan
has almost caught up to us, Yi Zhi Mei.
You're too modest brother Li.
Take care!Take care.
Take care.Take care.
I'll take my leave.Take care.
Shi-
What do you mean by this?
What do you mean what do I mean?
You're still denying it?
My mother said she wants me to go back to E Mei to succeed her position.
She wants you to go back to succeed. That's very good.
You should go back..
You want to break up Yi Zhi Mei?
If I leave
then Yi Zhi Mei will no longer be four people.
Yea, it'll be three.
Say it again.
Your mother has been waiting her whole life.
She's been waiting for you to go back to be with her.
What do you mean?
What do you mean what do I mean?It's annoying.
Last time, at E Mei...
You told my mother that I'm your wife.
What do you mean?
In that situation, of course it's fake.You know it very well.
Fake...
Right... it's all fake.
You said that this is our home. Is that fake too?
Did I think too much?
Or is everything you said... all fake?!
Your mother is waiting for you. Don't let her down. Go, hurry!
Li Ge Xiao, you sure are sly.
(Letter from Ying Wu Qiu: He kidnapped Hai Rui)
What do you mean?
What do you mean what do I mean?
My mother said she wants me to go back to E Mei to succeed her position.
She wants you to go back to succeed. That's good.You should go.
Say it again.
Your mother has been waiting her whole life.
She's been waiting for you to go back to be with her.
San Niang!
Don't be angry with ge ge.
I'm not angry. I'm thinking he must be hiding something from me.
He must have a reason to do this.
I think ge ge is looking for an excuse to feel better.
This counts as a good thing I guess.
Ah, right (3x). I've experienced been hurt because of love.
One should find a good method to heal from it.
Can you two be more serious?
When he can't solve a problem,
he always tries to be composed.
The more composed he is, the bigger the problem.
You don't mean...
that the problem this time is so serious that he must push you away?
Correct. let's think this through fast.
Why would he do this?Not letting us help.
I think it's best to ask him directly.
If he'd tell us then he won't do this in the first place.
Maybe he's met his match; a master of martial arts.
That person wants to battle him, so he's afraid and doesn't want to drag you down.
If you leave, then he can die without worries.
Hu ge, how come I feel like you're right this time.
Who do you guys think it is?
It's impossible. Yan Song is long gone.
That bastard Ying Wu Qiu
has already been exiled.
Even if the Turkics don't kill him, they'll at least cut off one of his legs or arms.
Did you guess that, or are you sure?
And also,
it's not the first time we go against Ying Wu Qiu.
His skills are far from ge ge's.
Brother Zhang, I'll leave him to you for now.
No problem.
Brother Li, leave him to me. Go save your people.
Bao Lai Ying, when we meet again,
either you die or I die.
Li Ge Xiao, don't you dare leave! don't leave!
Come back! Li Ge Xiao, don't leave!
Get back here!
Young master, if we keep dragging him like this, he'll die.
Brother Li has told us not to kill him.
We are bandits, not philanthropists.
How many things have done to us,
and how many of our brothers have died in their hands?
If we just let him go back like this,
how can I face my brothers?
If we let me go, I'll agree to anything.
I'll give you whatever you want.
if i helped
you guys can become the world's strongest clan.
Oh Ying Wu Qiu...
you can never surpass Li Ge Xiao.
And the reason is because you're like this.
i dont believe it
I don't believe that you won't be moved by silver and gold.
Someone like you will never understand.
There's something in this world
that can not be surpassed even by the most alluring of things.
I promised Li Ge Xiao not to kill you,
but I still have to get revenge for my brothers.
We, Bao Zi Bang, has been around many years,
and so we've made some foreign friends.
If you can defeat them and stay alive, then you're lucky!
lets go
Go
stop running
chase him
dont run
Look over there!Where is he?
Let's look on that side!Ok! Let's search!
Go over there!
He's over here!
Stop!Stay right there!
Don't kill me! don't kill me!
Listen to what I have to say!
You guys want to attack China
and wipe us out right?I have an idea!
What you're saying is alluring.
With my status,
you guys can attack our borders with your soldiers.
Then the fall of the country will be soon.
It'll be soon?
Did someone follow you?
You don't have to worry about the things I planned.
This... isn't this a map of the border stations?
You invited the Turkics?!
Your family no longer has a supporter,
so your only option is to find another one.
But you're asking us to betray our country!
This is your field of expertise.
Which one did you invite?
Ha La's people has assaulted our country for many years.
I'm guessing you already know of them.
General Ha La
You're dragging us to hell!
My son... this could be our way out.
Are you dumb from old age?!
The Turkics despise us Chinese.
And they hate traitors even more!
Even if we sell the map to them,
they won't care about us!
Besides, even if you're lucky to live after that,
you can only become their slave.Do you understand, father?!
What... how can you do this to us?!
You're right.
The Turkics has always looked down at us Chinese.
What you have to do is just to take this map
to them and let them attack the borders right away!
Then...
if the Ming Dynasty is gone...
What's it to you?
Don't worry about me.
Just use your clever brain
to convince Ha La and keep your life.
He's here.
You... what are you doing?!
I heard that someone wants to sell their country.
That someone is actually... the great Yan who was all high and mighty.
We're all old acquaintances,
so if you have something to say, say it.
Of course, minister Yan.
All these years... you've embezzled quite a lot from the military funds.
Also all those clever political essays you presented that neglected the frontier defense
has caused the country to fall into chaos.
My emperor
really wants to record your glorious achievements
in our great Han country's history books when we take control of the world.
What a fuss over nothing.
What you want is
the other half of the map, right?
Minister Yan,
your son, Shi Fan, has a way with his words.
Yeah.
You openly buy and I'll openly sell,
but you should watch that mouth of yours.
I'll tell you guys right now,
you guys are nothing without us!
And I'll also tell you,
without the other half of the map,
you guys will never be able to invade the capital city.
Minister Yan,
you should be glad to have a son like him.
Of course.
I want the other half of the map, so just name your price.
100 taels of gold, 100 beauties, and a safe escape.
Deal.
What if Ying Wu Qiu holds something really important to threaten him?
Stop guessing, stop guessing!
My instinct tells me that the problem isn't solved yet.
I'll go discuss this matter with official Hai.Ok.
Odd... how come all the lights are off?
Are you ok?
Official Hai... official Hai has been captured.
Yan San Niang, it's best if you don't move.
It's the same as suicide if you move.
The candles will light the ropes,
and no one can save you after that.
What do you want to do?
I want to give Li Ge Xiao a choice.
I want to see if he'd rather protect his lover or his country.
If he comes,
the Turkics will invade the capital.
Which do you think he'll choose?
Despicable!
Despicable? Not really.
If you don't want to put Li Ge Xiao in a difficult position,
and choose to suicide... I'll tell you right now. You'll drag someone down with you!
Official Hai!
If he doesn't come,
you'll both die when the time's up.
Brother Li. (3x)
Please sit, brother Li.Oh no, it's fine.
No need to be so polite.
Brother Li, please sit first.Yeah.
I came here to ask about official Hai's whereabouts.
If I disturbed you guys in anyway, please forgive me.
It must be Ying Wu Qiu's fault.
How come?
Qian Hu.Who are you?!
Stop right there!Don't move!
Qian Hu get out here!
Come out!
How bold of you Ying Wu Qiu!Now surrender to us!
I want to see Li Ge Xiao.
Do you mean... when official Hai disappeared
Wu Qiu appeared?
Right at the exact time.Who else could it be?
What did he say?
He said he won't say anything until he sees you.
You are the highest in command here now, right?
What do you think of this situation?
Currently, we don't have a leader to guide us.
Everyone here wants to have a capable person
to lead us through this.
I've left this place a long time ago.
Brother, we are all very clear on what's black and what's white.
Brother, we're willing to follow your orders.
Ok then... I'll meet with Wu Qiu first, then I'll decide.
Where is Lord Hai?
Why are you letting him go?!I want to kill him!
Could there only be thoughts of murder
in your heart?!
What if a crazy dog bit you?
Are you going to get on all fours and bite him back?!
Remember this!
Only forgiveness can defuse hatred.
Because I believe
if you insist on killing a person,
and that person dies,
the murderer will also die once.
The best way is to let go.
I'm so happy!
You're so serious.
You really almost killed me.
I came to let you know everything.
That dumb Zhang Zhong gave me to the Turkics.
And that's how I got the best business deal ever.
The Turkic soldiers will wipe the country out.
Not only did you kill our master, you also sold your country.
I'm not done yet.There's something else.
I have your girl.
I want to see what the fearless Li Ge Xiao will do.
There's no way you can confine Yan San Niang.
I have my ways.
The place where she's confined is filled with gun powder.
She'll be blown into pieces in two hours.
You're using the lives of everyone in this country
to play a game of choice with me?
You still don't understand me?
I, Ying Wu Qiu, don't want anything.
The only thing I desire is to win against you! (2x)
Five years ago, you made a mistake in choosing between your girl and your country.
Ru Yi died because of you!
I want to see what you're going to do now.
Yan San Niang is at a warehouse on the east side.
The Turkics will attack from the west side.
Two hours, two locations.
And the only person that can appear is you.
If you show up at the west side on time,
my partners will not sell the map to the Turkics,
but then... your woman will...
Lao Li, San Niang is missing.
I know. Ying Wu Qiu took her.
We thought you drove San Niang away because we assumed
that you were dealing with a tough problem.
Lao Li, I'll tell you this.
If San Niang can come back safely this time,
you should treat her better.
Don't worry, she'll be fine.
That's true.
There's nothing we, Yi Zhi Mei, can't do, right?
Then what are we waiting for?Let's hurry and save San Niang! Wait a minute.
You guys have a more important job to do.
Lord Hai. I am sorry
I really can't escape this time.I can't save you.
I know that mister Ge
will definitely stop the Turkics from attacking the capital.
Sorry for dragging you down with me.I don't mind if I die,
but if something happened to you...
then this world will have one less person that tells the truth,
You already did the best you can, so don't blame yourself, ok?
If I wasn't so impulsive, then Ying Wu Qiu wouldn't have had his way.
We're captured and became mister Ge's burden.
Or maybe... if I left earlier,
and not holding on so tightly...
then this wouldn't have happened.
So you were actually talking about love.
Sigh... you two really take the well being of each other into consideration.
We are partners.
Could it be that you don't know the feelings that Li Ge Xiao has for you?
I'm not a parasite in his stomach.
He doesn't say anything.
How can I know what he's thinking?
Some things are not easily said face to face.
Especially if it's to the person you have feelings for.
What are you saying?
Your self esteem is too low.
Did he say something to you?
It was when he lost you.
What exactly is it that you plan to do?
There's someone waiting for me in the palace.
You mean San Niang?No, you musn't. It's too dangerous.
I don't have much time. You must believe me.
This is my only chance.
There's no way I can go along with this plan of yours.
Listen up. I want to successfully infiltrate the palace,
and this is the only way.
No! This plan is too dangerous, too extreme!
You know me.
I'm always this extreme.
After Ru Yi passed away,
I thought alcohol was the only thing that can accompany me for the rest of my life.
But then there came a plum flower,
and that plum flower showed me that I'm not alone.
There's someone that really cares about me and is concerned about my well being.
That person is miss Yan.
It's not that I didn't know
her feelings for me all this time.
But I don't know if my heart
has enough room for someone else.
I've already lost Ru Yi,
so from now on
I will not allow myself to lose another person.
My only goal is to save San Niang,
and I'm depending on you for this.
I didn't notice that the road we walked were this long.
Don't you see how lucky you are?
Even my mother thinks we're a pair.
but we're really just partners.Isn't that funny?
In actuality, I'm just a book worm.
I don't really know much about love,
But I understand a man's heart very well.
Do you know? The person he cares about most right now is you.
Two locations, and the only person that can appear is you.
If you show up at the west side on time,
then my partners will not sell the map to the Turkics,
but then... your woman will...
I know he will definitely come save you.
I don't need him, and I don't want him to come.
Why?
Yi Zhi Mei can come this far
because we have faith and courage.
Drink, drink!Cheers!
Who are you?!
Get off the stage!
When the sky rains, the ground becomes slippery, and when one falls, one will crawl.
So stop looking for excuses for yourself!
I don't know how you came this far,
but I'm going to remind you!
the most difficult moment to endure
is the moment right before you succeed.
I know that you care for me.
Every time there's a problem,
he'll always have a plan to guide us through it.
He always said that courage and faith can create miracles.
That's the Li Ge Xiao I know.
Well said.
You... how come you're here?
Sorry I came late.
Why did you come?
Why can't I come?
Ying Wu Qiu said
if you come here, then the Turkics will attack the capital.
Don't worry about it.Let's get out of this mess first.
Save official Hai first.
Li Ge Xiao!
Li Ge Xiao you came.
You really came!
Then why did you sacrifice Ru Yi
five years ago for your
so called "Justice".WHY?!
Ru Yi, are u watching?
This is the man that you loved so much.
Look at what he's doing!
You were so selfless... was it worth it?Was it worth it?!
Li Ge Xiao,
I'm going to drag you to hell with me today to meet Ru Yi.
Get ready to explain this to her!
Let San Niang go.
I'll do whatever you want.I beg you.
Ge Xiao, take care.
San niang
No matter what your decision is,
I'll support you.
What hurts Ying Wu Qiu the most
is your forbearance for him.
He fails, and you're high and mighty.
That's the real reason why he's always in pursuit of you.
Promise me that you'll come back safely.
You finally took back everything from my hands.
I've never obtained anything.
I've only lost.
Do you think I can kill you today?
You can't.
Because there's no way I'll let you go again today.
I never understood why
you're so sure that
I won't give the map to the Turkics.
Because I believe in you.
Do you know why I keep
letting you go again and again?
Because in my heart,
you are forever the Bao Lai Ying from the past.
Never changed.
The reason you worked for Yan Song
all these years, kneeling down to him,
was for the chance to personally get rid of them.
Making him and his son miserable.
Right. The person to avenge Ru Yi is me.
And it can only be me.
Are you satisfied now?
Very satisfied.
As expected of the general to keep his promise.
And now it's your turn to keep the promise.
Give me the other half of the map.
Of course.
What a nice pair of father and son
that will sell even the land that their ancestors reside.
It's not like my surname is Zhu.This country isn't my ancestors', so I don't like it.
Yan Song, you betrayed me?!
You bastards! Our emperor personally came here today.
You guys can't escape this time.
So you guys should surrender!
Even the heavens assist my country.
Today, I will eliminate all of you who sell out their own country,
and all those who are foreigners, in one fell swoop!
I know you will definitely send someone
to deliver a secret message to the emperor,
to have the emperor personally go
and witness Yan Song's doings, giving him no way out.
The only thing I did was to send two extra people, just in case.
Why...
Why do you always guess my next step correctly?
Because we were best of friends before.
Fast, accurate, aggressive
As expected of Li Ge Xiao's sword skills.
But I'll tell you...
I prepared something else just for today's fight.
This is satisfying!Satisfying!
I won't stop until
my blood runs dry.
Li Ge Xiao, death doesn't mean defeat.
Living is even more painful.
I... I finally won.
I can see Ru Yi
before you.
Everyone has life,
but it doesn't mean that everyone understands life.
The ones that doesn't understand life
will see life as a punishment.
I was like that before.
I remember when I was younger, when my parents were still there,
I asked them
why I was named Li Ge Xiao.
They wanted me to remember
that I should be singing happily when someone leaves.
I didn't understand it back then.
I realized later
that the reason you cry and become sad because of a departure
is because you didn't do your best when you were together.
The tears you shed are because of the heartache you feel when you realize that you took things for granted.
If you cherish something when you have it,
then you won't have any regrets when departure comes.
Departure is welcoming
the start of a new beginning.
So isn't it worth us singing happily?
Just like how we've faced all the setbacks and hardships along the way,
The thing we're unable to surpass is not some violent revolution,
but the thing we can not withstand is ourselves.
My friend, continue to persevere for
our loved ones, our dreams, and our destiny.
How can we enjoy the fragrance of plum blossoms
if we don't first undergo an extreme cold?
Is it a thing for women to ruin the mood?
Today is different from before. Do you still need this?
Well I don't really need it, but I still need it.
You should drink less.
Don't say that I didn't tell you,
being too controlling is another one of women's things.
Well you had to be mine.
If I don't manage you, then who'll I manage?
This is bad, this is bad!
Shan Xi is in turmoil.The people there are in trouble.
Looking for trouble.
Then let's hurry and take action!
Alright. Let us Yi Zhi Mei get going!