(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
I miss you.
An engineering student can't even fix that?
Give me a minute.
Did you really go to engineering school?
Hello.
I'm sorry. I know it's late, but can you open the door?
What is it?
It's really urgent.
May I get the Wi-Fi password?
- Hurry. - Okay.
There's something wrong with our router.
Hello?
I fixed it! Turn it on.
I don't think it'll work.
(Thinking)
(Jung Soo Kyung)
Time's up already. Your session is over.
What about my prescription?
I have a meeting to attend.
My stomach hurts all the time.
If you turn right at the door, that's the washroom.
It's more difficult to sleep these days.
Give me a stronger sleeping pill.
If you can't sleep,
you need to tire yourself out.
Meet your boyfriend.
Isn't it a good time for you?
Dr. Jung, you're not qualified to be a doctor.
What about you? You won't answer any questions.
I asked you to write journals, and you didn't.
Do you think you're a qualified patient?
If I write journals, will you give me the prescription?
Yes. Write journals.
Start from your happiest moment...
to your worst moment. All of it.
I was 28.
When I quit this hospital which I worked for two years,
I thought I would face a drastic change.
Mending a relationship...
is one of the lies I realized...
while living this life.
A true relationship...
is found in the balance between not harming others...
and not getting harmed by others.
I seek for my own type of happiness.
I'm happier by myself.
(Individualist Ms. Ji Young)
Hello.
Hello, unit 704.
Unit 704. Hello.
Isn't it fun?
It's not fun at all.
Hello, 704.
Ye Jin.
Hello.
700...
Okay.
My...
gosh.
This is for unit 705, but can you take it?
- Pardon? - Thank you.
Hey!
(Please leave it with unit 704.)
Hello.
Here. This is for keeping the package for me.
Let's help each other from time to time.
I told you it was important.
Open up.
Why did you ask her to take it for us?
I didn't know she would do that.
I'm sorry. Don't be mad.
- It's not working anymore. - Here.
You're right. We should tell her to pay for it.
Let's break up.
What?
What is it all of a sudden?
Did I do something wrong?
Did I make you upset?
Say something at least.
That way I can explain myself or make an excuse.
Ji Young.
Ji Young!
Ye Jin, don't go! Where are you going?
I'm going to Mom.
- Where? Where is your mom? - She's somewhere.
- What are you talking about? - Ji Young!
- Why are you doing this? - Let go.
- There must be a reason, right? - Don't!
- I should know why. - I just want to end it.
Ji Young.
I'm sick of you!
Why are you doing this to me all of a sudden?
- Let go. I gave you enough hints. - Ji Young.
It's your fault for being slow.
Please don't go, Ye Jin.
- Let go. - Ji Young.
- I can't eat or do anything without you. - Ji Young.
Gosh.
- Ji Young... - Ye Jin, don't leave.
- Ye Jin. - What's wrong with you?
Ji Young!
Hey, come on.
Ji Young, at least talk to me.
Give it.
- Please. - Give it back.
- Ji Young! - I said, let go!
- Ji Young! - Please forgive me.
I'm leaving. What's wrong with you? You're so annoying.
Don't go, Ye Jin.
Ji Young. Na Ji Young!
Open the door, Na Ji Young!
Don't go!
Open the door!
Are all problems my fault?
Did all of this happen because of me?
If a penalty can be imposed, please go ahead.
It's not like you don't know each other.
Why don't you come to an agreement?
The penalty won't be much anyway.
It won't help the country.
I don't want to.
I don't want to either.
Hey.
What did we do so wrong?
Is it a crime to stop your lover?
Is it a crime?
Trespassing, damage to property,
stalking, concocting fear, and damaging women's rights.
If these are not crimes, what are they?
What are you talking about?
It's not completely wrong.
Right, sir?
She's requesting protective custody,
so you should stay here until tomorrow morning.
Pardon? Tomorrow morning?
But... If I stay until tomorrow morning...
Hey. Ye Jin.
I'm sorry. I deserve to die.
- For what? - For everything.
I'm sorry about everything, so don't go.
Byuk Soo, please stop.
Do you know how suffocating it is to have you chase me?
I feel like I'm being used because of your loneliness.
Hey...
How can you say that I used you?
(Affidavit of Incident)
Hey, Ye Jin!
Ye Jin!
Ye Jin, I'm going to wait for you!
Ye Jin...
That plant...
Didn't I give it to you...
for your parents' wedding anniversary?
I didn't get a chance to give it to them.
Then why did you leave it in the hallway to die?
I told you I hate raising things.
You need to fix that personality of yours.
Who are you to tell me what to do?
I dated you for three months,
but I never went into your place.
I don't know your birthday,
and you never introduced me to your friends. I...
Was I even your boyfriend?
You never told me that you missed me or loved me.
At least tell me the reason.
Tell me why we broke up.
Then let me ask you something.
On Christmas,
you said you are working. What is your plan?
Do you think you have the right to ask me?
You sneaked through my phone to see my schedule.
What's so bad about checking...
(I had a hard time.)
Fine.
I went through your texts to see if you were cheating.
That's why I'm asking now.
Who is the person that said they missed you?
Why did you lie to me?
Ji Young.
Na Ji Young!
You should be thankful I dated you...
until now instead of just sleeping with you!
Who'd like someone like you?
I hope you live like that forever and die alone!
I hope you do!
It'd be immature to blame someone else.
So I will only complain to myself.
It's because I haven't been careful.
It's my fault.
Could I see Kim Yeon Suk?
Are you his customer?
No.
He's my boyfriend.
Pardon?
It was so delicious.
- Hey. - Thank you for lunch.
- See you later. - Okay.
What's this? Are you cheating?
She's cute,
but she's too high maintenance.
So? Do you like your girlfriend because she's not?
Come on. A girl has to be sociable and cute.
That's the fun part of dating.
You should be happy.
"Do this for me. Do that for me."
"Is it me or work?"
"Are your friends more important?" She doesn't do that.
On top of that, she has a nice body and a pretty face.
It's good that she doesn't bother me like other girls.
- What is it? Is there a problem? - Something's off.
I feel like I'm dating someone abnormal.
She said she can't see me on Christmas due to work.
I was suspicious, so I checked her phone.
She's not working that day.
- Gosh. - Goodness.
People. Relationships.
Social life. Small misunderstandings...
and bothersome emotional disputes.
It's a waste of energy.
People force others out of line.
Selfishness is hidden behind empathy.
Foolish humanism.
None of it is real. It's all hypocrisy.
Today, I succeeded again...
in protecting myself from it all.
Sir. I won't do anything. Please let me go home.
I can't sleep unless it's my bed.
I have a stomachache. I need the toilet.
Thank you.
- Where are you running away to? - I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, sir.
There are only two hours left. I really have to leave!
I have to go.
What do I do?
Let me out!
Please let me out! Sir!
Hello?
Ji Young, why haven't you picked up?
- Must I use someone else's number... - Excuse me.
Are you sure you want a 12-digit password?
It's safer, but...
- it'd be annoying. - That's okay.
Okay.
One moment.
It's ready. You can set the password now.
Okay.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Don't bother saying sorry.
It's not like that'll make me feel better.
Can you get out of my way?
What? Hey!
Because of you, we...
Gosh.
She should have raised it well.
What a mean person.
He might die. It's room 301 at Nasan Hospital.
(Block number.)
Can humans live without each other?
The desire to be loved is one of the most basic needs.
(Business Proposal)
This heart. We often use it for "likes".
It derived from human's basic need to be loved.
Humans cannot live while ignoring the others.
We are in isolation.
(Ye Jin has blocked Byuk Soo.)
(This account is private.)
Mr. Choi. Can I borrow your Instagram ID?
Why? To look at your ex-girlfriend's account?
Just make a new account and request to follow.
She didn't accept it, did she?
- What is it? - She and I don't follow each other.
- But... - I have a stomachache. I'll be back.
Mr. Choi.
Mr. Park. I'm sorry,
but can you take care of this for me?
- Sure. Please leave it here. - Thanks.
I have an emergency at home. I'd appreciate it.
I'll take care of it.
- Can you do this? - Sure.
Mine too.
Sure.
Mr. Park.
- Not again. - I need your year-end tax adjustments.
Okay.
Here you go.
- Are you sure you printed it right? - Pardon?
My parents divorced, so it's just my mother's name.
I'm sorry I asked you.
It's okay.
What about income tax deduction form?
I forgot.
I'll bring it to you on Monday. I promise.
Okay.
Gosh, she's so cold.
(Mom)
Hey, Mom.
No, it's nothing much.
I was thinking of visiting you today.
That's true. I'll see you on the weekend anyway. Okay.
Mom? Mom?
Dad. What are you doing today?
You're busy?
No, it's nothing much.
Hey, do you have plans today?
You're busy? You're working late? Okay.
What are you all doing after work today?
Anyone want to drink afterwards?
Warning. He broke up with his girlfriend.
He's so annoying. I hate him.
- What a surprise. - Let's go somewhere expensive.
Okay. Are you paying today?
Of course.
- Mr. Park, we love you. - I love you too.
(Ye Jin has accepted your request.)
Hello.
What's this?
What was it again?
Don't forget to hand your year-end tax adjustments.
I'm leaving.
She must be mad.
Ji Young.
Do you want to go for beer?
No.
Come on. You're off tomorrow. When else can we drink?
It's annoying.
- Pardon? - I said, it's annoying.
Don't bother me, and go on your own.
Ms. Na, I know you're tired,
but did you just tell us we're annoying?
I won't switch shifts.
Hey, my daughter...
asked Santa that she wants to go to the amusement park.
She wished for it. I don't want her to be sad.
All the other kids will get presents, but not her.
The world won't come to an end...
even if your child knows the truth about Santa.
(Pictures)
(Delete pictures.)
(Deleting)
I'm going to delete it. I'll delete it all!
(Delete pictures.)
Delete it...
Mr. Choi, what if I miss her?
I'd at least have to see her pictures.
She started dating another guy right away.
On top of that, it was so quick.
We broke up just two days ago. How can this be?
Could it be? Did she cheat on me?
- Thank you for the drinks. - Thank you.
Mr. Choi. Actually, this isn't the first time.
The one before her. The one before her too.
The one even before that too.
Mr. Park, I'll clear some of the bottles.
Please let's go home now.
I'm going to be alone if I go home.
I don't want to be alone.
Don't leave.
Don't go, Mr. Choi.
(409 dollars)
It isn't even midnight.
(Dream Movie Theater)
(I didn't mean it.)
Don't go.
(12th Assistant Deacon)
"Midnight movie". "Late night".
"Horror movie". "Guess whom I'm with."
"Can you guess?"
"If you guess correctly, you get a prize."
- Did you get a girlfriend? - With a ghost?
- You're not alone, are you? - What's the prize?
You have the time.
You look happy.
Theater two is open now. You may go in.
(Did you get a girlfriend?)
Ta-da!
Can you give me a "like"?
Like.
No.
But... Hey.
No one bought a ticket to the showing of...
"12th Assistant Deacon" starting at 12:15am, right?
Well, sorry. There is one person.
Really?
Then give me the seat as far away as possible.
And a popcorn set please.
Okay.
We'll be watching together like good neighbors.
I'll cancel the ticket.
It starts in 10 minutes, so you can't cancel it.
Gosh.
Seriously...
Soda. You forgot it.
(Wise soul that trend died long ago.)
No...
Me? I didn't drink it.
I didn't touch your soda.
Sorry.
Seriously.
Darn it.
Wait for me.
It's scary at night.
Let's walk together. Why are you going alone?
I said I'd walk with you.
You shouldn't walk around alone...
so late at night. What if something happens?
Excuse me.
What the... Why... Why are you like that?
Why? Why? Darn it.
It's so cold.
The door is closing.
Hey. Why did you press close button when I was coming?
Hey. Look.
Don't you see me?
Hey.
Goodness.
Hold the door. I'm going up too.
May I get in?
Of course. Come in.
Why did you put so much on your lips?
What is that flavor?
Wait. Does that mean...
we kissed indirectly...
Is that why you're upset?
It's okay.
I'll pretend I kissed a stray dog.
What are you, a kid? An indirect kiss? Seriously.
If you think I'm interested in you...
I am not!
I was afraid of walking in the dark and wanted to...
walk together.
Okay, I see.
This is the fifth floor.
Going up.
Wait. Why do you watch movies alone?
Do you eat alone too?
Really? You do everything alone?
I'm not someone who can't do anything alone.
Were you an outcast when you were in school?
Don't you realize how extremely rude you are?
You think all the individualists...
have a problem.
I just find people who act like you...
annoying. That's all.
Wow. You actually know how to speak.
I've never seen you say so much before.
I didn't want to talk to you, so I was holding it in.
You'll end up dying alone.
You don't want to die alone, so you get married.
You don't want to die alone, so you have a kid.
Then the wife dies first.
Then your child will send you to a nursing home.
That's how you end up when you're a fool...
who struggles all his life...
because he's afraid of being alone.
How is that better than dying alone?
What... Why are you making up my future?
Because that's reality.
If you have money, confidence and courage,
you can be alone without any problem.
Without being a complete fool like you.
Complete fool... What the...
It's better than being self-centered like somebody.
It's called being individualistic.
Good for you.
Thank you for the compliment.
Go ahead and live well on your own.
I plan to anyway.
Why do you make your life so complicated?
That's right. That woman changes guys frequently.
You were the 2nd. Were you the 3rd?
What?
No, I was wrong. Sorry.
Yes. It's not that...
You were the fourth to be exact.
Darn it. Why that little...
I hate people. I hate other people.
I hate them more today than yesterday. This year...
Hello? This is unit 704.
Would you please tell 705 to keep it down?
Yes. Did you just hear that?
Who's doing the dishes at this hour?
Please tell her that is absolutely illogical.
Do you hear that? Would you tell him...
to use earphones when it's this late?
You hate me, right?
I hate you too.
I feel like I wasted time and energy because of you,
so I regret it.
If we run into each other again, let's walk away...
and just ignore each other. Okay, then.
"Okay, then"?
Not "Okay, goodbye," or "Okay, see you later,"
but "Okay, then"?
See? I told you there's no problem.
There's nothing else? This is everything?
- What? - About the guy next door.
He's a perfect fit for you.
He's hilarious.
You confirmed that I'm fine, so prescribe...
Nothing bad happened to you.
There was nothing wrong with your family.
You date well enough too.
So why are you depressed?
What's wrong with depression?
How many people are actually happy?
Why are you so hostile?
I'm not hostile. I react truthfully to how I feel.
Have you ever missed anyone?
Your parents or a boyfriend, perhaps?
Well, sometimes.
That's good.
That longing...
can be felt only if you care about someone.
There are some patients who have never felt that.
It's so sad.
How can you always end my sessions like that?
I...
can't treat someone who isn't honest to herself.
If you know someone who can, go there.
Write that again. Not for someone else,
but for yourself.
Darn it.
Ji Young.
Ji Young. I said things that were too harsh.
Are you sick? You're sweating.
You don't look well. Hold on.
- Listen to me... - Let go!
Are... Are you okay? Get up.
Don't come after me. Leave.
- Go. Please go. - Ji Young!
Ji Young, are you okay? Ji Young!
- Ji Young! - No. Don't come.
Were you an outcast when you were in school?
Ji Young...
What was that?
Was that a thief?
I'm using the bathroom.
Why are you opening the door?
I... I didn't know. I'm sorry.
That's not right.
Why are you using my bathroom?
I can't...
remember...
my door code.
Excuse me. Did you...
In your clothes...
I did not!
Should I report you for trespassing?
You're so mean!
Look who's talking.
You just broke the law. Do you realize that?
What's the locksmith's number? I'll get your clothes.
No. Just lend me something of yours. Anything's fine.
Are you kidding me?
My clothes are all expensive.
They aren't clothes you can get stuff on.
You really can't go into my home.
I'll reimburse you, so please...
Whatever! Then I'll just call the cops.
But you can't touch anything else, okay?
You can't.
No wonder she's so skinny.
I know. It's only been a few days.
Should I still make the code 12 digits again?
Just make it 4. Like 1, 2, 3, 4. Something like that.
She'll change it.
It's the same breed as Yang Soon.
So she does know how to smile.
Does she have a cat?
Here, kitty.
She doesn't fit at all.
(Family Registry)
Didn't I give it to you...
for your parents' wedding anniversary?
(Family member, Seo Yoon Sook)
What's taking him so long?
You could've just gone to work.
How could I leave my home...
with a trespasser inside?
I'll repay you.
I brought it in because I felt bad for it.
It didn't die completely.
Do you want it back?
No. I don't need it.
Look. Why are you so arrogant?
Aren't you embarrassed?
Don't you remember the post?
So?
Your code is 1234.
He said to change it.
Gosh.
(Family Registry)
Why did you do that?
Why did you pay Yun Hee's tuition?
Wow. Did you make all of this for me?
You worked so hard.
I'm just giving you some of what my family eats.
Mom, did you throw away my book?
I thought I could throw away...
things you left behind.
Why? Do you need it?
I have to take that course again.
Why did you throw it away without asking?
How much is that book?
- 50 dollars. - 50 dollars. Okay.
While you're at it,
can you give me some spending money too?
Why are you...
What? I'm his little sister.
- Right? - Of course. Here.
This is for my little sister since you live alone.
And this is money for your trip next week.
Thank you. Yes!
Do you want to go too?
What? Really?
I can go too? Really?
Of course. Why not? You're family.
Then the three of us should take a family picture.
I'll bring my camera.
Mom, Dad said he'll be here soon.
I'll go now, Mom.
Hi, Mom.
What? I brought the wrong containers?
It's the same food anyway.
That's true,
but Yun Hee said she'll go down to get it.
- Mom. - Yes? What?
I'm always thankful...
that you pack food for your grown son.
Byuk Soo!
Hey.
Here.
She says she'll move out...
as soon as she finds a new place. Okay.
You won't find a place as nice and quiet as here.
It isn't so nice and quiet lately.
It isn't?
Is that floor cursed?
Your next door neighbor put his up too.
Unit 705?
Yes. His roommate moved out,
so it's too big to live in alone.
He said it's to lonely or something.
Then I won't move.
(Real Estate Agency)
Hi. What a coincidence.
It'll be Christmas soon.
Wait. Didn't you and your boyfriend fight about that?
I was wondering...
Are you really cheating? You have another guy?
Stay out of it.
You won't be spending tomorrow alone too, will you?
If you're lonely, I can...
That's right. I won't be home.
I'm going away with my...
My family.
Hey. I told you not to touch my things.
Well... I didn't mean to.
It was all your fault.
My parents are divorced too.
Your family registry looked just like mine.
That's why...
So? Does other people's sadness amuse you?
That's not it.
It's just something we have in common.
You had a cat too, right?
So did I. Yang Soon...
That's...
I opened your drawer and happened to see...
We have that in common too.
I don't care whether your parents...
got a divorce...
or died in a car accident.
Why did you lie to your ex-boyfriend?
There's no need to announce your weakness to strangers.
Not unless you're stupid.
Is your boyfriend a stranger?
Even married couples...
become strangers to each other once they get divorced.
Just like your parents.
Why are you saying such hurtful things?
What did I do that was so wrong?
I just wanted to talk to you...
When a murderer is standing there with a knife,
who would just stay still?
If I don't stab him first,
I'll be the one stabbed.
I told you not to, but you keep stabbing me.
You don't care whether others are stabbed...
as long as you're safe, right?
Here's compensation for last time.
Let's end our relationship here.
Let's end it with this.
Forget it.
Hi, Mom. I'm shopping for stuff for the trip.
What?
I'm sorry.
Yun Hee says she'll be uncomfortable with you there.
Be understanding.
Okay.
Stop being so mean to your brother.
Think of all he does for you.
What? We don't share any blood.
He can do that much after...
being raised in our family where he doesn't belong.
(Mom)
Lovers, friends, and families taking family pictures...
captured unforgettable moments on their cameras.
In order to celebrate...
Four days ago, during the deep freeze,
she passed away all alone in her small home.
(Merry Christmas. What are you doing?)
(Want to meet up?)
If you're going to ignore me, don't read it.
If you're going to read it, don't ignore me!
Darn it. Jerks.
Hi, Suk Joon.
You must've heard about me.
Hey, Byuk Soo. Yes, I heard.
How are you holding up?
- Are you alone? - Yes.
Thanks.
You were worried that I'd be alone today.
Sorry, but can you do something for me?
What? Sure.
I have nothing to do anyway.
My grad school professor...
asked me to find some data for him.
I...
can't treat someone who isn't honest to herself.
A family trip?
He must be so happy.
(Delete pictures.)
Hi, it's Byuk Soo.
No. I won't do it!
Hey. You don't want to do it because it's Christmas.
Do you think I would?
And you call only when you have a favor to ask.
Don't call for things like that again.
The person you have reached is unavailable.
Please leave a message after the tone.
What?
She didn't go out?
Excuse me!
Can you please stop?
Darn it. Who cares?
Did she die?
She wouldn't die.
Did she faint?
Excuse me!
Was it my idea? You're the one that didn't do it.
- Don't blame me. - You mentioned it only once.
You're so thoughtless...
How could I ask you again when I don't see you?
- You need to be home first. - Mommy.
- As in you're not responsible? - Mommy.
- Why are you so arrogant? - The kitten.
Are you saying it's all my fault? Stop that!
Cats are too annoying to raise.
There's no Santa.
You start school next year, and you still believe that.
Why are you so stupid?
Santa gave me a dead cat as a gift,
and in exchange,
I cried like the worst kid on Earth.
Ever since,
there has never been a Santa on Christmas for me.
You should raise her since she's a girl. That's best.
I decide what's best or not.
- I'm in no position to raise her! - What about me?
- That great woman... - A child who's grown up...
does not need adults.
Just as Christmas is meaningless to a child...
who doesn't believe in Santa Claus.
No one needs to raise me.
I'll live on my own.
Like that, a child becomes an adult.
To a child who became an adult,
pity is insulting.
A sign that you are not mature enough.
A misconception that you are unstable alone.
Prejudice that you are not fine.
Today again, I hid my face...
to avoid being pitied.
Don't die. Don't die! I'm telling you! Don't die!
Darn it.
What are you doing here?
It's Christmas.
Are you okay?
And what are you doing here?
- It's Christmas. - You didn't go...
on your family trip?
A family trip on Christmas day?
Forget it. I can't stand it.
Still, it's better than being alone.
Why didn't you change your code or put the chain on?
That's not like you.
Why do I make life so complicated?
Why can't I be simple?
That's what I wondered.
Why do you hate me?
It isn't just you.
I hate everyone. That's just me.
People hate me too.
I'm sorry for hating you when you were nice to me.
But you know,
I'll keep being that way.
Whatever.
I don't like you either.
Anyway, why did you come in here?
I was watching the news,
and the streets were filled with people.
There are so many people in the world,
but I have no one to be with.
It was too sad.
I have hundreds of numbers in my phone...
and thousands of followers, but...
What?
Don't people like you have a lot of friends?
I worked hard all my life not to be alone,
so why am I alone on a day like this?
Doesn't everyone like people like you?
Aren't you surrounded by love?
For some, love is a given,
but not me.
It's not like people love you...
just because you try hard to be loved.
They use me because I'm easy. That's all.
Still, your family must love you.
I'm not their real son.
I was adopted.
They don't show it,
but they discriminate subtly.
That hurts a lot.
But I have no right to get angry.
Why can't you ask?
Get angry.
Why can't you ask why they do that to you?
Because I don't want to be abandoned twice.
I had my adoption dissolved once before.
It wasn't your fault.
The ones who abandoned you are the jerks.
I did nothing wrong to them.
I never hurt them.
Just because you hurt people less,
it doesn't mean you'll be hurt less.
Are you stupid?
What? Stupid...
Why are you getting so worked up about my life?
You're an individualist.
Exactly. Why are you telling me about your life?
Then what? Should we talk about work?
Just give up as I have.
Don't expect anything at all.
I really want to know something.
What if I give up?
If I don't expect anything,
will I not be lonely?
Oops.
Anyway, happy birthday.
I noticed your unique birthday on the form.
Do you want to come up here?
Sorry?
I'm going to leave.
And that's a single. It's too tight.
It isn't tight if we put them together.
What?
Do... Do you mean it?
I mean it.
(Individualist Ms. Ji Young)
Ji Young.
I don't like easy guys like you.
Do you even like anything?
Me.
If you won't open your heart, I'll just barge in.