You're a big venue now.
Global commerce,
sports franchises. . .
chit-chat cafes.
But you don't get it
because you don't see it.
Life is not what you think it is.
Because of guys like us. . .
you can go on thinking it. . .
'til reality sets in.
Reality's a motherfucker.
The first thing you do
when it hits you. . .
is wonder where we are.
We do our shit.
You do yours.
But remember. . .
it's a dirty world.
And without us,
it'd be a whole lot dirtier.
Welcome to Edison.
Heads up.
2 harbor cops just showed up.
We got problems in here.
If they come into bank, shoot 'em.
Any units near 12th and Plaza,
respond to an alarm at Plaza Bank.
Approach with caution.
We got it.
What was that?
You're outta your fuckin mind.
You know that? Fuck!
- You want onions with that?
- Yeah.
There you go.
- Stay down !
Go.
Get in the car!
What are you doing?
Stay calm.
I know you're hurt.
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
Okay buddy.
I know you're hurt.
Get you to your feet, okay?
All your friends are dead,
fuckhead.
It's just me and you now.
Come on GI Joe.
Come out and play.
Come on.
Drop the gun, walk away,
or I'll kill her.
Close your eyes, sweetheart.
You don't wanna see this.
It's okay, come on.
Come on, it's okay.
Just a flesh wound.
It's okay.
You're alright.
It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
That bad man's not gonna
hurt you any more.
It's okay.
On your knees!
Come on !
What's goin' on?
- Lock your fingers behind !
- Put your hands behind your head.
Come on crack whores!
Look at that China White, baby.
Look at that China fuckin' White.
That's my money, too.
That's all my money.
- Motherfucker.
- Okay, fuckhead. You squatters?
Fuck you talkin' about?
- You own this house?
- No.
- What about you?
- You got a lease?
- No.
You got a mortgage?
You guys fucked up tonight.
Don't look at me.
Don't fuckin' look at me.
Okay, this is how it works.
You never saw us.
And we never saw you.
The world just keeps turnin' .
- You ain't takin' us in?
- Nah.
Got to all school.
We answer up, get capped
for losin' that shit.
Yeah, maybe you should
leave town.
Motha' fuckers.
We'll get his license.
Rat his ass out to the Feds.
Tired of this bullshit.
Fuck that.
Welcome to the majors.
It gets easier after the first one.
Him.
Rafe.
Not ready, bro?
I'll take care of this shit.
The fuck?
Oh, you motherfucker.
You fuckin' spit at me?
I'll fuckin' kill you!
Aw, Jesus.
Jesus.
Oh, Jesus, Jesus,
Jesus, Jesus.
Come on.
Come on. Stop cryin' .
I haven't seen you
around here before.
Who are you?
Isiaha Charles.
I just moved here with my mom.
Who's he to you?
I just met him.
He gave me a job.
Where'd you do time?
I've never done time.
- You never did time?
- No.
Oh, that is good shit.
You want some?
I'm good.
All right.
This is how it's gonna work.
Your buddy was smokin' crack
and he got fuckin' crazy. . .
and he came at you with a knife.
Now tell me what happened.
My buddy, he got fuckin' crazy. . .
and he came after me
with a knife.
Which is when Lazerov
and I entered the domicile
in response to
a domestic disturbance. . .
and saw the defendant fire
one round from a bulldog.
- Is this that bulldog You refer to?
- Yes.
- Is this the knife You pried from
the deceased's hand? / - Yes
- What was he doing with him?
- Something to stab the defendant.
Now after the deceased deceased
did the defendant resist?
- No.
- did he say anything?
He cried, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
Cried?
What do you mean he cried?
He cried.
Jesus, Jesus.
That's enough.
- Jesus. Oh my God.
- That's enough, Officer Deed.
You may step down.
Thank you.
That'll be a 10 minute recess.
We'll reconvene at quarter past.
- What the hell was that?
- Testifying.
- to the Second Coming?
- Back off.
Officer Deed?
Officer Deed.
Yeah.
- Why'd he thank you?
- Who are you?
Josh Pollack.
Heights Herald.
- the Jewish handout?
- It's a community weekly.
The guy is Jewish?
You're shittin' me.
I don't know he's Jewish.
And, what do you care?
You busted him in Ashtown,
that's adjacent to the Heights.
Tell our Jewish friends not to worry.
They can still walk to worship.
So why'd he say thank you?
It's a manslaughter
and possession beef.
- It could've been murder.
- So Why did FRAT catch this?
Talk to public affairs.
Officer Deed, can you tell me why
FRAT is cruising the streets?
Talk to public affairs.
Guy thanked you?
Jack-off.
I hate that fuckin' guy.
- Who's that?
- Wallace. Pussy.
Hey.
How'd court go, Frank?
Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
- Something I should know?
- No. Same old, Same old.
Deed's first murder testimony.
Yep, weapons possession
18 months.
Rafe. Inspection Monday?
Be sure you're there.
Pollack.
Pollack!
Yes, sir?
What are you doing?
Article on the murder trial.
I told you to put the verdict
on the police blotter.
That's a sentence, not a tome.
It's a legitimate story.
Then find a legitimate paper
to publish it.
All I want is the verdict, okay?
Fraud.
Sorry, did you say something?
No, sir. I didn't.
That's what I thought.
Actually I said fraud.
Did you now?
You know why The Times
won't hire you Pollack?
You don't do the work.
A thousand words, not a single
fact except for the verdict.
Everything else is supposition.
FRAT wouldn't talk to me.
So the point of covert police
work is not to talk about it.
This incident is public record, sir.
Involving undercover police
who like to keep a low profile,
so they can sleep at night.
You can't imply nefarious activity
because a felon whispered
thank you to one of them.
I qualified it with a question.
You qualified. . .
Watch my lips, son.
You're not qualified to qualify.
Nobody cares what you think.
Only what you know and that's
diddly 'cause you don't do the work!
Unfortunate this is about as well
written as you are uninformed.
You know what?
I think you should try novels.
You're fired.
This isn't a real paper anyway.
Perfect for you.
Lazy little shit.
Get out while you can.
Shit.
Rafe.
Don't make yourself crazy.
You're gonna give
yourself a hernia.
Come on. Let's go to bed.
You want the free range
Chicken Kiev with potatoes
or vegetables over risotto
in a bell pepper sauce?
I'd like a meal prepared to order,
not manufactured for distribution.
Ashford was right.
About what?
All this articulate conjecture
wrapped around one fact.
- Isiaha Charles, illegal weapons
possession. / - Right.
- 8 words if you count the preposition.
- Another critic.
- You asked me to read it.
- It was mistake.
Because I agree with him?
Come on, sweetie.
You know I thought being fired
was the highlight of my day.
You're great sex.
But imperious and penniless
are serious social handicaps
and you should stick
with your strengths.
I was hoping for sympathy.
Poor baby.
Well, that woulda worked.
Yeah, that's bullshit.
Rafe.
Talk to me, please.
- Is It your headaches again?
- Leave It alone, please.
I said I'm okay.
What's wrong with you?
I'm worried.
I'm okay. I'm all right.
I'm gonna take a ride.
Rafe please,
you need to get help.
He couldn't'a done better,
believe me.
Hey, Rafe, what's up?
You're almost a no-show
for inspection.
Oh, no no.
I had dinner at Maria's.
I thought you were ending that.
I am gonna process ending it.
You can get inspected every day of
the week, Rafe, if you need it.
But there are no exceptions.
I need your commitment.
I made my commitment.
That's for sure.
All right.
Let's go have some fun.
- say hello to Marilyn.
- Hey, Marilyn.
Hey, hero.
The girls'll be happy to see you.
He's making me
a little bit nervous.
You stalking me now?
- I'm not lazy.
- You're stoned.
And you are a vision
of temperance.
- this Is Cambodia.
- It was Kampuchea at the time.
Wow. I knew you used
to be somebody but
- You're burying the lead, kid.
- Come on man, I'm a good writer.
So what?
That builds strong papers.
- And this story Is impor. . .
- Pollack.
I don't publish stories.
I publish coupons for merchants who
don't kidnap competition,
bomb busses
or immolate themselves.
- Am I wrong about the story?
- What do I know?
- Help me get It right.
- do the work.
I was in court, I took notes
and tried to talk to FRAT.
Talk to the defendant, huh?
He's in Longworth.
Afraid to visit prison?
How am I talk to somebody who
knows the defendant well.
How about visiting the scene of
the crime, make an assessment.
Okay.
- You're right.
- As if I need your affirmation.
I'm not telling you to do this.
I'm telling you not to.
Could be dangerous.
Will you help me or not?
Why the sudden urge
to get this right?
My girlfriend read it.
Agreed with you.
Right.
You're doin' this for pussy.
- Well I wouldn't put it that way.
- For Pussy.
What happened to you?
Don't talk to the system.
What the hell does that mean?
Make up somethin' .
5:52 a.m.
The call was for a D and D,
domestic disturbance.
We knocked.
Couldn't be heard over the shouting.
Well the time, 5:52 a.m.
5: 17, 6: 10.
There's no 5:52.
No report that date and address.
Filed by a Sergeant Francis Lazerov,
or an Officer Raphael Deed.
- FRAT files aren't public record.
- Why?
- We can't speak for FRAT.
- Who can?
FRAT.
Even if you were with a real paper
I wouldn't talk to you. That's Policy.
It's public record, Captain Tilman.
It's trial and conviction.
Not us, alright?
Here we go.
If you're gonna turn every beef
between two losers into headlines
that's gonna seriously compromise
our ability to social deviancy.
You know, we might as well
pack it up and close shop.
Screw John Q. Citizen.
Is that what you want?
I don't think so.
Have a good one.
- Bern !
- Sir.
It's Capt. Tilman, head of First
Response Assault & Tactical Unit.
Thanks a large part
to this gentleman
we're looking at an 82% reduction in homicides,69 in felonies,
71 in sexual assault.
With those number we can have
early intervention program.
In fact I see a day when
we won't need courts at all.
- Hi.
- No, You Stay away.
No. I'm just looking for
somebody. Ms. Melba Charles?
She lives here, right?
She's over there.
Oh, Jesus.
Isiaha Charles?
I'm Josh Pollack, I'm a writer.
- I was at your trial.
- Oh, Yeah.
Here.
Listen.
After Officer Deed testified,
you said thank you.
Why?
I can't talk about the trial.
Can we talk about you?
Who you were before this?
By the way, I'm very sorry
about your mother.
What about my mother?
Her stroke.
Stroke?
- You don't know.
- Whoa, when?
- a few days ago, I guess.
- How bad of a stroke?
Is my mother a vegetable?
I'm sorry.
Oh, Mama.
Motherfuckers!
A'ight, look.
You gotta get me outta here.
You gotta get me to my mother.
- I can't.
- No, You can.
If you get me out of here, I'll tell you
everything you want about the trial.
- I don't know how.
- the way they capped Rook.
- What?
- Stole the crack, the 40 G's.
Made up that shit about the knife.
I'll tell you all of that.
Ma. . .
I love you.
You hang on.
I'll be home soon.
I promise.
You get this to her.
You promise me.
Fuck!
I'm sorry.
Mrs. Charles.
Ma, I love you.
You hang on.
I'll be home soon.
I promise.
You call me now?
I'm not your personal editor.
Just read this.
This is a Pulitzer.
What's it for?
Blowing the judging committee.
What do you think?
You saw Isiaha's arrest report?
Copies of the court transcript.
- No mention of cash, coke or guns?
- No.
- the emergency dispatch?
- The copy's there.
There's no record of a 911
that time, date, address.
You talked to the District Attorney,
the Public Defender, Judge.
You told me not to
talk to the system.
What do you think?
It could dismantle the
department when it's done.
What's missing?
The other side of the story.
They're murderers.
If you believe Isiaha Charles.
You won't publish it as is?
I won't publish it at all.
But The Times will if you
get the department's side.
The department?
They're murderers.
Right.
You're doing this for pussy.
I'm doin' it for this.
Fourth estate, Pollack.
It's the only job protected by
the Constitution, and this is why.
This is tyranny.
When you see it
you're obligated to yell.
A risk you're unwilling to take,
and I don't blame you.
In your new enlightenment I'll take
you back to the Herald,
but don't call yourself a jeranalist.
The coupon king has spoken.
Good night, Pollack.
Oh, here, take this with you.
Go on, leave. Leave.
Go.
- get the door.
- got it.
You move, you die!
Spread 'em! Spread 'em!
- Here.
- Against the wall.
Hey Deed !
I got somethin' for ya!
Come on, baseball.
Watch your step!
Fuck.
Shut up, gimme your other hand.
Shut up.
All right, let's go.
Bern, I owe you. . .Anything
Not now, not here.
Girls, come out everybody come out.
- Laz.
- Yeah.
Take the girls out.
I'm going downstairs.
- Party at my house.
- Line up Here.
- Let's go.
- Come on, sweetie.
Come on.
Here ya go, cupcake.
The fuck am I gonna do with this?
I thought you gave up
muckraking, Moses.
It's Pollack's story.
You heard of anything
like this, Levon?
Sure all the time.
From felons.
Well, there it is.
D.A. 's office doesn't comment on
unsubstantiated accusations.
Why don't you come back
when you have specifics?
- We can't be more specific.
- What are We talking about?
Innuendo? Hearsay?
D.A. needs names.
Otherwise the office can't respond.
Jack, when did you start referring
to yourself as an inanimate object?
You run a community weekly Moses
and I'll always have time for you
but now that time is up.
Mr. Pollack.
Mr. Reigert. Mr. Wallace.
These aren't the good old days,
Moses.
They never were, Jack.
- Why wouldn't you give him
- Huh-uh.
- if You were to just
- Not now.
Ashford doesn't come here easily.
He didn't have anything
specific or actual either.
Ignore it.
I'm not insulting Tilman with this.
Yeah, it's Jack.
Can you come on over?
- Why weren't you more specific?
- You have a source to protect.
I was that vague, you fired me.
Do you know how
pervasive this is?
Are you think they're involved?
I don't know who's involved,
and neither do you.
Than why did we
even come here?
Levon Wallace,
city's best investigator.
If the story holds up
he'll confirm it.
What do we do now?
I publish coupons.
You should look for a job.
- Mr. Ashford
- Look, kid.
You've got a story, access to the
D.A. and his best investigator.
If you can't make a career of that
you don't belong in this business.
Mr. Ashford.
Stop the Mister. Okay?
I'm outta this game.
And your late night visits irk me.
If Wallace confirms your story,
then you have to put the question
to Tilman, Lazerov, and Deed.
Use a phone.
And pray they don't take the call.
Moses!
Look, kid.
It's Friday.
Go do what you're supposed to do.
Go get laid, for christ sake.
- Outta the way.
- I wasn't doin' a thing.
Yeah, whatever.
- Look out.
- All right!
Hey.
Just here to dance.
Have a good time.
What?
Oh, my God. . .
Poppy.
Pollack.
- Who's that?
- He's a reporter.
We have to go.
- Why?
- We have to go.
- That's the guy from your story.
- Shh.
He's kinda cute, right?
Are you dating other people?
Don't worry. Looks like
he just got engaged.
I saw that.
Tough break for you.
You never put a face on it do you?
Once published, it will ruin his life.
I'm not ruining his life.
I said your story.
God, it is always about you, right?
I do think about that. Okay.
I think about ruining somebody's
life.
You're not gonna get
self-absorbed and mopey?
Don't get all soft and mopey
Hey, what are you doing?
- What happened?
- Come on. Move it!
Get outta the way!
Move! Move!
Don't move, help's comin' .
Aw, fuck.
Officer Deed, Edison P. D. I have 2
down outside the Plaza Nightclub.
I have a medical bracelet here.
It says serum prothrombin
conversion, blood type O.
Stay still, buddy. Help's comin' .
- She needs help.
- I know. Stay still.
You okay?
Yeah.
Hell. Shit.
Wallace?
You ever answer your
fucking phone?
You?
I've been up all night.
Pollack got the shit kicked up
last night, so did Willow.
What? Who?
His girlfriend.
They're in the hospital.
How bad?
She's in a coma.
She's got factor seven deficiency.
It's a blood disorder.
They don't know how
she's gonna survive.
And Pollack?
Took a beating but he'll be all right.
Mugged?
Warned.
Who are you?
Deed. Edison P. D.
- You don't wanna be here.
- Who are you?
Moses Ashford,
I own the paper he works for.
- How bad Is he?
- He's banged up.
Sedated. Do you care?
- Tell him somethin'?
- Tell him What?
Tell him I have nothing
to do with this.
- with What?
- You gonna Tell him or not?
Officer Deed.
Is there any hope for you, son?
No.
Let go.
- What are you doin'?
- Go me.
It's not safe for him here.
Move him somewhere safe.
Come in.
Make yourself as
comfortable as you can.
The market will deliver.
It's on Wallace's tab.
You have run of the house,
but, no matches.
- No fire at All near the barn.
- You told me.
All that dry hay could catch fire.
This place has been in
Wallace's family for years.
Why do I have to stay here?
You don't have to stay here.
take a plane, go home to mommy.
I wanna be near Willow.
Believe me, it's safer
both of you if you're here.
When I publish.
You can't publish.
- Why not?
- Look at what they did to me!
Serious journalism doesn't
look so good up close, huh?
It's a little hard to tell with this large
thing hanging over my eye, thanks.
So who's a fraud now?
You know what? You don't
even know what it's like.
Life's a bitch, ain't it?
Think you can swim, then it's oh
shit, where are my water wings?
This isn't from swimming pool.
No, this is what you aspire to.
You want a prize?
Here's your shot.
See when you asked Charles
to tell you his story you committed.
Now you have a moral duty.
People depending on you.
Doesn't get any better than that, kid.
Hey, why are you doin'
this to me?
Cause you did it to me.
I'll call you later.
How can I help you, Frank?
Why were you at that club?
Yoga, exercises, aerobics.
What do you think? I was dancin' .
Dancin'?
Yeah. It's a dance club, Frank.
I'm fuckin' James Brown.
Watch me.
- Ow!
- Yeah, I feel good.
- I got soul.
- Neck bones, candy ass.
- Right, Right, right. right.
- Oh.
- After You clocked out. . .
- Hm?
- Tilman got a call.
- right.
That Herald reporter was
makin' noise at the Hall.
Nothin' hardcore but
he had to come to Jesus.
The girl need one, too?
I didn't know
she had bad blood.
- I figured She was a bonus.
- right.
Gave him a sermon, he's pissed
chapter and verse the girlfriend.
- He won't be gettin' dumb now.
- Yeah.
This is from Tilman.
- You gotta worry.
- right.
Pollack.
The kid's got nothin' .
His source.
Who?
Your Jesus buddy got
shanked at Longworth.
Drive safe.
Fuck.
Who the hell told you?
Lazerov said it came from you.
I went to the hospital, went in there.
And I saw a some guy,
I don't know who it was.
And I was Deed.
Deed was talking to him I left.
Lazerov said?
When did that start?
Please, give me a break.
- Give You a break?
- You know What Lazerov said
Can you over the hospital he's
taking you and Wu to the hospital,
nobody's calling me,
nobody's saying anything.
I thought you knew.
It's not up to me.
How do I know?
Oh, shit.
Well thank you.
Thanks for dropping by
and laying this shit on me.
Hospital security.
- Lazerov?
- You got that For me?
Yeah, Pollack was released
to Wallace and Ashford.
What'd you get?
Nothin' that can't be mitigated.
Except maybe the photos,
taken before help arrived.
And there's a bad news.
- Charles Is dead.
- What?
Knifed at Longworth.
Great. If Charles is dead,
we got nothin' .
We got a bigger problem.
FRAT collars dealers
with drugs, guns, flesh.
Guilty verdicts.
Whatever FRAT confiscates,
FRAT keeps.
$ 12 million cash
in the past 5 years.
Six million dollars for ordnance.
Four million for surveillance.
Tilman overpays by two,
three, 400 percent.
But take a look at
who he's buying from.
Surveillance from midland.
PC's from high tower.
Arms from Phoenix.
Oh, Digi-Vector
they built FRAT's website.
They own sports teams.
Car dealerships.
Retail chains.
City's leadership.
And the founders of
the Better Edison Foundation.
When did this pop up?
It hasn't yet.
Official opening's next week.
Reigert.
It's a political action committee.
The overpayments
end up right here.
Money laundering.
Yeah well, we're not gonna
find any memos on that.
You showed me the bones
of a covert fascist state.
Methodist Hospital.
Hi, I'm checking on a patient,
Willow Summerfield.
Are you a relative?
I'm a friend.
I was in the hospital with her.
Oh. One moment.
Shit.
Just spread it out here.
FRAT's basic profile.
Six-two, 200 plus pounds.
Perfect rifle, pistol scores. . .
each one of 'em prior to joining
FRAT had three physical. . .
fights in their jackets.
None are married, no kids.
The night Pollack was attacked,
he was there.
- Why Is that a surprise.
- he was with a girl.
She kept lookin' at an engagement
ring like she just got it.
So two things.
You don't take your honey to
a tune-up and FRAT don't marry.
Come on.
I really like living alone but,
I'm beginning to think. . .
What?
I think I need a woman in my life.
Well, shit, don't look at me.
He's not answerin' .
You dialed the wrong number.
I know my number,
I dialed it twice.
He's gone.
Motherfucker!
Damn it. Why don't I
call the County Sheriff?
The County Sheriff is Tilman's
duck hunting partner.
There. There.
Josh !
What the fuck are you doing?
Lazerov was at the farm!
I blew up that bastard's car.
You blew up his car.
He was gonna kill me.
Jesus Christ.
Well Tilman'll rein Lazerov
in for goin' to my house
but it doesn't mean you're safe.
He's homicidal.
He's killed 6 in the line of duty.
Six? And he's still
wearing a badge?
That was 15 years ago when Edison
was the murder capital of America.
When our biggest industry was
the production of crystal meth
and when drive-bys were a sport.
That was before you came back.
Did you see Deed give a girl
an engagement ring?
Yeah.
Why is that important?
No member of FRAT's
ever been married.
So?
It may be the only hook
we have to hang our hat on.
- Isiaha Charles can
- Charles's dead.
- What?
- he was knifed in prison.
Jesus Christ.
Your work ever ruin a life?
Did it?
You do this job right you'll
ruin lives, celebrate murderers.
They'll give you
a Pulitzer Prize for it.
I need you to reach out to Deed.
Look, you don't have
to do this with your life.
But if you're going to,
now is when you decide.
- Who Is this?
- It's Pollak.
What the fuck do you want it?
Meet me at Blunts.
Damn, Francis,
you are outta control.
You are outta control, Francis.
I thought you said you
wanted fear of God put in this guy.
So you thought that extended
to his girlfriend?
I just thought.
No, you didn't think.
You acted on impulse.
I've had to preach to a spouse,
but only after due consideration.
Do consideration.
You enlisted Marilyn, Wu and you
went to that hospital on impulse!
And now this!
The fuckin' punk was
writin' a story about me.
There is no story, Francis!
It's a bunch of allegations made
by a convicted felon who is dead.
And that's where it
woulda stayed had you
not dragged it to the front door
of Lee Wallace's family farm.
Instead of a kid makin' his first foray
into the world of journalism.
I got a seasoned investigator
up my ass probing FRAT business.
This is gonna require
all my attention.
Until it's resolved,
you're desk-bound.
You're takin' Wallace's side?
No.
He's a fuckin' poser.
Rodeo clown with Santa Fe
string tie bullshit.
Gimme a break. I've done everything
you asked me to do.
Yes.
He pissed on the idea
of FRAT since the beginning.
That's politics.
15 fuckin' years
I'm on the streets.
Gettin' rid of the cancer
that was killin' this town !
Fifteen years ago, Edison
needed brute force to survive.
Now, it needs finesse,
hardly your strong suit!
I've done everything.
Every fuckin' thing
that you asked me to do.
Yes.
And now what?
You're gonna throw me
in the fuckin' garbage?
I'm on your side.
Let's just go get in the car.
It's not fuckin' right
you takin' his side.
I'm on your side.
It's not right you takin' his side.
I'm not. . .
It's not fuckin' right
you takin' his side!
It's not fuckin' right!
Francis.
You're my guy,
you're number one with me.
Since day one.
What are you doin'?
You're my guy okay?
Let's get in the car
and get the fuck outta here.
Straight up?
That's no bullshit.
Let's just go get in the car,
all right?
And cut the shit.
- Let's get in the car.
- I'm sorry. I just need to sleep.
Yeah.
Smooth operator.
I'm in the book.
Your line
may be tapped.
Are you?
No.
I'm not wired.
You're shakin' .
Well I'm scared shitless.
I didn't do that to you.
Now where are they?
Down the street.
And who are they?
You should teach.
What?
You said you needed a woman
The only guys your age I know. . .
havin' sex regularly
are college professors.
This is who I am.
When's it hit the paper?
An officer of the court
wants to believe this story.
An aberration in a life that
has a chance of having value.
Man, my life is over.
- Come on.
- What?
Let's go on back.
Sit down.
Have a seat.
Let's go.
What do you mean
your life is over?
You have a beautiful fiance.
Yeah.
So you'd walk
from that for prison?
I'm not seein'
a lotta options.
The guys out there. . .
they think you got caught up in
this before you knew what it was.
I knew.
They think you
can get immunity.
They want you to tell your
story to a superior court judge.
Force Reigert and Tilman to resign.
Edison'll clean up its own mess.
You think the
court's not involved?
Un-fucking-believable.
Is anybody not
corrupt in this town?
I don't know. . .you?
If it goes to justice. . .
- be the guy to take it.
- Why?
Well I thought you were in love.
She can do better.
Can you?
I was studyin' plumbin'
when you called.
- I mean. . .
- Nice.
You know, I like to
think about that
comin' home to Maria
huggin' my children.
Just livin' a normal life.
Wha's up?
What happened to her.
- She didn't deserve this.
- You're right.
It was a righteous offer.
This is gonna get ugly.
No, no.
Let him go.
Just got a call
from Hanson at FBI.
Justice is setting
up a task force.
Sturm und drang.
If they had anything, they'd be
arresting, not searching.
And will they find anything?
- This isn't connected to you.
- You're connected to me.
And you're under a microscope.
Because of your. . .
your reckless behavior.
The girl's picture will
be everywhere tomorrow.
Wallace and Ashford
already know somethin's up.
If that kid's article
links me and Better Edison to
I am the reason that
this city is what it is.
This? This doesn't
get near to you.
Yeah well. . .
I wish I had your certainty.
FBI.
This is a Federal warrant.
We're taking all
FRAT evidence files.
In my office.
They have impounded your car.
Or what's left of it.
Anything that you need to
tell me right now, Laz?
No, Captain.
Sit on it then,
till O-one hundred.
Go.
Goddamn phones everywhere.
Fuckin' yid from the Herald.
- You don't know that.
- Bullshit. He was makin' noise.
And you
with your Jesus, Jesus, Jesus
beggin' to be looked at.
You say anything to Maria?
You flap your lips and
she could come to Jesus, too.
Get his keys.
And call nine-one-one.
Tilman shot Lazerov.
Lazerov's dead.
Apparently Lazerov attempted
to shoot Deed. Tilman intervened.
Well Tilman just served up.
Dammit.
Come on.
No, wait, Lee.
- What's the point, Moe?
- Wait a minute.
Forget it, Moe!
Forget the whole thing.
This isn't going anywhere.
Bullshit.
- Pollack!
- This shit isn't over.
What are you doing?
Isiaha's dead.
Willow's in a fucking coma?
I'll publish myself
if I have to copy it at Kinko's
and pass it out on the street corner.
It's a fucking disaster.
A fucking disaster! !
We were on the short list
for the Republican Convention.
The summer fucking Olympics! !
And now we're look at
a Federal consent decree?
There's a dead body
outside my fucking office! !
The fuck are we gonna do?
It kinda puts a little crimp in your
Better Edison thing, doesn't it?
We gotta do something
about him, Lee.
Who, Tilman?
Well. . .there it is.
You know. Yeah.
What about you, Jack?
Huh? Me?
Yeah you.
What are we gonna do about you?
Well. . . I'll be fine.
Thanks for asking.
All units. . .All units
please respond.
We have a five-twelve
at 6th and Main.
All units.
All units please respond.
We have a five-twelve at 6th and
Main.
Copy that dispatch.
This is two-six responding.
Hello?
It's me. Meet me at the courthouse
tomorrow morning at nine.
Rafe please talk
Hello? Rafe?
Josh?
- Maria?
- Yeah. Green. Hi.
Thank you for helping Raphael get
over his fear of doing this.
I'm Hector, Maria's father.
- Hi.
- Yeah.
Where's Rafe?
He's changing in
the men's room. Yeah.
- Okay.
Rafe?
Yeah, I'm out here!
What's goin' on, man?
What are ya doin'?
It's crazy, man.
Tilman shot.
Yeah, I know.
And your first reaction
is 'let's get married'?
It's what she wants.
That's her.
Hey, why are you doin' it?
Death benefits.
What' this?
It's the rest of your story.
Are you sure?
Am I sure of what?
Are you sure you want this,
and I want you to think about it.
Something goes wrong your
whole world comes crashin' down.
And mine, too.
What do you think?
I say write your fuckin' story.
Thank you.
Just remember.
These guys don't fuck around.
They're relentless.
Keep your head down.
And your door locked.
Thank you.
Come on, I gotta get married,
come on. Let's get out.
Rafe. Come in.
- Hey, Rafe.
- Wha's up, man?
Rafe. Sit down.
This is a police file photo
Pollack's girlfriend
at the Lazerov's come to
Jesus talk.
And there it is. The enemy
you can't beat a photograph.
Ashford's printing this as
a tease to polics story on FRAT.
So we say Charles is a liar.
He'd say anything to go home
and visit his dying mother, right?
Whatever discrepancies
there are between
his testimony and what's
actually in the police locker
will be offset when the Feds find the
drugs we planted in 's house.
You rammed the door
to compromise its security.
Keep the junkies from using
the place as a shooting gallery.
Lazerov was unstable.
So the Feds' will buy that.
All that's left is Pollack.
Pollack?
He's a kid.
Justice needs the case closed.
So we give 'em.
Herald needs its advertisers,
I can handle that.
But this kid pollack?
This kid polic is
like a pup with a bone.
He doesn't wanna hear
there's no meat on it,
he just keeps gnawin'
and gnawin' and gnawin' .
So. . .
Polic has to see the man.
It's a partner's duty.
To Laz?
To Laz.
What?!
What? What?
You know what.
You know exactly what.
You're the only one
that can put an end to this now.
I go to Justice, what I'm dealing
with threatens the people I love.
What's the matter with you?
You're havin' an
argument with yourself.
- Don't talk to me like I was
- I said It was a righteous offer. . .
but I'm not takin' it.
You're not listening.
I'm not talkin' about my offer.
I didn't say go to Justice.
I said you're the only one who can
put an end to this. Didn't I?
Yes you did
Yes you did.
Hello, you've reached the
answering machine for. . .
Moses Ashford.
Please leave a message at the tone.
Hey, it's Josh.
You're not gonna believe this.
I just got a hold of
the evidence we need on FRAT.
Listen, I don't wanna talk
over the phone, but
Moses, you're gonna
wanna see this.
I'm layin' out the story now
and then I'll email it to you.
Oh, and I'm also Fed-Ex'ing
hardcopies to all the big papers.
I'll talk to you later.
You've got email.
Right.
Yes, I know.
Yeah, I emailed it last night
but I'll mail a hardcopy to be safe. . .
so let me get your
address right now.
Okay, right,
perfect
Okay, it's on its way.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Fuck.
What're you doing?
In the car!
Move! Get in !
Oh my god.
Shit!
Fuck!
Fuck.
We're gonna fuckin' die.
Move it!
Go!
Open fire!
- Go! Go! Go!
- What?
Go! Go!
Go to the warehouse!
Look out!
Fuck!
Jeez
Hold your fire!
You hear me Deed?
Let's stop all this alright?
We don't have to do this.
All I want is the kid.
You hear me?
All I want is that kid.
Tell him whatever
it is, you won
and we can come to an extremely
agreeable solution here.
Same deal you gave Lazerov?
Motherfucker.
The fuck is wrong with you!
Let's finish this thing.
You go.
I'll light this up!
Move! Move!
Drop 'em.
Get up.
He's down !
Hey Rafe!
Come on out now.
It's over!
I got your boy here.
Come on, Rafe. Get out where
I can see you, Rafe.
I'll kill him now
I don't see you!
Get out a here!
We're finished.
It's over we're done.
You're goddamn right it's over.
- Put It down.
- FRAT's over.
Everybody's dead.
Everybody's dead because of you!
Because you couldn't do
what you were supposed to do.
Put a bullet in this
fucker and his story.
Well you do it now, Rafe.
Put a bullet in his fuckin' head.
Do what I tell you.
We walk away,
forget about this shit.
You kill him.
Right now you do
as you're told.
Do it!
You do it!
Because if you don't, I will.
- Duck.
- What?
Keep your door
locked, kid
Now not for another 15 minutes.
Don't say anything.
I'll be there in a minute.
Where have you been?
Laying out Polllack's story.
Yeah, well, the story changed.
And Deed wasn't here.
Detective Wallace.
D.A. Reigert's here.
Tilman?
Why are they here?
They're reporters.
The press is on the other side.
And material witnesses
to the dissension in FRAT.
Right.
Not much for the FBI
to work with, is there?
No they'll probably
close up shop.
This kind of story. . .
not really in the Herald's
wheelhouse, is it Moses?
No it's not.
No.
Tilman have any last words?
Well, there it is.
Good day, gentlemen.
He said there was agreement
between the D.A. 's office. . .
and judges regarding
FRAT related prosecutions.
That the cash evidence from
criminal trials wound up in the
Better Edison Foundation
for your political campaign.
That laundering this
money was systematic.
That principals from
Midland, Hightower
and other companies
were involved.
He said all that?
And that was
unmitigated slander.
I'm gonna go with it
if you run for any elected or
appointed office in this state.
Broke as you are, you think
that's a smart thing to do?
Now, Jack, did I get broke
doin' the smart thing?
In the night, when no
reporters were around to cover it
Wallace removed all
evidence of Better Edison.
Will are recovered.
Indeed, he got into
another line of work.
It would have violated a sacred
trust to turn him in to the law.
And the law already knew.
Justice is a lot
like journalism.
Sometimes the most
important questions
are the ones you
decide not to ask.
THE END
Subtitles by: