Yes?
Good morning.
Have you decided?
Yes.
Field work, bugging, photos.
You pay whatever the result.
And double if you need evidence in court.
I don't need it.
Just a moment.
OK.
Shall we get started, then?
Yes.
When can I expect something?
Hard to say.
A week or 2.
A day if it's clear cut.
Call me at the same time or late at night.
OK.
But, you realize...
Please.
- Goodbye.
Later. We've got a better job.
This guy's in a hurry.
He's paying 7K
And when it's all over
we get the fuck out.
What's going on?
Hey, you there.
2.50--
OK.
Can I give you a flyer?
- What's going on up there?
- Someone shot a red light.
- Any bodies?
- I don't think so.
We're moving.
Thank you, goodbye.
- How much?
- 2.50--
Can I give you a flyer?
OK. Here's 5.
- Thank you very much.
- Thanks.
Life...
That's the way it is.
People drive like maniacs.
I see it all the time.
A bit of clear road and they're doing 100.
Do you know how much fuel they burn?
Must be a lot.
You bet. And it costs.
I converted the car to autogas.
But does it run any worse? No.
Sure.
But it's not all the same.
Sometimes, when I buy
more expensive gas,
the car goes like a rocket.
Like a rocket.
I can do 100 in third, no problem.
Stop here on the right. By the entrance.
OK.
Here's the card.
24-48.
Don't write down the route.
There you go.
Have a nice day.
Thank you. Same to you.
Again? It'll kill you.
What were you saying?
That you should forget him.
I think he's seeing someone.
- Mum, what are you saying?
- You caught him lying.
I'm sure those "meetings" are dates.
Mum please, that's just his job.
Wait a moment.
I think we've found a donor
for the little boy in room 3.
I have to go, sweetie.
Alright. Bye.
Bye.
There was an accident.
A father and son. The son's
chances are slim, so...
This is him.
He's been here a month. He's not insured.
Fine. We'll need the agreement
of the donor's parents.
His parents need 14,000.
- But that's impossible.
- What do you mean?
They're very poor...
So is the hospital, dear.
Can't something be done?
Well. I can speak to the director.
- But half that sum is the minimum.
- Right, right.
- How's he doing?
- Not good.
- Are they ready?
- Yes.
Faster!
Out of the way!
- You're not allowed in here.
- I lost my way.
- How do I get out?
- There, down the stairs.
Sorry.
Yes?
Where the fuck are you?
I had to... had to sort something out...
What?
I...
Get here!
- I called her.
- Yeah?
Back to work. Spit roast her.
OK. I'm turning on the lights.
- After you.
- Thank you.
Hello.
What?
- Hello.
11.50.
There you go.
I'm not taking that.
- Why?
- It's ripped.
- But I haven't got...
- I don't care.
- But it's fine, it's from another shop.
- Take it back then.
But...
Too bad.
Leave it!
Give it to me.
Is this one good enough?
Thank you. All the best.
No problem. Good bye.
Have you got any more bags?
This one's broken.
Thank you. How much is that?
45.
Have a good day.
Careful, mind where you're going.
- What are you doing?
- I'm so sorry.
Kids.
- Come on.
- Sorry, do you live here?
Yes, on the top floor.
On your own?
No, with my husband and son.
My son's in hospital,
we're just off to visit him.
- What's the matter with him?
- He's waiting for a transplant.
I don't know if he'll make it.
Even then it costs a lot of money.
I'm from the Our Children Foundation.
Here's my card.
Get your husband to call
me today around 11 pm.
Maybe we can do something.
Thank you very much.
My husband will call for sure.
Sorry, have you got a cigarette?
I don't smoke. Goodbye.
Thank you.
Don't stare.
Look out, stupid!
But it's green.
It doesn't matter.
Morons. Jaywalkers.
It's my right of way too.
She wasn't looking.
Move!
And with a kid.
I was strict with my boy
and he turned out alright.
He's at university. He's smart.
Do you have any children?
Yes, I do.
It's here.
OK.
How much?
22.
Here's thirty.
Thank you very much.
Have a nice day.
Same to you.
- Good afternoon.
We're checking the electrics,
there's a leak, can we come in?
- Will it take long?
- No.
Go check that one.
Have you had any problems?
No, not really.
- Are you the owner?
- No, I rent it.
I see.
Let's have a look.
I can't see anything here.
If you have any problems...
call the owner.
Nothing here, have you got anything?
We'll be going then.
Sorry to bother you.
That's all right. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
We're on. Record.
They're talking.
We got lucky.
They're ready.
Have a listen.
Open the door please!
There's a leak!
You've got a leak.
We need to disconnect the mains.
Please sit down! We need room.
The socket!
The plug!
Now what?
It's done.
What was the problem?
We bypassed it.
Sorry, but that's our job. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
What the fuck was that?
Electricians.
They were here earlier.
So why'd you let them in again?
Say "Hi" from me.
Yes?
Hi.
Are you home?
No, I'm out walking with junior.
- What about the nanny?
- It's her day off.
Day off? You've only had her a week.
She had something to do.
Where are you? Maybe I'll join you.
What's up?
Nothing, I just wanted to see you.
Sorry, he's woken up He's hungry.
I'm going home so I'll see you this evening.
I've got a meeting this evening.
I'll wait up for you I have to go. Bye.
But...
- What happened, sir?
- Nothing.
- I'll clear it up.
- No. Get me a sandwich.
Yes, of course.
Hello, New Caf.
Hello, I'd like to place an order.
Sure.
One turkey sandwich.
Deliver it to Change Industrie.
Yes, you're on our system.
How long will it take?
About 30 minutes.
The money will be in reception,
leave it there, goodbye.
Thank you.
Order.
Just a moment.
What can I get you?
The nut cake I think.
- Is it fresh?
- It's still warm.
- How much is it?
- 30.
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
Coming!
Hi.
Here I am.
Would you like something to drink?
Yes
I've got some delicious tea.
Lovely.
Sugar?
No thank you.
Do you want the money now?
No.
Where's the bedroom?
There.
Puppets- a cat, a bear or a bunny!
Every child will think it's funny!
No thank you.
For your grandchildren, maybe?
Puppets- a cat, a bear or a bunny!
Every child will think it's funny!
I don't have any children.
Goodbye.
Are these for me?
Did you give the lady a present?
- Here.
- No, you can keep them.
Wave bye-bye to the lady.
Goodbye.
Yes?
Hi Mum, where are you?
In the park.
How's junior, did he sleep a little?
Yes, a little.
You can start walking
back. I'll be home soon.
- Alright.
- See you, bye.
Does your mother still not suspect anything?
I don't know.
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
What doesn't?
She doesn't like him.
As you know.
Yeah.
Stop here, I'll walk.
I don't want anyone to see us.
Sure.
I'll call you this evening.
I said get the fuck out!
Excuse me, can you back up?
Don't fuck with me, bitch!
- You're in my space.
- Fuck off.
Fuck off yourself, short-ass.
I said fuck off!
Out!
I don't want to!
You're having an abortion.
Why should I lose money just
because some cunt was careless!
I wasn't.
- Get in, bitch!
- It's your baby.
- Don't fucking bullshit me!
- I'm not!
You just fucking made it up.
Have a look, I'm 7 weeks gone.
Come on.
- A large one.
- What?
Whatever.
Same again.
I'll be going.
Hang on, I'll just serve this guy.
I need to cook your father's dinner.
How's he feeling?
Fine.
Look after yourself son.
Thanks, take care.
Bye.
Please take my seat.
Thank you, but maybe you're tired?
No, no.
Hello.
I'll have a kilo of potatoes,
a loaf of bread and some milk.
Anything else?
Yes, 2 apples.
That one.
And that one.
That's 6.50--
- Afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
- Yes?
- A bottle of orangeade.
- Large or small?
- Large.
2.30--
Hey, get off! Sticky fingers?
Piss off!
Bums.
Fucking low-lifes.
- Card 456?
- Yeah.
This gentleman's going to the airport.
The boot's open!
Listen...
Do that meeting report for tomorrow, OK?
Sure.
Hi babe.
Hi.
Why don't you answer?
I've had a ton of meetings
Listen, some fucking psycho
pulled a gun on me today.
You're kidding?
In the parking lot.
Did you call the police?
Are you kidding?
He was a fucking gangster
I don't want a bullet in the head.
But you're OK, aren't you?
Yeah, fortunately I'm OK.
Have you finished for the day?
Maybe we could go out somewhere or...
Don't think so, I've got a report to write.
OK, I understand.
Maybe we can eat at home?
I'll buy some wine.
Yeah, alright...
Maybe I'll make some
pasta and a salad and...
Sure, bye.
Love you, bye.
Do you want a sip?
You better go home, your wife's waiting.
I've still got some stuff to do.
You're all the same.
The same as what?
Yes or no?
Hang on a sec.
- Coming for a drink?
- Sure.
- 15 minutes?
- OK.
How about it?