I am afraid to die...
STATEMENT
If I die in a car accident,
in a mugging or any other means;
it will be the work of the same murderers
of my beloved son,
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones.
To my friend:
Chico Buarque de Holanda
I'm Zuzu Angel.
I was born in Curvelo, Minas Gerais.
I was married to an American,
Norman Angel Jones.
We had three children.
When we got divorced,
I already lived in Rio de Janeiro,
and supported my kids sewing
and designing clothes.
Little by little,
I established a brand.
1971 was the apex
of my carreer.
The success of my fashion in NY
widened my perspectives.
I was excited upon my return
to Rio de Janeiro,
all my dreams were
coming true.
Good afternoon, girls!
I was sure that if I got
a loan at a bank,
I could expand my business,
and launch my clothes worldwide.
I scheduled meetings, made contacts...
I dedicated myself to this project.
Zuzu! Congratulations!
On the other hand,
I couldn't fool myself:
My life wasn't only fun
and success.
What's your problem?
What else could you hope for?
It's been 6 months since
I last heard from Stuart.
Come on!
Are you OK?
Everybody, shut up!
Júlia, stand up!
Júlia!
Let's go!
Paulo! Hurry up!
Friends, I'm sorry
for being late.
The city is at a standstill.
Police are everywhere.
Don't tell me there's been
another kidnapping!
No! Lamarca's gang!
They robbed my bank agency.
Did they take the money
you promised us?
Don't worry! The insurance will pay.
Pelé says he's going to quit
the brazilian football team...
One more bank robbery
in Rio de Janeiro.
Who left the TV on?
Mom?
The american paper New York Times...
OK! I turned the TV off.
Congratulations on the loan!
Now we can prepare the clothes
for the next season calmly!
- Great, mom!
- Thank God!
Pretty flowers, uh?
I almost forgot:
Hilde called and
her paper wants to interview you.
I didn't know your sister
owned a paper now!
No, they want her
to interview you.
I'll schedule later.
Paulo "fell".
Pardon?
Pay attention, madam:
Paulo "fell". Try the Army.
What kind of prank is that?
I don't know any Paulo.
You don't understand...
- What do you mean "fell"?
- Was arrested.
Is he alive? Hurt?
I only know he was taken
by the Army.
- But is he OK?
- Nobody knows.
It's Tuti, isn't it? Stuart?
Go to the Army before
it's too late. Hurry!
What's up, mom?
Who was it?
Your brother, he was arrested.
Hey, Stuart!
My mom says I can't go
to your house
And you can't come to mine.
Why?
She doesn't want
a divorcée's son there.
My mother is not divorced!
Then where's your dad?
Does he live at home?
No...
Don't try to fool me, Stuart!
She's divorced!
- So what?
- So she is a slut.
Your mother is a slut.
Hey, son, won't you give me
a kiss?
What happened, Tuti?
They've been speaking ill about you.
Because I got divorced?
Don't care for what they say!
That bunch of fools.
Let me see.
But if you want
to defend your mom,
you have to get stronger.
Just beans won't be enough!
Go and wash up, son!
Go!
Yes!
Go, go, go!
Flamengo!
Tuti!
It's impossible, mom!
Didn't the person leave a name?
No, daughter.
- Couldn't it be a prank?
- No.
Call your sister.
We must leave now.
I'll get Tuti's ID.
Hurry up, daughter.
Did the man say
where Tuti was?
Was there a gunfight?
Is he hurt?
He said nothing.
Just that he was at the Army.
Didn't he warn anybody else?
They only call the mother, because
she's the only fool who cares.
Where are the people that he
defends to free him now?
Hilde! Did Tuti see you in the theater?
Yeah! I mean, I think so.
Because from the stage,
we don't see the audience well.
But there was this night I was
almost sure he was there.
I just hope that Tuti comes
to his senses and leaves Brazil.
Excuse me! I'm looking for my son.
Now? It is not a good time.
Do you want me to wait
until dawn!
If he's innocent, no problem.
Calm down!
- What's your son's name?
- Paulo.
- Family name?
- Let's go!
We don't do this kind of job,
we are tired
and you are very nervous.
And how do you expect me to be?
I'm just trying to help.
OK! I apologize.
Can I show you a picture?
This is my son.
His name is
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones.
His father is American.
Tell me: Is his name
Paulo or Stuart?
Because if you don't even know his
name, it's going to be harder.
People call him Paulo.
"People", who?
His friends!
But his name is Stuart.
Is he Brazilian or American?
- Does he speak English?
- It would help...
Frankly, I've never seen this face.
We don't even do this job.
I'm sorry, madam,
but we can't help you out.
The van is waiting.
I just need to know if he's here,
and if he is well.
Come back during "visit hours"!
Does your son
have a fake name?
Stuart!
- Wait a minute...
- Where is your brother?
Over there! He spent
the whole afternoon with Sônia.
Just what I needed!
Does this girl live here now?
- Don't be rude, mom!
- Rude?
I'm going to show him "rude".
Stuart!
- Stuart, What's going on?
- What do you mean?
What are you doing
locked in here?
Studying...
Right!
Didn't you have anything
better to do?
And this picture in the paper?
Students demonstrate in rio
We taught the imperialist
pigs a lesson.
Who are the pigs?
- The IMF is one of them.
- USAID...
Rockfeller. But yesterday
they learned something.
What did they learn?
We taught them a lesson.
So I heard on the radio.
Two windows shattered at Sears
and one at a Bank!
The gringos must know they won't
get away with exploiting Brazil!
The population backed us up.
People are really dissatisfied!
How can you be so na: L: Ve?
Ms. Angel, there's no freedom!
Artists are being persecuted.
The fascists beat actors
in 5 plays!
The people will put
an end to this!
You are so mistaken.
My seamstresses, for example.
They come to work like sardines,
and get on the bus before dawn.
They have neither the time,
nor the wits to back you up.
Do you defend the dictatorship?
Was that what I said?
Was it, Tuti?
You know it wasn't.
I said everybody is trying
to survive.
Nobody has time for politics.
People will realize, sooner or later,
that capitalism is coming to an end
all over the world.
Is that what you study,
Mr. Student?
I'm not just a student!
I have an ideology. I'm socialist.
You should help him come to his senses
instead of backing up this madness.
She agrees with me.
We chose not to close our eyes
to injustice in the world.
One of them was polite...
And the other aggressive.
I know how it works, Zuzu.
One bites, the other licks.
It's their technique in tor...
Torture?
It's a fact.
Shall we sit down?
Zuzu, the Army denies that
Stuart or "Paulo"
was arrested.
They say nobody was arrested
in the last three days.
Can't you come up with a writ?
No. The dictatorship abolished writs
in case of political crimes.
Now they can keep the prisoner
for 45 days without any notice.
Doesn't the fact that
Tuti is American help?
Does his father have any contacts
at the embassy?
Forget Norman. He went to Minas
to open an orphanage.
Fraga, tell me what I need to do.
I've always handled things
by myself.
Especially, my children.
These clothes are remarkable.
I tried to do something
typically Brazilian.
If I wore one of these,
Bosco would kill me!
I still make by order.
More traditional clothes.
If you want, don't even schedule.
Just show up!
Thank you!
Bosco is coming soon.
If we have your son, I'm sure
he's being well-treated.
I can't thank you enough, General.
It's a war.
A war against revolution.
That's why our prisoners are treated
according to the Geneva Convention.
To the letter!
I come here every day
to check on the prisoners.
Some time ago, there was this girl
who kept on crying.
I asked her why she cried so much.
She told me her husband
was killed here,
in my barracks.
Can you believe it?
And put both in the same cell.
Everyday, I visited them
and asked if they were OK.
But when he went to court,
the lad said he was brutally
tortured here.
Can you believe it? I got mad:
"What kind of talk is that?
I treated you like my children,
and you put me through this?"
Later, he admitted the lawyer told him
to say that
to get rid of the sentence.
May I come in?
Yes.
Excuse me! Did you see a prisoner
named Paulo around?
Say it, son.
No! I don't know who is...
Stuart?
No, madam! Never seen.
Thank you.
I knew your son wasn't here.
But I wanted you
to see for yourself.
And I didn't like what I saw!
Why?
Do you think I believe those clean
and pressed sheets?
They seem fake to me, General.
Madam, your son must
have left Brazil.
He didn't leave.
I'm responsible for the Army.
Have you been to the Navy
or the Air Force?
Ms. Angel,
why do you think your son
is here at the Air Base?
The Army says he's not there,
but I know he's been arrested.
Sorry.
What I meant to say was:
Why do you think your son's
been arrested?
Come in!
There's one thing I don't get:
If I got a call like that,
I'd think it was a prank.
But you believed! Why?
My son was in the student
movement.
But it's been a while since that
was dismantled. And then?
He left home.
Undercover?
- Where are they?
- In Captain Mota's office.
You said they mentioned a Paulo,
right?
Yes, sir.
Then you knew he had a nickname!
He once said it to me.
Why?
In case something happened.
Then he was into risky businesses?
Captain, you're better informed
than we are.
I'm sure you know Ms. Angel
has reasons to be worried.
After Dr. Fraga called, I tried
to get news from Stuart or Paulo.
Have you heard about a supermarket
or bank robbery?
No.
Political kidnapping?
It's been two years I don't see
my son very often...
But one thing you must know:
Was your son a communist?
You've been very kind.
I just don't understand how this
is going to help me find my son.
Even physical evidence
may help.
Does he have a scar,
a beauty-spot,
gunshot wound...
No, no.
You mean something else.
You want me to say that my son
is subversive or a terrorist.
Is he?
Is that what you are, mom?
- What?
- The General's wife's seamstress!
Let's face it, Tuti.
You win the revolution,
and I make the dresses for
the women of the committee.
Come on, mom!
Is he, Ms. Angel?
Do you think I'm going to fink
my son?
This is circus!
I want to know what you
did to him!
- What kind of game is this?
- Calm down, Zuzu!
Enough! They know about Stuart,
otherwise he wouldn't be doing this.
Do you accuse us?
If Stuart committed a crime and
was arrested, let him be judged.
If he is found guilty,
I'll bring
him apples during visitation.
But I can't stand your pretending
he does not exist, :
Or that he be sentenced without
a trial.
You can't do that!
Boss, this woman is crazy.
What did you say, Captain?
Crazy.
No, she's not crazy.
She's dangerous.
Keep an eye on her!
Zuzu, I'll issue petitions
in the Military Courts.
They'll have to say
if Stuart is locked or not.
Do you have a minute, Fraga?
I'd like some information.
These are hard times, Ms. Zuleika
Angel, very hard times.
I know what I've been through,
father.
My son, Stuart, was arrested.
He may be at the Air Base.
Then, I thought...
You take care of the prisoners there.
My child, unfortunately,
most prisoners are atheists.
But my son has a kind heart,
father.
Everywhere I go,
people say he's not there.
But he was arrested!
- Keep calm!
- How can I be calm, father?
I don't know how he is, if he is
being tortured. I don't know!
Ms. Angel, don't worry.
Everything they say about the
prisons is communist propaganda.
I don't know if your son is at the Air
Base, but I'll try do find it out for you.
I appreciate that, father.
One thing I know for sure:
The torture they talk so much
about is untrue.
They are mild electrical shocks.
It's a little machine that kills
nobody, my child.
But even being mild,
does the Church agree?
Ms. Angel, they chose the path
of violence.
Listen to your words!
The shepherd must protect
the herd.
Wasn't the law enough?
Now anything goes!
The shepherd must protect
the entire herd.
You don't represent
the Brazilian Church,
which was never in favor of torture.
You should kneel down, pray,
and beg God to forgive you
for thinking the way you do.
In regard to the terms from
document 692 of this court,
comma, I state that Stuart Edgar
Angel Jones
has never been locked in any
facility of the Army.
I state that the civilian
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones
is not and have never been locked
in the Navy.
Stuart Elgard Angel Gomes
is not locked
in the Jurisdiction of the
Air Force, period.
He's my son too, Zuleika.
Why didn't you tell me before
Stuart had disappeared?
As if we talked to each other,
Norman!
If you at least called sometimes.
I don't understand what
you're doing here.
I thought Tuti could be hiding
in your house,
or could have stayed here
on his escape.
Stuart's come here a couple of times.
He always brought clothes
to the children.
In one of the visits, I told him
he reminded me of my father.
Your father was a priest, Norman.
Exactly.
Both wanted to change the world.
My father battled sin and Stuart,
injustice in the world.
I'm sure Tuti didn't come here
to listen to your philosophy!
No!
He was a son visiting his father.
Last time he left, I thought...
I knew I'd never see him again...
Norman!
So soon!!
The last time he said
he'd get married.
- The girl...
- Sônia.
Yeah! He spoke highly of her,
said she was wonderful,
very altruistic.
Tuti! Tuti, my son, behave!
Don't be naughty!
That's not what I taught you!
Great!
You can kiss the bride!
To the newlyweds!
It's all settled then, João!
Don't worry, boss,
we finish tomorrow.
Please, don't forget!
Thank you.
What happened, Tuti?
What happened, son?
- I need to talk to you.
- Oh, my God!
What happened? Say it!
Sônia was arrested.
Oh, my God!
What can we do?
Her father is in the Army.
He'll release her.
You don't get to do anything.
If you never want me to get
involved,
what are you doing here, Tuti?
That's crazy, Tuti.
- Mom, you don't understand...
- Yes, I understand.
A bunch of medium class kids from
Rio de Janeiro "decided" that
they'd make a revolution in Brazil,
and my son is one of them.
Sorry! I shouldn't have come.
It was a moment of weakness.
It'd be good if you all had
more moments of weakness,
to understand you have great
feelings, but terrible ideas, kid.
It was out of weakness.
I shouldn't have come.
I hope you have more moments
of weakness.
Then I'd see you more often.
I gotta go!
The shop will be great.
Son...
Gotta go, mom.
Stuart left, disappeared
on the streets and I didn't hear
from him for a long time.
One day, I heard Sônia was
released,
and both were living anonymously.
Sônia! My son!
Tuti! How I miss you!
Let's go up. I've got something
important to say.
- What happened?
- Let's go up.
- What is it?
- Is anybody else here?
No, I'm alone.
Turn off the light.
Turn it off.
Sônia is leaving Brazil tomorrow.
And so are you!
No, I can't.
Sônia's just been released,
she can't possibly stay.
I'm not running away. I'm going
to spend some time abroad,
- then I'll come back.
- You're playing with fire.
It's definite, mom.
We want to stay here today. We had
a problem and have no other place.
We've been walking
for 5 hours around town.
Can we stay?
You're so rational!
I'm sure you won't miss
each other.
Sorry! I don't even know
what I'm saying anymore.
I'll fix you something
to eat.
Sit down.
What was it, Ms. Angel?
What is it, mom?
You don't want Sônia to travel
in these awful clothes.
I don't believe it, Ms. Angel!
Paris demands more from
Zuzu Angel's daughter-in-law.
She's going by way of Paraguay.
Try it out, Sônia.
Calm down!
Nobody arrives before 8 o'clock.
I'll come at 7. Get some rest.
Bye.
Tuti...
Are you getting pretty
for the French guys?
You fool!
A jealous revolutionary?
Soninha,
even if everything goes wrong,
we'll win. Don't worry!
Even if we don't see
each other again...
No! I'll come back. I promise you.
OK! Everything may happen,
but I want you to know
I love you,
and our dreams are worth
any sacrifice.
I love you too.
I feel the same way.
I love you. I love you.
But we don't need to suffer today.
Not today!
You mean Stuart is now in jail?
If we hope for the best...
- Your son?
- Yes.
I was dispirited on my way back
from Norman's house.
Out of despair, I believed Stuart
was hidden in his father's.
With all my hopes gone, it was clear
that something serious
had happened to my son.
But I couldn't imagine what
was in store for me in Rio.
"Madam,
it's very hard for me to say,
and I know it'll be even harder
for you.
It's not easy for me to be
so straightforward,
knowing that I'll be destroying
your hopes.
Hopes that last in a
distressed mother due
to the disappearance
of her beloved child
Especially, in this case,
where I have an emotional
connection and involvement.
Your son's death touches me too".
"Your son's death touches me too".
It's he. He's here.
In a green car.
Halt, boy!
Be quiet, man! Hands in the air!
"When Stuart fell,
he wore blue pants, a light-colored
shirt and a brown coat.
Let's go! Step on it!
He was taken in the trunk of
a car to Galeão Air Base.
On the night of May, 14th, :
I was tortured beside Stuart.
Paulo e Alberto, you already
know what I need.
Bring the salt!
Oh, bastard, son of a bitch!
It's all a matter of time
and pain.
Don't lower the cans! Damn it!
More time, more pain.
Less time, less pain.
Don't lower the cans!
Where's Lamarca?
Spin the wheel.
Paulista, Cid, Cirilo!
Where's Lamarca?
"In the middle of the night, there
was a lot of noise in the patio.
Cars were turned on,
there were shouts, questions
and a constant cough
followed by feet pressing
accelerators".
"As it was common after tortures,
they cut the water supply in the cells
to make people thirstier after the shocks.
Stuart was in a cell beside mine.
I noticed he was in bad shape.
He wouldn't stop coughing
all night long. I heard it!
He kept on saying three things":
"Water', "I'm going crazy",
and "I'm gonna die".
Quit being a fag, Paulo!
I'll give you an injection.
You won't die so soon.
"Almost at sunrise,
they opened the cell
and took Stuart.
He didn't move, was probably dead.
Somebody said":
"More food for the fish
in Marambaia".
It's over there, madam!
- Who is it?
- My son.
When is the funeral?
Could you leave me alone, please?
- Antônio?
- Yes?
You have children, don't you?
My son was in high school
less than 10 years ago.
Then he got involved into political
demonstrations of students.
He always hated guns and violence.
Then came the dictatorship,
censorship, prisoners... This horror!
But he didn't give up his ideals.
One day, I got a call
saying he was in jail.
I searched for him everywhere
but couldn't find!
Now, I get this letter
saying he was tortured,
and that he was killed.
Do you know why?
Because he didn't want to give
an address.
The name and number
of a street.
You know which address
I'm talking about, don't you?
My son died to save yours!
Sir, your mouth...
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have come
here. I'm confused...
Our sons fought together,
they must have been friends.
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
No! No newspaper in Brazil
will publish this letter.
It's forbidden to write your son's
name.
Even if you wanted to pay
for an obituary,
I couldn't publish it.
I'm sorry! I didn't mean to hurt you.
Elke, how was the fashion show?
Girl, it was great. But I'm so tired
and it was a hell of a mess.
I think you should get into
the fashion business, Hilde.
You're so pretty!
I want to be an actress.
Actress? To be stuck in a theatre?
"Terrorists WANTED..."
"HELP PROTECT YOUR LIFE
AND FAMILY - CALL THE POLICE"
- What is it, Elke?
- Your brother is dead! They...
Don't do it!
First they kill him,
and then set up a warning?
The guy is coming. This is useless.
Let's go, please.
- What's going on?
- I came to say I know this one.
- She is kidding.
- No, I'm not!
This is Stuart Angel who
was killed by the Air Force.
Let's go!
Look! Are you playing us?
- Me?
- Yes.
No.
FIY, the new collection
goes to the USA tomorrow.
Is it ready yet?
And gorgeous. They're gonna love it.
I'm glad I have you
to hold the fort here.
You can count on me. I'm leaving.
Lúcia.
Will you post these letters for me?
Each scholar, artist, politic,
each prominent person in this
country will receive my letter.
Gosh, it's a lot of people...
And this one is for "Presidente"
Médici,
so that he can't pretend he doesn't
know what happened to Tuti.
See how it's easy to walk
pretending nothing is going on.
Madam, this is happening
in your country!
Get it! It's important.
Oh, my!
Zuzu, quit it. You're gonna
frighten the clients.
I won't stop, Lúcia!
They are just like I used to be.
I was so na: L: Ve, making dresses
with flowers and birds.
Happy fashion in the
"country of the future"...
A future without my son,
and others' children!
You know what?
- Cancel the shipment.
- I beg your pardon!
- There's a due date.
I'll make do, Lúcia.
I do something else.
Please, don't mix fashion
and politics.
This militia can do anything.
More than they've already done?
I died the day I received
that letter.
Hello? Hi, Hilde.
What?!
They arrested Elke.
She already talked to Fraga
and he says he'll release her.
And what else?
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones!
The Court of the Military Justice
summons the accused,
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones,
to testify in the trial
taking place in this Court.
Last summoning!
Let's begin. You may sit.
Once fulfilled all the prerequisites
and legal proceedings,
I declare absent from the process,
set in motion by the Union,
for crimes against the national
security,
the accused, Stuart Edgar
Angel Jones.
My name's not Stuart anymore.
You're not called Stuart?
No.
Why?
It's safer.
Why? Don't you feel like a Stuart?
What do you mean?
I worry that you become
a person you are not.
You can call yourself Peter, John...
I don't care!
I just want you to be yourself.
We are always changing, mom.
You know what?
I'll still be Stuart for you.
Just for you.
Son...
Are you leaving?
Let it be clear, gentlemen.
I don't defend the citizen
Stuart Angel,
but his memory.
I finish my speech
in a state of fear,
and one certainty.
I'm sure that I defend a deceased,
that the Military attorney knows
he accused a deceased,
and that the judges know
they are judging a corpse.
I fear, gentlemen,
that this ignominious sham
taints the name of this court
forever.
For 4 votes against 1,
this Court finds the accused,
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones, innocent
for lack of evidence in the process.
It's all a sham!
Court dismissed.
You can only arrest if there
is freedom,
you can only judge if there
is freedom.
Only with freedom can you find
someone guilty or innocent!
But here, murderers disguise
themselves as judges!
You heed your words,
or will be arrested for contempt
of this court.
There was contempt of the law
when you arrested Stuart.
There was contempt when
you interrogated him.
Contempt is to torture and kill!
Contempt is to deny the sacred right
of a mother to bury her child.
And now this sham, in the name
of a rightful government.
What kind of Right is that?!
Where are our Rights?!
You must be crazy to have
done that in court!
But I feel so relieved!
Just like you did to me
in the airport.
But there was a price.
They cancelled my citizenship.
I don't have a passport anymore.
I'm an outcast now.
- Pretty fancy, no?
- That's insane...
It's here, Zuzu.
What a nice place!
And after the German boyfriend,
I found myself a Greek one.
- Did you learn Greek too?
- No way!
Is the tongue difficult?
His tongue was difficult.
In barracks, they wait.
In barracks, they practice.
It's always like this. It's never-ending.
In barracks, they wait.
They dream of pretty girls,
but have to leave the pretty
ones behind.
They shoot their people.
They stomp on their people.
It's always been like that,
and you know it.
I think it was the most thrilling
night of my life.
You're awesome, mom.
Do you think the press
will like it?
I think so. The journalists
were wild at the show.
Senator Church confirmed
tomorrow's meeting.
You must persevere
in your task here in the U.S.,
your contacts with the press,
politics, judges...
It's key, my daughter.
I wouldn't be able to do it
by myself in Brazil.
Sometimes, I feel
I'm in a crusade.
You can always count on me, mom.
FASHION GETS A POLITICAL SHADE
Ladies and gentlemen,
in a few moments,
we'll be landing on Galeão
international airport in Rio de Janeiro.
Please, return to your seats,
keep them in the upright position,
and fasten you seatbelts.
Will you excuse me?
My friends, I'm Zuzu Angel,
Brazilian fashion designer.
I'd like to tell you that in this
wonderful city we're landing,
my son... My beloved Stuart
was arrested, tortured and killed
by the dictatorship
that destroys this country.
Where's his body?
Gone!
I'd like you to know that
the paradise we see through
the window,
is soiled by awful crimes
like this.
- Ms. Zuleika Angel.
- Yes?
Somebody would like to talk to you.
- Why?
- Will you follow me, please?
And my luggage?
We'll take care of that.
Please.
I heard you put on quite a show
on the plane.
Information gets to you very fast...
And complete.
I can tell the color of
your underwear.
I just don't know your son.
Never saw him.
But you went abroad to accuse me
of murder without evidence.
I have a family.
My wife and kids were shocked
when they heard of it.
Your kids must be going
to the beach and parties.
Mine was tortured and killed.
Says who? A terrorist.
What are the evidences? None!
Stuart's body is the least
I can ask.
- There's no dead body.
- What?
If your son died the way
you believe he did,
after such a long time,
there's no more corpse anywhere.
But his murderers are free.
Then gather evidence against them.
I'll do that.
Whoever killed Stuart
will some day pay for it.
Ms. Angel, I suggest
you wouldn't turn me
into a personal enemy.
Murderer!
And besides,
you should be ashamed
of using your son's name
to make more money
in your business.
After my fashion show in NY,
my life was at a standstill
for two years.
The press being censored,
my complaints were known
by no one.
Due to this kind of atmosphere
I kept my daughter, Ana, in the U. S...
Hilde didn't want to go.
She was already working
as actress and journalist.
In 1973, a new tragedy:
My son's widow, Sônia;
was arrested when she
came back to Brazil undercover.
Before being killed,
she was shocked, beaten up,
raped with a bat, and her breasts
were torn.
Her body was never
given to the family.
I admit I felt let down by so much
violence and impunity.
But I kept working,
and creativity gave me strength
to face my pain.
On the 31st of December, 1975;
a new fact lifted my spirits
to keep on fighting.
Hi, Fraga! Come drink with us!
Happy New Year!
- I'm glad you came, Zuzu.
- Almeida!
Let's dance.
Almeida, I'm sorry, but Zuzu
has promised me the first dance.
How come? She's just arrived!
We settled by the phone.
Excuse us.
I'll be back, Almeida.
Zuzu, you look sad,
but still gorgeous.
I've been meaning to call you
What for? Settle this dance?
Nice party, isn't it?
It may be, but I'm not
in the mood for parties.
That makes two of us.
What's up?
Problems in the office?
It may be a problem,
but also a solution...
Gosh! If we're going to talk
so serious about work,
we'd better stop dancing.
- No, Zuzu!
- Fraga!
- It's got to do with you.
- With me?
With Stuart.
Last week, somebody came to me.
Who came to you, Fraga?
An agent of the repression
came to me.
Oh, my God!
It was one of the craziest days
of my life.
Did he threaten you?
No. He came to me willing
to tell everything he knows.
But he wants to talk to you.
To me?
He said he'd only tell it to you.
Why me?
He says he knows about Stuart.
I should have left before
telling you such nonsense.
Why did he decide to talk?
Revenge.
He thought he was a "model" agent!
Whatever it means...
Then, he says he was wrongly
accused
of keeping the money from
an urban guerrilla robbery.
The guy must be in a rage.
You mustn't talk to him at all.
What if he knows what happened?
The testimony of somebody from inside
could put an end to all this sham.
Zuzu, to even talk about this
we must pretend we are tourists.
We are afraid of being followed, taped...
We are afraid of everything!
Do you want to get deeper
into this?
You're a fashion designer,
not an FBI agent.
I know I'm not from the FBI, but...
It's easy to get into a cave, but
it's even easier to get lost inside.
You're right.
Let's forget this conversation.
I've never seen your son,
but know what happened to him.
Alberto's letter was a trump card.
You used it, but didn't win
the game.
Now you're alone,
and have got nothing.
This way you won't get far.
Do you agree?
You started well.
Call me lieutenant and speak low.
What's your strategy?
- Strategy?
- Yes,
to hurt whom we want to hurt.
I want to know if it is worth it
offering you my load.
I want Justice.
Injustice is the worst thing
there is, Ms. Angel.
Funny how two enemies
can help each other,
don't you think?
I don't know...
We'll always be on opposite sides.
You and I.
But still, I can help you
if your strategy is good,
and my rage doesn't go away.
We'll see about that in a month.
If I feel the same way
I feel today,
I'll testify.
Somehow or the other,
I'll let you know.
How can you guarantee
that you are...
Guarantee what?
That I'm really an ally,
and not an enemy?
Yes.
I can't. Use your intuition.
I've prepared my testimony,
Ms. Angel;
but your strategy is weak.
- Is it?
- Yes.
These people from the Amnesty
won't do.
I must use the restroom.
I left something in the car.
Have you been following me?
Me? I'm retired, Ms. Angel.
Then how did you know about
my meeting with the Amnesty?
I still have some friends.
Ms. Angel, you're being followed,
your phones are wired.
Don't doubt it.
I can't stay here long, Ms. Angel.
But you called me.
Let me be straight: Amnesty
They can make a lot of noise.
Noise? In this case, the noise
of the enemy is predictable,
and won't cause any harm.
An unexpected attack
from a friend would be better.
This is good strategy!
If you can find a strong ally,
my testimony is yours.
The U.S. Secretary of state,
Henry Kissinger,
had a busy schedule on his first
day in Rio de Janeiro.
I got it!
I handed it to him.
Will he read it?
Sometimes, it stays with an assessor that
sends it straight to the Brazilian police.
Good! The man I want
will know what happened.
They're following us.
Nonsense!
Don't pretend to be na: L: Ve, Lúcia.
I found out there are
some civilians,
entrepreneurs and bankers
financing the repression.
I'm sorry to get you
into my problems, Lúcia.
I think you should spend some
days with me in the mountains.
Stay away from Rio, you know, Zuzu?
Lt'd do you good.
No, daughter.
But I'll only spend three days.
It was sent to you.
OK, daughter.
Don't worry! Lúcia insisted...
OK! I'll call as soon as
I come back. OK?
Kisses.
"YOU'VE IMPROVED YOUR STRATEG Y.
WALK AROUND THE LAGOON
AT 2 a.m."
Zuzu?
I want to talk to Zuzu Angel.
Who's that?
Is it you?
She traveled.
Marina, the truck!
Are you saying your name or...
- Hi, Hilde.
- Mom,
thank God you didn't travel with
Lúcia! That's crazy, mom!
What happened, daughter?
A terrible accident on the road.
I've just found out, mom.
A truck crashed into Lúcia's car.
It can't be!
Lúcia... She...
- They took Lúcia to the hospital,
- I gave up in the last minute.
But she passed away.
Do you want me to drop by, mom?
No! I'll call you back soon.
I'm shocked.
We'll talk later.
"STATEMENT".
If I die in a car accident,
in a mugging or any other means...
"My name is Marco Aurélio Carvalho,
Air Force Officer.
I give this testimony
out of my own free will.
I was based for two years
at Galeão Air Base.
Following superior orders,
I investigated and took part in the arrest
of the civilian Stuart Edgar Angel Jones"
I've never seen your son, but
know what happened to him.
"I also took part in the interrogation
of the civilian Stuart Angel.
First in a room in the Air Base,
then in the patio".
Let's go! Go, go, go!
"I guarantee the authenticity of the
testimony from the prisoner Alberto Dias.
Stuart Angel's body, killed by
torture, was thrown in the ocean.
Tuti! Tuti!
Tuti!
International amnesty -
MR. RAY BUNKER
Mom!
Tuti!
You left me alone!
- You left me alone!
- No, my son!
Don't worry, mom!
I'm here with you.
Wanna go for a walk?
I think it'd do you good.
Sit here, mom.
Why so anguished?
It's part of life.
We make choices, dream;
but sometimes reality insists on
being bigger than our dreams.
You know what, Tuti?
Sometimes I think I didn't give
you all the support I could.
You, my son...
You wanted to change the world.
I only wanted to change my life.
Nonsense, mom.
I'm afraid you think
I abandoned you.
You? Abandon me?
Do you remember that time
on the beach
when I left you alone and went
for a swim?
No.
When I came back,
you were crying desperately.
I felt so bad.
Don't you remember?
No, mom, I don't.
But I remember once when
you hugged on the beach,
and I never felt so protected,
and loved.
Could it have been the same day?
Tuti, Tuti...
Now you are going to bed, mom.
Get some rest.
Then, go.
I've been looking for you for days!
You vanished!
I needed to rest,
be alone for awhile.
What's going on?
Are you hiding anything from us?
Nothing! I'm not hiding anything.
Ahn? OK.
Let go of the case.
We have a lot to talk.
Did you at least go home?
No, I came straight.
I had some ideas for the collection,
and felt like coming to the studio.
Chico Buarque sent to me.
What are you looking for?
A letter.
A letter Tuti wrote to me
many years ago.
I'll read it to you.
"Mom, you ask me if I believe
in God.
And I ask you: Which God?
It's been my mission to show you
God in humans.
For only in humans can He exist.
No matter how poor or
insignificant he may seem to be,
every human has a mission."
That's so beautiful, mom!
"Every human being influences
the very nature of the future.
Through our lives,
we create actions
that result in the multiple
reactions".
"All of us have this power!
The power to change the course
of History is the power of God.
In face of such divine
responsibility,
I bow in front of the God
inside me.
Stuart Edgar Angel Jones."
Today you make the rules
Your word is the law
There's no argument
My people speak low nowadays
And looking at the floor, you know
You invented this state
You invented all the darkness
But you forgot to invent
forgiveness
In spite of you
Tomorrow will be different day
I ask you
Where you are going to hide
from all the happiness
How will you forbid the birds
to sing?
"Zuzu Angel's death, in 1976,
was declared accidental.
Chico Buarque sent 60 copies of Zuzu's
statement to celebrities and the press.
No newspaper published it.
22 years later, the Commission of
Deceased and Missing For Political Reasons
set up by the Brazilian government,
through undisputed evidence,
and a witness,
came to the conclusion she was murdered
:
Hildegard e Ana Cristina Angel
founded Zuzu Angel Institute
to honor the memory
of Zuzu and Stuart.
They could never mourn
their brother's body."