Dedicated to
Monogram Pictures
BREATHLESS
After all, I'm an asshole.
After all, yes, I've got to. I've got to!
Michel...
Take me with you.
- What time is it?
- 10:50.
No. Ciao!
Gotta make tracks, Max!
If he thinks he's gonna pass me
in his crappy Renault!
I collect the dough,
I ask Patricia if it's yes or no,
and then...
Nothing like the countryside.
I really like France.
If you don't like the shore...
if you don't like the mountains...
if you don't like the city...
then get stuffed!
Little girls hitchhiking!
I'll charge a kiss per mile.
The short one's not bad. Nice legs.
Yeah, but the other one...
Oh, hell, they're both dogs.
Nothing like sunshine.
Women drivers
are cowardice personified.
Pass him!
Oh, shit, it's the roadwork!
Never brake.
As old man Bugatti said:
"My cars are made to run, not stop."
Shit! The pigs!
Contact's gone!
This is the pits!
Hold it right there!
- Miss Franchini's room?
- She isn't here.
- She does live here?
- But she's out!
Girls never have cash.
Coffee.
- How much for ham and eggs?
- 180 francs.
Make it one.
Gotta get a paper. Be right back.
Can I come in?
How's it going, precious?
No jacket?
It's in my Alfa Romeo.
- Want breakfast at the Royal?
- I'm late.
Gotta be at the TV station at 9:10.
It's torn.
What've you been up to?
Nothing much. Traveling.
- What's new in the Quarter?
- Don't know.
- You don't go out?
- Dancing sometimes.
Still in the movies?
No. You gotta sleep around.
Do you recollect Enrico?
"Remember" or "recall."
But not "recollect."
I work with him at the station.
As script girl.
When I was broke in December,
I was assistant on a picture.
At Cinecittà!
- You?
- Yep, me.
Ever been a gigolo?
Why?
Just asking.
I wouldn't mind.
Call me back in a few minutes.
Is Gaby back from Spain?
- He bought the Café Pergola.
- He did?
Great.
The black paint's a stupid idea.
- What's that say?
- "Why?"
But I switched to Luckies.
Can you lend me 5,000 francs
till noon?
I should've known.
You're rotten, Michel.
I'll pay you back at noon.
Anyway, I don't have that much.
- Here's 500 if you want.
- Keep it.
- So no breakfast at the Royal?
- I'm really late.
Is Mr. Tolmachoff here?
He's here, but he's not here.
Seen Patricia?
Come with me to Rome?
It's crazy, but I love you.
I wanted to see
if I'd be glad to see you again.
Where you been? Monte Carlo?
No, Marseilles.
There was a guy I had to see.
I tried calling you Monday.
I was out of town Monday and Sunday.
- I'll take one.
- That's nice of you.
What are you doing here?
I thought you hated Paris.
No, but I've got enemies here.
So you're in danger?
Yeah. Will you come to Rome with me?
To do what?
We'll see.
No, I've got lots to do here.
You going up or down the Champs?
- What's the "Champs"?
- The Champs-Élysées.
- I gotta be on Avenue George V.
- See you, then.
Come on, walk me.
Just to the corner.
- Take it back. No horoscope!
- What's "horoscope"?
The future. I wanna know
the future. Don't you?
Sure.
- What is it?
- Nothing. Just looking at you.
You're mad I left without a good-bye.
No, I was furious
because I was sad.
It's nice to wake up next to a girl.
Are you staying in town?
Yeah, I have to see a guy
who owes me money.
Then I have to see you.
You don't have to.
Why?
There are prettier girls than me here.
No. It's weird.
I've slept with two girls since you.
We didn't jive at all.
You didn't "jive"?
They were pretty,
but we didn't jive. It was sad.
So will you come to Rome?
I'm fed up with France.
I can't, Michel.
I have to enroll at the Sorbonne
or my parents will stop sending money.
- I've got money.
- We only had three nights together.
No, five.
- Why don't you wear a bra?
- That's no way to talk.
Okay, sorry!
What time is it? See you later?
Not later. Tonight. Okay?
- Where?
- Here.
Live dangerously until the end!
Have you anything against youth?
Sure do. I prefer old people.
Police Killer Identified
Is Mr. Tolmachoff in?
At the airline desk.
- Hey, amigo.
- Hey, sonny.
You the one who came by at 10:00?
Yeah, for my money.
It's ready for you.
- How's life?
- I got bored down south.
I came up to see a girl. And you?
I'm getting out of here.
I'm rusting away.
Better rusted than busted.
Over here.
Have the envelope I gave you?
Why'd the jerk cross it?
Sign it over to someone else.
Not to me.
I blew my last cent at the races.
And your pal, Bob Montagné?
- He's in the pen, the idiot.
- No kidding.
There's Berruti, but I don't trust him.
I thought he was your pal.
Is he back?
Yes, I saw him
in Montparnasse last night.
What's his number?
Élysées 99-84.
Can I call from here?
Who's the girl you came for?
A New Yorker.
Pretty?
She's funny. I like her.
Élysées 99-84?
I'd like to speak to Antonio.
I'll call back.
He's out. I'll try somewhere else.
- Bye, sonny.
- Ciao, amigo.
Inter-Americana Agency?
Yes, this is it.
Do customers have mail
forwarded here?
Know a certain Michel Poiccard?
Also goes by the name
of László Kovács.
Ask the gentleman over there.
If it isn't Tolmachoff!
Hello, Inspector.
In the travel business now?
As you can see.
Remember how you ratted
on your friend Bob?
What if I did?
You're going to do it again.
Michel Poiccard, 5'9".
Brown hair.
Former Air France steward.
Has his mail sent here.
Yes, I know him.
He been around lately?
Has anyone been to see
Mr. Tolmachoff recently?
Yes, just five minutes ago.
A fairly tall man.
Christ Almighty!
"Accessory to murder"...
mean anything to you?
The Harder They Fall
Bogey...
- I saw a man die.
- How'd he die?
In an accident.
Take me out to dinner?
Let me make another call first.
Wait for me?
Call from the restaurant.
I'll just be a second.
The French always say one second
when they mean five minutes.
Where we going?
Anywhere. The Latin Quarter.
- Sleep with me tonight?
- I don't know.
- Don't you like it with me?
- Sure, I do.
I just read something neat.
About a bus conductor.
He stole five million to seduce a girl,
posing as a rich impresario.
He took her to the Riviera.
They blew the wad in three days.
The guy didn't cop out.
He told her,
"It's stolen money, I'm a hood,
but I like you."
What's great is that she stuck by him.
She said, "I like you, too."
They came back to Paris
and were nabbed trying to rob
some fancy villas.
She stood lookout.
That was sweet of her.
Excuse me, got a light?
Here! Go buy yourself a matchbook.
I totally forgot!
- I have an appointment.
- Who with?
A journalist on the Champs-Élysées.
We're going to a press conference.
Where? Now?
None of your business.
You can really be annoying.
So you're leaving me?
But I'll see you tomorrow.
Not tomorrow.
Tonight, Patricia.
I told you I can't.
Why are you so mean?
Any taxis around?
I'm parked by the Opera. Want a lift?
What happened to the Ford?
It's in the garage.
Let me stay with you.
I've got a headache.
We won't have sex.
I just want to be with you.
That's not it, Michel.
- Why are you so sad?
- Because I am.
That's silly.
Why are you so sad?
Should I use "vous" or "tu"?
No difference.
But I can't do without you.
Yes, you can.
Maybe. But I don't want to.
Just look at that swell Talbot.
A 2.5 liter.
- You're a guy who...
- What?
Oh, I don't know.
Look at me.
I forbid you to meet this guy.
Woe is me!
I love a girl with a pretty neck,
pretty breasts, a pretty voice,
pretty wrists,
a pretty forehead,
and pretty knees...
But she's such a coward.
- It's right here. Stop.
- Let me park first.
Don't bother.
Get lost!
I never want to see you again.
You make me want to puke.
It'd be a shame
if that happened to you.
We'll see.
What's wrong?
If I could dig a hole
to hide in, I would.
Do like elephants do.
When they're sad...
Let me tell you a story.
It'll take your mind off things.
There's this girl I know.
The other day, I figured,
"I'll ask her to sleep with me."
It had never occurred to me before.
We met for lunch.
I wanted to say,
"We're friends. Let's sleep together."
I don't know why,
but it completely slipped my mind!
Later I suddenly remembered
and sent her a telegram saying:
"I forgot to suggest
that we sleep together."
Three hours later I get
a message back, saying:
"What an amazing coincidence!
I was thinking exactly the same thing!"
- This the late edition?
- Yes, sir.
Where's my key?
You must've left it in the door.
What the heck!
What are you doing here?
The Claridge was booked up.
So I came here.
I took the key downstairs.
There are other places
than the Claridge.
I always stay at the Claridge.
You're crazy.
Don't make such a face.
It doesn't suit you.
- What's "making a face"?
- Going like this.
It suits me just fine.
You're even crazier than me.
Goddammit.
I always fall for girls
who aren't my type.
Did you notice I followed you
last night? Answer me.
What's wrong?
Leave me alone. I'm thinking.
What about?
What's horrible is, I don't even know.
Well, I do.
No, nobody does.
You're thinking about last night.
Yes, you are.
Last night I was furious,
but now I couldn't care less.
I'm not thinking about anything.
I'd like to think about something,
but I can't seem to.
Well, I'm tired, very tired,
and I'm going back to sleep.
- Why are you looking at me?
- Because I am.
- You should've stayed with me.
- I couldn't.
You should've told the guy
you couldn't see him.
I had to.
He's getting me articles to write.
It's really important for me.
What's important
is going to Rome with me.
Maybe. I don't know.
Did you sleep with him?
I bet you did.
No. He's really sweet.
He said we'd sleep together
someday, but not now.
But he doesn't even know me.
Not you. Him and me.
We had a drink in Montparnasse.
I was there, too. At what time?
I don't know. We didn't stay long.
Why'd you come here, Michel?
Because I want to sleep
with you again.
That's hardly a reason.
Sure it is. It means I love you.
But I don't know if I love you yet.
When will you know?
Soon.
What's that mean, "soon"?
In a month, a year?
Soon means soon.
A woman will never do in eight seconds
what she'll gladly do eight days later.
It's all the same,
eight seconds or eight days.
Why not eight centuries?
No, eight days is fine.
Women always do things halfway.
It gets me down.
Why won't you sleep with me?
Because I'm trying to find out
what it is that I like about you.
I want us to be
like Romeo and Juliet.
That's just like a girl!
See? You said last night you couldn't
live without me, but you can.
Romeo couldn't live without Juliet,
but you can.
No, I can't live without you.
That's just like a guy!
Give me a smile.
I'll count to eight.
If by eight you haven't smiled,
I'll strangle you.
Two...
Three...
Four, five, six...
Seven...
Seven and a half...
Seven and three quarters.
You're such a coward.
I bet you're gonna smile.
Enough games for today.
You're a coward. Too bad.
Why do you say that?
You get on my nerves.
You do, too.
I'm not a coward.
What makes you think I'm scared?
If a girl says everything's fine
then can't even light her cigarette,
it means she's scared of something.
I don't know of what, but she's scared.
Have one.
None of those Chesterfields.
Hand me my jacket.
- This pocket?
- Give!
This your passport?
No, my brother's. Mine's in the car.
But it says Kovács here.
Oh, yeah? He's not my real brother.
My mom was divorced
by the time he was born.
See? I'm not scared.
- I never said you were.
- You bet, pet.
But you wish you'd said it.
And now you're annoyed. You can't.
I'm not talking to you anymore.
Do you ever think about death?
I do, all the time.
What?
Say something nice.
Like what?
I don't know.
Then neither do I.
I like your ashtray.
It's Swiss.
My granddad had a Rolls-Royce.
Great car!
Never had to raise the hood
in 15 years!
Seen my new poster?
Come here!
Come here, for chrissake!
It won't do here. Where can I hang it?
Why'd you slap me
when I looked at your legs?
It wasn't my legs.
It's exactly the same thing.
The French always say things
are the same when they're not at all.
I've thought of something nice.
What?
I want to sleep with you again
because you're beautiful.
I'm not.
Then because you're ugly.
Is it the same?
Yeah, kid, it's the same.
You're a liar, Michel.
No, lying's stupid.
It's like with poker.
It's better to tell the truth.
The others think you're bluffing,
and that's how you win.
What's wrong?
I'll stare at you
until you stop staring at me.
Me, too.
I'll hang my poster in the bathroom.
Can I make a call?
It's not bad here.
Just fine.
You like this poster?
It's okay.
Renoir's a really great painter.
I said, it's okay!
Think she's prettier than me?
When you're scared or surprised,
or both at once,
there's a funny glint in your eyes.
So what?
I wanna sleep with you again,
because of that glint.
Mind if I piss in the sink?
Guess what I'm going to say.
No idea.
I'm pregnant, Michel.
You heard me.
Whose is it? Mine?
I think so.
Have you seen a doctor?
Yesterday.
I have to go back Thursday
for the tests.
You should've been more careful!
Get me Élysées 99-84.
Is Antonio there?
You don't know if he's coming back?
I'll call again.
Élysées 25-32.
I'm calling the guy
who owes me money.
Mr. Tolmachoff, please.
Hey, sonny.
I couldn't find Berruti.
I wandered
around Montparnasse all night.
The police?
Thanks. Ciao, sonny.
Shit!
- What?
- I slipped.
Heard the one
about the condemned man?
As he's climbing the scaffold,
he slips and says, "That figures!"
Up close, you look like a Martian.
Because my head's in the clouds.
Some idea, having a kid!
But it's not sure.
I wanted to see what you'd say.
- Take your clothes off.
- What for?
You Americans are so dumb.
I don't see why.
You adore La Fayette
and Maurice Chevalier.
And they're the dumbest French!
I'm making another call.
Belle Épine 35-26.
Patricia, come here!
Mr. Mansard?
Will he be in this afternoon?
Tell him I'll come by.
I'm a friend of Tony's.
From Marseilles.
I've got an American.
An American?
László Kovács.
Not you. My American car.
I can't reach the guy
who owes me. What a drag!
Do you prefer records or the radio?
Quiet, I'm thinking.
I know them all by heart.
- How old are you?
- I'll put the radio on.
I'm 20.
You don't look it.
Why don't you like music?
It depends what kind.
Come on, Patricia, come to Italy.
What's the point of studying
at the Sorbonne?
You never took any exams.
Sure, the baccalaureate.
Then I packed it in.
What's "packed it in"?
I did other stuff.
Like what?
I sold cars.
Here, in Paris?
In New York.
You slept with a lot of guys?
Not all that many.
How many?
How about you?
Not so many either.
Know where I'd like to live? Mexico.
I hear it's really great.
When I was a kid my dad would say,
"We'll go next Saturday."
But he'd always forget.
No, Mexico doesn't grab me.
I bet it's not all that great.
People are such liars.
It's like Stockholm. You keep hearing,
"Swedish girls are terrific.
I laid three a day. Go."
I went. It's not true.
Swedish girls don't act
the way they do here.
And most of them are dogs
like Parisian girls.
No, Swedish girls are very pretty.
It's a myth.
One or two maybe, just like in Paris
or London, but not all of them.
The cities where the girls are pretty,
not gorgeous,
but like you, charming,
girls who rate eight on a scale of 10,
because they have a certain something...
aren't Rome or Paris or Rio,
but Lausanne and Geneva.
Say something nice, too.
I don't know what, either.
Would you let another guy caress you?
You know, you said I'm scared.
It's true, I'm scared.
Because I want you to love me.
But at the same time,
I want you to stop loving me.
I'm very independent, you know.
I love you, but not the way you think.
Then how?
Not the way you think.
But you don't know what I think.
You don't know.
- Sure I do.
- No. You can't.
I want to know what's behind your face.
I've looked at it for 10 minutes now,
and I still know nothing, nothing.
I'm not sad, but I'm scared.
Sweet, gentle Patricia.
Then mean, stupid, heartless,
pathetic, cowardly, despicable.
You don't even know
how to put on your lipstick.
Now you're hideous.
Say what you like, I don't care.
I'll put all this in my book.
- What book?
- I'm writing a novel.
- You?
- Why shouldn't I?
What are you doing?
Taking off your top.
Not now.
You're a pain! What is all this?
You know William Faulkner?
No, who's he?
Someone you slept with?
Hardly, sweetie pie.
Then he can go to hell!
Take off your top.
He's one of my favorite writers.
Have you read The Wild Palms?
I said no! Take off your top.
Listen. The last sentence is beautiful.
Which would you choose?
Let me see your toes.
Toes are important in a woman.
Don't laugh.
Which would you choose?
Grief's stupid.
I'd choose nothing.
It's not better...
but grief's a compromise.
I want all or nothing.
And now I know.
That's it.
Why are you shutting your eyes?
I'm shutting them tight
so everything goes black.
But I can't do it.
It's never entirely black.
Your smile...
seen in profile,
is the nicest thing about you.
That's you.
That's me!
We look each other in the eyes,
but what for?
I hate that name.
I'd like to be called Ingrid.
Sit on your haunches.
What's wrong?
I'm looking at you.
The French are stupid too.
I want you to stay with me.
We interrupt our programming
to synchronize our transceivers.
Funny... I can see myself in your eyes.
This is Franco-American
rapprochement.
We hide like happy elephants.
A woman's hips are touching.
It's hot under here.
If it was another man caressing you,
would you mind?
You asked me that.
And now it's time for
Music While You Work...
So that's that.
Do you know a book by Dylan Thomas,
Portrait of the Artist as a Young Dog?
On Sunday morning,
It's most satisfyin'
To enjoy a long lie-in
I'm getting dressed.
What time is it?
Noon.
Was it good?
Let's stay in bed.
Nope, I have to buy a dress.
Got your car?
My car? Sure.
Élysées 99-84.
Did Antonio come by?
This is maddening!
You don't know where he is?
No, never mind.
Michel Poiccard again.
Want me to wear a bra?
Do you prefer my eyes,
my mouth or my shoulders?
If you had to choose?
There is no press conference?
There is. At Orly airport.
I'm not much of a looker,
but I'm quite a boxer.
Going to your press conference?
I have to drop by the office first.
I'll come with you.
President Eisenhower,
with General De Gaulle,
will lay a wreath
on the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier.
Were you in the army?
What did you do?
I bumped off sentries.
"Bumped off"?
I laid them out like this.
Don't, Michel!
I'm exhausted. I'm gonna die.
You're crazy.
Yeah, totally bonkers.
What's "bonkers"?
That's me.
Your car's not here?
It's at the garage.
I'll go pick it up now.
Swell, a Ford!
- What floor?
- Sixth.
I got the wrong floor.
- Are you scared of aging? I am.
- You dope!
I told you,
the worst flaw is cowardice.
Buy me a dress at Dior?
No way! There are
nicer ones at the five-and-ten.
You don't buy dresses at Dior,
you make calls.
It's the only place
where you can call for free.
There are 12 phone booths.
France-soir!
Thank you, sir.
POLICE KILLER STILL AT LARGE
How long will it last?
Half an hour or so.
I'll go see my man, then.
Why did you call your novel Candida?
I'm convinced that the French
will give my book
a cool reception
because of their prudishness.
Mr. Parvulesco!
Can one still believe in love in our time?
Of course, especially in our time.
Was Rilke right to say, "Modern life will
increasingly separate men and women"?
Rilke was a great poet,
so he was probably right.
Out of my way!
You and your Pathé-Journal!
Are French women romantically
different from American women?
French women
are totally unlike American women.
The American woman
dominates the man.
The French woman
doesn't dominate him yet.
What's your greatest ambition in life?
Which is more moral: an unfaithful woman
or a man who walks out?
An unfaithful woman.
Are women more sentimental
than men?
Feelings are a luxury
few women indulge in.
Is there a difference
between eroticism and love?
No, not really.
I don't think so, because...
eroticism is a form of love,
and vice versa.
Does the soul exist in modern society?
Do women have a role to play
in modern society?
If they're charming and wear
striped dresses and dark glasses.
Casanova said that there's no woman
who can't be seduced
with displays of gratitude.
See Cocteau's
Testament of Orpheus.
How many men can a woman
love in a lifetime?
Physically, I mean.
More than that.
Miss, you're in the frame.
Two things matter in life. For men,
it's women, and for women, money.
See? You are a pessimist.
If you see a pretty girl
with a rich man, you know
she's nice and he's a bastard.
Do you like Brahms?
Like everyone, no.
- And Chopin?
- Makes me want to puke!
What's your greatest ambition?
To become immortal, and then die.
You Claudius Mansard?
Yes, Mr. Kovács.
I called this morning.
I was told you'd be in.
Yes, Mr. Kovács.
Tony sent me.
Didn't we meet in Nice?
Nobody phoned you?
Yes. But they said
it'd be an Oldsmobile.
It fell through at the last minute.
So?
So it's this one.
800,000.
But I can't pay you till next week.
You're a bastard!
And you, Mr. Kovács? What are you?
So what?
So you don't get the money now.
- Tough. Is it 3:00 yet?
- Quarter past.
Can I use your phone?
- Is Antonio there?
- He just left.
Goddammit!
He said to meet him at L'Escale at 4:00.
Four o'clock at L'Escale. Okay, thanks.
Don't bother. I carry my cash on me.
Lend me 10,000.
5,000.
2,500.
It's not running?
Hey, you!
You remove the distributor cap?
Pay for the call!
Pay for my taxi!
Step on it! Step on it!
Never mind the pedestrians!
Just move it!
Step on it, for chrissake!
The Thunderbird's fender torn off!
Me, not a scratch!
That's where I was born.
Look at the eyesore
they built opposite!
Buildings like that get me down.
They ruin the block.
I have a feeling for beauty, beautiful.
Go through Chatelet.
It's your fault if we're late.
No, it isn't.
Pass that Peugeot!
Don't shift gears!
Braking for a 4CV!
That scooter just passed you!
Take the next left.
Stop here. Be right back.
He left five minutes ago.
The friend who owes you money?
Antonio Berruti, yeah. It's your fault.
Now it's double or nothing.
- Why?
- Later.
Pass that 2CV, pops.
- Where you going?
- To the Herald.
Eyes on the road!
Why bother writing?
To have money and not rely on men.
Parisians look like tarts
in those short dresses.
Makes me wanna run up behind them
and do like this...
Don't mind me!
Stop here!
- Be right back.
- Okay.
- Not paying?
- Quick!
- Where are we going?
- The Champs-Élysées.
I hate cabbies who worry
about scratching the bodywork.
The Gestapo put up a wall here
so nobody could get away.
I've been thinking about that girl.
What girl?
The one with that guy on the Riviera.
You said you admired her.
Yeah, a normal girl. That's rare.
Come with me to the paper?
No, I have a call to make.
I'm going to see my tailor.
I'll pick you up later.
Ciao, kiddo!
You're late. They're waiting.
Over there.
You speak French?
You know this man?
Careful, kid.
You can't fool the Paris police.
Yes, it's Michel.
I didn't recognize him.
It's an old photo.
You were seen with him
this morning just outside.
Who saw me?
He was driving
a Ford Thunderbird 3382 GM75.
Where is he now?
I don't know.
Watch what you say, kid.
I've seen him five or six times.
I found him nice. I don't know
where he lives or what he does.
Known him long?
I met him in Nice last month.
I was on vacation.
He came to Paris to see someone
who owes him money.
Who?
I don't know.
He had an Italian name.
Think you'll see him again?
Maybe. Sometimes he calls me
and asks me out. Like this morning.
Got a work permit?
You don't want any passport problems?
No, I don't.
So if you see him, here's my number.
Danton 01-00.
President Eisenhower
is waving to the crowds...
Was that what you meant
by double or nothing?
More or less.
Let's go see a Western.
Yeah, better wait till dark.
Beware, Jessica
On the kiss's beveled edge
Time is a void
Avoid, avoid
Memory's broken pledge
You're wrong, sheriff
Your tale is noble and tragic
Like the mask of a tyrant
No drama so perilous or magnetic
No detail can make our love pathetic
Hey, cutie!
POLICE CLOSING IN ON MICHEL POICCARD...
- What's it say?
- I'm reading it.
The cops are stupid to be after me.
I'm one of the few people
who likes cops.
Let me caress you.
Say something!
- Wow!
- What?
- So you're married.
- Show me.
That was ages ago.
She was a wacko. She dumped me.
Or I dumped her. Don't remember.
I'm really fond of you.
What's it feel like,
riding in a stolen car?
- And killing a policeman?
- I was scared.
How did they know I knew you?
Someone must've seen us together
and informed on us.
- That's horrible.
- What is?
Informing on people.
No, it's normal. Informers inform,
burglars burgle,
murderers murder, lovers love.
Look, isn't the Concorde gorgeous!
Yes, mysterious, with all the lights.
I was a fool to keep this car.
Gotta switch.
- What?
- Switch cars.
Let's steal the Cadillac?
What about the keys?
You drive, I hide.
They leave the keys in the car here.
- What do I tell the man?
- Say good night, in English.
That'll shut him up.
The French are yellow-bellied.
"Yellow-bellied"?
Scared stiff. You scared?
It's too late to be scared.
MICHEL POICCARD: ARREST IMMINENT
I just gotta find Antonio.
Once you look for someone,
you never find him.
Who was that?
- Step on it, poppet.
- What's "poppet"?
Have you seen Antonio?
I'll tell you if I can kiss her.
It's not up to me.
It's up to her.
He's with Zumbach.
Carl!
- How's life?
- The same. Antonio here?
There he is.
- Who is he?
- Who? Antonio?
No, the other one.
Let's see those socks.
Silk socks with a tweed jacket!
- I like silk.
- Not with tweed!
- Hey, amigo.
- Hey, sonny.
I'll be off.
You been looking for me?
You called several times.
Yeah, I'm in the shit. Goddammit!
Got a minute?
- See that guy?
- What do I say?
Anything you want.
I'll just be a sec.
- What will they do?
- Take photos of her kissing the guy.
- What for?
- Blackmail, probably.
Be right back.
Who's the chick?
- To make things worse, I love her.
- Damn!
1.3 million. Can do.
What's the bank?
- B.N.C.I.
- Let me see.
What do we do?
Don't know.
- Where can I reach you tomorrow?
- Don't know.
The hotels are crawling with
goddamn tourists.
My friend in Montmartre
has a big place.
- Not Montmartre.
- Not Montmartre, he says.
Why not?
Too many enemies in Montmartre.
Try Zumbach's Swedish girl.
Rue Campagne-Première?
Call me there tomorrow.
Antonio said we could sleep here.
Sure. Sit down.
I'll be right with you.
Smile!
Why not pose? Pay's good.
You have to sleep around.
I was just thinking...
- What?
- I'm not sure.
About?
I don't know. Otherwise I'd be sure.
You dump your journalist?
Why'd you say hello?
To make sure
I didn't love him anymore.
You complicate your life.
That's it.
Drop me on the Champs-Élysées?
What are you playing?
The "Clarinet Concerto" by Mozart.
Do you mind?
No, I like that one.
I thought you didn't like music.
This one's okay.
My dad was a clarinetist.
My dad was a great clarinet player.
Want to go to bed?
Sleeping's so sad.
We have to separ.
- ...ate.
- "Separate."
You say "sleep together," but you don't.
What is it?
Nothing.
Come here.
Go buy a France-soir
and a bottle of milk.
What time is it?
Five o'clock.
Still busy.
- What?
- Nothing.
France-soir!
I'm looking at you.
It's your lucky day. Buy a ticket.
- A Scotch.
- Don't have any.
Make it coffee.
Danton 01-00?
Inspector Vital, please.
Patricia Franchini.
I've just seen the man
you've been looking for.
He's at 11, rue Première-Campagne.
Yes. 11, rue Campagne-Première.
Thirsty?
Antonio's coming. He just called.
We're going to Italy, kid.
I can't go.
Sure you can. I'm taking you.
Berruti's lending me his Simca Sport.
- A Gordini engine.
- Michel, I called the police.
I said you were here.
What! Are you crazy?
No, I'm fine.
No, I'm not fine.
I don't want to go away
with you now.
I knew it.
I don't know.
I just talked about myself,
and you, yourself.
I'm so stupid.
You should've talked about me,
and me, about you.
I don't want to be in love with you.
That's why I called the police.
I stayed with you
to make sure I was in love with you.
Or that I wasn't.
And since I'm being mean to you,
it proves I'm not in love with you.
Say that again!
And since I'm being mean to you,
it proves I'm not in love with you.
They say there's no happy love.
If I loved you...
It's too complicated!
On the contrary, there's no unhappy love.
I want people to let me be.
I'm independent.
- Maybe you love me.
- You think you are. You're not.
That's why I turned you in.
I'm better than you are.
Now you have no choice but to go.
You're crazy!
That's a pathetic argument.
You're like the girl
who sleeps with everyone...
except the one man who loves her...
saying it's because she sleeps
with everyone.
Why don't you go?
I've slept with lots of men.
Don't count on me.
What are you waiting for?
No, I'm staying. I'm in bad shape.
I prefer prison.
You're mad!
Nobody'll talk to me.
I can look at the walls.
Damn, Berruti!
Hey, amigo! I'll just park.
- The cops are coming.
- Your money!
The American girl turned me in.
- Get in!
- No, you go!
- No, I'm staying.
I'm fed up.
I'm tired.
I want to sleep.
You're nuts!
Damn the police. I'll save my neck.
I shouldn't be thinking of her,
but I can't help it.
Want my pistol?
- Don't be stupid!
- Get lost!
Makes me want to puke.
What did he say?
He said you make him want to puke.
What's that mean, "puke"?