Jonas, five minutes to go.
Things are really heating up
in Brasilia.
It's confirmed that
a further three politicians...
whose names have
not been released...
may also be involved
in the irrigation fraud.
And speaking of the heat,
what's the forecast for tomorrow?
Not a lot of change.
On Friday, some heavy rain over
South and Southeast Brazil.
The large mass of dry air, causing
the long drought in the Northeast...
will remain.
Just five minutes.
You're not that strong!
Jandira, same room as usual.
Six minutes then, Lázaro.
Home, Wedja!
- Jurandir, I only...
- Move, Wedja! Home!
- Let's go up!
- Do you hear me woman?
- You're not going anywhere!
- Oh, really?
You must be joking!
You keep your nose clean, I keep
mine. That's the way of the world.
Now, come on.
Stop that!
You fucking shit! Let's...
No change in the large mass of
dry air causing this drought.
ARIDO MOVIE
Could you switch down the volume?
Thanks.
Recife is hotter than ever,
or is it me?
Really sultry.
By the end of the day
you're done for.
And then,
there's the water problem.
Fuck me backwards! Excuse the
expression. But it's a real pain!
Water rationing! I don't get it.
Recife is surrounded by water...
and yet there's no water.
It really pisses me off.
A rifle-hot sun.
- What?
- Nothing.
How did it happen, Stella?
Was he really murdered?
I don't know.
They told me almost nothing.
And I didn't ask.
Your uncle Salustiano phoned.
At the request of your grandmother.
You know how he was. Any trouble,
and he was always mixed up in it.
I know nothing.
I can't even remember his face.
The last person in the world
I wanted to meet was your father.
You know that.
It's a shame what happened.
I feel sorry for you.
Don't know what else to say.
It's been ages since I saw
that family, thank God.
You want a whisky?
No thanks, mum.
I don't like drinking before I eat.
What São Paulo does to a person!
Mum. Dr. Feliciano has arrived
for the funeral.
That's all I know.
Salustiano told me that
Dona Carmo would only rest...
after I promised I'd convince you
to go to Lázaro's funeral.
Funny, isn't it?
But after all, you are her grandson.
And although you left long ago...
You should realize that
you are on TV almost everyday.
Funny.
It's never really occurred to me...
that dad and grandma
see me everyday.
Television turns you into a phantom.
You have no idea
the places you appear.
Anyway, you need to remember
that you're the star of Rocha.
The town celebrity!
I think I will have that whisky.
I'm so sorry, Márcio.
So sad!
Dona Carmo, my sympathies.
You can count on me for anything.
As if we needed this, Feliciano!
Look what they've done!
But life is just
one day after another.
And God, who has given me
so much joy...
- won't let things stay like this.
- You must remain strong.
Isn't he being buried today?
Wasn't that the plan?
I've already told her.
We shouldn't wait so long.
You can't put it off
for so long.
Salustiano is right.
The dead don't like long goodbyes.
It's already decided.
Only when Jonas arrives.
He's coming, isn't he, Salustiano?
They say he is.
BATH HOUSE BAR
For fuck's sake!
Have you decided?
The powder's a little bit rough.
Isn't, it?
I'm talking about the trip.
You're going or not?
We're thinking about
going with you.
There's no need. It's boring there.
And then for a funeral! No need.
No! We're going with you.
Are you going by car?
Don't know yet. But there's no need.
I prefer to go alone.
That's what friends are for.
Fuck off, Bob! He wants to be the
do-it-yourself man. Leave it out!
I'm pushing off.
I'm fucking knackered.
We'll sort it out.
I need to talk to the office.
I don't know who is going
to replace me.
Tomorrow we see what we're
going to do.
Stay a little longer.
Just a little.
Stay. I promise I'll be
as quiet as a fish.
We'll talk tomorrow. All right?
- Right.
- See you, man!
You're too fucking much.
You're a fucking bastard, Bob.
Now what have I done?
- The very essence of sensitivity!
- A real sweetie, huh?
- Watch out! You off your head?
- Sorry. I'm really sorry!
You see that?
God, Wedja!
What've you got yourself
caught up in?
Not so much you,
but your brother...
You think we can get
Jurandir away?
We'll see.
Why get mixed up with Lázaro?
You never imagined Jurandir
would accept that, did you?
Anyone except Lázaro.
Wedja, life can be fun...
but you've got to walk
as if you were treading on eggs.
Not to get mixed up in trouble.
And you go rushing straight in!
Just like your mother.
Pass me the food,
I'm off to the pasture.
I hope this helps to get Jurandir
out of trouble. What's the matter?
OK.
I'll be back soon.
Keep your nose clean.
If anyone asks,
I've gone to meditate...
because the world's gone
off the rails.
Don't serve any drink.
Not even for the CG boys.
Special orders.
Wedja, prohibition!
I once read that the most important
invention ever is page numbering.
- Toilet flush.
- Plastic!
Fuck off! Falcão, I read it
for fuck's sake! Don't fuck about!
The toilet flush was the greatest
invention of the last century!
Maybe in the last century!
The greatest invention ever
is page numbering!
Page numbering, paper, toilet flush.
Who fucking cares!
- Then there's cotton buds.
- Fucking cotton buds!
Beto!
Mum...
do you really think
this is the best way?
Shouldn't we sort it out,
our way?
He's no better than anyone else,
and he has the right.
He'll see everything our way.
He will.
- Márcio.
- I'm outside with the boys, mum.
Call me if you need me.
Márcio Greyck, Márcio Greyck!
Open your eyes!
It'll be all right, you'll see!
I think Jonas is going to fuck up
everything. It sticks here.
- And the stink?
- It's fucking rotten!
There are many ways to roll a joint.
I prefer the classical way.
You give the little 'shrimp'
a good rub...
and it has to be very dry.
And preferably...
the weed has to come from Cabrobó,
the famous "goat's shit".
Real rat poison!
You take the skin...
and throw everything inside.
Work it over a little,
taking out the seeds.
Seeds only give you a headache
and make it bitter.
They make it bitter.
Then comes the most
important factor - rolling.
If you don't roll
it really well...
then it's difficult to light.
And don't make it too thin.
Thin spliffs are for
the fags down south.
You smoke to get high,
and to get high...
it's got to be thick.
Then you close one end and leave
the other free to press it down.
Push it nice and tight.
Take off this piece...
light it...
You're a real crack.
Pass the ball, King Pelé.
Keep this one, fag.
There's a thicker one for me!
Guys... Guys...
I think we should go after Jonas.
He's really upset. No, thanks.
I'm worried about him too.
And I love the hinterland!
It's great!
The 'shrimps' there are this big!
Look the size!
What are you on about!
Jonas needs his friends. Let's go!
- Let's go.
- Come on!
How are you, Vera?
Looking for Jonas?
We said we'd give him
a lift to Rocha.
- He's not answering his mobile.
- He arrived strangely last night...
and left early this morning.
I hope he calls me.
He went after his father.
But I think he w'ont find him.
Well... I'd better go.
The boys are waiting.
Come round some time.
You only appear when he's here.
OK, madam.
I'll call round. Bye!
You see her? She was always
with us, even called me auntie.
Now she only comes when
Jonas comes. She calls me ma'am.
The only people that call me that
are the people here.
- She's such a pain!
- Where's the weather man?
- Spit it out Verinha.
- Madam says he's already left.
"And Jesus,
when he was baptized...
went up out of the water,
and lo the heavens...
were opened unto him...
and he saw
the Spirit of God...
descending like a dove.
And lo a voice
from Heaven saying:
This is my beloved Son,
in whom I am well pleased. "
He went by car?
That's why even Lázaro
couldn't take this woman.
A real fucking pain!
Let's get going?
I need to stop at home
to take a shower.
Hold on Bob!
There's no time for that!
If we're going to lend him support,
it has to be now.
- Take a shower on the way.
- They don't have any water there.
"The Pharisees also with
the Sadducees came...
and tempting him that he would
show them a sign from heaven.
He answered and said unto them,
When it is evening...
ye say, "It will be" fair weather:
For the sky is red.
And in the morning...
it will be foul weather today:
For the sky is lowring.
O ye hypocrites.
Ye can discern
the face of the sky...
but can ye not discern
the signs of the time".
Matthew.
Oh, glory!
There's no time to have a shower?
You're both too edgy.
What use would it be, Bob?
By this time there is
no water at your place.
Don't fuck about, Bob.
You were never really
that fond of water.
Let's go!
If it's philosophical, I'll disappear
without a trace of smell.
Concentrate, Madame Bernadette.
I'm passing you
my positive energies.
What's going on? Predict.
Concentrate. Strength!
The vibrations are beginning.
What's happening?
That young man, Madame Bernadette.
This city boy.
He's got a backpack!
What's in the backpack?
On his back.
This young man in front of me.
What is he carrying?
The city boy is carrying...
- clothes...
- Clothes!
...doubts.
- Doubts!
Doubts!
Very good!
And in front!
On his arm.
Time.
What is he carrying in front?
- In front?
- In front, Madame Bernadete.
No one escapes the inevitable!
This young man has no future!
It's like this...
I want Jurandir at any cost!
He's here.
He can't leave here
without me knowing.
He's not invisible!
I want to see him six foot under.
No sweat. No bother.
I've talked to uncle Salustiano,
and he agrees.
Jucão!
Go over to the farm and see
if you can calm things down.
The work must go on.
Keep the CG boys occupied
so that they don't get any ideas.
Don't want anyone
causing trouble.
Get it?
Move!
It's 8 o'clock here in Vietnam...
and our team is trying to get used
to the time difference.
It's mad!
There it's 8 o'clock at night,
and here it's 9 in the morning.
It's a real science!
A beer, please.
- What?
- A beer.
Remember me?
- Sorry?
- Remember me?
You knocked my drink
all over me yesterday.
And you screamed at me.
Sorry.
Aren't you Jonas Andrade?
The weatherman?
I thought it was you, but it's not
easy to recognise a weatherman...
without his jacket
and digital clouds.
I must be the only person to be seen
on TV everyday...
who remains anonymous
outside the studio.
Is that good or bad?
I find it more or less good.
Soledad.
Pleasure. Jonas.
What're you doing here?
Wow!
Is this game live or indirect?
I was born near here,
in Rocha.
I went to Recife and from there
to São Paulo, where I live.
Rocha?
- I'm going there.
- Really?
- You're on the bus?
- Yes.
If you want,
I could give you a lift.
I'd better stay on the bus.
I'm in a hurry to get to Rocha.
I only have to stop off quickly
in Deserto Feliz for an interview.
It'll be quick! Really.
And I'd enjoy the company.
No, thanks. I'd better go by bus.
It's leaving in a minute.
It's much quicker by car.
- Aren't you in a hurry?
- Yes.
So, It'll cost me nothing.
On the contrary.
I normally travel alone...
but I miss having someone
to talk to.
To talk about things as we go.
All right then. If it's not going
to put you out, I accept.
- Did you leave anything in the bus?
- I've got my jacket.
I think I left the digital clouds!
That was almost funny.
Soledad!
Why Soledad?
Why not?
- Dona Carmo!
- Father Antonio...
I give great regard
to your words.
I thank you for your concern
and your work.
But this is not a request.
I am determined...
to wait until
my grandson gets here.
Salustiano phoned his mother...
and that woman said
he was on his way.
Lázaro will only be buried
when his son arrives.
You see, Father...
Salustiano is my son,
but he is limited.
Dedé and Márcio are treated
like family.
You more than anyone,
know that.
Adopted into the family with my mercy.
Apart from this universe of
distant cousins and nephews...
my family is now my grandson
and Salustiano.
Lázaro will only be buried
when he arrives.
We can only wait
until the end of the afternoon.
I'm afraid to say that the situation
is becoming unbearable.
Yes! Water is difficult.
We can only count
on luck and God.
The two have to come together.
Luck, which is a divine blessing,
manifests itself in nature.
And is the face of God on earth.
Well, as I was saying...
I take my forked stick...
and walk around.
I've found a lot of water
for a lot of people.
Important people. The poor.
Even politicians.
But can anyone do it?
I mean, if I take the stick,
will I find water?
Huh! Of course not.
If it was like that
there'd be no water shortage.
First you need faith,
the kerosene of the soul.
Then the talent. There are those
who have it and those who don't.
Who has the talent of the word
has thought...
who has the talent of power
has the farm...
and who has the talent of
forked stick, has water.
But is there still water here?
Of course there isn't!
OK. No problem.
It was just to show your art.
Hello, Jonas?
It's you, Jonas...?
Jonas has been like that
ever since university.
Quiet. Introspective.
Shy.
Shy, shy, and bang,
consumed Little Red Riding Hood.
Shy until the first glass, then you
couldn't get a word in sideways.
They say a guy that drinks can't
get it up. That's why I prefer weed.
- Did that happen to Jonas?
- Leave it out.
Go on! Could he get it up or not?
Or did it just dangle?
Shut your mouth, Falcão!
You're as big a shithead as Bob.
It's just we're here smoking.
It's all about smoking...
there's something crazy...
you see the other talking, you start
to take on the other's personality.
There's a great film about that...
with that actor...
who was married to...
that woman who did...
- that film...
- Stop getting at me!
This fucking sun and
you just talking crap. Stop it!
It's more or less like this.
From this point,
the Valley of Rocha...
I am developing a theory about
the impact created by water.
The lack of water
within the communities.
And in this hinterland universe,
I've identified several nuances.
For example, in Rocha...
I'll find the mythical
and political discourse of water.
How the little water of the region
is distributed...
its political use and where it is.
I'm talking too much.
You must know Rocha better than me.
I've never been there.
No, I don't even remember the place.
My memories are so photographic
that I don't know if they are true.
A confusion in my mind.
I think things here
have stood still in time.
Why are you coming back?
My father's funeral.
I'm sorry.
You're here to bury your father
and I'm rattling on.
That's ok.
I'm not sure if I feel anything.
I left a long time ago.
I was around five.
A strange sensation. It's like
losing something I never had.
Like being part of a story
in which I never had a role.
You know what's funny?
I don't feel strange here.
Ah, look out,
look out, look out!
Calm down.
Habemus pope!
Has this hole been here long?
This place is not a hole, sir!
It's simple but worthy of respect.
No, I'm talking about
the hole in the road.
Ah! Yes.
This road has needed
repair for ages.
It's not like it used to be.
It's the tyres.
Not even this car
can take this road.
This'll take some time.
I'd like to have a better look.
I'd like to spend the day looking
at this engine. It's fantastic!
But I'm in a hurry.
How can anyone be in a hurry
in a place like this?
- Where're you going?
- Rocha.
So you've just arrived.
He'll not get far here.
That one's from another world.
A nothing.
I just hope he hasn't come
to ruin everything!
- He's gonna shit himself.
- I agree.
But when mum gets something into
her head, there's no going back.
You know that.
Your bar is incredible,
Zé Elétrico.
- Where did you get it all?
- Ah, all part of the valley.
You may not believe it
but I found it all here.
- It's surreal, Jonas!
- Going to Lázaro's funeral?
Yes.
How did you know?
There must be some reason
for coming here to Rocha.
- You're his son, aren't you?
- I am.
- My sympathies.
- Thank you.
Calm down!
Has the Recife bus arrived?
Not yet.
- What time does it arrive?
- Depends.
Sometimes at five,
sometimes later.
But never more than six!
Where're you from?
Jamaica.
- Thanks.
- Did you get the plate's number?
- 0624.
- The number of the goat!
- The goat always brings bad luck.
Get off!
No fucking way
I'm going to this funeral alone.
Especially with Bob
stinking like a skunk.
We could go to that bar,
with that wonderful native girl!
Cheyenne, General Custer.
The one at the door? Cheyenne.
So we fill up and have a drink.
Barren Mouths,
by Graciliano Ramos.
Get it? Barren Lives...
It's the first time
I've met a celebrity.
Wedja, Wedja...
Go inside and stay tuned!
All right, Wedja?
Thanks. She will bring the car back
so you can have a closer look.
- I'm really in a hurry.
- But I'd like to have a chat with you.
You know The Old Man, don't you?
The Old Man is one of us.
Who goes to the sky via satellite.
- I know him.
- Let's go? Thanks, Zé!
I'll be back.
The town is near here, isn't it?
Very near.
- Thanks!
- Thanks.
Go with God.
This way.
I knew you'd come.
Everyone was waiting
for you, grandson.
Jonas, pay your respects
to your father.
Sorry, Jonas,
but we have to be quick. Please.
Well, there's fresh beans...
sun-dried meat, goat's entrails,
roast goat, stewed goat...
chicken and sausages.
- Wow!
- Calm down, fuck it!
- Any vegetables?
- Vegetables?
There's tomato,
onion and cassava.
If cassava is a vegetable...
let's say that beer is too
and let's get going.
So bring vegetables,
cassava. Everything!
Thank you!
Thank you.
- Have they buried him?
- Now.
- They were waiting for Jonas.
- The son from the television?
Zé, you know he deserved it.
I'm poor,
but I've got pride.
That maybe so.
But this is going to stink.
Fucking family.
They'll find a way
of getting me.
Marcio, that son of a bitch!
A real fucking son of a bitch.
- The boy seems quiet. Polite.
- I don't want to know.
- And Wedja?
- She's ok.
She can look after herself.
Let's face it, it's like
she's always out for a good time.
She's what's left from the family.
No son of a bitch is going
to humiliate my family.
I won't stand for it.
I'd kill them all.
You have to wait for things
to cool down before you make a move.
The boys from CG are livid.
To and for. To and for.
Bring some smokes next time.
I'll see what time
I can bring your food.
Not even Wedja knows
where you are.
She mustn't know.
Follow your destiny, Lázaro!
Here on earth...
your family will continue
to honour...
your sacred memory.
- Vedja.
- It's "Wedja"!
Ah, sorry! Wedja, my dear...
bring some napkins, please.
And another beer!
Really cold!
For someone who came
to give support!
That's true! That is the truth!
Jonas didn't even want us to come.
She said he came here
with some woman!
What a bastard!
We'll talk later.
You knew this Lázaro?
- Of course, Bob.
- Daft question, huh?
Good evening.
I'd like to talk to Soledad,
the owner of that car outside.
It's Jonas, isn't it?
Soledad?
- Is she expecting you?
- Yes. At least, I think so.
Room 113.
Are you her boyfriend?
- No!
- I see...
- Why?
- Nothing! You can go up.
But this is
a decent establishment.
Of course! I'm going up.
He said nothing about coming
with anyone. Who could it be?
You know what I want?
Cacacha!
Did you get your things
sorted out?
Not really.
- I'm going to the bar to talk to Zé.
- Can I go too?
What?
Can I go with you?
Get out and clear my mind a little.
Today wasn't easy.
Of course, Jonas.
I spoke to some people
about The Old Man.
I had no idea he was so popular.
- Who is this Old Man?
- Didn't I tell you?
He's a religious leader.
His beliefs are founded
on the use of water.
I have to register his words.
It's exactly what I'm looking for.
I've never met him,
but I know he's quite a figure.
I've never heard of him.
Ah, but I have.
That's why I'm here.
- Let's go?
- Sure.
Leave your things here,
we'll get you a room later.
You've become my family today.
- Fuck! What happened?
- Zé Elétrico has just arrived.
All we need to do is behave!
He's all right, isn't he?
He told me not to sell alcohol.
Tell him you're friends of Jonas.
Wedja, what did I tell you?
Hi, Zé Elétrico.
It wasn't Wedja's fault.
It never is.
They're Jonas' friends,
the grandson from the TV...
She gave us food, sausages.
Come and sit down.
This girl is such a headache!
You're a little devil, Wedja!
This is Falcão.
A good guy! Vera...
Sit down.
Come down to earth.
Wedja! I wasn't going to,
but as you've permitted it...
bring a beer.
And could we have
the music back, too?
I see the night like the ocean...
that bathes the world
of sun with shadow.
I see life like that too.
Ocean of shadows...
- dreams, desires. He's great.
- Too much!
What are you doing here?
- Jonas!
- Jonas. Brother.
- You're here!
- We got lost.
I was teaching your friends...
They said they're your friends.
- Vedja...
- "Wedja"!
Wedja said...
that you left
just before we arrived.
So we stayed here talking
to Zé Elétrico.
- He's a real philosopher!
- Lf only.
I just see the world
in a different way.
I like listening.
I learned to think through my ears.
How was it there, Jonas?
We were worried.
Fucking worried!
Hi, I'm Soledad.
Hi. Falcão.
Vera...
- How's things?
- Fine.
We came to give you some support.
Then you disappeared!
I didn't know you were
with someone. It was a surprise.
We met on the way.
It was quicker like that.
I needed to get here quickly.
He was beginning to stink.
Fucking hell!
Where did The Old Man come from?
She's a beautiful native.
Wedja?
She's a time bomb.
Always ready to explode.
Boom!
She's fantastic!
- What was I saying?
- The Old Man.
He first came as a prospector.
He bought some land.
There was no water.
He opened some caves
but found nothing.
They say he got to know
some natives.
Then he started having visions
and receiving messages.
Mystical things.
That's how it started.
Then he started to build the castle.
Castle?
Yes, the castle...
on top of the reservoir,
which are always filled with water.
He blesses the water and it takes
on miraculous powers.
They say it's not only his faith
which makes it miraculous.
It's full of uranium.
Uranium?
Wow!
That's where the power
comes from!
You don't want to talk about it?
And he's there until today.
At the heart of the valley.
Heavenly Father.
I commend this body...
blood and soul of your beloved
son Jesus Christ...
who atones for
all the sins of the world.
For his pain and suffering,
have pity on this world.
Until tomorrow, Zé.
Go in the shadow.
- Bye.
Until tomorrow.
Bye, Wedja.
For his pain and suffering,
have pity on this world.
- That's the best way to dance.
- It's heavy work.
But like I was saying, it's mad.
We all know it kills neurones.
But alcohol is much worse,
Than weed, don't you think?
But nobody says anything.
And why? Industry!
Tobacco. Weapons.
Those with the money run the world.
And the victims?
Those who smoke the 'weed'.
Who is right?
To be honest, I don't agree.
Not everyone is prepared for it.
I think we should produce it
to sell to Holland.
What's that?
To smoke, I'll have to go to
the ends of the fucking world.
Your bag's there.
Your digital clouds are safe.
What's that noise?
For a decent establishment,
the rules are very flimsy.
Have you read The Stranger,
by Camus?
- No. Why?
- Nothing.
Each day
is like a cut-throat razor.
I feel a stranger everywhere.
Even in my dreams.
Have pity on this world.
For his pain and suffering...
have pity on this world.
For this pain and suffering,
have pity...
A mass of dry air from the coast
means today will be hot.
It will be sunny throughout the
northeast...
especially in the Rocha Valley.
Jonas!
Jonas.
- What's the time?
- It's early.
I've got to get up.
It's a long way
to the Old Man's farm.
I'm not sure where it is.
- Are you coming?
- I'd like to, but I can't.
I've got to go to
my grandmother's.
Wake up.
Let's get going for fuck's sake.
- Come on!
- Where to?
Paradise, brother!
Paradise?
Up your fucking arse!
The plantation of dreams.
The selection of the goat's shit.
The plantation that
Wedja talked about. Let's move!
Smoking dope gives me amnesia and
a million things I can't remember.
- Don't you remember either?
- Huh?
I should be back
at the end of the afternoon.
- We'll meet at Zé Elétrico's.
- OK. See you then.
Bye, Miss Soledad.
- Good morning, my boy.
- Good morning, Dona Carmo.
Take a seat, Jonas.
Make yourself at home.
Let's have some breakfast?
Do you think
she's spoken to him?
Must have done. If mum says
she'll do it, she'll do it.
But it won't interfere
with the plans at all.
She sent everybody away
when he arrived.
It's OK, Marcio.
Think calmly. Intelligently.
Isn't everything
kind of sorted out?
This won't change anything.
Don't stand on ceremony.
You're at home.
You look at lot like him.
Who? Me?
Yes. Doesn't he?
The spitting image!
Did he use to talk about me?
My God! Almost every day.
He never forgave
that mad mother yours.
She ran away from here
with you just a kid.
He never forgave her!
I never imagined he'd turn up here.
But be careful. He's famous.
Be smart about this.
I think you're the one that needs
to be a bit smarter!
You're shitting yourself!
I'll sort things out my way.
You know that
when I want something...
there's nothing
I won't do? Right!
In reality,
I have to do everything.
You stay there looking after
body boxes. All right?
- And the accent?
- Whose accent?
The television playboy.
Stupid prat!
Learn to talk like us properly!
Excuse me. You know where
that truck came from?
- The deputy's truck?
- Yes.
From The Dry Stream Farm.
That's where I'm headed.
Can you tell me the way?
- To The Old Man's Farm?
- Yes.
Just go the way the truck came.
And keep going.
A couple of leagues and a half.
You'll then come to
the Rock of the Dog.
It's got the face of a dog.
You then come across a tree trunk.
Turn. You then pass by...
let me see... one... two...
three gates.
- You're there.
- OK.
And the lizard?
A pet?
The teju?
To eat.
- Thanks.
- Any time.
My boy.
They want to wipe out our family.
I don't say that
only because of your father.
There are people who want to see
our family on its knees.
But do you know
when that will happen?
Never.
This is a brave family.
Courageous blood.
We haven't lost the family name...
just because we lost
the cotton plantations.
No. It's forever, Jonas.
Forever!
This was your father's.
Now it's yours.
I hope you know what to do with it.
Look, Dona Carmo.
I only came because of the family.
Because of you.
This is nothing to do with me.
Your father is dead.
Killed like a dog, and you say
it's nothing to do with you?
When your grandfather died,
your father said he'd take over.
And he did.
You're no better, Jonas.
Because your mother took you away,
you say "Nothing to do with me"?
And the land?
Nothing to do with you?
The house, the farm.
What about them?
This is all yours.
All of this is yours!
And it is to do with you!
Whether you want it or not!
Jurandir, things smell bad.
The CG boys are looking everywhere.
That's why I've got to get away now!
I'm gonna die here like a pig.
That's why you can't leave now.
They're up and down, stick your head
out now and you lose it.
Look, I appreciate...
what you're doing for my sister...
as well as your hate for
that fucking family.
But now it's my decision.
Wait just a little.
The time will come.
And what about this Jonas?
Poor devil!
He's got no idea how to hold
a knife, much less how to use it.
- Is he a bastard too?
- Don't know.
Doesn't seem like the same family.
I'm off.
Give me a
little longer, all right?
I love you, my angel!
It's like the Portuguese
discoverers used to er yo plant...
grows!
You asked for it. Take it.
"I will see you when I get there"!!
Good morning. Are you lost?
No.
- I'm looking for The Old Man.
- You're in the right place.
Ready for combat, are you?
What?
My godmother spoke to you?
We're gonna find Jurandir.
Then you finish it off.
If you need any...
I don't need any help...
because I'm not going to do it.
Why don't you do it?
You're a son too, aren't you?
My father died a long time ago.
Never knew him.
He died before I was born.
But the CG boys are out looking.
He must be in the woods.
He's a native, isn't he?
We find him. You do the job.
Did you know that...
every time Lázaro got drunk, he
imitated you on the television.
Everyone enjoyed it.
Look, killing is not that bad.
But thinking about it is.
You won't chicken out of it.
We're watching you!
What is it, Jucão?
They're there? Whose orders?
No, no, don't do anything.
Slowly. Let it roll!
After we squeeze him a little,
he'll be shitting himself.
Jucão, have you lost trust
or respect?
That's all right then.
Old Man!
Old Man.
Can I begin recording?
Just a minute.
Can I call you Old Man?
When My Father appeared to me
for the first time...
my name was Zé.
Then He wanted me
to be called Aquinetom.
- Now I'm The Old Man.
- Who is your father?
My Father is the father
of everyone on earth.
It's just that I am His
direct son...
as well as His messenger.
I speak directly to Him.
He illuminates me...
and I pass it on to those
who follow me.
The link of the divine
with the deep.
What did they want?
They think I know
where your father's killer is.
- The native?
- Yes. Jurandir.
Wedja, give me a moment alone
with our friend here.
What did they want?
Wedja! Disappear for two minutes.
Invisible.
Go to your room, the bathroom,
anywhere!
Hi, Zé.
Speak.
I went to my grandmother's...
and Márcio and my grandmother said
I had to kill the native.
I left there not really knowing
what's going on. So I came here.
I arranged to meet Soledad here.
She went to see The Old Man.
I don't know what's happening.
My own grandmother telling
me I had to kill the native.
- Márcio is crazy to find Jurandir.
- I'm not going to kill any native.
Nor anyone.
She gave me this.
My grandmother gave me this.
She said to find the native
and kill him. Márcio said so too.
I've never held a gun.
But I'm certainly not going
to kill anyone!
Jonas, Jonas.
You've landed yourself
in a right mess.
Don't you know your own family?
You think it's easy?
It's not.
There are things we do
because we want.
Others we do without wanting to.
- I don't really understand.
- I've known it for a long time.
But this is crazy!
This...
This is unreal. It's like things
here have stood still in time!
Jonas...
Your father died because he thought
he could do anything he wanted.
But the bullet
doesn't respect anyone.
And all because of a woman?
- Wedja.
- Wedja?
The woman was Wedja,
and the native is her brother.
That's it.
In the beginning,
there was only the Rocha Valley...
and the heavens covering all.
Then I arrived.
I started prospecting.
A lot of rocks.
I dug and dug.
And from then, time started.
I mean, the time here.
The cyclical time
that marks everything.
The natives didn't exist yet.
Come on, Jonas.
There's something you've got to see.
Then the natives came.
And then the other men.
Then the water appeared.
Where did the water come from?
The deep!
It flowed from the walls...
irrigating everything!
But what came in abundance
started to run out.
So I started to store water.
- The mimosa water.
- Where do you store it?
There's a lot of history here.
The people who lived in
this region...
knew how to use it well.
They respected the land.
And it respected them.
The true owners of the land.
The people who came after,
who invaded and killed...
called these first inhabitants
"indians".
Indians, Jonas.
The natives started to mix.
From owners, to workers.
The women became whore.
First we lost the land.
Then respect.
Then our teeth.
People appear telling us it was
all ours, all so beautiful.
But it wasn't.
There was war, dispute plenty and
little. But it was ours.
And we ended up with nothing.
We moved away.
I even lived in São Paulo.
I went to take marijuana and ended up
working in a brothel in the centre.
But I returned. Why?
Shit!
Where is...
- Where is the fucking ar?
- Outside that house.
You told me to. If we find the
house, we find the fucking car.
Where's the fucking house?
- My mouth is so fuckin dry.
- Everything looks the fucking same!
Calm down! Let's walk.
Let's walk.
Look!
The house! Isn't that the house?
Look.
Look there's the car! Thank fuck!
We just went for a walk.
Our friend, Wedja, she said...
Can you tell us where...
the main road is?
Where are you off to
in such a hurry?
We were there...
We're friends of Jonas.
- Jonas, from the television.
- Stick the television up your arse!
- Stealing marijuana!
- We were just travelling round.
Speak, boy. Little shit.
Hang on. Calm down.
Calm, brother!
Calm down, my arse!
Stealing weed? Aren't you ashamed?
We had no idea anybody
owned it.
Take it easy, man.
Look! How much do you want?
- Calm down.
- I'm not selling anything.
I'd like to get all his money and
shove it right up his fucking arse!
Look at the girl.
Afraid? Good and wet?
Good and wet?
Calm down!
Let's get out of here.
Take it easy!
Throw everything down here.
Everything.
Everything. Come on.
I don't want to see anything left
in your pockets.
The marijuana.
That's good!
Shit!
We didn't fucking do anything!
It's beautiful, isn't it Jonas?
You know...
whoever this land belongs to
has to run away.
Like Jurandir.
It happens.
He has to disappear.
Made a big mistake.
Either he dies or he runs.
Then it'll be Wedja.
That's how we disappear.
We used to be where the water was,
but now we're at its mercy.
We're no longer natives.
Only when they want
to speak badly about us.
We melted away.
But in exchange...
we go on living in your blood.
Evil eye, tuberculosis, fever.
It cures everything.
Even if you don't need it...
it's good to drink it...
it purifies the spirit.
It's immediate?
It depends on the belief.
As long as you believe
in The Old Man's words...
and the power of thought.
Otherwise...
The Old Man only uses this water
for blessing.
He doesn't use it for domestic
purposes, then it's black magic.
I don't know if you understand.
It's out there
and we can't see it.
Not exactly 'see'.
We can't understand it.
This rock. You see?
It's the Dog Rock.
You see?
There's a dog lying down.
Head on one side.
It's really a dog.
See? It was always there.
Even before the dog, the rock
already exists.
I only saw the dog
a long time after.
They used to say,
"There's the Dog Rock!"
And I couldn't see
any fucking dog.
After telling me
it was lying down...
I saw it.
Don't know how I never saw it.
See?
Things are there,
but we don't see them.
You know why? Prejudice.
People only see
what they're allowed to.
Laziness and prejudice.
That's why I like the great
musician Raul Seixas.
I don't like "formed opinions".
Are you better now?
Good.
Look. Over there.
Over there is the elephant.
That was fucking difficult to see.
I just couldn't see it.
I looked and looked.
"An elephant that has disappeared!",
I used to say.
Then one day, after smoking some
of the holy weed...
I managed to see the elephant
sinking into water. See?
The water up to its middle,
and then the trunk. His ear.
A revelation had been made.
I thought to myself...
"If that has always been there
and I never saw it...
then how many other things exist
under our nose like that?"
You must have an open mind
and stay alert.
If we don't watch our step,
we can slip into the imagination.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
It's all yours.
Even if you don't want it.
My dear...
it is and it isn't...
but it is being.
Now, there is a rush to Saturn!
Many are going there.
And they'll stay there.
I'll lock them there.
I have the key...
and I'll use it.
And where are you all going?
To Jupiter.
To drink the mimosa water from lo.
I'll settle...
and stay there waiting
for my next mission.
And what is that?
The return to Chaos...
and the recreation of the universe.
There is no life without
the state of liquid...
and I have the poetry of water.
Jonas.
Five minutes to go.
Jonas!
There are th¡ngs we
do because we want...
Others we do without wanting to.
Anyway you need
to remember that now...
The large dry mass hanging over
the region has begun to move on...
but there is no sign of rain.
The day...
The day will remain hot.
Hello?
They took the fucking lot.
Shit! Fucking everything!
Money, cards...
Blow the fucking lot into space!
- Sons of bitches!
- And Jonas?
We shouldn't have come.
We shouldn't.
Fuck Jonas.
Let's get the fuck out!
- Fucking hell!
- Bob, what's this?
Fucking hell!
He didn't get this one.
- Light it! Light it!
- Blow the fucker up!
Oh Fuck!
Hide it, hide it. Give it to me.
Stop the car.
- Hi! Sorry! It's just that...
- Pull over.
- We're pulling over.
- We're going to Recife.
We'll park here.
- On the left.
- Why did we have to come here?
Stop.
- Get out.
- Yes, sir.
- Let's get moving now.
- We're getting out.
Out.
Lean over there.
Open your legs.
The look is the light
that comes from the eye.
They killed Jurandir,
Jonas!
It's over, Jonas.
Lázaro is in peace, now.
Killed him like a dog,
and it's nothing to do with you?
Are you crazy, Jonas?
I never saw anything like it.
His father dies and the same day
he's sleeping with the slut.
Didn't even let the body get cold.
Hail Maria,
crazy as a plague of dogs.
Even got to be
Zé Elétrico's friend.
You knew he was hiding Jurandir?
It's not good. Not good.
Is it true, Zé Elétrico?
Did they really kill Jurandir?
I knew you'd hide that
good-for-nothing. Lying bastard!
We have to stay alive.
He's not a problem any more.
It's my fault.
My fault!
I knew Jurandir wouldn't
accept me going with Lázaro.
It's not your fault.
Things happen.
Some things make sense,
others no. This makes no sense.
Everything makes sense.
This gun was Lázaro's favourite.
Use it well?
Nothing. No.
I don't want to leave.
Really, Zé Elétrico!
Every time the same.
Always saying you don't know.
I smoke and I know all about it.
You've got to decide.
Time to finish with all this.
Jonas?
What's going on?
Jonas! Jonas!
Killed the native
and now he's high!
You know that when he was drunk,
Lázaro imitated you on television?
Let's finish with all this!
Ah! Feliciano.
How I enjoy our meetings.
Everything here
is getting sorted out.
You know how long
these things take.
Slowly, but steadily things
get sorted.
And they're going well.
The cotton plantations
are enormous.
Did you know...
that cotton is the most important
image of Jesus Christ on earth?
The drought and the lush.
The drought
and the vegetable garden.
I did know.
And I am happy that
all is going well.
Well, I'll leave you now.
God be with you.
Feliciano, make this boy a man.
He has much to learn about life.
It's good to learn early...
because the longer you leave it
the harder it is.
God bless you, Jonas.
My grandson.
What are you laughing at, Jucão?
Something funny?
So...
We haven't kept you too long,
have we?
I've stayed longer than I should.
But Luquinha has agreed
on Salustiano for mayor.
And the land?
That's what really worries me, not
the man sitting at the town hall.
What do you mean?
What are you on about?
- Of course we're worried about that.
- And the land?
I've arranged my part.
All is going well.
What worries me
is the fucking native village.
- Will they stay there?
- Don't worry.
The boys will stay looking
after the marijuana.
They'll get a provisional deed
in exchange for work.
- After we'll see what to do.
- We always have to combine...
power and intelligence.
I don't really know
where intelligence comes in.
It's more about power and luck.
If you get bad luck,
you're fucked.
Take no notice, Feliciano.
He's like that.
Only learns the hard way.
But with the grace of God...
he'll learn what you should do
with power and intelligence.
- Let's get going?
- Yes.
I must get back to Recife today.
Did you talk to The Old Man?
Yes. There's no problem.
- Did you send the water truck there?
- No. But this week it'll go.
Don't worry. He was a bit upset.
He was running out of miracle water.
Tell him to be calm,
We'll send the water.
Do you know what they did
with the Galileo probe?
What?
Threw it into the atmosphere
of Jupiter.
At least they had the intelligence
not to pollute lo.
Intelligence or care?
Care!
Here on earth they never had that.
That's true.
You know that from penal colony
in the universe...
we'll become a penal colony
in the Milky Way.
But...
- what is lo?
- You don't know?
It's our address tomorrow.
EXCESS OF INFORMATION,
LACK OF WATER
What's he doing?
I don't know...
but when he finishes,
something is going to happen.
Ripeados por Tylerg
Visita www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar