JYP's...
- Party People!- Party People!
These artists will sing a duetfor the first time on TV.
You know that, right?
(Baek Z Young and Gummy'sduet performance)
("You Are My Everything"by Gummy and Baek Z Young)
(The collaborative performance wasa treat to the ears.)
Thank you.
(The queens of vocalists,Z Young and Gummy)
(JYP's Party People isfor the viewers who drink alone.)
Our initials are JYP.
- JYP.- I was so surprised.
- What a rare coincidence!- I know.
Shall we have a toastfor our initials?
When we clink our glasses,we should say, "JYP". Let's go.
JYP.
- You should have whispered it.- I am sorry.
The two of you sanga lot of OSTs for dramas.
That's right.
("The Woman")
("Don't Forget")
("Love Is Over")
("You Are My Everything")
("Snow Flower")
("Love You Forever")
There are hit songs...
that bring back memoriesof the dramas when I hear them.
Which ones are the mostmemorable to you?
There is an OST I sang...
that almost went to Z Young.
It's "Because It's You".
Z Young was supposed...
to sing the song...
for a drama, "Iris".
Originally,"Because It's You"...
- It was an OST for "Iris".- It was an OST for "Iris"...
- with Z Young as the singer.- That's right.
That's right.
Then "Don't Forget" wouldn'thave been released.
These behind stories areinteresting.
- They really are.- That's right.
Shall we listento "Because It's You"?
I want to listen to it.
("Because It's You" by Gummy)
It brings back memories.
You told me about this song...
- in the past.- I think I did.
(The song brought good fortuneto both of them.)
(OST for the SBS drama,"Will It Snow for Christmas?")
("Because It's You" by Gummy)
My goodness.
(Her enchanting voice captivatesthe audience in no time.)
Listening to her up close wasa bewitching experience.
It was lovely.
Had the song been sung...
by Z Young,
it would have hada completely different feel to it.
(What would Z young's"Because It's you" like?)
("Because It's You"by Baek Z Young)
It was great.
- I seriously can't decide...- You could have sung it.
which version is better.
The two of you havedifferent styles.
Even though you sang for a moment,it sounded sorrowful.
- We should release a song together.- We really should.
Please write us a song.
- You will sing it together?- Yes, we will.
- We really will.- I am still in a daze.
Now that we got started,
we should listen to "Don't Forget".
Please sing it.
(She got "Don't Forget"instead of "Because It's You".)
All right, everyone.
Do you have your drink with you?
This is a songthat calls for a drink.
Do you have your drink ready?
("Don't Forget"by Baek Z Young)
(He is speechless.)
(Had Z Young sung"Because It's You",)
("Don't Forget" wouldn'thave come to be.)
- It's really nice.- I have so many goosebumps...
that I could turn into a gooseby the end of the program.
Her voice calls for soju.
Do you have soju?
(JYP's Party People isfor the viewers who drink alone.)
At JYP's Party People,
there is The Theme Song of My Life.
Gummy, is there a song...
- There is a song.- that is special to you?
It's a song of mine.
I was a trainee for seven years.
Back in my days,there wasn't a set system...
for the trainees.
- We had to train by ourselves.- That's right.
I endured the difficult timesand debuted.
I was determined to showmy talent upon my debut.
However, I had vocal cord nodulesas soon as I debuted.
I couldn't performat music programs.
I felt bad for my agency.
I was scared thatI might not be able to sing again.
It was a difficult time.
I even thought about taking...
a different path.
And I struggled a lotbecause it came...
with a financial problem.
It's scary. It really is.
Thinking about takinga different job...
brings tears to our eyes.
I can't imagine takinga different job.
Sometimes, artists say,
"I will singas long as there is one person..."
"who listens to my songs."
An employee at the agency said,
"It will be sadif I can't hear your songs."
My fans also cheered me on.
Listening to them made me think,
"I shouldn't be like this."
That's when I began to train again.
I started from the beginning.
I changed my vocalization a lot.
I wasn't completely healed...
when I recorded the second album.
The title song was "Memory Loss".
- Really?- Yes.
The agency was against it.
Thankfully, the song...
- made me okay.- It did?
You might not understand, but...
Please give us some tissues.
It's okay. I held back my tears.
(Gummy's The Theme Song of My Life)
("Memory Loss" kept her dreamof becoming a singer.)
That happened.
It was a desperate dream...
- that you pursued for seven years.- Yes.
When you felt likeeverything had ended,
this song led you back...
- to your dream.- Yes.
(It made her practice singingonce again.)
(That's why "Memory Loss" isso precious to her.)
Thank you.
I love this song. My goodness.
("Memory Loss" by Gummy)
That was the song. Thank you.
(Gummy sang the songwith despair and hope.)
It's incredible to hear yousing the song up close.
- It's so nice.- Thank you.
After that experience,
I realized how arrogant I wasto think about quitting.
There are artistswho struggle more than me.
I can relate to Gummy's words.
As you know, many things happenedafter I debuted.
What was good at first isn't...
always good in the end.
What was bad at first isn't...
always bad in the end.
- That's right.- It's important to get used to it.
You need to get used to it.
This is your chance...
to get drunk and sleepon a Saturday night.
Gummy and Z Young will sing a duet.
Are you ready?
(Z Young and Gummy's duet couldn'tbe better for fall.)
(JYP's Party Peoplewith EXO is coming up.)
("The Woman"by Baek Z Young and Gummy)
("The Woman" is a ballad OSTabout a woman in love.)
(JYP's Party Peoplewith EXO is coming up.)
- Party People!- Party People!
Everyone, this group isthe symbol of an idol group...
not only in Korea,but also all around the world.
It's EXO!
(The center of idol groupsall around the world, EXO)
(They received Grand Award5 years in a row.)
(Their albums became million sellers4 years in a row.)
(They placed 1st onKorean music programs 100 times.)
(EXO is the symbol of K-Popall over the world.)
All right.
EXO is a groupthat doesn't need explanations.
Your newest song is "Power".
- Yes.- Your newest album...
sold million copies once again.
I don't know how to explainthis incredible feat.
It has happenedwith all four of your albums.
Yes, it did.
That's right.It happened four years in a row.
("EXO's 1st album becomesa million seller")
("EXO's 2nd album becomesa million seller")
("EXO makes a recordwith 3 million sellers")
("EXO comes to have4 million sellers with "The War"")
All 4 of your regular albums soldover 1,000,000 copies.
Did the fact hit you?
To be honest,
it doesn't hit uswhen we hear about it.
It doesn't show onour account balances right away.
(He can relate to it.)
First, EXO seems a bitout of place here.
It's strange to see EXO in the club.
Have you watched this program?
(Do they knowabout JYP's Party People?)
- Yes, we have.- There is a fan.
- Really? Who is it?- Xiumin.
Xiumin is a fan.
- Really?- Yes.
When I am alone at home,I turn on the TV...
and drink lightly.
It feels great.
This program was madefor people like that.
- I guess it suited your taste.- Yes. I enjoy watching it.
All right.
It will be a special night...
in which you can enjoydrinking with EXO.
- That's lovely.- I came up...
with a special for today.
The Real EXO Special.
(The Real EXO Special)
You have seen EXO...
on the stage as well asin music videos and concerts.
Today, EXO will be up close as if...
they were your boyfriends.
(Let's study the real EXO.)
(Who is the most charming member?)
(JYP's Party People)
Please introduce yourself.
Don't talk about your positionin the group.
- Talk about who you really are.- Okay.
I feel like I am in a group date.
Who do you think will be the bestat introducing himself?
- Su Ho.- That's right.
- Let's start with the leader.- Okay.
I am Su Ho.
(The leader, Su Ho.)
The one who looks likea model student in EXO,
it's me, Su Ho.
(He looks bright.)
I am well-knownfor having a face...
that would receive approvalfrom a woman's parents.
My future fiance's parents willapprove of me right away.
- He has a nerve.- That's right.
- He really has it.- That's right.
My name is Xiumin.
I am 28 years old.
Well...
I have cute and young looks.
I like to drink.
(Xiumin, A man who has cuteand young looks and likes to drink.)
I am a boy-next-door.Thank you.
Hello, I am Byun Baek Hyun.
No one else in the world hasthis name.
I am incredibly chatty.
They say I have many talents.
I would like to play the piano.
(The piano?)
Please wait.I have to check the chords.
(The talented Baek Hyun will givea piano performance.)
So that's how the chords start.
Let's go. Let's go.Let's go right away.
("The Moon of Seoul" by Kim Gun Mo)
(He looks like he is singingfor his girlfriend.)
(Baek Hyun gavea sweet live performance.)
Thank you.
I was born between my father,Kim Ho Dae...
and my mother, Yeom Soon Mi.
I am the second son, Chen.
(The second son of Siheung, Chen)
I love to sing the most.
I always want to show my diligence.
Chen is very kind.
The fans call him Kim Kind.
(His kind nature earned himthe nickname of Kim Kind.)
Hello.
My name, Chan Yeol, means"A ripe fruit".
I am full of passion.
Ever since I was young,I grew up with musical instruments.
I play drums, guitar, bass,and piano.
You must've loved musicsince you were a kid.
Do you know whyI started learning the drums?
I saw an older boyplaying the drum game at an arcade.
I thought it was so cool...
that I startedtaking lessons in sixth grade.
Can we hear you play a bit?
(Since it's the EXO special...)
- Give him a round of applause.- Let's go!
Let's go, Chan Yeol.
(Random Live Performanceby Chan Yeol)
Now that we're half way through,
I feel like I'm observing you asyou each introduce yourselves.
I feel like I'm on a blind datewith you today.
The female viewers must beexcited today.
So who's next?
Hello, I'm D.O.
(D.O was born in 1993.)
I'm a normal guy who'senjoying life in his 20s.
There's nothing specialI'm talented at.
He's a good actor,so he's being modest.
Also, D.O is a talented singerand a great dancer.
He's also good at acting...
which makes himan irreplaceable member.
Is he normally this shy?
- Yes.- Always.
Contrary to what people think,D.O is very humorous.
He doesn't joke very often,
but he's hysterical when he does.
I'd love to see that oncebefore the end of today's show.
We should at least knowwhat you mean by his funny bone.
- It'll be a challenge.- He's right.
- If he does though...- Consider yourselves lucky.
Out of the eight of you,
who's the most seriousand who's the most lighthearted?
It's D.O and Baek Hyun.
- These two.- Yes, them.
They say opposites attract,so do you get along well?
- How are you two?- We're very close.
He tells me whenI should stop fooling around.
If I go too far,D.O hits me in the back of my neck.
So that's when I stop.
- You two are special to each other.- That's right.
Hello, I'm Kai of EXO.
(Kai, 26)
As you can tell,I'm quite tall and...
(Embarrassed)
- I bet you're embarrassed.- I am.
To be honest, he surprised mewhen he just introduced himself.
When he's on stage dancing,he can't be ruder or more arrogant.
- You know what I mean.- He's very charismatic.
He dances as if he'slooking down on everyone.
- He thinks he's the best.- Right.
You really are a phenomenal dancer.I was surprised at first.
- Really?- When he introduced himself though,
he seemed very shy.
Is he always like that?
He's like a sweet girl backstage.
- That's right.- He's quiet and shy.
(He becomes quiet and shythe soon as he walks off the stage.)
Lastly, it's our youngest Se Hun.
Hello, I'm Oh Se Hun,the youngest member of EXO.
There's a maturity to him though.
(Still, he's the youngest.)
As the youngest member,
which of the other sevendo you find most scary?
I'm actually afraid of all of them.
Liar!
- No way.- He's making us look bad.
- He's trying to play the victim.- What's the matter?
He's lying.
Yes, it's a lie.
He's very mischievous.
He's also super adorable as well.
He loves to drink nearlyas much as Xiumin does.
(Really?)
He's friendly and very loyal.
Se Hun, when do you wantto have a drink?
When I'm happy or sad...
- Always and every day.- I love sharing.
You want to drink when...
you feel joy, anger,sorrow, and pleasure.
(Se Hun loves todrink at all times.)
Where do younormally have drinks then?
We drink a lot togetherback at our house.
After a concert abroador an award ceremony,
we'd regather after dinner...
back in my room.
My room ends up a mess.
We feel most comfortablemessing up his room.
(Su Ho's the best for everything.)
- You've been singers for six years.- Right.
I'm sure there have been moments...
where one or all of youlost your focus.
How do you regroupwhen that happens?
We've never gotteninto a fist fight...
nor have everraised our voices and argued.
That's possible because...
none of us show our angerright on the spot.
We'd all keep to ourselves first,
and then address each otherover a few drinks later on.
When we do,
we're brutally honest.
We'd lay out everythingthat we had bottled up inside.
- I learned how petty we can be.- We say things like this.
We seem to rememberevery little incident.
This is what I think of our dynamic.
There are some people...
who can't take beingcriticized of their actions.
Normally, we get angry.
What's great aboutour members is...
that everybody is willing to listenand take constructive criticism.
Out of you all,who is worst at taking it?
- When notified of flaws...- It's Su Ho.
It's Su Ho.
(He gives up.)
- Isn't he the leader?- I'm not being funny.
Su Ho is a man of great pride,
so he sometimes doesn't admit...
that he's wrong.
Before you said that,I thought Su Ho was perfect.
All right.
So as I was puttingtogether today's show,
there was one thingI really wanted you to do.
I wanted to hearyou sing in real life.
Not as singers on stage,
but as young men who arejust singing next to us.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
- Yes.- Yes!
("Call Me Baby" by EXO)
(Just with the guitarand their voices,)
(the song brings them closer to us.)
I loved that. I've neverheard you like this before.
Don't you feel likeyou're closer to them now?
- Yes.- Yes.
That was really great.Is there another song you can sing?
(One more please)
Is there any other song?
(They suddenly sing the song,"Creep", which is a song...)
(Korean boyfriends love to sing.)
(The real live EXO singsan acoustic cover of the song.)
(This very special moment)
(The late night datewith EXO will continue)
(Party People, Fall Night with EXO)
Today, we're meeting EXO asyoung men that they are.
When we meet youin real life though,
you'll sing songssince you're still singers.
When we're on dates though,
- we usually don't sing our songs.- Of course not.
- It's too weird.- We can't sing "Growl".
So if you're...
"Growl"?
No matter how romanticallyyou make it sound,
you can't change its lyrics.
- Of course not.- Right.
It'd be funny if you sang it though.
(What if they sang "Growl"to their real-life girlfriend?)
(It'd be weird.)
Let's imagine that you'reon a date with your girlfriend.
When you someday meet someone,
which song would you sing?
Is there one you enjoy singing?
(Please, no.They should never date.)
They don't like the ideaof us dating.
They can't be alone all their lives.
(They're still against it.)
What about when they're 40?
(No!)
- No?- What about at 50?
What do you say to 50?
Should they live alone forever?
We'll date right before we die then.
My gosh.
- When they're at retirement homes.- At retirement homes?
Okay, we'll agree on that then.
(They can only date when they'reat retirement homes.)
At a retirement home...
(What would you sing as a serenadeat a retirement home?)
Let's say that you ran intoyour first love.
At a retirement home?
What will you singto this old friend?
- She's old too so...- That they approve of.
- What about my age- What about my age
- It's the perfect age to love- It's the perfect age to love
Everybody, cha cha cha
What would you like to sing?
("Gashina"!)
- "Gashina".- "Gashina" by Sun Mi.
"Gashina"?
(How could you leave meat a retirement home?)
Who is best atgirl group choreography?
- It's Su Ho?- Why would you say that?
I'm not good at all.
(He keeps pointingat Su Ho for everything.)
Should we see him danceto a girl group's song?
Shy shy shy? That I can do.
As I met a friend, shy shy shy
My goodness.
Dance to "Red Flavor".
I can't.
You're dressed in red,so you should.
(Baek Hyun's logic)
(The vivacious"Red Flavor" by Red Velvet)
(How will Su Ho dance to the song?)
I really can't do this.
(He does his best.)
(They're satisfied.)
- That was adorable.- You're quite good.
- That was amazing.- No, it was not!
You did great.
Who else has a favorite song?
- Chen.- To be honest,
there's a song that I've hadon my playlist for years.
The song that I never replace is...
"Sunday Morning" by Maroon 5.
(Chen's favorite song is"Sunday Morning" by Maroon 5.)
Here we are with EXO today,and Chen will sing next.
Please give him a round of applause.
(The sweet Chen bringsyou this song on Saturday.)
(Chen sings "Sunday Morning"accompanied by the band.)
("Sunday Morning" by Maroon 5)
(A sweet song on this fall night)
Nice.
That was amazing.
You were great.
You proved just howgood of a singer you are.
(It proved just how good he is.)
How can we notfall in love with you after that?
If there's one thing that Koreasuccessfully exported,
- it's K-pop.- That's right.
Idol singers areat the center of it,
and EXO is the leading group.
Something strange has beengoing on recently.
Among global fans,
the Ko Ko Bop Challenge hasbecome a thing.
In the Philippines,even the vice president joined in.
- Really?- Yes, it happened.
(The Ko Ko Bop Challenge isa globally spreading act...)
(of people filming videosof them dancing to "Ko Ko Bop".)
(A former vice presidentalso joined in the fun.)
Before we knew it,it became a widespread challenge.
It was even featured on the newsin America and Argentina.
We took a look at it...
and we were quite flusteredby the whole thing at first.
We've always wantedto express our gratitude.
If I'm being honest...
I don't know ifthis an appropriate term,
but in this industry,
we say that you got lucky.
Yes, it's exactly that.
It happened to me too.
I had no idea that"shy shy shy" would be a hit.
It was just a line in the songbut suddenly,
people became infatuated with it.
This challenge is alsovery similar in that way.
Shouldn't we seethe original artist of the song...
participate in the challenge too?
(How will it look whenit's done by the original artist?)
Let me lay out the situation.
The viewers are probablyin bed ready to sleep.
They're sipping beer when...
(He has intriguedthose already in bed.)
That's how it should be.
- It needs to be easy to follow.- Sure.
First, you start with a jump.
(The choreography thatmesmerized the world)
(1. Move your body back and forth.)
(2. Spread your arms like so.)
That's how the original goes.
(I see.)
That's the choreography,
but it's like this...
in the challenge.
(They shake their bodies more.)
Like this.
You have to bedoing something else...
and dance when the hook starts.
- Suddenly.- Yes, that's how it should be.
So keep that in mind as you dance.
The same goes toeveryone in the audience too.
You should be preoccupied...
and then suddenly dancewhen the hook starts.
We'll film that andpost in on social media.
Let's all participate in this.
(Ko Ko Bop Challenge,the worldwide phenomenon)
(Ko Ko Bop Challengeat Party People)
(They all seem preoccupied.)
(This isn't even his cell.)
(The host of Party People)
(Even Jin Young participates.)
- Let's play rock-paper-scissors.- Winner can flick one on the loser.
Rock-paper-scissors.
(They play rock-paper-scissors.)
(The best actor of the bunch.)
Chen, what's on your mind?
(Only he dances at double speed.)
Finally, we can post a video...
of EXO participatingin the Ko Ko Bop Challenge.
It's been six yearssince your debut.
Is there a momentthat you still remember?
Yes, our first showcase.
That day,
the first songwe sang was "History".
(They debuted by singing "History".)
- It was the first time on stage.- We were facing back...
and waiting for the song to start.
(They still can't forgetthe thrill of that day.)
I still can't forgetthe thrill of that day.
Later on, in life when I grow old...
and have kids...
(He tries to be sentimental.)
Well...
(Kids?)
I'm talking about my imaginary kids.
So my kids...
You agreed that he could dateat a retirement home.
If my kid asks when wasthe best time...
in my life...
Let's say...
that my dog finallylearned how to talk.
His barking can now be translated.
When my dog asksabout the best time in my life,
I'll tell him...
that it was whenI first debuted as a singer.
That's what I'll say.
You've been in the industryfor six years.
Who trained the longest?
- Su Ho.- Su Ho.
For how long?
Six and a half years.
You trained for 6.5 years andyou've been a singer for 6 years.
- That's right.- That's 13 years.
- So for nearly 13 years...- That's right.
You've been doing thisfor nearly 13 years.
There are so many restrictions.
You can't relax that easily,
and you can'tsimply go out for drinks...
with your friends.
You have to be carefulin every aspect...
and many restrictions follow.
I do imagine thatit'll be stressful...
though I've never livedthat life before.
So what or who comforts youwhen you're feeling down?
In my case, I travel a lot.
I guess I want to be free.Since many recognize me though,
I tend to go on travel...
somewhere far away from Korea.
That's how I relieve my stress.I also talk to my teammates,
listen to a lot of music,and watch many movies.
Is there a song thatyou find comfort in?
"I Want to Fall in Love".
("I Want to Fall in Love"by Kim Jo Han)
- I can relate a lot to the lyrics.- I see.
It's definitely how I'd feel.
You see...
(Su Ho can relate to"I Want to Fall in Love".)
I work out, I do my work,
and see movies on weekends.
- That's how the lyrics go.- Right.
I go to book stores...
and see if there areany good books to read.
I buy them only toleave them on my bookshelf.
(They're for decoration.)
- Are you decorating?- Exactly.
You're like the protagonistin the song.
Could we perhaps hearyou sing this song?
Come on.
My goodness.
(The Theme Song of My Life)
("I Want to Fall in Love" by Su Ho)
("I Want to Fall in Love"by Su Ho)
(Su Ho sang the songfrom the bottom of his heart.)
Thank you.
You sounded so sincere just now.
It must've been becauseyou feel this way too.
This song...
After our concerts,
I'm sometimes in a stateof despondency.
That's how I'd feel,
but having my teammates...
and our fans really help.
(He has his teammates and his fans.)
That's why I enjoy this life.
(Su Ho enjoys his life.)
(He's happy at this moment,thanks to his fans.)
While filming today's show,I suddenly got curious.
Whenever I look at D.O,it seems like he has...
a lot he wants to say.
Are you restrainingyourself from talking...
or do you really don't want to talk?
Which is it?
- The former.- Is it?
You do have something to say.
So during your six yearsin the industry,
what do you remember the most?
(What made thebiggest impact on him?)
There isn't anythingthat I specially remember.
(He's unpredictable.)
Are you sure?
- Everything is memorable.- That must be.
You probably aren't ableto name just one.
Tell me at least you have one.
Well, you see...
I don't like to add meaningsto specific events.
(He's being honest for 100 percent.)
That's why I...
Do you hate me for what I said?
This is all becauseI'm not good with words.
Let me ask you...
about your life asan insanely popular idol singer.
Does it suit you...
or does it sometimes go againstwho you truly are?
I do find myselfnot fitting in a lot.
(The life of fame doesn'talways suit him.)
I'm in my 20s,
and it's difficultnot being able to...
walk down the streetwithout being recognized.
That's how I feel.
I thought about quittingmany times too.
I'm trying to be honest here.
Everyone will probablysay the same thing.
Life isn't easy no matterwho you are and what you do.
(Everyone in their 20s will feelthe same way.)
Being with my teammates iswhat keeps me going I guess.
I feel the same way.In fact, we're all the same.
We just have a slightlydifferent job than others.
One that's different, not special.
We receive huge amountsof love and support,
and it's our job...
to know how to give back that love.
Being loved this much by someone...
and to have so many peoplethink of me are...
something to truly be grateful for.
So thinking about that...
gives me the strengthto keep going on as an artist.
Whenever I feel downor doubt myself recently,
I think about how I'm blessedto have this kind of job.
(The 6th-year boy band...)
(expresses their gratitudeto their fans.)
(The Theme Song of My Life)
("Hug Me" by Chan Yeol)
I'll leave it at that.Thank you.
(He sings of how deeplygrateful he is to his fans.)
Now, it's time to talk aboutyour new single "Power".
(Their single went platinumfor the 4th time.)
With "Power",
we wish to give our fansa surge of energy.
(They wish to bring them energy.)
We make this shape with our arma lot during the song.
(They incorporated this movea lot in their choreography.)
We drew inspiration from the gym...
in terms of arm workouts,
back workouts, and push-ups.
We all workout at the gym,so we do the bodybuilder pose too.
- D.O, you should show them.- What a great idea.
(We got that power)
(We're now stronger)
You should incorporatethose moves in the song today.
We'll change up the choreography.
Since this isan exclusive performance,
we'll see them perform "Power"...
with the bodybuilder pose in it.
("Power" by EXO)
(A song about howthey can be stronger...)
(by joining forces withtheir fans through music.)
(Only on Party People)
(It's the bodybuildercover of "Power".)
What I'm about to say can bea bit scary.
New Kids on the Block,The Backstreet Boys,
H.O.T, and g.o.d.
There were many boy bandsin this world,
but none of them were ableto stay at the top forever.
It's practically impossible.
Many people are still biasedwhen it comes to boy bands.
It's the same with the fans.
Many draw a linebetween being a fan...
of an artist or a boy band.
Fans of boy bandsor girl groups are called...
groupies, which isa derogatory term.
(Idols and their fans arelooked down upon.)
To be honest though,
I don't want our fansto be called that way.
I want us to be the oneswho shatter those opinions.
You need to move from just beingpopular to earning recognition.
It's easier said than done though.
It's tough.It's really tough.
You not only have to be talented,
but you must convincethose who are biased too.
Your popularity might go up or down,
but earned recognition issomewhat permanent.
Once you're recognized as an artist,
you can stay relevant forever.
I believe in myselfand my teammates.
Our fans will always have our backs,
so we'll get there too.
You're really sweet.
I'm trying to thinkof another adjective,
but that suits you the most.
You'll be able to reach your goal...
with this levelof teamwork and trust.
EXO's rival is EXO from last year.
(EXO's rival isalways EXO from last year.)
So today,
you met with EXO.
Now, they'll bring youan exclusive performance...
of "Boomerang".Please give it up for EXO.
("Boomerang" by EXO)
Thank you.