She's much better now, Jeff.
- I was scared to
death when I brought her in.
Thank God it's all over.
Guess, I should thank you, Doctor.
- She still needs
a lot of understanding
and love and, of course, time.
She's cured, isn't she?
- Well, that's a word
psychiatry doesn't throw around
the way we used to.
Cynthia may feel there are
still some things she needs
to take care of by herself.
But right now, being home
with you will do more good
than any psychiatrist.
- I'm thinking of taking
her on a little trip
back to the islands.
We had our honeymoon
there, and she loved it.
Sounds fine.
Try and keep her around people
she feels comfortable with.
We both want another baby, Doctor.
Cynthia.
You look good.
Thanks, I feel good.
- Okay, okay,
okay, who has the table?
Come on you guys, let's move it.
Sorry.
- Come on, girls.
- Are you all right?
I guess so.
- Here.
- All right.
- There you go.
- Here, you take this.
What the hell is this?
Need a beer.
Okay, who gets the cooler?
I'm sorry.
Oh, don't tell me we're going in that.
Give us a hand, would you?
- Hey, you gonna fly
this thing, Lindbergh?
No, I'm gonna fly it.
- Oh, you're gonna fly it.
- Yeah.
Here's the beer.
Paul, grab that line up there, will you?
It's gonna take me a
while to fix this thing.
Paul?
Yeah.
- Why don't you find a
place we can pitch a tent?
We'll probably be here for the night.
Okay.
Wanna help get the gear unloaded?
Give him a hand, Rob.
Paul, you want some coffee?
Hey, campers.
Hi.
I got coffee.
Oh, yeah, you got some good stuff there.
What's up?
I just can't figure it out.
There's power there, but the
instruments won't respond.
There's nothing I can do
now until the morning.
That's all right, gang.
We'll just stay here instead
of Jackson Island, right?
Yeah, well, where the hell is here?
I'd like to know I could get off one day.
- It's okay, I've packed
enough food to last weeks.
- Yeah, well, I'd still like
to know when I could get off.
Honey, honey, honey, don't worry.
We'll get you off.
Yeah!
Music, all right.
Woods are woods.
Come on, gang, it ain't that bad is it?
Come on, gang.
You're nuts, man.
Well, guys, I'm gonna go scuba diving.
Who wants to come?
No, I'm gonna take a look around.
Paul, you coming?
Forget it, honey.
I gotta sleep it off, okay?
You wanna go, Rob?
I only dive for muff, sweetheart.
You catch it, I'll cook it.
All right.
Cynth, you wanna go?
Sure.
How's it going?
Not good.
Electrical burnout.
Radio's out.
Nothing's workin'.
Stay right there.
You be good, you be good.
Cynthia?
Jeff?
Oh, can you hang on a second?
Hang on.
Hey, Cynthia.
Why the hell didn't you help her?
She could've drowned.
No!
She's dead.
It's my fault.
It's my fault!
No, Cynthia, she's okay.
I'm okay.
She's all right, Terri's all right.
She's all right.
Come on, come on.
Water in the wrong tube.
It's okay.
She's okay.
Are you crazy?
Don't ever do that again.
Hey, lighten up.
- Something moved in
those bushes back there.
Right over there.
Scared the hell out of me.
Probably a deer.
Some kinda little animal.
Maybe even a bird.
I wanna go back.
Hi, guys.
What happened?
- Terri fell off the
rocks and into the water.
She's okay.
Just shook up a little bit, that's all.
Yeah, I'm all right.
- So what's the situation
with the plane, Jeff?
I can't fix it.
I think we better check out this island,
see what we can find.
Oh, great.
- Paul, you stay here and
keep an eye on the plane
until we get back.
All right.
Hey, you guys, look at this.
Come on.
Oh boy, this looks like fun.
Think anyone lives here?
Gives me the creeps.
Anybody home?
Hello?
Maybe there's a phone inside.
Wanna try?
Oh my God.
- Geez, it's like we just
walked into the 1920s.
Look at this place.
Hey, look at this.
My grandfather had one of these.
I used to listen to it all the time.
You think it works?
All right.
Hey, toots, you're the cat's pajamas.
What's say we cut a rug?
Thought you'd never ask.
Al Jolson eat your heart out.
Oh, wow.
Hey you, guys, look at this dress.
- Wow.
- Mary Pickford wore one
just like it in Little Annie Rooney.
- That's neat.
- Look what I found.
One for you, one for me,
and now we're cookin'.
Oh no, this is me.
What do you think, huh?
All right.
Now we're cookin'.
Oh yeah?
Take me home.
Color coordinated.
All right.
Don't tape this.
Oh yeah?
Is that right?
- Hey, you guys, I think
we better take it easy, huh?
That's all right, children.
Been meanin' to get rid
of them old things anyhow.
We're sorry.
We kinda messed things up.
We'll pay for anything that's broken.
- Say, young man, that
scarf suits you real well.
I have a good mind to give
you one for your very own.
Well, thanks, it's really very nice.
Knitted 'em all myself, you know.
- Like I was saying, we're
really sorry for the mess,
and if you'd let us pay...
- Oh, now, now, that's
nothin' to make a fuss over.
You was just havin' some fun, that's all.
Don't cry over spilled
milk is what I always say.
- You haven't old us
where you folks came from.
From Seattle, sir.
We had trouble with our plane.
We had to put it on the beach.
Do you have a phone we could use?
Or any gas you could spare?
I don't believe in those contraptions.
However, I got a friend's
comin' around tomorrow morning.
Maybe he can do somethin'.
This the whole passle of ya?
Yeah.
Yeah, this is it.
My name's Jeff, and this is Terri.
Hi.
And Rob and Lynn.
And there's Paul, he's
back with the plane.
And Cynthia.
Oh yeah.
Where is she, anyway?
She's down there.
Down the stairs.
Oh God, Jeff, don't do that.
- Take it easy.
- You scared me.
Come on upstairs.
The people that live here just walked in.
Have you seen this room?
It's incredible.
It's a child's room,
but everything in it's about 50 years old.
Yeah, it's weird, all right.
I'd say they're a little
on the eccentric side.
Yeah.
Come on, they're waitin' for us.
Okay.
Hey, this looks great, Ma.
I'm glad you like it.
Don't you guys have any real names,
like Jones or somethin'?
Ma and Pa suits us just fine.
We don't set much store
by fancy manners up here.
Child.
Lord, we thank thee for the blessings
we are about to receive and
the food upon this table.
And we pray in the future
they will be the same,
that thou will bless the table.
And we eat now in the name
of Jesus Christ our Lord.
Amen.
- Young lady, I can't abide
the wastin' of good food.
Now, let's see you wipe the platter clean
like your friends done.
Don't you want to be in
the clean plate club?
Clean plate club?
I need a drink.
- You know, this is a real
nice place you have here,
but don't you miss not having electricity
and television and things?
Ma, do me a favor.
Let me have some whipped potatoes.
Why sure, Pa.
- Do you guys have a radio
or anything like that?
Must be hard to keep up with the news.
Did you know they sent an
exploratory rocket to Mars?
It's gonna be there in a couple weeks,
and then they're gonna...
- Young man, if you keep
tellin' stories like that,
your nose is gonna grow
longer than a broomstick.
Stories?
That's not a story.
You know, they've landed on the moon.
Pa, think it's gonna rain?
I don't know.
It was a little misty,
but I think it'll clear up before evenin'.
How 'bout you, Lynn?
Think it'll rain.
Rain, I don't know.
Who cares?
Just a minute, young lady.
There's no smokin' in this house.
Nice young lady don't smoke.
If you're a victim of tobacco,
then take your vice
and indulge it outside.
Fine.
Well, if everyone's done, I'll clean up.
Bad girl.
Now, now, you leave that to me.
Oh, there's nothin' down there
that would interest you, child.
In fact, I should've
locked it up long ago.
- That goes to the cellar,
and them steps is very steep.
Besides, it's cold as
the grave down there.
That's cold.
Better have one of Ma's scarves
before you go down there.
- You go on back to your
dancin' if you like.
I just love to watch young
folk doin' the new steps.
You know the Charleston?
Well, you're welcome to spend the night.
Hi.
It's gorgeous isn't it?
What's happening in there?
Ma's making coffee.
Hey, look at that.
A child's skipping rope.
That's weird.
You know that room I
went down into before?
Yeah.
That was full of kids' toys too.
Hey, that's Mary Pickford.
Yeah.
There's that cradle I told you about.
Please don't wake my baby.
Hello.
My name's Fanny, what's yours?
I'm Lynn.
This is Cynthia.
Hello.
My baby's been very ill,
and she needs her rest.
Oh, well, hope she gets better.
- Oh, she's all better now,
but she's still quite tired.
Ma says it's important for little girls
to get their 40 winks.
I go to bed every night at
nine o'clock, except sometimes
Pa let's me stay up late
to play with my dollies.
- There'll be no dollies
for you tonight, young lady.
Time you got ready for bed.
Yes, Ma.
Has Fanny been a good girl,
or has she been sassin' anybody?
No, she's been just fine.
Good.
Well, she's got a birthday comin' up.
Guess you can always count
on a youngin' to behave
when party time rolls around.
- I'm gonna be 12, and I'm
gonna have a birthday party.
- Yep, and if you're
really, really good, well,
you might just get a brand new dolly.
Oh, goody.
Now, that's enough chattering.
Bye, Miss Lynn, Miss Cynthia.
Land sakes, that child can be a caution.
As the saying goes, when she's
good, she's very, very good.
But when she's bad...
She's gotta be at least 50.
Don't you think so, Cynthia?
- Wait a minute, she
thinks she's gonna be 12?
- Yeah, she's gonna have a
birthday party any day now.
And she plays with dollies.
We got some really looney toons here.
Oh, she's a real goon, all right.
Her clothes are like something
out of Little Orphan Annie.
This is just too much.
Come on.
Fanny's been hidin' all day.
Shy as the dickens with new folks.
But she is to say good night.
Oh yes, let me see.
That's Jeff, and that's Rob and Terri.
And you already met up with the girls.
Well, say good night, and
then off to bed with ya.
Nighty night.
What are you doing?
- Just turning off the
lights so you young folks
can get some sleep.
It's only 8:30.
- Now, you're not so growed
up that you don't need
your 40 winks.
Okay, where do we sleep?
Just a second.
You hitched?
Huh?
Hitched, hitched, hitched.
Hiched means married.
That's what it means.
- Nope.
- Well then,
where do you think you're goin'?
Goin' to bed, get our 40 winks.
No, you're not.
There will be no devil's
play in this house.
Aw, for Christ's sake.
There'll be no cussin' and no buts.
Now, you young ladies
are gonna sleep in there.
And you boys stay out here.
Great.
Terri, are you awake?
Hm?
I hear noises coming from Fanny's room.
Listen.
I want to get out of here.
- Don't worry, we'll be
out of here tomorrow.
Check out Ma's PJs.
Listen, why don't you
try and get some sleep?
Oh, and don't forget.
Not 20 winks.
Not 30 winks, but...
But 40 winks.
What are you doin'?
Sorry, go back to sleep.
It's early.
Where you goin'?
Just for a walk, get some air.
Rob.
Hi, Rob, hi.
Hi, Fanny.
What you doin' up so early, Rob?
Nothin' much, just walkin' around.
Who's your friend?
He's not my friend, he's my brother.
Name's Woody, like President Wilson.
That's a nice name.
Hiya, Woody.
Say hello, Woody.
Hello.
Wanna ride in our swing?
Do ya, Rob?
Sure, why not?
Oh boy.
Hey, this is, this is great, guys.
But okay, guys.
Okay, Fanny, that's high enough, okay?
- Not yet, Rob, you
can go higher than that.
I'm high enough, Fanny.
God damn it, I wanna come down now, okay?
Come on, I'm not messin' around.
I wanna come down!
God damn it, I wanna come down!
I wanna come down, god damn it!
What the hell are you doin'?
Oh my God!
Hi there, had your breakfast yet?
- Yeah, thanks.
- Yeah.
Your friend come yet?
The what?
- You said your friend
was coming in a boat.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry, forgot all about him.
Yeah, he's comin' around.
He says, you know, I mean, if he makes it.
What do you mean if?
You mean he might not show up?
Well, I mean there's two kinds of if.
I mean if he shows up, that's a good if.
If he don't show up, that's a bad if.
You gotta have patience, son.
You should learn to read the good book.
He who waits, gets.
Come on, let's go find Cynthia.
Poor child's asleep.
Who'd have thought that boy
would find the old swing?
Kids ain't used that in a dog's age.
Kids?
What's for lunch, Ma?
Take off your hat, Woody,
and introduce yourself to the guests.
Hi, I'm Woody, who are you?
Well, this is Lynn, Cynthia, and Jeff.
They're gonna stay with us for a spell.
Oh, and there's another
girl in the back room,
but don't you bother her none.
Right.
And Rob's the one in the woodshed.
Poor soul had an accident
playing on that old swing
out by the cliff.
- We ain't never supposed
to go on those old swings
because they're terrible dangerous.
Pa would give us an awful
hiding if we did, right Ma?
Right, right, Woody.
Now, you go find your sister,
Fanny, and be a good boy.
And don't bother nobody.
And stay away from the woodshed.
Yeah, Ma.
I'm gonna fix us something nice to eat.
Fivesies.
- Hope that guy with
the boat shows up soon.
Me too.
- Yeah, I keep wondering
what's gonna crawl out
of the woodworks next.
First that Fanny, now Woody.
What a bunch of freaks.
Can you believe this family?
Because I can't.
I mean, they're out to lunch.
And that Fanny, with that ridiculous bow
in her hair and those clothes.
And that bloated, ugly, ugly face.
She's absolutely repulsive.
Well, I'm going back in, you comin'?
No, not yet.
Okay.
Hello.
Oh, were you listening to that?
Yeah.
You really mustn't pay any attention.
She gets kinda nasty sometimes,
but she doesn't really mean anything.
Gee, that's an awfully
nice dress you've got on.
Did your mom make that for you?
Uh huh, she makes all my clothes
and my baby's clothes too.
Baby.
Uh huh.
I have to go now.
Stay and play with me Cynthia.
We make awful good friends.
No.
Please, just a couple little games.
Wait there.
I'll throw first.
I did it.
Did I scare you, Cynthia?
No.
Shh, come to my room.
I want you to see my baby.
I can tell that you like little babies.
You ain't like the others,
always laughin' and
whisperin' about us kids.
Come look.
Oh no.
Teddy, Cynthia's my friend.
That's my other brother, Teddy.
You wanna hold her, Cyn?
No.
No, no.
Kiss her good night?
Shh, maybe we better take
Cynthia back to her room.
Hi, Miss Lynn, what you doin'?
Just walkin'.
Oh, you haven't met my brother Teddy.
No, but Cynthia told us all about him.
I'll see you guys later.
Hey, what she tell you about me?
Now, Teddy, you behave.
- Yeah, well, I just
don't like nobody sayin'
no bad things about me.
- Maybe she feels bad because
her friend got killed.
- Aw, whenever I feel
sad, I just jump rope,
and then I feel all better, don't I Teddy?
Yeah.
Why don't you jump rope with us?
I don't wanna jump rope.
I just wanna be left alone.
Oh please jump rope with us, Miss Lynn.
Pretty please.
Pretty please with a cherry on top.
Don't you freaks understand English?
Leave me alone!
Pretty please with a cherry on top
and whipped cream and bananas.
Enough, weirdo!
You're all a bunch of weirdos!
- For Christ sakes, Pa, is
your friend comin' or not?
You know, you keep yellin' like that,
you're gonna have that
little girl cryin' again.
- We can't just leave Rob
lyin' there in the woodshed.
Well, have you any other suggestion?
Is this guy gonna show up today?
There's a chance he'll show up, yes.
Bullshit.
Bullshit?
You listen to me.
You never say bullshit,
don't you understand that?
Never do that, or God
will send an angel down
to wash out your mouth with soap.
Where's Cynthia?
In the bedroom.
And Lynn?
She went out.
Well, go find her.
We're gettin' out of here.
The guy with the boat's
never gonna show up.
Get back to the camp with Paul.
Tell him to get that flare gun ready
in case we have to shoot
off a distress signal.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna go get Cyn.
We'll meet up with you there.
Come on, move it.
Okay.
Cyn?
We're movin' out.
- You don't believe what I
told you about last night,
do you Jeff?
- Look, I know you're shook up,
and that you met this Teddy,
but a mummified baby?
Jeff, I saw it.
I swear to God I saw it.
I went down there to Fanny's room.
I saw the cradle.
There's no baby.
Jeff, I know what I saw.
Okay, then what happened?
I don't remember.
I woke up in here this morning.
It wasn't a dream, it was real.
She had the baby in her arms,
and then she held it out to me to kiss it.
It's been a year since the accident.
It's over now.
It wasn't your fault.
You gotta stop torturing yourself.
You leave me alone.
Pa would whoop me bloody like
he did before when you...
Shut up.
I don't want you.
I don't need Woody neither.
I want Jeff.
I want him.
Stop, oh God!
Ma, Ma.
- Wicked.
- Fanny's gone crazy.
Wicked girl.
You're all wicked.
Come from your wicked world.
As the good book says, the
wicked shall be punished.
That child never does finish a chore.
Paul!
It's gone.
Oh God, it's you, Cynthia.
Oh God.
- Jeff's dead.
- What?
Fanny killed him.
And Ma just sat there rocking and smiling.
And they killed Lynn too.
Stop it.
Listen to me, the plane is gone.
Paul is missing, I can't find him.
They're gonna kill us all if we don't...
Listen to me!
- If we don't get...
- Stop it!
- You're it, and ain't none
of you never gonna get off
this island alive.
My Ma and Pa will see to that.
Hold it.
Hold it right there.
You're it!
There's gotta be a boat on this island.
There's gotta be!
Cynthia!
Where are you?
Oh, please don't hurt my baby.
- Let's go, Fanny, you're
gonna get us off this island.
Come on.
Come on, Fanny.
Ma, Pa, get out here!
Damn you, I know you can hear me!
Get out here!
No, no, wait a minute now.
Wait a minute, please.
Don't hurt her.
Don't hurt her my little girl.
- If you want your
little child in one piece
then you better show us where a boat is.
Now!
Pa, Ma, help me.
Oh Lordy, don't fret, child.
I'm scared, Ma.
Shut up!
Shut up or I'll blow
your god damn head off!
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
No, no, listen.
No, don't do anything.
Don't do anything like that.
Please listen to me.
I think I know where there's a boat.
It's on the other side of the island.
It's a fisherman's boat.
Now, I don't know what shape it's in.
You know, I don't know anything about it.
I don't even know if
it's got gasoline in it.
- Then you better get goin',
Pa, and show us where it is.
Tell 'em to come out.
Tell who?
You know who I'm talking about.
Tell 'em to come out!
Teddy, Woody, come on out.
Don't you move, you bastards!
Cyn, Cyn, try and start the boat.
Come on.
- Now, listen, please don't
do anything to my baby.
Please don't.
I fulfilled my promise.
I brought you to the boat.
There's the boat right over there.
Run, run!
Cynthia, run!
Should we go get 'em, Pa?
Nah, let 'em go.
Don't worry about 'em.
If they're on this island, we'll find 'em.
We know every inch of
it, don't worry about it.
- Can we play our game
now, Ma, like you promised?
Course you can, sweetie.
You boys, don't you be
late for supper now.
Finally got 'em all to bed.
Whew, what a day.
How you feel, Ma?
Aw, I'm all right, Pa.
All that ruckus today
got me thinkin' back.
Yeah, well, I been thinkin' too.
I been doin' a lot of thinkin'.
I been thinkin' that
if some soul came along
and tried to do us harm
that we'd strike 'em down
with the help of the
righteous almighty God.
Also, I been thinkin' about the children.
I don't want them to have
contact with the outside world.
They're gonna become contaminated.
So I think what's best is that
they should live here with us
forever and ever and ever.
No, stop it!
Listen.
That's a radio.
They don't have one.
They don't have a radio.
Come on, Cyn.
Come on.
Cynthia!
Run, Cynthia, run!
Run, Cynthia!
Don't be scared, Cyn.
I'm not gonna let those bad boys hurt you.
Come on, I'll take you back
to the house, to Ma and Pa.
No!
Leave me alone!
You killed her.
I'm gonna tell Pa.
Don't whoop me none, Pa.
I didn't mean it.
Well, she was bad.
You said so yourself, didn't he Ma?
Didn't he say so?
He did it.
He did it, Pa, just like I told you.
Then he...
No, you're tellin'!
Don't sass your Pa.
You was a naughty boy.
It was not my fault, Pa.
I couldn't help it.
Don't let him do it to me, Ma.
Get up on the hill.
Get up on the hill!
Come on, get up here.
Get up here when I talk to you!
And turn around and prepare
yourself for God's justice.
Turn around.
In the name of God!
In the name of God.
In the name of God, in the name of God.
- Pa, stop!
- In the name of God.
In the name of God.
In the name of God, in the name of God.
- And we'll pick blueberries
on the other side
of the island.
And Ma will make us a
blueberry pie, won't you Ma?
Oh, land sakes, child, we'll see.
- I'm so glad Ma and Pa's
lettin' you stay with us, Cyn,
'cause now I have someone to play with
'sides them rough old boys.
And we have a surprise for you
that you're gonna like real well.
Ain't that right, Ma?
Mhm.
Don't Cyn look pretty?
You made that dress just right, Ma.
Yep, pretty as a picture.
There.
Oh Lord, bless us for this day
and also the protection
you have always given us
and the peace and the
quiet of our little island.
And most of all, thank
thee for the blessin'
of the new member our happy
little family, Cynthia.
Amen.
Okay, Fanny, come on now.
Let's see what kinda lungs you got.
See if you can blow 'em out.
Now let's see if you can blow 'em out.
Come on, now, let's see.
Blow!
- Come on, come on, come on,
come on there are two more.
Two more.
That's right, well done.
Well, let's cut it up, Ma.
Cut it up.
Not you, you're always tryin' to be first.
That's why you're so god damn big.
Ma, am I a clean plate clubber now?
Land sakes, child, you sure are.
All right, come on, you two.
We got some chores to do.
- Now can we
show her her surprise?
Now, close your eyes.
Oh.
My big dollies.
So my child, happy birthday, Fanny.
Thank you, Pa.
The last one's Doc Brown.
Ma and Pa made him a big
dolly right after they had me.
Oh, I remember when Pa
made him a big dolly.
He just wouldn't stop botherin' us.
I don't remember 'bout him.
Don't you, sweetie?
He came here in his boat, he did.
Liked the fishin' so much, he
was gonna tell his friends.
Well, we couldn't allow that.
I helped you, didn't I Ma?
Sure did, Woody.
Now this pair, they thought
they could do anything
they pleased on our beach.
Wicked creatures.
Well, Teddy surprised them all right.
Guess you know the rest, huh Cynthia?
Pleased to meet you, I'm sure.
- Told you that scarf would
suit you real well, young man.
This is a pretty dress for the baby.
Sure is.
Mom made it for me special.
- Are you gonna put
this dress on the baby?
Okay, sure I will.
Baby, baby.
What's that, Fan?
A bassinnete.
I'm gonna give my baby a bath
before I put on her new dress.
Fanny?
Fanny!
What Cyn?
Put my baby down!
Ain't your baby, it's mine.
And I'm gonna give my baby a bath.
Put my baby down!
It's mine!
Naughty, Woody.
- Teddy, run up to my
room and get me the red yard
from my basket.
Ma, I'm busy.
Don't rile me, son.
Get the yarn.
What?
Cyn, what's gotten into you?
Naughty, Teddy.
Oh God almighty.
Oh God, why hath thou forsaken me?
Oh, Fanny, Fanny.
My God.
Oh God, I want to talk to you.
Yes, I do.
I want you to listen to me.
Listen.
My family
is dead.
And we lived by your teachings.
I beat it into 'em.
I taught it to them.
And what have you done?
You did away with them.
Well, I have news for you.
I renounce you, God!
I renounce you and I
give my soul to Satan!