Yeah. Are you serious ?
Absolutely.
Is she all right ?
I guess.
Jack !
I'm taking him around the park.
He needs to stretch his legs.
All right. I'll see you later.
We won't be long. Be good.
Hey, am I ever ?
Bye.
- Lucky man.
- Yeah.
So, someone said there
was gonna be tennis ?
Is that what I said ?
Because I was pretty sure
I said, "Long Island iced tea."
Wait, wait, there's tea in this ?
We're not playing tennis ?
Because I got this damn
hyper-carbon racket,
or whatever the hell this thing is.
Hey, Jack...
Where's Margaret ?
Addy.
Adelle ?
What's wrong ? You look terrible.
Margaret, I'm sorry
to be the one to tell you.
You're dead.
Boyd. Hey.
How's the promotion treating you ?
You must be thrilled.
I mean, you were no fun as Echo's Handler
and now you get to be twice as no fun
as head of security.
Yeah, well. So far, not a lot to do.
Miss DeWitt's keeping the Dollhouse idle
for the most part, after Dominic...
- After Dominic.
- Yeah.
Most of the Actives are on rest.
Echo's out, though ?
- Yep.
- What is she...
Having trouble letting go, Papa Bear ?
Aw.
We put a dead lady in her.
That's what I heard, but I didn't believe it.
A dead client ?
I guess she's special friends
with Adelle, or something.
I mean, not special friends.
Although, late night, too much wine...
So we can give you life after death.
Only if we really like you.
Hey, Boyd,
I need an Active.
What ? Why ?
I'm doing my annual anterior
insular cortex diagnostic,
and though it may sound simple,
it's actually a very complicated,
super-specific imprint
and I need head of security
to sign off on a subject.
Is there risk ?
Not if I know what I'm doing.
Sierra's been idle the longest.
Look at you with the big decisions,
big boss-man.
Life after death.
- Where does that end ?
- Same place it begins.
Death.
This is so stunning.
Really.
Last thing I remember
is coming here a month ago
for that dreadful process of yours.
Well, if we'd spoken in the meantime,
I'd have been able to tell you about
the last three weeks of your life, but...
Well, this way I don't have
to remember dying.
Undoubtedly, a plus.
God, it's all a plus.
I mean, more life !
Can you imagine ?
And this body...
Nice work, Addy.
I'm pointing to the sky.
- Shame it's only a loaner.
- That was always the deal.
I swear I've never felt this good.
Did being young feel this good ?
I seem to recall it was rather nice.
I wonder why we gave it up.
Please.
You're, what, 10 years younger than me ?
And, oddly, 15 years older.
Just remember, it's temporary.
Just a chance to indulge my curiosity.
See my own funeral.
Who wouldn't want that ?
To hear what the world
really thought of us ?
To count up the number who love us ?
Addy ?
- Are you all right ?
- Well, let's see.
My friend just died.
Come on.
We've got a funeral to go to.
Then maybe you can help me wrap this up.
Wrap this up ? Your life ?
Well, I thought maybe
I'd solve my murder.
The autopsy said it was
a massive heart attack.
I was perfectly healthy
and ridiculously wealthy.
And wealth can be
a dangerous thing to have.
You suspected this might happen ?
When I was three,
my nanny put ground glass
in my nap-time snack.
She wasn't going to let me eat it.
She was going to be the hero
who caught it just in time.
I snuck a cookie and spent
two weeks in the hospital.
Forgive me if I'm the suspicious type.
You had the scan so you could come back
and solve your own murder ?
I like a puzzle.
- Are you certain you're ready for this ?
- Of course.
Come on, let's go in.
I used to say I'd be late for
my own funeral, but I didn't mean it.
Not a bad turnout.
I'd like to hear more weeping, of course.
You know, you don't have
to do that for my benefit,
be all chipper.
Come on, my dear.
I'm doing exactly what you would.
Stiff back, stiff lip.
You know that's how you'd play it.
- Margaret.
- Not Margaret.
I'm Julia now.
You've really thought this through.
I started mentioning Julia now and then
to my family before we started the scans.
I wrote myself into my own will,
instructed the family to expect me...
While you spy on the servants
and the family friends
and the business associates.
A spy ? No, no, Addy. I'm a ghost.
Welcome.
We are here to remember
a very special woman.
Margaret Bashford wasn't
the first of that name.
- She was a formidable woman.
- Let me introduce you to the family.
I want to hear
how great you were.
Over there, Nicolas and Jocelyn.
My God.
Your children.
Watching them go through this.
One buries one's parents.
Unpleasant, but natural.
Do let's focus.
Like her namesake, strong...
Oh, my brother William came.
I haven't seen him in a dog's age.
Seems somewhat the worse
for being stupefyingly drunk.
So, no change there.
And lined up along the walls,
the loyal household staff.
The grooms from the stables.
Well, who are all the others ?
You know, all my closest friends.
I should probably remember their names.
Every one of them a suspect.
Ooh, someone's tardy.
Jack.
You never met my husband, did you ?
He is young.
Mmm.
When I met him, I stopped becoming
such a regular customer at the Dollhouse.
I can see why.
I was a lucky woman.
Until recently.
Almost there.
Almost...
Yes.
Tell me you got Speedforce 3.
And downloaded the bonus maps.
- Pizza ?
- On its way. Beer in the fridge.
Dude !
Oh ! I've also got this new kind
of Battleship game I invented
with real explosions.
- What, like you can really get hurt ?
- Yeah.
My man.
- Appetizers.
- Word.
Get ready to have your ass kicked
and possibly lose an eye.
- You're a better cook than you think.
- Hmm.
I don't think pasta should be that snappy.
It's al dente.
That's Italian for "Ow, my teeth."
Um...
I know the quickest way
to kill a relationship
is to take its temperature,
but are you okay ?
I'm just tired.
Okay.
So, there's nothing new ?
Nothing with work ?
You don't talk about
the Dollhouse much anymore.
No. I don't.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I know I'm being...
I'll be fine.
I'm fine and you're adorable.
You're beyond adorable, you're...
If you say "adorabubble," I'm leaving.
I wasn't going to, but I love the fact
you thought it was the next logical word.
- I'll clear.
- No, no, no.
Wow. What a gentleman.
Well, it could also be
I made a mess in the kitchen
and I don't want you to see.
You don't seem like an old friend.
I was backpacking, like the kids do.
She sort of took me under her wing
and showed me Morocco.
Hmm. And you stayed in touch.
She'd call and we'd talk for hours.
We were very close.
I think she liked having an outsider
to sort of share her little insights with.
Always gushing about her loved ones.
You know how she was.
What ?
We're talking about
the same woman, right ?
Tall, blonde hair.
- Margaret Merriam Bashford
- from Greenwich...
- Stern look stuck on her face ?
- Mid-50s, liked horses ?
- Yes. Margaret.
I knew her very well.
Mom wasn't exactly a bundle of warmth.
She tended to push people off.
Like a bulldozer.
She did like to befriend complete
strangers for short outbursts,
and have them stay for the weekend
wearing all of my clothes.
- Bulldozer ?
That wasn't a stranger.
That was Camille Beauvais,
the tennis player.
She was a stranger to me,
and she was rude.
She just looked better
in your clothes than you did.
Oh, my God, you slept with her,
didn't you ?
Technically, no, we didn't sleep...
Nicky, just like me
when I was your age.
Wooing all the women
and sort of worthless.
He is not worthless.
Nicolas has loads of potential.
Margaret told me.
It's funny how you not doing anything
was called potential,
and me working my ass off
was called a pipe dream.
This isn't a funeral for
your photography career.
What do you know, Uncle Bill ?
We haven't seen you since Mother
banned you after the boat fiasco.
I was, like, 12.
Yes, Margaret could be awful, but so can I.
And from what I can gauge,
the two of you are hideous.
So, come on.
You should have seen our mother.
Of course, you would have turned to stone.
Margaret was nothing like Mother !
- Your mother.
- You knew Nana ?
Right now we should be drinking...
- I wasn't aware you'd stopped.
...to Margaret.
To the woman she was,
and to all she left behind.
Split three ways.
I know Margaret was guarded,
but she did have a soft side.
She fell in love with Jack.
Well, she did like him better
than she liked us, I suppose.
She loved you.
I haven't seen much
of Prince Charming.
Deep in grief, I suppose.
Well, after she slapped him down
at long last, he's sulking.
- Slapped him down ?
- She left him the horses.
She knew he didn't know
anything about them,
didn't care about them,
but he got them instead of money.
Don't you think... No.
That's because she treasured
the horses and she trusted him.
Well, I'm glad that she's
not around to see how he's taking that.
What did he expect ?
They were in love.
Julia, I know we're being terribly shocking,
and you're being charmingly loyal,
but you may want to brace yourself.
You may be here to
mourn Margaret Bashford,
but the rest of us, we just live here.
Hey.
Oh, Nicolas. I needed some air.
I think I need to explain
something about tonight.
Mother thought sentiment
made you cloudy.
- Mmm.
- I know we sound harsh,
but she never would've wanted
a bunch of flowery tributes
that people didn't mean.
She was that hard ?
Well, a lot of it was fear.
She was terrified
that we'd have no ambition,
so she made us work for everything.
I like numbers, percentages.
So, she decided I'd work on Wall Street.
Rode me about it every day.
She wouldn't let it lie.
- That's not so...
- I was 12.
She wanted the best for you !
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
I'm not trying to lecture you.
I'm trying to comfort you.
You are ?
Inside, she...
She told me that she cried
over all your pains,
and she thought...
She thought all the time
about what it was like
when you were small
and she could hold you and...
And how proud she was
when you grew into this handsome,
confident man.
Are you gonna...
- I don't...
- Yeah ?
- I don't think so.
- You okay ? Want some water ? No ?
- No. I'm okay.
- Okay ?
Well, I mean,
it seemed like you wanted to...
- No.
- Subconsciously ?
- No !
- You said you wanted to comfort me.
Not with my tongue.
You also checked out my body.
I saw that. Oh !
God !
Okay, well,
this is a new personal worst for me.
I'm so sorry. I had too much wine.
Look, I
gotta go.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Oh, hey.
Wrong room, my mistake.
No, wait.
You must be Julia.
Margaret told me about you.
I don't know how I got so turned around.
Well, it's a big place.
Jack,
what Margaret did,
I hope you know it was a gesture of trust.
What... What... What she did ?
Leaving you the horses.
It was her way of saying
she knew you weren't
in this for the money.
Right.
So you get it ?
The horses,
her real loves,
my reward.
Her real... No. That's...
You were with them tonight, weren't you ?
They call me a killer or just a gold digger ?
Killer ? Why would they say that ?
Search me. Inheritance like I got ?
Not exactly worth killing for, is it ?
Addy, it's just so ugly.
I love these people, but I don't like them.
What if one of them... God...
Killed you ?
Am I being paranoid ?
You spent a year and a half
having regular painful brain scans
because you thought someone
was going to murder you.
So, paranoid is still a contender.
I thought it would be a maid.
Margaret...
Someone who resented my money.
A distant friend, maybe.
God, Adelle, there's just so much anger.
At least the first time I died
thinking people loved me.
All just a worthless illusion.
Illusions aren't worthless.
They're at the heart of most relationships.
I suppose you'd be out of a job
if they weren't.
We'll figure this out.
Of course. I should've stayed dead.
Yes ?
Eternal life.
Nice adjective. Excellent noun.
Is there more ?
Is that something we offer now ?
Because if it is, that's...
You realize that's the beginning of the end.
Life everlasting, it's...
It's the ultimate quest.
Christianity, most religion,
morality doesn't exist
without the fear of death.
I'm not planning on presiding
over the end of Western civilization.
This is a one-time situation.
You know that you're asking her
to voluntarily die when the time comes.
Well, if she resists,
I have a new head of security
who handles that kind of thing.
Yes, ma'am.
You can still help Echo, you know.
Tell me your take on this.
First instinct.
- Follow the money.
- That's not easy.
It is when the money runs.
I've looked into the horses.
One of them, King's Ransom, was
a derby contender not long ago.
So the husband stands to make a bundle.
So does the buyer.
I thought I'd send someone
to take a look around the stables.
A breeder with a naturally curious streak.
Drew Chilton ?
Glad to meet you.
Thanks for coming all the way out here.
Well, you've got some fine incentives.
Yes, I do. One in particular.
Right this way.
Hope you've been treating him right,
a fine horse like that.
Fresh water, fresh oats,
and barbecue on the weekends.
Who among us could ask for more ?
So, this place been in your family long ?
- Hey.
- Go away.
Sure.
Wait. I'm... I'm sorry.
I'm just...
God, I'm so emo.
Are you ?
I have to say,
there's a part of me that's not sad
to see someone mourning my friend.
Is that what this is ?
You lost your mother.
It's only natural you'd be so elmo.
- Emo.
- That's not a word, sweetie.
God, you sound just like her.
She didn't even know me.
She didn't know me any more than you do.
She didn't want to.
I'm sure that's not true.
I take pictures. I'm good.
She never came to a single one
of my exhibitions.
You were serious about that ?
I mean, obviously you
were serious about that.
You're right.
That was very bad of her.
I don't know what to say.
All of her lectures about being practical,
and then she throws herself
at some little tropical cookie
she picked up in Manila.
He is my age !
Some tropical... Jocelyn !
He played her like a fool.
He spent her money,
and he probably slept with every woman
who set foot in this place.
Did he...
- Tell me, did he ever try...
- With me ?
God, no.
Although I wouldn't put it past him.
If you don't believe me, go talk to him.
When your ass hits the sheets,
you'll know.
I spent my whole life
watching her being, you know, tough,
and it was okay that she didn't let me in
because she didn't let anyone in.
Right ?
And then two years ago, she meets Jack,
and she's all fluttering
and whispering secrets, and then...
Now there's you.
Whatever.
Holy...
Sorry.
You can't be here.
I need you to run some prints.
They're entered, all keyed up.
Just need authorization.
Comfy ?
I shouldn't do this.
I got prints on someone
who might be a missing person.
You got prints on someone
who might be a doll, you mean.
They are missing people, you know.
They just don't know it.
My God, it's her.
How do we access the file ?
Polly Keller ?
Oh, my God.
What...
They're gone.
What just happened ?
I just started to believe you.
Earth-identical gravity
and atmosphere on other planets.
- Is that two ?
- I'll give you one.
That's fair.
One ecosystem for a whole planet.
Good.
Human-alien cross-breeding
without scientific intervention.
Nice.
Flamey explosions and sound in a vacuum.
Yes !
Good job.
Oh, but there's so much more.
Light speed travel,
space storms and sexy, sexy aliens.
I said classic sci-fi errors.
Now you're just attacking
good storytelling.
Speaking of sci-fi,
can we play with the sleepies ?
- No.
- Come on, Topher.
We could have them battle one another
and bet on them like gladiators.
We can't play with the sleepies.
Or we could have them
act out skits we write,
film it and see who gets
more hits on YouTube.
That's not a bad idea, but no.
You want to play chess ?
A variant ? Flying chess.
Excellent. But how about every time
you lose a piece, you drink ?
Sounds good.
Advantage, me.
Hey. I couldn't help but...
- Are you going somewhere ?
- Yep.
I got the first ticket to Not Here.
Margaret belonged here. I didn't.
I just belonged to her.
- She seemed very devoted to you.
- Hmm.
Yeah.
- Was it hard ?
- Was what, what ?
Being married to someone older ?
A man like you would have options.
Hand me that tie ?
Maybe you didn't exercise those options.
Maybe...
Maybe you waited very patiently
until you were free.
I know who you are.
And I don't know which of them hired you,
but I know a spy when I see one.
What are you trying to find out ?
If I killed her,
or if I'm on to the person who did ?
Either way, what you're doing is sick.
Wearing her perfume,
trying this summer stock seduction.
You working for Nicolas ? Jocelyn ?
Tell them they're looking
in the wrong place.
Tell them I'm selling the horses
because I can't stand the constant
reminder of the woman I loved.
Oh.
They want a real bad guy,
tell them to look at dear old Uncle Bill.
He just came for the funeral.
Oh, no. Didn't he mention that ?
He came the day before she died.
He did ?
That was after the last...
The last time I spoke to Margaret.
He showed up out of nowhere.
Needed to talk to her.
About what ?
She said she'd tell me later.
If I had to guess,
I'd say he wanted to borrow money.
And I guess she said no.
William ?
Hey, hey. Hey.
Okay, okay.
Not short on spirit.
Oh, gorgeous.
I worked with his sire a few years back.
This one's got better hooves.
What about EIPH ?
No history of hemorrhaging.
His lungs are fine.
Who the hell are you ?
I'm gonna buy this here horse,
if everything works out.
He barely waited for her body
to be in the ground.
What was that ?
This was my mother's horse.
It was her favorite thing.
I can't believe the bastard's selling it.
He should.
This horse has got another
year of racing in him.
- You think so ?
- At least.
Won't fetch this price forever, though.
You know what,
I don't want to hear about it.
Whatever you're doing, stop.
Stop thinking, stop testing.
He's not for sale.
Do you believe in ghosts ?
Uh, sort of.
Just recently.
Margaret and I moved into
this house when we were kids.
We were convinced it was haunted.
Slept in the same bed the first night.
Anyway...
I'm getting the same
creepy feeling again, now.
Like Margaret is lingering here.
And she's angry.
Why would she be angry ?
Because she wanted more time.
You know, we hadn't said
one word to each other in 13 years.
She wouldn't pick up the phone
because she was too damn stubborn.
And you ? Why wouldn't you call ?
Because I was too damn stubborn.
But fate grabbed an old fool
by the scruff of his neck
and brought me here.
Just in time.
The day before she died.
I just knocked on the door.
Can't say she was thrilled
to see me at first,
but I expected as much.
The important thing, we reconciled.
Can you...
Can you tell me what she said ?
"Hey, remember the time..." "Yeah, yeah."
No, it wasn't the words that mattered.
It was...
She just looked in my face
and I looked in hers,
and we just both knew there
was no reason to stay mad.
Here's to you, Margaret.
Mmm.
Well, I guess I was the lucky one.
Nicolas would be coping with this better
if he'd talk to her about
his debts and all that.
Addiction, not for the faint of heart.
In a world where
all men are guilty until proven dead,
one man stands as our only hope
in the fight against...
I told you I've got your back.
Nice.
Or, "I told you you'd get it in the end."
"The quickest way to a man's
heart is through his back."
"I'm sending you back
to the future of being dead."
This one's going nowhere.
- What are we at ?
- Tied up. Best of 7 ?
Eleven.
Hey, you.
How was your day ?
You know, fine, I guess.
I let myself in a little while ago.
Hope you don't mind.
- You have a key.
- I know, but it's just your apartment
and with everything lately...
I don't know, I don't want you thinking
I'm in here nuzzling your shirts
while you're gone,
anything weird like that.
- Good to know.
- I mean, they smell really good.
Some of them not so much,
but overall your shirts are nuzzle-worthy.
Joke.
Geez, so grumpy.
That looks nice.
Cabernet. I bought it.
I should have gotten white, though.
Red wine makes my teeth purple.
- Paul, we have to talk.
- Okay.
Well, you don't have to talk,
but you have to let me talk at you.
Because I've been thinking a lot, and...
Just let me do this, okay ?
Good.
Paul...
Mellie.
I like being with you.
I love it, actually.
And you say everything's fine,
so I'm going to stop asking if it is.
If that means lying next to you
while everything's not fine,
then that's what I'll do.
I will give you what you need
and let you take it from me.
And if you want to give back, give back.
But it doesn't have to mean anything.
It doesn't have to mean anything.
I've still got it, don't I, handsome ?
I know. I miss you more.
Strange,
he doesn't like most people.
Who's there ?
I have a better question.
Did you think I wouldn't
recognize my own mother,
Mother ?
Honestly, it's a relief.
I couldn't tell a soul what was going on
and it was proving difficult.
How did you know ?
Well, little things, you know,
like the way you moved.
And I watched you through
your window the other night
when you were trying to go
to bed in your old room.
Same routine as always.
You checked the shutters,
flipped the light switch down the hall
that's impossible to find.
Nobody knows where it is but you.
But I didn't really know
until I saw you with King's Ransom.
Oh.
It was definitely after I tried to kiss you.
Well, I should hope so.
But, I mean, how would you
ever even think it was possible ?
The Dollhouse.
In Manhattan, right ? I am a customer.
- Nicolas.
- What ? So are you.
We're all adults here, sort of.
I didn't use it for anything like this.
I mean, life after death ?
I never even considered that.
I don't get to keep it.
I didn't think so.
Although, the possibilities...
Living forever, moving from body to body.
Brilliant.
People should know that
you are to be feared, Mother.
Even after death.
Feared ?
Nicky, I only ever wanted you to be happy.
I'm your mother.
I'm supposed to bear your burdens,
even if you lost everything.
I couldn't stop.
Gambling is all about ups and downs,
and when it seems like
you have all these...
All these resources,
you can just wait around
for another upswing,
so I kept chasing losses...
And then you hit bottom.
And I went below it.
Nicolas.
That's millions.
I knew that you would be ashamed of me
and that you wouldn't let it lie,
so I couldn't tell you.
I couldn't tell you.
Okay, okay. We'll...
It'll be all right.
After you died,
part of me was relieved
because you never knew.
But now, I just want you back.
You were taken from me too soon.
Smart boy.
You suspect that, too.
Look, he's supposed to
be worth over $4 million.
Go, go !
You think you can hustle me ?
Oh, what the hell do you mean ?
King's Ransom has been juiced.
Anabolic steroids, stimulants.
Enough to make his heart pop.
You really think you could hide
this with a little clomiphene citrate ?
I mean, masking agents
can't hide themselves, you know.
If I wasn't looking for it,
I might have been fooled,
but I ain't a baby in this freaking business.
You were going for a money grab.
Trying to pass that horse off
as race ready, raise his value.
He looks that way now,
but a couple weeks without that stuff,
he'll be put to pasture.
I know you're new to this,
but in layman's terms,
you just made yourself a $4 million pet.
He killed me. Oh, God.
Whatever he gave to King's Ransom,
that's what he used on me.
Okay, okay. Calm down.
We just have to think.
Why ? Why don't I just walk out there
and let him kill me twice ?
- I'm dead anyway.
- Because you can prove that he did it.
You can give him
the punishment that he deserves.
Run !
Sorry to disturb you, ma'am.
Not at all.
Victor tested the horse
and I just got the results.
My hunch was correct.
They were tied together.
Your friend was killed with a drug
that was being given to the horse.
The killer masked it,
so the coroner didn't find it.
- Any idea who ?
- No.
- Lf I went in...
- She has a new Handler.
You're going to have to get used to it.
Yes, I guess I am.
One other thing, Miss DeWitt.
Are you aware of this Topher situation ?
Yes.
There's no need to address
the issue with him.
I allow him one of these
diagnostic tests every now and again.
So, I guess Topher can make friends.
Loneliness leads to nothing good,
only detachment.
And sometimes the people
who most need to reach out
are the people least capable of it.
In any case,
it only happens once a year.
Come on, come on, come on.
He's coming. What's your plan ?
You got a gun stashed somewhere ?
No. You know how I feel about guns.
Though I'm warming up
to them right now.
Evidence.
There is evidence that he killed you.
Just the drug, but we can't prove...
No, not that.
A letter from Margaret Bashford
in her own handwriting,
written a week ago
and hidden somewhere in this room.
Nicky, that's brilliant.
Great letter. Says that he'd do it,
when he'd do it and how he'd do it.
Okay.
The jury's gonna eat this up.
What was the date, the day I died ?
The 19th.
It's all here.
How he'll use the same masking agent
he's been doping the horses with to...
Jack didn't know much about them.
We have to hurry.
Let's find a place to hide it.
How would he learn
how to drug a racehorse ?
Well, he must have had help.
It's not that hard to find someone
with that type of knowledge, you know ?
He must have...
Oh, mother.
You could never let things lie.
Nicolas. What are you doing ?
What in the hell do I have to do
to get you off my damn back, Mother ?
This was difficult the first time.
But being around you more,
it's getting easier.
Nicky, I love you.
I can even see why
you drugged King's Ransom.
You thought you could sell him,
get out of a hole.
I had to make him worth something.
In case all you left me
was the damn horses.
But Jack got stuck with them.
Even better.
So, you were going to kill me
no matter what.
It was the only way to
get out of the hole, Mom.
I didn't expect you to come back.
Or Jack to figure out you did it.
Jack gets into everything, doesn't he ?
My business.
My mother's bed.
- I really am sorry, Mom.
- No !
This is going to sting a little.
I knew it was you.
Come here.
Darling ! Are you all right ?
He killed my wife.
Jack, are you all right ?
He murdered Margaret. He killed my wife.
What the hell is going on ?
Call an ambulance. And the police.
Okay.
Margaret...
Yes ?
I hope she didn't know...
Didn't know the truth about her son.
It would have killed her.
It did.
"...most likely with clomiphene citrate,
"or any other drug used
to mask the doping of horses..."
My God. She knew ?
"On or around the 19th.
"You will also find
enclosed a last will and testament,
"adjusted in light of these
recent discoveries.
"As you may imagine,
"Nicolas now gets nothing,
"but he will be spending
his life behind bars no doubt,
"so what use would it be to him ?
"In any case, that means
more for everybody else. Yay."
Mother wrote this ?
"Jocelyn,
"I know that the tone of this document
"may seem out of character,
"but in these final days,
I am feeling different,
"wise and full of warmth,
"and I would love to say a few things
to each of you before I go."
That was pretty crazy last night.
I don't know if I can handle
that all the time, but...
I kind of liked it.
Not all the time, though.
So, you going to do more hunting today ?
For Dollhouse clients ?
I found one.
I don't know when I'll have the chance
to see something like this again.
I wish Margaret was here.
You could
pretend she could hear you.
No, I don't believe in that stuff.
I just hope I did what I could
when she was here, you know ?
I tried to show her as best
I could that she was...
She was my favorite person.
Plain and simple.
But I'll never know if she believed me.
I have a feeling she did.
Tell me you weren't tempted,
even a little, not to come back here today,
just to disappear in this body.
Maybe a little.
But I've had my turn,
and the people I love are moving on.
Besides...
Besides ?
I know you, Adelle.
You're too much like me.
I wouldn't have gotten
as far as the airport.
- Addy ?
- Yes ?
Will I see my whole life
flash before my eyes ?
Every single moment.