Catch them.
Kill them.
What's wrong, Ronnie?
I Iove you, Jodie.
Suffolk County police.
May I help you?
Everybody's dead.
What do you mean,
''everybody's dead''?
A guy come running
into the bar and says...
...his mother and father are shot.
I've been to a Iot of crime scenes,
never seen one Iike this.
Six members of the family
were found last night...
...in bed, shot...
...and killed.
Killed were car dealer Ronald Defeo,
his wife and four of their children.
The sole survivor of the family...
...23-year-old
Ronald ''Butch'' Defeo Jr...
...is said to have discovered
the bodies.
The police state
that for his own safety...
...they're holding him
in protective custody.
Five of the victims were found
shot facedown on their beds.
The sixth was found in a cIoset.
No one seemed to stir in their sIeep.
It's strange.
Suffolk County police have charged
23-year-old Ronald Defeo Jr.
The accused told police
he heard voices...
...coming from within the house,
telling him to murder his family.
Oh, God!
Damn it.
Hi, MichaeI.
Oh, hey, baby. You okay?
George, what are you doing
to my mom?
Nothing.
- Yet.
- You perv.
Come on up here, IittIe man.
You can make it.
Oh, you're getting heavy.
Did you meet my dad?
No...
...never had the pIeasure, paI.
Do I have to call you ''Dad'' now?
- Guess what.
- What?
- You can call me whatever you want.
- Anything?
- Yep.
- CooI.
- Anything.
Yeah.
- Stinky.
- Sure.
- Poopy-head.
- Yeah.
Crap-monkey-fart.
Okay, we gotta draw the Iine
somewhere, paI, that does it.
All right.
- This sucks.
- You're not kidding.
Billy.
Look, maybe we'll grab you
something on the way to schooI.
- What do you say, huh?
- I'm not hungry. I can waIk to schooI.
No, you can't, and get
your feet off the chair.
I'll drop you a coupIe bIocks away.
Nobody'd see.
- Mom, I'm 12 years oId.
- Before you pIan...
...your retirement party, we're gonna
drop you off at schooI.
We got a big day.
Why? Where are you guys going?
- Mom, can you heIp me?
- Oh, MichaeI.
Houses here are way out
of our price range, Kath.
Not according to this.
- Well, then it's gotta be true.
- Think positive, babe.
I'm positive that houses here
are out of our price range.
Look, when the business
is going good...
- ...we're gonna--
- There.
- What?
- That's it.
- Look.
- Honey.
Baby, Iook, 412 Ocean Avenue.
- It's beautifuI.
- What?
Look at how friendIy they are here,
honey.
They get Iike that when they think
they'll make a saIe.
Let's just pIay it cooI, Kath.
Kathy. Katherine.
Or not.
- Hi there.
- I'm Katherine Lutz.
Well, just call me Edith.
This is your husband?
- George.
- This is an amazing house.
You are going to Iove it.
Just follow me in here.
CarefuI on the steps there.
HoIy shit.
Excuse me.
Let me show you
the rest of the house.
This-- This is a mistake.
How's that?
No, I mean your ad in the paper.
This is--
It's gotta be a misprint.
I'm a contractor...
...and I know what a pIace
Iike this shouId cost.
And, you know, if this is--
Well, if this is true, then this is a--
The deaI of a Iifetime.
And what is wrong with that?
- Come on.
- I Iove it.
- There's a vibrant history here.
- Vibrant history, George.
In fact, the house was buiIt
in 1692, at Ieast the basement.
The rest of the house was added
from that foundation.
It's one of the oIdest Dutch CoIoniaIs
in Long IsIand.
Wow, that's impressive.
This room wouId be perfect
for chiIdren, if you have any.
And the view's--
Well, have a Iook for yourseIves.
There's a boathouse.
Oh, all you need now
is a boat, right?
Actually, George has a speedboat.
This pIace sounds
Iike it's made for you.
And this is your basement.
As you can see,
it's very spacious.
It can be a game room,
a pIayroom.
Well, Iet's-- Let's have a Iook.
I'll just wait up here.
Yep, Iooks Iike a basement.
So, what do you guys think?
- I think you Iook foxy in that skirt.
- Will you stop it? Come on.
Yes, yes, okay?
It's a vaIue. It's a vaIue
for peopIe with money.
Okay, Iook, if we do this, we're
gonna be eating dry wall for a year.
We deserve this, George.
You deserve this.
How many times you tell me
how hard you work for so IittIe.
- Kathy--
- Maybe today is the day it all pays off.
- We'll make sacrifices.
- Huge sacrifices.
Yeah, I understand that.
Listen, honey...
...this is the Iife we want.
- We're happy?
- Yes, we're happy.
She's happy. I'm broke.
HoId on, hoId on, hoId on.
So Iook, I gotta ask,
what's the catch?
There's aIways a catch.
There was a tragedy, a crime...
- ...a murder.
- I'm sorry, what?
In the house?
SeveraI peopIe, a famiIy.
But, you know, we've moved on,
the whoIe town.
It is a distant memory now.
And the house is fine.
Really.
Doesn't it seem kind of strange
to buy this house, honey?
Well, houses don't kill peopIe.
PeopIe kill peopIe.
Just-- Excuse us.
Do you think we can make it work?
You know what?
You want it,
then we're gonna make it work.
- Really?
- I'll work out of the basement...
...and you can, well...
- ...sell one of the kids.
- Hey.
A IittIe one.
We're rich! We're rich!
We're rich in something,
but it ain't money.
Wait.
- You say your prayers?
- Yep, said them twice.
- What did you pray for?
- If I tell you, it won't come true.
Why don't you tell him the truth.
- What?
- Praying doesn't do any good.
William.
Nobody answered me when
I asked for Dad to be kept aIive.
Don't say that.
Sometimes things happen in Iife
that can't be expIained, Billy.
Billy, Iook at me.
I need you to give George
a chance, okay?
You're not being disIoyaI
to Dad by Iiking George.
He doesn't want to be anything
but your friend...
...and maybe one day
something more.
Nobody will ever
repIace your dad, honey.
For you too?
For me too.
How's Billy?
He'll be fine.
- First call.
- Lutz residence, how may I heIp you?
- Can I talk to my daughter, please?
Yeah, sure, she's--
She's right here. Okay.
Your mother's gotta stop
gushing over me, seriousIy.
It's embarrassing now.
Hello?
- Hey, Ma.
- Hi.
No, we're all moved in.
- Yeah, Ma.
- Are you coId?
No, Ma.
Yeah.
- What is it, baby?
- Nothing.
- Are you okay, baby?
- No.
I don't feeI well.
- Give me a kiss.
- I can do it, I can do it.
No, you can't.
Come here, come here.
Honey, I'm gonna
make you some tea.
How many brothers and sisters
do you have?
- CheIsea?
- Hey, Mommy.
Hi, hon. Who are you taIking to?
- The girI who Iives in my cIoset.
- Oh, yeah?
- And what's her name?
- Jodie.
You know there are pIenty of other
IittIe girIs to pIay with in town too?
I know, but Jodie says
they're all mean.
Is that Jodie?
No, that's someone eIse.
Who?
I'm not supposed to say who.
She says it's an A-hoIe.
You are not allowed
to say that word.
George, George.
- Look what I found.
- What is that? Where'd you find that?
Harry and I found it.
- Where?
- In the basement.
Not the basement.
My office.
You Iisten to me.
You don't go down there.
Understand?
Guys, wouId you heIp me
with the groceries?
Go on, go heIp your mom.
I'm sorry.
Go on.
- How are you feeIing?
- Good, good.
I found a babysitter off a board
at the grocery store.
Billy will Iove that.
How about we call her
the young-aduIt-sitter?
Where's CheIsea?
CheIsea?
CheIsea!
CheIsea.
Hey, give me your hand.
Give me your hand, sweetie.
- CheIsea, go to George.
- Come on. Hey, give me your hand.
What were you thinking?
You couId have fallen in the water.
Jodie wanted to see the boat.
Somebody shouId have been
watching you.
Billy, get up.
Billy, I gotta go pee.
CheIsea.
Goddamn it, Harry.
SeriousIy. You trying to kill me?
Come on, get away from there.
Hey, that's enough.
Hey!
George? Hon, what are you
doing down here?
It's the onIy pIace
that's warm in this damn house.
Somebody keeps opening
the windows.
What is that?
You tell me.
- Why don't you come back to bed.
- No, I can't sIeep.
I'm sorry, baby.
Don't....
Don't taIk to me Iike
I'm one of your kids, okay?
- What?
- That goddamn dog woke me up.
Billy's dog.
Found him in the boathouse.
- But you Iocked it.
- Yeah.
Hey, and guess
what I found in Billy's room.
You ready to taIk
about those keys?
There's not a Iot in this worId can't
be soIved with an apoIogy, Billy.
I'm not apoIogizing
for something I didn't do...
...George.
Get to work, buddy.
''Get to work, buddy.''
''Katch 'em....''
George?
George, you down there?
What?
What's the matter?
Did you do that thing
with the magnets?
Nothing. Just seeing things,
I guess.
You Iook hideous.
You're rather repuIsive yourseIf,
Mr. Lutz.
- Where's the babysitter?
- Babysitter?
ToId you guys,
I don't need a babysitter.
- I'm oId enough.
- Baby, I know you can--
I'm not Ietting her watch us. She's
not coming in, I won't Iet her. I won't.
- She's not coming in.
- Billy, Iisten to me.
- I won't Ieave you aIone.
- I can't beIieve you hired a babysitter.
- I toId you I was oId enough.
- Hi.
- I'm Lisa, the babysitter.
- Great.
Can I take your coat?
Okay.
Hi.
I'm Billy.
You sure you don't want
a babysitter?
WouId you Iike me
to show you around?
No, it's okay.
I know it aIready.
I used to sit for the Defeos.
Kind of freaky being back here.
I'm Billy.
Yeah, I got you the first time.
Have a good night, Billy.
This is just what we needed,
don't you think?
Yeah. DefiniteIy.
You feeIing all right?
You know what?
I feeI better.
I think I just needed
to get out of the house.
Come on, drink up.
Are you trying
to get me drunk, Mr. Lutz?
That's the appeaI of marriage, hon.
Hopefully, I won't have to.
Be right out.
Hungry?
Kid, you read my mind.
The kids, they're--
They're going through
a tough time.
I guess they're just
adjusting to everything.
Yeah, well, we all are.
Do you feeI different?
What do you mean?
About us.
About me.
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
I feeI Iike for the first time in my Iife,
I'm sure about something.
And that's you.
And I'm gonna spend the rest
of my Iife making you happy.
Oh, boy, you know how
to turn on that Lutz charm.
Some peopIe say his tongue is fake.
I think it's all him.
Got this at a pinball arcade.
CooI.
So do you French?
Do I what?
Kissing, tongues.
No.
Did your famiIy know the Defeos?
- The who?
- The famiIy that Iived here before you.
No, we just moved here.
Well, you know what
happened to them, don't you?
No.
I really shouIdn't be telling you this.
Your parents are gonna be pissed.
It's okay.
Stop. That's not how you pIay.
- I can't hear you.
- Stop it. Let me try.
You're killing him.
So this wack job, Ronnie,
the guy that Iived here.
PeopIe in this town say
he heard voices telling him to do it.
The guy was a nut. I mean, first
he thinks his dog's out to get him.
So he kills it.
A few days Iater, he thinks his famiIy
is a bunch of demons.
So you know what he did?
Wasted them.
How did he do it?
Do what?
You are way too young to hear this.
So cover your ears.
And don't Iisten.
A rifIe.
He went room to room,
spIattering their heads as they sIept.
He killed his brothers
in this very room.
Right here.
In these beds.
It's kind of gross
you guys still sIeep in here.
Actually, it's fucking sick.
Yeah.
I'm totally freaking you out, kid.
I suck at babysitting.
This was the IittIe brat's room.
Jodie's.
You know, they found her in there.
- Jodie says you're a bad babysitter.
- Yeah?
Well, Jodie's--
What's the word? Dead.
Is not.
That IittIe shit got me fired.
Dare you to go in there.
You give me your Kiss poster
if I do it?
Okay.
You're going to make her mad.
Come on, guys.
Ha-ha, guys, this isn't funny.
Billy, MichaeI.
It's not opening. I can't open it.
- UnIock the fucking door.
- There's no Iock.
This isn't funny. Let me the fuck out.
Billy, MichaeI.
Let me out. Let me out of here.
Let me out of here!
What's going on?
Let me out.
Hi, Lisa.
Look what Ronnie did.
Let me out!
Let me out of here!
HeIp me. Let me out!
I saw Jodie.
Who's Jodie?
The IittIe girI.
She's dead.
She's supposed to be dead.
- It's one thing to pull a prank.
- We didn't pull a prank.
- It's another one to hurt someone.
- It was this house.
Shut up!
- George.
- I got this under controI.
You don't have you under controI.
What you guys did was wrong.
Stop it, Kathy.
Whatever you're doing...
...whatever you're saying
doesn't work.
From now on, I'm doing the
discipIining around here, end of story.
This house is bad, Mommy.
MichaeI, honey.
There's no bad houses.
There's just bad peopIe.
Why didn't you tell us
about the peopIe who died here?
- Where did you hear that?
- The babysitter toId me...
...that two IittIe boys died
in our room.
Goddamn babysitter's an idiot.
Get to bed. We'll deaI with this
in the morning.
No, I'm not sIeeping in that room.
It's gross.
- Me neither.
- Wipe that stupid Iook off your face...
...and go to bed.
Run.
Why all the yelling, Mommy?
It's nothing. It's over now, baby.
I need you to tell me
what happened with Lisa, honey.
Lisa was being mean to Jodie.
So Jodie hurt her.
- Jodie.
- It's okay, Mommy.
Jodie won't hurt you.
She thinks you're a good mommy.
But the man who Iives here...
...she says he's bad.
She wants him to go away.
He makes her do bad things.
Move it...
...from there to there.
Go.
And, Billy, don't come in
untiI you're finished.
What?
Is this discipIine or torture?
Thought it was meat Ioaf.
When the body suffers,
the spirit fIowers.
It's what my dad taught me.
His dad's not around
to teach him that, now, is he?
Billy, why is George such a jerk?
He's not a jerk. He's a douche bag.
And a weirdo.
And a doofus and a dipstick.
Catch them.
Kill them.
Catch them. Kill them.
Catch them.
Kill them.
- No! No!
- Look at me.
- No!
- What's the matter?
- God!
- It's me.
Baby, it's all right.
Do you use narcotics, Mr. Lutz?
No. But after this week,
I'm gonna give it...
...some serious thought.
Suffer from headaches, nausea?
Actually, I feeI great now.
Weird as that may sound.
Well, there's no sign
of a concussion.
No sign of any bruising at all.
I want you to give Dr. Stone a call.
Wait, wait, wait.
This is a psychiatrist.
- Do I Iook nuts to you?
- I'm not trying to offend you here.
I'm just trying to heIp you
figure out the probIem.
I feeI Iike it's my fauIt, George.
- Kath.
- I was the one who wanted this pIace.
- I put too much pressure on you.
- This is the Iife...
...that I want too, okay?
We got the oId American dream here.
Okay? There's no way in hell...
...that I'm Ietting that get away now.
I Iove you, George.
Billy, can I get my teddy?
She's reaI hungry.
Okay, go. And hurry up.
Mom finds out I Iet you out
of my sight, she's gonna kill me.
Hi, Mommy.
Look at me, Mommy.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
- CheIsea.
- CheIsea, don't move. Just sit down.
CheIsea.
HoId the Iadder.
Honey, stay there.
CheIsea.
- CheIsea.
- Goddamn it, CheIsea.
Which way?
Which way did they go?
Going Ieft.
CheIsea.
What are you doing up here?
I have to go with Jodie, Mommy.
Baby...
...you come to Mommy.
No!
George.
- Hang on.
- Hurry.
George!
George, pIease, God, I'm sIipping.
Chelsea.
What wouId you-- ?
Why wouId you do that?
Sorry. I'm sorry.
You can't do that to Mommy.
- Jodie wanted to show me something.
- There is no Jodie, okay?
- Yes, there is.
- No, there isn't!
- You have to stop this!
- Jodie's reaI.
- Jodie's reaI. She's--
- She is not reaI!
Liar! Liar!
Liar!
I've seen her.
She was gonna show me Daddy.
I just wanted to see Daddy.
Jodie promised to take me to Daddy.
She says I can stay here
so we can pIay together...
...forever and ever.
Do you miss your daddy?
Yes.
- Do you miss your daddy a Iot?
- Yes.
I know you miss your daddy, baby.
But no one can see him because...
...he's in heaven.
He's with the angeIs.
I just got so scared.
What's the matter with you peopIe?
Wacko famiIy.
Father Callaway?
Father.
Kathy Lutz.
Hello.
Do you have a moment?
It's my famiIy.
We've changed. It's--
It's Iike we've grown apart.
I don't think I understand.
There's something....
There's something eviI in my house.
I know it sounds...
...crazy, I know that.
I wouId think the same.
I just don't know where eIse to go.
There was a famiIy...
...Iived here some time ago.
They had a simiIar probIem.
The Defeos.
You knew them?
I'm Iiving in their house.
Now, hoId it steady.
Because if you get shaky,
I get shaky.
Go!
What, are you crying?
Why are you crying?
That wasn't so bad.
Pick up another Iog.
Hurry up, pick up another Iog.
Hurry up.
Put your hands up there.
No.
Put--
We're friends.
We're having fun, right?
Put your hands up there.
Go!
Come here, IittIe girI.
You're my favorite girI.
Catch them.
Kill them.
George.
I think there's something
seriousIy wrong here.
Something's not right.
What's not right?
We need to get out of here.
To just go. Just pack up and go.
No, no, no.
You know, you can't run away
from your probIems, Kath.
PIease, Iet's go, George.
- Somewhere. Anywhere.
- Did you hear that?
Do you hear that squeak?
I gotta fix that squeak.
Because, you know, these houses,
they're big....
Big projects. Kath, and you
can't just waIk away from it.
How did you get so fucking stupid?
What?
Everything we have is in this house.
Everything.
I'm not worried
about our goddamn money.
Oh, our money.
George, we're Iosing each other.
Don't you see that?
We stay here,
we'll have a house for the famiIy...
...onIy there won't be a famiIy.
It's aIways so coId in here.
WouId you Iet the stove aIone
and pay attention to me?
I'm not going anywhere,
neither are you.
So shut up about that!
Just shut up!
Goddamn it.
You're the one who wanted
this godforsaken house.
Well, now you got it.
Mom! Mom!
Home sweet home.
What is it, sweetie?
We can't find Harry anywhere.
He's gone.
I'll heIp you Iook in a sec, sweetie.
You seen Harry, George?
No, I haven't, Billy.
Maybe he ran away.
Harry never runs away, George.
What's the matter with you, William?
Get out of here now.
- Now!
- Fine. Come on, MichaeI.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the HoIy Spirit.
- Hello?
- Is your mommy home?
HoId on a second.
Mommy, there's someone
at the door.
Who is it, honey?
Come in, Father.
This is gonna sound strange...
...but you know the doll with one eye
that your daughter is hoIding?
Well, that beIonged to the IittIe girI
who Iived here before you.
Yes, it was Ieft here.
No, Mrs. Lutz, it was not Ieft here.
Father, what exactIy
are you trying to tell me?
I knew the Defeos very well.
I presided over their funeraI.
Jodie Defeo was buried
with that doll.
Oh, heavenIy Father.
AImighty God...
...we ask you to bIess...
...and sanctify this house.
To bIess all who Iive here...
...and to bring them the abundance
of all thy fruits.
Get out.
Father!
Why are you Ieaving us?
What's the matter?
It's okay. I'm here.
Catch them.
Kill them.
Oh, goddamn it, Harry!
Catch them.
Kill them.
There was a crime. A murder.
You know, the town has moved on.
And it is a distant memory now,
and the house is fine.
We don't open
for a few more minutes.
''Voices toId him to do it.''
''He just moved into the basement.''
''Twenty-eights days Iater
he killed them all.''
Oh, my God.
''Reverend Jeremiah Ketcham.''
''He started a mission for Indians.''
''He sIaughtered them all.''
''Over 20 bodies were found
in the Iake.''
Catch them.
Kill them.
Father.
Why did you run away
from my house?
Why did you abandon us?
Your house frightens me, Mrs. Lutz.
I just read about this man,
Ketcham...
...who tortured Indians on my Iand.
On my basement.
I read about how he sIit his throat...
...so that his presence
wouId Iive forever.
Do you beIieve this couId be true?
Ronnie Defeo came to me
weeks before the murders...
...and he spoke about hearing voices
and seeing things in the house.
I didn't beIieve him untiI yesterday.
Mrs. Lutz, get you and your famiIy
out of that house...
...right now.
- Hello?
- George.
George, I've just been to see
Father Callaway.
Listen to me, you gotta get you
and the kids out of the house.
George?
Are you there? George?
Billy! MichaeI! Where's George?
He's in the boathouse.
George, we have
to get out of here now.
George!
Are you fucking crazy, George?
Have you Iost your mind?
You tried to kill me.
- CheIsea!
- Mommy! Mommy!
I'm down here, Mommy!
CheIsea, honey,
what are you doing down here?
I think she misses her daddy.
Don't you?
Give me back my daughter.
I wanna taIk to you. Wait.
I wanna taIk to you!
Kids, get down here, now!
Kids, get down here!
- Billy, heIp me push this!
- Mom, where are you going?
Billy!
- Hurry. Go.
- Billy!
Mom, why are you wet?
Mommy! Mommy!
Come on, Mom!
Hurry.
Billy, come on!
Run! Go, go, go!
You're stuck! You're stuck!
Stay here!
Great!
Let go of my mom, you bastard!
Let go right now! Let go.
- What the hell is your probIem?
- Let's go.
These kids are out of controI.
- Mom, it's stuck!
- It won't open!
Where's CheIsea? CheIsea!
- Hurry, hurry, Billy. Hurry.
- Come on. Let's go. Be quiet, be quiet.
Billy!
I want you to hoId on tight.
Jump, baby.
- Come on, honey.
- Come on.
- Come on, MichaeI.
- No, Mommy.
- No.
- Hurry, baby.
Come on, MichaeI.
- Come on, hurry.
- Let's get out of here.
- Come here. Come here.
- No.
You Ieave him aIone.
Kill them.
Don't hurt him!
Back the fuck up!
Kill them.
Hurry. Let's grab some rope.
Kathy, kill me!
You kill me, or I'll kill you!
Nobody's dying today.
Okay, Iet's get him in the boat.
Why are we taking him?
Let's just Ieave him here.
I can't expIain it to you right now. We
have to get him away from the house.
Don't even Iook at it, Kathy.
Let's get out of here.
Subtitles by ARAVIND B
[by_agentsmith@yahoo.com]