What's the matter?
Tommy!
Hi!
Tommy, Tommy, Tommy!
Hey!
Hey.
Tommy.
Tommy...
What are you doing here?
Come to Mother.
John! One of the snails has gotten out!
Could you put it back with the others?
Okay! I'm coming, Mother.
Goddamn! One of my birds got out!
Catch him! What were you doing with
him out of the cage?
- No one likes to be caged in.
- You can't trust them for a minute!
Feed him!
Come on, come on!
Get back here!
Come here!
Be careful with the table!
Catch him! Don't let him go
into the kitchen!
Hurry! Catch him!
Catch him!
Be careful with the lamp!
Now where's he going?
John! Hurry!
You're in a lot of trouble.
What are you doing? Get down from
there! You're going to fall!
The bird is stuck behind the cupboard.
I can't reach him.
You've got to force him out. You can
do it. Get down!
Listen!
He's moving.
You stay here. I'll be right back.
Here.
Use this.
Be careful. Don't hurt him.
Don't force it.
Be careful!
Don't hurt him.
Slowly.
- I've got him, Ma! I've got him, Mother!
- Be careful! Don't hurt him.
Slowly.
He won't get away again. He knows
he can't hide from me.
Now, give him to me, John.
Give him to me.
Give him to me, John.
You did a good job, John.
John is a good boy.
You mustn't run off like that, Tommy.
You're very, very bad!
See what happens when
you disobey Mother.
It's a very rare genetic chain
which causes the distinctive
characteristics
and the unique shape of this kind of
retinal activity.
This is one of the rarest examples.
It's from Mr. Murphy's grandfather's
collection
which was started at the turn of the
century.
The Murphy family has continued to
add to the collection until today.
The collection includes samples from
every country in the world.
Obviously, the collection is only shown
to doctors and graduates for research,
under special permission by the Murphys.
Mr. Pressman is our orderly in charge
of its maintenance.
Pressman!
What are you doing over there?
Bring me the key.
Sorry, doctor.
I can't get used to these lenses.
They hurt.
Don't worry. It's quite normal for them
to feel uncomfortable at first.
These drops will help.
Please get them out of my eyes.
I can't stand it! They're cutting into
my eyes! Take them out!
Are you deaf? I told you to take
these things out of my eye!
They're hurting me!
- Take them out!
- Please, please.
Don't get upset. I promise they'll stop
hurting in a few minutes.
Take them out! Do you hear me?
You wear them! You need them
more than I do!
No. I'm not allowed. My mother would...
Excuse me.
Where are you going? Come back here!
Where is Dr. Murphy?
Get these things out of my eyes! They're
hurting. Get them out!
- Calm down please.
- How do you expect me to calm down?
- The man is a complete nut.
- I'm sorry this happened.
He's very sensitive to comments about
his eyes.
He's diabetic and he's
losing his vision.
Then why is he working here?
I'm sorry for not getting to you sooner.
John is usually good with the patients.
The schedule has been crazy because
of the holidays.
I never expected such a strange person
to be working in Dr. Murphy's office.
Not at these prices!
Our intention is to help everyone.
In fact, his mother is one of the main...
I don't care about anyone's mother!
I'm late as it is.
I want to see Dr. Murphy next time.
In fact, his mother is one of the main...
I don't care about anyone's mother...
I want to see Dr. Murphy next time.
You can see.
You have no idea
what it's like to really suffer.
But you will!
Just wait!
You'll be sorry!
She doesn't know how much they need you.
John is your best boy, isn't he Mother?
Yes, John. You're my best boy and
the best surgeon in town.
And now, you must start thinking of
the spirals.
The spiral that's coming into your head.
Think of the center.
The center of the spiral.
Imagine the spiral in your mind.
Think of the center and
you'll be with me.
All finished.
Slowly, my baby.
Deep, easy breaths.
Let your mind float into space.
Feel the power and flow of your heart.
Relax.
You can feel it.
Your eyelids are heavy.
Your eyes are closed
and you cannot open them.
Your blood is rushing from
your heart to your head.
Feel it. Your head is filling up
with blood.
Good.
Now your blood is flowing from your
head back to your heart.
Feel it! It makes you strong!
Now you are with Mommy as one.
Like before.
Together as one.
For years you were like a snail.
Hiding, happy.
Go get the buzzer!
It's impossible to get ready like this.
- Yeah?
- Ms. Robinson?
Just a minute. Who is this?
My name is John Pressman.
I'm from Dr. Murphy's office.
There's been a mistake. Ms. Robinson
took the wrong pair of contact lenses.
That sounds like her. Come in.
Come in.
What do you want?
I told you it's about Ms. Robinson's
contact lenses.
I see. Aren't you working late tonight?
Caroline, it's for you!
Who is it?
He's from Murphy's.
Oh, no! You!
- What do you want?
- I'm sorry to bother you so late.
You were right to complain about
those lenses.
They gave you the wrong ones.
I brought the right pair with me. I'd
be glad to put them in for you.
No, no, no. Not now.
I just finished putting my makeup on.
I'll go to the clinic tomorrow.
Come on, honey.
I want to see you with the contacts on.
You'll look gorgeous!
- I really don't have a lot of time.
- It'll only take a few minutes.
I promise there's nothing to worry about.
These are your exact measurements.
They won't hurt at all.
Oh, alright. But hurry, we're
late as it is.
Now, you won't feel a thing. I promise.
I hope not after what happened
this morning.
You're right. It didn't hurt.
You know how sorry I am for what
happened this morning.
I appreciate the fact that you didn't
say anything to Dr. Murphy about it.
I really appreciate it a lot.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I really appreciate it.
Caroline?
Oh my God!
Caroline! Caroline!
You're crazy!
Hello?
- Mrs. Pressman?
- Yes?
This is Marnie from Dr. Murphy's office.
He asked me about making an appointment
for your eyes. Mrs. Pressman?
We like John and appreciate his effort,
but lately he's been a little strange...
I understand the situation completely!
You needn't worry about John
returning to your hospital.
Dr. Murphy knows that John is the best
surgeon he's ever seen!
He's an orderly!
You don't want him anymore.
Jealousy!
You will all pay for this!
Now John go for those guys!
Don't stop!
Go on! Go on!
Go on!
Did you see that?
Yeah, so what?
Gross!
So disgusting.
Shut up and watch!
I was really scared.
Crazy!
That's right, John.
That's right.
John's a good boy.
Go on! Go on!
Go on!
It's too much.
Don't worry about it.
It's only a movie.
All those eyes! All this blood!
It's making me dizzy.
This guy is really sick.
What the hell is he going to do?
Oh, my.
Stop with that!
It's this film.
I don't want to see this.
It's making me sick!
Linda, I want to leave.
Never again. You're one big baby.
There's something about this guy that
gives me the creeps.
Come, on. This is fun.
He's an eye hunter.
You're serious?
You think this is funny?
- It's disgusting!
- Oh, come on!
Next time I'll take you
to a Disney movie.
Please.
I want to leave. I'm serious.
Tough. I don't.
My eyes are really hurting!
I can't see.
Are you going to blame this
on the movie too?
Mama Bear has the same problem with her
contacts. Take them out.
John!
Linda! Have you got a Kleenex?
For the last time, stop bugging me!
Mama,
I don't feel...
My head hurts.
Let those eyes go!
They let you go from the hospital.
From now on, all the eyes of the city
will be ours!
All the eyes of the city will be ours!
- I still feel dizzy, Mother.
- Eat! Eat! Eat! You need energy!
There's a knife. Good boy!
Very good! Do as I tell you always.
Put your hand over your heart.
Feel the power!
Blood is still in your head.
Slowly it empties to
return to your heart.
Your with Mother now.
You want to go back, don't you?
Mommy will open the door.
See the eye!
Slowly, my baby.
Deep, easy breaths.
Let your mind float into space.
Feel the power and flow of your heart.
Relax.
See the light.
The light beyond.
First,
White to black.
Black to white.
One and two...
and two are one.
Your eyelids are heavy.
Your eyes are closed
and you cannot open them.
The blood is rushing from your heart
to your head.
Feel it!
Your head is filling up with blood!
Now the blood is flowing from your head
back to your heart.
Feel it! It makes you strong!
Right
left.
Come closer.
Very good.
Left to right.
Right
to left.
Good.
Slowly,
softly.
Follow the light!
Very good.
Honey, what's the matter?
Are you okay?
I feel dizzy too.
I don't know what's happening to me.
Why don't you go to the lobby
for some air?
Alone? Are you kidding?
For years, you were like a snail.
Hiding.
Happy.
Hiding. Happy.
Hiding.
Happy.
One and two
and two are one.
Right hand.
Left hand.
This stuff really works?
Now run! Run.
Don't stop!
Run .
Run, run!
Run!
They are going to be very sorry, Mother.
They're not nice people.
Patty! Do you feel better?
Yeah, I feel okay.
- But I want to leave.
- Come on. I'm having fun.
I'm not!
Oh, no!
Now he's going to a movie theater!
Wow! That's going to be hot!
One, please.
Hey you! Put the ticket in the box.
Linda!
This is gonna be too much!
Oh, no!
Linda.
Be quiet!
Linda, I really can't take this anymore.
Please let's go.
I'm not kidding!
Patty, give me a break. It's not real.
It's make-believe.
Besides, if you want me to leave,
give me back my 5 dollars.
I can't stand it!
- Okay if you want to stay, I'm leaving.
- Good for you.
See you at school.
Excuse me. Where is the restroom?
It's down the hall on the left.
Hey! Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
That's right. John's a good boy.
Now go for those two!
Go on!
Do it!
Don't stop!
Yes!
Keep going. Don't stop.
Don't stop!
Now seriously,
Mother will always take care of you.
You're not alone!
You're safe with me.
Your eyes are my eyes.
Your hands are my hands.
I'm going to get some more popcorn.
Want anything?
You will do all that I say!
Leave me alone!
Linda!
Linda, he's in there!
What are you doing here?
I thought you left.
- He's in there! I saw him!
- Who?
Him! The man over there.
He's in the ladies room.
It's not him. He hasn't moved
from his seat.
Listen to me. I swear to God there's
a man in the ladies room.
Creep!
I'll do anything you say. Just go check
for yourself and see if he's there.
You're a pain in the ass! I'm never
going to the movies with you again.
- You're worse than my baby brother.
- Please? Just this one time.
Please?
Alright. I have to go anyway.
I'll get some more popcorn too.
I'll go with you.
No way! Stay here and
tell me what happens.
Linda, wait!
Here. Have some popcorn.
Linda...
John, come back home.
You're losing me. You need my strength
again, John.
No. I'm staying, Mother.
I can do it by myself.
Why? You can't do it alone!
Think of the spiral.
By myself.
John, think of the spirals. The center
of the spirals.
The spirals...
I feel...
Remember the spirals.
You need me, John. You know you need me.
Be with me John and do as I say.
Come back home before it's too late.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
Come back, come back.
Hi! Boy, you must know this picture
by heart. How many times...
Such a kid.
I can prove myself, Mother.
I don't need you anymore.
I can do it alone.
Poor kid. This movie's
really getting to her.
Yeah, it got to me too.
She's still pretty spaced-out.
What are you doing in the ladies room?
Get out! Don't touch me!
You pervert!
I can do it by myself, Mother.
Come back, I beg you! Come back!
Come back, come back!
Keep an eye on the register.
Don't be too long.
Thanks, I won't be longer than an hour.
Anyone there?
Miss, are you alright?
My friend is in the bathroom.
She's been gone for a long time.
She'll be right back. Don't cry.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I'm scared.
Is she okay?
I think so, but she's crying.
I'd like some popcorn please.
Are you okay?
What were you doing in the ladies room?
Say something to her.
Maybe you should go find her friend.
Excuse me, Miss. Maybe I can help you.
What's your friend's name?
I'll go look for her.
Linda.
Mother.
Just stay in your seat and I'll
have your friend back.
It's alright. Don't worry.
My husband went to get your friend.
Hello?
Excuse me?
Excuse me? Hello?
Hello?
Is there anybody in here?
Don't be silly. She's probably talking
to some cute guy in the lobby.
You'll see.
You won't see.
Don't worry, Mother.
I won't leave.
Nobody...
will...
Calm down, calm down.
No one is going to leave here.
No one.
Don't worry, Mother. I won't leave.
Nobody will.
I love you, Mother.
- Please! You have to help me!
- Excuse me?
My friend's in the theater!
There's a murderer in there! I saw him!
Hey! What are you doing?
Oh my God! Mary!
Are you...are you crazy?
But you have to help!
I'd like to help, but I can't.
But you can't leave!
He's killing people!
Hello, police?
There's a madman in the theater!
He tried to kill me!
Hurry!
Emergency! Calling all cars...
- I'll be right back.
- Don't leave.
Just be a minute. Stay put.
...he's killing people!
We need to get help!
Tell me where your friend is and
I'll see if she needs any help.
In the theater! There's a man going
around killing people!
I'm sure you're mistaken.
- Mama.
- Come home!
I'm going to kill you, you bastard!
- Quiet! Where are you going?
- I want some candy.
Quiet.
Laura, what's the matter? Laura!
Oh no!
Look! There's a man in the projection
booth! Come on!
Stop crying. It'll be alright.
Don't worry.
There's no way out!
No one's gonna leave!
- I'll go inside and look around.
- Don't go!
- I've given you everything you ever...
- Mother, please. Take me home.
I'll be a good boy.
You've got my power and my energy!
You idiot! How can you do anything
without me!
Come back before it's too late!
Bastard.
My God.
Let's go find a phone booth.
Mother?
I'll be a good boy.
John, don't do this to me!
Think of the spiral!
That's going to help you!
And the snails, John!
Remember we owe it to them, John!
John! Leave this instant!
I demand you leave the theater!
Why, John, why?
Get away, fly away!
Fly, fly, fly!
Come home!
No!
No, no I won't!
I'm sick of you! I hate you!
I despise you!
Don't worry, Mother.
Don't worry.
Stop!
Stay back!
Alright, take it easy mister.
I don't want to hurt you.
Get out of the way.
Get out of the way!
Do you understand?
Give me your knife.
Give me your knife!
Back! Get back!
I'm going to kill you bastard.
I warned you.
You had to leave me to be on your own.
Why didn't you listen to me?
I'm coming to take you home.
Don't leave the theater.
You fool! Alice gave up so much for you!
What's your problem?
What's going on?
Nobody leave your seats!
Get up! Get up!
Stay where you are! Don't move!
You get down! Everyone down!
Everyone down or I'll kill you!
I know what I'm doing!
There's a madman in there!
Stay calm, police are on their way!
Please don't let anything happen
to Patty.
- Please, dear God.
- No one will harm your friend.
We will find a way out.
Stay away from the exits!
Back, back!
I don't want to hurt anyone.
The doors are locked!
- She can stay here.
- Why don't you go inside?
I'm right here.
Take positions and stand by.
- What have we got here, Captain?
- Looks bad.
Don't move and nobody gets hurt!
Stay in your seats!
Stay calm! Get down!
I told you! Stay away!
There's no way out.
Take this one to the 2nd ambulance.
It's the third so far. Dead.
I'm waiting for you Mother.
Then hurry.
We'll take it from here.
Let's go!
- Unit One report.
- Pretty dark in there.
Armed Caucasian male, 5 foot 7.
Hostage, female.
They're in front of the screen.
Looks like he's got a .38.
Tell him there's no escape. He's
surrounded. And drop the girl.
Keep the lights off to
protect the people.
Establish a dialog with the guy.
Test his reactions.
...the L.A.P.D.
...got you surrounded.
There's no way out.
Let the girl go!
Put your hands in the
air and don't move!
No! I can't leave.
Not until Mother comes to get me.
A real weirdo.
In my opinion, there is no way we can
establish a dialog with this guy.
I think I'm going to pass out.
Try and breathe as evenly as possible.
I'm not going to drop the gun!
Just leave me alone!
Leave me alone! I'll kill her!
I don't want to hurt anyone!
I have to stay here.
She's coming to take me home!
Leave me alone!
Mother, please take me back.
I want to go home!
Don't say anything else to him.
He may kill the girl.
Wait for the right moment.
Don't take any chances.
Wait a few seconds, and if he doesn't
drop the girl, we'll turn on the lights.
Got that?
Yes, Mother. I'm waiting for you.
I'll be good.
Captain, I think we should stop the
movie. He's talking to the screen.
Have you got a clear shot?
No, not yet.
The girl's too close to him.
The light! The light!
I see the light!
I see it's power!
I'll be a...
good boy.
I won't hurt anyone anymore.
- I'm sorry I didn't believe you at first.
- It's okay.
It's gonna be okay. She'll be alright.
Don't do it!
You bastard!
You took my mother away from me!
Wait a minute - he dropped the girl.
Take him out clean. All units stand by.
What are you looking at?
I want your eyes too!
Like all the others!
- He's in there. He's got a girl.
- Don't worry. He's dead.
They got the killer. Your friend's
alright. She'll be out in a minute.
You certainly took
your time to get here.
We got here as fast as we could.
Roll over, calm down.
Patty!
I was so scared I couldn't see you!
I'm sorry I didn't believe you!
- Did he hurt you?
- I was really...
It must have been terrible for you!
I'm with you now, Patty.
Don't worry, I won't leave.
I promise I won't leave you.
She thought the scalpel was in her eye,
but it was all in her imagination.
In a couple of days, she'll be completely
recovered. It was quite a shock.
I think she'd be better
off staying here.
It was all in her imagination,
but for her it was quite real.
You don't have to worry any longer.
It's best we leave her alone now,
I don't want her excited.
Don't worry. Your daughter will be fine.
Your not going to leave me alone?
She's had enough excitement for today.
Don't worry, but I have to go now.
The doctor wants you to get some rest.
Stay.
I'll be back first thing
tomorrow morning.
Come on now. Time to go.
Come back tomorrow.
- You have to leave now.
- I have to leave, Patty.
Are you sure I can't stay? We won't
talk or anything.
- I'll just lay on the couch.
- Your friend needs to sleep.
With you here, she'll just start
remembering what happened.
- See you tomorrow.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
The girl in Room 22. If she wakes up,
give her this tranquilizer.
See you tomorrow.
Like the doctor said, it's all in
your imagination.
I really don't exist.