It scares us, just thinking about it.
When you hear it
you're gonna think we're insane.
It started out small.
Like a leg or a hand
was in a different position and...
And it's head was looking up
instead of down and...
Then one day
it was in a completely different room.
It's moving around by itself.
Camilla got in touch with a medium.
We learned from her
that the doll was possessed
by a girl named
Annabelle Higgins.
She had lost her parents
and had taken a liking to my doll.
All she wanted was to be friends.
When we heard this
we felt really sorry for her, I mean...
We're nurses.
We help people.
But then...
Things got worse.
How did you end up with it?
It was a gift from my mom,
for my birthday.
I don't know where she got it.
But...
We are beyond terrified.
God honour sacrifice.
And our sacrifices touch god's heart.
And move his hand.
Jesus said: This is my commandment.
That you love one another
as I have loved you.
Greater love hath no-one than this.
That he lay down his life for his friends.
Let us pray.
Good to see you too.
See you soon.
Hey you!
Ok. So eh...
Who won?
John.
But he cheats.
What? I Ehh..
It was two against one.
I had to do something, right?
Yeah Right!
Where did Sharon get off to?
We'll find her.
Thanks.
Bye.
Pete send you after me?
I swear, one day he thinks I'll just...
run off too.
Men!
What would they be without us?
I mean honestly.
We appreciate the last speech.
Sure thing.
You just make sure to take care
of this wife and baby for us.
Did we ask about names yet?
Sharon!
- What?!
It's not prying.
It's just conversation.
We're still working on them anyway.
But we're pretty sure...
John, if it's a boy.
And we're thinking Phyllis if it's a girl.
We were?
Yeah. You said you liked it.
He, I never said that.
It's my grandmother's name.
And I can't stand your grandmother.
Oh dear.
It's not only me.
I mean nobody can stand her.
No, she's right.
Everyone hates her.
Ok. Well...
On that note Sharon.
Let's go inside.
These two, they have a lot to talk about.
Thank you and...
think nothing of it.
Just remember...
children are a blessing.
Indeed they are.
And then they learn to talk.
I guess that's a no on Phyllis?
We shouldn't talk about the baby so much,
in front of them.
It just aint right.
Why not?
Well, they only lost their daughter
two years ago.
Loose their daughter? Mia?
She ran away
and joined up with the hippies.
By now she's probably got three husbands
and calls herself Star.
Well...
Even Star
is a better name than Phyllis.
Oh. You.. you didn't lock it?
No. Why would I?
You have to start locking it John.
I mean it's...
it's a different world now.
They call themselves "The Family".
But police officials
have labelled them a dangerous cult
residing on the grounds of Spahn Ranch.
Once used as the backdrop
for many well-known westerns.
The Family is estimated to have
close to thirty gatherers
Many of them with histories
of heavy drug use
and criminal behaviour.
...are in custody awaiting charges
for the brutal Tate and LaBianca murders.
They held Los Angeles in the grip of fear
before police investigators
were led to the suspects...
Hey Honey?!
Do you think you could shut off the TV?
It's making it a little hard
to concentrate.
...their leader, Charles Manson,
was sometimes referred to
as both God and Satan,
by his devoted followers.
And had predicted an
Armageddon like event he called...
Helter Skelter.
Thank you!
Hey, you know. You shouldn't even
be watching that stuff.
Alright. It could upset the baby.
There's new research out there...
Oh boy! More new research?
- It's true!
They are learning that the babies in utero
experience more of the outside world
than they ever thought possible.
They recognize voices
and noises. Songs.
You know, I bet the man
that did that research
spent millions of dollars
when they could have just
asked the mother for free.
How's it going in here?
Ehhm... Well...
I am trying my hardest to enjoy it.
Everyone keeps telling me that..
Once you're in the residency
it gets a million times worse.
Haven't even mentioned the fact
that I'm about to be a new father.
Why not?
I don't know.
Sometimes you just don't
wanna hear how.. difficult
it's gonna be.
Difficult?
You know. Maybe difficult's
not the right word.
Challenging.
Are you talking about the residency
or me and the baby.
I don't know.
All of it I guess.
I mean...
It's not like this is an ideal situation
for what I'm about to go through.
I.. We.. We're about
to go through.
I didn't mean for that
to sound like it did.
I'm sorry.
It's not like...
difficult or challenging
or bad things anyway.
Look..
I know that I've been a little...
caught up in my own world lately.
Some people might call it self centered.
Some people?
Most people.
Everyone.
Can we just go back
and redo the last two minutes, please?
Please?
It's fine.
I know you were stressed.
I'm just a little.. Ehh...
over sensitive lately.
Yeah...
Do you want me to tell you why?
Yes Doctor!
In my Ehm...
almost.. expert opinion
you are a little sensitive
because you are a lot pregnant.
Hey I'm sorry.
I mean... I am...
Yes, I'm.. I'm stressed about
finishing med-school
and I'm freaking out about matching but...
I've never been happier.
Ever.
Ok? And that's because of you.
And it.
You know what?
There's something I wanna give you.
Oh no. The last time you said that
I ended up pregnant
Yes you did.
Ok. Close your eyes.
I was waiting on this
until the baby, but...
You were feeling a little...
Guilty, yes.
Because of what I said.
Ok.
Open your eyes.
You didn't...
My god John.
That's the one right?
Yes.
Where did you find her?
I mean...
Do you know how long I've been looking?
- I know.
I had completely lost hope.
Oh, I have my ways.
We'll be a little short on the rent
the next few of months, but eh...
There.
She fits right in.
That completes the set-up, right?
Yes. It does.
Thank you.
I love her.
John?
John. Wake up.
What is it? The baby?
No no. Next door..
I heard a scream.
I.. I think something's wrong.
Stay here.
I'm gonna check it out.
John. Wait.
Shouldn't we call the cops?
Because you think you heard a scream?
Just let me go check it out.
They'd do the same for us.
If they heard me scream,
I'd rather they call the cops.
Think they heard you scream.
Just be careful.
I will.
John?
Oh my god!
You're covered in blood.
It's not mine. Go back inside
and call an ambulance right now.
Go!
911 operator.
I need.. I need an ambulance.
What's your location?
307 Gardener Road.
Yes.
What's your emergency?
I.. I don't know.
But..
There's a lot of blood.
Please. Just be as fast as possible.
I like your dolls.
My.. My husband's coming back.
Just..Just...
Take whatever you want.
Just.. Just get out.
Get out.
Get out of here.
Open up!
Open up! It's the police!
Open the door!
You're alright.
We got you.
I'm right here.
I'm right here with you.
In a tragic scene,
described by one investigator
as reminiscent of a horrific cult ritual.
A man and his wife
was brutally stabbed to death
by their estranged daughter,
Annabelle Higgins.
And her unidentified boyfriend.
The two are believed
to be members of a cult.
The male suspect was shot and killed
as police arrived on scene.
While the daughter was found
in an apparent suicide
her throat slit open.
One officer summed up these blood
soaked murders by saying:
In all my years I have never seen anything
quite as gruesome as this.
Damn well the amniotic sac
wasn't punctured.
And isn't ruptured.
We are seeing signs of strain
on the cervix.
Most likely caused by the trauma.
Which is why..
I am putting you on bed rest
for the remainder of your pregnancy.
Now..
You can get up and use the facilities.
If you do so delicately.
But anything beyond that would
be putting you and your child at risk.
Alright?
Thank you.
- Ok.
The lock!
I had them scrub everything.
At least twice.
You can perform surgery in there.
It's so clean.
You didn't have to do that.
You're on bed rest for a while.
You'd go crazy if I didn't.
Just.. Don't get all obsessed
with those daytime soaps.
You know I can't stand them.
I'll bring your sewing back in later on.
Ok? We can turn the whole room into your
own little sweatshop.
What is it?
You think the baby is Ok?
The baby is not even aware
of what happened.
Oh really? Because I heard there's some new
research that Ehm.. you know.
Oh yeah.
You heard the doctors.
So if you listen to them
the baby is fine.
The baby is fine.
You're its mother, right?
If it wasn't you would know.
What if something does happen?
What?
What's gonna happen? When...
Like when I go into labor, John.
Yeah.
You'll save the baby over me?
Come on.
We have to talk about it.
I mean, I can't have it.
If anything ever happened to it.
Hey, promise me.
You promise me you'll save the baby.
Yeah. Yeah.
I promise.
But you know what?
It's gonna be okay.
You are gonna be fine
What the hell is that?
John!
John?
It's okay.
I'm your friend.
You know that, don't you?
Are you Phil?
Of course I am.
Well, then I have a friend.
You have been...
...after dinner...
even dancing.
How'd it go today?
Eh. TV went out again.
Really?
Must be that room.
It never did that in the den.
What is all that?
Ehh..This is a bunch of random stuff
that I picked up at the store.
To satisfy any pregnancy cravings.
That's funny.
I haven't really
had any cravings.
Ohh! Pickles.
Oh my god. You know what would go
really well with Pickles?
John Gordon. We are meant to be together.
Yeah. I know.
Like eh.. Mustard and Pickles.
Did you have that big meeting today?
Yeah. I did.
He eh.. thinks I've got a real shot
at Huntington memorial.
Of course you do.
It's in Pasadena though.
So further from the beach.
Okay with that?
Change of view would be good.
Yeah.
There's this one day conference
in Sacramento
that he thinks I should attend.
That eh.. could help move things
in that direction.
Fly up for a day in a few days.
Only a couple of days?
I'll be fine.
We gotta get you back to bed.
You shouldn't be sitting up this long.
Oh! And Detective Clarkin called today.
Said he wanted to stop by
at some point this week.
I've already told him everything.
I.. I'd rather just forget the whole thing.
I know. He just said he wanted
to go over a few things.
The doll.
We need to get rid of it.
I mean, she had it in her hands.
No. You're right.
You're right.
Just Ehm.. Consider it gone.
I suppose you can tell Detective Clarkin
he can stop by whenever's convenient.
It's not like I'm going anywhere
anytime soon.
They were members of a cult.
We've confirmed
that it was Higgins daughter.
And her boyfriend.
You may have heard on the news...
That cults are taking over the world.
It's not quite as prevalent
as they'd have you believe.
You're gonna have a hard time
convincing us of that.
Were they satanic?
It's okay.
She should know.
Yes.
Yes it is. It is believed
they had interest in the occult.
That they did this to prove their devotion.
A sort of..
Violence for violence's sake.
But that's crazy.
Crazy people do crazy things, Ma'am.
But that's all this was.
I tell you what.
I'll dig a little deeper.
See what I can find.
But if I come up with anything further,
I'll reach anoth...
- No!
Thank you.
But Ehm.. Unless it has something
to do with our safety, I...
I'd rather not hear any more about it.
Okay.
I understand.
Hold it right,
right, right there.
Thank you.
I'm making popcorn.
Are you sure it's okay for the baby
to have this much butter and s...
How are you feeling?
Well, nervous.
They are gonna love you.
I love you.
I love you too.
I got you. I got you.
Hey.
Hi.
I'm so sorry that I wasn't here.
I'm so sorry.
Behind you.
Congratulations.
It's a girl.
This is my baby.
Oh my gosh.
Leah?
Leah.
Hi.
Hi Leah. It's your daddy.
Look at her.
John.
John. The fire.
Oh, Shh shh.
It's fine. She's fine. You're fine.
I don't know what happened.
It's like the house is cursed.
I can never go back there again.
I can't. Not with her now.
You don't have to.
Ever.
Hey honey.
You all set?
Any second now...
She's gonna...
And then...
You need to get out more.
Come on.
We'll be late.
You really think we should go?
I mean, Leah's being a little fuzzy.
Mia. She's fine.
Okay. You both need to get out of here.
You've been cooped up in here too much.
I know, but it's...
Look look. Get outta here.
It's beautiful. Okay?
Come on. You need this.
I need this. Leah...
She could definitely use some color.
Stop it.
Put some of that eh..
What do you call it?
Oh Cocoa Butter Milk.
We should just slap her with some
Cocoa Butter.
Okay okay, I will go
as long as you stop talking.
We promise.
Let's go.
- Come on
We cannot let fear control us.
For we are never truly alone
when we walk with God.
Isn't it true that the more we know
about something
the less fear we have from it?
We need to face our fears
to better understand them.
We need to shine a bright light...
on the monsters that feed
on our insecurities, on our anxieties.
And on the doubt
that we cast on ourselves.
We need to remember
that for those who have faith
this life of truth is everlasting.
Mia.
Mind if I take a picture
of your little one?
I like hang photos of the newest
members of the congregation
on the visitors bulletin board.
Ah, yes.
Sure. Of course.
No no no.
Hold her on your lap.
Oh, you don't need me in the photo.
Of course I do...
Mothers are closer to God
than any other living creature.
For only they can share
in God's creative miracle.
Uno, dos, tres.
Wonderful.
That should do it.
I still feel the Higgins' absence,
every Sunday.
I imagine it must be dif...
Oh, there's...
There's John. I should go.
We still have a lot of boxes to unpack.
Well, unfortunately I...
I don't have a prayer
to help you with that.
Well I
guess there are some things
we need to take care of ourselves.
Yes.
Goodbye.
Father Perez.
I think this is the last of them.
Somebody pop the Champagne.
I'll get her.
Wait a sec. How'd that get in there?
I swear I threw it out.
I don't know.
Things must have gotten mixed up
after the fire.
Here.. Give her to me.
No.
You gave her to me as a gift.
Like Father Perez said,
we should celebrate our strength, right?
You sure?
Yeah.
There. She fits right in.
General Hospital:
Where doctors and nurses
dedicate their lives
to that wonder which
is a human being.
That ever changing challenge
of love and hope.
Loneliness and despair.
General Hospital.
On ABC.
Doctors and nurses with first names
and last names
and tragedies of their own.
Uh!
Oh.. I'm so sorry.
Oh sorry.
Thank you.
Hi.
Do you live here too?
We live in...
- Don't tell her.
Were not supposed to tell.
She's a stranger.
That's a very good rule to have.
I like your doll.
I have one just like it.
You too?
A few actually.
I'm Mia and this is Leah.
Yeah.
What's your name?
It's Nan...
I said don't tell her!
Well...
Maybe one day we can all be friends.
Hey.
You're the new tenants at the
Palmyra, aren't you?
Yes.
I suppose this little one is
pretty much new to everything?
This is Leah.
She's adorable.
I.. I'm Mia.
Evelyn.. Hi.
Here.
This is my daughters favorite.
Maybe Leah will like it too
when she's a little older.
That's very sweet.
Thank you.
Well, feel free to stop by any time.
Hey.
Look what they drew for you.
See? That's us.
Making friends already.
I guess we're getting a little exercise.
Look at this.
Should we ehh..
Talk to their parents?
If Leah did something like this I..
I would wanna know about it.
Leah would never do anything like this.
This isn't even good. I mean..
Look at the proportions.
Ohh John!
Yes Mia. If she did
I would wanna know too.
Okay? So lets go...
Find out where they live.
Introduce ourselves.
But let's not make a big deal
outta this, Okay?
It's not like this is a threat or anything.
It's just one kid
with an overactive imagination.
I know. I.. I know.
I know.
You gotta remember that we moved here
to get away from what happened.
We packed up our clothes.
We.. We packed up our furniture.
We packed up the good memories.
But the fears...?
And the anxieties?
We promised to leave those behind.
It is not as easy as it sounds, John.
You're off at work, honey.
Adult conversation and I'm.. here..
Working yourself up over nothing.
Look.. I'm sorry...
Okay. You know what?
Tomorrow night.
I don't have to work late, okay, so...
I say I come home.
We sit down.
We have a nice dinner.
And we have some...
Adult conversation.
Okay?
Can we do that?
Cherish is the word I use to describe
All the feeling that I have
Hiding here for you inside
You don't know how many times
I've wished that I had told you
I've wished that I could hold you
You don't know how many times
I've wished that I could
Mold you into someone who could
Cherish me as much as I
Cherish you.
Oh, I'm beginning to think
that man has never found
The words that would make you wa...
Oh God..
Hello?!
Who are you?
There isn't anyone here.
It's just you and me and Leah.
I know what I saw.
It was her.
- Mia...
There are things happening that I..
That I...
That I can't explain.
What things?
Baby..Are.. Are you sure they're not just
manifestations of your anxiety?
I'm.. It's perfectly normal
for new mothers to experience
postpartum..
- You know that being a doctor
doesn't make you an expert
on everything, right?
I think we should talk to someone.
Like who?
A shrink?
I'm not crazy John.
I'm not crazy
I'm not saying that you're crazy, okay?
And I'm not talking about a shrink.
So we turn to the church, Father.
It's what my parents did when they...
hit a rough patch.
And it worked for them.
I understand of course.
But you two hit more
than just a rough patch.
In a matter of months you've
experienced the very worst of life...
And the very best.
A pendulum swing like that.
It's enough to shake
even the strongest foundations.
But you survived.
And instead of trying to forget
this bad history...
I think you should use it
as an example of how strong
you two can be when united.
You don't come out the other side,
of something like this, weaker.
You come out stronger.
You're right.
Good.
Hi!
- Ohh, Hi.
Mia, right?
- Yes.
And of course I remember Leah.
You are...?
Hi. John.
- Hi.
This is Evelyn Jones.
From the bookstore I was telling you about.
All right, yeah yeah...
Thank you for the book.
I couldn't help myself.
I saw your girls and I...
I felt like I had known them a long time.
So! Where's this beautiful family off to?
Oh, they're just...
- I have to get to the hospital.
They put me on the night shift.
- I think he did something terrible.
They say that I'm being rewarded.
Well.. If you guys ever want a tour
of the neighbourhood...
Don't hesitate to call me.
Blessed day!
- Bye.
We should probably go too.
Good morning.
I don't remember what day it was
I didn't notice what time it was
Help me!
Oh..ehe..
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Thank you for meeting with me.
It's fine.
I was a little surprised
to hear from you though.
Last time we spoke...
I said I didn't want to know any more.
Having Ehh..
Had a little distance I Ehm...
Well, I.. I realize I could use
some.. some closure.
I mean there.. there's just
to many unanswered questions.
I understand.
I brought what I have on the Higgins case.
That's Annabelle there.
The Higgins girl.
That was clearly taken before she
got caught up in the cult.
Looks a lot different than the last time
you saw her, doesn't she?
This cult that she was in.
Did you look further into it?
For what, specifically?
I don't know.
There must have been some motive
for their attacks.
Crazy people do crazy things.
...crazy things.
I know.
They didn't think they were crazy.
They have to have had a reason.
After a little more digging...
I did find that their act
was in devotional.
That they were...
They were actually trying
to conjure something up.
Like.. Like what?
The Devil.. Demons...
The Tooth-fairy, I don't know specifically.
It doesn't really matter any..
- Why not?
Well, because this is all
just a bunch of hocus pocus.
Ahm...
Please.
Ma'am.
These were miscreants.
They were probably hopped up
on god knows what.
And it made 'em...
see and do
all sorts of...
terrible things.
Does this mean anything to you?
Have you ever heard the expression...
"sometimes a cigar is just a cigar"?
Then you won't mind if I eh.. keep this...
one for myself?
Ehm...
One more thing.
Does the cult have a name?
They called themselves:
"The Disciples of the Realm".
Hello again.
Is there anything I can help you with?
Oh, no no no.
I.. I'm just...
just browsing really.
I just learned something.
You're a terrible liar.
What is it you're looking for?
Maybe I'll come back.
- Mia!
I'm old.
Which means that there's very little
that surprises me anymore.
And if it does, I'm too tired to show it.
Now. Are you gonna tell me?
Or are we just...
I think my family
is being haunted by a.. a ghost.
Isle four. Follow me.
I.. I know it sounds crazy.
The ghost of this girl haunting us.
But I.. I just...
No crazier than the red sea parting.
To non-believers it's all crazy.
Do you believe in this stuff?
Let's just say that...
I've had one or two experiences
in my life that eh...
helped me to keep an open mind.
I don't particularly think what you
are experiencing is the ghost of that girl.
Why not?
Well, ghosts haunts specific places.
Usually where something terrible
has happened.
Like your old house.
We.. We moved and it's still happening.
Which is why I don't think it's a ghost.
But now, that cult...
You said that they were trying
to summon something?
From what I've read in the past...
These cults, they don't summon ghosts.
They summon inhuman spirits.
Something that has never
existed in the flesh.
Demons?
What.. What do they want?
A soul.
And they won't stop until they get one.
What do I.. What do I do?
Hopefully the answer
is in one of these books.
My daughter, Ruby.
She passed away
when she was about your age.
I'm sorry.
Without her I felt like
I had nothing else to live for so...
But as I lay there,
waiting for it all to end...
I heard her voice.
She told me that it wasn't my time.
That God had another purpose for me.
You too have a purpose Mia.
To protect your family.
So don't think you're crazy
for trying to do that.
You do what you think is right.
You do what you have to do.
The Devil prays on the weak
and the vulnerable.
Seeking to devour their souls.
To perform...
Incantations...
Spilling the blood of kin.
Spilling the blood of the innocent.
How do I stop it?
Hey.
Leah!
What happened?
Happened? You gotta help this travesty.
Thank you for coming Father.
Yes. Of course.
Mia.
This Doll. May I see it?
John got rid of her.
Or tried to.
There she was at the bottom
of one of our last boxes.
I still don't understand what the doll
has to with this supposed demon.
Demons can sometimes
use objects as conduits
to achieve their desired goal.
Their desired goal?
Our souls John.
That's why it's after Leah.
It wants her soul.
No no no.
Demons can't just take souls Mia.
The soul needs to be offered to the demon
before it can take it.
Well, I don't plan on offering
my soul anytime soon.
The Devil is the father of lies.
Demons are his manipulators.
No one ever plans to offer their soul.
How can we get rid of it?
How do we stop it from coming back?
I don't know.
Not yet.
But someone at the church might.
At the very least I've
heard of a married couple
that the church has
worked with in the past
that deal with this kind of thing.
They're back east but a call
can always be placed.
What do we do in the meantime?
I can't have Leah anywhere near that doll.
Let me take her.
Perhaps if she's stored in a sacred place
it will weaken the demon enough.
It won't have the strength to return.
Thank you Father.
Of course.
Come on.
Let's get you to bed.
Doctors orders.
Oh, no no John.
I can't.
Not until I know it's not coming back.
Mia. Come on.
What if.. what if...
John. I can't.
- What if I just stayed up with her?
You get some rest.
Alright?
Okay.
Good night.
John.
Yeah.
Thank you for believing me.
I didn't know if.. if you would.
Mia!
Come on.
I love you.
I will always believe you.
Good night.
Do you think Father Perez is gonna help us?
Yeah. I do.
Come on.
May God have mercy on your soul!!
Frankly Mia...
It's none of your business.
This is between me and Leah.
And she said she wanted those pajamas.
You're gonna spoil her.
I didn't have a chance for grandkids.
Besides it's impossible to spoil a baby.
Oh oh. I don't know if that's the truth.
We just have to take that up
with Leah because
she also pointed out these dresses.
Oh Evelyn.
Oh sweetie-pie.
Oh, it get's crazier.
Oh mommy.
Okay. You know what?
My Ruby used to fuzz and fuzz
until I rocked her.
Put her down here.
She used to fuzz and fuzz.
Come on.
Come here Leah.
All right Leah. Okay. Here we go.
Here we go Leah.
We gonna rock that baby
all night long
You are a lifesaver.
What was it that you were humming?
Oh.. A little blues ditty.
It was the only thing that would
settle my Ruby down when she was a baby
Do you mind if I ask how she passed?
I don't mind if..
If you don't wanna talk about it...
Oh no. It's okay.
It was a car accident.
We were driving back from my parents.
They live up north.
So eh..
I was tired.
You know?
Family'll do that to you.
It was.. very late and I shouldn't
have been behind the wheel.
Last thing I remember was...
Looking over in the passengers seat.
At my daughter.
Asleep.
Yeah. She had grown into
the most beautiful young woman.
I woke up three weeks later.
And Ruby never did.
I didn't get a chance to say goodbye.
I didn't get to beg god to take me first.
I made the mistake and...
She paid the price.
Father.
Where is it?
Where's what?
The doll...
You took it with you.
The Evil...
It's presence.
I saw it John.
I felt it.
I felt how much it wants...
Want's what?
To take her soul.
But you said...
That it can't take Leah's.
You.. You said that it has to be offered.
A baby cannot offer it's soul.
Oh my god.
Mia!
Here. I'll get that.
Hello?
- Mia.
Father Perez was in an accident.
He said...
John?!
- Mia. Mia!
I need you to get out of the house.
Okay? I Ne...
...I'm leaving now.
Father Perez?
Is everything all right?
Father.
MAY GOD HAVE MERCY ON YOUR SOUL!
Who is that?
We need to leave.
Leah!
Leah. Leah!
Mia. The phone is dead.
Come on.
Wait wait wait!
- We'll have to go to my apartment.
You need to come with me,
No. I need to find Leah.
We'll get her back. We need
to get the church. They'll help us.
Come!
Leah!
What do you want from me?
What do you want from me?!
Give her back to me.
You give her back.
Leah!
LEAH!
Leah my baby!
Oh please God no!
Oh Please!
Where is she?!
There has to be another way.
Your soul...
Mommy's gonna save you Leah.
Mommy's gonna...
Mia!
Mommy's coming...
Hey Hey!
She's in there.
I can't get in.
Mia! MIA!
Mia. No no no no no.
Stop.
Okay okay okay.
Hear. Listen to me.
Please. Come down.
It took my baby.
Please. You gotta come down.
Please come down. Okay?
It wants her soul.
I.. have to give it mine John.
Mia! No!
Don't do it.
It won't give her back unless I...
No! No!
Mia! Listen to me.
Leah needs you here. Okay sweetie?
I need you here.
Please don't do this.
I love you John.
I love you.
I know you'll take good care of our Leah.
You kiss her every night.
When she's old enough John,
you tell her that I loved her.
No!
John! No!
Stop. Stop.
John. It wants her soul.
- Mia. Stop. Stop.
My baby!
Mia. Listen to him.
You can't do this to Leah.
A daughter needs her mother.
You said it needs a soul.
You said it needs a soul!
Please.
- Please let me save her.
You don't wanna do this. Anything else.
Stop stop stop.
- No!
You said you'd save her.
You said you'd save her before me.
You promised.
Think about our baby.
Think about Leah.
Okay?
Think about her. Please.
Don't do this to us.
- It wants her soul.
There has to be another way.
There is.
I can make it right.
This is what Ruby meant.
Oh. No no.
God honors sacrifice.
And our sacrifices touch Gods heart.
And move his hand.
Jesus said:
This is my commandment.
That you love one another
as I have loved you.
Greater love hath no-one but this:
That he lay down his life for his friends.
Let us pray.
Wonderful sermon.
You look well father.
- Thank you Mia.
And how are you doing?
We're doing much better now.
Thank you.
Has there been any sign of the doll?
No. Not since that night.
I thought the police took it.
But Detective Clarkin has no record of it.
But evil is constant.
You cannot destroy what was never created.
I just pray that whomever comes into
contact with the doll next
gets the help they need.
So do we.
Good to see you.
Bye Father.
- Bye Mia.
Oh! I almost forgot.
Oh. It's beautiful.
Thank you father.
The loveliest masterpiece
at the heart of God...
Is the love of a mother.
Thank you.
Anything I can help you with?
Oh. I'm just trying to find
something for my daughter.
Thanks.
She's a nurse.
Always helping people.
We looked everywhere for one of these.
Never did find one.
It's a collectors item supposedly.
That's why we.. prize it
a little higher than the rest.
You want me to ring it up?
- Yes please.