The Autopsy Of Jane Doe.
Horror 2016 English
[ LEAVES RUSTLING ]
[ WIND HOWLING ]
[ WIND GUSTING ]
[ LEAVES RUSTLING ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
[ SIREN BLARING IN DISTANCE ]
[ INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
It's getting late, Officer.
[ INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
Sheriff, you gotta
get down here.
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
We got an ID on her?
No, Sir.
No relation to Paul and Carol.
Who's she?
Well, for now, she's a Jane Doe.
You got something?
Nothing was stolen.
Not a scratch on the outside
of the house either.
Doesn't look like
someone broke in.
To me, it looks like
they were trying to break out.
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ]
[ SWITCH CLICKS ]
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ]
[ BUZZING ]
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ ROCK MUSIC ON STEREO ]
♪ I hit the floor around 4:47 ♪
♪ with the mornin‘ blues ♪
♪ Cryin‘ like a puppy dog ♪
♪ It takes some time ♪
♪ to come out ♪
♪ Face the musk ♪
♪ gotta pay your dues ♪
♪ You're the only one I want ♪
♪ Best time tonight ♪
♪ then I'm gonna cry ♪
♪ Gotta put this right ♪
♪ I've been dyin‘ ♪
♪ Girl I just ♪
♪ ain't been feelin‘ right ♪
♪ Yes I'm in trouble I know it ♪
♪ You shot me down ♪
♪ like a heart attack. ♪
♪ All over you yeah ♪
♪ My brown-eyed girl ♪
♪ I guess I swear her hair was ♪
♪ I guess I swear her hair ♪
♪ was midnight black ♪
♪ Midnight black Oh yeah ♪
♪ Midnight black Oh yeah. ♪
Cause of death?
How about we
skip this part tonight?
Come on, this one’s a soft ball.
Smoke inhalation.
You're telling me
that smoke killed Mr. Howard?
Damaged nasal passage
damaged throat, damaged lungs..
Damaged lungs, yes.
But incompatible with life.
So, you're saying
that's not the COD?
I'm saying look before you leap.
Where did the Police
find the body?
Uh, in his kitchen.
House on fire.
Front door is 30 feet away.
Yet, he's not
trying to get there.
Lungs are damaged
but airways not denuded
nearly enough.
So, he stopped breathing
before that fire
really got going?
Open him up.
Now.
Now you see here?
Down below the occipital.
A fracture.
That explains the swelling
in his brain.
Subdural hematoma.
That's what did it.
Not the smoke.
[ METAL CLANKS ]
Everybody has a secret.
Some just hide them
better than others.
Some people are better
at finding them.
You did good. You'll get there.
Nobody's even claimed him yet.
He was all alone,
that's why he died.
He died because
he fell and hit his head.
[ CELL PHONE DINGS ]
You got plans tonight?
Emma wants to go
see a movie at The Strand.
I thought they'd closed
that place down.
Uh, no, when was the last time
you even went to go
see a movie, Dad?
Uh, she has Alzheimer's
and he's building her a house.
The Notebook?
Oh, yeah, your mother made me
go and see it with her
for her birthday.
I fell asleep five minutes in.
Yeah.
Are you alright finishing up?
What's up, Tilden?
Hema toma.
[ GLASS CLINKS ]
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ MEOWING ]
Stanley.
Oh.
Hey, Dad!
Stanley got another one.
[ THUDDING ]
Dad?
[ BUZZING ]
[ SWITCH CLICKS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ LAUGHING ]
Jesus Christ!
It's so easy!
How'd you get down here?
The key was in the elevator.
Oh, my God.
I gotta say, this is not
what I was expecting.
You said it was old but wow.
I thought we were supposed
to meet out front.
Well, I got tired of waiting.
Where, where are you going?
I'm having a little look.
Come back.
God, the place just keeps going.
Well, three generations
of Tildens keep expanding
end up with this
state-of-the-art facility.
Hey, come on.
What's the rush?
I've been down here all day.
You got to see me at my job,
why can't I see you at yours?
You work at a book store.
Are these all people?
Just three tonight.
Can I see one?
Well, no. No.
You cannot see one.
Why not?
Because there's...
Some things you can't
un-see, okay?
Come on, I can handle it.
No. No. And my dad
is way too strict.
Try me.
So, what'll it be?
Oh are you serious?
Are you?
Hell yeah.
Pick one.
Not that one.
The one next to it.
A body's a body.
Yeah, well, I pick that one.
[ METAL CREAKS ]
[ BELL RINGING ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
What's that for?
To make sure he's dead.
There used to be a time
it was hard to tell
a comatose person
from a dead one.
So coroners tied bells
to everybody in the morgue.
So if they heard a ‘ting’
they knew somebody down there
wasn't quite ready to go.
So, why do you have one?
Well, I'm... I'm a bit
of a traditionalist.
Why did you cover his face?
There wasn't much
of a face left to cover.
Point blank gun shot blast
tend to do that.
Who shot him?
Angle of entry suggests
he did it to himself.
Until we found Strychnine
in his system.
And judging by the progress it
made through his bloodstream
he was already dead by the time
somebody blew his face off.
Why would anyone do that?
You sound like your boyfriend.
Leave the “why“ to the cops
and the shrinks.
We're just here
to find cause of death.
No more, no less.
You don't wanna see that.
It's alright.
[ BELL RINGING ]
[ LAUGHS ]
[ METAL RATTLING ]
Look who's easy now.
You should have seen
the look on your face.
I can't wait to see
the look on your face
when you're not
getting laid tonight.
Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
Hold on. Hold on.
Not even if I ply you
with popcorn and sourpatch kids?
You're lucky you're cute.
How do you get used to that?
You do and you don't.
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
Sheriff?
Where's your dad? What happened?
Bring her back here, Sheldon.
Dad, if you need me to stay...
Oh, don't worry about it.
You two go have your fun.
Did you see the look
on Burke's face?
I mean, he wouldn't be here this
late if it wasn't important.
Here we go.
Well, my dad... There it is.
I can't ditch him.
So you're ditching me again.
What's he gonna do
when you leave?
You haven't told him yet?
No. It's not that simple.
Wow.
Babe.
I'm gonna tell him, okay?
Hey, you think I wanna be here?
Down there?
This isn't my life.
I don't wanna be Austin Tilden,
the morgue worker.
Just, he needs my help
right now.
Come on, it's been two years.
He can take care of himself.
Come back in a few hours.
We'll catch the midnight show,
grab a drink at Thornton's..
Two drinks.
11 o'clock, I'm all yours.
I promise.
And don't, you know, don't smile
because a smile
means “yes“ you know.
I know it's in there.
Now, you're gonna
blow your whole game.
Maybe.
You're hot!
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
[ ZIPPER UNZIPS ]
Found her in the basement
of the Douglas place.
No ID, no fingerprints
in the system.
No one has a clue who she is.
I don't suppose you know
how she wound up there?
[ CAT GROWLING ]
Stanley.
Damn thing gets meaner
by the day.
Alvarez there was working
at Paul and Carol's place.
My best bet?
He killed our Jane Doe.
Needed a place to dump the body.
Didn't count the Douglas
being home
or Paul having a .38.
First thing tomorrow,
I'll bring him in
but for now, she's the priority.
Oh, still, it would
have been nice
to take a look
at the crime scene.
I got four people dead
and no god damn clue
how any of it connects.
Nobody's pissing
in your grits here, Shel.
But we do have protocol.
Press is gonna need answers
on this in the morning
and I got nothing.
Now they'll buy a 10-79.
I can give them
a B and E gone haywire.
But what I can't sell is her.
Time frame?
It's gotta be tonight.
Okay.
You didn't have to come back.
I know.
[ SHUTTER COLLAPSES ]
[ ROCK MUSIC ]
[ ZIPPER UNZIPS ]
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ]
This is the autopsy
of an unidentified female
henceforth known as “Jane Doe.“
Performing the autopsy
will be myself
Tommy Tilden, attending coroner.
I will be assisted
by Austin Tilden
certified medical technician.
This autopsy will be
conducted in four stages
beginning with
an external evaluation
followed by
an internal evaluation
of the heart and lungs,
the digestive organs
and finally, the brain.
We've got some beautiful
weather here
for the next few days.
Subject is
in her mid to late 20s.
Appears to be.
Subject appears to be
in her mid to late 20s.
Caucasian. Skin appears normal.
No out wards signs
of bleeding or bruising.
No scarring, no distinctive
external markings.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
Hair, brown.
Eyes.
Gray?
Huh.
You don't see clouding like that
unless a body's been dead
for days.
There's no validity.
No rigour mortise either.
When do you think she died?
Well, she's colder
than the ambient temperature.
What, conditions at the scene?
Could be confounding factors.
Look how small her waist is.
Like it doesn't really fit
the rest of her frame.
Could be congenital.
We won't know
until we open her up.
Mark it down on the board.
We'll come back to it later.
[ BONES CRACKING ]
Her wrists and ankles
are fractured.
How do you break
your wrists and ankles
without any outward signs?
Oh, I see it all the time.
Simple fractures.
Simple? Uh-uh.
Her joints are shattered.
What is that? What is it? Dirt?
No, no, this is denser.
Heavier.
It's... This is peat.
Haven't seen this stuff in ages.
It's under her toenails, too.
Yeah. There are trace
amounts in the hair.
She's covered in it.
Like, maybe she was
buried in it?
Where do you even find peat?
But naturally in the ground..
Up north.
Not around here.
Nasal passages,
no sign of inflammation.
No fluid
and no foreign substances
and ear canals are..
Clear.
Oh.
I hadn't expected that.
Tongue has been...
Severed.
Crudely. Non surgically.
Well, she could have bitten
it off, you know
she ODs on something,
tensed up...
These aren't bite marks.
I've seen something
like this before
about 15 years back.
Human trafficking around Norfolk.
Two girls
hands and feet
bound tight
to keep them from running.
Cut out their tongues
for making too much noise...
You think this was some kind
of a prostitution thing?
Can't rule it out.
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
[ FLY BUZZING ]
[ ZAPS ]
[ CAMERA CLICKS ]
Here, she has a molar missing
on the lower left side.
Take some impressions.
It's definitely
some kind of fabric.
Bag it. Send it to the lab.
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ CLATTERS ]
No external seminal fluid
present.
Give me a swab.
[ SIGHS ]
Ah, she's torn up inside.
There are ridges,
grooves in the tissue.
Abrasions?
No. Cuts.
Deliberate.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
Severed tongue, shattered joints
vaginal trauma..
The theory tracks.
We got a ways to go.
We'll now proceed
with the internal examination
starting with the heart
and lungs.
Help me with the block.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ ELECTRICAL CRACKLING ]
[ INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER ]
♪ Let the sun shine in ♪
♪ Mammy told me something ♪
♪ A little girl should know ♪
♪ It's all about the devil ♪
[ UPBEAT MUSIC ON RADIO ]
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
They're not supposed
to bleed like that. Right?
I've seen it.
An hour dead, maybe two.
It's caused by a build up
of pressure.
What is that?
Melanoma maybe?
On the inside?
Possible.
Let's see what the lab
comes back with.
Can you hand me the rib cutters?
[ DRIPPING ]
Today?
Shit.
What did you do?
Oh, I got it.
I need you to focus here.
I got it.
Well, you were right.
Her waist doesn't fit her frame.
It's not congenital.
Then what is it?
Well, if you wear one
long enough, a corset...
Didn't those go out of style
a couple of hundred years ago?
[ RIB BONES CRACKING ]
The lungs
severely blackened.
Wouldn't have taken her
for a smoker.
She could smoke 10 packs a day for 30 years
wouldn't explain this.
But that's what killed her,
right?
This amount of lung damage though.
I'd expect the body to be
covered in third degree burns.
It's like finding a...
A bullet in the brain
but with no gunshot wound.
Her heart's marked up.
Almost like it's been cut.
Well, not just her heart.
What do you think that is?
Genetic defect?
Could be scar tissue.
Scar tissue?
From what?
Imagine all this internal trauma
was reflected externally.
Shattered ankles and wrists
fire-burned lungs,
scarred organs.
What would she look like?
She'd be mangled.
Disfigured beyond recognition
but she's not.
I mean, how the hell
do you even do this?
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ CRACKLING ]
If you wanna kill someone
you shoot them.
Poison them or drown them.
A million easy ways.
You don't go to these lengths
unless you wanna make them
suffer
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
What the...
I'll get it.
So clean.
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
What happened to you?
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ CRACKS ]
[ GROANS ]
[ SWITCH CLICKS ]
[ RATTLING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ CRASHING ]
[ SWITCH CLICKS ]
What the hell happened?
Are you okay?
Something's in the vent.
[ GRUNTS ]
Thanks.
Oh, shit.
[ STANLEY WHIMPERS ]
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ]
[ BONES SNAPS ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ SWITCH CLICKS ]
[ INCINERATOR RUMBLES ]
Give me a minute.
What are you doing?
The drawer..
Must have not closed it
all the way.
[ SIGHS ]
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO ]
Stanley was a pain in the ass.
But he was your mother's.
One of the few things
of hers I had left.
Yeah, I miss her, too.
Right. Let's keep going.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
This is stage tree of the
autopsy of Jane Doe.
Beginning with the stomach.
And the gastro-intestinal
system.
Dad, you can talk to me.
I'm not keeping
anything from you.
You just... you put up
this act for people...
I'm fine.
Alright.
What is that?
A flower?
[ CLATTERS ]
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ]
Jimpson weed, paralysing agent.
Probably explains
the inflammation on her organs.
Hmm. Here's a weird thing.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
That settles it.
She's from up north.
Yeah, but how did she
end up here?
One thing at a time.
I'm just trying to make sense
of all this.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
Gusts are now being reported
at up to 60 miles per hour.
Rain is expected to top
three inches within the hour.
This one might be a bigger deal
than we were led to believe.
Dad, how about we just
finish this in the morning?
Burke needs a COD tonight.
Were not even close.
When we start something,
we finish it.
You want to leave leave.
It looks like
some kind of shroud.
And Old.
The stomach acids should
have dissolved this thing
I mean, the fact that
it's intact at all is amazing.
Now see, what is that?
Roman numerals.
Okay.
These numerals.
The order. T and... and this S doesn't fit.
What are you doing?
Someone pulled out her tooth
wrapped it in fabric
and forced her to swallow it.
And the drawing?
I don't know. Religious?
Possibly, uh, ritualistic?
Well, let's play that one out.
Every ritual has its purpose.
What MO have we seen so far?
First they bound her.
Then they ripped out
her tongue, poisoned her
paralysed her forced her
to swallow the cloth.
Then, uh, the cuts, the
internal mutilation, stabs.
Then as if that wasn't enough,
they burned her.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
Almost like a human sacrifice.
I got to tell you we have
serious weather reports
coming in from all the monitoring
stations across the state.
We've got a flash flood
warning now in full effect
for all of Grantham County.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
They've got concerns about..
You can't kill someone this way
without leaving a trace
on the outside.
She doesn't even have
a broken nail.
If we could just find out
why she was tortured...
Down here, if you can't see it
touch it, it doesn't matter.
Now, these bodies
are not just CODs, dad.
This happened to her
for a reason.
Trust me when I tell you
this is not a storm you
wanna get caught in, folks.
If you're home, stay home.
One thing's for sure.
You're not going anywhere.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
♪ Mammy told me something ♪
♪ A little girl should know ♪
♪ It's all about the devil ♪
♪ And I've learned ♪
♪ to hate him so ♪
Hey, dad?
♪ She say he causes ♪
♪ trouble when.. ♪
I think maybe
we should get out of here.
♪ He will never ever leave you ♪
♪ If your heart ♪
♪ if filled with gloom ♪
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
♪ Face it with a grin ♪
♪ Smilers never lose.. ♪
Help me with this.
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
♪ Face it with a glee ♪
♪ Open up your heart ♪
♪ and let the sun shine in ♪
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
Holy shit.
♪ When the light comes ♪
♪ pouring in ♪
♪ I'm happy because I never ♪
♪ wear a frown ♪
[ CREAKING ]
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
[ ELECTRICAL CRACKLING ]
[ THUDDING ]
[ PANTING ]
What the fuck?
Dad? Dad?
Here!
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
Let's get the fuck out of here.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
Come on, come on.
The generator.
There's not enough power.
[ THUDDING ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
It's stuck.
Help me with this.
Help me with this!
[ GRUNTING ]
The old sycamore fell.
[ WHIRRING ]
[ PANTING ]
Fuck!
The office. The land line.
[ THUMPING ]
What the hell was that?
I don't know.
[ DIAL TONE BUZZING ]
Oh, thank God.
Harding County
Sheriff Department.
This is Tommy Tilden.
It's an emergency. We need help.
Sorry, I've trouble hearing...
Put Burke on the line.
This is Burke.
Sheldon, this is Tommy.
You better get over here now.
Hello? Tommy, I can scarcely hear you.
Your voice is breaking up.
Sheldon! Sheldon, we're
trapped down here, godda..
Sheldon, please... Tommy.
[ BELL JINGLING ]
[ BELL JINGLING CONTINUES ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
What the fuck is going on?
It's her.
Everything was fine until Burke
wheeled her through that door.
Until we cut into her,
Your talking about a corps.
These things we found inside her
her injuries, those marks.
You can't say she's just a body.
[ GRUNTING ]
We should have left.
I wanted to leave.
Dad!
Oh.
No!
Dad! Dad!
Dad?
Oh shit oh...
[ GRUNTING ]
Oh, my God.
Careful, careful.
[ GROANING ]
Oh, Christ! Ohh.
Help me up. Yeah.
I'm fine.
They were Grey.
Her eyes.
It had her eyes.
That's what I've been trying
to tell you.
It's her.
Oh, no, that's not possible.
Her body.
Those things we found in side
those were impossible...
What ever the hell happened in here.
We are way past possible.
It's her.
So what do we do?
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
Rapid decomp.
Everything we took out of her.
That's almost like her body
was preserving it.
Must get her to the crematorium.
[ AUSTIN GASPS ]
[ RATTLING ]
[ SMASHING ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
[ SCREAMING ]
Fuck it.
Jesus!
Behind you, the extinguisher.
The pin. Pull the pin.
No.
[ ELEVATOR RUMBLES ]
The elevator.
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
Come on.
No, no, no, no! Fuck!
[ BELL RINGING ]
Come on. Come on. Come on.
[ BELL RINGING CONTINUES ]
Come on!
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ BELL RINGING CONTINUES ]
Go, dad. Come on.
Come on.
[ BELL RINGING CONTINUES ]
[ GROANING ]
Emma.
Oh, no!
Oh, no, no!
Oh, my God!
Oh. No! No!
No!
Oh, my God.
Oh, no, no, no! Austin..
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
Austin the elevator come on come on.
Come on, son.
[ ELEVATOR RATTLING ]
Fuck!
[ GRUNTING ]
I told her to come back for me.
I told her to come back.
No, you didn't do this.
You shouldn't be here.
All this is my fault.
You couldn't have known. Yeah.
Yeah, that's what
everyone told me..
About your mom.
You know why I use to call her Ray?
Ray of sunshine.
She thought it was corny
as shit.
[ CHUCKLES ]
But it stuck.
If I'd have known,
I would have helped her.
You know that, don't you?
Why, she was always so bright.
So happy.
To think she was scarring around all that.
Pain all that unhappiness every day.
I should have seen it.
But I didn't.
She had to deal with it alone.
All these mistakes..
My mistakes..
And you had to pay for them.
[ RUMBLING ]
Why hasn't she killed us yet?
Well, it's not for
want of trying.
Well, look what she can do..
If she wanted us dead.
When we cut into her..
She tried to stop us each time.
It's like there's something
she doesn't want us to find.
You wanna go back in there?
If we stay here, we're dead.
If we could just figure out
how she died..
Maybe we can figure out
how to stop her.
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ COUGHING ]
Dad? Right behind you.
Keep moving.
Austin?
[ SCREECHING ]
Ah! Dad?
No!
Dad?
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GROANING ]
Dad. Dad.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Okay.
[ WHIRRING ]
Brain... is normal.
There's got to be something.
All her other organs
are scarred.
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
What the fuck?
What is it?
That's why we couldn't find
cause of death.
She's still alive.
Alive?
We lit her on fire.
We took out her heart.
There's something, some energy.
Call it what you want, something
is keeping her going.
What the..
Leviticus.
Let me see that.
Twenty. Twenty seven.
If these are Roman numerals
then they'd be..
1693.
Any man or woman
who consults
the spirits of the dead
shall be put to death
for they are..
Dad.
Seventeenth century.
North East.
New England.
They are a Witch
and their blood shall be on
their own heads.
It fits.
Witches are a myth.
You can't keep denying.
There were no witches in Salem.
They were kids. Young girls.
Falsely accused,
wrapped up in hysteria.
One pointing to the next,
who pointed to the next.
But they were all, all innocent.
Only... they didn't hang her..
Or burn her at the stake.
They tortured her..
Mercilessly.
The ritual.
It didn't work.
What if..
What if
the ritual,
performed on an innocent
accidentally created the very
thing we're trying to destroy?
Everything they did to her.
Everything we've done to her.
She can feel it.
She wants us... to feel it too.
That's why
she's keeping us alive.
This is her revenge.
This is her ritual.
But why us?
Why the Douglas?
Why anybody?
We're on her path, that's all.
We were just stops
along the way.
Those who survived
got rid of her
and buried her
as far away as possible.
That hasn't stopped her.
Because no one got close enough.
No one could see what we have seeing.
Shes still suffering.
And it won't stop.
It won't stop until..
Until what?
Dad, until what?
I won't fight you.
But please.
Please don't hurt him.
Let me help you.
Dad!
Dad?
[ GRUNTING ]
No!
Dad!
[ GRUNTING ]
Dad.
No.
Please.
[ SCREAMING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ SOBBING ]
[ MUSIC PLAYING ]
Austin! Are you there?
Burke?
Anyone there?
Burke.
Austin!
Austin! Are you down there?
We're sawing down a tree
blocking your door.
We'll be with you
right now, alright.
Austin!
I'm here!
You'll be alright.
Just open up the door now.
It's stuck. Try again, son.
I can't. It won't.
Should open up now.
It won't. Should open up.
I'm trying. It's stuck.
Open up.
I can't. Open up!
I can't.
♪ Open up your heart ♪
♪ And let the sun shine in ♪
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
♪ Face it with a grin ♪
♪ Smilers never lose ♪
♪ Frowners never win ♪
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
[ SCREAMING ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER RADIO ]
No obvious signs
of forced entry.
Looks an awful lot like he...
I've known his family 20 years.
Whatever it looks like,
that ain't it.
Well, it's going to be
another nice one out there.
Today's our fourth
straight day of sunshine.
Looking at a high of 75.
Beautiful outdoor weather
but remember to use
your sunscreen.
What the hell happened here?
What do you want to do with her?
Get her out of here.
Already got a car waiting.
There's that, uh, funeral home
over in Ruxton.
Get her out of my county.
Take her over to VCU.
Let Ward Lamon deal with her.
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
Now, baby, listen
that was one time.
Hell, yes, that's a promise.
The word of God is powerful.
♪ Open up your heart ♪
♪ and let the sun shine in ♪
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
♪ Face it with a grin ♪
♪ Smilers never lose ♪
♪ and frowners never win ♪
♪ So let the sun shine in ♪
♪ Face it with a grin ♪
♪ Open up your heart ♪
♪ and let the sun shine in ♪
[ BELL JINGLES ]