The Vampire and Lycan
clans had been at war...
... for centuries before
I was born.
Their endless conflict hidden
from the human world.
I was turned by a Vampire.
And given the strength to avenge
my family against the Lycans.
And I was good at it.
Then I found Michael Corvin.
A human that was turned to
neither Vampire nor Lycan.
But a hybrid of the two...
... and everything changed.
Allies turned enemies.
And the Vampire elders I had
protected for over six centuries...
... now wanted me dead.
We retaliated.
Killed the elders...
... and for a brief moment
of time, we were safe.
But then, a new darkness arose.
In the nine days since the first
discovery of the non-human species...
... scores of so-called "covens"
have been uncovered.
Estimates of the number
of infected have skyrocketed.
Military sources confirm
that the primary measures...
... of defence against the non-humans
are based on ultraviolet light and silver...
... to which the infected
appear to have fatal sensitivity.
Tents have been posted at every
barricade throughout the city.
A test will be administered
to verify if you're clear of infection.
Spray her!
Spray her with silver!
- Get it out here!
- Help! Run!
- No, no!
- Run!
We've begun our
second attack wave...
... using ultraviolet and
silver-nitrate munitions...
... which are deadly
to the infected.
Due to the volatile situation...
... martial law was declared
two hours ago.
Many of us have lost
loved ones to this.
Please know that you cannot
help them or yourself.
It's shocking discovery that not
one, but two distinct species...
... may have been coexisting
within human populations.
The existence of Vampires
and Werewolves...
... now appear to have
actual basis in fact.
The city remains reluctant
to share any new information.
But we are getting reports on what
appears to be a mass cleansing.
Fire!
Get back!
No cameras!
There's no cure.
There it is!
Contact.
Engage contact!
Man down!
- Man down!
- Cover me! Cover me!
The Purge.
Human beings no longer
kill each other.
We are the enemy
they've been waiting for.
Escape has become
our only chance of survival.
Therefore, Michael and I
are leaving tonight.
Halt!
Delta 6 in pursuit!
Stop!
Get down on the ground!
She'll be here any minute.
- You be ready to go.
- Better hurry.
Tango Unit moving into position.
We have the hybrid in sight.
Hold your fire.
Leave this one alive.
Delta in position.
- Watch your flank.
- Secure.
- Move, move, move!
- Alpha Unit in position.
Arming silver grenade!
Michael!
Fire!
- Move in!
- Alpha 4, move in.
Grenades, fire!
Retrieve the bodies.
Subject 2 has escaped.
Security units on alert.
Defrost sequence initiated.
Lowering compression
in Subject 1 cryo-chamber.
Defrost sequence complete.
- Subject 2! Get it!
- Over there by the chamber!
Don't let it get away!
Security violation, Level 6.
All containment personnel
to Level 6.
Jacob.
Subject 2 escaped.
It's somewhere in the building.
We've got Subject 1
in full lockdown.
- Give me the status.
- Subject 1 has broken free.
- We need to flash-burn immediately.
- No, wait. Let me see.
Open it.
Put it back to sleep.
Hurry.
Releasing maximum dose
of fentanyl.
What is this place?
Where is Michael?
No, no, no.
All non-security personnel
clear the building!
Security command, outside now!
- There she is!
- Stop!
Don't move!
Multiple casualties on Level 6!
Medical to alert status!
Prepare for full containment
on Level 6!
I repeat, full containment
I see her.
East corridor. Send security.
No. Let her go.
She can lead us to Subject 2.
No, don't shoot!
Let her go.
Attention, all units.
Subject 1 and Subject 2
have escaped the perimeter...
... and are no longer
under Antigen control.
Secure the outer gates and use
extreme caution upon encounter.
Report immediately
upon coming into contact.
Hey, how did you get in there?
You're not allowed in here.
The pier is closed.
Since when?
A long time ago.
Come on.
How long?
About 12 years ago.
Since the cleansing.
Why?
You okay, ma'am?
Attention, all units,
code three call.
Receiving a report of an assault,
Exit 39 underpass.
Possible non-human aggressor.
Proceed with caution.
CDC already en route.
All area units respond.
Ma'am?
Hey!
- What are you doing over there?
- Stay right there! Don't move!
- Identify yourself!
- Get back here right now!
Whoever it is, they couldn't
have made it very far.
I'll alert CDC to keep an eye out.
They're en route.
- There's no way this attack was human.
- You don't know that.
Don't know what?
The guy is shredded. His throat
was found over in the gutter.
Just let me handle it.
What's to handle?
This has Lycan written all over it.
Detective, when was the last time you
heard about a reported Lycan killing?
A couple of years ago.
How many years have you
been with this department?
What do you mean?
I've been here for three months.
Exactly.
You question me less
until you know a bit more.
- Are we clear?
- Crystal.
Detective Sebastian.
Detective, we've just
received a report.
There's been a disturbance
at Antigen Labs.
A witness says there
may have been an escape.
They said someone jumped
out of a window.
This is a priority investigation.
We need you over there asap.
We're on our way.
Hey, let's go.
Johnson, you're the lead.
You got it, detective.
Will do.
Who's in charge?
There's a Detective Sebastian
here to see you, sir.
Where is he?
In the lobby, sir.
You'll be relieved to know that
the situation is well under control.
- What happened?
- I repeat, well under control.
I repeat, what happened?
Ah yes, there are reports
to be filed.
One of our test subjects
attempted to escape.
We were forced to put it down.
- So nothing got out?
- Only a stray bullet.
- And the test subject?
- Flash-burned.
Will that be all?
A few things to attend to.
You could imagine.
Doctor, we received
an anonymous call...
... that something else
escaped through a window.
Detective, our mission at Antigen is to
develop ways of preventing infection...
... not releasing it
into the general population.
I lost my son to this disease.
There's no room
for error with me...
... when it comes to
the safety of the public.
If something had escaped...
... the authorities
would have been notified.
You are an authority,
are you not?
Now, if you'll excuse me.
The guy in charge says it's nothing.
Let's go.
Yeah, and he's full of shit.
Look at this.
- Want me to report it, sir?
- No, I'll do it.
I don't mind.
I can do it for you.
All right, sir.
The prisoner that helped me escape,
the one you called Subject 2...
... was it a hybrid?
- Yes.
- What were you doing with us?
We...
... we help the government
identify the infected.
We were using your DNA
to try to find a cure...
... to prevent another outbreak.
You were told that I would lead
you to the hybrid. Why?
Subject 2 is restricted information.
I don't have the clearance.
You're lying.
No!
No, please!
All I know is there's some kind
of connection between you two.
Your brain waves fall into sync
whenever you're close to each other.
You can see through
each other's eyes!
Please don't!
I'm the one who let you go!
Now we're even.
What the hell was that?
Creepy is what.
- I'm calling it in.
- Let's go.
Shit.
Don't.
Why not?
We're the same.
Why are you following me?
We monitor
the police frequencies.
"We"?
Do you know what attacked that
human back there, under the bridge?
No.
Lycans.
What remains of them, yes.
They've been hiding down here
like rats ever since the Purge.
Diseased and starving, they rarely
show themselves above ground.
Which means that something
has got them riled up.
Something you're not telling me.
Michael!
Do you know her?
No.
They will come back in numbers.
We can't leave her here.
Come on.
Let's try the van.
Get in.
Move! Move!
There are three
of them behind us.
Go!
Hurry, Selene!
They're getting in the back!
Fucking piece of shit!
The girl!
They're taking her!
You drive.
She's not healing.
We have a doctor that can
help her, at our coven.
How did you find me?
What's your name?
Subject 2...
... and you are Subject 1.
I freed you.
Do you not know who I am?
They told me that I had no mother,
that she died when I was born.
I never believed it.
I...
... I felt you.
Saw images through your eyes.
But then someone
outside my door...
... they said since I was no longer
a child, the wait was over...
... that I'd be dead soon.
And that my own mother,
right next door...
... would never
even know I'd existed.
What did they tell you
of your father?
They must have
told you something.
- Do you see images through him?
- No.
Only you.
No, please!
She's never stepped foot
outside the lab.
How can she possibly survive?
I understand the risk of reporting
her escape to the authorities.
There's no record of her birth.
So questions will be asked.
I'm well aware of that.
But if she dies, all our years
of research will be...
Rather than tell me
how to do my job...
... why not take a look at your
own professional conduct?
And how your continual need
to endow this creature...
... with human traits has led to
the laxness of its security protocols.
It's not a human being, Lida!
It's not your child.
It's not to be coddled and pitied.
It's a blight of nature.
Stop worrying.
It'll come back to us.
Get Olivia at once.
Again you break my rules.
Why?
She was attacked.
She is not healing.
And for this you
compromise our safety?
You have no reason to fear us.
Do you think I'm foolish enough
to take you at your word?
No reason to fear a Death Dealer
who fell in love with a Lycan?
Who murdered
two of our elders?
And who, at every turn,
has betrayed her own kind?
Do you know who this is?
Yes.
But it was we
who betrayed her, Father.
Let her through.
She's not healing.
She was attacked
by a lower Lycan.
Two hours ago.
Her cell repair is active,
but weakened.
She has no origin bite marks...
... or scars.
I've never seen
a child like this before.
When did you last feed?
Feed?
Give her blood.
Child, you must.
Slowly.
There.
There, now.
She's healing.
- And quickly.
- Good.
Take her to my room.
She needs to rest.
No.
Look at the eyes.
I never believed it.
They do exist.
- This is not one of us.
- No, it's something more, Father.
What do you know of her?
I was held captive
at a place called Antigen.
One of the other
prisoners freed me.
I believed it was Michael Corvin...
... the only hybrid I knew
existed at that time.
Yes, yes, your Lycan lover,
long dead.
What is this, then?
None of your concern.
As soon as she regains her
strength, I will leave with her.
I used to hear stories
of the Death Dealers.
That they were a thing of the past,
never to return.
I'm glad they were wrong.
You knew who I am...
... and yet you still
brought me here.
Thank you.
You're a fighter.
We could use more
like you to teach us.
I'm not sure your father
would agree.
There was a time
when he would have.
That's why he dislikes you
so much, I think it...
... it reminds him of the days when
he defended us with fire and steel...
... rather than hollow words.
He knows how much we need you.
- I'm not a leader.
- But you fight for what you believe in.
You always have.
I don't know what
I believe in anymore.
I don't recognise this world.
But you haven't changed.
I saw it in your eyes
when you looked at the child.
You will protect her.
It's in your blood.
It's who you are.
When you leave,
take me with you.
You distrust me.
Of course you do.
I made you feel unwelcome.
And for that, I'm sorry.
Those eyes... they're special.
I know exactly what you are.
My father says that should
we survive as a species...
... these relics will help
our descendants know...
... who we were
and how we lived.
And what do you say?
That if we continue to live
as we do now...
... then we disgrace the past
and don't deserve a future.
We must resist the humans...
... wherever and
whenever possible.
Between the first
and second Purges...
... Lycan youth rallied in the same way
against the prudence of their elders.
Their calls for violent action
carried the day.
The result?
The Werewolves are nearly extinct.
Is that what you wish for us,
extinction?
Yet you bring her offspring
into our home.
Do you honestly believe the humans
will allow her to remain free?
They will hunt her down
at any expense.
- Then we can help protect them.
- Protect them?
- They leave tonight.
- This isn't prudence.
This is cowardice,
plain and simple.
How dare you?
How dare you...
... do so little?
I dreamt of the day
we would meet.
Like a silly little girl.
You're as cold
as one already dead.
Yesterday, I was with your father.
He was only a little further away
from me than you are now.
I went to sleep.
And when I awoke
the next day...
... I learned that overnight...
... 12 years had passed.
And instead of the only man
I've ever loved...
... there stood a girl
with his eyes.
My heart is not cold.
It's broken.
I'm so sorry.
What is it?
They're here.
Stay here.
Wait for me.
No, take me with you.
Please.
I won't let anyone hurt you.
I promise.
Lock the door.
Everybody to the shelter.
Now!
No!
Prepare the armoury.
Do as I say!
Go, go!
Pay heed to me!
No!
We stand and we fight.
Have you no sense?
Stop this now!
We lived safely for years and now
you brought humans into this coven.
They want the girl and they will
stop at nothing to get her back.
This day was bound to come,
with or without us.
Let's move!
Munitions, let's go! Everyone!
Are you mad?
We have no more than a handful
of fighters. We will be annihilated!
And what's your plan, Father?
Let's go!
Now!
- Where are you going?
- To get her away from here.
Your father's right.
I shouldn't have come.
- He doesn't understand how we...
- The humans will follow us out.
We just need to
hold them off till then.
They're only here for her.
She's more powerful
than any of us...
... and they fear the day
she discovers it.
I have to get her out of here.
Lycan!
Silver ammunition!
Now!
Defend the second rotunda!
Move! Move!
Open the door!
Let's go.
Move!
We need to go.
What the hell was that?
- Take her somewhere safe.
- No.
Take her.
Go.
Where is she?
They took her.
They accepted her.
As a gift from me.
Do you even know
what you've done?
Do you have any idea?
What would you
have had me do?
Fight to the last to protect the
very one who brought this upon us?
We're defeated.
Our coven is destroyed.
My son is dead.
Because of you.
Why?
Because he helped
that child of yours.
If they kill her, so be it.
Your son died because
he was fighting for all of you.
Because he knew that running
is not survival.
Those were Lycans.
Not extinct.
More powerful than ever.
That thing was more than twice
the size of any Lycan I've ever seen.
They risked showing themselves...
... after more than a decade
in hiding because of her.
And you handed her
over to them.
She is the last direct descendant
of Alexander Corvinus.
The only hybrid child
that has ever existed.
Whatever it is the Lycans
want from her...
... your son knew
it was worth dying for.
What are you doing?
David...
A force of two dozen Lycans...
... attacked and destroyed
one of our covens last night.
You're not surprised.
You knew the Lycans
were not extinct.
- How?
- Just a feeling.
I'm not good with feelings.
I want to know how.
This is not the place for this.
And you're not gonna kill me.
- Really?
- No.
Because you wouldn't need
a fucking gun to do it.
A few years ago...
... the government declared
"mission accomplished" on all Lycans.
The feds announced that we were
to only focus on your kind now.
Three months ago,
a friend of mine sent me this.
It arrived two days after he was found
hanging from his own ceiling fan.
Two hundred suspected
Lycan captures.
Every case was investigated.
Every blood test
came back negative.
So my friend began to wonder...
... "Were they all false leads or was
someone trying to protect the Lycans?"
Helping them replenish
their packs, letting them regroup.
What about your own department?
They have my daughter.
All I care about is getting her back.
If you're protecting someone,
I don't care.
I'm not after them, I just want her.
No.
Even if there are others
in my department...
... they won't have the authority.
This goes much higher.
I believe all the way to the top.
- Or to the bottom.
- What do you mean?
Who administers the tests?
We're a bit short on time,
so if you please, take a look at these.
This schedule will take you from
the moment we adjourn today...
... straight through to the final
manufacture of the vaccine.
If we stick to this plan, inoculations
should begin within three months.
Any questions, now's the time.
Because after today's surgery...
... there will be no
communication between us...
... until we meet up again
in the inoculation centre.
Doctor, in terms
of your test subject...
... he continues to demonstrate
immunity to silver?
Absolutely.
And additional inoculations,
administered only as a precaution...
... have triggered side effects
we never imagined.
Vast increases in strength,
muscle mass...
... self-healing, stamina.
You said she was essential
to our research.
- Yes, and will continue to be.
- How?
By vivisecting her?
You weren't meant to have that.
I cared for this little girl all these
years, and you expect me to sit by...
- ... while you...
- Harvest its genetic material?
I expect nothing from you.
I hired you to look after it...
... and for the most part,
you did an excellent job.
Saving the lives of thousands.
What are you talking about?
An entire species
saved from extinction.
Jacob...
After today, you won't have to
wait so long between injections.
Are you sure she's ready?
Oestrogen levels high...
... intervals between menses
holding steady.
It's come of age.
Everything's worked out
just as we'd hoped.
You're the first proof of it.
I'm proud of you, son.
Now that it's with us again...
... we'll have all the genetic material
we need, ready for cloning.
Enough to produce
an endless supply of vaccine.
Imagine...
... our species immune to silver.
No more hiding.
Every Lycan under our command
as powerful as you are.
I've even begun injecting myself.
I only wish Mother
were here to see it.
Your mother chose to
remain human.
She abandoned us.
Remember that.
Of course, Father.
Look, if you're right
about Antigen...
... who knows how many Lycans
will there be hiding in there?
The second you step foot inside,
you're gonna be surrounded.
I'm hoping so.
I know you want her back.
I can help you.
- Why?
- Just tell me what your plan is.
It's worse if you try to fight it.
Trust me.
So how is it you're actually able
to survive in the sunlight?
It was a gift.
From a man named
Alexander Corvinus.
The founding father.
I used to be married, to a nurse.
One day at work, she was bitten.
Nobody knew but us.
We lived like that for a few years.
Then came the Purge.
The feds were conducting
door-to-doors...
... and when they
knocked on ours...
Well, she... she told me
she loved me and uh...
... and she let the sunlight in.
I had to watch her burn.
Okay.
You got me?
Yes.
Good luck.
- Shit. It's her.
- In daylight?
- It's her! Go!
- Okay.
- Wait for my cue.
- I'm ready.
Ops Code A. Repeat, Ops Code A.
Breach on Level 1.
Intruder ascending in Elevator 4.
I want all levels secured
ready on that elevator now!
- Anaesthesia ready?
- Yes, sir.
Good.
Security units on alert.
Ops Code A.
Intruder on premises.
Secure the east wing.
All units, intruder's ascending
in the elevator.
Come on.
Let's go.
Move!
There's your cue.
Copy.
They're using silver-nitrate gas.
Bombs on all the floors.
It's Subject 1.
We need to evacuate.
Fine.
Start a propofol infusion.
We're not cancelling
this procedure, understood?
We're moving it.
You find her...
... and you destroy her.
With pleasure.
I'm here.
I got movement on a van
in Parking Level 3.
No sign of the girl.
They'll be on the move.
Just don't lose them.
She's in the service elevator.
Get her.
I'm coming down.
Selene.
Selene!
They're heading
for Parking Level 2.
Selene.
Selene, I need to know
where you are!
Oh, shit!
Do you copy?
Selene, where are you?
I see her.
Parking Level 2.
They're loading your daughter
into the van.
Selene, where are you?
Fuck it.
Hold it right there!
Stop! Stop now!
- Michael?
- Get her!
Selene, Lane has her in the van.
They're on the move.
Where are you?
They are leaving with her!
Do you hear me?
I'm on my way.
Come on, faster.
Don't stop.
Hit him!
Selene, they're heading
for Parking Level 1.
Selene, they're getting away
on Parking Level 1. Do you copy?
I'm coming.
Everything okay?
Levels are holding stable, sir.
Baseline vitals...
Fuck you.
Get away from her!
It's worse if you try to fight it.
Trust me.
I heal instantly.
I'm counting on it.
You came back for me.
I said I would.
Selene.
You should go.
There's a safe house
not far from here.
Go. I'll send them on a different
path, buy you some time.
Thank you.
Come on.
David.
Are we going back in?
We are.
What is it?
Michael?
The roof.
Though the world has changed,
our enemy remains the same.
The Lycans will rebuild...
... and will hunt for her father
as they did for her.
But as they grow stronger...
... so will we.
The Vampire coven will
not only survive this world...
... we will reclaim it.