♪ I got my version of heaven ♪
♪ I got a shield from a friend ♪
♪ If angels are liars ♪
♪ The stars are broke ♪
♪ But ain't we all in the end? ♪
♪ So shave your sweet intentions ♪
♪ Let 'em get the best of me ♪
♪ Scotch and angel dust ♪
♪ For breakfast ♪
♪ What will be will be... ♪
(cell phone ringing )
Oh.
♪ Slow-dance your shadows ♪
♪ Till we all fall down ♪
♪ The devil's little brother... ♪
- Wait, wait, wait.
- .' ls back in town. .'
Hello?
Who?
Uh-huh.
It's the ocean.
Yeah, I'm just walking
on the beach.
Whew.
Where?
At Petey's? What time?
Oh, yeah, yeah, definitely.
( Stutters )
I'm sorry.
Give me another hour, okay?
Okay, thanks.
♪ Slow-dance your shadows ♪
♪ Till we all fall down ♪
♪ The devil's little brother ♪
♪ Is back in town ♪
♪ Slow-dance your shadows ♪
♪ Till the sky cries out... ♪
- Bye-bye.
- .' The devil's little brother .'
♪ ls back in town. ♪
Man: Haven't you ever been
in love before?
Woman:
You're kidding, right?
We've known each other for what,
42 minutes?
The best 42 minutes
of my life.
(chuckles)
You're barking up the wrong tree
with that bullshit line, stud.
- Is that right?
- Mm-hmm.
What's that?
Nice.
How did you get so cynical?
Huh.
Product of a broken home.
What's your excuse?
Mom and Dad died in a car crash
when I was seven.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
What doesn't kill you...
( tires screech )
(sniffing )
Oh, whoa.
(woman moaning)
- Where are you going?
- I gotta be somewhere.
You're just gonna leave?
Consider yourself lucky.
( Pop music playing )
- Petey, Petey, hey.
- Hey, Molloy.
Hey, what's up?
Hey, anybody been asking for me?
- Yeah, some Swedish guy.
- Uh-huh.
- He wanted to give you a Nobel prize.
- Ha! That's not funny.
Hey, I just had an unbelievable
cheeseburger, the best fucking
cheeseburger I ever had.
They had fries.
They put the gravy on the fries--
unbelievable.
Hey, you have a...
Okay. Sorry. Sorry.
- Dude, you want my advice?
- No.
Here he is.
Hi, young fellow.
- Yates.
- How are you doing, brother?
Good, good, good, good.
Want a drink?
No, I'm good.
Ready for that chat?
- Yeah, let's go.
- All right.
Yeah. Later, Petey.
See you, mate.
Yates: Some lobo
is bringing a ki, 75% pure.
- What's it going for?
- 150 Gs.
Really? That's a pretty snazzy
neighborhood.
How do you want to do this?
What's the play?
Go in heavy, grab the junk, take the
cash, leave, sell it back to the lobo.
What about-
is there a risk factor?
It's low. I've dealt
with these assholes before.
Shouldn't be anything
if you have the artillery.
What do you mean, shouldn't be?
What the kind of guarantee is that?
You want a guarantee,
get yourself a fucking blender.
- You in or not?
- Yeah, I'm in. I'm in.
- You got a gun?
- Yeah, I got a gun.
I got a .33, I got sawed-off.
I can get whatever-
It's a Holiday Inn on Burke
by the airport. You know it?
I was baptized there.
It was a beautiful thing.
- I'll see you there Saturday.
- Yeah.
- Midnight, all right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm there.
I'm there, midnight,
Holiday Inn.
Oh, how's Bear?
( laughs )
Listen to this.
He's doing a six-week
court-ordered rehab.
Second night of freedom,
the fucker gets pulled over for DUI.
It took five cops
to get him in the car.
Only five, eh?
Yeah, I bailed him out.
He's good.
So we're on for Saturday?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, the Holiday Inn,
behind the Holiday Inn
on Burke, by the airport.
I'm there.
What the fuck do I want
a blender for?
Come here. Hit me.
Oh, you fucker.
Petey!
Oh, fuck.
What time is it?
-( People laughing )
- Fuck, what time--
what time is it?
Oh, you motherfucker.
This is fucked.
Where are you going, Molloy?
(cell phone ringing )
(line ringing)
( phone continues ringing )
What? What? What?
Yeah, I'm fucking coming.
I'm coming.
Fuck!
(line ringing)
( inhales)
Oh, fuck. Fuck.
You fuck-knuckle.
Oh. Oh.
Oh, fuck.
- Fucking Molloy.
- (cocks gun )
Oh. Oh.
(screaming )
- Oh, fuck!
-( horn honks)
( tires screech )
Don't be a hero.
On the ground.
Come on.
And the other one.
Kick it over.
Come on, move it.
- Drop the gun!
- Drop the fucking gun! On the floor!
-( All shouting)
- Easy, easy, easy.
On the floor, asshole.
Fuck you.
Get the fuck down.
Fuck off!
I fucking love that.
I love this guy.
( Exhales )
( hospital P.A. chatter )
Woman: Welcome to
the land of the living.
I was driving.
I felt like--
like my che--
like an elephant sat
on my chest.
You had a heart attack,
Mr. Molloy.
I had a heart attack?
It's hardly surprising,
given this toxicology report.
My best estimation
is that your heart stopped
somewhere around
the North Street exit.
( Horn honking continuously)
It seems that the impact
of your chest hitting the steering wheel
restarted your heart.
Do you understand
what I'm telling you, Mr. Molloy?
It's a miracle you're alive.
However, there are indications
that you've suffered
some heart damage.
Heart damage?
It's minor.
With medication,
you should be able to live
a normal life...
provided you clean up
your act.
♪ A ticket to heaven ♪
♪ Shouldn't be right ♪
♪ Somebody's talking ♪
♪ Shine ♪
♪ Doesn't it shine? ♪
♪ There for the taking ♪
♪ There for
the taking ♪
♪ Somebody's dream ♪
♪ A better man's dream ♪
♪ A ticket to heaven ♪
♪ A ticket
to heaven ♪
♪ Second chances
gleam for the win ♪
♪ Chances gleam,
where it falls... ♪
- Hey, come here.
-( buzzer sounds)
Come on, I'll buy you lunch.
I got something to tell you. Come here.
- I don't look hungry, do I?
- You do a little.
- No lie?
- Yeah, I got the ring and everything.
Bullshit.
Well, let's see it.
I didn't bring it to work, did I?
It's expensive.
When are you gonna
pop the question?
Friday night.
I got it all planned out.
I got a nice new suit.
I'm gonna get dressed up
really nice.
- Yeah.
- And then I'm gonna-- I'm gonna-
Parole officer.
I'm gonna leave you
with it, brother.
Thanks.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- Good.
- Everything going well?
Yeah.
All right, well, you know
the routine. Let's see it.
Yes, sir.
( Pills rattle)
So how is your mate Bear?
Keeping out of trouble?
Yeah, yeah.
No, we're both doing really good.
We're model citizens now.
(man chuckles)
Yeah, that's good.
- Keep it up.
-( snickering )
Something funny?
No, no, I was-
I was thinking of something.
He was telling me a joke
and it just registered.
Huh. This is new.
Yeah, she just got
her hair cut, so...
I just think
she looks stunning.
Well, they sort of make it all
worthwhile, don't they?
She does for me.
Well, say hello
to your mate Bear for me.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- It's good seeing you.
- Keep up the good work, mate.
Okay, thanks.
- See ya, Bear.
- All right.
- He says hello.
-( laughs )
Bear: You still haven't told her
you're an ex-con.
Molloy: That's not the easiest thing
to work into a conversation.
Yeah, okay.
Well, try this:
She goes, "How was
work today, Molloy?"
You go, "Better than doing
three to five years
- in the Long Bay Correctional, honey."
-( laughing )
That's a lot of help, Bear.
Seriously, listen, listen.
Better that she hears it
from you
than from your P.O.
I know.
Ba by!
I'm here.
Where's my gorgeous girl?
Hi.
Give me a kiss.
- Hi.
- Gorgeous, how was work?
- It was good.
- Yeah?
- I left early.
- I could see that.
- It looks great.
- Look at that.
- Look at this.
- I know.
Wow, we could probably
cook in here tonight.
We can cook
in here tonight,
but we've got
two of everything.
I see a garage sale
in our future.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What else do you see
in our future?
Well, actually I'm trying
not to think about it,
not get too far
ahead of myself.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
Really? And your five-year-plan-
that just doesn't exist?
That's not really a plan.
It's more of a reminder.
Oh, "I'll create
three new lines of jewelry,
establish an online presence,
open a shop in Melbourne."
Yes, okay,
maybe it is a plan,
- but seriously...
- What?
I'm trying to be
less anal about it.
What?
( laughs ) I'm trying to be
less anal about it.
- Wait, wait, what was that?
- You heard me.
- You know what?
- Yeah?
I love when you talk dirty.
Hey, Kel?
Mm-hmm?
- ( Sighs )
- What?
I love you so much.
I love you too.
- You hungry?
- I'm so hungry.
Okay, what do you
want me to get?
- There you go, mate.
- All right. Thank you.
- What's up, Sammy?
- Hey, Molloy.
How are the flowers
doing tonight?
( laughs)
Let me see this.
You know why he doesn't
ask her for it?
'Cause he's a pussy.
Holy shite.
When did you get out?
About a week ago.
I thought they had you
for another year.
They did.
I cut a deal.
Told 'em I had a big fish.
How have you been?
- Good.
Good, you know,
just one day at a time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How is your heart?
( Chuckles )
it's-- it's good.
The doctor says
if I avoid stress
I'll be good for another
100,000 miles.
That's good.
I gotta say, mate,
you're an original.
(chuckles)
Driving that car into
a fucking pharmacy-- fuck.
I was in jail
when I heard that,
laughed my
fucking ass off.
You got time for a drink?
No, man, I'm sober.
I've been sober for three years.
Oh, good for you.
Good for you.
- That's great. Look--
- My parole officer's been on me
like bark on a tree.
If he sees me talking to another ex-con,
I'm fucked. He's gonna violate my ass
so fast, it'll make your head spin.
- So...
- So I'll make it brief.
I got something on,
a two-man job,
high-risk. high-yield.
You've been out a week.
What, are you already
looking to go back?
I'm not gonna go back, mate.
I'm just looking for a partner.
Me?
What, are you
out of your mind?
Just hear me out.
Just drop it.
She got you
by the balls, eh?
What?
Your girl-- she's got you
by the balls.
- Anything else?
- No, that's it. That's it.
Hey, mate, are we cool on this?
I'm just fucking with you.
- Yeah, yeah, we're cool. We're cool.
- All right.
- Open the fucking register.
- Yates, just don't.
Just do what he says.
All right, all right, all right.
- Easy, easy.
- Shut up. Move over.
Sammy, just do what he says.
Do what he says.
Yates.
- Fill them up. Hurry up.
- No.
- Let's go.
- Fill it up your fucking self.
Fucking hurry up.
Jesus.
Yates, what the fuck?
Jesus Christ, Yates.
What the fuck's the matter with you?
The sooner you fill them,
the sooner he gets to see a doctor.
All right, all right, all right.
Hang in there, Sammy.
Go.
And your wallet.
Okay, here.
Here we go.
All right.
Smile.
And while you're at it,
some smokes.
Oh. Oh.
Come on.
What's up with you, mate?
Oh, Jesus. Oh.
Ow. Ow.
You all right?
Fucking-A.
Better living
through chemistry, eh?
What the fuck?
Sam.
Sammy.
What the fuck
are you doing?
(gunshot)
(distant sirens wailing)
- Hey, sweetie.
- Oh.
You scared me.
What took you so long?
Oh.
They're beautiful.
Thank you.
-( TV chatter )
- You know what's crazy?
It's that I've got
a whole other load
of boxes at my apartment.
Are you okay
with this, Jack?
What? I'm sorry, baby.
What?
Giving up this room.
I don't want you to feel
like I'm, you know,
taking over.
No, no, no, no, it's fine.
I want you to take over.
It's absolutely fine.
I just used it
for storage anyhow.
I'm just sorry it's so small.
Are you kidding me?
It's perfect.
Okay.
( News jingle plays )
Anchor: Two people
have been shot dead
in an armed robbery
at a convenience store.
Residents are not demanding police
crack down on gangs of armed thugs
responsible for a wave of crime
on the tourist strip.
We cross to our reporter
live outside the scene
of the latest shooting.
Reporter: Police who are searching
for two white male suspects...
- Sweetie.
- ...In a robbery in which...
- Yeah.
- ...two people were killed.
Honey, can I use
some of your muscle, please?
( Cat mews )
(distant siren wailing)
( shouting )
Yates: Smile.
- Kel.
- Yeah?
Kel, my car's running rough.
- Can I take you to work...
- Yeah.
- ...and pick you up after?
- Yeah, sure. Of course.
What's mine is yours.
- You all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
I'll see you downstairs.
Okay.
Thanks, sweetie.
Have a beautiful day.
Oh, I forgot cash.
Can I borrow some?
Oh, shoot.
- I must have lost my wallet.
- Oh.
Probably fell out
at work again. Sorry.
No, that's fine.
I'll stop by the ATM at lunch.
- All right.
- All right. Bye.
- Good morning, Lisa.
- You would not believe
the morning I have had.
(car lock chirps)
Fuck!
(siren wailing)
It's open.
Hi. Oh, I hope you had
a better day than I did.
Don't tell me. Lisa?
Yep. Major melodrama.
( Chuckles )
What happened now?
- Oh, off with the boyfriend again.
-( woman speaking on radio)
I just-- I just can't
hear it again-
breaking up, back together;
happy, sad.
Did your wallet turn up?
- What?
- Your wallet. Did your wallet turn up?
Uh, no.
I had to cancel
the credit cards.
Oh. Maybe you should
call the police.
Hey, hey, Kel.
- Have you been messing with my hat?
- No.
Not since the APA declared it harmful
to women and small animals.
You coming?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Curtis.
( kisses )
Honey, I'm beat.
Do you mind if we get takeaway
again tonight?
Okay.
We could get Thai.
There's that great place
up on Baldwin's.
They do a fantastic curry.
Yeah, that sounds good.
I hope you're hungry.
I got a lot.
What did you order?
I just was about to call you.
Your friend Gary popped by.
Who?
Gary.
Gary?
Love what you've done
with the place.
Oh, there he is.
Hey, big fella.
Guess what I found.
Must have fallen out
in the dark.
Kelly: Oh.
It's all there.
Anyway.
I'd best be
getting out of here.
- It was a pleasure meeting you.
- You too.
Just for the record,
you're too good for him.
That's what I keep
telling him.
Um, why don't you stay
for dinner?
We've got Thai.
And it never actually
occurred to me
that somebody sat down
with a chunk of silver
and fashioned it into a ring
or a bracelet
or whatever.
I know it sounds lame.
I'm sorry.
I'm babbling on.
You must be bored stiff.
Not at all.
It's fascinating.
I have a tendency
to be a bit obsessive.
Ask Jack about
my five-year plan.
I've just set up a studio
in our spare bedroom.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
I'd love to see it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Okay, so it's still
a work in progress.
Oh, no, it's great.
A little tight maybe.
Yeah.
It's a start.
I want to open up
my own shop one day.
- That's smart.
- Yeah.
- Cut out the middle man.
- Exactly.
-( Cell phone ringing )
- All I need is capital.
- Jack: Hello.
- Oh, that's beautiful.
You just seemed
a little jumpy yesterday,
so I'm just calling up to make sure
everything's okay.
Hey, yeah.
And work's all good?
You don't have any issues there
you would need to talk about?
- Work is fine, you know, just-
- Oh, it's beautiful.
- And this one too. It's my favorite.
- Just same old stuff, same old.
All right.
Well, just remember,
if you need me, you give me a call.
- Oh, I appreciate that.
- Kelly: It's my favorite.
Kelly: Yeah,
it's kind of the Aztec...
- Jack: Okay, yep. Thanks.
- Yates: May I?
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
- It's absolutely beautiful.
- Let's go. I'll walk you out.
- All right.
- Kelly: Okay.
- See you.
- See you. Nice to meet you.
- Yeah, see you around.
- Yeah, likewise.
- I'll be right back.
- All right, sweetie.
So tell me about this
five-year plan.
Stay away from her.
What do you think
you're doing?
Hmm? Look, I don't blame you
for not telling her
about our little escapade
at the convenience store.
Chicks can be funny
about that that stuff-
all that violence
and stuff.
What's it gonna take
to get you out of my life?
Now why the fuck would I want
to get out of your life?
What do you want?
I told you, I need a partner,
someone I can trust.
There's good money
in it, mate.
Think of Kelly.
You stay away from us.
If I see you, if I hear you,
if I even get a fucking whiff of you,
I'm gonna rip your fucking world apart.
You understand me?
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, fuck.
Oh. Oh. Oh.
What's going on, mate?
What's going on, big fellow?
Oh, what's this?
Nitro-- nitroglycerin.
Take when needed.
I guess that's about now, huh?
Did you lie about
your heart, mate,
said it was some kind of
genetic defect,
that you were born with it?
You sold me out, didn't you?
- What?
- You sold me out.
I had a fucking heart attack.
Still there was no need
to squeal like a fucking pig.
You know what?
You're gonna fuck--
you're gonna fucking
do this for me
one way or the other,
you fucking dog.
Honey, that was fun last night,
wasn't it?
Yeah, it was a blast.
Do you need my car today?
No, I'm all set. I just need
to blow out the fuel filter.
Oh, I love it
when you talk dirty.
- I love you.
- Have a good day.
- Gary, hi.
- Hiya, love.
Hi. ls everything okay?
Yeah, everything's fine.
I just was in the neighborhood
and I wanted to thank you
again for last night.
Like I said, anytime.
That's not the real reason
I'm here.
Really?
No.
I want to show you
something.
- Is Jack in on this?
- No, no, no, no.
But it does have something to do
with your five-year plan.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
It's not far from here.
I mean, it's, like,
five minutes.
Um, okay.
- Well, I'll just go and get my jacket.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. All right.
No worries.
Molloy, the boss said
you were looking for me.
Yeah.
Did you hear about
the convenience store job?
What?
You're different
than I expected.
Oh.
How so?
You're not Molloy's type.
Really?
Why is that?
You got too much class.
( Both chuckle)
The videotape is gonna show
me and Yates talking
like we were planning it out.
10 seconds later
he kills the kid.
Next thing I know,
I'm emptying the register.
10 seconds after that
he kills the woman.
Like you were in it together?
I couldn't go to the cops.
Well, if you did, we'd be talking
through glass again.
I don't know what to fucking do.
I don't know what to do.
- What do you think?
- I love it.
(laughs ) Oh my God,
Jack is going to absolutely flip.
Yates-
he didn't just happen
to run into you.
He planned this.
He set you up,
that crazy fuck.
What am I gonna do?
Have you told your woman
about any of this?
No, no, no, man.
Listen, Molloy,
I gotta go, all right?
But I'm off tomorrow.
Anything you need-
you just let me know.
Whew. Fuck.
How much do you know
about him?
- About his past?
- Yeah.
I know he moved here from LA
about eight years ago
after a divorce, no kids.
Left a good job in Sydney
'cause of the stress.
This is fantastic.
Why? Have you got
some dirt on him?
Might have.
(cell phone ringing )
Duty calls.
Lisa?
What are you talking about?
What space?
Well, he came by the shop
and said that he had
something to show me.
And you just went off
with him?
Yeah. Why wouldn't I?
He's your friend, isn't he?
No, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just-
Anyway, this space is fantastic.
You're gonna love it.
The light is-.
It's killer.
It's brilliant.
He said he's got some kind
of a deal in the works.
What kind of deal?
I don't know.
He didn't go into detail,
but just that he's closing
in a week or two
and when he's done,
he wants to invest.
He wants me to come up
with some kind of a business plan
by the weekend.
You really shouldn't have
just gone off with him.
Are you jealous?
No, I..
- You are.
- No.
Well, you shouldn't be,
'cause all we talked about was you.
(glass clinking)
(distant dog barking )
- What was that?
- What was what?
- Honey, what's going on?
- Stay right here.
What's going on?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I saw someone
checking door handles.
He-- he stole that car
I was just trying to stop him.
Stopping a moving vehicle?
Are you crazy?
It's okay.
Kelly: Let's go inside.
Maybe we should call
the police.
No, I didn't get
a license plate number.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
( Phone ringing )
Rule number one:
always know where the camera is.
I don't suppose
this is the original, is it?
You suppose right.
Piccolo's on Broadbeach,
20 minutes.
Hey, um,
that was someone
from work.
I gotta go meet him
for some coffee.
- He's having some trouble.
- Okay.
Come on, Kelly, pick up.
Damn it.
- Kelly! Kel--
- Yeah, I'm in here, honey.
Oh, that was a long coffee.
I've got to go.
I just called you, like, a minute ago.
Why--?
Well, I was just-
I was blow-drying my hair.
Hey, Molloy.
This was on my desk
when I came in this morning.
Thanks, boss.
(water running)
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Oh.
Oh, fuck.
No!
-( phone ringing )
- Oh my God.
Yeah.
I hate myself, mate.
I really do.
Listen to me,
you motherfucker.
If you come near her again,
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
Rule number two: don't make a threat
unless you can back it up.
All right, look,
we need to talk.
- We are talking.
- No. No, no, no, face to face.
You win.
You've proved your point.
I'll do the job.
I'm in, okay?
All right, mate.
I'm not feeling the love.
Just do the fucking math.
I want you out of my life
for good.
You understand me?
I do this job--
I get that video tape, the original.
And then you disappear.
That's what's gotta happen.
Sounds more than fair.
Meet me at 10:00
at Elsewhere.
Do you know where that is?
I was baptized there.
It was a beautiful thing.
I'll meet you there.
Don't be late, Molloy.
He posted pictures of me
on Facebook
in my army boots,
naked.
- Oh--
- Don't ask, Kel.
(car engine starts)
♪ A larger hand
turns the wheel ♪
♪ Too far away to feel ♪
♪ Jagged on the inside ♪
♪ The truth whispers in my ear ♪
♪ Oh, the future was so clear ♪
♪ Painted on the inside ♪
♪ Days turn over ♪
♪ Ever colder ♪
♪ Is this the end ♪
♪ Of the warm season? ♪
(chimes tinkling)
This here situation,
the way you tell it,
I don't see
no good end to it.
If it was the old days,
I'd take him out for you myself,
chuck a spear in his ass.
But I got a good woman now.
And she's in a family way.
I'm not asking you
to take him out.
I need a gun.
Oh.
I don't do guns, Molloy.
You know that.
I know,
but you know people who do.
Look, I wouldn't be asking,
but I don't know what else to do.
He got into my house
and took a videotape
of Kelly taking a shower.
And you're gonna do this
yourself?
I'm gonna do
whatever it takes, yeah.
I always liked you, Molloy.
You bailed me out of more jams
than I can count.
You always
treated me square,
like a person,
like a human being.
And that's why
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
You're out of your league
with Yates.
What, you think waving a pistol
around in his face
is gonna put
the fear of God in him?
It ain't gonna happen,
brother.
He ain't afraid of nothing,
and that includes God.
You flip the situation around,
say you were fucking with him,
getting into his shit
or sniffing around
his woman-
you'd already be dead
with your throat cut.
You ain't the man
you used to be, Molloy.
And you ain't a killer.
You ain't got it in you.
You know that.
I know that.
And Yates-
he knows that too.
Can you give me a gun
or not?
- Jack: Hey, baby, you still at work?
- Yeah, I'm just closing up.
Listen, I'm gonna go out with a couple
of the guys tonight after work,
shoot some pool,
have a few laughs.
Good. Seems like you could do
with a night out.
Kel...
Jack?
Are you there?
Yeah, I'm here.
I gotta go. baby-
Okay, love you.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Are you sure about this?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Ain't much good
without these.
What do I owe you?
Maybe you can help me
get my land back.
( Both chuckle)
Thanks.
I really appreciate this.
No worries.
Why do you think
he's doing this?
There's spirits that take over
weaker souls like Yates-
turns them into murderers
and thieves.
There ain't no "why" to it,
no understanding it.
It's just the way it is,
the way it's always been-
evil.
Are you still gonna do this?
I'm meeting him tonight
at Elsewhere at 10:00.
Then what?
♪ A snake around your soul ♪
♪ Kiss the dying sun ♪
♪ Streets breathe gasoline ♪
♪ Rope around your tongue... ♪
(cell phone rings)
Yeah.
How are you, mate?
You still on for tonight?
Yeah.
- Why wouldn't I be?
- Just checking.
I made another copy
of the convenience store tape,
left them on your
kitchen table.
♪ Feel your maker ♪
♪ Poisoned savior... ♪
- Put them on.
- .' Feel your maker .'
♪ Steal danger... ♪
And turn around.
Nice.
♪ Strut the walls... ♪
Come here.
♪ Squeeze the trigger now... ♪
-( Woman moans)
- .' Play the pretty fool .'
♪ All kingdom come ♪
♪ Feel your maker ♪
♪ Poisoned savior... ♪
- Kelly.
- .' Feel your maker... .'
Kel.
Kelly.
I'm going out
for a while, babe.
Gotta do a favor
for a friend.
I won't be long.
(tires screeching )
- Kelly.
- Go away.
Please just--
just let me explain, Kel.
I just need two minutes.
That's all I'm asking.
Hey.
Kelly: Hey.
The truth, okay?
The truth, all of it.
I did two stints in prison-
one for stealing a car...
and the other one
for possession of-- of drugs.
I was doing about three grams,
if not more, of coke
a day.
I was taking downs
to take the edge off.
And...
I would just drink...
all day long.
I've lied.
I've cheated.
I did about a dozen
armed robberies.
And I never gave any of it
a second thought.
It's just what I did
back then.
But that's the past.
I'm telling you, it's over.
And I had nothing to do--
nothing to do
with the convenience store.
I was being setup,
blackmailed by Gary.
His real name is Yates.
I'm so sorry
that I lied to you.
I'm--
I'm on parole.
And I didn't--
I didn't know if they were gonna
throw me in jail
or deport me back to the US.
And then
I would never have gotten
to see you again.
And I'm not sure if I was gonna
be able to take that.
Just go.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about our plans,
your plans.
♪ When you build her ♪
♪ Give her steel-plated rims ♪
♪ Make her heart beat ♪
♪ Like an engine ♪
♪ And not miss ♪
♪ Sandbag her ♪
♪ Against the flood ♪
♪ Or she may drown ♪
♪ Termite-proof ♪
♪ The parts of her ♪
♪ That touch the ground ♪
♪ Carve her name ♪
♪ Into the trunk ♪
.' Of a tree .'
♪ Just have sap run down ♪
♪ And land ♪
♪ At her feet... ♪
Oh!
God.
Bear.
( Phone ringing )
- Hello.
- You found my little surprise?
You sick motherfucker!
I take that as a yes.
Elsewhere, 10:00.
(chuckles)
( knocking on door)
Oh my God.
Hey.
Hey. Fancy seeing you.
- How are you doing?
- Well, aren't you gonna invite me in?
Yeah, I was just
on my way out.
Kelly just called me.
She said-
She's not here?
No, she-- she's having
car trouble.
- So she needed me to pick--
- Hope you don't mind if I just
come in and have
a little look around.
Yeah.
Um, you want something
to drink?
- No, I'm good, thanks.
- Huh?
- I'm good.
- Yeah?
I'm just surprised
to see you.
- Molloy.
- Yeah?
I don't normally do house calls,
as you know.
I've had a call from a friend of yours,
said they're a bit concerned about you.
So here I am.
Oh.
Everything's fine.
Mm-hmm.
"The Great Escape."
( chuckles )
Yeah, it's a great movie,
a classic.
Yeah.
So this is pretty much it.
L-- I-- I gotta get Kelly.
Like I tell you,
since I'm here,
might as well do this.
It'll take a sec.
Yeah. Yeah.
After you.
Um...
SO...
(Jack coughing)
Excuse me.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just got a little cold,
I think.
( Urinating )
Drink more water
and be safe.
There you go.
That's good.
(water running)
Okay.
That's it.
So...
So I don't mean to be rude.
I just gotta-
So everything's all right?
Yeah, no, it's great.
She's-- she's all moved in.
Uh, yeah, it's--
it's great.
Well, you know what?
I might have been wrong
about you.
Oh, well, there's a first time
for everything, I guess.
(chuckles)
Yeah.
Well, you just keep
out of trouble.
Okay. Thanks for stopping by.
Yeah.
Hey.
Shall we go talk?
Yeah.
After you.
Where are we going, matey?
Oh. Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Don't move.
Don't move. Don't move.
I told you to stay away
from us, didn't I?
You did. You did.
(chuckles)
You think it's fucking funny?
Yes, I do.
( laughing )
You fuck with me--
that's fine.
Whatever you got,
I can take.
But you fuck with her,
you fuck with Kelly--
that I'm not gonna take.
That I won't take.
And what you did to Bear,
motherfucker-
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Don't put your fucking hand out.
Bear came at me, partner.
- Get out!
-( alarm ringing)
( door slams )
(distant siren wailing)
Oh. ( laughing)
Come on, you.
(coughing )
Well, go on, shoot me.
Shoot me.
Not yet, partner.
We still have
one more job to pull.
(cell phone ringing )
Oh, fuck.
(groaning )
Yeah, hello.
Yates:
Did you have a nice nap?
I've got one more
surprise for you.
Meet me in 20 minutes,
305 Surf Parade.
( Tires screech )
You're so fucking
predictable, man.
Shut the blinds.
You four, over there.
Come on.
Hey, you don't need them.
Just leave them alone. Let them go.
- Shut up!
- Just let them go.
On the floor.
Hands behind your head.
Get down!
(women scream )
Feels good, doesn't it?
(women whimpering )
Come on, fill them up.
I'm sorry.
It's gonna be okay.
(women scream )
We're getting close, mate-
end of your life.
It's called karma.
(Jack groaning)
And as usual,
you're bringing someone
with you.
(women scream )
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Fill them up.
Come on.
You looking for these?
Give him his pills.
Back room now, come on.
Come on, open the safe.
Let's go.
Now be quiet.
All right, come on.
Hurry up, open it.
Good girl.
(whimpers)
Are you fucking with me?
- No. Just--
- You'd better not.
Just-- just hold on, okay?
I'll get it.
(woman whimpering )
Hey.
Shh. Shh.
- Here you go, mate.
-( pills rattling)
Kelly:
Why are you doing this?
He stole my fucking life.
You understand?
Three years
in a fucking cell.
And he's out here with you,
shacked up with Miss-
Miss April.
It's not fair,
not in my world.
You should have been
there, mate.
I was busy being dead.
Then you should have
stayed there.
Ladies before gentlemen.
( Gasps )
(screams)
Oy!
Oh. Oh.
(groaning )
- I'm sorry, baby. I'm sorry.
- Just hold on.
- I'm so sorry.
- Don't be silly.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, Kelly.
You have to get out of here.
Come on, Jack.
Come on.
Listen to me.
The 9'-IV"
the guy that did all those things
back then,
the guy
with the death wish--
he got his wish, Kelly.
He had a heart attack
and died.
He doesn't exist anymore.
And the guy
that you're looking at now--
the guy
with the nine-to-five job,
lives in a two-bedder,
loves Thai takeaway...
loves when his girlfriend
talks dirty to him...
( both chuckle)
...the way she smiles.
He loves everything
about her.
And whatever happens
with us,
that's enough.
Okay?
(siren wailing)
Listen to me.
If you want out,
now is your time.
For better or for worse.
Isn't that how it goes, Jack?
♪ You know I would ♪
♪ Slow the earth ♪
♪ To stay by your side ♪
♪ I'd tame the sea ♪
♪ To heal your hurt ♪
♪ And I'd turn the sun ♪
♪ Move the stars ♪
♪ If that's what you needed ♪
♪ To fade these scars ♪
♪ In a world ♪
♪ In all the lines ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Mends the broken places ♪
♪ Makes them stronger ♪
♪ Changes ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ Oh, and love ♪
♪ Is what pain replaces ♪
♪ Breaks us down ♪
♪ And makes us ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ You're my everything ♪
♪ One day we'll see ♪
♪ How far we've come ♪
♪ A universal way ♪
♪ From the darkness inside ♪
♪ Where shadows run ♪
♪ In the light of you ♪
♪ I'll face the truth ♪
♪ You're all I needed ♪
♪ A living proof ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Mends the broken places ♪
♪ Makes them stronger ♪
♪ Changes ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ And love ♪
♪ Is what pain replaces ♪
♪ Breaks us down ♪
♪ And makes us ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ You're my everything ♪
♪ Don't you know ♪
♪ I'm here to stay? ♪
♪ Only I would be ♪
♪ A touch away ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Mends the broken places ♪
♪ Makes them stronger ♪
♪ Changes ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ Oh, and love ♪
♪ Is what pain replaces ♪
♪ Breaks us down ♪
♪ And makes us ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ You're my everything. ♪
( Music playing )
♪ A larger hand turns the wheel ♪
♪ Too far away to feel ♪
♪ Jagged on the inside ♪
♪ The truth whispers in my ear ♪
♪ Oh, the future was so clear ♪
♪ Painted on the inside ♪
♪ Days turn over ♪
♪ Ever colder ♪
♪ Is this the end ♪
♪ Of the warm season? ♪
♪ What rises in your sleep ♪
♪ Wake to find
you're in too deep ♪
♪ Nothing left to cling to ♪
♪ The horizon blinding you ♪
♪ A feast of crows circling ♪
♪ Stories left to wander ♪
♪ Days turn over ♪
♪ Ever colder ♪
♪ Is this the end ♪
♪ Of the warm season? ♪
( Music playing )