All this time.
We won't have moved.
(BIRDS FLUTTERING)
SOLDIER: You got away
from the British?
- How many of you?
- Just me.
(GUNSHOT)
- Leave them.
- What?
- (GROANS) Get off!
- You'll get us both killed!
(DEREK GRUNTS)
How do we know it will end?
It will. It has to.
Maybe when there's no one left
to fight any more.
The_Passing_Bells - S01 - E05
Re-Sync & Edit
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha
(EXPLOSIONS)
(PANTING)
Push. Please.
Please. You're nearly there.
(JOANNA SCREAMING)
Ahh!
(EXPLOSION)
(CRYING)
Shh, shh.
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(GUNFIRE AND EXPLOSIONS)
(INHALING)
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(EXPLOSION)
WOMAN 1: I'm sorry, that's all I've got.
WOMAN 2: I've got more kids to feed
than you have.
WOMAN 3: Get off, get off me!
Ah!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
DEREK: Tommy!
It's a boy! They called him Thomas!
It's a boy!
(ALL CHEERING)
SOLDIER: Move back, dig in.
Move back, dig in.
We've done nothing but
go backwards for a month.
All I'm saying is,
why don't we keep just going back,
all the way home?
Just throw down our guns and go.
Do you think I want to be here?
(SHOUTING) Do you think
any of us want to be here?
But we are!
I haven't spent four years of my life
watching people that I love
die all around me just to
drop my rifle and go home!
Sorry, sorry.
I've watched my friends die, too.
I'm sick of it.
I suppose I can smell the end of it.
I'm just as frightened by that
as I am of fighting.
We keep moving forward,
but how come we haven't seen
any Germans?
We will.
I can't think what else
we're doing here.
Pushing them back, that's all.
They're saying that the Germans might
have had enough
now the Americans have joined us.
A bloke from the Irish Guards
said that he heard that
some of them are giving up
and heading back home.
Don't tell me,
- "This'll all be over by Christmas."
- That's what they're saying!
Yeah. And they said that in 1914, 1915
and '16 and '17.
All right but,
what if they're right
what they're saying this time
and we can go home?
I'll kiss everyone I see
from here to Blighty.
Well, maybe not everyone. (CHUCKLES)
It's got to be over soon.
- I don't know if I can do much more.
- We'll be all right.
No, I mean it, Tommy.
I think I'll go mad.
Just stick with me, all right?
We'll go home together.
- (BABY COOING)
- (JOANNA SINGING)
DAVID: There's an article about Poland.
"As revolution grows across Europe
"and the armistice gets closer,
"it is thought there could be
a new Peoples Republic of Poland
"within weeks."
Can I keep it to show my father?
(EXPLOSIONS)
Right, they're dug in 200 yards ahead,
and we'll wire down
till Artillery's gonna let them
know we're here.
(EXPLOSIONS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
- (SOLDIER GIVING ORDERS)
- Coming, sir.
Move yourselves!
Move! Move! Move!
Come on!
Move yourself!
We've got injured, come on!
Move!
"With Hungary and now Austria
out of the war,
"the Germans are becoming isolated
"and the armistice grows
nearer by the day."
Joanna Braun. Joanna?
"It is thought that German terms
"will soon be presented
to the allied and associated governments
"and finally...
"the war will be over."
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
MAN: At last!
Her dad's been killed.
I'm not sure if we'll get
any more leaves, son.
Not when top brass thinks
we've got them on the run
and all we're hearin' is "push forward".
I've got a baby, Sergeant.
Yeah? Well, if this armistice happens,
we'll all be home for good soon.
- Do you really think so?
- It'll happen. Just don't ask me when.
Hopefully before that nipper
of yours starts school.
I'll ask, all right?
Sergeant,
is there any chance of moving
Derek back to the supply trenches?
He's not right.
Go out there and find me a man who is.
(EXPLOSIONS)
I wasn't much use today, was I?
You've marched miles
in the past few weeks.
You're just tired, that's all.
We all are.
But you're doing brilliantly.
"Head down, push on till
the job's done," remember?
I try, Tommy.
But every time a shell goes off
I jump out of my skin.
My hands are always shaking.
My nerves are shot.
I don't want to die.
Stay close to me, you'll be all right.
Do you think I'm a coward?
No.
Don't ever say that.
We're all scared.
Right? Every single one of us.
Maybe you're more used to it than I am.
Sometimes my hands are shaking so much,
I have to wedge my arm into the sandbags
just to fire me rifle.
There's nothing wrong with being scared.
It just means you're human.
Being scared will keep you alive.
Now get some sleep.
Thanks, Tommy.
Why are you always reading that?
Reminds me of home, I suppose.
It was the first book I ever got.
I must have been about six.
I mark off the ones I've seen.
I sketch them sometimes, too.
It's funny I...
I don't think people realise
how beautiful birds are.
You know, you see them out here,
they even land on the barbed wire.
Something so beautiful,
in the middle of something so ugly.
Do you think it's true what people
are saying?
That the fighting will stop soon?
We'll see.
It's funny, innit?
A hundred years from now
none of us will be here.
And all this...
will be ancient history.
I wonder what people will make of it?
It doesn't seem that long
since I was putting his dad
to bed in the same room.
I'm sorry.
(BABY COOING)
My father died for
something he believed in
so I'm sad, but
I'm proud, too.
Just like little Thomas
will be when his dad comes home.
All the officers have been
called back to the command centre.
You think this is it?
Something's happening.
I can't believe he's coming home.
- Nothing's been announced yet.
- The papers say it's over.
Well, the fighting doesn't just stop,
they have to agree terms.
The price may be more than
we're willing to pay.
But we have no choice.
Choice or not, they're politicians
so it's going to take time.
They won't keep fighting, will they?
Not while they're talking.
- Probably.
- But that's stupid!
If everyone knows it's over,
why let more boys die?
That's not the way they see it.
Why not? Don't they have children?
Writing home?
Maybe if the rumours are true
I won't have to post it.
I can take it myself. (CHUCKLING)
But who knows
what we'll be going back to.
Does it matter?
As long as we're home.
It won't be the home we left,
if we lose this war.
There's no food,
no jobs.
My wife will be there.
Everything else we can just
rebuild, in time.
Right now I'd settle for
sitting in front of a warm fire.
Kaiser Bill's chucked the towel in boys!
We've got them on the run!
- What's that mean, Sergeant?
- Means he's abdicated.
They'll be like headless chickens now.
We'll be home by Christmas.
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING)
SOLDIER: We've heard that one before.
Did you hear?
I heard.
So that's it, then.
They haven't told us to start
packing up to go home yet.
Yeah, but they will do, won't they?
If the Kaiser's gone,
that's good isn't it?
Yeah. It's good.
It won't be long now.
(EXPLOSION)
All we need now
is for someone to tell that lot.
(EXPLOSIONS)
MAN: Place is agreed. Railway siding,
Compiègne Forest.
(SCREAMING)
Come on!
(GUNFIRE)
(SHOUTING ORDERS)
(EXPLOSIONS AND GUNFIRE)
(GASPS)
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
- Monday morning.
- Eh?
Looked in my diary this morning
and saw it was Monday.
Damn.
Missed Sunday roast again yesterday.
Beef and Yorkshire pudding
swimming in gravy.
Just think, back at home.
Everyone going back to work
after the weekend,
another week starting.
It's quiet.
They were shelling us
this time yesterday.
Maybe they're having a lie-in.
- Morning, boys.
- Sergeant.
Looks like a shell's taken out
a section of the wire.
It's your turn, Del.
It's all right, Sergeant, I'll do it.
Dead in line with the next elbow,
you should be able to
pull it back together and tie it.
It's all quiet over there
but keep your head down
in case they've got a sniper on watch.
Don't worry about that.
You didn't have to do that,
it's my turn.
You'd only get tangled up in the wire
and I'd have to come and get you anyway.
Thanks, Tommy.
Give me a shout when dinner's ready.
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(CLICKING)
(GRUNTS)
Take this. Go!
(GUNSHOT)
(LABOURED BREATHING)
SOLDIER: The war is over!
Germany surrendered!
The_Passing_Bells - S01 - E05
Re-Sync & Edit
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha