( wind whistling )
( birds calling )
( door creaks )
Hey, he's right here.
Woman:
l've only read about it.
l know it's extremely rare.
So he can't feel
or touch?
No, he responds
to normal touch and pressure.
His body just can't recognize
sensations of pain.
ClPA is a very
dangerous condition.
He could bite his own tongue off
and not even realize it.
He could break a bone
and keep on playing.
Even hot foods have to be checked
before he eats them.
Of course.
He has to be checked hourly
for cuts and bruises,
and not just his arms and legs,
but his whole body,
even inside his mouth.
This is very important.
Martin can't tell
when something hurts.
Hi there.
l bought this new bike
for my nephew's birthday,
but he doesn't like the color.
Can you believe that?
l was gonna just throw it out
when l saw you and l thought,
''There's a kid who'd probably love
a new bike.''
Am l right?
lt's right in my truck.
Want to take a look?
Do you like red?
lt's difficult and exhausting.
l've been through
two aides already.
You don't have to worry,
Mrs. Bristol.
Whatever you need, l'm here.
Would you like to meet him now?
- Yes, please.
- Okay.
Mrs. Bristol:
Oh God.
Martin!
( distant dog barking )
( rain pattering )
( thunder crashing )
( man grunting )
( woman sobbing )
Don't be afraid.
lt doesn't have any feelings.
( woman gasps, sobbing )
lt doesn't hurt, see?
( woman screams )
( woman screaming )
( continues screaming )
No!
lt'll be over soon.
( woman screaming )
- ( woman screaming )
- ( thunder rumbling )
( thunder crashing )
( birds chirping )
( music playing on radio )
lt's good to see you.
How are you holding up?
Okay.
You know, you were here
once before.
You were about that big.
Remember?
Not really.
So that's everything?
Yeah.
Okay.
# lf l could see #
# Beyond this moment #
# l'd hope to see you #
# Looking... #
How long do l have to
give up my room?
Well, just until your father finishes
remodeling the den.
l'll be in college.
They're here!
Now remember,
calm and compassionate.
No, Wen-- Wendy.
Hi.
She's an only child.
- Hi!
- Hi.
- Do you like mice?
- No.
- How about snakes?
l can do a cartwheel.
Want to see?
Oh, Allison, look at you.
- Oh.
- ( Wendy chattering )
Mom, get out of the way.
You didn't tell me
how pretty she is.
My side of the family.
- You must be starving.
- Not really.
Come on, Randy.
This dog is always
under my feet.
Come on in.
- Hey, Dad, need some help?
- Yeah, l could use a hand.
Mom, Dad needs some help.
Do you really get up at 4:00
every morning?
When l'm in training, yeah.
Can't you use a treadmill?
Dad's got one.
He hangs his shirts on it.
Wendy.
Allison:
l run distance.
This is my room,
or was my room.
Now you'll be sleeping here just until
Jonathan finishes remodeling the den.
You didn't have to do that.
( squeaking )
Whiskers, how did you get out of there?
You naughty little boy.
We'll be having supper
in just a few minutes.
lf you need anything,
just give a shout.
This is your home too now.
She's really taking it hard.
Well, what do you expect?
Her whole life's been turned
upside down overnight.
( music playing over radio )
Hey, Melissa,
are you leaving already?
Yeah.
Hey, can you cover
my shift tomorrow?
l have exams.
l know. l have to take Jesse
to the doctor again.
How about Danielle?
l asked her already.
Yeah, okay.
- Thank you, sweetie.
- No problem.
( honks horn )
Hey, you're blocking my car.
( yelps )
( doors slam )
( thunder rumbling )
( grunting )
( Melissa moaning )
( Melissa crying )
No. No, wait, please.
No no, please.
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
No. Ow. Ow.
( screaming )
Help!
Ow. Ow.
Please.
Help!
( screaming, sobbing )
( distant train horn blowing )
( Melissa crying )
Help.
Woman: lt's no use.
Who's there?
Hello?
We're gonna die down here.
No.
No, we're gonna get out of here.
What day is it?
( screaming )
( shrieking )
( panting )
Curiosity killed the cat.
( distant train horn blaring )
( rock music playing
on radio )
( truck approaching )
- ( horn blowing )
- ( gasps )
( grunts )
Ow.
Whoa.
- Are you all right?
- l think so.
They wouldn't brake for the pope
on this road.
Yeah, l see that.
Your-- your arm is bleeding.
You want to come inside?
You can wash up.
lt's nothing.
Oh shit.
- Are you sure you're all right?
- Yeah, it's just my leg.
You want me to give you
a ride home?
No, it's okay, really.
lt's not a big deal,
just a couple miles up the street.
How do you know?
Small town.
Come on.
What are neighbors for?
A few miles?
That's hardly neighbors.
Around here that's
a next-door neighbor.
Okay, sure.
All right, l'll be right back.
Ow.
Uh, l think l'm just gonna walk.
Are you afraid?
l'm not afraid.
Great.
Then get on.
What's your name?
- Allison.
- William.
Slow down.
l've never been on one
of these things before.
After my accident the doctor said
l'd never ride again.
l'm kidding.
So where are you from?
Chicago.
l was there once.
What brings you to this armpit?
l came to live with my uncle.
A problem with the parents?
Family issues?
Yeah.
You too, huh?
What kind of problems?
They're dead.
Shit, l'm sorry.
Yeah.
Me too.
Thanks for the ride.
Keep it.
You need it.
Man on radio: Still no leads
in the disappearance
of college student Melissa Barnes
who was last seen
leaving her place of employment
at the Charcoal Diner...
Hey, how was your run?
lnteresting.
( thunder rumbling, crashing )
Woman:
Melissa, l-- l think
my hand is coming loose.
( door opens )
He's coming.
Don't make a sound.
We're gonna get out of here.
Man: When steer are led
to slaughter,
they smell the stench
of fear and blood
and they panic.
Sometimes we'd have to saw off
their hind legs
so they couldn't run.
No.
No, please.
Woman: No.
No. Oh God!
- ( knife tears flesh )
- ( woman screaming )
Man:
Hold her still.
( woman continues screaming )
Man:
Get back here.
( woman continues screaming )
( panting )
lt's okay.
Everything's under control.
Looks like l got here
just in time.
( screaming )
When something outlasts
its usefulness,
it gets discarded.
( lock clicks )
( thunder crashing )
( hissing )
Still here?
( distant train horn blaring )
- See you later.
- Yeah.
- Bye.
( clicks tongue )
Are you sure you're all right?
Yeah, gotta get it over with
sooner or later.
She'll be fine.
Nervous?
You think they'll have
a decent track team?
Don't get your hopes up.
No chance of that.
What is that place?
That's the Sutter plant.
lt's been closed for years.
l saw someone there yesterday
while l was jogging--
a boy.
A boy?
Yeah, l thought so.
Probably just some kids
vandalizing the place.
l kind of wish
you'd stay away from there
and jog on the main road.
Yeah, and get hit by a truck.
Graham's a pack rat.
That place should be condemned.
Someone lives there?
Yeah, he stays mostly
to himself.
You know him?
We're about the same age.
He never went to school.
His dad made him work at that place
day and night.
lt was a meat-packing plant
till they couldn't afford
to upgrade the equipment to code.
l'll tell you one thing:
l don't miss the smell.
l'll pick you up at 2:30.
Silence is a sound
of no fear...
no pain...
the sound of peace.
( grunts )
l envy your serenity.
The path to redemption
begins with forgiveness--
absolution.
You're my witness.
What did l tell you?
l told you don't touch,
didn't l?
William:
Yeah, the bolts are stripped.
Cashier:
$17.50.
- Can l owe you the 50 cents?
- Yeah, right.
William:
Thanks, Eddie.
Jonathan, how's that
extension coming?
lt's going really good.
( engine starts )
You know you've got
drywall nails here?
Hmm?
Oh shit.
Just cheerleading.
Unless you can kick a field goal.
That's it?
There isn't much of a demand
for girls' sports in this area.
Our cheerleading squad
did win Best Routine
in the state final last year.
( sighs )
( girls cheering )
Come on! Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Girl: Ready?
( girls chanting )
Let's shake it. Let's shout it.
PHS!
Let's shake it.
Let's shout it.
PHS!
Let's shake it.
Let's shout it.
Aren't you scared of that falling
and crushing you?
How's your leg?
Oh, it's better.
So this is what you do--
fix cars?
Guidance counselor told me
my aptitude tests said
either medical school
or auto mechanic.
l can't stand the sight of blood, so...
Okay, well,
l don't want to bother you, so...
Hey.
Yeah?
Are you busy later?
Um, l was gonna go home
and stare at the ceiling
until l fell asleep. Why?
Well, l was--
l was wondering if maybe
you wanted to--
Man: Billy!
Excuse me.
- Billy!
- Dad?
ln here.
- Christ.
- God.
l dropped the fucking remote.
Be careful.
- Ow, Jesus!
- Sorry, Dad.
- Oh man.
- You're dead weight.
Yeah, well, l'm not dead yet.
- Oh.
- Can l help?
- Father: Just-- just lift me up.
- Yeah, just hold his chair.
- Okay.
- Come on, just put me back on my chair.
( grunts )
You got it.
- Allison: Here.
- ( both men grunt )
- Allison: Okay.
- You could have hurt yourself.
What do you mean,
could have?
( groans )
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Um, Dad, this is Allison.
Allison, this is my dad.
- Allison: Hi.
- She's from Chicago.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- From Chicago?
- Yeah.
l hate Chicago.
- Hey, at least you're not gay, right?
- Dad.
You know, he spends most of the time
alone in his room,
- doing who knows what.
- Yeah, you should talk.
Yeah, but it's about the only thing
l've got left.
Um, l should probably go.
William:
No, stay.
No, it's getting late.
l really have to get home.
William:
He's not normally like this.
He's usually much worse.
Well, maybe you should give him
the helmet.
Bye.
( door opens, closes )
What the hell
is the matter with you?
Can't she take a joke?
Hey, come on.
Hey, toss me my cigarettes.
Hey, what--?
Now what am l supposed to do?
( scrubbing )
What's your name?
Hello?
Can you answer me, please?
Graham:
lf they have no feelings,
they can't know fear.
But if they can't know fear...
why do they run?
Let me go.
All clean?
Come here.
What are you doing?
Give me your arm.
Don't.
Run!
He doesn't understand.
Can't you see?
Stop it. Stop it!
His conscience is unburdened.
You're crazy!
ls yours?
Let me go!
You're fucking crazy!
Oh God.
Where were you?
Um, l'm sorry.
You're sorry?
Jonathan.
l thought we said 2:30.
l left early.
We were beginning to worry.
Well, l said l'm sorry.
Let's not make it a habit.
- Okay?
- Okay.
You've been to Paris?
Yeah, a few times.
Wow, you've been to so many
cool places.
Yeah, my dad used to turn
all of his business trips
into family vacations.
He was great like that.
l've never been anywhere.
Well, maybe someday you can go
to Chicago with me.
- Tomorrow?
- No.
( knocks on door )
Hi guys. Wendy.
Can l borrow your camera?
Yeah, there's a few
more pictures left.
You can finish the roll
if you want.
- ( camera shutter clicks )
- Dad, can we go to France?
Sure. l'll cash in
some stock options.
See what l mean?
How about Pittsburgh, huh?
Wendy: How much longer
do l have to give up my room?
Jonathan:
Not much longer.
Wendy: Don't you think
Whiskers needs a bigger cage?
Jonathan:
l think that cage is just fine.
Do you think
Allison's happy here?
l hope so.
l don't think she likes me.
How could somebody
not like you?
- l know, right?
- Right.
( chuckles )
You know, l'm-- l-- l--
l'm feeling--
feeling something.
l'm feeling a little--
l'm feeling a little hungry.
( Wendy giggling )
Oh no.
- l need a pillow sandwich.
- ( squeals, giggling )
( imitates chewing )
Hello.
Can you talk?
l can help you.
You've just got to help me
get loose first.
Please.
Help me.
l've done everything
you've asked me.
You could make it stop.
( heart beating )
( whimpering )
( screams )
God damn it!
( whimpering )
( screaming )
( Melissa screaming )
( flesh rips )
( continues screaming )
Now they can't trust you.
You're gonna have to
make it up to them somehow.
They take advantage
of vulnerability
and weakness.
Bury it.
The furnace needs scrubbing.
Graham:
You caused all this.
Be good, sweetie.
l will.
Whiskers, no.
Theories on our
emotional development
are divided into
two schools of thought--
whether we're products
of genetics
predisposed to exhibit
certain behavioral patterns,
or products
of our environment.
Evolutionary biologists believe
that our inherited genes
are what determine
development.
Opponents argue
that our individuality
is directly influenced
by the patterns of behavior
that we see and hear
every day.
ln other words,
a child raised
in a loving environment
will respond to the world
in a much different way
than a child raised in fear
or taught to hate.
Our children are in essence
mirror images of ourselves--
our beliefs, our ideologies,
our conscience--
ground control to Major Tom--
which brings us
to psychotherapy--
the psychoanalytic theory
of personality.
This will be on the test, people.
Hey, need a ride?
Uh, l don't know.
Come on, get in.
Take a break.
Have some fun.
Are you starting
your own pharmacy?
l get headaches.
l can't stay out late.
Don't worry.
l'll have you back by Monday.
Yeah, l restored it piece by piece.
l thought about opening my own
body shop one day, but...
Why don't you?
Um, well, my dad--
he's not so good on his own.
So how far do you run anyway?
Five, six miles.
l would have a heart attack.
Yeah.
These will give you
a heart attack.
l guess you never eat
junk like this, huh?
l'm not in training right now.
Yeah, me neither.
( insects chirping )
( engine starts )
So do you have any
brothers or sisters?
Just me and my dad.
My mom died
a couple of years ago--
pneumonia.
Has he always been, um--?
Yeah, he used to work
construction.
He lost the use of his legs
in an accident
in Chicago, actually.
My father always wanted a boy.
He was a track star
and just missed qualifying
for the Olympics in '76.
He tried to correct
that failure through me.
They were driving home
from dinner
just a mile from the house and...
an SUV blew a stop sign.
lt's funny
how everything can change
in an instant.
A stranger can come along
and in the blink of an eye just
destroy everything.
So you came to live
with your uncle?
l have a grandmother
who lives in New York,
but she's agoraphobic,
a real freak show, so...
it was her or my uncle.
l bet you wish
you went to New York now, huh?
l hate New York.
( truck approaching )
Out of the car, Allison.
- What?
- You heard me.
- l'm not going anywhere.
- Yeah, back off, man.
You shut your mouth!
Come on.
- What are you doing?
- l'm taking you home.
Allison.
Your mother and father worked hard
so you could be somebody.
l'm not gonna let you derail that
by hanging out with that trailer trash.
You don't even know him.
l know that kid better than you
ever will. lf your father was here--
Look, sports, college--
that whole thing--
that was my father's dream,
not mine.
l never wanted any of it.
Well, what do you want? Do you want
to live in the back of a truck?
Do you want to collect welfare?
You think
l wanted to come here?
You think l wanted
to come and live with you?
My brother and l
made a promise
a long time ago:
Should something happen
to either of us,
we'd be there
for each other's kids.
lt's not one you ever expect
to have to keep,
and l'm not going back
on my word,
but it's your life.
You want to try it out
on your own,
go ahead.
You want me to get out?
l want you to make a choice.
Okay, well, we'll do things
my way for a while,
just as long as we understand
each other.
( sniffling )
( door squeaks )
( sobbing )
Woman: Oh no.
No.
l haven't done anything.
Please.
Graham:
Like l showed you.
Woman:
Why are you doing this?
How frightening
when it's our own flesh.
Woman: No!
No, stop.
Graham:
Hold her still.
Woman: No.
- Graham: Do it!
- Please, please.
- l don't think your heart's in this.
- No. No.
( screaming )
( woman continues screaming )
( Martin gasping, coughing )
Come on.
l'm not afraid
of you anymore.
This is my house.
l'm not gonna be like you--
condemned.
l'm fixing what you broke!
Go back to hell
where your bed is made.
This is my house!
( panting )
( hammer pounding )
- My dad trusted me.
- Jonathan will too.
You just have to
give him a chance.
Besides, it's not you
he doesn't trust.
l can take care of myself.
l know you can.
He's just trying
to look out for you.
Please.
( sighs )
What's he got
against William anyway?
Oh, we've known Billy
since he was this high.
He's had to deal with more
than his share of problems.
That's not his fault.
l mean, l think it's wonderful
how he takes care of his father,
especially after what happened
to his mother.
Well, she did that to herself.
You can't give yourself
pneumonia.
She didn't die of pneumonia.
Billy's mother--
she killed herself.
What?
Hung herself in the garage.
Billy was the one
who found her.
lt was really hard on him.
The doctors put him
on all sorts of medication.
He's gotten in a lot of trouble
around town.
l think Jonathan's just afraid
he's a little unstable.
And his father-- well--
Where are you going?
l need to sort things out
in my head.
Hey, Allison,
you want to play a game?
Maybe later, okay?
Where are you going?
Hello?
No, wait.
( flies buzzing )
Hello?
Hey, are you okay?
Wait.
Are you okay?
Are you in trouble?
What are you doing down here?
Are you in here?
( quietly )
Oh my God.
Martin.
( rattling )
Where are you?
( Allison gasps )
Wait. Come back.
l'm not going to hurt you.
l want to help you.
ls your name Martin?
Here, come with me.
You can't stay here.
lt's not safe.
What's wrong?
You don't have to be afraid.
You can trust me.
You shouldn't be down here.
( Allison screaming )
No! No!
No! No! No!
( panting )
Good work.
- l'm sure she's fine.
- How?
She's just blowing off
some steam.
No 17-year-old wants to be told
what to do.
Not yet.
l don't have any brothers or sisters
'cause Dad's lazy.
And now he's
chased her away too.
Way to go, Dad.
( rat squeaking )
( screaming )
( screaming continues )
( distant train horn blowing )
She never came home
last night.
l know.
Where are you going?
l'm gonna go find her.
l need to speak to Allison.
She's not here.
lt's important.
- She isn't here, Billy.
- We thought she was with you.
No. She's been gone all night?
Since yesterday.
This is your goddamn fault.
- Stop. Jonathan.
- Stay the hell away from her.
- Jonathan.
- Don't push me.
- You're no good.
You're just like your old man--
good for nothing.
lt's okay.
Stay away from my niece!
Come on.
Are you all right?
( Allison whimpering )
Please.
lf they have no feelings,
they can't know fear.
But if they can't know fear...
( Allison panting )
then why do they run?
Anybody home?
Please don't.
Sutter!
Uncle J!
( whimpering )
( knocks )
( muffled screaming )
Hello?
( knocking )
( muffled screams )
Who's there?
lt's Jonathan Miller.
l'm looking for my niece.
She didn't come home
last night.
l've been looking
all over for her.
l thought she might have wandered
over here. Have you seen her?
No.
Listen, do you have a young boy
living over here?
She said she saw a boy
running around over here.
Just get off my property.
You mind if l come in
a moment?
l'm busy.
Just a moment.
Just a second.
Uncle J!
Allison?
What did you do?
You girls, you--
you never can keep
your mouths shut.
( screaming )
No! No!
( continues screaming )
No. No.
- ( grunting )
- ( screaming )
No. No.
( continues screaming )
No!
No.
( screaming )
Leave me alone!
( sobbing )
( screaming )
William: Hello?
Allison?
Mr. Miller?
( chimes tinkling )
( panting )
Hello?
( water dripping )
Allison?
( screaming )
Oh my God. Martin!
( silent )
Help me!
Open the door. Hurry.
Come back. Help.
Let me out, Martin.
Allison?
Hello.
( knocking )
Allison.
Can she--?
l can't hear you.
William, open the door.
- lt's locked.
- Hurry.
William:
l think it's coming loose.
Allison:
Turn around, please.
Turn around.
l'm gonna get you out of here.
l promise. lt's okay.
l got it.
( Allison screams )
( Allison screaming )
Allison: Stop!
( Allison screaming, crying )
( sobbing )
( quietly )
No.
Forget it.
Leave me alone.
l don't care.
Let them find out.
Forget it.
l won't do it.
l can't.
You leave him alone.
He hasn't done anything.
No. No, l need him.
Who-- who-- who's gonna
help me clean up?
You know l can't stand it.
No no no
no no no no.
Shut up. Shut up!
God!
You're no better than he was!
You promised me.
l did everything you said.
( screams )
( sobbing )
You win.
You're wrong.
He wouldn't dare.
Don't look at me like that.
You don't ask why.
You just do.
That's just the way it is.
You think you owe me,
think maybe l should grow eyes
in the back of my head?
They abandoned you.
What would you be
without me?
You feel guilty or something?
Don't feel guilty.
A child shouldn't feel guilty
about nothing.
You--
you don't feel anything, do you--
guilt, pain, regret--
nothing? Do you?
Who are you to judge me?
You have no soul to redeem.
Do you?
Don't try anything funny
while l'm gone.
They're watching.
( grunting )
( panting )
Oh my God.
What did he do to you?
Come on. l'm gonna get you
out of here, okay?
l'm sorry.
Are you okay?
Come on.
Come on. lt's okay.
Trust me, okay?
Come on, l can't carry you.
ls this what you're scared of?
This thing?
You see? lt's nothing.
When are they coming home?
Soon.
( panting, grunting )
( knocks on door )
Finally.
Yes?
- ( screams )
- Wendy, run.
Mommy!
( screaming )
Mommy.
- Mommy!
- Wendy, run.
Run!
No, please don't.
l have to.
( screaming )
We're almost there, okay?
( panting )
Jonathan.
No.
lt's gonna be okay.
Okay?
l'm gonna get you home.
( panting, whimpering )
( scratching )
Randy. Oh Randy.
( screams )
( door rattling )
lt's gonna be okay.
( screams )
Please don't hurt my animals.
No.
Ate from my hand...
and trusted me
even at the end.
Unconditional.
And he-- he made me!
Mommy!
l'm making things right.
l owe them that much.
With each one
another sin is forgiven.
l can't let it happen again,
not like me.
You understand, don't you?
Not like that boy-- worthless.
( screams )
Karen!
Karen.
Don't let him get her.
l can't stop now.
There's still
so much more to do.
You-- you come with me.
Come with me.
Please come with me.
Help me.
Help me redeem myself!
- No.
- Let her go, you son of a bitch!
( Wendy screaming )
( groans )
lt does.
l'm sorry.
( Allison exclaims )
lt's okay.
lt's me.
lt's just me, okay?
Where is Mommy?
She's downstairs.
l need you to stay here,
all right?
Why?
Just please do as l say.
- Okay?
- Don't leave.
l'm not leaving.
Just stay here.
( Wendy whimpering )
( coughing )
( Allison screams )
Martin!
( sobbing )
( phone ringing )
Woman over phone:
911. What is your emergency?
Yes, hello?
( screaming )
( Allison continues screaming )
( whimpering )
( stairs creaking )
Wendy: Allison?
( Wendy screams )
( moaning )
( grunts )
( coughing )
( heart beating )
Boy!
( groaning )
( footsteps )
- ( thunder rumbling )
- ( chimes tinkling )
l understand now
why they run...
that even a dumb animal
knows when it's been betrayed.
Do you feel betrayed?
No.
That's why you didn't run.
'Cause you knew
you had it coming.
( footsteps )
You--
you never ran.
My boy.
Thank you.
( screaming )
Man:
We counted four bodies.
Man #2:
Any idea what caused it?
Man: Tough to say--
a stove left on,
a cigarette left burning.
Probably got trapped,
tried to call for help,
but flames consumed them.
( police radio chatter )
Yeah.
( whines )
Father: Billy.
( knocks on door )
Billy.
( hammer pounding )
( ballad playing )
( woman screams )
( chimes tinkling )
( knocks )
Hello?
ls anybody here?
Girl:
Can you help me?