- l'M NOT SCARED -
- Michele!
- Maria!
l fell!
Where are you going?
- They broke.
- l told you not to come.
Now what?
We'll tape them.
Let's go.
Come on, run!
- How gross!
- They passed by here.
There's a house!
Congratulations,
you finally made it.
My sister hurt herself.
- The others?
- They're down there.
- Who won?
- Skull.
- This place is mine.
- Why?
Because l saw it first.
Finders keepers...
Who's the rotten egg?
You, because you came last.
l had to stop
because my sister got hurt.
- You lose.
- Who has to pay up?
She does.
No fair, why always me?
Let's vote on it.
He can't always decide everything.
Let's vote, l say you lost.
- Me too.
See?
So what do l have to do?
- Show it to us.
- No way!
- What does she have to show us?
- Shhh!
- You lost, so do it.
- No.
No?
Aren't you going to say anything?
Alright, but l won't play
with you anymore, jerks!
- Are you crying?
- No.
Stop!
l'll pay up, l came last.
Fuck!
Walk across that.
He was the Lizard Man,..
..he could walk on walls.
Then he became the Glass Man,
if he falls he breaks.
- What are you saying?
- Nothing.
Leap onto that branch
and climb down.
Michele,..
..give me my glasses.
- l lost them.
- Mom will kill you.
Wait here.
A cave filled with gold and gems.
- Did you find them?
- Run, we're late.
There's Mom.
Where'd you go?
l was searching for you!
How many times l gotta tell you
to stay nearby?
Michele, this time....
- We went....
- Home, right now!
Dad's here!
Dad!
You're heavy!
Daddy's doll, gimme a kiss.
Where were you?
Playing by the stream.
How long are you staying?
For a bit. You broke 'em?
- Again?
- She fell.
We can fix them with tape.
- Michele, what did l tell you?
- Never mind.
Did you do your push-ups?
- No, he didn't.
- Yes, l did.
We'll see, if you don't beat me,
no present for you.
- A present? What present?
- What present? - You'll see.
So...
Christ, are your muscles
made of butter?
Come on.
You're a sissy.
Maria, help him out.
Give us the present now!
Anna, get the box.
Easy!
- A boat.
- No.
lt ain't no boat, it's a gondola.
- What's that?
- A boat you only find in Venice.
- With only one oar?
- What's an oar?
A stick that moves the boat.
- Pretty!
- No.
You can't play with this.
The Police
from the Artistic Heritage Unit..
..recovered two precious
16th century sculptures..
..attributed to Benvenuto Cellini.
Whose turn to get the wine?
- Maria's. - l don't feel like it.
You go. - No!
- lt's your turn.
- l'm not going.
- Why not?
- My head hurts.
That's what you always say!
Shut up, let me hear!
Knock it off! Go, Michele.
lt's not fair.
After the defeat
of the fencing team in Hamburg....
What happened?
lt's her turn to get the wine.
ln war, know how they'd decide
who went on deadly missions?
Whoever picks the broken one,
has to go.
lt's your turn!
You lost, go get the wine.
So they bury him..
..and he remains
in the belly of the earth..
..among secrets, corpses, bones,
skeletons, and darkness.
Where were you?
Your Mom's looking for you.
They're mad.
Are the shoes comfy?
We'll buy them.
Hope l can convince my Mom,
they're really cute.
- Anna, what do you think?
- Let me see. What do you think?
How much you want for these?
- How much are they?
- lt's a good brand.
l've got other models, too.
Pino, your son's here.
- Where were you?
- Wandering around.
Wandering like hell!
You know what time it is?
lt's almost 2!
No one knew where you were.
Your Mom went looking for you.
You gotta stop doing
whatever the fuck you please!
lf you wanna do as you please,
then leave.
Get lost.
Get lost!
Michele, come down!
- What do you want?
- Dinner's ready.
Tell them l'm not their son anymore,
l'm not coming back.
- You're not my brother either?
- No!
- Then can l have your comic books?
- No.
That has nothing to do with it.
Mom will get mad.
- Where's Dad?
- He went out, he'll be back late.
- What's for dinner?
- Mashed potatoes and eggs.
Good morning!
Did you fall out of bed?
- l had lots on my mind.
- What was on your mind?
Give daddy a kiss.
- l thought you were mad.
- What was on your mind?
- Tell us.
- Sad thoughts.
Get ready 'cause tonight
we're gonna arm wrestle.
Anna!
Buy me some sausages.
- Dad, when will you be back?
- Late!
Michele.
One, two, three, red light!
- What are you doing?
- l'm not playing anymore.
Want me to come along?
Forget about him.
Water...
Are you alive?
- Water... - What did you say?
l didn't understand.
- Water.
- You're thirsty! You want water?
- Thirsty.
- Wait.
Hungry.
You're hungry?
l don't have anything to eat.
l have to go home now.
lf you want,
l'll bring something tomorrow.
Are you a child?
What are you doing here?
l know you.
You're Amitrano's son, right?
You better not come here no more.
lf l see you again....
See them things?
They're always hungry,
they even eat bones.
Michele...
- What are you doing?
- Nothing, just playing.
Put everything back.
- l don't want anymore.
- Eat your meat.
lt gives me a headache.
- l can't take this anymore!
- Anna... lf she doesn't want it...
No big deal.
Someone's coming in a few days.
So no fuss and no whining.
Who is it?
A friend.
- What's his name?
- Sergio.
What a funny name.
A Dad and Mom
are expecting a baby.
But instead, two are born,
one blond, one brunet.
The brunet is normal,
the blond is crazy.
When she nurses him,
he bites her and draws blood.
The Mom doesn't want him anymore.
So she tells the Dad to kill him.
The Dad takes him up
to a tall mountain,..
..but he can't stab him
because it's a sin.
So he digs a hole
and puts him in it.
He brings him water and food
so he won't die.
So he..
..won't... die.
Hi, Michele.
What do you need?
What can l buy with 500 liras?
Don't know,
depends on what you need.
- Something good,
do you have chocolate cookies? - No.
Sweets are over there.
A doughnut, a chocolate bar...
Or a Kit Kat.
They're all good.
- Assunta...
- What is it?
lf someone's hungry,
what can they buy with 500 liras?
They can buy bread.
When someone's hungry,
they buy bread.
l wanted to ask you:
..do you know Felice,
Skull's brother? Felice Natale.
l hate him.
ls he the one who feeds you?
l saw him driving away from here,..
..so l thought....
l'm going home now.
Okay?
Bye bye.
Are you deaf?
Listen. Sorry.
l thought of something.
lf you won't eat the bread,
will you give it back?
Let me explain. lf Felice comes
and finds it, he'll figure it out.
Then l'll come get it.
Listen...
What's your name?
What's your Dad's name?
Mine is named Pino.
ls your Dad named Pino too,
by chance?
- l'm leaving.
- Coons...
Did you say something?
l don't understand.
- Coons...
- Coons?
- What do you mean?
- Raccoons.
lf you leave the window open,
raccoons will come in..
..and steal cakes, cookies...
- There are no coons here.
Raccoons can bite people.
Did you eat
a piece of meat yesterday?
lt's very important.
Are you my Guardian Angel?
l'm not an angel.
What's a Guardian Angel?
The one who says true things.
You can tell me,
l won't tell anyone.
l'm not an angel.
l'm Michele.
Michele Amitrano, fifth grade.
Dead?
- What?
- Am l dead?
- Dead? What?
- l'm dead!
l'm dead! l'm dead! l'm dead!
Remember when Mrs. Destani..
..told us about the miracle
of Lazarus? - Yes.
When Lazarus came back to life,
did he know he'd been dead?
No, l guess he thought he felt ill.
Do you think only Jesus can bring
the dead back to life?
Dunno, but my Aunt
told me a true story.
Once, someone's son died
all mangled under a car.
The Dad couldn't handle it,
he cried all day.
He gave a psychic all his money
to bring his son back to life.
So the psychic said: ''Go home,
your son will return tonight''.
The Dad waited,
but the son didn't return,..
..so he went to bed.
Then he heard steps in the kitchen.
He got up
and saw his mangled son,..
..with his brains dripping out.
His son said he hated him,
it was his fault he died.
He left him in the street
to go chase after women.
And then?
So his Dad set him on fire
with gasoline.
- He did good.
- Sure did.
- What are you doing?
- l have to pee, go to sleep.
- What do they say in Milan? - What
the hell do you want them to say?
They said it would end soon,..
..it's been months! What's going on?
l don't understand!
You don't need to understand. The less
you think, the less you'll screw up.
lt'll take time.
lt might take six months.
- Six months? - Six months,
a year, whatever it takes.
My ass!
Shut up!
They ain't telling us anything!
You don't need to know anything.
You just have
to keep the kid hidden.
Hide him and stay cool.
You've fucked up
over and over again.
He's the stupidest of all.
Like l said, you're not capable.
Relax.
Relax? They ain't paying!
They said Carducci had money
coming out of his ass.
Bullshit!
Shut up!
You're the worst here,
'cause you think.
- Me?
- Yes.
Fuck you, expert my ass.
You're an idiot, let me tell you!
The news!
Anna, turn off the light.
Turn up the volume.
Good evening.
Human rights defense..
..and patience in negotiations,
Carter says in Berlin.
ln Bonn tomorrow, the lndustrialized
Countries Summit begins.
Alarm in Trent for a toxic cloud....
l'll have one.
They ain't gonna talk about it
today either.
- They didn't yesterday.
- Well?
l can't hear a thing.
Here it is!
Throughout the whole region,
the search continues..
..for little Filippo,
kidnapped in Milan.
The Police are following new leads
which seem to be promising.
We will now air Luisa Carducci's
appeal to the kidnappers.
What the fuck does she want?
l'm Filippo's mother.
l'm speaking
to my son's kidnappers.
l implore you, don't hurt him.
He's a good boy,
well mannered, and very shy.
l implore you, treat him well.
The sum requested is steep,..
..even for our family.
- They'll cough up the money.
You threatened to cut his ear off.
l beg you not to do it.
l must make another request:
..tell Filippo his Mom and Dad
love him dearly..
..and always think of him.
- We'll cut off two ears!
Two!
Who are you?
l'm Michele, Michele Amitrano.
Sounds like the name of a singer.
l'm Materia Sergio.
Pleased to meet you.
Didn't they ever teach you to knock?
Sorry.
- Are you Pino's son?
- What?
- Yes.
You're a quiet kid.
l like quiet kids.
Are you obedient, too?
Then close the door and piss off.
- What?
- Close the door and piss off!