I've never before had the opportunity
of entertaining personages
from the... 'dark continent'.
I hope the reception was not boring
for you and your lovely wife.
Quite the contrary, Count Dracula.
The evening has been a splendid one,
and we've found your guests
to be most impressive.
I liked in particular
your Dr Duvalier.
It was you who impressed him.
Mamuwalde is the crystallisation
of our people's pride.
My Luva... she does
me too much credit.
But notwithstanding,
my people are eager
to bring our ancient culture
into the community of nations.
That may take a good deal of time.
It will at least be time well spent,
as opposed to an
exchange of banalities
with pseudo-intellectuals
and dilettantes.
Charming.
What with dignitaries of your stature
lending the weight of
your statesmanship
to the fulfillment of our objectives,
I believe we will succeed.
Luva?
To totally cease the slave trade?
I find that unrealistic.
Slavery has merit, I believe.
Merit?
You find merit in barbarity?
Barbarous from the standpoint
of the slave, perhaps.
Intriguing and delightful from mine.
I would pay for so beautiful an addition
to my household as your delicious wife.
Sir, are you ill?
Oh... I meant no insult, prince.
It is a compliment for
a man of my station
to look with desire on
one of your colour.
Sir, I suddenly find
your cognac as...
distasteful as your manner.
You're behaving like some animal.
- Really?
- Really.
Let us not forget, sir,
it is you who comes from the jungle.
Our evening is finished.
I bid you arouse your coachman.
We are leaving.
I do not think so.
How dare you!
Let me go!
Look out! No!
You shall pay, black prince.
I shall place a curse
of suffering on you
that will doom you to a living hell.
A hunger,
a wild, gnawing, animal hunger
will grow in you,
a hunger for human blood.
Here you will starve for an eternity,
torn by an unquenchable lust.
I curse you with my name.
You shall be...
Blacula!
A vampire like myself,
a living fiend,
you will be doomed
never to know that sweet blood
which will become your only...
desire.
No!
You will watch,
helpless and dying,
until the black flesh
rots from your bones.
Listen... for his cries.
They will comfort you
until your death.
No!
Let me out!
Help. Oh, help.
Mamuwalde.
Dracula?
But he is dead, gentlemen.
Quite dead.
He and his entire
household were destroyed
by the great Dr Van Helsing
almost 150 years ago.
Oh, what a pity.
I've never met a vampire.
You should have told us whose
house this was in the village.
Yeah, honey, now, wait.
This is gonna change
our deal drastically.
Oh, I see.
Well, I can assure you,
gentlemen, it is quite safe now.
The reports of the count
were grossly exaggerated.
Perhaps if I subtract
another ten percent?
- Fifteen.
- Very well.
Consider your deal closed.
We'll take everything.
You gentlemen had me
worried there for a moment.
- If you please.
- I'd love to.
- Right here.
- OK, great.
You are obviously not attuned
to the antique market.
You see, where we come from,
honey, the legend of Dracula...
that's the absolute créme
de la créme of camp!
We're gonna get a fortune
for these things.
Count Dracula was no legend.
- He was terribly real.
- Oh, I know.
I've seen all of his movies.
I'm a real fan.
Don't shock the poor man, Billy.
Hey, is there anything else? Like
secret passages and things like that?
Yes. When the castle was
restored a few years ago,
they found several hidden rooms.
Eugh, it smells terrible in here.
Billy, look at this!
Fantastic.
Oh, this is gorgeous.
Look at this, Bobby.
Honey, this is the coup
d'état of the century.
Is this included in our deal,
or are you gonna fleece us now?
You ain't gonna fleece us,
are you, baby?
Well, if you want it...
I can't wait to start
tagging all these goodies.
We're gonna be rich, my love.
Bobby, man, I can't see in here.
I'm gonna light one
of the greasy lamps.
Ta-dah!
If the fire department could see
you now, you silly lamp queen.
- Oh, this. I'm dying to open this!
- I'm not.
Look, I have a fantastic idea for this.
You'll probably die if I tell you.
In that case, spare me.
Let's get on with the tagging.
Listen! You know that chintzy
guest bed in the living room?
- Yeah.
- How about this instead?
A coffin?
It'll freak everyone out. Open it.
Oh, Bobby!
- Look what I've done!
- What the hell did you do?
- What did you do? Let me see.
- Ouch.
- Don't panic. Wait to see it.
- Oh!
Please stop. Hold this there.
Let me... oh...
- Bobby, hurry. It's bleeding.
- Just a second!
You're so dizzy. That's the trouble.
- Put it up here.
- Just a second. Stop it!
If you weren't so dizzy...
Stop that whining.
Look at me.
- Move your hand.
- That's tight.
I'm not a nurse, you know. All right?
Would you stop it, please?
- Take care. It's twisted.
- I'll take care of it.
I'm gonna bleed to death.
You're gonna bleed to death if
you don't keep your mouth shut!
Keep quiet. You make me nervous.
Bobby, I'll die.
I'm bleeding to death!
Would you stop it, please?
Child, be still! Stop!
What's wrong with you?
That isn't tight enough.
The blood's seeping through.
Bobby, look...
Bobby! Bobby!
No...
No, no!
No!
'I curse you with my name.
'You shall be...
'Blacula!
'A vampire like myself,
'a living fiend.'
These are the Williams girls,
friends of the family.
We've come to pay our
respects to Bobby McCoy.
Certainly, sir.
These things are
always so very tragic,
but I can perhaps be of some comfort
to you in this hour of need.
This is one of our smaller rooms,
but it can be expanded
to accommodate any
number of mourners.
Why is his hand like that?
This sometimes happens.
It's only a reflex.
At his mother's request,
the body has not yet been embalmed.
I'll just tidy him up a bit,
then leave you alone
with your thoughts.
Poor Bobby. We've known
him since we were kids.
Luva.
I just don't understand it.
I hope you can find some
answers for us, Gordon.
Why don't you two go on over
to Bobby's mother's house?
She's in pretty bad shape.
I'll stay here.
Let's go.
- Talk to you later.
- All right.
Did I startle you, sir?
I'm so sorry, but I can't
let you disarrange...
I'm Dr Thomas with the Scientific
Investigation Division.
Of course. I'm so sorry, doctor.
I didn't realise you
were a professional man.
I worked very hard
on that neck wound,
trying to make it look
as natural as I could
so it wouldn't be offensive
to his loved ones.
The flesh was torn right
out in a big chunk.
I've never seen a rat
bite that size before.
- Rat bite?
- Yes, sir.
How deep was the wound
before it was repaired?
I don't know. Two or
three inches at least.
- Two or three inches?
- Yes, sir.
Any other bruises or wounds?
A slight abrasion on the left elbow,
probably the result of a fall.
And you say you didn't embalm?
Yes, sir.
It's strange.
That is strange.
Look at this. His veins are empty.
They collapse with pressure
and don't return to shape,
and he wouldn't be this colour
unless he'd lost a lot of blood.
Who brought him in?
I did. Picked him up at
the coroner's office.
Did they mention... much bleeding?
I can't say as they did, doctor.
What about the other victim,
his associate?
I didn't prepare that one.
He was white. I don't get
many whites in here.
- Thank you for your help.
- Glad to be of service.
Any time you need my help,
don't hesitate to ask.
I'm at your service, doctor.
That's my job...
...doctor.
That is the rudest nigger
I've ever seen in my life.
Everything's just so
strange, Michelle.
I know.
Listen, would you
mind if I begged off?
You can handle Mrs McCoy on your own.
I'm just really beat.
Go on home. I'll just stop by
and see if she needs anything.
- Thanks.
- See you later.
OK.
Luva?
- Let go!
- Luva, it's me.
Wait!
Goddamnit, man!
You scared the hell out of me.
Where did you come from?
Are you all right?
What the hell you run
in front of my cab for?
Can't you see, man?
I lost her.
Shit.
You ain't hurt, man, but you lucky.
Chasing tail could get
you killed, you know.
I lost her because of you. Imbecile!
Imbecile?
Who the hell are you
calling an imbecile?
You the nut that ran
in front of my cab.
You the only imbecile
on this street... boy!
You'll find her. She's got
to be round here somewhere.
I bet you she's worried right
now and lookin' for you,
so why don't you just back
off of me and go get her?
I bet she's worried
to death about you.
I bet she's called
every hospital around.
Listen, take your hands off me!
I don't know you!
Tina, get the chain. It's me!
Michelle, thank God.
What you doin' with that knife?
Sorry. Get in.
What's wrong with you?
Tina, what happened?
A man tried to attack me.
He got my purse. I'm sure of it.
He got my keys and all my I.D.
When I heard you at the door
just now, I thought it was him.
Damn maniacs runnin' the streets.
It's all right. It's OK.
It's all right.
- They'll take care of it for you.
- Thank you.
- Bye-bye.
- Hi, Shirley. Sam here?
Sure. Sam, Dr Thomas is here.
- How ya doin'?
- Fine. You?
- Fine. You're lookin' good.
- Thanks.
Doc?
I got a call from the coroner's
office to check on Juanita Jones.
- You want to see her?
- That's why I'm here.
Thought you worked nights.
Everybody takes a vacation but me.
There she is, doc.
Fine job for a woman, running a cab.
You ask me,
she's looking for something.
You know what I mean...
"looking for something"?
Yes. Sam, get me a cup
of coffee, will you?
All right, I can take a hint.
Nah, that's ridiculous.
Jack, I'm beginning to
take this personally.
I'm tellin' ya, your men lost the report
on Bobby McCoy and Billy Schaffer.
Lost, my ass.
Maureen.
- Yes, lieutenant.
- Get the division reports on... who?
Bobby McCoy, Billy Schaffer.
From two nights ago.
- Southwest Division.
- Right, lieutenant.
Tell me something, man.
Off the record, of course.
Yeah?
Who checked the two bodies?
In that area, it should be Watson.
- Yeah, Watson.
- Is that the guy that...
called cyanide poisoning
"heart failure"?
I'm getting tired of
that kind of talk.
Division says those reports
were lost before distribution.
They said Dr Thomas' office
called this morning about them.
The sergeant told Dr Thomas'
secretary he couldn't find them.
Thanks, Maureen. Thank you.
So it wasn't my lack of
pull at headquarters.
Strange how so many sloppy
police jobs involve black victims.
You're getting paranoid.
Schaffer wasn't black.
We'll find them.
I'll send Barnes over.
- Yes, lieutenant?
- Get Barnes in here.
Look, what's going on?
I see where you've ordered an
autopsy on Bobby McCoy today,
and Juanita Jones is
scheduled for one on Friday.
What's going on?
What's the connection?
Did you want me, lieutenant?
Hello, doc.
Get to the Southwest Division
and find the reports
on Bobby McCoy and
Billy Schaffer, will you?
Sure, lieutenant. What's goin' on?
Do it.
You've got something. What is it?
- When I know, I'll tell you.
- Does it look organised?
There's been a lot of
Panther activity lately.
Panthers? Come on,
Jack, don't cop out.
Two faggot interior decorators
and a lady cabdriver?
Panthers? Oh, come on!
Anything is possible.
If it's possible, tell Barnes to bring
those reports to the club tonight.
It's Michelle's birthday.
Have a good time.
- Hello?
- 'This is Dr Thomas.'
Yes, Dr Thomas.
Mr Swenson, we're gonna need to
do an autopsy on Bobby McCoy.
I'll send for the body
sometime this afternoon.
That's impossible.
The family's here now.
I can't just throw them out.
Of course, Mr Swenson.
- What time do you close tonight?
- 'Eight o'clock.'
All right, I'll have my men
there a little bit after 8:00.
- They must be careful.
- They will be, Mr Swenson.
- All right, then.
- Thanks.
By the way, we had some
excitement ourselves last night.
Tina got hassled on the way home.
- Is she all right?
- She didn't go to work today.
We're having the locks changed.
She thinks he got her purse.
Next year, we move to the suburbs.
Like we did last year!
There he is again
And he's making my heart
skip another beat
- Now he's a-movin' in
- Watch out, baby
Yeah, he's self-assured
like he was before
And I know he thinks I
want him more and more
And I know he thinks I want him
More and more
Oh, hey hey
So to myself I say
Look the other way
when he comes by you
Look the other way when he
Comes by you...
Don't let him follow through
There! There he is again
And he's leading me on
with that lover's look
I said there he is again
And he's reading my mind
like it's an open book
Now he's a real bad man
And he's getting so close
that I can't control
And I know he thinks I want him
Oh, so much
So to myself I say
Look the other way
when he comes by you
Look the other way when he
Comes by you...
Don't let him follow through
Oh, there he is again
And he's looking at me
from across the street
I said there, there he is again
And he's making my little heart
skip another beat
- Now he's movin' in
- Watch out, baby
And he's self-assured
like he was before
And I know he thinks I
want him more and more
And I know he thinks I want him
More and more
So to myself
I say look the other way
when he comes by you...
Come join my friends.
I'd like you to meet my sister
Michelle and Dr Gordon Thomas.
- This is...
- I'm called Mamuwalde.
Nice to meet you.
Enchanté, mademoiselle.
It's my sister's birthday party.
Would you care to join us?
I'd be delighted, thank you.
Champagne, please? French.
That won't be necessary.
What do you mean? I like champagne.
Good. So do I.
Tina, where did you find your purse?
Mamuwalde returned it to me.
Thank you again.
You bear an amazing
resemblance to my wife,
whom I lost a short while ago.
I'm very sorry.
I loved her very much.
When you left the mortuary,
I had to follow you.
I didn't consider that
I might frighten you.
You were at Swenson's.
Were you a friend of Bobby's?
No, I was there making some
arrangements of my own.
But enough about death.
Here's to... life.
- On your birthday.
- Thank you.
Happy birthday, baby.
- To happiness.
- To happiness forever.
I know you been running around
Playing me for a fool
But one thing you don't know, baby
I know just what to do for you
You out there having fun...
Dr Thomas here.
What?
What do you mean, gone?
Listen, calm down,
Swenson. Calm down.
I'll get a man over there right away.
Don't touch anything, you hear me?
Swenson, damn it!
Don't touch anything!
I'm gonna catch ya, baby
Wait and see
Hey, hey, hey
Yes, I like what kind
of line you got for me
You told me you were going to score
I found that I was
due to be your amour
Well, all right
You wanted me to go for that
Girl, let's stay at home...
Look at that face. What happened?
That was Swenson.
Bobby's body just disappeared.
- That's impossible.
- Perhaps he wasn't dead.
What the hell does that mean?
He was as dead as you can get.
I examined him myself.
Just a passing thought.
What's happening? How's everybody?
How you doin'? My name is Skillet.
How's everything?
Let's pull up a seat here and
get some of this here...
- Join the party.
- ...champagne.
- Help yourself.
- French champagne!
We gonna be gone.
Happy birthday, Michelle.
What kind of down
birthday party is this?
And hold it. Get you.
All right, come on.
Beautiful! Why don't you all
scoot in here together?
Please forgive me. I must depart now.
I have indeed had a rare pleasure.
Brother, why don't you stick around?
- Please, don't go.
- Where's he going?
Mamuwalde,
please wait.
Say, man, that is one strange dude.
- Who is he?
- One strange dude.
I gotta check this cat out again.
Did you see the rags he had on?
That's a bad cape. I'd like
to beat him out of that cape.
Will you meet me here
tomorrow evening?
I need very much to see you.
I'll be here.
Beautiful! I think
romance is in the air.
- Hey, baby.
- Tina, you all right?
Sure.
Mama, how come you never
look at me that way?
There's a reason, Skillet.
I guess we're through,
so I'll take these prints,
run over to my studio,
develop these, and be right back.
Mama, don't you want
a little company?
No, thanks.
I know what would develop
with you in a darkroom.
- It wouldn't be my pictures.
- Right on, baby. I hear ya.
Yeah?
Hey... Wait a minute.
Where's that big dude with the cape?
He was standing right next to her.
Oh, God!
- Help me.
- What happened, lady?
Oh, help me, please.
Do you live here?
I need your help.
- You got your damn report?
- Not me.
Don't give me that crap. I sent
Barnes to the club last night.
No crap. I didn't get it.
- Christ's sake. Maureen?
- Yes, sir.
Get Barnes. Tell him he better
get his ass in here fast.
Anything on that missing body report?
Nothing. No fingerprints,
no signs of breaking and entering.
Not a thing. Who the hell
would want a dead faggot?
I can't take any more problems.
Then you'll be thrilled to
know I would like permission
to dig up Billy Schaffer
to do an autopsy.
You're nuts!
You know what I've got to do to
get permission to dig up a grave?
Besides, you've got something
you don't want me to have.
- I don't like it.
- I just don't have it all together.
If I told you my crazy idea,
you'd just laugh at me.
Forget the permits.
I don't work in the dark.
Jack, I need your help.
There's a connection here.
That's all I know.
Just give me a little more time.
Get me that permit, man.
Solid.
What's the sudden interest in ghouls?
The librarian thinks we're nuts...
and she's not the only one.
- Dr Thomas' office.
- 'Gordon there?'
One moment, please.
Gordon, it's Peters.
Yeah, Jack.
'Couldn't get permission
to exhume McCoy's grave.'
You're a big help.
Thanks a lot for nothing.
'I'm sorry. My hands are tied.'
- Yeah.
- 'I tried. It's tough to get.'
- We'll talk later.
- 'You understand?'
Yeah!
Yeah.
Baby, you better sit down, cos I
got something heavy to lay on you.
Lay it on me.
We're gonna dig up Billy's body.
Ghouls, vampires, now bodies.
I take it back.
We're not nuts, you are.
What's more, we're gonna
have to do it tonight.
No we're not.
You ain't gettin' this nigger
in no graveyard tonight.
Come on, baby. Come on.
You going with grown people.
You're supposed to stick with me.
- Gordon, I'm always with you, right?
- Right, right.
- But not this time.
- Come on, babe. Come on.
Just for me?
Nope.
You're so bad.
You're so good.
Run home and change
into some old clothes.
- I'll pick you up later.
- OK.
- Good evening, Tina.
- Hello, Mamuwalde.
- I thought we were to meet at...
- Yes, at the club.
But I couldn't wait to see you.
I need to speak to you alone.
May I come in?
Of course you can.
I found it a little hard
to leave you last night,
but I had no choice.
I wanted to run after you
and I've never felt that way before.
- You frightened me.
- No, you mustn't be frightened.
Let me try and help you understand.
Is it about your wife?
You are my wife.
That's impossible, Mamuwalde.
And yet you believe it.
I don't know what I believe anymore,
but help me, and I'll
try to understand.
We are of the Abani tribe, you and I,
northeast of the Niger Delta.
Our people are renowned as hunters.
Almost two centuries ago,
the ruling elders of my people
sent me, yes, and my bride to Europe
on a mission to protest
the slave trade.
The slave trade?
On that mission, I myself was
enslaved, my wife murdered,
and I was placed under
the curse of the undead.
Our assassin was the
vampire Count Dracula.
Count Dracula is a myth.
- He wasn't real.
- Oh, yes, he was real...
as real as I am now,
as real as you are
and my need for you.
You are my Luva recreated.
What are you asking of me?
I want you to rejoin me.
I can't.
Well, you must come to
me freely, with love...
or not at all.
I will not take you by force
and I will not return.
I have lived again to lose you twice.
Mamuwalde.
Stay with me.
Please?
Will you talk to me before
I go out of my mind?
Don't sweat it, baby.
We're almost there.
What do you expect to find, anyway?
Nothing, I hope. Hold the
light over here, will you?
Hurry up and let's get
the hell out of here.
Don't!
Gordon, no!
No! No! No!
Don't kill him! Oh, God!
No, don't! Stop!
- It's all right.
- He was alive!
- You killed him!
- Michelle, he wasn't alive.
He was killed by a vampire.
He wasn't alive or dead.
We just put him out of his misery.
Easy.
Easy, yes.
All those books.
You must have known something.
Why didn't you tell me?
You never would have believed me.
No.
Gordon.
Does that mean that Bobby...
Right.
He's a vampire, too.
He could be anywhere.
What are we gonna do?
You better tell Peters.
Telling him won't work.
No, we gotta show him somehow.
I wish he could see what I saw.
- Juanita Jones.
- What?
The cabbie. Come on, let's go.
- Morgue.
- 'Sam, this is Dr Thomas.'
- Yeah?
- You remember that lady cabbie?
What do you mean, I remember?
Nothing wrong with my memory!
Take her out of deep freeze.
Why?
'I'm coming over with Lieutenant Peters.
I want her body warm.'
Take her out, leave the room,
make sure to lock the door.
Yeah, yeah, OK.
Sam, don't "yeah" me. Lock it!
Do I remember?
All right, all right!
I'm coming!
This better be good.
First night off in weeks.
Sorry, Jill. It's important.
Don't you think I'm
used to it by now?
- Hi.
- Hi, honey.
You sure it's all
right if I stay here?
Course. Come on in.
Morgue.
Yeah. Oh?
My Tina...
you're so beautiful.
I won't let you leave me.
I must. There is no other way.
To stay is to die.
I wanna go with you,
but I'm afraid.
I promise you it will not be...
unpleasant
or painful.
But there's still time.
All time belongs to us.
I must go now. It's almost daylight.
I love you.
Sam?
Not in there.
Sam!
Oh, my God!
Jesus.
Sam! Sam!
Follow me and stay close.
That's what I couldn't
tell you about.
That's why you had to
see it for yourself.
I wouldn't have believed it.
Sun killed her.
Vampires multiply geometrically.
First night there was one,
second night two, third night four.
It's a goddamn epidemic.
It explains McCoy's
disappearance from Swenson's.
- And now with Sam...
- Do you have any suggestions?
How about an APB on McCoy and Sam?
APBs on dead men. Lovely.
Great headlines. That should
get us mass hysteria.
Forget hysteria.
Mass unemployment, starting with me.
We'd better swamp the city
with police, cars on every corner.
It won't make any sense...
to start until after dark.
Keep in touch with me.
Yeah, I'll let your
office know where I am.
Get some sleep. You look like hell.
Sure.
I got something to check out.
You and all your friends
Are gonna get together
in the end and tell me
What the world knows
About love
Yes, you will
Tell me how much you love me
Yeah, you gonna tell me
how it could have been
If I had known more
About love
Yes, you will...
- Good evening.
- How you doin'?
Sit down and have a drink.
Thank you very much.
Very thoughtful of you.
Hi. What'll you have?
Make it a Bloody Mary.
Mamuwalde, maybe you can help me.
Are you into the occult?
It has some fascination.
How about the heavy stuff?
Witchcraft, voodoo...
devil worship.
Well, we can't ignore
what the world characterises
as the "black arts", can we?
I think that there's
some truth in all of it.
I've come to that conclusion myself.
- What do you think of vampires?
- Vampires?
They're possibly the
most fascinating of all.
Do you... believe they exist?
Does the devil exist?
People have believed so
for thousands of years.
You seem well informed.
Oh, perhaps.
The police have a theory
about these killings.
Are we to assume that
they believe a vampire
or some other such
creature is responsible?
A vampire.
Fascinating.
However, many in the
department don't believe it.
I would think that to be the
vampire's greatest defence.
You're right.
Still, they're organising a search.
Search?
Yeah, find his resting place,
a vampire's coffin.
Perhaps the modern vampire
doesn't require a coffin.
They are rather elusive, you know.
What's happening, everybody?
What's goin' on?
- Hey, Skillet.
- How you doin'?
- How you doin', doc?
- What's happening?
My darling, we really
must be leaving now.
Tina, I wish you'd stay with us.
I'm sorry, but I'd rather
go with Mamuwalde.
Say, Mamuwalde, let me buy
that old cape from you, brother.
You know, he is a strange dude.
Ran off of me like he did
Nancy the other night.
Anybody seen Nancy?
No. She didn't bring my
birthday pictures back, either.
Haven't seen her
since the other night.
Look here, brother.
When you do see her,
tell Nancy that big Skillet
has got something
really groovy for her.
Mamuwalde.
He's with Tina!
How could you be so blasé?
What were you trying to prove?
They mean nothing to me.
No one matters but you.
Hold me. Just hold me.
Tina...
Come with me tonight.
Stop!
No, Mamuwalde! Please don't hurt him!
No, no!
Gordon, are you all right?
Hold it, mister!
You met him. Who is he?
God only knows. He calls
himself "Mamuwalde".
- Where does he hang out?
- Hang out?
In a coffin around here somewhere.
- Hi, babe.
- Hi.
- How is Tina?
- I don't know.
I tried to get her to lie down, but...
Tina, you should still be resting.
I will. What happened?
- We heard shots.
- He killed a cop.
- He killed him?
- He killed him, and he got away.
You should rest.
What do we do now?
Now we wait.
The only thing for sure is that
he has to return to his coffin...
before daylight.
- Danny, take a look at that fag.
- Yeah, I'm lookin'.
- Isn't that the one?
- Sure looks like the one.
How can you tell?
They all look alike.
Hello? Just a minute. Jack?
Yeah?
Where?
OK, tell them to keep a
bead on them but hold back.
They found Bobby.
He's picked up a friend.
- Oh, my God.
- Keep Tina here no matter what.
We'll leave some men
to watch the place.
Let's go. That guy
with him is in trouble.
- Keep this with you.
- OK.
The subject is heading east on 5th.
Get a grid over that area. Maybe we
can figure out where they're going.
They're gone, lieutenant.
We lost them in an alley.
Don't... repeat,
don't follow on foot.
We'll take over from here.
Right, lieutenant.
Name every building in that sector.
Go through it street by street.
We've pinpointed that sector.
'Buildings are as follows:
Jacob Iron Foundry...'
This will never work.
We got no choice.
We gotta keep going.
...Alameda and 3rd,
Direct Wholesale Clothing,
Torrés Cement,
'Andrew Brothers Warehouse,
Municipal...'
That's it! The warehouse.
That's where it started.
That's where they found
McCoy and Schaffer.
Barnes, where the hell
have you been? Come on!
What the hell is that?
Lieutenant!
Watch it!
Johnson!
It won't do any good! It's too late!
Get ready to throw these things.
Now!
Barnes!
Peters!
Peters, throw it! Th row it!
I got your back.
Good evening, gentlemen.
I say, were you looking for me?
I should have told you this evening
that I decided to move my coffin,
but, then, it was you
who gave me the idea.
Is that what you got
planned for Tina?
You know nothing of that!
Tina's life means more
to me than my own.
Does it?
I could dispense with
you now, doctor,
but I have a rather urgent
appointment elsewhere.
My God.
You've got no choice!
Whether you want to face it or not,
that man, if you can give him that,
has killed innocent people.
I know.
Just like that, "I know"?
Tina, this isn't some nut
from a Halloween party!
That man is the real thing.
What do you want me to do about it?
- You gotta help us.
- I can't.
What do you mean, "I can't"?
Look, Tina, anybody could be next.
Gordon or me. Is that what you want?
No.
We have to stop him.
It's the only decision possible.
Say you're with us.
OK.
Look, I gotta cut out
and help Peters.
If he comes for you
tonight, we're ready.
These streets will be
packed with police.
There's no other way, Tina, OK?
OK, the whole block is sealed off.
'You people will have
to get off the streets.
'Go to your homes.
'Please go to your homes.
'These streets need to be kept clear.
'We must have your cooperation.
'Please clear the street.
'Go to your homes.'
'There's nothing happening here,
nothing to get excited about.
'Now, please go to your homes.
'Please cooperate by
clearing the streets.'
'If we don't get your cooperation,
'we'll have to declare a curfew.
'Please leave the streets
and return to your homes...'
Where?
Tell me where.
Please clear the streets
and return to your homes.
'Please cooperate by
leaving the streets
'and returning to your homes.
'Please cooperate with
the police officers.'
A bat! A bat! A giant bat!
- It's him.
- Tina...!
Tina?
Gordon, she's gone.
Attention, all units,
this is Lieutenant Peters.
'All units, Lieutenant Peters.
Do not apprehend the girl.
'Just survey and watch for suspect.'
This is Unit 603.
We are proceeding east on Florence.
No sign of subject.
Come love, give to me
We will take the sky...
Hey, isn't that her?
Drive on by.
I see my main chance with you
If my main chance falls through
I could live forever
But I'd know I'll never
Have a chance at living
Again...
Unit 3, Baker 92. It looks like her.
'She's entering Underground
Chemical Plant No. 2
'at 6th and Church.'
Let's go.
What is it? What's going on?
You two take that side.
Come on.
- Where is he?
- Down there, sir.
All right, if you find him,
don't try to take him.
Just back off and yell
for me or Dr Thomas.
- Keep your eyes open for his coffin.
- Let's go.
Help me... please.
Tina... Tina... Don't die, Tina.
My Luva.
I cannot lose you again.
Forgive me. Now this is the only way.
You will be with me... always.
Dr Thomas!
You and your dear friends are dead.
Not one man shall
escape my vengeance!
Not one man shall leave here alive!
Search out every shadow,
every corner...
This will be your inglorious tomb!
Your tomb!
Your tomb! Your tomb!
We got him! He's up here. Quick!
Lieutenant.
Over here!
Stay here. Stay with her.
- Grab her!
- Let me go!
- Get her out of here!
- Let me go! Stop!
Stop it! Let me go!
Don't! She's my sister! Don't!
Oh, no! No, please!
Where the hell is Mamuwalde?
I'm here, gentlemen.
Move away from her.
Tina.
My lovely, lovely Tina.
What is left for this
cursed creature?
His only reason for living
has been taken away.
There's no need for that.