Hey!
Have I intruded...
No, I didn't.
I didn't.
How dare you?!
I loved that gold watch!
All right, all right!
It wasn't a gold watch!
Yeah?
What...does she look like?
Hair?
Blond, stringy.
It's dirty probably.
Never washes it.
Eyes... blue.
Big blue eyes.
I think she's really very stupid, yes.
She looks stupid.
Stupid girl, yes.
Her nose has no character.
A punk nose.
Mouth is too tiny.
Narrow mouthed.
Legs are alright.
Bosom?
She has no bosom.
No bosom at all.
Stop that!
You're very rude.
She has a very vivid imagination.
You know, she hears things.
Names... machine guns...
God knows what.
She thinks there's a war going on.
That's not all.
A little while ago...
...she thought she saw a unicorn.
Yes, I tell you.
Unicorn.
Of course it doesn't exists.
Anyway, it's a very insipid animal.
Oh God, she's moving about again.
Very curious.
What can I do?
She ran away...
The lady upstairs... she's dead.
But you don't hear me.
She's very dead.
No, you don't understand.
My name is Lily.
I see. Lily is your name too.
Funny. You spell it differently.
Who is he?
I'm sorry.
Your sister.
Yes, of course.
Your sister Lily.
But your mother is dead.
She passed away, I tell you.
She is dead! And I want you to know
that it was not my fault!
Let me out!
Open the door!
Open it!
You! It's all your fault!
I'm not gonna stay on top here for very long. Do you understand?
If you think that you can keep me here forever, you're wrong!
Let me get out right away!
Right away! Let me out!
Help!
Someone!
You're really awful!
I hate you!
You stupid old bitch!
All right! If that what you want,
don't let me out!
Don't! I don't care!
I hate you!
That...
- Hope.
Night of love...
around us.
Eyes, days, stars shines for
all remembered...
in one slow breath.
- Merged.
- Merged...
in one slow breath.
- But...
- The day hailed away...
with all his gleam.
Mighty death.
- Magical.
- Magical death...
threatening my life.
- How could my love die...
How could the endlessly living perish?
Yearning eternal blindness,
where forever love and rapture await.
Heart on heart.
Mouth on mouth.
All is illusion.
Set us free of this world.
Dream of fire endless promise.
Our hearts wonder wish,
As full death,
men named it evermore,
beautiful delusion.
Sweet awaited desire.
Never waking.
Never fearing,
nameless there.
Each to each, belonging.
With love alone,
all life source.
Would you please tell me what's going on around here?
What?
They've taken the city.
Oh wooden horse, my God.
And Brian? Brian is dead you say?
What about Helen?
Hello?
That radio gotta be fixed.
The girl.
She just lost her bloomers and
now she's eating the cheese.
Of course, there was Christmas cheese.
I know what you think about.
I don't like it.
She'll find out about the greeks.
Come here dear!
Come, come, my little one.
I'll explain everything to you now.
Every single thing you want to know.
Don't! Don't!
There's nothing to see over there.
Oh no.
Please don't go near the window.
It's not safe!
She's looking out, the silly little bitch!
Damnit! I told you this would happen!
She's a conniving little slut!
I always knew it...
She's making a dash for the door.
Of course it's closed!
She's trying to open it, she's kicking it.
Now she's coming back, the little...
She just fell...
Now she's off the window...
Have you seen a unicorn?
Where is that unicorn?
Answer me!
Out, out, brief candle.
Life's but a walking shadow.
Hey!
Stupid, stupid tree.
Did you say something?
I said you're mean.
What do you mean 'mean'?
Why are you keep running after me?
I find it rather tedious.
What is it you want exactly?
I don't know really,
but I'm not mean.
You're not?
What about those poor children...
I just saw you beating up?
- I'm not...
- Shut up, let me speak!
I saw how you kick that tree...
and trampled those innocent flowers to death.
And you dare to say you're not mean?
You should practice what you preach!
You're eating the flowers.
Suppose we change the subject?
I don't mean to be rude,
but you're not very graceful.
In my books, unicorns are slim and white.
The most beautiful things in the world
are the most useless.
Peacocks and lillies, for instance.
You know,
the old lady upstairs.
She didn't want me to see you.
Oh Lord, you mean that babbling-beady-on-the-while upstairs.
Don't pay any attention to her.
She's not even real.
What do you mean she's not real?
I touched her. I spoked to her. I even saw her die.
I mean what I mean.
My little one, I could give you some precious information...
concerning that old hag.
Lunatic driving baddie.
I'm leaving right away.
And I won't be back in 154 years.
Hey, come back!
I like talking to you.
Nobody talks to me here.
Humphrey.
What's the matter?
What's the matter now?
Who's Humphrey?
- You mean the rat?
- Yes, I mean the rat.
Did you have a fight?
Yes, but that's nothing new.
He's so opinionated and stubborn.
I love him, you understand my sweet thing?
We went in so many roads together.
So many seasons I've seen us passed.
So many hopes...
I see the waves in the ocean.
Hungry, hungry.
Just a minute, please.
Just a minute.
I'm afraid I don't have much milk.
Hey! Your friend's back.
Willy boy, Willy boy,
Where are you going?
I will go with you, if I may.
I'm going to the meadow to see them...
I'm going to help them make the hay.
I'm going to help them fill the barn,
with summer hay to lay upon.
Nobody home
No bread, no drink, no money
how we none
yet we shall be bliss.
Nobody home.
No drink, no bread, no money
how we none.
yet we shall be bliss.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Is nobody there?
Hello?
Can't you hear me?
Anybody hear me?
Just a minute, please.