The new shipment has arrived, Master.
Good, good, good...
What a marvelous, wonderful,
attentive audience you are.
And I may I add...
... a brave one too.
Now those of you who are weak willed
or coward would have fled by now.
Or regurgitated...
...over the seats in front of you.
But why, really?
This is just a theatrical presentation.
A show,
which offers no reality,
not a fraction of reality.
And just allows us, you and me...
... to tell into our deepest fantasies
far beyond erotica.
I'm...
Sardu
Master of the Theater of the Macabre.
Tonight...
... we begin with torture.
Again I warn you...
If should you find what you see...
is a little upsetting to your stomachs...
then just pretend we're play acting.
But if you're skeptical or bored...
then just pretend that what you see...
is real.
Are you willing to accept Sardu
as your lord and master...
and obey his every whim and command?
Listen...
I'll do anything you want.
Oh no, no, no, my dear!
We've just begun.
It's a trick!
Who said that?
Ohhh Mr. Maverick,
the famous football player.
Ralphus...
Would you care to try it
on Miss DeNatalie there?
The lovely prima ballerina.
Don't you dare!
A trick?
What you are about to see now is
the is the 2nd degree of torture.
The iron tourniquet.
She's dead, master.
She is dead.
Tell me, Mr. Maverick...
Why are you applauding?
She is a very good actress.
What if I were to tell you
that she is really dead?
Actually and eternally?
Trash!
I've seen better, years ago...
in the Grand-Guignol in Paris.
Ahh Mr. Creasy Silo,
the eminent critic.
Not here officially...
I don't review third rate magic shows.
Magic?
And let Mr. Silo
explain our next trick...
Dismemberment.
Ohh now we're getting
the proper reaction.
Now the eyes, Ralphus.
Call this a trick?
Not a trick...
Drama.
Pure theater.
The donation for actors, please.
Non of the actors receive any pay.
Thank you very much, sir.
A donation for the actors.
Mr. Silo...
A donation for the actors?
Actors?
No true actor would submit
to engage in such trash.
But you are going
to review my show.
Absolutely not!
You heard me in there ...
If I were to review your
so-called show even badly,
I feel some of my readers
might come just out of curiosity.
And I do not want to be responsible
for keeping your theater open,
one more day!
Then we shall see.
Really ?
Hey, don't listen to him.
I hate critics and he is
at the top of the list.
You know, I really liked your show.
Thank you, Mr. Maverick.
You ought to move it up town.
Ohh well...
And what did Miss DeNatalie
think of our show?
It was just so real.
That girl in the chair...
She was excellent.
She's a fantastic actress.
I'd like to meet her.
Well, perhaps another time.
She got a terrible headache.
Oh, I could imagine!
Good night.
Thank you.
Tom, will you please get me
out of here before I throw up.
Don't you dare ruin my dinner!
How delightful...
A little after dinner music.
I want Creasy Silo brought here!
You want us to kidnap him, master?
Yes, Ralphus.
I can't do it, it's too dangerous.
I'll get caught!
You must do this for me, Ralphus.
Then what will you do for me, master?
You've been a very bad boy today.
Have I really been that bad?
Must I be punished?
Now I find this artist makes
a very interesting statement.
I beg your pardon, haven't
I seen you somewhere before?
Welcome to the Theater
of the Macabre, Mr Silo.
I think your appreciation of my art shall
be greatly enhanced in the next few days.
I don't believe it!
I don't believe it, Sardu.
Thinking of all these is so trite
and kidnapping, so classical.
The eminent critic has a
sense of humor in times of stress.
But it won't suffice for
what is to follow, my friend.
Unless of course you agree
that my theater is true art
and you apologise to me
in the most sincere way.
Or...?
Torture.
This will never work, Sardu.
Allow me to show you.
No. No.
A most modern method
of reflex orientation.
Ralphus will now induce
500 volts to her nervous system.
If she does as she
is told, there is no pain,
if not...
excruciating agony.
She will soon learn, the only
thing to alleviate her discomfort ...
is her utterly correct
responses to my commands
and the sound of this whistle.
No. ..
Master!
Please don't hurt me any more!
Master !
I know, my dear.
We will soon find many
exciting things for you to do.
And in time you'll
learn to enjoy them.
Gidee Up!
So Creasy...
look on in awe at a man who has
turned all his fantasies into reality.
Not really.
One still escapes you ...
Success in the theater.
That is about to occur.
My new show
received critical acclaim.
You haven't the talent to
create anything but garbage.
A ballet is forming in my mind.
It will combine 2 art forms...
Sadism and dance.
Cos the public cannot
digest eroticism alone.
But to display sadism and
discipline in its purest form
would on lead to imprisonment.
But by simply disguising
it with a story, a minimal plot
and a score...
will result in my being
hailed as a creative genius.
Kill me!
Oh no, my friend.
You're going to be front
row, centre in my triumph.
After all...
what good is the show
without a critic?
Have you finished your ride, Ralphus?
Put her to work in the toilet.
Her mouth will make
an interesting urinal.
At last I'm glad to see some of the petro
dollars flowing back in this direction.
I can't say I'm not doing
my bit for the economy.
One million.
Whoa, there's no need to count it.
Your employer is an old customer.
He is very pleased with
the quality of the shipment.
They have done much to maintain
peace in my area of the world.
You tell Henry that
he is a very fine gentleman.
And a very good customer.
Will I be seeing him shortly?
No, not likely.
At this moment, he is
flying back to the Middle east.
To be on hand to supervise
the reception of the shipment.
Personally!
If that is agreeable
with everybody concerned.
Go away!
Filthy bitches!
Get back!
Away, bitches!
Stay back!
Sluts!
Are you hurt, master?
It's just a scratch.
Still untrainable!
Still refuse to accept
me as your master, eh?
Ralphus.
Master?
Starve them to bed.
A dinner by candlelight?
How romantic!
How's the fillet?
Tender?
You are eating one of my
trainees that didn't quite work out.
You mean I didn't spoil your appetite?
Nothing you can say
or do will revolt me.
My next show will.
Your shows ...
would revolt...
anyone.
It will be built around ballet.
You haven't the talent
to stage a proper ballet.
It will star Natasha DeNatalie.
She'll never dance for you.
Not willingly.
Yes, master?
Ralphus.
Be a little chap and run along and
collect Natasha DeNatalie for me.
Tom ..
you do everything just so well...
even make love.
Well, no matter what I do, nothing
compares to you on the stage, beautiful.
You make Lincoln Center just come alive.
I have to get to work, though.
Estonian ballerinas...
- Tom.
- Hmm.
Do you find me attractive
as a star of the ballet...
or as a person?
Both.
Oh, come on, I think
you just like dancing.
Not when they look like you, I do.
Natasha
I'll be late for rehearsal.
One cup of coffee?
No.
Will I see you tonight?
Well ..
after the performance.
You know, Tom ..
if I had time...
you would be the only person
I would spend it with in this world.
Welcome.
So, you've decided to leave Lincoln
Center and come to dance with me?
Do you like?
I like very much, master.
Then do what you please with her,
only don't incapacitate her.
She must dance for me.
Ralphus!
No marks on her body!
Who is this?
Natasha? No, she is not here.
She did what?
She didn't come to the theater?
How long has she been missing?
Jesus Christ!
Why didn't you call me earlier?
Natasha DeNatalie has joined my company.
Her absence will not be taken lightly.
The Police will track her here.
They haven't tracked anyone here yet.
I've been in business for years.
DeNatalie is a celebrity.
Public opinion will force them...
to come here.
It's nothing...
have it your missing high schoolgirls...
whose feat is of...
no interest, not even parents.
Now, will you dance for me?
Continue.
She is stronger than we thought.
24 hours without sleep, warmth,
and comfort and she still denies me.
Really, I quite admire her courage.
It's really quite a challenge.
This is the New York Police
Department emergency number 911.
There is no one in at the moment.
You are listening to a recording.
At the sound of the beep,
leave your name, telephone number,
a short description of the crime
and their perpetrators.
Is she dead, master?
Not quite.
If she dies no new show.
I know, idiots.
And all our work will have been in vain.
Call the doctor.
Will she live, doctor?
I've given Ralphus a prescription.
How much do I owe you?
My malpractice insurance is going up.
How about taking it out on trade?
Another operation?
What kind?
Ooh, you make it up.
This won't hurt a bit.
Pretty patient.
No. ..
Now...
I like coming to Sardu's...
'cos he lets me do anything
I want to, to the patients.
Understand ?
Hi, aren't we going to
have a pretty operation.
I don't have many...
pretty patients...
because I get into a lot of trouble...
and my mother doesn't like it.
I live with my mother.
Please.
Please don't hurt me.
I'm not going to hurt you.
I'm a doctor.
I'm going to cure you.
Of everything.
Please. Please
I'll do anything.
You will?
Can you do something with your mouth?
I love mouths.
I should have been a dentist.
But...
My mother said that a
doctor is much classier.
You won't bite?
Okay, open wide.
You sure you won't bite?
Let's make sure you won't bite.
That's it...
Now...
When I was in school...
they used to say that...
I couldn't do that.
Now...
you can't bite.
Doctor?
Well, you're not going
to do her hair, are you?
No.
A little bit of a
elective neurosurgery.
I was just going to see
the doctor out, master?
What did you say?
I was just going to see
the doctor out, master.
Doctor!
Get rid of him!
Yes, master.
Permanently.
Would it be easier to
get a taxi out of Broadway?
No, it's quicker this way.
You'll like it.
Right here!
... my office in a cab.
I'm not trying to wait for the subway!
This is faster.
Come on.
Right this way.
Okay, I ... thank you.
Say goodbye to Sardu.
Bulls eye, coming up.
Who is it?
Sergeant Tucci,
New York City Police Department.
Come on in.
You left a message on
our service, Mr Maverick.
Right, right.
How about a drink?
No, I haven't got the time.
Got another case uptown.
- Listen, have you got any leads for...
- Fine place you got here!
No wonder.
That was some contract you just signed.
I mean, keeping the chips
for the rest of your life.
And those hairspray commercials,
- really something!
- The DeNatalie case...
Do you have any leads?
Only you, QP.
Me?
You!
I don't understand.
Huh, you were sleeping with her.
You could have got into
an argument or something?
Hey, come on.
Don't worry about it.
A little money upfront and I
can prove that the mayor did it.
This rotten town.
What did you expect?
My father worked for 25 years, for what?
Niente
He didn't live to see his pension.
Now, was he was an honest cop, too?
He was a clerk in the
Department of Commerce.
When are you going to find Natasha?
How much is it worth to you?
Worth to me?
Well, you son of a bitch.
She is a citizen, man.
Take it easy...
I know she is a citizen.
So she's a citizen...
Saw her pictures in a file at
the Missing Persons Bureau.
They mail it to 50 police departments.
Nobody is going to
bother looking for her.
She will show up...
dead, if she's lucky.
You want to be smart, QP?
Take some of this money you have...
and grease the hands of justice.
Make that, the wheels of justice.
Alright.
How much?
Ten grand.
Well, how is our little patient today?
I won't dance.
Enough of that!
Time to recoup your energy.
Ralphus has made
some chicken soup for you.
There...
He made it especially for you.
Delicious?
My mother taught me...
I used the whole chicken.
The secret is cooking it alive.
We have a little entertainment
planned for you today...
some thing that may happen to you...
if you still insist on not dancing.
Lights!
The rack.
A legitimate form of punishment,
legalized by both the
Church and the State.
Action!
This is going to go far beyond
every stretch of your imagination.
Slowly, girls!
Slowly!
- QP?
- Yeah.
Sergeant Tucci.
I finally figured out what happened
to your girlfriend Natasha.
What?
The Times critic Creasy Silo,
disappeared last week, right?
Right.
Yeah, they ran off together.
Bullshit!
Extremely plausible.
Tucci, I want my money back.
It's only a theory, QP.
Listen...
I'm working on it.
Yeah, well, you better be.
Our second
demonstration, my dear.
Add punishment for little girl who
refuses to take her dancing lesson.
Due to her tender age,
we're being most gentle with her.
Help me!
Now, as long as
you do as we tell you ...
the longer you'll stay alive.
Open your mouth, I'm going
to put something nice into it.
Good!
Bite down hard.
Don't let go.
You may lose your head.
Now, let's see how long you can
go before you open your mouth.
Why, I almost forgot...
We're going to cane you for
being a very bad little girl.
Help me!
How many times do I have to tell you,
you're white and I'm brown, idiot!
How much we play for, Master?
Well, let's start off
with the finger in the pot.
You don't have any more chips, master.
Why is it you always win?
Play on!
But you don't have
any more chips, master.
I bet you an arm and a leg, I do.
What's this about a hunger strike?
Well, I won't have it.
You're as much a part
of the scene as Natasha.
Ralphus.
Force feed him.
Allow me to introduce to you...
your rival...
Maya.
Natasha!
She will not dance for you either.
Oh, yes, she will ...
but she'll do a dance
of a different kind.
I shall now demonstrate to
you what shall happen to you...
if you do not immediately
agree to start rehearsal.
I think your colleague has
hung up her dancing shoes forever.
Now are you planning to
cut short your dancing career?
I will dance!
Oooh, she will dance.
She will dance.
Theater Macabre.
Nope. Master Sardu
can't come to the phone.
He's tied up for the moment.
She shall dance.
You were wrong, Creasy.
She shall dance for me.
Have some champagne.
That's enough.
"Ballerina Flips Lid For Freak Show"
Your little girlfriend didn't disappear.
She just went off Broadway.
- Right here in Variety.
- Give me that.
Christ, I don't believe it...
You know broads...
Come on.
She wouldn't give up Lincoln Center
for that rat hole in Soho!
Ooh, they kidnapped her
and tortured her.
Wise up!
But she's not
appearing willingly.
Yeah.
Hey!
What kind of show
does this guy Sardu put on?
Ahh, nude ones.
I wonder how much he's paying off ...
I got to talk to her.
Careful, Ralphus.
Careful.
We want him to look
his best for opening night.
No, no.
You wouldn't dare
allow me appear in public.
Oh, yes, I would.
And you're going to have
the best seat in the house.
Ok girls, take ten.
Well, Ralphus, what
do you think so far?
Nah! It's too long, master.
Too long?
Then why didn't you cut
out the last Inquisition joke
and make your exit on the Gestapo.
Ralphus!
- Master?
- Yes.
- About my billing?
- Don't talk to me about billing!
I thought you gave that all up when
you left the William Morris Agency!
Actors...
Master will be with you in a moment.
He's on the telephone
with his press agent.
It's some witty place.
You know something, QP?
There is more in here than meets the eye.
Yeah what?
I smell money.
I always thought these
Off-Off Broadway gimmicks
were front for something else.
So for what?
I don't know.
Something big.
Mr. Maverick.
Well, it's certainly
nice seeing you again.
Either way.
John Tucci.
Sergeant John Tucci,
New York City Police Department.
Really?
You are both coming
to our opening tonight.
Listen...
I'd like to see Natasha.
Oh I'm afraid not.
She's exhausted.
Rehearsal after rehearsal.
You know what a perfectionist she is!
Ya, I know all about that.
I just want to see her, alright.
Why?
I mean, we're all going to Sardis
aren't we, afterwards, to celebrate.
I said I wanted to see her.
Well, absolutely not.
This is the theater.
You know what an opening is like?
In fact I can hardly afford to spend
these few moments talking to you.
Produce the lady, Sardu.
Please...
Produce the lady
or produce your license.
Capish.
If she's not here in five minutes...
there's going to be so many
violations against this place...
that you won't be able to
open a can of beer tonight.
If you insist...
I insist!
Very well.
But don't take up
too much of her time.
Hey there, you got a nice
way of getting things done.
It's called tact.
Hi, Tom!
I'm sorry I didn't called you, Tom.
But I've just been so
tied up with my new show.
Were you here willingly?
Of course!
I mean, Lincoln Center
it is just so boring.
You know, one night Giselle act or the
other, that would be the only thing that
I would have to look forward to.
Believe me...
Sardu is a genius.
This is where it's all at...
right here in Soho.
Yeah, but this is a S & M show.
It's not S & M.
This is art!
And ..
please, will you come
to the show tonight.
And now Ralphus will show
both of you gentlemen out.
Don't bother, Sardu.
We'll find our own way out.
Come on, Tom
Master...
Master!
Oh, Master, please
don't punish me, Master.
Master.
Master..
You did very well, Natasha.
Thank you, master.
I don't know what the hell
is the matter with her.
I thought I know her like a book.
Something doesn't smell right in that place.
Maybe she's right.
Sex and sadism might be
the new thing, I don't know...
She was trying to tell you
something QP, and you missed it.
Like what?
- She never danced Giselle...
- I know, how do you know?
I am a freak for anything in a tutu.
- You?
- Uh, uh.
When I was a kid,
I wanted to become a dancer.
But I come from an Italian family...
My father wanted me to do
something honorable...
so I became an honest cop.
But I want to get this guy, Sardu.
My way.
What are you doing back here?
I have a show opening
in less than 2 hours.
Business, Sardu.
Business?
Monkey business.
I don't understand.
Understand this!
Ralphus...
Shut up!
You kill a cop in this town and
you're as good as dead, Sardu.
Capish
And you have a record
a mile long, downtown.
Three open murder charges.
Now ...
where's this place, the front door?
I'll cut you in.
Of course you'll cut me in.
But what's going on here, Sardu?
White slavery.
White slavery!
You were keeping years ago.
My show must open tonight.
How much you willing to pay
for your show to open tonight?
I'll give you $50,000.
$50,000?
You making that money off these broads?
I do volume business.
I ship all over the world.
International, huh?
Well, I guess then we'll
have to up the ante, Sardu.
A 100, 000.
Alright, I accept
your proposition, Tucci.
Good.
Tonight.
I can't get my hands on that much...
Well, you better get your
hands on that much cash.
Now you don't keep
any money in the banks.
Because the IRS will be down
here with their hands out.
And don't give me any garbage
about safety deposit boxes.
Tonight.
Good
Up front...
before the curtains go up, Sardu.
Well, what did you find out?
I hate to disappoint you, kid.
He's on the up and up.
Sardu's on the up and up.
A little weird...
but on the up and up.
Giselle?
What about Giselle?
She did it 3 years ago, in St. Louis.
and she's got 8 performances next year.
You know my problem is?
I've been at this job too long.
I don't trust anyone.
So it means, you're
going to drop the case?
What else can I do?
She wants to be in a freak
show.  It's a free country.
Hey, maybe some weirdo goes down there,
gets turned on to ballet, who knows ...
Hey, cheer up.
Why don't you and I go?
You don't still want to go down there?
Why not?
It it's ballet, I'm on my way!
Well, who might have say,
what is art and what isn't?
Let's go.
Break a leg, Ralphus.
Whose, master?
Ralphus, that was just
a theatrical expression.
Hey, Ziegfeld!
You forget about me?
Wait here.
I'll take a look,
see what I can do.
I think I'll take a look, too.
I said, wait here.
I promise you, you will have a
banquet before this night is through.
Stay back!
Back!
Excuse me.
Listen...
Sardu is holding Natasha prisoner.
What?
He's got a white slavery
action, 2 -300 girls a year.
Tortures them.
White slavery?
It's all over town, you close 'em up
on east side, they move to the west side.
You close them up on Park Avenue, what
do you think, they move down to Soho.
White slavery in this day and age?
You haul them into court and
the judges let them go, you know why?
Because they are in on the take,
like everybody else is.
I don't believe it!
Where do you think
half the girls wind up
will come into this town
belong to show business?
Off, off Broadway?
But this time, Sardu's gone too far.
And I'm going to fix him.
That freak wants to be a celebrity.
Hey, hey, hey, calm down!
Many innocent people here,
you want anybody get hurt?
Take it easy.
Watch the show, huh.
5 minutes to deck...
5 minutes...
You look positively magnificent, my dear.
Thank you, master.
The Schubert's already inquiring
about moving our show up to Broadway ...
and then...
Hollywood!
And the chief inquisitor said:
"You must be a secret Jew,
your tongue smoked!"
I thought I told you to
stop at the Gestapo joke.
Listen to them,
listen to them...
They love me,
they love me...
Actors.
And now...
our prima ballerina,
Natasha DeNatalie...
in a composition of my own...
"The artist, seduction and death...
of a critic".
Is that Creasy Silo?
Quiet!
Only the two of us?
What about the rest of the police force?
They will make too much noise.
Anyway we want to keep it out
of the papers, don't we?
Tucci.
If I make it official, we gonna
have to cut it up too many ways.
Cut what?
Sardu's treasure.
He's got a fortune
stashed away down there.
I mean, look!
Silver certificates.
He hasn't spend a nickel in years.
Hey, don't you have
any sense of justice?
And what about the people
down in that dungeon right now?
We'll take care of it.
Later.
Oh Christ. People ought to be
more careful of what they leave ....
What the matter, kid?
Never got a little head before?
Come on.
You're hereby placed under arrest!
You have the right to counsel,
not required to make any statement
without the presence of counsel.
It is your right to remain silent and
anything you say maybe held against you.
Understand?
Good!
Natasha!
Ralphus
Master wants you.
Come here, you little pervert!
I may have to get some of these keys.
Keep your eyes on these...
weirdos.
Okay, Sardu, freeze!
And your boyfriend...
too.
- Hey, who's in there?
He is making love to Creasy Silo.
What?
Creasy?
I killed Creasy during the "pas de deux".
There is no .... I can take.
Tucci...
Do me a favor?
Hit me again!
If he opens his mouth again, kill him!
Please?
Jesus Christ!
Alright, ladies,
Shall we all spring you later?
Shit!
Cut it!
There's plenty of time
to play with that later.
You know how to get in though?
Okay, ladies,
We got to get a job to do.
Come on.
We gotta help him.
Let's get out of here!
My master!
You hurt my master.
Come on!
What's the matter with you?
I must get back to my master.
Come on! Let's go.
Let's get out of here!
God damn it!
Tom!
I'm coming, master!