RUST AND BONE
I'm hungry.
Want some?
Stop it.
I said stop it!
Sam!
Come on, hurry!
Tired?
- You're Ali [Alain]?
- Yeah. Get in.
You took your time!
- I've been looking for an hour.
- Move over, move.
I called Anna.
I couldn't find you.
You like my truck?
You really do?
I don't like boys
who don't like my truck!
So you want it?
You seem nice.
Eight truckers laid off.
So I talked it over with Anna.
I decided to go independent.
I bought this rig.
What's that for?
To eat outside when it's nice.
We get sun here.
I'm still buckled in.
Look at this.
See those dogs?
They're Aunt Anna's.
Whose spare parts?
Our neighbour's, Che.
He does repairs on the side.
Lucky for us.
Tell me when.
Make you big and strong.
When you see your sister last?
I don't know, 5 years.
That long?
What does she do?
She works in a supermarket.
- Cashier?
- Yeah, exactly.
Not those! She'll kill you.
On top. The most expired.
Organised by date, top to bottom.
- Those.
- Start on top.
Want one?
Anna brings them from work.
They throw them away
once they expire.
But you can eat them for another week.
Make a good living?
- We manage to make ends meet.
- What do you do?
Deliveries. Frozen food.
Mostly fish, but other stuff too.
Depends on the loads I find.
Want coffee?
Yeah, sure.
He looks like you.
Some reunion!
No kiss for your brother?
Just this, for him?
At least she packed his passport.
Oh please,
she just forgot it was in there.
They used the kid to smuggle drugs.
No way.
She told me so herself.
How will you tend to him?
I have no time. I work.
Richard too.
Was he in school there?
You don't even know?
You're killing me.
- Did you go to school at Mom's?
- Yes.
I'll see if I can enrol him nearby.
He needs clothes.
He can't go like this.
I'll ask the neighbours.
Want to sleep?
- Should I close the door?
- No need.
Here you go.
Give him some.
Gentle. I'll be back.
Don't hurt them.
He licked me.
Don't open.
Want to come eat?
They're cute.
We know a breeder.
He leaves them a month.
A little extra money.
- You doing okay?
- I'm exhausted.
- That won't start.
- You'll see.
Don't trust appearances.
Fine to go to work.
- You kidding?
- Not at all.
Che!
Where's your toolbox?
In the back.
Can you give us a hand?
When is Mom coming?
Soon.
Soon, I said.
But when?
I don't know.
What was your last job?
Short time in a slaughterhouse.
It closed.
Never in security?
Assistant security guard
in a stadium for six months.
Night-watchman. In a parking lot, too.
Ever do any combat sports?
Boxing for six years.
Kick-boxing for two.
Can you prove it?
Pictures? Boxing permit?
I won a regional championship
in Belgium.
I have a belt.
You quit?
The coach did.
- Why?
- He died.
You don't smoke?
You don't drink?
I didn't hear.
- I don't drink.
- No drugs?
One good reason to hire you?
Trust me.
So?
I'll call him next week.
Is that his son?
You didn't mention the kid?
I didn't ask.
Your hands are cold.
You win. Go on in.
Four against one. Not fair.
Enjoy!
See? It's easy.
It doesn't matter what you say.
Just so she remembers you.
Bit of luck, they're drunk, depressed.
There you are. Nice guy.
- Does it work?
- You bet.
Step back, please.
You okay? Tilt your head back.
Good. Take a few breaths.
Asshole!
Breathe.
I have to get home.
Any friends here?
I came alone. I have my car.
- You can't drive.
- I'm fine.
I'll call a cab.
I have my car. I need it.
You're sweet.
Bitch! Yeah, you, slut!
What the fuck?
Shut up!
Shit.
Still bleeding?
I'm fine.
You got hurt?
It's starting to swell.
Go to the Annex often?
Why do you go alone?
To dance?
To meet guys.
Oh, yeah?
You don't dress like that,
just to dance.
How am I dressed?
I don't know.
Look.
And?
You're dressed like a whore.
Excuse me?
- How do you call it?
- Enough.
- No surprise you...
- Shut up.
- How will you get back?
- No idea.
Forget it.
- For a cab.
- Forget it, I said.
Good night, then.
Got any ice up there?
- What?
- Ice cubes.
Wait. I'll go see.
I can come up.
Someone's up there.
So what?
So wait and I'll come back.
Okay.
Come on.
- Steph?
- There's ice here.
What happened?
There was a fight.
- But you're okay?
- Fine.
Who's he?
Bouncer from the Annex.
The Annex?
Why the fuck were you there?
What are you looking for?
Ice cubes.
He hurt his hand.
Can we talk for a minute?
Get off my back!
Any better?
Yeah, it is.
Is that you with the whales?
Is it your job?
I'd never have imagined!
Surprised a whore can train orcas?
You can go. You're done.
Talking to me?
Go on, please.
I left my number, if you need it.
You okay?
You're upset.
I saw your face there.
Where?
With the bouncer.
I saw how he shut you up.
I see. He shut me up.
Yeah, he shut you up.
No more orders, Simon.
Meaning?
No more orders, that's all.
Get out. It's filthy.
Get out.
Damn it. You're filthy!
Don't touch me.
Move it. Anna!
Take off your pants.
You smell like shit.
Lift your arms.
Come here.
Stay put!
What are you doing?
- Where were you?
- Doing ljaundry.
What the hell?
Don't cry!
Turn that thing off.
- Where's Anna?
- She went out.
Come shower, Sam.
Stay out of there!
Anyone here?
Steph!
Wait!
What did you do with my legs?
Your brothers called.
They asked for you,
but I thought it best to wait.
What would I have done?
Give that to me.
Give it to me, now.
Please.
What were you thinking?
How about a little stroll?
I don't feel like it.
Right!
Good. Left!
Left, right!
Watch your guard.
How you doing, Foued?
How's it going?
Hold on.
- You forgot Sam.
- I'm at the gym.
- The school called.
- I'm going.
You kidding? You forgot...
I said I'm going!
Mr. Van Versch, may I talk to you?
I know.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I was at work.
Look how late it is.
Third time in two weeks!
Next time I'll have to call the police.
Come here!
Move, god-damn it.
Fucking pain!
- Don't like dogs?
- Not him.
He doesn't like assholes.
Move!
What's his problem?
Fucking reeks, too.
All?
Yeah, it's me. Who's that?
Stephanie.
Remember me?
We met at the Annex.
The fight, the ice.
Stephanie, sure!
How are you?
You hear what happened?
I saw it on TV.
So how do you think I am?
I don't know.
How about you?
The usual.
Still a bouncer?
No, a security guard.
Four nights a week.
I'm here.
Come in.
Been here for long?
Just got here.
The doorbell wasn't you?
Sit down.
Something to drink? Coffee?
I just have instant.
That's fine. Need any help?
Have you been here long?
It's been...
two...
three, four months I think.
It's not bad here.
It's temporary, because...
I'll do it.
Insurance pays for this.
No one comes to help you?
Help me what, walk?
To clean up and stuff.
Yeah, people come. Lots of them.
You okay?
Does it stink in here?
A little.
It's me who stinks.
Let's go out.
Come on. Get dressed.
I won't go out.
Be careful.
Stop pushing or I'll puke.
I'll do it.
I want to take a dip.
You don't want to?
Why? No bathing suit?
Do you even realize?
Who cares? No one's here.
I'm going.
I think I will go in.
Really?
Can I have a towel?
I'm done.
How do I do this?
You have to carry me.
Hang on.
Don't let go too fast.
You okay?
Fuck, this feels good.
Thanks.
I won't need these.
Garbage.
There's nice stuff here.
This for example.
You can wear it over pants.
You liked this.
You liked this dress.
It's for you.
I'll keep this one.
See those fists.
Damn! Look at that.
I fought him before.
Twice at nationals.
Damn good fighter.
Knee, right.
One right is all it takes.
What do you want?
To come in.
Who's he?
Are you Martial?
The boss mentioned him.
He's with the company.
Check this out.
Two rights, then again. He's 200 lbs.
- He's not 200.
- At least 190.
They should stop.
Why don't they stop?
Knee, knee.
And again.
- Like that?
- What?
- Fights.
- Yeah.
- Can you fight?
- A Little, yeah.
Ever fight?
A long time ago.
I boxed. Kick-boxing too.
Want to make some money? Fighting?
You shitting me?
A guy organizes fights
near Nice, a gypsy.
Betting, money.
How do you know him?
I put cameras in a garage
he stole some Mercedes from.
We met when he wanted the tapes.
What kind of boxing?
Like Kick-boxing? You use your feet?
We use everything. Elbows, knees...
We fuck each other up, bad.
Last man standing wins.
You're strangling me.
First time doing it?
Not scared?
Scared of what?
How much do you get?
I don't know, 500, 1000.
Depends if I win.
You fight for 500?
Get tuned up,
put your health at stake, for 500?
My health at stake?
Don't overstate it.
I can give you 500.
Cancel. I'll pay you tomorrow.
If you're loaded, sure.
But I said I'd do it.
If it's not the money, then why?
- I never said it's not the money.
- So why?
What a pain!
Why? To fight. For the fun of it.
Like you and your fish. Why?
Because it's fun.
The money and the fun.
See how I ended up?
Spare me.
Where's your stroller?
If you go to your fight...
you think I can come?
Two casts for two prosthetic devices.
To get you walking.
After the sockets,
we'll choose the knees.
Hydraulic, pneumatic, electronic.
Electronic knees?
You don't have to think.
It positions itself.
Do the feet move?
No, they don't. They're carbon blades.
Flexible, but don't move.
- I'll walk like a robot?
- No, just fine.
There are feet,
not covered by insurance...
that can give you heels
0.4 to 2 inches high.
For women it's important.
Damn!
You can go. I'll take a cab.
I don't mind.
Take Sam for five minutes.
The breeder's here.
Can you watch your son?
- Yeah, sure.
- Keep him inside, okay?
...competing since 2009.
But that doesn't mean he's not been training,
so obviously we can expect...
Go to Daddy. Stay with him.
Stay put.
Your hands are cold.
Driving Luke Wise backup
against the cages.
Seem to remember
a bit of judo background...
Don't touch.
...is a judo extraordinaire.
Famous for judo
in his home country of Romania.
Not only is he dangerous on the ground,
but he can strike effectively...
so you have more things
to worry about
See him?
- Look how strong he is.
- Who?
The guy in black.
Both times he scores,
once across the body...
Just a second. Stay here.
What did he say?
...release that grip around the head,
look to get up on his shoulders.
What others?
How many?
We didn't agree to that.
Fight them yourself, fatso!
Where are the dogs going?
Don't worry. Go inside.
Tell him I don't give a fuck!
I said, keep him inside.
I'm on the phone!
Take care of your kid instead!
Come here!
What the hell?
Let go!
Take care of your kid!
Calm down.
Calm the hell down!
Fucking pain in the ass! Enough!
- He's fine.
- Get the fuck out!
Get out. Hands off him!
He's fine.
Hands off him!
Get the fuck out!
It's all over.
- Martial, slower!
- Buckle her in.
Sit up. Your seat belt.
- Who's she?
- His girlfriend.
Okay. Open up.
He thinks he's on ESPN.
Who are all those guys?
Dealers, I guess. Guys with cash.
Feel okay?
Yeah, great.
Any trouble, take a fall.
How much in bets?
About 2000, but it'll go up.
What do I do?
No women. Stay here.
Ready.
Come on.
That was fast.
Fighting again?
What?
Another fight after.
I need to run.
Fuck.
Pull over. I want to rinse off.
What's the noise?
- What's that for?
- For my son.
You have a son?
Let's go.
And when you're there, you hit him.
Lay off.
But you hit him!
Not on purpose. He's not dead.
Why'd you bring him along?
You should have left him there.
That's for you.
What is it?
What I owe, plus a few months.
- Where did you get it?
- I won a fight.
What fight?
It's all you found?
Getting beat up?
You want it or not?
Don't look at me like that.
I cheated.
Like it?
- Like it?
- Yes, Ali.
- Want to swim?
You're stronger than them
and they're swimming.
- Give me a kiss.
- Don't want to.
You do. Give Daddy a kiss.
I don't want to!
Over there.
Come back now.
My job isn't to monitor customers.
It's to monitor staff.
Say you manage a place like this.
Too many workers,
and union reps bust your balls.
- What then?
- I fire them.
You need a good reason to.
You check if they loiter
in the rest-room...
smoke on the premises...
take long breaks.
Then you force them to quit,
or fire them.
My cameras are for that
I don't work for the retail chains.
I work for the managers.
Guys in three-piece-suits.
They can't get enough of me.
I've equipped every chain store
in the area.
You have the right?
The right?
Since when does that matter?
If management is caught spying
they go straight to court.
Me, straight to jail.
Left, left. On your left.
Hold on. I'll wave.
That's great.
- When?
- Two days ago.
Can I see?
Want to swim?
I don't know.
I'm not sure I want to get undressed.
Seeing anyone? A girlfriend?
You have no one?
They're not girlfriends.
What are they?
Quick fucks?
A lot of them?
You mind talking about it?
Couldn't care less.
Were you with a lot of guys?
Before?
I was with Simon.
Is that all?
There were others, but not that many.
I was very...
I liked being watched.
I liked turning them on.
I liked getting them worked up.
But then I got bored.
And now?
Nothing.
I forgot what it's like.
I don't know if it still works.
No more desire?
That's not what I said.
Sure, I feel desire.
Change the subject.
I'll do that.
Come on.
I have to use these legs now.
You want to fuck?
What?
To see if it still works.
If we fuck, you'll know.
Just like that?
I'm not sure if I can.
Your call. You tell me.
Hold on.
Come here!
Do you mind if we don't kiss?
No problem.
Breasts okay?
Yes.
You're crushing me.
No more talking now.
Okay.
Gentle.
You okay?
Was it good?
It still works?
Yes.
No, I don't know.
Hard to say after one time.
Yeah, but I can't right now.
I have to go.
That's not what I meant, actually.
It's new, so...
- Was it good or not?
- Yeah, it was.
If you're up for it, just call.
If I'm OP, no problem.
What's OP?
Operational.
When I'm free, when I can.
When you're OP, we...
All right...
Nothing. It's great.
I'm off, bye.
Sure, I've missed it.
OP?
Shit, get dressed.
- What is it?
- My sister.
You scared me.
Why are you there?
Came to meet a girl...
You bring girls here now?
Stephanie, come meet my sister!
The girl from Marineland.
Poor thing.
Four for us.
That's enough.
Is that him?
- How old is he?
- Five.
I'm out of grapefruit.
I brought Vita-Mix.
Maybe you prefer tea?
- I'll make you tea.
- It's fine!
- I have biscuits.
- It's fine.
No big deal.
- Want to go?
- Why?
Her damned tea and biscuits.
- She's really nice.
- Sure, she is.
She's tense.
She feels like a cashier with you.
You sleep here?
You have a nice room.
Why are you looking at me?
Does it scare you?
Want to see?
Does it hurt?
Go on.
Use this hand to grab my leg...
on the side.
Same movement.
Good job.
You okay?
No, I'm not. He'll kill me.
Ready?
Want to get down?
Dance!
I'm going.
- We'll talk tomorrow, okay?
- Leaving?
I'm off.
Later, guys. Thanks.
Want a drink?
Can I buy you one?
- Champagne.
- Two champs, Mika.
I'm Pierre. And you?
Marie.
Come here often?
On and off.
I'm sorry. Not tonight.
I don't feel like it.
No problem.
I'm leaving.
Thanks for the drink.
I'm sorry, I...
- Sorry for what?
- I couldn't know.
Know what?
I couldn't know...
you had a...
- Didn't have...
- Have what?
You okay?
You all stay late?
I don't know.
And your night?
Normal.
You think it's okay, talking like that?
I ask how it went with the girl.
And you answer me 'normal'!?
What should I say?
Nothing.
What?
Normal, like picking up
some bimbo there with me?
- What would you say if I did it?
- Nothing.
Really?
You're being a pain.
What's the problem?
What am I to you?
A friend?
A pal?
A buddy like Foued and the others?
You fuck your buddies?
If we continue, we have to do it right.
Let's show some manners.
I mean consideration.
You've always been
so considerate with me.
Is that a plan?
We continue, but not like animals.
What is it?
I'm OP.
I'm OP, that's all.
Why are you staring?
Not up for it?
Why not?
We're calling the cops anyway!
Get the equipment.
Spying on your employees!
Be man enough to look me in the eyes.
Don't touch me.
He's guilty and he calls the cops.
What are you doing?
Packing up.
Your equipment?
No pictures.
You work for them?
I said, no pictures.
No pictures? You film us!
I'll smash your head in!
Don't worry.
We got your faces!
Shut up!
I need to leave for a few months.
Ali wants more fights.
You can take over while I'm away.
He's okay with it?
He told me to call you.
Why me?
I guess he trusts you.
I don't know the scene, those guys.
Seen me with those beasts?
Yeah.
It's all in here.
For the rest, ask and I'll answer.
What about the betting?
Can you count on your fingers?
This one?
Over there?
I see you have a slight problem there.
Yeah. An automatic, sorry.
That's just what you need.
But it has to look hot.
RIGHT
You okay, RoboCop?
What a madhouse.
- How much?
- 3 400.
Ready?
I'm here.
Don't look at me like this.
What are you doing?
Taking a leek.
Can I have my T-shirt?
- What time is it?
- Six.
I went out like a light.
I don't want you seeing me like this.
Hang on.
Come here.
What? What is it?
We're allowed to now?
Follow me, please.
Management wants you.
Wait here.
You're here too?
Yeah. And you?
Know why we're here?
So?
I got fired.
Don't worry, honey.
Check this out.
That's him packing up.
This is when he tried to hit me.
He left afterwards.
I caught him red-handed.
You okay?
- What are you doing?
- I'm hungry.
Shut that.
You can't eat here.
You can't eat.
What's this about?
I got fired. I'm unemployed.
What's the connection
with me not eating?
The connection?
There were cameras in the storing place.
They saw us taking expired food
and fired us.
You got your sister fired.
How does that feel?
How much did you get?
Are you paid per store or a flat rate?
No comment?
I take you in, see to your kid.
You get me fired, but no comment.
Great.
I couldn't know.
You couldn't know?
I don't understand.
How could you do something like that?
Whose side you're on? Theirs?
What's going on in your head?
You couldn't know what?
That you were fucking us over?
That we'd end up flat broke?
Calm down.
Calm down, I said.
Get your stuff and beat it.
Don't show your face here again.
Move it.
OP?
Ali the shit he left.
His message said Strasbourg.
God knows if he's still there.
He never called you?
Did you try the gym?
They have no idea.
If I had a number, I'd give it to you.
Even after all the crap he did.
You believe me?
I believe you.
Imagine!
He left his kid.
It all means jack shit to him.
You don't know him.
I don't?
What did you expect from him?
I don't know.
Not this.
Keep moving. Raise your arms.
Keep your arms up. Aim.
Any further and I can't back up.
You got a new truck?
I changed bosses.
Back to being exploited.
Ali.
Put on your coat.
Are things okay?
It's fine.
And Anna?
She's fine.
Working part-time in a school cafeteria.
She likes it.
- She knows about today?
- Sure.
Tell her I can't help now,
but once I have money...
Don't worry.
When's your fight?
- Next month, the 9th.
- Keep me posted.
Come on, Sam.
I'm handing over, Mr. Sam.
- My mittens.
- Give me a kiss.
Extraction.
I'll go deliver.
I'll pick him up at 7 tonight.
Seven p.m., okay?
I have to be back tomorrow by 11.
Don't worry.
Sam! Make a snowman!
Goodbye!
I'll get you some fries!
Okay.
I want to skate too.
They're skiing.
They were skating.
- Skiing, I said.
- Skating.
Skiing.
You're bugging me.
Faster?
I'll let go and you steer.
Start steering now!
Careful.
Get the sled.
Get on.
One, two, three, go!
One more.
Ten more minutes, okay?
Sam!
Sam.
Help!
Sam!
Sam.
Let's go take care of you.
Can you hold it?
Yeah, go on.
Yeah, he's better.
I'll put him on.
She wants to talk to you.
Is it Anna?
It's me.
Do you mind?
How is he?
He woke up an hour ago.
Is he hurt?
I don't think so.
How are you?
I busted my hands on the ice.
Bad?
They're fractured.
And you?
I'm okay.
What are you up to?
You mean now?
Or just in general?
- I wanted to say...
-You don't need to.
I'll let you go.
I'll call you back to see how Sam is.
- Give him a kiss.
- Don't hang up.
Don't hang up.
I won't hang up.
For three hours...
he was in a coma.
For three hours, he was dead.
I was afraid to lose him.
Don't leave me.
I won't
I love you.
Twenty-seven bones
in a human hand.
Certain monkeys have more.
Gorillas, 32.
Five in each thumb.
A man has 27.
You break a hand,
you break a leg...
after a while,
calcium joins it back together.
It ends up even
stronger than before.
But break a bone in your hand
and you'll see it never heals.
You'll remember it at each fight,
with every punch.
You'll be careful.
But one day...
the pain will comeback.
Like needles.
Like broken glass.
RUST AND BONE