Oh I'm very sorry, I didn't notice
It's been 20 years since we've had people
visit, but I hope you'll enjoy your stay.
I also noticed, you won't be
needing any help with luggage?
Can you sense her?
Saya-sama.
What happened?
Please take your father's sword.
I don't understand
This sword...
has the power to slay demons.
It is a blessing, and a curse.
You still have much to learn
However
We have no more time.
The demons have found us.
Kato
Wait here
And don't come out.
I told you not to follow.
But we need to stick together-
We mustn't.
Kato
There is no need, I must go alone.
You
Just what are you planning?
I must complete my mission.
You can't, Kato.
You cannot face the demons yet.
It is my task for now.
Now, go.
Why are you still standing there?.