The nightmare again?
Don't worry, don't worry.
Don't worry.
It'll soon be over.
Dad?
- Going already?
- Soon. Tod's not here yet.
Oh, don't go yet.
Here.
- Happy birthday, darling.
- But it's tomorrow.
Well, what's wrong with now?
Open it.
Oh, sorry I couldn't
find any pretty paper.
Oh, Dad.
It's beautiful.
It's the most precious
thing I can give you.
I'll treasure it.
No,no, no... Don't just treasure it.
It was meant to be worn.
It must be worth a fortune.
Supposing I'll lose it?
You won't.
Wear it always.
Wear it now.
Here.
Happy birthday, darling.
Thank you.
Hi.
Glad you could make it.
Shut your bloody row!
I sometimes wonder
why I took this job.
Well, we know that,
don't we?
Get him inside.
What about
a bit of fun?
Let's have a look at
old Snakey Berrigan.
My God, he hasn't been in the
jacket all night, has he?
Seem to have quietened him down;
he's not doing any of his crazy bits.
Perhaps he'll let up later,
when we get the harness off.
...stars... the Milky Way...
the Galaxy...
...pulsar...
Hello, cat.
When are you going to
let me speak to him?
- Who?
- Your father.
- Not now.
- Not now, what does that mean?
You don't feed him enough.
He should be gorged
and fat and purring.
Darling, there are areas of
research you can help me with.
Sometimes I think there are only
two things you want me for.
- You're absolutely right.
- Am I?
Yes. Absolutely.
You drink too much.
Madre mia.
I thought you'd never see it.
- When did you get it?
- Birthday present.
- From your father?
- What are you going to give me?
I've never seen anything
so beautiful.
He must have got it
on the expedition.
What do you know about it?
I don't know anything
about it.
Don't you want to know?
I'll ask him later.
It's the first time he's given anything
away about the expedition.
Anything in any meaning
of the word "giving."
No reports, no journals,
no findings—nothing.
Absolute secrecy.
Perhaps there was
nothing else to give.
You've never had anything else like it?
No other presents?
No.
All these years,
and now this ring.
It's unlike anything
I've ever seen before.
I know, we can find out
from a friend of mine. Okay?
Okay.
Be careful. He can
be dangerous.
I'll be close at hand.
Thank you, doctor.
Oh, come on, Berrigan,
you know what I want,
and it's in there,
isn't it?
Get your hands off me,
you maniac!
I'm afraid we
have to go, sir.
At once, please.
Okay, show us
your sarcophagus.
- Knock it off, Arthur.
- Yeah, that's what I mean.
Maybe later.
Promises, promises.
- Hello, love.
- Hello, Tod.
- Geoff about?
- Behind there.
Tod! I didn't
expect you today.
I wasn't planning on coming over
but there's something
I had to show you.
What do you make of that?
My God.
Where'd you get this?
- Whose is it?
- It's mine.
Isn't it lovely?
No!
Death is afar still.
He will have
no use of you yet.
There's hardship.
And strife.
But it's outweighed by the joy
of children's voices.
That's Teddy and Tricia,
my Ron's twins.
Are they coming home?
Oh, it's so hot. I shall
have to take this off.
Oh, what is it,
Miss Dickerson?
I can't go on.
The vibrations are wrong.
I shall have to ask you
to leave, Mrs. Caporal.
Next week, by all
means, we'll continue.
You saw something there
for me—you're afraid to tell me!
Get out now.
Take your coat with you.
It's so beautiful.
Fantastic how it
catches the light.
Can I have it back?
I should ring Geoffrey,
and see how he is.
He'll be fine.
The doctor said so.
Was it this
that frightened him?
I thought it was me.
Probably reminded him
of someone.
That's not much
of a compliment.
He's late.
He'll be here.
Go on, you can go.
You've fussed enough.
I can't just leave you.
Suppose he doesn't come?
He'll come.
You heard what the doctor said.
"You've got to expect these things
when you reach your age."
Go on with you.
Don't fuss.
All right, then.
Look after yourself.
Night.
I'm glad you've come.
I'm glad you wanted me to.
What happened?
- It was her.
- "Her?"
As large as life.
Standing over there.
And the ring.
She who has no name.
How could it had happened?
We'd have known.
That damn Fuchs'd
have needed to see.
And though he does believe
he'd do everything himself.
But it was her.
Well, don't you believe me?
Are you ready for this?
She is Margaret Fuchs.
- His daughter.
- What?
- It's impossible.
- And in a few hours' time,
it will be her birthday.
I, Tera,
Queen of Darkness,
Priestess of Ancient Egypt,
have lived before.
My spirit has never rested
through all these weary centuries.
My soul has wandered
among the boundless stars
while my mortal body waited.
Now, as the time draw nearer
to the predestined hour,
I have guided these people
towards my tomb,
made them the guardians
of my most sacred relics,
to protect with their lives,
until they are reclaimed.
That will be soon.
Soon.
Can you read it,
Professor Fuchs?
"She who is buried here,
shall henceforth have no name,
shall cease to exist
in the minds of man,
as she has ceased
to exist in life."
Look!
We do have her name.
Tera.
Mrs. Fuchs.
She's dead.
Doctor, quick!
Oh my God!
Look!
What is it, the nightmare?
I must get home.
- But darling, it's 3 AM.
- I don't care, I've got to go.
- But now?
- Yes, now.
Okay, okay,
I'll take you.
What kind of danger?
I don't know what, I just
feel that something's wrong.
Did you feel that?
Yes. Something seemed to—
Dad!
Out of the way, we'll
have to break it in.
But I've never been down there.
Nobody's allowed down there.
So we'll be the first.
Dad!
Oh, Dad.
How did it happen?
There's no one else here.
No other way in or out.
Doctor Putnum
has my instructions.
Call him.
He left instructions?
Did he expect this would happen?
Is this what you dreamt?
- Just call Putnum.
- All right.
Thank you, doctor.
Putnum's on his way.
Should we move him?
Yes. I'll take him
to his room.
Don't worry.
He'll be okay.
Do you want
the police involved?
Well, we have to report it.
And we must find out
what happened.
How it happened.
His instructions,
what were they?
That there should
be no police,
and that you and I should
make decisions on his behalf.
I see. Then he knew something
like this might happen.
You'll have to ask him
when he wakes.
He must tell you everything.
For his sake as well as yours.
Why can't you tell me?
Truly, I wish I could, but I've never
been allowed into his total confidence
beyond the odd
hint and suggestion.
But in those hints and suggestions,
something truly astounding.
At last he'll be able
to show the world of science,
just how little it knows.
I'll be back tomorrow, Margaret.
He should stay like this
for a few days.
If there's any change, call me.
He's my priority.
- Goodbye, Margaret.
- Goodbye.
Geoffrey.
Can you hear me?
Can you hear anything?
Father, what do I have to do?
What do I have to do?
Tod?
Don't be scared.
Do you remember, me?
It was rather a long time ago.
Tod!
Your father and I
were friends, and I've
come to help you,
as he can't.
Corbeck?
He said you were never
to be allowed in this house.
You need my help now, more
than anything else in this world.
Margaret?
- You've seen her?
- Yes.
And you're wearing the ring.
Do you know what it means, the ruby?
The symbol of
the god to come.
How much do you know?
Nothing.
Oh, he left you
in ignorance of all this?
It's a strange
and fantastic affair,
but it's not entirely
frightening if we know,
if we try to understand.
The idea of this
Queen of Darkness,
it obsessed your father
since he was a young man,
and he stumbled across,
uh, a veiled reference
to such a creature,
in a medieval tract on sorcery.
But she was buried a legend.
And she had no name.
And your father was determined
to find the truth, and...
...make his mark on
the world of Egyptology.
He dreamt of big things.
But he didn't know how big.
So then you assembled a team?
Yeah.
Yes, and began our search.
We found her tomb
in the valley of the sorcerer,
hidden, a secret,
for was a figure of great fear
to the priests, of her time,
who killed her.
I think your father must
have been driven by some...
...occult knowledge that even he
was unaware he possessed.
It was his destiny.
And what then?
Then?
Horror. Wonder.
There was an attack
on one of our bearers,
and at that moment,
horrifyingly,
fresh blood was released
in her veins.
How could this be?
How could she be
so perfectly preserved?
And you?
Born exactly at the moment that
your father first looked on her.
Born in her image.
Born as we spoke her name,
which the priests
hadn't entirely obliterated.
Tera.
Thought I heard
you call me.
Yes, I... I did.
We have a visitor.
Corbeck.
Friend to the family.
Julian called me and
asked me to come over.
Tod Browning.
- Suppose you heard all that.
- I did. Some of it.
Must have sounded
insane to you.
I have studied areas of
parapsychology, ESP, et al.
Oh yes, parapsychology,
the paranormal plane.
Telekinesis the
modern approach.
She has some kind of
power, that's obvious.
Good. I'm glad we
don't have to convince you.
- I'd like to see her.
- Her power is astral,
latent, able to be tapped in a way
that I do not comprehend,
and neither does Julian.
But we must understand,
or it will be directed against us
as it was against Julian.
And that gives us
an important first task.
And what's that?
Margaret, you must contact
all the old members of our team,
who bare your father
and I no love.
Geoffrey Dandridge is
one of them, isn't he?
Yes.
He's a friend of mine, but
he's never once mentioned this.
Geoffrey always preferred
to forget as much as possible
about the entire affair.
He was a superstitious man.
He was also a scientist.
But, as you say, most things
begin with superstition.
We can start with him.
If you wish.
What can these people
do to help us?
Not us. Tera.
They can help reunite her
with her soul.
- Hello?
- Tod here, Geoffrey, how are you?
Oh, I'm fine now, Tod,
but very busy.
It's about Julian Fuchs.
That was his daughter,
Maragret...
- I won't have anything to do with it.
- I know why you were frightened.
Jesus, he's scared.
Then we shall start with Berrigan.
We thought Mr. Berrgain's
family were all dead.
And now you're his second
visitor in the last few days.
- Another visitor?
- Mm.
- Who was he, doctor?
- Oh, I've no idea.
But you know, since that time,
he's been like a man possessed.
What does he do
with his time?
Every waking hour,
poring over his books.
Ordering more.
Always writing.
As if time
were running out.
I think his fantasy world
is dominated by the presence of...
...some demoniac being.
He fights against the clock
to try to understand,
to bring some... order
in the world he's created himself.
I see.
There's no way for us
to break through to him,
and so, you see,
we can't help him.
Now...
I hope this won't disturb you.
...then came the executioners.
- And they put the sun screws on me.
- Thank you, doctor.
Her blood poured
out of the nails.
Everywhere.
I couldn't use my hands
for four weeks.
T-th-tha—this is...
I'm not ready yet.
There's more to do.
Please don't be frightened.
Try to listen and understand.
If he thinks I'm Tera, then...
You know who I am?
Yes.
And you're afraid,
aren't you?
You're here to kill me.
You've been waiting all these
years, torturing me,
and now that I'm close to
the answer, you come for me?
I don't wish to kill anybody.
I just want what's mine.
My familiar.
The snake.
Yes. You're powerless
without it.
I haven't got it.
No, no, don't, no!
No, no, no!
No, no...
Not this way.
But I think it's something to tell the
doctor and have him get it for us.
No!
There's another way.
- ...no, leave me alone...
- Restrain him.
Hello, Margaret.
- How is he?
- Oh, he's fine.
His neck's healing very well.
The danger has passed.
Blood pressure's normal.
But there is a slight
sign of paralysis.
On the left hand side.
So be prepared.
Have you and Mr. Browning
discovered anything of any value?
No, it's all up to my father.
Yes, of course, he knows,
but he was too scared.
Never knew what kind of Pandora's Box
he might have down there.
Wanted to keep you out of it,
so that you'd be safe.
Seems like I've been involved
all my life, doesn't it?
Maybe even longer.
Good night, doctor.
- Your father's journal.
- What does it say?
Your mother died
as you were born.
I know. She died
giving me life.
No, not exactly.
What, then?
Your father and the others found
the tomb, were in the tomb,
at the exact moment
of your birth in London.
These two events were
more than a coincidence.
They were a unity. And he says
she created this unity.
He says here: She achieved
dominance over sleep,
over the will.
She would lie as if dead
in her sarcophagus,
as though willing her body,
as though preparing for some
abstract metaphysical state.
An astral body
with a free will.
A conscious intelligence.
We can keep people frozen
in suspended animation.
People with cancer,
waiting for a cure.
Their bodies idling
like a machine.
Not dead, not alive.
Waiting.
Non-life. But waiting.
I get a feeling
of great loneliness.
Of her dreaming alone.
Dreaming of things far different
from those around her.
A land far away
in miles and years,
yet close to her heart.
No scheming and
malignant priesthood.
No repressive archaic laws
or endless rituals of death.
A land where love is the divine
possession of the soul.
That'll be the day.
Don't laugh, Tod.
I can feel it in my heart.
See it with my sleeping eyes.
Perhaps it was her dream
to make it come true.
Yeah. Perhaps you're right.
Let's go.
Does old Snakey want
his little pet, then?
This really is something.
Old Snakey found it
in Egypt, didn't he?
I wonder why it makes him
feel better seeing it.
Only Snakey knows.
And he's not telling, is he?
Must be a reason.
He's crazy, that's the reason.
Now, no more of your
screaming, okay?
'Cause no one's gonna
take a blind bit of notice.
- Okay, that's it.
- Must be worth a fortune.
Must it?
Only if you're crazy.
Oh, dear.
The dawn chorus has started.
Well... Now it's your turn
to make me laugh.
No!
It's—it's coming!
It's coming!
The snake!
Let me out!
I don't wanna die!
Let me out, oh!
Margaret.
Margaret?
Dad!
Oh Dad, are you
really all right?
- What time is it?
- No, try and lie still.
My... my whole side...
Dr. Putnum thought
this might happen.
What's become of me?
You've had a terrible shock.
Try and remember.
I'd been out with Tod,
and when we came back,
we found you in the cellar.
You're safe. Oh, I was sure
you would be.
Is that why you gave me the ring?
To protect me?
Tell me.
It belonged to Tera,
didn't it?
- You know?
- Everything you have belongs to her.
But...
How could it protect me?
The priests of her time
cut the hand from her.
Not only did it symbolize
what they believed was her evil,
they also thought
that with her body incomplete
her power would be destroyed.
Evidently, it wasn't that simple.
Then this ring was on that hand.
A talisman for you.
I have given you so little.
To protect me?
Or give me her power?
You've got to
tell me everything.
Look, Berrigan's dead. Somehow the
snake he had was transferred here.
How could it...
so soon?
- Listen, Corbeck's been telling me—
- Corbeck?
Yes.
- You called him.
- Lies are all he'll ever tell you.
He is never to come here.
He is not to be involved.
Not now.
Trust me. Wait until
the time is right.
Don't have anything
to do with Corbeck.
This ring, if we have it,
where's the hand?
Promise me.
Berrigan's dead.
But you knew that.
And we have the snake.
But you knew that too.
But you found me.
I didn't know
you'd do that. I'm glad.
My father's recovering.
He can talk.
- He told you?
- Yes.
- Everything?
And don't tell me
he lied.
Delusions, theories...
He doesn't know the truth.
But what you call
the truth is lies.
- For your sake.
- That's what he said.
You're both trying to use me,
but you don't care about
what might happen to me.
And what you say is all lies.
Well, not any longer.
I'm important to this affair.
Born in her image.
I don't know how or why, but
you need me, I do know that.
This force may have us trapped,
but it fascinates me.
It's part of me.
Your father believes that
Tera is a force of evil.
And he spent these years trying
to find the root of that force,
while trying to keep
the evil bottled up.
And you want
to let it loose?
I don't accept it
as a concept.
Then what do you accept?
See, Tera is far beyond the laws
and dogma of her times.
And of ours.
Beyond good and evil?
Love. Hate.
She's a law compelling
beyond good and evil,
and if we can find out how far
beyond, how much we can learn.
But why do we need the relics?
I think you know why.
You feel it.
- Resurrection.
- Yes.
A rebirth for Tera.
For her knowledge.
For her ideas.
And for us?
Complete control.
Over life, over death.
Secrets hidden.
Obscured.
Unguessed at for ages.
With our hands
to use as we will.
And my father?
- We cannot afford the weak.
- What do you mean?
He has no real courage,
no real strength,
only a cheap,
intellectual conceit.
- But all his years of study...
- He's been afraid.
That's why he wanted nothing to with me,
and that is why he filled Berrigan
and all the others
with the fear of God.
Well, the meek shall
not inherit the earth.
They wouldn't know
what to do with it.
Can we afford
to let him be part?
To let them control it?
Are you going to go on
allowing them to use you?
- No.
- Good.
Well, then together, we will share
whatever we contrive to make.
Tell me... What would you do
to possess it all?
Anything.
Well, then, together
we will do everything.
Not yet.
There's still some
shopping to do.
Dandridge annd Dickerson.
Oh, not now, Tod,
I'm busy.
What do you mean, busy? We're
going to see Geoffrey, aren't we?
It's not a good idea.
Look what happened last time.
Seeing me again
might kill him.
Yes, well,
go on home, then.
Look, Dad's nearly recovered,
you can talk to him tomorrow,
but just don't bother me now.
- What do you mean?
- I'm in no danger.
Oh, let me alone.
My turn to surprise you.
This is your house?
It has some rather interesting
views. I am considering buying it,
but I may change my mind,
it all rather depends on...
...circumstances.
Do I need to
ask you to leave?
What are you
doing to Margaret?
Why, what's she
doing to you?
Just tell me
where she is.
Shopping.
It's ten to six,
Mr. Dandridge.
Mr. Dandridge?
Then you'd better go now.
- Or you'll find the shops all shut.
- All right, then.
But you won't work
too late, will you?
Will you?
You're fussing.
All right, then,
take care.
Oh wait, I forgot to show you this.
You didn't know, did you?
One of your colleagues died.
Mr. Berrigan.
Berrigan?
Didn't think you knew.
Night.
My God.
Corbeck?
Tod, is that you?
Veronica?
Who are you?
Are you feeling better now?
You have a relic
from the tomb.
The Skull of
the Sacred Jackal.
We want it.
You killed Berrigan.
You and your father.
He was afraid he'd die
if he gave it up.
Is that what you think?
Supposing you die
if you keep it?
Had you thought of that?
We want it, Mr. Dandridge!
What the hell
are you doing here?
I changed my mind.
You seemed determined
that we should see Geoffrey.
Corbeck said
you were shopping.
Did he?
What are you two up to in there?
Where's Geoffrey?
He's not there.
Come on, Tod.
No. I want
to look around.
If you must. But you'll
be wasting your time.
Geoff?
Look!
I know.
Margaret?
Margaret, where are you?
You two'd better not know
what the hell you've been doing.
Margaret, I hope
to God you don't.
But it's ended. We're getting
out of this, all of us.
This is something
precious and fantastic.
Two people have died because of
what you've been dabbling with.
- It could kill you.
- No!
- Or you.
- Like smoking, or driving cars.
You are insane.
- And you're going crazy, c'mon.
- Let me go!
Come on, before
it's too late!
- Where are you going?
- To get help.
- And who can you get to help you?
- Help for you.
Tod, don't!
Or you're dead!
Tod!
- He'd have died anyway.
- But I wished him dead!
Don't fight it.
Let it flow through you.
Let it be yours.
Look at the ring.
When I saw you wearing it
I knew the time was near, or else
he wouldn't have given it to you.
The stars shift their relative
position in the heavens.
Through enormous distances.
But they appear small.
They are measured by centuries,
not by years.
But they do not correspond to
their position in the constellation
as it was when she was alive.
They are in the position
that they are in now. Tonight.
- She chose it.
- So you must not weaken.
You were born for this.
You are coming of age.
Margaret.
What have you done to her?
She's alright.
- She needs help.
- She doesn't exist.
She's a pawn,
an instrument, a vessel.
- No!
- Oh, let's face it.
When tonight is over, she will
be dead, and Tera will live.
- It is tonight, isn't it?
- No, no...
I won't go through with it.
Not now.
All you've done is lock yourself
in here and play games.
"How clever I am."
"How is it possible? Wouldn't it
be fun if it were all true?"
Well, it is true.
Undeniably so.
And you?
You are scared.
Every waking moment,
you are scared.
And she's made you see,
hasn't she?
See your conceits.
See your games.
Tera has given you a warning.
"Don't let me down.
Don't try and back out,
or you are dead."
You know what
you've got to do.
And you know that
there's no help for her.
Yes.
Then I'll just go
and bring some things,
and then I think we'll be
almost ready for her, won't we?
The one last relic.
The third phase of her soul.
Without it, we can
stop this nightmare.
Unless it's all too late?
Tod!
Do it.
Using her as a guinea pig?
As an experiment?
Put her out.
She mustn't awake.
Mustn't be conscious.
Do it.
Time is just a moment
out of space.
What are the dead
but memory?
And when the memory dies...
There are mighty things,
but life itself is mightier.
Life itself is...
Get back to bed, Margaret.
I'm going to give you something
to help you sleep for a while.
Useless.
But you're not well, Margaret.
You need to rest.
I've been sleeping too long.
Julian!
Afraid?
I'm only trying to help you.
Why should I be afraid?
Because I want
to see you die!
Putnum!
No...
What are you going to
do with the body, Julian?
You have an incinerator.
It takes longer, but it's safer.
You see, I'm not even going
to ask you why you killed him.
Now, then, let me
give you a hand.
But you've done enough
to ruin everything.
You've sat and studied, brooded,
and watched and done nothing.
But I've searched,
I've traveled the world.
I've come to
the age of understanding.
I have recovered
the Scroll of Life.
Soon the moment will be here.
Tera will be reborn.
- But you don't understand...
- I understand everything.
That you  need me,
that we need Margaret,
and that only I
can control her.
No, not anymore.
It's out of our hands.
- Tera's in control.
- We control Tera.
We give her life.
Without us she's dust and ashes.
Now, then.
Where is Margaret?
She killed Putnum,
and ran out.
God only knows where.
We know where,
don't we?
Answer it.
Help me.
I'm...
Margaret Fuchs.
Gunther.
Must be his daughter.
Margaret?
No! It's happened!
You have to help me.
You know its power.
I have no mind left.
No will.
I'll face you!
I won't run!
She can live or die,
I'll be safe.
You'll be safe
if you give it to me.
Yes, I'll get you.
Only don't make it kill me.
Please.
Don't!
Yes, that's it,
give it to me.
No!
No, don't!
No, don't! Don't!
No, no! Don't!
Come.
We must go.
The Scroll of Life.
No! No, don't read the scroll.
Destroy it!
It can only bring
evil and destruction.
The worst that's in you.
The worst that's in all of us.
That's all we've seen
from this business.
But it's not what Tera wants.
You've abused the power
she's given you, thanks to him.
Do it my way.
Wait and watch,
with patience and trust.
Wait until she is ready.
She is ready now.
All but the lamps.
No...
Not like this.
You can't only have good things,
beautiful things, holy things.
They're worthless
without their opposites.
Get the lamps.
No.
The lamps.
Celestial Osiris,
Isis and Horus,
this before us is
a child of the gods,
a being of majesty
and might.
Her astral spirit wanders
the cold places and dark,
seeking reunion with her soul,
with her body,
so that she may rise,
as is the privilege and
destiny of the gods,
so that she may
walk again on this earth.
Let life flow again
in this body,
let the soul rejoin it,
let the astral spirit
be rekindled.
Osiris, Isis, Horus...
What use is this
if we're to die?
Instruments of her will,
using all of us.
You didn't find her.
She found you and
led you to the tomb.
Made you devote yourself
to her.
And the others? Just guarding
the relics with their lives?
More chances for her
to be reborn.
Once she regains her place
usurped by the priests.
We're as meaningless
as all the dead.
These thousands of years.
But, Margaret, you died
when your mother died.
And suddenly,
you were alive.
She is you!
- He mustn't finish the scroll.
- Osiris, Isis, Horus,
I command thee, gods of
the upper and lower worlds...
The scroll.
Help me!
Help me...
- Is there no information?
- Nothing.
She's the same as she was
when they brought her in.
Naked and more dead
than alive.
- No relatives, no visitors?
- None.
They say all the others were
crushed beyond recognition.
She's the only one who
can tell us who she is.