If something gets bathed in the moonlight,
it becomes a myth.
That means our story will become a myth.
(The Bride of Habaek)
(Episode 15)
Well, we're being really
romantic right now, you know.
But why is it that I keep
thinking about that thing?
About what?
The seafood noodles I
told you about earlier.
I keep ruining the mood
by thinking about how...
there were 12 clams in the bowl of noodles.
My mom and dad kept arguing
even at the restaurant.
I was on pins and needles,
so I kept counting the clams
in the bowl of noodles.
There were 12 of them.
"There are so many of them."
"Dad, there are 12 clams in this."
I wanted to say that,
but my mom kept throwing
a fit at my dad nonstop.
What was so important?
My dad said nothing and just kept quiet.
That got her even more exasperated,
so she said whatever that came to her mind.
I kept counting the clams over and over.
No matter how many times I
counted, there were 12 of them.
What do you think...
was so important to my dad?
You said you're a deity.
Then grant me a wish.
Let me meet my dad.
I want to ask him why he had to
dump all of these burdens on me...
and if he's been able to sleep at night...
and eat since leaving like that.
I want to tell him to
take them all from me.
He couldn't even save his own daughter.
How is he going to save the world?
If I could ask him that question,
I'd have nothing more to wish for.
- Have you tried to look for him?
- No, I haven't.
What if I do and find him here in Korea?
If he never visited us even though
he's been here the whole time...
Then what should I do?
How do you feel now?
Is that really your wish?
Meeting your dad and telling him
what you've wanted to say to him.
I think so.
What is it?
Nothing.
This is nice.
What's nice?
Do you know why people get married?
It's because they don't want to part
after a whole day of fun together.
But we live together, so we
don't have to part ways.
Living together is a good thing.
Is there a marriage system
in the world of deities?
I can say that there is. But then
again, I can say there isn't.
What does that mean?
You can get married if you want to,
but it's neither exclusive, nor
does it have any binding power.
What? Come again? If that's the case,
can both parties cheat on each
other whenever they want to?
It's very freewheeling.
That's why people are not sure
who Lady Yuhwa's mother is.
Who is Lady Yuhwa?
Your daughter.
Ju Mong's mother and King
Yuri's maternal grandmother.
You're King Yuri's maternal
grandfather, so she's your wife.
- I've never been married.
- Whatever.
Don't even try to pretend.
You look like you're sulking.
- What did you just say?
- Give me a glass of water.
Well, why do laws and systems exist?
Their power comes from
their legal binding force.
What? Freewheeling?
Gosh, is it like "Animal Kingdom" or what?
Is it because they're all Mr.
And Ms. Nature?
By any chance,
is polygamy practiced in
the world of deities?
How did you know?
Even some deities have many husbands.
- Are you serious?
- Isn't it obvious?
We neither grow old nor die.
How can we be expected to be
faithful to only one person?
What's the matter?
Then in your case...
How many times have you been married?
- I've never been married.
- Then what about Lady Yuhwa...
Come to your senses, woman.
Get me another glass of water.
One more glass.
Hey, what are you doing now?
Can't you see?
I don't want to go to bed.
What?
If you don't want to go to bed,
what do you want to do?
Soo Ri is working all night tonight.
Just tonight.
- So?
- So...
I'd like to...
I'd like to watch some TV with you.
- TV?
- Sit down.
He looks unfamiliar.
He's new.
Introduce him to me. Who is he?
Come here.
- Have we met?
- No.
- So Ah.
- Yes?
What makes you do this?
- I read your diary.
- What?
What did you say?
Not everyone gets to lie on my lap.
Why would you read someone else's diary?
I thought it was written for me...
20 years ago.
What?
I read a poem you wrote
when you were little.
It's titled, "Daddy's Lap".
"Daddy's lap is mine."
"Go away, Sang Yu."
"Curse you, Sang Yu." Do
you call that a poem?
You said you were an amazing
poet when you were little.
Isn't there a rerun of "The Divine Dinner"?
Hey, I know what you're thinking.
If I had your ability,
I'd take charge of cooking
until the day I leave.
When are you leaving?
A message will come.
It could come even tomorrow, right?
Our relationship is time-limited.
When I was an intern,
I'd meet patients with a terminal
disease and their families.
And I'd feel guilty for some reason.
How would I actually know
how they were feeling?
I just tried to comfort them...
the way I was taught to.
In fact, I had no idea what was
going through their minds.
It might have been a better
idea to just cry with them.
I'd pour out irresponsible words instead.
Still, I learned something.
I got to see people
preparing for goodbyes...
and what gets left after those goodbyes.
For the rest of the
family or for themselves,
they would find a reason why
they should not wither away.
Their wandering minds...
would find a place to stay in the end.
Can I ask you something?
What about you?
How do you cope?
I have at most 40 to 50 years left.
But your life never ends.
Can I...
be greedy?
Can I ask you to remember me...
as long as you can?
What are you doing?
You're up.
I woke up early, and I
had nothing else to do.
There was a rerun of "The Divine Dinner".
And?
And what?
Come on.
Are you making breakfast for me?
I found a guy who makes breakfast for me.
It's just that I'm hungry.
I see.
Then I'll go back to sleep.
I don't usually eat breakfast.
Sit down.
My stomach feels heavy if I have breakfast.
I'll wash myself first...
to pay my respect to the meal.
He's so cute, but I can't tell him.
He'd get furious.
Should I just try?
What if he transforms or something?
This is too much for breakfast.
Who would eat all this?
- Do you know what garbage...
- Just say you're happy.
That'd be simpler.
Have a seat.
Let's eat.
You can start.
So this is how it feels...
when someone cooks for you.
Eat.
Let's eat.
I locked the door, but I
couldn't find any pot.
He came to give me the keys.
He couldn't find any pot.
I had to think a lot.
You'd be away from your clinic for a while.
I couldn't decide whether I should
have them delivered to you...
or ask you to meet me.
- You can't do that.
- I know.
That's why I came here.
- Would you like some tea?
- It's too early for tea.
There is no such rule.
In my house, there is.
We don't drink tea in the morning here.
We have breakfast instead.
If you haven't eaten, have some breakfast.
- Mr. Shin is very busy...
- I wouldn't mind.
Gosh.
Ms. Yoon, you're a good cook.
I made it.
She didn't do anything.
I made everything.
- I see.
- You probably don't know.
She's a terrible cook.
She can sleep anywhere too.
She falls asleep right away.
That's why I always have to...
carry her to her bed.
She's such a handful.
There's more. She can't even
turn on the light at the door.
That's why I always turn it on for her.
Also, she rarely cleans.
That's why I clean her place for her.
I take a warm bath every morning.
It doesn't suit her,
but she gets so shy...
whenever she sees me naked.
Hey, look.
Am I wrong?
You said you just can't get used to it.
- Hey, please.
- Am I wrong?
Did you say you just never get sick of it?
Let's eat.
Since you two live together,
you know a lot about each other.
Oh, right. Ms. Yoon.
The new owner of the
building your clinic is in.
It's me.
Are you serious?
Is it... Is it really true?
Is that why we got our
rent and deposit lowered?
I told you...
that I'd just buy the building itself.
I told you that I have a lot of money.
A building owner...
Thank you so much.
I'm hugely indebted you.
Not at all.
I did it for all tenants of my building.
It seems that Chairman
Shin has been too greedy,
and they've suffered a lot because of it.
Thank you very much.
- I'm so relieved now.
- Please don't mention it.
I should be a good landlord.
You're already such a wonderful landlord...
I'm a king!
I am...
a king.
I like how the house shows traces of time.
I was born in this house.
Half of it is owned by the bank now though.
It's all right.
It's okay.
Please stay still.
- Ms. Yoon.
- Yes?
Are you sure we never met in the past?
Yes, as far as I remember.
Then why do I keep...
How dare you try to pull a trick?
Have a seat.
In my house, we drink tea after each meal.
That's the rule here.
Make some tea for us.
What is this?
He's trying hard to look
patriarchal, but it's so awkward.
What an astral sight.
A water deity who's the
king of all deities...
and a half-human-half-deity.
Why did he get changed?
I want it in my mug.
I have my own mug. I call it Yong Yong.
A master and his servant
are both drawn on it.
The design is very artistic.
I worked a part-time gig...
and bought it for her.
I want this in my mug.
Well, you should just
drink it in this today.
I'll do that if that's what you want.
I should go wash the dishes.
You two look lovely together.
Then why are you here?
The key?
That childish trick of yours
won't even make me blink.
Even if you can't outdo your contender,
he may reveal his shortcomings
if you keep jabbing him.
Like I've told you,
waiting is what I'm best at.
You'll spend the rest of your
life realizing how futile...
that waiting is.
And you'll think that this
lifetime of yours is an epic fail.
I envy that confidence of yours.
I'm a king.
Ms. Yoon told me that I shouldn't be...
intimidated by others' backgrounds.
That's pointless.
Anyhow, time is on my side.
And come to think of it,
money is on my side too.
- I'm a king.
- I'm a building owner.
What would be more powerful
between money and a king here?
- Shall we see?
- What?
- Ms. Yoon.
- Yes?
You've forgotten about the shift
at the farm in two days, right?
I'm sorry.
This isn't good.
We are friends, but we
also have a contract.
I'm really sorry. I've
been all over the place.
Well... You'll leave in
the afternoon, right?
- Then I'll also...
- Where do you think you're going?
I don't know what this is about,
but you can't take her no matter what.
She's indebted to me.
When she broke the contract for the land,
she agreed to pay the penalty.
She must earn money and pay me back...
in order to fulfill her
obligations and end the contract.
I'll see you that day.
It's because you didn't
allow me to sell the land.
Give me some money.
My servant didn't sell her
land to the halfie...
and have to pay him a penalty.
She owes him money because of us, so...
What a joke.
It looks like that was
Ha Baek on the phone.
It looks like Mr. Shin is doing a good job.
He's doing what the coach told him to do.
I don't want to hear that name yet.
Try not to bring him up.
No, I'll keep talking about
him until you get sick of it.
What is this about?
I heard that women dream
of having breakfast...
made by men they love.
Only foolish human women
would dream of such a thing.
Try to think like a human
for a few minutes, then.
Shouldn't it be with the man I love though?
How many more steps do I have to take?
50 or 100?
Will I be able to get there?
Get out. I'm going to take a shower.
All right, then.
She's the most difficult
woman to deal with.
I know that, of course.
Ha Baek.
Not today.
My schedule is fully packed.
I'll call you.
When I return to the world of deities,
I'll be sure to turn one
of you into a saury...
and the other one into a sparrow.
Yes, My Lord.
Money. Are you earning a lot of it?
Pardon me? Yes.
My duck boat is swamped with customers now.
Oh, right. Lord Joo Dong called.
What? Where is he?
- Why isn't he coming back?
- He'd be back soon.
He said you shouldn't go
anywhere and wait for him.
But why did he call you?
He could've called me.
He said Lord Moo Ra told
him not to call you...
because you keep asking for money.
How dare she.
He is...
the one who saved me.
He saved me. But...
What?
What are you talking about now?
What was that about?
"He saved me." That was all good.
But she said, "But".
That's what keeps bothering me.
I'm sorry I'm a bit late.
My co-worker who has the shift
after mine was late for work.
- Mr. Nam.
- Yes?
I keep having the same dream,
and I can't ignore it.
I never hear the most important part.
Is there anything I can do?
I... I don't know.
Why? Gosh!
Hey, what's up?
Is everything all right with you?
What's this about?
It sounds like you want something to be up.
My friend, you've become bitter
after a bad relationship.
My relationship wasn't bad.
Then there must be something
wrong with your dating style.
You love in order to say goodbye?
Some people say they break up
even though they love each other.
But no one loves in order to break up.
You left out "properly".
It's to break up properly.
- Hang up.
- Hold on.
How is he doing, your
boyfriend who saved you?
Who is in such a ridiculous relationship?
You know it won't work. Why
are you trying so hard?
So when you borrow money, you pay interest?
I'll pay you a lot of interest
when I'm back in Land of Water.
No one needs money in the world of deities.
I'm not talking about money.
Tell me if you need anything.
Can you even give up the throne for me?
It's not like I want that.
I might not like you, but I don't
want that kind of tragedy.
I'd like you to be around for a long time.
Is that a no?
I could give you anything,
be it money or diamonds.
But Moo Ra doesn't like that.
I listen to my girl.
On the internet,
people call someone like you a pushover.
I don't have a problem with that.
I'm leaving.
Hold on.
- I have something to tell you too.
- What is it?
What is it?
What is Moo Ra like?
Did you meet Ha Baek?
Did you attack his weakest part?
It's not like that.
Good. Show him how superior you are...
and how weak he is.
Do you mean that?
I can't send him like this.
He has to become a wreck.
By the time he leaves,
he has to become a total wreck.
You guys are so extreme.
Moo Ra is the most loyal one among us...
as you may already know.
But once she turns her back
on someone, it's the end.
Then why did you do that?
I'm an exception.
Moo Ra and I are beyond that.
I came to the wrong person.
You don't know Moo Ra well.
You want to know what she
really thinks, right?
You're amazing.
You don't know anything,
yet you know everything.
You know everything, yet
you don't know anything.
That's how I'm different from you guys.
Fine, you're right.
You're so elusive.
No one can ever know how far you can go.
If you pay me,
I'll give you advice.
Heartless punks. Are they serious?
Where are you going?
I'm going to pay the cancellation fee.
I told you not to.
I'm sorry.
He insisted on tagging along.
He's a good worker.
I don't know everything
about the world of deities,
but considering what I've
heard about Ha Baek,
this is unbelievable.
I can see why Hye Ra is so bothered.
He wants to pay the
cancellation fee that way.
I've told him I get paid for my
daily work, but he doesn't care.
Maybe he doesn't understand
the concept of daily pay.
If he doesn't, I could explain to him.
But he does.
Apparently, he read about a case
of a chairman on the internet.
A human chairman got paid
500,000 dollars a day.
As the emperor of deities, my
worth would be immeasurable.
But I'll give him the
honor of measuring it.
Let's go.
So how much does the king
think his work is worth?
50 million dollars.
50 million dollars?
He wants you to pay him the amount
minus the cancellation fee.
50 million dollars?
You seem to now understand
the power of money.
Your strategy was clumsy though.
Do you think if So Ah had enough money,
I wouldn't have a chance?
Regardless of money, you'll never
have a place in her heart.
You know too little about her.
You think so?
Let me tell you what you don't know.
I doubt there is anything.
There is.
It's something you don't
know because you're a deity.
I know it because I'm a human.
What?
Humans...
are lonely from the moment they're born.
Jin Geon. What is it?
Someone came by.
- Who?
- He left something for you.
- What is it?
- Give me your hand.
All right. Thank you.
This will be planted somewhere else.
- Let me help you.
- It's okay.
Go to him.
It's okay. He's not a kid.
Deities in Land of Water would
be shocked to hear that.
A kid?
I'm really curious.
Is he such a big deal?
I don't know.
The cave was my whole world.
But when Joo Geol Lin told me
about the world of deities,
half of it was about Ha Baek.
Locked up in the cave, I thought of
Ha Baek as the deity of deities.
The deity of deities?
Not all deities have the same powers.
Some powers are allowed
to only certain deities.
Ha Baek could do everything.
He was born to be king.
But there are two things
even Ha Baek can't do.
He can't revive the dead.
Also,
he doesn't have the ability I have.
Still, Ha Baek isn't
intimidated by me at all.
To be honest, I liked that about him.
By the way, are you really okay?
He could go back even tomorrow.
He might be gone when you wake up.
He's back so that I can
go on living my life...
even if that happens.
Are you done?
Yes.
50 million dollars. Tell them
that I'm giving them a discount.
Give it to me.
What are you doing? That's so unlike you.
Why is it unlike me?
You still have a lot to learn.
Shall I show you the vast scope
of my chameleon-like charms?
Don't.
Don't do that.
Hold tightly onto your chest so
that your heart doesn't explode.
I said, don't do it.
Gosh, seriously.
I told you not to do it.
How do you feel?
Isn't your heart racing?
Browsing on the internet...
taught me that human women call this sexy.
Oh, boy.
Bend your head down, please.
Why did you do that all of a sudden?
- Is your heart okay?
- My heart is totally fine,
but my four limbs are
cringing so badly right now.
Come here. Let's have
you sit on that chair.
Why do you keep acting
out of character today?
Isn't it like how you...
peeked at me from the back in
front of the house that day?
What?
You said you have 40 to
50 years left to live.
Then you should have...
more memories of me...
so that you won't run out of them.
You're so good at saying
things like that nonchalantly.
I'm not saying it because I don't care.
You know that I'm selfish, right?
I'm telling you this because I'm selfish.
Try your best...
to not be lonely...
for as long as you can.
I will...
remember you for a long time.
Are you mad that he didn't
pay you 50 million dollars?
He promised you that he'd pay
you 5,000 dollars a day.
You should work there every single day.
If you work 10 days,
you'd make enough to pay off the penalty.
If the two of us earn money together...
That actually sounded so funny.
Let's go back there
tomorrow and the day after.
The two of us should go there every day.
Let's work together.
Let's stay together.
All right.
Where have you been?
Why do you look like that?
Why are you here?
I have good news for you.
Congratulations.
Oh, I got this made according
to the customs here.
Such formality does matter, you know.
I even picked my dress
according to this color.
I figured I should make this much effort...
when I deliver this kind of news to you.
The messenger must've been busy.
He left without even delivering
this to you in person.
The sixth red tide has come,
so please get ready, Lord Ha Baek.
The details are inside.
I kept them simple...
and wrote them in big letters so
that you can read them easily.
I'm off.
Let me say this just in case.
You know what will happen...
if you choose not to go back, right?
Let's go in.
Come on.
Let's eat something. I'm hungry.
Come and eat.
You actually look pretty
dashing even from behind.
Come on.
It's not like you didn't know.
Why do you look so sad?
They're not asking you to return tomorrow.
Why do you never tell me...
not to leave even if you don't mean it?
Why is that?
Will you not go back if
I ask you not to leave?
No.
I can't do that.
See? Exactly.
Don't sound me out like that.
I'm not the kind of woman
who holds men back.
I'll tell you why I'm not stopping you.
Think about it.
You're only cool because
you're the king of deities.
You'd be nothing here if you
weren't the king and had no power.
You'd just be a jobless person
who likes taking a warm bath.
You don't like working, and you're
only interested in driving cars.
I'd have to earn money
and take care of you.
Don't watch those kinds of movies
where the main characters...
fall in love and say they
don't care about money.
If a man acts that way, they'll
get abandoned by their lady.
My goodness.
My gosh, how is he going to be a king...
with such a sensitive heart?
Lord Ha Baek.
- I'm home.
- Why did you come so late?
There are so many places I can work
at, now that I have an ID card.
The 24-hour barbecue place
asked me to work there today.
In the morning, I worked
part-time by the river...
- Stop working part-time.
- Pardon?
I've received a message.
Then does that mean we're
really going to go back?
Notify that you're going to
stop working part-time...
so that the same thing won't happen again.
Okay.
Are you that happy?
You should've seen the look on his face.
I thought the skies were
going to fall down.
Ha Baek really must've
gotten on your bad side.
I even thought about not telling
him about the message...
so that he'll be able to
just stay here forever.
That's a bit too harsh, even if
you only said that out of anger.
Ha Baek will die if he
doesn't become the king.
Will you be able to live without him?
Ha Baek knows that too. That's why
he's not hesitating on going back.
So just cut him some slack.
You're so annoying.
Who do you like more? Me or Ha Baek?
(Please be mine, Hye Ra.)
Tell me. Who do you like more?
You...
What?
Me? Not Ha Baek?
Yes, I'm talking to you.
- What's that?
- What?
(Please be mine, Hye Ra.)
This?
- It's a gift from your fans.
- What?
I heard you got angry at your fans
and told them not to give you gifts.
I heard they're too scared of
you to give their gifts to you.
Well, yes.
But they apparently keep sending you gifts,
and Mr. Kim didn't know
what to do about them.
So I told him to give them to me.
I like anything that has your face on it.
(I'll protect you, Hye Ra.)
By the way, about that
gift box in your room...
Yes, that one. I ate some
snacks from that box.
Okay, good job.
But why do you have that?
What? Well...
I told Mr. Kim to throw everything away.
He must've put it back here again.
What would he know?
You're a deity, so you don't
need the love of human beings.
These pair of socks would
only feel like a joke to you.
You even look down on my diamond gifts.
Aren't I right?
Right.
These kind of things are
just for lowly human beings.
There. I'll take it.
I like it because it has your face on it.
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Do you want to go with me?
This is where...
I had made a foolish mistake.
It was 11:35pm at December 20, 2004.
I even remember the exact time.
After my dad left home,
I studied hard in order to become happy.
It was just like what you told me.
I only believed what I wanted to believe.
Like you said, that made things
much easier to cope with.
Your dad abandoned us.
Just think of it that way.
If I hadn't done that, I would've
had to spend my whole youth...
trying to understand my dad.
But...
even my mom was struggling to
endure the hardship behind my back.
I really hated her.
I was doing a good job of hanging
in there even after my mom died.
Even on that day,
I was doing fine and studying at school.
But suddenly,
this strange feeling took over me.
It suddenly came to me,
instantly took over my thoughts,
and pushed me from this bridge.
"When there's so much love in this
world, why didn't the deity..."
"save any love for me?"
"Why did the deity leave me out?"
"Why..."
"does the deity only hate me?"
If my dad picked up the phone,
that would mean the deity loves me.
If he doesn't,
that would mean the deity...
- really hates me.
- Dad...
That's what I decided to think.
Please...
The receiver cannot answer your call.
Please leave a message...
My dad's cell phone never turned on again.
So I decided to take revenge on
him in the most terrible way.
I'm going to make you regret
for the rest of your life.
Of course, it just ended up becoming
my most embarrassing memory.
Once again,
I need to say goodbye to someone I love.
I wanted to know how I really feel.
I wanted to know...
if I still felt like how I did
when I jumped from this bridge,
or if...
I had matured and become an adult.
I wanted to check.
Thank you for...
giving me your love.
Let's go home and eat.
So this is better laid out
than the other proposal.
Hey, I've been giving it some thought.
And I can't seem to know your intention.
Why do you look like that?
Did you say you want me to
become a decent human being?
I'm a human being who has
22 pairs of autosomes...
and one pair of X chromosomes.
You told me to become a human being,
so I thought there could be a
hidden message behind that.
So I even ended up
studying the DNA sequence.
My head's burning right now.
And I took countless pills
to get rid of my headache.
It's been a while since I've
graduated, so I forgot everything.
Why did you make me study everything again?
Ja Ya.
What's wrong with you?
He's looking down on me.
I know he goes to church,
but why is he trying to make me study?
Did you get orders from my grandpa?
That's what happened, right?
How much did you get from him?
You received money, didn't you?
Hey, say something. You got
money from him, right?
How much did you get? Did you get a lot?
Let me go.
Are you stupid?
What does the DNA sequence...
have anything to do with kicking Ms.
Yoon out of the building?
That's exactly what I want to ask you.
Do you have feelings for So Ah?
Ja Ya.
You should quit your job.
Your job requires intelligence,
but it also requires you
to have a big heart.
What are you saying?
I'm not interested in
becoming a sexy celebrity.
You should learn how to
have a bigger heart...
and become a decent human being.
"A bigger heart"?
"A decent human being"?
Why is the list getting longer?
(The one and only, Hye Ra)
What's wrong?
Is this your first time seeing me topless?
Did you also get that towel from my fan?
Yes, it's really nice.
It has your name on it.
My gosh, what's wrong with him?
I don't even have a lot of them.
(Hye Ra is mine.)
What are you doing?
Hey, this moisturizer is really nice.
You...
What?
What's wrong?
- Is that...
- Are you angry...
- that I'm using these gifts from...
- No.
- Why would I be angry?
- Didn't you say that...
you hate getting gifts from humans?
Yes, I hate them. They're filthy.
Just tell them that you want
them to give you gifts again.
Why are you being so
stubborn for no reason?
- It's all useless.
- What do you know?
I didn't know anything until a moment ago,
but now I do.
The design isn't that pretty.
Do I have 50 steps or 100 steps left?
Or could I already be inside her heart?
I'll try confronting your sincerity.
Get lost.
Okay.
I guess she's not that
interested in diamond rings.
Let's get her a gold ring.
A gold ring.
What are you doing here at this hour?
What's wrong?
I finally solved the last puzzle.
What?
I told you that I keep
seeing you in my dream.
Are you here to talk about that again?
Have a meal while you're here.
Eating isn't important right now.
No, that's all I care about right now.
It would've been nice if you didn't come,
but I can't send back
the only friend I have.
But you really are a nuisance.
I told you, didn't I?
At first, all I could see was...
a blurry image of someone coming
up to me and saying something.
For some reason, it felt like it was you.
But guess what?
A few days later, you came to
me all wet because of the rain,
but I still couldn't hear
what you were saying.
But a few days ago, I
could finally hear you.
That person...
Yes, keep going. Who are you talking about?
is the person who saved me.
It was him.
But...
So I naturally thought that
it was your boyfriend.
I got angry at you for boasting
about your boyfriend in my dream.
You can check with Soo Ri.
Yeom Mi, hurry up and get to the point.
I need to serve the rice now.
You said, "But".
- "But"?
- Yes.
You said, "But".
That means there's something unexpected.
That "But" kept bothering me.
But I really couldn't hear anything
after that. It was so frustrating.
- Is it like "The Usual Suspect"?
- It's more shocking than that.
Anyway,
a moment ago, I was able to
hear that mysterious part.
Okay, congratulations. So what did I say?
You said something shocking.
"That person is the one who saved me."
"But..."
That person is...
the one who saved me.
- But...
- But that person who saved you...
But the person who saved me...
is going to be the deity
that takes away my soul.
- What?
- You said the person...
who saved you is going to be the
deity that takes away your soul.
That means you're going to die.
What?
(The Bride of Habaek)
Ms. Descendant is going to die?
No.
Today will be the last day.
Why does this have to happen to me?
You're going to use that
remaining power on her?
It's the deity's duty to protect humans.
If you fail to become the king...
What will happen if I die?
Stop talking nonsense.
How can I call myself a king if I
can't even save that one woman?
How is that more important than your death?
- You're going to die?
- I told you that I'll protect you.
You're going to disappear from my memory?
I love you.