Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
You're not looking at me, Mike.
You're not looking at me in the eyes.
That's weak.
Only weak people do that.
I could look you in the eye
if I wanted to, Daddy.
I just don't wanna look you in the eye.
I guess you're just a weak person.
You must have got that from your mother.
It probably would have been better for you...
to have been born a girl.
Then we could have named you Michelle.
You see, weakness is more acceptable
in a girl, Michelle.
I'm sorry, I mean, Mike.
I keep forgetting.
Wait a minute.
Why don't I call you Michelle all the time?
Then I wouldn't have to be so goddamn
ashamed of you and your weaknesses.
I could think of you as a girl all the time...
by your frocks, dresses,
and frilly hats and scarves.
You could be Daddy's little girl.
I wouldn't have to be so fucking ashamed
of being seen with you in public, would I?
What do you think of that, Michelle?
Sound like a good idea?
Don't, Daddy.
What?
Did you say something?
Such a soft little girl's voice.
I couldn't hear what you said.
I hate you, Daddy.
- Speak up, girl!
- I hate you!
I hate you, because I love...
It makes me feel...
guilty inside, hate.
I can't let the heart speak.
Then don't speak.
Don't speak to me. Show me.
Don't tell me.
I'm not interested in what little girls say.
Show me!
Show me your anger.
Then I can understand it.
There you are, Daddy.
I see you, Michelle.
I see everything.
This is me, Daddy.
This is what you do to me inside.
Go all the way through it.
Go all the way through it to the end.
Come out the other end.
Don't stop in the middle.
I'm watching you.
I'm watching everything you do, Mike.
Wow.
The man is a genius.
Dr. Raglan would like to thank you all
for coming this afternoon.
I believe your bus is waiting outside now.
Thank you.
Candy...
it's me, honey.
Daddy.
Okay, honey.
Warm enough?
Okay, put the whale down. Turn around.
Hold your hair up.
Oh, my God.
Sorry, Hal...
but Mr. Carveth is still here.
He's starting to get passionate
about the whole thing.
Okay, send him in.
Mr. Carveth.
Thanks a lot.
Frank, it's been some time.
What can I do for you?
I want to see Nola.
I want to see my wife, now.
You know she's still undergoing
intensive therapy.
I can't let you break that isolation.
You let her see Candice
on the weekends, don't you?
Yes, Frank, I do. But that's different.
Visits from her daughter
was in her program from the very start.
Her program has just changed.
What do you mean?
You sound hostile.
My daughter's been beaten severely...
and scratched and bitten!
Her mother did it...
her mother,
who is under your psychiatric care.
That's an incredibly heavy
accusation to make.
Did Candice tell you that?
Candice won't talk about it.
She pretends
the whole thing never happened.
But it was Nola...
or some other crazy
you have stashed away up here.
Either way, no more weekends with Mommy.
The kid stays with me.
To take Candice away from her
at this stage...
could send Nola over into the deep end.
It's a critical time for her.
I happen to think that Nola's
been in over her head for a long time now.
You have no legal right to deny access.
Any time you'd like
to test the matter in open court...
I'd be more than happy to oblige.
For the ultimate good
of your own family, Frank...
we'd be prepared to do just that.
But don't you force it.
You bring Candy back to her mother
next weekend. She won't harm her.
There must be some other answer
to what you've seen.
Until you give me that answer...
Candy is not coming back.
Yes, Hal?
Prepare Nola Carveth
for another session tonight, will you?
Sure.
And, Chris...
make it phase two, after supper.
Okay, Hal.
This guy Raglan
is strictly an emotional opportunist.
He's a legit M.D., right?
He's a real psychiatrist.
Yes.
Goddamn it, psychoplasmics is a rip-off.
It's a sideshow. I've seen it in action.
It doesn't matter what you think.
You listen to me.
You call up this Raglan,
and you be a real mensch with him.
Otherwise, it's just a matter of time
before the cops show up at your door...
and you lose your kid for good.
The law believes in motherhood.
If I can dig up enough testimony to prove...
that Raglan's a dangerous fraud,
that Somafree is crawling with crazies...
it's no place for a kid, any time...
You're getting warmer.
But when Candy doesn't show up
at Somafree next weekend...
your wife can take legal action immediately.
You could find yourself belted with a writ
in seven days.
If I give Nola enough time,
she'll really hurt the kid.
I know she will.
I'll do anything I have to.
Here's your daddy.
I bet he knows all about this zipper.
There we go.
All set, now.
I'd love to talk to you
sometime soon, Mr. Carveth...
about school activities and Candy.
You missed the last open house.
Okay, soon.
Thanks.
See you tomorrow, Candy.
Thank you very much, Frank.
- For what?
- For bringing me my grandchild.
I know if it were up to Nola,
I'd never see Candice.
Juliana, that's not true.
Nola and I both know how much
she needs her grandma, especially now.
You're sweet.
I guess you know, now, what it feels like.
- What it feels like?
- Being a parent.
Being blamed for everything.
To have the past distorted, so you
don't even recognize yourself anymore.
Your child's version of the past, that is.
Juliana, Candice is only five.
She's working on it right now, believe me.
Thirty seconds after you're born,
you have a past.
And 60 seconds after that,
you start to lie to yourself about it.
I guess I've been indulging in a horrid bout
of nostalgia these last few days.
It must be the weather.
At least now I have a partner in crime.
- I've got to go.
- Of course.
'Bye, Daddy.
Take your time, we'll both be just fine.
I'll be with you in a second, sweetie.
I'm just gonna get a refill, and then
we'll look at those lovely old pictures.
Mommy.
Yes, Candice?
Yes, sweetie?
Mommy, you hurt me.
You hit me with your fists,
and then you scratched me with your nails.
You hurt me.
I didn't, sweetie.
You must have had a bad dream.
Mommies don't do that.
Mommies don't hurt their own children.
They don't?
They never do?
They sometimes do.
Sometimes, but then they're bad mommies,
they're fucked-up mommies.
Like whose?
Like whose mommy?
Like mine was.
Fucked up and bad.
No, I'm not, Nola.
You're being so unfair, sweetheart.
Mommies never do that.
Mommies never hurt their own children.
You did hurt me.
You beat me and you scratched me.
You threw me down the stairs.
Show me what I did.
Don't stop it now, darling, show me.
Show me your anger. Show it to me.
Go all the way through it.
Go all the way through it, till the end.
Right to the end.
That one's my favorite.
This one's your favorite?
Yes, Mommy in the hospital
when she was a little girl.
That's right. I remember this picture.
Your Grandpa Barton took this picture.
Tell me the rest of the story
that goes with this picture.
Why was Mommy in the hospital so much?
Some days, she would wake up
and she would be covered...
with big, ugly bumps.
And the doctors were very worried,
because they could never find out...
what those bumps all over her skin
really were.
I guess I didn't stack the dishes too well.
I better go see what the damage is.
While I'm there,
I think I'll freshen up both our drinks.
Jerry.
Hi, Frank.
You're really falling behind on this.
The Brenleys think that they are going to be
moving in here by May.
We're not going to make that, for sure.
Maybe by June.
I heard that the city plumbing permit
got held up...
because of a change in the building code.
Mr. Carveth.
Telephone call for you.
- Hello.
- Is that Mr. Carveth?
- Yes.
- Mr. Frank Carveth?
- This is Frank Carveth.
- This is Sgt. Martel, with 78th Division.
One of our officers noticed
a broken kitchen window...
while on a routine patrol
of the neighborhood.
He found your mother-in-law's body
in the kitchen.
The murder weapon was on the floor,
next to her.
He then found your daughter upstairs,
sound asleep in the bedroom.
It seems she missed the whole thing.
- Where is she now? I'd like to see her.
- With our police psychologist, Dr. Birkin.
- Psychologist? Why? Was she hysterical?
- No.
On the contrary, she was very cool
throughout the whole thing.
A little too cool, I thought,
so I asked Dr. Birkin to talk with her.
Just for an opinion.
In the meantime, can you think of
the names of any persons...
who would have a motive
to murder this woman?
You see, it doesn't seem to me to be
a simple case of an interrupted break-in...
or, say, a rape-murder.
Juliana had a long series of lovers.
I never met any of them.
What about her husband?
His name is Barton Kelly.
He works for the government, out in Halifax.
They were divorced over 10 years ago.
- Dr. Birkin.
- You must be Candice's father.
I'd like to take her home now.
Please. Give me just two minutes with you.
It's important. Have a seat.
To put it bluntly, I don't think your daughter
escaped this incident entirely unscathed.
- You think she saw what happened?
- I suspect she did.
Or she saw something
which traumatized her, confused her...
disturbed her in some way.
The officer who found her
said that she was very difficult to wake up.
To me, that indicates
a kind of abnormal deep sleep...
which a lot of people,
even children, will use...
to escape something
that's too painful to face.
And she says that she doesn't remember
being brought to her grandmother's...
or seeing her at all.
Do you think she'll remember, eventually?
Mr. Carveth, I think you must
encourage her to remember.
Why?
My concern is that the child
could have a very serious breakdown...
if she doesn't come to terms
with what she's experienced.
You see, these things tend to
express themselves in one way or another.
I've seen five-year-olds like her...
with ulcers as bad
as any middle-aged businessman.
Okay, I get the picture.
- Now can I take her home?
- I think that's fine.
No problem.
You're sure you don't want a story?
You don't have to read, you know.
I can make one up for you.
Do you want to tell me a story...
about what happened today at Grandma's?
You go to sleep, honey.
I'll leave the hall light on.
Damn.
No outside calls. You're in isolation.
You know that.
I tried to reach Dr. Raglan. He hasn't come.
He's on his way.
Chris...
Is something wrong? Anything?
Then it's me again.
Nothing's wrong, except with me.
No, that's Frank talking,
Frank twisting my words.
He won't be patient, he won't trust me,
he won't wait until I get well.
He thinks...
that I'm turning into my mother.
Day by day, moment by moment,
he thinks that I'm trying...
to make Candy into Baby Nola.
Is he right?
No. That's the last thing on earth I'd...
Who's that?
It's Daddy.
Frank hates me, Daddy. He despises me.
He thinks I'm trying to harm my little girl...
and I know that he's thinking of a way
to take her away.
And that's very unfair of him.
That's very arrogant of him.
You mustn't be too hard on him,
Nola, sweetheart.
He's just trying to be a good,
protective father.
No.
Yes.
He's just doing
what a good father should do.
He's protecting his little girl.
There's nothing wrong with that, is there?
He doesn't want to see her hurt.
He doesn't want to see her hurt by anybody,
not even her own mother.
Now, is there anything wrong with that?
No.
No, there isn't.
After all, it's just what I did for you, isn't it?
Frank's protecting Candy
the same way as I protected you, isn't he?
Isn't he?
No.
What do you mean, "no"?
- What do mean when you say "no"?
- I love you, Daddy.
I don't want you to think
that I don't love you.
I mean, you didn't.
"Didn't"?
"Didn't" what?
You didn't protect me.
You didn't.
You didn't, and you should have.
You shouldn't have looked away
when she hit me.
And you shouldn't have walked away
from the table...
when she twisted my words.
You should have stopped her.
You should have hit her when she hit me!
And you should have smacked her
when she smacked me.
Oh, God, I love you.
But you didn't protect me.
And you should have.
You pretended it wasn't happening.
You looked away.
And you should have.
Why didn't you?
Didn't you love me?
Look, there he is.
There's your grandfather.
Barton.
Hello, Frank. How you doing?
Good to see you.
- Let me take that.
- Hello. How you doing, Candy?
I guess you don't remember
your old granddad?
Right this way.
You didn't have to come way out here.
We could have met later, at the hotel.
I just didn't like the idea
of you coming in alone.
How long you plan to stay in town?
I guess we could
have the funeral tomorrow...
but Juliana's parents
might want to come in from Arizona.
Then there's that sister in Vancouver.
I don't know just how it's going to work out.
- All right. What hotel are you staying in?
- Park Plaza.
You know, I was even thinking
about going out to that old house again.
I still have the key, after all these years.
Juliana used to make a big fuss
about never having changed the locks.
I could never understand why.
Maybe it's because she really couldn't admit
that we were finished.
When I think about you and Nola...
and this sweet child having to go through
the same heartaches we went through...
it's enough to make you cry.
Yes, it is.
I'm here to see Mr. Jan Hartog.
Come in. Right in.
Sit down. I'll be right there.
Sit down. I'll be there in a second.
Goddamn son of a bitch.
Okay.
That's my...
heart, over there on the floor.
- Your heart?
- My second heart.
Your first heart
makes your blood circulate, right?
But what about your lymphatic fluids?
I don't know.
Movement, walking and running, fucking,
rolling on the floor, anything.
People have this whole other system
they don't even know about.
The lymphatic system,
it's like the blood system...
with its own style of veins and arteries...
but no heart.
You have to keep moving
to get it to circulate.
And they've just given me pills.
They do that every day.
And I've got to move them
through the lymphatic system.
Goddamn it.
Pardon my sweat.
I'm gonna take a bath, real soon.
So, Mr. Carveth...
how did you get my name?
My lawyer knows your lawyer.
I see. I get it.
Is your lawyer
preparing a case against Raglan, too?
Basically, yes.
- Slightly different from yours.
- How different?
My wife is still in therapy with Raglan.
I'm claiming psychological damage,
not physiological.
I see. Give him some more time
with your wife...
and you'll be able to claim
physiological damage, too.
Wouldn't this look impressive in court?
Do you like it? I do.
That's Raglan. That's psychoplasmics...
and it's called lymphosarcoma.
And it's spreading.
It's a form of cancer
of the lymphatic system.
You blame Raglan for that?
Raglan did it.
Raglan encouraged my body...
to revolt against me.
And it did.
I have a small revolution on my hands...
and I'm not putting it down
very successfully.
Then your lawyer really thinks
he can prove Raglan's responsible?
Are you kidding me?
You can't prove something like that in court.
Right from square one,
you're into, what, metaphysics?
How do you know
I'm not going to get cancer at age 32...
whether I'd gone into
psychoplasmics therapy or not?
No, we'd get laughed out of court.
Then why are you going into court?
Revenge.
Even if we lose, people will get nervous
about psychoplasmics.
It will be bad publicity.
They won't even remember
whether we won or lost.
They'll just remember the slogan:
"Psychoplasmics can cause cancer."
Catchy.
Is that going to help?
Maybe.
I'm not alone.
I'm in touch with a lot of people
who did psychoplasmics.
We might form a club.
I want to help you.
Okay. Thanks.
Dr. Raglan?
Yes?
I'm Barton Kelly, Nola Carveth's father.
Glad to meet you.
I'm sorry to accost you like this...
but your receptionist wasn't too helpful.
She probably knew I was on my way to...
Did you know
that Nola's mother died yesterday?
That she was murdered?
Yes, the police spoke to me.
- Then you've told her.
- No, I haven't.
That's why I'm here, to tell her.
Mr. Kelly, your wife's death
was a tragic and shocking thing.
That's why Nola must not be told.
What?
Nola's going through a very critical stage
in her therapy.
I'm not sure she could take it.
Are you saying that
I'm just supposed to bury the girl's mother...
and not tell her about it?
Yes, that's what I'm saying.
You are one ignorant son of a bitch,
Dr. Raglan.
Now, I have left my phone number...
on your front desk.
If I don't hear from my daughter
by tomorrow afternoon...
I'm coming back up here to get her.
Shall I have him stopped?
No, it's all right.
He's drunk.
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
- You two look like you're having fun.
- We were.
Daddy, Ms. Mayer said she was starving.
Can we feed her at our place tonight?
Candy...
We could if she wanted to.
What do you think?
Well, I...
We could talk after Candy goes to bed.
Sure.
As soon as Candy realized
she had me alone...
she got me to play
"mother and daughter" with her.
She obviously needs mothering,
and isn't getting it.
Sometimes it just kills me to think
I might have screwed my kid up already.
She's not even six.
It's not just you.
Sometimes when I'm being easy on myself,
I say, "It's not your fault.
"You got taken in.
"You got involved with a woman
who married you for your sanity...
"hoping it would rub off."
Instead, it started to work the other way.
Hello?
It's Barton Kelly, Frank.
How are you?
Just mediocre.
I made a mistake.
I came back to the old place.
It's got me.
I'm depressed as hell.
Barton, get in a cab, will you?
- Just tell him to take...
- That's not all.
There's Nola, too.
How do you mean?
I went up to that place to see her.
They wouldn't even let me talk to her.
They said no to me, her own father!
Jesus.
So I'm going back up there, to Somafree.
We'll leave just as soon as you get here.
Soon as I get there?
I'll be waiting for you.
I know you'll want to go up there with me.
- You're not far from here, are you?
- Barton, listen to me.
I don't think that's a very smart thing to do.
I'm doing it, with or without you.
Okay.
I'm only about 15 minutes away. Wait for me.
I'll be there.
You're a good lad.
We'll go up there together,
and kick their ass.
I'm waiting on you.
I've a feeling
I've just been recruited to baby-sit.
Would you? It'd take 45 minutes.
He's drunk.
He'll drive his car off a bridge,
unless I talk some sense into him.
45 minutes?
That's all it'll take.
Okay.
Thanks.
Help yourself to some coffee.
Here.
Look at this while I'm gone.
If you like it, I'll give it to you.
45 minutes.
I shouldn't have...
I never planned it to be this way.