- Great!
- A and E.
So is the country like that?
Yes, boy you're city.
- Look darling, Shore Street 17.
- I saw.
- Are you all right, Davey?
- I'm fine.
God!
In that house we stand?
No, Davey.
It can not be that.
Dracula subtitles.
What ruin!
Exactly as described in the ad:
"Suitable for a large family."
It's huge A.
Marian.
What's the point? Do not find yourself a house
that's such a price ...
Maybe I'll stay elsewhere,
in any house for vacation, or ...
No, that's
Let's see if we find someone
Let us be clear.
Also on ...
I hope you are home.
Rolf familiar.
I came home from vacation.
I know, I know ... you expect.
I am Walker, administrator.
I deal all around.
Join.
Let '.
- You like?
- It's ...
- This is home for rent?
- Absolutely!
It's beautiful, right?
Join.
Do your comfortable.
Acomodaþi sure,
I call them up on the owners.
Boy, take care of furniture.
Yes?
- I do not believe it.
- Not me.
Can I leave a little on the outside?
You do not have to come with me.
Not wine, but to stay close.
- You got it?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
What ramshackle-down.
Kill me.
- No need to put the soul.
- I can not abþine.
- Where's Davey?
- On the outside.
Do you mind if I close the door
to escape the smell that?
Marian look.
- Extraordinary.
- Are wonderful.
But they all look the same!
That must have some 100 years.
This is very new.
But how?
Wine!
I apologize
that I have left to wait.
I had a terrible morning!
If îþi allows program
You can throw that mirror? It's broken.
- It's not only destroyed this way.
- Old beast.
Þâfnoasã Baba!
Allardyce are pink.
And my brother will come soon.
Rolf familiar.
My name is Ben.
She is my wife, Marian.
Charmed.
- Do you have and a boy, right?
- Yes, our son, David. It's in the garden.
- It's all right?
- Yes, the children cheer this place.
Should discuss the details.
Are you a man practically
Like my brother.
In ad wrote that price is "reasonable".
"Very reasonable" as far as I remember.
And it really is, for the right people.
If we had "the right person"
what amount should be about?
First I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
You will rent the house just for you?
No. Will and Elizabeth come,
Ben's and rectum.
- How many years does he have?
- 74.
An old?
You do not mind and it's around?
No.
Elizabeth is an expensive.
If you sit from 1 July
until early September
'll take care of house
and you'll deal with it?
Just us?
Sure.
I do not know what to say,
a house so big ...
Just me and the wife ...
House takes care of her single,
Mr. Rolf.
Believe me.
I'd like to make an issue
of it ...
but you will care for the house and we?
I think so.
Suppose that price would be somewhere
around $ 900 ...
- I do not know if ...
- For all summer ...
Help!
This is my brother.
Walker, for God!
- Calm down, come now.
- The elevator broke down again.
- Go, go.
- Excuse me.
I want to get off.
Incredible, no?
It's a bargain.
Do not sit and think.
- Honey ...
- It would be foolish not to accept.
I have just þicniþi like them.
Look ...
This man is an idiot,
should we give out. Hear?
He is my brother, Arnold.
As you see, is excited about today.
You're the ones who will
to rent the house, right?
Yes, just talk details
your sister.
I like Pink.
- And have a son.
- Yes, our son, David.
- Play in the garden.
- Really? Let me see it.
Fast, Pink, to see him.
Here it is.
It's not adorable?
What lovely boy.
How many years does he have? Eight, nine?
- Has 12 years.
- 12? What nice.
It's a little naughty, right?
- Sorry, I should walk ...
- No, leave it, okay.
- Închiriaþi often?
- It depends.
My sister wants to say
we need calm and relaxation.
I approach the end of the race ...
- Oh, brother ...
- Well said.
We like the house?
- Very much.
- Really?
Tell them how it's summer
when everything comes to life.
That's incredible.
I have never seen anything like that ever.
Over the centuries have passed this house,
Rolf lady.
Countless years have passed.
And this house will last a long time
Once you you will not be.
It is immortal.
- I really believe that.
- And I.
It may seem silly.
But when someone loves a house
and my brother and me ...
I apologize,
I want to be rude, but ...
We're waiting to see what is "and Mecheria".
Trick?
Well, with only $ 900 ...
This whole house is ours?
It would be something.
- But not one and Trick.
- It's not
It's about our mother.
What about it?
A woman who looks 85 years 60.
My sister would say ...
our mother
no it never leaves the house.
In fact,
out of her room or not ...
It will not create any problem.
Perhaps it'll never see.
He sleeps most of the time.
And when not sleeping, listening to music
or working on her collection.
Old photos.
It has thousands of photos.
Memories of a lifetime.
A love so much.
I just have to leave a tray of food
on the table in the lounge, three times a day.
I like to think we least ...
- Ben, no!
- Thank you.
- Mom.
- Davey?
What happened?
- I hit the knee.
- The wound looks nasty.
- What happened?
- I tripped over something there.
Should i clean the bruises.
Let's go into the kitchen.
- Come on, you have some bandages.
- Come on baby.
Where are you taking that plant?
Your sister said she wilted.
Really?
May look it once.
Is not strange?
I think you were rude.
Really?
Those people should go and
to a mental institution.
They let you carry the enthusiasm,
that's all.
Should internaþi.
No such house rents
only $ 900.
Why not?
Maybe not interested in money.
They want someone to take care of the house.
Understand.
Maybe you're right.
But the old woman and a 90-year ...
85.
85 or 100, so what?
And not a woman of her age
with two strangers.
You will not have to worry Thi.
I will take it from her.
- Sure. And if you die?
- O Lord!
It matters not so much
for you?
You know I did.
But I will survive.
The question is ...
I will survive?
Allardyce.
Yes, Mr. Rolf.
Great.
My brother will be happy.
On 1 July.
Everything will be ready.
Thank you. Goodbye.
- Sit comfortably?
- No, my whole body shake.
But mouth-Thi see that go.
I forgot to tell you, I want to
driver's license renewed.
Are determined.
Îþi admire perseverenþa, matting Sheet.
That's why they
I took a good long time.
Just to relax
when driving.
I am always relaxed driving.
But I have some instructors and I. nervo
We have plenty of space.
I do not believe it.
It's great, right?
It looks abandoned.
You can not.
What happened?
They had to leave.
To go?
"Feel-good and not you worry.
Arnold and Roz Allardyce. "
- God.
- I know, is crazy.
If something happens?
How do we give them?
Elders sometimes do silly things.
A and E.
But he knew two are almost insane.
- What about the old lady?
- I'll take care of it.
It's your field.
David luggage.
- Marian, I do not believe it!
- And it's all ours.
I'll be right.
Lady Allardyce?
My name is Marian Rolf.
We rent new and i.
Is everything okay?
You need something?
Memories of a lifetime.
Marian, where are you?
- What are you doing here?
- Take the tray.
- Have you seen it? What is?
- He sleeps.
We will see later.
Listen.
I will climb into the room just old.
Allardyce is very old lady
and will have to take care of it.
I do not want a bother anyone.
Dur.
- Come to see what I found.
- What is it?
Let '.
It's in the kitchen.
Let's see.
No clock is not working.
Sin, are so beautiful.
I think we should be back.
One to watch them myself.
You will take care of everything, right?
- Benji!
- Tia.
Is not great?
- Great.
- Elizabeth Matu Sheet, look.
Lord, are all here.
Benji, here's your first pregnancy.
Need to change the bulb.
Yes.
I'm crazy, right?
Ciudaþi?
Ciudãþeniile can accept this.
- Fuckin 'stopper.
- Do not swear in front of the child.
We take lunch Mrs. Allardyce.
Prepare a snack and you.
- Great, I got it.
- I always said that is good.
Have you seen those old objects?
I think I saw you some chocolate.
Matu  Sheet Elizabeth, you've seen
many antiques yet?
Even here is chocolate.
A full-box.
What you say a toast
for this house
- Hi, my slave!
- Good.
It's great
What have you done?
Where did that?
It was close to wall carpet.
You like?
Worth a fortune.
- I'll take the vacuum cleaner.
- Thank you, baby.
You made itself clear on here?
I have to do and upstairs.
How was the city?
All right.
Not much to it.
- Put the bags in the kitchen.
- I go.
Why not come and see us
as cleans the pool, you might be amused.
Are occupied.
Have you succeeded even now?
If you think so isteþ
Why did you fix it?
Davey, go and show him your father
how to do.
I will show.
I do not undermine
parental authority.
Should gather dirt in the tank.
And you have to fix that pump.
Father.
Look.
On this there compressors
a small object, called switch.
Here you go.
Try.
- Do you think will go?
- I am ready to bet.
- How much chicken?
- $ 5.
Benji, you're a technical genius!
Here's a cemetery.
Father, come and see what I found!
It's an old bicycle.
You know, Davey? All those îngropaþi
here are the Allardyce family.
I found no grave
for after 1890.
Bit strange.
Want a candy bãieþelule?
- Leave me alone!
- You can not get rid of me!
Lady Allardyce?
Are you okay?
I am concerned.
A week since I came in November,
did you eat almost anything.
You do not like food?
That told me to bring you pink.
Coborâþi night in the kitchen?
That's how you doing?
Lady Allardyce,
please answer me.
Where is mother?
She said she comes and she does not?
You know like your mother ...
May do what you lungs?
There are as before.
- Do you smoke too much.
- I know.
And I drink too much ...
I am an old woman
will not take 80 years ...
You put chlorine in the pool?
You know it kills germs.
I do not worry respects microbes
but snakes and sea.
When you go in the pool?
Go and ask her your mother.
- Quickly!
- I'm going.
Mother
Mother, are you up?
Let  swimming mother
I found it on anywhere.
We searched the whole house.
Do not worry.
It's probably the bathroom.
Great?
Move to jump, Father.
- You should go to the Olympics.
- Sure ...
What is that?
Nothing.
And get me.
Maybe you're doing well with the ball.
But you are a weak swimmer.
I'm going anyway.
Davey!
The pool is deep!
Do not give large.
A large snake.
Help!
- Do you feel like playing, Davey?
- Yes.
- Want to throw?
Get on my shoulders.
Ben, no!
- It was moving to!
- Do you want?
End.
It is enough.
Benji, you're worse
rãsfãþat than a child.
- That was powerful.
- Îþi like, Davey?
What are you doing?
Stops you!
Lord.
Drown.
It's past 2:00.
Yes?
Could you sleep?
- A little.
- Want to try?
A little later, maybe.
- I'll smoke here, right?
- Why not? If not you like, exit! It
You wanted to hurt him Davey.
Just play your
the out of control.
You've never been face.
A and E.
I'm sorry ...
But I can not think of anything else.
I can not get that out of mind.
Ben, I know how are you.
- I know I've wanted to do something like that.
- Bullshit.
I wanted to hurt him, do not understand?
You're sure punishment.
Davey is right. It's good.
If there is something more complex
îþi only imagine?
What do you mean?
Those dreams,
the death of my mother ...
... Returned.
Baby, it's been so long.
There's nothing wrong.
Absolutely nothing.
Lord.
It completely changed.
Looks like new.
It's all available to you.
Îþi like?
It's great.
I removed the TV,
not fit here anyway.
Now just
I find something to do.
There are many things
you can do.
You could start working on PhD.
- It's all right, right?
- Room?
No, what happened yesterday.
Uiþi must.
Let's go over what happened
and they again from the beginning, ok?
What nice.
David wants to learn to paint.
You going to find some landscapes.
Hi, Davey.
- How do you feel?
- Okay.
- Thi've got tools, Davey?
- Yes.
- Friends?
- Father!
- Not want to get in the pool.
- You do not have.
Îþi promise.
I do not like to go to bed
without you.
I am here in a while.
I know.
- Filter the pool seems to function, right?
- Yes, because someone isteþ.
The rest ...
It seems that everything ...
Smells like detergent?
I polished furniture.
I washed floors.
What, honey?
I came here ...
just to see if I could.
I thought it would go
more than that.
I tried.
- Looks like you got a þicnit.
- And so do you.
The pool looks great,
why not take a bath?
- You go and you?
- I did suit me.
What would have to go without?
Me first?
Come on.
It's great.
- It will help you get over it?
- Yes.
Why not?
Give Thi down everything.
Come.
The more I was alone.
I am missing you.
There's time, honey.
It's a water sport.
Good for circulation.
Okay my circulation.
Go back!
- Marian?
- See that you ...
I'm not saying to be something extraordinary,
after 13 years ...
But even less passion.
Do not understand. How I became
repulsive so suddenly?
Repulsive?
You're very sexy.
Ben, I do not want!
Not here.
Marian, for God.
Please do not understand.
You do not have ...
Good morning.
- Where did you find this?
- In the hall closet.
This house is full of valuable things.
You never came to bed last night, right?
When I came by the pool ...
I was in the room Mrs. Allardyce
to see if it needs something.
I slept in a chair.
I think I was very tired.
Where are you going?
I'm going to clean the driveway ...
to do something.
What about you?
It's already lunch.
Can not someone to sleep
more in this family?
I find it strange, matting Elizabeth Sheet.
Usually have more power than us.
I.
Vacation makes me exhausted.
You stayed too long in the sun.
Why not paint somewhere in the shade?
Lord!
I have to go to the hairdresser.
Stop pet.
No one would need
a visit to the hairdresser.
- And you're încãrunþe start.
- I know.
I think the rectum inherit and to Mary.
At 33 years already fully bed.
Davey is looking for.
He wants to go on a trip.
What's so funny?
You know what I'd like to do now?
To go back to bed.
- It's not awful?
- No.
Why do not you sleep a little?
One to tell you do well.
Maybe I will.
I'll do it!
For God, Elizabeth,
What about you?
Lady Allardyce?
Can I enter?
I knew that you're here.
You should not be in bed?
I think they know
on our host.
Sleeps.
Too bad.
I thought I would like
to see my work.
I'm sure, but when she wakes up.
- Elizabeth, you have some business.
- Sorry, I did not want to interrupt you.
- Tell him that I wanted to see her.
- We appreciate the intention.
- And if you want to stay with someone ...
- I'll say.
Take care on stairs.
Go back to your job.
I'll be fine.
Davey!
- What happened?
- Gases.
- God! Is that okay?
- Yes, breathing.
Breathing, boy.
Hold it, I'll be right back.
Breathe.
- Are you all right, Davey?
- I think it's better.
What happened?
Damn stove ...
Do not understand how it could happen
something like that.
Have you had breakfast?
No, I fell asleep again.
Infact.
- How is Davey?
- It's good.
Ben led him into the city.
Davey's okay, thank God.
Nor I know what fear was.
Poor Davey.
I want to know
I do not I touched that stove.
- Of course not.
- I'd remembered.
- Nobody said anything like that.
- I just wrapped.
Have you covered?
Davey you were in his room last night?
Yes, I wanted to see what it does.
Sometimes I sleep.
What have you done to his room?
Thi I said, I just wrapped.
It was cold.
This house becomes more cold.
Doors to the room by Davey
is always open.
Last night was locked.
I locked myself.
I grabbed anything
only blanket that I wrapped.
Just as I remember.
Well, I've locked it too.
It was locked alone!
But the windows?
Were open.
They were closed when Ben entered the room.
Come Thi senses, Elizabeth!
As I could?
How ...
when þipi to me and accuse me?
Do not accuse.
Where's Ben?
Benji I would think.
And I believe you.
Not true.
It's obvious.
May all forget something
from time to time.
At your age ...
Do not forget anything!
I know what I did!
Sure, my dear.
How about cooking something to tell you
for breakfast?
But old ...
I am so confused ... Mrs. ...
Allardyce.
- Yes! Maybe it ...
- Elizabeth Matu Sheet!
Get this over with!
Tell Ben that are above.
Îþi bring breakfast room.
Just as I take him and them?
Other old?
Do not bother.
Elizabeth.
- Benji.
- I woke up?
Are you OK?
You feel like drinking a martini
on the terrace?
You know what I said?
He was angry.
I spoke seriously.
He has no right
to talk to me and a.
Better die ...
Better die
than to do him harm by Davey.
You two do not you have ever fought.
What happened now?
Ask her your wife.
- Perhaps because they are old.
- Elizabeth, you are not old.
That does not mean
minds that I lost.
If I have closed the windows or door,
So how she said ...
I'm sure I said something like that.
I'd remember ...
Such things do not look.
I'd forgotten to something so important, right?
Sorry, Benji.
But I was very angry.
I do not like here.
I want to leave this house.
And you feel the same.
I know that.
Nervo and we all i.
How about to come down ...
and to drink?
And give him the opportunity to Marian
-and to apologize.
All right.
Just for you.
I love you.
You know that?
Ben, you scared me.
You know how much you upset her?
I'm sorry, but last night
it was in his room.
Why would minds?
I said lying.
Just that and not remember.
And she's to blame for all other
strange things in this house?
Do not understand what you mean.
Let's go down.
Should not they know it and I?
- Where is it?
- In her room, sleeping.
No one likes to come here.
Her collection.
You'll close here.
Why are you the so nervous?
I am not.
But I want to upset.
Why þii that locked door?
That's how she prefers.
It's just an old lady.
- It ...
- Thi gave the key?
No, the key was in the envelope
left by Mrs. Allardyce.
And watches the keys to this
were all in the envelope?
Watch keys were in their enclosures.
Why do you ask?
Do not understand how you have time to deal
only one of all these clocks.
So.
I sure did.
What is this, an interrogation?
What's this?
And get you something?
Not to bother you?
- What you think?
- Do not know what to think.
Can you tell me.
I'll try.
I'm sorry for what happened
last night at the pool.
I do not know of a bore and I a.
Do you need more time
to find yourself a better excuse.
Davey.
Look what you did!
- Do not lay a hand on anything!
- I wanted to break it.
Do not touch you anymore
of precious things.
- What is happening with you?
- Nothing.
Then you react like that
Davey broke when that vessel?
This house ...
It's more than I thought.
This house is not yours.
It's not our property, understand?
But it is my responsibility
how to take care of it sitting here, right?
Please be patient.
I need more time.
Why?
To get involved and more?
Summer is the end and knives.
- I to tell you a question?
- Of course.
What's more important to you?
House and all that ...
... Or us?
What question is that?
Okay, rephrase.
If you were to ask me thi ...
you cancel the house?
To quit?
Why?
If I were to be reached in time to Davey?
What does that have to do with the house?
Or leave us?
I can not believe you talk seriously.
I'm serious.
Do you know how ridiculous call?
You mean that the house
is to blame for what happens?
You leave, and asked if I was thi that?
Even if everything would be in my imagination?
You do it?
Father!
Mom!
Matu and of Elizabeth!
Up.
God.
Marian Davey take it from here.
Now!
What number is that Dr.
call it when Davey was sick?
- Where is the phone?
- On mãsuþa lobby.
Stay with it.
Have you called?
No.
Got busy.
Can not always busy.
No?
Across busy.
Wherever we tried.
Even the office.
Do not be surprised?
Do not understand what you mean.
And I'll try.
That's how you do.
- I succeeded.
- Yes?
But everywhere busy.
I was my imagination.
I'm sure.
What matters
is that the doctor will come.
Can I do anything?
No.
See what makes Davey.
Stay down and waiting for it to doctor.
Ash from the ash Sheet Sheet,
ground of the earth.
And I hope in an eternal life
through our Savior Jesus ...
Because of her faith,
this courageous woman
received eternal peace
Besides our Creator ...
the heavenly kingdom ...
And even if a complaint now
do not forget
and that the new will be given eternal life,
as a reward for our good works.
I love candlelit dinner.
- Life goes on, right?
- Why not?
- Do not standby EMS, darling?
- To be honest ...
I'm not hungry.
Elizabeth's death.
That does not mean anything to you?
Yes.
Davey!
It does not matter anything to you
In addition to this unfortunate house!
It's not true.
Why did not you come
Elizabeth II's funeral and rectum?
You know I can not let a single
Mrs. Allardyce.
Not good to put glass directly
on the table this beautiful mahogany.
Pour into a glass-Thi
and glass go into the kitchen.
- But no longer drinks.
- Take a cup.
Is better than glass.
It's silver.
But I want a drink, not a cup.
Do you say mother, Davey.
Stain the table.
- Do not standby EMS?
- Thi I said I'm not hungry.
Neither me, now.
I call her old.
I want to see.
Stay away from the door!
- Marian, unlock the door a.
- I can not.
Safe is the key to it.
The door is locked.
What you know about it?
Tell me!
Let me go ...
Please.
We leave this house ...
Did you hear?
Get out of here.
How to go?
How?
We make bags and leave.
- Can you lock this room before?
- Stop it.
I just thinking about this house
and the elderly.
It's dependent on me.
Just me.
Nobody can take care of it
apart from me.
Do not think ...
Are you obsessed with this house!
- For all that is here.
- I'm not obsessed.
We destroy this house.
Honey, this house represents
everything we wanted.
And now is ours ...
As long as ...
Marian ...
Whether you come with us or not ...
Tomorrow ...
back.
What?
What we had before.
I had nothing.
But what we have now?
- Davey, wake up.
- What is it?
- Wake up, we gotta go.
- Why?
Because this house.
- Everything changes.
- What?
Bricks þiglele.
Replace ...
with new ones.
Do not ask questions.
We must make a move.
- Dad, wait a little.
- Go.
Father!
- Wait!
- Get in the car!
Lord!
Stops you, Dad!
Waiting for my mother!
Stops, please.
I do not know what happened.
I think it was hit on the head.
It's good.
We go back.
THI Thiele apparently normal
what happens ...
because you're involved.
Are you involved
in what happens here.
Dad, what about you?
Doctor, will be better?
It is highly sedated,
will sleep all night.
But tomorrow morning
will be hospitalized.
Understand.
We do not have the necessary facilities here.
Will be taken to a hospital in the city.
But it will be good?
It's not my field,
but with careful attention ...
I'm sure I can take care of me.
If you need me tomorrow
I find the cabinet.
- Thank you.
- I must not driving.
Mother?
Tata feels good?
Yes, the doctor said
he needed rest.
- You are right?
- Yes.
Tomorrow we go home?
I do not think, honey.
Your father will be better here.
You should sleep.
Good night.
Davey, exit the water,
mass is almost ready.
Come on, Mom,
I do not go where it is deep.
You spent enough.
Where Thi-e robe?
I think I left my room.
Stand with your father, I bring him Thi.
Hey, Dad.
Are you OK?
Want to see what swimming?
I know pretty well now.
I practiced all day.
Want to see how swimming
in deep water?
Now I can swim there.
Well, be careful.
I practiced for you.
Look.
Davey!
Do not swim there!
Father!
Help me!
Are you OK, honey?
I tried ...
Father!
Talk.
I could only watch.
I know, honey.
Not that you could move.
I hate this place.
I want you out of here.
We leave.
Get out of here.
Even today.
You said you are going.
Go, baby.
Right now.
Are you OK?
Are you sure?
I forgot to tell Mrs. Allardyce
that leave.
Marian ... please.
I do not want to go back to that house.
Ben ...
We can not leave
free to call old.
- Mom, let's go at once.
- Please, do not return home.
We let our numbers,
like to know where we can find
If you need help.
Does not last long.
Lady Allardyce?
I am.
Marian.
I'm going there take it your mother.
Marian, you're here?
Lady Allardyce?
I do not want to bother you,
look for Marian.
He said he comes
to tell you that we go.
Lady Allardyce ...
I know you came here.
Are you sure you talked to her.
I can tell you where it is?
I have a question.
I answer, please?
I answer?
Marian?
I expect, Ben.
God!
Mom!
It's wonderful.
Mãreaþã ... as it once was.
And our mother ...
S back.
Our treasure.
It was played ...
... In all its brilliance.
Mãreþia them ...
... Belongs to us again.
Subtitle - Translated By - Dracula Khan