My name is Michael Westen.
I used to be a spy until...
We got a burn notice on you.
You're blacklisted.
When you're burned,
you've got nothing...
no cash, no credit, no job history.
You're stuck in whatever city
they decide to dump you in.
- Where am I?
- Miami.
You do whatever work comes your way.
You rely on anyone
who's still talking to you.
- A trigger-happy ex-girlfriend...
- Should we shoot them?
An old friend who used
to inform on you to the FBI...
You know spies...
a bunch of bitchy little girls.
- Family, too...
- Hey, is that your mom again?
- If you're desperate.
- Someone needs your help.
Bottom line:
as long as you're burned,
you're not going anywhere.
For spies,
top-secret clearance
is just the beginning.
SCI, the right to view
sensitive compartmentalized
information...
is reserved for the most trusted people
in the intelligence community.
That kind of access
comes with fewer constraints,
limited oversight, and
a frightening ability to do real harm.
I'm getting a little jealous
of that badge.
I remember when you couldn't
keep your hands off me.
I've waited years to see my name
on this again.
Now that it finally is...
A psychopath blackmails you
into using it
to destroy files
in the CIA's computer system.
And when I do this,
Anson Fullerton
goes back to being a ghost.
I don't want you doing anything
for that man.
If I don't do this, Fi,
you'll spend the rest of your life
in jail for something you didn't do.
You think he's just gonna hand
over the evidence he has on me?
He'll keep forcing you to do his bidding.
There is no end to this.
That is a possibility, but right now,
I don't have much choice.
I'm not willing
to throw in the towel yet.
Can you call Anson,
tell him you need to meet?
For what?
Make up a reason.
But if you can get him
away from his car,
Sam and I can plant this tracker.
We can follow the rat
back to his nest.
Anson's not gonna hide blackmail
material under his pillow.
Maybe we get lucky.
- It's too risky for a "maybe."
- It's even riskier to do nothing.
We can't win if we don't play.
18 bucks for a mojito?
What kind of a tourist trap is this?
A tourist trap with a good view
of Michael's meeting place.
You're wishing
that was a sniper rifle?
Can you think of anyone who deserves a
bullet more than that soulless bastard?
For now, let's just stick
to finding out where he lives.
Okay, here he comes.
Break a leg, Fi.
You look tired.
Laboring on my behalf, I presume?
We better walk and talk.
Can I buy you a lemonade?
You haven't answered my question.
There's a little delay.
A delay?
You have official access and the tools
to erase my name from that file.
- Why isn't it done?
- Clearance is being held up.
- It shouldn't be long, but...
- No.
What?
There's a great sentence
in your psych eval.
It says, "Westen is particularly
skilled at social engineering,
"creating rapport with targets
and steering them towards an objective."
I know your moves better than you do.
I don't know what you're planning,
but I'm not going to fall for it.
I can't see them.
Am I clear?
We're good. Mike walked
Anson out to the dunes, so...
Yeah, go for it.
Friday.
Have my name erased
from those files by Friday,
or Fiona gets used
to taking group showers.
Hang on, Fi. He's turned around.
Get out of there.
No. There's still a way to do this.
He's headed to the bridge.
He's gonna have to cross the light.
I'll catch him there.
Stoplights
are one of the worst places
to approach a target trained
in counter-surveillance.
Without having to worry
about driving,
their full attention
is on their surroundings.
They can use their mirrors
to pick up tails
and check the area
for surveillance teams.
But if you need to plant a tracker
on someone who's on the move,
you have to go the extra mile.
Don't try that.
Westen Team
u-sub.net
sous-titres.eu
Anson's not stuck in traffic.
He's making another stop.
All right. Good.
Show us where you live, doc. Come on.
No.
Looks like
he's just going to the dentist.
Sam and Fi are on his ass.
He's bound to go home.
Just relax.
Hey, Maddy.
Hey, ma.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't do this on the phone.
Do what?
What is it?
It's Andre.
He was shot.
- He's dead, Michael.
- What?
When?
Last night.
Who's Andre?
He was my best friend
since childhood.
- How's Ricky?
- His brother's dead.
He sounded like he was in shock.
He wanted to know
if you would come by.
You boys looked so sweet back then.
It's easy to forget what little
hell-raisers you could be.
You know, growing up,
Andre always thought
of you two as family.
I am so sorry, Ricky.
I thought he was still in jail.
- When did he get out?
- Eight months ago.
He kept saying he was gonna call you,
but I guess he...
He never got around to it. It's okay.
We hadn't talked in a long time.
I know you two had your differences,
but you'd have been surprised.
Andre turned his life around.
I'm really glad to hear that.
It wasn't a hollow promise this time.
I mean, he was working in the community,
trying to make a difference.
All he wanted to do
was make his little girls proud.
Do the cops know who did this?
Honestly?
They don't care.
They just figure Andre
got back in the game and...
Got killed for it.
But I know that is not true.
Andre made some mistakes,
but I've always known
he had a good heart.
You should eat something, honey.
I'll make you a plate.
If there's anything you need...
you don't hesitate to call me.
There is one thing.
I need to talk to you for a minute...
Outside.
I found this burner in Andre's car.
He got five calls
from a blocked number yesterday.
If we can figure out who made 'em,
I think we find his killer.
- Why didn't you give this to the police?
- Come on, man.
Cops don't cut
their coffee breaks short
to find out who called
a dead ex-con in Overtown.
I have a friend
who can trace the blocked calls,
but...
Are you sure you want me to do this?
You might not like what we find.
Now, I know you gave up on Andre
a long time ago and I get it
but I never did.
Now, I just need to know the truth.
I'll look into it.
The advantage of having
a GPS tracker on a vehicle
is it allows you to stay close
to your target without being seen.
Okay, Anson just turned left again.
He's back on Biscayne.
- Again?
- Yeah.
Guy's driving around in circles
like he's Pac-Man.
He must be worried about being followed.
Maybe he's going someplace important.
Okay.
He just turned right.
He stopped.
4th and Elm. Fi, get there. Let's go!
The disadvantage a following
someone without visual contact
is that
when they get out of their car,
you've got to catch up in a hurry
or risk losing them.
There he is.
Damn it.
Dollars to doughnuts
he's heading home,
but there's no way to follow him
without getting made.
If we get a better vantage point,
we won't have to follow him.
Fi, no. No, no, no.
Come on.
Slow down.
You said you wanted to go faster.
Van!
You're distracting the driver.
There he is.
3 blocks, 11:00.
- Now we know where the bastard sleeps.
- Don't spike the ball just yet.
There's got to be 300 units in it.
We can't knock on every door
until we find him.
No...
But it's a start, Sam.
Whether it's espionage,
international gunrunning,
or managing a local street gang,
the preferred method of communication used
by people involved in illegal activity
is the burner phone.
Cheap and disposable,
they can be used a few times
and thrown away...
which means, if you're using
one to trace someone,
you've got to move fast.
So, I had one of the techs at my firm
trace the calls on your brother's phone
to that house right there.
- Did you get a name?
- The calls came from another burner.
Last one was
about a half-hour before...
Andre was...
All right.
- Let's go find out who he was talking to.
- Way ahead of you.
Figure I'll take the front.
You take the back.
You got one for me?
You should stay in the car,
just kind of...
Whoever's in that house either
killed my brother or set him up.
You don't know.
- That's why I'm going in.
- Slow down.
There's a chance whoever's in there
might know who you are.
Now, you asked for my help.
Trust me and stay back.
All right.
Do your thing.
It's a good idea
to keep your initial contact
with someone who might be dangerous
non-threatening.
You're a lot less likely
to get shot at.
Miami Gas and Electric.
We got a report
of a leak in the area. Hello!
Although just because
something's less likely
doesn't mean it never happens.
Get the hell off me!
I don't think so.
Dolly?
What the hell are you doing here?
You know her?
I thought you were friends.
Why did you kill my brother?
I didn't kill Andre!
- Why were you trying to kill me?
- I didn't know who you were.
Who did you think we were?
- Who killed him?
- I don't know!
I ain't telling y'all anything.
Let me go!
Let's take a little ride.
I know you're not feeling chatty
but we need to have a conversation.
Y'all ain't cops.
I don't have to tell you a damn thing.
No. We're not.
But we're happy to take you to them,
along with this.
Come on.
We both know a convicted felon
can't walk around with a gun.
You ready to go back to lockup?
Dolly, listen to me...
I promise none of this
comes back on you.
I want to know who killed him.
Dion Carver.
Dion's a gangster
from the Magic City Overlords.
I guess Andre
got back in the game after all.
Andre wasn't doing dirt.
He's been on the up-and-up
since he got out of prison.
Y'all heard the shot caller
of the Overlords got killed last month?
Yeah, well, the street's
been hot ever since...
people pointing fingers,
stirring up old beefs.
Andre said the only way
to cool things down
was to find out who really did it.
He figured out it was Dion
and got killed for it.
You told Andre who did it?
How did you know it was Dion?
Dion and I, sometimes...
You know, we see each other.
And one night,
he comes home covered in blood,
carrying two duffel bags.
Thought I was asleep.
I looked in the bags
when he was in the shower.
I've never seen so much cash.
So Dion robbed and killed
the leader of his own gang?
I told Andre what I knew.
I thought that I was helping,
and now Dion's gunning for me.
You can still help Andre.
First, we need to find
someplace safe for you.
- What are you thinking?
- We're gonna take down Dion,
like your brother wanted.
Seriously, you stashed Dolly
at your mom's place?
Yes. Now, can we borrow
the Porsche or not?
Listen, Dolly knows everything we need
to pin Dion for killing that gangster.
She should be at the police station.
No. Dion and the O.G. he killed
were like brothers.
It'd be his word against Dolly's.
And the words of known junkies
aren't worth much down at the precinct.
Unless we can prove Dion had motive.
And to do that, we need to get him out
in the open with the stolen cash.
Now, Dolly said
he's gearing up for war.
I already called, told him
I have a friend selling heavy weapons.
He is ready to meet.
Okay, okay. Listen,
I hate to rain on this parade.
Dion's not gonna make million-dollar deal
if a witness knows how he got the cash.
- We're gonna make the deal sweet.
- Yeah, you hope, but saying that...
I turned my back on a friend.
And now he's dead.
I can't make that right,
but I can take down his killer.
We're gonna get Dion
to bring out the stolen cash,
and we're gonna take the cash
and Dolly to the cops.
I'm not asking you for permission.
I'm asking to borrow your car.
All right...
Under one condition...
I make the approach.
Mike, this is way too personal
for both of you.
Ricky has to be there to make the intro.
Someone's got to keep a level head.
I should be the one
that goes in there with him.
All right, Jesse.
You're in.
I'm still broke up
about what happened to Andre.
He was like family to me, man.
You have no idea how much that means
coming from you.
Who we got here?
Dion,
this is Khalil, the friend I was
telling you about from Los Angeles.
- What's up?
- You run guns?
I run security.
You hear about a rapper getting busted
on a yacht, you can blame my ass.
Let's just put it like that.
- So, what you got for me?
- I'm glad you asked.
Your man asked me a question.
May I please?
You got them trained.
I like that.
It's a Desert Eagle.
It's the most powerful gun
on the streets,
and it is a cap gun
compared to what we're selling.
I'm talking USAS-12S,
RPGs, body armor,
night-vision scopes.
You name it.
We're calling it the...
the "Scarface" deluxe package.
But wait, there's more...
Everything half price.
What's the catch?
My dude wants to unload
the whole shipment for a million.
And what am I supposed to do
with all that artillery?
Use your imagination.
You arm your whole crew to the gills,
you sell the rest.
How much an M60 going for
on the streets right now, Rick?
Let me see.
Let me get out my little calculator.
A lot.
You'll quadruple your profit.
Think about it.
You'll never make that slinging dope.
Why am I trying to convince this dude?
I thought you said he was a player.
This dude is standing in front of you.
He the biggest player in Overtown.
Look, I get it. I see this
all the time in the music biz.
Talented cats, spotlight comes on...
Shrinks up.
Can't everybody handle the big time.
I'm sure you can get your hands
on some MAC-10s,
maybe street sweepers.
But guess what.
So can everybody else
you got a beef with.
I'm trying to provide you
with the opportunity
to separate yourself from the pack.
But I can see you ain't ready.
So have a nice life.
- I didn't say no.
- All right.
Now, first off, I want a demonstration
of what I'm buying.
And I want to meet your supplier.
If it turn out
that you're wasting my time, partner,
knowing Ricky ain't gonna help you.
You feel me?
Yeah, I feel you, D.
A tough reality of surveillance
is that no matter how many hours
you spend outside a building,
you can't see through walls.
So, if you want to learn
which unit in an apartment complex
your target is using
without raising his suspicion,
you need to find someone else
to go in for you.
College campuses are a great place
to find a highly intelligent
and enthusiastic workforce.
The student body
may not get up before noon,
but they'll be eager
to give you their free time,
if you can come up
with a worthy cause.
We've been contacted by a group with
a proposal to fight corporate waste.
Guys, join me in welcoming environmental
attorney Mr. Charles Finley.
Thank you.
Thanks, Dakota.
It's really heartening to see so many
young people working to save the world.
But did you know
that there are wonderful opportunities
to do some good right here in Miami?
For example,
there are some condo complexes
with carbon footprints
that are larger than Sri Lanka.
A country.
Mr. Finley's firm
is leading a class-action lawsuit
against the Marina Parkway complex.
That's right,
because they are the worst offenders
of nonrenewable energy
east of the Mississippi.
And for some reason
they're getting tax breaks
for being "energy efficient".
Are you kidding me?
We got to put a stop to this.
So I need you to document
every tenant in that complex
so that we can calculate the ratio
of power suckage to tenants
on said properties.
We need volunteers
to knock on every door,
on every window, on every gate.
We got to get that information out.
It is time to hold
the Marina Parkway accountable!
- I have a question.
- Yes, sir?
I assume your firm will earn
a third of the damages if you win.
- Are we being paid for this canvassing?
- What are you, kid? Pre-law?
Listen, I don't know about you,
but the satisfaction
of stopping an ice cap from melting
or saving a nest of baby penguins...
is all the payment I need.
Where's Sam? You talk to him
about coming to the deal?
Dion said it's a non-starter
if he doesn't meet the supplier.
- He'll meet the supplier: me.
- You not in the right frame of mind...
I've had plenty of time
to get my head straight.
I'm not sending anyone else to scam
a cold-blooded killer with a gun deal.
Besides, we have bigger problems.
Like what?
Like, I can't get the guns.
What?
Mike said it wouldn't be a problem.
Wishful thinking.
I don't have that kind of inventory,
especially since I've had
to keep a low profile lately.
People, the wheels are in motion here.
This is happening. I can't hit "rewind."
We might not have to.
Fi happens to know where one of
her "associates" keeps his inventory.
- So you want to steal the guns?
- No.
We'll sneak in,
do the demonstration, sneak out.
Except that's crazy.
Doesn't mean it won't work.
All right. I'm calling Sam.
We're definitely gonna need some backup.
Like con-artists,
spies sometimes find themselves
in the unique position
of selling things
they don't actually own.
To close the deal,
you just need a believable story
and a lot of confidence.
Of course, when your cover ID
is a weapons supplier
who's crazy enough
to deal with a murdering gangster,
it doesn't hurt
to act a little crazy, too.
I trust Khalil made it clear. We have
a small window to make this deal happen.
You're trying
to make room for a new shipment.
But you don't move good product
at half price
just 'cause you want
to clear floor space.
So, tell me, why the rush?
You got me.
Chalk it up to a banking error,
as in my banker is dead.
Cash flow has been turned off,
and I've made certain promises
to certain Colombians that must be kept.
So if we're gonna make this deal happen,
we just need to do it right now.
Show me what I'm buying.
Where do we begin?
Looks like Mike's doing okay in here.
- Just wish he'd hurry up.
- He'll be fine.
You are supposed to look the road,
make sure there are no surprises.
Feast your eyes on this.
USAS-12 shotgun.
Take it for a test-drive.
You feel that?
That is sexy, right?
I got a silver 4x4 heading our way.
I thought you said
no one would be here.
I can't control it if someone
stops by the office on a Sunday.
That guy makes a surprise visit
Mike and Jesse are dead.
- What the hell is that?
- Gas grenade. I come prepared.
Excuse me, sir.
Can I talk to you a moment?
Easy, fella.
It'll be over soon.
What's going on?
Whose truck is that?
You almost had a party crasher.
We stopped him, but not quietly.
My associate was just asking
about that truck.
Better make up a good story.
Thanks.
That is great news.
Just make sure
the blast area is clear.
Dion, I had that truck brought in
for a little demonstration.
Now, for the grand finale.
You can't truly appreciate an RPG,
until you have held it in your arms
like your firstborn child.
Just imagine your enemies
coming down the street for a drive-by
and they don't know
you've got this in your arms.
Make it sing, baby.
Make it sing.
So, we got a deal?
Let's just say I'm gonna need
to stop by an ATM.
Whether it's getting a bureaucrat
to hand over state secrets
or a gangster to bring out the stolen
money that will get him busted,
spies know convincing people
to take action when they don't want to
is only half the battle.
The hard part is making them
do it on your schedule.
Dion called. He needs a week
to pull together the money for the deal.
A week? The man's sitting
on a million dollars.
A million dollars that we need him
to bring out for your plan to work.
He's stalling.
He's just trying to buy time
until he finds Dolly.
She's the only person
who knows he stole the cash.
He'll want to kill her
before he spends it.
We're not waiting
for him to hunt her down.
But what else can we do?
He already heard the sales pitch.
We need to make sure
he knows he's got to act now.
Mike, you push him too hard,
you could get killed.
That's why we need a plan
in case it gets ugly.
Jesse and I are gonna talk to Dion.
Jesse's keys are gonna be bugged.
I need you and Fi close by,
listening in.
You know the players in Dion's crew
better than us.
If you sense something going wrong,
you can give me a heads-up.
I'll get my stuff.
Mr. Carver,
when I said I needed this
to happen now,
I meant right now!
I'm doing a deal tomorrow
with you or without you.
What in the hell
is that supposed to mean?
You talking to other buyers?
This is
a once-in-a-lifetime deal, dawg.
You thought
we wouldn't explore other options?
Come on, now.
You forgot to do your homework.
The last fool who backed out
of a deal on me
he had a real nice funeral.
Hey, D.
Hector just called.
Somebody saw your girl
on Rows on 5th,
and she about to catch a fade,
player.
- Really?
- Yes, sir.
Hey, Billy,
break out a bottle of Dom.
What?
What did they just say?
Hector is one of Dion's shooters.
Sounds like the gang
just found Dolly.
She's supposed to be at Madeline's.
I guess she left. They just said
she was going to catch a fade.
- "Catch a fade" means...
- She's getting shot in the head.
- How do I get to the Row?
- It's an alley at 5th and Jensen.
You know how a banger from Overtown
who was never the biggest
or smartest, even,
ends up in a place like this?
Vision.
That's great,
but I don't need your champagne.
- I need a deal.
- Relax.
The last little obstacle to our business
has been taken care of.
I'm a do you one better
than your deal, Mr. Turner.
A hell of a lot better.
Dolly...
- Hey, Ricky.
- What happened?
I was feeling so bad.
I just needed a fix.
I'm gonna be fine.
I'll tell 'em what I know.
I want you to save your energy now.
I'm gonna...
Come on, now.
Come on.
Dolly, you stay with me, girl.
She's gone.
We got to get out of here.
Right now. We've got to go.
Come on. Go.
Part of being a good operative
is knowing what to do
when things go wrong.
If an entire operation
depends on a single witness to a crime
and that witness gets murdered,
you've got a hard choice to make.
Risk more lives or cut your losses
while you still can.
I've got more bad news.
Now that Dolly's out of the way,
Dion didn't just go for the deal.
He wants me to be his new supplier.
So instead of going to jail,
he's making a power play?
Without Dolly to tell the truth,
he can make up any excuse
about how he got the money.
Then he's got nothing to fear.
Jesse and I are meeting him
at Stubby's tomorrow.
Now, we're gonna tell Dion
our shipment was delayed,
but we won't be able to keep up
that charade for long.
- Why go to the meeting at all?
- To buy you time.
You need to leave town.
Tomorrow.
- Andre's funeral is Thursday.
- I know, but it won't be safe for you.
Once the gun deal goes bad,
Dion will come after you
for setting it up.
Sam's working on a new ID.
You get whatever cash you can...
So Dion gets to walk around
with a pile of cash
and Andre's blood on his hands?
And I'm supposed to get on a bus
with a fake name and some pocket change?
It's just until we figure out
another way to take him down.
You said this would work!
You gave me your word.
I'm sorry, Ricky.
I am trying.
It's not your fault, Mike.
It just is what it is.
Damn it!
Hey, Fi.
Finley's army came through.
Looks like the kids narrowed down
the hunt for Anson to three condos.
Great,
we'll figure out which one's his...
right after I drop off
Ricky's get-out-of-town package.
Hey, Fi.
I'm sorry things went bad.
You know, it's just a bump in the road.
Here, fake ID, credit cards,
new cellphone.
- If I were you, I would head out west.
- Can you do me a favor?
Tell Mike not to worry
about making that meeting.
He's going.
He wouldn't leave you hanging like that.
You don't understand.
He cannot go to that meeting.
It's not safe.
- What the hell are you talking about?
- Just give him the message.
Please.
- What do you need fertilizer for?
- Just reseeded the backyard.
Wire cutters?
Kerosene.
Jesus, Ricky.
You made a bomb.
Like I said.
Tell Mike to skip the meeting.
Screw that.
You can tell him yourself.
As a spy, you get use to the idea,
that today's enemy
could be tomorrow's friend.
Unfortunately,
it also works the other way around.
Under the wrong conditions, your friends
could turn into adversaries.
And the closer they are,
the worse it is.
We're running out of time.
Where is the bomb?
I said no.
I'm sorry,
but Dion's gonna get what he deserves.
Dion's not the only person in there.
Everybody in there
has blood on their hands!
This isn't the right way, Ricky.
It's the only way.
I take out
all the Overlord shot callers in one go,
maybe there'll be peace in Overtown.
You do that,
you will only make it worse.
Dion shot Andrew down like a dog.
He left him in the street.
And I want him to pay
as much as you do.
But don't let him
turn you into a murderer.
Andre wouldn't want that,
and neither do I.
So we just let Dion walk away?
No, you let me take care of this.
You trust me.
I will take him down.
But you got to tell me
where the bomb is.
There's a storage room
in the ground floor,
right under where they're meeting.
I snuck in through the alley
in the back. There's a door there.
It's Dion.
What should I tell him?
You tell him we're on our way.
- Shouldn't we be defusing the bomb?
- I don't want you to defuse it.
We're gonna make a tweak on it,
use it to our advantage.
It's back there,
right behind those boxes.
Really think
we should just turn this thing off.
Whatever Michael's planning,
it'll work with an explosion.
This baby has to blow.
We'll just do it without killing anyone.
There's enough nitrate in here
to take out a city block.
- Where did you learn to do this?
- The Internet.
Don't quit your day job.
A bomb's effectiveness
comes down to two factors,
the amount of fuel mixture used
and the location of the charge.
If you want to create
the sensation of a big blast
without the devastating effects,
you need to reduce the explosives
and place the charge in an open space
instead of against
a load-bearing wall.
Do it right, and your explosion
will still have all the bark,
even if you take out
most of the bite.
She's ready.
Now, these are the guys
I been telling y'all about,
the reason I called
for this sit-down.
Now, it ain't no secret
these are some tough times.
We lost our leader.
Some of us have blamed each other.
I want know who was behind it
as much as y'all do.
But you know what I want even more?
I want to put food on my table.
And I want to stop losing corners
to every gang in Miami.
Now, our enemies
think the Overlords are weak now.
They think we so busy
pointing fingers at each other
that we can't handle our business.
It's time for us
to set the record straight.
This is Khalil and Mr. Turner.
Thanks to these two,
the Overlords have a new revenue stream.
Guns, fellas.
And now the only crew bringing
more heat than us is the National Guard.
We have a problem,
a "let's talk outside" kind of problem.
Man, are you crazy?
I called this meeting.
I understand that. That's why
you'll want to hear what I have to say.
All right, me and my boy right here,
we gonna have a little chat,
go over some of the finer points.
Now, Khalil, he'll walk y'all
through our first order.
We'll be right back.
Anybody here know anything
about the USAS-12 automatic shotgun?
All right.
You got your little private moment.
Now, what the hell going on?
There's been a little snag.
My guy over at the ATF says
my warehouse is under surveillance.
Can't even go near it.
This don't smell right.
You trying to play me?
I'm sorry to put a damper
on your day.
I'm the one whose entire inventory
is off-limits.
I warned you what was gonna happen
if you pulled out of the deal.
You don't believe me?
Here.
Call this number.
It's the ATF. You call that.
You ask for Agent Torres.
You say you're a concerned citizen.
All right.
I'm-a call your bluff.
Moment of truth, Mr. Turner.
- What the hell?
- You just blew up Stubby's. Let's go.
- Can't believe they just did that.
- Did what? What the hell just happened?
Are you an idiot?
They tried to blow us up.
Turner tries to screw me out of my cut,
and Dion made a play to run Overtown.
Dion's crazy, but he'll never...
Settle all his beefs in one shot?
He just did.
Or you think he's lucky,
walking out of here
a minute before the place went boom?
He probably set it off
with a cellphone or something.
It's true. I saw Dion dial his phone
right before the blast.
Dion's asking for a toe tag.
- I say let's give it to him.
- Hell yeah.
Hell yeah.
I see.
- This is about Andre.
- About you murdering him? Yeah.
What you gonna do, man?
Shoot me?
Come on, Rick.
You ain't got the stones, man.
I'm not gonna kill you,
but your gang is.
They think you just tried
to blow them up.
Come on, man, you're crazy.
I'll tell them what really happened.
They gonna be looking for you.
Why's that?
His phone's not the one
that triggered the bomb.
Cops can track things like that.
What do you think your friends
are gonna do when they find out?
Who do you think they'll come for?
I am so sorry, man.
It hurts me to my soul, what I did.
But I can make it up to you, man.
I can get you money.
Andre's little girls.
I'll set them up for life.
Anything you want!
I want my brother back.
Can you make that happen?
The only way you get out of this
is to confess to Andre's murder.
You think the Overlords
can't find me in prison, man?
You might as well shoot me now.
I won't last a day in there.
Not if you cut a deal. You give up
what you know about the Overlords.
They'll put you in isolation,
but at least you'll be alive.
- That's more than you deserve.
- So, what's it gonna be, Dion?
Are we handing you to the cops
or throwing you to the wolves?
Got a call from Sam's buddy
over at the Miami PD.
Dion made a full confession.
He flipped on his gang.
He's in solitary
for the rest of his life.
Wherever Andre is right now,
he's smiling.
Thank you...
for talking me out
of what I wanted to do.
I'd have regretted it
the rest of my life.
Don't mention it. I'm glad you pushed
for answers on your brother.
I'm sorry I doubted him.
Do you boys remember the summer...
you took the engine
out of my lawn mower...
and built a go-kart?
Andre drove that thing
like a mad man.
"No fear. No fear, Michael."
Except until he lost control and then
took out that rose bush. Remember that?
Man had thorns in his eyelids.
Andre never told you
that he came back a week later...
with an apology.
And a new rose bush.
He planted it all by himself.
You're not saying that...
These are from Andre.
Told you.
He had a good heart.
Thank you, Mrs. Westen.
Okay, honey.
Breaking into
a trained operative's place
is an extremely dangerous
thing to do.
The consequences of getting caught
range from jail time to death.
Making it crucial
to protect your team at all costs.
That's why it's best to schedule
a break-in for a time...
when you're sure your target
is going to be away from home.
Ideally
because they're meeting with you.
He just pulled up, Fi.
You guys get in yet?
- Just made it in.
- You find anything, you call me.
Anson has gone out of his way
to keep this place a secret.
We'll find something.
Hey, Michael.
I thought you'd be busy today.
Or am I already free and clear
of the CIA's systems?
Not exactly.
Maybe I overestimated
your affections for Fiona.
I need to know before I go in there.
Before I break
into the CIA's computers for you.
I need to know
that there is an end to this.
Like a guarantee?
That everything's gonna be okay?
Would that make you feel better?
That reminds me.
I had the most interesting conversation
with your mom...
in one of our sessions,
just touching.
Let's stay focused...
Do you remember the time that you poured
all your dad's liquor down the drain?
You hated what happened when he drank.
And you thought you could fix it.
Your heart was in the right place,
but it didn't work out so well, did it?
No, it didn't.
No, your dad went into a rage
and your mom got the worst of it.
The point is,
little Michael always thought
he could fix things, and I admire that.
But at some point,
you have to grow up.
And you have to realize that,
try as you may,
you can't keep your dad from beating
your mom or save Nate from his demons,
and you can't prevent Max
from bleeding out in your arms.
And now as much as it hurts,
you've to do something really terrible.
But don't worry, Michael.
We're gonna get through this together.
Whether it's a stray hair
arranged to detect
someone's opened a drawer
or a cabinet
booby-trapped with explosives,
skilled operatives
know how to secure their hiding places.
So if you're searching a pro's home,
you can't just toss the place
like a cop with a warrant.
If you don't find any measures
taken to counter intruders,
that tells you something, too.
Usually
that there's nothing worth finding.
No computer,
no clothes hanging in the closet.
Why the hell does he come here?
I think I know.
This.
What is that for?
It's an antenna
for a combat-network radio.
The army uses them to encrypt
transmissions in the battlefield.
So I'm thinking
that Anson is relaying his signal...
from some government
building's network.
So, he does that, he can reach out
to anywhere in the world.
That's it?
That's all that's here?
A glorified telephone?
At least if we know how he's sending
his messages, we can intercept them.
It's nothing
that's gonna help Michael right now.
Intelligence-agency computers...
make use of the most sophisticated
anti-hacking techniques on the planet,
but any system can be compromised
if it's compromised from the inside.
Hackers know you can't put a drive into
a computer port without it registering.
So if you need to sneak software
into a system without leaving a trace,
you need to hide it
in another accessory.
Wiring a thumb drive
to the inner workings of a mouse...
gives you access...
without raising red flags
after you're gone.
Sometimes betrayal
is as easy as pushing a button.
But the hard part is being able to live
with yourself after you've done it.