Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Man is un???
Nothing is impossible for him.
What seemed to be a unthinkable undertaking yesterday
are history today.
The conquest of the moon for example
Who talks about it anymore
Today we are already on the threshold of conquering are galaxy.
and in the not to distant tomorrow
Will be considering the conquest of the universe.
and yet man seems to ignore the fact that on this very planet
there are still people living in the stone age and practicing cannibalism.
..... Primitive tribes isolated in ruthless hostile enviroments
where the prevailing law is survivial of the fittest
And this jungle its inhabitaince refer too, as the Green Inferno
Is only a few hours flying time from New York City
was it to remind us that four brave Americans
went there to make a documentry on life in the jungle
was it also to remind us for instance
that before venturing into space.
We should become more aquanted with the planet that we live on.
Four young and fearless Americans children of the space age.
Armed with cameras, microphones, and curiosity.
Alan Yates, director famous for his documentry's on
Vietnam and Africa.
Faye Daniels, his girlfriend and script girl.
and there two cameramen,  Jack Anders and Mark
Tomaso
Four youngsters never came back.
But let's have a look at them
at the beginning of there incredible adventure.
Here at the border between Brazil and Peru.
They are about to board a plane to take them to the Rio Ocoro.
A last outpost from which they will continue on foot.
Deep into the Amazon Jungle.
Into the area known as the Green Inferno.
Hey, are you really not scared?
Not at all...I've been in plenty of dangerous places with them.
What about you, Alan?
Well there's one thing scares me.
and that's marriage..
He'd take me to the North Pole to put it off...
I'd say you succeeded this time too.
And this last time.
Yes, provided that to come back in one piece.
Alright, alright...Let's go.
Well you four are certainly the first to embark on such an adventure.
There was a expedition in 59 and another in 67
And neither of them came back.
Yeh, that was Smith and a bunch of Frenchman.
Yeh, Frenchman, they were amateurs a bunch of jerks.
They never succeded in doing anything.
For us the difficult doesn't exist.
The impossible just takes a little more time.
We have Felipe our guide.
All right, gentlemen, are you ready?
Those are the last pictures we have of them.
Two months have passed since they were last heard from.
Are you still alive?
And if you so where are they?
These are the questions that the rescue team sponsored by
New York University and the Pan American Broadcasting System.
...hope to be able to answer.
Thank you for accepting Professor
Monroe. Good luck
Professor Harold Monroe, NYU's noted anthropologist.
Has taken part in various expiditions exploring primitive cultures.
But this will be his first journey into Amazonea
Here you are Lieutenant ...
Well Professor Monroe...Do you think you can turn that
Thanks... All I can say is that your...
Anthropologists and missionaries, are made out of special stuff.
If hell holes like this didn't exist
I'm sure you would invent one.
Where as I'd give both my ???
well let's say I'd give anything to be somewhere else.
Look, Lieutenant.
I'll be as little trouble as possible, it's just...
I'm sure you got enough problems of your own.
I'll have to be honest with you...
No, no thanks...
I need your help in organizing your expedition.
How can I refuse.
You have been recommended by everybody.
Only a sure guarantee that you'll
still be breathing when you return
Look, I know this is not  going to be a picnic, believe me.
This is not my first trip into bush.
A skunk must of pissed that...
Lieutenant ...
This lighter belonged to Faye Daniels'
Come with me, Professor. I'll introduce you to your guide
He's the best there is, if you can get along with him
Chaco Hey! This professor of Monroe.
Hello ... Nice to meet you.
Lieutenant here was telling me...
What a excellent guide you are.
You gonna take all of this with you in the jungle?
Yes, well forget it. We gonna need some weapons...
some amunition plus some medicine
that's all we need
I already told your friends.
The more you carry, the quiker you get tired...
the sooner you die.
Alright,alright...
All I wanna know Mr. Chaco is
do we have a chance of finding them alive?
Who's to say?
The only thing I know, is were gonna risk our lives to
save those fuckers...Let's go
Great warriors, these Yacumos!
They're afraid of know one except the Tree People.
No white man has ever seen them
Or the ones who have, never lived to tell.
Did you see this?
The sacred scar of Ateri
That's what is is. a son of a shaman.
and he's been concicrated to the spirit of the jaguar
Which also explains what they were doing this far from home.
What do you mean?
They were caught, yet they are not really cannibals.
To chase evil spirits outta the jungle
White men's spirits
Come on, Professor ...
Quit worrying Yacumo!
You can't aford to waist your strength helping that savage.
He'll out live all of us!
Can you make it?
will have to wade across.
But there's no piranhas here.
Come on!
Come on...come on...
There may not be any Piranhas
but there is always a few hungry cavemen around.
Leeches!
Leave that shit alone.
He can't do it by himself and there's three of us here..
Why can't we help him? Don't try this again Proffessor.
Here, we do as I say, and this bastard...
needs to know who is the strongest.
Chaco justified, Senior. This guy is completely
full of hate.
Soon as you don't look, this guy will slit your throat.
They went this way. Yacumo eat here
A pit dug for.
And what does this mean?
We're following the same trail, right? Right.
Hey, Professor!
I recognize these teeth.
This is Felipe Ocana.
He knew the jungle as well as I do.
That makes me feel terrific.
I wonder what was his mistake?
See that? We're near his village, he can already smell his home.
Mira!
Here comes dinner...
Hey. Mira!
A vole!
Today we eat meat, Ok?
This is Miguel ... hurry up I'm hungry
It's dying that's for sure...
Hey, Chaco, what in the hell are you doing?
it's for our Yacumo friend.
A little bit of this stuff
and he'll forget all about trying to run away tonight.
Atalaka, catra!
This will make you very happy, just wait and see.
Drug addicts in the jungle.
hey, give him some of this.
A little muskrat stomach.
He'll love it.
You like that? Eat it it's all yours, go on stuff yourself.
What the hell is that?
I swear, that looks like a ritualistic punishment for adultery. That's what it is.
Just sit back and enjoy the show, because afterwards he's gonna take us to the village.
Don't be a fool!
Come on, Professor!
That punishment is  considered a divine comandment.
If he had not killed her. The tribe would have killed him.
Here he comes!
Follow him!
it's know masterpiece but, it'll do.
Please let me try Chaco, please let me try...
Ok, is it possible that this way that don't know..
How many of us there are until we talk with them?
Miquel not learn fast?
Terrific, just terrific!
They're coming ..
Where?
I do not see a thing
Don't worry, they are there ..
I know they are there, but
Where?!
I do not see anything.
Come on, let's send out our ambassador.
Andale, Miquel.
Mierda una Buena Suerte!
Andale, muchacho ...
We 'may be in trouble ....
Good you've raised deductive reasoning to an art.
Instinct ...
Something says your friends have made quite a mess of things.
Wait!
If Miquel pulls this off, I swear
I'll buy him a bottle of whiskey.
This is suppose to demonstrate they're good intentions.
There, their going to show themselves now.
Where the hell are you going?
They're going to lead you into an ambush.
No, this is a sign of a good professor.
You could a fooled me...
They just want to show us they are brave warriors.
They want us to follow them to the village.
Follow them?
Ya, to return the prisoner and to talk.
Listen, I do not know about this.
I think they want us for dinner tonight.
Chaco ...
Pretend you've seen nothing.
OK.
Friends shot him.
Let's hope he doesn't die from ????
Get busy, Miquel!
Breath easy it's alright now, Professor.
Kimnamma ...
Cheers, Professor ...
You now have the honor of drinking Hisimo
Yes.
The group we are looking for...
Is probably headed for the center of the jungle.
or the center of the Matos.
No white man has ever seen before.
This area is under the domination of two cannibal tribes.
They are so fierce, they are feared by all of the tribes in the area.
Including the tough courageous warriors of the Yacumo Tribe.
These are the two super powers of the Green Inferno.
Perpecually at war with each other.
The Yamamomo or Tree People.
and Shamatari, or Swamp People.
Each considers the other fair game.
Hunted...
Then eatin.
This will keep you high and dry.
No, thanks.
Yacumo blame the Alan Yates' crew..
...for the great calamity...
exactly what happened remains a mystery.
Only know the four whites picked up and moved on...
Hey! Shut up!
God, we're in the middle of a hunt.
tree people or both?
Both hunting each other...let's get going.
Despite the fact that are intervention saved them from the Shamatari
The Tree People
Although they welcomed us into there territory
continue to behave strangly towards us.
With a mixture of fear and distrust.
Never the less we've been permitted to observe the execution..
of one of the warriors. Death by mutilation.
Criminal ??? the Chief
Criminal for the way he was detroyed.
Must have done something horrible to incur the wrath of his own people.
It is not clear whether it was to pay a debt of honor towards us...
or only to demonstrate how they dispence justice?
Careful, they're referring to us...
We weren't able to get anything out of the Yamamomo.
Except for the wristwatch they gave us.
as a token of the gratitude to a ally
In our eye, they continue to fear and mistrust.
So I decided to try a experiment in psychology.
to strip myself completely
Clothes, weapons, dogtags, rings everything to become like them...
Naked and unfettered as Adam.
The Tree People would not let us bury the ghastly remains.
they had painted ochre
To drive away the evil spirits which the dead represented.
Once again I ask myself
What unspeakable crime could have called for such attrocious retribution.
I know are lives are hanging by a thread.
But I can't turn back without at least trying to recover
the footage Allen Yates and the others paid for with they're lives.
I'm thinking of the enormous human and scientific
interest it's going to contain.
I must do something.
Chaco and Miguel can't possibly understand this.
Yet, I must somehow gain the confidence of these savages.
Afterall, they to have rules of conduct.
Hold it.
You did it, God damn it!
They just invited us to dinner.
By some incredible act of God
they hadn't tried to open it.
Hoping the climate hadn't damaged it to much
And so in exchange for the tape recorder.
The Cannibal chief let you take away the cans of film. Is that it?
Yes, they thought since I was capable of capturing the human voice
that I was also capable of capturing their spirit. This convinced them...
that I was the only one capable of capturing there spirit.
This convinced them that I was the only one capable of breaking the evil spell
That had been cast over the Tribe...
...by the murder of the whites...
Of course, they had no inclin of what was really in those cans.
How could you explain what a movie is
They just felt they were a threat.
Why do you say threat?
Well the Yamamomo's understood how important
these film cans were to Alan Yates' crew
They thought these silver boxes contain power
The power which I must say again...
Caused much damage and violence.
A fantastic story. Thank you, Professor
Monroe.
Your very welcome.
As we conclude this special interview
We would like to remind you Wednsday at 9pm
here on Pantheon.
Will be presenting Part 1 of The Green Inferno.
The dramatic film testimony, of a extrodinary adventure...
...that took them all the way back to the stone age.
And you would be the ideal Host of the program?
That's right.
Professor Monroe,
as a eye witness as well as a scientist, you would be the most...
Yes
But before I make any decisions
I'd like to review all the film material.
As of yet we've seen none of it.
Professor Monroe, I can assure you...
that they know exactly what they want.
That maybe...
But mean while their all dead, aren't they?
Which is exactly why we have to let the public know the truth.
Will let the people be the judge.
Better yet, will let the people who knew them best be the judge.
Their parents, their wives...
This is a documentry they shot for us...
...about a year and a half ago.
Can I start?
- Yes, please do.
Pretty powerful stuff
Well just to give you an idea how Allen and the others worked.
Everything that you just saw was important.
You mean this was...That was no enemy army...
Allen paid those soldiers to do a bit of acting.
You'll have to excuse me now. I'll join you later.
Yes, thank you.
Shall I go ahead?
Yes...
This is Jack ...
Faye ...
Allen...
and this is Mark ...
They have worked together for years.
They were terrible prima donna
I have to admit they were real pros
The stuff they shot could really gut punch you.
Yes I can imagine.
There ratings were fantastic.
Higher than most of the big comics.
And they know how to play a audeince
Allan especially
Look at this bit they shot before leaving.
Yes, were coming back anyway...we got Felipe our guide
Come on up here...
Yes there we go ok...
This shots dark because the diaphrams
...setting on the camera was wrong.
There not hes got it right.
Forget it.
There's no electricity where were going
Nope, this is anything but a well organized
...safari with all the comforts.
Weapons...
Camera ....
medicinal supplies.
That's about it!
Will be covering hundreds of miles on foot.
And that's another thing...
Who knows when will have another shower.
Of course I don't think Faye will have any problem...
remaining the sexiest  script girl in history.
Are you really shooting! Jerk...
Okay, okay,
that's enough.
Has anyone seen my pants anywhere?
What do you want those for?
I put my head, Stupid...
I thought ever since Jack took them off two years ago...
You do not need them anymore.
Right, Mark?
That's right!
You idiot.
Knock it off...
Are you shooting again?
You idiot.
Crew of clowns.
They had a great sense of the theatrical.
Like I said ...
Real proffessionals...
What was I saying, Professor?
I tried working with Allan a couple times
...and I just couldn't handle it.
You know he pushed his people to the limit...
Demanding everything including blood.
And talk about paranoia.
God have mercy on his soul.
He was one ruthless son of a bitch.
... I feel we have a duty to tell the public the story Mr. Yates.
You know I really appreciate your coming.
You're the first person to come...
...and talk to me about Allan and what happened.
What I'd like to know proffessor is
What happened to my son?
Tell me?
Faye - no, it was not her real name.
she always wanted to be an actress
her real name was Tina.
Excuse me a minute.
Children, look I'm just going to be
...speaking with this man a minute. and then will play ok.
As you can tell we're very different in our characters.
but Tina, very energetic.
Very hard working...
very ambitious,
extremely ambitious.
I use to say to her
Do you ever think you'll be at peace with yourself?
Anyway ...
Now she is...God rest her soul.
Elizabeth! Elizabeth!
Excuse me, Ms. Anders,
...just two minutes.
How did you feel about Jack?
What's the use. What I'm I suppose to say about Jack?
After two years of marriage...
I was with him for just four months.
What are you doing?
I'll See ya.
He was always on assignments.
India, Asia, Africa.
Ya sure he was good in bed. But, he liked to eat too.
No brains though
To easily influenced ...
Alan was his god you know...
You know what I mean?
You guys think I can get any bread out of this.
Mr. Tomaso
Mr. Tomaso, please ...
I just want to ask you one question about your son.
Ya what do ya wanna ask me?
Look, your son was of special importance to the news world.
Can you tell me something about him?
My son, my son was no good.
He doesn't work he doesn't go to school.
Wants to lay around the house all day.
He's no good period! Now that's it....
Now I gotta go back to my job.
Don't bother me no more!
But Mr. Tomaso, please, your son was very well known.
By a lot of people...just one question.
OK, just one ..
About your son what kind of man was he?
My son, my son was a son of a bitch.
And he was no good.
That's it, my son is dead!
I don't wanna talk about him no more.
Now leave me alone!
Good Bye.
Mr. Tomaso, millions of Americans ...
Mr. Tomaso, please ...!
Why didn't they print the whole thing?
the negative needed special treatment.
because of the humidity
The quality isn't the best, but its pretty good
considering the lousy conditions they were shooting in.
Unfortunately two reels were light fault.
we had to throw them out.
I put a piece of black leder between
one sequence and another.
Good, that's were will put the interviews with the families.
...and the one in which you talk about your search for them.
Go ahead Bill.
... This first segment is silent.
Evedently they always didn't use the mics.
though they were attached right to the camera.
just above the lens, the gun barrel see?
... Remember this is a very rough cut.
Almost like watching ???
alot of this stuff will be thrown out in the actual editing.
Here we are there should be some sound coming in now.
No, no, not yet.
Here ...
Felipe ...
We've been walking for six days in this marvelous air.
Today is Saturday the 25th
If I were in New York, I'd probably be out shopping.
Get the camera.
Damn thing.
Wait, wait, wait ...
How much of the material is without sound?
Less than half.
Every so often I laid in some stock music.
...to juice things up...
What is it?
The Yacumos passed this way
We not far from the village.
Move away!
Jack, get the shot!
This is fucking dangerous.
Shut the fuck up!
Look at it...
We've been walking through the jungle for days.
With the feeling we're moving in circles.
At night we have to sleep in the trees, so we don't get bit by...
...the snakes or spiders.
Felipe, are guide claims we're near the big river.
Where the Yacumos live in the village.
Look at my foot!
Damn forest.
Allen do you want some tea?
Ahhh!!! Puta! Puta!
... Cut my leg
.... Cut my leg!
Puta!
Kill the leg
Grab the leg...
Hold him down...
My God...Jesus Christ
Cut my leg
Cut it off! Come on put it on the fire...
Come on, do it.
Are you still shooting? Ya...
Do it now...I'm gettin' all...
Do it!
Felipe was a great buddy and a top-notch guy.
Will miss him.
But even more will miss the security he gave us.
We decided to go on.
But we've only got the compass...
...and our insticts to show the way...
Panning to you Allen
Faye, give us some earth shattering
You know this is gonna make us famous.
You think so?
How famous?
Real famous and real rich.
What you going do with your money?
Gonna by a house...
and a piece a ass...
Do you think this is funny?
Think that's funny Uh?
Ya that's the only way you can get it.
Where's Faye?
I don't know.
Turn the camera off, will you.
Christ, what's taking you so long?
Well, I had to wait in line with the rest of the animals.
You're disgusting!
Ha get outta here..
I said get outta here with the camera.
Hey, I just want a little peak.
Will you get outta here!
I told you to turn the goddamn thing off.
I'll get you...
Come on push
Look there's a gator.
Get out of the water.
No, no, forget about me.
Film it, film it...
Come on, get on the raft you guys.
Snake!
Were saved...
Anakondadan
Saved from the jaws of death.
Come on...
I wonder where there village is?
Just shoot in the air
and follow them...
And when they scatter how we gonna get there?
No, wait.
I know what I'm doing.
Don't you get it?
We can never keep up with them.
This way that buck will go slow enough...
...to take us right to the village.
Well, what do you think Proffessor?
It's not the best way of establishing peace with the Yacumo tribe.
I'm beginning to understand...
...why they greeted us with such hostility.
Do you think this is bad. This is nothing.
Allan did much worse.
Just watch.
They could play it rough when they thought they had too.
remeber how they set up some of those excutions.
Faye!
Here we are at the end of the world in human history.
Things like this happen all the time in the jungle.
It's survival of the fittest.
In the jungle it's the daily violence of the strong overcoming the weak.
Jack!
Let's do it!
Jack a torch.
Ready!
OK!
The massacre of the Yacumos by the Yamamamos.
A set-up...all a set-up!
Get this fucker.
right
That's it.
Keep them inside.
Get in, Get in.
Get em' back inside.
It's beautiful.
Alan!
Here!
Show them how we do it.
Oh, you motherfucker.
Get the fuck outta here.
Do you believe this?
You fuckin' turkey.
I'm drained.
You must admit it's acceptional footage.
I didn't expect such impact and exceptional footage.
I don't think exceptional is the right word.
You don't?
No
what's exceptional about a primitive tribe like the Yacumos being terrorized...
...and forced to do something that don't normally do?
Come on Proffessor,
Let's be realistic
Who knows anything about the Yacumo civilization?
Today people want sensationalism..
The more you rape there senses the happier they are.
Oh yes, the typical western thought.
Civilized that what Allen thought and that's why he's dead.
The Yacumo Indian is a primitive...
...and he needs to be respected as such.
did you ever think from the Yacumo point of view...
that we might be the ones that are savages?
Well, I never thought of it that way.
But it's an interesting idea...Yes
Let's say things are reversed, right.
...and the Yacumo attacked your house...
...defiled everything you held holy.
You know that pig that was killed?
That was food for those people.
What if someone came into your house and you're hungry
...and took the little bit of food you had
...in the fridgerator
...and threw it down the toilet
would you behave in a civilized way?
Do you like people to make money off your misery?
We have succeded in establishing....
shall we say...diplomatic relations with the Yacumas
But, what are we for them?
These are people who have never seen a white man before.
...or heard the sound of a gun.
We know they are really afraid of our powers.
But for how long?
And can we really be sure they don't hate us, like...
...most people hate what that don't understand
When the old members of the Tribe feel death approach
they wander off to a secluded spot.
After she dies this old women
This old women will probably end up as lunch for some alligator.
In the jungle nothing goes to waist...nature recycles everything.
You are about to witness an ancient ritual...
Never before seen by civilized man.
The Tribe is a primitive social unit.
Bound together for the basic needs of survival.
To protect itself, the tribe must eliminate any diseased elements.
Now don't go away.
What your about to see...
...may simply be described as social surgery.
Had a long discussion last night about whether
...to keep going or turn back?
Wasn't easy to come to a agreement.
Perhaps we shouldn't push are luck.
God knows we've been lucky so far.
But you know what finally convinced them?
The chance to become famous.
To reach that spot where...time stopped...
...3 or 4 thousand years ago.
Yamomamos the Tree People live in constant strife with their...
...enemies the Shamatares
See this guy?
This was a Yamamomo warrior...
....killed by the Yacumos.
Just to give you an idea, to the Yacumos this is a savage.
I'm not speaking as a scientist but as a man of the street.
This so called documentry footage is offensive...
...it's dishonest and above all it's inhuman!
Yes, yes, of course...we all know what Allen was like
He over did it as usual.
But what you saw is a rough cut.
Perhaps I haven't made myself clear. But I...
...But I refuse to have anything to do with this material.
Look! Professor...
We are talking about the most sensational documentry to come along...
...in years.
...and you want us to just shelf it forget about it...
As if it had never been found?
Is that what you want?
Yes.
Yes, That's precisely what I want.
I've seen the rest of the material, you haven't
You haven't seen the stuff your editors...
...didn't have the stomach to put together.
If you have you wouldn't hestitate to agree with me.
John? Go ahead...
Somewhere in the middle of this Green Inferno
...where no civilized man has been before.
The jungle here's different.
It's almost hospitable.
So far we've seen no sign yet of the Tree People.
The Yanomamos...
Whe're beginning to wonder if they really exist.
Or if they're just a legend.
I think we got one...
Look what we found...
Some taste you guys have, she stinks...
She's marked. what do you guys think she is? A Yamomamo?
Or  a Shamatare?
Why don't you ask her?
What do you want to do with her?
Take good care of this little monkey.
Judging from the looks of this girl...
We found the Yamomamos Tree People.
We're gonna have to be very careful.
Cause these people our known for their cruel
Get her! Come on!! Alright...
Alright...I got this little monkey
You go first.
Oh, drop on her...Oh ya
I can't help it
Oh, go ahead alright...
Open!
Jack! What do you want to use for? Porno films? You stupid ass!!!
That's not a bad idea...How about jungle Joeys'?
Hey, you want me to keep shooting?
Do you want me to keep shooting or what?
That's a stupid question.
Hurry up Casanova it's Jack's turn...Jack's next...
OK Jack...Go ahead...
Come on ..
We only have three cans of film left, we can't use this...
Why do you wanna waste it like that?
Shut Up...
Aren't you gonna get some Allen?
The only thing he get's off on is his camera!
Kay, Mark!
Stop shooting Mark!
Stop it Allen!!!
You Bastard!!! God Damn You!!!!
He's changing reels.
Alright...Hold it tight, tight
Oh, Come in for a close up...
Watch it Allen I'm shooting.
Oh Good...More.
It's unbelievable..
It's horrible...
I can't understand the reason for such cruelty?
Must have something to do with some obscure sexual rite or
...with some profound respect these primitives have for virginity.
You rolling Mark? Ya
Look up there on the right.
Wait they're all around us.
Keep rolling...We're gonna get a Oscar for this.
Jaaack!
Jack! Allan, Allan you can't!!!
Look he's had it anyway..He's still alive you bastard!
Unless you can watch,,,get the fuck of me...goddamn it!
Keep filming Mark I'll cover you.
Got it right down to the last foot.
We really srewed ourselves this time.
trying to stay there for the last shot.
I don't even no where we are now.
But, I know that...
They followed us...
...and we lost everything trying to escape.
We're Screwed! We're Trapped!
I'm gonna try an scare em' away with this.
I hope it works.
Stay by me, Faye!
Don't get ????
Stay over here!
You motherfucker!!!
Allan...
Allen Save Me! Faye!!!
Allan AHHWW!!! Help Me...
She's had it Allen...
We've gotta think of ourselves
Take the film back home Allen.
Think of the Film.
Save the Film.
John
I want this material burned, all of it.
I wonder who the real cannibals are?
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player