Giorgio.
Why do you roll so quickly?
I don't roll so quickly that that.
Is it again far?
No, watch,
"Castello "Orsino di.
Like what does he/it look?
He/it is on a hill,
as in a fairy tale.
No, he/it is cold,
you are going to catch a cold.
When I received your letter,
I believed in a swindle.
Forgiveness?
I have difficulty believing
that I inherit a castle.
That way, lady, miss.
What, mom, is there?
Nothing, but make attention
where you walk.
This part has been constructed
700 years ago.
Welcome in the Castle Reilly,
ladies.
He/it is cold, mom.
Are the rooms ready?
Of course. Follow me.
How John can be him related
of a duchess?
I called on a deprived detective
and one recovered you, M. Reilly.
You are the son of fire
the duchess's s.ur,
the last of the Orsini lineage.
Dad, I believe
that he/it says that you are duke!
Yes, your father
is the heir legitimizes the title,
of the castle and all goods
that this one contains.
I fear that the family
lost his/her/its fortune
during the war.
There is not any money therefore.
M. giannetti.
In how long can liquidate one
goods of the domain?
Do you want to sell?
Yes, all. As soon as possible.
How much is the domain worth?
Difficult to say,
only the duchess lived
the castle, these last 40 years.
The Americans are there.
Here is my s.ur Agnese.
She/it will make the kitchen and the household.
Hello, I am called John Reilly.
Here is my wife Susan
and my daughter Rebecca.
Your room is there
and the one of your daughter nearby.
Your mother and you
are the "signora"
and the "signorina" of the "Castello."
I am the housekeeper.
One has work
if you want to sell,
he/it is going to be necessary us
a list of goods.
- An inventory?
- Precisely.
I must speak of it
to realtors.
Sorry, I spin.
Do you sleep to the castle, Agnese?
Yes, I have a room
close to the kitchen.
You will be able to prepare
another room?
Do you wait for someone?
It is for my husband.
I will prepare another room.
To the menu tonight,
it is spaghettis bolognaises.
It is perfected, thank you very much.
You remain a short time
to the castello?
Do you sell and do you leave?
Soon?
When all will be adjusted.
It is well.
You sell and you leave.
Soon.
Who is it?
It is I.
What do you want?
It is our first night here,
I told to me
that one could start again to zero.
I was going to lie down,
I took my soporific.
I am going to wake you up,
Beautiful to the sleeping wood.
You are so beautiful...
John, please...
I, Suzie, miss you.
I miss you so!
Stop!
For God's love,
that makes 9 months that I didn't drink!
You were adorable,
I should forgive you.
I would like indeed
but I don't arrive there!
Then, why did you come here?
She/it sleeps nearby!
Excuse me.
Good, I am going to lie down.
One should stop and should wait.
I told your mother
that I will bring you back
home to dine.
One is already late.
Does that go, behind, JJ?
Yes.
- Sit you!
- I have it.
Sit you, I tell you!
Dad!
Becky?
JJ?
Do I can you to help?
No-thank you, I am I just coupe.
In full night?
I fell
while looking for the toilets.
You were awake
by something?
Why, that is your case?
The old people sleep little.
- You also, you heard it?
- What?
The moan.
As a child who cries.
My brother...
he/it didn't tell you
history?
Thank you, I don't drink.
Which?
The duchess had a son.
Giorgio.
The "beautiful child."
Why didn't he/it inherit?
He/it died
at the age of 5 years.
5 years? Of what did he/it die?
No one knows.
The duchess's husband...
she/it had married an American
during the war,
he/it abandoned them,
her and the small boy.
A short time after,
Giorgio was buried.
Then, the duchess dismissed
everybody
and lived alone.
She/it didn't leave the castle
during 42 years!
Until his/her/its death.
To lose a child makes if pain...
And one feels guilty.
When the American left it,
the duchess became "pazza."..
Madwoman.
People of the city say
that she/it took vengeance
while killing the child.
Lord...
it was also his/her/its child.
It is contrary to the nature,
contrary to God.
Why do you tell me all that?
People of the city also say
that the night,
when the streets are desolate,
one hears Giorgio... he/it cries.
A child who cries...
They say
that the castle is haunted.
The book is green.
The lake is blue.
The flower is red.
My love, does that go? What is there?
That goes. I assure you.
What is it as flowers?
I don't know, I picked them
around the castle.
Ladies, I am going to begin
the inventory of the treasure.
You accompany me
for a small visit?
It is not recommended.
One remains to this floor.
Go, one goes there.
Hold. Pay attention.
Doesn't worry you for me,
one is going to have fun.
What?
A room filled of toys...
It is a nursery, I believe.
Approach, Beck.
What is it?
A horse... a rocking horse!
What?
Let's sit ourselves on this bed. There.
During that time,
I look for the treasure.
One would say that someone lived here.
If you were duchess,
where is that
what you would hide your jewelry?
I don't know.
Under the bed?
Why not...
One can always watch.
Is he/it there?
No, my love.
There is not anything. Just...
of the oldies.
Let's continue to look for.
Don't get along like a scratching?
Beck, one second.
I look at some things.
Hello, pussycat.
Where are you, pussycat?
Do you go where?
What do you want?
Where do you go, nasty cat?
That is sufficient, one goes back up, now.
Wait!
What is there below of so important?
Leave me! Go see elsewhere!
My God...
It is necessary that I come out of here.
A someone there?
Is it you, imbecile of cat?
Is there someone?
Come there, pussycat!
Come there, pussycat.
Pussycat, come, I leave.
I am there, dad!
Dad, I arrive!
Where did you have passed?
I heard your father to call you!
There is someone here!
What? What happened?
I opened a door
and I followed the cat below.
Are you silly or what?
You could have wounded yourself!
In fact, me...
But you are wounded.
Just a cut. It is anything.
- Where did you have passed?
- She/it got injured because of you.
What did you make?
She/it was with me.
What excuse do you have this time?
One is not going to kick it!
Can you supervise it, no?
Listen! There is someone here!
Rebecca, promise me
of more to make that ever.
To walk me
as someone normal?
If you want to visit the castle
or the city,
say-the-I and I will accompany you.
Mom, it is my handicap!
It is my challenge,
I must manage all alone.
And you manage well.
Excuse me.
- You don't have any friends here...
- A friend would believe me!
Listen to me,
there is someone here.
Enough spoken of that.
Go,
put your glasses, one is going to eat lunch.
My love, I want that you know
that I am your friend
and that I will always be there
for you.
Only, you make yourself the ideas
because you would like to have
a friend here.
Is there a cat here, Agnese?
No, but Gabriela
adored the cats.
Gabriela... was it the duchess?
Did you know it?
Yes, I was domestic
when she/it was teenage.
How was she/it?
She/it had everything that she/it wanted.
Otherwise...
Was she/it pretty?
She/it was beautiful.
What?
As you. But eat,
you are too thin.
It is true,
she/it has an appetite of bird.
The Americans
don't eat enough.
To share one meal,
does that weld a family, no?
This mirror broke itself!
It is the bouquet.
7 years of misfortune besides!
The setting was warped.
These things are so old.
Maybe a gap of temperature
sudden...
Or someone else to the castle!
Who is there?
Who are you?
I know that you are there!
There is someone!
- What happens?
- A nightmare?
There was someone,
I am sure of it.
Calm you, I believe you.
I am going to look for.
Dad, pay attention.
Don't worry. I arrive.
Calm you, my love. I am there.
JJ?
My small boy...
Your daughter heard something
this night
and felt a presence in the cellar,
is it well that?
But you didn't see anybody,
if I understand well?
No but I heard some tears.
You heard to cry
Signora Reilly?
No.
What did he/it say?
That the doors are closed and that him
a traces of break-in there.
No one of the outside
didn't enter in the castle.
But you won't be sure of it
if you don't search.
There are more than 150 pieces
to the Orsini castle.
One cannot make any research
with so few proofs.
My daughter affirms to have heard
something.
It is surely the case.
There are a lot of noises
in a castle, especially the night.
Everybody believes that I invent.
No, I believe
that you didn't understand.
It is you that don't understand!
One waits for you
that you searched the castle!
And that say yourselves the mirror?
How you are you injured
to the hand?
Do you think about me?
Why would I break my mirror?
What you saw
disturb you maybe.
John, she/it slept little
the last night.
As us.
I have something to show you.
What therefore?
Come, it is necessary that you see that.
Here, Susan.
It is bizarre, she/it disappeared.
There was a boy's photo
who looked like JJ.
I assure you, the double of JJ!
She/it was there.
Who is "Giorgio?"
The duchess's son.
He/it died to 5 years.
John, stop. It is not funny!
When I saw the photo last night,
I thought that it was JJ.
- Of what do you speak?
- I felt the presence of JJ.
Me also, I sometimes feel it.
It is not about that,
he/it was really there.
I know, it is for that
that I wanted that the police searches
and find something.
He/it died.
JJ died.
I know.
Stop!
You are not anymore a child!
He/it died, I was of it,
but listens,
his/her/its soul, his/her/its ghost was there!
Agnese says that the castle is haunted.
No, it is your conscience. You deny
the reality without giving you account of it.
It is different, there.
No, not of everything!
It is never your mistake!
You were alcoholic
because of your father
and turned of the faculty because
politically incorrect.
- And there, you use JJ.
- No!
If! It is not the ghost of JJ,
it is you, John!
It is you that drove
while being drunk!
You returned blind Becky
and killed our son!
And do you now, punish myself?
Yes, God didn't make it.
He/it let you pull of it to you
without a scrape.
What do you want that I make?
I would have preferred that it is I!
Me also.
The international language...
No, sorry, I don't smoke.
Do I can you to offer a glass?
Give what she/it wants to the lady.
Did you hear?
The same thing.
That is that that you...
I am distressed, Joe.
He/it tries to tell you
that he/it closes the bar.
Hold therefore...
He/it closes it for me, yes!
You should go back at home.
That goes, I understood.
I leave,
I caused enough like that problems.
Hold, for your pain, Joe.
It is for her,
give him what she/it wants.
What?
Do I have to you a glass of wine, no?
I know a small friendly place
open all night long.
Excellent!
Silence!
The noise circulates quickly, here.
It is not about being disturbed.
What ruffian you make...
If he/it pleases you,
it is necessary that you leave.
I am distressed.
No, indeed...
it was very well but...
It is necessary that you leave.
What?
I am beast...
Take them.
Take them!
M. the policeman.
It is you that I come to see.
Alone together.
You will see me me also.
What do you want?
Help us to recover
Sylvana Lucci.
Who?
She/it didn't go back
at home yesterday.
I am not informed of anything.
The last time that one saw it,
she/it went to the castle with you.
She/it is not here.
No one saw it again
since last night.
She/it is not here.
Can I throw a .il?
You refused yesterday.
It is you that refuse,
now.
Some what it is bothersome?
It is just to bore me.
Sylvana Lucci has a small child.
In other words,
a mother disappeared.
Am I suspected?
Has a crime been committed?
No. Useless to search, therefore.
Then, come to the station
to answer some questions.
Not before having spoken
to my lawyer.
Did you bring a woman here?
I was alone.
You were drunk!
Who are you?
What do you want?
Free me!
I am a friend of the police officers.
To the help!
Free me. I have a child.
Please!
You don't listen to me!
I listen to you
but I don't agree.
If he/it always drinks,
he/it needs us!
I am tired, Becky.
I am so tired...
If one remains together,
one of us will finish mad.
If that happened
as you say it,
there is not any proof against you.
Anything didn't happen other.
Then, they will recover Mrs. Lucci
or they will find an explanation
and you will be cleared.
You know of course this lady
is the police officer's mistress.
What?
It is a prostitute,
she/it had to hit itself/themselves the whole city.
Me including.
But the other men
didn't make him a child.
Is the child of him?
Ille denies
but everybody knows it.
A charming small boy.
One cannot prove anything
against you.
It was my s.ur,
she/it found the bag of Sylvana.
His/her/its purse, I want to say.
She/it will have forgotten it.
A woman doesn't forget
his/her/its purse.
I fear that they stop you,
now.
What?
It is ridiculous! I didn't make anything!
If the police finds the bag...
What is one going to make?
I am your lawyer, I believe you.
It is not a proof.
And then, why would say it one
to the police officers?
I swear you
that I don't have him anything makes.
We agree.
Agnese will give me the bag.
I will keep it
until one recovers Mrs. Lucci.
He/it remains to speak money only,
now.
I don't understand...
Since your business complicates itself,
I must increase my fees.
It is the blackmail!
Species of illegitimate child.
He/it is time
that you know the truth.
Of what do you speak?
I speak of the first woman
of your father.
What scandal...
The duchess of Orsino
who marries an American soldier!
The duchess?
Yes, they got married
and had a child.
Then, your father had enough
and ran away
with his/her/its young s.ur in America.
My parents
never spoke to me of it.
Why would they have made it?
The duchess could not divorce,
she/it is the nobility.
The marriage between your father
and his/her/its s.ur is therefore illegitimate.
Your father was never married
to your mother!
It is you, Giovanni,
the illegitimate child.
Beloved, go up by car.
- I must say goodbye.
- No, go up!
- Do you go where?
- One leaves.
Listen to me, they are going to stop me.
Why?
They didn't always recover
this girl.
You brought a prostitute at home!
And Betty was there.
If you leave,
I will seem guilty!
I should have left 2 years ago.
If he/it pleases you...
I implore of it to you.
You give the whip for
that one whips you, I am not able to anything there.
The whip?
Why did she/it have a whip?
I know what happened!
And I can prove it!
Goodbye, dad!
To soon, my love,
I promise you it!
I am grieved, Mrs. Reilly,
but we must take
your husband to the police.
I am sure
that he/it will be able to explain itself.
One must search the castle.
Make your work,
my daughter and I return to Rome.
You should remain to Orsino
to answer some questions.
One ignores everything of this history!
We must interrogate you.
But first, your spouse.
Thank you for your cooperation.
You keep us
against our will.
Where is Agnese?
I don't know anything of it.
One wanted to greet it
but one didn't find it.
Where is the staircase?
Someone must remain with my daughter.
It is a policeman,
he/it is going to remain with you.
What, mom, happens?
What do you play?
Rebecca is right,
there is someone in this castle.
God forgives to you.
And has.
Nothing that of the stones!
He/it is not there!
- Who?
- Giorgio Of Orsino!
He/it has never been buried!
He/it is living!
Don't you therefore understand?
He/it is in this castle!
Where is my s.ur?
I ignore it.
He/it removed it maybe!
Follow us, M. Reilly.
What? A small minute.
Listen to me!
Go to the floor,
in the duchess's room.
She/it has a whip! For what to make?
On whom did she/it use it?
Think!
She/it didn't let enter no one.
And who was there since the departure?
His/her/its son!
He/it didn't die!
She/it hid it!
She/it made her/its scapegoat of it
to take vengeance of his/her/its husband
who left!
Very intelligent.
It is he that broke the mirror,
who approached Rebecca!
Believe me, it is necessary
that you searched the castle!
My God!
I stop you, M. Reilly.
What?
It is not I.
Why would I have fact that?
Everything that you say
will be able to be kept against you.
It is not I, I swear it!
Help me!
Please, help me.
I am innocent!
Grimaldi and Benedetti
will spend the night here.
You will go by the police
tomorrow with your daughter.
Sensible. Thank you.
Is that going to go?
Can one have water?
Find me someone
who speaks English!
M. the policeman,
are you willing to listen to me?
Do you answer my questions?
Sensible but take my family
far from this castle!
Why?
There is a maniac over there,
they are in danger!
And that is this "maniac",
Giorgio Of Orsino?
You saw this empty coffin.
Why bury it if he/it is empty?
It was 40 years ago.
It is yesterday that interests me.
Why murder Sylvana?
I kill me to tell it to you
since in a little while,
I didn't kill it!
It is he!
That is sufficient with your histories.
Say me the truth.
One asked for water. Acqua.
Does she/it arrive?
I go there.
She/it arrives, my love.
One is going to take itself/themselves of it, my love.
One will go back soon home.
You believe
what that is dad the murderer?
Yes, you believe it.
You believe that he/it killed JJ.
You must like JJ more than me.
Why do you say that?
You hate yourselves
since he/it died.
My love...
One likes you all two,
do you know it, no?
Yes.
And whatever it occurs,
your father needs our prayers.
Pray then with me.
Celestial father,
if he/it pleases you, watch over us,
protect us
in this period of unrest.
And help my mother
to forgive to my father.
God,
make that our family
is united again.
Will one inform tomorrow morning, okay?
Here is that my migraines come back.
I have your medicines.
I thought
that anything would be more ever normal.
Where is this water?
Do you listen to me?
Yes, my love, I listen to you.
I put some to me
that it is more normal,
I don't like the normal.
No, indeed!
Now, I put some to me
of all these silly things,
the car,
the dance of year end...
When I will have a boyfriend,
it will necessarily be someone of good
since he/it will put himself/itself of it
that I am blind.
I will judge to what he/it is indeed,
not to his/her/its appearance.
It will be the love,
the big love.
It is you!
If he/it pleases you,
I answered
to all your questions
and now,
take my daughter and my wife
far from this castle!
One doesn't give orders, here.
And you will answer our questions
as one waits for it of you.
Now, say me
why you killed Sylvana.
I didn't kill it,
I kissed it!
Why do you make me that?
What do you want?
Please, leave me!
The police is there,
she/it is going to stop you!
Stop!
Free it!
Take me!
Go, take me!
Save you, mom!
Mom, he/it is there, he/it arrives!
Giorgio!
Forgive me.
I am distressed.
I like you.