Now, on the day I was born
The nurses all gathered round
And they gazed in wild wonder
At the joy they had found
The head nurse spoke up
Said leave this one alone
She could tell right away
That I was bad to the bone
Bad to the bone
B-B-B-B-B-Bad
I broke 1,000 hearts
Before I met you
I'll break 1,000 more, baby
Before I am through
I want to be yours, pretty baby
Yours, and yours alone
I'm here to tell you, honey
That I'm bad to the bone
Bad to the bone
B-B-B-B-B-Bad
I'm a-gonna tell you
how it's gonna be
You gonna give
your love to me
My love is bigger
than the Cadillac
After I show you I'll be back
Your love for me
has got to be real
Holy shit!
Come on, Arnie.
He's coming.
He's changing his shirt.
That's noise pollution,
what you're doing.
You might as well be dumping
toxic waste on our lawn.
Hey, Dennis.
I'll be right there.
Just leave it.
It's okay.
Go on. It's okay.
Arnie, your lunch!
Try and keep it cold.
There's yogurt in there.
Right.
Slow down!
Are you guys having a war?
She's pissed otf
'cause I'm taking shop. My dad too.
It won't embarrass them when you
fix their stupid Volvo for free.
- What?
- Last night, we're playing Scrabble.
It's neck-and-neck between me and her.
We blew my dad away early.
So, at the end, I had this choice
of "ratio" for five lousy points...
- or...
- Or what, Arnie?
"tellatio" for 24 points
and the game.
- What'd she do?
- She won by seven points...
because obscenity's not allowed
in Scrabble.
- And it's in the dictionary!
- You jerk, Arnie. Jesus.
You know, Arnie,
I was thinking...
Uh-oh.
No, seriously.
Now that we're gonna be seniors,
I figure it's about time...
that we got you laid.
- You know, like this year, huh?
- You need a girl to get laid.
- What about Gail Justin?
- I don't like her mustache.
Fuck you! What do you care
if you get a little hair in your mouth?
Okay. How about Sally Hayes?
She's cute.
- She's a sophomore!
- So what? She's a walking sperm bank.
I know. Come on.
I don't have the minimum deposit
to open an account.
Are you kidding? You carry
your lite savings between your legs.
Come on, Arnie.
I think maybe
I'll just beat off.
Are you playing
football this year or what?
Somebody's got to pick it up
when you fumble.
- Hey, Terry.
- How's your gimpy knee?
It's better.
Coach wants me to practice.
Yeah? It's about time. I've been eatin'
dirt with your name on it for weeks.
Hi, Dennis.
Oh, hey, Roseanne.
How you doing?
I'm okay. They gonna
let you play tootball?
Yeah.
Doc says I'm as good as new.
Then I guess
I'll be seeing you out there.
I hope so.
Well, T.T.F.N.
Yeah. Ta-ta for now.
I wouldn't put that in my mouth.
- You don't know where it's been.
- Get outta here.
But we know where it hasn't been.
With you.
- Having trouble with your locker?
- No.
- Did you see the new girl?
- I just got here!
- I'm in love, and I'm fussy.
- I never noticed you were fussy.
Drop dead, Cunningham.
- What's her name?
- I don't know. She's in the office.
She looks smart,
but she's got a slut's body.
Oh, shit. Here she comes.
I think you'll like it here, Leigh.
Give me something
for my lap.
We have a good band. Went to the Rose
Parade. Not a bad way to meet boys.
I would like to get involved
with the yearbook.
We have a territic yearbook staff.
Won a prize last year.
So, what about admitting
Red China into the U. N.?
- I think we already did that.
- Yeah, but...
do you think it was a good idea?
She smiled at me.
I want to have deep,
meaningful sex with her.
- Go get her, Bemis.
- Think I should?
You've got nothing
to lose but your virginity.
Dennis, can you give me a hand?
- I can't...
- Yeah.
- He doesn't have a chance.
- I don't think so either.
She's much too classy for him.
- There you go.
- What did you do?
Lucky. See you at lunch.
Hey, Charley.
Have you seen Arnie?
- Yeah. He's still in the shop.
- What's the matter?
Buddy Repperton has his lunch.
- Buddy Repperton.
- Hi, Dennis...
Come on, pizza face.
You want it?
Come get it!
If it's yours,
why isn't your name on here anywhere?
"Arnie Cuntingham."
Why doesn't it say Cuntingham?
Just take it, and let's go eat.
That's all you got to do.
Come on.
That's funny, Buddy,
real funny.
Go get Mr. Casey.
Come on.
You want to go for it?
Put the knife down.
- Put down the knife.
- You want to make me?
You've got a knife and he doesn't.
That makes you a chicken shit.
- Yeah. That's chicken shit.
- Yeah?
- Put it down.
- Yeah, put down the knite.
Put down the knife, okay?
Get him, man!
How do you like that, dickface?
All right, break it up!
Right now.
You kids take a walk.
Get lost.
Not you, Moochie.
- I ain't been doing nothing.
- You all right, Dennis?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Real cute.
Three on one.
They started it.
- That's not true.
- Shut up, cuntface!
Shut your mouth!
I don't have to listen
to garbage like that, Buddy!
What were you saying?
Repperton's got a knife.
You fucking liar!
It's a switchblade.
That's bullshit, Mr. Casey.
He's lying. I swear to God.
Did Repperton here
pull a knife on you?
Yeah.
Empty your pockets, Buddy.
Fuck I will.
You can't make me.
If you mean I don't have the authority,
you're wrong.
Try it, you bald fuck, and I'll
knock you through the wall! Fuck!
You two boys go up to the office.
Stay there.
Don't go anywhere.
You've got enough trouble.
Now...
if you don't empty your pockets
right now, I'm gonna call the cops.
Go to the office, Buddy.
I'll fix you!
You're gonna wish you were
never fucking born!
So, all in all,
it wasn't a bad first day.
Think Repperton
will try to get even?
No, he's a douche bag.
He'll tind somebody
else to pick on.
- They kicked him out, you know.
- Good.
They kick Moochie out?
Probation.
Those assholes.
Stop the car! Quick!
Go back!
- What's the matter?
- I want to look at her!
- All right, Arnie.
- Just go back. All right?
Jesus Christ.
What is it?
Do you know someone who lives here?
What?
Jesus.
Be careful, Dennis.
- This is a piece of shit.
- She could be fixed up.
- Yeah.
- Oh, she could be really tough.
Forget it. This baby's got
93,000 miles on it.
Probably 193.
I don't care.
- I bet it won't even start.
- She'll start.
You need these.
How much do you want for her?
- Whatever it is, it's not enough.
- Jesus, Arnie.
Sonny, you ever owned a car before?
- Yeah, he owns a Mustang...
- No. I just got my license.
Name's George LeBay.
Arnie Cunningham.
What are you asking?
Start her up.
Really?
Her name's Christine.
I like that.
Come on. We gotta get going.
My asshole brother
bought her in September, '57.
You got your new model year
in September.
Brand-new, she was.
She had the smell
of a brand-new car.
About the finest smell in the world,
except maybe for pussy.
When he got her,
she had six miles on the odometer.
Goddamn Roland went through hell
and back with Christine.
If your brother loves this car so much,
why is he selling it?
'Cause he's stone cold dead.
Died six weeks ago.
So, Mr. LeBay...
how much do you want for her?
I've been asking 300.
I'll make it 250 tor you.
250? This isn't worth 50 bucks.
The money's not important,
and there'll be no bringing her back...
'cause I'm selling this shit hole
and buying me a condo.
You got a deal.
I'll get the pink slip.
Will you stop and think about this
tor a moment?
- Where are you getting the money?
- I've been saving all summer.
- For college.
- You already have a car.
He's screwing you.
You could get a decent car
for that much money.
Christine is decent.
The guy's weird, Arnie.
He's fucking weird.
- So that was 300?
- Yeah, that's it.
- You said 250.
- 250 would do it.
It this is a good idea,
let's just come back tomorrow.
Do you realize
she's 20 years old?
I mean, that makes her
officially an antique.
Great. Darnell's junkyard
is full of official antiques.
I'm buying her.
I don't care what you say.
It's your funeral, man.
Would you give
Arnie a break?
He doesn't know what he's doing.
You don't know half as much
as you think you do...
shitter.
You did what?
- She's outside.
- You're kidding, right?
You can't buy a car.
What are you talking about?
- You're 17 years old.
- Oh, boy.
Actually, you're wrong.
I couldn't finance it,
but buying it for cash is no problem.
Registering a car at 17
is something else...
and for that
I need your permission.
You know how we do things.
You could've consulted with us.
I've consulted with you
about every damn thing I've ever done.
If it's something I want,
I get outvoted, two to one!
This is no committee meeting.
I bought the car, and that's it!
It most certainly
is not it!
How could you have
let him do this?
I didn't let him.
He wanted the car, and he bought it.
I tried to talk him out ot it.
I doubt you tried very hard.
- Yeah, well, I'm going home.
- I think you should.
That's it. I'm getting
the fuck out of here.
- What kind of lang...
- What did you say!
You wanted me in college courses.
I'm there.
You wanted chess club instead of band.
I'm there too.
I've managed 17 years without
embarrassing you or landing in jail.
I'm gonna have this one thing!
You are not keeping
any car at this house.
Fine!
Thanks for the milk.
- What's the problem?
- Could you honk your horn for me?
Christine's doesn't
seem to work.
- Ah. Sure.
- Thanks.
Stall 20.
Get it over there
and shut it off...
before we all
choke to death.
Kiddo, if you sold him that piece of
shit, you ought to be fuckin' ashamed.
I didn't sell it to him.
I tried to talk him out of it.
You should have tried harder.
I knew a guy who had
a car like that once.
Fuckin' bastard
killed himself in it.
Son of a bitch was so mean...
if you poured boiling water
down his throat...
he would have pissed ice cubes.
Okay.
That's the last time...
you run that mechanical asshole
in here without an exhaust hose.
I catch you doin' it one time,
and you're out. You understand?
- Huh?
- Yes.
I'm gonna tell you
something else right now.
I don't take any shit
trom you kids.
This place is for working stiffs,
gotta keep their cars runnin'.
It's not for rich-assed, snot-nosed kids
draggin' on the Orange Belt.
I don't allow no smoking in here
neither. You go out in the junkyard.
- I don't smoke.
- Don't interrupt me, punk.
Don't interrupt me.
Don't get smart.
- Ah, sir?
- What?
Those men over there are smoking.
Better tell them to stop.
You trying to help your buddy
right out of here, Chuck?
Then shut your pie hole.
I know a creep when I see one.
I think I'm looking
at one right now.
You're on probation.
You get it?
You screw around with me...
I don't care how much money
you paid up in front...
I'll throw you out
on your ass! You got it?
- Huh?
- Yes, sir.
Good.
Now get the hell out of here.
We're closed.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah. I'm okay.
You know, you better find yourself some
other charity besides me and Christine.
What is it about that car?
I don't know.
Maybe it's just that for the first time
I've found something uglier than me.
And I know I can fix her up.
You're not ugly, Arnie.
I know what I am.
Queer, maybe, but not ugly.
Fuck you.
Oh, bug out, Dennis.
You don't need this shit.
Where have you been?
You had us worried sick!
You don't just up and drive off
whenever you...
As I walk along I wonder
What went wrong with our love
A love that was so strong
He's done all this shit
in three weeks.
Look how cockeyed he works.
He's got tuckin' brand-new
windshield wipers...
for a busted windshield.
Well, the boy does
have good hands.
Good hands.
Bad taste in cars.
You know, Papa,
you can't polish a turd.
When I said you could scrounge through
that shit pile out back...
I didn't mean you could build
your whole fuckin' car with my stuff.
What do you care?
You're not doing anything with it.
Hey! Don't think you
got the gold key to the crapper.
Nobody takes advantage
of me, understand?
Yeah.
If it wasn't for me, it'd cost you
a shit pile to put this heap together.
I know.
Look.
I know you ain't got money
falling out of your asshole.
If you did,
you wouldn't be here.
Maybe we could work out
some kind of a deal.
You...
pick up around the place.
Do a few lubes...
put the toilet paper
on the little spools...
shit like that.
Do that and you can...
you can raid my junk pile
for whatever you want.
I might even throw in
a few bucks.
I'll have to think about it.
Well, don't think about it too long!
I'll throw you out on your fuckin' ass.
Forever, my darling
My love will be true
Always and forever
I'll love just you
Just promise me, darling
Your love in return
May this fire in my soul, dear
Forever burn
My heart's at your command, dear
I'll bet you a dollar
she says no.
Just 'cause she shot you down?
She says no to everybody.
Look what she's doing
to that pencil.
I wish I was an eraser.
Go on, studley.
Ask her out.
Mind your own business.
Just read the book.
Yeah. Come on.
Just don't tip the table over.
What are you reading?
- History.
- Oh.
- It's pretty boring, huh?
- Yeah.
Listen, do you like music?
What about dancing?
Yes.
Do you think you might...
want to go dancing with me...
like maybe this Friday night
after the game?
I'm sorry. I can't.
Why not?
I have a date.
Mr. Gilder! Are you lost?
No, ma'am.
Why don't you return to your own seat
and get back to work.
Yeah.
Arnie, stay here
so we can talk this over.
Mister, this is not a hotel
you can just drop into.
- I don't need this.
- What do you need?
- I need to leave. I'm late.
- You come back here this instant.
Oh, shit.
Greetings to you too.
Hey, man, no glasses.
You're lookin' good.
I can't make it.
I meant to call you, but I forgot.
Is Dennis going with you?
- Are you going with him?
- Am I?
No. I've gotta do an errand
for Darnell.
- You need a ride?
- Got his car. Thanks, though.
I'm sorry about the movie,
but this is work. Gotta go.
- Don't worry about it.
- Did you have plans with Dennis?
You are going to have no friends at all
if you keep treating people this way.
Get off my back!
You're his best friend.
What's going on?
I don't know.
I hardly see him anymore.
Neither do we.
Ever since he bought that car
he's been obsessed with it.
And you know what else?
When we signed the registration papers
at Town Hall...
they told us the man
who owned that car last...
died in it
of carbon monoxide poisoning.
Jesus.
Does Arnie know about that?
Arnie doesn't know anything anymore.
What the hell do you want?
I know about your brother.
I know he died
choking on exhaust fumes.
You don't know shit, kid.
My brother died
'cause he wanted to.
He ran a rubber hose
from the exhaust pipe.
Arnie wouldn't have bought it
if he'd known somebody died in it.
Either you're dumb or you
don't know your friend very well.
He had the same look
my brother always had.
Probably the only thing my brother
ever loved in his life was that car.
No shitter ever came between him
and Christine. If they did, watch out.
His five-year-old daughter choked to
death in it. He wouldn't get rid of it.
He rode around without a care
in the world except for Christine.
Only time I ever interfered
was when Rita killed herself.
- Who's Rita?
- His wife!
He didn't care
a rat's ass about her.
She died the same way he did.
Then I made him get rid of it.
For decency, you know.
Of course, the car came back
three weeks later.
What do you mean, "came back"?
Keep a-knockin', but you can't come in
Come back tomorrow night
and try it again
You said you loved me
and you can't come in
All right. Fifty.
Pass on go.
Ready?
Want me to go deep or flat?
Flat. I'll hit you
on the second shot comin' around.
Hey, Trelawney.
- Is that Cuntingham's car?
- Yep.
I know where he keeps it.
Down...
set, go!
Fucking shit!
Get a stretcher!
Come on!
"5,000 Dirty Limericks."
Ought to keep you busy for a while.
This is the third time
I've come by.
Must be dynamite drugs.
You're always asleep.
Doesn't quite kill the pain.
Rockbridge hasn't won a game
since you got hurt.
That makes you a hero, right?
Did I tell you that I'm not gonna
be playing football again? Ever.
The doctor said that
one centimeter more...
and I would have been paralyzed
trom the waist down.
Shitters did some job on you, huh?
So what's this
about you and Leigh Cabot?
- We like each other okay.
- Ho-ho. Listen to Mr. Cool.
She just happens to be
the most beautiful girl in the school.
Well, it's not what you think.
I really...
respect her mind.
She lusts after my body.
What can I say?
Fuck you.
I saw you guys at the football game.
How'd you ever get that car
tixed up like that?
Oh, just plain
old-fashioned hard work.
I still can't keep her at home.
Mom says it makes
the yard look crowded.
I'm surprised they let you register it.
I told them it they didn't,
I'd drop school.
Are you serious?
They just don't want me to grow up
because they'd have to face getting old.
Has it ever occurred to you...
that part of being a parent...
is trying to kill your kids?
See you around, pal.
I'm sorry, Arnie. I can't.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
I can't. Here.
In that car.
What are you talking about?
Why not?
'Cause I hate that car.
You care more about that car
than me.
That's crazy, Leigh.
Who do you spend
more time with?
Look...
You're gonna get a cold. Come on.
I thought girls are supposed to
be jealous of other girls, not cars.
This car's a girl.
Oh, please.
Cut it out. Don't.
What? You don't like me
slapping your girl?
It seems like nobody
likes my car these days.
Oh, shit!
You're mine
And we belong
Together
Yes, we belong together
Yes, it belongs to only me
What the hell
are you doing?
Get your goddamn
hands off her!
Whoa, whoa! Hey!
You gonna be all right?
Yeah, I'm fine now.
You scared the hell out of me.
Then get rid of that car.
I'm not going in it again.
Wait a minute. Don't you blame
your choking on Christine.
It happened, Arnie.
When I choked, something happened.
The radio came on.
- Everything got bright.
- So, what are you saying?
I could've died,
and you couldn't even help.
My door was locked.
You didn't want that man
to help me either!
I thought he was attacking you!
I could have done the Heimlich maneuver.
But you didn't.
There are other things.
That radio.
All it gets is those old songs.
Sometimes when we're making out...
it just stalls.
As if the car
were jealous, Arnie.
A goddamn car!
I'Il get it.
Know what I think?
I think you're just
sexually frustrated.
I'm sorry, okay?
Can I at least call you tomorrow?
I don't know.
Come on.
Come on, baby, please.
It's all right.
Everything is the same.
I love you like I do
Don't know why I love you
Don't know why I care
I wonder why I love you like I do
Is it because
I know you love me too
Check this out!
Keep a-knockin',
but you can't come in
I'll just be a second. I just have to
get my wallet out of Christine.
Want to come in with me?
Please.
You know, I've been thinking.
Maybe we should apply
to the same colleges next year.
- Really?
- Yeah.
If we get accepted
by the same schools...
we could take it as a sign of fate.
You'd have me to help you
through math, and if...
Arnie, what's wrong?
Who did this?
Don't touch me, shitter!
This is just what you wanted!
You get away from her!
Arnie, I'm sorry.
Sorry?
Yes.
I...
That is, we...
It's your fault.
If you hadn't been so damn selfish that
you wouldn't let me park my own car...
in your precious driveway,
this never would have happened.
That's not fair.
Oh, it's tair.
Can't we even talk about this...
like rational human beings?
One of them took a shit
on the dashboard of my car, Ma.
How's that for rational, huh?
Why don't we...
Your mother and I have decided
to help you buy a new car.
Well, that's what
everybody wants, isn't it?
Well, fuck you.
I'm fixing up Christine.
Listen, mister, you've been
disrespectful to us once too often!
You apologize to your mother
right now!
Take your mitts off me, motherfucker!
I'm hittin' the sack.
We'll make it better, huh?
Can't hurt us anymore...
not if we work together.
We'll show those shitters
what we can do.
Show me.
Little bitty pretty one
Come on, come to me
Lovey dovey, lovely one
Until I'm on my knees
Is that you, Cunningham?
Hey, you ain't mad, are ya?
Oh, shit.
You're a dead man now!
Where have you been?
You hear about
what happened to Moochie?
Yeah.
Almost makes you feel sorry
for the little bastard.
How's Christine coming?
Oh, cherry.
I spent a shitload ot money on her,
and she's perfecto now.
That's funny, you know, 'cause...
I heard she was totaled.
After I cleaned up the broken glass,
it wasn't so bad.
I bet you a hundred bucks...
it was Buddy Repperton.
Maybe.
So what if you fix it up and he
just comes back and does it again?
He won't do it again.
What does that mean?
Man, I gotta go.
I hope you didn't think
I could hang around here all day.
Yeah, that's you, Arnie,
always in demand.
Stay loose.
You know it.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Lean machine.
They let you out early?
Yeah, that's right.
I'm Rudolph Junkins,
State Police, Detective.
I'm just missing a study hall.
I got to get to work.
I don't care about that.
I want to ask you about your car.
You do nice body work.
I thought this thing was totaled.
- Who told you that?
- Why, hell, everybody.
Local police, your mom and dad,
your girl. Cute girl, by the way.
It wasn't as bad as it looked.
The report said
they punched holes in the body.
Damned if I can see the fill.
You can if you look.
It's right over there...
and back here.
I've been lucky with parts.
I replaced the entire door on this side.
- Yeah?
- See where the paint doesn't match?
Nope. A hell of a job, Arnie.
Well, thank you very much.
So what do you want?
I really like this shade of red.
Didn't think they made this anymore.
Do they still make this shade?
Well, they must.
I bought it, didn't I?
- Where?
- Baker Auto out on Route 5.
- You still got the receipt?
- Tossed it out.
You know, it's funny...
Cigarette?
No, thanks.
Usually when somebody trashes a car,
we get photographs.
Wait. They didn't really trash it.
That's not what Leigh said.
She was so shaken up,
giving me all the details...
she broke down crying.
I understand...
one ot the perpetrators
defecated on the dashboard.
I would've thought you'd
be madder than hell at that...
and I would've thought
you would've reported that.
Shit wipes off.
Moochie Welch
kind of got wiped off too.
I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No.
Scout's honor?
I'm not a Scout.
The kid was cut in half. They had
to scrape his legs up with a shovel.
Isn't that what you're supposed
to do with shit...
scrape it up with a shovel?
Don't get smart with me, son.
Your girlfriend is
more convincing than you are.
She's not my girlfriend.
And since when is it against the law
to fix your own car...
when somebody else busts it up?
Since never.
Then you get otf my back.
I need to see you.
I care about you.
Look, I love you.
I think we deserve one more try.
Don't you?
Would you give me a yes or no!
Please don't do this to me.
Just be straight with me.
You've had it, right?
Well, fuck you, bitch!
Want to do the honors?
I'd love to bring her along.
Sure.
- She can earn her way.
- Bullshit.
Let's get Vandenberg.
Baby!
I'll never be your beast of burden
My back is broad
but it's a-hurtin'
All I want is for you
to make love to me
I've walked for miles
My feet are hurtin'
Asshole.
Watch this.
Let's give this asshole
some of his own medicine.
He's backing up too.
Some shithead's following me!
I hope he comes in here!
- Is that Cunningham?
- It can't be.
Look at my car.
Come on, prick!
We're not finished yet.
Come on!
Hello, Henry? This is Will.
Listen. Cunningham get there?
The order okay?
Good.
Listen. He was driving
my Caddy, wasn't he?
Good. Yes. Take it easy.
Okay, Jack. Come on out.
The ride is over.
If I'm gonna have to come in
and get ya...
I'm gonna get ya.
Why don't you do us both a favor.
Come on out.
I got a girl named Bony Moronie
She's as skinny
as a stick of macaroni
Oughta see her rock and roll
with her blue jeans on
What?
Not very fat
Just skin and bone
I love her and she loves me
We're all happy now
as we can be
Makin' love
underneath the apple tree
Well, I told her mama
and her papa too
- What's goin' on?
- You tell me.
- Where were you last night?
- Home.
- What are you doing to my car?
- You didn't go out at all?
Of course I went out. I got Darnell's
car out front with a load of parts.
- You want the receipt?
- Yeah.
How come you're showing up just now?
Why didn't you unload
the stuff last night?
Because I was tired, that's why.
If you don't believe me,
you can ask my mother.
Why do you keep
butting into my life?
Because we found your boss,
Will Darnell, dead in your front seat...
with a shotgun by his side.
- Why?
- I was hoping you could answer that.
Somebody saw your car cruising
behind Buddy Repperton last night.
He's dead too.
So are Don Vandenberg
and Richard Trelawney.
Guess nobody'll be trashing
your car anymore.
Well, all I know...
I got a Cadillac full of parts...
and I'm supposed to be
at school in half an hour.
We'Il take care of the Caddy.
I don't want you touching it.
Honest, I don't know what's going on.
I swear I don't.
May I please speak to Dennis?
It's a girl.
Happy New Year.
Can I come over there?
I need to talk to you.
- What, about Arnie?
- About Christine.
You first.
I'm afraid for Arnie.
I thought you wanted to talk
about Christine.
What do you know about that car?
I know that the guy
who owned the car before Arnie...
Yeah?
His daughter choked to death
in Christine.
How do you know that?
LeBay's brother sold Arnie the car,
and the guy's a jerk.
- He just came out and told me.
- I think I was supposed to be next.
Come on.
Arnie would never do that.
Not in a million years.
I don't think he's Arnie.
It's that car.
I swear it's the car.
Maybe.
I'm going to Arnie's tonight
for New Year's...
- I wouldn't.
- It's okay.
We do it every year.
His folks are going to be there.
Maybe if I get him alone,
maybe he'll talk to me.
What if he doesn't?
- What do you mean?
- I don't know.
What if that car doesn't let him?
Then we destroy it.
Well, come on
let's go
Let's go, let's go
little darlin'
And tell me that
you'll never leave me
Come on, come on
Well, now, swing me, swing me
all the way down there
Come on, let's go, little darlin'
Let's go again once more
My man, you really operate
on those babies.
Yeah, I manage.
We got the old rust bucket tonight.
You wanna watch what you call my car.
She's real sensitive.
Is she?
Sorry, Christine.
Good boy.
Let's motorvate.
Have a beer.
Don't be shy.
My car's your car.
A toast.
Death...
to the shitters
ot the world in 1979.
Come on.
I can't drink to that.
What can you drink to?
What about to us?
You know, to friendship?
Oh, friendship. Right.
That's real good.
Come on!
I want you to see this.
This is great alignment.
You just don't see this anymore.
Don't be scared.
I'm scared for you,
for what's happened to you.
It's this fucking car.
I know you're jealous.
We'll always be triends,
as long as you stick with me.
You know what happens
to shitters who don't.
No. What does happen?
Let's not kid each other.
Who are the shitters?
All of 'em.
Leigh's on your side.
- Oh, yeah?
- She cares a lot about you.
She does.
Yeah.
Don't you like this beer?
I thought you liked beer.
Did you hear what I just said?
Let me tell you
a little something about love.
It has a voracious appetite.
It eats everything...
friendship, family.
It kills me, how much it eats.
I'll tell you something else.
Feed it right,
and it can be a beautiful thing...
and that's what we have.
When someone believes in you, you can do
any fucking thing in the universe...
and when you believe right back
in that someone...
then watch out, world,
'cause nobody can stop you ever!
You feel this way about Leigh?
What? Fuck, no!
I'm talkin' about Christine, man.
No shitter ever came
between me and Christine.
Watch this.
Oh, shit.
Chicken shit!
Man, there is nothin' finer than being
behind the wheel of your own car...
except maybe for pussy.
It's kinda spooky in here, huh?
Looks like they cleaned out
the whole place.
Jesus.
That's where he used to keep it.
Down there.
Yeah.
You better get started.
Yeah!
What do you think?
Let's try it.
Christine's gonna come
through the door.
You better get in the office
and stay out of sight.
Once she gets inside, hit the button
and bring the door down.
Then we'Il have her trapped.
What if he doesn't come?
Christine will.
You better get in the office.
Keep your head down.
When you hear me start this thing up,
that's when you hit the button.
Leigh, don't move!
Stay where you are!
You shitters!
Oh, God.
Arnie's dead.
I'll forever love you
The rest of my days
I'll never part from you
Are you okay?
I think so.
Rock, rock, rock
Oh, baby
Rock and roll is here to stay
It will never die
It was meant to be that way
Though I don't know why
I don't care what people say
Rock and roll is here to stay
We don't care what people say
Rock and roll will always be
I dig it to the end
It'll go down in history
Just you watch, my friend
Rock and roll will always be
It'll go down in history
I wouldn't feel so bad, if I were you.
You two are heroes, you know.
Yeah. A real hero
could've saved Arnie.
We didn't do so hot.
Some things can't be helped.
Some people too.
Yeah.
I love you so, dear
And I'll never let you go
Come on, baby, so
God, I hate rock and roll.