[ Music & Noise ]
[ Music & Foreign Language ]
[ Noise ]
Hi.
It is crazy out there.
Are you feeling any better?
I still feel nauseous.
I found us a boat.
What? Really?
Hey, I'm very thankful that
we're here now, together.
Me too baby.
What time is it?
I'm going to call the kids.
They're sleeping.
Maybe I'll
wake up your mom.
Oh my god,
please don't do that.
What do you--
Hello? Laurie.
Hey babe.
Honey, let me talk to her.
[ Fireworks ]
[ Noise ]
[ Foreign Language ]
Come on.
Okay.
[ Foreign Language ]
So what did he say?
He said that tomorrow
he's going to come the island
to get-- deliver some meat.
[ Motor Whirring ]
[ Music ]
There it is.
[Foreign Language]
[ Music ]
[ Noise ]
[ Noise & Foreign Language ]
Watch your feet.
[ Music & Foreign Language ]
Pescador!
Oi, pescador!
Hey, what are you fishing?
Hey, pescador!
[ Foreign language ]
Francis, what
are you doing?
Come on let's go.
[Foreign language]
[ Water Lapping ]
You know, this island
is famous for its own carnival.
Really?
Yeah.
We just missed it.
[ Water Lapping ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Music & Birds Chirping ]
He reminded me of
the-- this surley sailor.
What's the name--
from the Philippines?
[laughter] From the tattoos.
Yeah, kind of.
Kind of a younger
version of him, yeah.
You don't want to-- okay.
What do you think?
Well, it's
not very crowded.
[Laughter]
[ Music ]
[ Footsteps & Music ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
This is weird.
Hello!
Are you sure
this is the place?
Hola?
[ Noise ]
Looks like they
just up and left.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Beeping ]
They can keep
hiding or whatever,
but I am thirsty
and I need to eat.
Okay, a lot of
soda, a lot of beer.
Oh, no, not the red thing.
I don't-- no.
Salud.
And to eat, I mean--
Well, can I
introduce you in--
No.
All right.
You relax.
I'm going to find a store.
Just sit tight.
Just make it quick.
I'll be right back.
[ Birds Chirping & Noise ]
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Birds Chirping & Noise ]
[ Music ]
Buenos dias!
Hola!
[ Music ]
[ Music & Foreign Language ]
[ Music & Noise ]
Hey.
[ Birds Chirping ]
Hola!
Come on in.
It's hot outside, huh?
You want a soda?
What's your name?
Como te llamas?
[ Music ]
Maria.
Maria, que bonita.
[laughs] Oh, the baby?
You want to be a mom someday?
[ Music ]
Oh, did you feel that?
[ Music & Noise ]
Okay.
Oh.
[ Birds Chirping ]
Oh, Maria!
Maria! Wait!
Do you know
where everybody is?
[ Birds Chirping ]
Hey, I got some food.
Did you see anyone?
Anyone at the store?
I did not.
Oh.
But I did get
you a present.
[laughter] That's nice.
It's not possible.
No, I've been
thinking it about, really.
The only possible explanation is
that, you know, it's carnival.
You know, everybody is
still asleep or drunk.
Yeah, but even
the old folks?
Especially the old folks.
I saw a girl.
Where did she go?
Well, she's right here
but she just left, ran off.
So you're still hungry?
Mm.
We got bread, crackers,
palmitos, some olives, and
oh, look what I got
for Laurie.
Oh.
Right?
That's so cute.
She's going to love it.
Francis, do we have
enough gas to get back?
Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
Yeah?
[ Music & Noise ]
Hi. Buscador, hey!
Hola.
[ Foreign Language & Music ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
Yes. It is nice.
Weird, but nice.
[ Noise & Foreign Language ]
Hello? [foreign language]
I can't understand you.
Can you speak English?
Can you hear me?
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Noise ]
I think it was
the same woman
who called before
when you were out.
Somebody called before?
Mm-hmm.
Did you understand what
she said?
[ Foreign Language ]
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Can you hear me?
Please speak English, pl--
[ Foreign Language ]
What's going on with her?
That woman sounded desperate.
Fran, let's
get out of here.
[ Music & Noise ]
Hey! [Laughter] Oh,
the rest hotel.
The best hotel.
Oh, yeah, best.
[ Music ]
Shall I show you
to your room, Senora?
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Music ]
Come on.
Seriously?
[ Music & Bell Ringing ]
[ Music ]
Okay. I'm going
to find somebody.
[ Music & Noise ]
I'm dripping in sweat.
I would kill for a shower.
[ Birds Chirping ]
Okay, here we go.
I think there're some
Swedish people here.
Oh, really?
Maybe they can tell us
what the hell is going on.
[ Birds Chirping ]
Where are you going?
Going to go look for 'em.
Like, knock on their door?
Be right back.
Okay.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Music ]
[ Music & Footsteps ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Music ]
Beth.
[ Birds Chirping ]
Beth!
There you are.
Francis, come here, quick!
[ Birds Chirping ]
What's up?
I just saw an old man.
Yeah?
Yeah, you see him?
He's right there.
I can't see anything.
Come on.
You can't see his cane
sticking out right there?
Go talk to him.
What are you talking about?
Oh, hey!
Chika!
[ Music ]
[ Music & Child Laughing ]
Francis.
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Nina!
Hey! Hey, hey, hey--
[ Foreign Language ]
Hey!
[ Music ]
Okay, okay.
We'll see through, okay?
[ Music ]
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Music & Children Shouting ]
[ Music ]
[ Noise ]
Beth! Hey!
Go inside.
What is going on?
Beth, go inside now.
Hey! Give me that.
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Laughter ]
Come back here.
[laughter] Hey!
Hey!
What was wrong with her?
I don't know.
What are you doing?
Oh my God, are you bleeding?
[Inaudible Remark] Why
aren't you talking to me?
Are you hurt?
No, I'm not.
I'm fine. These kids
killed that old man.
What kids?
That little girl?
I went to get alcohol
and stuff to clean him up.
I came back and
then [noise] tied--
these little fucking kids, these
kids, they had tied him up
and they were-- they slaughtered
him, this old man.
They killed him.
Oh my God.
[ Music & Noise ]
They wouldn't stop laughing.
We have to get
out of here, now.
Just give me a second.
No, we don't
have time to think.
We have to go right now.
Beth, let me think.
I mean I don't know that
ur boat is still there.
There's all those
ids on the dock.
Let's just-- okay?
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Inaudible Remark ]
Hello? Can you hear me?
[Inaudible Remark] I can
hear you, where are you?
[Inaudible Remark]
Where are you?
Hello, hello, hello!
[ Noise ]
Okay. This is what
we're going to do.
We're getting out
of here, okay?
Okay?
I'm going to go upstairs.
Look, look to the suites.
No!
You're going to stay here.
You're going to
watch that door.
If you see anything or you
hear anything, you scream.
No! I'm coming with you.
No. Beth, I need
you here, okay?
Take this.
I'll be right back.
[ Noise ]
If you see
anyone, just scream.
[ Music & Noise ]
Jesus! Fuck!
[ Music ]
Francis?
[ Noise ]
[ Music ]
Francis? Francis?
Francis! [screams]
[ Foot steps & Music ]
Beth!
[ Noise & Music ]
Woo! Hey!
[ Music ]
Hey! You!
[ Foreign Language & Noise ]
It's okay.
[ Discussion in
Foreign Language ]
He said that,
all the kids woke
up the same time last night,
they're laughing and shouting
and they all started
running into the houses
and attacking all the adults.
[ Discussion in
Foreign Language ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Radio Voiceover & Music ]
Well, it seems like it's
only happening here.
[Foreign language]
[ Noise ]
Hello? Hello?
[Inaudible Remark]
Where are you?
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Noise & Screams ]
We got to do something.
[ Discussion in
Foreign Language ]
[ Noise & Music ]
[ Music ]
[ Panting ]
Beth, it's me.
[knocking on door] Beth?
Beth? We're going now.
We're going.
[ Foreign Language ]
Did you find her?
She's dead and
everybody's dead.
Papa? Papa?
What is that?
Senor?
[ Foreign Language ]
Papa?
Senor, por favor.
[ Foreign Language ]
Senor?
[ Music ]
Por favor.
Senor!
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Woman Crying ]
Oh my god.
Shh. Okay.
[woman sobbing] It's okay.
I know it's hard for you
but we have to run now.
Come on.
No. I can't.
Just leave me here.
Go find out.
Beth, look at me.
We have to run, all right?
We're going to make
it out of here.
We have to go.
Now.
I can't.
Come on.
I don't think
I can keep up.
Come on.
[ Music & Gasping ]
Ah!
Hurry up.
Come on.
Beth! Come on.
Get up!
I can't.
Get up.
Come on.
I can't.
Come on!
Come on.
[ Music & Gasping ]
Come on. Almost there.
Come on.
[ Music & Noise ]
Fuck! Come on!
Come on! Come on!
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Engine Starting ]
Fuck! Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Come on.
Go, go, go, go.
Yeah.
Francis.
[motor revving] Go!
Go! Go!
[ Music & Noise ]
How are you feeling?
You okay?
Ah.
We're getting out
of here, all right?
Just hold on a second.
Just hold on a second, okay?
I'm going to throw up.
Okay. Okay,
there's something here.
Here. Hold on. Hold
on. Hold on. Hold on.
There's a shack.
I'm a going to through.
Just wait and sit.
Can you move?
Okay. Good.
Nice and easy.
Come on.
[ Noise ]
Just wait. Just wait.
I can't.
Just hush.
[ Noise ]
Come on. [Inaudible Remark]
Okay. Hola!
[ Foreign Language ]
I definitely think
I need some water.
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Pause ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Foreign Language ]
Francis.
[ Music ]
We got to go.
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Music ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[Inaudible Remark]
Come on, come on.
Why aren't you moving?
Come on.
Move.
Come on!
[ Music & Noise ]
Oh, damn it!
[ Noise ]
Francis, what
are you doing?
No!
[ Noise ]
[ Music & Noise ]
Go, go, go.
[ Music & Shouting ]
Are you okay?
Beth, are you hurt?
[ Music & Noise ]
Come on.
What?
Back here, come on.
[Inaudible Remark] Back here.
[ Music & Noise ]
Can't get in.
Get in or you'll
be [inaudible].
Get them.
What? [Noise]
Can't get in!
Get out of the way!
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Inaudible Remark ]
Francis! Get down.
[Gunshot]
[ Music ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Crying ]
Why are they doing this to us?
Why the fuck --
Shhh. Hey,
they're gone now.
What do we do with them?
[ Crying ]
Why?
Shhh.
Why did you kill
that little boy?
Look at me now.
Hey, look at me.
I can't take it.
Shh.
Everything's okay now.
Okay? Okay?
You scared them.
Let's just wait here, okay?
[ Noise ]
[Foreign Language]
I didn't see anybody.
[ Noise ]
Drink this.
[ Music ]
[ Foreign Language ]
[Child Shouting]
Do you hear that?
[ Noise ]
What is that?
I don't hear anything.
They're laughing.
[ Noise ]
Beth.
What?
Hey. Baby,
you're imagining.
Yeah, yeah.
No. Do you hear that?
It's him. He [inaudible].
It's him.
No, no, no, no, no.
He's the one.
No, no.
No.
[ Music ]
What's going on?
[Groaning]
Something is wrong.
[ Groaning ]
Okay. Okay, fuck.
Okay, we're going to--
we'll probably going to
have the baby right now.
Are you doing contractions?
Ooh.
Baby?
[ Groaning ]
[Background noise] Okay,
let's just sit down.
Come on. Come on now.
[groaning] What are
you feeling, Beth?
Come on help me out, baby.
Sit down.
Feel it.
It's stabbing me.
I don't feel anything.
I don't feel anything!
You don't feel it?
All right.
[groaning] Let it out.
[Inaudible Remark] Take
it out, it's killing me.
It's killing me!
Okay, okay!
Okay! Hold on!
It's killing me!
Okay!
Hold on!
She touched me.
Okay.
Okay. Come on now.
Come on. Hang in there.
Come on. Beth?
Beth? Beth.
Ah.
Beth? Come on.
Beth? Come on now.
Beth? [crying] Oh
God, no, no, no.
No. Come on.
[ Music ]
God. Oh my God, no.
No.
[ Sobbing ]
No. No. No.
No. Beth.
[ Sobbing ]
Beth.
[ Sobbing & Coughing ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Noise ]
[ Popping ]
[ Music & Noise ]
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Noise ]
[ Music ]
[ Foreign Language ]