Mr. Gunther?
She can't talk.
I cut her tongue out.
What a shame.
I really liked you.
Liked?
So be it.
Who's there?
Don't stop undressing
on my account, lady.
Really.
I don't mind at all.
You just keep on peeling away.
I like that red.
Looks real hot.
Matches your lips.
Ooh, I like this, too.
Sweet. Kind of slutty.
You know what I like better
than nasty red bras like this?
I like it better
when they're off.
Know what I'd like?
I'd like it if, for once...
you'd use the door instead
of climbing in the window.
I'm gonna come.
Not yet. I'm not ready.
I don't think
I can hold it back, Sophie.
You have to.
I'm not ready yet.
Oh, I'm gonna come, sweetie.
Oh, think of something.
I'm not ready.
Think of what?
All I can think of is coming.
I don't think
I can hold it back.
Don't you dare come,
Hank Peterson.
Are you thinking of something?
- What are you thinking of?
- I don't know.
- Alaskan zombies?
- Oh, that's good!
I think I'm...
I think I'm getting close.
You can come now.
I can't...
Hank.
What?
- Do me a favor?
- What?
You won't tell anybody
about this, will you?
Hello? I came to see about
the vacant apartment.
It's been rented.
Creep.
No, really.
No, that's all right.
I'll just...
I'll just pick it up myself.
Thank you.
Hi. Are you the owner?
Um, I came to see about
the apartment.
Is it still vacant?
As a matter of fact, it is.
May I take a look at it?
Why not?
Hey, do I know you
from somewhere?
No, I don't think so.
Are you sure?
Yes, you have a face
I think I'd remember.
You're a beautiful woman.
Oh, why that's...
Uh, thank you. Um...
My name is Lori Bancroft.
You don't mind
if we don't shake?
This way, please.
Pretty girl.
Yeah. Mr. Gunther always runs
to the pretty ones.
What do you suppose
his secret is?
How do you mean?
Well, everyone
has a dark secret.
I just wonder what his is.
It's wonderful.
I love it.
It's just the right size.
It's affordable.
It's not anything like
that creepy old haunted house...
I lived in last year.
What a nightmare.
I'm convinced the man
across the hall was a vampire.
Well, maybe he wasn't
a real vampire, but...
You know what I like best
about this place?
I have no vampires.
That's good.
No, I like it because it's
walking distance to school.
You do rent
to college students, don't you?
Mm-hmm. Yes, I do.
If I find they are the right
choice for the apartment.
I try to be selective.
Well, that's good.
You should be...
selective.
This is a great kitchen.
Will you take it?
Pardon?
The apartment...
will you take it?
I need to know now.
Sure, I'll take it.
It's perfect.
It's a deal, then?
Well, you bet.
It's a deal.
May 8, 1986.
I used to kill
in the name of science.
Now I kill...
because
I'm addicted to killing.
It's the only way
I can feel alive.
Now, Martha,
let's see, where was I?
It's the part
where I talk about father...
sending mother and me
to Argentina in 1944.
June '53,
I finish medical school and...
begin my practice.
Martha, it isn't good
if you don't eat.
Come here, please.
You must eat, Martha.
Come on, another one.
Swallow it down. Come on.
I can't kill you.
Who would I talk to
if you are dead?
Hi, Karl.
Hey, could you give me a hand?
Sure.
You have a sweet tooth.
- Oh, well, they were on sale.
- A sackful?
Oh, why is it
I can never find my key?
Oh, I have a master key.
I'll open your door.
Oh, I'm such a goofball
sometimes.
- Thanks.
- There you are.
You're welcome.
How about a glass of wine,
Karl?
No, no, I couldn't.
I don't drink alcohol.
It poisons the body.
Oh, it's a small vice, Karl.
Everybody has
at least a few vices.
- Don't you have any vices?
- Like what?
Oh, I don't know, the usual...
drugs, gambling...
fast cars, women.
- Well?
Well, say something.
I had women, OK?
It didn't work out.
Jessica here
is our most famous tenant.
Really? What are you
famous for, Jessica?
I'm a soap opera actress.
I play a soap opera actress
on a soap opera.
- Are you serious?
- I'm afraid so.
Here, Lori,
try this on for size.
- What is it?
- Tequila milk shake.
- Gotta say no to that.
- Oh, come on. Be a sport.
What do you think?
It's the worst stuff
I ever tasted.
Oh, it is, but, honey,
it does wonders for your woes.
I just can't figure it out.
It seems every time
I start sleeping with a guy...
with any sort of regularity...
he disappears on me...
without so much as a "Been
nice knowing you, Harriet...
"but I've got to be moving on."
My latest fellow and me,
we were just starting...
to get good at it
when he just up and whooshed.
Gone, like a fart in a storm.
I didn't mind that he was
undependable, unemployed...
uncivilized, uncouth, uncool,
and lazy as a pig.
From the sound of it, Harriet,
you were probably better off.
Honey,
alone again is never better off.
Anyway...
enough of this poor little ol'
pitiful-as-a-dog me shit.
Drink up.
Man...
That was close.
Don't scare me like that.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
Mr. Gunther...
I hate to bother you
this late at night, but...
would you mind going down
to my apartment?
- Sure.
- There's a strange noise.
- Vampires?
- No, no, no. Not this time.
More like The Exorcist.
Would you like to come in,
Lori, for a moment?
Thank you, Mr. Gunther.
It's... it's late.
Are you sure?
Well, I only came up here...
because I was disturbed
by the noise.
Oh, it was probably the rats.
Isn't there something
you can do?
- Sure, I'll take care of it.
- Thank you.
Are you sure you don't want
to come in?
Thank you, Mr. Gunther.
Good night!
Good night, Lori.
I was chief surgeon
at the National Hospital...
when I began
practicing euthanasia.
As a doctor, I was able to end
their pain by mercy-killing.
Then, in 1971...
a very strange thing happened.
I began reading
my father's diaries...
and was shocked to learn
that euthanasia...
was the same word
he used as an excuse...
to kill Jewish people.
Euthanasiengruppen.
Thank God
I have a sense of humor.
It makes life much easier
if you can laugh.
We don't have to love forever
Just tonight
We don't have to say
sweet whispers
Just tonight
We don't have to be true lovers
Just kiss me tonight
We don't have
to hold each other
Just tonight
We don't have to say
"I love you"
Just for tonight,
lovers tonight
Hold me tonight
Make me believe
You need me tonight
I'm coming, Sophie.
Don't make me feel like a fool
Don't think
that I would ever cry for you
But why should I want
one more night with you
When I don't really love you
Anymore?
Hank Peterson,
will you quit playing around...
and just get in here?
I'm hot.
So be it.
Dr. Gunther?
My name is Joseph Steiner.
Do you remember me?
May I come in?
Please let me alone.
Dr. Gunther, I have spent
three years looking for you.
You should know by now
that I'm a very tenacious man.
You were not easy to find,
but I found you.
And I am not going to go away.
Just a moment.
You are a murderer, Dr. Gunther.
Oh, I can't prove it.
Not yet anyway.
But during the five years
you were the chief resident...
at the National Hospital
in Buenos Aires...
sixty-seven people
admitted under your care...
with routine illnesses died.
And, as you know, Dr. Gunther...
one of those sixty-seven
was my brother.
Mr. Steiner...
I'm a doctor
for twenty-seven years.
I delivered babies,
I healed the wounded...
and I cured the sick
every day of my life.
Surely,
some of my patients died.
One of them was your brother.
I'm sorry about that,
but I am only a doctor.
Do you recognize this man?
Ehrenfuhrer SS Officer
Karl Werner Reitlinger.
Principle designer of
the instruments of torture...
used in the Einsatzgruppen in
over 100 Concentration Camps...
executed in 1945...
by the international
military tribunal...
for crimes against humanity.
This is a picture
of your father, isn't it?
Mr. Steiner,
I'm going to ask you to leave.
- Dr. Gunther...
- Mr. Steiner...
I ask you to leave.
Good-bye.
I will be watching you.
December 8, 1973.
I have been practicing
euthanasia as routinely...
as I perform my other
everyday medical procedures.
February 17, 1974.
Due to a clerical error...
I mistakenly terminated
the life...
of a perfectly healthy man.
A quick undetected injection,
and his heart stopped.
To my surprise...
I did not feel remorse.
Instead,
I began to understand...
the unusual sensations...
my father described
in his writings.
Killing is my heroin...
my opiate...
my fix.
It gives me
a god-like sensation...
that goes beyond that
special feeling doctors have...
because they can save lives.
When you can take life away
as easily as you can give it...
that is a feeling
very few people ever experience.
You're a really
difficult woman, Martha.
You haven't even
touched your milk yet.
Do you want some of it?
Here you are.
I'm a happy man, Martha.
Just a sec.
Let me find the switch.
Nice place.
It has your touch.
Thank you.
Can I fix you a drink?
Tonight would be
a good night to drink...
a lot.
Do you go to the ballet often?
About as often as
I'm audited by the IRS.
- How often is that, Alfred?
- Too often.
Both experiences
are terribly boring.
Oh, is that what we were?
Bored?
Sometimes culture confuses me...
and I think
I'm having a good time.
Anyway, that's the way I felt
tonight at the ballet.
You enjoyed the ballet?
Oh, no, not at all. You see,
that's what confused me.
The ballet confused you?
No, culture confuses me.
I just wasn't certain
it was boring...
until you told me
about the IRS.
Jessica, I have no idea
what you're talking about...
but I find you
absolutely charming.
Aren't I?
I like you, Jessica.
I like you, too, Alfred.
You remind me
of my Uncle Morris.
What a rotten human being.
Oh, I didn't mean
you were rotten, Albert.
- I just meant...
- Alfred.
Alfred. I mean, you're just,
like, uh, older, you know?
Like my rotten Uncle Morris.
I'm sorry.
Um, why don't l, uh...
slip into something
more comfortable?
Yes. Why don't you?
What are you doing, Alfred?
Well, l... I just...
I heard this, um...
l... I can't quite describe it.
Well, it... it sounded
like a tap-tap-tapping.
- Mice!
- Mice?
Baby mice.
You get used to it.
Oh, boy...
I like your cane, Alfred.
It's long...
slick...
and hard.
Nice ring.
Thanks.
It has survived four wives.
I'm rather fond of it myself.
Just how rich are you, Alfred?
Oh, does it matter to you
that I'm rich?
Well, yes, it does matter to me
if you are rich or not.
I wouldn't have gone out
with you in the first place...
if you weren't.
But don't be offended by that...
because I don't go out with
anybody unless they're rich.
Jessica,
you are absolutely an original.
Yes, I am.
- Now, what the hell is that?
- Uh, the baby mice.
There. It stopped.
Sorry, kitty.
Jessica, I just cannot
make love with that sound.
I'm really very sorry.
And if I were you...
I'd talk to your landlord
about hiring an exterminator.
"May 9, 1986.
"I am intrigued by
my own special relationship...
"with death.
"Ever since arriving
in America...
"I have meticulously
documented my killings...
"in order to explore
this addiction to death.
"And lately
I have begun to wonder...
"if I have fallen from grace...
"with the world."
Excuse me for disturbing you,
Miss Bancroft.
My name is Josef Steiner.
I spoke with you earlier
on the phone.
Oh, right, right.
Come in.
Do you mind if I smoke?
Personally,
I can't stand smokers.
They're a nasty hazard
to society.
Well, then, why do you smoke?
Compulsive personality type,
I suppose.
As I told you earlier
on the phone, Miss Bancroft...
I'm investigating your landlord
Dr. Karl Gunther...
and part of
that investigation...
involves getting
certain information...
from some of his tenants.
Yes, well,
I don't know if I can help you.
As you can see, I just
moved in here a few days ago.
You're Lori Bancroft,
age twenty-six...
born in Tucson, Arizona.
Journalism student
at Brown University.
Single. Both parents living
in Santa Fe, New Mexico.
Your father is editor
of the Santa Fe Chronicle.
Your sister Kate died
when she was only four.
Just exactly who are you
investigating, Mr. Steiner?
I believe Dr. Karl Gunther
killed my brother.
OK...
Mr. Steiner or...
whoever you are...
I think you better leave.
Miss Bancroft, I have spent
three years trying to prove...
Dr. Karl Gunther
killed my brother.
I just need a few more pieces
of the puzzle.
Look, I don't know you...
and I don't know anything
about Dr. Gunther...
and I'd rather not get involved.
Miss Bancroft, you are involved.
There's something going on
in this building.
I don't know what it is...
but I think
you can help me find out.
Mr. Steiner,
I don't know what kind of ax...
you have to grind
with my landlord...
but I'd just as soon
not be part of it.
No. It should be painful.
Miss Bancroft,
I don't mean to alarm you...
but I would be concerned about
your safety in this building.
Dr. Gunther?
"May 9, 1986.
"Like my father...
"I am fascinated...
"by the delicate balance
between life and death..."
"good and evil."
So be it.
Heil, heil Hitler!
I am my own God...
my own jury...
and my own executioner.
Heil, Gunther.
Who's swimming in your bathtub?
What?
Sophie,
we need to get out of here.
Sweet whispers, just tonight
We don't have to be true lovers
Just kiss me tonight
We don't have
to hold each other
Just tonight
Become a friend of the rats.
Sieg heil!
Get off!
Oh, God!
So be it.