Blackie!
I'll be right back.
I'm just gonna tie him up.
Calm down.
Calm down!
Neve?
Is... is that you?
It's Neve!
Call here parents.
Shh.
Calm down, Neve.
It's gonna be all right.
What happened?
What was she doing in the forest?
Henry and Maud are coming.
They're close.
They think she's afraid
of the house,
that she jumped out
of the window to escape.
Neve, do you hear?
Your parents are coming.
Oh, God, Lucas,
look at her mouth!
Jesus Christ!
Shh, Neve, Neve...
Neve...
Shit.
Her tongue has been cut.
Looks like a bite.
Who did this to you?
Was it the dog?
Neve...
Neve, what happened?
Ryan and Lucy,
go back upstairs, now!
She's covered
in scratches and bruises.
She must have fallen,
either with the dog or earlier.
Oh my God.
What's all this blood?
- Oh, God...
- Who did this to you?
Did someone break in
to the house?
Why did you jump?
You could have killed yourself.
Okay, let's go, now.
Come on, come on.
It wasn't me-e-e!
It wasn't me, Daddy!
Okay, let's go upstairs.
Mommy's upset, let's go.
Shh. Shh, shh...
Who is that?
Do you know them?
Hi.
Come in.
Maud, Neve, come downstairs.
Look who's here!
Sit down.
- Would you like some tea?
- Yes, please.
Please.
How are you?
Not too shaken up?
She looked so terrified.
That wound...
I don't know what to think.
I'm gonna ask advice
from a friend in Galway,
who's a shrink.
Hiya, Neve.
How you feeling?
We came to see how you are.
Say hello, Neve.
You've got to
exercise your tongue.
Hello.
Are you all right?
Two years is not long enough.
I'm sorry we couldn't be there.
I know Mary loved Henry.
He was her favorite doctor.
I just hope she soon
settles into the house.
A shelf fell down yesterday.
It was my fault, I didn't
put it up properly, but...
She thinks things move.
The house creaks, it's normal.
She's forgotten what it's like
living in the country.
But, if she doesn't settle,
then we'll have to move.
Even if it means
going back into town.
After only one month now,
it's a bit of shame,
but, still...
And we're gonna have to
do her bedroom up again.
Let her choose everything
this time.
Maybe she'll feel better then.
And I've cut the branches down
outside her window.
They were casting shadows
over the wall.
We had to do that, too,
for our kids.
They were scared stiff by them.
And leave a night light
on for her.
Oh, we bought one of those
this morning.
Do you not miss living in town?
With your high class patients?
No, I'm fed up with all that.
Besides, the country's better
for the kids.
That's enough, Neve.
Leave him alone.
How many times
have we told you, dammit!
I'm sorry.
Neve is still
very jealous of her brother.
She doesn't mean to hurt him,
but children don't always realize
how violent they can be.
You're still a little tired,
sweetheart.
Go upstairs and have a rest,
and I'll come up and see you.
Nat?
You okay?
Yeah, I just...
I have this ringing in my ears.
Hmm?
It's... it's okay.
It's gone now.
Come on, let's hurry up.
The kids are waiting on us.
Shh.
Don't be afraid.
Everything's all right.
Trust us.
Can you give Mummy a smile?
A good night kiss?
Mummy...
Daddy...
What's that noise?
Who was that screaming?
Neve!
What are you doing?
Bring your brother back here,
now!
Neve!
Neve, protect your brother!
Go downstairs!
Downstairs!
Go!
Aargh!
Brooke!
...no sign of them.
...to control...
We have recovered two adults,
we're still missing
two children.
Over.
Check around the back.
There's something here.
Come here.
- Come here.
- No!
Aaah!
Ciaran...
Ciaran!
No!
Let go of me!
What's wrong with him?
It's okay, it's okay.
My little brother!
Neve... Neve, it's me.
It's Joseph.
Neve!
Ciaran!
His ribs were compressed
too tight for too long.
He suffocated to death.
That wasn't the smoke.
The cupboard protected them.
She was squeezing him so hard,
could she... have...?
Maybe, but...
I don't think she would have
had the strength.
She's saying that
the house went crazy.
Poor girl.
I mean, even if she doesn't
remember the attackers,
we're gonna try
and keep her here
during the investigation.
I'm not sure where, exactly.
And it's going to take time
to find her a foster home.
We can take her.
Yes, of course.
Of course.
It might take a while.
It would be better for her
to start back at school
at start of term,
so she doesn't fall behind.
We can keep her
for as long as she needs.
We have a spare room.
Well, okay then.
Just the time being.
It'll help me out.
It's very kind of you.
If there's anything you notice,
you let us know.
I better go.
I didn't have
her medical records.
I suppose her father
looked after her.
All those marks and scars...
She had a bad accident
when she lived here
when she was little.
She was a bit of a daredevil.
She must not have changed.
Last week, she cut her tongue
escaping her house.
Last night, was she...
Was she hit or abused
in any way?
I'm not allowed to tell you.
She's had a shock, so...
Don't be surprised if she's
withdrawn or difficult.
Don't cry.
Not in front of her.
Oh...
Nat?
Okay.
It's okay.
I'll be all right.
Neve?
No... No!
Be careful!
I'm Tanya.
I'm the welfare officer
from school.
I'm here to help you.
She's only here
for the time it takes
to find the best possible
solution for her.
Don't go overboard,
or get too attached.
I'm just saying it
for your sake.
You okay?
Do you like your new room?
Another girl...
Another girl
used to live here, but...
she left.
Well, we... we can talk
about that another time.
Did you try any of
your new clothes on?
Do you wanna go
and buy some more?
Do you want to have
a quick wash?
No.
Okay, well...
that doesn't matter.
Dinner will be ready
in about an hour,
if you want to go outside
for a breath of fresh air.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Just looking out the window.
Do you want a glass of water?
Can't you sleep?
I don't know.
Tell me if you're too hot,
or you're too cold,
or you need, ah,
thinner blankets.
If you're frightened,
you can come in
and sleep with us.
Or I can come in
and sleep here with you,
if you prefer.
Okay.
Good night, then.
It was a long war.
They didn't fight
like we do nowadays.
Look at those weapons.
What do you call that long
blade with the handle?
See the soldier standing up
in the center of the picture?
Don't worry, Neve.
You've only missed
the first few days.
You'll soon catch up.
Shush.
I haven't heard the bell yet.
It's a sword.
A sword.
Okay?
Turn to the next page...
Morons, you stink!
- Morons.
- Eww!
I thought it might be nice
if we ate lunch together
from time to time.
Just the two of us.
What do you think?
And what about
the other children?
Are they nice?
I don't know.
And is everything going okay
with Nat and Lucas?
And Ryan and Lucy,
do you get on?
Oh, you're still very sad.
That's normal.
Do you want to talk
about your parents
and your brother?
Not necessarily about
what happened.
We can talk about before.
Your own memories.
Did I tell you about the day
I ate all the caviar
my parents had put aside
for an important dinner?
Do you know what caviar is?
Ow!
Neve.
Are you okay, sweetheart?
Is something the matter?
Tell me.
They're silly, aren't they?
When I'm finished
with these two,
I'll give you a bath, okay?
But not with them,
because you're a big girl now.
Is... is Lucas home yet?
That's enough, you two.
Come on, now.
You know, Neve,
you really must have a wash.
I've left towels and soap
in your room,
but you haven't touched them.
It's been too long now, really.
It can't go on like this.
It can't.
I... I'll help you.
Okay.
Head back so it doesn't
sting your eyes.
You're it!
- You be it.
- Come on, kids.
Come on, stop fooling around,
you need to get dressed now.
Lucy, you... Ryan!
He didn't touch me!
Neve?
What is going on?
This is...
I can't have this.
I'm sorry, Neve.
This is ridiculous.
Come on, get up.
Stand up.
- Neve...
- No!
Come on.
Neve, the water is not clean.
It's already been used,
and it's cold.
You'll feel better afterwards,
you'll see.
Now, now... turn around.
Let me help you.
Don't be scared.
That's the way to do it.
You remember, don't you.
Oh!
Hurt myself with that damn...
Sorry.
No... No!
It's okay, it's just a draft.
Just some clothes on the floor.
Everything's fine, okay?
There's nothing to be scared of.
Trust me.
They've nothing.
Nothing whatsoever,
not even a lead.
I know you spoke
to Joseph today, Neve,
down at the police station.
He came to school.
He wants to punish
those bad people
who did all that nasty stuff
at your house.
So that's why he's persevering.
You do understand?
And also, so it doesn't
happen again.
I've already said it.
It's the house.
We can call
your father's sister later.
The one who lives
in the States.
Wouldn't you like
to see her, or speak to her?
It's my belt.
One of the trouser loops
is broken,
and the belt keeps rising up.
It itches.
Someone at school
thought you were my sister,
that you'd come back.
Ryan!
My dead sister Mary.
You were friends
when you were little.
Your daddy was her doctor.
She had cancer.
Fee, fie, foe, fum!
Finished, finished,
finished, finished!
Lucy, please.
Hey, give that back!
- Give it back!
- Hey!
That's enough.
If you're not back at the table
by the time I've counted to ten,
you're going straight to bed.
One...
Two...
Nat, we're all out of beer.
Three...
Four...
I'll get some.
Ryan and Lucy,
come help me pick a bottle.
- Yaay! The cellar!
- The cellar!
- I'm not scared.
- You're a scaredy cat.
- No, you are.
- No, I'm not. You are.
Ryan, no running.
We used to have
another little girl, but, em...
she died.
We didn't say anything,
because it happened
a long time ago.
That's all.
And we didn't want it
to upset you.
Something touched me!
Ryan, just... I'm gonna
switch the light back on.
Did you knock it over?
That doesn't matter, don't cry.
Neve?
Oh!
Nat?
Nat?!
Stay where you are!
You have to...
Nat!
You okay?!
Are you hurt?
Daddy... Daddy!
What happened here?
- Daddy!
Daddy...
Are you hurt, Ryan?
No.
Shh, shh.
Neve?
Oh, Neve...
What...?
Neve!
Leave her alone, okay?
I'll put these two to bed,
and then I'll-
I'll be right back, okay?
Sorry.
Let's throw everything away
that could harm anyone,
and we'll sort out the rest
tomorrow, okay?
Nat, this is impossible.
Have you seen what she's done?
It's not the same
for Ryan and Lucy.
They were bumping
into everything.
And scared.
They hurt themselves.
But her...
- Why did she...
- I don't know, Lucas.
Don't you think she got scared
by all the screaming
and the noises in the cellar?
Maybe it reminded her
of that night.
I went into her room just now,
and she was so scared,
as if I was gonna...
You've got to speak with Tanya
straight away.
- This is not normal!
- Lucas...
We can't give up on her
at the first problem
we encounter.
She is traumatized.
We'll see tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
♪ Hush,
little baby, don't say a word ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy you
a mockingbird ♪
♪ If that mockingbird won't sing ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy you
a diamond ring... ♪
♪ If that diamond ring
turns brass ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy you
a looking glass ♪
♪ If that looking glass
gets broke... ♪
No, please!
Aah!
What the hell
are you doing there?
Go home!
Didn't you hear me?
Get outta here.
Get lost!
Are you coming outside with me?
Help us, please.
Help us.
Please.
Please...
- Mommy!
- Shut up!
No.
No!
What's going on?
Who's doing that?
Make it stop.
Make it stop!
I'm not doing anything, Mummy!
What is it?
What is it?!
Peter... Peter!
Let her go, Mummy!
Please, I'm begging you!
Neve!
Neve.
Neve, can you hear me?
Jenny will pick
the little ones up
from school,
don't worry about that.
Neve says she hasn't seen
Peter or Emily.
They've disappeared.
Couldn't get anything
out of her.
It's just a coincidence.
I'm not sure.
There are fingerprints
of several children
all over the house,
and Neve's are amongst them.
It doesn't prove anything.
She could have left them
there anytime.
What?
What do you think
Neve has done?
You think she murdered
an entire family?
Nobody's saying that, Nat.
But the circumstances
surrounding both murder scenes
are very similar.
And she ran away
from your house
just when it was happening.
So?
She can't even remember
who killed her parents.
I don't know,
that's what she says.
Children are very easily
influenced.
And these people, these...
murderers...
Maybe she knows them.
Or maybe she's listening
to what they tell her.
I just...
I... I don't know.
What?
Lucas...
Say something!
Maybe it's best just to keep her
out of the way for a while.
Everyone knows everyone's
business around here.
People are superstitious.
They're gonna start
imagining things.
No, she must go
back to school as normal.
You must tell people
to stop talking rubbish.
And I'll do the same.
She'll never get over this
if nobody helps her.
What about your daughter?
She's the same age as Neve,
isn't she?
And she has a birthday party
next week,
you should invite Neve.
It would suit you to keep her
cooped up here,
but Henry helped your
little girl when she was tiny.
People protect themselves.
They protect their kids.
That's all.
No one's going to leave you
in the lurch, Nat, okay?
I'll come by tomorrow.
But I'm asking you
to do one thing.
Keep an eye on her.
She mustn't go out alone,
or sleep by herself.
We can't find her
wandering the streets.
How many different species
can you name from memory?
according to
the estimated figures,
between five and a hundred
million different species
inhabit our planet.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Neve...
Aren't you coming outside?
Yes.
- Why is she here?
- It's her...
- ...the murderer.
- She killed 'em.
Killed her family,
and Peter and Emily's mum.
Hey!
What's going on here?
Come on, break it up.
Break it up.
- What are you doing?
- Why are you being so mean?
- Lucy!
- Come on, come on.
- Stop being so nasty.
- Neve, wait. Neve!
Back, back.
Come on, go play.
Come here, come here.
You're having
your birthday party,
I want you to invite her
at the weekend, okay?
- No, Mummy, please no.
- Yes, darling, come on.
- It's okay.
But I have to go
and check on Neve,
she's in there
on her own, okay?
She's got nobody, and you've got
me and you've got Daddy, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay?
Okay.
Now, go on.
Be good.
Neve.
Shall we go back
to the classroom?
Well, then...
I'm having a birthday party
on Saturday.
You can come.
My mum will explain.
Let's stay concentrated,
please.
Got to get out.
Sit back down, Neve.
It'll soon be break time,
and I'll come down to you.
Got to get out of here!
Neve...
Come on, come with me.
What's the matter?
Come on, we'll ask someone
to bring us two lunch trays,
and we can eat in the office.
Just the two of us, okay?
Are you okay?
It's... it's me.
I'm... I'm the one
who does all that.
I make objects move when I cry.
I made... I made them
kill my parents.
Peter and Emily's mother.
Neve, what are you
going on about?
No one can do that.
It's not your fault
if bad things happen.
Come on.
Let's go eat.
And how is everything going
in Nat and Lucas's?
Are they nice to you?
They keep talking to me.
Hugging me, smiling at me.
And don't you like smiles?
A smile is kind, isn't it?
Well, you're right, it depends.
But you can usually tell
if someone's smile
is kind or nasty, can't you?
I heard you'd been invited
to Anne's birthday party
on Saturday.
That's great.
I bet you will have
lots of fun.
I used to have little parties
when I was young.
Well, I already told you
about the one with the big dog.
But there were others.
You want to touch it?
Hey.
You already know each other,
don't you?
But maybe you don't know
that Matthew Collins
is my baby's daddy.
Well, there are a lot
of unanswered questions here.
She was assaulted that night
the first murders took place.
Maybe by that gang.
Ah, I don't know.
I'm wondering if it doesn't
go further back...
if it's not her parents
that abused her that night...
and even before.
She's got all the symptoms
of an abused child.
And look at
Peter and Emily's mother...
It's a strange coincidence.
Try to think about
something else for a while.
For our sakes, and the baby's.
I'll come and pick you up
after school.
Okay?
I better get gone.
See you later.
How was school today?
They told us
about Peter and Emily,
and their mother.
They said we must
always stay together,
and tell someone
if we see a stranger.
We mustn't go into the forest.
Don't' worry, sweetheart,
it won't be for too long.
Here.
You haven't had
too many sweeties today.
Here.
Come on...
I'm gonna read you a story,
and then it's bedtime.
Story about murders?
I think not, sweetheart.
Would you like anything else?
I'm going to my room to read.
Oh, Neve...
Stop pushing me away.
We'll never get on
if you keep on treating us
like your enemy.
Neve, my sweet little kitten...
You can read downstairs,
with us.
I know it seems
like a nightmare,
but one day it'll be better,
you'll see.
Trust us.
Stop it, Neve, please!
You're gonna wake up
Ryan and Lucy.
It's just for tonight, we can't
let you sleep on your own.
Wandering around
the countryside
alone at night like that
is dangerous.
- Shh.
Aaah!
Neve, stop it.
That's enough now.
Stop screaming.
Neve, please, Neve.
Stop it!
Neve...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I just wanted you
to stop screaming,
and come to bed, I...
I just wanted you
to be a good girl.
No, no no.
No, Neve, what are you doing?
Nat...
She'll sleep in her room,
but I'll stay with her.
It's just for one night.
Can block up her window
tomorrow.
Come along, Neve.
Go to sleep, please.
It's late.
What the hell are you doing?!
Who gave you these?
I got them from
the album downstairs.
I like them.
What gives you the right?
Who do you think you are?!
These are ours,
they're not yours!
I forbid you to touch them!
Lucas, have you gone crazy?
She took those,
she was playing with them.
Daddy!
You go to them, I'll stay here.
Neve, why would you take these?
This is our little girl, Mary.
The one who got sick,
do you remember her?
Why would you show them
to Lucas?
It hurts us, we-
We loved her so much.
Then why is she dead?
But Neve...
That wasn't our fault.
She was seriously ill.
There was nothing we could do.
We loved her,
and that had nothing to
do with her being ill.
Try and get some sleep now.
Mary...
Hi, my name is Olivia.
Welcome.
Neve, the other children
are in the garden.
Join them.
Look.
She's the prettiest doll
in the shop.
Do you like her?
Anne loves dolly parties.
Have you heard of them before?
No.
I... I want to go home.
I don't want it.
Ah, we... we can't go home now,
sweetheart.
That wouldn't be very nice
for Anne.
Anyway, I'm sure you'll play
lots of other things,
and there'll be cake,
and presents, and...
I think Colette has even
organized a treasure hunt.
I'll be right here, okay?
- Hello.
-  Hi!
Are you coming to play?
Have fun and be careful.
Give me a shout
when you're hungry.
...so disgusting.
Don't do it again.
They sound like
they're having fun.
Yeah, it was a good idea
of yours.
I'm so glad she came.
Hi, what's your name?
...mentally sick people...
Are you feeling okay?
Do you want a glass of Coke?
Can I see your doll?
She's lovely.
I don't like the dress.
It's pink.
It should be blue.
On second though,
she's not very lovely.
Is she bold?
Do you have to punish her?
Mine's crazy, I have to look
out.
Awake, asleep.
She's ugly and fat.
Ooh...
It's not your ear again, is it?
You really must see Gwendoline.
I'm sure it's tinnitus.
I've got her number,
I'll go get it for you.
Thank you.
Hang on a sec.
Oh!
Neve!
Get away from there, Neve!
Neve, come here!
Colette!
No...
Neve, don't!
Be careful!
Get in the kitchen!
- Go on!
- Neve!
Go, what are you doing?!
- Go, quickly, move!
- Neve!
Neve?
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm out looking for her.
No, I want to be the one
to find her.
Are they hurt?
Well, they're talking
a load of rubbish.
Well, we left lit candles
on the table.
It's our own fault.
What do you think Neve
is actually capable of?
Well, what else
could it have been?
No, I don't want to call Lucas.
I want to find her myself.
He's looking after
the other two.
Neve?
Who's there?
Who is that?
Neve...
You frightened me.
Neve.
- Neve...
Who's screaming like that?
Don't be afraid.
Neve.
Neve?
Where are you?
What's going on?
Neve, please say something.
What...
What did they do
to you and your brother?
Neve, help me.
I've hurt myself.
Lucas...
I'm in Henry and Maud's house.
Neve...
Neve, give me my phone back.
What's going on here, Neve?
What the hell are you doing?
Answer me.
Answer me, Neve.
Answer me!
Gently.
Don't be afraid.
Let me do it.
See?
It isn't hot.
You're tired.
You're hungry.
But be good children.
Mommy and Daddy are tired, too.
Arrgh!
Aah!
You talked to the children
about what they said at school?
Not yet.
They'll have to be punished.
They don't realize
everything we do for them.
Back then...
people didn't used to get
involved in education.
Nowadays, everybody has
their own opinion.
Are you giving me
a goodnight kiss?