[Creature Growls]
subtitled by  ienishtien
- [People Chattering]
- ##[Industrial]
[Man]
That's a hot babe comin'up.
[Chattering Continues]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Growling Continues]
[Chattering]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Oh, yeah, baby. You know
what daddy likes, don't you?
Ooh.
[Grunts]
- [Crowd Gasps]
- [woman] what the hell is that?
- [People Screaming, Shouting]
- He's got a gun! He's got a gun!
- Come here!
- [Screaming, Shouting Continue]
[Man]
He grabbed some chick!
- Hold it! Let her go!
- [Screaming] Help!
Let the girl go.
- Freeze, asshole!
You know what we got here.
- We'll do it!
[Screams]
- Let's go.
- [Continues Screaming]
[woman]
Oh, my God!
Stop, damn it!
[Shouts, Indistinct]
- No! Lance!
- [Grunts]
[woman]Josie... You should
let him take some nudes.
- Wayne takes awesome nudes.
- Yeah, right. That's gonna happen.
- You have a problem with that?
- I've got a huge problem with that.
I don't want my girlfriend's naked body
plastered all over the Internet.
Okay. Nudes, idiot.
Not girly pictures.
wayne's an artist.
He's not a pornographer.
- Here. You don't believe me?
- No.
Mm-hmm?
Yeah, fine. Whatever.
They're ethereal.
They're sensual and erotic.
They're naked pictures. Christ!
Look at them. Say it how it is.
You're afraid, when everyone
sees what a hot piece of ass
Josie is, you'll lose her.
It's safer just to keep her
as a part-time waitress.
[Laughing]
I am not afraid of losing her.
Then what's the big deal?
Be supportive. Stop being a prick.
Me? You're the one
who started this.
You're the one who talked her
into this damn thing.
[Mimicking] You should be a model.
You'll make a load of money.
why not?
Chick has it goin' on.
Besides, she ain't gonna pay
for medical school by waitressing.
You should stop treating her
like a possession.
She's a smart girl.
Money won't buy her. So stop trying.
why does she keep breaking plans
with me? That's what I wanna know.
All right, so...
why are you askin' me?
'Cause you're her friend?
- That's right, I am her friend.
- Yeah.
And I don't talk
about her business.
Did you and Josie
have another fight?
Oh! What, you guys sit
around and talk about it?
what happened to not talking about
other people's business?
Okay. You did get
in another fight.
You know what? Fuck you.
Fuck her and fuck...
- Fuck the both of you guys.
- Yeah, in your dreams.
- ##[Continues]
- Watch it. Comin' through.
[People Chattering]
[Sirens wailing In Distance]
- We've got to hurry.
I'll go with the truck.
Yeah.
- Hurry.
- Why?
we need this guy
in lockdown.
what's the hurry?
I don't understand.
Trust me.
[Banging, Pounding]
what the hell's
going on in there?
Lance!
[Growling]
[Man Shouting, Indistinct]
Get that out of here!
[Loud Growl]
- Turley!
- Lance!
Lance! Get out!
Officer down! Officer down!
- [Police Radio Beeps]
- [Dispatcher Over Radio, Indistinct]
Oh, my God!
[Police Radio Chatter
Continues, Indistinct]
[Growling]
- [Growling]
- [Gunshot]
[Chain Link Fence Rattling]
- [Police Radio Beeping]
- He tore right through the back panel...
between the prisoner compartment
and the driver's cab...
killed the driver
and Detective Hartigan, then got away.
- [Police Radio Chatter]
- Broke through the access doors.
I've never seen
anything like it.
- [Radio Static]
- [Tapping]
[Seat Belt warning Chiming]
- Hey. Where we going?
- [Police Radio Chatter Continues]
Do yourself a favor, McGowan.
Don't ask a lot of
questions right now.
[Engine Starts]
Yeah.
This is some secret
operation, right?
- You're D.E.A.
- [Sighs]
F.B.I.?
Or maybe working
with the D.E.A. or F.B.I.?
Hey. I need a little help
understanding here.
we just bailed
on a crime scene.
- [Squad Room Chatter]
- [Object Thuds]
what's going on around here?
why the shiny guns?
what happened
back there in the truck?
Did you ask all these questions
back in school, McGowan?
Just because you're assigned to me for
a couple days to learn the ropes...
doesn't give you the right
to come in here and start asking.
All right. Look, I understand
that at graduation day at the academy,
they make you feel all bright and shiny
and on top of the world...
like you know everything,
but you don't.
This is the real world.
Things go on out here...
things you've never heard of,
things you can't explain.
Never seen anything break through
steel like that. That's for sure.
I really don't have time
to catch you up to speed,
so I suggest you do what I say
when I say it.
And maybe, just maybe, we'll make it
through the night in one piece.
- That's not good enough
for me, Detective.
- I lost my partner tonight!
He is dead.
There are a bunch of people
out there that are gonna die
tonight that have no idea.
That thing that killed him
is still running around.
I suggest we focus.
All right.
All right, McGowan.
I'm gonna give you the 99-cent answer
to all your questions,
but I suggest you take very good notes
'cause I'm only going through this once.
Do you remember
the Moonlight Slasher murders?
Yes, of course.
The Moonlight Slasher
is a werewolf.
- A werewolf.
- Yes, a werewolf... half man, half wolf.
- Try to keep up, McGowan.
- [Laughing] I don't understand.
Stop trying to understand.
Listen.
- But werewolves?
- Yes, I know. Werewolves.
They exist.
They are very real.
- Get over it.
- [Laughs]
I'm just gonna tell you exactly what
Hartigan told me two years ago...
when I first came
onto this detail.
There's werewolves, and there's
hybrid werewolves.
Now, werewolves are normal...
normal werewolves.
You're shittin' me. You must have gotten
cracked in the head back there.
You saw what that thing did back there.
You saw what happened to Hartigan.
Tell you somethin'?
All right.
Nine hundred years ago,
a human Saxon knight
made it with a werewolf. Boom.
we got hybrid werewolves. And the biker
guy back there... the one that got away,
the one that killed Detective Hartigan
and the other officer,
ripped through solid steel
and made you shit your pants...
he's a hybrid werewolf.
That hybrid werewolf is out there
right now searching out...
the next matriarch
pure-blood.
He needs to mate with her,
breed out the next generation
of pure-blood werewolves.
That's the end
of the history lesson.
This is where we come in.
First of all, I don't give a shit how
or why these hybrids exist, but they do.
Fact is, they're enough of a problem
that there's a quiet little office...
in the back of the Detectives' Bureau
dedicated to dealing with them.
That, before tonight, was Detective
Hartigan and me. Now it's just me.
Slow down.
Just slow the fuck down.
- You expect me to believe all this crap?
- I don't care what you believe.
All right?
A partner's dead tonight.
A very good cop was killed,
a good friend of mine.
And I sure as hell don't plan on letting
that thing get away with it.
Now, you're either
with me or not.
- You have exactly
zero seconds to decide.
- Give me a second.
[Sighs]
Fine.
Fine, okay? Fine.
welcome to the party.
McGowan.
[Sighs]
The day started out so... normal.
- [People Chattering]
- ##[Country western]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Soup and salad.
And grilled cheese.
[Plates Clattering]
Hey, I'll take Mary's dinner.
There you go.
Hey, Mary.
Got your favorite.
Oh, bless you, child.
Oh, you shouldn't have
gone to all the trouble.
I... I do just fine.
Oh, it's such a relief
to sit down.
Mm-hmm.
It's beautiful, huh?
Oh, I could sit
and stare at that for hours.
Are you feeling all right?
Yeah. I feel fine. Why?
well, maybe you should
just take it easy tonight.
Go home early. Curl up
with a good book, you know?
Tonight is not
a good night to be out.
what are you, a fortune-teller
or something?
[Chuckling]
No. I just, um... know things.
Then tell me my future.
Tell me that I'm going to be
rich and famous...
and that I'm going to be accepted
to medical school...
and do something really important,
really special.
I don't know. Sometimes...
I feel like
there's something...
that I'm supposed to do.
Like-Like a calling
or something.
I don't know.
How long have you
felt like this?
My whole life.
More so lately.
why are you always
so concerned about me?
You're always
looking after me.
How come?
Oh,
I suppose you could just
say it's in my blood.
[Laughing]
well, go on. It's your favorite.
I'm sorry. I...
I didn't mean to touch you.
It's all right.
I'd better get back to work.
Good night.
Good night, Josie.
[Dispatcher Over Police Radio]
Nineteen-Adam-four, please respond.
[Sighs]
Two-Adam-seven, please respond.
That's us.
No. No more radio.
Not tonight.
But how are we...
Never mind.
These look like silver.
[Scoffs]
Boy, you don't miss much,
do you, McGowan?
[Sighs]
[Growling]
- You can't be hungry?
- I gotta talk to somebody.
Mary?
- Oh.
- Lance is gone, Mary.
we had him.
He tore through
solid steel.
Killed Lance, got away.
It was unlike anything
I'd ever seen before.
He was stronger than
all the others combined.
Detective McGowan.
She's all right.
- What did he look like?
- Biker, low-rider type.
Leather, denim, tattoos.
- Darkwolf.
- Who's the Darkwolf?
Uh, it's not "who."
It's "what."
- Help me stop it.
- I have been protecting
this bloodline for 900 years.
I'm sorry. Can someone
clue me in here?
For nine centuries,
this has been handed down...
from protector to matriarch,
on the eve of her first transformation.
The beast that you encountered tonight
is like no others.
He's much stronger
and much more dangerous.
He's a dark prince,
a king in waiting... a Darkwolf.
what's he waiting for?
He's not "waiting for."
He's "searching for."
He seeks the girl.
He desires to mate with her.
wait. You're saying this "dark prince"
is Prince Charming...
and this girl's some
sort of Cinderella?
Ah, you're catching on,
Snow white.
Mary... how do I stop this thing
before anyone else dies?
Darkwolf is not going
to be easily defeated.
He can only be killed
with silver through the eye.
The man that you met... the biker...
he is the human form of Darkwolf.
You know, if this thing
is looking for this girl,
it seems to me... you've got the girl,
you get the bad guy.
Mmm. You're just smart
as a dull tack, aren't you?
Hey, I've had just about as much as
I'm gonna take from you...
McGowan. Mary, she's right.
If this girl's in danger, she should
know about it so she can be protected.
No. There can be
absolutely no interference.
The girl must see the signs
for herself.
She must feel the burning
of the first transformation.
without that, she will
never know her destiny.
If he tracks her down
and mates with her,
my race will perish,
and there will be more
soldiers of darkness coming.
And without us, they will
conquer your race as well.
Humans will be no more.
[Growling]
[water Running]
- [Gasps]
- Oh.
- Where's the fire?
- Sorry.
- Let me help you.
- Thank you. I... Thanks.
- ##[Jazz]
- [People Chattering]
No turkey sandwich
tonight, Turley?
No. Not-Not tonight. I'm just
waiting for a couple coffees to go.
Oh, here. I'll get that.
- Nice.
- What's that?
Sunglasses.
[Sighs]
who's that in the bathroom?
where's Hartigan tonight?
He, uh...
He died earlier tonight.
Oh, my God.
- I'm so sorry. I...
- Yeah. It's all right.
what happened?
A, uh... arrest went bad.
God, you guys come here
all the time.
I'm really, really sorry.
Thanks.
Hey, girl. You're lookin' hot.
Are you ready?
- Yeah. Hey.
- Hey, babe. What's up?
I just... I gotta go clock out,
and you guys go sit in a booth over
there, and I'll be there in a minute.
[Stacey]
Move it, chick.
Tom. Oh...
Right. We'll, uh,
be in this booth right here.
what is the matter with you?
Are you trying to mess things
up between the two of you?
- Who does this guy think he is?
- Who?
- This guy right here.
- [Loudly] You mean that guy there?
- Yes.
- [Laughing] Yeah.
Yeah, you know something?
You're right.
The nerve of that asshole. He's just
sitting there, saying nothing...
paying no attention to us,
totally minding his own business.
I say we kick his ass.
Come on.
[Low Growl]
[Growling Continues]
[Screams]
Oh. Uh, thanks
for the coffees.
- I'm sorry about your partner.
- Yeah.
[McGowan Screams]
- [People Gasping]
- Somebody call an ambulance!
- McGowan!
- [Gasping] I saw it.
- Shh! Don't talk. Don't talk. Mary.
- [Crying]
[Man]
I think she may be with that guy.
[Growling]
Mary. Hang on.
Help's on the way.
- [Moaning]
- Mary?
Stay back. Mary?
Take her, quickly...
be-before it returns.
who? Take who?
The girl. Take... the girl.
who's the girl, Mary?
I don't know who the girl is.
- Her?
- You have to-to protect her now.
I can't any longer.
what about the other
protectors like you?
I-I am the last.
I'm not a protector, Mary.
I can't baby-sit some girl.
If you have the girl,
it-it will come to you.
Don't let her touch anyone.
what? Why?
If she touches the skin,
Darkwolf will follow
that scent,
and-and it will kill them.
She's a waitress, Mary.
She could've touched hundreds of people.
[Crying]
we're all-all she has now.
- [Sirens Approaching]
- The-The silver...
silver bullet will...
will protect you.
Mary?
- [Crying]
- What's goin' on?
- What happened?
- Oh, my God. Are you okay?
- [Siren Stops]
- [vehicle Door Opens, Closes]
- [Police Radio Chatter]
- Come on.
wait. Where are we going?
Are you just gonna leave her here?
Detective McGowan's inside.
- Come on.
- Wait a fuckin' minute!
- Hey, back off!
- Who are you?
Police. Back off.
I'm her boyfriend.
She's coming with me.
we-we'll wait for you
in wayne's apartment.
Oh, this is so not cool.
- Okay, everyone, we need
everyone to step back, please.
- Come on. Let's just go.
- Does anybody know this woman?
- What... what is this?
- [Crying]
- You okay?
No! No, I'm not okay.
- You were friends with Mary.
- Mm-hmm.
[Sniffling]
She was a nice old lady.
She never caused
any problems for anyone.
I used to bring her food
when she'd show up.
Mary ever talk to you
about anything?
Sometimes. Why?
Anything in particular?
where are we going?
- Am I under arrest or something?
- No, you're not under arrest.
Look, if I'm not under arrest,
then I-I want you to take me
back to my friends now.
- I can't do that.
- What?
I know my rights, okay?
I didn't do anything.
You're in protective custody, all right?
A material witness.
A witness to what?
I didn't witness anything.
In fact, I was busy
talking with you...
when either of those things
happened, if I recall.
A lot of this probably
isn't making much sense.
It's making no sense!
I'm just a cop caught up
in the middle of this.
I'm not Mary.
I can't do her job.
what does Mary have to do
with any of this?
She was protecting you.
The homeless lady?
- From what?
- All I can do is tell you
what she told me, okay?
You're goin' through a change,
a kind of a transformation right now.
- [Growling]
- And because of that, someone's...
something is trying
to track you down.
why?
To mate with you.
[Gasping]
You're saying...
that there's
something out there...
who wants to hook up
with me?
Uh...
- Let me go!
- Josie! Don't!
Let me go, damn it!
what do you want from me?
I understand this is a lot to deal
with right now. I understand.
Just... I've seen
what that thing can do.
Every full moon,
this thing goes on a rampage...
- [Darkwolf Howling]
- Looking for you.
It's not gonna stop...
till it finds you.
[whimpering]
what am I supposed to do?
[Crying]
I didn't ask for any of this.
It's not your fault, all right?
It's not your fault.
Look, I can do my best
to protect you, okay?
But protecting you
isn't gonna solve the problem.
- I gotta find this thing.
- [whimpers]
I gotta stop it.
- Do you understand?
- [Crying] No!
Josie? I need you
to understand. Okay?
- Shit.
- What?
There's a... a book.
A book Mary gave me...
I lost it.
- She gave me a book to give you.
- To give to me?
Yeah. She said it would
explain everything you
were going through tonight...
the transformation, the...
[Sighs] I must've left it back there
when I was running around.
Obviously, it would've explained
everything a hell of lot better
than I can.
where are we going?
- [Camera Shutter Clicking]
- ##[Techno]
[Man]
Oh, yeah.
[Chattering]
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
All right.
[Continues Chattering]
Yeah. Oh, wow.
That's good.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, babe. Hey.
- Mm!
- Mmm!
- Where you been?
- A whole bunch of shit
went down at the diner.
A cop was attacked,
and some bag lady got killed.
- Seriously?
- No, I'm kidding. Yeah, seriously.
It's probably
gonna be on the news.
- Where's Josie?
- Some cop took her away in a car.
Apparently, she's some sort
of witness or something.
- So we're not shooting.
- You pick up on things real fast, huh?
well, shit! I mean,
I rescheduled because of her.
Sorry. What do you
want me to do?
- [Line Ringing]
- [Camera Motor winding]
[Message Machine]
Hey, it's Josie.
Nice.
Yeah. Anna, Stacey.
- Hey.
- [Scoffs]
[Sighs]
Shit. Miguel!
The film's cold, man.
It was in the refrigerator.
what do you expect?
You were supposed to take it out
of the refrigerator.
I'm a fucking
makeup artist, okay?
I'm not a fucking cook, okay?
[Sighs]
what is this?
She looks like a slut.
I didn't do her makeup.
She did.
You look like a slut.
well, ain't that a bitch.
- [Mumbling, Indistinct]
- So what are we doing here?
[Stacey] waiting to see, I guess.
Cop didn't say how long they'd be.
Fuckin' assholes.
Nobody can tell me where she is.
You tried calling
her cell phone?
Oh. Yeah, I called her cell phone.
I got her voice mail.
She never turns it on.
So what are we gonna do, sit around?
[Scoffs]
Tell me about it.
- She'll call when she's done.
- No.
This is bullshit. I'm not
waiting for her to call. I'm
gonna go find out where she is.
where are you going?
You don't even know where they took her.
I don't know. I'll start
at the nearest police station.
Oh, geez. Hey, you.
Hi.
[Growling]
[Loud Growl]
[Darkwolf Howling]
[Metal Clanks]
Oh, right.
[Grunts]
Son of a bitch.
Hmm.
Don't be reading
someone's private shit.
- What's wrong with you?
- I thought this was yours.
You're saying, if it was mine,
it's okay to go reading it?
Mm-hmm.
Maybe there's
a name somewhere,
a phone number,
and we can get it back to them.
Don't go looking through
everyone's private shit.
! Mira!
[Snaps Fingers]
! Mira!! Venga!
! Mira acqui!
what the hell is this?
This is some weird shit.
will you guys stop being
so goddamn nosy? This is
someone's private thoughts.
No, it's not, babe.
I mean, look.
It's some kind of, like,
notebook or something.
It-It... It's got pictures
and drawings and maps and shit.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
I don't know.
what am I thinking?
[Snaps Fingers]
! Mira!
Hmm? No?
[Howling Playfully]
- Dude, I like it.
- And then we go to the roof?
Shoot against the moon.
Rockin'!
[Hissing]
You guys are
seriously weird.
## [Techno, Loud]
[wayne's voice]
No. Leave a message.
- [Beep]
- [Tom] Pick up, somebody. Hello.
It's Tom. I went out the wrong door
and locked myself in the alley.
- Someone come down and let me in.
- [Beep, Click]
#Snatch a piece of the sky #
#I'm all on fire #
# watch his motion #
#Fuel desires #
#Fan the fire #
# To incredible size #
# where is time #
#I'll be waiting #
# when the lights
don't light up anymore #
# Time will take him #
# when the nights have
washed his dreams ashore #
#I'll be waiting #
#How he sparkles #
# O'er the dreamers #
# Though the years
slice his youth #
#Like a razor ##
##[woman vocalizing]
[Growling]
[Monitor Beeping]
How's L.A.P.D. 's finest
doing? Any better?
Looks like we need
to change this for you.
I'll be right back.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Growling]
[Screaming]
Just, uh...
This is your girlfriend?
what?
Is this your girlfriend?
No. It's my sister.
She died a couple of years ago.
- I'm sorry.
- [Television Clicks On]
It's got to have
made the news.
[Announcer On Tv,
Indistinct]
[TvAnnouncer]
It's currently 79 degrees.
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
[Metal Clicking]
You expecting to go to war?
Yeah.
Downtown Los Angeles
where a homeless woman...
was found dead
outside this local diner,
ironically, just moments
after a police officer...
was unexplainably attacked inside
the diner's restroom.
Now, police sources,
as of yet, are making no comment,
uh, but the rumors
are starting to fly...
that both the homeless woman
and the police officer...
were possibly victims
of a wild dog attack.
Again, this is pure speculation.
There is no need for panic.
- That's the guy.
- We'll give you all the details...
as well as an update
on News Five next.
- Reporting from downtown Los Angeles,
- Who?
I'm Nick Kazinzakis.
The guy I'm looking for.
Do you have a bathroom?
Right there.
- Hey. Maybe I should...
- No. You're not coming in the bathroom.
[Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
[Screaming]
You okay?
[Growling]
[Distorted voice]
Help me!
[Sobbing]
Shh. All right.
You're gonna be all right.
It's all right.
It's all right. It's okay.
- [Muffled Sobbing]
- It's okay. It's okay.
Here. It's okay.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
[Sobbing Quiets]
It's okay. Hey.
It's okay.
[whimpering]
I'm so scared.
Mary was right.
It's happening.
It reversed itself.
It may not reverse
next time.
That guy... on Tv.
He's the one
who's after me?
- Yeah.
- [Crying Softly]
He's a lycanthrope
in human form...
but he has to mate
as a wolf.
Hey.
[Takes Deep Breath]
Thank you.
For what?
I don't know.
For being here...
helping me.
How'd you get involved
with all this anyways?
- Uh...
- Do they have a sign at your office...
down at the police station that says
"werewolf Hunter" or something?
[Both Laugh]
No, not exactly.
I-I just sort of
backed into it.
A couple of years ago,
I was assigned to my partner...
my former partner.
A lot of the larger
metropolitan areas...
Chicago, New York, L. A...
they have special divisions,
and they're assigned
to deal with... special issues.
- Like werewolves.
- Yeah.
Do they got one
for vampires too?
- [Chuckles] Funny you should ask. No.
- [Chuckles]
Oh, there...
There is one good benefit though.
what's that?
we get to hear all
the great werewolf jokes.
- Ooh. Great werewolf jokes?
- Yeah. Like, uh-uh...
- What happened to the werewolf
that ate too much garlic?
- What?
- His bark was worse than his bite.
- Oh, that's bad.
All right. Why-why...
why was the werewolf running so fast?
- Why?
- He was in a hairy.
- [Laughing]
- Or, uh...
why-why... why was the werewolf
arrested in the butcher shop?
- Why? Why?
- Because he was chop-lifting.
[Laughing]
That's awful.
- Or, uh...
- No more! No more! That's bad.
You're okay, Steve Turley.
You're-You're okay too... Josie.
Josie.
I don't even know
your last name.
Pagano. Italian.
[Cell Phone Rings]
Turley. What?
when?
I'm on my way.
[Growling]
[Darkwolf Howling]
You guys ready?
- Let's do it.
- Mm-hmm.
##[Techno]
[Hushed Murmuring]
##[woman vocalizing]
##[vocalizing Continues]
##[Techno Continues]
[Growls]
[Shutter Clicking]
[Growling]
[Beeping]
[Moaning]
Oh, fuck.
- [Growling]
- [Screams]
[Moaning]
[Gasping]
[Sighing]
- [Motor winding]
- I gotta develop this shit right away.
[Laughing]
[Sirens wailing In Distance]
[Police Radio Chatter]
You don't need
to see that.
what made it attack her again?
Doesn't make sense.
- [Josie] what are you talking about?
- Doesn't make sense.
what?
- What?
- Who have you touched tonight?
Touched? What are...
what are you talking about?
Have you touched anyone?
Detective McGowan.
In the diner, you said
you ran into her, right?
[Stammering]
- What are you talking about?
- In the diner, in the bathroom.
You said you saw
Detective McGowan, remember?
- Yes.
- Did you touch her?
- I-I don't know.
I don't know!
[Stammering]
I bumped into her.
She-She...
I dropped my purse,
and she helped me pick it up.
Yes. She helped me.
I did. Why? Why?
Mary said anybody you touched tonight
would be imprinted.
what does that mean?
Your touch.
Your touch, your scent.
Anybody that you touch...
physically that you have contact with...
your scent will be
imprinted on them.
He'll seek them out
looking for you.
what?
This is my fault?
Mar-Mary's dead because of me?
Anyone I touched is gonna die?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Tom.
Tom. He touched me. He held me.
when we were watching
you and Mary, he-he held me.
He touched me!
- Where is he?
- Uh...
- Where is he? Where is he?
- I don't know!
He's over at my friend
wayne's apartment.
Come on.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Wayne in the darkroom?
- Yeah.
- Who called?
Mm, I didn't check
the machine.
[woman, French Accent]
Hi, wayne. This is Caroline.
- You got my pictures yet?
- Bitch.
Pick up somebody.
Hello. Yeah. It's Tom.
I went out the wrong door
and locked myself in the alley.
Someone come down
and let me in.
Oh, my God. He's been
down there this whole time.
Come on. We gotta go down
and let Tom in.
Tom! Hey, you out here?
I wonder how long ago
it was he called.
## [Headphones: Heavy Metal,
Loud, Indistinct]
Tom!
Maybe he already got in.
[Growling]
Yeah. Somebody let him in.
There's no other way
out of here that I know of.
Somebody must have
let him in.
Let's just check up here
a little bit further.
- You coming?
- What the hell else am I gonna do?
- [water Running]
- [Pounding]
- [Pounding Continues]
- Somebody answer the fucking door!
Everybody go and don't
tell me nothin'.
[Pounding Continues]
what?
[Breathing Heavily]
Hey.
Oh, please.
what do you want?
- Where is she? [Grunts]
- Who?
The girl! Where's
the fucking girl?
who? I-I... I haven't touched her,
whoever she is.
- The girl from the diner!
- What diner? Josie?
- [Distorted voice] where is she?
- I swear! She didn't show up!
## [Continues, Indistinct]
# On the seventh day
our love began again #
our sins were washed away #
#Yeah ##
[Growling]
No more. Please.
[Growling Continues]
Oh, fuck me.
[Howling]
wayne, Stacey, this is Josie. Get out of
there now. I don't have time to explain.
There's something in there.
You gotta get out of there.
Somebody pick up!
Shit! They're not answering.
Tom!
where does this go?
You know?
I have no idea.
wayne would know.
God, it looks like somebody
pulled it open recently.
Maybe it leads out.
Tom?
Oh, God, my phone.
I'll just call him. Geez.
## [Continues]
## [Man Singing, Indistinct]
what the hell?
[Phone Ringing]
- You're going in there?
- Yeah. Come on.
[Ringing Continues]
Tom.
Tom?
That ringing...
that's his phone.
Tom, where the hell are you?
Tom!
watch out.
- Shit.
- [Ringing Continues]
I hear it.
where is it?
Be careful.
Uh!
- [Screaming]
- Oh, my God!
[Both Screaming, Shouting]
[Darkwolf Breathing Heavily]
- Damn it! Knock!
- Wayne...
- What if I'd been
in the middle of something?
- Tom's dead.
He's been stabbed
or cut up... something.
- Whoa. What the hell
are you talking about?
- Come on!
- Look.
- Oh, dude.
Oh, my God. This is...
Oh, this is harsh.
[Darkwolf Howling]
Oh, my God. What...
You saw this,
and you didn't say anything?
we didn't come up this way.
we came up the back stairs.
we should call the police.
Miguel!
[Stacey Gasps]
Shit! Over there, you guys.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Oh, my God!
what the hell is going on?
- [Growling]
- [Screaming]
[Growling Continues]
[Screaming]
wayne! Wayne!
Help me!
wayne, let's go
to the fire escape!
Shit! Come on. Shit!
Run!
Go!
Go, go, go!
[Growling]
- Damn!
- In there.
where the hell are we?
In here! Go!
No! Oh, my God!
- No!
- [Growling Continues]
[Howling]
- Come on, come on, come on.
- No! Wayne!
[Stacey whimpering]
[Elevator Stops]
what the fuck is that thing?
I have never seen anything
like that before.
Is it a fucking wild animal
that escaped from the zoo?
- That's the thing that killed Tom.
- Dude, I don't know.
God!
It looks like...
It looks like what I saw when I
was developing the film that we shot.
what are you talking about?
In every shot, there was
something in the background.
I mean, first I was pissed
because I thought my lens messed up.
You know? But then when I looked at
the negative really close, there it was.
It was in every shot.
That... That thing
was up there all that time?
what the hell is it?
A fucking rabid dog?
It sounds like
a massive wolf or something.
I think you just nailed it
right there, babe.
- Nailed what?
- Werewolf.
- Are you sure it wasn't Dracula?
- I'm serious, Stace.
I mean, that book you found...
the one that we used?
what the hell was
that shit all about?
what are you saying? I brought
that thing because of that damn book?
No. I don't know.
But I know one thing... I mean, I saw
what it did to Miguel, Annie and Tom.
I mean, this thing
has got some serious issues.
we gotta get out of here.
Oh, God!
That's wayne's assistant.
Oh, God.
wayne, Stacey, this is Josie.
Get out of there now.
- I don't have time to explain.
There's something in there.
- Oh, fuck!
You've gotta get out of there.
Somebody pick up!
[Beeps]
- [Groaning]
- What is it?
Oh, it...
[Continues Groaning]
- You all right?
- [Crying]
[Continues Groaning]
[Crackling]
[Grunting]
- [Snarling]
- Josie.
[Growls]
- [Labored Breathing]
[Sniffing]
[Continues Sniffing]
[Snorting]
Josie.
[Grunts]
Josie, it's okay.
[Snarls]
[Grunting]
- [Growls]
- I don't wanna hurt you.
[Growling]
Josie, no! No!
Transformation. Transformation.
Transformation.
"First transformation."
Okay.
"On the night of the first
transformation, she must be led...
into the light of the full moon...
or else she will
be locked forever...
in a limbo between
human and werewolf form."
Josie!
- [Growling, Screaming]
- Josie!
[Groaning]
[Groaning Intensifies]
[Howling]
[Continues Howling]
[Growling, Screaming]
[Josie Crying]
There. It's okay.
It's okay.
You think that thing's
still down there?
- I don't know.
- [Darkwolf Howling]
That's a definite,
resounding yes.
There's a loading dock
on the basement floor.
- If we could somehow get to that...
- No.
That thing's on the ground floor.
That's the way we came in.
You don't wanna
go back down there.
I wanna callJosie again.
God, I hope she didn't
go to the apartment.
- We should get going.
- I know.
[Phone Ringing]
- Hello?
- Josie.
- Stacey, where are you?
- Get out of there.
Josie, get the hell
out of there.
There's this thing,
and it's chasing us.
I know. I know about it already.
I know it's here. Where are you?
wayne and I are stuck in a freight
elevator in the old warehouse building.
Josie, Tom's dead.
That thing got him.
Are you there?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Jo-Jo.
I really am.
You okay?
Tom is dead.
My boyfriend.
I'm sorry.
Stacey said the wolf's got her
and her boyfriend trapped...
in some freight elevator
at the warehouse on 7 th Street.
This is Turley.
where exactly are you?
Hold on.
Tell him where we are.
Hey. We're in that old warehouse
across from my apartment.
Yeah, I know where it is.
There's a loading dock
in the front of my building.
All right. We can be there
in a couple minutes.
- Can you guys make a break for the dock?
- Like we have a choice?
[Beeps Off]
How you doing?
Fine.
[Darkwolf Panting]
[Growling]
[Tires Screeching]
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
we're at the loading dock.
They're here.
[whispering]
One,
two,
three!
[whimpering]
- Come on! Get in!
- Close the...
- Behind us! Move!
- [Shouting]
what are you waiting for?
Get the hell out of here!
Go, go, go!
[Screaming]
- No!
- [Darkwolf Snarling]
- [Shouting]
- [Brakes Screeching]
I'm sorry about Tom, Jos.
No, regular bullets
won't affect this thing.
Get back to me
as soon as you can.
All right.
Here's the plan.
we're gonna move you guys down to
the basement into a secured structure.
It's an old fallout bomb shelter. It has
heavy steel doors. They should hold.
I'm not going down
to hide in some bomb shelter.
You have to, Josie.
This thing's coming for you.
You've got maybe an hour
if we're lucky.
with you down there safe,
I can do what I have to do.
And probably be killed in the process,
just like your partner.
No! Nobody else is gonna die tonight
because of me,
especially you!
You're going down
into the shelter.
You said it yourself, Steve.
This thing won't stop.
It won't give up. It won't stop, ever.
- I want to help.
- Out of the question.
- I can maybe distract it... long
enough for you to get to it!
- No!
Look, I don't wanna
run anymore.
I don't want any more people
dying because of me!
This thing ends tonight.
whatever it takes,
it ends tonight.
And I'm helping.
Then you understand
what you're risking.
I gotta agree with
the cute cop here, Jos.
I don't like the idea...
you putting yourself out there
like some kind of bait for this thing.
It's my decision.
I need to help.
All right.
But you two
are down in the shelter.
No way. If she's not going,
we're not going either.
- Right, wayne?
- Stacey, this isn't your problem.
- You have to go down there.
- No way.
[Steve]
Look, I can protect her, maybe.
That's gonna be hard enough.
But all three of you... impossible.
- Deal with it, dude.
- I can just order you
down into the shelter.
And we'd resist,
and then you'd have to arrest us and put
us in jail, and we'd still be here.
[Sighs]
All right.
we don't have a lot of time.
Maybe 30 minutes
left to full moon.
This thing's gonna step up the chase.
That means we gotta be ready.
Let me introduce you
to a very good friend of mine.
Thank you, madame.
Ah! Goddamn it.
Man, that was smart.
Hey, slick,
you forgot to sign in.
Oh, shit.
[Growling]
Freeze!
[Panting]
[Guttural Groaning]
- [Man Screaming]
- [Darkwolf Growling]
- [Clamoring]
- What the hell?
- [Gunshots]
- Stay here.
- But I...
- Stay here!
He's in the building!
- [Clamoring, Gunshots Continue]
- What do you see?
There's a whole bunch
of shit going down.
[Man]
Get on the radio right now!
- [Gunshots Continue]
- [Darkwolf Growling]
It's here.
- [Gunshots]
- [Screaming]
- [Screaming Continues]
- [Gunshots Continue]
[Man On Radio]
Harper! Harper, are you there?
what's going on?
what's happening?
Harper, talk to me!
- [Screaming]
- [Gunshots]
[Shouting]
[Gunshots Continue]
[Darkwolf Panting]
- [Gunshot]
- [Growling]
[Gunshots]
[Darkwolf Breathing Heavily]
[Growling]
- [Growling Continues]
- [Gunshots]
what the hell
is going on out there?
[Thud]
[women Gasp, Squeal]
we've gotta get you guys
out of here. Now.
Okay.
Come on.
Oh, my God!
[Breathing Heavily]
Shh, shh, shh.
Go.
- [Growling]
- [Screaming]
Hey!
well, if it isn't
the big bad wolf!
Let's say you and I
go for a little walk.
It's a full moon tonight,
fucker!
It'll be...
romantic.
[Continues Growling]
No!
[Darkwolf Running]
[Growling]
Come on!
[whimpers]
I hate to end all this fun,
but this date is over!
[Screams]
No!
- [Screaming]
- [Growling]
[Howling]
- [Continues Screaming]
- [Growling]
Josie!
[Shouting]
Shoot him in the eye!
[Josie Shouting]
[Screaming]
[Gunshot]
[Thud]
Looks like some fleas are gonna
be looking for a new home tonight.
we're done. It's over.
So what do you think
you'll do now?
I don't know.
I don't think I'll
stay here after all this.
Maybe I'll go home and spend
some time with my family.
- Sounds good.
- Yeah.
Think you'll tell them
about all this?
[Sighs]
when they're ready.
- Yeah.
- Maybe.
I guess no one's really ready
for something like this, huh?
- No, not really.
- Yeah.
Mary would've been proud.
You were a great protector.
Thanks.
- You need a lift?
- No, I'm okay.
Stacey and wayne
are gonna pick me up.
Okay. All right.
Take care of yourself, all right?
Yeah, you too.
Hey, Pagano.
why'd the werewolf
cross the road?
why?
He saw you coming.
No more stupid jokes, Turley.
- ##[Techno]
- ##[Men Chanting, Indistinct]