[POUNDING ON DOOR]
[BABY CRIES]
Shh.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Hello?
Are--are you ok?
Do you speak English?
[DRIPPING]
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Here.
Uh, come in, come in.
Here.
Uh, I'm gonna
get you a doctor.
Lie down right here.
Ok?
Ok, yeah, just lie down.
Oh, my God. Oh, God.
Shh.
Ok.
[RINGS]
[DIALING]
[BEEP]
Oh, my God.
Ohh.
Aah!
[BABY CRYING]
[GRUNTING]
Please.
Please, please don't.
I'll do anything.
Please.
Aah!
Alex?
Huh?
What?
You thirsty?
Yeah.
Ok. All right.
All right.
[SIGHS]
[WATER RUNNING]
Careful.
[CHUCKLES]
Thank you.
You're welcome.
[SIGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ I wanna sing
with the big chief ♪
♪ I'm getting' wild
with the wild man ♪
♪ I wanna spy
with the spy boy ♪
♪ I wanna sing
with the big chief ♪
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Thank y'all. Thank y'all.
We let Alex shine a little
bit on that last one.
The bad news is my man won't
be with us too much longer.
He's decided
to leave the nest.
Fly off on his own.
[LAUGHS]
Think you can handle it?
[AUDIENCE GROANS]
All right. 2, 3, 4...
[NEW SONG STARTS]
Look, there's a reason why
you can get a big house in
the sticks for dirt cheap.
It's a wasteland.
The next she wants to stay.
She's all over the map.
Well, if you think it's such
a great idea, then why wait?
I knew it.
You don't wanna go.
It'll be fine.
3 hours away?
I'm never gonna see you.
I just can't imagine
raising a baby in the city.
This house, it is like a
Malibu Barbie dream house.
I mean, this would
be a project for me,
not some client.
And Alex is cool with it?
All these demos
and even if just a
couple of them pay off,
then he can support me.
I'm very happy for you.
Thank you.
Oh, God.
[SIGHS]
You know what that
look was, right?
Yes, I do. Ahem.
But she'd be
just as happy with
a placeholder ring.
I don't wanna be that guy.
I'm not gonna get
her a piece of shit.
I thought
maybe you were one
of those people
who doesn't believe
in marriage.
Your parents were
married, right?
3 times each.
Aha.
Now we're getting someplace.
Oh, so sorry.
When you stare at us
while you're talking,
then we know you're
talking about us.
Oh, women have
amazing powers.
Uh, can I get you
a non-alcoholic beer?
No, we have to go
back to the office.
We have to finish
up some work.
Yeah, you guys are going
to Chippendale's
where some oily guys gonna
give her a lap dance.
I don't have a lap.
[LAUGHTER]
Bye.
May I?
May you what?
What are you--oh, God!
Oh, my God, my back!
I-it's all these things
I never thought about before.
I don't have a little sister,
I never even babysat,
and now I worry about
everything, like,
what if I drop him
on his head?
No, I'm being serious.
They come with skulls.
My mother's a disaster.
I mean, what
if that's genetic?
What if I inherit all
her maternal incompetence?
I don't think there's
a gene for that, Penny.
Penny?
[EXHALING DEEPLY]
Oh, my God.
Ha ha.
Yeah.
Oh, my God!
Yes.
God damn it, why don't
you answer the phone?
Listen, if you're
still with Alex,
tell him we are
at the hospital.
We can't a hold of him
and Penny is in labor.
Call me when
you get this.
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
Ok.
It's gonna be ok.
[NO AUDIO]
I missed it.
It happened really fast.
I can't believe
I missed it.
Come in, come on, here.
Hey.
Ahh.
Ok.
Thanks.
Hey.
So tell me everything.
Honestly, I-I don't
even remember.
It's like I blacked
everything out.
[LAUGHS]
He's so cute.
[WHISPERING]
You're so cute.
[GURGLING]
Ok. This is your dad.
Oh. Hey.
That's your dad, huh?
Boy, we can just,
uh, about handle
anything now, huh?
Hmm.
This side is up.
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[BEEP OF ANSWERING MACHINE]
PENNY:
Hey, I know you're working,
but I talked to
the realtor in Stanton.
I told him if he
cut his fee in half,
we could close
the deal right now.
He must be sick of my haggling
because he went for it.
I just think
we have to do it.
It's such a steal.
We'd be crazy
to pass this up.
And I really believe I can turn
it into something spectacular.
Anyway, I'll grab something from
carmine's on the way home.
We can start
hammering it out.
I just wanna make sure
you're ok with this.
If you're having any doubts
at all, just let me know.
Ok? I love you so much.
Well, it looks a little
dreary in the late months.
But you know,
in the spring with plants,
trees, I mean, it's gonna--
we could just paint it,
paint the brick.
Hmm.
It's from Michael.
"May this beautiful tree
represent your growing
love and blooming hopes,
and blah, blah, blah."
Does it really say,
"blah, blah, blah"?
Yeah. [LAUGHS]
Tanner.
Oh. [LAUGHING]
Hi, buddy.
You just hangin' out?
Oh, yeah.
♪ Dun-dun-dun ♪
[BABY MURMURING]
PENNY: Inspired yet?
There's something I don't
mind being left behind.
Yeah, I just
something else we couldn't
have in the city.
How would you like
your rib-eye cooked?
Aah!
[BABY CRYING]
I'm sorry. You ok?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Get rid of that thing.
Well, now
everything we cook's
gonna taste like baby.
That's not funny.
[BABY CRIES]
That's in the kitchen.
Out back.
Oh, and that
goes upstairs.
[INAUDIBLE]
[BANGING]
Hey, hold on!
Hold on!
I'll--I'll help
you with that.
Here, I'll get the door.
You've gotta be kidding me.
This was--this
was supposed to be gone.
Can your guys get
this shit outta here?
I cannot put my piano
in there with this stuff.
So what, just leave it
here on the ground?
[SIGHS]
What is all this crap?
Sorry.
How's little T?
He's good.
He's napping.
Can I give you a hand
with anything?
No, but maybe later
you could help me
with the monitor?
Ok.
Poor girl.
Probably wondering what
she did to deserve this.
Hmm.
A lot of crap in here.
Shit!
No!
God damn it!
Are you on channel A
or channel B?
[BABY CRYING]
Channel B.
Should I put it
back on the shelf?!
You don't have to yell.
I can hear you
through the monitor.
Ok.
Yeah, put it
back on the shelf.
I think you have it
pointing at the ceiling.
You need to point it
down to the crib.
[STATIC]
Just move it a little
bit to the left.
[GASPS]
What's wrong?
Oh, God.
Where are you
taking my mom?
I'm sorry, babe.
But the effect with the
camera was a little creepy.
Well, what about
the monitor?
It's good.
Move it two inches
to the right.
[BABY MURMURING]
[BABY CRYING]
What's goin' on with him?
I don't know, but I
cannot go back in there.
[BABY CRYING]
[GRUNTING]
That counts as a turn.
[LAUGHTER]
[BABY CRYING]
Oh, God.
[BOOM]
What the hell is that?
Ow.
Oh, my God.
[RUMBLING]
What's going on?
Oh, my God.
I don't know.
[BABY CRYING]
Go see.
Yeah.
I don't understand.
I'll--I'll check it out.
Why don't you
take him inside?
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES]
I'm gonna throw up.
How could we not know?
We saw it on a Sunday.
We moved in on a Sunday.
We can't
live like this.
With Tanner
not sleeping?
It was his first
night like that.
We'll--we'll get rest.
You need quiet.
I'll manage.
I mean, that was--
that was the whole point.
Nah, we'll be fine.
I mean, how long
can this last?
A few weeks?
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES CONTINUE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ Here in the leaves
of the fallen tree ♪
♪ my body's
breaking down on me ♪
♪ mmm
♪ my pain
won't mind at all ♪
[BABY CRYING]
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES CONTINUE]
[BANGING, GURGLING]
MAN: Bitch!
[GASPS]
Alex?
Son of a bitch!
These dumb asses didn't
hook up the dryer exhaust.
I could hear you all the way
upstairs in the bathroom.
Oh, I didn't know
I was that loud.
No, it must be the pipes.
Just another charming
idiosyncrasy of this house.
I--I got it.
You know, I don't like
you leaving the baby
alone up
there like that.
No, I--I--I've got
the internet hooked up.
He's just watching florin.
Ok.
MAN, ECHOING VOICE:
What are you doing?
What are you--
what are you doing?
Come on.
Play something.
[PLAYING PIANO]
Hey.
I need help
with the baby.
[DOOR SQUEAKING,
CLOSES]
[BANGS PIANO KEYS]
Look, I just need you
to bathe him for me.
I have to go lie down.
Ok.
Make sure you
clean the sink before
you put him in, ok?
Wait.
I-I don't put the baby
in the sink full
of dirty dishes?
Shut up.
[WHISPERING] I'm gonna
put you right here.
Right there.
Look at that.
You ready for your bath?
Hmm?
[DISPOSAL RUNNING]
[CLANGING]
[SIGHS]
[SIGHS, CHUCKLES]
I found Tanner's blankie.
It was in the guest room.
Hey, buddy.
Look what I found
in the guest room.
I found your blankie.
Yeah.
Yeah, do you like that?
God, what is
the matter with you?
God!
Did you not think
to check the water?
I did check it when
I was filling it up.
Oh, my God.
If I hadn't
come in here--.
I can't even leave
the baby alone with
you for one minute.
I can't do
everything myself.
No, just go.
I've got it.
Don't even.
[BABY CRYING]
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES CONTINUE]
What are you doing
on the floor?
Hey.
Oh.
You're getting heavy.
Ahh. Ohh, ohh.
Ohh.
[GASPS]
[BABY CRYING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Let's see if we can get
some sleep for an hour.
Penny?
Hey.
What happened?
Here.
Let me take him.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
You're freakin' me out.
No.
Penny.
I'm fine.
Hey, hey.
I'm ok. I'm ok.
Talk to me.
What just happened
in there?
Don't yell at me, all right?
I'm tired and I'm--
I'm scared.
What are you scared of?
Ahh. I saw...
What?
Somebody in the house.
It was
through the mirror.
She ran by and
then she was gone.
I don't know.
Maybe I was asleep.
I can't even see
straight anymore.
I'm losing it, too.
They say people
start to hallucinate.
It's a fact.
I googled it.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
I don't know if I can
stand much more of this.
I need to sleep.
I mean, how long
has it been?
Five days?
Something like that.
I've lost track.
[SIGHS]
It'll get better.
I promise.
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES CONTINUE]
[BABY CRYING]
WOMAN: Get out!
[GASPS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[BABY CRYING]
Penny?
Penny.
Wake up.
[BABY CRYING]
God! What?!
What's going on?
[SIGHS]
You ok?
Yeah.
I just had a really
weird dream.
At least you're sleeping.
Can you turn out the light?
[YAWNING]
[BABY CRYING]
Ohh.
I can handle it.
[ENGINE STARTING]
[BABY COOING]
I know we haven't
known each other,
just maybe
a few months now,
but...Normally I'm
not a train wreck.
You know,
I'm actually really fun.
Like, not like party
girl fun, but...Fun.
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES CONTINUE]
Damn it!
[SIGHS]
Pretend you didn't
see that.
If daddy sells one
of his demos...
He'll pay for therapy.
For both of us.
MICHAEL: Hey, Alex.
It's Michael. Friday.
I left a message
for you the other day.
All that peace and quiet
driving you crazy yet?
Johanna and I would
love to come down and,
uh, check the place out.
I'm sure you're ready
to get drunk
and admit
that you screwed up.
Because you know
you screwed up, right?
Big time.
What were you thinking?
[VOICES OVERLAPPING]
This is your life now.
Whole entire life is
nothing but that house.
You haven't written a demo,
not one verse, not one note
of music the whole time
you've been here.
You just stagger around like
a zombie, having nightmares
about a woman,
because she told you
she saw a woman
in the house.
She put it in your head
and now look at you.
Is that what you wanted?
Did you not see
Tanner sitting here
right in front of you?
Why did you leave him
at the top of the stairs?
Y-y-you're telling me
that y-y-you didn't
put him in the wagon and
set him right there?
Yes, I put him in the wagon,
but I had him in the nursery.
You just said you didn't
put him in there.
Ok. Y-you have got to
manage this situation
better, all right?
I did not put him at
the top of the stairs, Alex!
I didn't. You're walking
around in a complete stupor!
Ok, I gotta get
outta here.
I'm gonna go
to the store.
[CRUNCHING]
Sweetie, put
some shoes on.
What's wrong?
Are you sure
you're ok to drive?
Uh...
I just drifted
off for a second.
You forgot the list.
I talked to Dr. Gordon.
He said try gripe water.
He may be having
gas at night.
Gripe water.
Are you sure you're
ok to leave?
I'm fine.
Ok.
Don't be gone long.
[BABY MURMURING]
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Thank you.
[SIGHS]
Whoa!
For a second there,
I thought you were
the grim reaper.
I'm too young to die!
[BEEPING]
So I would
normally never ask
a customer this,
but, um, are you ok?
I'm hangin' in there,
I suppose.
New baby?
5 months old.
Oh.
Doesn't sleep?
Now when he's supposed to.
He's got it all upside-down.
[SIGHS]
They got a term for it.
It's called
day/night confusion.
That'd be a really
good name for a band.
[BEEPING]
What?
You like babies?
Um, I wouldn't choose to
like, hang out with one,
but I know sometimes
it can't be helped.
Are you asking me if
I'll baby-sit for you?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yes.
Does your TV work?
You didn't answer my
question about the TV.
Ok, all right, look,
our cable doesn't work.
But our DVD player
works great.
Ok, ok.
Take it easy.
I mean, we just need
someone to--who will, uh,
to stay the night
with the baby.
That, I mean, that's it.
Ok.
I can trust you?
Like, I'm not
gonna touch your
liquor cabinet.
I had one too many
wine coolers once
when I was 14,
so I don't touch
the stuff.
Smart girl.
So, um, I normally
would ask 10 an hour,
but since I'm gonna be
doing this overnight--
whatever you want.
I mean...Here.
Ok. [CHUCKLES]
Yeah, you just
gave me a hundred, so...
[CHUCKLES]
Hi.
So I have a baby brother
and a baby sister.
And my older sister
has a baby.
And my older brother
You wanna hear
about my cousins?
No, that's...
No, that's good.
Nice place.
So, um, if he sleeps,
then you can bring him
upstairs to his crib.
But what's been happening
since we moved in here
is he wakes up
every 15 minutes.
If that's the case, I would
just keep him down here.
You know you don't
put him to sleep
on his belly, right?
And if he---if he's sleepin'
and you get tired, you know,
you can just crash
out on the couch.
Or, um, coffee.
We have a coffee maker.
No, I don't do caffeine.
She doesn't drink
either.
And no red meat.
If that matters.
Well, that's
actually kind of cool.
But really, I don't want
you to worry about me.
Or the baby, of course.
[MUFFLED]
So this is not gonna be
a problem for me
[NORMAL VOICE] But you
know what I can't do?
So, uh, y'all
might want to be
thinking about bed, huh?
Yeah.
Electric chairs
that carries you up
and down the stairs.
What?
Nothing.
Never mind.
Electric chair.
I think she was
making a joke.
[SIGHS]
Thank you for this.
You were right.
I love hearing you
say I'm right.
Get some sleep.
You don't think
there's something wrong
with this place, do you?
I think one
good night's sleep
and all this shit's
gonna go away.
Ok?
Yeah.
[BABY MURMURING]
[SQUEAK]
Hal?
We're doing good down here.
I think he's gonna
stay down for a while.
Um, do you wanna
put him in his crib?
Or should I do it?
Um, do you want me to...
You know what?
I'm gonna get him for you.
[SCREECHING]
[DRIPPING]
[SQUEAKING]
[SCREAMING]
[GASPING]
[GROANING]
It was too good to last.
Need more sleep.
Like 24 hours more.
How about 12 more hours?
Deal?
Hmm?
12 more, honey.
Sunday.
They have to take
the day off.
Sunday.
Uh-huh.
It's the lord's day.
[LAUGHS]
Hallelujah.
Come on.
Let's go see
Tanner and pay her
and see if
she can come back.
[BABY CRYING]
[GASPS]
What kind of person would
you let in this house?
Some teenager you met
at the grocery store!
Penny, calm down.
I mean, we don't even
know her last name!
Do you even know
her first name?
I mean, what is going
on with this house
that someone
would leave in the
middle of the night?!
You're--you're
taking it too far.
No, I'm not!
Penny, please!
Stop, ok?
Stop what?!
Look. I know it's wrong.
I-I take full responsibility.
But she's gone,
for whatever reason.
And we were a few feet away
in our room, sleeping.
We didn't even have
our monitor on!
The entirety of human history
until a couple of years ago!
And babies died every
night their cribs!
Penny, please.
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES CONTINUE]
[BABY CRYING]
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
And you get
the hell out of here!
What the hell is
the matter with you?!
Don't you assholes
have any children?!
What you're doing
is illegal!
You cannot do
construction on Sunday!
Ok, it's ok, man.
We've all been
in your shoes. You know?
It's happened to me,
trust me, more than once.
You tied one on Saturday night,
induced yourself
into a junior coma,
and you lost an entire day.
Welcome to Monday.
If you got a sick day,
I think I'd call in.
It looks like you could use
a little more shut eye.
Why don't you go
crawl back in bed.
I'll make sure
we keep it down.
[NO AUDIO]
ALEX: You have to get
out right now.
I've seen it.
Get in the fuckin' car
and start driving.
Why won't
you believe me?
God damn it, why won't
You think this
isn't hard for me?
Wake up!
Why are you lying to me?
[BABY CRYING]
[THUNDER]
[BABY MURMURING]
I'm sorry.
I didn't picture our
life quite like this.
You must hate it.
The rain is nice.
They'll probably
have to stop.
Isn't the rain nice?
I can't remember
your name.
I'm sorry.
You see her, too.
I'm not crazy.
[BABY CRYING]
[BANGING ON DOOR]
Please!
Please! Please! Please!
Please! Please!
[WHISPERING]
The baby's asleep.
I don't know
if you've realized,
but it's actually
quiet right now.
This is the first time since
we moved in this place
that I can actually
get some work done.
So if you have any love
left in your heart for me,
could you please, please stop
pounding on the window?
[THUNDER]
I'm worry our whole
nightmarish ordeal
is...undermining
your ability
to play piano.
You have got to let me
get some work done.
All you can
think about is work
when we're in the fifth
level of hell?
I know how difficult
this is for you.
Difficult? What is wrong
with you, Alex?
There's something wrong
with this house!
There's something
horrible here.
Penny, whatever
you think is going on, ok,
whatever you
think you see...
It's not real.
I've got something.
[PILLS SHAKING]
I want you to take these.
Look--
no.
I-I know you're scared.
I'm scared, too.
We are falling apart.
We cannot function
like this.
I can help you.
I could take care of Tanner.
No--
no, I'll take care of him
and then you sleep.
I have to be here
to protect him.
Don't you understand?
Then something's
gonna happen.
It's the only way we're
gonna get through this.
God, I want to go home.
I want to go home.
You just need
to get some sleep.
Here.
Take these.
No.
What are you doing?
Stay away from me.
Stay away from you?
All I've ever done is taken
care of you and the baby.
You wanted this baby
just as much
as you wanted to
move into this house.
That's not true.
You think I'm an idiot?
You can't do this to me!
You can't treat me like this!
I said stay away from me.
I would never hurt you.
All I've ever done is given
you everything you wanted!
[BABY CRYING]
Take the fucking pills!
No.
How are you feeling?
Are you feeling
anything?
That smells good.
Can I have some?
[BABY CRYING]
All right. Sorry.
Switch.
[PIANO PLAYING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[MUMBLING]
Did you think
I forgot about you?
I didn't forget
about you, noodle.
I'd never forget about you.
I--I know you're
sitting right there.
[EXHALES]
Oh, my God.
Tanner.
Tanner? Tanner?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[WOMAN SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
Alex!
Alex! Alex, wake up!
Wake up! Alex! Wake up!
Come on, wake up! Alex!
Wake up!
I did something terrible.
I can't find Tanner.
You gotta help me.
[MUTTERING]
Please wake up.
Please, please, wake up.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[BANG]
[BUZZING]
MAN: The national weather
service has issued
a flash flood warning
for Harold county
until 10:30 PM,
central standard time.
At 6:55 central standard
time the public reported
water flowing over
the following roads...
I-45 between Carlos road
and James street, I-40...
Honey, you've gotta
wake up!
Alex! Alex! Wake up!
You've gotta wake up.
We have to go get Tanner.
Alex, wake up,
we have to get Tanner.
Alex!
There's something here.
There's something here
that's gonna get us.
I'm not going crazy.
I'm not crazy.
[KNOCKING]
Did you hear that?
Do you believe me?
Do you believe?
Did you hear that?
Can you hear?!
[BANGING]
Go away!
[RATTLING]
No! No!
I just want my baby.
Tanner?
Go to hell.
You're not real.
Oh, God!
Michael!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Good God.
What's happened to you?
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
No, no, no,
you don't understand.
I have to go find Tanner.
Take it easy.
I've got you.
I'm gonna
get help. Ok?
I'm gonna go and get
some help. Everything's
gonna be ok.
Just relax. Just relax.
[CREAKING]
[NO AUDIO]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
What the hell?
What's going on here?
She's not real.
Help me.
[ECHOING]
She's not real.
Penny...
Penny. Penny, you've gotta
tell me what's going on here.
She's not real.
She's real.
Real, real, real,
real, real, real.
Ohh.
Oh, God.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GROANING]
[GASPS]
[THUD]
[BOOM]
[SCREAMING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Oh, God. Ok.
Ok.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[RUMBLING]
[BABY COUGHING]
MAN: Stay away...
From my family!
Help me.
[CLANGING]
Oh, God.
[RADIO IN BACKGROUND]
MAN: Remember, we
will not be undersold.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
WOMAN: It's been more than 6
weeks since a local woman
wandered away
from her hospital room
in Stanton only
to disappear.
The woman was being
treated for shock
following the death of
her 8-month-old daughter
who perished
when a fire broke out
at their home in Butler county.
Rescue efforts tapered off
after multiple searches
of the neighborhood
turned up nothing.
But the case is
getting a second look
after the disappearance of
another woman in the same town.
19-year-old Nancy Leggero
was reported missing
this week after failing to
show up at the supermarket
police in Butler county
are now wondering
in the disappearance
of the two women.