We just moved in
Chanyeol
Moon Gayoung
D.O.
Baekhyun
Sehun
Lay, Xiumin, Chen, Tao, Kai, Suho
EXO Next Door
[Episode 7]
I said, what are you doing?
I think you got
the wrong impression.
That's right.
It's a misunderstanding.
Didn't he make you cry?
No, never!
Tell him, Yeonhee.
Yeah.
It's been a long time and
I was just happy to see him.
What?
You know each other?
You sure you're glad to see him?
If you're done saying hello,
why don't you get going?
What?
Yes, of course.
I was leaving.
It was nice to see you.
I'll send you a Line message.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Yes. It's a 100% true story.
Yes!
I was totally defenseless.
And they came out of nowhere.
Something doesn't feel right.
Do you think that guy was
taking Incheon Gal's money?
Nah, they are too old for that.
They know each other.
I find it odd, also.
He calls Incheon Gal by her name.
And she was so happy to see him
that she cried?
In that case...
Maybe it's her ex.
What? Cho Minhwan?
Your first love?
What first love?
He's just a dark part of
my dull past.
EXO played a part in
shining a ray of light
into your dark love life.
What?
What on earth are you
talking about?
A guy meets a girl who used to be
insignificant to him.
And the most amazing guys
in the world are now protecting her.
Question.
What's the first thought
that crosses his mind?
Drum rolls...
She used to like me!
So what?
That was a long time ago.
She used to be mine.
He wants to mark his territory.
He starts to think he can defeat
all the other incredible guys.
Cho Minhwan will call you
within three days.
I bet my pinky on it.
Nah, no way.
He won't call me.
Incheon Gal!
Yes. I'm coming!
By the way,
how old is your brother?
He's a high school freshman.
That means...
What? A high school student?
Busted.
You sneaky thing. You hid the fact
that you're in high school.
You hid the fact that
you've got supernatural powers.
Supernatural powers?
Why did you approach me?
What do you want?
Your millstone drip coffee,
I can't forget it.
Plus, we used to be friends.
I can make coffee for you
any time.
Just promise me one thing.
Do not use your super power
when you're with me.
That endless wackiness,
I'm addicted.
Alright. Are we good now?
That's your style?
Hey, friend.
Can I ask you
something about your sister?
Sure. Ask away.
He's not her ex,
He's her first love!
Don't they say
you never forget your first love?
So, that's his first love?
Do you need something?
Can't you clean better?
I didn't clean there yet!
Why are you so distracted?
Thinking about your first love?
These are girl's lines.
I know. Try to act.
Oh, Incheon Gal.
Come here.
This is a job for the only girl
in our house.
Our? Girl?
What is this?
It's my script.
I need someone to read it with me.
I'd rather watch than participate.
Do you have time?
It will mean a lot to me
if you help me.
Sure, I'll do it.
Where do I read?
Start reading from here.
[Comes close and hugs her]
[Kisses her eyes, nose, and mouth]
I can't look at your face.
Be true to your feelings.
Look at me.
Look into my eyes.
I can't.
Can't you see the instructions
written in the parentheses?
You have to act it out
so D.O. can get into character.
D.O., start from your last line.
Camera!
Ready, action.
Look at me.
Look into my eyes.
When I look into your eyes,
I'm finally at peace.
Ah, I've got to tell the others.
Alright.
I'll tell Xiumin first.
'Look at me.'
'Look into my eyes.'
D.O. read those lines
with a longing look.
And Incheon Gal's reaction was...
Was?
I don't know
how to put in into words.
Come on.
You got me all curious.
And what about Chanyeol?
He calls Incheon Gal
all day long.
He says that name
dozens of times a day.
I think he's just
making her life miserable.
I thought so too.
But I was wrong.
I have definite proof that
Chanyeol likes Incheon Gal.
- Definite proof?
- Yup.
What is that?
Are they in a love triangle?
It's too long to explain
over the phone.
Right.
This is an international call.
I really want to know, though.
Don't worry.
This call is completely free.
Didn't you know that?
We can talk all night long.
Can you talk all night, too?
Sure! Tell me everything.
Don't you dare leave anything out.
Alright.
Let me go into detail, then.
Oh man...
I heard it with my own ears.
Really?
[Incheon Gal]
What do you want now?
Yes?
You have to change your style.
You're going to play hard to get.
It's not you. I guarantee it!
What about...
You're saying
Incheon Gal likes one of us?
It's natural that even thinking
about it makes you blush.
That's not surprising at all.
You're holding it upside down.
The EXO member
she really likes is...
Real love?