[ SILENCE ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ ANIMAL HOWLS ]
[ SIREN WAILING ]
[ WOMAN TALKING OVER POLICE
RADIO ]
Just a minute.
What have we got? A group of 30-Somethings.
It's like a massacre in there,
A group of 30-Somethings.
It's like a massacre in there, sir.
Who called it in?
Sir. Who called it in?
The caretaker,
Who called it in?
The caretaker, Mr. Marc Ruber.
The caretaker, Mr. Marc Rubber.
What were they doing here?
Mr. Marc Rubber.
What were they doing here? Ghost-Hunting.
What were they doing here?
Ghost-Hunting. Ah.
Why can't they do drugs, like
Ah. Why can't they do drugs,
like normal people?
Why can't they do drugs, like
normal people? Oy, Rubber?
Normal people? Oy, Rubber?
I'll take over.
Oy, Rubber? I'll take over.
You found them?
I'll take over. You found them?
Yeah, around 6:00 this
You found them?
Yeah, around 6:00 this morning.
What were they doing here?
Morning. What were they doing here?
They were working on some
What were they doing here? They were working
on some haunted-TV-Show thing, I think.
They were working on some haunted-TV-Show
thing, I think. [ CHUCKLES ]
Haunted-TV-Show thing, I think. [ CHUCKLES
] As long as they pay me, I don't
[ CHUCKLES ] As long as they pay me,
I don't care.
As long as they pay me, I don't care.
What time did they arrive?
Care. What time did they arrive?
Around 5:00 P.M., Evening
What time did they arrive?
Around 5:00 P.M., Evening past.
Around 5:00 P.M.,
Evening past. I locked them in, and I left.
Past. I locked them in, and I left.
You locked them in?
I locked them in, and I left.
You locked them in? Vandals, you see?
It's that time of the year.
Vandals, you see?
It's that time of the year. It's winter.
There's nobody around here and
It's winter. There's nobody around here
and can't have people wandering in
There's nobody around here and can't have
people wandering in and out, now can I?
Can't have people wandering in and out,
now can I? Anything could happen.
And out, now can I? Anything could happen.
Were the doors still locked
Anything could happen. Were the doors still
locked when you arrived this morning?
Were the doors still locked when you arrived
this morning? Not a bolt out of place.
When you arrived this morning? Not a bolt
out of place. And you didn't see anyone
Not a bolt out of place.
And you didn't see anyone else?
No.
Else? No.
[ SCOFFS ]
No. [ SCOFFS ] You
don't seem so sure.
[ SCOFFS ] You don't seem so sure.
I'd stake my life on it,
You don't seem so sure.
I'd stake my life on it, detective.
Oh! Oh, oh, oh.
Detective. Oh! Oh, oh, oh.
Except for the ghosts, of
Oh! Oh, oh, oh.
Except for the ghosts, of course.
Thank you. [ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS]
[ WOMAN SPEAKING OVER POLICE]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[WOMAN SPEAKING OVER POLICE RADIO ]
What's this? It's homemade cacti.
The victims put it up as part of
It's homemade cacti. The victims put
it up as part of their investigation.
The victims put it up as part of their
investigation. And now it's part of ours.
Their investigation. And now it's
part of ours. How many are there?
And now it's part of ours. How many are
there? I think I saw at least one in
How many are there?
I think I saw at least one in every room.
So, there's maybe 20...
Every room.
So, there's maybe 20... Maybe?
I want an exact figure now.
Maybe? I want an exact figure now.
Then, I want you to bring me all
I want an exact figure now. Then, I want
you to bring me all the tapes direct.
Then, I want you to bring me all the tapes
direct. I can't afford any of these to
The tapes direct. I can't afford any
of these to turn up on the 10:00 news.
I can't afford any of these to turn up
on the 10:00 news. Hold on a second.
Turn up on the 10:00 news.
Hold on a second. Jesus.
That's one of the better
Jesus. That's one
of the better ones.
That's one of the better ones.
I think we better have
Ones. I think we better have
another word with our Mr. Rubber.
You can't smoke.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
So, tell me. How come I've got a bunch
of kids in my morgue, found in your
How come I've got a bunch of kids in
my morgue, found in your building?
Kids in my morgue, found in your building?
I don't know.
Building? I don't know.
It's a mystery to me...
I don't know. It's a mystery to me...
unless, of course, it..
It's a mystery to me...
unless, of course, it.. Was a
Unless, of course, it..
Was a ghost.
Was a ghost. Cut
it out with this
Ghost. Cut it out with
this paranormal bullshit!
Cut it out with this paranormal bullshit!
Bullshit?
Paranormal bullshit! Bullshit?
If you've seen the things that
Bullshit? If you've seen the things
that I've seen, you wouldn't say
If you've seen the things that I've seen,
you wouldn't say that.
I've seen, you wouldn't say that.
Jericho manor is filled with
That. Jericho manor is filled
with some pretty desperate
Jericho manor is filled with some
pretty desperate characters.
Some pretty desperate characters.
And now, they're joined by five
Characters.
And now, they're joined by five more.
You better talk to this clown before
I do something I regret. [ SCOFFS ]
[ CLEARS THROAT ] Oh, yeah, I get it.
Oh, yeah, you're the good cop
Oh, yeah, I get it.
Oh, yeah, you're the good cop now, right?
Oh, that's a good one.
Now, right? Oh, that's a good one.
You sound like you've been in
Oh, that's a good one. You sound like
you've been in a police station before,
You sound like you've been in a police
station before, Mr. Rubber, which would make
A police station before, Mr. Rubber, which
would make sense because this is actually
Mr. Rubber, which would make sense because this
is actually the fifth time you've been under
Sense because this is actually the
fifth time you've been under caution.
The fifth time you've been under caution.
And it's the fifth time
Caution. And it's the fifth
time that I'm gonna be released
And it's the fifth time that I'm
gonna be released without charge.
That I'm gonna be released without charge.
Look. I'm black.
Without charge. Look.
I'm black. I'm American.
Look. I'm black. I'm American.
I married a brit. So what?
I'm American. I married a brit.
So what? All right.
I married a brit. So what? All right.
I'll give you the benefit of the
All right. I'll give you the
benefit of the doubt for now.
I'll give you the benefit of the doubt
for now. Just tell us everything you
Doubt for now.
Just tell us everything you know.
Everything? I don't want a history
of the battle of Gettysburg.
I don't want a history of the battle of
Gettysburg. Just tell us everything that's
Battle of Gettysburg.
Just tell us everything that's relevant.
All right.
Relevant. All right.
Lord Cromwell.
Four of them showed up last evening
around 5:00. And then, another one came a
Evening around 5:00. And then, another
one came a little bit later... Cocky,
And then, another one came a little bit
later... Cocky, little son of a bitch.
Little bit later... Cocky,
little son of a bitch. And then what?
Little son of a bitch. And then what?
The tall one did some talking
And then what? The tall one did some
talking to the camera, a few bits about
The tall one did some talking to the
camera, a few bits about the manor.
To the camera, a few bits about the manor.
What bit, exactly?
About Jeffrey heath.
Who the hell is Jeffrey heath?
You don't know the story,
Jeffrey heath?
You don't know the story, detective?
[ CLICKING TONGUE ]
Detective?
[ CLICKING TONGUE ] Enlighten me.
What am I, a fucking tour
Enlighten me.
What am I, a fucking tour guide?
Just tell me!
Guide? Just tell me!
All right.
Just tell me! All right.
All right, if you insist.
All right. All right,
if you insist. One evening, lord and
All right, if you insist. One evening,
lord and lady Jericho returned home after
One evening, lord and lady Jericho returned
home after an extravagant evening, to find
Lady Jericho returned home after an extravagant
evening, to find their two precious children had
An extravagant evening, to find their two
precious children had been slaughtered by an
Their two precious children had been slaughtered
by an ex-Employee named Jeffrey heath.
Been slaughtered by an ex-Employee named
Jeffrey heath. Jeffrey heath had taken those
Ex-Employee named Jeffrey heath. Jeffrey heath had
taken those children... and slit them open...
from gut to gullet. And then, in either
a moment of regret, contrition, or some
And then, in either a moment of regret, contrition,
or some macabre celebration of what he
Regret, contrition, or some macabre celebration
of what he had done, he carved off his own
Macabre celebration of what he had done,
he carved off his own face with a sickle.
Had done, he carved off his own
face with a sickle. And now...
face with a sickle.
And now... the faceless ghost of Jeffrey
And now... the faceless ghost of
Jeffrey roams the countryside, looking
The faceless ghost of Jeffrey roams the
countryside, looking for new victims.
Boo!
[ LAUGHS ] All fairy tales.
Fairy tales?
All fairy tales. Fairy tales?
No, no, no, no, no.
Fairy tales? No, no, no, no, no.
I saw him with my own eyes.
No, no, no, no, no. I saw him with
my own eyes. As a matter of fact...
I saw him with my own eyes. As a matter
of fact... I saw him last night.
As a matter of fact... I saw him last
night. All right, you need to start
I saw him last night. All right,
you need to start dealing in facts.
All right, you need to start dealing in
facts. Tell us what happened after they
Dealing in facts. Tell us what
happened after they linked the camera.
Tell us what happened after they linked
the camera. Um... well, the tall one was
Linked the camera. Um... well, the tall
one was talking while the short one was
Um... well, the tall one was talking
while the short one was filming.
Talking while the short one was filming.
And everybody else just watched.
Filming. And everybody else just watched.
Feeling he's to blame for the
And everybody else just watched. Feeling
he's to blame for the death of his children,
Feeling he's to blame for the death of his
children, lord Jericho took his own life.
Death of his children, lord Jericho took his
own life. The following occupants have not
Lord Jericho took his own life. The following
occupants have not fared so well with the manor's
The following occupants have not fared
so well with the manor's curse, either.
Fared so well with the manor's curse,
either. [ MAN SCREAMS ]
Curse, either.
[ MAN SCREAMS ] What the hell are you doing
[ MAN SCREAMS ] What the
hell are you doing out here?
What the hell are you doing out here?
For fuck's sake, what now?!
Out here?
For fuck's sake, what now?! Look.
For fuck's sake, what now?!
Look. This is private property.
What the hell are you doing
This is private property.
What the hell are you doing here?
You have to get off this land
Here?
You have to get off this land now.
Oh, hi, Mr. Rubber.
Now. Oh, hi, Mr. Rubber.
I'm sorry.
Oh, hi, Mr. Rubber. I'm sorry.
But who the hell are you?
I'm sorry. But who the hell are you?
I'm Anne-Marie...
But who the hell are you?
I'm Anne-Marie... Anne-Marie hardy.
We spoke on the phone earlier.
Anne-Marie hardy.
We spoke on the phone earlier. Oh... yes.
I thought perhaps you would be
Oh... yes.
I thought perhaps you would be older.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Older. [ CHUCKLES ] So,
this is the ghost-Hunting
[ CHUCKLES ] So, this is the
ghost-Hunting group you talked about.
So, this is the ghost-Hunting group you
talked about. And who might she be?
Group you talked about. And who might
she be? Oh, she's our psychic.
And who might she be? Oh, she's our
psychic. You don't participate in the
Oh, she's our psychic. You don't
participate in the black arts, do you?
You don't participate in the black arts,
do you? No! Nothing like that.
Black arts, do you? No!
Nothing like that. My gift is pure and...
No! Nothing like that. My gift is
pure and... Now can we get in there,
My gift is pure and...
Now can we get in there, please?
We want to get started soon as
Please?
We want to get started soon as we can.
You have any idea what you're
We can. You have any idea what
you're letting yourself in for?
You have any idea what you're letting yourself
in for? Are you frightened yet, boy?!
No. Perhaps you should be.
[ LAUGHS ]
So, um, what time can we stay here till?
You weren't 100% clear on the
Here till?
You weren't 100% clear on the phone.
You can stay here until
Phone. You can stay here until
6:00 a.m. Or nearly light, and
You can stay here until 6:00 a.m. Or
nearly light, and I'll let you out.
6:00 a.m. Or nearly light,
and I'll let you out. Let us out.
I'll let you out. Let us out.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
Let us out. I'm sorry.
I don't understand. You go in.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
You go in. When it gets dark, I leave.
I come back at 6:00 a.m., And I
When it gets dark, I leave. I come
back at 6:00 a.m., And I let you out.
I come back at 6:00 a.m., And I let
you out. What's not to understand?
Let you out. What's not to understand?
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
What's not to understand?
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ] I'm sure it's like a
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ] I'm sure it's like
a misunderstanding or something.
I'm sure it's like a misunderstanding or
something. It's okay. I'll handle it.
Misunderstanding or something.
It's okay. I'll handle it. [ CHUCKLES ]
It's okay. I'll handle it.
[ CHUCKLES ] Now, Mr...
rubber, was it?
Now, Mr... rubber, was it?
Rubber.
Rubber, was it? Rubber.
[ LAUGHING ] Look.
Rubber. [ LAUGHING ] Look.
I'm sure we can come to some
[ LAUGHING ] Look. I'm sure we can
come to some kind of arrangement.
I'm sure we can come to some kind
of arrangement. I tell you what.
Kind of arrangement. I tell you what.
Unless you do what I previously
I tell you what. Unless you do what I
previously stated, you can get off this
Unless you do what I previously stated,
you can get off this land... now.
Stated, you can get off this land... now.
But look.
Land... now. But look.
All I'm trying to say is...
But look.
All I'm trying to say is... But nothing.
Now look.
But nothing. Now look.
I only have two rules in life.
Now look. I only have two rules in life.
One is to never, ever trust a
I only have two rules in life. One is
to never, ever trust a beautiful woman.
One is to never, ever trust a beautiful
woman. And two is to never, ever come
Beautiful woman. And two is to never,
ever come back here after dark.
And two is to never, ever come back
here after dark. Do you understand me?!
Back here after dark.
Do you understand me?! Do you understand?!!
Do you understand me?!
Do you understand?!! Yes, yes, sir.
Do you understand?!!
Yes, yes, sir. Mm-Hmm.
Yes, yes, sir.
Mm-Hmm. [ WHISTLING ]
Mm-Hmm.
[ WHISTLING ] [ NO AUDIO ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
Be careful what you look for.
The ghost hunters went into the manor.
I told them be careful.
Manor. I told them be careful.
I closed the door.
I told them be careful.
I closed the door. That was it.
What do you think?
We don't have enough to charge him.
We've got no choice.
Charge him. We've got no choice.
Okay, that's it for now.
We've got no choice. Okay, that's it
for now. But be warned, Mr. Rubber.
Okay, that's it for now. But be warned,
Mr. Rubber. We will meet again.
I look forward to it,
detective.
Detective.
What's this? All the tapes
from the camcorders, the cacti.
All the tapes from the camcorders,
the cacti. All right. Thanks.
Camcorders, the cacti. All right.
Thanks. Keep an eye on Rubber.
All right. Thanks. Keep an eye on Rubber.
If he was the only one who knew
Keep an eye on Rubber. If he was the only
one who knew where they were, he knows more
If he was the only one who knew where
they were, he knows more than he lets on.
Where they were, he knows more
than he lets on. He wasn't, sir.
Than he lets on.
He wasn't, sir. Wasn't what?
Wasn't the only one who knew
Wasn't what? Wasn't the only
one who knew where they were.
Wasn't the only one who knew where they
were. Apparently, these kids are quite
Where they were. Apparently, these kids
are quite a big deal on the internet.
Apparently, these kids are quite a big deal on
the internet. They actually advertised exactly
A big deal on the internet. They actually
advertised exactly where and when the next
They actually advertised exactly where and
when the next ghost-Hunt was going to be.
Where and when the next
ghost-Hunt was going to be. Shit!
Ghost-Hunt was going to be. Shit!
So, that opens this up to every
Shit! So, that opens this up to every perv,
nerd, and psychopath with
So, that opens this up to every perv,
nerd, and psychopath with a computer.
Perv, nerd, and psychopath with a computer.
Fucking great.
A computer. Fucking great.
In the meantime, lean on Rubber.
Fucking great. In the meantime, lean on
Rubber. Let him know we're onto him.
In the meantime, lean on Rubber.
Let him know we're onto him. All right.
We'll swing by for another chat.
All right. We'll swing by for another chat.
Do you want me to help you look
We'll swing by for another chat. Do you
want me to help you look through these?
Do you want me to help you look
through these? No, I'm fine.
Through these?
No, I'm fine. I'll do this.
You just focus on him.
I'll do this.
You just focus on him. You sure?
You just focus on him.
You sure? Yes! I'm bloody sure!
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
Thanks.
I don't envy you watching these.
[ SIGHS ]
These. [ SIGHS ]
tell me about it.
[ SIGHS ] Tell me about it.
What would drive somebody to
Tell me about it. What would drive
somebody to butcher a group of kids?
What would drive somebody to butcher a group
of kids? It's a sick world... No doubt
Butcher a group of kids?
It's a sick world... No doubt about that.
Well, however it was, I hope
About that. Well, however it was,
I hope they go to hell.
Well, however it was, I hope they go
to hell. They'll know what to do with
They go to hell. They'll know
what to do with him down there.
Anything else you need, detective?
No, I'm fine.
Detective? No, I'm fine.
Just make sure no one disturbs
No, I'm fine.
Just make sure no one disturbs me.
I'll put a note on the door.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
Okay. And... go.
Uh, lens cap's still on.
And... go.
Uh, lens cap's still on. Amateur!
Uh, lens cap's still on.
Amateur! I knew that.
Take two.
I knew that.
Take two. And... go.
Welcome to the...
And... go.
Welcome to the... Welcome...
Welcome to the...
Welcome... And... go.
Welcome to today's episode.
And... go.
Welcome to today's episode. Sorry.
Welcome to today's episode.
Sorry. [ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
Sorry. [ BIRDS
CHIRPING ] Go.
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ] Go.
Welcome to today's episode of
Go. Welcome to today's episode of
"seeing is believing," the
Welcome to today's episode of "seeing is
believing," the internet's number-One and
"Seeing is believing," the internet's
number-One and scariest ghost-Hunting show.
Internet's number-One and scariest ghost-Hunting
show. I am, as always, your host,
Scariest ghost-Hunting show.
I am, as always, your host, Amanda helms.
I am, as always, your host,
Amanda helms. And joining me on today's
Amanda helms. And joining me on
today's investigation is our gorgeous
And joining me on today's investigation is
our gorgeous producer, Anne-Marie hardy.
Investigation is our gorgeous producer,
Anne-Marie hardy. And for the first time, a
Producer, Anne-Marie hardy. And for the
first time, a hunting virgin... The sexy
And for the first time, a hunting virgin...
The sexy psychic, Sheila cage.
Hunting virgin... The sexy psychic,
Sheila cage. On camera, Jason Copeland and
Psychic, Sheila cage. On camera,
Jason Copeland and meeting us there will be
On camera, Jason Copeland and meeting us there
will be Mr. Gadget himself, Paul Moore.
Meeting us there will be Mr. Gadget
himself, Paul Moore. And... cut.
Mr. Gadget himself, Paul Moore.
And... cut. Yeah, where the hell is Paul,
And... cut.
Yeah, where the hell is Paul, anyway?
I don't know, but he's
Anyway? I don't know,
but he's actually starting to piss me
I don't know,
but he's actually starting to piss me off!
Actually starting to piss me off!
I'll give him a call and see
Off!
I'll give him a call and see where he is.
Voice mail.
Where he is. Voice mail.
I'm gonna kill him.
Voice mail. I'm gonna kill him.
All I ask for is a little
I'm gonna kill him.
All I ask for is a little professionalism.
Is that too much to ask?
Professionalism. Is that too much to ask?
I mean, how many times have I
Is that too much to ask? I mean, how many
times have I told him if he doesn't get his
I mean, how many times have I told him if he
doesn't get his fucking ass here, I'm going
Told him if he doesn't get his
fucking ass here, I'm going to...
Fucking ass here,
I'm going to... [ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
To... [ MACHINE WHIRRING ] Right,
guys.
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ] Right, guys.
The plan is, when we get there,
Right, guys. The plan is, when we get
there, do links outside about the
The plan is, when we get there, do links
outside about the history, the curse, the
Do links outside about the history, the
curse, the sightings of Jeffrey heath and
History, the curse, the sightings of
Jeffrey heath and the kids, et cetera.
Sightings of Jeffrey heath and the kids,
et cetera. Then, Jas, you set up all the
The kids, et cetera. Then, Jas, you set
up all the cacti inside before we do our
Then, Jas, you set up all the cacti
inside before we do our walk-Through.
CCTV inside before we do our walk-Through.
Okay?
Walk-Through.
Okay? Okay.
[ UNENTHUSED ] Yay.
Okay. [ UNENTHUSED ] Yay.
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
[ WHIRRING CONTINUES ] As you can see,
ladies and gentlemen, we are now
As you can see, ladies and gentlemen,
we are now approaching today's location,
Gentlemen, we are now approaching today's
location, the magnificent Jericho manor,
Approaching today's location, the magnificent
Jericho manor, considered by many to be one of
The magnificent Jericho manor, considered by many
to be one of if notered by many to be one of
Considered by many to be one of if notered
by many to be one of the most haunted
If notered by many to be one of the
most haunted building in the southeast.
The most haunted building in the
southeast. Hey, Jas, keep the camera high
Building in the southeast. Hey,
Jas, keep the camera high up.
Hey, Jas, keep the camera high up.
It'll catch my double chin.
Up. It'll catch my double chin.
Some hope.
It'll catch my double chin.
Some hope. [ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
Some hope.
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ] Come here after dark.
Do you understand me?!
Come here after dark.
Do you understand me?! Do you understand?!!
Do you understand me?!
Do you understand?!! Yes.
Do you understand?!!
Yes. Yes.
Yep. Yes.
Yes. Yep. Yes.
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
Sweet. [ SCREAMS
] [ LAUGHS ]
[ SCREAMS ] [ LAUGHS ]
what's wrong with you, you
[ LAUGHS ] What's wrong with you,
you pussy?
What's wrong with you, you pussy?
It's just a...
pussy?
It's just a... y-You crept.
You shouldn't walk about all
Y-You crept.
You shouldn't walk about all stealth-Like.
Where you been, Paul?
Stealth-Like. Where you been, Paul?
Oh, banging some bird.
Where you been, Paul?
Oh, banging some bird. You're late.
Oh, banging some bird.
You're late. Oh, whatever.
Where are the walkies and the
Oh, whatever.
Where are the walkies and the torches?
Well, I ain't got them.
Torches? Well, I ain't got them.
I thought you had all the
Well, I ain't got them.
I thought you had all the gadgets.
Oh, yeah, E.M.F. Readers,
Gadgets. Oh, yeah, E.M.F. Readers,
thermal imagers, that sort of
Oh, yeah, E.M.F. Readers,
thermal imagers, that sort of stuff.
Thermal imagers, that sort of stuff.
Oh, shit.
Stuff. Oh, shit.
You really are fucking useless,
Oh, shit.
You really are fucking useless, aren't you?
Useless?
Aren't you? Useless?
You show me someone who can rig
Useless? You show me someone who can
rig this place top to bottom with
You show me someone who can rig this
place top to bottom with motion-Sensored,
This place top to bottom with
motion-Sensored, face-Recognition cameras.
Motion-Sensored, face-Recognition cameras.
Face-Recognition cameras?
Face-Recognition cameras. Face-Recognition
cameras? How'd you get this, though, on
Face-Recognition cameras?
How'd you get this, though, on our budget?
I know a guy who specializes
Our budget?
I know a guy who specializes in them.
How do you know a guy who
In them. How do you know a guy who
specializes in cacti equipment?
How do you know a guy who specializes
in cacti equipment? One word...
specializes in cacti equipment?
One word... "dungeons & dragons."
[ CHUCKLES ]
"Dungeons & dragons." [ CHUCKLES ]
uh... that's two words, you twat.
[ CHUCKLES ] Uh... that's two words,
you twat. My god, you're such a geek.
Uh... that's two words, you twat. My god,
you're such a geek. It's your fault about the
My god, you're such a geek.
It's your fault about the walkies.
Give me that camera back.
Walkies. Give me that camera back.
And it's three words, penis.
Do you think this hairstyle makes me
look fat? [ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ]
Makes me look fat?
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ] Oh, hello, Paul.
Where the hell have you been?
Oh, hello, Paul.
Where the hell have you been? Oh, not now.
Where the hell have you been?
Oh, not now. Go on, then. Tell them.
Oh, not now. Go on, then.
Tell them. Tell us what?
Go on, then. Tell them. Tell us what?
Dickwad here has forgotten
Tell us what? Dickwad here has
forgotten the walkie-talkies.
Dickwad here has forgotten the
walkie-Talkies. Oh, and the torches.
The walkie-Talkies. Oh, and the torches.
Why don't we use our cameras
Oh, and the torches. Why don't we use our
cameras for light and call each other on
Why don't we use our cameras for light
and call each other on our phones?
What the... My battery's dead.
Jason?
My battery's dead.
Jason? Mine, too.
I don't understand.
Mine, too. I don't understand.
It was fully charged this
I don't understand.
It was fully charged this morning.
It'll be the spirits.
Morning. It'll be the spirits.
They can do that... Draw on the
It'll be the spirits. They can do that...
Draw on the powers to feed their own.
They can do that... Draw on the powers to
feed their own. We must be dealing with
Powers to feed their own. We must be dealing
with something very strong if they've
We must be dealing with something very strong
if they've already taken all the power.
Something very strong if they've already taken
all the power. Makes you wonder what they'll
Already taken all the power.
Makes you wonder what they'll take next.
Ah, brilliant.
Take next. Ah, brilliant.
Where'd you find Looney tunes,
Ah, brilliant.
Where'd you find Looney tunes, honey?
And what the fuck are you
Honey?
And what the fuck are you filming for?
Oh, enough, Paul.
Filming for? Oh, enough, Paul.
Well, she's wasting the
Oh, enough, Paul. Well, she's wasting
the battery and more fucking film.
Well, she's wasting the battery and
more fucking film. I said enough!
Battery and more fucking film.
I said enough! Come on, darling.
Put the camera down.
Come on, darling. Put the camera down.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
Put the camera down. [ ELECTRICITY
CRACKLING ] Oh, what the fuck?
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ] It's over here.
Shit!
It's over here.
Shit! What's wrong?
Fuse box.
What's wrong? Fuse box.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
Fuse box.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ] It...
What are you stuttering
It... What are you stuttering about,
you Muppet?
What are you stuttering about, you Muppet?
Well, can we fix it?
About, you Muppet? Well, can we fix it?
I don't think we're supposed
Well, can we fix it?
I don't think we're supposed to.
Well, are you saying it's
To. Well,
are you saying it's been done deliberately?
Well, are you saying it's been done
deliberately? What would he know?
Been done deliberately? What would he know?
Hey, guys, don't look at me.
What would he know? Hey, guys, don't
look at me. You're the only who knew the
Hey, guys, don't look at me. You're the
only who knew the fuse box was down here.
You're the only who knew the fuse
box was down here. Oh, come on.
Fuse box was down here. Oh, come on.
Anything could have happened,
Oh, come on. Anything could have happened,
and you know it.
Anything could have happened, and you
know it. I mean, look at that thing.
And you know it. I mean, look at that
thing. It's at least a hundred years
I mean, look at that thing.
It's at least a hundred years old.
Probably with all our equipment
Old. Probably with all our equipment
charging, we overloaded it.
Probably with all our equipment charging,
we overloaded it. He's got a point.
Charging, we overloaded it.
He's got a point. Geez.
Next, you'll be telling me it
Geez. Next,
you'll be telling me it was the spirits.
Okay. Well, why don't we split up
and before we do the links get some
Well, why don't we split up and before
we do the links get some stuff on tape?
Ready?
We're very excited today to introduce...
Cut.
Introduce... Cut.
Sorry.
Cut. Sorry.
Some of the auto focus on these
Sorry. Some of the auto focus
on these cameras are gone.
Some of the auto focus on
these cameras are gone. What?
Cameras are gone.
What? Two secs.
Don't blame me.
Two secs. Don't blame me.
Blame the budget.
Don't blame me.
Blame the budget. There we go.
And back to your marker.
There we go. And back to your marker.
Ready to go?
And back to your marker.
Ready to go? Ready.
We're very excited today to
Ready. We're very excited today to
introduce to all our viewers our
We're very excited today to introduce to all
our viewers our new psychic, Sheila cage.
Introduce to all our viewers our new psychic,
Sheila cage. So, Sheila, tell us a little
New psychic, Sheila cage. So, Sheila,
tell us a little about yourself.
So, Sheila, tell us a little about
yourself. My name is Sheila, and I am
About yourself.
My name is Sheila, and I am psychic.
Cut.
Psychic. Cut.
Sheila, I realize you're a
Cut. Sheila,
I realize you're a little nervous.
Sheila, I realize you're a little nervous.
I need you to be a little more,
Little nervous.
I need you to be a little more, um...
animated?
Um... animated?
Yes, exactly... Animated.
Animated? Yes, exactly... Animated.
You see, our viewers expect a
Yes, exactly... Animated.
You see, our viewers expect a little drama.
You know, theatrics?
Little drama. You know, theatrics?
Something to stop them from
You know, theatrics? Something to stop
them from clicking the "stop" button and
Something to stop them from clicking the
"stop" button and starting to watch a monkey
Clicking the "stop" button and starting
to watch a monkey skateboarding.
Starting to watch a monkey skateboarding.
Do you mean sell my soul to
Skateboarding.
Do you mean sell my soul to the devil?
I happen to take my gift very
The devil?
I happen to take my gift very seriously.
And rightfully so.
Seriously. And rightfully so.
But, you see, so do I.
And rightfully so. But, you see,
so do I. And if I'm ever gonna get on
But, you see, so do I. And if I'm ever gonna
get on television, I need to shine, and
And if I'm ever gonna get on television, I
need to shine, and so do the people around me.
Television, I need to shine,
and so do the people around me. Understand?
So do the people around me.
Understand? Perfectly.
Understand?
Perfectly. Ladies?
I'm ready when you are.
Ladies?
I'm ready when you are. Okay.
Just go from "tell us about
Okay.
Just go from "tell us about yourself."
So, Sheila, tell us a little
Yourself." So, Sheila, tell
us a little about yourself.
So, Sheila, tell us a
little about yourself. Hi.
About yourself. Hi.
My name's Sheila, and I've had
Hi. My name's Sheila,
and I've had the gift since I was 12.
My name's Sheila, and I've had the gift
since I was 12. I'm what they call
The gift since I was 12. I'm what they call
"clairaudient," which means I
I'm what they call "clairaudient,"
which means I hear spirits communicate with
"Clairaudient," which means I
hear spirits communicate with me.
Hear spirits communicate with me.
So, we're here, in the
Me. So, we're here,
in the infamous Jericho manor.
So, we're here, in the infamous Jericho
manor. Are you picking up on anything?
Infamous Jericho manor.
Are you picking up on anything? [ EXHALES ]
Are you picking up on anything?
[ EXHALES ] I'm starting to hear the
[ EXHALES ] I'm starting to
hear the presence of a man.
I'm starting to hear the presence of a man.
Is there a name?
Presence of a man.
Is there a name? No, not yet.
But it keeps saying to me, "it
No, not yet. But it keeps saying to me,
"it was all my fault."
But it keeps saying to me,
"it was all my fault." What was his fault?
Was all my fault."
What was his fault? I'm not sure yet.
What was his fault?
I'm not sure yet. Say that again.
You... You okay?
[ DEEP VOICE ] Don't touch me.
[ NORMAL VOICE ] Is that the
Me. [ NORMAL VOICE ] Is that
the type of thing you wanted?
[ NORMAL VOICE ] Is that the type of
thing you wanted? Fucking brilliant.
This place really gives me the
heebie-jeebies. [ LAUGHS ]
The heebie-jeebies.
[ LAUGHS ] Heebie-Jeebies?
What?
Heebie-Jeebies?
What? That's funny.
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
What was that?
I don't know.
Hello?
Close it!
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
Okay, that's weird.
Was that the wind?
I definitely closed that.
[ SCREAMS ] Aaahhhh!
Aaahhhh!
Aaahhhh! Aaahhhh!
[ LAUGHS ]
Aaahhhh!
[ LAUGHS ] Paul!
That's not funny, you prick!
Paul! That's not funny, you prick!
Oh, come on.
That's not funny, you prick!
Oh, come on. It was fucking hilarious.
Oh, come on.
It was fucking hilarious. [ LAUGHS ]
It was fucking hilarious.
[ LAUGHS ] Asshole!
Come on.
Asshole! Come on.
Can't you take a joke?
Come on. Can't you take a joke?
Fuck off!
Can't you take a joke?
Fuck off! You're pathetic.
Pathetic?
You're pathetic. Pathetic?
I'll tell you fucking what,
Pathetic?
I'll tell you fucking what, Jason.
You're pathetic.
Jason. You're pathetic.
You're nothing but a failed
You're pathetic.
You're nothing but a failed cameraman.
And you, a failed fucking
Cameraman.
And you, a failed fucking producer.
And I'm sick of you whinging and
Producer. And I'm sick of you whinging
and moaning, as if this is some kind
And I'm sick of you whinging and moaning, as
if this is some kind of award-Winning show.
Moaning, as if this is some kind of
award-Winning show. Well, it's not!
You got about a thousand hits a month.
Deal with it.
Month. Deal with it.
You're nobodies.
Deal with it. You're nobodies.
Pathetic? Me!
You're nobodies. Pathetic? Me!
I must be, hanging around with
Pathetic? Me!
I must be, hanging around with you lot.
That's it. I'm out of here.
Well, you can't leave!
We've got a show to finish! Tough shit!
And you, you'll be hearing from
Tough shit! And you,
you'll be hearing from my solicitor.
And you, you'll be hearing from my
solicitor. The place is locked,
My solicitor.
The place is locked, remember?
You couldn't leave if you tried.
Remember? You couldn't leave if you tried.
Watch me.
You couldn't leave if you tried.
Watch me. Come on, Paul.
Oh, leave him.
Come on, Paul. Oh, leave him.
He's not worth it.
Oh, leave him.
He's not worth it. Drama queen!
How you ever went out with that
Drama queen! How you ever went
out with that guy is beyond me.
How you ever went out with that guy is
beyond me. What's his fucking problem?
Guy is beyond me. What's his fucking
problem? First, he blames me for the bag
What's his fucking problem? First,
he blames me for the bag and now this!
First, he blames me for the bag
and now this! I could kill him.
And... action.
Here we are, in the infamous
haunted theater.
Built in 1878, this extravagant extension
is a perfect place to begin our night.
Extension is a perfect place to begin
our night. [ TAPE FAST-FORWARDING ]
Jesus. This is meant
to be entertainment.
Sir? Can't you read?
Read what?
Can't you read?
Read what? The sign.
No sign, sir.
The sign. No sign, sir.
Forget it.
No sign, sir. Forget it.
What do you want?
Forget it. What do you want?
It's Rubber.
What do you want? It's Rubber.
He's disappeared.
It's Rubber.
He's disappeared. What?
We went for another word, but
What?
We went for another word, but he's gone.
His wife's not seen or heard
He's gone. His wife's not seen or
heard from him since he left us this
His wife's not seen or heard from
him since he left us this morning.
From him since he left us this morning.
[ SIGHS ]
Morning.
[ SIGHS ] Okay.
Put a warrant out for his arrest
Okay. Put a warrant out for his arrest
and then get a car to the rounds
Put a warrant out for his arrest and then get
a car to the rounds of his usual whereabouts.
And then get a car to the rounds of his usual
whereabouts. In the meantime, I'll keep
Of his usual whereabouts.
In the meantime, I'll keep checking this.
See if I can spot our Mr. Rubber.
Checking this. See if I can spot our
Mr. Rubber. Anything useful so far?
See if I can spot our Mr. Rubber.
Anything useful so far? Not really.
This guy Paul looks a bit
Not really.
This guy Paul looks a bit suspect.
The rest of it just looks like
Suspect. The rest of it just looks
like some crappy ghost show.
The rest of it just looks like some
crappy ghost show. You want me to finish
Some crappy ghost show.
You want me to finish watching it for you?
No, I'll do it.
Watching it for you? No, I'll do it.
You just make sure I'm not
No, I'll do it. You just make sure I'm
not interrupted by anyone else until
You just make sure I'm not interrupted
by anyone else until I'm done...
interrupted by anyone else until
I'm done... including you!
Sir.
Including you! Sir.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
Sir. [ DOOR CLOSES
] Dickhead.
[ DOOR CLOSES ] Dickhead.
We're about to conduct a
Dickhead. We're about to conduct
a Ouija board to see if we can
We're about to conduct a Ouija board
to see if we can drum up some energy.
Ouija board to see if we can drum
up some energy. So... here we go.
Drum up some energy. So... here we go.
Fingers on the glass.
So... here we go. Fingers on the glass.
Spirits, use our energy to move
Fingers on the glass.
Spirits, use our energy to move this glass.
Move it to these letters to
This glass. Move it to these
letters to spell out your message.
Thank you. Now,
move the glass to the letter of your name.
I'm... Im picking up the energy
of a man approaching the table.
Energy of a man approaching the table.
He's telling me he's curious as
Table. He's telling me he's curious
as to why we're on his land.
He's telling me he's curious as to why we're
on his land. Is this you, lord Jericho?
To why we're on his land. Is this you,
lord Jericho? Are we on your land?
Is this you, lord Jericho? Are we on your
land? Tell us if you want us to leave.
Are we on your land? Tell us if you want
us to leave. If we could get out, that is.
Tell us if you want us to leave.
If we could get out, that is. Come on.
If we could get out, that is.
Come on. Give us a letter.
Is this you, lord Jericho?
Give us a letter.
Is this you, lord Jericho? Okay.
If you're not lord Jericho, who
Okay.
If you're not lord Jericho, who are you?
"D."
"E."
"A."
"T."
"H."
"Death." Is that supposed to scare us?
Worked on me.
Is that supposed to scare us?
Worked on me. Come on.
Give us another message.
We're getting bored now.
[ ANNE-MARIE SCREAMS ] Over there!
What was it?
Over there! What was it?
I saw a shadow of a man
What was it?
I saw a shadow of a man looking in.
I swear.
Looking in. I swear.
Could that be this guy?
I swear. Could that be this guy?
I didn't feel him over there.
Could that be this guy? I didn't feel him
over there. But I do sense whoever we're
I didn't feel him over there. But I do sense
whoever we're dealing with is a dark spirit.
But I do sense whoever we're dealing with
is a dark spirit. He doesn't want us here.
Dealing with is a dark spirit.
He doesn't want us here. That's for sure.
He keeps telling me to leave
That's for sure.
He keeps telling me to leave over and over.
Okay, guys, fingers back on
Over and over.
Okay, guys, fingers back on the glass.
Anne-Marie?
Annie?
Well, then, death, was that you skulking in
the shadows? Why don't you come out where we
Skulking in the shadows? Why don't
you come out where we can see you?
Why don't you come out where
we can see you? You know what?
Can see you? You know what?
I think you're a coward.
You know what? I think you're a coward.
You won't even give us your real
I think you're a coward.
You won't even give us your real name.
Maybe he can't spell his real
Name.
Maybe he can't spell his real name.
He spelled "death" all right.
Name. He spelled "death" all right.
Is that it?
He spelled "death" all right.
Is that it? You can't spell your name?
Give us your name.
Are you lord Jericho?
Are you lady Jericho?
Are you the man who slaughtered the
Jericho children, Jeffrey heath?
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
He has arrived.
He? The devil.
Aah!
The devil. Aah!
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
Aah!
[ GLASS SHATTERS ] [ EXHALES ]
Lord Jericho, are you here?
Jason, remind Annie never take a few
suggestions for a location again?
Few suggestions for a location again?
[ SIGHS ]
Again?
[ SIGHS ] I'm calling out to the spirits
[ SIGHS ] I'm calling out to the
spirits of the Jericho manor.
I'm calling out to the spirits of the
Jericho manor. I mean you no harm.
If anybody's there, move the
furniture.
Touch me.
[ LIGHT TAPPING ] Hello?
Who's there?
Hello? Who's there?
[ LOW GROWLING ]
Stop it now, I swear to god.
[ GASPS ] Paul, if that's you fucking
[ GASPS ] Paul,
if that's you fucking about.
Paul, if that's you fucking about.
It's not Paul.
About. It's not Paul.
[ GASPS ]
It's not Paul.
[ GASPS ] [ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
Let me out! Somebody!
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTS ] Fuck!
Jason?
Jason, if that's you, you can piss off!
I mean it, guy.
Stop messing around!
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
Look.
Stop it before someone's gonna get hurt!
[ BEEPING CONTINUES ]
[ BEEPING RAPIDLY ]
[ BEEPING STOPS ]
Piece of shit.
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING IN DISTANCE ]
What I'm sensing in this room
is a fear.
I call to the spirits in this room to come
forth. I mean you no harm, and there's
Room to come forth. I mean you no harm,
and there's nothing left to fear.
I mean you no harm, and there's
nothing left to fear. Can you hear me?
[ KNOCKS ] [ KNOCKING
CONTINUES ] Is that you?
[ KNOCKING CONTINUES ] Is that you?
Two knocks for "yes," please.
Is that you?
Two knocks for "yes," please. [ KNOCKS ]
Two knocks for "yes," please.
[ KNOCKS ] [ KNOCKS ]
this is similar to what I
[ KNOCKS ] This is similar to what
I experienced with Amanda earlier.
This is similar to what I experienced with
Amanda earlier. They're only very faint knocks.
Experienced with Amanda earlier. They're only
very faint knocks. So, I hope the camera can pick
They're only very faint knocks. So, I hope the
camera can pick them up, but I can definitely
So, I hope the camera can pick them up,
but I can definitely hear them.
Them up, but I can definitely hear them.
Thank you very much!
Hear them. Thank you very much!
Do you see what I'm holding
Thank you very much!
Do you see what I'm holding here?
This is called a camera, and it
Here? This is called a camera,
and it has a microphone on it for
This is called a camera, and it has a
microphone on it for recording sound.
Has a microphone on it for recording sound.
Can you tap the microphone, this
Recording sound. Can you tap the microphone,
this bit I'm pointing to, here?
Can you tap the microphone, this bit I'm
pointing to, here? [ EXHALES LOUDLY ]
Bit I'm pointing to, here?
[ EXHALES LOUDLY ] The problem with asking
[ EXHALES LOUDLY ] The problem with
asking spirits to do things, almost
The problem with asking spirits to do things,
almost perform, really, is that just
Spirits to do things, almost perform, really,
is that just like we would, if a complete
Perform, really, is that just like we would,
if a complete stranger started shouting
Like we would, if a complete stranger started
shouting orders, we'd just do exactly the
Stranger started shouting orders,
we'd just do exactly the opposite.
Orders, we'd just do exactly the opposite.
I'm sorry for ordering you to do
Opposite.
I'm sorry for ordering you to do things.
Do whatever you want.
Things. Do whatever you want.
Bang on the window, move the
Do whatever you want. Bang on the window,
move the chair... Whatever you want.
I'm getting the name john or Jonathan.
Say that again.
Jonathan. Say that again.
He used to be a servant here.
Why is he showing me that?
I keep getting the word "danger."
It's, like, in big, red letters
"Danger." It's, like, in big,
red letters and flashing right in front of
It's, like, in big, red letters
and flashing right in front of me.
And flashing right in front of me.
What's in danger?
Me. What's in danger?
Is it john?
What's in danger? Is it john?
Does john still feel in danger?
Is it john? Does john still feel in danger?
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
Can you repeat that, please?
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ] Who?
Who's coming?
Who? Who's coming?
[ GASPS ]
Who's coming?
[ GASPS ] Shit!
[ DOORKNOB RATTLING ]
No. No!
Come on, you stupid, bloody
No!
Come on, you stupid, bloody thing.
Shit!
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ] ye.
I thought perhaps you would be
Ye. I thought perhaps
you would be older.
I thought perhaps you would be older.
And I presume that this is the
Older. And I presume that this is
the ghost-Hunting group we talked
And I presume that this is the
ghost-Hunting group we talked about.
Ghost-Hunting group we talked about.
Yeah.
About. Yeah.
What is she supposed to be?
Here we are, in the beautiful Jericho manor,
the scene for tonight's investigation.
Jericho manor, the scene for tonight's
investigation. So, Jericho manor was built
Tonight's investigation.
So, Jericho manor was built about...
so, Jericho manor was built about...
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
Where's Anderson?!
Sorry, sir, he's gone out. Where?!
He said he was following up a
Where?! He said he was following
up a lead on that caretaker.
He said he was following up a
lead on that caretaker. Oh, shit!
Lead on that caretaker. Oh, shit!
Anything I can help you with,
Oh, shit!
Anything I can help you with, sir?
Yeah, I've been stuck next
Sir? Yeah, I've been stuck next
door going through a pile of
Yeah, I've been stuck next door going through
a pile of tapes I assumed were in order.
Door going through a pile of tapes I assumed
were in order. Now I find out they're not!
Well, you know what they say
if you assume.
Amateurs.
[ SCOFFS ] Fucking amateurs!
What was all that about?
[ SIGHS ] I'm not really sure.
Sheila? Where the hell are you?
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
Hello?
Someone doing a video?
[ RATTLING ]
[ MUSIC BOX PLAYS ] [ GASPS ]
Jesus! Don't do that to me!
Where have you been?
Don't do that to me! Where have you been?
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ PANTING ]
Jesus! Sorry.
Anything?
Sorry. Anything?
No.
You were gone ages. I was getting worried.
Yeah, I was just chatting
I was getting worried. Yeah, I was just
chatting with Sheila about her camera.
Yeah, I was just chatting with Sheila about
her camera. It looks like she's got another
With Sheila about her camera. It looks
like she's got another that loses focus.
What?
Do you think she's pretty? Who?
Do you think she's pretty?
Who? Sheila.
Who?
Sheila. No.
I only have eyes for you.
No. I only have eyes for you.
Tell me a secret.
I only have eyes for you.
Tell me a secret. What?
I mean, what kind of secret?
What? I mean, what kind of secret?
Like, I wet my bed till I was 12
I mean, what kind of secret? Like,
I wet my bed till I was 12 type of thing?
Like, I wet my bed till I
was 12 type of thing? Ew!
Type of thing? Ew!
Not that I did!
Ew! Not that I did!
I just... You know, something
Not that I did!
I just... You know, something like that.
No.
Like that. No.
I want to know something that no
No. I want to know something that
no one in the world knows apart
I want to know something that no one
in the world knows apart from you.
One in the world knows apart from you.
Okay.
[ GASPS ] [ PANTING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
No!
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
Come on, you son of a bitch!
[ PANTING ]
[ GAGGING ]
Fuck!
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ] [PANTING]
A word. Thanks.
Any news on Rubber yet?
Thanks. Any news on Rubber yet?
Nothing. Why?
Any news on Rubber yet?
Nothing. Why? Shit.
I've just seen a kid butchered
Shit. I've just seen a kid
butchered with a sickle.
I've just seen a kid butchered with a
sickle. Sound familiar to someone's
With a sickle.
Sound familiar to someone's story?
Could you I.D. The killer?
Story? Could you I.D. The killer?
Was it Rubber?
Could you I.D. The killer? Was it Rubber?
No, I couldn't see him, but
Was it Rubber? No, I couldn't see him,
but I'm sure it's him.
Find him.
[ SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE ]
[WOMAN PANTING]
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ] [
GASPS ] [ SQUEALING, PANTING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Aaahhhh!
[ CRYING ]
tsk-tsk-tsk-tsk.
Aahhh!
Aah!
[ CRYING ] Please leave me alone.
Please.
Alone. Please.
Why... Why are you doing this to
Please.
Why... Why are you doing this to me?
Why?
Me? Why?
[ PANTING ]
Aah-Ah!
[ CHOKING ]
Ow!
[ GAGGING ]
Aah!
Please. I'll do anything.
[ PANTING ]
[ UP-TEMPO DANCE MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ SINGING ] Just one of my many talents...
Singing, presenting, acting.
Just one of my many talents... Singing,
presenting, acting. Simon Cowell, if you're
Singing, presenting, acting.
Simon Cowell, if you're watching...
[ WOMAN SCREAMS ]
Probably Annie scared by an orb again.
Okay, we are probably
Again. Okay,
we are probably three-Quarters of the way
Okay, we are probably three-Quarters
of the way through the investigation.
Three-Quarters of the way through the
investigation. We had a good start with some
Through the investigation. We had a good start
with some knocking, some whistling, and,
We had a good start with some knocking, some
whistling, and, of course, the glass smashing
Knocking, some whistling, and, of course,
the glass smashing against the wall.
Of course, the glass smashing against
the wall. I think the whole team agree.
Against the wall. I think the whole
team agree. This has been the best
I think the whole team agree. This has been
the best investigation we have ever done.
This has been the best investigation
we have ever done. Okay.
Investigation we have ever done.
Okay. I'm gonna get the whole team
Okay. I'm gonna get the whole
team together, and we do one last
I'm gonna get the whole team together, and
we do one last Ouija board before we go.
Hey, guys, time to meet in the hall.
Guys?
Guys?!
This is not funny! Annie, I will kill
you if you're going along with this.
That is it! I'm gonna give you to the
count of five to get out here, or I
I'm gonna give you to the count of five to get
out here, or I promise you, you'll regret it!
Of five to get out here, or I promise you,
you'll regret it! [ DISTANT GROWLING ]
Promise you, you'll regret it!
[ DISTANT GROWLING ] 1...
2...
1... 2...
3...
2... 3...
4...
3...
4... 5!
Annie?
Jas?
[ CRYING ]
[ GAGGING ]
Annie? [ CRYING ] Annie?
Come on. Get up.
[ CRYING ] Annie?
Come on. Get up. Come on!
Annie? Come on. Get up.
Come on! [ CRYING ] No, please!
Come on!
[ CRYING ] No, please! No!
[ CRYING ] No, please!
No! Please!
[ DISTANT GROWLING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ POUNDING ON DOOR ]
Aah! Aah!
[ SNIFFLING ]
I don't know what's going on.
Everyone... everyone's dead.
It's someone in the house, but I
Everyone's dead. It's someone in the house,
but I don't know who it was.
It's someone in the house,
but I don't know who it was. [ RATTLING ]
If I don't make it, I want whoever
finds this to post to my mom.
Whoever finds this to post to my mom.
Mom, I just...
Mom. Mom, I just...
i just want to say thank you.
Mom, I just... i just want to say thank
you. Thank you for putting up with
I just want to say thank you.
Thank you for putting up with me.
I know that I'm not the easiest
Me. I know that I'm not the
easiest person to live with.
I know that I'm not the easiest person to
live with. I know I was obsessed to become
Person to live with.
I know I was obsessed to become a star.
But I only did it for us... A
A star. But I only did it for us...
A better life for us, 'cause you
But I only did it for us... A better life
for us, 'cause you deserve the best.
Better life for us,
'cause you deserve the best. [ CRYING ]
Deserve the best. [ CRYING
] [ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ CRYING ] [ THUNDER
RUMBLES ] [ DOOR OPENS ]
[ CRYING ]
[ GASPS ]
Oh.
Sh-Sheila?
I thought you were... where have you been?
Hiding.
Where have you been?
Hiding. I called out.
I heard, but how do I know
I called out. I heard,
but how do I know you aren't the killer?
I heard, but how do I know you aren't
the killer? How do I know you're not?
You aren't the killer?
How do I know you're not? [ LAUGHS ]
How do I know you're not?
[ LAUGHS ] You really don't trust
[ LAUGHS ] You really don't
trust strangers, do you?
You really don't trust strangers, do you?
You blame me?
Strangers, do you? You blame me?
We're the only people in the
You blame me?
We're the only people in the house.
It has to be you.
House. It has to be you.
Well, on that basis, I know I
It has to be you. Well, on that basis,
I know I must be looking at the killer
Well, on that basis, I know I must be looking
at the killer because I sure as hell didn't
Must be looking at the killer because
I sure as hell didn't kill anyone.
Because I sure as hell didn't kill anyone.
Oh, come off it!
Kill anyone. Oh, come off it!
The only thing I don't know is
Oh, come off it!
The only thing I don't know is why.
Look at me.
Why. Look at me.
I've been attacked.
Look at me. I've been attacked.
Yeah, by me.
I've been attacked.
Yeah, by me. No! Earlier.
Yeah, by me. No!
Earlier. Bullshit!
No! Earlier. Bullshit!
Will you just listen to me
Bullshit!
Will you just listen to me for one second?
I'm telling you.
For one second? I'm telling you.
I've been attacked.
I'm telling you.
I've been attacked. Okay.
I've been attacked.
Okay. Say I believe you.
By whom?
Say I believe you.
By whom? I don't know.
My battery went.
I don't know. My battery went.
I couldn't see.
My battery went. I couldn't see.
All I know is someone knocked
I couldn't see. All I know is someone
knocked me out, and I woke up bound and
All I know is someone knocked me out, and I
woke up bound and gagged in the kitchens.
Me out, and I woke up bound and gagged in
the kitchens. Your battery's working now.
Gagged in the kitchens. Your battery's
working now. This isn't my camera.
Your battery's working now. This isn't
my camera. You must really think I'm
This isn't my camera.
You must really think I'm thick.
Well, look, then.
If it wasn't you...
then, who?
[ SICKLE SLASHES ]
[ SQUEALS ]
[ PANTING ] [ CRIES]
[SICKLE SLASHES]
[ CRIES ] [SICKLESLASHES] Aah!
[SICKLE SLASHES] Aah!
[CRYING]
[ZIPPER UNZIPS,
SICKLE SLASHES] Aah!
[ MONITOR SHUTS OFF ]
[ RATTLING ]
Aah!
[ CRYING ]
Aahhh!
Wakey, wakey.
Aah! Stop that.
It will affect the sound
Stop that.
It will affect the sound balance.
Terribly sorry, but I can't have
Balance. Terribly sorry,
but I can't have you ruin my final shot.
Terribly sorry, but I can't have you ruin
my final shot. What do you want from me?
You ruin my final shot.
What do you want from me? Want from you?
What do you want from me?
Want from you? No, no, no, no, no.
You see, it's all about what I
No, no, no, no, no. You see,
it's all about what I can do for you.
You see, it's all about what I can do
for you. You see, I'm gonna make you...
Can do for you.
You see, I'm gonna make you... famous!
Just let me go, please.
Famous! Just let me go, please.
I swear, I won't tell anyone.
Just let me go, please. I swear,
I won't tell anyone. [ CRYING ] I promise.
I swear, I won't tell anyone. [ CRYING
] I promise. You're missing the point.
[ CRYING ] I promise. You're missing
the point. I want people to know.
You're missing the point.
I want people to know. Now...
I want people to know.
Now... [ CRYING ]
Now...
[ CRYING ]...are you ready for your
[ CRYING ]...are you
ready for your close-Up?
...Are you ready for your close-Up?
No! Please, no!
Close-Up? No!
Please, no! No?!
No! Please, no! No?!
I thought you wanted to be a
No?!
I thought you wanted to be a star.
No, I don't.
Star. No, I don't.
I just want to go home!
No, I don't. I just want to go home!
Oh, come on now.
I just want to go home!
Oh, come on now. Don't be sad.
Oh, come on now.
Don't be sad. [ LAUGHS ]
Don't be sad.
[ LAUGHS ] Be happy!
This is the opportunity of a
Be happy!
This is the opportunity of a lifetime.
[ CRYING ] Please, please,
Lifetime.
[ CRYING ] Please, please, let me go!
Tsk.
Let me go! Tsk.
You disappoint me.
Tsk. You disappoint me.
Amanda.
You disappoint me.
Amanda. You really do.
Ah, the youth of today... They
You really do. Ah, the youth of today...
They want it all wrapped up and
Ah, the youth of today... They want it all
wrapped up and handed to them on a plate.
Want it all wrapped up and handed to them
on a plate. They aren't prepared to put in
Handed to them on a plate. They aren't
prepared to put in the hard work!
They aren't prepared to put in the
hard work! What do you want from me,
The hard work!
What do you want from me, you freak?!
Oh, freak... I like that.
You freak?! Oh, freak... I like that.
What do I want?
Oh, freak... I like that.
What do I want? I want you to die.
What do I want?
I want you to die. Why me?
I want you to die.
Why me? Why you?
Well, let me see.
Why you? Well, let me see.
You disgust me.
Well, let me see.
You disgust me. That's why.
Your kind get all the attention,
That's why. Your kind get all the
attention, all the money, while people
Your kind get all the attention, all the
money, while people like me get spat at!
Long hours, low pay, used to be admired.
Know what I mean?
Admired. Know what I mean?
Used to be admired, but now
Know what I mean? Used to be admired,
but now people pay false worship to the
Used to be admired, but now people
pay false worship to the idiot box.
People pay false worship to the idiot box.
The idiots watching with their
Idiot box. The idiots watching
with their plastic gods.
The idiots watching with their
plastic gods. Well, no more.
Plastic gods.
Well, no more. No more.
I ain't gonna be a faceless man
No more. I ain't gonna be a
faceless man in the crowd.
I ain't gonna be a faceless man in
the crowd. I'm gonna eradicate you
In the crowd. I'm gonna eradicate
you talentless, wannabe stars one by
I'm gonna eradicate you talentless, wannabe
stars one by one until people fear to be
Talentless, wannabe stars one by one until people
fear to be famous and realize who the true
One until people fear to be famous and
realize who the true gods in society are.
Famous and realize who the true
gods in society are. [ CRYING ]
Shall I tell you a little story?
Three years ago... Three long, lonely years,
my beloved wife was diagnosed with a rare form
Lonely years, my beloved wife was
diagnosed with a rare form of cancer.
Was diagnosed with a rare form of cancer.
It was the only one in the
Of cancer.
It was the only one in the country.
What are the odds?
Country. What are the odds?
Anyway, on my wage, a copper's
What are the odds? Anyway, on my wage,
a copper's wage, we couldn't afford the
Anyway, on my wage, a copper's wage, we couldn't
afford the private clinics or flights to
Wage, we couldn't afford the private clinics
or flights to america, so, I had to watch my
Private clinics or flights to america, so, I
had to watch my beautiful, kindhearted wife
America, so, I had to watch my beautiful,
kindhearted wife deteriorate right before my
Beautiful, kindhearted wife
deteriorate right before my eyes.
Deteriorate right before my eyes.
She suffered more than anyone
Eyes. She suffered more than
anyone should ever suffer.
Here's the thing. Amanda, do you know
what the main news was that day on the
Amanda, do you know what the main
news was that day on the telly, hmm?
Main news was that day on the telly, hmm?
The main news the day my world
Telly, hmm? The main news the day my
world came crashing down, the day she
The main news the day my world came
crashing down, the day she died?
Came crashing down, the day she died?
[ CHUCKLES ]
Died?
[ CHUCKLES ] [ VOICE BREAKING ] Some
[ CHUCKLES ] [ VOICE BREAKING ]
some footballer was gonna sign for
[ VOICE BREAKING ] Some footballer was gonna
sign for some fucking football team and
Footballer was gonna sign for some fucking
football team and get 100 grand a week.
Where's the justice in that?
I'm sorry. Hmm?
[ CRYING ] I'm sorry.
Hmm? [ CRYING ] I'm sorry.
Oh, thank you.
[ CRYING ] I'm sorry. Oh, thank you.
But I'm not to blame.
Oh, thank you.
But I'm not to blame. Yes, you are.
But I'm not to blame.
Yes, you are. Yes, you are!
Yes, you are.
Yes, you are! Aah!
You are still pathetic,
Aah!
You are still pathetic, attempting fame.
You flaunt your face, your
Attempting fame. You flaunt your face,
your "talents," your body.
You flaunt your face, your "talents,"
your body. You got thousands of admirers
"Talents," your body.
You got thousands of admirers and for what?
Have you ever put your lives on
And for what? Have you ever put your
lives on the line by running into a
Have you ever put your lives on the line by
running into a burning building or faced a gang
The line by running into a burning building or
faced a gang of drunken thugs on the street?
Burning building or faced a gang of drunken
thugs on the street? No, of course you haven't.
Of drunken thugs on the street? No, of course
you haven't. But it's your face in the
No, of course you haven't.
But it's your face in the magazines.
It's your kind that get to drive
Magazines. It's your kind that get
to drive the "mercs," the "beemers."
It's your kind that get to drive the "mercs,"
the "beemers." You're fucking crazy!
The "mercs," the "beemers."
You're fucking crazy! Ah, yeah, possibly.
You're fucking crazy!
Ah, yeah, possibly. Listen, Amanda.
Ah, yeah, possibly.
Listen, Amanda. [ CRYING ]
Listen, Amanda.
[ CRYING ] You should really be thanking
[ CRYING ] You should
really be thanking me.
You should really be thanking me.
'Cause when people see what I'm
Me. 'Cause when people see
what I'm gonna do to you...
'cause when people see what I'm gonna do
to you... you're gonna be really famous.
Gonna do to you...
you're gonna be really famous. Wait!
You're gonna be really famous.
Wait! What?
You forgot one thing.
What? You forgot one thing.
What?
You forgot one thing. What?
No one steals my limelight!
[ SICKLE SLICES ]
It's okay.
It was for you, my darling.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay, see, because you've
It's okay. It's okay, see,
because you've just become a star!
It's okay, see, because you've
just become a star! [ GAGGING ]
Just become a star!
[ GAGGING ] [ SICKLE SLICES ]
[ BLOOD DRIPPING ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ] So, you got my money,
huh? I just wanted to check the
So, you got my money, huh?
I just wanted to check the details.
[ BONES CRACKING ]
All right.
Aah!
[ VEHICLE DOOR CLOSES ]
[ CHANGING RADIO STATION ] The report stated
that their publicist refused to comment on
The report stated that their publicist
refused to comment on their rumored divorce.
Publicist refused to comment on their rumored
divorce. In other news, police are still
Their rumored divorce. In other news,
police are still hunting for marc Rubber in
In other news, police are still hunting for
marc Rubber in connection with the massacre at
Hunting for marc Rubber in connection with the
massacre at Jericho manor house last night.
Connection with the massacre at Jericho manor
house last night. The caretaker of the manor has
Jericho manor house last night. The caretaker
of the manor has been missing since police
The caretaker of the manor has been missing
since police interviewed him earlier this
Been missing since police interviewed him
earlier this morning and is considered
Interviewed him earlier this morning
and is considered extremely dangerous.
Morning and is considered extremely
dangerous. Anyone who has information
Extremely dangerous. Anyone who has
information regarding Mr. Ruber's
Anyone who has information regarding
Mr. Ruber's whereabouts...
Regarding Mr. Ruber's whereabouts...
[ CHANGING STATION ]
Whereabouts... [ CHANGING STATION
] [ MID-TEMPO DANCE MUSIC PLAYS ]
# catastrophe and history, over land
or the sea # # crisis theory mastery
Over land or the sea # # crisis
theory mastery by the life given me #
# catastrophe and history over land or
the sea # # crisis theory mastery,
Over land or the sea # # crisis
theory mastery, by the life given me #
[ LIQUID POURING ]
[ TYPING ] Oh, hi.
My name is crysta.
Oh, hi. My name is crysta.
And I'm gonna be a big star!
My name is crysta.
And I'm gonna be a big star! [LAUGHS]