Get in that bed!
It's too dark, I can't sleep.
Brian, do you know
what time it is?
But there's a monster in
here and he wants to get me.
If you don't lie down
right now I'm gonna getcha!
Come on there.
Uncle Mike?
Sometimes mommy tells me a
story, will you tell me one?
No, not right now, Brian.
I hafta press the cat
and vacuum the ceiling.
Maybe later.
Oh please, just one?
Brian.
Please?
All right,
any story in particular?
Three little pigs?
Jack and the beanstalk?
I don't care.
Um, puss in boots?
Rumpelstiltskin?
Whatever.
Princess and the pea?
Ugly duckling?
Sleeping beauty?
If you like.
Brian, what story?
Hmm, why don't you make one up?
Alright.
J1 the three little pigs
j1 were blown out of their digs
x3 and their houses
and huts were despoiled
a1 the wolf huffed and puffed
j1 'til the pigs cried enough
ii how can this wicked
monster be foiled
j1 two piggies were eaten
d before he was beaten
41 down the chimney the
wolf was hard boiled
j1 it's no wonder why
i3 I turned out like I did
ii remembering my
bedtime tales as a kid
j1 it's no wonder why
i3 I turned out like I did
ii remembering my
bedtime tales as a kid
j1 a boy strong and proud
j1 climbed way up to the clouds
41 on a product of
magic bean spillage
d brave and defiant
j1 he swindled the giant
41 whose wealth came
from plundering village
a1 then he picked up an axe
41 gave the beanstalk
some whacks
d dumped the giant on
most of the village
j1 it's no wonder why
i3 I turned out like I did
ii remembering my
bedtime tales as a kid
j1 it's no wonder why
i3 I turned out like I did
ii remembering my
bedtime tales as a kid
a1 in the cloak of the night
j1 I wake with a fright
j1 got a blanket over my head
j1 you can say I'm insane
j1 but it's stuck in my brain
h rumpelstiltskin's under my bed
d some call it obscene
i1 but the violence on screen
41 vents the internal
turmoil of drama
j1 those buckets of Gore
a1 were spilled ages before
ii George romero,
Hitchcock or de palma
i3 and our fears and our stress
j1 throughout time's
been expressed
d through the fairytale
symbolic drama
j1 it's no wonder why
d we turned out like we did
a1 remembering our
bedtime tales as kids
j1 it's no wonder why
d we turned out like we did
a1 remembering our
bedtime tales as kids
j1 it's no wonder why
d we turned out like we did
a1 remembering our
bedtime tales as kids
j1 it's no wonder why
d we turned out like we did
a1 remembering our
bedtime tales as kids
um, once upon a time,
a long, long time ago.
There was a Fisherman's
son named Peter.
He was all alone in the world.
So it came to pass,
since he had no money,
he sold into slavery.
Bought by two evil witches.
So then, one day...
Good?
You bet it is!
Does my heart good
to see a handsome lad
enjoy my cooking.
The secret is baby slugs.
The big ones are too chewy!
You have to wait for
the really rainy days.
But you are worth it.
You're making me sick!
(Get up, b0)!-
there's work to be done.
You go to the village,
find the local parson.
If I'm not wrong
he fancies himself.
Thinks he's quite a ladies' man.
Are you listening to me, boy?
Tell him you know
two lovely ladies
who are just dying to meet him.
And you lead him here.
What lovely ladies?
Never you mind.
Make sure he has a sip of that.
Leave the rest to me.
You wouldn't be
tricking me now, would you boy?
They are beautiful?
Hmm?
Aye. That they are.
They got all their teeth?
Can't kiss a tart with
rotten teeth, you know.
I would suppose.
Are they, are they sassy?
You know...
Sassy!
Sassy.
Boy, what'd you say
your name was again?
Peter.
Do I see you in my church?
They're almost here.
Well, get ready.
It's alright, boy.
I can find my way.
Where's my sassy?
Grand!
I bet you ladies have never
had such a prominent
man as I, huh?
Mmmmm.
You little vixens!
It's a bit of bondage, eh?
Oh yeah.
Has the lad told 'ya
that I have the largest
parsonage in the district?
And my flock of Norman.
They pray to me, you know.
So that's what you're up to.
And squeak!
(Flaughs)
What is this stuff anyway?
It's gettin'...
Get this stuff off of me!
Here we are.
Take the divine left hand
from a holy man.
The one that mirrors his heart.
Well ain't nothin' holy
about that one.
Shhhh!
Pay attention.
Brain of a black cat,
heart of an eel.
Grind them together
until they congeal.
Brain of a black cat,
brain of a black cat.
Black cat, heart.
What was it?
Heart of a weasel?
No no fat 0l' fool,
an eel, an eel!
I'm not fat!
You're not fat.
Eel.
Eel?
No eel!
Here we are!
Now grind them together and...
I know, I know!
There, that looks
pretty congealed!
Now pour in a vial
of hemlock and ale.
And top it all off with
a black piggie's tale.
Oh how sweet.
Now, my friend,
guide us true.
Where's our sister?
Where's magoga?
West?
The paupers' field.
Peter, come along!
Stop playin' with the nice man.
What have I told you about
talkin' to strangers?
Is this it?
Did we find her?
Shhh!
Quiet!
What is it, hanagohl?
She's here.
She's here!
Get out the way!
Do you mind?
Where is she?
Magoga.
What have they done to you?
Why did you wait so long
to dig your sister
magoga up anyway?
This one asks
too many questions.
Ahh there's no harm.
You see, Peter, the
spell to bring her back
can only be cast when the
full moon and the solstice
come together on Friday.
Once every 36 years.
37.
37?
Are you sure?
No, I've spent the last
28 years followin' it out.
Of course I'm sure, stupid.
I'm not stupid!
You are stupid,
mother always said so.
Mother always liked you best.
Mother was a good woman.
Nasty woman, she was.
Ls that it? Are we ready?
No, there's one last
ingredient to be got.
This is your busy day, boy.
Your hair, too.
Can't lure the sorta girl we
need if you're all a mess.
Remember, squeaky clean!
Here, maybe I better help you.
No, no no no, florinda.
I can do it.
Can I have my clothes now?
Please, now?
Ma'am?
Mmmmm?
What did you mean when
you said "that sort of girl?"
All in good time.
Ma'am?
Mmmmm?
I don't mind going out
and getting you herbs and
animals for your magic,
but I didn't know you were
going to hurt that priest.
We do what we have to do!
Yeah, but killing people?
There are some things
you just won't understand.
Leave it to hanagohl and me.
Leave what to you and me?
What's his problem?
He don't like you and me
killin' people.
Oh, that's too bad, innit?
You do as you're told,
you lazy turd.
Now hurry up, the both of 'ya.
Reminds me of
myself in my youth.
We're not going to hurt her,
are we?
You can't keep killing
people, it's just plain wrong.
I don't know what's
gettin' into you!
If you won't do this
one little thing for me,
well then, you can just
go on back a-home, mm-hmm?
Yes, ma'am.
What do you want me to do?
You get her attention.
Then I'll sneak up on her
with a cloth.
What do I do?
Think of something.
Hello?
Can I help you with that?
I'm fine.
Um, I seem to be a little lost.
Village is that way.
Thanks.
So, uh, do you live here
by yourself?
No, I share the place
with a bunch of dwarfs.
Can I help you with something?
I've been pretty much
walking for the past few days
and I was wondering, do you
have some food or something?
A beggar.
I shouldn't be taking people in.
Our parson's just been
found murdered!
I mean who knows what
kind of lunatic you'd be?
Take a seat.
This bread is very good, much
softer than we make at home.
Baked this afternoon.
You're staring at me.
You're very pretty, Miranda.
Maybe...
Peter, what is it?
Good work.
Help me get her into the barrow.
We may yet make a warlock
out of you, Peter!
And hanagohl will be so pleased!
You two took your
ol' sweet time.
It's almost midnight!
So.
So this is our sacrifice, is it?
Come on, don't stand
there, give us a hand!
Hasn't she got
the loveliest eyes?
I want 'em after!
I get the eyes!
You got 'em last time!
I never get anything good.
I get the eyes!
Well, I claim
all the teeth, then.
Ohhh!
Come on, it's gettin' late.
Ma'am?
What is it?
Can I be the one
to use the knife?
What?
Yes, do let him,
i think he's ready.
No, it's too important.
You do it.
He can kill the next sacrifice.
It's time.
Go ahead, make me proud.
Don't worry.
Stay calm and follow my lead.
Go on, read it!
You read it.
I can't read.
You know I can't read.
Umerigus, leviathan,
demons of the pit, hear us.
Lord of the plague,
send us the soul
of our forsaken sister.
Nourish her with this dance.
And fill her full of hatred.
Take this life in
thy darkest name.
A life for a life!
Now, you fool.
Now, kill her!
Peter!
Ungrateful witch!
I'm going to kill you!
I'm gonna cut you into
pieces when I'm through
with your little slut!
Witch!
I'm gonna hurt you
like you hurt me!
You know, it woulda been
a lot easier
if you just ran away
when I suggested it.
Excuse me, sir, but you
could you please tell us
how to get outta here?
You killed my sisters.
I'm gonna make this
very painful.
Ew, that's a mushy icky ending.
Well what kind of an
ending would you like?
Hmm, how 'bout a scary ending?
And you'll go to sleep?
Promise.
(0k3)!-
just then, magoga jumped
back to life, and...
Better?
Much.
Okay, good night, kid.
Good night,
night-night.
Uncle Mike!
Isn't she just adorable, folks?
What now?
Thank you, thank you!
What is it?
A monster was gonna get me.
Oh Brian, for Christ's sakes,
the miss nude bayonne
competition
is on cablevision right now!
One more story, please?
Which story?
Hmm, little red riding hood.
Little red riding hood.
Hmm.
(0k3)!-
once upon a time, there was
a little girl called Rachel.
Actually, she wasn't
all that little.
She was a hot looking
high school senior,
with clear blue eyes
and fine firm breasts.
That's not the way
mommy tells it.
Shut up, that's the way
i tell it.
Anyhow, one day she came home
after cheerleading practice,
and she realized she wanted
to go jogging.
Rachel, Rachel!
I need you to run an errand
for your grandmother.
Okay, mom.
Uncle Mike, this story stinks.
Where's the big bad wolf?
Isn't there supposed to be
a big bad wolf?
Well yeah, I'm gettin' to that.
Meanwhile across town there
lived this guy named Willie.
Was he a wolf?
Well, uh no.
Technically he wasn't,
not full time anyway.
What's happening, my man?
Got a little present
for you from the islands.
Oh really, I love there.
Hmmmm.
Save that for my vacation.
Er1j'°y-
lunch hour, ha.
So how much do i
owe you this time?
Uh, $25 will do it.
I could only get seven
for you this time.
You know we had an arrangement.
I know, just uh, raise the
price when you resell 'em.
Yeah, sure.
I don't know who would take
this shit anyhow, frankly.
I took two a-these, knocked
me out for two days.
- Excuse me.
- Hello.
Yes ma'am,
what can I do for you.
Well I'm here to
pick up a prescription
for my grandmother?
Name's Krieger?
Uh huh, is this a house account?
Uh, yeah.
Oh, all outta the charge
slips, I'll be right back.
So, what's your name?
Rachel.
It's a pretty name.
Thank you.
Biblical, huh?
I wouldn't know.
Doing anything later?
None of your business.
Here you are, miss Krieger.
If you'll just sign here.
(0k3)!-
Rachel.
Oh, where?
Just anywhere
on the bottom is fine.
Here you go.
Thank you, bye bye.
Bye.
Always a pleasure.
Take this.
It'll help you forget.
Right
sorry.
Where were you?
Just running.
Waiting for you.
Hi.
Not here.
You're not gonna back
out on me again, are you?
You wanna go someplace else?
You gave me the goddamn
grandmother's medicine.
What are you talkin' about?
- Oh shit.
- Oh shit is right.
I need those pills.
Well maybe you should
ask granny for 'em.
Maybe you should ask
granny tomorrow morning,
she's gonna be sleepin'
pretty well tonight.
Just give me
her address then, quick.
Oh man, I can't do that.
Listen to me, you little shit.
If I'm not out cold
by moonrise tonight.
Get me her address.
Now.
Here we are.
This is it.
You're serious, aren't you?
What do 'ya think?
How very classy.
Well, lucky for you, I just
happen to have some candles.
Oh.
And, an air mattress.
How very spontaneous.
Um, did you happen to bring
an air pump by any chance?
Yes, can I help you?
Yeah hi, um, is Rachel here?
No.
She's not here.
What's your name?
Willie.
Willie, ah, if you
leave your number
I'll have her call you.
No, no, you can't do that
you see, it's kinda important.
Look can I just, can I just...
Oh absolutely not.
No, if you can't leave your
number you'll have to go.
Excuse me.
Open the door.
I will not, now you go
away or I'll call the police!
Lady, will you just
open the door?
Lady.
Lady!
Open the fucking door!
C'mon, lady!
I have a meat cleaver here
and I know how to use it!
Alright.
Wait.
- What?
- I gotta pee.
I'm back.
I missed you.
Hi.
What's the matter now?
Making love, here.
Spiders.
Nah, it's too cold for spiders.
You scared?
Relax.
Fuck.
No.
I'm not ready.
I don't look any different.
What?
Nothing.
Did you hear that?
- Hear what?
- Shhh!
I don't hear anything.
Sorry we did it?
No.
Good.
Hey come on, it's gettin' late.
What time is it?
I don't know, must be about six.
Oh shit, my grandma's
gonna kill me.
Who's there?
Stop it!
Well, we're here.
You don't want me to
walk you to the door?
No, I'm in enough trouble.
Wait here, I'll be back.
Gram?
What, help.
Gram!
Operator, oh please,
something terrible's happened.
Oh, send an ambulance, yes.
My address is 80 oakley road.
And please hurry!
Dr. Martin, Dr. Martin.
Please dial 314.
Please dial 3...
Don't you think it's
time you headed home?
It's my fault.
How can you say that?
I wanna be here
when she wakes up.
Can I get you
some tea or something?
No.
Gram?
Rachel?
Oh, Rachel.
Gram, I was so worried.
It's okay.
How do you feel?
I ran to the door.
That bastard jumped me
from behind.
I'm so sorry, I should've...
Gram?
Are you alright?
Grandma!
What big teeth you have!
Red riding hood is grabbed
in a frenzy
of snarls and growls.
Ripped apart and unfortunately,
no one lived happily ever after.
The end, good...
Night.
Uncle Mike?
Uncle Mike!
Ahhh, monster!
Monster!
There is no monster in here.
There's no monster in here.
Nothing here, nothing here.
Definite deficit of monsters
in here, isn't there?
No monster in here.
Nothing in here.
Okay, so you see there's no
monster in this room, right?
Just one more story, please?
Goldilocks and the
three bears, please?
Nooo!
Just one, please!
- No no no no no more.
- Please! Just one!
It's time to go to bed.
- And I'll go to bed, please!
- Brian, no no no, Brian!
Once upon a time, on a
bright, sunny spring day.
While the birds were singing
and the bees were bee-ing.
There lived papa baer, and
mama baer, and baby baer.
And a little girl named
goldi lox.
Alright, alright,
just what do you two
think you're doin'?
We're goin' home.
Sure you are, maybe
you'd like some money
to take along with you?
Sure, that'd be real...
Let me handle this!
Now we don't want any
problems from you, pal.
We'll be outta here
in a few minutes.
Okay, okay, why don't
you just give me that gun
before you get yourselves
in trouble?
Now don't try anything funny.
Look dad, it's mama!
Oh no, I'm not fallin'
for that old one.
Oh, I am sorry i am late!
But you wouldn't believe
the day I had,
one thing after another.
First, this morning,
i get a phone call.
Mr. Henri got his head stuck
in the revolving doors.
So I get to my 3:30...
Hairdressers, then, I'm sitting
down, watching, donahue...
Why don't you tell us
on the way?
Oh yes.
Hang on, boys.
Heads up.
See.
Only grazed him the first time.
J1 life these days can be a mess
j1 daily decisions we distress
a1 dreading what each
brand new day might bring
h ah, their voices in your head
41 and do you dive
beneath the bed
h every time the phone
begins to ring
41 well if your psyche's
all undone
a1 there's a place
where you can run
41 where folks are
weavin' baskets
j1 and even flies are having fun
papa.
What?
I have to go.
Oh baby, you shoulda
thought a-that
before we left the asylum.
Happens every time
we go anywhere.
Can we stop for ice cream?
No!
Just where are we goin' anyway?
Remember that nice little
house we used to live in?
I think it's vacant now.
Oh yeah, the one in amityville.
H I beg to see where maybe bliss
h and there is nothing
wrong with this
41 those students can have
trouble findin' dates
a1 if you need a place to play
j1 find yourself a hideaway
fl after all it worked
for Norman bates
d hahahahahaha
it's not that I'm not flattered.
It's just that I'm, well,
not ready to make
that kind of commitment.
I'm sorry things didn't
work out between us.
You are kind of cute.
Oh will you be quiet?
Well, I guess we better
head inside.
I really should be angry at you.
You boys are all the same.
Just want one thing
and one thing only.
Just like all the rest.
Afternoon, boys!
Why don't you give us a kiss?
What kind of girl
do you think I am?
That kind.
Let's see, Norman, this is Fred.
Fred, Norman, you two should
get along well together.
You have a lot in common.
Time for news view
from the channel 12 news.
This morning the calm Serenity
of the saints preserve us
home for the helplessly insane
was shattered
by the bloody breakout
of beresford "papa" baer
and wilmont "baby" baer,
who are each sewing
combined sentences
of 4,726 years
for their assorted crimes.
With me is lt. Jack b.
Nimble of the Metro police.
Tell me, lieutenant, are
there any new developments
in the breakout?
Well our best clue so
far is a set a-tire tracks
from the car.
Surely, there are
quite a few cars
with similar tread patterns?
But not with dentures in them.
In addition to the baer
family's bloody escape today,
police believe the murderous
goldi lox,
who escaped last week,
is now in our vicinity.
Miss lox has been...
Hey Leo, that's me!
Since the age of eight,
exhibits extreme
psychotic behavior
and is believed to be
responsible for the deaths
of at least 14 people,
including her own parents.
You are gonna me a star!
I'm the darling of the
media already.
Captain quick,
tell me what is your strategy?
That is, exactly what
measures are being taken
to end the ghastly,
murderous spree of miss lox?
Well uh, we plan to arrest her
and, of course, put her in jail.
That oughta do it.
Moreover, it has been alleged,
although this reporter
finds it highly unlikely,
that miss lox has some
unusual psychic powers.
Although we hasten to add,
this has never been confirmed.
In other news, president...
Consider it confirmed.
Are we almost there yet?
I'm hungry-
oh there's a picnic basket
there in the back there.
Now we're gettin' somewhere.
What the hell is this?
Porridge?
Why must we always
have porridge?
Don't you know how to make
anything but porridge?
Tradition.
Well, let's start
a new tradition.
Steak, pork, yak,
anything but porridge.
You know we can't afford steak.
Not on your salary.
Which, at the moment,
is nothing.
Right, we need money.
How 'bout welfare?
What?
Welfare, that's ridiculous.
Our family will get our money
the way we've always gotten it.
Honorable!
Hey, hey you can't
do that, stop!
You can't do that!
Whoopsie.
And that was the scene today
as the notorious baer family
successfully pulled off a
daring daylight robbery.
I'm fortunate enough to have
in the studio with me today,
lt. Nimble, of the area police,
in charge of the
baer family apprehension,
and captain quick, of
the state police,
in charge of the
lox investigation.
Gentlemen, thank you
for taking time
out of your busy schedules
to be with us today.
Sure, anything
to get on television.
Captain quick, what do you
think the recent murder sprees
say about today's society?
Hmph, I don't know.
Well it's um, uh, it's
because of, uh, today's
permissive sex and, uh,
and recreational violence.
It's like a huge,
festering pus wad
and it just keeps
getting larger and bigger
and grows larger and
larger until it explodes
covering us all with a
sticky, slimy, smelly mess.
It's like when you
lay down with dogs,
you get up with puppies.
Well let's follow that up,
lt. Nimble.
In cases such as these,
what are the chances
for a successful rehabilitation?
Well, l..
You gotta catch 'em first.
- What?
- You have to catch 'em first.
What do you mean by that?
Nothing, remember I've
seen you in action, heh.
Are you saying I'm a bad cop?
Yeah, I'm callin' you a bad cop.
Oh yeah?
Hey fellas, we are on the air!
Why I oughta...
Someone's in there, all right.
J1 my, mmmmmm, my Eden
maybe we could throw in
a few of these
just to soften up the area.
At the community college,
silly, I took, uh, pyrotechnics,
hand-to-hand combat,
and what else?
Oh yes, macrame.
Nah, too messy.
Let's go in with the old
avon lady bit.
Just cover us with the uzi.
41 oh, ummm
j1 vee El, oh oh oh oh yeah
41 oh oh, ummmm, oh
i3 vee ummm
someone's sleepin' in my bed!
Someone's sleepin' in my bed.
Somebody's sleepin' in my, yuck!
J1 I like walking in the rain
d do do do Dee ee dah ta da
i3 doot doot doot do doot do
d la ia la la la la
j1 ree Lee up boo ippity
you were expecting perhaps
Janet Lee?
All right, get out!
Look what I found.
I'm sorry, I didn't
think anyone lived here.
Aren't you cute.
What's your name, honey.
Goldi, goldi lox.
Actually, it's golda, I was
born during the six day war.
Isn't she darling.
Shall I waste her, dear?
No, don't, I'm...
I wouldn't be much bother.
I can cook and do
all sorts of things.
Well, I don't know.
What do you “fink, mama'?
I think she'll fit in
just fine around here.
She'll be like the daughter
we never had.
And you'll be like the
parents I brutally slaughtered.
She's been spotted
here, here, and here.
Now our reconnaissance
says she has to be here
in this deserted house.
So, here's the plan of action.
In one hour we'll form on a
highway just outside the house.
Once we group, we go in,
in plainclothes cars.
We'll line up out front and
wait for her to come out.
And bring plenty
of firepower, boys.
This little girl's our dynamo.
D you musta been
a beautiful baby
i1 musta been a beautiful child
huh?
Oh, hello baby.
You startled me.
Gee, I'm sorry.
Papa asked me to
bury these guys.
So tell me, why do they
call you baby, anyway?
I don't know.
I guess I got it
when I was younger.
Oh.
I like you, baby.
You're so... different.
I'm just a regular guy.
No, don't ever say that!
You've got to be different
from the rest.
I like you, too, goldi!
Kiss me!
Wow, what a woman!
I love 'ya!
Baby!
Oh I love you.
Baby.
Baby!
No, too rough, no.
'Baby!
"No!
- No, no.
- Baby.
Baby!
"No!
If only I'd known.
Sorry, boys.
She loves me.
We know the baers are holed up
in that house across the field.
Now considering the
shrewd criminal mind
we're dealing with...
She loves me not.
We decided to enter
through the rear.
That's my idea.
She loves me.
You spell the name, n-i-m...
She loves me not.
B-l-e.
Now, in case there's shooting.
Remember, drop low
and to my right.
That's my best side.
She loves me!
We thank thee, lord,
for what we are
about to receive.
Porridge again?
With all that commotion
i didn't have the time
to go to the store today.
And on top of all that,
it's too hot!
What do we do?
Well, why don't we go
for a walk until it cools?
Nah, screw it, let's go
get a pizza.
Papa, I have to go.
No!
No way. I told you,
i don't like hairy fish.
All right, no anchovies.
Do you want anything else?
Can I have a drink, papa?
Sure, why not?
I'll have a double
bourbon and whiskey, please.
I'll have a yoo-hoo.
No, no you won't.
Choco pop, okay?
What about you, little Princess?
Coke.
She's one...
Alright men, that's far enough.
From these positions we
have optimum viewing capacity.
I don't want anyone to advance...
Further, until you
hear my signal.
The thing to do here...
Is to remain calm...
Alert, and relaxed.
- The key...
- Ls not...
_tq__
- over...
React!
I'm gettin' too old
for this type of life.
I didn't want you to be
part of it.
I had other plans for you.
Senator baer.
Governor baer.
President baer.
Not this.
If only we could
just settle down
quietly somewheres.
Ah, not now, we're probably
on every police blotter
in the country.
Where will we go, what'll we do?
California, we'd
probably blend in there.
Nobody would notice us there.
Yeah!
And you can become one of
them television preachers.
Fire!
Cease fire, cease fire!
And so the scene here
is total carnage.
To repeat, the infamous
baer gang has been wiped out
by a fierce firefight
that utilized
the combined efforts
of local authorities
and the state police.
In addition, the report
is that little goldi lox,
who is known to have
killed a dozen plus people,
was also consumed in the fray.
There are a great many bodies...
Okay that was two
specials and two cokes.
Okay that'll be...
I can't breathe.
My treat.
And they all lived
happily ever after.
Oops.
Though not everyone
they came across was so lucky.
Okay, no more stories?
No more stories.
Okay. Good night.
Night.
Uncle Mike?
Thank you!
Nahhh!
I3 I was leanin' on an oak tree
j1 I was lookin' pretty tough
a1 when this kickin'
red sweaterjammin'
41 came by running
through the rough
41 she was wearin'
high heeled nikes
d as she sprinted
through the wood
h she had sexy thighs
and her big blue eyes
j1 were peekin' through her hood
y:
J1 hey you in red
j1 why don't you wait for me
j1 did you hear what I said
j1 can you slow down please
i1 you don't have to run
d we can have some fun
j1 honey don't you be a tease
j1 I got a cold wet nose
a1 real flashy clothes
j1 and I burn to be your pet
41 I got lonely pangs
j1 so ignore my fangs
j1 I ain't bit no one yet
d but she said no
j1 she just kept goin'
a1 and juggin' down that trail
j1 I'm no punk, I never give up
i1 just a wolf after a tail
y:
J1 hey you in red
j1 why don't you wait for me
d whoa there red
a1 come on and slow down please
i1 you don't have to run
d we can have some fun
j1 honey don't you be a tease
j1 I said hey cutie pants
d give me a chance
h let me see what's
in your basket
j1 I'll be good to you
j1 I do just what you wanna do
a1 all you got to do is ask it
a1 I was graspin' at straws
j1 sprain my two back paws
i1 stumblin' after her
j1 so I yelled
j1 I'm a wolf among men
j1 come on back to my den
41 run your fingers
through my fur
i3 yeah
y:
J1 hey you in red
j1 why can't you wait for me
i3 slow down there red
41 you know this ain't
the grand prix
j1 forget your mama's advice
i3 wolves can be nice
41 just wait up and ha ha
d you'll see
y:
D come on