[male] In the rolling hills
of a simple farm community
untouched by time,
a gruesome secret
has been protected
for generations.
[motor starts up]
Hey!
- I brought you a surprise.
- A surprise, huh?
I love you.
Faith stowaway often at this farm.
Oh! Get away from me,
William Gluntz.
Ugly, Hittite pig brain.
- Stop it, Gluntz!
- Incubus.
You retard!
[Gluntz] Incubus.
- [girl yells]
- Servant of the incubus.
Ma!
William, William!
Hell fire to the incubus!
Hell fire to you, Hittite!
Get back where you belong, William.
You're gonna be
in trouble with Isaiah.
Infidel.
He chasin' you again?
He broke my paints, Ma.
I'll get ya some more.
Get on back home, Faith.
Go on.
You, know, uh...
William never really hurt anybody.
Tell that to Faith.
Every time she comes near that place
that Gluntz idiot starts chasin' her
like he was some kinda
guard dog or somethin'!
Of course, I know it ain't nothin'
you can help.
Well, you tell her
she's welcome over here.
Well, I like her at home.
Out of people's hair.
Anyways, you have my thanks.
Okay, in a while we'll be calling
on you for somethin'.
You do midwifin', don'tcha?
Hey,
don't say... when?
It won't be until spring sometime.
Well, I hope it's a girl.
Boys ain't nothin' but trouble.
Incubus!
She incubus!
Whoa.
Uh!
Ow.
We have no use
for that kind of machinery.
So do not covet what he has.
He is dead.
Do you understand?
Yes, Father, I understand.
I'm sorry.
Damn it.
Damn, damn, damn, damn!
[female] Faith?
Faith!
You hear me callin' you?
Dinner's ready.
Sorry, Lou, I guess I'm just too busy
thinkin' about what I'm doin'.
I think...
I think girls should...
paint their nails.
Not stuff like this.
Lots a girls paint, Momma.
There ain't no shame to it.
Wait 'til you see the next one
I'm gonna do.
It's gonna be my masterpiece,
that's all.
[male] Martha, what are you up to?
What's this?
Thanks... for the best anniversary
I've had so far.
It's not surprising
since it's our first.
New manure spreader?
Portable.
We'll save the bow.
Already we're history, right?
Nice suit. [chuckles]
Poppa knew this would happen
if he let me go off.
Glad you went anyway?
Glad your stuck out in the country
with your crazy Hittite?
Ex Hittite.
What's wrong?
Oh, just a little, uh, trouble
with the tractor.
I pulled the wheels off.
I may go out and pack
the bearings a little later.
You're a little bombed, no?
- Poo.
- Who's bombed?
Besides, isn't there...
Isn't there anything else you can do
tonight except pack bearings?
Hmm?
[dog barks]
[door creaks]
[tractor starts]
[motor stops]
[chicken cackles]
[cackles]
[tractor starts]
What the hell are you...
Jim?
You in here?
[gasps]
[cries out]
Jim, Jim?
Ain't no need for you to wait
any longer, Mam.
I'll stay 'til you're through.
They usually do that
when one of their own dies.
Funny.
He kin to them?
Kin.
Evil one is among us.
Do you believe she calls
and tells us not to come?
That's Martha.
Turn here.
I never thought
she'd isolate herself so much.
[sighs] Who are these Hittites anyway,
Amish or what?
No, no connection.
According to Martha, the Hittites make
the Amish look like swingers.
Ain't no way we're gonna
get in there.
There's always a way,
if you want one.
Will, you gonna do it?
Or are you afraid your girlfriend's
gonna come around and catch ya?
Ain't my girlfriend.
Nah, you just come around
and peek in her window.
Watch it.
Okay.
Father Isaiah said this place
was with the incubus.
If he knew...
Now who's chickens?
You get blue, you just call me.
I'm sorry that it... it took this for us
to get to know each other
a little better.
- Thanks.
- It's nothin'.
Wow, big as a house.
I gonna look.
- Dare you to touch the blood.
- Dare you.
Double dare goes first.
[chickens cackle]
[yells]
Honey, we thought you heard us.
Oh, I'm so glad you're here.
[cackling]
[dog barks]
[female] Do you have a clear deed
to this place?
Did Jim leave a will?
Jim was very careful.
He'd just inherited this farm
when he got into a big fight
with his father, Isaiah.
Well, what happened, anyway?
Jim was the first Hittite
to go away to school...
to the city.
Isaiah was furious to begin with.
And then when Jim
came back with me...
Isaiah kicked him out
of the family.
He forbid anyone
to even talk with us.
Called me the incubus.
What's an incubus?
Some sort of a devil
that seduces the faithful
in his sleep.
Or it just comes after you
and takes you like a beast.
Oh, God.
It's been an awful shock.
You'll feel better
when we get you back to L.A.
I'm not going anywhere
at least until spring.
Just stay with me for a week
and I'll be all right.
I love you both.
To old friends.
You know what the cost
of a shoe is?
I was fetchin' the calves to feed.
Caught in the mud.
My foot was stuck in mud
and when I pulled it out
my shoe came off.
There is no mud
on the shoe you have.
I washed it, so...
More than the cost of the shoe
is the cost of the lie.
I will go get it.
- If I could find it.
- You will find it.
If it takes all night.
And while you are searching,
keep in mind the wages of sin!
Whoa.
Matthew,
it is best I speak to this one.
Yes?
I have come only to speak
for one of my people.
[Matthew] It's my boy.
He went out yesterday.
He lost one of his shoes
and I told him to go find it.
But he never returned.
I've asked everyone.
Have you seen him?
William?
- The big boy?
- Oh, yes.
This must have been yesterday...
in the evening maybe.
I'm sorry.
If... if you see him...
If I see him, I'll drive him by.
Where's your farm?
- By the river, just by the...
- Matthew, Matthew,
you see how the glib
serpent's tongue deceives you?
Would you put your son
in her ungodly machine?
If it would bring him home.
She is with incubus.
She could not speak the truth
if she knew it.
Go.
Wait by the wagon.
I will have one more word with her.
If you should see
the boy before me,
I am the elder.
One more word.
I, too, have lost a son.
I am certain in my heart
he would want this land
to stay with his people.
His people.
His people turned
their backs on him.
You ordered it.
Our people are prepared
to offer a good price.
A very good price.
You want your answer right away?
If you like.
May you be damned in hell!
[Martha] I shouldn't have let him
get to me like that.
If I owned a piece of property
like this and I kicked the bucket,
my parents would start building condos
on it on the way home from the funeral.
Lana!
Chow!
Stop shouting, I'm up.
Yeah.
How's the champ?
I'm fine.
Vicky's done everything but
inject me with chicken soup. [chuckles]
- How are you?
- I'm okay.
You're up before noon.
You must be sick.
Just couldn't sleep, that's all.
And when I finally did
get to sleep, I...
I had this really awful nightmare.
I dreamed about this man
whose skin was all gray like ash.
Came to my door and...
This house?
No, just... just a house in a dream.
Anyway, he came
and he banged on the door.
And he just said my name...
[whispers] real quiet.
"Lana, Lana..."
Lana, what a bummer you can be.
Well, then I took this big cannon
and I aimed it right at the door
And it didn't go off, naturally.
No, it did.
But when the smoke cleared...
he was still there.
Just... changed.
How did he change?
He'd...
He'd become a spider.
He...
He whispered my name again.
[whispers] But this time
right in front of my face.
Said it like a lover would say it.
[whispers] "Lana."
I woke up in a cold sweat.
It's a cold room.
I should have put you in with Vicky.
I'm so pissed off at you,
Lana Marcus.
Well, we came here
to cheer up Martha,
not make her so depressed
that she wants to blow her brains out.
God, you're right, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You can choose to look at the shadows
or you can choose to look at the light.
- [gasps and screams]
- Jesus.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to peek.
Can I come in?
Look how many I brought you.
They're all grade A large too.
And we'll never miss 'em.
Fact, I'm sick a eggs.
I really am.
It's eggs this, eggs that.
Sometimes I'd rather eat dirt.
Here, these are for you.
Now, don't you worry
'cause I candled all of them.
There ain't gonna be
no little beady eyes
staring up at you
outta your sunny-side ups.
Uh, terrific.
You're Louisa Stohler's daughter,
right?
Mm-hmm, I'm Faith.
F-A-I-T-H, like in believe.
Faith, uh, this is Lana and Vicky.
And I'm Martha.
It's nice to meet you all.
You're not a Hittite, are you?
No, I ain't a Hittite.
And don't ever say that,
I hate 'em.
We ain't even farmers.
Ma's a waitress.
Oh, those damn Hittites.
All they done is try to run us outta
here like they done everybody else.
My momma won't budge.
Just like you don't, Martha.
Well, gotta scoot.
I'll bring ya some more eggs real soon.
That's fine, but we have plenty now.
Oh it's... it's no trouble.
Okay, you bring 'em.
Boy, I bet you miss him a lot, huh?
I had a pet once.
It was just this dumb old bird
with a broken wing.
Next thing I knew he was dead.
Cried and cried for him all night.
Just like I would for a brother.
I know how it is.
Please don't do that.
I like your room a lot.
It's real nice.
Are, uh... are those two visitors?
They'll be stayin' a while.
Oh.
Come on, gang.
Come on, I'll beat you to the wagon.
[growls]
Hey.
Hey!
Hey is this...
[yelps]
[horse blows]
Hi.
Where is your red car?
How'd you know I had a red car?
I saw it yesterday on the road.
By Jim's farm.
You know Jim?
Martha's Jim?
Jim was my brother.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
We rejoice for the dead.
Hey, they are in a better place.
I'm John Schmidt.
Vicky Anderson.
[horse blows]
You didn't think he was
so terrible, did you?
My father shunned him
for leaving the way.
What my father says
will always be the law.
But he was my brother.
Well, I guess I better go.
Why?
I feel like I've been
through a time warp.
There's no cars, no jets.
No telephone poles
or power lines.
What is a warp?
That's when somebody
from the 20th century
wakes up one morning
back in the 18th century.
This century's more peaceful, I think.
Really.
[horse whinnies]
- What's wrong?
- It's my father.
John?
You do not work?
No. I mean yes, Father.
Something troubled you?
- No, Father.
- We were just talking, sir.
These things are not for us.
John.
You'll be working now, ya?
- Yes.
- Ah.
I'm Vicky Anderson,
I'm a friend of Martha's.
We are the kindred of God.
We have no business
with the serpents.
A field is all, ya?
Yes, Father.
Your cousin is a sound woman.
You are to shun the rest.
You understand?
Yes, Father, I understand.
Git up!
Hey!
Hey, hold it!
Foot worked loose.
Got another?
Yeah, in the barn.
Well, where is it?
I'll get it.
Thanks.
It's, uh, back where we park
the tractor... there's a toolbox.
Here, you'll need this.
[door creaks]
[chickens cackle]
[door bangs] [cackling louder]
[tractor starts]
Vicky.
Vicky, if you think
this is funny, it's not.
[cackling]
Martha! Martha!
[sobs]
[clattering]
Vick?
[whimpers]
[creaking]
Vick, you back?
Ah!
[screams]
[Martha] Lana?
You need help with that?
[sighs] Oh.
[screams]
He said he ain't gonna
let me touch him.
Never harmed no one.
He was touched.
You didn't have to hurt him.
Mr. Gluntz, you don't think
I killed William?
Mr. Gluntz, there's no use
making accusations
'til we have an autopsy or...
I'll never let you put
your knives on my boy.
He's suffered enough.
Sheriff,
this is our affair.
We will bury William.
You want me to find
who did that or not?
We already know who did this.
- Who?
- The incubus.
Your laws cannot crush the incubus.
Ours can.
Take him home, Matthew.
Well, I'll be damned.
These boys eat brimstone
for breakfast, I swear.
If I was you, I'd get out tonight.
I'll come back with you tomorrow
and get your things.
Meanwhile, I'll get a court order
and look at that body.
You want me to run
just because you can't find a killer?
Your friend said he was hangin'.
You found him in the straw.
She goes on about death
running after her
wearing a black bathrobe
or something.
On the other hand,
if someone did do it,
it wasn't someone you'd want
to tangle with, believe me.
If something happens,
I ain't gonna be here in time
for nothin' but cleanup.
[car starts]
[whispers] Are you okay?
Never felt better.
Did the sheriff find any clues?
No.
What did this person look like?
[whispers] What person?
The one you saw in the barn.
There was nobody there.
Just me.
Maybe you two better go back.
Why don't we just wait and see
what the sheriff finds out.
Okay.
[footsteps]
Hey.
How ya doin'?
Okay.
Did you get some sleep?
Not much.
Do you want to play
some backgammon?
Sure.
Martha's in the tub, huh?
Yeah, she's got the right idea.
Okay.
[water running]
Lana?
Hey, if anyone wants to use this,
just sing out.
Touch me there again
and I'll scream.
What is it?
[beating]
What happened?
Bed, huh,
I'm going back to bed.
[door closes]
What was it?
[choir singing]
John, what are you doing out here?
The meeting has begun.
I wanted some air.
Isaiah's back.
You should come inside.
He expects you there.
You are the eldest son now.
[singing continues]
[singing ends]
This is a most grievous day.
[sobs]
An incubus has crept into our fold
and defiled our flock.
William Gluntz,
an innocent man-child
is dead.
Killed by the messenger
of the incubus.
Death came to William.
Death took him.
Because someone
took him to that forbidden place.
Who?
Remember that lying
is the sin of the serpent.
And the wages of sin
are death!
Leopold Smith step forward.
Leopold Smith, kneel
and confess thy wrongdoing.
I went into the forbidden barn.
I... have shamed us all.
And more.
It was me who dared him
to go into the barn.
I humbly ask God for forgiveness.
[sobs]
We shall make it impossible
for the incubus to rest comfortably
in your soul.
One we have lost.
Another shall we save.
[congregation] Amen.
If thine eye offends thee,
pluck it out.
If thine hand offends thee,
then in God's name cut it off!
Is that usual,
snakes coming into houses?
Oh, it happens enough.
Morning, Mrs. Schmidt.
Morning, Sammy.
Fill the tank and this.
Okay, Stretch?
- Coming?
- Yeah, in a minute.
I've just got some business
in here I gotta take care of.
I think I'll, uh, get a lot of...
about ten lbs. of chocolate.
What do you think?
Used to work every time.
[horse neighs]
Hey, uh, you want me
to come over with you?
Just wait a sec.
That's okay,
I'm not afraid a Hittites.
At least, not all of them.
That one is good.
This one is proper.
You think?
Whatever you like, Melissa.
[cash register rings]
Why don't you surprise me?
I'll fetch the flour
while you choose.
[horse and buggy passes]
[stutters]
About what happened yesterday...
We're really not that unfriendly.
[whispers] Well.
Isaiah should not have
treated you that way.
That's all right.
I suppose, to your father,
jogging shorts and a t-shirt
make me a Jezebel.
You know about Jezebel?
You wanna do somethin'
some time?
Well, just a movie or something.
I think the one in town's
Lassie Meets Godzilla.
Can't be sinful.
And nobody will know.
I knew it.
Melissa, Melissa.
Melissa.
I'm sorry.
Say it.
She's prettier than I am.
She's not.
No.
Swear it.
I'll never talk to her again.
I was weak.
It's just hard waiting.
You better take me home.
It's you I want, not her.
I can't.
[ripping]
[cries]
[grunts]
What's that for?
What are you up to?
Oh, my God.
What, has war been declared
or what?
Where did you get that thing?
Got it from Sammy
back at Coopers Junction.
Oh, [chuckles] Stretch.
Anyway, uh, I told him
about the snake
and, uh, also told him
I was an old hand at this.
Here.
You fire guns before?
No.
No?
Oh, good grief.
Well... doesn't take an Einstein
to pull a trigger.
See that green bottle right there?
Oh, God.
- Oh, I'm deaf.
- What?
I got it, though.
Here.
[sighs]
You don't think it would have
bounced off, do you?
Wait a minute.
What are you aiming at?
Paint can.
Not gonna to take any chances.
It's just about the size
of a man's chest.
[whispers] Squeeze.
[gunshot]
Melissa?
Who did this?
You will follow me to the barn.
- But Father...
- Obey!
I need to talk.
You need the fear
of God in thee.
- Kneel.
- Father...
Kneel!
Father?
No!
You're cursed.
No more.
Please.
Go!
You are a stench
in the nostrils of God!
The devil has you now!
Melissa, come with me
and we'll talk.
She is too pure
to hear the devil.
All our hearts and ears
are stone to you now.
Your brother will not look at you.
Your mother will never feed you again.
You are not of us now... go.
Go to thy whore.
Go.
Join your brother in hell!
I gotta get out of the house
for a while.
You'll be okay?
We're fine.
[sighs] Okay.
Get outta here.
All right.
- Bye.
Stay outta trouble.
I always try.
[clunk] [knocking]
Who is it?
Louisa Stohler.
Hi, Louisa.
Can I come in?
Oh, sure.
Sorry.
Left your hat in my truck.
- Oh, thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
Come on in.
Thanks.
Louisa, this is my friend Lana.
And Vicky you just missed.
Uh, pleased to make
your acquaintance, Lana.
Nice to meet you.
- Sit down.
- Oh, thanks.
Louisa's Faith's mother.
- You remember Faith?
- Yeah.
Yeah, well, it's kinda hard
to forget her.
Once you've said hello,
she goes on so.
And that's partly
why I come down.
I thought maybe
she might a snuck down here.
Started getting in your hair.
Well, she's been very generous
with the eggs.
So that's where they disappeared.
I'll go get the basket.
I'm sorry about all
the trouble down here.
I don't suppose the sheriff's
been much good.
No, as a matter of fact,
all he does is tell us to get out.
Well, I wouldn't be surprised
if he was a Hittite hisself.
Men around here is hopeless.
Well, I guess my old man
made me hate the whole breed.
[sighs] Yeah, as soon as Faith was born
he was over the fence and gone.
I swear, if Faith had been a boy,
I think I'd a just stuck her
in the river like sack a kittens.
Here.
Listen, I hope you don't scold Faith
for coming by.
No.
No, there's nothing personal.
I just like to keep an eye on 'er.
She's so dumb.
She couldn't pour piss
from a boot
if the instructions was printed
on the heel.
Well.
Nice you came by.
Watch the Hittites.
[whispers] Watch 'em.
I mean, if you're gonna stay,
you gotta watch 'em.
'Course, your Jim,
he was different.
Bye.
Thank you.
John?
What are you doing here?
Huh.
You didn't drive your buggy
30 miles, did you?
I hitched.
Hiked and I hitched.
What's wrong?
Something happened?
No.
It's just some trouble between
my father and me.
Come on.
I'll drive you back.
We'll talk.
[gravelly voice] Lana.
Open your mouth.
Wider.
[coughing, gasps]
Hey.
You all right?
Just a... bad dream.
Something got in my throat.
[sighs] Scare you?
What, who me?
I knew it.
You're just as scared as I am.
It's all a big front.
Just look at you.
You're shaking.
I'm not scared.
It's just...
Just what?
Well, it's just there's a draft
in here or something.
[female screams]
[Rod Stewart sings "Maggie May"
on the radio]
[gears grind]
This is wonderful.
This is much better
than a horse.
It's much better to even try it,
don't you think?
Thanks for listening.
Whoa!
Oh, close, but no cigar.
I guess I'm not so good a driver.
You kidding?
For your first time, you did great.
Well, wh... what is it you do
to start it running again?
What's your hurry?
Huh?
Oh.
Is this, uh...
Is this where we say
we've run out of gas?
Could.
John!
John.
[distant howl]
What?
Something I did?
No, I just thought
I saw something out there.
There's nothing out there.
Everyone around here
goes to bed by dark.
[snap]
That's probably
a raccoon or opossum.
Maybe we should go.
Not at all, I'll go...
I'll chase it away.
- John, don't.
- Don't worry.
[whispers] John!
Did you see anything?
Only ghosts and goblins.
[kissing]
[yelling]
John.
[whispers] John.
No!
Don't worry,
she'll be home soon.
Even when we were in college
I used to sit up like a mother hen.
Hey, how 'bout
let me fix you a snack?
Peanut butter and jelly sandwich
might be nice.
Big glass of milk?
Okay, you got it.
Hey, would you like this on toast?
No.
Oh!
Lana?
Lana, listen, stop it.
Oh, he did this to me.
Someone's idea of a joke, maybe.
Just don't freak out on me,
come on.
It's no use.
You can't lock him out.
He comes in whenever he wants.
What are you talking about?
Death.
He's after me.
Jesus, Lana.
Just get a hold a yourself.
He tried to get me in the barn.
Martha, I saw him.
I wasn't dreaming.
Please don't do this.
He spoke to me
like in my dream.
Just reaches out
and touches your...
Don't!
Just go sit down.
I'm going to go into the bedroom
and check the windows.
For what,
if there's nothing
to be afraid of?
Go sit down.
Jim.
[screams]
Faith.
[cries out]
[screams]
[female] I command thee
whosoever thou art,
thou unclean spirit,
and all my companions
possessing this land.
Divine mystery
of the incarnation,
Resurrection in the century
of our Lord, Jesus Christ.
By the sending
of the Holy Ghost
and by the coming of our Lord
to judgment,
count on me
thy name,
the date
and the hour of thy coming out.
[gasps]
I command!
Louisa!
[screams]
Can't let you go now, little bird.
I wouldn't a hurt you.
I only hurt the ones
that were keeping us apart.
[screaming]
I tried to be a little girl, Lou.
I tried so hard.
I ain't got no secret no more.
Not if she lives.
Tried to kill her, didn't ya?
You put the snake after her.
Hey, listen,
she come to me
and she laughed about you.
Yeah, yeah, she could tell.
She could tell that you were...
that you was half and half.
She laughed at you.
She laughed and laughed
and laughed at you!
No, she did not, my Martha.
She's not yours!
She can't be, never will be.
She's carrying his child.
You ain't never gonna
have her... never.
Lana?
- Lana.
- What?
Get up quick.
- Give me the gun.
Come on.
Why?
Gotta get out.
Where are we going?
To the truck.
It's him, it's him!
Get off!
Uh!
I'm sorry.
[gunshot]
Operator.
Operator, this is an emergency.
I've gotta keep...
[horse whinnies]
[wagon wheels rolling]
[screams]
[groans and screams]
Melissa.
Messenger of the incubus is dead.
Sure you don't want
to come back with me?
The seed's planted.
I stay.
Bye.
[car starts]
[whispers] Martha.
Beware.
Beware of the incubus.
Jim?
[creaking from below]
[howl]
[male] The beast that thou sawest
was and is not.
And shall ascend
out of the bottomless pit
and go into perdition.
And they that dwell
on the earth
shall wonder.