J1 are you washed in the
blood of the lamb?
J1 are you washed in the blood
j1 in the soul-cleansing
blood of the lamb?
J1 are your garments spotless?
J1 are they white as snow?
41 are you washed 'm the
'mood oi the lamb'?
J1 have you been to Jesus
for the cleansing power?
41 are you washed 'm the
'mood oi the lamb'?
J1 are you fully trusting
in his grace this hour?
41 are you washed 'm the
'mood oi the lamb'?
J1 are you washed in the blood
j1 in the soul-cleansing
blood of the lamb?
J1 are your garments spotless?
J1 are they white as snow?
41 are you washed 'm the
'mood oi the lamb'?
J1 are you walking daily
by the savior's side?
41 are you washed 'm the
'mood oi the lamb'?
J1 do you rest each
moment in the crucified?
41 are you washed 'm the
'mood oi the lamb'?
J1 are you washed in the blood
j1 in the soul-cleansing
blood of the lamb?
J1 are your garments spotless?
J1 are they white as snow?
- Wind.
Wind!
- Regina!
Spells can't keep us out.
The spells can't keep us out.
- George!
George, help me!
Oh, thank god it's you.
My spells can't keep them out now.
They're getting stronger.
Did you bring the daggers
and the diary?
George?
Stop it.
Please, stop it, George.
Oh!
No!
Remember?
If the crystal breaks it's
the end of both of us.
- And now, my pig, you die!
- No.
No!
Stop!
Please!
- I can't stand this anymore.
Cory, would you talk to me?
- About what?
- About anything, about
what you're thinking.
- I'm just thinking about driving.
- How much farther is
your grandparents' farm?
- I don't know.
I think not far.
- Cory, what was
your dad like?
- Cow-
- dad.
- Well, what was
it like when you saw him?
- He was just an old drunk.
Stranger.
- You know, it's funny.
- What is?
- I really wanted you to
find your dad.
I thought it would help
you undo the knot you have
yourself tied in.
Now I'm sorry you ever
laid eyes on him.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It means that in the past 48
hours you've not looked to me
in the face once.
In fact, since you found your
father, you've completely
and totally cut me out of your life
and I'd just like to know why.
- I brought you with me.
- Yeah.
But for what?
You've not even spoken
10 words with me
since we started up
here this morning.
So?
- It's just that since...
It's since I saw my old
man there's uh...
It's been this voice inside
my head like a loud speaker
telling me to get to that farm.
I've been here before.
- What?
- In a dream.
- Welcome home, Cory.
- Cow-
Cory, are you all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm okay.
- You just seemed
to go somewhere else.
- Well, I'm fine now, really.
- How are you, folks?
What can I do for you?
- How do we get to the
Carter place from here?
- You can't.
There's no such place.
- This map says it's
right near here.
- That map is wrong.
Now, unless you want some gas,
why don't you just move on?!
- Cory, maybe he's right.
The map could be wrong.
Let's just go home.
- No.
This is the place of the dream.
The farm is near, I can feel it.
Hello!
Anybody here?
- Hey, harman!
- A moon for the misbegotten.
- Oh, please!
Cory, I just want you to lighten up.
- Bathroom's out back.
- Oh, no, I wasn't--
- can we get something to drink?
- We have beer, coke,
water and goat's milk.
- Coke, please.
- Same.
Thank you.
Has anyone else been in here today?
- Old man deavers a week ago.
And Mrs. Wilson came by with
the little Linda last week.
Are you little Linda's friends?
Did you meet her when
she went away to school?
I don't think little Linda
really went away to school.
I think maybe little
Linda got into trouble
and they sent her away.
Did you meet little Linda at school?
- No, we don't know little Linda.
Uh, can you tell us how far
the Carter farm is from here?
- I've never heard of it.
- That's got to be Dell's Jeep.
- Good.
I wanna get moving.
- Elaine.
- Hi, Dell.
Dell!
- Well, now, don't you
look good enough to eat?
Cow, my man!
" Ow!
Hi, Dell.
How was the drive?
- Sucked!
But you know how women are:
We passed that last mall,
Terri panicked, and we had to stop.
- I just got to get some
outdoor clothes.
- And you, you do look
good enough to eat.
That is why I keep her around.
- Bonnie, babe!
- Hi!
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- You look
simply marvelous.
- Oh, and you look
absolutely divine.
- Oh, thank you, thank you.
- Bizarre greeting
rituals of the subculture.
Good afternoon, Mr. harman.
- Jack, man, I'm glad to see you.
- Well, your message sounded urgent.
So, here we are.
- Thanks for coming.
I mean that.
- I know.
- Well if you two homos can keep
your hands out of each other
for a second, let's
get something to drink.
- Maybe Cory can tell us why
we are here in the sticks.
- Anybody want a beer?
- No, thanks.
- No, we're fine.
- I'm fine.
- What is it, just a no week?
- Not for me.
- That's why I keep her around.
- His thing is about this big.
- What's so funny?
What is it?!
- Nothing, Dell.
- No, what is it?
- It's just a little thing,
Dell, it's not worth mentioning.
- You're right.
- So, Cory, uh...
Why did you bring us up here?
- I found my father.
- Is he okay?
- No, uh...
He slit his wrists the
day after I saw him.
- You didn't tell me that.
- I know.
I just couldn't.
Four days after he was born, uh...
His family disappeared
from a farm near here.
- Where was you dad when
that happened?
- He was in an
Incubator in a hospital
and if he hadn't of been there he'd
of been gone too.
- Did anyone ever find his family?
- No, but right after I was
born, he came up here
to find out what happened.
And he never came home.
I think something bizarre has
been going on at that farm
for a long time.
I'm gonna find out what.
I need your help.
- Count me in.
- Me too.
- Let me give you some advice, son.
Take your friends and go home now.
- We've got business at that farm.
It belongs to me now.
- You do not own that property.
- Oh, yeah?
Then who's the owner
of that land, old man?
You, maybe?
- The dead.
- You know, you not only
got an attitude problem,
you're also out of your fucking mind!
- You got to learn to
respect the elders, boy,
before one of them hurts you.
- Now just hold on a minute here,
Mr.
We don't want any trouble.
Do we, Dell?
- No, no, no, no, no, no trouble.
- Then all of you, get in them cars
and go back where you came from.
- What is it, harcourt?
What are you trying to hide?
- I saw what happened
to the Carter family.
It was the drought of 29.
A hot dry wind blew that summer.
The cattle and the crops
were burning to a crisp.
The smell of death hung in the air.
It happened on a Sunday.
All the families were in
church, except the Carters.
And they never missed church,
so that evening I went up to
see if they were all right.
And...God help me, I saw them...
I saw--
- saw what, what did you see?
- Blood everywhere!
Black blood on the walls!
Figures in the dark,
laughing, coming at me.
And I screamed, then I ran.
And I never told a soul.
Til now.
Hell, it ain't even loaded.
Please, boy, don't go up there.
- I have to.
- I know.
Well, you just follow
that road to...
Till it ends.
- Thanks.
It's alright.
- Good afternoon, ladies
and gentlemen.
Welcome to the wonderful
world of magic.
Today we will take you to the
land of illusion and fantasy,
where the common place is fantastic
and the fantastic is common place.
- I didn't know your former
boy was gonna be here.
- Well, neither did I.
- A Princess should
always have flowers.
- Skinny little chicken shit!
I'll shove that karate
crap up your ass!
- Be my guest.
- Gentlemen, easy now.
Easy now, don't hurt the rabbit.
- Dell, Dell, Dell, Dell, cool out.
I asked these guys to
come and help me, okay?
This I don't need.
- I have to agree with him.
We don't need the fist
of fury demonstration,
you know what I mean?
Hi, Cory.
- Hi, Stacy.
I didn't think you guys
were gonna make it.
- What?
And miss the chance to
play a grand resrot like this?
To bring magic and wonder
to the hinder lands?
The hangout with the
beautiful people?
My man, there just isn't
any other place to be.
Besides, you needed us to be here,
so...
Voilé.
Here we are.
- Glad to have you.
- So, uh...
What exactly is the nature
of this little expedition,
if I may ask?
- Follow me up the road
aways and I'll show you.
Dell, are you still coming?
- Yeah, yeah, we're in.
- What about you?
- I don't know why or where,
but I wouldn't miss it for anything.
- All right, let's get going.
- Next time, you little faggot,
I'll drop you like a bad habit.
- Shazam!
- Son of a bitchin' idiots!
- Still onboard?
- All the way, captain.
- You're making a bad mistake, boy.
- Maybe so, but it's mine to make.
- Damned fools!
- What are you going to
expect to find up here?
- I need to have some
answers about who I am.
- Jeez!
What do you think happened here?
- I wonder who it is?
- Stay away from it!
Don't touch it!
Please.
- What is it, Bonnie?
What's wrong?
- That!
- It's my dad's older brother.
- How do you know that?
- I just know, that's all.
- Here's the answer to
the mystery right here.
Somebody, somebody
arranged one or two here,
tortured whoever is in that
cross and set fire the house.
They must have died in the fire.
- I don't know what happened
here, but you can sure tell
death walked through this place.
- Cory?
Cow-
cow-
- I'm going inside.
- Cory, wait.
There's something really wrong here.
I think we should go.
- Bonnie's right, Cory,
i feel it too.
Don't go in there.
- I have to see what's
through that door.
You guys can wait out here.
- Hey, catch.
- "To Regina, with all my love."
It's my grandmother.
- "Nunc protestas, satane vivet."
- Get out!
Get out!
- Cory!
- What the hell is going on here,
harman?!
- I don't know, I don't know!
But what was that Bonnie read?!
What did it say?!
- It was Latin, it says,
"now Satan shall walk."
- This baby will do the
trick against whatever moves.
- I don't care what it is,
i say we get out of here now
before the sun goes down.
- Do what you want.
Whatever is here killed
my grandparents.
I wanna find out why.
- Let's get the hell out of here,
come on!
- My battery is dead.
- So it's mine.
- We have to get out of here now!
- She's right.
This place is possessed.
- Be serious.
I tell you, what we witnessed
here is hallucination.
- Come on, Jack, what happened
in that house was real.
Saw it with your own eyes.
- Well, then I don't
believe my own eyes.
Things like this simply
don't happen.
- Jack, there is something
here, something evil.
- Evil?
Evil, where?
- There.
It's been waiting all this time.
- Waiting for what?
- For us, for us to come here.
Promise me something.
- Anything-
- if we die, don't bury me here.
- You're not going to die,
Bonnie.
- Promise me.
- Okay, I promise, but
nothing is going to happen.
I won't let it.
- Let's get her out of here.
- Okay, let's grab what we can carry
and walk back to the station.
- Man, look how fast that fog is
rolling in.
- I think we're in trouble.
- I think you're right.
- I've never seen a fog like this.
- It's not the same forest.
- Of course it is.
- Yeah, an I'm the pope.
The same power that was in
that house is doing this.
- Look, it's coming back!
Where the hell are we now?!
- God, it's cold!
- Oh, no, here it comes again!
Oh, god!
- Oh, no!
- Son of a bitch!
- Dell, stop!
- Hey, where do you
come from, little girl?
- Dell, are you all right?
- You can't leave.
- No!
- You are mine.
- You...
Lied.
- Now what do we do, harman?!
- Well, whatever is here
isn't gonna let us go.
- Then no shit, Sherlock!
Do you have any other
hot news for us?!
- Yeah, the sun is gonna
be down in a few minutes.
We got two choices: The cars
or the house for the night.
I think we'll be safer in the house.
- But something in there
just tried to kill us!
- I don't think so.
I think whatever it is is
only trying to warn us away.
- And how the
hell do you know that?!
- I don't!
It's just a feeling I have.
- Well, that's just great, pal,
it's because of your feelings
what got us into this shit
hole in the first place!
- I'm going back inside.
- Well, I'm not sleeping out
here with you and no buick.
- Lead on, mcduff.
- You're crazy.
All of you, you're all crazy!
- We have to talk.
- Chuck, there's nothing
left for us to talk about.
- Come on, Terri, i
can see it in your eyes
back at the cafe.
- Chuck, you're mistaken,
I'm Dell's now.
I'm gonna stay with him.
- Terri, I love you.
- Chuck, it's too late for that.
Dell needs me.
You don't.
Life is just a game to you.
It's not to me.
I need somebody who's
serious about me.
Dell is.
- We could fight if you want to.
But we don't have anything
to fight about.
- Well, let's go inside then.
- Good idea.
- I think it's gonna be okay.
Let's clean up.
- Cory.
- Grandmother?
"Being the diary of Regina Carter,
"born June 8th 1889.
"L conjure thee, oh delos,
protect this my child
"from the evil touch.
"Rise now and approach me."
Christ!
Are you trying to give me
a heart attack?!
- I could ask you the same thing.
Oh, god!
I made you some food.
- Some weekend, huh?
- Yeah.
Really know how to show
a girl a good time.
- I know it may not seem like
it, but I'm glad you're here.
- Oh, I'm glad to hear you say it.
- I found my grandmother's diary.
~ oh!
- "It is dusk.
"L know tonight I will die.
"Even the spells grandmother
taught me can't save us now."
' Spells?
- Yeah.
"L know that someday you
might come to face the evil
"that comes for me.
"In the bottom drawer of the vanity
"you will find two daggers
"which are part of the
sacred set of seven.
"The other five have been lost.
"It is written that with all seven
"you can kill the son of Satan.
"I pray these two might help you."
I found something.
This farm was built by
my great-grandfather.
He and a group of settlers
followed a preacher named Anders
to this valley.
But when they arrived,
Anders began preaching
about the false god of the Bible...
And the true god he had found here.
- He was a Satan worshiper?
- Yeah.
Trying to raise the devil.
Then three little girls disappeared.
The searchers found them...
What was left of them in an
altar behind Anders' place.
- He was a real sick pup.
- There was a big fight.
Anders and all of his
followers were burned to death
in his house.
- That sounds fair.
- I hope they cooked slow.
- After that, everything was
okay until the summer of 1929.
That was the year my
father was born.
"June 8th.
"Mrs. James just had triplets.
"They were killed right
after the birth.
"None of the babies was even human."
- All the children were the same.
Except for Cory's dad.
- What was so special about him?
- I have no idea.
But the last entry reads,
"everyone is dead
except George and I.
"It's all hopeless.
"L can hear them rising
out in the barn.
"It's the..."
And that's what
happened to my family.
- Now we're in the
middle of all this.
- Will the meat puppets from
hell show tonight?
- My son, if they do,
we'll just have to go out
and kick some supernatural ass.
- Charles, my man.
I like your attitude.
Very American, very...
John Wayne.
- Very what choice do we have?
- It's a good point.
- Man, I just wish we had some
hand grenades or something.
- I'd rather have a
tahitian vacation.
- Not Tahiti.
- Why not?
- Voodoo, man, they do
voodoo in Tahiti.
- Let's say Chicago.
- Vegas.
We know nothing spiritual lives
in Vegas.
- Good point.
Vegas, it is.
- '(Co-hem!
Chuck.
Stacy.
Come out!
I'm here for you.
Come out and play with me.
Chuck!
Stacy!
Come out.
- Demon.
- Stacy!
- Hey, Cory, guess what we just saw!
Cory?
Hey, harman.
Hey, Jack, wake up!
- I guess it only wants us.
- Here I am.
- Let's go.
- Why not?
They're playing our song.
- Alright.
Let's dance.
- Over here.
I have something for you.
Surprise!
- Eat this!
Oh, man, I think we're in trouble.
- I think you're right.
I think we might just
get out of this.
- You doubt it?
Hey, Chuck.
- What, maestro?
- Presto.
Eh.
- I made it.
I made it!
Fuck yqu!
- Surprise!
- What happened?
What was that?!
- It came from outside.
- Where are Chuck and Stacy?!
- Stacy!
Chuck!
Oh, no!
' My god!
No!
- Terri, look, we got
to keep our act together,
and we're gonna get out of this alive.
- Didn't you see the blood?
- Hey, trust me, I'll
get us out of this, okay?
- Okay-
- Dell, we're gonna
check the backroom.
- Yeah.
- Why didn't you tell the
others about the daggers
and the spells in the diary?
- Tell them what?
That my grandmother was a witch?
She used spells to protect
her son and this house?
Dell's half crazy and
Jack's a basket case.
One more thing and
either of them could lose it.
- Maybe those spells could help us.
- They didn't helped her much,
did they?
Keep this with you.
It may be some protection.
- You don't think we can beat it,
do you?
- I'm sorry I got you into this.
- Don't even think that,
Cory, I got me into this.
I'm here because I love you.
- How did I get so lucky.
- Magic.
- Honey, you're alright,
it was only a dream.
You're alright now.
- It's not big deal, Dell.
- God, I wish I was home right now.
- Quiet!
That's a car!
- It's Willy and reena!
- Don't shut it off.
Don't shut it off!
- What did you say?
- I said, "don't shut it off."
- Why not?
- But what we did wrong?
We just got here.
- Get back inside.
- Hey, cow-
look, pal, Terri and I aren't
gonna spend another night
in this damned house.
Now we're going through
that front door
and we're going for help.
- Dell, are you sure you
wanna do that?
- Yeah, I'm sure, sure
as I'm about anything.
Are you positive
you wanna come with me?
- Like I told you before,
honey, wherever you go, I go.
- That's why I keep her with me.
- You may need this.
- Thanks, Cory.
Let's get out of here.
- I don't think they're
gonna make it.
- I don't think so, either.
Better get back to work.
Jack.
- Yeah.
- I'll be back in a minute.
- Alright.
- Grandmother?
Grandmother?
Is it you in the house, isn't it?
What are the demons afraid of?
Grandmother?
- Cow-
- this house is as secure
as it can get.
- So what do we do now?
- I guess we wait.
- N-
- what do you mean?
- Well, I say we attack it.
Now, Bonnie mentioned she
felt something from the barn.
- Jack's right.
My grandmother mentioned the barn.
Maybe there's a door with
the leads into the barn.
The same way that leads
into this house.
- And if that's the
center of this force,
we got to find some way
to destroy it.
- Now you're talking.
How about you, guys?
- Sure that beats waiting.
- I don't wanna go, but
if we have to,
let's get it over with.
- I'll get the flashlights.
- I'll get the shotgun.
- Oh, no!
- Shit!
Terri?
Terri!
Terri, where the hell are you?!
- Can't you hear it?
- Hear what?
- Death!
- But I loved you.
- I loved you too.
- What was that?
- It wasn't human, that's for sure.
- Look.
- Come on.
- What is that?
- It's an altar to the devil.
- God, it's horrible.
- But there's something
kind of beautiful about it.
No, it really is beautiful.
Help, get it off me!
Help me!
- Run, Willy!
- It's just us.
The gruesome twosome
- Dell looked enough to eat.
- But you're dead.
- You can't kill what's
already dead.
- Stay right there or I'll
have to blow you in two.
- That thing won't work in here.
This is the house of the damned.
- Cory!
Help me!
- Leave!
Oh, you don't like this, huh?
- God, where's Willy?
- He must still be in the barn!
- Shit!
- Forgot something?
- Ah!
- Isn't he cute?
- Cory, don't use the dagger!
- You killed me.
- You all will scream in
the hell tonight!
- All of you, ha!
- Get ready!
Now what's happening, harman?
- Don't you see?!
Ha!
Grandmother's old spell still works!
They can't reach us!
- Are you sure?
- Yeah!
Eat it, scumbags!
- Come and get us!
- Cory, now what happened?
- Shit!
The demons must have
broken the spell!
- Here, take this.
I'm gonna check the back rooms.
- Jack.
- Yeah?
- Watch yourself.
- Good luck to you too.
- So friend, we meet again.
- Where did they go?
- I don't know.
Maybe they're still
afraid of the house.
- Jack!
Jack, I'm coming for you!
- Get back!
- No!
No!
Let me out!
Jack!
Jack, it's Bonnie.
Please, help me.
- Bonnie?
Bonnie!
- Help me!
- Bonnie?
- Please, help me, Jack!
Jack!
Please, Jack!
- Bonnie!
- Help me!
Jack!
' God!
This can't be happening.
- Check Stacy's bag for more ammo.
Hurry!
- There's no way we can
keep them out!
- Take the diary and
tell Jack to get in here.
- Jack?
- Elaine.
It's Jackie.
- Oh, no, Jack!
Not you.
- It doesn't hurt.
- Jack, we can fight this.
- Don't fight.
I'll make it so sweet.
You'll give the father
much pleasure.
- Goodbye, Jack.
- You alright?
- It's Jack.
He turned into one of those
things, I used the last dagger.
I saw his soul.
- It's okay.
You did him a favor.
You saved him.
- Ah!
- Kill them.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm not.
- I have arrived, my children.
Gather now.
Come, my sheep.
I am come to take you.
Yes, you, the faithful.
Tonight reap your reward.
The wait is finally over.
Come now.
Now shall your suffering end.
Our time is at hand.
Gather now for the time has come.
I bring you greetings from
the shallow father.
Yes, my children, come unto me.
So, my children, at last
have we gathered.
And after all these years
shall we complete the cycle.
- Father, take us.
- All fought for him.
All love him.
- Tonight shall we open the
door for our beloved father.
Yeah, my flock.
Come.
Come unto me.
- No!
No!
No, please, help me!
- Bonnie!
- Oh, god, help me.
No!
- No!
Stop!
Bonnie!
- No!
- Cory, help her!
- There's nothing we can do for her.
- No!
- Now thou souls, i
come for thee!
- The book!
The book!
We've got to try it!
Draw a circle with the
chalk, go!
- Father of darkness,
i, your son, have arrived.
I have waited long for
this night Cory harman.
After all these centuries,
now this world will be mine.
This is a hell of a time to
say it, but...
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- Oh thou, white light,
oh, spirits of goodness and peace,
oh, earth mother who
watches over us...
We of this humble flesh,
born of thee...
We who breathe thy breath,
- if thee find us worthy,
we beg of you,
join us now to thee.
- Am I not beautiful?
- Thy will be done.
- So, the old witch, she
possessed the great secrets.
- Yes.
- They did her no good.
I took her husband and her head.
- And now you're gonna pay for that.
- I will teach you agony
before you die.
You were always so weak.
- Please, god!
- The power of your god
is nothing, little man.
I am come to rule this world.
You are the last of your line.
The death of your soul will ensure
the gift of mine.
Die, child little man.
- Oh, he's coming around.
Thank god, Cory.
I can't find your pulse.
I thought you were...
- Man, you gave us quite
a scare there for a while.
You were like somewhere else.
Cory, are you alright?
- Yeah.
Just a little woozy.
Where am I?
- We're at your
grandparents' farm, remember?
We drove up here.
- What happened to me?
- We walked in the front
door, looked around
and you just went out like a light.
- Man, you hit the floor so hard,
it was like you had
belted by Mike Tyson.
- Jack!
Jack, you're alright!
You're all alive!
- Of course we're all alive.
- Just like real life.
- You were just dreaming.
" Qopsi
- surprise!
- Cory!
Cory!
Help me!
- And now my pig-
taste the flesh you loved so well.
- Cory, I'm sorry.
I love you.
- I love you too.
If she's dead...
Dad?!
- I always loved you, Cory.
- No, dad.
Don't!
Stop it!
It won't work.
I'm not afraid of you.
You're the one who's terrified.
- I fear nothing from you.
- Another lie.
You're terrified of us
because we're alive.
We can feel.
You're only a shadow.
You hide behind your cheap magic
tricks because you're dead.
God changed you into a snake
and a chicken shit at the same time.
- I don't need magic to
take your soul.
And when you die, I will
have your woman.
She will make me fine sons, and
how she will beg for death.
- Cow-
cow-
- get the diary.
Read the last spell.
Do it now!
- We call upon the power of light.
Drive this evil in upon itself.
Set it back into the
darkness from where it came.
We call on thee god of light.
Burn this abomination. Cleanse it
from thy blessed earth.
- No!
- They will be done.
- Cory, you're human again.
Is it over?
Is it really over?
Hello?
Hello!
Harriet?
- Elaine, is that you?
Oh, I'm so glad you came.
My uncle, he was--
- I know.
- Elaine, come here.
I have a surprise for you.
- That's okay.
We have a surprise for you too.