THE DIABIC DOLL
Translated from Spanish by DougTrash
Http://cinespacemonster.blogspot.com.br/.
You will never win.
You will always lose.
And you sympathize.
Of all the good
news in London...
I have to get stuck
with the Great Vorelli.
It must be for something.
We'll see.
Did you talk to this Hypnotist?
This... Dr. Heller?
I spoke to him earlier.
He said he will find his way to the theater by
himself and that he does not want to see you.
He said he could not stand talking
to a journalist at night...
but will come to the office
tomorrow at 10:30...
to give you your opinion about Mr.
Vorelli.
Quite independent, is not it? He does not
know that we will pay for his services?
I do not think money
interests you very much.
These retired specialists do not
care about money, or so they say.
Well, take note so that you will not
forget to be available to Mr. Heller,
Tomorrow at 10:30.
What else?
And the girl who will be willing?
Oh, I'm sorry, Mark, I forgot to tell you.
The one we choose does not want to do this.
You're scared.
Afraid of what?
From Mr. Vorelli.
That things are wrong.
Where can I get another one?
It will be difficult. At this time.
Yes...
Hello, may I speak to Marianne?
Hello. Hello, Marianne?
How are you?
Yes. Marianne, would you like
to go to the theater tonight?
Ladies and gentlemen, I will suggest to
this man that his life is in danger.
Who can die at any moment.
Mr. Harrison...
Look me in the eye.
Mr. Harrison, you told me that in China...
Once he saw a man run
down the street.
I want you to imagine
that he's in his place.
Who is on his knees.
On my knees...
It is about to be
executed by a soldier,
who will shoot a bullet at the back of his neck.
He's alone. Look up to see
the faces of the crowd.
In a few moments, it will move away.
Leaving him dead on the pavement.
You turn around... and see the
soldier standing behind you.
Threatening and cold.
Your weapon is ready to fire.
You have little to die for.
Wait for the sound of the gun.
The pain the bullet will cause you
while piercing his head.
Wait for the sound of the gun.
The tremendous pain that the bullet will cause
while piercing his head.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
I need another volunteer.
Someone?
Maybe this young lady in line seven?
Vá.
Mark, I do not think so.
Come on, you promised me.
It's fine.
Well, it's very easy on your part.
Would you mind telling me your name?
Marianne Horn.
"Are you afraid, Miss Horn?"
- No...
I do not think so.
Are you a professional artist?
No, no.
I knew it was not.
She seems to be a very sober young woman.
Let's see, Miss Horn.
You dance?
Everybody Dance.
Ballet?
Do not. Not since I did some
classes when I was a kid.
I understand.
MS. Horn, do not be afraid.
S... look me in the eye.
Ladies and gentlemen, tonight we have
a modern dance specialist with us.
He will dance with Miss Horn and assure you
that she will dance as well as he does.
Miss Horn, at some point you
will begin to listen to music.
When that music starts,
you'll become a dancer.
You are Marianne Horn again.
But a magnificent
dancer was lost.
And now, ladies and gentlemen, I beg you
to pay attention to my next number.
- What happened to you?
- I do not know.
"Where did you learn to dance like that?"
- Mark, I do not know.
And now, ladies and gentlemen, I will
introduce you to my esteemed collaborator:
Hugo.
When you see it, you may think that it is
nothing more than a simple doll of a venturi.
In fact he is, but...
has unexpected talents.
Well, Hugo, what are you going to
do to make the public fun tonight?
Whatever you wish, dear Vorelli.
Except for that sort of thing.
- What are you talking about?
You just laughed as I spoke.
What's wrong with that?
It is an old trick of the ventures.
Everyone is doing it now. It's beaten.
Perhaps we can show the public
a variation on the subject.
Give me some wine. I want wine.
A doll drinking wine?
Do not be ridiculous.
I want some. Give it to me.
I know what wine is.
I took it once.
Why can not I have wine?
You're a doll, Hugo.
What? Was that beaten up?
Look at the audience applauding.
They're not clapping you,
they're clapping me.
Yeah, me. Hugo, the doll.
If it's for you, you should go and
thank the public, should not you?
Go to the spotlight and thank.
You have to obey me.
Hugo...
Walk to the spotlight and thank.
Thank you.
Go back to your master.
Do you know who this girl was?
What were you seducing yourself in your head?
MS. Horn. Marianne Horn.
One of the richest girls in England.
Your aunt will give a bouncy
ball on Saturday night.
I think I will call her
to offer her my talents.
Marianne, Marianne, come to me...
What did you say?
Anything. Because?
I thought you had said my name.
You must be hearing things.
You know, I must admit that
Vorelli is certainly different.
And the doll is fascinating.
He scares me. It really does
seem to have unusual powers.
Yeah. The paper had a pretty
good idea about Vorelli.
I still think he's a scam,
but a very good one.
I would like the opportunity
to examine this doll.
And in that, you can help me.
Oh, I can? That's what you think.
I've had enough.
Let's go, please.
What can I do?
Well, your aunt is going to
give her annual bouncy ball.
You could go to the great
Vorelli and invite him.
I know he will. I saw how he looked
at you when he came onstage.
Besides, your aunt will love it.
I would have the opportunity
to examine the doll closely.
Because you will invite him
to spend the night.
It's the only way I can do it.
The newspaper clippings on Vorelli do
not explain anything about the doll.
No one has ever touched him and
no one knows how he handles it.
What do you say?
Well, you know he's very attractive.
Maybe I could be
attracted to him.
Well, I'll take the risk.
What do you say?
That's right.
The things I do for you.
Yes it's good.
This Vorelli is too good.
Must have some trick.
This is the work of a
very trained hypnotist.
The art of hypnosis has advanced a
lot since the time of the spells.
How do you explain that the doll walks?
I think if I examine it, it would prove
to be a perfect mechanical device.
But the tension between Vorelli and
the doll was there, everyone felt.
Mass hypnotism, Mr. English.
It is as real as individual hypnotism.
What we saw was a dramatic production.
I'm telling you, a succession
of theatrical tricks.
Do not forget what I told you.
I do not want any more pictures of me.
If you continue like this, you already know
what will happen. Do not repeat it again.
- You can come in now.
- Thanks.
I'm so glad to see you again, Miss.
Horn.
I did not even know you remembered me.
Not on the contrary.
I have not forgotten you.
Thanks. But I came
to ask you a favor.
That you go to your
aunt's benefit.
Yes. But how did you guess?
Very predictable.
It is very simple.
I read in the papers that your aunt
is giving her annual bouncy ball.
You're right.
Follow me?
What is?
A Sicilian wine.
A little sweet, but
pretty good at this time.
I always drink.
It's called: Sangre della Virgine.
The virgin's blood.
Smell. It has a delicious aroma.
"Is not it too early to drink?"
"But this is a special occasion.
By the bountiful dance.
You mean you will?
- If you want to.
- Oh, I really want it, this is wonderful!
I did not expect that I could come in
here and accept my invitation, this way.
But you know it's bouncy.
"Your honor..."
- It will not be anything.
My aunt will be so happy.
I do not know how to thank you.
I will be delighted.
But... he still has not drank his wine.
It is very sweet.
Look at him...
Deep and thick...
red and white...
deep... thick...
red... cold...
"Then will you come?"
"If you ask me."
Thanks. After your presentation
we will send you a car.
Thanks.
I have, thank you.
Aunt Eva, this is your fourth bowl.
- No, honey. My fifth.
- How are you.
Excuse.
- Are you having fun, my dear?
- Yes.
- You look beautiful.
- Thanks.
Oh, Mark is coming to.
- Hello.
Mark, you're absolutely wonderful.
You're behaving divinely.
Made us great publicity.
I thank you very much.
But I warn you that you must continue
to behave well with Marianne.
She adores you.
Do not worry. I'll do it.
Forgiveness. I have to
talk to Lady Hampton.
What's the matter with you?
Hey?
Hm?
Oh, nothing.
I was daydreaming, I guess.
Mark, I do not like this.
Do not you? Your aunt loves it.
She does not know what she wants to do.
As long as you can raise
funds, what does it matter?
It's just that... I do not know.
I wish I had never seen him.
Mark, when do I introduce Mr. Vorelli?
You can already submit.
Oh gosh.
Do not worry. Everything will work out.
Ladies and gentlemen, we have a
big surprise for you tonight.
Please, let's get a
little closer here.
Thanks.
I'd like you to
form a semicolon.
I am delighted to introduce
The Great Vorelli and Hugo.
Well, Hugo, I think I
should sing a song.
Do not! I'm tired!
Well, I think you're in a bad mood.
I'll leave you alone and when
you're ready to act, act.
In the meantime, if you'll excuse
me, I'd like to eat something.
I just got back from the
theater and did not have time.
Oh. Ham.
Really like.
Cannibal!
And what would you eat to
become a cannibal? Sawdust?
Give me something to eat! I'm hungry!
Who ever heard of a
ventriloquist dummy?
I can eat. I can eat like you.
You're not the only one who likes to eat.
Do not be ridiculous.
I'm hungry! I want to eat something!
Now!
Of course you do not expect me to serve you.
Very well. Serve yourself for yourself.
Do not drink too much, Hugo.
The wine will cause the sawdust
of your stomach to swell.
It's a doll, Hugo.
A common puppet.
Hugo!
Let go of that knife!
I said...
drop it
It frightened the ladies.
You have to apologize.
Tell them you're sorry.
I'm sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
And I...?
I...
Yes tell me!
I'm sorry...
Master!
Master.
It went up ten minutes ago.
He would have come back.
When he comes down, I'll go upstairs.
I gotta take a look at that doll.
It's impossible...
There has to be somebody inside.
A very small man or maybe a boy.
This is either mechanical.
Honey, it was fascinating, wonderful.
Wonderful.
Have you ever seen anything
so incredible, Mark?
No, never.
There it is.
Excuse.
Congratulations.
- Mr. Vorelli, it was magnific.
- Thank you.
Yours is an incredible doll.
But how do you do it?
It's my mystery, ma'am.
I think I'd like to have a drink, Marianne.
Want to join me?
Thanks.
- It was a great performance.
- Oh yeah.
And when I call you, you will come.
Wherever you are, you will come.
But until I call, you'll be yourself.
The lovely old girl.
And now I'll leave you, my dear.
Good evening, beautiful Marianne.
Come with me.
Remember if. He promised to obey me.
You have to obey me.
Come on, Marianne...
Marianne...
Now...
Come to me...
Marianne...
You came, Marianne.
He obeyed me.
But you do not know you're here.
You will not remember anything tomorrow.
I will not remember anything.
She is very beautiful, my Marianne.
You must learn to respond.
- Is afraid of me?
- Do not.
So why do you resist me?
You're not that strong. My thoughts
have already penetrated your mind.
See? I just have to think.
Help me!
Meet me!
In Berlin, 1948.
Find me in Berlin...
Hugo!
- Your breakfast, Mr. English.
- Thank you.
How was the party?
The doll spoke to me last night.
He entered my room.
Did the doll come into your room?
That's it.
And what did he tell you, Mark?
I know it sounds crazy but
you asked for my help.
He told me about Berlin.
Berlin, 1948.
When did you start having those nightmares, Mark?
I'm sure it was not more than that.
It was not a nightmare.
This doll talked to me.
It was all as real as...
You're not serious.
Very serious.
Hello?
For you, Mark.
- Hello?
- Hello, Mark.
Mark, Marianne is not doing very well.
The whole house is in a
mess after last night.
I was wondering if
you could come here.
What happened?
You know, Mark. The charity, the
preparations, the same party.
She's nervous.
Anyone would stay.
But are you okay?
Dr. Keisling, the
family doctor, is here.
He would like to have a word with you.
Hello? Mr. English?
Yes, Doctor.
I'm sorry to make you come here, but I
think you'd better come and see Marianne.
What is the problem?
No, nothing serious, but...
I urge you to come.
Right. I'll be there in two hours.
Very well.
It will be a pleasure to meet you. Thank you.
Glad you could come so fast.
Yes...
She seems to be in a state of semicom.
With moments of delirium.
Make him stop, Mark...
Marianne, my dear...
Make it stop...
Honey, what have you got?
He's calling me, Mark...
Please, make him stop...
- Who's calling you?
- Please please...
Please, make him stop...
Let's let her rest.
Maybe if I fall asleep the fever will come down.
Please, make him stop...
A very strange case.
No, thank you.
I expected her visit to calm her down.
Maybe she's hypnotized...
Think about it.
Vorelli.
I do not understand.
Doctor, he was put into trance
by a professional hypnotist.
A man named Vorelli.
The Great Vorelli.
Mr. English, at this time.
Hypnotized. And for what reason? Because?
You said that you yourself do
not understand the symptoms.
You just said it's a
very strange case.
I'll have to study it in depth.
It could be an unknown virus.
You know Dr. Heller?
The expert on hypnosis and mesmerism?
Yes. I once attended a
conference at the university.
A very interesting man.
I'd like you to see Marianne.
It's clear. If you think it will
do anything, I will not object.
But in the meantime, let's
continue with the tests.
Thank you, Doctor.
You do not believe a
word I say, do you?
Let's say that I keep, as you
Americans say, an open mind.
This, come this way.
Thank you.
Ah.
Would you mind telling me your name?
- Miss Penton.
And what kind of work
do you do, Miss Penton?
I play the cello in the symphony orchestra.
Oh really?
So you must be a
connoisseur of good music.
Yes, I think so.
And what does music do to you?
Well... I feel things.
I suppose different types of music
make you feel different things.
Oh, yes, definitely.
I understand.
Now, Miss Panton, do not be afraid.
Just look into my eyes.
That's it.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
I will prove to you that we do
not all have secret desires.
Desires that go against
what surrounds us.
And how music can actually
get them to surface.
Miss Panton, in some moments you
will be listening to a record.
When you hear music start,
you will become a stripper.
And you'll dance for us.
Would you like a cup of coffee, Mark?
Yes.
Yes thanks.
- Hi, Dr. Heller.
- Hello.
Hello, Mr. English.
Hello, Doctor.
Lisa, bring us coffee.
Yes of course.
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
- I just saw Miss. Horn.
"And how is it?"
Well... back to being
in a state of semicom.
By the way...
I spoke to Vorelli this morning.
He confirmed my theory
that Marianne...
has a subconscious
fear of hypnotism.
It's his fault, is not it?
We can not blame him.
Marianne let herself be hypnotized.
He offered to hypnotize
her again...
and disrupt the control
it exerts on it.
But... it's dangerous, Mark.
Too dangerous.
We have to find another solution.
Yes, but which one?
I'm still not sure.
It will take a lot of time.
The mind is very fragile.
We have to be
gentle and patient.
I have to do something.
Hugo...
She said you're ugly.
VORELLI KILLER
Good morning, Mr. English.
Finally we got to talk to Mr.
Heller...
Forget it. Call Bob Garrett
at his number in Berlin...
Call your hotel.
He will know where he is.
Hi, Mark.
How's your little newspaper?
How is the action in England?
Action? What action?
What are you talking about?
It's women. What was he going to refer to?
The girls.
Forget it. I have a job for you.
One what?
Hey, I have work to spare here.
Right now I'm at
the typewriter...
writing an article
on the Berlin Wall.
Write down what I tell you.
Wait a moment.
Sweetheart, give me water and paper.
Thank you.
Right, Mark. Start talking.
A magician, hypnotist.
Called The Great Vorelli.
He worked in Berlin.
I want you to investigate everything.
I repeat, all I can about it.
I want you to come back years later. Come back to 1947.
I want to know who he is, where he
came from, and with whom he worked.
Check the archives of the police,
the hospitals and the theaters.
Understood?
Slow down, Mark, slow down.
How do you spell the name?
V-o-r-e-1-i.
Vorelli. Very well.
Now get out of bed
and go to work.
Very good very good. Keep
calm and all that is said.
"Hey, how do you know I'm in bed?"
- I know you, Bob, I know you.
Call me when you have something.
Goodbye, Bobby.
Bye.
"Vorelli's helper
was found dead."
Listen to this: "Miss Kardina was
last seen by Carlos Sandis,"
"the stage manager, at 7:15."
"On returning to the theater for the
evening performance, he found her dead."
"Mr. Jack Walton, Theater Director,"
"said that Mr. Vorelli
was in his office."
"That you've been talking to a customs
official about your passport..."
"and exit procedures
for travel to Spain."
"The customs officer proved Mr.
Walton's statement."
"They were interrupted by Carlos Sandis,
who had just found the corpse."
And here is the best. Listen:
"Mr. Vorelli said, open quotation marks:
That poor girl did not have an enemy. "
"It's a horrible crime."
"I hope the police persevere,
find the killer and justice."
"I'm going to miss her a lot."
The Great Vorelli
with a perfect libah.
Do you know what I think?
That he killed her.
I do not know how, but it was him.
We'll see what Bob investigates in Berlin.
What we have done so far has not helped.
This new American remedy seems
to have a calming effect.
There is something.
Mr. Vorelli called back today.
You seem very worried about Marianne.
Yes. He calls regularly.
Very nice.
Doctor, I think you should go up.
Ms. Still delirious.
I feared this.
Another injection, nurse.
Half a pound and a half.
They call you on the phone.
From your office.
How are you?
Hi, Lisa. What is there?
A clue? What does it mean?
Did you say that?
Get me a ticket for the
first flight to Berlin.
Call Bob and tell him to pick me up.
And book a room at the Hilton.
I do not know how long I'll stay there.
Marianne...
Yes, yes, it's coming...
All right, Grace.
Grace, you look very beautiful.
Do you know what your job is?
Yes sir.
Poor Magda.
I will miss her in so many ways.
Tonight, you will stay in her place.
Yes sir.
You can go now, Grace.
I'll try not to disappoint you, Mr. Vorelli.
I'm sure you will not, dear.
Well, where do we start?
Relax, Mark, relax.
I'll tell you everything.
In 1947, Vorelli began
to work in Vaudeville.
But before that he was a doctor.
Doctor?
As it seems to me, after obtaining his
license, he refused to exercise...
and became fanatical by
the Eastern mysteries.
He even studied them.
At where?
In Egypt, Huron, Burma.
He has been with the llamas
of Tibet for a full year.
Always studying the same thing.
Hypnosis?
Do not. Not exactly.
What he most believed was that he
could separate a man from his soul.
Difficult to imagine, Mark.
And why did you dedicate yourself to Vaudeville?
In December 47 he was expelled
from the Medical Society.
But I could not figure out why.
But the truth is that he was expelled.
The next time someone saw him was
when he started acting in Vaudeville.
He had a number with a boy and a girl.
Hypnotism and all that.
He hypnotized them and they did things.
One of the numbers that Vorelli did
was stick a dagger in the boy.
Through a friend I was
able to find the woman.
It is to her where I am taking you now.
I think it's just the American
police looking for something.
No, we're not cops.
And what do you want?
Know what happened in 48
when you worked with him.
An accident happened, did not it?
Yes.
He did not hear me.
His companion, a boy,
was part of the number.
Oh yeah. Hugo.
Hugo?
Tell us about it.
Would be better...
cut Vorelli's throat.
It's been a long time.
I was too young.
Vorelli hired Hugo and me.
We made a number.
We were a couple of dancers.
We won little money
but we were happy.
Vorelli said we'd win more.
Right.
Continues.
Vorelli hypnotized us.
It made us do things.
But off the stage we
were not ourselves.
Then Hugo changed.
Vorelli became his master.
And then... I brought that doll.
Oh, he looks like Hugo!
Yes, he could look like me.
It will look like... It will look like...
Out of here!
And do not come back until I call you!
You will not believe it.
The police did not want
to believe me, but I did.
One night when I went
into the dressing room.
I saw the rehearsal.
It was as if...
he would take Hugo's soul...
giving it to the doll.
I tell you what I saw!
I believe you, Mercedes.
So you're the first.
And I'm not the only one who knows.
There is another who knows.
Tell me what happened next.
He said.
Vorelli hypnotized us.
It made me do ridiculous things.
And he and Hugo did incredible things.
He thrust a dagger
into his chest.
So, one night...
This time, Hugo, you're going to die!
He is my slave.
You will not feel anything.
This is the power of hypnotism.
Watch.
Vorelli had done the same thing many
times and Hugo had not felt anything.
But that time Hugo felt
the blood coming out!
It's hard to believe.
Nobody believes.
Neither the police nor anyone.
Hans, come here.
Maybe you believe in Hans's version.
Did you call me, Mercedes?
Hans. Here he is.
He will tell you.
These gentlemen are journalists.
They want to know something about Vorelli.
Say it. In front.
Tell them about the doll.
Well, I can not say much.
I was the janitor at the time.
It was not even on the
stage when it happened.
It was in Vorelli's room.
Enjoying that he was away,
he cleaned the room.
I did not see anything... but I heard.
I heard the dagger thrust
into Hugo's chest.
And I saw the doll...
The police came soon. Confusion.
The interrogation.
Witnessed in court?
They asked questions. I answered,
they laughed, they called me crazy.
What was the verdict?
Vorelli took the risk.
"Accident".
Hugo died three months after the...
"accident".
In the hospital, in bed.
He did not move for three months.
He was lying on the bed.
Looking at the ceiling.
And then he died.
Died.
Gentlemen, we do not want to drive them
out, but we have to take care of business.
Customers are waiting, you know.
If it's over, I'd be grateful if
you could give us 100 marks...
information.
We've lost more than that in time.
It's fine.
Bobby, can you take
me to the airport?
At first I thought it
was a mechanical doll.
Or until there was a person
alive inside the doll.
I even went into his room
and examined the doll.
It was nothing more than a wooden doll.
I've never told you this before, Doctor.
The night I examined the doll, he
came to my room and talked to me.
"You were dreaming."
- I knew you'd say that.
I thought it was a dream, too.
But what this doll told me
took me to Mercedes in Berlin.
I know you're thinking
that I'm crazy,
but somehow, he put the
life of a man in that doll.
You have a tremendous imagination.
But I do not like it, Doctor.
Marianne is in bed.
Much like Hugo Novik.
For three months he lay
immobile in a bed.
You are exaggerating the problem.
The case of Hugo Novik was catalepsy.
- Catalepsy?
- Yes, no life.
A perfect case of traumatic shock.
This explains the case of the dagger.
Instead of saying that it would not hurt,
he probably said he was going to die.
Or almost.
For three months, Hugo lay in
a hospital without moving...
while Vorelli completed
his transfer.
He put his spy inside that
doll before Hugo died.
And over the years, Hugo Novik's
soul has been inside the doll.
It's crazy.
Besides, Marianne did not
suffer a traumatic shock.
Or maybe yes, I do not know.
The night Vorelli showed
up at his aunt's house,
something happened in your room.
The next day, she was
helpless in bed.
Either way, Hugo Novik's took
place fifteen years ago.
His power may have
increased since then.
You're wasting your time, Mark.
I tell you he stole
this man's soul.
I do not know how and I can not give
you a scientific explanation...
but I know that's what happened.
Mark, do you really believe we should
seriously discuss this matter?
A soul transferred by a
Vaudeville magician.
Vorelli is not a simple Vaudeville magician.
Look at Marianne.
She is a very nervous young woman.
Her case is a case of
interrupted hypnosis.
"That I can understand.
- Very well. What do you suggest?
Forget all this madness.
Forget about Vorelli.
You're tired, nervous.
Maybe even a little jealous.
Are you convinced of that?
You have my word.
I wish I could believe you.
Doctor Heller.
Oh, yes, Dr. Keisling.
Yes...
Oh good.
Marianne is awake and
perfectly normal.
Yes, yes, of course. I'll come this afternoon.
Good.
Thank you, Doctor. Bye.
Thank God.
Mark, take my advice. Forget
Vorelli, forget the doll.
Marianne is much better.
Vorelli is not the villain what you imagine.
Maybe you should not stay too long.
Yes sir. It's clear. I understand.
You'll tell your uncles that you love me.
I love you. I love you.
And you'll tell Mark
he'll marry me.
I'm going to marry you.
Now I have to go.
But when I call you, you will come.
Remember if.
When I call you, you will come, Marianne.
- Hello.
- Hello. How are you?
It's good to see you.
- You're much better.
- Thanks.
Dr. took the pills.
Mark, I have to tell you something.
I'm staying with Vorelli.
I'm in love with him.
Is what?
I'm in love.
Sorry, Mark.
How can I explain?
It happened the night you slept here.
I do not know. I do not know what to say.
Forgiveness.
Well, Hugo.
Tonight we will fly to Spain.
And the rich and beautiful Miss
Marianne Horn will become my wife.
What a delicious idea.
Tonight will be our last performance.
All four.
You, Hugo, my beautiful fiancee,
my ugly wooden doll and me.
And then, after a few months, the
transformation will be complete.
My beautiful wife will die,
leaving me all her money...
and for you, a small,
ugly wooden companion.
Of course...
You're ugly too, are not you?
Serve me another.
How stupid I am.
I made a lot of unnecessary spending
on an article about a phony.
A third-class impostor.
The only woman that I cared about
in life falls in love with him.
If you do not fire me after this fiasco,
it's because you're as crazy as I am.
Sleep, my Marianne.
Sleep deeply.
I'll wake up my beautiful Marianne
after tonight's performance.
Hugo, today will be our last presentation.
You've lost control too often.
There's so much time in
his little wooden body...
who is becoming a person again.
I think I should give you a little lesson.
Oh, dear Grace.
I'm very busy.
I thought you needed me.
Not now, my dear.
I have to get things right
with the director before I go.
I'll go to your room...
- Very well.
"When you're through with him."
Hugo... I am your master.
Go back to your cage or I'll destroy you.
Do not be alarmed, Mr. English.
Vorelli is now
on the wooden dummy.
I am peaceful, Master.
The situation is reversed.
Do not be afraid of Marianne.
He's sleeping soundly.
When you wake up it will
be the same as before.
Mr. English, get me out of here.
I am the Great Vorelli.
You can not do this to me.
Please, Mr. English.
Do not let him do that.
I'll do anything you want.
Take me out of here.
I'll do anything you want. Please.
I am The Great Vorelli.
END
Translated from Spanish by DougTrash
Http://cinespacemonster.blogspot.com.br/