(RUMBLING)
(MAN BREATHES DEEPLY)
Let's just take
it from the top,
Mr. McCall.
Mr. McCall?
I told you,
I didn't do it.
(VIDEO CAMERA WHIRRING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
WOMAN: Good night.
Oh, fun for you.
See you tomorrow.
(CHUCKLES)
What?
EMILY: Good night.
We'll clean up.
I love you.
(GRUNTING AND PANTING)
(HINGES SQUEAK)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(HAIRDRYER WHIRRING
IN DISTANCE)
(DOG BARKS)
ZACH: Whoa! Shit!
Maverick, stop.
SAMANTHA: Jesus Christ!
No, come on. Get off!
You scared the shit
out of me.
ZACH: Go away. Come on,
buddy. Get out.
SAMANTHA: (SCOFFS)
You're not supposed
to see me tonight.
ZACH: Come on,
that is a dumb tradition.
You don't believe it.
No, I don't believe it.
ZACH: Oh, shit, you do.
Okay, I kind of do.
What are you doing--
- Okay, ready?
- Okay.
Ladies, oop,
and gentlemen...
I'd like to present
the McCalls.
- (KISS)
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
- Almost.
Okay, I gotta get dressed.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
old on, hold on.
Strike that pose.
Right there.
I want to capture our
last night together.
(CHUCKLES)
We're not dying.
My dad used to
follow us around with
one of these constantly.
- My mom gave him so
much shit for it.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
I think it's sweet.
I wish I had
something like that.
My whole childhood
is kind of a blank.
ZACH: That's kind of why
I want to do this.
I used to think
my dad was so lame,
with all his nostalgia
and all that.
But I kind of get it now.
I kind of want
this for us.
I just want a record
of all the important things
that happen to us.
And all the random
stupid stuff that
we'll forget about.
Mmm, yeah.
Tomorrow,
we are officially family.
So, tonight I want to
start our family history.
Family history.
Yeah.
I love that.
Good. (CHUCKLES)
(WEDDING MARCH PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
In sickness and in health.
To love and to cherish.
Till death do us part.
With this ring,
I thee wed.
And pledge myself
to thee forever.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
(SINGING) ♪ Love me tender ♪
♪ Love me true ♪
♪ All my dreams fulfilled ♪
MAN: Whoo!
♪ For, my darling, I love you ♪
I just wanted to say
thank you to Ken
and Sally...
for making me
feel so at home.
I've never really
felt like I was part
of a family before.
So, thank you
for being so welcoming
and wonderful.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
- Dad had the first camera.
He'd carry it on
his shoulder like this.
I wanted you to know
that I think you are
a wonderful brother.
- I'm being serious!
This is a beautiful event...
(CROWD LAUGHING)
and I'm really grateful
that you invited me.
(LAUGHS)
We were in the same foster
home together for a year.
And we were more
than friends. Family.
I hope that you guys
will be happy forever.
- So, here's to
happily ever after.
- (CHEERING)
- Oh, gosh.
(GUESTS CHUCKLING)
Mmm.
- Mmm.
- Are you okay?
(LAUGHS)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
AND LAUGHTER)
(SIGHS)
Sam...
my beautiful wife.
This was the most
perfect day.
I can't believe
we're married.
(CHUCKLING)
When we watch this
a lot of years from now...
just remember how
good-looking I was.
I love you so much.
I promise I will
always protect you.
Keep you safe.
I love you.
PILOT: Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain speaking.
I'd like to welcome you
to the Dominican Republic.
This is gonna be awesome.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(HORNS HONKING)
(DANCEHALL PLAYING ON RADIO)
ZACH: Now,
the honeymoon begins.
SAMANTHA: Ooh.
Oh, wow!
(CHUCKLES)
ZACH: We're gonna do this
swimsuit issue-type thing.
SAMANTHA: Oh, God!
- No, no. You're gonna
go in the water.
- Uh-huh.
And then you're gonna
come out of the water.
(LAUGHS)
Is that how
I'm gonna do it?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Don't worry,
I'm right behind you.
SAMANTHA:
This is gonna go fast.
ZACH: No, it's not.
SAMANTHA: Oh, my God.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
♪ Christopher Columbus. ♪
ZACH: Oh. Really?
SAMANTHA: Yeah.
This is the first cathedral
in the New World.
"The Cathedral
of Santo Domingo.
"It's Gothic style
highlighted with
Renaissance details."
SAMANTHA: (WHISPERING)
Oh, my God.
I have never seen anything
so fucking perfect
before in my life.
Look at this sea of white.
Oh, my gosh.
(GASPS)
What's that?
♪ That's my husband. ♪
Wake up.
Hey.
- (YELLS)
- (SCREAMS AND CHUCKLES)
♪ Oogum, Oogum, Boogum,
Boogum, Boogum... ♪
♪ Now, baby
You're casting
your spell on me ♪
♪ Your high heel boots
In your hip-huggin' suit ♪
♪ You got it right
You're outta sight ♪
What is that?
It's the coolest
wedding present ever.
Mason gave it to us.
It's an adventure cam.
- Oh, good, that's what
I always wanted.
- I know.
ZACH: And now we can
go zip-lining. Come on.
Just get your game face on.
All right.
- (SHRIEKS)
- Hold on. Hold on!
(ZACH CHUCKLES)
(DRUMS PLAYING)
SAMANTHA: Wow.
(HORN BLOWING)
SAMANTHA: Where are we?
(MAN YELLS)
(SINGING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Zach, come here.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
We're going here.
(CHUCKLES)
ZACH: Whoa. Come on.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
ZACH: Hey, wait up,
wait up.
(WOMAN CHUCKLES)
- Welcome.
SAMANTHA: Oh, thank you.
ZACH: Hi.
- Welcome.
- Have a seat.
SAMANTHA: Okay.
WOMAN: I will
study your palm.
Okay. Which one do you want?
This one. (CHUCKLES)
ZACH: I don't
think it matters.
SAMANTHA: I don't know.
They're different.
WOMAN: You've had
some hard times.
But now, you're so happy.
(CHUCKLES)
- You're happy now.
ZACH: She's good.
(LAUGHS)
No family.
No past.
You were born from death.
What do you mean?
They've been waiting.
ZACH: Do you want to go?
SAMANTHA: Yeah.
WOMAN: They've been waiting.
ZACH: Whoa.
They've been waiting.
SAMANTHA: All right.
Thank you. That's fine.
ZACH: Whoa.
- They've been waiting.
WOMAN: You are the first.
The first of many.
You will bring the end.
SAMANTHA: You know what?
Let's go, let's go.
Can we get out--
SAMANTHA: Ow! Ow!
WOMAN: You were
born from death.
SAMANTHA:
Let go of me, please.
ZACH: Ma'am, let go.
SAMANTHA: Let's go,
let's go, let's go.
- Zach, come on.
- Okay.
ZACH: Hey, are you okay?
What did she say to you?
- Nothing. Fucking nothing.
I don't know.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey. Forget her, okay?
She was crazy.
What did she whisper
in your ear?
I don't know.
It was just a bunch
of gibberish.
She stank of rum anyway.
I just want to get back
to the hotel.
ZACH: I don't remember
this street, do you?
SAMANTHA: Do you wanna
go down this way?
ZACH: Let's turn around.
(MAN YELLS INDISTINCTLY)
SAMANTHA: Okay.
- (SCREAMS)
ZACH: Jesus!
(DOG BARKS)
(WHIMPERS) Let's go.
(DOG WHINES)
ZACH: They don't have
any street signs.
SAMANTHA: Can we
head back towards
where the party was?
(WHISTLES)
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: Are you are a taxi?
- Yeah.
ZACH: That's your family?
- Mi family. (SPEAKING SPANISH)
DRIVER: Babies?
ZACH: Oh, no, not yet.
DRIVER: No?
(ZACH SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CHUCKLING)
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
(ZACH SPEAKING SPANISH)
- Someday. One day, yeah.
I take you
somewhere fun. Eh...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: No, no, no.
We're good. Thank you.
We just want to go
back to the hotel.
DRIVER: No, no, no.
No worry.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
This place, eh...
It's special.
ZACH: What do you think?
One more drink?
SAMANTHA: No.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
SAMANTHA: Twenty minutes?
ZACH: Twenty minutes.
It's our last night.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: Deal.
SAMANTHA: All right, fine.
One drink.
(ZACH SPEAKING SPANISH)
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
We here.
ZACH: We're here.
Yeah. This looks...
great.
Oh. Okay.
(CHUCKLES)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
SAMANTHA: Okay, gracias.
ZACH: You don't look happy.
SAMANTHA: Well, where are we?
ZACH: I don't know,
but it's gonna be cool.
DRIVER: Careful. (CHUCKLES)
SAMANTHA: Right. Okay.
Oh!
ZACH: Look at this little guy.
SAMANTHA: Hi, little guy.
DRIVER: Whoo.
SAMANTHA: Ooh!
ZACH: I'm right here.
Shh.
(DISTANT DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
- You hear music?
SAMANTHA: Yeah.
ZACH: It's musica.
SAMANTHA: Yeah, I hear it.
Wait, this is--
No, Zach, let's go back.
This is crazy.
Let's turn around.
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: We'll be all right.
I'm right here,
I'm right here.
All right, I'm right here.
SAMANTHA: Don't...
ZACH: We'll go slow.
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: I'm sorry, what?
(DRIVER CHEERS)
Oh, wow. Okay.
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: It's fine, I promise.
- See?
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DANCE MUSIC BECOMING LOUDER)
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
(LOUD UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
It's special!
(CHUCKLES)
ZACH: This is insane!
(DRIVER SPEAKING SPANISH)
Oh, see how great.
Here we go.
SAMANTHA: Cheers!
Yes! Beautiful!
ZACH: Here we go.
- Ah!
- I'm gonna hold my nose.
ZACH: Ah!
That's not how
you take a shot.
You sipped it.
No!
ZACH: You gotta do another.
One more.
Oh, my God!
Congratulations!
ZACH: Oh, thank you!
- They just got married, too.
ZACH: No way!
SAMANTHA: Yes!
(LAUGHS)
ZACH: I'm done.
Oh, yes!
Oh.
(DANCE MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
These men are
staring at me.
ZACH: What?
I said, "These men
are staring at me."
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
I guess you'll do.
I can't dance anymore.
ZACH: Hi!
SAMANTHA: Hi!
Hey, babe,
let's put it away.
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
MAN 1: Si?
MAN 2: Si?
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MAN CHANTING IN LATIN)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(MEN CHANTING)
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(MILD RUMBLING)
(MAN WHISPERING IN LATIN)
(OTHERWORLDLY ROARING)
(ZACH SIGHS)
(SIGHS)
- Come on, wife.
(SAMANTHA GROANS)
Time to get up.
- Come on.
- No.
ZACH: Yes. I'm sorry,
but we gotta get up.
(SAMANTHA SPUTTERS)
Ugh.
I'm so hung over.
ZACH: Yeah, no kidding.
Mmm, oh, God,
get away with that.
ZACH: Come on,
I'll get you some water.
We gotta get up
and catch this plane.
Okay. (GROANS)
Oh.
ZACH: Yeah,
my head is killing me.
Me, too.
Oh, shit. I'm stuck.
(COUGHS) Mmm.
SAMANTHA: How did
we get home last night?
ZACH: I don't know.
The guy in the cab?
Stop. Not right now.
ZACH: See you later,
Santo Domingo.
- Well, we're home.
- Mmm.
ZACH: Home sweet home.
(SAMANTHA SIGHS)
ZACH: The honeymoon is over.
( SAMANTHA  SIGHS )
Ooh, wait, wait, wait.
- Hold this.
SAMANTHA: Oh.
ZACH: Oh, sorry.
- (CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Okay, here we go.
SAMANTHA: All right.
Whoo-hoo!
- (GRUNTS)
(SAMANTHA LAUGHS)
Welcome home,
Mrs. McCall.
(SAMANTHA LAUGHS)
(ZACH GRUNTS)
SAMANTHA: Ugh.
ZACH: Oh.
- Suzie left the door open.
- Great.
ZACH: That's great.
SAMANTHA: Oh.
Yay, home.
Ooh, presents.
Crate and Barrel,
Crate and Barrel.
ZACH: I'll go get the bags.
All right.
We got the panini grill.
And that thing from Allison.
And what is this one?
ZACH: Oh, I don't know.
Open it up.
Mav, do you want
to open this?
- All right.
- He doesn't care.
This is the juicer
that I wanted!
I'm gonna make so much stuff
with flax and probiotics...
and things with kale.
- Kale?
- Mmm.
(WHISPERING) Kale... kale.
(KAREN LAUGHS)
SAMANTHA: Oh, Mav!
Oh, my God.
SAMANTHA: Look at him.
KAREN: Oh!
Hey, did you see
the "Sold" sign on
the Anderson house?
For real? Maybe
someone will finally
fix that place up.
KAREN: I hope so.
It's terrible.
Your husband,
he can't grill for shit.
ZACH: Sam, come on.
You're gonna miss it.
This will be awesome. Ready?
Just like we practiced.
Are you kidding me?
Come on, Maverick.
No, no, no.
You're supposed
to catch it.
SAMANTHA: Zach.
- Yeah?
ZACH: Come on, ready?
Eye on the prize.
Yes. yes, yes!
SAMANTHA: Zach.
- What?
Can you turn that
off for one second?
Whoa.
What is that?
Uh...
(STAMMERS) it doesn't
make any sense.
I've taken
the pill religiously.
I've never missed one ever.
ZACH: Whoa, whoa, whoa...
You're pregnant?
- Yes.
- Oh, my God.
We're having a baby.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Holy shit!
- (SHRIEKS)
- Oh, my God.
That's so amazing.
(LAUGHING)
I feel good
about this office.
- How about you?
- I feel good.
Except that says
three stages of pregnancy,
and there's four pictures.
Okay, so this isn't
a math office.
It's a doctor's office.
(CHUCKLES) I hope that
doctors can do math.
Well, the doctor didn't
make that sign, clearly.
Do you think the doctor made
the "Dirty Area" sign?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
- Oh, hello.
BOTH: Hi.
Mr. and Mrs. McCall.
Hello, how are you?
I'm Zach.
I am Dr. Ludka.
Nice to finally meet.
Yes.
- Hello, lucky lady.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- I'm good, how are you?
Okay. You ready?
(INHALES DEEPLY) Yeah.
Okay, this is gonna
be quick and painless.
ZACH: Awesome.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Sorry.
- "Awesome."
You know you get a copy
of the ultrasound, right?
Oh, yeah, I just, um...
This is his thing.
- It's our thing.
We just want to film
a bunch of this so he/she,
whoever, can see it later.
- It's for the baby.
- Okay, sure.
- Is it okay?
- Oh, yeah, perfect.
- Okay.
- Make sure you
get my good side.
ZACH: Done. Right there.
SAMANTHA: Both sides.
This is gonna
be a little cold.
(ZACH CHUCKLES)
Mmm-hmm.
- A little gooey, huh?
- Yeah. Oh!
That's great.
Okay.
DR. LUDKA: Ah, there we go.
ZACH: Oh.
Can you see?
There's your uterus,
right there.
And there's the heartbeat.
(DR. LUDKA CHUCKLES)
Huh, um...
ZACH: What?
Oh, don't worry,
I'm just gonna make
a few adjustments.
SAMANTHA: Is it okay?
Uh...
Ah, there we go.
- So, you're about
seven weeks along.
ZACH: Ooh.
And everything
looks really good.
ZACH: Honeymoon baby.
- (CHUCKLES)
The pill is about
99 percent effective,
but, occasionally,
this happens.
Okay.
ZACH: She winked at me.
- I saw that.
- Because I got good sperm.
(DR. LUDKA LAUGHS)
- This is what you started.
- What? It's good,
strong sperm.
DR. LUDKA: I'm gonna
prescribe vitamin B...
- and iron, since
you're a vegetarian.
- Mmm-hmm.
ZACH: Yeah, I've been trying
to break her of that.
- It's for the baby.
- Mmm-hmm.
But, overall,
you're pretty healthy.
I'm expecting a pretty
smooth ride, here.
ZACH: Awesome.
- Great.
- Okay?
ZACH: Thank you.
DR. LUDKA:
One more thing.
ZACH: Ooh.
Congratulations.
The due date is March 30th.
ZACH: Hey,
he looks like you.
- He doesn't!
ZACH: A little jelly bean.
Ooh, will you hold this?
DR. LUDKA: (LAUGHS)
Oh, sure.
It's our first family video.
Oh, sweet.
That's awesome.
- Sorry. Thanks.
(ALL LAUGHING)
DR. LUDKA: All right,
I expect you guys back
in five weeks.
ZACH: I think
Maverick drank my wine.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
Aw, Mav,
he's such a lush.
ZACH: Hey, have your
ankles and toes
started swelling up?
SAMANTHA: Oh, my God,
with the ankles.
Yes, they're swelling up.
I read in the baby book,
it says that those things
swell sometimes.
They do.
My entire thing is
swelling right now.
It looks good.
You could use
a little meat
on your bones.
Mmm-mmm.
I don't like it.
ZACH: Hey, ew.
I mean, whoa.
What? Oh, God.
ZACH: You haven't
noticed that?
No, what is that?
- Oh.
- Does it hurt?
No, I think my body
is being taken
over by hormones.
Ugh, this is not supposed
to be happening yet.
Don't look at that.
All these weird things
are gonna happen to you.
You're making a person
inside of your person.
(CHUCKLES) Seriously,
that's amazing.
- Sam.
- Mmm?
You're making a baby.
I can't do that.
Yeah.
(SAMANTHA SNORING)
(ZACH SIGHS)
(SNIFFS) Mmm.
(MAVERICK WHINES)
ZACH: Oh,
she woke you up?
Yeah. So, your mother snores.
Even though she
categorically denies it.
But we now have
hard evidence.
So, if she ever
denies it again--
Oh, hey. Sam.
Sam, hey.
Jesus, Sam.
Sam.
- Hey.
- (MOANS)
Go to sleep.
ZACH: What are you doing?
Hello.
ZACH:
They're getting restless.
So, I'll leave it to Sam.
We're having a baby.
(ALL CHEERING)
- Oh, my God!
(ZACH LAUGHS)
What?
MR. McCALL: We get to be
grandparents again.
Stop.
SUZIE: Congratulations.
Flip it. Flip that
card that you just
had in your hand.
Thank you.
Seven, king,
so I get it.
(ZACH LAUGHS)
Tofu?
ZACH: What did
you think it was?
I wish you wouldn't have
told me it was tofu.
I mean, did they
do a sonogram?
SAMANTHA: Oh, yeah.
Did you get a picture?
SAMANTHA: She wants
a picture to show
everybody immediately.
MRS. McCALL:
Oh, ultrasound.
If you go with a C-section,
your body just
bounces right back.
- Great.
- What?
Natalie, why don't you
try to not micro-manage
their entire thing?
I checked
under the fridge.
It's not there.
You lifted the fridge up?
I looked under it.
We'll find it.
I couldn't find it.
When I do,
I'll email it to you.
I hope you find it.
SAMANTHA: We will.
I'm just gonna be on
pins and needles to see it.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my God, Sam,
you're bleeding.
- Oh, God.
- Oh, jeez, here.
ZACH: Sam, here you go.
This is clean.
Tilt your head back.
(ALL MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
ZACH: This is where
you'll go to school.
I got beat up here
a couple times,
but that's not gonna
happen to you.
You're gonna be
a much cooler kid.
(BELLS TOLLING)
Ah, this is where me
and your mom got married.
Very pretty church.
This is where
we walk the dog.
Here's the Anderson house.
It still looks like shit.
- Shit, fuck. Maverick!
- (BARKING)
(GRUNTS) Maverick, God damn.
- Hey, hey. Maverick!
- (BARKING CONTINUES)
Come here. Hey, no, no.
No, no, we don't live here.
Come on.
- (GROWLING)
- All right, come on.
Come on.
- This is your house.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
That's your room
up there on the left.
Your granddad says
that it's a money pit...
but it's got good bones.
Shit.
- Hey.
Do you think this
looks too mish-mash?
Um...
Do you want the truth?
ZACH: I'm giving our baby
a tour of the house.
SAMANTHA: Yeah?
- Hey, that's not the house.
- Sorry.
ZACH: And the grand
finale, your room.
Formerly known as
your mother's office.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
- But now we are converting.
- Thank you for giving
up your office.
- Mmm-hmm. Whoa!
SAMANTHA: Jeez.
- (CHUCKLES)
Watch it, there.
I study on the couch
all the time, anyway,
so it's not a big deal.
It's a pretty
good room, though.
She really didn't
do anything in it,
so I think it's only fair.
It's gonna be
kind of cool, though.
You and I are gonna
hang in here.
SAMANTHA: Hey.
- Do you see this guy
across the street?
ZACH: Huh?
SAMANTHA: He's just
staring up at the house.
ZACH: What the fuck?
SAMANTHA: Oh, it's creepy.
ZACH: Hey.
SAMANTHA: Hi.
- How was class?
- Ow!
Ugh. It was fine.
I just had to leave
because I'm starving.
I think there's some
leftover Pad Thai
in there.
I know,
I don't want that.
Okay.
- (GRUNTS)
- Um...
- I'm just gonna eat
a bunch of cookies.
(ZACH CHUCKLES)
How are you feeling?
Fine.
I'm just hungry.
(SAMANTHA IMITATES DRUM ROLL)
EMILY: All right.
- Whoo! Get ready.
ZACH: Hey, no!
- Oh!
SAMANTHA: What?
EMILY: Hello?
I told you that
this was off-limits
until I told you that
it was on-limits.
SAMANTHA: But it's just Emily,
I want her to see it.
EMILY: it looks so good.
- I don't care about Emily,
I care about you.
EMILY: Oh.
- Okay. Thanks.
SAMANTHA: Great.
Are you guys gonna
pick a color or...?
SAMANTHA: One of these days.
EMILY: This looks
really good, though.
- Oh, look! Oh, my God.
ZACH: Yep.
SAMANTHA: That's really nice.
EMILY: You made that?
ZACH: It's gonna
look way better.
SAMANTHA:
You're doing a great job.
I'm very proud of you.
(EMILY CHUCKLES)
- Well, here's the crib.
SAMANTHA: Uh-huh.
- Hey!
SAMANTHA: Oh, wow.
That looks really good.
ZACH: Yeah, we got it at
the antique place
and then I brought it home...
and sanded it down
and refinished it
and stuff.
Made it baby-safe.
I know you're big
on baby safety.
EMILY: Yeah, it looks great.
SAMANTHA: Cute sheets.
(GROANS)
ZACH: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- I got you. Okay.
SAMANTHA: Ah!
I got you. Sit down.
Are you okay?
EMILY: It happened
this morning, too.
- This bad?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Hey. Just breathe, okay?
- Mmm.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
EMILY: Lie down, maybe?
Are you sure?
I'll just sit here
for a sec. (EXHALES)
- In...
(ALL INHALE)
- and out.
( ALL  EXHALE )
In...
Do you see what
I'm doing for you?
I'm learning how to breathe.
(SAMANTHA INHALES LOUDLY)
(BOTH EXHALE)
You might actually
have to know
some of this stuff.
ZACH: I know this stuff.
I know how to breathe.
Okay. I know that you
know how to breathe,
but there's other stuff.
- (INHALES)
- Okay.
(CHUCKLES) Stop!
INSTRUCTOR: You are strong.
You are healthy.
Your body is going through
a beautiful transformation.
(WHISPERING)
That's a load of shit.
INSTRUCTOR: I want you
all to imagine a place
that's calming, quiet.
Make it a specific memory.
Where are you?
(WHISPERING)
On the beach
on our honeymoon.
INSTRUCTOR: How old are you?
Are you alone?
Breathe into this memory
that brings you joy.
(WOMEN GROANING)
INSTRUCTOR: Okay, everyone,
please breathe.
If you're gonna sit up,
sit up slowly.
Very slowly.
Keep breathing, everyone.
Please remain calm.
ZACH: Sam. Are you okay?
ZACH: So, this is happening.
- Yep.
We are buying
baby stuff.
- ♪ Baby stuff! ♪
- (CHUCKLES)
- Let's go crazy.
- Yeah, let's go nuts.
Ooh! Uh...
Do you want to practice
a little diapering?
Get a little wrap
around this guy?
ZACH: (STAMMERS) I'm good.
- You don't want to do that?
He's not even in a box.
He's clearly dirty.
Yeah, where'd this
baby come from?
I don't know you, baby.
ZACH: You bent him over,
looked at his ass to see
where it came from.
I just wanted to know
if he had a name
or something.
SAMANTHA: Ah...
(CHUCKLES)
It's a milk pump!
SAMANTHA: Not at all.
- No?
- No.
We need one though, right?
Yeah, we do
actually need one.
I never want to see
you do that ever again.
(CHUCKLES)
Probably not.
No, I think we got everything.
This is all a baby needs,
right here.
Ow!
ZACH: Are you all right?
- (GROANS)
ZACH: I'm gonna go
get the car, all right?
Just hold on.
SAMANTHA: No, I'm fine.
ZACH: No, seriously, Sam.
Please, just wait there.
I'll be right there.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
- (ANGRY YELL)
ZACH: Oh, shit! Sam!
SAMANTHA: Motherfucker!
MAN: What are you doing?
Are you fucking crazy?
- Get away from my car!
ZACH: Stop, stop!
- It's okay. It's okay.
- (SOBBING)
ZACH: We're gonna
get some help.
We're gonna get some help.
It's all right,
it's all right,
it's all right.
SAMANTHA: What happened?
What happened?
Breathe. Just breathe.
Just breathe, just breathe.
(GROANS) What
is wrong with me?
Something is wrong!
ZACH: Hey.
- You look really pretty
when you're pensive.
- (STIFLED CHUCKLE)
I'm serious.
Hey...
Look what I found
behind your ear.
(ZACH LAUGHS)
- Nothing.
- Oh, hello.
ZACH: Hi.
Hi, Samantha.
I'm Dr. Dylan.
ZACH: Where's Dr. Ludka?
Dr. Ludka had to take
a leave of absence.
I'm covering for her.
Well... (COUGHS)
Excuse me.
Is she gonna be back
anytime soon?
She filled me in,
and I've studied your file.
ZACH: Well, will she be back
by the time we deliver?
Yeah, can we talk to her?
I don't think
she's gonna be able
to come back.
Let's talk about
your symptoms.
ZACH: Oh.
Okay.
DR. DYLAN: Huh.
The baby looks healthy.
But it's turned around.
We're not gonna
be able to find out
if it's a boy or girl today.
ZACH: It's gotten
so much bigger.
SAMANTHA: Mmm.
(GAGS)
ZACH: Sam, are you okay?
(DOOR OPENS)
ZACH: She just
needs a minute.
Sorry, the nausea
hasn't really gotten better.
It actually seems like
it's gotten kind of worse.
DR. DYLAN:
Well, it's not
entirely unusual.
ZACH: Um...
She's been
getting nosebleeds, too.
Are those...?
DR. DYLAN: Yeah, it can be.
She just doesn't seem
like herself lately.
Is there a history
of mental illness
in her family?
Uh, I don't know.
She took some meds
during college for anxiety.
I don't really know
what they were.
Um...
We don't really know
anything about her family.
Her parents were killed
in a car crash
and they had to cut
Sam out of her womb.
I'm sorry. I had no idea.
(DOOR OPENS)
SAMANTHA: Hey.
ZACH: You look beautiful.
(SAMANTHA SCOFFS)
SAMANTHA: I'm really sorry.
ZACH: It's all right.
DR. DYLAN: It's all right.
DR. DYLAN: Um,
I'm gonna do an amnio now,
just to rule out any issues.
Especially since
you don't know what
may run in your family.
ZACH: Okay.
- Are you all right?
- Mmm.
Okay. Good.
I'm good, too.
Good. I was worried
about you.
- I know. I could tell,
because you asked.
- (CHUCKLES)
Uh, is this gonna hurt?
DR. DYLAN: Oh,
it's just a little pressure.
It'll be over
before you know it.
I need you to stay
very still.
Nurse,
watch the monitor, please.
- (BREATHING NERVOUSLY)
- Are you ready?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Just relax.
Take a deep breath.
- (INHALES DEEPLY)
(GROANING) Mmm.
Mmm-mmm.
ZACH: Are you okay?
- No.
NURSE: It's okay.
Something's wrong.
Can you get it out?
- Keep her still.
ZACH: Is everything okay?
- No, no. Mmm-mmm.
ZACH: Just try to stay still.
DR. DYLAN: Samantha,
we're almost there.
- Can you get it out?
Can you get it out?
Please, get it out!
You're gonna hurt yourself.
Sam, please.
Get it out!
ZACH: Can you get it
out of her? Thank you.
- It's out.
It's done, it's done.
- (GROANING)
ZACH: Hey, hey. It's done.
It's okay. All right?
It's okay.
SAMANTHA: I can't do this.
I can't do this.
It's all right.
ZACH: I'm really
worried about her.
I don't know what to do.
DR. DYLAN: Do you think
she'd ever actually
hurt herself?
ZACH: What?
No. I don't know,
I don't think so.
Just to be safe,
we'll be keeping
a close eye on her.
ZACH: Okay.
(MEN WHISPERING IN SPANISH)
(DOG BARKING OUTSIDE)
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
(WHIRRING)
(LOCK CLICKING)
ZACH: I'm gonna fix
this door someday.
SAMANTHA: Yeah,
that'll be great.
ZACH: Watch your step.
(CHUCKLES) Okay,
thank you.
ZACH: I'm so glad my sister
bought me that flashlight.
SAMANTHA: (SIGHS) Oh.
(SAMANTHA CLEARS THROAT)
ZACH: How are you doing?
I feel like
a hot air balloon.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
- You're going upstairs?
- Mmm-hmm.
- I'm gonna
go take a bath.
- Okay.
I'm just gonna check
the score on the game.
All right.
(SAMANTHA SIGHS)
This thing takes
forever to turn on.
(SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON TELEVISION)
We need to get
a fucking maid.
(WATER RUNNING)
(SAMANTHA HUMMING)
(WATER SHUTS OFF)
(WATER SPLASHING SOFTLY)
(SAMANTHA HUMS QUIETLY)
(GROWLING AND BARKING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
Oh, look.
That's beautiful.
ZACH: Wow. Nice.
ZACH: Do you want
to take off while
we wait for the results?
Go to a spa, or...
Let's just get out of town.
- It's a good idea.
- Yeah.
I'm just thinking, though,
you've already taken
so much time off of work.
And I've got finals
and we should
probably be close to
the doctor right now.
ZACH: All right.
It's just a thought.
It's a good thought.
I'm gonna be all right.
I know.
(MEN WHISPERING)
SAMANTHA:
One second. Okay.
ALL: Surprise!
(GASPS)
MRS. McCALL:
Happy birthday, darling.
Wow, thank you.
Great, son.
How are you?
I'm very well, thank you.
Hi, Ma.
BRITTANY:
Happy birthday, Aunt Sam.
Oh, my gosh.
MASON: Happy birthday!
No, I'm fine,
I just gotta rest.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
EMILY: Why are you guys
hiding in the corner?
ZACH: Hey.
EMILY: Looking good!
- Thank you.
- Um...
She's just gonna
go upstairs for a little bit,
take a rest.
I gotta lie down.
I'll be back.
I'll come up in a little
bit and check on you.
SAMANTHA: I just
need a few minutes.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
I'll clean all this up.
No, I got it, I got it.
- I'm gonna
help you, too.
- It's fine, I got it.
You guys got everyone here,
I'll clean it all up.
It's no problem.
That's what
friends are for.
- Can I have some cake?
- Yeah, here you go.
- Is this too big a bite?
- No.
Oh, that's cute.
MASON: We're the sweetest.
EMILY: We're so cute.
How's Sam?
I don't know,
I haven't been up there
since she went up.
Honestly, in general,
she has not been herself.
The doctor says that
everything is fine,
and we've done
all these tests.
But she's just convinced
that there's something
wrong with the baby.
- She's adamant about it.
- Wow.
BRITTANY: Braedon.
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
Braedon?
Come on,
I know you're in here.
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
- (GASPS)
Braedon.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Braedon?
(WHISPERING)
Braedon, come out.
It's not funny anymore.
(CREAKING)
Braedon.
- Get out!
- (SCREAMS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
ZACH: I think
I just saw you move.
All right, come on.
Do it again.
Lift this back
so we can see you.
All right, buddy,
let's go.
Ah.
You're sleeping
like your lazy mother.
Lazy bones.
(CHUCKLES)
- It's all right.
(MAVERICK BARKING)
(SCOFFS)
Shh.
ZACH: Mav, hey. Hey.
(GRUNTS)
You know, we talked about
the summer courses.
So, I figured
I'd just get a couple
of classes going...
and then go back
to the full load
in the fall.
You don't want to just
wait until the fall?
(SIGHS)
No, I don't want to
just wait until the fall.
(STAMMERING)
Okay, I was just
thinking because--
I know, it's just
that this has come up
and I...
No, I know.
But the baby is
coming in March.
I know it's not
gonna be easy.
But I don't want
to put everything
on hold just to--
We're not putting
everything on hold
indefinitely.
I gotta keep working.
But if I stop
doing it now...
then I feel like
I'm not gonna be able
to start back up again.
I'm gonna be stuck
in this house
and I'm gonna
become some housewife.
Then I'm gonna
turn into your sister.
I'm gonna be Natalie,
and I don't want to be her.
Sam, you're not
gonna be Natalie.
It's you and me.
That's what
it's turning into.
I know that...
but this isn't what
I wanted to begin with,
okay?
I didn't want
to get pregnant
and now I am.
And I just want life
to go back to normal.
I don't want to talk
about it anymore
and my fucking hair
is falling out, okay?
Sam! Whoa.
- Hey.
ZACH: Hi.
Are you excited?
- Yeah!
- Yeah, why?
Because today's
my First Communion.
ZACH: Oh, shoot, my bad.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Hi.
Oh, I'm so glad you're here.
How are you feeling?
Well, well, well.
Are you ready
for your big day,
young lady?
You've got
the whole family here.
Yeah.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
- Hello, Sam.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- I'm doing well,
how are you?
(COUGHS) I'm good, really.
So, when is
the little one due?
ZACH: One month.
- One more month.
- One month. That's good.
ZACH: Are you all right?
MR. McCALL: Do you want
a bottle of water?
No, I'll be fine.
One month.
That's the home stretch,
right?
ZACH: Yeah.
- (COUGHING)
I've just got
something in my throat.
I'm so sorry.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
(CHOIR SINGING HYMN)
I think that's
the nicest procession
I've ever seen.
Boys and girls,
we are so proud of you.
And we are so happy...
to have you here this
morning on this big
important day in your lives.
...newest members
of our church
to gather round
for the Liturgy
of the Eucharist.
We are here to celebrate
with you today
your first Holy Communion.
Also, the first time...
you receive our
Lord Jesus Christ
into your souls.
Uh...
(COUGHS)
Excuse me.
Uh, this sacrament...
(COUGHS)
(GUESTS MUTTERING QUIETLY)
It is a sacrament...
(COUGHS)
(ALL MURMURING)
MAN: Father Thomas,
are you okay?
(COUGHS)
Where was I?
(CHOKING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
He needs help!
ZACH: It's okay, Father.
Go call 911.
Thomas, Thomas.
ZACH: Hey, whoa, Sam.
- Hey, hey! Stop, Sam.
- (GRUNTS)
Look, it's me.
Hold on. Stop. Stop!
- All right.
Hey! It's okay.
- (GRUNTING)
SAMANTHA: I don't remember
what happened back there.
With Father Thomas.
Did I...
Did I do that to him?
What? No.
(SOBBING)
- Hey.
- (SNIFFLES)
What the fuck
is wrong with me?
ZACH: Hey, hey! Stop, Sam.
Look, it's me.
It's Zach.
Hold on. Stop. Stop!
- All right?
Hey! It's okay.
- (SAMANTHA STRUGGLING)
Zach...
ZACH: Let's just go.
Let's just go home.
FATHER THOMAS: Oh, I am
so sorry. Where was I?
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(REWINDING)
FATHER THOMAS:
Jesus Christ into your soul.
(REWINDING)
(CHOIR SINGING HYMN)
(MUSIC PLAYING BACKWARDS)
Born from death.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZACH: Look at this little guy.
SAMANTHA: Hey, little guy.
Yeah, I hear it.
No, Zach, come on.
These men are staring at me.
ZACH: What?
SAMANTHA: I said, "These men
are staring at me."
Hey, babe,
let's put it away.
(MAN CHANTING IN LATIN)
(MEN CHANTING IN LATIN)
(MAN WHISPERING IN LATIN)
(OTHERWORLDLY ROARING)
ZACH: Come on.
SAMANTHA: No.
ZACH: Yes. I'm sorry,
but we gotta get up.
SAMANTHA: Ugh.
I'm so hung over.
ZACH: Yeah, no kidding.
Hey, Mason,
it's Zach. Um...
Can you come over
for a little bit?
I need to talk to
you about something.
Thanks. And I'll meet
you outside, in front
of the house, okay?
I don't want
to bother Sam.
Okay.
SAMANTHA: (COUGHS) Mmm...
How did we get
home last night?
ZACH: I don't know.
The guy in the cab?
What the fuck?
He was like our cab driver,
on our honeymoon.
So I came home,
looked at all the tapes,
and there's all
this mystery fucking--
Look at this.
MASON: You sure, man?
Maybe it's some weird shit
they do down there
to scare tourists.
Whoa, what the fuck?
What the fuck?
It's gone.
(STUTTERS)
MASON: What are
you talking about?
I was literally just
looking at this shit
right before you--
I was looking at this
right before you came in,
and now it's gone.
It's empty. It's gone.
The fucking tape
is gone now.
- Fuck!
- Why don't you just
take a breath, man?
No, I don't need
to take a...
Wait, hold on.
What the fuck?
NURSE: We've been
monitoring him 24/7.
ZACH: Uh, do you think
I can talk to him privately?
NURSE: If he needs anything,
we'll be right outside.
ZACH: Father Thomas,
how are you?
I had a small stroke.
Yeah, we heard.
Are you gonna
be all right?
How is Sam?
Um, she's okay.
That's actually
why I wanted to...
I'm glad that
she's okay.
...talk to you.
Um...
I saw these weird symbols
on our honeymoon.
And, um, I just don't know
really what they are.
And I thought you might...
because everything
I've seen says they're,
uh, religious symbols.
So, uh,
there's these ones...
and then there's that.
There's a bunch more.
These are the only ones
I've actually seen in person.
The other ones were
all just linked to it
when I started looking.
John, first John.
What?
First John, 2:18.
"And children,
this is the last hour.
"You have been told
the antichrist is coming...
"and so, that there are
many that are coming.
"That is how we know
it is the last hour."
What are you
talking about?
These are from early,
early religion.
These are...
early religion,
there is a sect,
dissident.
They tried to bring
the church down
in its early days.
They did rites,
and they used
those symbols.
They painted them
on the point of entry
and on the nest.
The point of conception
and the point of birth.
ZACH: What?
So that he could get in.
There was ash all around.
There was ash everywhere.
The antichrist is coming.
"So will there be
many antichrists...
"and that is how we know
it is the last hour.
"They will be coming."
I didn't mean
to upset you.
- It's the last hour.
- I'm really sorry.
I don't think you can be
here with that anymore.
You have to go now.
- I need you to
go now, Zach.
- Yeah.
I'm very, very tired
and I need you to go.
- Put that away.
- It's gone.
I'm really sorry.
I didn't mean
to upset you.
You've upset me.
Just go.
- Go.
- I hope you feel better.
Now! Go!
- Okay, all right.
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
ZACH: Nurse?
Nurse, can you--
Um this one is from you.
This is from Emily.
(WOMEN CHEERING)
There's more to come.
That's just a taste.
EMILY: Whose is this one?
SUZIE: I don't know.
It doesn't have a name.
Does this belong
to anybody?
Well, anonymous.
SUZIE: It's nameless.
- Anon.
SUZIE: You're just getting
gifts from everywhere.
Sorry, whoever this is from.
Brooke!
- What a sweetheart, Brooke!
(WOMEN CHEERING)
I didn't read the note,
so, I don't know
what's happening.
BROOKE: That's nice of you.
EMILY: Sam, are you okay?
(GLASSES CLINKING)
ZACH: How was the shower?
SAMANTHA: Fine.
(DISTANT CLATTERING)
Did you hear that?
(ZACH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CAR ALARM
RINGING IN DISTANCE)
ZACH: Fuck.
Every window in the house,
but a lot of them in these.
This is really mostly
where I see it,
so I don't know what to do.
You know, I have to admit,
it is, uh, kind of weird.
Someone was in here,
all right?
Someone broke
into our house.
Wait, hold on a second.
But, look at the porch.
(MUFFLED CONVERSATION
IN DISTANCE)
I can file a report,
and call us if there's
any other problems.
That's all I can do for now.
You have a nice night.
(KISSING)
(SIGHS)
STEVE: Okay, here we go.
- Here he goes.
ASHLEY: You're gonna
break your neck.
JAY: Uh, uh, uh!
(ASHLEY SHRIEKS)
JAY: Oh, he got it!
No way!
Wow, I'm so impressed.
- What's up?
JAY: Take this.
I gotta take a piss.
Oh, fuck.
I'm out.
Do you want to come?
Will you hold it for me?
STEVE: No,
she doesn't want to.
Since Jay's gone,
do you want to...
JAY: Hey, guys!
You gotta come see this!
- What is he doing?
STEVE: Fucker.
You're fucking me up.
JAY: Look what I caught.
ASHLEY: What is that?
STEVE: Oh, fuck.
Dinner is served, y'all.
ASHLEY: Jay, stop.
- That is so gross.
STEVE: Oh, what in the fuck?
ASHLEY: Please,
don't touch it.
Oh, it fucking stinks!
- Hey, take a photo.
STEVE: I'm taking a video,
jackass.
ASHLEY: it smells like shit.
STEVE: Touch it,
see if it's still warm.
You guys, there is
something over there.
STEVE: You're so fucked up.
ASHLEY: Look!
Do y'all see that?
JAY: Shut up.
STEVE: What?
ASHLEY: Wait.
STEVE: Yo.
JAY: Hey.
ASHLEY: What is she doing?
STEVE: Ash, stay back.
JAY: Ma'am,
are you okay?
STEVE: What the fuck
is she doing?
(SQUELCHING)
ASHLEY: Oh, my God.
STEVE: Oh, shit!
ASHLEY: Ma'am,
are you okay--
(ASHLEY SCREAMS)
(STEVE GASPS)
What the fuck!
Run! (PANTING)
(JAY GRUNTS)
STEVE: Come on, man.
Get up!
- (SCREAMING)
What the fuck!
Oh, shit!
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
No! No!
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Oh, fuck.
ZACH: Hey,
are you all right?
Yeah, I'm good.
Actually, I feel
a little bit better.
ZACH: Good. Um...
Do you need anything?
No, I'm good.
Thanks.
Okay.
(SAMANTHA HUMMING)
(CLATTERING)
ZACH: Sam?
Sam?
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
Hey.
(HUMMING)
Sam.
(SAMANTHA CONTINUES HUMMING)
What are you doing?
Sam?
Hey.
What's going on?
Are you okay?
Sam, what the fuck
is going on?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
- (GRUNTS)
SAMANTHA: (SCREAMING)
Don't touch us!
Sam, it's just me.
All right?
It's just me.
- Stop, stop, stop! Sam!
- (GRUNTING)
It's okay, I think
you're dreaming.
Hey, stop.
- It's okay. It's okay.
(SAMANTHA PANTING)
ZACH: It's me.
No, it's me.
- (WHIMPERING)
ZACH: I got you. I got you.
It's me.
It's all right,
I'm right here.
See, see? Look,
it's just me. Okay?
Are you okay?
It's okay.
SAMANTHA: (TEARFULLY)
What's happening?
ZACH: Nothing.
You just had a dream.
(SOBBING)
It's okay.
ANSWERING MACHINE:
...the McCalls.
Leave us a message,
and we'll call you back
as soon as we can.
Hey, Dad, um,
it's Zach. Uh...
Look, I think Sam
and I need to come over
and stay with you and Mom.
Sam is really freaking out
and it's gotten me
really scared.
It's just not normal, okay?
And I know this sounds
really crazy...
but I swear, there have
been people watching us.
We just don't want
to be alone, okay?
I think we'd just
feel a lot better if we
were with you and Mom.
So, uh, call me back.
Fuck.
(PANTING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
ZACH: Hey!
Hey!
(MAVERICK GROWLING)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
ZACH: Hey.
- Hi.
Thanks for coming over.
Sam is upstairs,
she's sleeping.
Is she feeling okay?
ZACH: Yeah, she's fine.
I just need to take off
for a minute.
I didn't want her to wake up
and have no one be here.
Okay. Where
are you going?
ZACH: Just don't
answer the door.
Okay, bye.
Weirdo.
(ZACH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(OPENS FRIDGE DOOR)
(BOTTLES CLINKING)
(SNIFFS) Hmm.
(SUZIE HUMMING)
SUZIE: Sam?
- (SCRATCHING)
(FOOTSTEPS ASCENDING STAIRS)
Sam?
Hey, Sam?
Hey.
Sam?
Samantha?
(SCRATCHING)
(SCRATCHING CONTINUES)
SUZIE: Sam, Jesus!
What are you doing?
Sam, hey, hey!
Give this to me.
Stop, stop, stop.
Sam, stop.
- Give this to me.
- (SCREAMS)
Sam!
Sam, stop! (SCREAMING)
(ZACH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(SONG PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOG BARKING)
Fuck.
Shit.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(MAN CHANTING IN LATIN)
Fuck.
Fuck!
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN BLARING)
- Oh, shit!
(STARTS ENGINE)
OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
- I need some help.
Something is
happening to my wife.
Please, send someone over.
OPERATOR: What's the address?
- 901 Harrison Street. Please.
OPERATOR:
Sir, I'm sorry, I can't--
Shit.
What the fuck?
ZACH: What do you want?
- Leave us the fuck alone!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Sam?
Ah!
Fuck.
(GRUNTING)
Shit. Fuck.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Sam!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(RUMBLING)
What the fuck?
Sam?
Oh, Jesus. (PANTING)
What the fuck?
(CHANDELIER CHIMING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Sam!
Shit! Fuck!
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Sam?
Sam, what are you doing?
(SCREAMING)
What are you doing?
Stop, Sam. This isn't you.
Please. Please,
just come with me.
Please, let's go.
We gotta get--
(ZACH SCREAMS)
(COUGHING)
(GROANING)
Oh, God.
Suzie?
Suzie? Suzie?
Fuck. No, no.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Fuck.
Sam.
Please. It's okay.
Come on, please. It's me.
Come on. Just come
with me, please.
I'm sorry.
It's me, come on.
No! (SCREAMS)
No! Stop!
Please.
Sam. Sam!
Sam!
What are you doing?
Please, just let me down.
Sam! Fuck!
No! No, Sam!
Sam, no!
(SCREAMING)
Stop! Please stop, Sam!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
SAMANTHA: Zach?
- Sam.
SAMANTHA:  Zach.
- I'm here.
SAMANTHA: What happened?
What happened?
ZACH: It's okay, it's okay.
SAMANTHA: Is the baby okay?
Yeah. I love you.
Is the baby okay?
Yes, it's okay.
Don't worry, it's okay.
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
SAMANTHA: I'm sorry.
ZACH: No. I love you.
I love you.
I'm so sorry.
No, no, Sam.
Sam.
Sam, no.
Fuck.
(ZACH SOBBING)
Please...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
No. No, no!
Stop. Just stop, please.
Just leave us alone, please.
No, leave her alone.
Leave her alone!
(BABY COUGHING)
(BABY CRYING)
No.
(POLICE SIREN APPROACHING)
Don't, don't, don't...
No, no. No!
(SNIFFLES)
POLICE: So, what did you
do with the baby?
They took it.
And this is the same
"they" who killed your
wife and your sister?
You know, we checked.
The Anderson house.
(CLEARS THROAT)
It's been abandoned for years.
Completely empty.
And there's no Dr. Dylan
at Willow Oak or any other
hospital in the area.
Why don't you tell us...
what really happened?
Mr. McCall?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
WOMAN: Look at it. Oh, my God!
MAN: I got it, sweetie.
That's so amazing.
It's like a dream come true.
Okay, last day
of the honeymoon!
Au revoir, Paris.
All right, let's
do one together.
Can we come back
next year, baby?
We are gonna come
back every year.
Okay, good. Promise?
- It's been awesome,
hasn't it?
- Best trip ever.
I love you so much.
I love you.
WOMAN: Let's get a taxi.
- You got it.
- Perfect.
- Bonsoir.
You want a taxi?
Yes, please.
- Come, get in.
WOMAN: Okay.
CAB DRIVER: I take you
somewhere fun, eh?
WOMAN: Okay, yes.
CAB DRIVER: Authentic.
Outside the city, but...
MAN: All right, good.
WOMAN: Let's go somewhere fun.
CAB DRIVER:
It's first time here?
- Yeah, it's the first time.
CAB DRIVER:
And newlyweds?
WOMAN: Yeah, how did you know?
♪ Oogum, Oogum,
Boogum, Boogum, Boogum ♪
♪ Now, baby
You're casting
your spell on me ♪
♪ You got me doing
funny things like a clown ♪
♪ Just look at me ♪
♪ When you wear
your bell-bottom pants ♪
♪ I just stand there
in a trance ♪
♪ I can't move
You're in the groove ♪
♪ Would you believe,
little girl ♪
♪ That I am crazy 'bout you ♪
♪ Now go on with your bad self ♪
♪ Now mercy, mercy on me ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ When you wear
those big earrings ♪
♪ Long hair and things ♪
♪ You got style, girl
That sure is wild ♪
♪ And you wear
that cute trench coat ♪
♪ And you're standin'
and posin' ♪
♪ You got soul
You got too much soul ♪
♪ I just say who got the blues
Say who got the blues ♪
♪ Say who got the blues now ♪
♪ Castin' your spell on me ♪♪
(ONCE UPON A TIME PLAYING)
♪ Once upon a time
When I was in high school ♪
♪ I was in love with you, lady
And you treated me so cool ♪
♪ I was driving a Chevy '72 ♪
♪ It had four
on the floor, girl
120 it would do ♪
♪ And I remember Marvin Gaye ♪
♪ Singin' What's Going On ♪
♪ And there was a war, baby
Somewhere across the sea ♪
♪ I don't wanna go
and fight, girl ♪
♪ 'Cause you were
really lovin' me ♪
♪ I remember
Martin Luther King ♪
♪ Lord, he was the man, babe
That gave us all a dream ♪
♪ And I remember Marvin Gaye ♪
♪ Singin' What's Going On ♪
♪ Don't play with my love ♪
♪ And I remember Marvin Gaye ♪
♪ Singin' What's Going On ♪
♪ They used to have
sweet music in the park ♪
♪ Lord, up at Monterey
straight down
to the Melody Bar ♪
♪ You used to wear, girl
Them hot pants ♪
♪ When you strolled
down the hall
All the boys wanted a chance ♪
♪ And I remember Marvin Gaye ♪
♪ Singin' What's Going On ♪
♪ Don't play with my love, oh ♪
♪ I remember Otis Redding ♪
♪ Sittin' at the Dock
of the Bay ♪
♪ But then he went away ♪
♪ And I remember
Sam Cooke, y'all ♪
♪ So Bring It on Home to Me ♪
♪ From your love
I can't be free ♪
♪ I remember Elvis Presley ♪
♪ And them Blue Suede Shoes ♪
♪ Lord, they gave me the blues ♪
♪ I remember Marvin Gaye ♪
♪ Singin', yeah
Let's Get It On ♪♪