Melody of Love
Goodbye.
We'll never meet again.
Every day is a dream
I can't believe this is real
Every day
This feels like magic
I'm getting closer to you
Will you listen to my heart?
Wasn't that great?
Yeah.
I definitely saw an improvement.
Deulim's up next?
Begin.
Every day is a dream
I can't believe this is real
Every day
This feels like magic
I'm getting...
I'm sorry. I'll do that again.
That won't be necessary.
Let's give her another chance.
Deulim, whenever you're ready.
Thank you.
That won't be necessary.
Shouldn't we give her another chance?
We're in the middle of auditions.
She can rehearse as much as she wants,
but there's only one chance at auditions.
We're not here to give out free chances.
That's as far as she goes.
I guess we have no choice.
You're the last one, right?
Yes.
Good work.
That was really ruthless.
Let's go.
Get ready.
I'll be in my office.
You did well. Don't worry.
You would have gotten high marks if you didn't make that mistake.
What a shame.
That's okay.
You were great up there.
Really?
You amazed me.
Today I saw why you were the lead.
I don't know what to say.
Are we going out to dinner tonight?
Should we go?
You worked hard for the auditions.
Let's go.
Come join us.
Do you mind if I go home?
Did something happen?
You seem down.
I'm sorry I disappointed you.
If you want to become a successful musical star,
you have to let go of some of your other desires.
It's not easy to achieve your dream.
Don't lose focus in the next round of auditions.
You said you want to prove yourself.
Live up to that.
I will.
You'd be at the top if it wasn't for the mistake.
Thank you.
Go home and rest if you don't feel like joining the dinner party.
But promise me you'll do nothing but rest.
All right.
Suim.
Are you busy?
No. Come in.
Sit.
I heard you're having auditions today.
Were you worried about Deulim?
She wasn't feeling well yesterday.
I could tell.
Did she do badly today?
She made a mistake.
She did?
But she worked so hard.
Her throat wasn't in the best condition.
I was a little hard on her.
She might not get a part?
We're doing evaluations now.
I can't give you the results.
Oh no.
She has another round of auditions left.
She'll have to prepare herself.
Can she overturn these results?
We'll have to wait and see.
Everyone's working really hard though.
I didn't want to ask you this,
but can you help her out?
If she doesn't get a role,
I'll feel horrible.
Why should you feel guilty?
I told her to give up Hyeonu and focus on her career.
I felt so cheap saying that.
Do you think she gave up Hyeonu for you?
I don't know what she's thinking.
I can't tell if she knows the truth about us or if she's really tired of Hyeonu.
But there's no way to ask.
What'll you do if Deulim knows the truth?
And she gave him up for you?
I don't know.
I don't even want to think about it.
I thought she'd do well today though.
What if she can't win any roles?
I know how you feel but I can't do her any favors.
Deulim wouldn't want that, either.
Yeah. I was stupid.
Hyeonu would want to know the results, too.
You should call him.
Once the results are out.
Don't feel too guilty.
I know how hard this was for you.
Taegyeong.
This is so hard.
But I can't tell anyone.
This feeling
Is coming to me every day
Every day
Deulim.
Suim.
Why are you practicing again?
I made a couple mistakes.
There's another round.
Don't push yourself too hard.
What if you ruin your voice?
Why don't you rest today?
Were you worried about me?
I wanted to come to support you but I was too late.
I'm glad you didn't see it.
If you saw me make that mistake,
you would've been really upset.
Deulim.
Should we go have some fun?
We can watch a movie and go eat out.
Really? Okay.
Here.
That's okay.
Eat up.
You're trying to stay thin, right?
Yeah. I want t o look pretty.
It's been so long since we laughed like this.
Deulim.
I'm sorry I put you through a hard time.
I really am.
That's okay.
I'm the one who yelled at you without knowing how you felt.
I didn't want to do that.
I should have helped you.
I'm sorry I didn't.
Suim. I'm fine.
Can you really break up with that man?
You really like him.
Why are you mentioning him again?
He's the reason you didn't do well on your audition, isn't it?
It's not that.
I was overreaching.
It happens when dumb kids try to cram for an exam the night before.
I have such a positive personality.
Look at me, eating like this.
Eat up.
Don't worry about me.
And don't give up on that guy of yours.
Why does this taste so bad?
It's sweet to me.
Maybe you lost your appetite.
He's been like that ever since he went to the other dry cleaner's.
Why?
Did you go there to spy?
Yes, because we had no customers.
That place was crowded though.
It's probably temporary.
So don't worry.
You don't know how customers are.
That's the way it is with restaurants.
Even if the food is good,
they all go to the new place on the block.
We might lose money this month.
How will we fill the hole?
We might have to close down the shop.
What'll we do?
Do you have money for a new business?
We can't keep running at a loss.
Don't think that.
We've had that cleaner's for 20 years.
What else will we do?
Yes.
You should focus your energy into one project.
I'm home.
- Hey.
- You're home.
Did you eat?
Suim bought me a great dinner.
And we even saw a movie.
It's hard to believe you fought yesterday.
Their fights don't even last long.
That's how it is with sisters.
It's like cutting a radish with a knife.
Isn't it cutting water with a knife?
It's tough to cut a radish with a knife.
Why do you have to be so critical?
You don't have to be.
Everyone understood me.
That's true.
Didn't you have auditions today?
Did you do well?
Well...
My voice gave out in the end but
I can do better next time.
I knew it. You came home so late.
You weren't taking care of yourself.
Why don't you go rest?
Goodnight.
What is it?
I'm a little dizzy.
You have a fever.
What if you have the flu again?
Why did you stay out so late?
I'm okay.
Take her to her room.
Let's go.
She's upset over the auditions.
She won't get the lead?
Why didn't you come home sooner?
Why did you stay out in the cold?
I didn't know she was sick.
I would've brought her home.
I wanted to stay out late.
I'm okay.
Your father won't forgive you if you do this to yourself.
You have to take care of your health if you don't want him yelling at you.
Okay.
This looks like the flu.
Let's get her a fever reducer.
Go see a doctor tomorrow.
Okay.
I want to sleep now.
Why are you both giving me such a hard time?
I'll go get some medicine.
Who is that?
It's my friend.
Why is she calling at this hour?
Yeah, it's me.
This is Gu Sejun.
I know who you are, girl.
Why are you calling at this hour?
Your kids must be there.
Yes.
It's cold, so go inside.
May I ask why you called?
I wanted to hear your voice.
We used to talk as parent and teacher.
Yes.
It feels strange to talk to you like this.
Yeah, let's meet up sometime.
I'm a little busy these days.
Bye.
Goodbye, Jeongja.
Goodbye.
Who was that?
You scared me.
Don't you know how to knock?
I did, but you didn't hear me.
Who was that? The Witch?
No.
And stop calling her that.
Who was that?
You kept your voice low.
It must have been a woman.
Do you have someone else already?
It's not what you think.
I knew it!
I don't care who she is as long as she's not the Witch.
I told you not to call her that.
Mom says to come out and have some fruit.
I'm home.
Son, you're here.
Hi. I'm going to my room.
Taegyeong, come here.
What is it?
It's about Hyeonu.
Does he like someone else?
Who told you?
I guess it's true.
I told you!
Who is she?
Why do you want to know?
Don't fall for Suim again because of this.
I don't want you to be with her.
You don't know what might happen.
This is about pride.
You have to marry up.
To someone better than Suim.
I'll make her pay for what she did to you.
Why does your pride matter in this?
This is about his marriage.
His feelings are what matters.
I'm doing this for his own good.
Suim has to regret refusing him.
I don't like that you're saying this.
He's busy with his new performance.
Oh.
Did you set a date with Ms. An?
Yes.
It's next Saturday.
Listen.
I told you I'm breaking up with her.
For that divorcee?
Will you stop calling her that?
She has a name.
What is it?
How is her name important?
To me, she'll always be known as divorcee.
Honey.
She comes from a painful past.
That would be rude.
And it's common to get a divorce these days.
I wouldn't say this to anyone else.
But my own brother wants to marry one.
I can't help the way I feel.
It wouldn't be fair for Ms. An to keep seeing a shell of a man.
I'm not going to be with her.
You won't get away this easy.
You hear me?
You think you can be with that woman in spite of mom?
In high school, kids called me the Bulldozer.
I've still got it.
I can't wait to see you in action.
Is Hyeonu not going to give Suim a chance?
No.
But Suim liked Hyeonu so much.
Would it be okay if she came to you?
She's the one I like.
I don't care who she liked.
I care that I like her.
That matters more to me.
Suim's such a fool.
She doesn't know what she has.
I'm not coming back to the theater.
We'll never see each other again.
What's wrong, Deulim?
Did you have a bad dream?
Suim...
Are you in pain?
No...
- Breakfast is ready.
- All right.
Didn't Hyeonu come home last night?
He had some paperwork to go over.
He called to say he'll be working late.
Is everything okay?
Yes. Don't worry.
Why don't you go check on him later?
I'm going to take him a change of clothes.
I'll take that.
I'll drop by on my way to work.
I can go instead.
Let's eat.
Is Deulim up?
Didn't you see her leave?
Did she leave?
I thought she was in bed.
She was gone when I got up.
But she's not feeling well.
I'll stop by to see her later.
Okay.
Suim.
Yes?
Did you find out about the guy she's seeing?
No. I've been busy lately.
What if Deulim got sick from going on late night dates with that boy?
I don't think so.
She's been at the theater rehearsing for the auditions.
Okay. Get ready for work.
Okay.
You're here already.
Hey.
Didn't you go home last night?
No. I stayed here.
You slept here?
I had a drink.
And I didn't want to go home.
But you should have.
Your family must have been worried.
They'll only worry about me getting injured.
When my heart's already broken.
All this over a girl?
I feel so powerless.
I feel like a useless person.
Hyeonu.
Hello.
Dad.
Is everything okay?
Yes.
But you should sleep at home.
I brought you some clothes.
Change. I'll be outside.
Have a seat.
Is this hard for you?
Do you hate me?
I made you a lawyer when you wanted to get into musicals.
And I want you to marry Suim.
I know this may come as a burden.
But Hyeonu.
Yes?
When you become a father,
you want certain things for your son.
I wanted you to follow in my footsteps.
I wanted to validate my life that way.
Dad.
Which is why I was strict with you
every time you strayed from the path.
I don't know if that was hard on you
but I've always wanted the best for you.
You're to follow in my footsteps.
You're too young to know now,
but it's rewarding to live as a man of the law.
You'll find out soon.
You said you wanted to do just things.
Not everyone can practice that in society.
You were born with great character.
And you need someone who can
understand you and hold your hand.
That's how you can do the right thing.
But I can't be with Suim.
Try to look at her good qualities.
That's how you can approach her.
Dad.
Don't sleep out. Sleep at home.
Your grandfather will worry.
Are you leaving?
Yes.
He slept in the office last night.
He had a bit to drink so he felt sorry about going home.
There's a good place in this building that sells really good stew.
I'll get him some.
Try to be understanding of Hyeonu's behavior.
I told you this before but you're the only one who can help him.
Don't get weak.
Do you understand?
I'm sorry.
You trust in me
but I may not be enough.
Don't say that.
I wouldn't know how to face you.
Father.
Go back to work then.
Hello.
I need to ask you something.
I was going to ask to see you.
Have a seat.
Do you want something to drink?
Actually, I...
Tell me the truth.
Is Sejun seeing that woman he was with before?
Of course not.
That can't ever happen.
Why did Sejun say he doesn't want to see me anymore?
He's never had a real girlfriend.
He doesn't know how to express himself.
I thought that was it at first but I don't believe that anymore.
You know how a woman has a sixth sense.
Don't worry about that.
I'll drag him to the family meeting if i have to.
Just bring your parents.
Okay. I'll trust you.
Please do.
Sejun! Just wait till we're married!
I'll get you for this!
I'm sorry I have to keep saying no.
That's okay.
I have 97 times left.
Sejun.
Ms. An.
Hello.
What are you doing with Sejun?
Ms. An, I...
No other reason.
We were discussing my son.
Is he in trouble?
He's not getting into trouble anymore.
He's behaving well now.
Goodbye.
What's left?
What did you mean by 97 times?
Yes, I...
You're not in...
She didn't borrow money from you, did she?
What?
I don't know what that means.
Where were you?
I was with your sister.
I told her everything.
That's fine.
You can do whatever you need to do to make yourself feel better.
Do you promise?
Yes.
All right.
I'll see you on Saturday.
Oh, I meant excluding that.
This is the information on the theater Sanghyeon wants to purchase.
Let's look it over.
They made almost no money last year.
I didn't think the finances were this bad.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to ask you something.
Do I have to excuse myself?
No, it's about Sanghyeon.
Sit.
What about him?
I heard he's about to buy a theater.
You're advising him?
Yeah.
You know what that theater means.
How can an investment company but up a theater like that?
But you two are helping him with the acquisition?
Yeah.
The theater has no other options.
Even if they need the money,
you can't ask them to change the CEO and the whole cast.
How can you be the face of this?
I worried about that, too,
but I decided to do as Sanghyeon wants.
That's all I can do.
Hyeonu.
If I say no to this,
Sanghyeon will go to another lawyer.
And he'll get what he wants.
The outcome will be the same regardless.
How is that the same?
You'll feel horrible after this is over.
Horrible?
Will that change anything?
Even if I feel guilty?
This isn't right.
I have a headache.
Let's go have a drink.
Again?
It's still light out.
I thought we were done for the day.
You should go too.
Want to go?
I have work to do.
Then let's go.
Why do you look so awful?
I'm fine, so don't worry.
Give the acquisition another thought.
Or just walk away.
I have to take this so I can give more benefits to the theater.
Drop this.
How did the auditions go?
Fine...
I guess Suim didn't tell you.
She told me to tell you.
What?
Deulim made a mistake.
Mistake?
She wasn't feeling well.
And the results?
Her scores were the lowest.
How can it be that bad?
Everyone else worked hard.
Oh.
She told me she'd do well.
She came today but
she seemed really weak.
This is Deulim Cleaner's.
Who?
I've been telling myself I should apologize after what happened at the family meeting.
Don't worry about the past.
I taught Suim myself at the judicial institute.
I see.
She has a great character.
She was flawless.
I could tell she grew up well.
Thank you for saying that.
I've always kept one eye on her.
And I learned that she and my son went to the same college.
I knew this was meant to be.
I want Suim to be my daughter in law.
Let's be in-laws.
I know you're fond of my girl.
I wanted to thank you for being so kind.
I'm sorry this is coming so late.
But a marriage can't happen because the parents want it to.
There are a lot of problems.
I know you're very disappointed in my son.
But Suim's so strong.
If we're patient enough,
I know this will end well.
I don't know.
I don't want to tell my daughter to be patient any longer.
Sir.
A marriage isn't easy, even if the kids like one another.
Which is why...
I don't think I can tell my daughter to marry your son.
Please.
Sir, please be patient with us.
I'm sorry this had to end.
Excuse me.
I said I'd never see you again but I came back. I'm drunk.
Don't drink.
Deulim.
Can't we be together?
Don't you think you can fight this with me?
You said you'd trust me.
You said you'll stay with me.
You said you won't give me up.
Don't.
Why are you doing this?
I didn't want to see you again but I couldn't help it.
I feel like if I drink again,
I'd end up here again.
What is she doing in the street?
Don't do this. Go home.
Deulim?
Subtitles by KBS World