Should have stayed in Missouri.
You shut up with that.
You wanted to come.
I say we do it now.
I don't like it, neither.
But we about run out.
She didn't want her boy to starve.
It ain't your place.
It's already decided.
We can always go back.
Fine.
Then I'm doing
what I goddamn got to do.
Be strong.
She's in heaven.
Pop, I'm hungry.
Not too deep.
Come on.
How is he?
What you'd imagine.
How long are we supposed to wait?
He'll be back. Maybe with food.
We wait.
How long?
As long as it takes.
I ain't talking to you!
Hey! We got to stick together
and think smart,
or we'll everyone of us be dead.
Shut up, old man.
Donner?
George, is that you?
You're still here.
- You made it.
- Lucky me.
I knew you would!
Jed.
Got overrun by Indians.
It was a massacre.
Dead, all of them.
I barely made it out.
The four of us are it now.
Find a way out of the valley yet?
Donner, you son of a bitch,
you said stay with the damn wagon.
Easy, boy.
Maybe this will put you in a better humor.
Got me a raccoon.
Can you believe it?
George. George!
I'm going to make you last a while.
He killed them all.
Ate them alive.
Donner party... the whole thing...
it wasn't an accident.
George Donner brought them up
there on purpose.
There's an ancient curse
in those mountains.
If you eat human flesh...
living, human flesh...
something comes into you, you turn.
You absorb their life-force.
Then you need more.
You crave it.
Donner had already been turned.
He had the hunger.
They say he's still up here.
Still hunting.
Okay. So if I cut my finger
and you sucked my blood...
No, I might have to take a nibble.
Okay. So you ate my finger,
then you would turn
and absorb my life-force?
We're not in Donner country yet.
So I guess you'll have
to wait for me to eat you.
Gross! Thanks for the visual.
You do know in reality,
George Donner died that winter, right?
I mean, most of them actually survived.
But they didn't kill anyone on purpose.
And definitely nobody got eaten alive.
How do you know? Were you there?
I did a report about it in the 8th grade.
You know, a lot of people
up here believe that legend.
They think Donner's real.
Sure. And half the people
in Iceland still believe gnomes.
Okay. Now, we're talking about gnomes?
This conversation
is officially really stupid.
Music. Music's a good call.
Where are the CDs?
Under the seat.
Bear repellant?
My dad makes me carry that.
I guess you might run into
a bear out on the slopes.
Well, it works just as well
on carjackers and assholes.
I guess I'll have to behave myself.
I guess so.
Why are we stopping?
Deer and Ale.
Oh, God! I hate that place.
Since when?
Your parents always stop here.
It's tradition.
Exactly.
I've been wanting to do that for two hours.
We're finally getting our weekend.
Didn't I tell you
I would make this happen.
Well, you have to give Thomas
a little credit for inviting us up.
I do. You're right.
My God, best ribs ever!
Jesus, get a room.
I don't think they make enough
napkins to deal with this,
so I'll be right back.
How's everything here?
Couldn't be better.
Great.
Where do I know you from?
Maydo High, right? You went to Maydo.
No.
Sorry.
Just holler if you need anything.
Bored?
No.
Do you snowboard?
Ski. Cross country, actually.
Really? I love cross country.
Yeah, all those people
on the slopes, it's just...
Sometimes when I'm on a lift
and I'm looking down,
and they look like ants,
I think, what it would be like
if they actually had to hike up
before they could ski down.
There would be, like, four people,
which I'd like a lot better.
Yeah. Me, too actually.
Should we sing "Kumbayah" now?
Oh, wait. Better...
you guys sing,
and I'll go to the bathroom.
I'll go with you.
Thomas.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nicole's a bitch, okay?
Everyone knows it.
I don't know how Kayley deals with her,
even if they are cousins.
Look, you just got to put her
on the payroll.
What?
Put her on the payroll.
See, after this weekend
at your cabin, she'll owe you.
At Woodside,
it's all about who you know.
Knowing her is a good thing.
You don't even have to be friends.
Just let the situation work for you,
and then she's on the payroll.
You know what I mean?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so.
Trust me, I transferred in here
two years ago myself.
I know what it's like.
Watch and learn, grasshopper.
You have to be nice to him.
I'm being nice.
Look. I'm only here so your
parents would let you come.
Come on! Be fair.
I went to fucking Cabo
with you for a week,
and I didn't tell your parents
or my parents anything.
You had fun.
No, you had fun.
I got to hold your hair back
from the toilet.
You owe me, and you know it.
Fine.
He's a loser.
Just treat him like a human being.
That's not too much to ask.
Man, what's up with this traffic?
Hey, Thomas, can you see
anything out your side?
Close the window! It's freezing!
There's a chain control stop up ahead.
Ever put on chains before?
I have. I can help.
Sweet. I got to wiz.
So how long have you known Mike?
Gosh. Known him?
A year and a half, I guess.
We've been dating for, like, three months.
Cool.
What?
Nothing. I just didn't know
you guys were together.
He didn't mention it?
Nah, he just said he had
a friend with a car.
Are these them?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Whoa. Let me put them chains
on for you.
60 bucks will get you going
right quick.
60? It's usually 40 tops.
It's a bad night tonight. I'll go 50.
Thanks, but I'm good.
You know, most people,
they'd rather stay
in their cars, heater on...
especially with the recent trouble.
Yep.
A gal showed up dead here
a week back. No shit.
Saw her picture in the news and all.
Cops is looking for a guy.
They say it's for questioning.
Do you want to know what I think?
I think he...
Hey. How's it going?
I was just telling your friends
here to watch out.
A gal got offed here last week.
Oh, yeah? Maybe Donner got her.
Was she eaten?
Where'd you hear that?
That's kind of what I heard too.
I got a buddy who knows the coroner.
Said it was like some kind
of animal attack.
Insides gone, body all chewed up.
She was probably alive for most of it.
But you can't believe
everything you hear.
Y'all have a safe night now.
Asshole!
Locals love to freak out
the weekend crowd.
Holy shit!
James Michael Epstein.
"Mr. Epstein is wanted
for questioning
"by the Truckee county sheriff's
department in regard
to the disappearance of
Ms. Rita Hill, 42, San Mateo. "
Let me see that.
This is right near our place.
Hey, buddy I got those for you.
80 bucks ought to get you
on the road right quick.
Come on, let's get this done.
Let's do it.
Okay. Which way up here?
I'm not sure.
You don't know how to get
to your own cabin?
My dad always drives.
Don't touch me!
Sorry. I didn't mean to.
Whatever.
Just don't fucking touch me, okay?
Nic...
What? He was leaning on me.
I'm sorry.
Okay, so it looks like
it's a left on Evergreen Gap
and then your third left onto Toland.
And then we're 1683.
It's the second driveway
on your right past the gate.
What are you doing, Nicole?
Sexting with Derek?
Shut up, dickwad!
Wow! This is your cabin?
Holy shit!
Where's the butler?
I'm sorry.
Could you not do that? We just...
we need to not get into everything.
My parents don't know we're here.
Okay. Fine.
Yeah, I like this one.
You think?
Chicago?
New York. It's New York.
Okay, guys. History for a pie piece.
"Name the California oil scandal
that resulted
in the indictment
of the Secretary of the Interior. "
Teapot Dome.
How did you know that?
That's why he's my partner.
The boy's got a memory like firetrap.
Is this the only thing there is to drink?
I'm not going to make it
through this game sober.
My parents keep some liquor
downstairs.
They don't really drink much.
So... maybe we could
just have a little.
They probably wouldn't notice.
No complaints here.
What do you want?
Can I see what there is?
Yeah.
So what do you drink?
I love vodka.
Do you have any mixers?
Oh, my God!
What if it's his parents?
He'll be grounded for life.
He said they're in Europe.
Thomas!
What's going on?
Your neighbors?
We don't have neighbors.
We should lock the door.
Babe!
Oh, shit.
Can't believe you made it.
Come on, ass-hat!
Jesus Christ! Would you guys stop?
Motherfucker!
Tap out!
All right.
Fuck!
Tap out means stop, meathead.
Why did you bring them?
You said you were bored.
So I brought the party.
All right, I got to take a piss.
And it's fucking dire.
And that's the only reason
I let you win, you bitch.
Blow me.
- This okay?
- Hey, so...
Mighty Mike, how's it hanging, bro?
Hey, Kayley.
Mike.
Hey, Derek.
Brody, grab the beer.
What the hell?
Look, I didn't
invite those guys. Just Derek.
Thomas said no one else.
He's my boyfriend.
This is not what we talked about.
I told you even four people was too much.
It's okay, Thomas. I'll handle it.
Hey, everybody.
Look, I know you had a long
drive, but... I'm sorry.
You can't stay here.
Thomas said we could only have
the four of us up here.
I guess Nicole forgot that or something.
I'm sorry.
Too late. The road's closed.
Dude! I got piss all over me!
AJ, I swear to God!
It's just water, baby.
Never know with you.
Brody.
What's up?
Kayley wants us to fuck off.
What?
Thomas can only have
the four of us up here.
I'm really sorry.
But you guys have to leave.
Mike, buddy,
what's up with this?
Thought we were bros.
Well, if the road's closed...
You want us to die out there
in the cold, Kayley?
It's not that. I like you guys.
You know that.
It's just we made a promise.
- To who?
- Thomas.
Who the fuck is Thomas?
This... This is Thomas.
Thomas...
AJ, Valerie, Brody, Derek.
This is Thomas' place.
I mean, it's his parents' place.
Sweet place, dude.
You, uh, mind if we crash.
What about you, Mike?
You telling us to fuck off too?
That'd hurt my feelings.
I mean, where else are they going to go?
Well, all right.
Thanks, Mike. Thanks, Tom.
Val, you get your fat ass downstairs.
- Fuck you!
- Exactly.
So what's the deal tonight?
Dude, the payroll.
Just like I said about Nicole.
After this,
these guys will be your friends.
And you want that.
Just roll with it.
This could be the best thing
that ever happened to us.
I mean, to you.
Okay? Just take it easy.
Anything goes wrong,
I'll take care of it.
What's up, man? Nice sweater.
What, did you steal that
from my grandpa?
This is my room.
Dude, chill. One dude doesn't
need a bed this big, okay?
The two of us though...
we'll use it.
You know what I mean?
Be careful with the drinks, all right.
My parents don't know we're here.
Oh, shit! Watch the beer, bitch!
Didn't you hear the man?
You ducked, pussy. Drink.
No way. That was interference.
She came out.
- Drink, bitch!
- Let's ask the judge.
Mike, your call.
You're the judge?
Snowball was unobstructed.
Throw counts.
Fuck you. I can out drink
all you bitches anyway.
Derek, you're up man.
Let's see how you do.
What was I saying? Yeah.
The dude that killed that chick,
fucking rail on him.
Even kill him.
Who's going to say shit?
Fuck yeah. Beat his ass.
Then turn him over to the cops.
Who are they talking about?
The wanted guy from the flyer.
Epstein. Whatever his name was.
Fuck yeah. Cave his teeth in.
Use this.
Throw it.
Sure, hold on.
Ready?
Fucking serious.
Throw it, hard as you can.
Dude, do it. Nail him.
AJ, shut up!
What if I hit you?
Then I'm going to walk over there
and beat the living shit out of you.
Come on, you pussy. You scared?
Guys...
Dude, do it. Knock him out cold.
You better hope it does.
Brody, you could fucking take him.
No. Brody's big,
but he's a fucking coward.
Aren't you?
Guys, seriously.
Do it!
That wasn't even fucking close, man!
The master plan.
Easy tiger. Drink up.
Who's next? Mikey. You're up.
My God! Mike, don't.
Fuck it, why not?
AJ, this guy's a rookie.
Fuck yeah. It'd be my pleasure.
All I have to do is not duck.
No movement of any kind.
Mike, AJ's a pitcher. He's going...
He's drunk.
Nothing to worry about there.
Bottom of the 9th.
Bases loaded, full count.
Pitcher looks.
Likes the sign.
Wind up.
Pitch.
That is the fucking game!
Fuck! That hurt.
- AJ...
- Did you see that?
That shit was fucking epic.
AJ, drink.
What? No, fuck you. He flinched.
No, he did not flinch.
Drink. Nice, dude. That's balls.
No, no, no. Wait. No, no, no.
Fuck that.
I hit him right between
his fucking eyes.
I know. But he's not
a pussy like you. So drink.
Fuck you!
Did you see that?
Hit the fucking tree
from 40 yards, bitch.
What was that?
Excuse me.
Would you mind not doing that?
When the snow melts, there's going to be
broken glass everywhere.
Maybe you guys should come inside.
Thomas. Thomas, all right,
you got to understand
something, man.
There's two things I really like...
drinking...
and fucking people up.
And we're almost out of beer.
No, shit.
Brody, do you think you can make
a run to that 7-Eleven for a refill?
Dude.
- Not a problem.
- Thanks.
Guys, Thomas is right.
Maybe we should call it a night.
Look, we'll clean up the bottles. Cool?
Go inside. Relax.
You guys are being assholes.
I'm going to bed.
Are you coming?
Brother's chilling.
Just opened a fresh beer.
Yeah. I'll be up in a little bit.
Right. I'll see you in the morning.
Thomas?
Can I come in?
Hey.
So I just wanted to say sorry
about downstairs.
And I know this wasn't the way
that the weekend was supposed to go.
So I'm sorry.
That's okay.
It's just...
your friends.
Listen, Thomas,
Woodside messes with you.
I don't know if it's all
high schools or what.
But it's like everyone has an agenda.
And it's okay if you don't have one.
But if you can't deal with the fact
that everyone else does,
then... it...
It gets really lonely.
Yeah.
Well, anyways,
maybe we can still get
to the mountain tomorrow,
let some people burn off
some steam on the slopes.
Yeah. Maybe.
Get in the Brody-mobile, bitch.
Go get the fucking beer!
Fuck you!
Go get the fucking beer, already.
Fine!
Pussy!
Kayley, you asleep?
Kayley?
What are you doing in there?
I got my own room.
Why?
Obviously there's other things
you'd rather do than hang out with me.
Oh, no. Come on.
I was just being friendly.
Yeah. Well, tell that to Thomas.
You should really go talk to him.
He'll be fine.
Mike, he invited us up here.
He's your friend.
I hardly know the guy.
What is wrong with you?
Kayley, wait. What are you doing?
I thought we came up here
to be together.
Yeah. That's what I thought too.
Fuck me.
That adds up to nearly
25 inches in the mountains.
You'll want to check with the slopes
before you show up.
Some may have closed for the day.
The weather report...
I can't believe you let him go.
Well, I'd like to see you
try and stop him.
You try calling?
That's a great idea.
That never occurred to me.
Except for the fact that
his cell phone has no bars
and, apparently, Thomas' parents
can't afford phones.
What's going on?
Brody's missing.
Christ, he's not missing.
Party people here ran
out of beer last night.
And he drove out to get some.
He's not back.
He's probably stuck in town.
20 bucks says he's
banging some local chick.
Or stuck on the side
of the road somewhere, freezing.
Where's Nicole?
What the hell do you care?
Still downstairs.
How far away are the neighbors?
We could use their phone.
It's a few miles.
You'd have to go back to the main road.
Well, I think we should
go look for him.
Anyone care to join me?
I will.
Mike?
Sure. Okay.
Brody?
This will take hours to dig out.
Yeah.
Let's at least make sure
he made it to the end of the driveway.
Nice place the little prick's got.
Did I tell you I found a liquor cabinet?
Give me another hour.
Then we'll hit it.
I'm going to go get dressed.
I can't believe she can still
walk after last night.
What about you, Derek?
You get some action last night?
No.
I haven't been able to start
shit for the last two weeks.
I mean, wasn't great before.
But... fuck!
Derek?
Can we have a talk?
Yeah.
Did you sleep okay last night?
Pretty well. A little cold.
I would have kept you warm.
I bet.
I'm not a bad guy, Kayley.
Yeah, well, not being a bad guy
is not the same as being a good guy.
Guys...
Shit!
What the hell was your problem?
You remember AJ's party
two weeks ago?
The one you couldn't make.
Yeah. So what?
Oh, my God.
Brody!
Has he said anything about it?
Like it never happened.
Who else knows? Cops?
No. No one else knows.
Derek! Easy!
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
I wanted to forget about it.
I'm going to fucking kill him.
I know.
Oh, no, no. Jesus...
Oh, my God!
What the fuck happened to him?
A bear?
Bears are hibernating right now.
We got to call 911.
Shit! Maybe we can hike
up there. Get reception.
It's a longer hike than it looks.
We need to get back and tell everyone.
I'll go.
I don't think that's a good idea.
We stick together. Come on.
We can't just leave him here.
Hey! Where you two been?
D, try this. It's good shit.
So guess what we found.
I can't believe we didn't see it last night.
What?
A fucking hot tub.
You guys in?
I didn't bring my bathing suit.
Bingo!
Geez, it's okay. Fine.
You don't have to go skinny dipping.
Okay. On 3.
1, 2, 3.
Feel nice?
Yeah.
You want to know something
that's gonna feel even better?
Come here.
Actually, baby, just...
just give me one second. Okay?
I had a lot to drink.
I got to go empty out, okay?
Wow. That's so hot.
Way to kill the moment.
Get comfortable.
I'll be right back.
Don't you go nowhere.
I'll piss our initials in the snow.
God... gross.
I told that guy.
Seriously.
V. Capital A.
You ready for some action?
Valerie?
Jesus Christ, someone help!
She's dead!
Somebody help!
Shit!
Somebody fucking help me!
Holy shit! Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ! Holy shit!
What happened?
I don't know. I don't know.
I said, what the fuck happened, AJ!
Oh, my God. Valerie...
Everybody...
Don't touch me.
Listen! Brody's dead too.
The same way, but worse.
I don't know.
Maybe there's an animal, a bear.
L... I don't... fuck!
Okay. Okay.
We got to get everyone inside.
Get this place locked up, all right.
Oh, no. Please, don't. No.
I'm not fucking leaving.
Come on! Come on!
I don't want to leave.
Nice place you got here.
Tell them what you told me.
I was taking a piss, and she was alive.
Then I turned around,
and I swear I saw...
I thought it was my imagination at first.
- But then I saw what...
- Bullshit!
- Derek.
- You son of a bitch...
I what? I what, Derek?
Things like that don't just happen.
Exactly.
You must have seen something
or heard something.
I didn't hear anything.
But I think I saw...
I think I saw someone.
A person?
Oh, my God. What if it's
that guy they're after?
The guy on the flyer.
What did he look like?
I don't know.
He was...
Oh, shit! We got to get
the fuck out of here!
Get the fuck away!
Everyone, stay calm.
It's him.
It's him. I know it.
What? Who?
Donner.
Jesus Christ.
This is what happens.
Locals, they talk about it.
The half-eaten bodies
like an animal attack, but worse.
Thomas, that's a campfire story.
No. It's not.
Then who is it? The guy Epstein?
You think he could do that to Valerie?
You think he could take down Brody?
It doesn't matter who it is.
We can handle this.
We just need to dig the car out.
Right. Good.
We're all in this together.
Right, Derek?
We have a few more hours until dark.
Do you have snow shovels?
In the garage.
We need weapons. Do you have a gun?
Knives, axes, baseball bats.
Anything that would hurt,
that would slow him down.
Great. We're dead.
How's this?
That's good.
Now, we're talking.
I want to be the one to kill him.
Oh, shit.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
What?
The tires are slashed.
Okay. I've triple checked the doors.
They're all locked.
- We should sweep the house.
- Lock the windows.
Pull the blinds down.
We'll take the bedrooms.
You stay upstairs.
Where are the phones, Thomas?
Why don't your parents have phones?
My dad... he says he comes here
to get away.
He doesn't want to be reached.
They don't have one handset
somewhere for emergencies?
I can look.
Okay. AJ, you and I will take the back.
Derek, you stay here.
What?! No!
We need someone to watch our backs.
He's bait.
Okay, baby?
Fine.
After you.
Who's this, Thomas?
Your mom?
That's a family friend.
All right, next window.
There's something I want from you.
What?
I want you to ask for my forgiveness.
For what?
For what you did to me.
At your party.
I'll be right back.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I think you do.
Look. I don't remember
anything from that night, okay?
- So...
- You do.
I was super drunk, and so were you.
You know.
I don't remember it.
Look. Put that down. Just talk to me.
It's just the two of us.
We've been friends
for a really long time.
If you ask, I'll forgive you.
But if you don't...
Look.
Whatever happened...
Tell me why.
Tell me why you did it.
I just...
couldn't help myself. Okay?
Look. I'm sorry.
Okay.
Don't move.
Why?
I don't want to get blood on me.
This is far enough.
Whoever's out there
is going to come after AJ.
And the rest of us can go.
They're going
to ask what happened.
So?
Sorry, buddy.
You brought this on yourself.
Poor baby.
No, please. Please!
No, wait! No!
He's taking him.
You ready?
AJ, no!
Oh, my God!
AJ, what are you doing?
Come back!
What's happening?
AJ, he went out there.
He saw the guy,
and he took off after him.
- And you let him go!
- Are you crazy?
Derek tried to stop him.
He said he was going
to kill the guy.
He said help him
or get out of the way.
So you got out of the way?
Fuck you, Mike.
You would have done differently?
Yeah. I would've.
I'm not like you. I'm not an asshole.
What was that? I didn't catch that.
Get in my face and say that.
Guys.
We need to go after him.
Fuck that.
No. We need to get out
while we still can.
In the dark? And leave AJ?
AJ could be dead or close to it.
If the killer has him,
that gives us time.
No! We get him back.
No!
Fuck AJ.
He made his choice.
Not our problem.
- I'm with you.
- Me too.
AJ, are you out here?!
Wait.
He was bleeding
when he left the house.
There's two sets of footprints.
It's like something's been dragged.
Look. Changes direction here.
That...
That must be where...
There's an old shed about
100 yards through those woods.
Thomas, you okay?
I don't trust them.
We need to get AJ.
You go back.
Keep an eye on Derek and Nicole.
Can you handle them?
Yeah.
Good. Lock the door.
Hey, Derek, Nicole.
What do we do if he's there?
Hey, we do what we have to, okay?
I didn't want to say anything
with everyone else here.
But my parents keep
a snowmobile out back.
Ready?
Is he dead?
Yeah, he's dead.
Watch out!
Mike!
You're okay. You're okay.
You did it.
Shit! What do we do now?
I'll take care of it.
Go back and tell the others it's over.
"Made in China. "
Epstein.
Thomas, Derek, Nicole, let me in!
We got him. We got Donner.
Hello?
Hey, why is the door unlocked?
1683 Toland.
Shit!
Kayley! Kayley! Derek!
Anybody!
Nicole?
Thomas?
Thomas, what's going on?
What are you doing?
The flesh has to be living
for it to do me any good.
So I have to keep you alive.
I'm sorry.
This way, more blood stays
in your heart and brain.
Jesus...
Thomas, no.
Thomas, let me go.
I'm your friend.
Talk to me.
We'll get help for you.
I'll get help for you.
Nobody can help me.
Mike! Help!
Help me! No!
I think he has his hands full.
Nicole!
Mike, help me!
No!
Mike. Mike, it was him.
Thomas did all of this.
Mike, help me.
Cut her down.
Mighty Mike.
I don't understand.
Kayley was right.
Donner died a long, long time ago.
But legends are funny things.
Just lying there,
waiting for something,
someone to make them believe.
I created a new Donner.
I always do.
Can I help you?
I'm sorry to bother you, sir.
I'm just out cross country skiing,
and I've run out of water.
Do you mind if I fill up my canteen?
No. Sure. Come on in.
I gave Epstein the hunger.
His girlfriend...
fought it as long as he could.
But the hunger... it always wins.
So...
Brody?
First one's always mine.
Then I let Epstein out of the shed.
Just like a magic trick,
the key part is distracting the audience.
We kill Epstein and then
I finish the rest of you.
That was supposed to be it.
But what Derek and Nicole
did to AJ...
there needs to be some justice.
Nicole, she didn't fight it.
Didn't even try.
When you first get the hunger,
you're like a wild animal.
And all of the civilization
gets stripped away.
So it was all you.
Me?
It was your idea.
I barely mentioned the cabin,
and you were talking about
your friend with a car.
I just followed your advice, Mike.
Put you on the payroll.
So I guess I owe you. Leave now.
Head south over the mountain.
Eventually you'll hit Highway 80.
What you do then won't matter.
Or you can stay and die.
Mike, please help me.
Mike! No!
Let's start.
The first few winters were hard.
I lived like an animal.
With each passing year,
this place grew less wild.
And so did I.
Found an orphanage.
And then foster parents.
I went to school.
And as long as I came back to feed,
I hardly aged.
Practically couldn't be hurt.
It's easy...
new school, let's go camping.
Let's get a houseboat. Let's go skiing.
There's plenty of great getaways
in Donner country.
Don't worry about Mike.
He won't make it.
I always save one to hunt.
You don't have to do this, Thomas.
I know there's a good part of you.
Don't you get it, Kayley?
We all become the thing we hate.
No.
You can choose.
You can't choose not to be hungry.
This will sting.
So will this.
Go!
Mike! Mike, watch out!
Please, don't do...
Fuck you!
Okay.
Upstairs. Phones. Phones.
No! No! No!
I know. Me too.
Going to be a short trip.
They're going to take you into town
now for an examination, okay?
One thing, though,
you said there were two bodies
in the cellar?
Yeah.
Because we only found the one.
What?
Don't worry.
I'm sure it will turn up.