STUDIO 2.0 presents
In Association with
KTB and KOFIC
A Film Dorothy Production
October, 1979
This footage is
a record of the brain surgery
performed in 1942
on General Hirai
of the Japanese army.
Dr. Kim Dong-Won
performed the operation,
being the best neurosurgeon
respected by the Japanese
medical society.
That's all for today.
JIN GOO
As I mentioned before,
today's footage
will be on the test.
DONG-KYU LEE
If you weren't paying attention,
get help from my assistant.
KIM TAE-WOO
Tell your friends at the protest,
they'll be failing for sure...
KIM BO-KYUNG
...if they miss next week's test.
It's Dad.
Let's have lunch together.
Oh, already?
Are you busy?
Dinner?
No, it's okay.
I can take care of myself.
Don't come.
Stubborn girl.
The desk?
Yes, what is it?
It's really my old album.
They found it at Anseng Hospital?
After all these years?
When are they tearing it down?
The hospital.
Oh, tonight.
Since it's the weekend.
All right.
See you at home, then.
Okay.
Directed by Jung Brothers
You should get anything
you left inside.
After tonight,
it will all be gone.
Are you lonely, Dad?
Huh?
Of course not.
The coffee tastes good.
Dad.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
You know Stepmom
had heart problems
even before the marriage.
Yes, but your mother and all...
Mom passed away
while having me.
Stepmom had a chronic disease.
Neither was your fault.
It's just...
...they both passed away
like that,
within less than a year
of marrying me.
Dad!
I know. I know.
I'll be back
from the in-laws' tomorrow.
Then I'll stop by
with some food.
Don't come so often.
I can just hire help.
Otherwise, I'll miss you too much.
I'll come by again with Yoon-Hee.
That was the last time
I saw my daughter.
I thought
I would forget with time.
I had lived a quiet life.
I see that those four days
37 years ago
had made my life
an endless nightmare.
On that night,
I died.
EPITAPH
In February 1942,
just as I began
studying medicine,
the Japanese attacked
Pearl Harbor,
and imperialism was at its peak.
But inside Anseng Hospital,
it was as quiet
as the eye of a storm.
Do ghosts really appear
in the mirrors?
Sure.
Staring at mirrors in the morgue?
Scary.
But you better not
break that mirror.
- Why?
Hey, the rounds.
Let's go.
Lucky bastard.
What?
While some of us
stay up for weeks,
someone's going
to sit back and relax.
But sure, you're
in high society now.
Keep your voices down.
Jung-Nam Park.
You're on morgue duty
this whole week.
- A week?
The refrigerating system is faulty,
so make sure to check it often.
- Lucky.
- Congrats, Jung-Nam.
Director's orders,
so don't fuss over it.
Yes, sir.
Aoi is back from Tokyo.
I see.
Do you remember her?
Only that I saw her
when I was young.
Right.
She's all grown up now.
She's grown so beautifully.
My husband and your parents
would have cared much for her.
I'm just sorry
that they couldn't see
two such fine young people marry.
I'm always thankful for your care.
Taking me in
after my parents passed away
and supporting my education.
I only did
what I thought was proper.
I truly think of you as my own son,
and not just
because of the betrothal.
Thank you.
I know it seems a bit rushed,
but we should have it in Spring.
I'd like for you two
to marry right away,
but it will take some time
to prepare things on our side.
Anyway, that's my decision.
Yes, Ma'am.
AUTOPSY LAB
Time of death
was about 30 hours ago.
Judging by the odor, isn't it longer?
But, of course, you must be right.
A soldier was killed
while delivering documents
from Busan to Seoul.
The body was mangled,
but the papers left untouched.
Who in the world
would do something like this?
What was the motive?
He's only been
in Korea for one week.
Dr. Kaneda,
I'd like a word with you.
A Japanese soldier was murdered,
so the press will be determined
to get any information out of you.
Therefore,
don't comment on anything
in front of the reporters
besides your medical opinion.
I'll handle the difficult questions.
As I mentioned before,
the victim was stabbed
by a sharp and long metal object.
Doctor!
What led the killer
to mangle the body?
Looking at how the body
was stabbed
many times
after the victim had died,
it seems the killer may have had
much hostility toward the victim.
That student will need time
to get used to autopsy.
By the way, are you ready
for your first lecture?
Everyone says
they're a tough crowd,
worse than us back in the day.
I'm so tired.
How's autopsy?
I threw up everything
I ate this morning.
Wimp.
We've all been there.
Never mind that.
What's with the murder case?
Guys, another body just came in.
Anyone seen it?
Another one?
The teenage girl?
So you saw it.
This girl's body just came in,
all frozen up
like a piece of meat.
I tell you, it's perfect.
This one is a real looker.
Almost like an angel
fallen from heaven.
Put the mirror away.
The door left open,
and the bodies
still lying around...
Jung-Nam Park.
Yes, sir?
You're scared,
aren't you?
No, sir.
Clean these bodies up
and put them in.
Yes, sir.
Those chemicals will spill over.
Line them up right.
Yes, sir.
Don't waste time
doing stupid things.
GHOSTS
Professor.
Then does that mean
you believe that ghosts exist?
Don't you like the ring?
I used to have one like this.
A keepsake from my parents.
But I lost it last year
while moving to Seoul, like an idiot.
To be honest,
I never thought
of becoming a doctor.
You see, I liked to draw.
In a few months,
I'm marrying
the director's daughter,
and I've never even met her.
When I look at you,
you just look so happy.
It's like your best years
have been sealed forever.
ANSENG HOSPITAL
Why are they coming out
in this weather?
Why not? It's snowing.
It's nice.
Idiot.
That's strange,
isn't it a bit late for snow?
Jung-Nam!
Why didn't you bring
your dead friends?
Man, I just love blackouts.
Please...
Don't let them fix it,
just for one night!
Hey, the lights!
Damn it.
No!
I'm sorry.
Jung-Nam!
Leave us at least
a few bottles to use!
Jung-Nam Park, are you okay?
Yes, sir.
She needs to realize
it's not her fault.
Then she'll come
to accept her parents' death.
I'm sorry, sir.
Let's try medications
and psychoanalysis treatment.
Yes, sir.
Jung-Nam?
Here you are.
I was looking for you.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Yes, Ma'am.
They still haven't found the body
of the man
she committed suicide with.
It took over four days
just to search.
How cold she must have been...
Anyway, what was the time
when you were born?
Oh, about 2 a.m.
On June 3rd, 1920.
I see, 2 a.m.
That was why I came to see you,
but here I am rambling on.
What's that sound?
It's so creepy.
Who is sobbing
at this time of night?
It's coming from the funeral home.
Where did the drawing go?
I don't know
how to thank you, Sister.
Am I being greedy
by marrying her dead soul
to his living body?
Perhaps so.
But I can't let her soul reunite
with the man that made her die.
This child was brought in
two days ago,
after barely surviving
a car accident.
What's wrong with you?
Get over here and grab her!
Come on!
Look for injuries!
Yes, sir!
2 days ago
Hold her down!
Poor girl.
She has to survive,
at least for her mother's sake.
That's her mother?
Yes.
There aren't any injuries.
It's like a miracle.
A miracle?
What is?
She survived without even a bruise
in a crash
that took her whole family.
They say life is up to fate.
Things aren't always
for us to decide.
There it goes again.
Mommy?
If she wasn't hurt at all,
then why the nightmares
and aphasia?
Just seeing her parents die
is enough shock for a little girl.
And she was the sole survivor,
which might make her feel guilty.
Mommy.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Since it's your first day,
we'll stop here.
Asako.
Can you remember
what you told me?
It's okay.
When I was five years old,
there was a deserted house
a few blocks from my house.
My brother and I went there
to take some eggs
that a pheasant had laid
inside the well.
He told me to stay back,
but I didn't listen
and leaned over,
and I fell down the well.
It was deeper than I thought,
and the water had all dried up.
I kept crying and calling for him
because my right leg was hurting.
He tried to climb down a rope,
but he fell in, as well.
I was so scared,
but he kept telling me
that we were sure to be rescued
and not to worry.
I did what he said
and survived on eggs and water.
And just like he had said,
people came to rescue us.
But they said
that he was already dead,
still holding on to my hand.
People still say...
...on that night...
...he was the reason I survived.
I know what you're going through.
I was in that place before.
Try to feel better, Asako.
Everything will be fine.
Koshiro?
Koshiro!
Koshi...
From now on,
you should call me Dad.
- Hurry up, Han!
- Yes, sir!
Asako.
Let's have one more talk together,
and you won't have
nightmares anymore.
It's just like yesterday.
Okay.
Just relax.
Don't worry.
I'll be right here, next to you.
Right now,
you're going to meet that man.
The man that you love.
Let's go now
to the time you first met him.
Over there.
Asako.
It's your new dad.
Let's say hello.
I'm Koshiro Onji.
It's nice to meet you.
I love you too, Koshiro!
I love you too.
Asako, you should call him Dad.
I'm going to sleep with Koshiro.
Stop fooling around, Asako.
Koshiro is driving.
That's enough.
Sit down.
I wish you would just go away.
Asako, come on.
What are you doing?
Why do you get to sleep with him,
and why do you get to love him?
I hate you! Just go away!
I'm going to live with Koshiro!
Asako!
It's...
It's all my fault.
It's not your fault, Asako.
The emotions
trapped in her subconscious
have been brought out and resolved.
She also has regained
her consciousness.
I think I've done everything I can.
Ma'am?
I see.
That's good to hear.
Good work.
Asako's mother
can rest in peace now.
Please take care of her
from now on.
I am counting on you.
Yes, Ma'am.
You'll be okay now, Asako.
I'll finish up my rounds quickly,
and then I'll stay here with you.
Everything will be fine, okay?
She was fine just a minute ago.
- Any emergency measures?
- Done, sir!
Go on ahead!
Doctor!
- Get a syringe ready.
- Yes, sir.
Asako?
Asako! Come back!
Open your eyes! Asako!
Mom...
It's okay.
It's not your fault, Asako.
Doctor.
Asako!
Sir!
She's gone.
You did your best, sir.
They say death heals all wounds.
In that last moment,
what could have given her
such peace?
Perhaps Asako
had stayed a bit longer
in order to find that peace.
AUTOPSY LAB
3 days ago
Time of death
was about 30 hours ago.
A soldier was killed
while delivering documents
from Busan to Seoul.
The body was mangled,
but the papers left untouched.
Who in the world
would do something like this?
What was the motive?
I still didn't know back then
the fact that my wife
didn't have a shadow.
That student will need time
to get used to autopsy.
By the way, are you ready
for your first lecture?
Everyone says
they're a tough crowd,
worse than us back in the day.
In those times,
all scientifically
inexplicable phenomenon
was accounted for as superstition,
but with various
cultural characteristics.
For example, in the East,
being haunted
or possessed was actually
a cultural interpretation
of multiple personality disorder.
What about the ghosts
in haunted houses?
It's an interesting question.
Ghosts.
They're believed to be
the souls of the dead.
A western scientist
did something interesting,
where he attempted
to weigh a person
just before and after death.
You would expect
the weight to be the same.
But oddly enough,
there was a minute difference
between the two measurements.
Based upon the result,
some people say
that this difference
is the weight of the soul.
It's certainly difficult
to explain scientifically.
Professor!
Then does that mean
you believe that ghosts exist?
Well, probably not the ones
in haunted houses.
Like most of you,
I haven't actually seen them.
However,
I would like to believe
that we have souls.
It would be too depressing
if we didn't.
Wouldn't you agree?
It was a Korean soldier
that escaped four days ago.
It's the same as the previous cases.
Yes, both the weapon and method.
He was just a child.
A serial killer
after Japanese soldiers...
Until the investigation progresses,
please keep this case quiet.
You too, Jung-Nam.
Yes, sir.
Jung-Nam!
Why didn't you bring
your dead friends?
Someone made some rice snacks.
Try some, Doctor.
In-Young,
did you go anywhere last night?
Pardon?
Never mind.
Did you have any strange dreams?
I'm so tired these days.
I can't remember how I got to bed,
let alone my dreams.
Do you like it that much?
These two,
don't they look like us?
When we're outside in the garden.
I'll say.
Even the streetlight looks the same.
Hold on.
Honey?
Wait.
Just stay still.
Honey.
Walk slowly towards me.
You...
In-Young.
One year ago,
In-Young died in Japan.
How could I have forgotten?
And...
How can she be standing before me?
Dear, don't ever leave me.
I'll be with you even after I die.
Can you promise me
that you'll never leave me?
Why would I ever leave you?
I'll stand by you,
even in the afterlife.
In-Young.
Don't do it.
I know...
...that you're in pain.
But...
...we were always together.
Stop now, honey.
I'll take care of this.
Give that to me.
Now!
In-Young!
No!
Nurse Choi!
In-Young.
Do you like it that much?
What's on your mind?
I was waiting for you,
worrying if you had left me.
In-Young.
Let's go back to Japan.
Your arm...
What happened?
Why are these cuts?
In-Young.
Major!
It's a nurse from Anseng Hospital.
Why did the killer leave her body
on such a busy road?
In order to conceal it, of course.
It was dark and foggy that night,
and if you're in a hurry,
this may look like quite a cliff
when looking down from up there.
But...
...why is it a nurse this time?
Since it wasn't a Japanese soldier,
maybe someone copied
the serial killer.
No.
It doesn't look different to me.
It's the same killer.
It was next to the body, sir.
Was the Korean soldier
wearing a jacket?
No, he wasn't, sir.
This is Dong-Won Kim
from Anseng Hospital.
I'm the culprit
of the recent murders.
Please come and arrest me.
- If Kim shows up, keep him here.
- Yes, sir!
You're sure it was Dong-Won Kim?
Yes.
Let's go.
It may be hard to understand,
but there are two people inside me.
Dong-Won Kim and a murderer.
In short,
the culprit
of the recent serial killings
is me, Dong-Won Kim.
Dr. Dong-Won Kim?
Furthermore,
do not believe anything I say or do.
I state again, the serial killer...
...is me.
Go and search the hospital.
I will go meet Dr. Kaneda.
Yes, sir.
Dr. Kaneda.
What brings you here?
I guess Dr. Kim isn't in?
He hasn't come home yet.
He's running late today.
I see.
How long have you two
been married?
Almost a year now.
I see.
Come in and have a seat.
I'll get you a cup of tea.
Insane.
Completely insane.
Doctor.
Yes?
I've heard that back in Japan,
Dr. Kim...
Yes, the culprit got away.
Send somebody
to Anseng Hospital now.
Yoshida.
Yes, sir!
Gather up all of the patients.
Who else is in the hospital
right now?
The patients
and the director...
One intern went to do an autopsy.
Autopsy?
Yes.
What in the?
Nurse Choi!
I never ordered an autopsy.
Damn it!
What's going on?
Woo-Shik!
- It's Dr. Lee!
- Doctor!
What happened?
- A hit and run.
- What do we do?
None of the doctors are in.
Get him to emergency.
Jung-Nam, get the director.
Okay.
Aoi.
I already miss you so.
I love you.
Ma'am.
Put it down.
Put that knife down now!
I said, now!
Major.
Please make me stop.
In-Young, my dead wife,
is inside me.
Please.
Please, just stop me!
You're not Dong-Won Kim.
Your husband
died last year in Japan!
He's just a false image
you created!
You are In-Young Kim!
They're believed to be
the souls of the dead.
However, I would like to believe
that we have souls.
It would be too depressing
if we didn't.
Wouldn't you agree?
Give it up now.
Stop!
How lonesome...
I haven't seen you ever since.
But I know that you
were always by my side.
Tell me.
If you were going to leave me
all alone,
then why didn't you just
take me with you that night?
Back then, we believed
everything would last forever.