I can do it.
Go away.
Hey.
No, you...
leave me alone.
Come on, come on, come on.
Get off!
I'm going to do it.
I'm going to it.
Gonna do, do, do it.
You're just cheating now.
No, I'm not.
I can win this.
Not you.
You're a loser.
Ugh.
Goal!
Yes!
How about it?
Shall we play another game?
I'm sick of you
and your childish games.
You're just scared of losing.
Come on.
No.
I'll just play by myself.
# Looking back on days #
# And speaking up for more #
#'Cause lights go down
as people get wiser #
# Just remember #
# In the nighttime #
# It's the right time #
# As the ceiling
hits the floor #
# It's the season #
# I got no reasons #
# Are you feeling insecure? #
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
Well, look, I'm just getting
through the door.
So, yeah, if you just give me
five minutes,
I can email it to you.
Okay.
Yeah, okay. Bye.
Hi, love.
Hey.
Finish the article?
More or less.
And you?
So-so.
We still need more tests
for the new drug.
More tests?
Poor little guinea pigs.
Done your homework, you two?
- Yes.
- Mm.
How's the hand?
Does it still hurt?
Are we still sulking?
What's the problem?
It's because of that concert
she wants to go to in London.
Emma, I've already
told you once.
That evening, I have to stay
late at the lab,
and your father has a meeting
at the magazine.
We need you
to take care of Mark.
Again?
Yes, again.
I can take care myself.
That's enough of that,
thank you.
Besides, you're still too young
to be going to concerts.
Alex and Rose are going,
and they're nearly
the same age as me.
Two years older is not
"nearly the same age."
You know, instead of thinking
about going out so much,
you should try
studying a bit more.
I don't care
what your cousins are up to.
I know what's best
for you, okay?
But, Dad...
You know what,
you never let me do what I want!
Yes! Got it!
Please stop playing
with that game?
Emma, stop shouting.
You know, if you want something
just say.
Stop bawling
like a five-year-old.
I thought their heads
had dropped
and they'd conceded,
but they've come back strongly.
Penalized for that challenge.
Emma!
Emma.
Lucy!
I don't know what's happening.
Call an ambulance.
Come on, quick!
Um, yeah.
I need an ambulance.
My daughter, she's having
a fit or something.
Yeah.
Emma Evans.
Mum.
Have you and Dad
had a chat yet about
what we said
about secondary school?
Yes.
And?
We both think
it's still too soon.
Probably next year.
But for the moment,
the important thing is
that you get better.
Okay?
Hey.
How's my favorite sister?
Mm.
So... any news?
No. John's talking
to the doctor now.
Oh, here's Dad now.
Hi, Chris.
Well, it's good news.
All the tests
have turned out negative.
Hmm?
And?
I find this incredible,
but they don't seem
to have the slightest idea
what caused the attack.
So what are we
supposed to do?
Nothing.
Just wait and hope
it doesn't happen again.
And how are you feeling, Em?
Emma.
I'm fine.
Don't worry.
God won't let anything bad
happen to you.
I'm going to get
another drink.
Chris.
I know Emma's been
to see you
several times this year,
hasn't she?
Yeah, she helps me out
in the canteen.
Why?
Has she ever said that she was
depressed about anything?
She's a teenager.
She just wants to go to school
like everyone else.
But... you know that.
Lucy, maybe we're making
a big mistake.
What do you mean?
It's only natural
that Emma wants
to be with kids her own age.
Oh, John, we've talked
about this over and over again.
You know the statistics
as well as I do.
Kids who study at home start
college much better.
Emma isn't a statistic, Lucy.
She's our daughter.
And she is just... she's just
not happy at the moment.
When she's older,
she'll thank us for everything
we're doing for her.
You'll see.
Drive safely, darling.
Do you hear me?
Yes, Mum.
Don't worry.
Hi.
Hey.
How'd you get on
at the doctor's?
Fine.
It was nothing in the end.
- Great. That's good news.
- Hi, Emma.
Hi, Auntie.
You missed one
hell of a gig, Emma.
So shit they wouldn't
let you come.
Your parents just need
to chill out.
Are you okay?
Sorry.
My mum's crazy.
She treats me as if I'm
the same age
as my spoilt brother.
Well, you two, I'm off.
When I finish my exams,
we'll have another party.
Take care, yeah?
All right.
You be nice to Mum.
Yeah. See you in a bit.
Emma, what are you doing
out here?
They're waiting for you inside.
Come on.
Okay, yeah. Okay.
Okay.
Can I have your French homework,
please?
Oui, professeur.
Oui professeur.
Fine, Mark.
Emma.
Why isn't it finished?
Emma, you can't keep using
the excuse of your hand...
I have to go
to the bathroom.
Sis?
Haven't you been taught
to knock?
The door was open.
It's my fault, then,
I suppose.
Well, what is it now?
You were writing
on the mirror,
and your eyes were...
It freaked me out.
Oh, get lost, you creep.
Happy birthday, cous.
I have a little prezzie for ya.
Enjoy.
Emma?
Yeah?
I need to talk to you.
Can you come down to my study
for a minute?
Yeah, I'm coming.
Emma.
What's wrong?
What?
If I tell you, you have to
promise you won't tell Alex.
Yeah.
My parents are taking me
to see a psychologist.
Is that all?
Emma, loads of kids at my school
see psychologists.
It's fine.
But the thing is,
the guy that they're sending me
to see is, like, a freak.
Why?
He hypnotizes people.
What if I tell him about
all the dodgy stuff I get up to,
and I don't even
realize it, like?
Look, we can easily find
a solution for that,
if you want.
All right, well,
I'm just going to dim
the lights a little bit.
There.
That's much better.
Good.
Now we can start.
Now, if there's anything that
you don't want to talk about,
you're under no obligation
to do so.
What I want is that
you feel relaxed.
All right.
Your parents tell me
that they teach you at home
but that you would
really rather go
to the secondary school
with teenagers your own age.
Is that right?
Yeah, that's right.
Are you comfortable?
Yeah.
Your hand...
does it hurt?
Not anymore.
Exactly what happened?
I slipped in the bathroom
and knocked over
the mirror and cut my...
cut myself with it.
Emma?
Emma, are you okay?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Good.
Now, what I want you to do
is to concentrate
on my finger.
Okay?
Concentrate.
Look at my finger.
Look at it.
That's it.
Start relaxing.
Your heartbeat slows down.
And it's slowing down.
That's good.
Your arms are heavy.
Your eyelids are heavy.
Your heart is slowing.
Good.
Your arms are heavy.
You need to sleep.
Good.
Would you say
that you are happy, Emma?
Have you ever
taken drugs, Emma?
Have you had sex yet, Emma?
Do you do everything
your told, Emma?
Emma?
- Emma, wake up.
- Emma's not going to wake up.
How are you doing?
What happened today,
it wasn't your fault.
You know that, don't you?
If you want to talk about it...
or anything...
But, Emma, your voice.
The guy had a heart attack
because of what you said.
You went straight
for the jugular with him.
I was under hypnosis.
I... I don't remember anything.
Anything?
Oh, Emma.
Good.
Would you say
that you are happy, Emma?
Have you ever
taken drugs, Emma?
I have no idea what I did.
And what, you think I can kill
someone just by talking to them,
even with that voice?
What, so it's just
a coincidence, then?
Is that right?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, that's right.
Oh!
What are you doing?
- Oh.
- What are you doing?
I think I pressed
the wrong button.
Emma, you've deleted it!
What have you done that for?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
For God's sake.
Emma, what are you doing?
I said I'm sorry, Rose.
I've got class.
I'll talk to you later.
Do you want to try?
No. I'm okay, here.
Dad, what's wrong with Emma?
Nothing.
She's fine now.
She's acting weird.
You wait till
you're a teenager.
You'll be just as bad.
No. I won't be like that.
Well, we'll see, won't we?
Emma.
What happened, sweetheart?
It's fine.
Emma, Emma.
Everything's fine.
It's fine. It's fine. It's fine.
Okay?
It's fine.
Everything's okay.
Everything's fine.
Hi, Emma.
It's Christopher.
Listen. Your dad called.
Seems he and your mum
are really worried.
Are you okay?
Look, there's nothing wrong
with me, all right?
Okay.
But if you do want to talk
about it, anything at all,
just call me, okay?
Anytime.
Yeah, okay.
Bye, Uncle.
Bye.
Creator of Heaven and Earth
and Jesus Christ.
Father Taylor.
Stop this now!
This has gone far enough.
Do not allow...
No vuelva a acercarse a ella.
The decision has been taken.
Emma, your breakfast is ready.
Mum,
it's just that the other day,
when I saw Uncle, I...
I remembered
what had happened.
Hasn't he ever spoken to you
about it?
No, not much.
I've only heard him say that
he misses being able
to say Mass.
Yeah, he went through
a really bad time.
Do you think that girl
was really possessed?
The Devil doesn't exist, Emma.
The girl was very ill.
That's all.
So it was all his fault, then,
that she died?
No, I didn't say that.
In his way,
Christopher did everything
he could to help her.
Mark, are you going
to be long?
I need to come in.
I'm in the bath,
and I haven't finished yet.
Just let me in for a second
to get something.
Wait until I say so.
Okay.
Let's see how ticklish
you still are.
No, no, no, no.
What's wrong?
No.
Don't do that to me!
You know I don't like it!
I'm sorry.
No! Go away!
Hi, darling.
Are you okay?
Hey.
What's wrong?
Oh, darling,
what's the matter?
Emma?
Emma, are you there?
The number you have reached
is currently unavailable.
Please try later.
Miriam, what can I get
for you?
A bit of everything?
How are you, Rufus?
Hey. I believe you.
Or at least I believe
you believe it all to be true.
Look, Emma.
Carrying out an exorcism
is a very serious business.
To start with, I'd need
the permission of my diocese.
And even if I asked them,
they'd probably refuse.
The communion of our saints.
Forgiven us of sins.
The resurrection of the body
and life everlasting.
Is that because of what
happened to that girl?
You just don't want
to help me.
No, no.
I do. It's just...
All right.
You have to trust me.
Okay?
Here.
Take it.
Ugh.
All right.
It's all right.
It's all over now.
It's all over.
Are you okay?
Now do you believe me?
Yes.
Do your mum and dad
know you're here?
No.
Look.
Because of your age, I can't
help you without their consent.
But if you tell my mum,
she won't let me do anything!
You know that.
Yeah.
I'm not lying.
It was the night
of my birthday party.
We played on the Ouija board.
We wanted to invoke the Devil.
What did you want
to do that for?
I don't know.
But the important thing is,
something evil entered me
that night.
I'm just...
I'm just frightened
it's gonna force me to...
To what?
To harm myself.
Or Mark or you both.
No, I'm sorry,
but I don't believe it.
I can't accept it.
- But, Mum...
- Your mother's right, Emma.
It doesn't make sense.
We are looking for another
psychologist to treat you.
That's what you need,
not a priest.
Oh, and there's something else
we've been thinking too.
We would prefer you
to carry on studying at home,
but, if you like,
then next year,
you can go to the same
high school as Rose.
So aren't you pleased?
Yeah.
I'm just tired.
Oh, Spirit, if you are there,
give us a sign!
Fuck.
Are you moving it?
You prick.
Ooh, I am the Devil.
That was funny.
We have to take Emma
to the hospital again.
What we should do
is call Christopher.
No way.
He's the one who put all this
into her head
in the first place.
I shouldn't have let Emma go
and see him so often.
What we believe is irrelevant.
What's important is
that Emma believes it.
Just listen to me
for a second, will you?
You've said it yourself:
placebos work because
the patients believe in them.
Well, getting Christopher in
to do an exorcism
just might be the placebo
that Emma needs.
What the hell
are you talking about?
You know full well
it's not the same thing.
Look, we have to do something.
I'm too tired for this.
Good night.
Shit.
Listen. I think
your parents are right.
Emma, evil spirits
only exist in films.
You're just scared.
That's your problem.
No, I'm not.
For God's sake.
What then?
You think I'm mad too, do you?
No.
I think that your uncle
the priest
has been putting these
crazy ideas into your head.
Emma, Catholics really get off
on all that Satan crap.
It's your dad's fault
for marrying one.
Ugh. My mum doesn't even
believe in God.
Mm.
Well, all of her family
are Catholic,
so she's got it in her blood.
So have you.
Oh, look.
It's going to be fine.
Emma, you're gonna be fine.
Look, don't be silly.
It's fine.
Okay?
Don't be silly.
I knew you were a dyke.
- No, I'm not.
- Oh, yes, you are!
You're just
a dirty little bitch,
a dirty little dyke!
You're a cow!
Rose, what happened?
No! Fuck off!
Please, Rose, please.
I didn't mean to. Please.
No, don't fucking touch me!
Ow.
Oh, my God, Emma.
I'm so sorry, Emma.
Emma, you're bleeding.
Emma, I'm so sorry.
Get away!
Rose, go!
Rose, go! Go!
Emma, I'm so sorry!
Hi, Alex!
Hey, I've been talking
to Rose,
and she told me
that you had a row.
What about?
Didn't she tell you why?
No, not at all.
She won't say
a damned thing about it!
Come on.
What's it all about?
Uh, it's nothing.
It's a stupid thing.
It's not important.
Look, I finish my exams
in a couple of days.
Let's meet up
and talk about it, yeah?
Yeah.
Can you get a move on
with those carrots?
Mmm.
This is going to be yummy.
How long has it been
since we last cooked together?
Hmm?
You loved to help me out
when you were a kid.
Making cookies
was your favorite thing.
You used to eat half of them
before they'd cool down.
I thought you were
playing football.
No. Dad told me
to come in here,
or I'd catch a cold.
Oh. Well, go on,
get the dishes, then.
Well, if you'd rather do
the cooking,
I'll make the table.
Bowls or plates?
Plates.
Mum! Mum!
God! Emma!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
What's the matter?
Stop it, Emma.
Stop it.
What's going on in...
I don't know.
Hold her by the ankles.
Watch she doesn't kick out!
Sweetheart.
It's all right.
it's all right.
You're okay.
You're all right.
Everything's fine.
Everything's gonna be okay.
All right?
Chris, it's John.
I'm calling because...
could you come over
to the house when you can?
It's about Emma.
You.
You have to help us, Chris.
I have a couple
of ground rules.
Firstly, I'll need to stay here
until Emma is well again.
If something happens,
I don't want to be
two hour's drive away.
Mark's room's free.
You can sleep there.
We've sent Mark
to your Auntie Sarah's.
And we're going to give
the classes a rest for a while.
All right?
Second rule:
no questions.
I'll only tell you
what I think you need to know.
And of course you can't take
part in the exorcism sessions.
The Devil is a very good liar.
My faith may help me
to distinguish
between the truth and lies,
but without faith,
it's too dangerous.
And no one must know I'm here,
not even your sister Sarah.
Emma, have you talked to Alex
or to Rosie about
what's happening to you?
No.
Good.
Let's keep it like that.
You can go to bed now
if you like.
We'll start first thing
in the morning.
Best if you're not tired.
Good night.
Oh, there is one more thing.
I'd like to record
everything that happens
in the exorcism sessions.
If the diocese gets wind
of what I'm doing,
I want them to know
that I had a good reason
for disobeying them.
I think that's a good thing.
All right.
That's it, then.
We start tomorrow.
Are you sure this
is what you want, Lucy?
Don't worry.
God never abandons
anyone to evil.
Everything's ready.
There's nothing
to be scared of.
You probably won't remember
any of it afterwards.
Please, sit down.
Don't worry.
This is just so that
you can't harm yourself.
Put your foot down.
Holy water.
The circle is to prevent
the Demon
from using you to harm
anyone outside it.
Of course, if I'd been able
to get the support
of the archdiocese,
we'd be doing this
on holy ground,
which is where the Devil
is at his weakest.
But don't worry.
This circle should hold him.
Uncle.
In nomine
lesus, exorcizo te.
In nomine lesus,
dice nomen tuum.
In nomine lesu, si es hic,
manifesta te.
In nomine lesus,
exorcizo te.
dice nomen tuum.
In nomine lesu, si es hic,
manifesta te.
In nomine lesus,
exorcizo te.
dice nomen tuum.
In nomine lesu, si es hic,
manifesta te.
In nomine lesus,
exorcizo te.
dice nomen tuum.
In nomine lesu, si es hic,
manifesta te.
In nomine lesus,
exorcizo te.
dice nomen tuum.
In nomine lesu, si es hic,
manifesta te.
Away from me,
ye wicked.
I will keep the commandments
of my God.
Hold thou me up,
and I shall be safe.
Yea, my delight shall be ever
in thy statutes,
for they imagine but deceit.
In the name of the Father,
in the name of the Son,
in the name of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
How do you feel?
I can't remember anything.
But I'm just really tired,
and my whole body hurts.
Don't know.
What happened?
That's between
the two of us...
and God.
Bu...
this is all absurd.
I mean, there must be
a non-theological reasoning.
I've heard priests say
that the Devil is only
a metaphor for evil
and not something real.
Unfortunately, the Devil
doesn't need bishops
to believe in him
in order to exist.
And in Jesus Christ...
Father Taylor,
Stop this now!
Ana.
Dime algo.
We are taking Ana away.
This has gone far enough.
Please.
The decision has been taken.
Sofia, es demasiado pronto.
Por favor, no se la lleve.
Piense en su hija.
No vuelva a acercarse a ella.
Padre, no deje que me lleven.
Padre.
Oh, Lord, please help
this innocent girl.
Do not allow a victory for them.
Do you think
I'm going to die too,
like... that girl?
Ana wouldn't have died
if they had allowed me
to finish what I started.
Okay?
Uncle,
There's one thing
that I haven't told you,
and I think
it's probably important.
But you have to promise
that you won't tell my parents.
Of course.
Get to your room!
In nomine lesus,
dice nomen tuum.
In nomine lesu, si es hic,
manifesta te.
How long do you think
you'll be?
Great.
Yeah, all right.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Look, uh, I'll see you
in a few minutes.
Okay. Bye.
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
No one is listening to you!
John, no.
It really hurts, Dad.
Can you ask him to untie me?
This is madness.
Listen to me.
You heard her.
For pity's sake,
you're hurting her!
You don't understand.
That's not Emma talking!
Get off me!
Thank you, Daddy.
You're so helpful sometimes.
Do you love me, Daddy?
Dad?
Do you love me?
Tell me you love me.
- I love you.
- Release him.
I command you:
release him immediately!
Oh, You bastard!
Release him immediately.
Fucking priest!
You understand now
why I told you to stay out?
That thing inside Emma
is a supremely skilled
manipulator.
You must never trust him.
Ever.
I can show you the videos
I've recorded.
No.
It's no longer necessary.
Look, it's best that Emma
never knows what happened today.
Okay?
Yeah.
And if you
still don't trust me,
I can put you in touch
with another priest.
No.
I'm sorry I didn't
believe you earlier.
Please help her, Christopher.
Help her.
Alex.
Hey. You here already?
Hi, John.
Have you seen Emma?
No.
Isn't she in her room?
No. I've looked everywhere.
She's not here.
Well, do you have any idea
of where she might have gone?
And you're sure you can't
remember what you said to Rose?
No. When I go like... that,
I never remember anything.
What I don't understand
is how your parents
can believe all that crap.
It isn't crap.
Oh, whatever, Emma.
But things can't carry on
like this.
The first thing to do is
for you to come home with me.
I'm sure my mum
will think of something.
No, Alex; my uncle told me not
to talk about it to anyone,
and he found out.
Your uncle
is a religious fanatic.
After what happened
to that girl,
fuck, your parents should never
have let him step foot
inside your house.
Oh, you don't understand.
If you tell your mum,
they'll put me in an asylum.
I'm not mad, Alex.
For God's sake, Emma,
you're only 15!
You don't realize it,
but your uncle's
brainwashed you.
That's what's happened.
That's what Rose says too.
And just because I'm 15
doesn't mean I'm an idiot.
I didn't say that.
And anyway,
you didn't seem to care
that I was only 15
when you got with me.
What?
The night of my birthday.
Don't you remember?
No, I don't.
I was tripping.
I don't remember a damn thing.
Aah!
Alex!
What the fuck?
Alex?
Alex.
A-a-alex.
Alex!
Alex! Please!
Alex, please wake up!
Alex! Alex!
Alex.
Alex?
I caused the accident.
And the cockroaches
weren't even there.
You weren't to know that.
Either way,
it wasn't an accident.
The Devil feeds off pain.
That's how he gets his strength.
And he especially enjoys hurting
the people you love the most.
He used you.
Look.
You can't tell anyone else
what's happening with you, okay?
And you must make sure
you're never alone
with anyone who's important
to you.
How is Alex?
Better.
No spinal injuries, but it will
take him several weeks
before he can walk again.
Have you had a chance
to speak to him?
He's under sedation
at the moment.
And what about you?
You all right?
Do you want to see Alex?
- Let's go home, Mum.
- Yeah.
Darling, I've got to stay with
Mark tonight at Auntie Sarah's,
but I'll come and see you
tomorrow morning.
Okay?
I'm not hungry.
You have to eat.
We need you to be strong.
Don't worry, Father.
I'm not going
to starve to death.
I'm not like that other girl.
Padre, no deje que me lleven.
Padre.
Silence, Demon.
Take it easy, Father.
We're together forever.
John.
Are you sure Mark's your son?
You did everything you could
to make sure
Lucy didn't get pregnant again,
and yet...
Do you remember Steve?
Lucy's colleague,
who was so good-looking?
You all right?
What happened?
Nothing.
Nothing happened.
I'm gonna go to my room.
It's the first time
that... this thing
has shown itself
outside the room, right?
It's getting stronger,
isn't it?
I'm going to bring
somebody else in.
I've been overconfident.
I can't do it alone.
Who are you going to call in?
Father Ennis.
He's my old mentor.
He's in Rome, though,
so it'll be a few days
before he can get here.
By the way,
I've already told Emma,
but it's important
that you and Lucie
should know this too.
You must make sure that Emma
is never alone with anyone.
And another thing.
You must forget everything
you heard just now.
But what she said...
The Devil always lies.
Always.
You can't allow him to use you
for his purposes.
Well, I say good night, then.
Good night.
- Leave me alone.
- Please, please.
Lucy, please.
You think it's been easy
to say that?
You're accusing me
of having an affair.
How am I supposed
to react to that?
Look, please, just believe me.
It's not easy to say,
but it's something that was said
the other day by Emma.
Yeah, but she's not very well
at the moment.
But if I didn't say something,
then I'd be thinking about this.
That he's not your son.
How can you even think
that such a thing
could be true?
I'm not gonna take
any kind of tests.
Hi.
- Hi.
- How are you?
Is Auntie looking after you
all right?
Yes.
That ball's mine.
Can I have it back?
And what will I get
in exchange?
A kiss?
If I'm not getting anything
in return,
I think I might keep it.
That ball's mine.
Dad gave it to me.
Get lost!
I'm going to tell Auntie.
Catch!
You're stupid!
Mark. Where are you going?
Come back.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Hi.
Rose.
I...
Let's go, Mum.
It's all my fault.
I killed him.
Can I tell my mom
the truth?
It's too late for the truth.
It wasn't your fault.
I should just kill myself.
That's what I should do.
Hey.
Apart from anything else,
you'd be condemning
your soul to Hell.
That's a victory for the Devil.
You can't let Mark's death
have been for nothing.
Come.
Mum, are you there?
I need to tell you
something that...
that I should have
told you before.
It's all my fault, Mum.
All of it.
One day, I went to visit Uncle
in the canteen, and...
I told him that I had played
on the Ouija board.
Why did you want to do that?
I don't know.
I thought he'd get angry.
He just laughed instead
and said that invoking the devil
wasn't as easy as it seemed
and that playing
with the Ouija board
just... just wasn't enough.
I thought that's what you do,
though, with the Ouija board,
because it's supposed
to invoked spirits, yeah?
Well, spirits
but not the Devil.
I mean, in order
to invoke the devil,
you need to make
a blood sacrifice.
Sacrifice?
Their own blood?
I'll show you.
Uncle Chris knows
a lot about it.
He has loads of stuff
about the Devil in his flat.
He showed me how the girl
who died did it.
Ana invoked the Devil
using this pentagram.
She drew it with her own blood.
I pretended not
to be interested,
but I memorized it.
I memorized it all.
The night of my birthday,
I played on it again.
Oh, spirit, if you are there,
give us a sign.
Uncle was right.
It was a waste of time.
But that night,
when I came home,
you were waiting up for me.
Where the hell have you been?
Do you realize what time it is?
You realized I was drunk,
and you shouted at me.
You find it funny?
You will not leave your room
for the next month.
You will stay in,
you will study,
and there will be no allowance,
no friends, nothing.
I... hate you so much.
Aah.
Get to bed!
Get to bed now!
Mum...
I've never been so angry.
I got really, really angry.
What happened after that,
well, it wasn't an accident.
I didn't slip in the bathroom.
I did it on purpose.
I cut myself because...
because I wanted to.
I started to draw
the pentagram.
And just... just like
that girl did.
And it worked.
And I felt that something
took over my body.
He... he asked me
what I wanted.
I want to be free.
I told him I wanted to be free,
especially
free from my family.
But I didn't know it would be
like this, Mum.
I didn't even believe in...
the Devil existed.
I'm so sorry.
Mum, say something.
Mum, please say something.
Say anything.
Just please say something.
Please.
Mum.
What are you doing?
Mum, what are you doing?
Mum!
What are you doing?
Mum.
Please stop.
What are you doing?
Mum, please.
What's wrong?
Mum, look at me, please.
Mum.
Mum!
Where are you going?
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me.
Please forgive me!
Mum. Mum.
Mum, no!
Mum!
Mum, Mum, you're all right.
You're all right.
You're okay.
Can you hear me sweetheart?
Sarah's coming
to the hospital with you.
I'll come as soon as I can,
all right?
Father Ennis.
It... it's Christopher.
Did you get my message?
Please. You must come.
It's very...
I beg your pardon.
Monsignor.
I forgot.
Good morning.
I'm going back to the hospital,
take some things to Mum.
How is she?
She's resting.
Can I come with you?
No. It's better you don't.
Christopher will be down soon.
If anything happens, he'll...
he'll take you to the hospital.
I'll see you later.
Hi, Chris.
I'm going to the hospital
to take some things for Lucy.
How are you doing?
Well, tired,
but I'll be all right.
- Give her my love.
- Okay, will do.
I'll see you later.
Hi.
How are you doing?
Emma, your mum's gonna be fine,
you know?
God won't...
Let anything bad happen
to her, I know.
You told me the same
in the hospital.
I'm not going to carry on
doing the exorcisms.
Emma.
If it hasn't worked so far,
what makes you think
that it'll work now, like?
I can't do any more.
Emma, please.
Uh-uh.
I'm going to ask my dad
to put me in
a psychiatric hospital
or something.
You're not mad, sweetheart.
No?
I see insects
that aren't really there.
I hear voices in my head,
and I kind of caused everything
that has happened.
If you'd seen
what I've seen...
Well maybe that's it,
because I haven't seen anything.
I want to see the tapes.
All of them.
No, I can't.
It'd be too painful for you.
In that case, forget it.
Listen to me, please.
I've asked another priest
for help.
He'll be here
in a couple of days,
and between the two of us,
we will be able to help you.
I don't care.
Emma, think
of your mum and dad.
You can't give up.
Are you going
to show me those tapes?
No.
Sorry about earlier.
I didn't mean to be rude
or offensive.
Don't worry about it.
I'm going to my room.
Everlasting God.
I don't understand you,
priest!
Silence!
Be quiet, or I swear...
You'll do what?
You're not doing anything
to let me leave this body.
What do you want exactly,
little priestling?
What is your little game?
Don't tell me you don't
find me attractive.
Hold your tongue!
Uncle.
Why did you do that?
Oh, Emma,
are you okay. sweetheart?
You're okay.
In the name of the Son,
in the name of...
Dad! Dad! Dad!
No one is listening to you!
John.
Daddy?
Do you love me daddy?
I love you.
You bastard, fucking priest!
Thy Kingdom come,
thy will be done,
on Earth as it is in Heaven.
Thanks to you, I've gotten
stronger and stronger.
Not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil,
for thine is the kingdom,
the power, and the glory.
Amen.
At last.
I've caught you.
Don't worry.
God won't let anything bad
happen to you.
Ana wouldn't have died
if they'd allowed me
to finish what I started.
You can't let Mark's death
have been for nothing.
I memorized it.
I memorized it all.
I mean, in order
to invoke the Devil,
you need to make
a blood sacrifice.
Hey.
Look, I know this has been
really hard on you,
but we can't allow him
to prevail.
We must keep on fighting.
You've never fought him.
You have never tried to get
the Demon to go away.
Don't be silly.
I've seen the tapes.
No. Look.
Look, you can't
possibly understand
what's happening on those tapes.
I'm not stupid!
Okay?
You knew if I did
what you explained
that the invocation would work.
You told me all about it
even so.
No, no, that's not true.
You made that decision
by yourself, Emma.
This whole thing
is a lousy trap!
You're mad,
and that's all.
You're stark raving mad.
No. Emma...
Emma.
Leave me alone.
I didn't trap you.
Don't you touch me.
You have to understand.
All I wanted was that
what happened to Ana...
what's happening to you now...
never happens to anyone else.
You've completely destroyed me
and my family.
That's what you've done!
That's what you... Fuck!
No one has ever proved
the existence of the Devil.
You and I have done this
together.
No.
And I've got him on tape.
Now the truth will be known...
by everyone.
But why did you take
such a long time?
And... and why did you have
to put me through th...
I needed the Devil to grow
stronger so that I could...
I... I'm so sorry, Emma.
I had no choice.
He's too strong in you now
for me to conquer
single-handed.
But when Ennis arrives,
it will all end.
I promise you.
Now...
give me the tapes.
Mark d...
Mark died because of you.
Because of you.
Mark... Mark died be...
Marked died because of...
because of you!
My brother died because of you.
I will always regret
that I was unable to save him.
But I promise you, he will be
remembered as a martyr.
I'm going to tell everyone.
No. No, Emma.
No, Emma.
You sick freak!
I fucking hate you!
Don't you understand?
This is bigger than all of us.
- Emma, stop it, please.
- Bitch!
Now listen.
Give me, give me...
No!
Emma, Emma, I'm sorry.
Emma, no! Stop!
I'm sorry.
I said stop!
I'm sorry, Emma,
but you know I can't allow you
to destroy the truth.
Where are they?
Give them to me.
You're pathetic, priest.
Do you know something?
Your plan was ridiculous.
What do you think?
That Ennis and his friends
in Rome
don't know the truth already?
Your tapes
won't help you at all.
I could have destroyed them
if I had wanted to.
Why do you think I didn't do so?
You're naive, priest.
You've destroyed the lives
of your family for nothing.
You're lying.
No!
Behold the cross of the Lord.
I exorcize thee,
most vile spirit,
the very incarnation
of our enemy.
Emerge and flee
from this creature of God.
He Himself commands you,
He who commands the seas,
and the winds, and the storms.
Hear me and be afraid,
oh, Satan, enemy of the faith.
Abandon the body
of this innocent child.
I command thee.
In the name of Christ, depart.
Depart!
God, the Father,
commands thee.
God, the Holy Ghost,
God, the Son, commands thee.
commands thee.
Don't be silly, priest.
Christ, God's word made flesh,
commands thee.
Shh. Calm down.
Calm down.
Almost finished.
You've done a very good job,
little priest.
Very good job indeed.
What's that mean?
Without you,
I could have never managed it.
So much pain.
The Evanses turned out
to be a wonderful feast.
No!
God, who so loved the world
that He gave up his only son
for those who believe in Him...
Christopher.
What the hell are you doing?
Commands thee!
Abandon the body
of this earthen child.
No! It's not your daughter.
Bastard priest!
I'll kill you!
If you go near my daughter
again, I'll kill you, you hear?
Kill you!
Almost finished.
Dad.
Dad. Dad!
No, dad!
Dad, please!
Dad.
There he is.
And everything
that has happened is his fault.
Everything.
If it weren't for him,
Mark would have never died.
Mum would've never lost
her mind.
I know. I know.
So what are you going to do
about it, sister?
What are you going
to do about it?
I can't.
You're a coward, Emma.
You let him destroy your family,
and you're not going to do
anything about it.
You disgust me.
This is your last chance.
Kill him and avenge them all.
It's true, sister.
Kill him.
You have to kill him, Emma!
Please... kill me.
Kill me.
Kill him now!
Shut up, once and for all.
No.
I wanted to die.
I want to be dead.
Emma.
My name is Ennis.
I'm an old acquaintance
of your uncle's.
It's over, Emma.
The Devil has gone.
How do you know?
Open your hand.
Why did he go?
I don't know.
Perhaps he thought
you were dead.
Or, more probably,
he had simply achieved
what he wanted
when he entered your body.
It is impossible to know.
Where is my uncle?
I'm sorry, Emma.
I'm afraid Christopher
didn't wait for God
to pass judgment
on his mistakes.
What Father Taylor did
is unforgivable.
But you may be sure that God
will make him pay for it.
And the tapes?
They are in a safe place.
Don't worry about that.
No one will ever see them.
What I want is my family back.
Can your God
give that to me...
Father?
Can he?