Fear...
a little death that consumes you.
From the common to the abstract,
everyone is scared of something.
I got a cockroach.
Somebody kill it. Somebody kill it.
Somebody kill it. Kill it. Ohh!
I was always taught
you had to live with it, accept it.
I watched as others fought back.
Agoraphobia, nyctophobia,
hydrophobia, acrophobia.
There are literally thousands
of classified phobias.
I figured out a way to give
my patients a fresh start
without the inhibitions and restrictions
their phobias had placed in their lives.
Oh, the chamber here animates your phobias
in the form of hallucinations.
No!
Total immersive exposure therapy,
that's where I went...
pushed to the edge of science
and sensory deprivation.
We had the technology
to find a cure all along,
but everyone else was blind to it.
Smarter men than me all failed,
but not me.
My agenda was pure,
and I figured out the key
hiding in plain sight,
which they all had overlooked,
the amygdala,
the portion of the brain
which feels fear.
Everyone else had danced around it
and treated it like something sacred,
but I took a slightly
different approach.
The amygdala also acts
as a kind of projector
in which the signal
can easily be received
and, most of all, bounced back.
It was working.
Round after round,
I was fighting fear and winning.
No!
Some of my colleagues tried
to debunk my theories, calling me insane,
dangerous, outrageous,
but they were just jealous.
But something, something went wrong.
Now close your eyes,
and just concentrate
on the sound of my voice.
Which one do you want? Strawberry?
Vanilla? Chocolate? What?
- Vanilla.
- Vanilla?
Don't do this. Please don't...
Talk to me.
I need you to tell me
what you see.
Nothing.
Tell me what you see.
A door.
Good.
Is it the door to the diner?
I don't think so.
That's it, Paige.
Focus on the sound of my voice.
Paige, you're not listening to me.
Focus!
Paige...
...focus!
That's it, Paige.
- No.
- Focus on the sound of my voice.
I'm scared.
- Paige.
- No!
Paige, it's just a hallucination.
All you need to do is open your eyes.
Let me in.
Paige! Paige!
Open the door.
All you need to do is open your eyes.
Open your eyes, Paige.
Paige, open your eyes!
Paige. Paige!
Paige!
Sara. Sara, are your lights out, too?
I'm fine.
Really? Why, 'cause you lit
a couple candles?
You know what? I think I have bedbugs.
Could you check my neck? It's really itchy.
I feel like I can feel them
crawling on me. It's just gross.
- Right there.
- Relax. Relax. Relax. Relax.
- Damn it.
- Nothing.
- Really?
- Nothing except lice.
Oh, fuck you.
Why don't you light some more candles?
Shut up.
So you got your hot date over there?
He's warm enough, I guess.
Remember that friend of his
I told you about?
- No, I don't.
- You don't know what you're missing.
No! Just let me finish grad school
and worry about all of that other stuff.
- It's all about sacrifices.
- Sacrifices for the greater good.
I know. You can spare me
the speech. Thank you.
Shut up. I'll have the last laugh when I'm
a horribly underpaid teaching assistant.
Thank God.
Now get out, itchy bitch.
I have school in the morning.
- You could teach this kid a thing or two.
- Get out.
- What?
- Get out! Come on.
Oh, come on. He's kind of hot
and edgy and dark.
I know you like 'em dark.
The darker, the better, bitch.
Okay.
Oh, God.
God.
Hello?
It's not my fucking job!
I'm not a fucking magician
or mortician. I am...
Osborn, are you fucking nuts?
For the past few days,
I have gone above and beyond.
I... yeah. Well, you know,
it's just a matter of time
before the checks start fucking bouncing.
- Hey.
- Oh, my God. Where the fuck are you?
I'm... I'm at the clinic.
Please tell me
you're getting an abortion.
Look, I'm sure I'm fine.
I just... I wanted to talk to Andover.
What, you couldn't call?
You had to drive 4 hours?
Yeah, well, the place looks like shit.
I'm not sure the fear business
is doing too well.
And I overheard Bauer on the phone.
I think that something happened here.
God, I hate that convict creep.
He's so rapey.
Listen to this shit. I saw this article
about this bug from Japan.
It flies and shoots acid into your eyes.
Listen, I gotta go, okay?
I'll be home later.
Great.
Hello?
Dr. Andover?
Now, we discussed how important it is
for you to revisit these images, right?
Okay, just concentrate
on the sound of my voice,
and breathe.
Stop!
Sara, it's not real!
Dr. Andover?
Dr. Andover.
We're closed.
Come on. Come on. You're okay.
Come on.
It's okay. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Yo! Yo, can I get some help over here?
- Excuse me?
- Yo, lady, I just drove 5 fucking hours.
- I just need you to come...
- Wait. You're Dylan Dunn, right?
Yeah. Yeah, that's me. Yeah.
Yeah, you're Sara. I remember you.
Caylee's outside, and she's really sick.
She needs to see the doc right away.
Caylee's here? What's wrong with Caylee?
We gotta get her in a room.
We gotta get her to see the doc.
Hey. Caylee.
Why aren't you eating?
I... I just can't.
- Hey, listen, I'm gonna go get a drink.
- Yeah. I got her.
Caylee, you were doing so well.
Tell me, why aren't you really eating?
I know.
I know you saw it.
You saw him, too.
What?
Hello! Can I get some help?
Caylee, are you okay?
What the hell is this shit?
Get her prepped, please.
- We're closed.
- Caylee. Caylee.
Here. I got her. I got her.
Come here. Come on.
Come on. Get up. Get up.
We got you.
What makes you think
you had a fear aftershock?
I mean, but it was so...
real.
Like the mask, the gun.
I could smell the gunpowder.
Okay, within days of being
in the chamber, Sara, sure,
but you haven't had a session in a year.
It's... it's unheard of.
There hasn't been one documented case
of fear aftershocks reemerging
since he built the chamber 20 years ago.
I don't understand why I can't
talk to Dr. Andover.
You know, what was
that thing that he was in?
Don't worry about that.
It's always been a secret part
of his process.
What do you mean?
Even though he can't see what you see,
it still takes a heavy
emotional toll on him.
Well, then why doesn't he just
go into the chamber himself?
Because it'd be counterproductive,
I mean, possibly even dangerous.
He's the only one
who knows how to run it.
He'd be the first to tell you, Sara,
he has no fear to treat.
I don't know what's going on here,
but our fears are coming back.
And what is this black stuff
she projectile-vomited all over me?
At first, I thought it was
stomach bile, but it's thicker,
more viscous.
All I can tell you, Sara, is we've never
seen anything like it at the clinic.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
It's Paige.
Paige Peterson?
She's dead.
- What do you mean? She was better. I...
- She was better...
for a while.
She came back months later
insisting on talking to Andover.
Just like me now.
Did she die in the chamber?
I... Sara, I can't give you any more details,
Sara. I've already said too much.
And I'm afraid you're wasting
your time here.
Look, I can't go backwards.
I put up with those hallucinations
in the chamber.
I slept with the lights on.
I did everything.
Caylee is clearly sick, okay?
I'm not leaving.
S...
Sara.
Rewind. When did you know
that you could take the lead
and finish it out strong?
Uh, from the beginning.
I don't question it. I don't question it.
You just keep riding hard. You stay focused.
You keep doing it, you're gonna win,
you're gonna win, and that's
what I do. Done. Did it.
Another trophy for your mantel...
Try to relax, okay.
We're gonna get you something
for your pain, okay? Just relax.
Okay, I'm afraid Caylee is much sicker
than when we initially treated her.
Her sitophobia and body
dysmorphic disorder
have reached a point she could die
if she doesn't start eating.
I don't get it. She was cured
when we were here last year.
Why can't you treat her
with traditional means?
I'd have to run more tests to find out.
Why don't you just put her
in the damn chamber?
It's not an option, apparently.
Why? That's the reason why we came here.
Where the hell's the doctor?
He's supposed to be here.
Why won't he see her?
I understand. Listen, between us,
I'm working on a backup plan
and hoping Andover will get onboard.
Caylee's life may depend on it.
He needs to get his head out of his ass.
Listen, I'm gonna stay and help
with Caylee. You don't have...
maybe a clean shirt and a few vacancies?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
I have done as you asked...
you promised me. You promised me.
Give me what I want.
Please. I need it.
Paige Peterson, addendum.
This afternoon, I just...
You have time for a bubble bath,
but not to talk to me?
I'm sorry. I just...
I don't understand what's going on here.
You and me both.
Things have been rather
trying around here lately.
I heard about Paige.
It was an accident.
- Right?
- No.
I was responsible for her, Sara.
I wanted to help her.
I wanted to help all of you.
You did help me.
You saved my life.
I saw the shooter.
The shooter?
No, that... that's never
happened before.
Prolonged aftershock, I know.
Osborn schooled me.
I think it's time for one more session.
Paige was just one more session.
Everything was just fine,
and then she somehow lost her way.
She lost me. I...
she was beyond my reach.
Sara, I nursed her for months.
She didn't require oxygen. She didn't need
life support. How's that possible?
I could tell.
I could see that she was
still suffering, that...
she was still terrified.
How did it end?
I simply closed her eyes.
And she was gone.
I really appreciate
your wanting to help.
I really do, but...
I just can't do this anymore.
So if you'll excuse me,
I have some things I need to do.
Do you know that Caylee is throwing up
whatever black stuff that is in your vial?
You'd know that if you
came out of your office.
And unfortunately, Dr. Andover,
I'm not leaving.
The Fear Clinic is open for business.
Nobody can find out about this,
or we're in deep shit.
Dang! Fuck! I hate that fucking shit!
Well, that's Osborn's problem.
She can break it to the doc.
Son of a bitch.
You stole millions of dollars
worth of power
juicing up illegal grow farms.
You mean to tell me this is a challenge?
You know what?
Your fucking mama is a challenge.
Here's what I think. Why don't we just
get this son of a bitch back upstairs,
and I'll piggyback the breakout box?
Ah, fuck no. Look, for one,
Andover destroyed the...
whatever power supply was up there.
You need to figure something out, and fast.
How much you say she was
cutting us a check for?
So much we'll never
have to work here again
or do anything that winds us
back in the joint.
Well, that's a good thing.
Ooh, sexy bitches
Are my favorite kind of bitches.
You dumb-ass. I hate that song.
I daisy-chain a couple,
three gennies together,
I can have this thing
up and running by dinnertime.
- Boom.
- I'll be back.
Yes.
Hey. Baby, listen.
They're gonna keep you here
overnight for observation.
Well, they're gonna make you better.
They're gonna fix you.
They're gonna do it
without that Fear Chamber.
No.
You have to get me in there,
no matter what it takes.
- You want to lose me? Huh?
- Fuck no, I don't want to lose you.
God, I feel like I've already
lost too much of you. I...
All right.
All right, I'm gonna get you in there.
I'd do anything for you.
I like that.
Paige?
Where are we?
What happened to you?
In the chamber, what happened?
You thought you were building a box.
You built a door instead.
Door?
What door?
A door for me.
Every time you put someone
in that thing...
it made more cracks,
so I peeked through
the cracks you made...
became a little easier to turn.
I won't let you through again.
Paige Peterson,
female,
age 26,
deceased.
This black substance
seems to induce
hallucinations upon contact, which...
leads me to believe
that it's some kind of...
phobic residue,
a fear waste, if you will.
Why hasn't it manifested itself
before now?
Caylee.
Show me.
Where?
I understand.
If that's what you want.
Ooh.
I am fucking hungry.
How are you feeling? You hungry?
You know my mom's doing
that whole dinner thing tonight, right?
Yeah. I gotta eat something
before then, though.
We could just go grab something
somewhere close.
- What's up, buddy?
- Hey, hey. What's up, dude?
- I just saw you on the video.
- Oh, yeah? How'd my hair look?
I don't know. You were
wearing a helmet, stupid.
Oh, you're so...
It was so cool, though.
And when are you going
to teach me those awesome flips?
No way. Your sister would fuck...
freaking kill me. Can't do that.
Hey, brat, you want
a milkshake over at Eli's?
Are you kidding? It's freezing.
Hey, come on. Don't be a wuss.
It's warm in there.
Come on. What do you say?
- Uh...
- Milkshake?
- Fine.
- Done deal.
- Ooh. Come on.
- Let's go.
Ah, shit, honey. Sorry about this.
Hate these damn things.
Always chewing up my wires.
Hey.
Know how you catch a unique squirrel?
Unique up on him.
Osborn, please come to the
reception area for patient intake. Osborn.
Mrs. Patton.
I'm Osborn, the head therapist here,
specializing in PTSD.
- So happy you could make it out.
- Of course.
Hi.
I'm Sara.
He hasn't spoken since
the shooting, I'm afraid.
Blake.
Why don't we get you in an exam room
and get you all settled in, hmm?
Bauer.
Till then, you want to have a seat?
I have to admit,
this is not what I expected.
Wasn't always like this.
You've been here before?
I came here after the incident myself.
Dr. Andover really helped me.
He cured me of my scotophobia.
I'm sorry. It's fear of the dark.
So why did you bring Blake here now?
Well, at night...
just for a few minutes, not every night,
it's like he sees something
and it really scares him.
He sees something relating
to the incident?
I don't know.
I know nothing can bring him back now,
not the way he was.
But I can't stand the thought of him
being terrorized by something
and then not knowing what it is.
I think he's in the right place.
Do you know that that kid
can barely move,
but hurts himself every night,
he's so scared?
Yes, I promise you
we are gonna help Blake.
How? By giving him fucking fluids
- and a lollipop like Caylee?
- Keep your voice down.
No! This is bullshit, and you know it.
That kid is suffering. Caylee is on the brink
of death, and he's too chickenshit
- to use the chamber?
- Sara.
He said he'd never fail us, right?
Well, he's failing us right fucking now.
Before you get angry...
this is your life's work.
I had it repaired for good reason,
and two of them are in the waiting room.
What you and this box have done
for me and my claustrophobia,
for all the people you've helped,
it is not over, and you know that.
In...
In over 20 years,
I've never had reason to doubt
that this was anything but a cure,
a magic bullet.
I thought I did everything right.
And you did. It was a terrible accident.
Paige was a tragedy, and it's...
it's not gonna happen again.
I don't want anyone else hurt.
We can save this boy,
another victim of that shooting,
one that was hurt so badly,
he flew under our radar all this time.
Can't we give his mother some peace
and let her know what's tormenting him?
I don't know if I can. I...
I don't know.
You can.
You can, and then you'll see
there's nothing to be afraid of.
Don't worry, Doctor.
Have a little faith.
I don't understand.
Why are we taking the stairs?
Elevator's out.
And why is it in the basement?
All ready to leave you to it, Doctor.
No, please, you stay this time.
Given the, uh...
given the patient's condition,
this is new territory for both of us.
- Certainly.
- Thank you.
Right this way.
The chamber is a very private experience
for our patients.
It's imperative
for Dr. Andover's concentration
that he has no distractions
during the session.
- Well, aren't you going to put him to sleep?
- We don't deal in dreams here.
At no time are our patients ever asleep.
Now...
close your eyes,
and just listen to the sound
of my voice.
I need you to relax and listen
to the sound of my voice.
We're going back,
back to the restaurant
on the day of the shooting.
The restaurant is full
of people eating dinner.
Blake, what do you see?
Blake?
Are you there yet?
- Blake, focus.
- Don't do this. Please don't...
Focus, Blake.
Blake, you're not focusing.
His heart rate is elevated.
Do you want to stop, Doctor?
No. Blake.
Blake!
What's happening?
- Bauer, would you come get her, please?
- Is he okay?
It's okay. Ma'am,
I need you to come with me.
Penlight.
It's okay, Blake. We're gonna
get you out of here in just a second.
Bauer, his chair.
We got you. We got you.
Hey, you've reached Megan.
Leave a message, and I might call you back.
Megan, will you please call me back, please?
I'm really starting to get worried.
- Fuck.
- Girlfriend trouble?
Listen, I need access to a car.
Well, I could probably do that.
But it'll cost you.
Fuck off.
Is there a problem here?
Oh, no, sir. We're just...
we're just kidding around.
I can't find Megan. It's been, like,
6 hours. She's not answering her phone.
Mr. Bauer,
you will go get the young lady.
- Now.
- Yeah, okay, sir.
All right.
Sorry, sir. Sorry, sir. Sorry.
Thank you.
I don't fucking get you guys
with this chamber thing.
You guys are all freaking obsessed.
You don't get it.
Everything fades once you're in there.
You don't have to be afraid
of anything anymore.
It's bullshit.
What do you mean?
All right, fear
is a primal thing, right?
Hey, babies were born with it.
It's part of our damn genetic code.
We've evolved and we have survived
because of it.
I know all about fear,
and it's got no place in my world.
And now you've got some fucking guy who
builds this box, and he wants to play God,
and he wants to start digging around
in our heads and shit. No way.
No. I'm pure instinct.
I don't need no fucking box.
Yeah, well, you're not getting in mine.
- You were a patient, right?
- No, I wasn't a patient here.
I was in that thing once.
I was only here one time.
It's just she used to show us videos
of all that crazy shit you did with bikes.
Oh, yeah? Well, what's he got
to say about his first ride?
Now, that wasn't very nice, now, was it?
Hey, don't be an asshole.
Ah, yeah, we're gonna
go back and eat inside.
All it takes is one trigger-happy fuck,
and next thing you know,
you got nobody to push the buttons
on the control panel.
Have a little respect.
Just a little.
Guess he wasn't as lucky
as the rest of us that night.
Help. Hello. Somebody, hello.
Megan, your old room's waiting for you.
- There you go.
- Super!
I missed you, Megan. You're like a ray
of fucking sunshine in my day.
As usual, you guys corner
the market on hospitality.
Hospitality. I'll fucking show you
hospi-fucking-tality.
-  Sexy bitches...
-  It's way past midnight
There's a howling wind,
oh, God what can it...
Oh, thank God.
Ow.
I was so worried about you.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I don't know. I...
I just thought it would
pass on its own, I guess.
I've got so much to tell you.
Hey, babe.
I'm gonna take a shower.
I'll see you after your session, 'kay?
Come here.
- Come here.
- What's up? You okay?
- No.
- No? What's wrong?
Come on.
Now just focus
on the sound of my voice.
Now...
you're going back.
You're going to return...
to the restaurant.
Are you there?
Are you in the restaurant?
You see your boyfriend. You see Dylan.
I'm safe.
I see them.
Caylee,
I need you to tell me exactly
where you are.
I'm safe.
Good.
So now it's just a few moments
before the incident.
Do you see anyone approaching the door?
I can see him.
Can you see your brother?
Do you see little Kevin
sitting opposite you?
I can see him.
What's he wearing?
Picture it, Caylee.
What are you eating? Picture everything.
I don't want to remember everything.
I can't. That's not what I'm supposed to do.
Yes, that's precisely what you're
supposed to do. Now trust me.
Now look to your brother.
No!
- I can't.
- Caylee, look at Kevin.
Get me out of here!
I want you to picture everything.
Get me out of here! Get me out of here!
Caylee. Caylee,
I know it's painful for you to relive
that day, but you can't hide from it.
I'll have Gage help you
to your room, Caylee. Just relax.
What the fuck was that?
That wasn't supposed to happen.
He promised me!
- Come on. Come on, hon. Let me help you out.
- You fuck. Get off of me! Get off!
- Okay.
- I'm not a fucking cripple!
- I'm not the one in the wheelchair.
- Okay. Okay.
Move! Move!
That wasn't about food at all, was it?
No. No, it certainly was not.
Hey.
You mind if I come in?
It's okay.
You want to know a secret?
I was always afraid of the dark...
ever since I was a little kid
in my bedroom.
And then when the shooting happened...
the guy followed me,
you know, like me and only me
when he started shooting out the lights.
And, you know, at that moment,
I wasn't even scared of him.
I was scared of the dark.
I was scared of monsters in the dark.
Anyway...
Dr. Andover really helped me.
Until lately.
I'm starting to think maybe it's smart
to be scared of the dark.
S'okay.
S'okay, be...
I se...
I see monsters...
too. I see mons...
Blake.
Sara, Dr. Andover
would like to speak to you.
Hey. I'll be right back.
Blake?
Blake, are you okay?
What's wrong, Blake?
Fuck!
Take it easy.
Yeah.
Hard. Hard. Hard.
Hurt me. Fucking hurt me. Fuck!
Harder. Oh, harder.
- Hard...
- Caylee, what the fuck... fuck is...
fuck is wrong with you?
Fuck, can't we just be normal for once?
Get out. Get out!
You're fucking useless.
- This is fucking bullshit.
- Get out.
He's moving again. He's talking.
- I know.
- Blake moved.
- His brain activity has tripled.
- Why can't you see that that's amazing?
Because, Sara, what's happening here
to Blake simply isn't possible.
The chamber wasn't designed
to work that way.
The chamber doesn't cure gunshot wounds.
It simply opens a door
into a portion of the brain that most people
keep locked away. That's it.
Then why did you tell his mother that
you thought he was going to be helped?
Yes, I thought perhaps we could
improve his... his function a fraction
using sensory techniques.
But this? Oh, no.
- This is impossible. This is dangerous.
- Or it's a miracle.
Or and if it's not a miracle,
it's a really fucking great side effect.
I honestly don't understand why
you're not calling medical journals
and telling them that it works again.
Because I invented the goddamn thing.
I know what it's capable of.
Look, maybe this will make sense.
Blakey? Blakey?
Blakey! Baby, are you okay?
Oh, baby. What? What?
What do you see? What?
What, honey? What's the matter?
You're okay. You're okay.
You're with Mommy.
Mommy's here. Mommy's here.
Mommy's here.
This is the amygdala.
It's the part of the brain where the emotion
of fear is generated from.
And until today... until today,
Blake's entire frontal lobe
was severely damaged by that bullet...
utterly, totally unresponsive.
I think this is about the chamber.
I think it's doing something
to all of you.
I think it's doing it for a reason.
Sara. Sara, don't look at me like that.
Listen, I know this sounds crazy,
especially coming
from a man of science, but...
I'm truly afraid that there could be
a malevolent entity at work here.
You can't quit.
It's not an option.
Besides, what reason would a malevolent
force have for making Blake smarter?
...what reason
would a malevolent force have
for making Blake smarter?
So that he can be made
to feel fear again.
How bad is it?
It's not that bad.
I need you to take a deep breath.
All right, Megan?
- I'm going to have to cut this. Okay?
- Okay.
Okay, just take a deep breath, okay?
Relax. Breathe. Breathe.
You're gonna feel some pressure now.
All right? I have to squeeze it.
- Oh, God. Ow. It hurts.
- I know, sweetie. Just take a deep breath.
Please stay still, Megan, okay?
Calm down, sweetie.
- It itches. It...
- I know, sweetie.
- It's like there's something inside.
- I know. Just breathe. Just breathe.
Stay still so I can clean this, okay?
Okay, sweetie.
- Oh, Christ. It hurts. It...
- Take a deep breath.
It feels like there's something
crawling in there.
Is there something in there?
Oh, what the hell is that?
What is that?
Hey.
You mind if I come in?
Sure.
I didn't know you had tattoos.
- Did that hurt?
- I don't know.
Do you remember anything?
What do you remember...
about that night, Blake?
Sara.
I get flashes
in the chamber.
It's... it's not like you guys.
I don't...
When does your mom come to get you?
I don't know.
I don't care.
She seems a little overprotective.
Yeah.
That's one way to put it.
- She cares, though.
- Can we please just not talk about her?
S... I'm sorry.
You know what would have
been really nice?
Just if we could have
known each other before
any of this shit happened.
I would have liked that.
Corner lamp,
patient room 2A.
- Ah!
- Fuck!
- It's me, fuck-nut.
- Jesus Christ, Bauer.
What are you doing?
Where'd you get that creepy-ass thing?
It's cool, right?
I found it in the basement.
No, it's goddamn weird.
Gives me the heebie-jeebies.
All right, all right.
Put your fucking vagina away.
Fuck you! You scared
the shit out of me, boy!
Goddamn jokester motherfucker.
Aw, horseshit.
- Don't know how to do your job, old man?
- I do my job the same way I do your mama,
8 hours a day.
Might have to switch me up
some circuits in here.
Goddamn it.
Ah, we're gonna need to be ready
for emergency lighting anyway.
That storm's coming up strong.
What the fuck?
I'm glad you and...
you and Sara are getting along.
So, uh... how are you feeling?
Good. Thank you.
Now, Blake,
during your session in the chamber,
did you see anything strange?
Hear a voice other than mine
trying to speak to you? Hmm?
May I?
Ah. Oh.
The mask from the diner.
Is that what you saw?
I understand how traumatic that
could be for you to remember, Blake.
It's scary.
Blake.
It's... it's a scary mask.
Blake... it's just a mask.
All of us wear masks every day.
We hide behind social masks.
We need to wear them.
We couldn't survive without them.
What frightens you isn't this mask.
What scares you is what it represents.
Blake, I need to ask you something
that may make you feel uncomfortable,
might upset you.
Go ahead.
I need to know exactly
where you were sitting in that diner.
I don't know.
All right. What were you wearing, hmm?
You remember that?
- Talk to me. What did you have to eat?
- I don't know.
French fries? How did you get there, Blake?
Who did you come with?
All right. What was your meal that day?
What were you wearing?
- I don't know.
- Blake, you can do this.
- Talk to me, Blake!
- You look at me,
and you don't know anything.
Doc. You gotta come with me.
- Were you even there that day?
- Doc.
The basement. It's the bug chick.
It appears Blake's
developed necrophobia.
I think it's a good idea for me
to go prep her room,
prepare for a worst-case scenario.
I'm not even sure I know what
a worst-case scenario is around here.
I know, but I don't know
what else to do.
She will claw herself apart.
At least in here,
we have a chance to reach her.
You can reach her.
Or something else may reach her.
Sweetheart, I'm gonna need you
to close your eyes.
Megan. Megan.
Megan.
No!
A masked gunman has opened fire
inside a popular restaurant tonight,
killing 6 people,
including a 7-year-old boy.
Police are still looking for the suspect,
who is said to be wearing a mask
and is heavily armed.
Get the hell on,
you annoying son of a bitch.
Hey, you know
what's going on with the lights?
Obviously, there is a power surge.
Dr. O thinks my time is better off
spent putting beds together
for goddamn crazy people.
By the way, your friend's down
in the chamber. She freaked out.
- Who? Megan?
- That's the one.
Can you take me to her, please?
You know what? I am goddamn tired
of being a chambermaid.
I need to reroute power to the emergency
lights anyway. Come on. I'll take you there.
Shit.
Megan. Megan.
Megan, talk to me. Open it!
- I'll see what I can do.
- Can't you open it?
Megan. Hey. Hey, Megan. Talk to me.
Look at me. Look at me. Hey.
Bauer, get your ass down
to the chamber now!
Let's get her out of there.
Get her head down there.
What the hell is wrong with her?
Listen, I can't find Andover anywhere.
He is fucking gone.
- Oh, Jesus.
- What's wrong with her eyes?
- God, she doesn't even blink. That's trippy.
- Don't touch her.
I saw the same thing with Paige.
Her heart rate and blood pressure
are impossibly low.
By all accounts, she should be dead.
Sweetie, come on. It's okay.
Don't close her eyes,
even for a minute.
You guys, she needs real medical attention,
more than I can give her here.
Under normal circumstances, I can cover
RN duties, but nothing is normal here.
We need to get her to a hospital
before her body goes into shock.
- I can carry her out.
- No. Someone's got to go to the hospital.
That ain't gonna happen, all right?
All the doors and windows are jammed tight
with this tar shit. It's impossible.
Yeah? Well, hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
- I still don't have a damn signal.
- I ain't got one either upstairs.
Whether it's that storm or this shit,
I don't know, but here's what I'm thinking.
- We're fucked.
- Okay, I need more medical supplies.
When this sedative wears off,
if she even comes out of this,
we need extra blankets
to raise her body temperature,
- and there's not enough down here.
- I'm gonna go get supplies, all right?
- No. No, no, no.
- I'll be back in a minute.
Honey, wait a minute. None of us know what
the hell's going on around here, all right?
Everything's gone up shit creek.
I don't think you should be
- running around there all by yourself.
- I'll take my chances.
Goddamn, that is creepy.
Paige.
Please, help me.
I know who you are.
I won't let you through again.
The door is closed.
You were taking
so much food off my table.
I'm going back.
You're home now.
Her body
temperature and vitals say she...
she should have expired,
but she's beyond my reach.
It's as if something else is holding on
to her, not letting her die,
keeping her in a state worse than death,
a kind of fear loop.
I stupidly
tried to eradicate a fundamental
and necessary human function,
the oldest human emotion.
And now fear itself,
now it wants to live
and breathe on its own.
I think... I think an entity
is coming through into our world,
and now fear itself,
perhaps planning to use all of us
as a host, a vessel.
'Bout time you get down here.
Can you give me a hand?
Lazy fucker.
Come on. Quit looking for your girlie
magazines and get over here. Help me out.
Thing ain't gonna jury-rig itself.
Fuck.
What the fuck is this?
What in the fuck?
Look, I know the sounds of gunshots.
We need to get the hell out of here.
And how are you gonna do that?
I'm gonna find a way.
Fuck! Fuck!
What's going on? Did you find him?
Bauer, can you please
go find Andover for me?
- Yeah. I mean, it wants me.
- Please?
It needs me to... it wants me to join.
- Bauer.
- I'm not in.
- I don't want...
- Bauer.
- I don't want to be in.
- What is going on with you? Bauer?
- This is the door.
Bauer? Bauer!
You really think he's gonna
let me leave here, don't you?
"He"? Who the hell
are you talking about, babe?
He's coming.
Bauer, can you please
go get Dr. Andover for me?
What... what is going on with you?
Bauer!
Bauer?
- You still don't get it, do you?
- Oh, no, no, no. You don't...
- He's coming.
- No, no.
- That's how you leave!
- Bauer?
- Hear him, baby?
- No, listen to me. You're talking crazy.
The window. I pushed on the...
It pushed back!
- Look at me.
- It's not letting me leave.
- No! No! No! No!
- Bauer, it's okay. It's okay.
- It'll all be over soon.
- No, I got an idea. I have this.
Caylee!
Bauer!
You promised me.
You promised me I could be with him.
You promised me you'd get me
out of here. Go away!
I keep my promises.
You want to see Kevin?
Worse than death, a kind of fear loop.
My hundreds
of sessions curing the phobic
are starving this thing somehow.
It's relentless and,
worst of all, patient.
It needs to feed,
and it won't be denied its meals.
Dr. Andover?
Have a little faith.
Is that... is that you?
Are you okay?
Everything's going to be okay.
Worse than death,
the kind of fear loop.
Andover?
Andover!
Please.
No! God!
Sara,
you were right about one thing.
Sometimes it's smart
to be scared of the dark.
No!
Blake.
Blake, it's not you.
Blake, this isn't you.
Then tell me, Sara,
why does this mask feel so familiar?
You're not wearing a mask.
Look.
Feel your face.
You killed all those people!
You should be dead!
I do remember you.
It was me.
I did it. I'm so sorry.
Blake, we have to go.
Don't. No.
How did it end?
I simply closed her eyes.
Fuck!
Dylan.
You want to see Kevin?
Stop! Get off me!
There's nothing left to fear.
It's just us.
I know.
But it'll be back,
and it'll be stronger.
Fear never dies.
It wanted you all along.
Was my fault.
I opened the door.
Then let's change the locks.
Maybe it's time
for one more session, Doctor.
Fear, it is relentless.
It needs to feed,
and it won't be denied its meals.
After seeing what it did to get to me,
my concern is that fear itself
will use me, my clinic,
and the chamber to feed, to...
to consume...
all of us.
Now close your eyes.
Concentrate on the sound of my voice.
It's way past midnight
There's a howling wind
Oh, God, what can it be?
Something out there evil
Is coming straight for me
The house is dark and very cold
I know there's no one here
Why am I scared to death?
Just petrified with fear
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the house
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the dark
The dark
When I opened up the door
and snapped on the switch
The room was filled with light
Then something black and very fast
Flit upon my sight
What I feared most as a child
Was the coming of the night
Now my horrors have become quite real
My nightmares breathe new life
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the house
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the dark
Dark
Yeah
What is it in the house
That the darkness brings to life?
I sense their eyes upon me
As I grab a butcher knife
Whatever it is that waits for me
It hides beneath my bed
And if I try to sleep tonight
By morning, I'll be dead
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the house
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the dark
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the house
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the dark
Yeah
Yeah, 'cause I'm shaking,
and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the house
'Cause I'm shaking, and I'm thinking
Of something evil lurking
Waiting for me in the dark
Fear never dies.