Should you insist on having bobble
you should save on the chin too.
In order to balance the whole thing.
- Balancing?
- Yes.
- Can you come here a minute?
- No.
It's that time now, you know.
Yes, but I have not the time.
I have to work.
It's cool.
- Nervous about meeting?
- Occasionally.
Can Kenneth Skoglund be kind
and contact the front desk?
Kenneth Skoglund to reception.
(phone signal)
- What are we waiting for?
-Kenneth.
- Is there anyone who has seen him?
- Kenneth Skoglund to reception.
Have you seen Kenneth?
- I  go. You can sit here for so long.
- Kenneth Skoglund to reception.
(phone signal)
Hello?
Kjelle?
My computer is blue again on the screen.
Blue and a lot of text:
"A problem has been dectected".
Then it blows warm air from the fan.
Should it do that?
No thanks.
Put them in the conference.
- It's medwurst.
- No, put them in the conference.
- Have you seen Kenneth?
- No.
I did not ask you.
- Have you Pillat on settings?
- No.
Not been in the BIOS and tried
clock the CPU or flash memory
- Kenneth Skoglund to reception.
-... In somebody damn hesitant VPN tunnel?
I have no idea.
It's best if you come here with it.
I have all the installation files
and tools and stuff here.
- Can Kenneth Skoglund come...
- Hello?
(phone signal)
- Kenneth Skoglund to reception.
- Um... Yes, I will.
Skoglund!
Is there anyone who has seen Kenneth?
- What Kenneth?
- Skoglund, I told you. Are you deaf?
- Duty calls.
- Yes, again today.
Haha, yeah... It's good.
Ken...
(Phone signal)
Kenneth Skoglund
to material supply.
(Kenneth groans heavily)
What is it that happened?
Oh, where are you? - Hello.
Some are waiting for you there.
We have a small meeting.
If you have the desire to look past
so surely it would be pretty good.
Kenneth Skoglund to reception.
Well, you want me to start...
For clarity only.
As. And...
Ja... Why does it look like this then,
you wonder.
Well, it is then simply
because of the... or the mismatch-
-resulting
between supply and demand.
Contraindications our resource,
so to speak.
Here then...
Here... 0Ch here.
That should not be sitting here.
The  we put there instead
so it becomes much clearer.
Then on the other hand this
we see a line representing-
-our mâlfokusnivâ.
But in December we reach-
-the critical point
for liquidity, KPR-
-in the form of a crosspoint.
And it is then analyzed
in some parts down here.
We take for example:
master who vandalized-
base stations that failed,
shaky power grid and...
We lose customers.
It is well these points
I think-
-that customers do not want,
but rather then vice versa.
Are you with me? On the contrary.
Yeah. Thank you, Kenneth.
This was well
the worst Monday meeting date.
Yeah, it's fucked.
This was the man's not wiser.
It was expected not-
-when you got into the car four forty-five
and drove 40 mil on an empty stomach.
Sitting here like a fool, being invited
the loaf and watch the kids artwork.
It is obvious that it happened
shit here since you took over, Tord.
It's 2011 now. You may uproot your
and give us a sensible report.
Give us a report, dammit.
Something you can hold in your hand.
It hoped we get here today.
But apparently it has the
something happened along the way.
I did not sejva. I got of those
blue screen on the computer and mass text.
But it is mending now-
-So it should be possible to recreate
somehow, it said.
I ate a fish casserole in front of the television and
slötittade the quiz.
They broke for commercials
shortly before the final round.
So they show one of our commercials
and I sat thinking quietly:
"How the hell was really the
who made this film?"
Now I do not.
I think that it is a clockwork concept.
But is it really?
(Door slamming, heavy footsteps)
Please God, help me.
A mature profiling, we said.
I think it is stylish.
It's damn quasi noir.
"We hear you." That's what we do.
Hello, hello?
It looks just like the Women's Shelter,
fixed with free sms first month.
Do we get the arrow pointing up again
we have to reinvent ourselves.
No one would invest money
in these kinds of formal experimentation.
We know how
quarterly report will look like. We have to show-
-we have things going on, that we are
attractive, retain their market value.
Less Bergman, more Crazy Frog.
Yes, yes, I get it. But we must surely
still account for something.
Just ask Kenneth pressing "print", so
has the well report by tomorrow?
I take fourth on the carpet,
if that's okay.
- Is that like...
- Shh!
There is a fan, Gil Grissom.
The spins and cools.
- It was not that I...
- Where have you backup disk then?
You save well on backups,
be hoped.
- Huh?
- Sometimes.
- Regularly?
- Irregular.
Simply insert an external hd
in usbzn and autosejva every day.
- Yes, it should perhaps have done.
- Mm.
Otherwise we would not have needed
sit here today.
What do you think?
Is it possible to save anything?
What the hell do you think? It is clean
Bondi Beach. The only thing missing-
-'s a fucking umbrella in the motherboard.
You have sand in your computer. And what is it?
I do not see what it is.
What is this? Is that hair?
Is it your hair?
Cut bangs at home next time-
And set your PC in a fucking cupboard
if you can not keep clean around you.
The problem is that you're so damn noob.
You will with noobiga me questions.
- Noob...?
- Noob!
Picking out a Pentium II in machinery
so, you can manage for a while.
With Excel and everything.
Put ​​a postitlapp on the bulletin board
so that we know what you did.
Okay.
So now, Kenneth.
(Door closes)
Hello?
- Thank you.
-Go.
It must be tough
to be cleaner and...
The clash a bit, but I go
a course now, so I'll live.
Well, that's good.
Now we approach Prästberget.
We'll be there in about 15 minutes. Come on.
Roger that. 15 minutes.
I wait until further then.
- How the hell do you succeed with that?
- Throw the stone.
- It's not loud then?
- Climb then.
That they just can. There are four,
five times we have been here for years.
- Snorkels Kids on Cocillana.
- Cocillana?
Cough. It is totally passé
with plastic and glue now.
Now it cough syrup.
It is the thing.
(Electrical buzzing)
(beep)
Renew your profile, press 1.
I'm about average, I guess.
With a few extra pounds
as I'm about to work off.
A friend used to say
I look-
-as a mixture of Ola Ullsten
and Ted Danson.
on the sitcom "Cheers", that is.
Uh... the best of both worlds,
maybe you could say.
Remember what we said now, Bridget.
Breathe gently through your nose,
out through your mouth.
(Breathing nervously)
So yes. This gârju good.
This is going great.
Yeah, now it's Jörgen. Then you
pinch voltage on PL 4046th
Prästberget, four, zero, four, six.
Is it disconnected,
cut and dried?
- Yes?
- Hey, you, Stig.
- Hello? Repeat.
- Yes, I can.
PL four, zero, four six Prästberget.
Is that clear, disarmed?
- Uh, roger.
- Perfect. Then we make tonight. Goodbye.
- It's just to run!
- Here we go!
Okay.
(Screams)
Please contact Kenneth Skoglund.
Damn, I have no... Fan!
- I just wanted to so a little seed.
- Yes, I understand that.
What the hell is it now?
Yes, this is good, this, Bridget.
Do not worry, it's fine.
(Hysterical women cry)
Roland?
He may be here tonight, then we take
him to the ICU tomorrow.
It is not life threatening, just
to oversee, so we'll see tomorrow-
-when he wakes up the way he is.
- Roland? Do you hear me?
- I think not.
BSOD - Blue Screen Of Death.
Sauron?
Birgitta? Motherfucker.
What happened, Birgitta?
Welcome to Loveline.
... You have no new messages.
(toot)
(un, m, m)
This is estimated
repair costs.
Accepted tort filings,
far. As the pile Iärju increase.
And here is
incoming business invoices.
And then we have our outgoing invoices,
incomes.
- What do you want me to do with it?
- Burn it up.
Wear it down in the parking lot
and burn it up.
I joked,
but it's a tempting idea.
Burning up all that shit.
Burn down the whole building.
So are the days of trouble later.
You can let the papers remain
and wear down the rest to Kenneth.
Ask him when you can finally
expect a full report.
Yeah, maybe I'll help you carry.
It is not necessary. I run bodypump
three times a week, so I'm good.
Yes... it is a heavy yoke
you have got shoulder after the old man.
Designate a focus group. Now we are reforming.
Young and fresh, we have.
And in color.
So... They're for you.
Valter wondering if you finish
with the quarterly report.
No, my computer is still
for repair. But it will come.
Ouch, man.
Damn.
Try to turn it on now.
This was certainly yours.
- Is it running?
Yes, but the screen was a bit small.
Relax, we're not finished.
As.
Ta-Daah!
It's good to go.
You know it is
the internal size that matters, right?
Now suck it in the coffee arm.
What's the password?
"Blizzard".
How do you spell it...?
How much will you remember?
Do you remember anything
from the accident itself?
- No.
- And after that?
When you woke up, you will remember
anything of what I said?
You wondered how I felt.
And then...
... Told you what had happened,
that I had been in an accident.
And...
... I had gotten
current through the body.
3a  I something more?
Um...
You told me that I...
... That I had the power...
... By the arm...
... And down in. .. scrotum.
And that it had gone out in. ..
... Testicles then.
Then out of the harness, safety harness.
And then...
... So you tell me
I could not have children.
- Have you told Karin yet?
- No, I have not done.
I think you should.
And I think you ought
be glad you're alive, Roland.
You have to start at the end,
simply.
These kinds of accidents usually get
a much more tragic...
-... A much more tragic outcome.
- Mm.
- But you're alive, Roland.
- Yes.
You live and can walk.
- Or did they?
- Mm.
- It's good.
- Yes.
- Have you purchased balloon?
- Mm.
You should sue the bastard.
Release a tarantula
just like that, right in the face.
- Tarantella.
- Damn, that is.
There must be
some kind of law against that sort of thing.
- Yes, gross misconduct or something.
- Yes, you feel it.
- But apparently it was my own fault.
- Asch.
Yes, I think so anyway -
tuning the därjäveln once and for all.
- But I guess I can not do.
- Yes, tuning the bastard.
- You can not sue people.
- Yes, I think so.
Tuning the bastard
and head to Majorca for money.
- Berit, you can not.
- Why not?
We have a date tonight.
Lisa Karlsson? Frank Björklund?
Sonja Andersson?
Veronica Heikkinen?
Valter Sigvardsson.
I congratulate you all.
Raise your hand again, so we see that
we counted correctly. Six pieces with me.
Congratulations.
Rest of you NCK unfortunately not place this year
in the focus group. We thank you.
So... you can leave us now,
so we'll get to work.
Time is money, as I said.
- Ulla, I read your name?
-Uh... yeah, it...
... That... yeah, it was... that I heard.
No, I guess I did not really know.
It was Lisa Karlsson, Frank Björklund,
Sonja, Veronika and Valter.
And then there was Ulla there.
Please Ulla, do not start again
with this.
- It's new train all the time.
- No, it does not.
You said that last year too.
Ulla, I am extremely sorry,
but you're not the one we are looking for this year.
We hope for next year...
You have just opened the gates
to hell, just so you know it!
(Slams the door)
Yes. What a star-studded bunch, huh?
A marvelous team. Are you tagged?
Welcome to Loveline.
Push your personal code.
You have a new message.
Hello, "I called Tarja.
I heard of your... your profile
in Love / ine.
And I'd love to meet you.
I think we match each other.
I love Ted Danson. Troubled
funny in that "Three men and a baby."
in touch. My code is twelve,
nineteen thirty-seven. Hugs and kisses.
Congratulations.
No!
- Hey! How does it work?
- God, you scared.
It's fine, I'm almost finished.
You, uh, we need to talk.
- What if?
- Ohoj!
- Cake,
- H not!
- We'll talk after work.
Yes,
And then angles you up.
But... huh? Would you eat this?
Yes, it is only today.
Karin's parents will.
We have nowhere else to sit.
You can set it there.
We'll put it in the center here.
- How is the situation then?
- It's great.
- Or what do you mean?
Yes, no, or I guess it is...
Yes, how you feel.
The Iåterju good about it is great.
No, it's just the
to go and think.
- On what?
-Voltage supposed to be off.
It was... the excitement was on.
So one gârju and think a little...
- Why? How could it happen?
- Yeah.
No one knows yet.
The hâllerju on and investigate that.
We're on hearing the work environment authority,
so... well, we'll see.
- May I ask you a question?
-Mm.
Littereringen - remember it?
- PL 4046 is the well? What then?
- Yes, but are you sure?
Wondering if I'm sure of it?
Yes, uh...
We've been there a thousand times type,
so yes. What's the question?
Are you honest and say it is so, then
I believe in you.
- If I'm honest?
- Yes.
If you say it is 4046
then I get to believe in you.
It is well clearly you have faith in me.
What the hell are you doing?
- Are you stupid? It's not my fault.
- I'm not stupid.
- No, but you may take and give to you.
- I have become sterile.
What, sterile?
How so sterile? What?
We can not have children.
NOW. Igor! Now!
Yes, it's alive!
Can you stop scratching?
You must anoint with ointment of those.
- Roland...
- Wow, you have spilled a little there.
- Take some of the pants too.
- Roland balls went up in flames.
He can not get any child anymore
Because of the accident.
- What, flames?
- The electricity went through my body...
... And out between his legs.
He ​​can not... He Became sterile.
- God. Huh?
- Yes.
- What says Karin?
- Karin? He has not...
He's gonna tell tonight.
Karin does not know anything yet.
No, but I supposed
put parquet ago.
This is only until further
while you run in and out.
It works pretty well anyway.
- What will the parquet then?
- Yes, that's the big question.
- I sägerju laminate.
- Yes, and I say dark oak.
Okay.
Beware the nails of the feet only.
And here is the children's room.
- I want it pink for the day.
- Ah, it's time now.
I'll be knocked up to autumn with
delivery to summer, it said.
- And you can deliver, then?
- Yes, I hope so.
Then it's calcium that apply.
Calcium, folic acid and cranberries.
- Now, if you want a girl.
- And hold the scrotum hot, Roland.
- It did Bosse when we got you.
- Mom...!
He received 40,000 volts right in the package
so it can not be something problem.
- Right, Roland?
No, no.
Ha! Contrary, as the skipper said,
and put the stern to the wind. Cheers!
And let's drown the salte fan
with a ball in the blow hole.
Tjo, tjoo!
Tough, tough, tough, tough, tjo, tjo, tjo!
- What a fucking blowhole?
-It's "Moby Dick."
When he sets off from the port
so says Captain Ahab it.
- In the version then?
- Yes, it's the last. But...
- Yeah, right... Tp (30.
-Shell
I am the strongest woman
on this planet.
Well... There he lay,
-with arms hopkrullade like this.
Aaron, there are surely more spiders
for you out there.
Not like Sauron.
But... now I really feel guilty.
Is it my fault?
No, Bridget, you may not think so.
A tarantella is
a wayward creature-
and it makes the as it wants,
when it wants and how it wants.
- It must of course respect.
- Mmm.
You are so tender, Aaron, do you know?
And you, it's like...
... You know everything about everything.
And you know everything about me.
Yes, Bridget,
this with doctor and patient...
Bridget, I do not believe it.
- But you're probably just trainers?
- Yes, I've actually diploma.
But the friendship that we have grown now...
I think we should continue-
-be friends and...
Yes, I have a little gift here
to you. Here you are.
- What is that something?
- It's a aftonhud.
- Aftonhud?
- It's a prototype.
It is not on the market yet.
It is soothing to sleep at night-
and also protects against mites
and small arachnids.
It's a damned alert thing,
I must say.
- I may well not me on this?
-Well, it is stretch.
- Well.
- Yes.
- It is soft.
-Sure
There is a little gap here also
for those times you need.
So, with Velcro.
It's actually really handy.
(Velcro ritsch)
Ja...
Excuse me, can I get a knife and fork?
- Does it taste good, Ted Danson?
- Why, you... please tell me Kenneth.
Well, Tarja, it... Four small dishes
's no surprises.
But still good and affordable.
And it's a little of each.
- And yours?
- Let's not talk about me.
We'll talk about you.
What do Mr. Danson if
more than to eat Chinese food?
I brought a small gift.
Welcome.
- I make candles.
- Make candles? Oh, oh, oh, oh!
It is pretty damn interesting
how to play with shapes-
and add both flavor and color.
Smell.
Smells like coconut.
There is like that aroma candles.
Yes, scented candles.
I call it djungelkub.
You can do pretty much as you want.
And even with beeswax,
which is a bit of a classic-
-one hand rolls.
Yes, then there will be enough
very much dip the wick.
What do you like?
Kuk.
Cock, dick, dick, dick.
And some scrapbooking.
With cocks.
How to Open a bottle of raki
and cozy up to it at my house?
I have not finished eating yet.
It included fried banana and ice cream.
- I can fry your path!
- And so the day tomorrow...
(Tarja sings Finnish tango)
- What I would remind you of?
- What?
There was something important we would talk about.
Um... Yes, that's right.
Well, Karin...
Mm?
- I sat and thought about the floors.
- Mm.
That we can run laminate
-instead of parquet.
- I see no difference.
- There are many square meters.
So we spararju few hundred or thousand
maybe.
Maybe we can put it in the kids room.
And try to get it done.
Yes, exactly. Exactly.
There was little so I thought.
Hell.
(Finnish Tango)
Grrr!
Mister Danson...
Hoochie coochie woman!
Komsi, Komsi!
Sooo, come, come, Komsi.
MJGU. grrr...
- Mister Danson.
- My name is Kenneth.
Meow!
No, it is fully here. Be on time.
So maybe you have time to lift.
How's quarterly report,
Kenneth? Huh?
I can not understand that man.
- You should struta the bastard.
- Struta?
I was strutad in Cambridge.
In the middle of the lesson. Hell, yeah.
What the hell...?
- Kjell?
- Shoot,
- Where  in  hell  is  my computer?
- Now we have made this...
If you look in your desk drawer.
See? It's a Blackberry.
It has Excel installed.
- You can run with it for a while.
- I've saved stuff on the computer.
Look down and you'll see a usb stick.
Where's your stuff saved.
-  But have you  cooked  my   old computer?
- It was stone dead and cremated.
I need to finish this today.
Do you understand? Kjell, Kjell, Kjell?
There have been some more paper.
Tord know what this will
mean for us financially?
No, for all väntarju
on your report.
- Will it ready today, you think?
- I have no computer.
No, I see it. Tord want to meet you
today in the conference ten thirty.
He sounded pissed.
(Phone signal)
Hello "...
- Roland?
- Yes?
Why have you locked?
It's kind of time now.
I thought we would take the opportunity.
I just showered and should then
to hit... meeting with the physiotherapist.
- So I do not have time.
-What, you do not have time?
So, you can open?
What happens when our dreams
to start a family falls apart?
How should we respond?
How to deal with grief?
Is there help to search?
The answer is: yes, there is.
Hello, my name is Ruben Holmgren
and is licensed doctor,
fertility clinic here in Orebro
where we help the barren
to be fruitful.
It is a stressful time for many.
And sometimes, you can not really
as you want.
But many forget is
the doors
actually opened
when the other is closed.
hang with, and I'll explain.
Scrotum, the intricate collection
point for millions of sperm.
body's own self-temperate byastuga.
Hello?
Hello!
My god, what have you done?
Maybe I should change the planer
or it's stress upon you.
It flared up yesterday,
and since then I have been lying awake.
- Does it show much?
- Yes.
- I'll see if I do not have anyone ointment.
- Fuck that.
Where is he?
Does he on the floor?
Roland is the physiotherapist,
by hand.
I had thought that we would
talk about this all three.
He probably told you
with the accident and all.
Yes, he has.
But it's nothing you should go around
and remorse over.
It was an accident.
It was not directly your fault, Hey.
Shit, I thought you'd be
to pieces over this.
How then, do you mean?
He has talked about this
with family and kids and everything.
We can still have a family.
We can still have children.
(Communication radio blips)
a bitch!
You fucking bitch!
-  Yes'?
-Jorgen, it's Magnus here.
You should be on the work environment authority
about the investigation at two o'clock.
Yes, yes, yes, okay. What the hell?
By discipline, we learn,
not true, Kenneth?
It seems terse make
example of someone like this, but what do you say?
A for once,
twice is a habit-
-but what is the third, fourth,
fifth, sixth, seventh time?
This is more like a behavior.
And so we do not want it.
So we can not have the
of an established business.
So thank you for today.
Lesson is over.
Valter is coming
with the PR agency PR Hanneman & C0
-As we have heard many good things about.
We will take a short stretch our legs so long.
No, but it is smooth,
because it's so darn easy to hold.
And environmentally friendly.
- I'll rest of the day.
- Really? Do you really have time for that?
I have a fever.
Have you filed quarterly report?
Kenneth? Kenneth?
Kenneth
(small dog barks)
What is this fucking crazy talk!
(Dog barks)
Yes, quick question...
How many of you like Stalis?
Huh? Just - quite a lot, huh?
Take a look at this guy then.
This is my son Emil.
He ​​also likes Stalis.
Though he is only three or four years old.
And a half.
He ​​is four and a half years old.
It's clear as hell
that Clark Kent sleep well at night-
-when he is liked
of such a diverse audience. Huh?
- Four and half to sixty.
- Yes, there is a way to go to sixty.
Is not it time for Unicorn
getting a face?
Your own Superman? Here is
a little thing that we have outlined.
4G man.
Huh?
We can leak in the roof, and I'll
powerpointa you through it a little.
(Mast falls)
(chainsaw)
(motor legend Silence)
Hey! That's for damn I
who is the victim here! Karin!
- You were supposed to have said something!
- I do after all it Now!
But what, now? How do you feel
to feel like a fucking idiot
-When I'm on the last
to hear about it!
Take it easy now.
Relax, sweetie, calm. Please.
Take it easy now. Now we sit
and talk about it like adults.
- As we look at the options.
-Who fucking alternative?
What many forget is the
doors that open when others close.
Now you are ridiculous, Karin.
Karin?
Now this is the way that we do
a thorough troubleshooting on this.
We back and go step by step to the accident
-
and try to collect as much information
as it ever goes.
You know we've heard-
-At your inkall and it's something with
it is not right really.
And so we talked to Stig Ulander
who was working that day.
- Do you know him?
- Yes, do...
Of course, we talk every now and then and we
have been seen, but I can not say...
Path Ulander can not confirm
your inkall this day.
Can he confirm my inkall
to the control center?
This sounds really...
I talked to him...
I talked to him twice
and it is he who has responded...
Excuse me, can you just...
Take it easy?
No, she can not, she stenograferar
for our conversation.
This is weird shit.
Where was the Stig?
Stig was tied to the toilet
with a tennis ball in his mouth-
and with droopy pants
to the ankles.
There is no immorality involved,
if you thought that.
But it was very traumatizing
Stig.
(Jörgen hear it all distorted)
... get something out of it...
I... I did not do anything wrong.
I think you are absolutely right dotted
with this. Congratulations, brilliant!
It will be great to see how the
receive this IRL, in real life.
Yeah, I know.
Raise the roof, match
Tjo!
Now we distill this. Huh?
No, no. So we go off on
goodies ago. Now we distill this.
Tord, I think it's a little mystique
about this thing.
What? Now, uh... take up the rest.
Yes, we have no more.
- We have no more?
- I just bought it for 1200 bucks.
And you can not pull it off either.
I'm sorry.
Cheers to you, Dad.
Now we are back on track.
- Maybe it's the catch...
- Shut up.
- Is there a Luger or?
- Hell if I know.
Because if it's a Luger
should sit a catch...
(Shots)
(tinnitus howl)
Is there a little sore when I...
... Press a little here?
Oh no. It smarts a little.
If I turn it to the side then?
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
And then you have these eliminated
both on the neck and cheek.
How long have you had it?
Yes, it came a few there late.
It was quite a while ago, now...
So, just poof, poffade up and...
And so it is that dizziness
and a little tingling or what...
I saw your Unicom jacket outside.
- What are you working on, Jorgen?
- I am electrician.
It's very diverse.
We do lots of stuff.
Now we have installed the radio masts
and transmitters, most of mobile.
Is there a vulnerable environment, do you think?
I think the radiation levels.
We mäterju of levels.
Then know and stay below it.
Yes, but you know, every little helps.
Is not that what they say?
No, I do not
what you mean by that.
I think we see
a severe EHS here.
Yes, that is...
Electrical hypersensitivity is perhaps most hittepå.
Yes, if it's something psychological...
No, your body can tolerate only a certain amount of
with electromagnetic radiation-
-before saying from
and become hypersensitive.
- It is a kind of allergy.
- When it goes away? It disappears well?
Well...
Now you'll get anything from me here.
, Hi-
, Hello,
Now you'll
contact details of me here.
This is a support group.
Very safe environment.
They know much more about this than I do.
If you have any questions.
And I'm sure you have.
Good luck now. Ugh, yes...
- So, you should get a swab of the ear.
-Oh.
Yes, it was nicely shot.
It's a shame that it's just a painting
and the old man is dead long time ago.
Sorry.
Come and sit.
I understand you had a setback
and uphill-
-with your computer and the quarterly report
Then it was well
damn stupid of me-
-to struta you for all...
But I do not know, I have a little...
I'm not so good at that
with people and expressions.
- Cheers to you.
- Shell
It's good it here.
Sorry.
I gave my first girl in school-
-
of an engagement ring molded saffron.
For  Jimmy Sandstrom on Angleramp
had said it was worth more than gold.
And it is well to be sure, but...
They kept on messing with me too
once.
- Saffron?
- Yes, it was expensive wines.
I had might as well have purchased
a bag Iussebullar.
What, hypersensitive?
What does that mean?
Well, honey, it is well that the
allergy whatsoever, I understand.
Some can not stand apples.
I can not stand electricity.
- Do we stay in the dark for life?
-I have no idea.
This is why I want to hit
and hear me.
- Can it really be here?
- Yes.
It may well not fucking be.
A careful examination of radiation risks must be done.
Before subjecting an entire population-
-partly for a new kind of radiation
that nobody knows anything about-
and partly a marked increase
of microwave radiation.
I shudder to the core
when I hear of the 4G network-
-as they kick off the fourteenth.
On Friday!
We then? We? Where are white road?
We are refugees in our own country.
You can even hear how fucking crazy it sounds.
Deprived, damn!
I'll tell you
that none of us is safe anymore.
- Would you like that?
- No.
- Would you like that?!
No, I thought so.
So... hell for humanity!
Bloody armjävel! Watch the damn thing.
The kommerju never grow out.
- Have not we sacrificed enough now?
- J0.
- Have not we sacrificed enough?
- Have not we sacrificed enough?!
- Yes!
- Have not we...
- Yes! Jooo!
Jooo!
Jo!
Ja... Five minutes,
five minutes, five minutes.
There is coffee and buns.
Hello.
(Whispering)
Wood oven baked.
- Go ahead.
Thanks.
Oops!
You know what I like about you?
Guile you will rapporteurs with.
You rush in with a wad of ear
and think you can force your in-
-take part of our agenda, eat our
buns. Do not you think I get it?
I did not know you had a meeting.
The doctor has told
that I would get in touch with you.
- Doctor?
- Yes.
Mhm? Funny feeling much?
Lemonade in your hands?
Cheeks? Is this true?
Is not it better that you tell
what you think I can help you with-
-instead of me to stand here
and guess which thing ye?
I need help elsanering.
Elsanera Pokey... Not?
No. Sure, it was -92.
Now it is not -92.
What you need is an oasis.
- An oasis?
- An oasis.
Fuck!
(VERY)
Ooh!
Motherfucker!
- Haha! I think it will be fun.
- No one will take anything, but fun it is.
- But with Goebbels is a bit much.
- Do you like it?
I delete it, it is gone.
- It is fully here.
- No, it's not full.
Make Kenneth,
you can take my place.
What the hell kind von oben attitude?
I have a gift for you.
Then you would be able to have Excel on the left-
and anything Word document on the right,
so you can multitask after all.
- It will be good?
- What's that smell here?
Is that de la Renta or?
- No, no, no, it ärjasminmynta.
- Yeah.
It's from the lights.
Yes, I can see.
I make them myself.
- Yes, you can... You may take one of these.
- Really? Yes please.
- I call it venus cake.
- Penis Cake? Did you say that?
No, Valter, venus cake.
It actually smells a little cake.
- Yes, very muskig.
-The smells, the more when they are lit.
Here we can not stand by and drälla. We have
press release and launch at. 16.
Yes, we get the wedge. - Hello, Kenneth.
"I make my own light."
It screams serial killer on the man.
- It's good that he has a hobby.
- They said about Jeffrey Dahmer too.
Make sure to be down before sex.
Take it easy with that.
I go to Jorgen and install.
Focus, Ulla.
(Warning signal, operating machinery)
Prästberget?
No, I'm sick.
I can not even talk in this one.
Cell phone.
Ring Roland. He's back now.
He ​​may need to get there in therapy.
Mm. Well, where were we lucky.
Yes, hello to you.
- What the hell is that?
- It's an oasis.
- And will you live in?
- Yes, for a little while then.
Sure, Sorro.
There are major raw cozy out.
It is perfect! Right down there alone!
Come on.
Perfect!
Roland?
We have received less downtime.
It would be great if you could check out.
Hey, Roland? Do you hear me?
- Prästberget?
- Yeah, right.
- Where  is  Jorgen? Have you asked Jorgen?
- He is sick.
- With some kind of fur allergy.
- Yes,  I'm there in twenty.
When Unicom began building out its network
here in the early 90's
-nobody had
really knows his limits.
For us, it was as intolerant
to live in a giant microwave.
OOPS. Well, damn.
Expansion goes on.
But there is no one who cares.
- AII is about money.
- Yes. Well, maybe so.
_ * Huh?
- Neh nothing
I get so angry sometimes.
We are a few out here in the compound
sometimes, then, now and then-
-try, we think of something a little rebellion.
So there and then.
And last so...
Damn, that was the blackout in the whole town.
You must have noticed it.
Strange that.
Now we approach Prästberget.
We'll be there in about 15 minutes. Come on.
Roger, 15 minutes.
I await the time being then.
Yes, then it's Jörgen.
Then you pinch voltage
on PL 4046, Prästberget.
-  Yes'?
-Hey you, Stig.
- Hello? Repeat.
Yes, I can.
PL 4046, Prästberget.
Is that clear, disarmed?
that.
Motherfucker!
It was hell you talking to me!
The power was supposed to be
You fucking idiot bastard!
You're so fucking fucked in the head!
It's so damn tiring.
No one cares. Get it?
No one cares about us. Then you get
find other ways to make yourself heard.
What, find other ways
to make yourself heard?
- What the hell does that mean?
- You'll see.
(Try to start the petrol engine)
Hello?
What are you doing?
Must all stand there? Someone may well
Hell lookout too.
Nervous?
Just take it easy.
You're a tiger, Tord.
Check, a tiger.
Okay, now I'm out here.
See you soon - "online".
And you, take it easy on those.
Do you have an eye on the situation there
so it syncs with all connections?
(Phone signal)
But...
Ladies and gentlemen!
To-o-o-word Wedin!
Yes! Yes!
Korn on, come on!
Come on!
I say that Nick Borgen:
"We are all the winners."
Although the clouds are heavy
and the curtain went down, we are all winners.
Only we hang with. Not true?
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Hey!
The fourth generation is here.
4G network is here.
A new standard is here.
- Hello, Walter!
-Full / o, Sweden.
How is the situation up at Forge Lake?
It's a bit chilly, I think.
No. And there's no such thing as
bad weather, only bad clothing.
Yes, absolutely.
The latter we can agree with.
Where did you dig up that old
leather coat? German surplus stock?
You look like a little chorizo ​​
in felt hat, I think.
Thanks, Tord.
I thought we could redirect
focus a bit to what you see behind me.
Prästberget and its mast ,
soon be activated.
(cars)
(flasher)
Car!
Where is Roland?
Roland? Roland? Do you hear me?
What the hell?! Uh!
- You take it easy!
- You can not!
We must away!
With our misfortune that the
many companies have to contend with.
But we took the bull by the horns
and are ready to put it behind us,
and lit a small candle
for the future.
Thank you, Valter, for those words. Hear ye.
We are reaching the climax, before the
red light comes on Prästberget-
-I would like to thank our
investors, perhaps most of all...
What the hell?
4G man! Yes! Unicorn King!
So!
(Phone signal)
(Woman whimpers)
(dial tone)
- Cheers to you.
- Yes, bowl.
You motherfucker should have fan
some kind of trophy. Right?
- Pushed you back here all the time?
- You never know.
But hey...
Here, relax a bit now. You've...
- I do not drink.
-Really? No, no.
Then there will be more to us.
Bottoms up.
- What do you have now invented?
-Now, I do not.
- What the hell is going on?
- Fredrik?
- Well, I do not know, everything is just dead.
- What?
- What is it that is dead?
-Everything just went out.
What, extinct?
Can I hit it in there now.
Excuse me.
Ha! Hey you! Hello there!
You! Yes, I saw you!
- Forgiven,
- You come down and pick it up.
- ÖQOna-fucking-böjg
-yep.
\ \ \
Come.
- Do you live?
- We think so.
You...
Karin, I would have said something from
start. It was just so damn wrong.
You know something? I am with child.
Huh?
Is it mine?
(Karin laughs)
- But how?
- It must have been after the crayfish party.
Have you woken up on the wrong side today
or what is this about?
It could well be said.
All week.
- But now it's over.
- What?
Yes, the week. It's Friday.
Is it?
- Who is it you remind me of?
- I do not know. Ted Danson...
Now wait a minute.
The Iâterjättekonstigt, but...
I have a painting at home in the hall.
On one of those crying babies.
- Have you seen them?
- Yes.
When I see you now
I think of that picture.
It is really nice.
You look like Barbamama.
Hello.
- Where have you been?
- Oh, yes...
- Itch a lot?
- It tingles most now.
There is less visible
Now when you start getting stubble.
It's fine, I think.
- Need a light?
- Shit, you scared.
Are you really sure about this?
(Sighs heavily)
Fits you?
Mmm!
It smells almost like shampoo.
Yes, it is...
It's lavender and thyme extracts.
Self-mixing.
And this is dyed horsehair.
I call her "Anne of Green Gables."
What cute.
I'm actually very happy myself.
This is probably
the best I've done.
Oops. But...
God, how great.
- OOPS.
These buggers generates enough power.
- Are not they lovely?
- Very.
They are good against sweating too,
it said.
Among other things.
(Velcro ritsch)
Handy.
Text: Thomas Jansson
Scandinavian Text Service 2012