Subtitles by DramaFever
[A Bird That Doesn't Sing]
Episode 7
Lift your face.
What's wrong?
She said something to you?
Was she giving you a hard time?
It's not that.
No.
No, Mom.
Don't come near me.
Was that her mom?
What?
Oh, nothing.
Here.
For twelve years,
I lived getting beat up.
You think I would be scared of this?
Dying?
I'm not scared at all.
I don't care if you harass me,
just don't harass my daughter!
Oh Yu Mi, I never abandoned you.
Seven years ago, you were
the one who left me.
From now on, I'll protect you.
I'll never let go
of these hands ever again.
My daughter...
I'll protect you.
Ms. Oh, please go to the VIP room.
Please go to the Soo Yeon Cosmetics
headquarters in Sinsa Dong.
A little more on the inner lips.
I love it.
Nice, right?
I see why you were
so adamant about this.
It's a great idea.
I told you, my Ha Nui did it again.
"My Ha Nui"?
Okay.
- Ms. Oh, are you finished?
- Yes.
Everyone is going
to talk about how pretty
the female employees at
Soo Yeon Cosmetics are.
Everybody looks so good.
How about if you include
average people as models?
They can be of all different ages.
That's a good idea.
I think that would be nice.
This one will be a big hit too.
You know she doesn't
just complement anyone.
Oh, yeah.
Way to go, we rock, yay, yay...
On that note, I'll treat
everyone to lunch today!
Let's go.
Of course, you don't say
you'll treat me to lunch.
- Come with us, Director.
- No thanks.
I have lunch plans.
Sexy Q came out nice.
And you've got a good
marketing concept.
Your mom must be so proud.
I wish I had a daughter like you.
Hold on.
Yu Mi!
Let's go eat lunch together.
You didn't even eat breakfast.
I'm not that hungry.
You go eat.
Yu Mi!
You haven't been smiling, sleeping,
or eating well for these past few days.
If I were you, and you were me,
what would you say?
I'm so disappointed in myself that
I can't be of any help to you.
Give me a hint.
How can I help you?
I just don't have much appetite.
Did you hear from your mother?
Why do you ask that so suddenly?
That customer that walked
out of your makeup room...
Is she her?
No...
She's my regular customer.
- What do you want to eat?
- Something expensive.
Ha Nui, don't worry about me.
Go eat something good.
I'll eat if I get hungry.
I just don't have much appetite.
You worked hard,
you should come with us.
Let's just say that I ate.
Yu Mi...
What does it feel like
to have no appetite?
How is it possible
It drives me nuts that
I have so much appetite.
- What diet?
- You can eat.
- No, I need to diet.
- What are you talking about?
I feel like there's a wall.
It's so upsetting.
But I'm still so worried about her.
"Let's not care.
She probably wants to be alone."
"Let's wait until
she feels like talking."
I know all this
- but I still get worried.
- That's who you are.
Does she have something
that she can't share with me?
She didn't say anything
to your mother, right?
She isn't eating at all.
I'm afraid she'll faint.
Do you have any idea
how I can help her?
What is it?
What is it now?
Healing food for the one you love?
Healing food.
I'll be right there.
I just need a few minutes.
Where are you going?
- Going out for lunch?
- Yes.
I'll be back.
- Shes a bit strange these days, no?
- She must be worried about something.
- But she's not the type to talk.
- I feel bad for her mother-in-law.
She's a talented girl,
but she has a bad personality.
Ha Nui's the one with
great personality.
She's got a lot of heartache,
but she can't show it.
She has no choice
but to keep it all in.
Yu Mi reminds me of the old you.
I don't like gloomy people.
They're so frustrating.
Don't even think about hiding
me in a corner somewhere.
- Sit down.
- There are so many people here.
- Come on, let's get out.
- When you were twenty-two
and you tried to kill yourself on
that bridge after getting dumped
there were people there
when I dragged you down.
When you blew all your
money on horse racing
and I brought you home when
you were sleeping on the streets
I didn't try to hide you.
Why are you bringing that up now?
Jo Dal Yeon might come to see you.
Why?
Did something happen?
I just met with her.
- We fought a little.
- What?
Why would you provoke that crazy woman?
When I think about that night,
I pee in my sleep.
You fought when you should
be crawling before her?
Why would you poke around the beehive?
She harassed Yu Mi.
How can I do nothing?
I put her in her place.
- Where?
- In front of Yu Mi.
What?
I apologize in her place.
My mom made a mistake.
How touching.
What's with you two?
- I'm sorry.
- Why are you always so sorry?
I'm so sick and tired of
hearing that from you.
Are you scared that
I'll do something to your mom?
Or have you still not been able
to get rid of your nice girl complex?
I'm sorry.
No matter how much you beg,
I won't forgive your mom.
I can't say that I have
nothing to be ashamed of.
But at least I never ran away
with someone else's money.
If people like your mom live well,
how is that fair?
Yu Mi.
I'm really curious.
Are you doing this because
you really care about your mom?
My grandmother raised me
after my mother ran away.
After my grandmother passed away,
I went through so much hardship.
If I ever meet my mother again,
I would never forgive her.
What's your true feeling?
Yu Mi must have been so shocked.
She's such a fragile girl.
Is that why she called me "Madame
after not seeing me for seven years?
- What do you mean?
- She's my own daughter, I know her well.
She's a strong girl.
I really don't know.
So Yu Mi's okay.
You irked that crazy lady, what
if she treats you even worse?
Get 300 million in Nam Gyu's name
and send it to me quick.
You think 300 million is a joke?
Do you know what kind
of trouble he'll be in
if they find out he spent company money?
After everything he's done
for the company
he can't even touch that money?
What a good life...
Soo Yeon Cosmetics was nothing
but a small start-up company.
Who do they think made
the company grow this much?
Using a few hundred million won
is embezzlement?
Get me the money by today.
Nam Gyu's working hard trying
to expand into the Chinese market.
I should be helping him, not thinking
about ways to steal company money!
My conscience won't allow me.
Oh my God...
No way.
You should go in, first.
I'll be right there.
Let's go.
Hello.
What are you doing here?
I was just passing by, and I saw a cafe.
You work here?
Yes, I wasn't sure if
it was really you.
You look so elegant.
Have a cup of coffee, my treat.
No.
It's good to see you here.
And I want to thank you
for putting ointment on Min Ji.
What the heck?
Why are they so close?
They are smiling.
They know each other?
What the heck is going on?
Seeing you out like this,
you seem so different.
You are so glamorous.
I'll take it as a compliment.
Our department just
launched a new lipstick.
Maybe that's why, but I've
been noticing everyone's lips.
It must be a job-related illness.
I don't think so.
What?
An artist getting cervical disc
or intervertebral disc...
Someone who gets varicose veins
from working while standing all day...
Those are what you call
job-related illnesses.
People who do hard labor
will laugh at you.
Yeah?
I guess so.
Oh.
I work for the product development team.
We want to use employees and other
regular people to model our new lipstick.
I would like you to be part of it.
As a model?
I'm taken aback.
And a little flattered.
When do I have to let you know by?
Tonight?
I have a cooking class
in the afternoon.
You can call me tomorrow morning.
You take cooking lessons?
Getting ready for marriage?
I don't know what happened to my sister.
She can't sleep or eat well these days
so I want to make her yummy food.
And my dad's birthday is coming up,
so I want to cook for him myself.
You are very considerate,
unlike young people these days.
I'll think about it, and call you.
Okay, I'll be waiting.
Then.
You want to cook for
your father's birthday?
Too bad, by then, he'll
be over at our house.
Keep dreaming.
He should have received
the gift by now.
Just like the green forest
that grows despite
the heavy rainstorms and strong sunrays
using nature's wisdom
Soo Yeon Cosmetics will bring you
clean and clear complexion.
We will bring you...
Who is there?
Mr. Oh?
This package arrived from Korea.
From Korea?
Yes.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Yu Mi.
Wow, I wonder what she sent.
"Package was delivered"?
What's this?
Mom!
Your mom's not here, yet.
Should I call her?
- What?
- Your daughter came by.
She came to apologize for you.
She works in your place.
And she apologizes in your place.
What kind of a mother are you?
I told her that I won't
accept her apology.
Mi Ja.
I'm very angry today.
I'm sure you're ready to pay
for irritating me, right?
You better be prepared.
Do you understand, Chun Mi Ja?
She's not picking up?
Let's get back in the car.
We can drop off your friends,
and come back later.
You're that cute girl.
You must be the princess
that moved in next door.
You live in unit 302, right?
- Yes.
- Why is she going back on the bus?
I can't get in touch with her mom.
Do you want me to take you home?
Yeah, Mi Ja.
Chun Soo Chang.
You better take care of it
by tonight, got it?
Mi Ja, Mi Ja!
Yes.
I'm on my way there now.
Our neighbor?
Will you do that for me?
Yes, please tell her that
I'll go pick her up later.
Okay.
Finally, I'll get to go to
Nam Gyu's house today.
My brother, Attorney Sung Soo!
Prosecutor Park!
What brings you here?
I came to see you.
- You don't believe that, do you?
- Of course, not.
Investigative files from
Macheon murder case.
I have to take on this case.
You know Dad is worried that you are
taking on all these scary cases, right?
What case do we have
that's not scary?
Did you hear that
Professor Lee Joong Myung
will take office as
the director of the law school?
His students are getting together.
Let's go.
- Today?
- Yeah.
Nobody will be home anyway.
Mom went out to transform
herself from head to toe.
It looked like she was going
out for a date with Dad.
I need to go to Min Suk's place today.
Oh, that chef?
Why?
- You're going to take cooking lessons?
- Yeah.
What?
Are you serious?
I can't just keep on making
abalone porridge.
Park Sung Soo,
you're the best.
You put into action what
other people only dream about.
- You're the best.
- The best.
I need to get going.
We stayed in the same tummy for
ten months, eating the same food.
How can we be so different?
We drank the same breast milk
and the same formula.
Where does your filial piety come from?
You talk so much
when I need to get going.
You better control
your drinking today.
You better not call me all drunk.
I'm going.
Mom would have been so disappointed
if she only gave birth to me.
Thank you for being born with me!
Madame, are you sure it was
okay to leave the hospital?
I had no idea what to do
when you collapsed in front of me.
I'm okay now.
It's not just once or twice.
This is crazy.
You should have just given up
on the twins then.
Don't say that.
Why is my illness the kids' fault?
I'm not making anything up.
You wouldn't be sick if you
had take your medicine then.
There's a right time
to receive treatment.
You didn't put
a single pill to your mouth
saying it's bad for the baby.
You didn't even drink a drop
of tonic medicine, either.
It's a miracle that you spent
ten months like that.
You're the one who loved the babies
the most when they were born.
I did love them.
But who knew you would suffer
all your life like this?
Now, they are all grown up,
and they think they grew up on their own.
I get so upset.
It's because of them that
you suffer like this.
They don't even know that
you risked your life to have them.
That's not true.
You better not say any
of that in front of the kids.
I kept my mouth zipped
for twenty-five years.
Why would I say anything now?
I'm just venting right now to
you because I'm so upset.
Mom.
It seems like you're
in a good mood today.
I got energized after
eating your abalone porridge.
I'm on my way to see Dad.
Good.
Go enjoy your time together.
- And enjoy your meal.
- Okay.
See you later.
Let's make a toast.
- Nice to see you.
- It's been a long time.
I hear you have something up your sleeve
for the National Assembly Inspection.
I'm not doing anything different
from others, nothing special.
There's a rumor that you're
living at your office these days.
What big item do you have on your hands?
You might get kicked out of
the house by your wife.
What's he talking about?
At our age, it's harder to please
our wives than the citizens.
- Don't you agree?
- That's true.
You have a guest coming in.
We're expecting someone else?
No, everyone's here.
Honey...
What's going on?
I thought she was too sick to come out.
What's wrong with you?
Worrying is an illness, too.
Why did you do that when
she's completely fine?
Since you came all the way here,
please come in.
No.
Please go ahead with your conversation.
I'll get going then.
- Go get her, what are you doing?
- Please excuse me.
Wait...
Look...
Hi.
Hey, Park Sung Soo!
- You really came.
- It's been so long.
Have you been well?
How's your mom doing?
Thanks to you,
she's gotten a lot healthier.
- I'm not late, am I?
- Not at all.
It's my wish to see you be sorry
for being late once.
Please take care of this.
Better if you can put the recipes
on each of the places.
I need to use the bathroom.
Hey, make sure you wash your hands well.
Of course.
Hello.
Can I help you with anything?
Seriously!
What the heck!
You're sitting on my hand!
I'm dead, he is the chef?
Why does he have to be the teacher?
Nice to meet you.
You're not going to cook
like that, are you?
- Pardon?
- Go wash your hands.
And remove your nail polish.
Nail polish too?
Okay.
She seems very familiar...
Why did you put your hands on my butt?
- Are you a pervert?
- Perv...
You were sitting on it
on purpose to trouble me?
Trouble you?
But why is she so nice today?
Out of all the chefs,
why did it have to be him?
I can totally see how
much he will nag.
She doesn't look like the type
to be taking cooking classes.
Are you happy now?
They are all clean now.
Tie your hair.
If I use this, I'll
lose a lot of hair.
Don't leave out any hair,
and tie it tight.
Nobody wants hair in their food.
Okay.
Tight.
Is everybody here?
You're not the chef?
No.
Then why did you give out the recipe
and boss me around?
I never told you that I'm the chef.
If you're not here to chat,
let's listen.
It's very nice to meet all of you.
Hello.
Let's take a look at
the ingredients.
Why did he act like
he's the teacher?
What the heck?
Do you know what's most
important about cooking?
You're not taking notes?
Don't ask me later.
- Take notes.
- I will.
Why did you hit me with your head?
You're the one who stuck
your butt out at my head!
What's going on over there?
Get up.
You shouldn't do this here.
You're here to make healing
food for your loved one, right?
Yes.
We'll start right now while
thinking about that one we love.
I feel a wall between us.
It's so upsetting.
But I still get so worried.
"Let's not care.
She wants to be alone."
"Let's wait until she
wants to talk."
I think this,
but I still get worried.
Yu Mi.
Stop making Ha Nui so worried.
I'm really curious.
Are you doing this because
you're worried about your mom?
If I meet my mother again,
I would never forgive her.
What's your true feeling?
Tae Hyeon.
Don't think about anything.
Close your eyes, and listen.
Dad.
Thank you.
You may feel burdened,
but please do well.
I have your support,
there's nothing I can't do.
I will make our company expand
into the Chinese market.
- Just wait.
- I'm counting on you.
Yu Mi.
I'll be back.
Honey.
Next up, Soo Yeon Cosmetics
will give their presentation.
How the heck am I going to get in there?
No.
Think straight.
This is so wrong.
Chang Soo.
- Hello, President Hong.
- What brings you here?
Nam Gyu is on a business trip in China.
Yes, I know.
I feel so bad when I think about
how he must be working right now.
Yeah.
Even if he said he's okay,
I should have sent someone with him.
- I regret not doing that.
- I'm sure he'll do great.
Don't worry.
I can help you if you
need a signature.
No.
I was on my way out
and just stopped by.
A habit is a hard thing to break.
Then get home safely.
I love you, Boss.
I wonder how he's doing.
He must be feeling the pressure.
That's it for our presentation.
I like that you don't use preservatives
but wouldn't that mean
a short shelf life?
What will you do if products go bad
in the distribution process?
I understand why you are worried.
The first thing people worry about
with natural cosmetics is the shelf life.
So we've researched other ingredients
we can use in place of the preservatives.
This product expires September of 2017.
There's more than two years left.
How is that possible without
using preservatives?
It's possible because
we are Soo Yeon Cosmetics.
Only using natural ingredients
we have the technology to give
this product a long shelf life.
There will be no problem selling this
in the Chinese market.
You can't call a makeup natural just
because it has a few natural ingredients.
We are endlessly developing our unique
ingredients for aroma and moisture
and that's why it's possible.
Please take a look at
the main ingredients
in the product in front of you.
Do you know what the main
ingredient they used is?
Filtered water.
Water.
But Soo Yeon Cosmetics
doesn't use any filtered water.
Instead, we use extracts from
flowers and natural spring water
to continually improve
our customers' complexions.
Are you that confident?
We want to present China
with our natural products.
That is the motto for Soo Yeon Cosmetics.
Welcome.
Mom.
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
Not at all.
Min Ji's such a lovable girl.
- Thanks to her, I had fun.
- Mom, Grandma taught me Korean.
She did?
Wait.
You must be the one
who moved in next door.
Hi, honey.
You finished?
Thank you for working hard.
Yeah.
Hello?
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
It's nothing.
You must have worked
so hard all alone.
I guess we had a guest.
I've been wanting to meet you,
and we finally meet.
Hello.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Can't you see we're the slowest?
Stop being so precise!
Who cares if it's 3 or 5 centimeters?
Come on!
Oh Yu Mi, you look
pretty when you smile.
Anyone even a little impatient
would never get to eat your food...
- Why would you worry about that?
- Take me out of your plan.
Chun Soo Chang!
Nothing will go according to your plan.
We'll see about that.