23.976 English (from SDH)
Are you Kathy Nicolo?
Yeah.
Is this your house?
House of Sand and Fog (2003)
Nadi, of course,
agreed that it was a wonderful idea
to cut down the trees
at our home on the Caspian,
to have the sea spread before us,
to reach infinity with our eyes,
to see forever.
But then, our life went the way of the trees
when the Ayatollahs ripped the soul
out of our beautiful country.
Well, enough.
Today is not a day for the old.
It is a day for the young.
To the future.
To our Soraya.
May she be a happy wife
as she is a bride.
And, perhaps,
she will not forget her poor
mother and father so soon
and return to us and give to us
many little grandbabies.
A father can dream.
He's so tan.
- Retirement has been good to the colonel.
- He's not. He works for Boeing.
He doesn't work for Boeing.
My son works for Boeing.
Who knows what he does now?
# I love you
Es todo. Terminamos.
- Hello.
- Kathy?
- What time is it?
- It's, um, 9:00.
- Mom, it's 6:00 a.m. here.
- I don't think 6:00 a.m. will kill you.
Your father got up at 4:30
every day of his life,
God bless his soul.
So, how's it going?
How's the program?
Fine. I'm fine.
One day at a time, right?
I just hope it's working.
How's everyone there?
Frankie's good.
Salesman of the month again.
You know your brother.
His Lisa's In her seventh month.
Wow.
How's your better half?
Fine.
He's right here.
He's sleeping.
Sleeping? Hmm.
Mom, I'm really tired.
I'm gonna go, okay?
Listen. I almost forgot.
Your Aunt Frances won a trip to Reno.
We're gonna come out on the 18th.
I thought we'd stop by.
The 18th?
Yeah. Two weeks.
Yeah, okay.
Um, Nick's gonna be away
on business, though.
- Again?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
- I'm gonna go, okay, Mom?
- You're still not smoking, right?
- Bye.
'Cause they say it's a slippery...
Just a second!
You Kathy Lazaro?
Yeah. Why?
Due to the nonpayment of business taxes
associated with this property,
the county has petitioned the court
on its behalf to reclaim these costs.
It should come as no surprise to you.
I'm sure you've had ample warning.
We've sent many notices.
Now the house is up
for auction tomorrow morning.
Auction?
What are you talking about?
Are you out of your mind?
There's no smoking In my house.
Hey, Chuck.
'Cause I see your number right here.
Yeah. We gonna meet down there?
Supposed to be a hot one today.
I'd dress lightly if I were you.
It's okay, 'cause I'm not leaving.
I'm afraid you have no choice,
Mrs. Lazaro.
All of your things will be auctioned off
with the property.
Do you want that?
Look, you can't evict me.
I never owed a fucking business tax.
It doesn't make sense.
Okay, well, this is where I get off.
Deputy Sheriff Burdon will assist you
In vacating the property.
Do you have a lawyer?
I can't afford a lawyer.
I'm a house cleaner.
Here's the number
for the legal assistance office.
They may be able to help.
Nothing's written In blood.
You just have to clear out today.
You might be moving back In next week.
In the meantime, maybe you can call
some friends or family.
Stay with them.
There's no one to call.
I'll tell you what.
I know some movers
that owe me a favor.
Brian.
Go down to Safeway
and get some boxes.
Let's help this lady pack up.
Lester.
May I help you?
My car is parked here.
You asked yesterday also.
Oh, oh, what happened to you?
I fell.
- Again?
- Yeah.
Wash up.
Do not get blood on the floor.
The house was repossessed
for tax payment delinquency.
It's got three bedrooms, one bath.
A widow's walk would increase
property value.
What is this "widow's walk"?
A deck on top of the house
so you can see the ocean.
We still got time here.
Feel free to look around.
Nadereh.
Today God has kissed our eyes.
Do you remember
our bungalow on the Caspian,
how I ordered the trees
cut down on the west side
so we may view the sea?
Please, be quiet.
Do you remember how the general
brought his family there for New Year,
how beautiful it was?
What is the matter for you today, Behrani?
Nadi?
I today have bought for us
another bungalow.
I purchased this home
for a price no one would believe.
It is worth two, maybe three times that.
We will live In this home
for a short while
and then sell it and
find one even better.
Nah! Nah!
Perhaps you did not come here
to live like a gypsy.
But I did not come here
to work like an Arab...
to be treated like an Arab.
For four years we have lived
a life we could not afford
and spent almost everything
to marry Soraya with a good family.
This apartment alone has cost
us over $140,000 In rent.
And what of Esmail's
university education?
Soon we will have nothing.
And then you will see what it is like
to walk In the shoes of the gypsies.
So...
tomorrow, you will begin packing,
and there's no more to discuss.
Do not open your lips.
$500? They evicted you
from your house for that?
You got it.
Um, are you staying with friends?
Yeah, I'm with a friend.
- How much is this gonna cost me?
- It's on a sliding scale.
Um, how come you didn't do something
about this earlier?
I did.
I went to the courthouse,
months ago,
and I signed a statement saying
that I never owed a business tax
because I never owned a business.
I even had it certified.
And what about the follow-up mail?
I didn't open it.
It's very important to me that
I get my house back by the 18th.
I'm expecting company.
- When did you sign that letter?
- I don't know.
March?
Well, I hate to be
the bearer of bad news,
but the county's
already sold your house.
What?
- No. They can't do that.
- The auction date's been set for months.
Don't worry. They'll rescind the sale,
or we'll file a lawsuit against the county.
- We'll get your house back.
- Before the 18th, right?
It's possible.
Fuck.
Hello.
- Sorry.
- Shit.
- I didn't mean to scare you.
- Don't do that.
You all right?
Yeah. I'm fine. You?
Good. Good.
You working undercover or something?
Excuse me?
No. I'm off.
I just... I drive by this way, and, uh...
figured I'd check In on you,
see how you're holding up.
They already sold your house?
Technically, it's mine and my brother's.
My dad left it to us when he died.
I haven't told my family.
My lawyer's trying
to get them to rescind it.
So I'm trying not
to harp on the negative.
You have any kids, Mr. Burdon?
Two.
Call me Lester.
My husband left me eight months ago.
No one knows that, either.
Do you mind if I give you
some professional advice?
No.
Do it all through your lawyer, Kathy.
I wouldn't drive past that house
till the keys were back In my hand.
Thanks for checking In on me.
Sure.
Night.
Hey, Kathy, wait.
Listen. This is my direct number
at the department.
Most of the time, I'm on patrol.
But if you ever need anything,
anything at all, just leave a message.
- See ya.
- Good night.
It is like our garden In Isfahan.
Hello?
Yeah?
Your credit card didn't go through.
That's two days now.
God, I'm really sorry about that.
Look, um, I'm gonna get
my paycheck on Friday.
Is there any way we can
let it slide until then?
The only affordable way
to put a terrace up there
is to put the stairs
on the outside.
It'll have to block
that kitchen window.
I could do that for about a grand.
If we have to go through the roof,
about $4,000 to $ 7,000.
- But this window must be obstructed?
- I don't see any other way.
That is acceptable.
Can you start today?
Hey!
- What are you doing?
- Excuse me?
What the fuck are you doing?
This is my house.
Who are you?
Who said you could do this?
- Are you Mrs. Behrani?
- No.
Mr. Behrani hired us.
You're gonna have to talk to him.
Oh, fuck.
- Whoa, lady.
- Shit.
Damn!
Stay right there.
Don't move.
Hold on.
Ah! Oh, man.
- Let's get her inside.
- Fuck.
Come on.
Careful.
Could we use your bathroom?
She stepped on...
Sorry, ma'am. Could we use
your washroom to clean her foot?
- Okay.
- It is okay.
For one moment, please.
Here.
I got it.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Have you had a tetanus shot lately?
I'm gonna be sick.
Is she bleeding?
Excuse me.
- Esmail, a bandage.
- Okay.
I don't want to ruin your towel.
Here.
I use this for skateboarding.
Don't worry. I washed it.
Okay.
This is, of course, our family pictures.
Thank you.
I think I should go.
What happened?
I'll tell you what happened.
My yard is a construction site.
- You were there?
- Yeah, I was there. I was at my house.
I stepped on some nails.
I was bleeding on my own doorstep,
waiting for a stranger to open my door.
You can't just go over there.
You've got to let us handle this.
I want them out of my house.
They're already more at home there
than I ever was.
Did you get their name?
Ah... Bahroony?
Behmini, something like that.
They're Middle Eastern.
- Gary?
- Yes, Connie?
Will you type a letter
to the courier service
and make sure that it
gets to a Mr. Behrmini?
It's damn hard to sell a house nowadays.
This is what you call a real buyer's market.
Well, sorry,
but she comes In at...
$174,000.
- You're late, Behrani.
- I am not late.
I have come to tell you that I'm no longer
to return to this job.
You tell the office, Colonel?
No.
So why tell me, man?
Is this you?
Hmm.
"... inform you... that under
these circumstances...
"currently owe, or as a property...
"we request that you vacate
the property immediately."
Mother whores! Goddamn it!
Mr. Barmeeny is here.
Oh, Mr. Barmeeny.
My name is Behrani.
Colonel Massoud Amir Behrani.
I wish to speak with Mr. Walsh, please.
I'm Connie Walsh.
This is my office, Colonel.
Please come In.
I'm sure our letter came
as a shock to you, Colonel.
The situation is this: Pacific County
has made a number of mistakes.
First, they levied a tax
on my client which she did not owe.
Second, they evicted her for nonpayment.
And third, they auctioned the property.
- Unfortunately, this is where you come In.
- But I now own the house.
I paid for it In cash.
I have a bill of sale. Here, please.
Would you sell the county back the house?
They would make it as comfortable
a transaction as possible.
Please listen to me very carefully.
The only comfortable transaction possible
is if the county tax office
paid to me $174,000.
Mr. Behrani, you only paid
a quarter of that amount.
The market can already pay me this.
Good morning, Miss Walsh.
Wait, please.
From a legal standpoint,
you are In the right.
But the true owner of this house
is living In a motel, Mr. Behrani.
All her belongings are locked In storage.
Why should she wait to get back
into her home that was wrongfully taken?
Just because you want to turn a profit.
Things are not as they appear.
It is a matter of necessity
for me and my family.
I'm sorry. I do not have
a choice In this matter.
Hey.
This is a surprise.
Good one or a bad one?
It's good.
What happened to your foot?
Oh, I, um...
I stopped by my house, and they were
doing construction on the roof.
I stepped on some nails.
Thanks for letting me
ride along today, Mr. Burdon.
So, how's the El Rancho?
I'm not there anymore.
I'm staying at the Bonneville now.
I don't know it.
You're looking at it.
I haven't had a drink
In three years, Lester.
Oh, I'm sorry. I... I should have asked.
I didn't know.
No, it's okay.
The fog's coming In.
I'd like to ask you
a personal question, if I could.
Okay.
Just get it over with.
Why is your husband no longer with you?
I wanted kids.
He didn't want kids.
But I guess if he really wanted me,
he would have wanted them, too.
I think he's a fool.
Maybe we should find you
a place to stay.
Do you remember the beauty
of the Caspian Sea, Esmail?
The water like glass.
The beach sand like gold.
It is beautiful here.
Massoud, when must we move again?
Not too soon.
Perhaps once we get a buyer, we will
tell them to wait until autumn.
Would you prefer that?
I will do as you wish.
There was this little runt of a guy.
Kept beating up his wife.
Except she wouldn't press charges.
We'd show up,
and there they'd be at the door
like Romeo and Juliet, arm In arm.
She had welts and bruises all over.
So, one night we get called out there again,
and I slipped down their hallway
and stuffed two eight-balls In his closet.
Turns out he was on parole.
He goes back to jail, she's safe,
and I slept like a baby.
Did I just lose you?
No.
I'm sorry. I, um...
To tell you the truth, I think
the wine's distracting me.
- I'll send it back.
- No, it's fine.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
See, when I think of my sobriety,
I don't think about wine.
Alcohol was never a problem.
Well, you're a grown woman.
Cheers.
- What are your kids' names?
- Nate and Bethany.
Nate is four. Bethany is nine.
- Where is your house?
- In Millbrae.
In a housing development
called Palomino Meadows.
You have to drive through it
to get to the mall.
Yeah, I know where that is.
God, I've probably driven
by it a dozen times.
I've probably even seen your wife.
- Carol.
- Yeah. Carol.
- What's your situation, Les?
- I married my best friend.
And for seven of
the last nine years,
I haven't wanted to give her more
than a hug or a peck on the cheek.
That's my situation.
- What about her?
- It's not the same for her.
Do you want to come inside?
Massoud.
We are blessed.
- What time is it?
- It's 10:00.
Oh, God.
I should have been home hours ago.
I'm sure Carol called the department.
I'm sure they asked her
if I was feeling any better.
Things are finally In motion.
I'm finally gonna get it over with.
It?
Telling her the truth
about how I feel.
How do you feel?
I feel found.
Well, Kathy, bad news.
The county's done their part,
but the new owner won't go along.
He's asking for four times
what he bought it for.
We can sue the county,
but it'll take months.
Do you mean that...
I can't legally get my house back?
It would've been a lot easier
if you'd just opened your mail.
You can't expect the law to work miracles.
I don't expect miracles.
I expect you to do your fucking job.
I don't know what I'm doing
sitting here talking to you.
And as you see,
very excellent rooms.
It is cool inside,
even during the day.
And from the widow's walk,
sunsets are quite beautiful.
There is very little fog In this area.
- When would the house be available?
- Not until autumn.
- We would need time to find a new home.
- That might work for us.
Yes. She has come for a tool her boyfriend
carpenter may have left behind.
I have been expecting her.
One moment, please.
I am happy you came.
Please, this way. I will show you.
My family knows nothing of this.
I'd like for it to remain so.
You have me confused
with someone else.
I'm quite certain I know who you are.
I'm Kathy Nicolo.
I know my lawyer talked to you,
Mr. Bahrooni,
- but I thought we could meet face-to-face.
- My name is Behrani. Colonel Behrani.
Colonel Behrani, I'm sorry.
My father left this house
to me and my brother.
Tell this to the bureaucrats
at the County Tax Office.
They have made a mistake, not I.
They said they'd give you
your money back. You've put that deck on.
I'm sure they'd repay you for that.
I'm sorry, but I've nothing more to say.
Why should I be penalized
for their incompetence?
You should sue them for enough
to buy ten homes.
I'll even sell you this house
for the right price. That's all I require.
I don't know where he left his hammers.
I've nothing more to say.
Let go of me.
You can't expect to just move In here
and make money off of this.
This is my house.
I lived here, and you stole
this house from me,
you son of a bitch!
This is a stolen house!
He's trying to sell you
a stolen house!
What'd you tell your kids?
I told them the truth.
My old man walked out on us.
I swore I would never do that to my own.
What happened?
My lawyer couldn't get the house back.
So I went to see the owner.
- And he put his hand on you?
- It's okay. Don't worry about it.
That's not right.
He's got no right to do that.
Who is this guy?
His name's Behrani.
He's a colonel.
Behrani?
What country is he from?
I don't know.
But his wife hardly speaks any English.
Maybe they haven't been here that long.
Maybe they don't know their way around.
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna pay 'em a visit.
Officers tend to listen to other officers.
It's worth a shot.
What if he doesn't listen?
Then I'll make him listen.
Oomadan! Oomadan!
Little bird.
Little bird!
Welcome to our new home.
- Does it go down the hill?
- It is an investment property, Soraya.
Like our second home on the Caspian.
It's an investment home.
Let us go to the roof porch,
for the view.
Jesus, look at them.
What are they celebrating,
stealing a woman's house?
Fuck these people.
You're a very wise man,
Genob Sarhang,
to live In such a place that gives you
a view of God's wonders.
Did you post that sign, sir?
Yes. Is there a difficulty, officer?
And that's your sign
at the bottom of the hill?
Yes.
Please, come In, officer.
I am new to the area.
Is a permit required to post signs?
Not on the house.
- But the utility pole's city property.
- I see.
Very well. I will put the sign elsewhere.
Thank you for informing me.
You're a long way from home,
aren't you?
This is my home.
I am an American citizen.
Were you a general?
I was a colonel.
Officer, what more can I do for you?
What's your name?
Massoud Amir Behrani.
And the names of your family?
Why do you need the names of my family?
What is your name, Officer?
Deputy Sheriff Joe Gonzalez.
Let me ask you a question.
Are you selling this house on your own?
I do not wish to offend, Officer,
but if you'll excuse me,
I have work to do.
Civil code 1101.
Yes, you have informed me.
I suggest you come with me
to witness the removal of the sign.
No, I'm talking about
the disclosure law, Colonel.
You, as the owner, have the obligation
to tell all prospective buyers
anything about the property
they have a right to know.
I do not understand.
- You sure about that?
- Are you interrogating me, Mr. Gonzalez?
I don't know. You tell me. I understand
your friend, the Shah, made a habit of it.
I don't know who you think you're
speaking to, but I've had enough.
You have done your job.
Now you may leave.
You're used to giving orders, aren't you?
Let me get right to the point here.
Pacific County has offered you money.
They don't want any trouble.
The only one that seems
to want trouble is you.
You don't want to do the right thing,
which is to sell this house
back at the price you paid
so it can be returned to the real owner.
The real owner, Mr. Behrani.
Now, that just won't wash.
I have more than one contact
at Immigration.
People get deported every single day.
There are a lot of things
I can do, Colonel.
I suggest you call the movers,
so I won't have to.
What happened?
Well, the guy's obviously
not right off the boat.
I think you're right.
He probably buys up seized property
to make a killing.
I set him straight.
I think he'll listen.
He will.
So, what do we do now?
I mean...
Look at us.
We're both homeless.
Listen. My friend has
a cabin a few miles south.
We can stay there.
Give to me an answer, Behrani.
What did that man say of deporting?
- He said nothing, Nadi.
- Do not lie to me! I heard him.
Who was that man?
Tell to me, Behrani.
What have you done?
It's none of your business
what I have done.
Have you no faith In me, no respect?
That man said I must remove the sign.
- Coward! Liar!
- Mawmawn.
You kasif liar!
It is your fault we were
forced to flee from Iran.
- It is your fault we are here.
- Mawmawn!
Yours and your Savak friends!
Mawmawn!
How long can we stay here?
Until we get things figured out.
You hungry?
I could eat.
Do you still love her?
Look, it's just...
it's not her.
She's a good person.
A good mother.
Would this have happened anyway...
even if you hadn't met me?
Yes.
I miss my dad.
He worked really hard for that house.
It took him...
thirty years to pay it off.
And it took me eight months
to fuck it up.
Hey. Hey.
Come here.
We're gonna get your house back.
Soon.
When this is all done,
I promise,
I'll move you back In myself.
My son.
Do not follow the example of your father
one day when you are married.
Do not do as I did last evening.
Do not be disrespectful, son.
Look at me.
Bawbaw... were you a Savaki?
No.
I only bought
fighter planes for Shah-jahn.
- Why did that man say we'd be deported?
- I do not know.
But we are American citizens.
We own this house.
They can do nothing to us now.
I feel bad for that lady, bawbaw-jahn.
The woman's house was taken from her
because she did not pay her taxes.
That happens when one is not responsible.
Do you understand?
Do not feel bad.
Americans do not
deserve what they have.
They have the eyes of children who
are forever looking for the next distraction,
entertainment, sweet taste In the mouth.
We are not like them.
We know rich opportunities when we see
them and don't throw away God's blessing.
You know I must raise money
for your education.
I can get another paper route.
Man meedoonam,
azizam.
I know.
You are a kind child.
Quickly becoming a man.
You have my respect for your heart.
Soon all this will be over.
Bawbaw-jahn.
Thank you.
Hey.
Have a good day at work.
You need to see what you're doing
to this family, Les.
Look at your children,
at the damage you're causing.
- This is not the time for this, Carol.
- When is the time?
When I'm not on my way to work.
Stop it!
Do you want to get arrested?
Is that what you want?
You want to arrest me? God, go ahead.
Arrest me In front of our children.
Daddy, please.
Please!
Oh, God, I didn't mean to do this.
Don't go.
Please, don't go.
We checked, and we have
no Joe Gonzalez on the force.
Did he have anything else on him
that might help us to ID him?
We have hundreds of deputies
In the department.
He wore a golden star,
a badge with two
pistol barrels crossed...
and letters of gold spelling F-T-O.
There are only eight field training officers
In the department.
Tell me if you see him here.
Yes. That is him.
That is the man who threatened me.
It's Burdon.
You're completely confident
this is the officer?
I'm sorry this happened to you, sir.
I can promise you,
it won't happen again.
Hi.
What do you think?
I cleaned the whole place.
What's wrong?
Kath, I need to go home
for a while today.
I need to go home and explain
things to Carol better,
to Nate and Bethany.
I should be home when
they come back from school.
- You just said "home" three times.
- It is my home.
At least until we make another one.
- Are you coming back?
- In a couple of hours, three at the most.
I'll understand if you don't.
I don't deserve you.
Of course you do.
Fuck.
I told the kids that this was just temporary,
you were taking time off, like a vacation.
I didn't know what else to tell them.
Tell them the truth, Carol.
Hello?
Deputy Lester Burdon?
Hello.
- Deputy Lester Burdon?
- Yes?
Lieutenant Alvarez with Internal Affairs.
Dispatch yourself to my office immediately.
Can it wait till I'm back on duty, sir?
No, deputy, it cannot.
Be In my office In 45 minutes,
or you can come In tomorrow
and drop off your badge.
Please, a moment. Wait.
Oh, excuse for me, please.
Oh, I am sorry
for keeping you to waiting.
How is your foot?
- Better. Thank you.
- Oh.
Can I come In?
- Please, come In.
- Thank you.
I grew up In this house.
It's the house my father left
to me and my brother when he died.
The county evicted me
from this house by mistake,
and your husband bought it,
and now he won't sell it back
for less than four times what he paid.
I don't want to argue with him.
You know, I really don't.
It's just that if this goes to court,
it could take...
- They are to deport us?
- I don't know.
You must see.
They will kill us.
They will shoot my children.
Hey. Hey.
You don't understand a word
I'm saying, do you?
Please, you are a very nice girl.
Please, you write for me everything.
I want for to understand,
for discussing with my husband.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Do you think you can frighten me with your
stupid deputy coming here telling lies?
What do you think I am?
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- Don't!
In my country, you'd not be worthy
to raise your eyes to me. You're nothing!
- Nakon!
- Tell your deputy friend
his superior officers know everything.
You tell him that.
This is our home!
- Please...
- Our home!
Please stop!
Please to stop, Behrani.
- Kathy? K, is that you?
- Yeah.
Mom said you sounded
strange on the phone.
What's going on?
I need help.
I really need some help.
What's wrong?
Do you think you could
just come out here?
Please?
K.
K, I'm sorry.
I just got a real shit storm here.
We just got the new models In,
there's inventory...
I'll be right there.
Just give me a second here.
I just feel lost, Frankie.
You know? I just, um...
I just feel lost.
Look, Ma and the aunts
will be out there on the 18th.
They can help you, bring you back,
straighten you out. Okay?
I'm sorry, K,
but I gotta go. Okay?
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
Chin up, baby sister.
I'll call you later.
Okay.
Hey, don't tell Mom, all right?
Okay, bye.
Fuck.
Pack of Royals.
Wild night, huh?
Seems to be heading In that direction.
- Have a good one.
- Thanks.
This and, um, three on two.
- You need a funnel with that?
- No. Just a book of matches.
Oh, God!
I'm sorry.
I don't want the house anymore.
I don't care.
Nadi! Nadereh!
I can't...
Don't go.
Nakon. Nakon.
You must sleep now.
You must rest.
Please, some tea.
Please, have bath to relax.
Shh. Esmail.
That car In the driveway,
is it that woman's?
The woman has tried to take
her own life.
We must help her.
Pesaram, she is a bird, a broken one.
Your grandfather used to say that a bird
which flies into your house is an angel.
You must look upon his presence
as a blessing.
We have a guest In the house.
You must be a gentleman,joon-am.
Very kind,
very polite,
very quiet.
Hello?
Do you need anything?
Nah!
Bolandsho, bolandsho.
Your mouth...
your mouth to open.
Very good. Your mouth.
Very good.
Yes. Yes.
Biroon!
Ah, very good.
I feel sorry for her.
- We should have moved.
- Ghazatoh bokhor.
Yes, perhaps you are right.
We should have moved.
Put her down! Put her down!
- Aah!
- Put her down!
What did you do to her?
Step back!
Shut up!
- Listen! Listen!
- No! Move!
Les...
- Don't.
- Move!
What did you do to her?
- She took a whole bottle of my mom's pills.
- Bring 'em to me.
How many? When?
English! English!
My wife says, 20 tablets,
perhaps half an hour ago.
My wife made her lose her stomach.
She has vomited the pills.
She also tried to shoot herself
with that pistol.
I discovered her with it In her automobile.
She was quite upset.
She'd been drinking a great deal.
That's bullshit.
Come here.
Pick her up.
Carry her into that room.
Carefully!
Step away.
She'll be okay.
All right, come on.
I don't want to see this door move.
Get some rest, 'cause tomorrow
you're selling this place back to the county.
Kath?
Kathy?
- Kathy!
- Hmm?
Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
- Bawbaw?
- Yes?
- I have to go.
- Use the toilet.
Your mother will not look.
Esmail.
Today I want you to pretend
to be frightened of this man.
- You must do everything he says.
- Why?
He's weak.
He's nothing without his gun.
He's very scared.
And a scared man is dangerous.
We will...
remain lions In our hearts, pesaram.
- You're here.
- I'm here.
Sir. Sir.
Please let us out so my family can eat.
- What's going on?
- I locked them In the bathroom.
Why?
That's crazy, Les.
No. What's crazy
is trying to kill yourself.
Kathy, why?
I didn't think you were coming back.
Well, I'm back.
Do you really want to die?
I just wanted things to change.
You will get out when
you call the goddamn county!
Sir.
Sir, may I speak with you?
- What?
- Please open the door.
I wish to speak with you directly.
I think I have a possible resolution.
You and I will go
to the government office
and I will sign the necessary papers
for returning the house to them.
They to me will write
a check for $45,000.
This check I will give
to you and the woman,
In exchange for putting
the house In my name.
- You would do that?
- I would do that.
Wait.
- We can't do this, Les.
- I think that this can all work out.
He signs the house to the county.
When he gets the check, he gives it to us,
then you sign the house back to him.
It's wrong.
It's just wrong to do it this way.
This has got to work.
This way, you get some money.
He gets what he wants, the house.
It's a win-win situation.
No one gets hurt.
Let's just go.
Please, let's just go.
Kathy, we could use that money.
To start new.
- It's our only choice now.
- He'll never let it happen.
All right, leave the keys
and go do what you promised.
But your son stays here with me.
You're not back soon,
Ishmael and I will be gone.
But we have made an agreement.
No.
I will for you do nothing
without my son.
Nothing.
Shit.
Fine. Let's just do this.
Move it, Colonel. Come on.
You, too, Ishmael.
Excuse me, Mr. Burdon.
- Slow down.
- Deputy Sheriff Burdon.
Sir? I know you're busy.
I just wanted to say
I appreciate everything you taught me.
- I just wanted to say thanks.
- Hey, I appreciate that.
And good luck to you, Brian.
All right.
Now, you listen to me.
When we get In there,
you and Ishmael here,
you're gonna have
to hear me a lot better.
You have to do exactly what I tell you.
Help. Somebody, help us!
Somebody call police, fast!
My name is Esmail, not Ishmael.
Pesaram. Pesaram!
Help, somebody! Call police!
Esmail, please.
Drop it now!
- I said drop it!
- Wait!
No!
We have an officer-involved shooting.
Goddamn it, this kid
is gonna bleed to death.
Call to hospital!
Hospital!
Sir...
I want only my son!
- Sir...
- I want only my son!
I want only my son!
My son!
It is him, he has done this.
I will kill you!
Pesaram, I am here!
What is your name, Deputy?
Sir?
- What?
- What is your name?
I'm so sorry about all of this.
I have a headache.
Please, excuse for me.
Please, I must to my son.
Burdon corroborates the whole deal.
Mr. Behrani?
You're free to go.
This is your recourse. You can press
charges against Deputy Burdon...
Please, I must to hospital, please.
Your son is at St. Vincent.
He's three blocks east.
We can get a police escort!
I want only my son.
Emergency!
I must see my son.
He is here.
- He has been shot.
- His name?
What's his name, sir?
Behrani.
Esmail.
He's In trauma.
You can wait In the lounge.
Please, God, don't take my joon-am.
I make my nazr. My nazr, hear me.
Please to hear me.
I will give everything to one
who is less fortunate.
Yes! I will make it for the broken bird.
Please, God, I'm making nazr
to this woman.
To Kathy Nicolo.
And I to you promise,
if you heal my son,
I will return her father's house.
I will also give to her
all the money I have.
My God, Khoda.
I make nazr only for my son.
Please, I want only for my son.
I beg you, I will do whatever is your will.
I will purchase ten kilos
of the finest seed
and find an American mosque, and I will
feed them to all the birds outside.
I will let the birds cover me
and peck out my eyes.
Please, God, my nazr is In your hands.
Hi.
You've reached the Burdon family.
We're not here right now,
but if you leave a message...
we'll call you right back!
Let's go, Burdon.
- Nadereh.
- Hmm?
Massoud.
Drink this.
Some tea.
I am tired.
Soon we will return
to the flowers of Isfahan...
the mosques of Qom...
and to the fine hotels
of old Tehran.
I have taken us so far off our course.
But now it is time to return.
It is time for us to go home,
to our destiny.
Oh, God!
Please!
Are you Kathy Nicolo?
Yeah.
Is this your house?
No, it's not my house.