Translated subtitles, synchronized
and revised
June 13, 1980.
CRYSTAL LAKE CAMPS
Come here. Come on now.
You are the last.
Killed all the others.
It will be easier for you
of which was for Jason.
Why are you doing this?
You must be punished
so did with it.
You left him drowning.
Jason was my son.
No, no please.
Should be taking care of him.
It will be punished!
Jason ...
... my special boy.
They should be punished, Jason.
So did you,
and that made me.
Kill the Mother.
CRYSTAL LAKE
THIS
Really!
Careful ...
... with the lions of the mountains.
Has many here!
Lions--the mountains?
--Yes, we have to make a bonfire ...
... because they are afraid of fire.
--Shut up. You are talking nonsense.
Richie is talking crap!
--I am not talking nonsense.
--Are you too!
Okay, you will see
when a show there ...
--Beware!
--Nice try ...
I am not concerned with
be eaten by mosquitoes.
I want you to give us
tapas in the ass before eating?
--Oh, yeah? Like this?
--I love.
Whitney, where are you now?
--Here.
--Really?
Here, the same thing.
--Hey! You are reading right?
--I!
--Come on, guys. Here.
--Where are we going?
--This is heavy, and is heat.
--Where are we?
Man, we screwed.
--No we are not.
--We are, yes.
Not everything is
No GPS, Richie.
Had a sign that we
less than a mile ...
... then we
close. I think.
You think?
You do not know how to use it, it is
almost night. You know where it is or not?
Look, I planted
shit, Richie. Okay?
I had this track
a source of second hand.
We must be close,
gives up to smell it.
Look, let's camp here.
Tomorrow morning ...
... you and I,
we get the grass ...
... We 're gonna get the maximum possible,
and put in the truck.
E--back before breakfast.
--Hey, guys!
And nobody needs to know.
Nor need that has a
perfect place and clean here.
Perfect! Camp here. Hey!
You know how much money we earn
selling this herb?
Fuck you money!
So, I listen. Relax ...
--I am relaxed, you know why?
Because I will be rich, and knows
what are the rich? Relax.
You have to relax.
I need to relax?
You need.
Hey, guys! Staff.
I found some huts
old there ...
... must be that
old camp.
Who wants to look?
Only we make it?
No more shit European, yes
drink is a true American.
Know that the camp was
closed for more than 20 years.
A woman was
completely crazy.
Killed all advisers and
blamed for the son to have drowned.
He was deformed, or
retarded, or something ...
Mom was mad.
Apparently, there was
a survivor.
One girl cut the head
this woman with an ax.
--E is still worse ...
--Of course I cut.
His son, Jason ...
... again.
He was there.
He saw his mother
be decapitated.
A friend of mine who
camped here ...
Camped yes! He said that the police
Jason asked about this ...
You know?
Do not believe in me, as always.
--I do not believe in me.
But I am sure that this story ...
happens in a place called
Camp Crystal Lake.
You know how many lakes should
have the name of Crystal Lake?
It's the same thing with drinks,
for example, water.
Go to the supermarket, every bottle
Crystal water is something.
--Aquafin.
--Okay.
Could have happened anywhere.
Just to scare children.
--Moreover, the beer is treating you well?
--Better than you.
You can drink it.
Its the one, my.
Four will not
can piss right.
--Know that this happens to me.
--This is what you think.
Can I talk to you?
--You marshmallow in my knee.
--Where are you going?
--Give a quickie.
--Really?
Hey, Mike!
USA condom.
Size Extra--Small.
Sometimes we have to do things
crazy to survive.
If we were dying of hunger,
and you were dead.
I eat your leg.
--What love.
--Thanks.
Why eat my leg?
I can teach you to fish.
Vai--fish!
--Not as fish.
It was not what you told me.
Look, I
stay here long.
The history of
Wade you scared?
Please, I just ...
I feel good here.
So far from my mother.
His mother who asked me to get it
town for a few days.
--Really?
--It.
She is in good hands
have a nurse there.
Come on ...
... make sex,
with her boyfriend.
Those tendinhas
of shit ...
We can do food.
Take a walk in the woods.
And then we came back
to another.
I am an idiot.
Richie!
The data from event
are not hitting.
--Dude, that shit.
--Yeah.
You know what?
What?
We are less than half
miles away.
Shut up!
You know what I
leaves happy, Richie?
Global position systems,
antennas and mobile phones with GPS ...
NASA's technology
in the palm of your hand.
All this connected mandingo
signs pro space. Signs!
The satellite to handle, and he turns around
you say: "Thank you, GPS ...
I now send you a sign! "
And all this in the palm of your hand.
Technology, man,
is unbelievable.
Wade, get out man. Speech
those for other nonsense.
Actually have something
better to do?
So, Richard, my friend ...
I am leaving out.
--Do it, man.
--I do.
"May the Force be with you."
Fuck! Yes!
I love you ...
... you and you.
And you too.
My God.
What the fuck ...?
Wait! No! No!
CRYSTAL LAKE CAMPS
Should be the camp that Wade said.
Come--out.
--No, I am not related.
Come on. Come on.
Wow, look at that.
Mike, where are you going?
--Come on inside.
--No.
--Where is your sense of adventure?
--What is.
--Are you afraid?
--No.
I bet you have things
ways here.
Mike, do not go there.
And if you have someone living here?
There is nobody living here.
You hungry?
Wow, looks like this
shit is old.
It is as if it had been dragged
of another century to come.
Look at this.
Hey, it looks like you.
--It does not!
--It seems so.
It is legal, could keep it.
It seems the fourth
of a child.
The boy's story
not called Jason?
I want to leave now.
--Oh, what is?
--Please.
--You like?
--Yes, wait for me.
--I think I will ...
--No, we at the same time.
We like that.
Stop! Shit, I heard something.
Hey, I'm serious.
--What?
--I think Wade is looking at us.
Fuck, let the freak look.
Okay?
Wade ...
Dude, you're out there in
looking, that is not cool!
Come on, man!
I think I did.
--Wait!
--Oh, my God.
Wade!
I'll kill you!
Okay.
--Okay?
--All right.
No, tell him
leave us alone.
I will not leave it outside
with an erection.
Will not achieve anything
if you do not.
Do not move! Okay?
Richie?
Richie, stop it.
Wade!
If you jump to any tree, I
beat you in the face, as you notice.
Come on, man. I have to
to go back to my tent.
Holy shit.
Damn,
found the grass.
Wade? Wade!
Amanda!
Whitney, you have to see it.
Mike ... come on.
No, really.
You must see this.
Someone was here.
What is that?
Something in there.
Looks like a type of dog.
Are you crazy?
Oh, my God!
Is there anything out there.
Let's see.
Get off the floor!
Run!
Run, Whitney!
Oh, God.
Whitney, help me!
Whitney, please help me!
Crap.
FRIDAY 13
After 6 Weeks
Oh, my God. A baby
have more space in the womb.
Hey, Lawrence,
that such an aid?
Not handle well, man. The only black
fill the tank for you? Damn.
Sure. Hey, Nolan.
How about you buy me?
Yeah, man. Hey, if you want
also give a quickie.
Okay, well ...
We left for later.
Hey, man! I have a
hearted.
Thank you. It is a gift,
indeed, but ...
Look, I'm looking for my sister,
is missing for 1 month and a half.
Why all this?
Do you think sex is?
I am taking this pile
and not have to fill me ...
And this is not for sex.
--And what are they?
--For an experiment.
Okay, but I will not
pay for this shit.
Mind if I put a
notice in the window or something?
I heard, very sad.
I would fill
the store with it ...
but the owner who
dictates the rules.
He is a true ...
He is here? Can I talk to him,
he can understand the situation.
Hey, go buy something? Already
here a long time, so ...
Sure, okay.
So are 2 water
and gasoline.
2 water and gasoline.
I must be an idiot.
All right, brother?
Yeah, okay. Thank you.
But I am not your brother.
Will not longer be my friend
after that, leaving me?
--Let him, Trent.
--I? This guy is an idiot.
Yeah, I am that I am
being an idiot.
Lord, thank you
in any way.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Fasten your seat belts!
DISAPPEARANCE
Has anyone seen WHITNEY?
WELCOME TO CRYSTAL LAKE
Welcome back, Clay.
Good morning, officer Bracke.
Son, I know you think
we are not on your side ...
and that we are a shower
the police provincial imbeciles.
But I did everything that
could in this case ...
3 did dozens of interviews
and searches for his sister on the spot.
You know how many thousands of people
disappear each year?
Included in that state.
But there was no
no evidence ...
that something has happened to Whitney
Miller ...
or the other boys in Crystal Lake.
Has no car, witnesses ...
nothing.
One of the boys was
her boyfriend, right?
Sure.
Well, probably
resolved traveling together.
My mother just died
of cancer, I told you?
--No, sir.
Well, he died.
He was ill for a long time,
Whitney and her care.
Every day.
And then my sister did not
appears for the funeral.
If you knew my sister,
it would not be possible.
She is not here, son.
Look in other places, as
doing the other families.
Cool.
Crap.
Man to the ground!
Someone is getting
sign here?
Are you kidding?
I have a business
treat this week--end.
What business?
Music, see discography.
Really? Which kind? Rap?
Why is that
be racist ...
look, I
label. Okay?
For I am not black
I hear Green Day?
All right, I was stupid.
So what kind of music?
Rap.
Here it is.
Oh, my God.
Okay, guys. Has 2 bedrooms
up there, 1 down here ...
Someone goes to sleep on the couch.
This is a scary pussy.
It is a cat of the mountains
the first that my father killed.
It seems that nothing here has
value, but in fact has.
--Is larger than our room.
--Hey, get the feet of the table, please.
So, to feel at home.
--What do you do first?
--What do you want?
Well, I brought my brinquedinho.
I think that breaking a branch.
Lucy ...
the baby is his?
--No, you're cheating me.
--No.
--I saw a bald other day!
A bald!
Hello?
I just wanted to ask you ...
I ask you ...
was a person?
My sister ...
came camping here
with some friends.
E is missing.
She is not missing,
is dead.
What?
Who disappears here,
disappears forever.
The outsiders come here
and do not know where to go ...
get into trouble.
Do not let him be at peace.
So he does.
Who?
Who? Madam, please, who?
I can not stop
to take it.
Yes!
Guys, watch out
the floor, please, is new ...
This is a game
you play in the street.
Hey, this is a legal place.
Want to take a spin
to do an exercise?
It would be nice, but not
I leave them alone.
What are you talking about?
Have you seen what they are
doing there?
They are crazy.
Of rotten drunk.
What do you think you gonna do?
--Stealing the head of the deer?
--They could.
How will they do to escape it
we are all in the same car?
Well, I exercise?
Why learn something nice but
missing someone you practice with me.
Ah, love that. What love.
--I take a walk, do you want?
--Whether it?
--Of course I do.
--I know.
Brings me a beer?
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Jesus Christ.
Lucky to be full ...
I, therefore, you cut
as a salami, kid.
Okay, did not want to distract him, only
I wanted a little of your attention.
This is the property of
Mr Garret ...
is lucky to have not
filled his ass with bullets.
Someone was stealing
things of the Lord Garret.
Look, I just came here to
ask you something, right?
Looking for that girl,
perhaps has seen.
Is missing
more than a month.
I have seen, man.
--But not seen.
--Thanks.
--Take care.
--You too.
Hey! Hey, hey! I forgot.
Want to buy a
bit of grass?
Really! I am full of shit
growing in my planting. Want?
No, thanks.
Are you sure, man?
I have a lot ...
Are you sure? Vai lose good.
You fucked up now, boy.
Skip right. Idiot.
Just relax. Okay?
If you are not comfortable with
them here, that called?
To admire his house?
No, to have a
good week--end.
Hey, guys, want to go see
other side of the lake with us?
You know that ...
no, all is well,
is already getting late.
It is, get my truck.
I trust you.
Do me a favor ...
take the petrol and
filling the boat ...
is the south side, go the way
of land and turn right.
After ... why not
type everything in the browser?
Technology!
Have fun, bye.
Do not take my boat ...
I am the only one who knows
ran it. Okay?
The orders, Captain.
That's right.
At the time he said:
"Do not take my boat ...
that was a guarantee
that I pegaria.
Even acting as
a sociopath ...
I can say that I found
that ... exciting.
Hello, sorry to bother but
I'm looking for my sister.
Oi.
--No luck?
--No, nothing yet.
--I?
--Yes ... bright.
She is beautiful.
Thank you.
Want to get a little
and have a drink?
I think her boyfriend
would not love.
Do not worry about it,
he will be fine.
Here is an American junkie
looking for food.
It will be interesting.
Hey, Trent, remember ...
Clay.
Yes, of course,
remember the Clay.
Why is he
in my home?
--Hey, rookie, beer?
--No.
He has to go, has
things to solve, right?
Sure.
Look, if you have
hunger, we can ...
Sure. Hey, Clay ...
it is obviously
trying to be nice, but ...
can not stay here, no offense,
but this is a private party ...
and I do not know you.
--No, I do not know.
Funny,
I just say that.
A few seconds ago
I do not know you.
If I were you, would soon
before I irritate ...
--Oh, yeah?
--It.
--What happens?
--Calm down, Trent, right?
So come on, I will follow.
Jenna, what is? Where are you?
Sorry about that.
All right.
The house is his.
Where is your car?
I have no car,
but I have ...
Cool!
This thing runs?
Yes, it did.
So where is it now?
Well, I was not yet on the other side
the lake, then I take a look.
--Want company?
--I would love the company.
This shit heavy, huh?
Damn, that's it.
Bitch.
Oh, Daddy is going to
a lambidinha.
Like that, bitch?
You know I like.
What the hell was that?
Must be someone trying to
steal my grass up there.
Crap.
Jinai, are you, honey?
It's a time, Jinai.
Remember the night
particular we have?
When you get
my virginity.
So sexy, more tightly than
never. I will eat you both ...
What the fuck ...?
Motherfucker, that
fuck it was true!
I do not know, really think
should take the boat?
--I know.
--What?
Always talk much, but in the end
it's just a scared little girl.
Oh, yeah? Okay, then.
Want to see what really
is there? Then go.
Sure. Go!
So you and your sister
were very close.
Yeah, we were very close when
young, but then we separate.
I left the house with 17 years
and it was with my mother ...
I think it was something that
I had to do.
I know there, it always
was responsible.
So when was the last
time you talked?
There are 6 months.
We fight, actually ...
she called me and said
I wanted to see me.
That had me and I
never appeared.
Excuse me.
What is this?
It's a GPS.
Okay, you ready?
Okay, come on!
Damn!
Tag. Get one.
Likes balls
in your hand, right?
What? Whats up That?
--Seem good, no?
--That.
Play!
Fuck you.
Vai you. Vai take
a shot in tennis.
--You baby, baby.
--Really?
--Yes.
--You missed it. During all game.
Come on, baby.
Drink, drink, drink.
Drink in tennis!
I will not drink in your shoes,
you nor USA socks.
Are the rules,
baby in tennis.
My house, my rules,
I will not drink that shit.
--Right.
--Oh, no.
--Want to taste?
--No.
--I?
--Yes.
Feygeles the world!
Gross.
Here!
What are you doing? Care!
Stay away from me.
Oh, my God!
Help!
Let's take a look at this
hut, then came back.
You should
call the police.
I called the police, already
gave up looking.
Everyone, except me.
So should
seek more, because ...
--Okay?
--I am well, I'm fine.
--Are you sure?
--I.
We outta here.
I hope that battery.
It is better to hide.
Where did he go?
My God, we must go.
I have to follow it.
He has a corpse with him.
Come on tell my friends.
--Okay?
--Yes.
What is this?
Help!
--Come on.
--Yes.
Me!
Clay.
Crap.
Go!
Please do not hurt me.
All right.
Jason, all is well.
--Here.
--Right.
In my next life ...
want to ...
a button on the pocket
back of her pants.
Vai there and talk to her.
You kidding?
I have more chances to eat
a penguin than eat it.
Let's leave it stronger.
A toast to the problems
with parents and with stalker ...
we are all a
great and happy cliché.
What the fuck is that?
Please try not
burn my house.
Forgotten as
drink it?
Put on the lips ...
blow ...
and suck.
You do this?
Fuck, man! Just
break the chair of my father!
A hell of my lip!
--Fuck her lip.
This is a family inheritance.
--Oh, sorry.
--Damn!
You know, I can fix!
I just need some tools.
--He can fix.
Better--go to the shed ...
the building of tools,
is down there.
Yeah, okay.
Trent, sorry man.
Will not disappoint.
Call me Magic Hand
because I masturbate a lot.
Grab a flashlight, moron.
Sure it will fix.
Let's finish this.
It was an ugly chair
you stick it.
Hello, my name is Trent, and my dad I
gave that chair as a child.
Hello everyone.
Yes!
You are even rich!
Fucking hell.
The poor call it home.
Jesus Christ.
You never USA this shit.
Asshole of shit.
You ski ...
Bottled in Scotland.
Seems to have that money.
I knew you had a reason
to be your friend, Trent.
Fuck! I am the Chris
Wilss that shit.
Guard me, fool!
Your breasts are too.
You know how to make a
girl feel special.
I know it.
Come on, baby. What
have for me? Shows.
Catalog of costumes for bath?
What kind of catalog.
This should serve.
As end
a perfect day.
I killed the fright!
Where is everyone? It has a face
outside carrying a corpse.
Jenna, Where is the phone?
I do not know. Up there?
They are taking me
because I'm stoned?
This is not legal,
because I quit smoking, right?
Where is the phone?
Hi, I report a murder.
My name is Clay Miller.
Yes, I am in a
home in Crystal Lake.
Fast!
They are
sending someone.
--Police?
--Yes.
--Where are the others?
--I do not know. I was here all day.
Nolan went to Chelsea and
the lake, or something.
E--Trent and Bree?
--Are in the room.
His nipples, fuck,
are so succulent.
Everything in you is
perfect, baby.
Trent, Bree?
Are there?
Shut up!
Get out there!
Ignore.
You have a guy out there!
Yeah, Trent.
I will teach you ...
you will learn!
I'll show you now ...
Jesus!
This is a sport
of men ...
Curved like my penis.
An exchange, two laps
to the right ...
back to the middle e. ..
God, you gave me
susto a bitch, brother.
You are looking for that?
Because ... complete
your fantasy.
Yeah, baby.
That was ...
... great.
At the top of the list.
--Who shut the lights?
Chewie, is still out there.
The phone is dead.
Do you have a cell phone, Jenna?
--No signal has.
--What the fuck you doing here?
--Give out of here, man!
--Easy.
--He just wants to help.
--And you ...
left with this
subject for 8 hours ...
throughout the forest?
You know? Why
the two do not give out?
Listen, you idiot.
We have a bigger problem.
You crazy? Have a killer out there
and was he who cut the lights.
Trent does not understand?
Chelsea Nolan and not returned.
Lawrence, what are you doing?
My friend is still there
outside, I get it.
No, it looks expensive. Do not go
out there, please.
I told you that I am fast,
nobody can get me.
You always amaze.
Chewie!
Chewie, is there?
Chewie is in here?
Damn!
Let go!
Here, son of a bitch!
This is bullshit, it
normal light missing here.
Guys, help me!
Me!
Please help me!
--Lawrence!
--You can not go outside.
--We have to help him.
--We can not!
He is using his friend as
bait. He wants us to leave.
You do not know that.
Jesus, where are the police?
We have to help him.
Somebody help me!
Oh, my God. Please!
Someone must do something!
Shut up! Shut up!
Everything will be fine, the
police is coming.
What are you doing?
Trent!
Jenna?
Police!
Thank God.
Police, open!
--Shit!
--No! My God!
--Close the door.
--Okay.
Crap.
--What are you doing? He is in the house?
--He killed the cop.
Damn, you have a gun?
Come now!
What are you doing?
Give me the gun!
Is anybody there.
Take a look.
Bree is dead.
He killed Bree!
Come on.
Where are the keys?
Relief, has a
police hurt!
My keys are gone.
Where are my keys?
Hey, Jenna! Fuck this guy,
let's get out of here!
Come on! Hurry!
Where is the fucking gun?
Damn!
He was coming here.
--Come on.
--Okay.
Help!
--What was that?
--God.
Me! Help me.
Here.
--Clay?
--Whitney.
--Oh, my God, Clay.
--All right, all right. I am here.
--Okay? Okay?
--Yes.
Just get out.
--Come on, it will come.
--Break it.
Just drop it. Break it.
Stretch your hands.
We must leave, go.
--We gotta go.
--Just do it!
Oh, God.
I can see he is coming.
We gotta go.
Come on, hurry!
Come on.
Has no exit.
What do we do?
Hurry.
Come on. We can go there.
Follow me!
Stay calm.
Give me your hand, Jenna, come on.
No, fuck! No!
This may be an exit.
Quick, come on.
Come on.
--Damn! You are stuck.
--Come on!
Give me your hand.
Give me your hand!
Sure. One, two ...
Run, run!
Clay! Stop!
No!
Fuck you!
Whitney. Whitney!
Come on.
Fast. Go!
Hide.
Jason.
All right.
You can stop now.
Jason.
Say "hi" to mommy.
In hell!
Translated subtitles, synchronized
and revised by moral victory
Portuguese
>
English
swap
Translate