Jessie,
you get in this house right now!
Oh, Mom.
Right now.
No!
Who are you?
Well, I'm Mrs Voorhees,
an old friend of the Christys'.
No. They're all dead.
They're all dead.
I'll go look.
Don't leave me. He'll kill you, too.
I'm not afraid.
No!
Did you know that a boy drowned
the year before
those two others were killed?
The counsellors
weren't paying any attention.
They were making love
while that young boy drowned.
His name was Jason.
I was working the day
that it happened. Preparing meals.
Here. I was the cook.
Jason should have been watched
every minute!
He was...
He wasn't a very good swimmer.
We can go now, dear.
No!
My sweet, innocent Jason.
My only child.
Jason.
You let him drown.
You never paid any attention!
Look at what you did to him.
Look what you did to him!
No!
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her.
She can't hide. No place to hide.
Get her, Mommy.
Kill her.
No!
My men pulled you out of the lake.
We thought you were dead, too.
Do you remember very much?
The boy. Is he dead, too?
- Who?
- The boy. Jason.
- Jason?
- In the lake.
The one who attacked me
and pulled me under the water.
Ma'am, we didn't find any boy.
Then he's still there.
God!
Hello?
Hi, Mom.
I know. I'm sorry.
I meant to call earlier,
but I fell asleep.
Really, I'm fine.
I need a little time alone,
that's all.
I know you and Dad worry,
and I appreciate that.
Come on, Mom,
we've been through all this before.
I have to put my life back together,
and this is the only way I know how.
Look...
Mom, please. It's late,
and I don't want to get into it.
I'll call you tomorrow. Bye.
Mom!
Hello?
Cute.
You want something to eat?
Keep your eyes peeled.
I think we're getting close.
There's the gas station.
OK, let's call Ted.
Hey, Teddy, buddy!
We just rolled in.
Yeah, Sandra's here.
Hi, Ted!
You gonna come get us or what?
Yeah, OK. Give me the directions.
Here, wait. Alright.
OK, go ahead, I'm writing.
Alright, Old North Road,
and then look for a Dairy Queen?
OK. And then over...
I told the others.
They didn't believe me.
You're all doomed.
What? No, nothing, no.
No, go ahead.
Alright. So... covered bridge.
OK. Then what?
Alright, then past an old cemetery.
And then...
left down an old dirt road
for half a mile.
Oh, my God! They're towing us!
Shit! I'll call you back.
- Wait!
- Mister!
This is my truck! Come on!
Asshole!
Shit!
Welcome to God's country.
You ratshit!
Thanks, Max!
Max owns the gas station.
He's crazy, too.
I should have known.
It's great to see you.
It'll be like old times.
Yeah, that's what I'm afraid of.
Help me load my gear.
So, Ted, what's the scoop?
I know that guy Paul
that's running the course. He's OK.
He's kind of macho, though.
Takes the whole thing seriously.
Senior Camp Counsellor Course.
We'll probably get
a Brownie badge if we survive.
If we survive?
That's right.
You're second assistant.
Oh, no!
Wait, listen.
There's a bear and a rabbit
in the woods taking a dump.
"The bear says to the rabbit,
""Does shit stick to your fur?"""
"The rabbit says, ""No, Mr Bear."""
So the bear wiped his ass
with the rabbit.
What is that?
- Where'd this sucker come from?
- I don't know. Let's move it.
This place is spooky.
- Somebody dragged it here.
- But what for?
You guys, look at this.
Camp Blood.
- It's on the same lake as we're on.
- Camp Blood?
- Let's go.
- Can't we take a look?
- No way.
- What's the problem?
You don't want to know.
Not before lunch.
Need some help?
No, it's OK. I got it.
Thanks, anyhow.
OK, let's settle down.
Welcome
to our Counsellor Training Centre.
You've all worked as counsellors
at one camp or another.
Terry, Vickie,
you were upstate last summer.
Scott! Good to see you here.
You need it.
Mark, we worked
a season or two together, right?
OK. The rest of you
I'll get to know soon.
There's one thing
I don't have to tell you.
Being a counsellor isn't
the gravy job everybody thinks it is.
What we'll do
over the next two weeks,
if the rest of my staff shows up,
is go back to basics.
Survival, first aid, boating,
archery, rifle range, all of it.
What the hell...?
I'll be right back.
Hi! I'm late.
What is this crap, Ginny?
You're my assistant.
- Everyone else got here hours ago.
- I said I was sorry.
You did?
I'm sorry. OK?
- My car's sick.
- You could have called.
Paul, I tried,
but your phones aren't working yet.
OK, get your gear stowed
and help me outside.
Paul, look,
the course starts today, right?
Well, here I am.
And I promise you,
I'll never ever be late again
in my entire life. Is it a deal?
Alright. What the hell!
Ginny,
I was starting to worry about you.
Bullshit, Paul.
Ginny, put your car on the lot, OK?
This place is starting to look like
a Burger King. Where was I?
"You were about to give your ""Let's
keep our shit together"" speech."
Mr Holt.
Right, Ted. Right.
OK, a few words about safety.
Axes, knives, lanterns, saws.
They can all be trouble.
Their misuse
is the main cause of camp accidents.
Take care of your equipment
and it'll take care of you.
A word of caution
about our friends in the forest.
Among other things,
this is bear country.
Contrary to what everyone hears,
bears are dangerous.
That means no food fights.
Change often.
Food odours cling to clothing.
If you're a woman, don't use perfume.
Keep clean
during your menstrual cycle.
Having trouble? You got to
treat 'em gentle. Just like kids.
Use that child psychology
you're majoring in.
Try it.
It's more fun
using that child psychology on you.
You're such a sucker for it.
I don't want to scare anyone.
But I'm gonna give it to you straight
about Jason.
His body was never recovered
from the lake after he drowned.
The old-timers in town
will tell you he's still out there,
some sort of demented creature,
surviving in the wilderness.
Full grown by now.
Stalking...
...stealing what he needs, living off
wild animals and vegetation.
Some folks claim
they've seen him, right in this area.
The girl who survived that night at
Camp Blood, that Friday the 13th...
...she claims she saw him.
She disappeared two months later.
Vanished.
Blood was everywhere.
No-one knows what happened to her.
Legend has it that Jason saw
his mother beheaded that night,
and he took his revenge.
A revenge he'll continue to seek if
anyone enters his wilderness again.
By now, I guess you all know
we're the first to return here.
Five years...
five long years he's been dormant.
And he's hungry.
Jason's out there...
...watching.
Always on the prowl for intruders.
Waiting to kill.
Waiting to devour.
Thirsty for young blood.
Hey, come back!
Now we've got that out of our system,
I don't want to hear
any more about it.
It's ancient history. Jason drowned,
Mrs Voorhees was killed,
and Camp Crystal Lake is off limits.
You got it?
Got you, huh? What d'you think?
The second act needs work.
- Too bad.
- C'mon.
You got him. You got him now.
Go on.
- That's luck, right?
- Thanks a lot.
Next.
- Hi, Terry. Do you wanna dance?
- No, thank you.
Hi. How about you?
Do you wanna dance?
So there I was, sitting in this
fast-food joint, thinking to myself,
Scott, old boy, what are you going
to do with the rest of your life?
I'm striking out all over the place.
Well, I think I've got you. Check.
Wrong, white man.
Checkmate.
Well, what next?
I could get my arm broken by Mark,
my brains
ponged by our electronical wizard...
...or bed.
Good night, Paul.
See you in the morning.
I just gotta see that place.
- What place?
- That camp. Camp Blood.
You're crazy.
Maybe there is something
in that legend.
- I'm serious.
- No way. I'm not going there.
- Besides, Paul said it's off limits.
- We'll see.
Hello?
Who's there?
- Paul, goddamn it!
- Hey, calm down.
You'll wake the natives.
I'm not supposed to be
fraternising with the staff.
I won't tell.
I missed you, Ginny.
I was worried
when you didn't show on time.
Paul, there's something
I think I should tell you.
BEWARE OF BEARS
Hey, come on!
What's the matter, guys?
Jeff, the women are showing you up.
We've got about half a mile,
then we'll have lunch.
Try to stay on this trail,
because there's poison ivy here.
- How far are we from camp?
- You're gonna trip on that.
After lunch
we're gonna do some more running.
- Here you go, Ted.
- Thank you, dear.
- Come and get 'em!
- I'm here.
Muffin? Here, girl.
Terry, lunch.
OK. I'm coming.
Jeff, are you ready?
- For what?
- Camp Blood.
- We're not supposed to go there.
- They'll never know we're gone.
Jeff, I'm serious.
I really wanna see it.
When we get back to the city,
we can tell everyone we were there.
Oh, come on, you chickenshit.
OK, let's go.
OK, you guys. I got one. Ready?
What's green and red,
and moves at 100 miles an hour?
- What?
- A frog in a blender.
Ha-ha. That wasn't funny.
- What's brown and sits on a piano?
- Your face.
Beethoven's last movement.
God!
This must be it.
- Oh, my God!
- What is it?
Looks like a dog.
- It's too mangled to tell.
- What did it?
Wild animal, I guess.
What are you kids doing out here?
Keep your people away from
that place, Holt. It's condemned.
Next time I catch anybody,
I'll run 'em in.
- He said...
- I'll handle this.
- Might get a warrant against you.
- Really?
Look, Holt... people say what you're
doing with these kids is great.
You've got a good reputation.
But if I was you,
I'd have located in the next county.
You're too close.
It's been quiet for five years.
That's how we want it.
So do I, Officer.
You two, take off.
We'll talk at dinner.
- We'll never do it again, sir.
- Thanks, Mr Holt.
You're not even
going to reprimand them?
No punishment?
What kind of place is this?
- Ginny?
- Yes, Paul?
No seconds on dessert
for Jeff and Sandra tonight.
You OK?
Shall we tell Terry
about what we saw?
No way. As far as I'm concerned,
we didn't see a thing.
Hey, you!
Oh, my God!
Who made this shit?
OK, people.
Today was fun and games.
I like to start you out slow.
Tomorrow, we'll get serious.
Anybody wants a last night
on the town, now's your chance.
Who else? We only have two cars.
Our wanderers
have volunteered to watch the camp.
Isn't that nice of them?
I'll stay, too. Muffin may show.
Well, I'm gonna go change.
I'm pretty tired.
I think I'll stick around, too.
- Would you get me a coffee?
- Don't drink too much.
Hey, you staying?
Yeah. Nothing spoils a party
like a drunk in a wheelchair.
That's crap.
We can go together if you want.
I appreciate that,
but I'm in... training.
- Then I'm staying, too.
- Suit yourself.
- How about it? You coming?
- You buying?
- Sure.
- You got a deal.
Can I have the keys?
Beer time!
Take it easy. Have fun.
I'll have a Jack for you.
- See you later.
- Bring back my truck in one piece.
- I'm going for a walk.
- We'll wait up for you.
Go, Scooter.
Now I know
how you afford grad school.
You always find some fool
to fix your car and buy you a beer.
You got it.
Muffin?
- Here we are!
- Alright.
Everybody, get some beers! Alright!
C'mon, Mark.
You're gonna lose. Alright.
Cheater.
OK. Two out of three.
Jeff... don't wear yourself out.
You wanna wrestle, come with me.
Later, Scooter.
Wanna take me on?
Sure. Have a seat.
- I only want your fingers.
- What?
Take your pick.
They're Ted's. It's OK with him.
Football and hockey.
Which one do you prefer?
The one with the puck.
- You mean hockey?
- Is that what you call it?
OK. What d'you wanna play for?
Position.
Looking for something?
- Come and get it.
- Give me my shirt, Scott.
If I get my hands on you...!
Scott!
It's no longer funny, Scott.
Help! Goddamn that Paul.
Him and his wilderness bullshit.
- What can I do?
- Get me down.
- I'll have to get a knife.
- Well, hurry, OK?
I ought to let you hang, you pervert.
C'mon, Ter. Give me a break.
- You gonna cut the crap?
- Anything. I promise.
OK.
Don't go anywhere.
Very funny!
Where is she?
Scott, I'm gonna cut you down.
But if you ever do this to me again,
I'm gonna kill you.
Scott?
Look at this.
I think I'm in love.
No, it's just tremendous affection.
Are you sure
you don't want me to clear those?
No, I'm collecting these.
Have it your way. I just don't want
the bar to fall down on you.
Thanks.
- I think she likes you.
- I think so, too.
This whole thing's ridiculous.
Two of our kids got hauled in today
because five years ago,
some girl panics and falls out
of a canoe. It's absurd.
- What if there is a Jason?
- Bullshit, Ginny.
No, what if there is a boy-beast
running around Camp Crystal Lake?
Try to think beyond the legend.
Put it in real terms.
What would he be like today?
Some kind of
out-of-control psychopath?
A frightened retard?
A child trapped in a man's body?
Let me out!
- He'd be grown by now, right?
- Right.
The only person
that ever knew him was his mother.
He never went to school,
so he had no friends.
She was everything to him.
Yeah. Deranged killer.
No. You're missing my whole point.
I doubt Jason would have even known
the meaning of death.
At least until that horrible night.
He must've seen
the whole thing happen.
He must've seen his mother get
killed, all because she loved him.
Isn't that what her revenge
was all about?
Her sense of loss, her rage
at what she thought happened,
her love for him?
Bizarre, isn't it?
He must be out there now, crying
for her return, her resurrection.
- What d'you think?
- I think you're drunk.
I'll drink to that.
Hit us again, sweetheart.
Not me.
Paul, I'm really serious
about this stuff.
Jason's a legend, Ginny.
Your turn. Three goals,
or you're gonna lose.
I've heard that one before.
Mark, what happened
that you have to be in a chair?
Motorcycle accident
paralysed my legs.
Is it permanent?
The doctor thinks so. I don't.
I don't intend to be in this thing
the rest of my life.
Just your legs, huh?
Is everything else OK?
Oh, I do alright, one way or another.
Toke?
I'm in training, remember?
For what?
What does the winner get?
- What does the winner want?
- Guess.
Want to stay together tonight?
I was just about to ask you.
My cabin or yours?
Ted's in mine.
I don't think that would work out.
We've got the whole camp.
We'll find our own cabin.
Just let me get some things, OK?
- Sure.
- I'll be right back.
Oh, damn it.
Terry, you turkey.
There you are.
Vickie?
Vickie, is that you?
- I gotta sleep.
- I'm tired.
- You quitting already?
- You'd have me out till breakfast.
- I'll ride with you, OK? Night, Ted.
- Night, Ginny.
When this place closes,
come straight back to camp.
- Yes, boss.
- And let Maggie drive.
Yes, boss.
OK, let's make a run for it.
- Move it!
- I'm going!
This thing'd better start.
- You fixed it.
- That's what worries me.
Are there any after-hours places
around here?
Sure are.
Mark?
Mark, where are you?
Is anybody still here?
Sandra?
Jeff?
No!
Nice night!
Yeah, for a duck.
God.
What the hell
are all the lights on for?
They wouldn't have
left the place like this.
Think something's wrong?
I'll check upstairs.
These kids
smoke better dope than I do.
Paul!
Yeah, Ginny, what?
What is this, a joke?
They wouldn't do anything like this.
Ginny, c'mon.
Wait for me.
Kitchen light's still on.
Must be the main fuse again.
- Paul, what's going on here?
- Nothing.
Where is everybody?
I don't know.
The rain's stopping.
We'll go look for 'em.
Paul, there's someone in this room.
There's someone in this fucking room!
Oh, my God!
Paul?
Answer me!
Keys.
Come on!
Please start.
Oh, shit!
Oh, my God!
Please help me.
Oh, God...
Jason! It's all done, Jason.
You've done yourjob well,
and Mommy is pleased.
That's a good boy.
Now, come to Mommy. Come on.
Come on.
Mommy has a reward for you.
Jason, Mother is talking to you.
Come on.
That's my boy.
Come. Kneel down.
That's a boy.
Kneel down.
That's my good boy.
That's a good boy.
Good Jason.
Ginny!
Come on. Let's go.
Ginny.
Jesus!
Come on.
C'mon. I'll carry you.
It's alright.
Hey, you're alright.
God!
You're OK, Ginny.
It's alright.
Oh, Muffin!
Come here, Muffin.
Paul?
Where's Paul?
Synchronised by hdan for KiNESiS version.