No!
Come here.
Come here now.
No.
You're the last one.
I've killed all the others.
It'll be easier for you than it was for Jason.
Why are you doing this?
You need to be punished for what you did to him.
- I didn't do anything.
- You let him drown.
Jason was my son.
I didn't do anything.
No. No.
No. Please.
You should have been watching him.
Every minute.
Jason.
My special, special boy.
They must be punished, Jason, for what they did to you.
For what they did to me.
Kill for Mother.
I'm serious.
You gotta watch out for mountain lions.
They're all over this place.
- Mountain lions?
- Yeah, we'll be fine. They're afraid of fire.
Dude, shut the fuck up.
I'm calling bullshit.
Richie's gonna call bullshit.
- Bullshit!
- Richie's calling bullshit.
- Guess what, I'm not bullshitting.
- Bullshit.
Okey, fine. You'll see when a mountain lion comes out...
- Dude, there's one right there!
- Nice try.
I am more afraid to be eaten by mosquitoes.
Hey, you wanna slap that ass one more time for Daddy?
- Did Daddy like that?
- Yeah, Daddy does like it. A lot.
Whitney? Where are you right now?
- I'm here.
- Are you?
I'm here. Right in the middle of nowhere.
- Hey, are you reading that right?
- I'm reading it right.
- Come on, Pizarro, let's go.
- Where are we going?
- These are heavy and it's hot.
- Where are we?
Dude, we are way the fuck off.
- No, we're not, act...
- Yes.
No, we're not. Not everything shows up on GPS, Richie.
There is a sign that said there was a mine around here.
Did that come up?
No. We're close, I think.
You think? Dude, you don't know how to use this thing.
It's almost dark.
Do you know where it is or not?
Look, I didn't plant this shit, Richie, okay?
I got this tip from a secondhand source.
We should be close. I have to smell it.
Look, we're gonna stop here.
Tomorrow morning, you and me, we get up
at dawn. We go, we find the crop.
We cut down as much as we can.
We ditch it in the truck.
- Back here before breakfast, okay?
- Hey.
- Guys. Guys.
- Nobody knows a thing.
We don't even need that thing. There's a perfect
spot right over here. It's already been cleared.
Perfect. We'll camp here.
Hey. Do you know how much money
we're gonna make selling this weed?
- We're ganna get a lot of fucking money.
- Yeah, okay? So listen to me. Relax.
- I am relax. You wanna know why?
- Why?
Cause I wanna be fucking rich.
You know what rich people do?
- What?
- They relax. You need to fucking relax.
- I need to relax?
- You need to relax.
Hey, guys. Guys.
I just found some broken-down cabins over there.
It's gotta be the old camp.
Who wants to go check it out?
Is this all we brought to drink?
No Heineken?
Fuck that Euro shit.
This is Pabst Blue American Ribbon, my friend.
You do realize this camp was closed down, like 20 years ago?
Some woman, she went fucking nuts.
Killed all these counselors.
Blamed them for her son's drowning.
He was like...
deformed or retarded or something.
Really?
Mom got hers.
Apparently there was one survivor.
This girl...
she cut that lady's head off with a machete.
It gets weirder.
I'm sure it does.
Her son...
Jason...
he came back.
He was actually there.
He watched his mom being beheaded.
Actually a friend of mine, he went to camp around here...
- Oh, jeez.
- He went to camp around here.
He said the cops came.
They were looking for that Jason guy.
All right, you know what?
- Don't believe me.
- Nobody does.
Don't believe me.
But I'm pretty sure, the way the story goes...
the place was called Camp Crystal Lake.
Do you know how many lakes are probably called Crystal Lake?
It's like Crystal Geyser, Crystal Water.
Go to a supermarket.
Every single bottle of water is "Crystal" something.
- Aquafina.
- The...
- Okay, fine.
- Okay.
The story could have happened anywhere, dude.
It's that's how they get little kids to shit themselves.
- How's that beer, treat me a beer-snob?
- Better than my own piss.
You can drink that, by the way.
Yours, hers, hers, mine, yours. I swear, piss is sterile.
- For the record you will never drink my piss.
- That's what you think.
Exactly. What about me?
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Mm-hm.
I got marshmallow on my knee.
- Where you guys going?
- Go make out.
Oh, yeah?
- Hey, Mikey?
- Sweet.
Wear a condom.
An extra small one.
I get it, though, dude.
You do what you gotta do to survive, you know.
If we were all out here starving to death and you were dead...
I'd eat your leg.
- That's really sweet. Yeah.
- Thank you.
Why would you eat my leg, man?
I can teach you how to fish. Just go fishing.
I don't eat fish.
That's not what you told me.
Listen...
I don't think I'm gonna stay the whole time.
Did Wade's story scare you?
Please.
I just...
I don't feel right being here...
so far away from my mom.
Your mom was the one that told me
to get you out of town for a few days.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And she's in good hands.
She's got her nurse right there.
Come on.
Have sex with your boyfriend in a cramped little tent.
We can get hammered, blow some chunks in the woods.
Then we can go back Monday and deal with whatever.
Hey.
I'm a fucking idiot.
Richie?
- The ephemeris data just didn't sync up.
- Oh, dude, that sucks.
Fucking right.
- Do you know what this means?
- I wanna...
What?
We're, like...
We're, like, a half mile away.
- Less.
- Shut up.
You know what makes me happy, Richie?
Global positioning systems.
GPS to the layperson.
NASA technology in the palm of your hand.
Knows what this little fucker does?
This guy sends a signal up into outer space.
Signal.
Satellite gets it, turns it around.
It's like, "Oh, thank you, GPS. I'm gonna send a signal to you."
Back to the palm of your hand.
Technology, man.
It's fucking remarkable.
It is un-fucking-believable.
Wade, you gotta bounce, dude.
Tell your dumb shit to somebody else.
Why, because I'm fucking teaching you something?
That's probably it.
Say, Richie, old buddy, I'm gonna bounce.
- You do that, brother. Okay.
- I'm spent.
May the Force be with your Schwartz.
You're in so much trouble.
Oh.
Fuck, yes.
I love you.
And you. And you.
I even love you.
Oh, my God. Look at this shit.
What the fuck? What the fuck?!
What's this? No, no! No! No!
That must be the camp that Wade was talking about.
- Let's check it out.
- No, I wanna go this way.
Come on.
Wow, look at that.
Mike, where are you going?
- Let's go inside.
- No.
- Where's your sense of adventure?
- Oh, come on.
Come on. What are you scared of?
No.
I am willing to bet there's some pretty cool shit in here.
Mike, don't go in there.
What if some homeless person lives here?
No homeless person lives here.
You hungry?
Wow.
Look at how old this shit is.
It's like it was dragged here from another century.
Check this out.
Hey. It looks like you.
- No, it doesn't.
- Yeah, it does.
It's cool, you should keep it.
It's a little kid's room.
Wasn't Jason the name from Wade's story?
- I wanna go.
- What?
- Like, right now.
- Oh, come on.
Please?
- You like that?
- Yeah. Wait for me. Wait for me.
- No, I think I'm gonna...
- Oh, no. Don't do that again.
- We'll do it at the same time.
- Hang on.
- I'm almost there.
- Shit. I heard something.
Stop it. Wait, I'm serious.
- What?
- I think Wade's watching us.
What?
Well, fuck it, let the perv watch.
Right?
Shit.
Wade.
Dude, if you're out there whacking off, man, that is not cool.
Come on, dude.
I think we're good.
- Don't come yet.
- No, no.
- Tell me when you want to.
- Wait.
Oh, God. Oh, God. Okay.
Shit. Fuck. Shit.
Okay.
Wade!
I'm gonna kill you.
Okay.
- Okay?
- Okay.
No, go get him.
Tell him to leave us alone.
I'm not gonna go out there with a boner.
Well, you're not getting any until you do.
- Go.
- Do not move, okay?
Richie?
Richie, stop fucking around.
Wade.
Dude, you jump out from a tree, I'm gonna
punch you in your face, I shit you not.
Come on, man.
I gotta get back to the fucking tent.
Holy shit.
You fucking jerk, you found the weed.
Wade. Wade!
Wade. Wade.
Amanda!
Amanda! Goddamn!
Richie!
Fuck!
Oh, God!
Cool.
Whitney, you've gotta see this.
Mike. Come on.
No, I'm serious. You've gotta see this.
Somebody's been here.
What is that?
There's something in there.
- Looks like some kind of a doll.
- Are you crazy?
Oh, my God! Ah!
- Ah!
There's something out there.
- Stay here.
- No.
Ah! Oh, my God!
Get away, get back!
Get off the floor!
- Get up!
- Mike!
Holy fuck!
- Ah!
- Mike!
- Mike. Mike, Mike, Mike.
- Get out!
- Mike. Mike, get up. Come on.
- Go!
Help me!
- Mike! Mike!
- Run.
Run! Run, Whitney!
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Whitney! Whitney, help.
Whitney, please. Help!
Whitney! Whitney.
Whitney!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Shit.
Come on. Shit.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Babies have more space in the uterus.
Hey, Lawrence, how about a little help?
Dude, that's not a good look for you, man.
you ask the one black guy to pump the gas for you? Shit.
Okay. Nolan.
How about I pay, you pump?
Sure, man.
Hey, I give a wicked blow job too.
Okay, well, um, we'll try that out later.
Whoa. Hey, bro, that's... I have a heart murmur.
What are you doing?
- Thank you.
- Where'd you get a knapsack like that?
It was a present, actually.
But I'm looking for my sister.
She's gone missing, about a month and a half ago.
My parent's cabin is stocked.
You think you're actually gonna get laid?
Your parents do not have Combos or Funyuns.
And they definitely don't have Fritos.
And this is...
not for sex.
- What are you gonna use them for?
- It's an experiment.
Okay. So just get behind me.
I'm not gonna pay for that shit.
Would you mind if I maybe just put a flyer
in the window or something?
Oh, I heard about that. That's sad.
If it was up to me, you could wallpaper
the whole place with them...
but the owner makes the rules.
And he's a real:
Um...
Well, is he here? Maybe I could talk to him.
Maybe if he understands the situation...
Are you gonna buy something?
I mean, you've been up here for quite a while yapping, so...
Sure. Yeah.
Thanks. So we have two waters and some gas.
Two waters and some gas.
Guess I'm an asshole.
You okay, bro? Is everything good?
Yeah, everything's fine. Thanks.
But I'm not your bro.
So you don't wanna be friends, after this?
You don't wanna hang out?
- Let it go, Trent.
- It's not me. This guy's being a dick.
Yeah, it's me. Obviously, I'm the one being a dick.
Sir, thank you very much anyways.
- Yep.
- I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Seat belts.
Welcome back, Clay.
You mean that, Officer Bracke?
Son, I know you think we're not on your side...
that we're just a bunch of dumb country hicks out here.
I put two 10-year veterans on that case.
We did three dozen interviews and ran
a county-wide search for your sister.
You know how many thousands of people disappear every year...
even in this state alone?
But there's no evidence that anything happened to Whitney
Miller or any of those other kids at Crystal Lake.
There's no car, no witnesses.
Nothing.
One of those kids was her boyfriend, right?
Right.
Well...
they probably just took off together.
Our mother just died of cancer.
Did I tell you that?
- No, sir.
- Well, she did.
She was sick for a long time...
and Whitney took care of her every single day.
And then my sister didn't show up for the funeral.
See, you just don't know my sister.
That's not possible.
Well...
she's not here, son.
You may wanna try looking someplace else.
That's what the other families are doing.
- Can you say that with a...?
- Wow.
Can you say that with a little more hatred?
- Nice.
- Shit.
Sir Lancelot, thank you.
- Oh, man down.
- Take it easy, guys.
Is anyone getting a signal out here?
Are you fucking with me right now?
I got business I gotta do this weekend.
What business?
Music. I'm trying to start a label.
Oh, yeah? Like what kind? Like rap?
Why you gotta go racial?
Look, don't put me in a box, all right?
What, because I'm black I can't listen to Green Day?
You're right, that was dumb.
So, what kind of music?
Rap.
Here it is.
- Oh, my God.
- Yep.
All right, we have two bedrooms upstairs.
We've got one down.
Someone can take the couch.
It's comfy as hell.
- Wow.
- Nice, huh?
- Damn.
- That is a fierce pussy.
It's actually a bobcat. It's my dad's first kill.
Dude, I didn't think this long-ass car ride was gonna be worth it...
but it's kind of worth it.
This is bigger than the dorm.
What can I say?
Hey, take your feet off the table, please.
So make yourselves at home.
- What do you wanna do first?
- What do you wanna do?
Oh, well...
I brought Sweet Lucille.
I think you all need to meet her.
Lucille? Baby, is that you?
- Lawrence, you've been cheating.
- No.
- I saw you with a bowl the other night.
- No, you...
A bowl.
Hello?
Christ.
- I just wanted to ask you a question.
- Hush.
I wanted to ask you if maybe you've seen somebody.
My sister.
She came camping up around here with some friends...
and she's gone missing.
She ain't missing.
She's dead.
What?
People go missing around here they're gone for good.
Outsiders come, they don't know where to walk.
They bring trouble.
We just wanna be left alone.
And so does he.
So does who?
Ma'am, please. So does who?
- You, baby. It's all you.
- Stop peer-pressuring me.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, shit.
- Yes!
- My fucking eye!
Guys, watch the floor, all right, please?
That's stained oak.
- This is an outside game. Come on.
- Wait, I got foam in my contact.
Hey. This is a great spot.
Do you wanna go for a hike?
Get some exercise?
That'd be nice, but, well, I can't exactly leave them here alone.
What are you talking about?
Have you seen what they're doing inside?
Crazy. Some drunken hoodlums.
- Hoodlums?
- Hoodlums.
What do you think they're gonna do?
- I mean, steal the deer head?
- You're right.
How are they gonna pull off the getaway?
We're all leaving in the same car.
Come on. Do you want some exercise?
Because I have this really great move that I've been practicing...
and I need someone to practice it with.
Very charming. Very charming.
Oh, come on.
- I'll go on a hike. You wanna go on a hike?
- Yeah, you like hikes now?
- I love hikes.
- I knew it.
Will you get me a beer?
Excuse me.
Sir?
- Hey!
- Oh, shit. Jesus.
Sorry.
Jesus Christ.
You're fucking lucky there, stretch.
Came that close to hitting the start button
on the whoop-ass machine, boy.
Look, I didn't mean to startle you.
I was trying to get your attention.
This is Mr. Garikes' property.
You're lucky that old mummy fart didn't come
out of here and put buckshots in your ass.
Somebody has been stealing his fucking kerosene too.
Look, I just came in here to ask you something, okay?
I'm looking for this girl.
Have you seen her?
She's been missing for about a month.
I wish I had, man.
- I ain't seen her, though.
- Thanks.
- Take care.
- You too.
Shit. Hey, hey, hey.
I forgot, did you wanna buy some weed?
Seriously, I found a fucking shit ton of it
growing out there. A little bushel.
- Sell you some.
- No. Thanks.
- You sure? I got a whole bunch of it.
- I'm good.
You sure?
It's your fucking loss, dude.
It'll fuck your shit up, boy.
Good times...
fucker.
Just relax, okay?
These guys are your guests.
If you're...
If you're not comfortable having them here,
then why did you invite them?
So they could admire your place?
No. I just wanted to have a good weekend. You know?
Hey, guys. Wanna check out the other side of the lake with us?
Um... You know what?
It's getting, you know...
No. That's okay. It's...
It's okay. It's getting kind of late.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Take my truck.
- Nice.
- I trust you.
And can you do me a favor?
Will you take the gas cans to the boat?
It's on the south end of the lake.
Just take a right onto Town Road.
- Take a right.
- Okay, and then?
Why don't you just type "boat" into the nav?
- Technology, right?
- See you.
- Have fun.
- Later.
Don't drive my boat.
I'm the only one that drives the boat, okay?
Aye, aye, captain.
Damn straight.
What does that say about me
that the second Trent said...
"Don't take my boat out," it was guaranteed that I would.
It means you're a sociopath.
Now, what does it say about me that I find that hot?
Hi, I'm sorry to bother you, but I'm looking for my sister and...
Hey.
- No luck?
- No. No, not yet.
- May I?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
She's pretty.
Thanks.
Do you wanna come in for a second, grab a drink?
Uh...
I don't think your boyfriend would like that too much.
Don't worry. He'll be fine.
And here we have the stoned
American male, foraging for food.
Thanks.
This should be interesting.
Hey, Trent, you remember...
Clay.
Yeah. Of course I remember Clay.
Why is he in my house?
Hey, new guy. Beer?
No, no. He's gotta get going.
You got flyers to pass out, right?
Yeah.
Right.
- Look, if you're hungry, we...
- Okay.
Look, Clay, obviously she's just trying to be nice.
But you can't stay here.
No offense, but this is a private party.
- I don't know you.
- No, you don't know me.
That's so funny, I just said that.
Like two seconds ago, that I don't know you.
I would probably leave soon before
I get pissed off and, you know...
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
What happens then?
Hey, look. Take it easy, Trent, all right?
I'll just... I'll walk you out.
Yeah.
Jenna. Jenna, come on.
Where you going?
Sorry about that.
That's all right.
It's his house, you know?
Where's your car?
I do not have a car,
but I do have her.
- Nice.
- Thanks.
- This thing runs?
- Yeah. Yeah, it runs.
So where you off to next?
Well I haven't been to the other side of the lake, You had saw
so I was probably gonna go check that out, you know.
- Do you want some company?
- I'd love some company.
What's up, beaver bear?
It's a big motherfucker, huh?
Fuck, yeah.
You hot bitch.
Let Daddy have a little lick.
You like that, bitch? You know you do.
What the fuck was that?
Don't smoke my weed, motherfucker.
Somebody better not be stealing the kerosene up there.
Shit.
Gina.
It's just you, baby.
It's been a long time, Gina.
You remember that special night we had?
You remember when you took my virginity?
You're sexy.
You're still tight as ever.
I'm gonna fucking pound you so hard.
What the fuck?
What the...?
That shit ain't fucking right, dude.
What the fuck?
I don't know, you really think we should take the boat out?
I mean he's gonna find out.
- I knew it.
- What?
You're inhibited. You talk a big game,
but inside you're just a scared little girl.
Oh, really? Oh, okay, fine.
You wanna find out who's really scared? Let's do it.
All right. Let's go.
So you and your sister must be pretty close.
Yeah. We were pretty close when we were younger.
We kind of drifted.
You know, I mean, I bailed when I was 17,
and she stayed with my mom.
She kind of had to, I guess.
I don't know, she's always been the responsible one.
So when's the last time you talked to her?
About six months ago.
We got in a fight, actually.
She called and said she wanted to see me,
said she was counting on me...
and I never showed.
Excuse me.
What is that?
It's a GPS.
- All right, you ready?
- Ready. Let's do it.
Yeah. Oh, shit.
Yeah.
Pick it, pick it.
Oh, you like that, you like the balls in your hand, huh?
Which one? Which one is it?
Is that the one?
- Those feel good, don't they?
- That's the one.
Shoot.
Fuck.
One of you has gotta shoot the boot.
That's you, babe.
That's you.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
You missed the shot.
I've been carrying you the entire game.
- Come on, baby.
- Drink up, drink up, drink up.
Shoot the boot, shoot the boot,
shoot the boot.
Shoot the boot.
Fuck that. I'm not drinking out of your sweaty-ass sneaker.
You are not wearing socks, dude.
You lost 10 in a row. Shoot the boot.
My house, my rules.
I'm not drinking that shit.
- Fine.
- Oh, no.
- To all the felching...
- No. No.
- welching...
- Yes.
pussies of the world.
That's disgusting.
Oh!
Yeah.
What are you doing, Nolan?!
Nolan!
Nolan. Oh, my God.
Nolan.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Nolan?
Oh, shit. Oh, my God.
What do you want from me?
Oh, my God.
- I never liked camp.
- Why?
Bad food, bugs, cheap toilet paper.
Know what? Stay. Maybe we should
check these cabins out, you know?
- Sure.
- Come on.
Let's just check out this last cabin, then we'll head back.
Come on.
You really should call the police.
Yeah, I've already called the police.
You know, they're not looking for her anymore.
No one is, except for me.
Then they should look harder because...
Oh! Ow.
- You all right?
- I'm okay, I'm okay.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Let's get out of here.
Watch your step.
Give me a sec, I gotta change out my batteries.
- Someone's coming.
- Oh, shit. Let's go.
Oh, my God.
Where's he going?
- Oh, my God. We gotta go.
- Shh.
- I gotta follow him.
- He had a dead body.
- We gotta go. We gotta warn my friends.
- Okay, okay.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
What is that?
Help!
Come on, let's go.
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Help me!
Help!
No. No.
Please don't hurt me.
It's okay.
Jason.
Clay.
Shit.
Come on.
- This way. Come on.
- Okay.
In my next life...
I wanna come back as...
one of the buttons on the ass pocket of her jean shorts.
- Just go over there and fucking talk to her.
- Are you kidding me?
I have a better shot at fucking a penguin than that girl.
- Let's light this bad boy.
- Great.
Here we go.
Yes.
Hey.
Here's to Daddy's shoes and fucking douche bags.
- Let's just all be one big happy cliché.
- Yes.
Dude, what the fuck?
Please, try not to burn down my house.
Did you forget how to drink that?
Just bring it to your lips...
blow...
and suck.
- You're really good at that.
- Mm-hm.
Fuck, dude!
You just broke my dad's fucking chair.
My fucking lip, man.
I don't care about your fucking lip.
This is a family heirloom.
- Oh, shit. Oh, my God, I'm so sorry.
- Fuck!
I just... No, I can fix this.
I just need some tools.
- He can fix it.
- You know, you better pull some MacGyver shit.
All right, go to the toolshed.
It's down the path.
Yeah, okay. I'm just... Trent, I'm sorry, man.
You won't be disappointed.
- They don't call me "wood wizard" because I masturbate a lot.
- Grab a flashlight, you fucking idiot.
Thanks.
Forget about it. He'll fix it.
Let's go finish this.
That's a ugly fucking chair anyway.
Hi. My name is Trent. My daddy bent me over this chair
and beat me when I was little, so you need to fix it.
Hey, now.
Yes.
You people are rich.
Holy crap.
Poor people call this a house. Jesus Christ.
You have never used this shit.
Fucking douche bag.
Skis. What the fuck?
Ha! Ha!
"Lagavulin, product of Scotland."
Oh.
That just smells like money.
I knew there was a reason to be your friend, Trent.
More? Oh, absolutely. No...
All right, you don't have to force it on me.
Fuck.
You can grease wheels with this shit.
That's payment for being a douche bag.
Okay.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, wow. Your tits are stupendous.
Wow, you really know how to make a girl feel special, huh?
That's what I do.
Yeah, they can go. Take off my pants.
They can go.
Oh, man.
All right. Let's see what you've got.
All right, give me something, baby.
What you got for me? Give me something.
Goddamn. Not even a swimsuit? Shit.
Goddamn winter catalog.
Oh, okay.
Gonna have to do.
Lady, I'm about to ruin your perfect day.
All right.
Shit. You scared the piss out of me.
Where is everybody? There's a guy out
there carrying a dead body.
Jenna, where's the phone?
I... I don't know. Over there?
You fucking with me because I'm high?
That's totally not cool becuase I just
finished fucking smoking, okey.
Where's the phone?
Hi, I want to report a homicide.
Clay Miller.
Yeah, I'm at a house by Crystal Lake. It's...
Yeah, that's it. Hurry.
They said they're sending someone.
- Police?
- Yeah.
- Where is everybody else?
- I don't know. I've been here all day.
Chelsea and Nolan left, like, hours ago.
They went to the lake or some shit.
- Well, what about Trent? Bree?
- They're in the bedroom.
- Your tits are fucking just...
- I know.
so juicy, dude.
You got perfect nipple placement, baby.
This better not go on the fucking Internet.
These would win in a fucking titty contest.
Trent, Bree. You guys in there?
Trent! Bree!
Shut the fuck up!
Get out here!
They're just fucking with us.
- Ignore her.
- Come on, guys.
Get out here. There's a guy out there.
- We're busy in here, baby.
- Trent.
Yeah.
Okay. All right, Trent.
Let me educate you.
You ever seen a crossover before, huh?
I'm gonna show you right now.
I'll bet you never...
Whoa. Ow.
Jesus.
Hey.
Now, this is a man's sport.
You're even curved to the left, like my penis.
Okay, it's overtime. Line change.
Chewie's on the ice.
Send the puck around the back of the net.
Here we go. Pass back to the middle. Oh!
Oh, my...
No, no, no.
Shit.
Oh, God. You scared the shit out of me, bro.
Are you looking for this?
Because it completes your outfit.
Oh, fuck.
What the fuck? Oh, Jesus.
No.
Oh, my God, baby. Getting close.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I got aboat eight seconds, then I'm going.
Oh, God.
I'm going soon. I'm going.
No.
That was...
Stupendous?
To say the least, yeah.
- Who's messing with the lights?
- Oh, shit. Chewie's still out there.
Phone's dead.
- Jenna, do you have a cell? Do you have anything?
- No, nothing has a signal.
What the fuck are you doing here?
- Trent...
- Get the fuck out of here, buddy.
- Easy.
- He's just trying to help us.
You leave with this guy for eight hours,
fucking all over the woods?
You know what? Why don't both of you just get the fuck out?
- Listen dump shit there's a bigger problem...
- Shut up.
Are you serious?
There is a killer out there.
He's the one who cut the lights, okay.
Trent, don't you get it?
Chelsea and Nolan never came back.
Lawrence, what are you doing?
My boy's still out there.
I'm gonna go get him.
No, look man. Don't go out there. Please.
Look, I told, all right?
You can't get a handle on me.
I'll surprise you every time.
Chewie?
Hey, Chewie?
Chew, you in there?
Chewie?
Chewie, you in here?
Oh, fuck.
Get the fuck off me.
Take that, motherfucker.
Guys, this is bullshit.
All right, The power goes out here all the time.
Help me!
Help! Help me!
Please, help me.
- Lawrence.
- No, no, no. You can't go out there.
- We have to help him.
- No, we can't, okay.
He's using your friend as bait.
He wants us to go out there.
Well, you don't know that.
Jesus, where are the police?
I can't move.
- Help me!
- We have to help him.
I can't die like this.
Help me, please. Trent.
Somebody, help.
Oh, my God, please.
I can't fucking...
Somebody's gotta do something!
Please.
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
Everyone's gonna be okay, all right?
The cops are on their way.
What are you doing?
Trent.
Jenna?
Police.
- Oh, thank God.
- Go, go.
Police, open up.
- Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Go, go, go.
- Oh, my God.
Get the door.
Okay. Shit.
- What are you doing? Is he inside the house?
- He killed the cop.
What the fuck, you got a gun?
Let's go now.
Jesus! What are you doing?
Give me the gun.
Someone's in there.
Check it out.
Bree's dead. He killed Bree.
Come on.
There's no gun, no keys, nothing.
Let's go.
Where are the keys?
- Help! We got officers down.
- My keys are gone. Where are my keys?
Hey, Jenna, fuck this guy.
Let's get out of here.
Go. Go. Go, go, go! Jesus.
Oh, my God.
Shit. Where the fuck are you, gun?
Fuck.
Fuck it.
- Oh, my God, that's... that's Chelsea.
- We gotta keep moving. Go.
All right, this way.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Help!
Shh.
- Who was that?
- Let me out!
- Oh, my God.
- What the fuck?
Help me!
Help me.
This way.
- Clay?
- Whitney. Whitney.
- Oh, God, Clay.
- Thank God.
Are you okay? You okay? Thank God.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
You're okay. You're okay.
Okay. You're okay?
Oh, God.
- Okay.
- Yeah, just get me out of here.
Fuck.
- Come on, you guys, let's go.
- Can you break it?
- No, just break it, just break it.
- Okay.
Yeah, just go. Go. Just fucking do it.
- Hold still. Hold your hands.
- Okay. Hurry up, hurry.
Do it. Fucking do it.
- We gotta get out of here.
- I don't wanna hit you.
- Just go. Just fucking do it.
- Okay, okay. Okay.
Hurry.
Oh, God.
Holy shit.
Okay, okay, okay.
You guys, I can see him. He's coming.
- What?
- We gotta go.
- Grab onto me. Grab onto me.
- Let's go. Come on, hurry.
Go, go, go.
Go. Come on.
Go. Go.
It's a dead end.
What are we gonna do?
Clay?
Hurry.
Here. Here.
Come on, we can get through here.
Follow me.
- Go, go, go.
- It's safe, guys.
Give me your hand, Jenna.
Come on, hurry.
Give me your hand. Okay. I got you.
Oh, my... Fuck. Jesus, God, no.
- Oh, God. Clay. Clay.
- No. No.
- Oh, fuck.
- Oh, God. Oh, God. Clay.
Come on, we gotta go.
Look. I think this might be a way out.
All right. Let's go. Come on. Hurry.
Let's go. Watch out.
Come on.
- Hurry.
- Damn it. It's stuck.
Come on, come on.
- Come on.
- Hurry.
Give me your hand. Give me your hand.
Give me your hand. Okay, okay.
On three. One... Come on.
- Run. Whitney, get...
- Clay! Clay! Clay!
Stop it!
No!
Clay! Clay!
Shit. Shit.
Fuck you.
No, no, no!
Whitney!
- Whitney.
- Clay. Clay!
Come on. Let's go.
Hurry.
Come on.
Hide.
Shit, fuck.
Jason.
It's okay.
You can stop now.
Jason.
Say hi to Mommy...
in hell.