In ignem iacto unguenta pretiosa,
et mira sumio.
Tibi supplex...
donem honorem!
No!
You promised!
You promised not our child!
Whore! He is the one.
You can't hurt him now, you bastard!
His blood will flow.
Come.
Take him away! For ever!
Do it now.
You will take his place.
Don't be afraid, little one.
You'll be safe.
Lucifer!
Rubrum e iugulo
ut tibi supplex donem honorem.
The child had been saved,
so it seemed.
And I vowed that he would never know
the evil from whence he was spawned.
And when his father
finally died a horrible death,
I felt sure that the curse
had passed for ever.
I can't believe
you inherited this place.
I know. Me neither.
I suppose we'll just have to
get used to the good life.
Do we get to hire
a maid and a cook?
Are you kidding? It's gonna break me
just to keep the lawn mowed.
Well, we could always sell it
and move to Westwood.
- Very funny. Very funny.
- No, I like this place... I think.
What's that?
- I don't know. It looks...
- Like a grave.
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna take a look.
No, don't. It's kinda creepy-looking.
Come on, Becky. It's mine, isn't it?
I don't know. Looks sorta old.
Must have been hard growing up
without a family. I mean...
Rebecca, this is Wolfgang.
He's sort of the caretaker around here.
Wolfgang, this is Rebecca.
Hi. I...
You scared me.
Well, we'll go back to the house.
We'll see you later, Wolfgang.
So Wolfgang's the only family
I've ever known.
Who read all these books? Your dad?
Yeah, I guess so.
The Secret World of Magic?
The Black Magic Ritual.
The Grimoire of Abra-Melin.
You all right?
You probably scared him
more than he scared you.
Why don't you start cleaning the upstairs
and I'll work on the downstairs?
What do you say?
OK. But if there are any more rats,
the deal's off.
I've been thinking.
About having a party.
- Here?
- Sure. Why not?
It's not like anybody
could wreck the place.
Whoa!
This is it! Eddie, Eddie.
They got food.
Eddie, these are my friends.
They love me, man.
- And this is where they're at.
- That's good. That's real good.
But what if they're not?
Then I'll have to get some new friends.
Man, you should have seen the quim
I poked last night.
I'm so unhappy.
Toad Boy needs sweetmeat for his tum.
Will you knock off
that Toad Boy shit already? Jesus!
- You don't love me. You just pretend.
- Shit, I can't talk to you, man.
- Hey, Dick.
- Jon.
- How you doing?
- All right. It's him I'm worried about.
- Hey, Mark. How you doing?
- I'm miserable.
So, wanna dance later?
Think you can handle it?
- Try me.
- I might.
I went out with Mark last night.
You're kidding?
- You mean Toad Boy?
- Don't ask me why.
No, things were really nice, they were,
but then he just got so weird.
Do you think he's a virgin?
I don't know.
But I certainly know who isn't.
Hey, Rebecca.
Can you lead me to the nearest beer?
In the refrigerator.
Thanks.
So... who's your beautiful friend?
- I'm Donna.
- They call me Dick.
But you can call me... Dick.
Break dance!
I think I busted my head.
Thank God.
I thought that you really hurt yourself.
- What do you guys wanna do?
- We could play hide-and-go-seek.
Yeah!
What about Trivial Pursuit?
- Yeah.
Why don't we just play charades?
Yeah.
- Strip poker.
- Yeah.
No way.
All right!
I got an idea. Let's do a ritual.
You guys, it's kinda spooky in here.
Everybody listen up.
I want everybody to take a sip. Go ahead.
I'm gonna draw a circle
and I want you all to stay inside it.
Go on, man.
So now what are you doin'?
I'm gonna conjure up a spirit,
and it's gonna appear
right here in this triangle.
Yeah. OK.
I believe you.
Jonathan, how do you know
how to do that?
I don't know. I must have read it in a book.
Rebecca, take the rock
and put it at the north point of the circle.
Where?
Take the candle
and put it at the south point.
Right there.
Yod hay vau hay.
You do the hokey-pokey and you turn...
Hey, knock it off!
Ateh malkuth...
ve-gedulah ve-geburah...
le-olahm. Amen.
Te nunc transforma in formam veram
quod eludet species mentem meam.
Shut up, goddammit!
I'm sorry. Jeez.
O Surgat, I conjure thee...
that thou come
before this circle immediately
and agree to obey my orders.
Come, I order thee,
in the name of the most Holy Trinity.
I order thee to manifest thyself at once,
without injury to me or any in this room.
Come, I order thee.
Come, I order thee,
in the name of the most Holy Trinity.
Come, I order thee.
Well, that was fun.
- Yeah, let's go get another beer.
- Nice try, Jon.
- Where's Robin?
- I don't know.
- Maybe the toad monster got her.
- I don't think that's funny.
She's not the kind who would just leave.
Honey, I think we'd better go find her.
- Yeah, come on.
- No, wait. I need to dismiss the spirit.
So do I. Where's the bathroom?
Upstairs.
Come on.
- Robin?
- Hey, Robin!
Jeez!
Dude.
- Dude.
- What?
I don't think she's in here.
Well, I don't think so either.
- Hey, let's check out the closet.
- Check out the closet.
You bozo!
- Hey, Mike. Mike.
- What?
Wasn't he over there?
I don't think she's here.
Robin! Hey, Robin. Where are you?
Hey! Robin.
Robin! Hey, come on.
There she is.
Hey, Robin, what are you doing?
Robin.
Robin?
- You OK?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Come on, little girl.
I'll have you feelin' better in no time.
- I made a big decision today.
- What?
Well... I decided to withdraw
from school this quarter.
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
Listen, I just think
I should take some time off.
Stay home and fix this place up.
I walked around this place all day today.
I thought of these great things I could do.
Terrific. Can't you just wait until
you've graduated to fix up the house?
No, I can't wait.
I got this urge to do it now.
Look, when I inherited this house,
I inherited a lot of responsibility.
I'm just trying to do things right.
I want this to be a nice home
for both of us.
This place is gonna need work and
I can't do it if I'm going to school full time.
You understand?
Yeah, I understand.
I just want good things for you.
I know.
And so it had begun.
The evil one willing the boy on,
using the boy's curiosity
as a powerful weapon.
I could but sit and wait, gripped
by the fear of events foreshadowed.
- Hey, kiddo.
- Hi. How did it go today?
See for yourself.
I can't believe it.
You know something?
I'm really proud of you.
Wait. There's more.
Open it.
It's really beautiful.
- What is it?
- It's a talisman.
It'll protect you from...
- From what?
- From everything.
- Even my physics professor?
- Mr. Bolton? Yes, especially him.
You never take it off, OK?
I promise. I love it.
Jonathan?
Dinner's ready!
Are you OK? You look terrible.
I'm fine.
- Well, come and have dinner.
- No. I'm not eating.
- Why not?
- I'm...
I'm fasting.
You're fasting?
Jonathan, I don't know what you're up to,
but I just cooked dinner for us.
So you can do
whatever the hell you wanna do.
O Paimon, I conjure thee.
Empowered with the strength
of the greatest power.
I command thee, creature of the water,
bring forth life unto this world.
I command thee, come. At once!
Welcome to this world.
I am your master.
You may roam about the grounds,
but you must remain invisible
to all but me.
Remain obedient to me at all times.
Understood?
I call upon thee, Vepar,
and thee, Procel, and thee, Ashtaroth.
Bring forth the fury
of thy tempest before me.
With these words:
non humus somnifera exsulat
ignis et que erat.
Somnifera facta sunt.
Come. Now!
Show me thy might!
Come now, that I might
anoint myself with thy power!
Yes! Come now!
Yes! Yes!
Thank you, Vepar, Procel, Ashtaroth,
for having appeared
and for having fulfilled my request.
Thou mayest depart in peace.
Ye shall return when I call upon thee.
Now, indeed you are
a powerful instrument.
Jonathan?
What are you doing?
Rebecca. You're home early.
Would you please tell me
what's going on here?
I get it.
Oh, no. Don't change for me.
I will leave you here
to do whatever you're doing,
and I will go upstairs
and make dinner for myself,
since you're not even eating these days.
- No, Becky, wait.
- No, don't!
Becky, listen to me!
Becky, come on, wait!
Rebecca.
Look, will you listen...
Look, talk to me.
What the hell's going on here, Jonathan?
You tell me that you wanna drop out of
school so that you can fix up the house.
- Right?
- Right.
So I come home and I find you...
in the middle of I don't even know what.
- Why'd you lie?
- I didn't lie.
I have been working on the house.
That's all I've been doing.
I got sidetracked. I figure this stuff
has got something to do with my parents.
I don't know who they were,
so I'm curious. Don't you understand that?
No, I don't understand it. That's just
the problem. I don't understand.
Don't do this to me.
When I walked in that room,
I saw someone that I didn't even know.
I saw... a stranger.
Rebecca, please.
Look, it's nothing. Honest.
Look, I'll cut it out. I swear.
Rebecca, I love you.
You know that.
I just get scared, that's all.
It's the last time
you'll hear anything about it.
I swear.
Hi.
- Rebecca.
- Hm?
I love you.
Well, I love you, too.
What are you saying?
What? Jonathan.
Jonathan. What are you doing?
Stop it! Jonathan!
What are you doing?
You bastard!
- Becky.
- No, that's it. I've had it.
- Listen...
- No, you listen to me.
I've had it with your black magic,
your rituals, your lies, everything.
Goodbye, Jonathan.
Leviatan, Ermogasa, Vmirteat, lorantga.
Agtnaroi, Taetrimv, Asagomre, Nataivel.
Agtnaroi, Taetrimv, Asagomre, Nataivel!
- We are here, Master.
- What would you have of us?
I will have you serve me.
- That precisely...
- Is why you've called us, Master.
- And we will.
- Most faithfully.
Forsaking all others... you will obey me?
- Unquestioningly.
- We are yours.
Drink.
- How may we drink?
- If you do not release us from the triangle.
If you are worthy to serve me,
you will drink.
If you are not worthy, you will burn.
The choice is yours.
- Me. Me first.
- No, me first.
Excellent. Well done.
What are your names?
- I'm called Grizzel.
- And I am called Greedigut.
- And who am I?
- You are Jonathan.
Our master. What is it you wish, Master?
Knowledge. And power.
These things we can do.
What about Rebecca?
Do you want her as well?
- You know of Rebecca?
- We know of many things, O Master.
- Yes, I want her.
- Then you shall have her.
- As for the other things...
- There must be a master ritual.
There must be seven others
besides yourself.
When the moon is full.
The ritual is fraught with danger, Master.
- Don't speak of it.
- What?
- Answer me now!
- The ritual is dangerous.
But you must perform it
if you want knowledge.
And power.
What do you want?
You. I want you.
I want you to come away with me now,
tonight, away from this house.
No. Never.
I could never leave this place.
Your eyes.
What have you done to your eyes?
It's a sign. A sign of power.
I don't want this.
I love you, Jonathan, but I'm leaving.
It's over!
Becky, I love you.
I'm so sorry, Jonathan.
Please forgive me.
The evil one had him now.
The things that would be unleashed
that night were to be horrific.
And I was powerless to stop it.
What is that? Mushroom dip?
There's a lot of it.
- Nice house.
- It's really nice.
Really grand. It's really special.
Really wonderful.
You've invited me here and all that.
You know what? You're a prince, an earl.
A prince among earls.
King of the soirée.
Bad manners, dude.
I'm sorry. Rebecca, I'm really sorry.
- Small faux pas.
- Don't worry about it, Mark.
You know what they say: a faux pas a day
helps keep your friends away.
- I'm really sorry.
- Mark, it's OK.
No, it's not...
How come you and Jonathan
aren't eating?
We ate already.
Rebecca, why don't you sit down?
All right, darling.
Why are we wearing these ridiculous
glasses? I can barely see what I'm eating.
It's all part of the evening I have planned.
It's gonna be great.
A toast.
To my friends. Forgive me.
Mesabim, Etosa.
Boros, Azote,
Drink.
Queladim!
Come.
Recabustira, Cabustira, Bustira, Tira, Ta.
Hear me, all you hosts gathered here.
Give me the knowledge.
I will have the wisdom and the power!
Answer me, my friends.
Beseder, Eliele.
Sepped, Eliele.
Beseder, Eliele!
- Beseder, Eliele!
- Sepped, Eliele.
Sepped, Eliele.
Sepped, Eliele. Sepped, Eliele.
By the force
of these terrible words of power...
Aglon! Tetragram! Retragrammaton!
Soter Emanuel! Te invoco!
Aagh!
A toast. To my friends.
Rebecca and I are going to retire early.
You're welcome to spend the night.
The house is yours. Just pick a room.
- Wine cellar.
- Oh! You madman. Yeah!
- Good night, everyone.
- Good night.
So... can't wait to pick a room.
Children, your true master has returned,
and tonight you will do my bidding.
Baby, I've been waiting
for this moment ever since we met.
All right!
Mark, would you hurry up?
God, it's kinda spooky out here.
Wasn't Rebecca acting kinda weird at
dinner? The way she looked at me when...
- Gotcha!
- God!
Come on. Let's sit down.
Come on over here. Come on.
- Right here.
- That wasn't funny.
Sorry.
- Nice night.
- Spooky.
Is that a little girl's tum?
Don't, Mark! You're tickling me!
Please stop!
Sounds like Toad Boy's on the attack.
Mark!
My... Mark, my bracelet.
Don't worry. I shall retrieve it.
I can't see anything.
Yuck! I touched something weird.
Mark.
What the hell's in there?
Man, that chick is really a screamer.
Where are you going?
Water. Want some?
No, thanks.
- I'll be back.
- I'll be waiting.
Aagh!
Who are you?
Come here.
No doubt about it, Mr. Dick.
You are a lucky guy.
Who are you?
You got any matches?
- Yeah. I got reserves.
- Great.
You got any that work? Jeez!
Well, there's gotta be some around here.
I'll be back.
I'm sorry, Rebecca.
I'm sorry I had to do it this way.
But it worked.
It'll all be worth it. You'll see.
I just hope you can forgive me.
Jonathan?
What am I?
- I'll tell you about it in the morning.
- Yeah, I'm so tired.
Sleep now.
Matches.
Matches...
Nah.
No, don't do it here.
- Outside.
- Yes, all right.
Pull!
Shit.
Where's that guy?
There it is. Get it.
- I despise these creatures.
- Quiet!
Malcolm is the master, blast his soul. He
always has been and will be until you rot.
No, it is not so.
I cannot do this thing. I cannot.
Ooh! Oh! Ow! Oh!
Quiet. Quiet. He'll burn us both.
Hey, dude. Don't bogart that joint.
Come to me. Come to me, my children.
All of you.
Let me show you my love.
Come to me now.
Jonathan?
Oh, boy. What a dream.
Why, Jonathan? Why?
Becky!
No!
Becky?
No.
Becky.
My God.
I can make you live. I've got the power.
Becky.
Where's my robe?
Where the hell's my robe?
Aren't you going to greet your father?
You did my bidding well, Jonathan.
You...
Grizzel, Greedigut.
You tricked me. I'm your master.
No! I am the master.
I own them as I now own you.
Come... and greet your father.
Vepar, Procel, Ashtaroth. Help me now!
Where are your gods now?
They too are mine.
Not bad.
Although at your age I was much better.
You...
You killed them.
You killed Rebecca.
Hm?
Yes, I suppose I did.
But it was you I really wanted, Jonathan.
You were to resurrect me.
And what should have happened
25 years ago will happen now.
I will have your youth, Jonathan.
Greater things
command all of us, Jonathan.
I suppose that in another time,
another place,
I could have loved you as my son.
My soul is not my own,
and you must be my sacrifice to Lucifer.
Again... a good effort.
But it is your love
that weakens you, Jonathan.
You can never oppose me.
A shame.
She's so pretty.
May you rot!
- Becky.
- Jonathan.
Forgive me.
I love you, Jonathan. Please.
Take me away from here. Take me.
Hold me.
Kiss me.
I love you.
- Oh, Becky. I'm so sorry.
- It's all right, my love.
Come to me.
No, Master Jonathan. Don't listen.
It's a trap, yes!
No!
You little worms!
You shall burn for this later.
But now... I am tired of playing.
You try my patience.
You are my life! And I will have my life!
Kiss me, my son.
Kiss me.
Let me drain the life from your lips.
You will not have the boy's life!
You are no match for me, old man.
Die, evil one!
Get out of here while you still can!
Aagh!
No. No.
Dick, come on, wake up.
We gotta get outta here.
- Come on! Let's go.
- Jonathan. How?
Don't ask.
- What's going on?
- Just get in the car.
You got a cigarette on you?
Would somebody mind telling me
what the hell is going on?
It's a long story, Mike. But it's over now.
Is it, Jonathan? Is it really?
Yeah, really.