My name is Jerrod Hartfeld.
A video production company lead. Here in California.
The reality is mainly specialized in broadcasting.
The Tornado Hunter show is on our own.
Letter from a shooting.
The presentation was part of a new reality series. The title is deadly.
Lance Preston Young was the producer.
The idea was that he and a few paranormal investigator
felderítenek spirits, places and things as related.
Has been for many years before these types of programs like this.
I did not think it's time.
My name is Lance Preston.
Even when I was a kid my parents moved to a haunted house.
With that we are there, stayed with me forever.
Since then, the obsession was to record
and demonstrate that these things are real.
Hug and paranormal expert nyomozóimmal
felgöndörítjük as the current most popular hangouts.
We'll be all night, and everything you add!
When finished, it's time for some
Meeting of the grave!
Everything went pretty well.
The cut was good. We were very excited.
At last there was something.
Then came the sixth.
Want to say something?
Yes! I want to clarify this.
What you see now is not a movie.
No?
We have dozens of hours of raw material together.
A rabbit second, we can not in any way.
This is simply raw összevágtuk only.
(Do not copy the movie)
Signal!
Hello! Hello! Test Site, you!
Lance Preston.
I do, so you will be able to go through the background.
He moved a little, but ...
Ready? I'm ready!
Still there. Only what I want.
A little further back. Is that good?
Good afternoon! Welcome to the new section of encounters with death.
As always, I am a presenter. Lance Preston.
I am very happy to welcome you today
One of the most terrifying scene I have ever seen.
Collingwood is located behind the psychiatric hospital.
This is one of six buildings, an area of ??80 hectares.
Wait, wait, here comes a car.
From there, Matt, I'm not saying it again.
Between 1895 and 1960
More than 80,000 sick and mentally disturbed man was home.
1963 after the closure of several ghosts seen.
Objects that are moving by themselves. Sometimes you can hear the laughter of a madman.
Tonight! My team and I have closed eight hours here.
The trap closes private sunlight.
The more advanced tools Ghostbusters
Collingwood House of psychiatric cases to hunt ghosts.
Court. Nice!
Yes?
Morgan! Morgan Turner! Hello! Yes! Hello!
Sorry! Thanks for coming!
I know the roads and all that. Never mind.
I am delighted that csinálhatom.
It will really be on TV? Yes!
In this hope! This section is not, just buy!
Do not worry, everything it collects.
Morgan Turner is with me.
Local historian, who is here with us,
to shed light on the dark past of the hospital.
Morgan? Can you say that when the school was built?
The story is very similar to Collingwood in similar institutes.
Built in 1893
to relieve the county hospital shoulder the load.
Then, of course, is not understood as a mental illness.
A pioneering treatment early.
It is that mental health services more like a szeméttelepnek
The members of the family were embarrassed.
I see.
The conditions were minimal.
People sometimes slept on the floor without blankets or clothing.
In fact, there was something fun place.
Can you tell us something about Arthur Freinken?
His story is perhaps the most interesting.
Of course! I ask.
Harvard neurosurgeon Freinken above.
It was placed here between 1937-1948.
The agymûtétes experiments because there was a small rebellion.
He was the mainstay of the frontal lobe surgery.
About 140 of the frontal lobe surgery performed.
August 15, 1948 in six patients with the outbreak of the room
Freinken and was stabbed in his office. His body was found the next day a nurse.
This death was completely irrelevant to the death of the famous baseball player.
Wow! This story is very happy!
Morgan, our honest opinion, do you believe in ghosts?
I do not know, but if there is a good place to find them.
The traffic today was really shitty. He also had six hours of high from it.
Death awaits you. Oh my God!
I think we'll see. This is very lame!
This may take a while, this is an old lock. We should not have to use it.
Take it easy, buddy.
Slow down, the background music. All fear.
Well, that's it! We're fine.
Come on.
Oh my God!
This is the main entrance.
Nice! Yes!
If they are members of the family, then there is the reception they were able to login.
This is fucking scary! This is crazy!
The take? Buy it!
I wish to record it!
No smoking.
Stumped, can not. There are fire alarm.
Here I am Kenny Sandivol. Current caretaker, was eight years ago.
Kenny! Do you think this place is haunted?
Well ... I have not done before. Talk to you or the camera?
Yes! Note that this is not ...
I'm not sure to believe in ghosts or souls or anything, but
I have been here I've seen strange things.
Especially at night you can hear the sounds of pipe and construction sounds.
It is very hard to tell, but it's as if they were not alone.
Come on, let's see!
Come on. Well.
It's like those tartanának corridors forever.
Yes.
Hard to believe that there are thousands of happy people.
There were thousands of people.
Day is so dark here.
Are you afraid? Yes.
There are certain ways I will show you where.
Guys! If it is dark now, you may want to wait until tomorrow.
Not all working lights, very dark.
Guys, see the following screen. Yes.
Good evening closes, but will be open for a couple of times in the morning.
What?
I can say.
It is as if something or someone who would want to go or something.
This is a paranormal hotspot.
It will be good? Perfect.
Helping people in these small rooms?
Oh my God! This is officially the ass!
Is this true? Yes, quite true.
A couple of years a person was here. That did it.
He spent the time to scribble on the wall.
So it's a real sick room?
Here was a real patient. Really?
I do not know if he died here, but it was long ago.
Very afraid.
What the fuck? Kenny! This is great!
The man, the sound sucks.
Is this true?
Probably a girl committed suicide.
What? Here?
One patient committed suicide? Yes, slashed his wrists in the bathtub.
Oh my God, this is very sad.
They say some people, this room have heard that the water flows.
I have never heard such a thing.
Where do we go now?
The service tunnel running.
I can not wait to see it.
Are you okay?
Kenny! That's exactly what I was looking for!
These tunnels connecting the buildings.
Almost a mile long.
Aware of how easy it is to lose here.
Once, when I got here, the wind is very cold.
As if it stops. I felt like someone to listen.
Very strange feeling.
What is it? Only the shadow.
This is Garry Krefeld in Krefeld company.
It worked a little behind.
Is that true?
In 1983, another attempt to revive the state space
but in the end everything will be scratched. Damn, sorry.
Say again? Yes, it would be nice.
Me and my team so we've been here for two weeks.
Have you ever met a supernatural phenomenon?
The boys thought they heard voices. Then he went a few tools.
I thought it was thieves. But I did not see anyone, so ...
It was an accident! Yes.
A man went up the ladder. Right there.
He swears that something is pushed down the stairs. Nagyott fell.
I hit my knees, and then quit.
This is not a new vibrator, but it was a smart ghost.
The new ghost shaking like an echo of the past.
Again and again through it all.
The intelligent ghost, is actually a soul.
Interaction with the intent to influence.
The pressure has been reported, and dobásról karmolásról well.
Bizarre, but it happens.
So the two of you that many of you are here?
Yes, many children come here gímibõl.
Csavarogni.
You see anything?
Yes.
It was here we were.
Here. Smároltunk. But all the same.
I looked up and I swear to God. I swear I saw someone there.
Blanca ... Mantle at home ... ... Yes, I wore white robes at home.
He was a skinhead.
Projection Operation wrong.
Why not ask the custodian quickly?
Sorry! Excuse me, sir!
A television programs, an interview would you like?
I'm standing here next to the current problems.
Noticed something strange in the house?
No! Not really. What do you mean?
Well, I heard strange sounds, or have you seen ghosts?
I just started working here.
It started to work. This is very good.
TC could relax a little? What if you play to the camera?
He made as if you see anything?
I have to go back to work. Well.
It will be fast, wait, wait! Do you have a little more?
Here's $ 20!
I'm standing here next to the current problems.
Noticed something strange in the last 10 years?
Yes, I saw a ghost. Here.
It was very frightening.
A building next to the spirit. Unbelievable.
This is a paranormal hot spot you've never seen before.
Three. Two, one ...
The location and size of the scope of their medium heat.
Gray Houston will help in the investigation.
Houston! Feel anything?
Wow! What energy is here!
As if thousands of people speaking at once!
Here's something else.
Dark Soul!
It is possible that a demon!
Tonight, we must be very careful!
We do not want such a thing have fun! Of course!
That's it!
I still feel something?
Yes.
I feel a great sadness here.
A deep sadness.
I see a patient. Female patients. A girl. No water here. Red. Red water.
Blood. Blood. He died here. He slashed his wrists in the bathtub.
The guard said that a girl committed suicide here.
Houston! This is amazing!
The spirit is still with us.
Court.
Yes!
It was too much? No!
Lance! How do you feel your back? I feel good.
This is a good place.
Do you think we're seeing now is the spirit? Yes, thousands of people. Sure.
Wow! They become a little less antiseptic.
It would be nice. But if it fails, at least something good should ijesztgetõs.
Wait, wait! TC
Want to be a beautiful sunset?
Bitch!
Camera window, go!
Okay, it's fucking scary! I go from here.
Here are the current technical wizards, Matt.
Matt! Why not take us through what you are doing?
Ten cameras love the hot spots.
You can take them all on tape.
But back to the hard drive.
Everything here comes my wireless equipment.
He always knows what is happening.
Soon, Matt. What time is it?
This is a discussion of EMF. Electricity is detected in the air.
People are not energy but kileng paranormal activity.
Infrared sensor.
Like the EMF, but it shows the temperature change.
The spirits are believed to cause a change in temperature.
These are called cold spots in business.
One, two, three.
This is a normal voice recorder. Well.
EVP-t buy it. Wait, just as quickly.
That explained what EVP.
Electronic voice phenomenon.
These include the sounds that people can not hear.
and if you hear something, we know that someone wants to communicate.
This is my favorite. Talk Geiger.
On. Go. Look at this. Hard fucking.
I guarantee that if something paranormal, you will receive.
Well, now we close!
My friend Kenny is it locked out.
Kenny! Thanks for everything. See you at 6 am kkor!
Exactly 6 hours! Good luck!
I am a demon! Demon child!
I can not wait to see it in the morning ...
You see, we spent all night with a stranger.
What are you doing? I talked to Kenny.
He shut the door? Fear not, because the show is.
What if you need something outside?
Very good! This is a real thing, folks!
This is where the largest ever investigated!
And the most dangerous!
I draw your attention, was built as a prison.
Since there is a grid of the window. He would not leave, even if we wanted.
Kenny does not arrive until tomorrow, trapped in this desperate.
We will work in total darkness.
Three dark vision camera, all collected.
Matt is a hot spot for static cameras.
Well around the world. When finished, it's time for some
Ghostly encounter!
Very good! Now walk through the halls of Western institutions.
More than 50 years, abandoned.
We are looking for souls who are not comfortable when they lived.
And he probably is not based on the afterlife.
This feeling, this is great. It's cold for that.
This was the corridor that could be the person seen with a shaved head
down the hall.
Sasha, the EVP-t switch.
Is there anyone here with us?
You're a sick or away?
Here they have lived in the house? Play again!
"Is there anyone here with us?"
"You're a sick here?"
"Here have lived in the house?"
Nothing.
Wait a minute! I felt like ...
Spirit, do not be afraid of us!
If so, show yourself!
I think this cold is based. He wants to cheat.
She wants to go to this!
If you have a soul here with us, give me some sign.
Open the window!
Just a little!
Now I use this camera to take some kind of phenomenon.
Usually, no human eye sees.
Recognize photography as a ghost.
One more.
We have to wait until the photos are ready.
If there is a ghost behind me, I know it later.
You're the one who writes these walls?
Or just want to communicate?
Why do not you contact me?
If a patient who committed suicide in the bathtub, in this present
you show!
I'm usually in the Horn!
Camera 2 and 4 inches, has a temperature phenomenon.
Guys, why do I have to sit here alone?
You said that you feel something?
Very, very dark negative energy I feel here.
Not only energy, much, much soul.
If you have in mind, please introduce yourself!
Give us some sound!
As I said, these tunnels as if we tartanának.
The smell is normal.
Did you hear that? I've heard.
Well, I heard something. What the hell is that?
I do not know, come here. This way. Follow me.
Where does that sound? Behind the door.
There.
Damn. Do you want to open it? You can slide the camera?
Yes Not really, but ... Damn.
Son of a bitch.
Shut up! Rats!
Can you believe this? Really?
This is not a big deal. Pet.
You are a very big cock. This is not funny.
This place is as popular as Tesco!
This can make a real electro-plasma material.
The first thing we discovered in our team.
I think they should go once at the top.
I need a shot just over the top runners.
A broker Lebegue than what we were doing in the castle.
The hell? Yes exactly first class.
Fear, fear, fear.
Dead queens! King me!
What the fuck?
Glory Hole.
Kitchen dead.
He told me to do it for my lunch! Bitch!
What the hell is this?
This becomes more and more frightening. How I did not notice?
I love Lance.
Damn.
That form. Wait, wait.
Yes, dear?
If you yell, you give him the phone.
Toki Hello!
What would you say to the mother? Are you afraid of szörnyektõl under your bed?
We talked about this already?
There are no monsters, baby. None.
If so, then we will not get home.
You know that Dad will always take care of you.
Tell your mom so you can sleep with him.
Dad will not be home until morning.
Tomorrow we pizzázni. Soon I'll be home.
Siamese.
Why do I do this myself.
Damn, so cold here.
What the hell is that?
Guys, enough! I do not play!
Not a good time szarakodni!
What the fuck?
Where are you?
Perhaps the wind.
Solid. Maybe a tornado to promote awareness. Think how difficult it is?
TC, what was it? Whatever it was, I fucked up.
You need to replace the pants, when we returned.
You can not say? I told you, the movie
then turned and closed the door of shit.
I thought you are. Added this?
I said it first, but you are so busy ...
Are you serious? Added this? Let's see!
Oh my God!
This is scary!
I accept the apology! I accept the apology!
I can not believe I've seen!
Realizing what he had seen a record
TC by the filmmaker.
This is the door behind me slammed shut.
No decks, windows. Not that condenses.
We will try to contact them.
Is there anyone here with us? Please give me sound.
Something Csapkodjatok.
Csapjátok the door a few minutes.
Csapjátok in the way you want.
Go ahead. Slap!
Now! Please! Give me a sign!
Spirit! Wake up the screen!
If anyone here, please give me a sign ...
Damn! Damn!
Totally thought that there is something here.
Damn! What the hell is that?
Oh my God!
It was very scary, guys!
From here you come!
Damn, I see nothing.
Have you heard?
What? Oh, shit!
Your Holy crap!
What the fuck?
Hello!
This is pretty fucked up, guys.
What the hell is this guys? Up there! Matt?
Matt? Is there anyone in the room?
There is someone above us?
No, but what the hell is going on?
Obviously, someone who knows that we have traffic and szarakodik.
Why are we at all?
Because the sound came from here! Oh my God!
Hello!
Is anyone there? Someone messes with us.
If someone is having fun, not funny!
I'm calling the police! We reserve the right to be here!
Do you have permission, but no!
Not so loud now! Shut up, I try to speak.
Guys, come on. What if all this true?
Trying is the EVP.
What is your name?
What?
In a room with us?
Where are you?
Come on, Sasha. Play.
"What is your name?"
"What?"
"A room with us?"
"Where are you?"
What's that sound? What is this?
What the hell is that? Added this?
I do not believe it, man! I put my tape!
Sasha!
Please! Please! I want to go back to the room!
Measure to some shit! Something in me breathe!
You have to go from here! I can no longer be here!
Stop! Wait a minute! Why wait?
It did in five years, but I've never seen anything like that.
I do not care, I just want to clear the fuck out of here.
Houston, lekíséred and come back here. No? Well.
I would prefer below. No! No!
We still have a face to the camera.
Damn I'm afraid not think it will go.
T be a professional shit! Keep your character!
I found something! No?
You're not doing this to me.
Well, I'll be back. I'll go with you.
No! No! You're coming with me! Come on!
Why do this? Are you kidding? Have you seen this shit?
If we could get the thing to find millions!
Moments ago, that the corridor
We recorded evidence of the paranormal.
Sasha completely terrified, because he touched the back of your mind.
We are trying to contact.
Spirit here in this corridor.
Please to show a signal. Show yourself!
Please!
If you are still with us, or give me a sign! A sound or touch my hair.
Do you see anything in your hair?
No. Wait, give me light. No, nothing.
Do not you dare ask me. Did you know ... We are a team!
I think it's gone.
The truth? Playing very scared. Maybe that's all they are doing.
Yes! I mean, I do not know.
Come on! If you are doing something!
Done, do it again!
What you fear?
Jesus Christ! Forget it.
Lance! He's gone. I think playing with us.
Plays. Do not talk crazy shit already. Relax a little.
Can we go home?
Lance! There are people who all his life in search of answers.
Right.
TC, what time is it?
4:40
Let's go home. What did he say when it comes to people?
Guys, I think there is enough vaccine. The bags and go.
It's about going home!
Összepakolsz here? Yes!
I think the eyes.
Are you sure?
Yes, that's all. I think not.
This is not true? Damn! This is a dead end!
Guys!
Shit!
This is not a good direction!
Come on, come on!
TC, buy it! What should I buy?
What are we missing? Do not miss it!
Do not miss it! We come to this!
Matt! Matt! The stations are?
Matt! We lost, I need some information!
What the fuck is not responding?
Do not go there! TC! Why not?
Because we're going back here.
If we are going in one direction, we will achieve. No?
What? North?
It was just around the corner on the inside of the tub. You know the girl.
We had to do. We had this one, TC!
My eyes do not you! Explain that you are looking for in the bathtub. This is not the
bath.
I know it is not.
TC! We will be! You said, six hours?
Here the dream? Kenny will be at 6? I can not stay here long.
I can not wait. Can not wait.
I'm not going in the dark. I can not wait.
Where are they?
Damn!
Where were you? I did not hear that call?
You know what? The tin is a string would have been better.
There was nothing in it? No, I'm calling.
Have you heard on the radio?
No, I have not heard. You or me? No.
Why not open the door to Lance?
Lance!
What I had to close the door?
Good shit sucks!
What do you see? What is it?
The hair of shit! Ah, yes!
Very rude!
Add to your computer. No, no, no! No time to do so.
Get your cameras. Guys! Rise, let us pack up and up.
Kenny will be here soon.
Would anyone. Please. No, no, no!
Everyone has to stay here. Sorry.
But things ... I know!
You have a radio? Yes, here I am.
Is working well? I hope so.
You hear that? Yes, I have.
I quickly turn around, right? Very cool, man.
Do not leave without me!
Well, it lelépni time here.
Damn!
What the fuck?
Lance, are you there?
Guys, I found something here.
Hello!
Lance!
Guys, do not mess with you!
Be reduced in the morning.
For an hour we have not seen any phenomenon.
Ghostly encounters. He gives me Preston.
Again. No, I have to ...
Again.
Ghostly encounters. He gives me Preston.
That's it. I'm not doing this.
No matter, because the morning light is better.
It's a good idea. Where is Matt?
What the hell is taking so long?
Matt?
Matt? Are you there?
Matt? Lance!
The radio did not work before.
Guys! I know it will sound stupid.
I am the last person to want to go.
Complete darkness that can be killed and wounded.
You're right, it can be damaged.
Boys must be found. Very good!
This is ridiculous! Let's see!
TC! Bring your camera. Sasha, that's fine. Why?
Listen! If so, then add all!
Thanks for your help! Hey! It is good to sit here alone!
Oh, my God!
Matt!
Where are you? Where the hell are you?
What the fuck?
Damn.
Why is this shit?
Damn!
Well, well, well!
What if you leave? No, I would not do that!
There seems to be elpakolta. It should be here.
TC! Exit, Sasha and I do.
Why do this? This is a terrible idea!
What is it? It must be somewhere! Not to mention things here.
Sasha, come with me. TC, you look.
It's like when he kicked the girl.
Matt, where are you? I want to go! That's it!
Ijesztesz us!
Cigarettes, cigarette butts look for you!
Come on, Matt!
That's bullshit, man!
I want the boy dead.
Matt! Come on, man!
You'll shoot your wife!
It's too late! Damn, man!
The hope is that he is dead!
Matt! I'm not playing here with you! Where the hell are you?
What the fuck?
Lance! Sasha!
Damn! What happened? What happened?
What? What? No! No!
Do You good man?
Raise, raise alone! What?
Raise, raise alone!
God, I swear, someone ...
Pushed! What?
Something hit me bitch!
I looked down the stairs, someone lelökött neck for this reason.
Oh my God! I looked back, but no one was there.
These things are playing with us. Do you understand? All night. Eldurvultak.
They call, they call it Kenny! What are you waiting for?
Very good! Very good!
Call Now! Calm down, I'll call!
Oh my God!
Are you okay? Not me!
Shit!
I can not get a signal! Test yourself.
Perfect.
Perfect bitch.
What are you doing, TC?
What do you do? Help me.
You can not burst the door, TC! Then listen!
We can not do any harm. We are responsible.
Be patient, wait! A man can not come soon!
Come on, what the hell?
This anger is!
You think I care? Not at all!
Veszekszünk What the fuck?
I'm sick of it, I'm tired. I want to go.
I lie down and sleep.
You know what? This spectacle of one man.
Put the fucking camera.
Help!
Very good!
Need Help? No!
Stay there.
Shit, shit. On three, okay?
One, two, three ...
Son of a bitch!
Are you printing? Yes! Print.
One, two, three ...
Me to hell?
No! This is the porch!
This is a fucking porch!
Here we came in, right?
Yes!
This is the porch!
It does not exist.
That's impossible!
Here we have our shit to you, right?
Here we have them!
There's no sense of this.
Here we come in!
This is another corridor!
I do not know ...
You may have turned somewhere.
Or other of the sides of buildings.
Lance!
This is the same door!
I've had to be getting out of this guys.
Yes!
Houston! The Pick me!
Alright!
Watch out for the door, look out the door!
My would SAK But
Listen to stand?
Okay, okay!
Fuck me to go with you?
Three!
One, two, three ...
Pics!
Fuck me written on it to go?
My cock is going to?
Perhaps SAK that this half
Will exit.
To be shut up Shut up.
Do not do it.
This, you see?
Go away.
Leave the man
to perform work.
Got it?
Come on!
Would you give a second?
Pics!
Trap we fell in!
Look for something to
We can take HIM to grill!
What do we ensure, when outside,
lehegesztve go?
It was closed down at you know when?
Otlet What a great!
There is no obvious
all the window grille.
No, no! Of the above!
On those screens were not, right?
We need to find to roof!
Want is what? Jump
Such a height?
Hany Pray go, Sasha?
8:44
Do not joke with me already!
Pics!
I said to kids, that I'll be home!
I have to do tomorrow!
Nobody is interested in your problem
Studio to your stupidity.
Guys, let me think
a minute!
That does not make no sense.
Every fucking whore.
Yesterday I went to
when the sun comes up.
You want to say fuck you to me?
It should be sunshine
Ora 7:54 OTA.
You always have this.
The sun does not always come.
There's no sense of this.
This is not a fucking joke!
Shut up!
This is nonsense!
Help! Please!
Somebody help!
Listen! Let's be rational.
This is a building Regime. Right?
So, like a power vessel anomalies
Because of her thoughts are faster to
and we feel therefore that I
days should be.
This explains, in that there is no sun above.
Kenny also arrived.
Electronic Anomaly. Yes.
This fucking idiot!
Point you say that
rationalism think!
Is this your idea? This is not a
sci-fi movie whore!
Here there is nothing rationalism!
So rationalism than any more!
I looked to my cell phone.
Say 13:12.
13:12 Delut
I do not think young.
In be good to have.
I do not know. Everyone is very tired.
A little sleep. Break.
Kenny is, I'll wait.
I do not know where to
will meet with us.
There's no sense of this.
Mar 20 Orach not sleep.
I set an alarm to Pray
and a little sleep.
To fuck me?
Houston, for my problem?
What's the matter?
Hell are you doing to me?
Heck Happened to Me?
Eg you young!
Someone Or Something
lámpánkat to breaking.
I am in total darkness. Torches and cameras are.
At this time wear. I checked my cell phone.
At 8 am.
7 hours of sleep.
TC just wanted a sandwich to eat on ...
This should látnotok!
Lance! The smell, shut up!
What are you doing ... Shut up!
All this food, but there are a lot of our water.
I do not know, I think in the fall.
Why not try to go through the tunnel?
Kenny said the tunnels connecting the buildings.
Maybe we can find a way out of another building.
Do you see here is a great wall of China?
I will not go through the tunnel. When the lights go out, for us.
I remember when they told me the sun?
Tûzkijáratot Vi. If we go to the roof, maybe we could climb.
What's the verdict? We will stay or go? I do not care, just go away!
I do not want to be here. Everyone! I will!
The roof! Yes! Very good!
Let's pack up and go! Come on!
Give a little light, boys! Come on!
To get this?
Lance? Where? No, no, no!
You said, you know where. I never said that. I anoint.
You said that you know where the stairs! He said there is a ladder!
Therefore, we come from, but anyway! I have seen from the outside!
Very good! Damn!
I do I can do it, guys!
What the hell is that?
Hello! Is anyone here?
TC! Is that it?
Do not ask a thing already! Stairs or not?
Stay together.
Hey, just világítsatok! Forward, forward!
Get away from me sometime! Get away from me sometime!
Wait, guys! Slow down!
What the hell are you?
Yes! Yes! (Output ceiling)
No!
Shut up, shut it! See!
Fucking solid!
It's as if you were there long ago?
It makes no sense!
Damn!
To take the camera to my face bitch!
What do you think? Not. Not.
We went up the stairs for some time. Was completely closed.
I take everything, because if you go, people want to see this!
Look at this! Here we climbed the stairs, right?
You are in the room.
When we got here, we should at least be here. No?
You think? I do not know!
TC, which ... Lance! Lance!
What, what?
Here we are? There should be.
This does not mean anything. It says we're the first.
Note that here we are. I know, but ...
TC! Now take this? Yes, I understand.
This is fucked!
Damn! What, what?
What the hell is that? Did you hear that?
Can you hear me? What is this?
What is this? Matt? Matt?
This is the shit! Matt!
Matt, right?
Guys, let's go back! Matt!
Not here! Not here!
Moved?
Let's get outta here!
Every day we try to find a ladder.
Not. Have not been found.
This place is a maze of shit.
TC said, as if constantly changing around us.
I have not found Matt.
I do not know well at all.
We should not have shit.
Fáradtak éhesek és vagyunk.
Egy kicsit aludni Megpróbálunk.
Fogunk Váltásban aludni.
Figyelni mindig Valaki fog.
TC! Once again, man? Yes.
We got up at this time. This should látnotok!
Turn the camera off of shit!
Come on, Sasha! Everything you need!
People need to see this!
Beware! Beware!
Sasha, this should be taken into account.
Not that anyone came here and did so in silence.
Cut, cut.
Matt!
I swear I've heard!
Hello?
See? I told him that I learned! He is alive!
Matt! Are you okay?
Can you hear me?
Frozen!
Tell us where you are, the plank!
Maldita sea!
That is no longer here.
We need to find.
How do we find that still can not find the front door.
It can not be far behind. The speakers are pretty crappy.
Listen! How do you know?
Matt! Are you there?
Sorry, sorry! Damn!
Matt! We have heard! Where are you? Damn!
Sasha, try all the frequencies! You can not very well!
What did you say how far it was? I do not know what these descriptions ...
So tippelnél? 200-300-400? 200 meters of pure sound.
Maybe 300 meters. Let's go further.
After szarakodik, right?
Stay together. Come on.
The impasse. Impasse.
Where the hell are you?
Guys, this is completely useless.
Already found it would be a career ...
Damn!
What was that?
Matt was!
What the hell are you doing, buddy?
Lance! Lance!
Damn!
Make hozzáérj!
Lance! Lance!
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Turn off the light! Turn it off!
Have you seen his face? The cheek!
Shut up!
Have you seen his face?
Why does this happen? Oh my God!
Damn! Damn!
We're doomed! We lost our Houston-t!
Matt!
Guys!
Sasha!
TC!
Lance!
Is anyone here?
Help! Guys!
Even a few hours we're here.
Houston is gone.
Matt wanted to get on the radio, but not responding.
What the hell is that?
These crazy shit happening around us. Damn!
I do not know how long you can get.
We are not alone.
My name is on the bitch!
How the hell my name on it? Damn!
First szétkarmolják my back. So ...
What the hell is that?
When we awoke, the doll was for.
Fuck!
What the hell cheated you out of there? I did not want!
What the hell are you here? I did not want!
That's it! That asshole!
What does that mean? The fact that we're screwed!
Do you understand? That's what!
This is crazy!
This is a crazy bitch!
Do not look! It's not like me!
What the fuck?
There is something! What the fuck?
Enough!
As if we could turn around.
Still I can not find Matt and Houston.
Will you stop? What do you mean? What?
Are you kidding? This show.
I do not do a show! I just ...
You just things, right? People want to see this!
Matt Houston and disappeared. You have to leave here
and find them.
You're just doing this shit.
Okay, guys. Relax a little.
I just ...
Let the hell out of here!
You can run so fast? Come on! What the hell are you?
Oh my God! Come, come!
No, no, no, no! Arise!
Of your mind? Arise!
Arise!
I can not. I can not. But, you know? I know!
Arise! Arise! I know, I know!
Recover yourself! You need to do.
Here we go.
Bloody hell! What is it? What is it?
I found something! Come here!
What the hell are you waiting for? Come here!
Look!
Matt? What is it? I do not know, man!
Matt, you have to!
Near the room shit.
Dude! Do not mess with you! Matt, are you okay?
Damn!
As the patient has any fóbiája childhood.
Matt! Oh my God!
Arise! Come, come!
Come on, wake up!
Take it back!
Come, come! Here, here!
Come on!
Put him in bed. Left him there.
Do you see anything? No! Very good!
Where were you? Where did you get the bracelet?
Damn, talk to us! Look at your wrist!
Matt? Matt?
How did you get so many injuries?
Matt! What did they do to you? What did you see?
Had enough of this. She needs to know where the exit is!
Of course that is out as well! We can go! As we will be better!
What? What do you mean, when we will be better?
What the hell does that mean?
I was not ready yet.
The process is slow. But the patient's response to treatment!
As your mind! Minh would be stoned! Talk about stupid things!
TC! Shut up! They say that close in.
Do not be sad, everything is fine.
It will help you too!
Oh my God!
TC! Look at the door! You have already!
Look!
If anything is here! See if you can not get anything!
It is Matt!
Meghülyült.
TC is still here with us!
What is it?
All is well. What are you doing?
I do not feel well.
I think there is something wrong with me.
Yes, a little gay. I think I have a fever.
Here, drink. Thank you.
Sleep. I can not sleep.
I've never been able to sleep.
What the hell is that?
Jesus!
Come, come!
Go! Go!
Quick, here!
Do you see anything? What is it?
There is blood in the bathtub! There is blood in the bathtub!
What? Come on!
Where to go? Come, come!
What the fuck?
Matt? Matt?
What the hell are you doing? TC! Bring your kádtól!
Come here! Matt!
TC! What the hell are you doing?
Damn, I can not!
Oh my God! Oh my God!
Help, help!
Decide!
He's gone!
Fucking gone!
Suddenly he was gone! Without a Trace!
Damn! No! No!
This is an elevator!
Open up! Open up!
This is the elevator shaft.
If we go through the tunnel, I could go to a different building.
Come on!
Damn! Damn!
Listen! Be careful Matt. I'm looking for some tools.
Stay here, hurry!
What the hell is that?
Jesus! In a language? Damn!
What? What? What is happening here?
The light! Go for it! Come on!
Here is a ladder. This will go down.
How can we take mate?
I'll go ahead and then transfer. No?
Back! Stay!
Lance! Lance!
Where is the button?
Here it is!
Gone!
I do not know, just gone!
Well! Well! But I come back!
Where the hell are you? Matt?
Jesus! He jumped! He jumped!
Come on!
Relax! Gotcha!
There is nothing wrong. There is nothing wrong.
Here in the tunnel.
Finally, here we are. Come on!
I can not. I can not go.
Come on, Sasha! Out!
Kenny said they are linked to the buildings!
To do this to me!
Only I do not know! Very good! No?
Stay close! Let's do it!
It should not be too far!
We are close!
No! No! Have already been érnünk!
Here must have been! What the fuck!
I can not go!
Wait a minute!
I want my mommy!
What kind of day ...
What day is today?
I do not know what day it is.
Throughout the day, going in one direction, but can not get anywhere.
My leg really hurts now.
They will not succeed. Can not be waived.
Who's there?
Who is it?
Sasha?
Sasha, where are you?
Where are you?
Damn!
What?
"What?"
Slowly running out of battery.
You can only turn on the lights if necessary.
But I do not need more light.
Just go ahead.
I could go on for hours.
It's like a game.
How far can you go?
If someone watches.
Fuck!
He planted a shit!
Iodate you, guys!
Eston is paragraph Ustek.
You hear nothing? You hear nothing?
You hear nothing?
Vien live!
I woke up and ...
Do not know much room Time, But ...
There is a door!
Look!
Eston services can not!
Total Mind Encantada!
Jesus!
That's impossible!
No! I am not happy!
I'm not crazy! No! No! No!
All Best plupart Mars.
Finally I can go home.
Siri Meetings. Lance Preston.
I'm posting it out.