Hey guys, we're on the October 30th DVD update,
and the next film I want to talk about is Grave Encounters.
Grave Encounters.
Grave Encounters?
Grave Encounters!
So someone follows a bunch of ghost hunters filming
a new reality TV show, to which leads them
to an abandoned mental hospital in the search of the unknown.
Turns out to be a lot more realistic than they had hoped for.
They run into grave encounters.
The effects are well done.
The camera work is terrible.
The only downfall with the film, and,
and it's a big one: not a lot of scares.
It's fuckin' scary!
It's fucking...horrible!
You're watching it, and it just twists with your mind.
And there's some pretty freaky shit in there,
with people's faces being all out of WHEOOO!
I can't tell if that shit is real.
That shit is scary!
That's some scary shit!
This thing creeped me out so bad, I'm not lying here,
so bad I was like creeped to sh...like serious.
The ending.
I need to talk about the ending,
because this ending was one of the worst fuckin' endings
I have ever seen in my life.
I think I'm going to give this film Grave Encounters
a pass...one skull out of four.
I believe that's it for this week.
This has been Alex's Movie Madness...
ah, please subscribe to my channel,
Alex underscore movie kid 88.
Thank you for watching...and Happy Halloween!
Whoa, whoa!
- Where you guys going?
- Wouldn't you like to know.
- Ah, lucky!
- Hey, give me your number!
Look at me, motherfucker!
Hah, hah!
Oh my God, he ha ha,Tessa.
- Tap that ass, baby!
- Fuck off Trevor.
Isn't there some freshman you can go grope here?
I hope so.
I know you don't like dick, but c'mon,
you gotta be willing to make an exception.
How you doin'?
Is he gay or what?
Happy Halloween!
Oh, my God!
That's awesome... r...wha...er...
You want to make out with a Greek god?
Yeah.
So are you Michael from Thriller
or are you dead Michael over here?
Oh, I'm dead Michael, baby.
Wooo!
Where the children at?
Aaaah!
Give me some more.
Wait, you're rolling up in here
with this little piece of shit?
Oh, woh, woh, woh, alright?
My, my camera may be small, right,
but my Thor has a mighty big hammer dick,
unlike yours, tiny eight.
Yeah, baby!
Hah, ha, ha.
What have we got over here?
Oh, my God.
Jennifer!
....When am I not filming?
- Where's Alex?
- I dunno know.
- Is he here?
- Did he come with you?
- He did not come with me.
Wow, I was really looking forward to seeing him tonight.
Do you wanna make out?
I'm in.
I'll take a rain check.
You should keep drinking, though.
It'll taste better.
Ah,ha ha.
Back at the dorms.
Shit!
Are you fuckin' kidding me?
Ahh!
Learn to fucking knock, bro!
Get that fucking camera out of my face.
There's a fuckin' rager going on at Beta Alpha Kapa...
and you're here jacking off!
Are you kidding me?
There's a real pussy out there waiting for you, man.
Jen wants your body, bro.
Jennifer's there?
Like I said, she's lookin' good.
Not as good as this, but...pretty good.
I don't have a fuckin' costume, so I can't go.
Wrong!
You do have a costume.
I have one left over from Frosh Week.
No.
I'm not fucking...I'm not fucking wearing this!
- Ah, you are wearing this.
- I'm not fucking wearing this.
- It's Halloween.
- I am not...No...absolutely fucking not.
I cannot believe you let me talk me into this.
Hee, hee, seriously!
- Your ass is banging, dude.
- Look at this.
Fuck off, dude.
I'm not going out in public like this.
- Hey Trev! Buddy!
- All right, my man!
You should listen, listen to this.
Fuckin' no class in the horror genre anymore.
No class. I'm telling you.
It's all just quick cuts...
...and giant lens flares.
CGI.
They need to go back to using models...
- and make up effects.
- Yes! I am...
- Yes, they do.
- ...in total agreement with you.
- You're so right, Alex. You're so smart.
- It's the old school. The old school way.
Oh, I am on the same page with you.
Carpenter, Craven...
Where the fuck are those guys in our generation?
Where the fuck are you?
This film school fuck's the next Craven.
- Who?
- None of them.
I'll tell you where they are.
Right here brother.
Speech!
My name is Alex Wright.
Future motherfucking genius, baby!
Alex Wright's got an announcement, ladies and gentlemen...
I am going to make a horror film...
...that will reinvent the genre!
- Yeah, you are!
- You know it.
I know it.
It is going to be artistic.
It's going to have...vision.
'Cause I'm a fuckin' visionary!
And I'm allowed to say shit like that.
Party on, motherfuckers!
Ahhhhh, that's glorious.
Sleeping Beauty...
Rise and shine, bitch!
Mhhh.
How you feeling, big guy?
Look at you.
Who's your friend?
Fuck!
You might want to check your timeline.
Why?
I mean, theres some pretty racy photos of you on there
from last night.
What did you do?
Just tell me what the hell you did.
Keep looking.
You'll see it.
- Ah...ah, there's a sexy one.
- Looks like he's grabbing my tits.
Well, there's the thing.
Why the hell would you let me drink
a whole thing of tequila?
You took it from me and wouldn't give it back.
- Who the hell is this dude?
- No idea.
Jared's a horndog.
Really drunk.
He teabagged you, hmgh.
What the fuck, man.
Why the fuck would you put that up?
- Take it down!
- No, no, no, no. Look, look.
I even tagged it.
Look, I said "my balls."
- I don't give a shit.
- It's a fucking YouTube sensation.
It's got fucking 26 likes, man.
My balls are gonna go viral, baby.
- You fuckin' kidding me?
- Group shot.
Mwahh!
Not one fucking person tried to fucking help me?
They were very...Dude, it was still you.
You were the center of attention, man.
- You were practically a star.
- I'm untagging myself.
I'm untagging myself.
Fuck you.
Hi, do you guys know where I can find, ah, weed?
Marijuana?
Yo, dude. I'm looking for weed.
It's my doc assignment:
High times in film school.
All right.
What are you doing?
Just, ah, checking for comments on my reviews.
You're such a nerd.
Whatever, man.
My reviews are a good way to get my name out there.
Check it out.
I got a video response.
It's a guy from the film I just reviewed,
'Grave Encounters'.
Weird though, I don't remember this scene being in it.
Well, who sent the video?
Ah, Death Awaits.
Death Awaits.
Message Death Awaits.
Find out where he got the video.
Boom, problem solved.
Can we please go get some tacos?
Gary!
Gary, stop. That's enough!
Don't be such a tease, Stacy.
You know you like it.
Gary!
Stop!!
Ow!
You bitch!
Look, I know it's been exactly a year ago tonight
that your father disappeared,
but you need to move on, already.
Awh, awh!
That fucking tease!
Hello?
Who's out there?
Whoever's doing this, it's not funny anymore!
Gary!
C'mon, what is taking so long?
Oh, c'mon!
Gary, Gary, ah, I'm sorry.
Ah, okay, lets...let's just go.
I'm cold.
Gary?
NOOOOOOOOO!
And...cut!
- Cut! That was money.
- Top take two. Mark.
Money.
Jared, we're going to go to the,
ah, bird's-eye view shot. Is that good?
Yeah, that sounds good.
Oh, my God, Jennifer.
You are officially on your way
to being the next great scream queen.
- And I'm going to help you get to that spot.
- Really? - Yes!
Ah, Alex, how is a guy supposed to stand up
after he's dead?
That, that doesn't make any sense.
That's gonna be an awesome jump-scare.
Trust me, man.
I know what I'm doing.
I'm a pro.
Trev, Death Awaits replied.
Who?
What did he say?
Well, check it out.
What, wha, what is that?
Is that a phone number or something?
Forty-nine, fourteen, one-twenty...
Nah, it's too many numbers to be a phone number.
Who, who is this?
Who sent it?
Alex has a YouTube stalker.
Doesn't make sense. I checked out the websites.
I double-checked it out with Google Maps.
It doesn't make sense, man.
I just don't know why he sent it to me.
No, no, no. Wey, wey, wait.
Go back to that, to that last part where you were saying
about the longitude latitude numbers.
That was good stuff.
Okay, yeah, all right.
Forty-nine, fourteen, a hundred and twenty-two,
forty-eight.
The message from Death Awaits.
It's...longitude and latitude numbers, I think.
Where do you think they lead to?
Vancouver, Canada, to the exact location
of a mental institution called... [CENSORED]
Now, I think this is the place
where they filmed Grave Encounters.
They called the building Collingwood within the movie,
but Collingwood doesn't exist...
(CENSORED) does.
And it's all the same shit they talked about.
Ya know, built at the turn of the century,
crazy doctors, lobotomy...All that shit.
It's all real.
It all happened.
Where the hell's the night vision button?
There it is.
Where the fuck are you?
Dude, Trev, look at this.
- I can see why people think this is scary.
- You watchin' this?
So many people online think this is real.
I'm not the only one.
People thought the Blair Witch Project was real, too.
Yeah, and Paranormal Activity,
and that stupid one in space on the moon.
It's just a marketing gimmick, Alex.
That's exactly what they want you to think.
It's just a movie.
And...I mean, it's not even a very good movie at that.
I mean, look at these special effects.
None of the actors in this film have done anything
since this film release. Not a thing.
Can you explain that?
He's been dead for fuckin', like, eight years now.
Kenny Sandwall.
Suicide. 2004.
Self-inflicted shotgun wound.
The dude went crazy.
What about your own movie, Alex?
You still need to cast the role of the police sergeant.
You need to get on that shit ASAP.
Hey everybody.
I actually have some questions that I need help
getting answers for the movie I was reviewing last week,
Grave Encounters.
I'm trying to get in touch with the directors
or some of the actors or anyone involved with the film,
but I can't find any information on them.
There's something about it that doesn't make sense,
and I just kinda want to get to the bottom of it.
So if you or anybody you know
knows how to get in contact with them,
please just comment back.
It would be greatly appreciated.
Help!
Help! Somebody help me!
Please, please
Why are you doing this?
Just let me go.
Aah!
Help! Help!
Aaaahhhh!
Time for your appointment.
No, no, no, no, no.
Aah!
Aaah, you fucking psycho!
Looks like you've got a cavity.
Please.
No, no, no, no, no, please no.
This might sting a little.
Please, no.
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhheeeeeeiiiiiiii!
Cut!
Cut, cut.
Ah!
What'd you think?
- D'ya like it?
- Umm.
It, it was good.
It wa...it was good.
I just, ah, I just got some...
I'm just trying to think.
I got some stuff.
You don't seem very happy about it.
- Like, was it my performance? You want me to do it differently?
- No, not all. It wasn't your performance.
Well no, because, like, I rehearsed this
four different ways, so we can...
Not your fault, okay?
- It's not...
- Dude, what the fuck you talking about, man?
The footage looks amazing.
It looks...good.
I'll give you that, but its cliche, man.
Look there's a guy in a mask and a girl getting tied up.
We've seen this before.
Yeah, dude, it's fuckin' torture porn, man.
People love that shit.
Saw made like a hundred million dollars.
Yeah, I don't really care.
I dunno.
I need to rethink the whole third act.
Just wrap everyone, okay?
I need to rewrite the ending.
All right everybody.
That's a wrap for today.
- Really?
- Fuck, yeah.
Ah, hell, yeah!
Let's go get day-drunk.
Hey, Jen, that was really good.
That was scary.
Thanks.
- Turn that frown upside down.
- Sorry...Can you not film me right now?
All right. So I just logged on to my email,
and I had a message from that YouTube user
that's been messing with me for the last little while.
Check out what he sent me.
This is a photo of Sean Rogerson
when he was younger.
The woman next to him must be his mother.
It came with a phone number.
It's, ah, local to Washington,
so I'm going to give it a shot.
Maybe it has something to do with his mom.
See what I can find out.
[Phone ringing]
- Hello?
Hi, is this the, ah, Rogerson home?
Yes.
And I'm just trying to get a hold of Sean.
Is he around?
Why do you want to speak to Sean?
Well, I'm doing a thesis project
on a film he was a part of called Grave Encounters.
I'm trying to get an interview with him.
It would be really helpful if you guys...
if I wasn't the only one who was navigating...
Well, you aren't.
The GPS is helping you out.
Well, yeah, a lot of good that did us.
This is why Terminator turned bad.
They don't want to help us.
Computers don't want to help us.
It's just in their nature.
This is it.
It would appear to be.
All right, so what's this broad's name again?
Delia, Trevor, for the eighteenth time.
And she said that Sean would be here for sure?
Sean would be here at three o'clock,
he'd be down for an interview.
Let's make it happen.
Ich, ni, san, let's go.
- Jared, you...
- What?
...ah, hold back.
We're going to film this from a wide...
See I don't know why you brought your camera.
Why'd you bring your camera?
It's for my fucking documentary,
for the fifteenth time.
- Your documentary doesn't really apply to this scenario.
- Your documentary doesn't apply to this scenario.
That's precisely what my documentary
is about is this scenario...
Shut up!
- Hi.
- Alex?
Yes, Alex, and this is my friend Trevor.
Hi, I'm Trevor.
Nice to meet you.
Why don't you come in before you catch cold?
Thank you.
Guys! Wait up!
Can, can I get you boys some tea or some coffee?
I've got some really nice tea in the pot.
Um, I'm, I'm good, but thank you though.
I appreciate it.
I'm, I'm, I'm fine as well.
I think we're all good.
How's the, how's the frame look?
It looks hot.
Mrs. Rogerson, is Sean around right now?
Ah, he just stepped out.
You just missed him, but he'll be back soon.
Okay, but, Sean is alive.
I mean, he's ah, he's ah, he's okay.
Of course.
I'm always teasing him about being a workaholic.
He's acting on a new TV series right now.
He loves to act.
He always wanted to be an actor, even when he was a little boy.
You could wait for him, if you like.
He's going to be so pleased to see you.
He love sit when people come 'round to visit.
Sean lives here?
Oh, well, all his life, yes.
Of course, ha, ha.
Why don't you wait up in his room?
He'd like that.
It's up the stairs, on the right.
Most valuable player, 1996.
Look at this.
I don't think anyone has lived here for a while.
That's definitely him when he was younger.
Yeah, he looks like the real Slim Shady.
Ha, check out some bad hair.
Likes cats.
You do too.
Ah, well.
Shit!
What are you doing in here?
Sorry, who are you?
I'm Mrs. Rogerson's caretaker.
Yeah, um, Mrs. Rogerson actually said we could,
we could wait here.
We have an interview with Sean.
You need to leave now.
- No, we have, we have...
- You need to go. - ...permission to be here.
You need to leave!
Out, out!
- Why...?
- Get out! Now!
- Hey, we're not...trying to steal anything.
- This is ridiculous!
- Like, like, she said we could come in here.
- Yeah!
- We just want to talk to Sean for a second.
- Out!
Sean's getting back real soon,
just as soon as he gets back from the, the hospital.
Delia, which hospital do you mean.
What are you talking about?
The hospital for crazy people.
Then you know about Grave Encounters?
You know about the TV show?
I, uh, hi, I helped him find his name,
you know, Lance Preston.
That was his stage name.
- Get the camera off!
- Don't touch it!
- Out!
- All right, all right! I'm going.
You're getting her too worked up.
Delia, one more thing, though.
What happened to Sean, okay,
what happened to the rest of his crew?
I really don't....She invited us here.
We're her guests.
We just want to do an interview with Sean, that's it.
She is not supposed to answer the phone.
She has advanced dementia.
She's going to be in full-time care in January.
Dude, you catching that?
She knew about Grave Encounters.
Look at her!
- Shes fucking crazy, man!
- Yup.
Oh my fucking God!
She's still waving!
Dude, she's ripping him apart.
You gotta fucking roll on this.
Yeah, dude, she was pissed after the play.
No, Alex, the point is...
that you said you were gonna be there,
and you fucking weren't.
The circumstances aren't exactly...
I know it sounds bad when you put it that way,
but it's not how it's...
- This was important to me too and...
- I know, I know. I'm sorry.
And you promised that you were going to be there,
and then you just weren't.
- Like, I was looking everywhere for you...
- I know.
I'm sorry, but look at this, seriously,
just look at this!
You are obsessed!
This is a movie!
It's not just a fucking movie.
Listen to me.
I called the Vancouver City registrar, okay.
The RCMP has a fucking case file dated March 28...
- I don't care.
- ...2003. - I don't care.
Okay...
You know what?
I'm so sick of hearing about this fucking movie.
You go ahead and do whatever you want.
You don't have to deal with me anymore, okay?
- Bye Jen.
- Fuck-off, Trevor.
Jen!
No, not right now.
I'm sorry.
Jen!
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
Wow!
What the fuck was her problem, you know?
I feel bad, ya know.
I feel bad about the fucking play,
but what do you want me say, huh?
This is more important, ya know?
- Yeah, um, I don't know...
- What? You don't agree with me?
Well, uhh.
Okay, let me lay it down.
A friend to a friend, okay?
Aaahh, Jen is probably the only girl on this campus
you have the slightest chance of getting your dick wet with.
True.
Yeah.
So true.
- Yeah, yeah, thank you.
- And, and, in saying that, if I were you,
I would lay off the whole conspiracy theory shit.
Conspiracy theory?
- Dude, I love you. I'm trying to help.
- Look at it.
Look at the fucking evidence.
Look at it!
Missing. Missing.
Crew feared dead.
Fuck!
What else do I need to fucking prove to you?
- See what I mean?
- Yeah.
Wake up to the fucking Rain Man, every morning.
Fuck you, dude.
The Rain Man was a fucking genius!
Everybody, I know it has been a while since I have posted,
but a lot of crazy shit's gone on with this whole
Grave Encounters thing in this last little while.
I did an interview with Sean Rogerson's mom.
Listen to me, Grave Encounters is real.
And my friends don't believe me,
you probably don't either, but I'm not crazy.
I've done my research.
I just need proof.
I need to...go back to Tacoma...I don't know....
maybe check out some articles and look up some more...
"Okay, something just started printing''...
Okay, so we know that the printer has just turned on.
And it's printing something, without me doing anything,
it started.
Two, three, eight, four Melrose Ave., Los Angeles.
This looks to be some kinda...call-sheet...
for a music video or something, tomorrow, in LA.
Hartfeld Productions...
How do I know that name?
Gerry Hartfeld, he produced Grave Encounters.
And the call sheet that was printed off for me?
It's for a music video he's doing tomorrow.
I can't have you in fucking LA for two days.
Man, what about our movie?
This is more important to me.
Are you really seriously gonna fly all the way over to LA
just for some stupid call sheet?
I'm only gonna be gone for two days.
I don't see the big deal.
Whatever, dude.
The life vests should only be inflated...
Yeah, you're now being filmed from outside...the car.
We're in LA...as in Hollywood...the, ah,
film Mecca of Earth.
I wouldn't say "beautiful" cause of all the smog, but...
Okay, we're at the studio...
I'm with, ah, Hartfeld Productions.
You're name?
Ah, Roberto...Smith.
I got, ah, I've got this call sheet.
I'm PAing today.
Music video.
All right, Roberto.
You go in in Lot C.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Movie people.
That's him.
That's Gerry Hartfeld.
Cut it!
Cut, cut!
Guys, where's the confetti?
We're two hours behind, let's go!
Reset!
I found Gerry.
I'm going to go try and talk to him now.
No, no,no, no, I'm not gonna cover it over...
'Scuse me, Mr. Hartfeld.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Hold on a sec.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Alex Wright.
I'm filming a documentary,
and I, uh, just want to maybe get an interview with you.
Okay, this is not allowed on my set, okay?
And you can stop it right there,
because I am not gonna do any goddamn interview.
Security?
This guy is not supposed to be here.
Playback!
I know about Grave Encounters.
I know what the fuck you did!
- You get him out of here!
- What the fuck'd you do?
Hm...I just tried to talk to Gerry Hartfeld.
He had security kick me out,
I mean he's clearly hiding something.
Fuck, I just...Idon't know,
I don't know what to do anymore.
Whoa!
Yeah?
I'll talk to you, okay?
But not here, and not on camera.
You be at my offices tomorrow at two o'clock, hmm?
Yeah, okay.
- Thank you.
- Mmmhh.
Fuck, yeah!
Testing, testing, one, two, three?
Testing.
Give me some good stuff.
Welcome to Hartfeld Productions.
How can I help you?
I have a meeting with Gerry at two o'clock.
- Alex?
- Yeah.
Please sign in.
So, how much do you know, hmm?
Give it to me straight.
I know everything.
I know Grave Encounters was real.
I know Sean Rogerson and the rest of the crew are dead.
To be clear, unless there's actually a body,
you're not legally dead.
You're a missing person.
And, thank God for that.
So, you admit it.
The footage is real.
Yeah.
Every last frame of it.
Well, except for a few cheap visual effects
that we added at the last minute.
What about the...families?
Christ, kid!
It's called the non-disclosure agreement.
You made them sign a non-disclosure agreement?
You're goddamn right I did, and you know what?
For a nice chunk of settlement money,
they were more than happy to sign it.
You think I'm a big scumbag, right?
I guess I just don't understand why you did it.
Listen, when I first saw those tapes, I was scared to death.
You understand?
I mean, I even thought about destroying them.
But after all the settlements,
I was close to bankruptcy, and so...I had an idea.
Why not release it as a film?
You know, maybe we could recoup some of our losses.
And it worked great.
They already want a sequel.
Grave Encounters 2.
Can you believe that?
The directors, the Vicious Brothers, who are they?
Um, why don't you follow me?
When you fuck this thing up...
when ya, when ya put the audio...
Meet the Vicious Brothers.
Hey Gerry.
Yeah.
That's Colin, right there, and that's Stu.
They're my interns.
See, I just had these guys pretend to be the directors
of the film and then go out and do all the press.
And because they're non-union,
I don't have to pay them scale...
Hah, you know, you get all these students,
and all these kids up here from UCLA and USC,
and they're just so goddamn incompetent...
So now you know the truth.
How you gonna get away with this?
We already have.
I'm gonna tell everybody.
You go ahead.
Who's gonna listen to you?
You're a nobody.
The only reason I agreed to this meeting was
to see if you had anything solid against me.
Which...you don't.
We'll see about that.
Yeah. Yeah, we will.
I'm gonna leave now.
The guy's a fuckin' douchbag.
Who's gonna listen to you?
You're a nobody.
See?
This is why I asked you to come.
Well, yeah, man, I mean if this is true, that's fucked up.
I didn't ask him to say any of this.
Wow!
He's a fuckin' douche!
Well, he's also right.
I mean nobody's gonna believe us.
We need proof, ya know.
What d'ya mean, proof?
I've been thinking a lot about this.
Guys, this is the film I wanna make, right?
Okay, think about it.
We're already in the second act, right?
I mean, you've been filming everything on your...
camera phone?
Jared, you've been filming it.
Think about it, dude.
It's a documentary, but it's also a horror film, right?
How is it a horror film?
Okay, I got another message from Death Awaits.
He lives in Canada, right beside the hospital
where they shot Grave Encounters.
That's how he knows so much about it.
See, he wants to meet us on the inside of the building.
That...is where we get our proof.
You want to drive to Canada?
It's like a two-hour drive.
We'll bring Jared, Tessa...
we'll film the whole thing.
Its a goddamn movie, man.
For the fifteenth fucking time,
I'm not driving to Canada to go on a fuckin' wild goose chase.
- I'll go.
- Are you kidding me?
I mean, can you explain this?
No, but...
Why would he say that?
I don't know.
Jared, you in?
You're coming, right?
Cinematography credit.
- You're in?
- Yeah!
Let's do this!
You're my producer.
I need you there.
We could get into Sundance with this shit.
All right, this is the shit that could put us on the map.
Trust me.
- Okay, all right, let's do this.
- Yes!!
Oww!
No, we don't own it...you know who has to pay for it
gets messed up?
Alex!...cuz if I'm at the border wait, honestly.
We're going to fuckin' BC.
There's BC bud!
Hey, you should tell us about Grave Encounters
another time.
We are on our way to (CENSORED) Hospital.
Makin' movies.
This is where we are right now, okay?
How do you know that?
Take it.
Border crossing!
- We're going the right way.
- Is it illegal to bring marijuana...
- Are you kidding me?
- ...across the border?
No, Trevor, it's totally illegal.
Well, Canada's loose on that, right?
Oh, my God, are you fucking kidding me?
Alex, pull over.
We need to drop something off.
- Oww!
- You like it so much.
I can see it in your eyes!
Do you know how to get to (CENSORED) by any chance?
- Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Vancouver.
- Vancouver!
Keep out!
Violators will be...
- I'll do it.
- Then do it.
All right.
That's one tough bitch!
Is there...is that it?
That's...
Do you see that?
Are you kidding me?
- Are you looking at that building?
- You see that?
Well, I'd say they succeeded
in building a fucking creepy building.
Jesus Christ!
This place is huge!
Alex, do you know which one they shot at?
I think this is it.
Let's go check it out.
[sirens wailing]
Security guards!
Security guards.
Oh, shit!
Roll on this.
Fucking Canadian rent-a-cop, you guys, seriously.
You guys, let me do the talking.
Trevor...
Don't say anything.
Sh, sh, sh...
Excuse me.
This is private property.
Didn't you see the sign back there?
Sorry.
Hi, I'm so sorry.
We're film students, and we're just trying to get
some shots for a school project.
We're just trying to get some exterior shots of the building.
That's all.
Well, I'm sorry.
These buildings are full of asbestos, all right?
It's highly dangerous.
You guys are going to have to get out of here.
Turn the camera off.
No!
Absolutely not.
You're not allowed to be filming here, okay?
Theres no filming on the premises.
I understand that.
We'll leave.
You're gonna, you're gonna have to give me the tape.
- I'm not giving you shit, buddy.
- I need the tapes from all the cameras.
- No!
- Give me the tape. Give me...Give me the tape!
Woh, woh!
What the fuck!
Keep going.
Keep going, Alex!
- What the fuck just happened?
- Fuckin'...Shit!
Just keep going.
What a fuckin' asshole!
Why would a mental institution
that's been abandoned for over thirty years
have a fuckin' security guard, huh?
I don't even know what to call you.
Shhh, what are you doing?
We're gonna get fuckin' kicked out on the first day.
- Huh?
- Seven one three.
This one's good.
This is it right here.
We, uh, we just tried to capture some shots of the hospital
from outside, but we were harassed by a security guard
who tried to take one of our cameras away.
He said it was because of "the asbestos."
That's...that's clearly bullshit.
I mean, they're trying to hide the truth.
They're trying to hide something...
they don't want people to...
Breakin' in, bitch!
Motherfuckers can't stop us!
Well, fuck the police...eeee, ha, ha, ha!
Knock it off!
Knock it off.
Guys!
Movie's fucking retarded.
This is why we came up here, you guys actually
think the movie is real?
That's the whole point of this, Tess.
Ohh! Yeah!
I'm not, I'm not responsible for my actions.
I got another message from Death Awaits,
saying to meet him in the room at the West end of the tunnel
at three a.m., sharp, tonight.
We have got, uh, eight night vision cameras
that we're going to put up on tripods like that one
throughout the building.
This super bad-ass camera is shooting in high resolution.
Thermal camera.
Because we're fancy like that.
An EMF meter.
Make mine really big.
That's what she said.
- Cheers.
- Cheers!
Tonight, we're going to try to find proof
of what Gerry Hartfeld's been trying to cover up for ten years.
That this film is the real deal, that the spirits of (CENSORED) exists,
the crew of Grave Encounters died trying to find them.
Yeah, boy, we're going to light the fires,
we're going to kick the tires.
Yeah, baby.
All right...ugh.
- Okay, let's go!
- Let's do this!
Oh, fuck!
It's the guard!
Down, down, down!
Dude, turn your light off!
Turn your light off.
Shhh, Tessa!
Anybody there?
Shhh.
Shit, get down!
Fuck!
Hello?
(RADIO): ....There's some suspicious persons.
There's a couple of guys in an old Cutlass.
It's an off-white in colour...
parked in the parking lot for a long time.
All right.
All right, I'm on my way.
Okay, it's time to make a break for it.
Go!
All right, you heard the sarge.
Let's go. Move your ass.
Shhh...that does not mean to be loud, Trevor.
Okay, sorry.
Oh God...Wait for me!
Don't die baby!
Oh fuck, we'll see ghosts in here!
Holy shit!
- Death Awaits.
Well, it's definitely the right building.
Tess, bolt-cutters.
Oh, no, I'm doing this shit.
- Suit yourself.
- Don't touch...
Ooooh!
- How come you get to wear a balaclava?
- Shhhh....
Yeah.
Wah!
Really?
Oh, my God!
- Oh wow!
- Wow!
This place isn't creepy.
Shit, it's just like the movie.
Oh, my God, is that police tape?
Why would the police, like, come here
if this was just a movie?
'Cause it's not just a movie.
You done yet?
This hallway's...kind of creeping me out.
Yeah, I'll be, I'll be done in a second.
You're okay.
All right!
- It's good.
- Okay, let's go.
- Weird.
- Oh, ha, ha.
- This way.
- Wait. That way?
Okay.
I think this is the way.
Demons in the halls.
Demons in my mind.
Demons you will find.
- All right, let's go, let's go.
- Fuck that!
- C'mon man.
- Right.
All right. Let's go.
- Hurry up!
- Woah, woah, woah, woah.
Hold on.
Haaaaaa...
Hey, is this where the black guy died?
Yeah, well, the ethnics always die first.
Whew!
(Whistles) Shit, man.
Damn, that's fuckin' high up.
C'mon man, let's go.
You're gonna fuckin' fall out of there, seriously.
Okay, guys, let's set up for the intro.
Okay, Jared, you set the last camera in the tunnels.
- Can't say that.
- Yes, you can.
Alex's awesome documentary, take one.
..typical tie-in...
Ready?
It was March 20th, 2003, when Sean Rogerson
and the crew of Grave Encounters were shooting
their sixth episode of a reality television series here,
in this very building.
They encountered something horrible.
Something that would cut their lives tragically short.
It was sold to the American public as fiction,
yet in fact, it was reality.
Later tonight, we'll be meeting up with an anonymous source
known only as Death Awaits,
who first tipped us off.
In the mean time, we'll be conducting our own
paranormal investigation in hopes of uncovering the truth
behind the decade-long cover-up.
Everybody good?
Jared?
Yup.
- Tess, you got it?
- Yup.
And, three, two, one.
Action!
This building is massive, and it's super easy to get lost.
So, to make sure that doesn't happen,
and that we can always find our way back,
we're dropping these glow sticks behind us.
We have this military-grade GPS system
that we got from the spy shop.
Just in case, in the unlikely event that one of us
gets separated from the group,
we also all have these.
[air horn]
Fuck! Would you warn me next time?
I'm wearing fucking headphones.
- Sorry.
- Jesus!
I think it's safe to say we're definitely prepared
for the worst.
Yewawwwwwhhhh!
This is the very bathtub where T.C. Gibson,
a.k.a. actor Merwin Mondesor lost his life.
We will now attempt to communicate
with the spirit world in hopes of reaching Merwin.
I'm going to record an EVP.
If the spirit of Merwin Mondesor is here with us now,
speak freely.
Don't be afraid.
I'm sure your wife and your daughter would love to hear from you.
RECORDING: If the spirit of Merwin Mondesor is here
with us now, speak freely.
Don't be afraid.
I'm sure your wife and your daughter would love to hear from you.
Sweet.
Fuck off, Trevor.
If there are any spirits with us right now, speak freely.
Give us a sign.
Make a noise.
Create a cold spot.
Jared, get the thermal camera on, ah...
Oh, oh yeah.
Okay, yup.
Cool!
Dude!
What the fuck!
There's like a weird mist behind Trevor.
- What do you mean...there's a weird mist behind me? What is it?
- Just let me see what it...
- What?
- Yes, I told you. This was real.
- What is it?
- Ewwh!
Aw, Trevor, you farted!
It fucking reeks!
Awwwwh.
Is the thermal cam picking that up?
- Yeah.
- Seriously?
Keep rolling, keep rolling.
Ewwww!
You did.
You did it.
You're an animal.
That's really immature.
That's awesome!
It's so cool...
This is the very tunnel that Sean Rogerson
spent his final moments alive, deranged and suffering
from starvation.
As you walk deeper down these tunnels,
it's almost as if you're walking deeper and deeper
into the depths of madness.
Literally, the tension is building...with every step.
Are you serious?
That's a bit much.
What's a bit much?
- Deep in the depths of madness?
- Well you've gotta inject drama into things.
You win awards with that kind of shit.
Yeah, you're gonna win a Razzy...
Fuckin' gross, you guys, look.
Eww.
- Jared, Jared, cover this.
- Yeah, man.
Seriously, what does this?
What leaves a half-eaten rat on the ground?
That's disgusting.
Its says, meet in the room at the West end of the tunnels.
Doesn't really get anymore West end than this.
Time is it?
Three twenty-five.
Maybe he's running late.
Fuck, no.
He bailed on us.
Without him we have nothing.
This whole project is a disaster.
Fuck!
What is this?
Hell, no way!
This is a spirit board.
A what?
You put your hand on the piece with somebody,
and you try and get spirits to move the letters.
C'mon, we should play it!
This is never gonna work.
Yes, yes, yes.
It takes two.
I'm speaking to the sprits of (CENSORED).
We know that many of you were mistreated and abused here.
You may therefore be angry in the afterlife.
Are there any spirits here with us now?
- Well, that isn't exactly how you do it...
- Shhh!
- Are you doing that?
- No, are you doing that?
Must be Casper!
You're doing that.
I'm not.
- You're so fucking around with me.
- I'm not doing it!
Okay, um...Who are we, who are we talking to?
You...just give me a name.
- Oh, my God, you guys.
- Hey, fuck off guys.
D...E...A...T...H...
A...W...A...I...T...S.
- Shit, are you kidding me?
- Holy shit!
Death Awaits.
It's not a person.
Fuck, the YouTube guy?
- This is ,this is fucked.
- Shhhh!
What do you want us to do?
Shit!
- Fuck me!
- Oh my God!
What does it say?
T...H...N...
Film everything.
Oh, shit! Back away!
Jesus Christ!
Guys, seriously!
This is not a joke!
You guys okay?
Alex, let's just go.
Ahhh!
What is it?
What the fuck is it?
Alex!
Move it!
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- There's no fucking way that shit...
- There's no way.
- Shhhh!
- Did you get it? Did you get the coverage?
- Yeah, I got it.
Oh, Alex, I cannot fucking believe it!
Wait a sec.
What is it?
[crash]
Fucking Christ!
Shut the fuck up!
What was that?
[crash]
[screaming]
Damm it!
Don't move.
- All right, all right. Fine!
- You just gave us a fucking heart attack!
You realize that trespassing is a criminal offense.
Did you think I wasn't going to see the busted lock?
I understand that, but I'm not leaving without my equipment.
It's not even mine, really, it's our school's.
I don't give a shit where it's from, all right?
You can take that up with the cops.
God, don't be such a fucking dick, man.
Shut up!
Shut your mouth.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry, sir.
- You better not be filming.
- I'm not. I'm not.
- He's not.
You're not even a pig.
You're a fuckin' rent-a-cop.
- Trevor, shut the fuck up!
- Thank you.
Listen to your fucking friend, for once in your life, will ya?
- Sir, you don't need to...
- Aaaaaahhh!
- What the fuck?
- What the hell was that?
Alright.
Who else is with you?
- There's no one else.
- Nobody, it's just us.
Bullshit!
Who else is here?
- Nobody's with us. That's what I'm...I'm sorry.
- There's something really weird going on in this building right now.
I don't know what it is.
- What are you talking about?
- I don't know...I...
This place is fucking haunted.
Did you not notice that?
Give me a break, will ya?
Now, all of you, stay here and don't fucking move.
- Shhh.
- Sir, you really shouldn't go up there.
Oh, gun's out.
The fucking cop guy's got his gun out.
Hey, you want this right now?
Shut the fuck up and stay here!
- Alex!
- What?
- Alex, let's get the fuck out of here, man.
- No, we can't leave, I already told you.
- Yes!
If we leave now...
Shhh!
If I leave, I'm the one who's in shit, time,
and money for all those cameras.
There's like fifty grand worth of cameras up there.
If you stay, you're going to be arrested.
If you guys wanna leave, be my guest.
Go!
I'm staying.
If I don't get the cameras and that footage back,
I don't have a film, all right?
I won't have a fucking film!
[gunfire] [screams] [gunfire]
- Yo, were those gunshots?
- Yeah, they were.
No, no, no. Alex, get down here.
Alex!
Uh, Alex, dude, fuck it, man.
Please, let's just leave.
Look, why are we going towards the fucking gunshots?
- He's an asshole!
- He's going by himself!
Yo, let's go!
C'mon.
Fuck! Fuck!
Shhhh!
Hello?
You in here?
Hey!
Just let us stop.
Is that his fucking flashlight?
Oh, my God!
Shit!
Hey!
Hey, you okay?
You gotta be fucking kidding me!
- Where did he go?
- I don't fucking know.
Seriously, I want to go.
Yeah, I agree with her, man.
We gotta get out of here.
Okay, I'm with you.
Hold on.
Let's just split up into two groups.
It's gonna be faster that way.
Are you fucking kidding me?
That's retarded Alex.
- Why the fuck would we split up? That's so stupid.
- Just go fast.
Tessa, if we do this together it's going to take forever.
Yeah, fuck you!
Dude, I'm not walking around on my own in here, okay?
- Man up. Go with Tessa.
- Man up?
- Go get the cameras.
- When did you lose your brains?
Why does this have to be a fucking argument all the time?
Why don't we just do one thing...
Why does this have to...
This is so fucking stupid.
I cannot believe we're doing this right now.
Can you get that flashlight there?
- Can you please hurry up?
- Okay, come here.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go.
Jen, Jen, calm down.
Tessa, I found the room.
Jared, where are you?
Go to the end of the hall.
Where?
[Loud screech]
Oh, fuck!
Fuck!
Shit.
Tessa?
Tessa, get over here.
[Whispering]
What are you doing?
Oooooaaaaaahhhh!
Jared, where are you?
Oh my God! Jared!
Fuck!
Oh, shit!
Shit!
You guys, you guys, I need help!
You guys, hello!
[air horn]
What the fuck happened?
- What happened, what happened?
- I don't know. I just heard a crash and he was gone.
- He must have fell.
- What?
- Okay, what, what happened...
- I don't see anything..but let's 'sticks up' and fly.
Camera's rolling on everything.
Oooooaaaahhhh!!
Did you see that?
You fuckin' see that?
- Okay, no, no, no, no!
- Something threw him through the fucking window!
- Let's get the fuck out of here. Let's go.
- Tess, we need to go. We need to go.
C'mon!
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Okay, an exit.
C'mon, it's an exit.
- Jenny, call 9-1-1.
- It's not working. I can't get a signal.
Keep moving. We'll call when we're outside. C'mon.
Fucking dead. Jared's fucking dead!
- What?
- What the fuck? - No.
- This is supposed to lead to the front entrance.
- No, no, no, no.
That's impossible!
Look, look at the glow sticks.That's impossible!
Well, maybe the guard moved it, I mean...
- Why the fuck would the guard move it?
- I don't fucking know!
Haah.
Slow down!
Wait!
C'mon!
I'm getting the fuck outta here!
Uh, okay, okay, okay.
It says that we're right here,
so we just have to go down two flights of stairs
- ...and then in that direction.
- No, you're looking at it backwards.
The exits are that way.
Well, we're on the fourth fucking floor.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Alex, can you get over here, please?
Can you take a look at this?
- What's the point?
- So we can find a way to get out of here.
You still don't understand.
The map's fucking useless.
What are you talking a....
Is it this way?
Oh, my God, this place looks awfully dark.
Jesus Christ!
Look.
They had a child's ward here?
Okay, let me go first.
- Oh, my God.
- They just leave this up here?
Fuck!
- You guys hear that?
- [music box]
You guys, you guys.
Oh, my God.
Oh shit, you guys. Look!
You're seeing the impossible.
You getting this?
- Trevor, come back here.
- Trevor, get away from there.
Trevor, stop!
Oh shit!
Sweetie, what are you doing here?
Where are your parents?
Hello.
I'm Caitlin.
What's your name?
Do you want to play a game with me?
Do you want ta...
[loud roaring]
[screaming]
- You guys, move out.
- Slow down!
Tess!
Tessa!
What the fuck?
Where, where is she, where is she, huh?
[air horn]
- Did you hear that? Did you hear that?
- Tessa!
- Tess!
Alex?
Trevor!
Where the fuck are you guys?
Oh shit.
Don't be afraid, okay.
She won't harm me.
[loud roar]
Oh my God!
Fuck you!
Leave me alone.
Fuck!
[loud roars]
[screams]
[heavy breathing]
How do you work this thing?
C'mon, c'mon.
You guys!
Alex!
Oh God!
C'mon.
You guys!
Fuck!
Where are you?
[banging doors]
[screams]
Get off me!
Don't touch me!
Help me!
Aaahhh!
Get the fuck off me!
Aaaahhhh!
(Sobbing)
Please!!
My name is Alex Wright.
This is Jennifer Parker and that's Trevor Thompson.
We came here to find the proof that the movie
Grave Encounters was real.
It's all fucking real.
We already lost Jared and Tessa.
- I don't think we're going to be seeing them again.
- [sobbing] Don't say that!
- Shhh, shhh.
- Don't do that!
There has to be a reason why it brought us here,
why it brought me here, I mean.
Film everything.
He wants me to film everything, and I don't...
I don't know why.
- Alex, turn the fucking camera off.
- Fuckin' shit! I'm NOT going to turn the camera off.
[Loud bang]
Shhh...shhh...shhh...shhh...
I am not gonna let anything happen to you, okay!
Nothing is gonna happen to you.
[whispering]
Why the fuck are we going upstairs?
[electrical sounds]
What is that?
Uh, please don't go in there.
What if it's Tess?
It's not.
Man, Alex, turn it off.
Turn it off, turn it off, fucking turn it off, man!
Fucking security guard!
Jesus!
Turn it off...turn it off...turn it off...and fuck me!
(Sobbing)
Is he dead?
I think so.
Aaaahhhh!
- I'm trying.
- Turn it off, turn it off, turn it off.
Please.
My God, it hurts.
Get it off, get it off of me, please.
[screams]
Well, it was fucking stupid for me to come here.
- Sh, sh, shhhh.
- Okay.
- Quiet.
- Fuck, I can't believe...
Look.
Guys, look.
I mean it looks like this shit's coming off already.
- Bet I can pry it off.
- What?
Okay, let's go quickly, quickly.
Just don't fucking stand there, give me the crowbar.
- Hurry up.
- It won't come off.
Come on.
You guys, get it off.
Come on, come on, come on.
Oh shit, okay.
Come on, come on.
Let's get out of here, let's go.
Let's get out of here, right?
[screaming]
[growling]
Get the bag.
Come on.
Forget the bag!
Let's go!
Hurry! Go!
Run, run!
[growling] [screaming]
Oh, shit!
C'mon!
Go, go, go, go, go, go...
C'mon! Let's go!
Jen!
Oh shit!
[roaring]
- Christ, let's go!
- Fuck!
[siren wailing]
Jared! Jared!
You can't help Jared.
Come with me. Come here.
We gotta go!
Fuck!
Trevor, get the camera.
Shit!
He took the fucking camera!
[sobbing]
We made it out of the building.
We fuckin' made it!
Did ya see that?
Did you fucking see that?
I told you it was real.
[sobbing]
- Alex!
- Alex, what the fuck are you doing in there?
Alex, get out here!
- We have to do something about it.
- Don't think about it. Get your stuff!
Fuck off! We have to do something.
We can't just leave!
- We'll call someone.
- I don't know where the fuck it went!
Trevor, hurry up.
Fuck you, Alex.
[ding]
[elevator music]
I'm upset you got so obsessed with that fucking movie.
I'm sorry.
What the fuck do you want me to say?
I'm sorry, huh?
I didn't know anything of this was going to happen.
Tessa's probably dead.
But you get your fucking project credit, huh?
- Shut up.
- Shut up! Shhh.
What the fuck?
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no...
We were just in the hotel!
Fuck, don't do it. It's fucking useless.
No, we weren't. We were in the building.
- What the fuck you mean we were in the building?
- What the fuck do you think!
It's what the building fucking does!
(Sobbing)
Take your bag, huh.
No, I don't wanna.
No, I don't want to go.
- No, I don't wanna go.
- Come on, just keep walking. Go.
This is...fucking bullshit!
Alex, where we gonna go now, man?
I'm not fucking dying down here.
To lose them now would just...
I think they're about ready to snap.
[breathing heavy]
[creaking sounds]
What the fuck is that?
Jen!
You guys, I can't see anything!
- Jennifer!
- Alex, where are you?
Jen, Jen, where the fuck are you?
- Jennifer, where are you?
- I'm here.
- I'm right here!
- Okay, shit.
Trevor, turn the thermal cam on.
Yeah, okay.
Fuckin' see anything?
It still works.
Still works.
I can see you guys.
Jen, keep walking. Come towards my voice.
I'm right here.
Right here.
[Ghostly whispers]
- Let's go. C'mon, let's go.
Oh God!
What do you see?
- You don't wanna know.
- Tell me, what do you see?
Ahh!
[growling]
Tell me what you see.
What is it?
Ahh!
Turn that light off!
- Turn that light off!
- You gotta help us!
- Please help!
- Come with me.
- Please, please.
- Follow me.
C'mon.
Get in!
Hurry!
Trevor, you back there?
Turn it off...
Move!
Fuck!
Guys, guys.
Stop, stop, stop, stop!
My fucking foot's caught!
Guys, don't...
What the fuck?
....What the fuck?
Fuck me!
Oh, fuck!
Ahhhhhhhhhh!!!!!!!!!
Trevor, Trevor!
Oh, my God, Trevor!
Where were you?
What happened?
What the fuck happened?
I don't want to talk about it.
Who are you?
Agh, agh!
Right, that means the changes are getting longer!
You been living in here?
First sixty-five. Minus one eight five.
Right there!
Ugh, ugh, ugh!
- Wait.
- Ugh, ugh!
You're Lance Preston.
Sean Rogerson, the actor, right?
You've been alive this whole time?
Who's alive?!
Who's alive?
[rat scurries]
[kissing sounds]
What's he doing?
Hi buddy.
Are you my friend?
- Fuck!
- Hee, hee, hee, hee...
Ah, gross!
Oh, oh, oh my God!
Ewww...I think I'm gonna be sick!
Want some?
You gotta help us find a way out of this goddamn building!
Be patient.
- What?
- Patience?
Yeah.
What ward are you in?
Uh, Sean, we're not patients, okay.
We're film students.
We broke into the building.
Why?
Why would you do that?
Because we needed to find the truth, okay,
about your film.
What?
What film?
What film!?
- Good evening, and welcome to another episode...
- Sean!
This is the trailer for your movie
Grave Encounters.
Hah, hah, hah.
"...a dumping ground for embarrassing family
members rather than..."
Oh.
Ashley.
Fog came for her...
...took her away.
Shit, there must be a way out of here, right?
Anything.
You must know something.
Kenny's got the keys!
- Don't fuckin' touch me!
- Kenny's got the keys.
He's gonna come for us.
Just wait a couple more days.
He's not going to come for us, Sean.
Listen to me.
He committed suicide years ago,
so he's not gonna come for you.
You must know something.
You've been in here for nine years.
An air duct, a fucking window.
Something!
Nine months, two days, eleven hours.
He thinks he's only been here for nine months?
You've been here for nine years, not nine months,
do you understand?
Your mom, okay, I met your mom.
Lovely lady.
Lovely lady, but she's really ill, Sean.
- Your mom is very ill.
- Shut up! Shut up!
Kenny's comin', Kenny's got the keys.
Trev, wake up!
- Alex, why are you filming this?
- This guy's completely out of his mind.
Look at him.
He's fucking psycho.
Ten years in this fucking place!
Why did you have to give him a pair of fucking scissors?
He's not gonna do anything.
It's fine.
I don't trust him.
Sean, what are these drawings of?
Huh, huh, huh.
That's the door.
Huh, it's beautiful, isn't it?
This doesn't make any sense.
Yeah, you know what?
It doesn't fucking lead anywhere.
Sean, this is just a free-standing door.
Ye, ye, you go right through it.
Maybe, maybe not.
But Sean's been through every single door in the building,
except this one.
This is the fucking way out, and you know that?
Lock, lock, locked!
It's too thick!
But the bolt-cutters, the bolt-cutters
could cut right through that.
You have...bolt-cutters?
Yeah, we have, we had a whole bag of tools,
but we, we lost it.
Where did you...you lose it?
The Building?
It's giant.
It's big!
As big as a city.
It's bigger, bigger, bigger.
Constantly shifts and changes.
But there are patterns.
I've mapped them.
Where did you leave the bag?
I don't know.
There was a...it was a, it was a hallway with...with...
there's, there's bathtubs in all the rooms.
Hydrotherapy room.
Here!
Four hours.
Six!
Seven, eight hours.
This is fucking crazy!
It's just a free-standing door.
It doesn't fucking lead anywhere.
- Alex, this isn't Narnia!
- N'yeah, okay.
I'm sorry, but this is really fucking crazy.
This is stupid.
You know what else is crazy?
Running through a hotel and ending up
in the same fucking place you started.
We've gotta avoid this area.
What's, what's in that area?
- That's where Doctor Friedkin is
- Wait, Doctor Friedkin?
He was the head physician here.
I read about him online.
The rumour was that he was into the occult,
held rituals in the basement...
experiments on the patients.
Where do you think this came from?
That's where he went in.
[scream]
He opened a gateway, you know.
Friedkin did.
He took the real world and the spirit world and...
he smashed them together.
Then he tore a hole in the building
and put...right through it.
That door is the only way out.
You have to believe me.
Alex, come on.
I can't believe we're doing this.
Why the fuck are we following him, Alex?
Dude, please, bad, I have a bad feeling about this guy.
- We don't have any other choice, all right?
- Alex.
Jesus!
What the fuck?
I thought you said you knew where you were going.
Just...hang on a second.
Move!
Come on, let's go, and don't wait here.
Fucking Christ!
We can just go.
Jeez, you're wasting our...
Ha, ha, ha.
See, I told ya!
Jesus Christ!
What is that?
This way.
In here.
- Go!
- Okay, let's go.
You know that you're drinking out of a fuckin' toilet?
What the fuck are you doing?
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Jesus Christ!
Quit staring and help me!
It should be on the other side.
[banging] [roaring]
Get the fuck out of the way!
I'm going through first!
Waaaahhhh!
Oh fuck!
You okay, man?
Trevor!
That doesn't make any sense.
- Are you all right?
- Trevor, is the bag down there?
Yeah, the bag's here.
What the fuck?
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Do you got me? - Yes.
- Okay.
- Careful, dude.
Got the bag?
Thank God.
Let me see those!
These might work.
Uh, okay, what do we do now?
We rest a few hours.
Then I see what's behind the door!
What are you doing?
Just in case something happens.
Lie down.
This is a bad idea.
Fuck you, Alex!
Fuck, you dragged us out?
Stupid!
Mom, Dad, Jason, if you guys are watching this,
it means I'm...probably dead.
So I guess this is my last will and testament.
You go to my room...
[loud noise]
[sobbing] Never should a been such a dick.
Okay, but I'm waking up and I'm here,
and recording a fucking will,
and I'm only 21 years old and don't want to fucking die.
I just want to go home.
I'm fucking so afraid.
[loud bang]
Hello?
Is anybody there?
What the fuck?
Jesus!
Sean, you scared the shit out of me.
What do you want?
Woah, watch out!
No, no, no.
He made me do it.
He made me do it, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You did this!
We just woke up.
Trevor's dead.
We found him in one of the bathrooms.
Sean did this.
Shoulda listened to Trevor.
I mean, he told me not to trust him.
Sean took all of our equipment.
The bolt-cutters, the water.
All he left us is this shitty fucking bag!
[sobbing] We're never gonna to get out of this building.
We're gonna die in here.
Listen to me, listen to me.
Calm down.
Stop filming me!
- Stop filming me!
- Shhh, Jennifer, shhh.
Now listen to me very carefully,
'cause I am not going to let anything happen to you.
Okay?
I'm not going to let anything happen to you.
We're gonna get out of here, I can promise you that.
How?
I don't know.
Wait!
Shh, wait.
Where the fuck?
Fucking map, he left the fucking map.
Can you read it?
- Uhh.
- Can you read it?
- Yeah, yeah, I think so. I think so.
- Okay, this is what we're looking for.
We need to get to the room with the door before him.
We need the bolt-cutters.
That's our only chance of getting out of here, okay?
Are you sure it's that way?
This is good for something.
It's been a long time since I've been on camera.
Might be a little...rusty.
Hee, hee.
I'm...Lance Preston,
and welcome toanother episode of Grave Encounters,
hee, hee, hee, hee, ya.
Welcome to another episode of Grave, hee, hee, hee, hee.
I'm Lance Preston,
and welcome to another episode of Grave Encounters.
The rest of the cast is no longer with us,
but I...am still here.
If we're lucky, maybe we can make contact with them.
Why'd you lock the door, Lance?
I want to go back to the hotel!
I'm sensing a dark and evil spirit.
Lance?
It even possibly might be a demon.
I'm done playing this character!
I'm getting out of here!
Which way's the room?
What's the right door?
[laughs]
Finally!
No.
Goddamn it!
What the fuck?
Nooooo!!!
Bullshit!
Broken promises, myeaahhh!
Liar!!!!
Red door?
Bullshit!
Liar!
You said that one of us
could leave through the red door.
I even killed one of them so they wouldn't follow me.
What did I do wrong?
Huh?
Answer me!
How can I do that
if you won't let me leave?
Collect the tapes?
You want me to collect the footage?
Huh?
Yeah, I could do that.
I could try.
[loud bangs]
"Finish the film" What film?
What are you talking about?
Hello?
Okay.
Okay, all right.
Collect the tapes.
The tapes.
You're sure it's this way?
The map says its just up ahead.
- Jennifer.
- This is it.
Wait.
Sean told us to avoid the surgical ward.
I don't think we have any other choice.
What the hell are these things?
- When did Doctor Friedkin do this?
- Fuck!
What the fuckin' twisted...
Oh, my God.
Alex, this isn't right, we have to go,
we have to keep moving.
Alex, let's go.
Jennifer, we gotta get out of here.
[loud bang]
C'mon, c'mon, get in this.
Turn the light off, turn the light off.
Shhh.
Keep you mouth shut, keep your mouth shut.
- Oh, my God.
- Be quiet!
Jennifer, be quiet.
Hold him down.
Is that Doctor Friedkin?
Don't do this, don't do this.
Jennifer, be quiet.
Keep your mouth shut.
Ahhhhhh!!!!!!!!
[Baby crying]
A baby?
A fucking pentagram!
Fucking kidding me.
Fuck!
[bottles crashing on shelf]
- Shit!
I don't think they heard us.
[roaring]
[screaming]
Don't look back, go!
In here, in here, in here!!!!!!!!!
- Shhhh!
- Shut the door, shut the door, shut the door!
- Okay, I think we're right here.
- I thought you said you could read this map.
- I am trying!
- You sure? Right here.
I don't fucking know!
- Oh shit, Jennifer, look.
- How the fuck did we get here?
How the fuck do we get anywhere
in this fucking place?
And it looks like he's already been here.
Did you think he went through?
Looks like it.
- We're too late.
- We're too late. He got out.
[laughter]
Oh, it doesn't work that way.
You killed Trevor, you fucking psycho!
Your friend was dead the moment he stepped foot
in the building.
You all were.
Alex, look at this.
It said...if one of us collected all the tapes
they could go.
And it's gonna be me.
Now you guys are gonna have to stay behind.
I'm sorry.
I've been in here way too long.
Do you have any idea what ten years in here
could do to a person?
I just want to go home.
Now give me the footage from your cameras.
I need to finish the film.
I'm not giving you anything.
This is my film.
The building said I need to finish the film!
- Now give me the footage!
- Waaaaahhh!
Give me the camera!
Give...
Get off him!
It's the only way, so fucking die already.
The building chose me, not you!
I need to finish the film!
Are you okay?
- You okay?
- I'm not sure--
You fucking bitch!
I'm gonna kill you.
What the fuck is that?
Alex, hang on!
Hang on!
- Alex!
- I can't!
I did what you said!
You liar!
Alex.
Alex, are you okay?
He's gone.
It just sucked him out.
What do we do now?
Just try to finish the film.
Finish the film.
This is what it's all been about, why it contacted me.
The building wants an audience.
Alex, what are you talking about?
I think I just figured out the ending of my movie.
You're the star.
Alex, what are you doing?
You heard him.
Only one of us is getting out, so what d'ya say, Jennifer?
You always told me you wanted your death scene
to be...epic, right?
This is it.
I mean, don't make this harder than it has to be.
Alex, please.
I'm sorry.
So sorry!
Should have fucking made it.
I'm so sorry, I mean, I really, really am.
Alex, stop!
I'm sorry.
Alex, Nooooo!!!
It's over.
Go to sleep.
I'll do it.
I'll finish your film.
Others will see it.
They'll come.
I won't let you down.
[laughs]
[Siren wailing]
Sir!
Got a report that you wandered across the I-5.
Seven-eight-twenty-three, we got a Caucasian male,
large duffle bag, requesting backup.
Sir!
No, no, my cameras!
I need my footage.
I'm not going back, uggghhh.
I need my cameras!
Where am I?
- Where am I?
- Huh?
What city am I in?
You're in Los Angeles.
So, Gerry, can you tell us how Grave Encounters 2
came together?
Well, sure.
I mean, look, I was just as surprised as anybody
when this kid comes walking into my office to tell me
that he's just filmed the sequel to Grave Encounters.
I mean, I thought he was nuts, ya know, but, uh,
as it turns out, Alex here is quite a talented director
and, uh, I really think that he's got
a bright future ahead of him.
And this thing has got everything.
Ya know, its got ghosts sending messages
through the Internet, uh, young girls being killed,
guys being sucked through walls.
It's...wild stuff!
Hopefully, you enjoyed it.
But, I...I want to be very clear about one thing,
as I made this mistake with the first film.
Everything you've just seen...is fake, okay?
Every single shot has been, uh, doctored or manipulated.
It's just a movie.
Is there anything you want to add before we wrap all this up?
Look, whatever you do, don't go looking for the building.
All right? Don't go looking for (CENSORED).
It's not worth it.
There's nothing there.
Random question
- Yeah.
- Are you ready?
- 'kay, I'm ready.
- Okay, you were at the Halloween party.
- Yeah.
- I was, like, throwing myself at Alex like...
- ...like if I was another person, and I saw me,
I would be like, that girl's a slut.
Just like...nothing from him, like, absolutely nothing.
I've been trying for months now
and he just can't take a hint.
Alex is pretty shy though.
He's always been a pretty shy guy.
Yeah, but he wouldn't have to do anything outgoing
at this point.
Why the fuck do you think I'm here right now?
- You're not filming this, are you?
- No, I'm not filming this.
- Are you fil...
- Oh shit! - I think you are filming It's going.
Oh fuck!