I guess...
I do like you after all.
What did you do to her!?
You ditch her for a year
and then come back with a girlfriend
and even get yourself engaged.
Don't come back now and
act like her fucking boyfriend!!
I love you after all that's happened.
What a selfish thing to say.
I can't think of any other woman but you.
I can understand why you're hesitating
but I don't think you should
keep things the way they are now.
Makino?
Who could it be?
Episode 6: Confession turns Chaotic!
Sorry for dragging you out here
but the walls were too thin in there.
What is it... that you want to tell me?
To you, has the young master
already became your past?
Huh?
Why are you asking me now?
Shortly after the young master
arrived at New York
there was one accident.
Triggered by one innocent phrase the
young master said at a certain party.
I never liked the way that ass--oh
I mean our president--does things.
He didn't mean much by it, as always,
but the media took it as words from the next
president and made a huge deal out of it.
People interpreted it as uncertainty in
the future, and our stocks plunged.
I can't believe it...
Just by a word from Doumyouji?
The Doumyouji group suddenly faced a crisis
and the only solution was a mass lay off.
Among those laid off was a
Japanese man named Ken Uchida
whom the young master loved like a brother.
The lay off crushed his family
and he struggled to make a living.
One day, Ken Uchida came to see the president
and asked for employment. However
the president could not answer him
and losing all hope
he committed suicide in front of
the young master's own eyes.
That's when he began changing.
I think he started realizing that to stand at
the top means to be responsible for the millions
of lives and living that are
involved with the corporate group.
That's why he was so desperate to change:
to bury his feelings for you
and to stand at the top
of the corporate group.
It was during that time that he saw you again,
and shared his time with you again.
He must have no longer been able to
lie to himself about his true feelings.
But... aren't you completely against
Doumyouji and I dating?
I have to return to New York tomorrow as well.
However
Please don't lower your guard just
because the president herself is absent.
The next step has already...
Eh?
It's only when the young master is with you
that he acts human.
As someone who will eventually
stand at the top, I wish for him
to always be like so.
I hope you understand my meaning.
Ma-ki-no.
What's wrong?
You gave me a call.
That was
Nishida-san, wasn't he?
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Not really.
Hey, let's go for a drive somewhere right now.
I guess not.
I'm sorry.
I'm just really confused now.
Will you be more confused?
Now that I do something like this to you?
Hey Sis! It's been a while.
No, I just... need your help.
I'm serious... Please...
And you just left after that?
Well...
I guess you can't help it.
Not after hearing about
Doumyouji-san's past like that.
Hey, what are you going to do
for this year's Valentine?
Eh?
Maybe this will be a good opportunity for you
to be honest about your feelings once again.
Yeah....
Maybe I should do something
on Valentine's day too.
By the way...
Yuuki, have Nishikado-san ever
let you ride on the back of his motorcycle once?
No. Why?
There's no mistake about it!
Mistress!
That seat is... reserved.
What do you mean, reserved?
It means he's only going to let
one special woman sit there.
One special woman?
Now that you mention it...
I don't give girls rides.
I wonder if... Nishikado-san has someone
he can't forget or something.
Good question. I'm sure he must have
experienced his first love too.
First love, huh...
I wonder if he still cares about her...
You can't give up, Yuuki-chan!
What? You're going back now?
Because the midnight buses are the cheapest.
Call us as soon as anything comes up, okay?
I can get some spending money
by the end of this month, right?
W-What? You can't?
Of course it's possible.
Exactly. Your father is currently famous
as the Man of the Sea right now!
See you later then!
Make sure you lock the doors
and turn off the gas!
Somehow, Mom and Dad seemed
suspicious, didn't they?
Yeah.
Oh, I need to lock the doors.
What?
Uh...
I... ran out of... sugar.
And I'm currently... looking for someone
who could share some sugar with me
in the neighborhood.
Huh? Isn't that a little...
What I mean is...
I was trying to make a commoner's food called...
jaga-niku or something.
You mean niku-jaga?
Hey! We were just about to have dinner!
Why don't you eat with us?
Eh?!
Please, come in.
Sis, please make jaga-niku.
I want to eat it too!
Like I said, it's niku-jaga.
Oh, that's right!
- Can I borrow your room?
- Eh?
I want to study for as long as possible.
Wait, what are you talking about?
Aren't you already done with your exam?
What are you doing?
O-Oh! That's right!!
What a coincidence. I'm going in!
Hey!
He must have no longer been able to lie
to himself about his true feelings.
What are you...
I'm serious...
about what I said yesterday.
I want to say it again, properly.
Stop!
Where... is your hand right now?
N-N-No, that's not it.
It was an accident--
Get your hand off me now!
Grandpa...! B-Bodies fell... into our room!
Sorry.
Kagayaita no ha
What shined was
Kagami demo taiyou demo nakute
Neither the mirror nor the sun
Kimi dato kiduita toki kara
But you. Since then
Ano namidagumu kumo no zutto
Behind those tearful clouds
Ue ni ha hohoemu tsuki
Is always a smiling moon.
Love story mata hitotsu
Another love story
Kidutuita yume ha kinou no kanata he
Take the wounded dreams to yesterday
Sora ni hibike ai no uta
The sky will echo with the song of love
Omoide zutto zutto wasurenai sora
The sky will always, always remember the memories
Futari ga hanarete itemo
No matter if we are separated
Konna sukina hito ni
For the girl I love so much
Deau kisetsu nido to nai
Even if we won't meet the second time
Hikatte motto saokou no lady
Shine more, you're the best lady
Kitto sotto omoi todoku
My feelings will definitely, gently reach to you
Shinjiru koto ga subete Love so sweet
Believing is everything Love so sweet
Waratte motto saigo no lady
Laugh more, you're the last lady
Kitto sotto omoi todoku
My feelings will definitely, gently reach to you
Shinjiru koto ga subete
Believing is everything
Akenai yoru ha naiyo
The sun will always rise
Shinjiru koto ga subete Love so sweet
Believing is everything Love so sweet
Distributed for free.
Timing by Tianj
Translated by Lily @ jLand.wordpress.com
Visit the site for translation notes.
Hey, Rui
have you talked to Tsukasa since then?
Nah
Are you seriously serious about Makino?
Who knows?
It's not "who knows?"
What are you gonna do about it?
About what?
But if Tsukasa's feelings are
all going towards Makino
Is he going to break things off
clean with Oogahara Shigeru?
At this rate, I don't think your friendship
with Tsukasa looks too good.
Who cares?
The worst that can happen is...
Rui...
Besides
the one who has to make the decision
is neither me nor Tsukasa, right?
It's something Makino needs to decide--
But what about Shizuka?
Huh? Didn't I tell you?
Thank you for everything.
Shizuka and I are over.
No way...
Yes, way.
Hey, hey, did you hear?
That peasant girl's apartment floor fell and
they're going to tear down the whole building!
No way! That's picture-perfect misery!
- But the news is bottomlessly pleasant.
- My, that was quite nice, Minako.
Wow wow
Are they serious?
You were with him, right? The one who
bought the entire apartment building from us?
Y-Yes...
Do you know him?
Well, I guess, in a way.
I see.
Oh, here's your change.
Then, do you happen to know his friends too?
- You mean the F4?
- Yes, them.
Yes, I guess you can say... I know them.
I see.
Onee-san!
Long time no see!
I'm not Yomogi, by the way!
Tsukushi-chan.
It smells so good!
All done.
I need to talk to you. Make some time.
Here is fine. Thank you.
Sis! You got here fast!
Tsukasa, I brought you a souvenir.
Thanks.
But before that, Sis,
about what we talked about the other day...
It's all right.
Eh? It's all right? But...
I said it's all right.
Makino!! H-Hi...
What kind of dumb sound is that?
You realize Tsukushi-chan just lost a place to live.
Oh! I was just... thinking about that too.
I have a good idea.
It's really all right. I can't possibly ask you to...
You can! You promised
you'll leave everything up to me, didn't you?
Hey, what happened? What's going on?
Can you believe this idiot
called me to ask me for my help on
how he can break his engagement
and start all over with Makino?
Hey! Don't say such
embarrassing things in front of her!
But it's important!
Tsukasa, there's no lie in
those words of yours, is there?
Yeah.
Then it's decided!
Come with me.
- Hey, wait. What's going--
- You stay here and clean that up.
I'll be waiting at the same cafe as last time.
--Shigeru
Don't make a face like that.
Come on in.
You can use this place
anyway you want from today.
Are you serious?
I think you'll be able to hide here
for a while if you're careful.
But...
You don't like... being close to Tsukasa?
T-That's...
If you still think it won't work out, it's okay.
That's a problem between the two of you.
But... I don't want any more people to suffer
because of what my mother has done.
Eh?
When I was in high school,
I used to date a boy from
an average working class family too.
YOU too?
But talks of marriage with the son of
a hotel chain owner suddenly came up because
my mother wanted to expand
her hotel business back then.
Just like Doumyouji now...
Yes.
I rebelled a lot, too
but in the end, she said she'll cut all
business ties with his father's company
and that was it.
Furious wasn't even close to what I felt.
I honestly hated Mother then.
So that's why you've always been supporting me.
But because he really takes good care of me now
I can honestly say I'm glad that
I got married from the bottom of my heart.
But... I also think about
what would have happened
if I had married the person
I really, really loved instead.
We could have eloped if we had wanted to
Or like Shizuka-chan, I could have
given up my family too, but...
In the end, I didn't have
the courage to give up this life.
But it's weird,
because even now, part of me is still
blaming my old self for it.
Like why didn't I try harder?
That's why I don't want Tsukasa to
go through the same thing.
Especially if it's with you, Tsukushi-chan.
Onee-san...
Please consider living here.
It'll also be a good opportunity for you to
settle things with Tsukasa once and for all.
Right?
Sorry for making you make some time for me.
What are you talking about?
I'm really happy you asked me out.
So
Do you want to drink something?
Here's the menu.
Oh thanks.
Look, look, look. Look at this!
Tada!
It's about our wedding,
but where should we hold it?
I want one overseas with just the two of us,
But you know how our parents are
always talking about networking?
They probably want a formal wedding and stuff.
Oh, I'm having them make the
wedding dress now. And it's so awesome!
If you see me in that,
I bet you'll fall in love with me again.
- Um...
- Oh, did you decide what you wanted?
- Excuse me!!
- Actually, I could care less about the drink...
I'm not going to break up with you.
If you break up with me, I might just die.
- You serious??
- I am.
- What a chain of events.
- I know.
- What about Susumu-kun?
- That's just it.
Don't worry about me!
I'll go live with Mom and Dad.
But what about school?
I've already got into high school,
and it's almost the end of the year. It'll be okay.
But it's not okay.
Besides, it's better if I'm not here, isn't it?
- So he went to your parents' place?
- Yuuki-chan.
My lessons are starting. I'll call you later.
- Did Tsukushi-chan find a place to live?
- Yes.
Thank goodness!
But looks like she has a lot of troubles already.
Yeah...
It seems like everything's
riding on Valentine's Day.
- Valentine's Day?
- Yes.
Valentine's, huh...
I don't have a very good memory of that.
Oh, really?
Yeah, really.
The word Valentine is taboo in front of Soujirou.
It's not really taboo or anything, it's just...
- Then I'll give you chocolate if you give me a ride!
- Hey, wanna join me?
I really can't do that.
Can I really stay here?
- Welcome home.
- Oh, hey, Sis.
Tsukushi-chan is going to start living here with us.
I see--
What??!!
The rest is up to you. Good luck.
Then I'll excuse myself now.
You're leaving all ready?
But moreover, is Makino really going to live here?
You shouldn't attack her while she's asleep.
I won't!
I mean, thanks, Sis!
You're awesome! You're the best!
Before you get so excited, you need to
settle things with Oogahara Shigeru-san first.
Breaking your engagement with
her and choosing Tsukushi-chan is
something that'll require a sacrifice from
both your part and the corporate group's part.
I know.
What you are about to do is
to love someone at the
stake of your life, you know.
Whatever you do,
make sure you do them carefully.
Don't do anything rash.
- Welcome.
Would you like to buy some Valentine chocolate?
- Thank you very much.
- Welcome.
Would you like to buy some Valentine chocolate?
You and I are both Saturn according to astrology,
so regardless of happy or painful times,
we're destined to be together.
I couldn't fall asleep at all
-  and I couldn't even make lunch this morning.
- Makino!
- Eat over here.
- We'll treat you.
- Thank you so much.
- Don't worry about it.
So where are you going to stay now?
I-I'm staying with someone I know...
O-Oh!! Did you know Yuuki's taking
Japanese tea lessons, Nishikado-san?
Really? Which school?
I'm... not sure...
She's got some courage.
You should go see her one of these days.
- Are there any cute girls?
- Of course!
Oh! Yuuki's new friend is really cute!
All right! Let's go take a peek next time!
- If we have time.
- Of course we do.
Hey, Tsukasa.
W-W-Wooooah Makino-kun! It's been a while!
Hey, hey, hey, you guys are so easy to figure out.
Something happened, didn't it?
Nothing, right, Makino-kun?
Not like we have any secrets.
Hey!
So what about this secret?
Something did happen, didn't it?!
You're up to something bad again!
W-Why are you two ganging up on me?
T-Treating me like I'm a criminal or something.
- I'll call my lawyer.
- Lawyer??
I completely forgot!
The results are coming out today!
Hey, Tsukasa, you can't keep any secrets from us.
The more people know about Makino and I
the bigger the ripple gets for sure.
What do you mean?
Makino is staying at my house right now.
Huh??
Does your mom know?
No.
That's why I'm planning
to approach this with caution.
After all, it's love that I'm
staking my life on.
Your result is inside.
Rui
let's talk with just the two of us.
Hey, hey, let's do this peacefully.
Let's go, Akira. These two have
got to work things out themselves.
Thanks.
Please, God...
Passed
Thaaaank yooooou!!!
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
Hanazawa Rui
Hello? Hanazawa Rui?
I got into law major!
Congratulations.
We should go celebrate.
Don't worry about it!
You've done more than enough for me already.
Hey, Rui, who are you talking to on the phone?
Makino. She got into law--
Hey, wait, is Doumyouji there?
He is.
Do you want to talk to him?
N-No! I'll call you again later.
Ack, she hung up.
I see you're definitely picking a fight with me.
Why did you call me if you're with him?
Shigeru-san?
Makino has been staying
at my place since yesterday.
I see.
Aren't you surprised?
I am.
Aren't you jealous?
What?
Is that strange?
I...
guess you can say I woke up by your words.
I tried to forget about Makino because of what
happened at New York but it's like impossible...
She's still... the best in my heart.
There should be a way I can be with her
and not cause trouble for anyone else.
And even if the marriage talk falls apart,
there are many ways to rebuild the company.
When I realized that
no one can stop my feelings anymore.
Are you telling me to give up on Makino?
To put things simply, yes.
Valentine.
Eh?
I wonder who Makino will give her chocolates to.
Hanazawa Rui-san, isn't it?
Don't tell me it's Tsukasa...
I see!
Um... Shigeru-san...
You said "congratulations" to me, didn't you?
The night Tsukasa asked me to be his girlfriend,
You said "good for you" to me, didn't you?
Tsukushi, you said there's nothing
between you and Tsukasa, didn't you?
I can believe your words, can't I?
I can believe you, can't I?
Hello?
- Sorry I didn't come to work today.
- It's okay, don't worry.
What's up?
I'm having Sara-san teach me
how to make chocolate.
So, have you decided yet?
Who you're going to give your chocolate to.
You've held yourself back for so long.
You don't have to do that anymore, okay?
Yeah.
Thanks.
See ya.
So Tsukushi-chan is still mulling over
a lot of things, huh.
Looks like it.
Isn't this it? It says Japanese Room.
But really, this place is too small to make tea.
Hey, Sara-san, where are you going?
There she is.
Yuuki-chan, we've come to see you.
I've humbly come to serve my tea.
Hello, my name is Mimasaka. Nice to meet you.
Thank you very much.
Eh? Nishikado-san?
Um, that's Sara-san's cup,
so please use this one instead.
Sara? You mean Hinata Sara?
Yes...
Do you... know her?
No... not really.
Nishikado-san?
Hey, what's wrong? Where are you going?
Hey! You're leaving?
- If you are, what are we going to--
- Why don't you stay, Mimasaka-san?
Tsukushi
you said there's nothing
between you and Tsukasa, didn't you?
I can believe your words, can't I?
[ Valentine's Day ]
Please be careful! Stand back!
Young master is currently out!
They knew each other?
Probably, because Sara-san
didn't come back after that either.
Maybe she was Nishikado-san's first love...
What about you?
What are you going to do?
I...
Tomorrow, I'm seeing Makino.
Rui
did she call you?
Nope.
I won't hesitate to do what I need to do.
Namura-kun, here you go.
Oh. Thanks.
Let's go.
Sorry. Were you waiting for a long time?
No, I just got here.
You have something you want to give me, right?
I'm... really not sure...
Don't worry.
Just hurry up and hand it over.
This.
Hm?
What do you mean?
I'm giving it back to you.
I want to put a firm end to this.
That's what it means.
This has to be a joke...
I've thought a long time about
a lot of things and this is my answer.
You were too late...
After hurting so many people
we can't just stay together and
be happy by ourselves.
Cut the fuck out!
Is that all I am to you?!
Eh?
If you say you don't want a thing like that,
it means NOTHING to me!
I won't be sad or anything!
I...
can't think of anyone...
I can¡¯t think of any other woman but you!!
This is my first gift to a woman
so I'm going to kill you if you lose it.
You're in love with me, aren't you?
I am.
I'm in love with your
stupid, selfish, stubborn self--
To Tsukasa whom I love very much
Let's be together forever
--Shigeru
Excuse me.
Oh.
Have you not slept?
It's none of your business!
Pardon me.
How will you have your breakfast?
Let's see... Bring it...
What are you doing?
Don't stare at me so much.
Why are you pro-wrestling
so early in the morning?
Pro-wresting..?
You mean cosplaying? ..Sir?
So what are you doing?
Please let me work here from today.
Huh?
It's true that I don't have a place to go and I'm
really thankful you're letting me stay here
But I can't just freeload... I must not... so...
Are you serious?
I want a reason!
to be able to live here... with you.
Makino...
That's why...
this is my best attempt to give you... a reply...
Sir.
But... as a servant?
I don't see any problems with that.
Tama!!
We just happened to be short on staff anyways.
Let's have her work for us.
...Who is she?
Tama... when did you come back?
Late last night. I've been asked
to look after you by Kaede-sama.
Eh?
No need to worry.
I am not so cruel as to refuse people with needs.
Now, please follow me.
Ow ow ow ow!
It hurts! Granny, can you
please go a little slower--
Don't call me as lightly as granny!!
I have been the head servant of this house
for sixty years, since the previous generation.
I will not stand having you
call me on such friendly terms!
I'm sorry.
Call me senior.
Now that you said you'll work,
I'll have you work frantically.
There are plenty of things to do around here.
I won't show any mercy.
Everything I say here is the order.
Do not forget that.
I'm going to stake my life on you.
Does that mean I still have a chance?
That's the most important thing is.
You've got to be kidding me.
Don't you both overwork yourself.
Do your best.
Next is your turn.
You're going to let me stay here tonight.
You can't get in touch with Yuuki?
She seemed to have
disappeared since Valentine's Day.
In that case, it makes somewhat of a sense,
doesn't it? That both of them are missing?
Yuuki?? Hey, Yuuki??
I'm going to tell him flat out,
"You're not the one for me."