(Episode 13)
Thank you,
The Prime Minister is coming,
What is this mess?
My apologies, sir,
You said to keep it confidential, so,,,
I'm sorry,
Please move,
Sorry,
Go and take care of it,
Prime Minister,
your shot was amazing,
You shine in politics and in golf,
You're so good at everything,
My family has been talented for generations,
Since your grandson will become a special,,,
scholarship student at Hankuk University,
this means we'll all be from the same school,
I can see that things will work out well,,,
since we're from the same school,
Thank you for all your efforts,,,
in helping our campus,
Like I said, it's conditional,,,
although it's almost ready,
The rest is up to Mayor Cho's luck,
- You should go, - Okay,
This one?
- Your form is good, - Yes,
Keep it like that,
Nice shot!
It's a hole-in-one,
Congratulations, Mayor Cho,
I hear this will make you lucky for three years,
Mayor Cho, looks like you have to treat us,
There's no doubt about it,
I'll host you on a full course,,,
for today and the next round too,
By the way, your shot was just as good,
Get a full shot,
Ms, Ma,
Good work,
Well, I always do a good job,
You suit being a cooperating attorney,
I look forward to working with you again,
I doubt we'll be working together again,
You must be mistaken,
I don't like helping others,
I help you, then you get all the credit,
All I get is a few hundred dollars,
Then what will you do now?
One moment,
- Yes, ma'am, - Where are you?
I'm coming to the office now,
What do you think? I'll be a prosecutor,
You just wait,
I'll come back as a prosecutor,,,
and become your senior,
I'll change your easygoing mind,
Okay, I'll wait,
(Witch's Court)
Recording,
Here,
Seriously,
Give it to me,
What's wrong with this?
Hey, Do your job properly,
I told you to check on the scanner before,
- I'm sorry, - Jin Yun Hee,
You,,,
dropped one of your earrings,
- I see, - There's jewelry inside,
You should change them,
Okay,
Sir,
Marks don't mean anything,
Just looking at the family is enough,
To have your grandson enroll,,,
is an honor for Hankuk University,
What do you think?
Of course,
Like Hyungjae Group's Ahn Tae Kyoo,,,
and the daughter of Chief Secretary Min,
the children of great families,,,
are making the school shine,
Thanks to that, we were able to revamp,,,
the school gym and the auditorium,
South Korea is such a great country,
By helping each other,
we're making developments,
On that note,
I'm thinking of extending,,,
the school to Yeongpa,
Are you talking about a new campus?
Yes,
If Juyoung-dong will give the permission,
I would give,,,
full support,
Juyoung-dong in Yeongpa?
The Ministry of Land and the Ministry,,,
of National Defense will be against it,
That's why we're bringing it up,
If Hyungjae Group's White Town development,,,
sets in place near the school,
we'll be able to service,,,
even your grandchild's grandchild,
My grandchild's grandchild?
That sounds sweet to my ears,
Here, let's drink,
Yes,
Hey, Don't get mad about something like this,
- I'll buy you chicken, - Forget it,
- Stop being mad, - Let me go,
Gosh,
Why would he tell me on his way home?
I told him to do his job properly,
Not everyone can become the chief,
Gosh, Chief, this, Chief, that,
What would they do without me?
Yes,
Yes, sir,
Okay,
His secret to connections is simple,
He hires women for them and lobbies them,
He gets people on his side by providing,,,
women of their tastes and by throwing money,
That's very like him,
Even if we get him arrested for that,
it will only be seen as a compulsion,
Shouldn't we chase after his money?
No,
(2004 Cheong-Ungag Sexual Favors Issue)
Cheong-Ungag?
This is the case that made Cho what he is today,
In 2004 when Cho was a commissioner general,
Baek Sang Ho received bribes from hostess bars,
With that money, they made a slush fund,,,
and found a place they can lobby,
That's how Cho,,,
became a member of the National Assembly,
So ever since 2004, Cho grew bigger,,,
by providing women and lobbying?
That's right,
He made a space just like Cheong-Ungag,,,
and is providing sexual favors to high figures,
I'm going to put together a list of the regulars,,,
along with the evidence,,,
to arrest Cho Gap Soo,
A lobbying space?
Where is that?
It's Kingdom,
You're Ms, Min's secret agent,
(Jin Sul Hee)
I'm that woman's,,,
younger sister,
Her name is Jin Yun Hee,
She has the same goal as we do,
How do you know about Kingdom?
Because I've been there already,
Hyungjae Hotel, level K,
Level K?
(You have one new voicemail,)
(Voicemail)
Hey, can you come save me?
I'm at Hyungjae Hotel's K,,,
That's where Kong Soo Ah's incident happened,
Did you know already?
I only found out recently,
After Yun Hee penetrated Kingdom,
Had we known earlier,
we could have taken care of Kong Soo Ah's case,
Lobbying, sexual favors,
and concealing a murder?
All of Cho's weaknesses are there,
I witnessed one of them last night,
It's recorded on this,
Here,
I couldn't get anything for a while,
so I thought I was wasting time,
But I found something bigger than I expected,
He's Kim Ho Kyung,
The chancellor of Hankuk University,
You know him, right? The Prime Minister,
He's involved in illicit admissions,
He's acting as the broker between,,,
high-ranking officials and Hankuk University,
Illicit admissions?
If I keep tailing him, we'll get something,
Right,
Here,
Do you see the reflection of the car?
I met with the owner for the dash cam footage,
However,
someone asked to buy it, so they sold it,
They sold it?
Could it be Ms, Ma?
She's investigating Baek Sang Ho's death,
No, I don't think it's her,
She would have met with Baek Min Ho first,
That means someone wants to cover up,,,
Baek Sang Ho's death,
Could it be Cho Gap Soo?
Mr, Yeo, Jung Young Ho got arrested,
He was handed over to Mr, Koo,,,
from the Immigration Office,
Who is he?
He's the researcher from NFS that forged,,,
the evidence for Kong Soo Ah's case,
Is that so?
Great,
Jin Wook looks even more handsome in there,
He's sexy,
Jung Young Ho,
Do you admit that you forged,,,
the analysis report for Kong Soo Ah's case?
No, I don't know anything about this,
This is the statement from Lee Sang Joon,
the researcher in charge of DNA testing at NFS,
He said that the knuckle,,,
was never asked to be analyzed,
We were also able to restore the report,,,
you deleted from your computer,
(Restored files from Jung Young Ho's computer)
Just before handing in your resignation letter,
you received 200,000 dollars to your account,
(200,000 dollars)
Are you still going to say you don't know anything?
Who hired you?
I was hiding abroad,
so I couldn't be here,,,
for my father's passing,
I want to stay with him for his funeral,
Please get me indictment without detention,
Then I'll volunteer to turn myself in,
I told you, didn't I?
We need to find another way to get the list,
I told you not to go there as a hostess!
What should I do then?
Can we arrest Cho with the list?
We have to get inside,,,
to get real evidence of their wrongdoings,
Even still,
How can you go,,,
to entertain Park Myung Il?
What else can I do?
Do you have another idea?
If you do, tell me,
Get out,
I don't need your evidence,
so take it and leave,
Ms, Min,
Go do whatever you want!
Ms, Min, but,,,
- Where are you going? - Yes,
I'm sorry,
I did it because I couldn't think,,,
of any other way to catch him,
So,,,
please catch him this time,
Never act on your own without my order,
Can you promise me?
Yes,
You two are okay now, right?
Can we listen to this first?
Choi Yong Woon, the scanner can break,
Why did you embarrass me in front of a woman?
What? Hey,
I told you to call me a chief at work,
We're not at home,
Chief, my foot,
If I was the one who passed on the video,
I would be in your position!
Hey!
I told you not to talk about the video,
If Cho Gap Soo finds out,
he'll kill us both!
Watch your mouth, okay?
Pay attention,
We got the statement from NFS,,,
admitting that the evidence was forged,
Both you and Ahn Tae Kyoo,,,
don't have any evidence left,
We have to start from the beginning,
You mentioned Ahn Tae Kyoo's video,
We can flip this case around if we have that,
Do you know where it could be?
Or do you know anyone who might have taken it?
- If you can,,, - How can I trust you?
I can't trust anyone right now,
Even my brother, whom I trusted,
died while trying to resolve my case,
I won't give up,
I'll set right everything that went wrong,
I have nothing else to say,
We don't have much time,
If you think of anything,
tell me before the statute of limitations expires,
I went to your brother's house to find the video,
but Cho Gap Soo got rid of the house,
I'm sorry,
I'm the one,,,
who did that,,,
to Sang Ho,
That prosecutor, Ma Yi Deum,
was holding a grudge against me,
I should've nipped it in the bud,
I failed to do that,
so it's my fault,
Once we appeal,
your sentence will be shortened,
Suffer,,,
just a little longer,
When you get out,
you need to fill in for Sang Ho,
That way, he could relax up above,
What happened,,,
to our house,,,
and my brother's things?
Don't worry about a thing,
I kept everything as is,
Your house and your brother's things,
They're all being kept safe,
I need to tell the prosecutor something,
Your visit is over, Go in,
They said a video, right?
That's what I heard,
So they gave the original to Cho Gap Soo,
If he gave an obedient thug,,,
the title of chief,
the video has something that can destroy him,
It may be quicker,,,
to get the video than the lobby list,
We need to find out where it is first,
Carefully approach Choi Yong Woon,
Not him,
I already tried,
but he's suspicious of others, so I gave up,
Okay,
Then I'll meet Dong Shik,
- You will? - Naturally,
I'm gifted,,,
at seducing men,
What was that?
Dong Shik,
He'll be mine soon,
You little punk,
Fruit platter please,
Excuse me,
Yes?
I'd like to give him this,
This?
Yes,
His glass is empty, Go on,
Okay,
What's this?
She sent it,
You should drink with me, considering all my effort,
Check, please,
This is humiliating,
Why doesn't he like me?
Come on,
I said let's have a drink,
What's wrong with you?
Dong Shik?
Yun Hee,
I have a girlfriend,
A girlfriend? Her?
- Let's go, - Sweetie,
who's that old lady?
Are you cheating on me?
What?
What do you mean? I have standards,
She's a crazy woman, Let's go,
Yes, he is cheating!
That liar, He was saying how much he liked me,
He kissed me too,
Babe! I said let's have another drink,
I don't look so bad today,
Ms, Ma?
You have the wrong person,
Wait, It really is you,
It is you, Ms, Ma,
You know, I believe all jobs are equal,
So do I,
Pardon?
I'm busy, so,,,
- But,,, - Okay,
But,,,
I heard lawyers have it tough lately,
but must she really do that?
What do you mean?
Nothing, Let us live a good life, at least,
Goodness,
You saw, right?
I had to get rid of that crazy woman,
Sorry for saying you were my girlfriend,
I don't mind,
What?
You don't need to apologize,
I was happy being your girlfriend,,,
for those few minutes,
What?
What do you mean?
You didn't know?
I liked you from the first time I saw you,
Me too,
How is the appeal preparation going?
We have plenty to rebut the assertions,,,
the prosecution has made,
This has to be the last time,
Are you confident we'll win?
Yes, You may rest assured,
Tell me,
how long have you worked for Gap Soo?
I was scouted,,,
by Hyungjae when I left the prosecutors' office,
so I'm going on five years,
Five years?
Then you've done a lot,
Are you interested in working for me now?
At 10am at Yeongpa Cultural Center,
you have a lecture on "Making a Happy Yeongpa",
At 2pm,
you have the Regional Business Conference,
At 5pm,
after visiting Yeongpa Market,
you will be leading a meeting,,,
on how to revive the business district,
- Yes? - It's about Baek Min Ho,
I think he's going to tell that prosecutor something,
Take care of it,
Yes, sir,
Hey,
Found it,
What,,,
Bring him,
No!
That isn't mine!
Come on,
I know you can do it,
Get my Yun Hee out,
When did she become "your" Yun Hee?
Since yesterday, She and I love each other,
So she wants to quit going to the Kingdom,
Really?
- She says she loves you? - Yes,
She wants to quit the Kingdom?
- Drop the garbage, - Hey,
Do I look like I'm kidding?
No,
The future Prime Minister really likes her,
Replace her with someone who looks like her,
What if things work out and we get married?
Then things could get awkward,
Will you do it?
Get it together,,,
unless you want to get in trouble with him,
- Hello, sir, - Did you see,,,
my hole-in-one golf ball in the Kingdom?
Where is it?
Where am I supposed to find it?
Darn it, Seriously,
Can't he do this himself?
Darn it, He took it with him,
(Babe, When do you want to come over?)
No, It's too dangerous,
I don't know how long I'll have to wait,,,
if I miss this chance,
Should I go with her?
Someone who has been to crime scenes should,,,
That's worse,
You want to trespass and steal as a team?
It isn't trespassing, He invited her over,
We know where the video is,
We can't sit back and do nothing,
What if he catches you leaving with the video?
Can you guarantee nothing will go wrong?
Let's look for another way,
That's right, I thought about it,
and we shouldn't break the law,
Do as she says,
There are plenty of ways,,,
to legally use the government's power,
Like what?
Ways that I know well from experience,
Give me your number,
Text we when you schedule the date to go over,
As I'm sure you could tell,
I work differently from Ms, Min,
I like that,
So? Did you look into it?
Yes, Jin Yun Hee,
Her sister was Jin Sul Hee,
who killed herself in 2004,
Okay,
Send me the documents and photos,
(Family Registry: Jin Yun Hee)
(Sibling: Jin Sul Hee, deceased)
A rat sneaked in,
I'm sorry, sir, I'll take care of it,
No,
Even if she has guts of steel,
she wouldn't have come if she were working alone,
I'm sure there's someone behind her,
Find out who that is first,
Yes, sir,
- What? - How did it go?
Did you find a replacement?
Darn it, Seriously,
You ignored everything I said, didn't you?
Get my Yun Hee out quickly,
What's your problem?
Stop overreacting, you punk, She,,,
Anyway, she doesn't really like you,
How do you know that? Did you meet her?
She's so apologetic to me about what she has to do!
I really want things to work out with her,
Hey! You're my friend, aren't you?
Can't you do this much for me?
You frustrating moron,
Did he hang up on me?
I'm losing my mind, Darn it,
I hear you're seeing Dong Shik,
I am,
He's going crazy about how much he loves you,
What about you?
Well,,,
Stop coming here,
What?
You can stop servicing the elders,
Why?
Did I do something wrong?
That's not it,
Seriously,
Dong Shik, that punk,
keeps begging me to get you out,
You must feel weird doing this while seeing him too,
Ignore what Dong Shik says,
It's okay,
To be honest, we're not that far along yet,
I want,,,
to continue working at the Kingdom,
It suits my personality,
I like it,
Do you mean it?
Yes, I have no intention of quitting,
Fine, Okay,
You may go,
Okay,
Did you hear that?
Love? As if,
She's using you, Wake up, punk,
Baek Min Ho, come out,
Don't tell me you think there's hope, do you?
Don't say anything stupid,
and just stay quiet,,,
if you want to stay alive,
Okay?
Go,
I'll tell you everything,
If I'll die whether or not I talk,
I should talk,
I won't be the only one suffering any longer,
The location where Kong Soo Ah was attacked,
It was not in an ordinary hotel room,
It was in the Kingdom,
It's in Hyungjae Hotel, on the K floor,
Kingdom?
A secret lobbying place that Cho Gap Soo created,
That was where the video of Kong Soo Ah,,,
was filmed too,
You're sure Choi Yong Woon isn't coming home today?
(Yong Woon is going away for work, Come over,)
Okay,
- What is all of this? - I told you,
It's a way to legally use the government's power,
Awesome,
First,
leave them in the bathroom,
And make sure to put one in Choi Yong Woon's room,
Okay,
I'll call it in after 10 minutes,
Once they're in place, get out of there,
I'll say he secretly videoed women,,,
and have the cops search his place,
Okay,
- I'm here, - Hey, Come in,
Thank you,
May I use the bathroom?
- Sure, That way, - Thanks,
Ms, Min,
I'll find the video,
I'm with Yi Deum,
- Dong Shik, - Yes?
I'm hungry, Will you make me instant noodles?
Were you hungry?
I'll cook it right away,
Thanks,
What are you doing?
What?
Bathroom,
But,,,
you just went to the bathroom,
I looked into Jin Yun Hee,
It looks like Min Ji Sook,,,
and Ma Yi Deum are working with her,
Ma Yi Deum?
(Ma Yi Deum, prosecutor)
Hey,
Did you think I was an idiot?
Dong Shik,
Yi Deum!
Shoot,
They walked in on their own,
so cut off their feet,
Put a weapon on them after you kill them,
Then you can say it was self defense,
No one can complain,
Ms, Min, I'll find the video,
I'm with Yi Deum,
The phone has been turned off,
Ms, Min,
Hyungjae Hotel has a secret,,,
Wait, Just a second,
I think something happened to Ma,
I'll go,
The phone has been turned off, Please,,,
Did you approach me intentionally that night?
They're psychotic,
Step aside,
Hey,
Why did you come here?
What were you looking for?
You have the video, right?
Hand it over,
Video?
The one you threatened Cho Gap Soo with,
Hand it over,
It'll be better for you,,,
to hand it over while I'm being nice,
How are you so confident?
You should worry about yourself,
Do you think,,,
you guys will walk out of here alive?
What? Did you think we'd tremble in fear?
Hey, I was a prosecutor for seven years,
I've seen countless punks like you,
You don't scare me,
You should cooperate before the cops come,
I called them before I came here,
You did?
What a little,,,
You'll rot in jail if you keep refusing,
See? See? Police! Help!
Over here! Here!
- Help! - The police are here,
Make them go away,
Is anyone home?
Excuse us,
We received a call,
Does either of your number end in 7451?
I called it in, actually,
I'm sorry,
It was a prank call,
What?
He and I were fooling around,
and I called as a prank,
I didn't think you'd really come,
I'm sorry,
You should know better, You shouldn't do this,
Because of pranks by people like you,
those who really need help,,,
lose their chance to get help, Do you understand?
Yes, sir,
I'm sorry,
Don't do this again,
Wait,
I'm sorry for wasting your time,
It'll never happen again,
Have a good night,
- Please be careful, - Yes, sir,
Get inside,
Just a minute,
- I'm a prosecutor, - Yes, sir,
- We must search there, - Pardon?
An abducted woman is in there, Please hurry,
- Abducted? - Yes, sir,
Come in,
Let go!
- Darn it, - Yi Deum,
- Let go! - Yi Deum!
Let go of me, Let go,
- Ms, Ma, - Choi Yong Woon,
Get Choi Yong Woon first, He has the video,
Hurry,
Darn it,
Sorry, I didn't think it through,
Shoot, Seriously,
Hold on,
What about the video? Is it in there?
Ms, Ma,
Why are you so reckless?
What if something worse had happened?
You should've told me at least!
Why are you getting so angry?
I'm sorry,
I was wrong, I mean it,
That's why I came like this,
Worry about yourself, Look, You're hurt,
It hurts, right?
Are you okay?
It hurts,
Seriously,
(Attorney at Law, Min Ji Sook)
(Seoul Central District Prosecutors' Office)
The defendant insisted,,,
that Baek Min Ho murdered Kong Soo Ah,
and submitted a glove,,,
with Baek Min Ho's blood as evidence,
Jung Young Ho of NFS, who analyzed the blood,
submitted this written statement,
He states that no such evidence existed,
and that he forged it per Ahn Tae Kyoo's request,
It proves he concealed his own crime,,,
and that he was the real murderer,
Defense, Do you have anything to say?
I'd like to submit,,,
Lee Sang Joon's letter of resignation from NFS,
Why are you submitting this?
He was the NFS technician who analyzed the glove,,,
the prosecution submitted into evidence,
He was fired for embezzlement,
If we accept the assertion that the glove evidence,,,
was forged as per Ahn Tae Kyoo's orders,
we must also question,,,
the glove the prosecution submitted,
(Letter of Resignation)
Both pieces of evidence the parties submitted,,,
lack credibility, and thus,
we will exclude both from consideration,
Prosecution,
Do you have any other evidence?
The trial is over,
Let's go,
Your Honor,
I'm the defendant Baek Min Ho's new counsel,
Ma Yi Deum,
(Witch's Court)
I submit a video of Ahn Tae Kyoo assaulting,,,
the victim into evidence,
We need to silence the prosecutor first,
He caught us off guard,
Three months of suspension?
We decided to go to Bujin,
Is this for me, Mom?
Something necessitating a special investigation,
We need Baek Sang Ho's journal then,
This calls for a fatal blow,
Evidence regarding Baek Sang Ho's suicide?
Team up with us,
Let's catch Cho Gap Soo,