Just fire me instead!
If you really want to fire someone
that badly, start with me!
Nam Jung Gi...
you really want me to do it?
Just kill me instead!
[Episode 12]
Fine! If you really want it, I--
you think I can't fire you?
You just asked me to, didn't you?
You insolent punk... and after how
I doted on you so much, all this time!
Geez.
So why the hell did you
all receive bribes?
At the very least, you shouldn't have
gotten caught if you did, you punks!
What is it that you
really want to protect?
Do you still, by any chance
believe that there's something more
important in this world than money?
There was once a time
when you believed that, too.
And you saw the value of things
like happiness, pride, and love.
And in that state, you were dazzling
enough even though you had nothing.
And now I've come to realize that
those things are all useless.
So? Is your present self even happy?
Aw, are you worried about me?
I want you to be happy. I felt this way
before, and I still truly do. Trust me.
Sorry, but I don't believe in the
trust that humans have to offer.
You can easily buy that
from people with money.
And it's a fickle thing.
At the very least,
money doesn't lie.
From now on, pick up
my calls immediately.
When I tell you to come, come.
And when I tell you to go, go.
Be meek and do as I tell you,
like you did before.
Then maybe, just maybe,
you can protect those people.
Though I'm not sure they're
worth protecting.
What's going to happen to us now?
You saw how the President was
acting toward Deputy Chief Nam, right?
Yeah. He was being real stubborn.
But why, exactly, is
he trying to fire people?
I think that I'm probably going
to be the first one to be fired.
I'm a temp worker, and I
sold Lovely out last time.
No, that's not true. Chief Ok is
covering that up, remember?
Just trust in her, okay?
And you're the only designer
on the Marketing Team.
It's not like they're going
to fire the only designer.
Really? Will I really be okay?
I'm the one who should be worried!
I left work early and was late
because of my kid last time.
The President yelled at me about that.
But you're in charge
of our online store.
There's so much work to be
done for that right now.
There's no way they'd fire you over
being late a couple of times.
- Don't worry.
- Yes.
You were one of the founding members
of this company, with the President.
Right? I'll be okay, right?
And we can't develop new products
without Deputy Chief Nam
so it won't be him.
Then...
No way... will it be me?
Well, yeah. I don't specialize in one
thing and just do a little of everything.
- I'm sure I'd be the first to go.
- Hey! That's not true!
There's so many things that you do!
Don't you worry.
You're Deputy Chief Nam's
right-hand man!
I'm sure that Deputy Chief Nam
will protect you, for sure.
We're the team that developed Pat Pat,
so why do we have to go through this?
I know, right? Exactly!
This is driving me crazy!
Hey, we've been outside
for too long. Let's go!
Do those people even value you?
What do you mean by that?
If you were to tell those people to pick
between you and money right now
which one would they choose, I wonder?
- Want to bet on it?
- Crazy bastard.
If those people do choose you,
I promise to get out of your hair.
I'll leave you and Lovely alone,
forever.
- Are you that confident?
- It's money, after all.
I've never met a person
who said that they hate money.
Oh, Chief! Did you just
get back from someplace?
I had a personal affair to attend to.
It's utter chaos here right now. Do you
think you could convince the President...
Do you like money,
Deputy Chief Nam?
Excuse me?
Well, who in the world would
say that they hate money?
Would you want to quit working at
this kind of place if you had money?
Well, I can't make a
statement like that, but--
Having to endure the haughtiness of
superiors, and having to grovel...
isn't it true that you wouldn't have to
endure these things if you had money?
Um, why are you asking this
sort of thing, all of the sudden?
- Chief.
- I was just curious.
I wanted to know what
this place means to you
and whether or not it was worth
more than just money to you.
Well, whatever.
Where have all of you been?
You should be at your
desks more at times like this.
We felt too uneasy to sit still,
so we went out for some fresh air.
Oh, the Chief is here!
- Did you try talking to her?
- Huh? Yeah.
- I did, but...
- What did she say?
Does she have a countermeasure planned?
- She asked me, "do you like money?"
- Huh?
That's all she said before
going back into her office.
- What the hell does that mean?
- Exactly. I have no idea.
Oh, how nice.
You're worried about a
lot of things as of late, right?
It's not easy to do restructuring.
Well, nothing lasts forever.
Isn't that right?
Of course! You can cut
out needless expenses
and your product will sell
well as long as it gets produced
and it's only a matter of time before
you find replacements for them, anyway.
I have tons of people working for me who
do nothing but collect their paychecks.
And it really pisses me off, it does!
You've made a courageous decision.
Let's clap for him together!
- All right! Claps!
- Claps!
Geez, you people.
If everything goes well this time around
I'll help you out, so don't worry.
I heard you found an investor.
Couldn't you maybe introduce me to him?
- Can I get in on that, too?
- And you can't leave me out!
Well, CEO Lee is quite
a busy person, you see.
I'll try talking to him about it
after the restructuring is over.
- Wow... you're our savior!
- I thought Director Kim was.
As if! How could I compare you
to that Director Kim?
Of course! You're obviously the best!
- Yes, of course!
- Obviously!
Did you call for me, sir?
- Yeah, come on in.
- Yes, sir?
I have something that I need
to ask of you this time.
Yes, sir? Just say the word!
Hand in your resignation letter.
Excuse me?
Resignation... letter?
Yeah, a resignation letter.
Can you do that for me?
Please forgive me just this once, sir!
If there's something that I did wrong
I'll take responsibility for it!
If there's something you don't like
about me, just say the word!
Please, just let me go
this once, sir!
I'm telling you, Manager Yang
is such a dramatic person!
Excuse me?
The thing is,
someone came to scout you out.
I've heard a lot about you
from Director Kim.
I heard that you're quite
a skilled individual.
That's why I wanted to ask you to do
some freelance work for me.
This is the down payment I'd give you,
regardless of how long the project takes.
One? Do you mean 1,000...
Think bigger, my friend.
I'm talking about 100 million won.
Just finish up this one project well
and come back to me.
If you do, I'll make sure you can
come back to your original position.
You have confidence that
you'll do well, right?
Thank you, sir!
Why are you thanking me?
You should be thanking CEO Lee.
Thank you, CEO Lee!
I'll do my best!
All I did was write a number, and
I've got him bowing down like this.
You can't even catch that?
Seriously?
- That's right!
- Honey.
- Should I just quit and be a housewife?
- I mean...
it's getting harder and
harder for your mother
and Ji Ho will be starting school soon.
I feel like I'll have to help him
with his studies a bit.
What nonsense is that?
In difficult times such as this -- yes!
Geez! Anyway, in these times, it
won't work if I'm the only breadwinner.
Right?
It won't work, right?
- That's right! Yeah!
- Lower the volume!
Have you been eating well?
Is there anything going on at work?
Of course not.
Everything's fine.
- Mom, you're not sick or in pain, right?
- No, I'm totally fine!
Make sure you're obedient
to your superiors
and serve your President well, okay?
And make sure you get
promoted this year, for sure!
Of course I will.
Don't worry, Mom.
I'll talk to you later.
How will I make a living
if I do get fired?
Do you like money,
Deputy Chief Nam?
Would you want to quit working at
this kind of place if you had money?
Having to endure the haughtiness of
superiors, and having to grovel...
isn't it true that you wouldn't have to
endure these things if you had money?
What could it be?
Why did she ask me that?
Oh, this is so frustrating!
Oh, good work.
Go on home and rest now.
Please reconsider, President.
With the opening of the duty-free shop
and getting onto the e-commerce site
there are so many things
that need to be done.
We should be looking to hire more people,
so doing this now makes no sense!
The decision has already been made,
so don't argue and just do as I say!
Who did you make the decision with,
without the consent of the employees?
Wasn't it with that man, Lee Ji Sang?
You said that you'd take care of it,
and wouldn't give him executive power.
Has that person already begun
to become involved with management?
Who's involved with management, now?
I'm still the President, you know!
I told you, didn't I?
All he cares about is his own profits.
He doesn't care if the company fails!
He's an investor who will be of
no help to helping the company grow!
I'll be the judge of that! Stop being so
over-involved in all company affairs
and just work hard on the work
that you're responsible for!
I'm the president of this company!
I am!
You know, the world is actually
quite a simple place.
People who've had a taste of money
can't ever go back.
You'll need to realize
that soon, Da Jung.
Hey, there's really nobody
who's suitable?
- No.
- See?
I told you that you should've
taken more drastic measures.
If you just leave them, they're
going to try and endure until the end!
Don't you know how tenacious
those people are?
- What should I do?
- It's obvious.
Make them want to
quit of their own volition.
So, how, exactly?
Just leave that to me.
I'll do all the dirty work.
So you just worry about
getting the investment funds.
Ms. Jang Mi Ri. Did you
buy the tissues on your desk?
No, they were here.
I see.
"Egotistical."
These are meant to be used by everyone,
so why are you hogging them to yourself?
Those tissues are expensive ones,
you know. Use them in moderation.
- What the hell?
- Deputy Han.
How many cups of coffee
have you had today?
- It's my third. Why?
- "Addicted to caffeine."
All that is coming out of company
funds, so drink in moderation.
Why are you pissing me off?
It's not like a cup costs that much.
Manager Shin, what are you doing?
You're on the internet when
you're supposed to be working.
Are you writing comments
online or something?
It's a beauty community site.
I'm working right now!
"Addicted to using the internet."
Hey, punk!
I feel like you smoke longer
than you actually work here!
- "Nicotine addition."
- What?
Doing other things during working
hours will add up against you, too!
- Got that?
- What the hell are you doing?
Let go! I'm doing worker
assessments, obviously!
I'm going to be using this to take into
consideration during restructuring
so just be aware of that.
- How ridiculous.
- Why don't you just put a CCTV here
- and "Big Brother" us?
- Oh, great idea.
I'll be sure to do that for you. CCTVs.
- What did you say?
- Manager Shin. See me.
Sure!
Why is the President acting that way?
I'm sure you know something about it!
Deputy Chief Nam. Are you aware
of the fact we have an investor?
An investor?
That guy is giving our company a
ridiculous amount of money right now.
And it's all thanks to that that we can
have ads everywhere for our new product!
So, that investor told him to do this?
To fire all the employees?
He said that he'd give us
even more money
if we decrease our expenses
and trim down our staff a bit
so it's not an offer that the
President can exactly ignore.
So you all are trying to kick out
employees just for some more money?
- How could you do this to us?
- Geez! You really are an idiot.
You know,
Deputy Chief Nam...
it's best to take cover and
do nothing during a typhoon.
If you try to fight back, you
might be blown away. Got that?
At times like this, we must
stick together, we can't wuss out.
Obviously. We can't just act alone to
try and be the only one to survive.
- Got that, everyone?
- Yes, ma'am!
We'll only survive if we stick together!
If we split apart, we'll all die!
You like sugar in yours, right?
Why are you acting like this
all of a sudden? You're scaring me.
Um, sorry about before.
I was just a bit alarmed, is all.
My voice got louder
without me realizing it.
I'm planning on quitting drinking coffee
now. Um, what do you like?
I have a coupon for a family restaurant.
Ew, no thanks.
- What are you doing?
- You have a lot on your plate now
- so you're quite fatigued, right?
- So?
Let's drink together sometime.
I'll pay for it.
You want to buy me dinner and drinks.
Why is everyone like this lately?
- Wasn't I originally an outcast?
- Oh, of course not!
Who'd make you into an outcast?
Hey, no. You're all being
way too obvious. Lay off.
Geez, I ought to...
Goodbye, sir!
Let's show him our strength!
Let's present the issue to him
and don't any of you dare hand
in a letter of resignation. Okay?
Obviously. Let's endure
for as long as we can!
Let's not render ourselves into
pathetic people! We can do it!
I know that both of you are
trying to butter Manager Shin up!
What am I supposed to do?
You people are too much.
At first it felt like everyone was
helping and cooperating with one another
but it didn't take long for everyone to
try and find their own way out.
Could I say with confidence
that I'm not the same?
Does this make sense?
I have to curry his favor to survive?
Who? You're not talking about
that damn Manager Shin, are you?
Yeah! He's the one doing our
performance reports right now!
He hates me because of
what happened last time!
I'd rather die than try to
curry that damn man's favor!
I think I'm going to be fired,
no matter how I think about it!
What kind of criteria is that
for restructuring?
- Wow, that really sucks.
- I know, right?
So can you talk to your
Big Sis about this for me?
And tell her to please
help me to not get fired.
- Huh?
- I hate Manager Shin
and I have nobody
that I can rely on at work!
So please, put in a
good word for me! Okay?
Okay. Well. Yeah, sure.
I'll try asking her
to protect our Mi Ri!
- Don't worry.
- Bong Gi!
Thanks, Bong Gi!
- I'm sure it'll all be fine!
What is it that you
wanted to talk about?
I thought of a way for us to fight
against the restructuring with our power.
How about we all agree
to take a pay cut, instead?
For now, we can return
our bonuses
and try to help the company in
any way we can. And if we do that--
It's not like the company
is in dire straits
so why do you want to
collect less severance?
They need to decrease spending
because that's what the investor wants.
And it's better for all of us to survive
than for someone to get fired.
- We can't do that.
- And why not?
I thought that the company was
in an emergency situation.
We'll all take pay cuts and
decrease our expenses!
It's not like the company will fail
if they don't get the investment
so why are you offering to
take a pay cut?
But even so, I can't just sit
and watch someone get fired.
Just look at what Manager Shin is doing!
Is that really fair judgment?
What does coffee drinking and talking on
the phone have to do with performance?
It's not fair, nor is it unbiased.
Then, you do it.
What?
Do a fair and unbiased
review of the employees.
- Um, I--
- You know our team the best.
Analyze their performance
in an unbiased way
and submit that to be considered
for the restructuring process.
- But Chief, I'm really--
- Do it.
Wouldn't it be fairer to leave it to you
rather than to someone like Manager Shin?
And so, you want me to do it?
Damn it!
Don't worry too much.
Just trust me. Okay?
Thanks, Bong Gi.
- Oh, it's here.
- I'll be going, then.
Be careful on your way home!
Restructuring, huh?
What to do?
I'm worried about Mi Ri,
but about Jung Gi, too.
- Mr. Nam Bong Gi!
- Yes?
Your name is Nam Bong Gi, right?
And it's not Ok Bong Gi.
How dare you!
What?
I don't know if they changed the
passcode, but the door won't open.
And they won't pick
up the phone, either.
And I was waiting and waiting,
and it got so late.
Oh, but it's been so long
since you first got here!
You were standing there all this time?
I don't really want to take these back
with me, so can I leave these with you
for you to give to my
kids when they get back?
Oh, of course!
No problem, here!
I'll store them in the refrigerator
and give this to them.
- Which suite do they live in, again?
- 1301. I'll leave it to you, then!
- Yes, of course.
- Thank you!
Geez, looks like the kids
changed the passcode
because they considered her a nuisance.
They don't even know how
their parent feels. Sheesh.
You're done with work already?
Hey! Son! Jung Gi!
What's wrong with him?
You do it.
Wouldn't it be fairer to leave it to you
rather than someone like Manager Shin?
Maybe something happened
at work again? Sheesh.
And why are you walking around
with those on at nighttime?
Hey, punk!
Hey, Bong Gi!
I held back all this time
because of Deputy Chief Nam
but I can't anymore.
Stop lying about your identity and
toying with Jang Mi Ri, right now!
Or else I'll really let you have it!
Got that?
And why's he so down?
I guess he failed another audition.
Damn it, what do I do?
I'm going to go insane!
What do I do?
What are all of you hiding?
You know, I was taking a look, and
you score the lowest in diligence.
What?
Why me?
You arrive late and leave early.
Well, that couldn't be helped
because of my child.
But in exchange, I've been putting in
extra hours and got all my work done.
Well, documentation doesn't lie.
I'm just telling you the truth as it is.
Also, you should re-use paper cups.
How can a company stay afloat
with people wasting cups like that?
You sure don't value the
company's assets at all, do you?
Work, punk. What the hell
are you looking at?
What? So I'm the one
who's been targeted?
- Hey, Deputy Chief Nam!
- Yes, President?
I heard from Chief Ok that you didn't
like Manager Shin's method of assessment
- and complained about it.
- What?
- Well, yes, I did.
- Therefore...
you said that you wanted to do a fair
assessment yourself. Is that right?
What? I, um...
that's not what I said...
I believe that it is your rightful duty
as the Deputy Chief of our department.
But, um, I don't have
the right to judge anyone.
The lives of the Marketing Team
members are on the line here
but you want to pass over this duty
to the General Affairs Manager?
- Is that what you're saying?
- I mean, no, not exactly--
Sheesh! All right, give it a shot, then.
Do the performance reviews
and report back to me. That's all.
President!
- Chief!
- He outranks me, I can't do anything.
Chief!
Wow! So our lives depend
on Deputy Chief Nam now?
But even so, he'll be fairer
than Manager Shin.
President.
President!
I can't do it! How could I fire
someone from our team?
It's my decision,
so why can't you do it?
- Do it!
- Don't be like that, sir.
Please reconsider! Who are the people
who made the company what it is now?
It's all the employees here!
So how could you possibly
think about firing them, overnight?
What? Who made the
company what it is now?
- All the employees of Lovely!
- Hey!
How dare you spout such nonsense?
Who's the one who went crawling around
for funds so I could pay all of you?
Do you people know how I feel?
Do you? Huh?
I begged and pleaded so much to
bring us to where we are!
But what? You people made
the company what it is?
Hey. I'm the one who made this
company what it is now!
Lovely is mine!
I thought I could finally take a break
and then you all betray me like this?
- President!
- Shut it.
Bring me the results by
the end of this week.
And if you can't,
I'll fire you instead.
- President!
- Got it? Now get out! Get out!
This can't happen. I still have a lot
more payments left on my apartment
and Ji Ho's cram school fees when
he starts school will be no joke!
I really can't get fired. Can't like,
someone else volunteer instead of me?
But even so, you have a
husband and your own place.
For me, it'll be the end
if I don't make any money.
Where could I go after being fired from
here after just being a temp worker?
House? As if! Except the veranda, the
entire apartment belongs to the bank!
But even so,
I can work nights
and even work weekends
when they call me out.
But it's hard for you to do
that because of your child.
Hey, are you two trying
to survive on your own?
You're saying that all you need
to do is kick me out, right?
Wow, I didn't know you two
were going to be like this.
Deputy Chief Nam.
Take this.
All right. Your lives are
in his hands now
so you don't need to hate me anymore!
So you're really going to do it?
You're not on the President's
side too, are you?
Whatever. I'm not submitting a
letter of resignation, no matter what!
Fire me if you want!
Whatever!
What a shitty company.
What do we do now?
That's why I asked Bong Gi for a favor
to put in a good word for me.
Try asking him too! We have to try and
get any advantage we can right now!
You still haven't gotten a call from
that bastard Nam Bong Gi?
What?
What do you mean, Nam Bong Gi?
Deputy Chief Nam.
I have something to talk to you about.
Um, Deputy Park. I'm not really in
the state to be talking right now.
If it's not urgent, let's talk later.
Before you worry about who to fire,
why not manage your brother better?
What are you talking about?
You didn't know that he lied
about being Chief Ok's little brother
and toyed with Ms. Mi Ri?
He even lied to her, saying that he'd
make sure she wouldn't get fired.
- What?
- What kind of situation is this?
I mean, everyone is on edge already
because nobody knows who'll be fired.
Even if you can chalk it up
to immaturity
he shouldn't have lied about that!
Um, is that true?
That punk really did that?
Why don't you ask him yourself?
So his name isn't Ok Bong Gi?
- Ms. Mi Ri.
- So what you're saying is...
Bong Gi is actually
your younger brother?
I'm so sorry. This is all my fault!
It's all because of me!
I'm so sorry, Ms. Mi Ri.
How could you-- I didn't know
you were this type of person!
He was toying with your subordinate,
pretending to be someone else...
you knew that, and yet you did nothing?
- No, it's not like that!
- I'm so disappointed in you!
This bastard!
- Oh, Dad! You're just getting home?
- Yeah, you're home a bit late.
Nam Woo Joo, go to your room
and listen to some music.
Uncle, you caused trouble again,
didn't you?
- Huh? No.
- Nam Woo Joo. Now!
Yes, sir.
Why do you live your life like that?
What are you saying?
What's wrong with my lifestyle?
How could you pretend that
you were Chief Ok's little brother?
Hear me out first, Big Bro.
It's not that I deliberately did that.
They misunderstood and thought
that I was her younger brother first!
All I said was that I was close
to someone at Lovely Cosmetics--
- You terrible bastard.
- Big Bro!
All you do is drink all night
when you're unemployed
and you have no source of income,
but use all the money you want.
You make a big deal out of yourself
and think of life to be easy
and now, you're even lying
about your identity?
And this kind of scum
is my little brother?
- Are you finished?
- You think life is a joke, right?
It's totally fun, right?
Meanwhile, do you know what kids your
age go through to just try and survive?
I do! I'm right beside them, watching.
Who else puts their all into
surviving as you do, after all?
You wake up early in the morning
and work until late at night.
You have to go back to work, too, at
night or on weekends when they need you.
You can barely get a proper
glimpse of your only son's face
and do everything at work,
besides eating and sleeping.
But here you are, worried
that you'll be fired in your forties
because of internal restructuring.
Is that really the right way
to live your life?
- You little--
- I work hard, too!
It's hard for me, too! I'm just living
my life a bit differently than others.
So, Big Bro...
don't worry about me.
Yeah. Who am I to judge
how someone else lives?
I gave my youth to this company
and yet I'm worried about getting fired.
And I'm here wondering if I should
fire someone so I can survive.
Who am I to judge?
Jang Mi Ri.
- Mi Ri.
- Terrible bastard.
- Who is it?
- Oh, hello.
So you are home today. I rang a couple
of times, but nobody was here.
Oh... Woo Joo's grandfather.
What brings you here?
Your mother left this with
me yesterday. Here you go.
Damn it, I told her not
to bring stuff like this.
- You have it.
- Why would I do that?
Your mother-in-law made this for you
and your husband with love and care!
Well, as you can see, we always come
home late, and we always eat bread
for breakfast, so we don't
need side dishes.
Also, nobody eats them.
We'll end up throwing them
out when they go bad anyway.
But even so, you can't
just throw food away!
Then you eat it!
Or throw it away!
Um, excuse me!
Ji Hoon's mother!
Oh, geez. I can't just throw
precious food away.
I'm sure she'd be quite upset if
she knew her children act this way.
Geez, this makes me so worried.
Oh, Ms. Mi Ri. I called because
I was worried about you.
- Are you sick?
- I'm just whatever.
I feel humiliated that I
fell for his act like an idiot
so I don't want to come to work.
But still, you can't miss work
at a time like this.
Well, isn't this good for you?
You can use this in your
employee performance reports.
The younger brother lied to me,
and the older brother will fire me...
how charming.
Deputy Chief Nam, I printed out the
sales report for the 99 lipsticks.
- Good work, Deputy Han.
- Make sure you note the online event.
- What?
- Write that I'm responsible
for the sales going up. I'm responsible
for at least half our figures!
Of course, Deputy Han. Of course
I'll acknowledge your efforts.
Please cut me some slack,
Deputy Chief Nam.
Sure. Got it.
You know that yesterday was just because
of your younger brother and that
I actually really like and
respect you, right?
Everyone is desperate.
And I don't have the right to judge
them based on their desperation.
No, nobody in the world can truly judge
the worth of another human being.
[Employee Assessments]
I wonder how many points
I'm worth, as a person?
I want to have courage,
even though I'm so terrified
so that I don't become
the absolute lowest of the low.
Here you are.
This is my performance report.
Please sign off on it.
- Is it really this person?
- Yes.
- You're not going to regret this?
- I... will not.
Honestly, I don't have the
confidence that I won't regret it.
But even so, I'm not ashamed of my life.
I'm satisfied with just that.
[Document to be Approved:
To be fired: Nam Jung Gi]
Want a shot?
- Um, you know--
- You'll have to give me allowance now.
I handed in my letter
of resignation today.
[People to be fired:
Han Young Mi]
What?
What's going on?
No way. This really isn't right.
What happened, Deputy Chief Nam?
There's no way this could be.
I didn't write your name there!
I really believed in you.
Wow. This is too much.
You want me to leave?
Why? Why me?
Why me? What did I do so wrong?
All I did was work hard!
Think long and hard about it while we're
offering you a year's worth of pay.
Why is it Deputy Han Young Mi?
I definitely wrote my own name down!
Really? The paperwork that Chief Ok
gave me said "Deputy Han."
- What happened?
- Talk to Chief Ok about it.
- Leave.
- And also!
You can't fire Deputy Han.
Deputy Han... no, Young Mi has been with
us since our first factory was built!
We were even with her as she had Ji Ho
and went to his first birthday party!
President! You really can't do this!
But how long can I keep letting her
slide because of those things?
We're in a pinch, so we have
to do what we have to do.
I'm not running a charity here.
A charity? Then what does
that make our employees?
We've never even
demanded overtime from you!
Do you think that we're volunteers?
What did you say?
When your mother passed away
a couple of years ago
Deputy Han took care of your
funeral guests for three whole days
without getting a single penny!
Well, that's that and this is this!
Stop trying to twist things
around like that!
President, you really can't do this!
This is too inhumane!
We've been comrades from the very start!
Shut it already! How dare you talk
back to me? You're only a deputy chief!
From now on, relay all your
messages to me through Chief Ok.
You know, companies
need order and hierarchies!
Otherwise it would be pandemonium.
Damn it!
- I chose Deputy Han.
- Why did you do that?
I told you, I'll leave!
I'll take responsibility!
- And why are you doing that?
- Because I'm the highest-up.
I took a bribe from
another company, too.
You're not the only one
who took it, though.
At any rate, I said I'd
take responsibility
so why did you change it
as you pleased?
Deputy Chief Nam!
You're the Deputy Chief.
How are you going to
raise Woo Joo if you quit?
What about your father?
And your younger brother?
What about your family,
who depends on you?
Will it really be okay if you leave?
No, it won't be. Still, there isn't
a person who'd be okay if they left!
It's true that I won't be okay, but
the others won't be okay, either!
There isn't a single person
that is okay to just fire!
You know, I really thought about what
I did so wrong to be targeted and fired
but I did think of something
that I did wrong.
Never talking back or complaining
and doing what I was told to do.
Having the best interest of the company
at heart and never using vacation days.
And giving up my paid-for vacation
for my 10-year anniversary here to work.
And all that has led me to this.
On the other hand, someone else is
a sexual harasser and is still here.
Listen, Deputy Han. I'm a part
of the company's royal family.
You should have a conscience. How could
you think to drag me down with you?
Deputy Han. I'm so sorry
for being so powerless.
I'm so, so sorry.
I had to work without
talking back even once.
And I still can't say anything
even as I leave. How cruel, really.
Here's a gift.
I'll be going, then.
A company that just casts aside someone
who'd been a comrade just yesterday.
And me, who can
only stand and watch
as my comrade is taken from
us due to the power of money.
Is it really right to
live my life like this?
How can you just quit
without any notice?
I mean, I just wanted to
take better care of Ji Ho...
Why do you need to worry
about that, when I'm around?
Are you doing this because I complained
a few times about watching him?
- No, it's not that.
- Oh, whatever.
Go back to your company and
take back your resignation letter.
- How am I supposed to do that?
- We have so many expenses right now.
Do you think things will be okay with me
being the only one earning money?
Yes, child. How could he
manage that on his own?
Don't worry about Ji Ho, and
take back your resignation letter.
Um, Mother, can't I take some time off?
I've been working since I graduated
college, and I'm so worn out.
You know, I had to start working again
100 days after I gave birth to Ji Ho.
I'm so overwhelmed with
issues at home and at work.
I'm going to take some
time off for the time being. Okay?
Honey. You think you're the
only one who wants to relax?
- I want to, too!
- And you do, when you get home!
You take weekends and holidays off.
But this is my second job!
Do you know that?
Wow, someone would think
that all I do is boss you around!
Hey, you have to earn as much as
you can while you're still young!
Geez, seriously.
She has no conscience.
Are you trying to put him through
more than you already have?
Oh, I'm oh-so sorry
for being a terrible daughter-in-law
who just makes your son suffer.
But you know, I can't just take
back my resignation letter. I got fired.
- What?
- I got fired.
I was one of the people they
fired during the restructuring.
- Oh my.
- I held on for as long as I could.
So let me just breathe
a little now, okay?
Who is it?
Manager Yang!
Oh, I was wondering what I'd do
if I couldn't see you before I left.
Why did you submit your
resignation letter all of a sudden?
I suffered because I trusted you when
you said not to trust Director Kim
and I ended up getting stabbed
in the back for that in the end.
I don't have any residual
feelings here anymore.
Oh, really? Where are you going, then?
Well, I don't want to tell you just yet.
But I'll give you a call
when I get settled over there.
Goodbye.
He doesn't look like someone
who just got backstabbed, though.
Thank you.
Thank you!
Wow, so fast!
Thank you, CEO Lee!
All right.
It's your turn this time.
[Contract to be on Executive Board]
I finally feel like our company
is making its mark!
It's truly an honor
to be able to serve you.
Please take care of me, President Jo.
Hello, Deputy Chief Nam.
What great weather we're having.
It seems like it's getting warmer soon.
Oh, want me to make you some
iced coffee to cool you down?
- Sure, Ms. Mi Ri.
- What about you, Deputy Park?
- Sure.
- What about you, Deputy Han--
The space that we cut away
in order for us to survive
left a more deep, residual
pain that we'd expected.
But we had to bury that pain in our
hearts and live with what we did.
Yes, I sent the estimate via email.
Please check it.
As for the meeting, shall we plan it
for three days from today?
Yes. Yes, I understand.
Um, Deputy Han!
Have we grown stronger, or weaker?
Mi Ri, Mi Ri, Jang Mi Ri, I'm so sorry.
What I did was terrible.
I'm so sorry, Ms. Mi Ri.
I'm sorry.
Mi Ri, Mi Ri, Jang Mi Ri.
Hi there.
Ms. Mi Ri!
Wait up!
Bong Gi, Bong Gi, Nam Bong Gi.
Bye.
You were the one who kicked me out,
so why do you want to see me?
I'm sure saying something
like this now is futile, but
the one who gave your name
to the President wasn't me.
At any rate, I'm so sorry that
I couldn't protect you.
I already know that I was
being targeted from the start.
I know it wasn't you who
did that, so don't be sorry.
Geez. It sure is fun to tease you
for the first time in a while.
And having time off isn't
as bad as I thought.
I reflected on why I lived
such a stressful life before
and I can play with my son all I want.
I can even make my husband breakfast.
So don't you live like that. Living
like that isn't all there is to life.
So you're going to take some
time off for the time being?
But even so, I guess I'm not all bad.
I've been getting some offers.
That's great. You are skilled, so you'll
be fine no matter where you go.
- But, um, where is that, exactly?
- Don't worry about it.
It's not a huge place.
It's pretty small.
When's your first day there?
I'm thinking about starting there
after playing for another week.
That's a relief.
Congrats, Deputy Han.
Thanks, Deputy Chief Nam.
Oh yeah. I almost forgot.
I came to bring this to you.
What's this?
Geez, when did you have
the time to set this aside?
Geez, you sure do have a
knack for looking out for others.
- That's all I know how to do, though.
- Don't belittle that.
Don't you know what a
difficult thing that is to do?
Who in their right mind would
submit their own name to be fired?
Are you an idiot?
Be happy no matter where
you go, Deputy Han.
Perhaps what we did was just
to make each other feel relieved
to try and pretend to overcome
this well, by acting like adults.
And that's what we did, but...
Here's the additional
information from the HSN.
Great. What about the preparations to
have our product in the duty-free store?
The interior is all finished, and all we
need to do is set up the displays.
- What about e-commerce?
- Oh, yes.
We've been getting lots of complaints
about the current delivery service
so we're thinking about
switching to another one.
- You take care of that.
- Yes, ma'am.
Hey, do I look okay? Huh?
I look good, right?
Come on, hold it properly!
Yes, like that.
CEO Lee.
Welcome to Lovely.
Let's plan an event for the day
that the duty-free shop opens.
- Yes.
- Yes, ma'am.
Chief Ok. Deputy Chief Nam.
Come out here, everyone.
I have someone
I want to introduce you to.
All right, say hello.
He's an investor of our company
and a head director at our company
starting today: CEO Lee Ji Sang.
Head Director?
Nice to meet you.
I'm Lee Ji Sang.
Nice to meet you,
Chief Ok Da Jung.
Subtitles by DramaFever
[Ms. Temper and Nam Jung Gi]
Manager Shin. Why are there
so many holes in our finances?
The industry term for
this is "embezzlement."
- What? Manager Shin did?
It's really tense up there right now.
I don't want to press criminal
charges, so just retire on your own.
[Vice Chief Yang Joo Ho]
- Oh, hello, everyone!
- Why are you here, Manager Yang?
- I was scouted.
- What?
Send me there, too. I want to reclaim
the life that Ok Da Jung ruined for me.
What are you trying to pull right now?
Who's blabbing so much
so early in the morning?
- Oh, Deputy Han!
- Who are you, lady?
How dare you be so
rude to me, you young'in?
Dad, I want to marry the lady next door!
Dad. Dad! Big Bro!
Are you okay?
- Deputy Chief Nam likes Chief Ok, right?
- About CEO Lee...
I heard that he invested money
here because of Chief Ok!