Subtitles by KBS World
My mom must be very busy.
It's near here, so I'll take you.
Thanks.
By the way, how did you recognize me?
Seonhui sent me your photo once.
Seonhui's a nice person, isn't she?
My mom's always nice.
Was she the same when she was a child?
I'm so curious about her childhood.
She was the same.
She did everything for the younger kids.
She was smart and a good student.
She looked like a spoiled rich kid,
but her actions were the exact opposite.
Just like how she is now.
You really love your mom, don't you?
Because she's my mom.
Right. She's your mom.
Jeongae.
Seonhui.
Did you come to greet me?
How did you know?
Goodbye.
Thank you for bringing me.
Sure.
I really don't know what you're thinking.
If you're going to tell Eunsu...
What are you so afraid about?
Do you know how you look right now?
As if you're afraid of your precious jewel
being taken away or broken.
Eunsu's your daughter.
Just make her your daughter.
She completely believes you're her mom.
So what could I possibly say to her?
I'll have to leave her be.
That's what she wants, so I'll have to let her be.
Don't worry, Seonhui.
What could change?
Nothing.
I'll let you live as you have been.
Happy?
Why did she come looking for me
and make this happen?
She should've let me live in hiding.
What is it, mom?
Well, I...
About earlier.
Yes?
What did you talk about with my friend?
Something you never tell me.
What is it?
What?
She said you looked like a spoiled rich kid
when you were little.
What?
You were a good student and smart, but
your actions were the opposite. Very clumsy.
How come you never changed?
You didn't talk about anything else?
No, we didn't.
Yes, to find out who Jiwan's date is.
I'd have to be like a detective.
Why is everyone so interested in
Jiwan's love life?
Should I come, too?
I couldn't.
No, I won't.
Kang Yeongju, why are you here?
What about you? Why are you here?
I should ask you both the same!
You're tailing Jiwan on your day off,
so how could I stay home?
I'm trying my best to turn this
into an actual date, but you!
You ruined it! You did!
To me this is a valuable experience!
Things like tailing and staking out
can be important experience for my writing.
You're the one who's in my way!
What a funny notion!
You'd go see a ghost to write a horror novel?
Be quiet!
Get out of my way!
Hey!
He really was meeting Ms. Seo?
What kind of co-workers are that close?
Jiwan's really seeing that witch?
Why, I ought to...
- Stay still.
- Why?
Well...
Co-workers could do that for each other.
Of course.
Co-workers can do...
Stuff like that...
Not!
Jiwan! I'm against this flirting!
What are you doing? You want them to see us?
They're co-workers,
so why did they come to a hotel?
I don't know.
It must be about work.
What kind of co-workers
come to a hotel together?
They must be mad! In broad daylight!
Kim Jiwan!
What are you doing here?
Well, I...
I was passing by, and...
I was walking by, and...
This is where the launching show will be?
I thought you were on a date...
You were working.
You were working hard. It's great.
That's a very awkward laugh.
So they are just co-workers.
You can tell your family they are co-workers.
It wasn't Ms. Seo.
They were just working.
They are co-workers.
Nothing more, nothing less.
But I'm never wrong.
How odd.
Really?
They did nothing outside work?
Nothing.
Okay...
No, they're not dating.
They're just co-workers.
Co-workers.
Oh, Eunsu's not answering her phone.
I should call Jiwan, then.
Yes, of course.
Jiwan.
Hi, Yeongju.
Are you with Eunsu right now?
No.
I'm working because of the launching show.
Oh, I see.
When are you going home?
I'm on my way.
I hear the shaved ice at
the cafe you frequent is good.
Yes, their coffee and shaved ice are all good.
I should go there, then.
Okay.
Honey, what should we have for dinner?
Spring vegetables are in season.
Should I make some dishes?
It's okay.
Let's just eat whatever we have.
It's dinner time. Where are you going?
Mom, I'll be right back.
Have dinner without me.
Honey, did you see her?
I did.
Why did she get all dressed up?
I'm suspicious of her.
Maybe she went out to meet a man.
Jiwan.
When did you get here?
Hi, Yeongju.
Were you at a wedding?
What?
I was on my way home...
You're having shaved ice and coffee alone?
What?
I'm not alone.
We're having a launching show
at the Da Vinci Hotel near here.
We've been there to check it out.
I see.
You want to join us?
No, I came in because I saw you.
I should go.
Okay...
Co-workers can have shaved ice together.
It was a hot day today.
But why are they eating at my seat?
Those cookies.
Yes?
Don't ever make them again.
What?
What kind of cookies were they?
They were all broken, sweet and bitter.
How could you be so bad at it?
Don't ever make them again.
You can't bake.
Fine. I'll never make them again.
And don't ever get hurt again.
You've worn this all day, right?
It's time to change it.
What's wrong with you?
You get scratches, fall down or burn yourself.
Stop getting hurt.
It bothers me.
Don't let it bother you.
Then make sure I won't be bothered.
You should be more careful.
I like shaved ice, too.
Yeongju.
Open this door.
Why was your mascara running?
Were you crying?
Leave her alone.
She wants to be alone.
Did she grow up alone?
I raised her when she was growing up,
so why does she want to be left alone now?
Yeongju!
Open this door! Tell me what it is!
Why are you crying?
You want me to die of frustration?
What's going on?
What is it? Tell me so we can resolve it.
What is it?
My foot...
What?
What's wrong with your foot?
I got a blister.
What? Your foot looks fine.
Oh, that looks like it hurts.
Does that happen when you wear heels?
Why didn't you wear your normal shoes?
I knew you were making a mistake.
Why did you do that? Just be yourself.
Right.
I should just be myself...
What are you talking about?
Eunsu framed someone of plagiarism to win?
I don't know why people are saying that.
I think it started at Design.
I've been ignoring it because it's false,
but it's gotten out of control.
Out of control? How?
They're saying Hyeondo's got her back.
That's nonsense.
Hyeondo's the one who
discovered the plagiarism,
and that's probably why people assume that.
People in Design spread that rumor?
Would you like this?
It's okay.
You never say yes to anything I give you.
That girl over there.
They framed the winner for
plagiarism to make her win.
She must know some powerful people.
She's got no experience or a degree.
Everyone thought it was weird.
Really?
Everyone in Design is waiting
for the right moment to get her.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm all right.
I'm sorry.
Oh, no.
Everyone's watching, so just go.
Hyeondo.
Who cares if anyone's watching?
Did you commit a crime?
Why do you care about what others think?
Thank you.
Didn't I tell you to lower
the company logo by 2mm?
You didn't mention the company logo.
You just mentioned the product logo.
If you lower just one logo, it ruins the balance.
Do I have to point out everything?
It's the basics!
I'm sorry. I'll do it again.
You didn't check for typos?
I checked many times. There can't be any...
Pull yourself together!
Don't you dare tell anyone you won the contest
if you're going to do a subpar job.
Get what I tell you done right!
Must I point out every single detail?
Aren't you ashamed of getting paid?
Kim Jiwan!
Come with me.
Let go!
Why did you drag me out from there?
Didn't you hear what she said?
She wasn't wrong.
Being yelled at is a process of learning.
It's not just anyone. It's your little sister.
How can you be neutral about your sister?
How could you do that?
Then, what will you say?
You're going to use your father's position
and threaten Ms. Bae?
Why can't I use my father's position?
Everyone knows I'm the owner's son.
What about Eunsu, then?
You want people to think
she got hired because of you?
But that's not true.
When everyone says it's true, it will seem so
even if it isn't.
Kim Jiwan!
I'm angrier than you!
Don't you know your doing this puts
Eunsu at a more difficult position?
But I can't just sit and watch.
Eunsu will take care of it.
She can take care of it by herself.
Let's not get involved, making it more difficult.
I've seen plenty of kids like you
who get hired using connections.
Do you know how annoying it is to have
the likes of you ruin our reputation?
Get out!
You don't need to work here.
You have great connections. Why work at all?
You'll get paid and get promoted anyway.
I said get out!
Are you deaf?
What are you doing?
Please check these again.
I'll learn and get getter.
I'll work harder to make up
for my shortcomings.
I'll study all night if I don't know something,
so I can catch up very quickly.
But...
Don't insult me for something
that's not work-related.
I won the contest fair and square.
I never relied on anyone to get this job.
Hey!
And...
I checked them dozens of times.
There are no typos.
Please check them again.
I'll check them, and we'll talk again.
You're really worried about Eunsu, aren't you?
It's hard for me to let it go easily,
since she's my little sister and all.
Eunsu's doing a good job.
She's worthy of being your sister.
Thank you.
But I'm worried.
Rumors can be quite vicious.
Rumors are just rumors.
Eunsu will get though it.
Just like you did.
How do you know so well?
I can tell.
You two are very similar.
But...
How did you know I was here?
Are you following me around?
Follow...
Jiwan, shouldn't you get back to work?
It's a personal loan.
You've met this month's quota.
Good job.
Honey.
Honey, I'm home.
What is it?
You're home?
Oh, my, honey, what are you doing?
What's going on?
Take that off right now.
Just sit here. I'm almost done.
Don't come in.
Don't even come near.
I'm going to finish what I started.
Finish what?
He's going to leave me lots of dishes to wash.
What?
Red ginseng?
Happy Marriage Day
Thank you. I'm sorry!
Why couldn't he write a bit more?
One line? That's it?
Oh, there's so much to eat.
Right?
Here.
- Enjoy.
- Okay.
It looks good.
Let me see...
You bought this at the market, right?
And this came from Yeongcheol's Side Dishes.
Hansik's makes better
side dishes than Yeongcheol's.
This was $5, right?
At Hansik's, it's $4.
If you keep doing this,
I won't want to do this for you again.
Oh, really? Why, I'm sorry, honey.
So don't ever do this again, okay?
Okay.
Now that you said that, I know I must.
Honey, what's going on?
Did something nice happen today?
A gift and dinner? What is it?
I can't buy you luxury brand bags anymore,
so I have to look after your health.
If you get sick, I'll be the one who suffers.
Oh, whatever.
When your job gets too hard, you must quit.
Just promise me that.
It's not like you're having it easy.
They must be pressuring you
to meet the quota.
No.
I've already met this month's quota.
I won't have to worry about it for a while.
Really?
Honey, I'm so happy for you!
That's great! I'm so happy for you.
Don't worry.
You two are home already?
Dad, you came home earl...
Please continue.
I'll leave you two alone.
Don't say that.
Come and have dinner.
It looks like I might get a little sibling.
What did she say?
Maybe she feels better now.
She didn't tell you what
the other night was about, did she?
Minja.
Don't worry about your kid tonight
and enjoy your dinner.
Okay, Jaecheol.
You eat, too.
Try them.
Hyeondo, I'm used to drinking soju by itself,
but you're all about style,
so why are you drinking like this?
If your mom sees you,
she'll say it's because you take after me.
Is something bothering you?
Oh, you gave me back my car,
so why would anything bother me?
But if you gave me back my credit card...
Really? I can take your car away again.
You want it?
Really?
Now, I'm sure there's something bothering you.
Have you ever held yourself back for mom?
I do that every day.
Doing nothing for the sake of the other person.
How does that make sense?
I did something for someone,
but it turned out, I did it for myself.
Well...
I'm not sure who the other person is, but
she's amazing for making you think this way.
If it took that much thought to decide,
whatever that is, you're doing it for her.
The girl you're seeing right now,
if she makes you think this hard,
she must be worth it. Yes.
I don't know who it is, but I'm all for her,
so just bring her and let me meet her.
Okay.
I'll bring her home soon to meet you.
If you used half the energy you use on that girl
at work, you'd be doing twice as better.
That was why I married your mom so early.
So I can focus on work.
What about mom do you love so much?
I mean, she's my mom, so I put up with her,
but if she were my wife, well...
Stay away from my wife!
You can't see how attractive she is
because she's your mom.
I would never get sick of that woman.
Like mom said, she is your first and only love?
An unrealistically hopeless romantic
who married his first love?
Don't you dare!
Don't drink too much. Go to bed.
Whoa, you are!
Mom was telling the truth.
You're like one of the handful of men
whose been with only one woman!
Goodnight, Mr. Hopeless Romantic!
Hi.
Are you all right?
Of course.
Ms. Bae gave me a compliment today.
I'm going to work even harder.
I'm not going to use inexperience as an excuse.
I'm going to work harder, and prove to them
I won the contest with my talent,
so will you watch me from afar?
Don't be too friendly, don't try to step up.
If you keep trying to help me,
I'd want to rely on you.
Sure.
I won't be friendly at work anymore.
You're not angry, are you?
I'm hanging up.
He is angry.
Excuse me.
Who are you?
It's okay.
Oh.
Hello, Mr. Shin.
We meet again.
It's me. Haengsuk.
We met in front of Seonhui's restaurant.
Oh, hello.
I thought it might be you.
What brings you here?
Actually,
I've been working near here for a while now.
At the porridge place over there.
Please drop by sometime.
I'll make you delicious porridge.
I'll try.
Goodbye.
Front and back, he's my type.
Front and back, he's just dark everywhere.
This customer?
Yes?
Oh, the yam porridge?
He paid.
This customer,
why do you think he didn't finish it?
Because he didn't want to finish it.
Why didn't he want to finish it?
How would I know?
Maybe he was full, or maybe it tasted...
Next time, ask why they didn't finish.
Yes, sir.
Whoa.
What took you so long?
Oh, right.
You tend to come here in the evening.
Why did you come back?
Because I get more ideas when I come here.
For some reason, I can focus better.
Maybe they have good feng shui.
When I see you, I don't want to work anymore.
Don't stay stuff like that in front of me.
I have a temper, too, if I'm mad.
Say it to my face!
A man shouldn't mumble.
Why would she say that? How offensive.
And a writer shouldn't be a sexist.
No wonder people say her script is old.
I can hear you.
Jiwan!
Hi.
Oh, he looks nice in a suit.
You're here again?
This place must be great for writing.
By the way, who is he?
Your boyfriend?
No.
Hello.
I'm Yeongju's friend's older brother, Kim Jiwan.
Hello, I'm Heo Seonggeun.
It's nice to meet you.
He's not my boyfriend.
I said he's not my boyfriend.
Why would you think he's my boyfriend?
If he's standing with me, he's my boyfriend?
Shouldn't you at least ask me who he is?
You just jump to "boyfriend" when you see
a man standing next to me...
Uh...
I made a mistake.
It's okay.
I've been going through something.
Goodbye.
You're so insensitive.
Insensitive...
That was him, right?
Against 4 men! Looks great in suits.
The untamed!
The man in your script.
You have a major crush on him, right?
You could tell?
It was so obvious.
Everyone except one person knows.
Things like that are obvious to
the people around,
but not to the people involved.
When you're absorbed
in your emotions, you can't see.
Is it fun for you?
Yes.
What a jerk...
That's why your script was full of emotions.
I thought about what I loved about your script.
And I loved how
the female character saw the male character.
She was in so much pain
that I wanted to console her
and tell her not to hurt anymore.
Your crush is very useful for you!
See?
When you experience it, it becomes real.
You're like a con artist.
Let's talk business, shall we?
Hi, Yeongju.
Hi, Eunsu.
Did Jiwan say anything?
No, is something wrong?
I was a bit rude to him.
Can we meet today?
We can't, not for a while.
I'm busy getting ready for the launching show.
You are?
Are you sure you're busy?
It's not that jerk who's keeping you busy?
Don't call him a "jerk."
I'm sad enough because my mom hates him.
Your mom knows how to read people.
Of course she must hate him.
Are you cursing your friend's love life?
I'm busy. Bye.
Oh, talk about being blinded by love.
Eunsu has a boyfriend?
Mom!
Ever heard of knocking?
You keep doing this every day.
If you're not hiding anything,
why are you so surprised?
Who is it? He's a jerk?
You heard me.
Why? Is he that bad?
Eunsu doesn't have good taste in men.
How bad is this one?
It's not like that.
It's just that he can be flippant,
but you...
What is it? Is he someone I know?
No. How could you know him?
You're hiding something from me, aren't you?
You've been doing that a lot!
Why did you come home crying
the other night? You're not going to tell me?
Do I have to get your permission to cry?
Eunsu's boyfriend?
No, she doesn't have one.
She'd tell me if she had a boyfriend.
Maybe she didn't tell you
because something's wrong with him.
I'm saying this because I sympathize.
Why do you think I pay
so much attention to Yeongju?
What if that naive girl meets someone weird?
I couldn't handle that.
She doesn't.
You know she's been so busy with work
after winning the contest.
She has no time to meet anyone.
Is he from work?
Maybe they just met recently.
I heard he's flippant.
But then again, for your family,
that might be good.
What is it? You have someone in mind?
No, I don't.
That's the party room.
Why did I think of Hyeondo?
Hyeondo must be really flippant.
I thought of him when I heard the word.
The new product launching show's tomorrow?
Is it going well?
It's not like they've never done this.
They are all veterans.
I'm sure they'll do a good job.
Here.
Your favorite, roasted rice tea.
You sure have cheap taste.
You seemed bothered by something
for a while, but these days, you look peaceful.
Things aren't bad.
Troubles have been sorted out,
the company's doing well,
and Hyeondo seems to have grown up.
On top of that, you've become sweet.
I've been too good to you lately, haven't I?
You must feel guilty about something.
If you're unhappy,
you can move out of my room.
I don't know what it is,
but don't let me find out.
I like how you are right now.
You won't believe me if I tell you it's nothing.
Sure, I won't let you find out.
You can be so nasty.
You're unhappy when I'm nice to you.
Come by my office tomorrow.
I'll buy you a new car.
Really?
You weren't just saying that
in front of Mr. Park's wife?
Whatever it was, I said it, so I must keep it.
Oh, how lucky I am!
I know you deserve it.
While I crawled my way up,
you crawled up with me.
You actually know that?
After meeting you, I had a hard life.
After meeting you, I had a hard life, too.
Marrying once is hard enough,
so I wonder how those men who marry
two or three times actually manage it.
You envy them?
Why don't you learn from Mr. Park?
Wow, look how my design changed...
Eunsu, get ready before everyone gets here.
Go and get the manuals and samples.
Yes, I'll go right now.
Making the joint this way gives more support?
Eunsu, why are you still here?
I'm sorry.
- Hello.
Let's include Eunsu in the meeting.
Watching her design get developed by
professionals might help.
But I have to go get the samples.
We don't need them.
We don't have time. Sit down.
Sit.
Thank you.
Check everything you can before the show.
Mijin, what's going on with the testing booth?
We're setting it up so the reporters can test it.
Okay.
Jiwan, did you sort out the RSVP's?
The major media companies said
they'd be here.
I'll put the list up after I check them again.
Those who are flying in tomorrow,
I reserved pick up service for them tomorrow.
Good.
I edited the president's greeting message.
Okay.
I think we can give this to him.
Everyone!
Tomorrow's the day.
Don't let your guards down,
and check everything two or three times.
Got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Yes!
New Product Launching Presentation
Hyeondo, what are you doing?
You must line them up!
Put them in the right place!
Can you lower that a bit?
A little to the left.
Yes, a bit more to the left.
To the left.
Generally speaking, medical devices are
thought to be for patients or the elderly,
but our new product is for
students and younger...
I'll take the next question.
The man in the back, please go ahead.
Best Global's company motto is
to provide the best service using
top technology and hard work
to promote good health for mankind...
Yes...
We promise to produce and
provide world-class products.
The audio function is unusual,
but can you play any song you want?
Well, we installed the sounds of nature
to help the user relax.
But you can upload any kind of music you want.
However,
I don't recommend disco or hip-hop music.
If you get too excited and get hurt using it,
we can't be held responsible.
Hello, mother.
Well...
I think I saw Eunsu's mother here.
Jeongae?
Jeongae's there?
I was wondering if you knew...
I'll call you back.
Hello, mother.
Did Jeongae go there to meet Eunsu?
I don't know.
I was in a hurry...
Then why did Jeongae...
I think I made a mistake.
Don't worry, mother.
I have to go.
Sir.
Oh...
What are you doing here?
Aren't you in charge of the launching show?
I'm sorry.
I was looking for someone.
Did you see a woman walking this way?
Why do you ask?
I think we have an uninvited guest.
I was just trying to check.
No, there's nobody here.
Okay.
By the way, what are you doing here?
Do I have to explain that to you?
No, sir. I'm sorry.
You should go.
I will.
Excuse me.
You should've met with me when I asked you.
I wasn't going to cause trouble.
I told you I have something to say.
After that, I won't ever show up again.
Go somewhere and wait for me.
I'll call you when I'm finished.
Are you sure?
If you try to avoid me again,
I don't know how I'm going to react.
If you show up like this again,
I don't know how I'm going to react, either.
Fine.
Call me, and it better not be too late.
Excuse me!
We've met before, right?
I'm Eunsu's older brother.
Can we talk for a minute?
Well...
As long as it's not here.
I saw you when you were little.
It's been so long.
You grew up to be a fine young man.
You look so much like Sangjun.
You know my father, too?
We grew up in the countryside
everyone knew everyone.
As for Sangjun's family, everyone knew them.
Why did you ask to see me?
Did you come here for Eunsu?
Eunsu?
I heard you're Eunsu's birth mother.
Seonhui told you I'm her birth mother?
That's unexpected.
You're acting like you're Seonhui's real son.
Does Eunsu work here?
At the hotel?
Once was enough,
so why would I come see her again?
That girl...
She grew up to be a pretty young lady.
She must have a lot of admirers.
So you didn't come here for Eunsu?
Mother and I thought...
I haven't seen her for over 20 years,
so why would I start now?
Seonhui's so weird.
She think's everyone in the world is like her.
If that's the reason, I want to leave.
Why did you give Eunsu away?
Even if things were bad,
you could've come to see her.
Didn't Seonhui tell you?
I didn't leave Eunsu with Seonhui.
I abandoned her.
You're making me feel like an evil witch.
To be honest, Seonhui was a better choice.
I had no idea Sangjun would go bankrupt.
I thought about pros and cons
and abandoned Eunsu for her sake.
How could you say such a thing...
Seonhui raised you into a stuffy man.
Is Eunsu as stuffy as you are?
Jiwan!
They are looking for you inside.
Hurry up and go.
Are you crazy? How could you leave?
- Eunsu.
- Seriously,
whenever you create this kind of trouble,
I don't know how to handle it.
Right.
I'm sorry for being an irresponsible brother.
But you love having mom and me, right?
What? What are you talking about?
Hurry up and come.
Gather around, everyone in Marketing!
You've done a great job today.
Thanks to all your hard work,
the launching show went well.
Let's enjoy today, okay?
I'm taking you all out for a drink!
Let's go.
Just like I said,
what do you think I did at that moment?
As the team leader, I couldn't sit and watch.
I stepped forward.
I hate stepping forward, but I did.
Why? Because I had no choice. Okay?
You're amazing, Mr. Yun.
By the way, Eunsu.
Yes?
What are you looking at
when I'm talking to you?
No, sir.
I'm paying attention to you.
See?
This is why I like you so much.
You're affable.
Of your friends...
Where did Jiwan go?
He had to finish something up
at the launching show.
- I couldn't handle it.
- He should've told me.
Jiwan is such a responsible person, right?
Jiwan is.
So...
Where was I?
I didn't know which parking lot it was.
So what could I do to get out of this trouble?
What kind of strategy...
Mr. Jang Hyeondo
Still, how could he leave without a word?
Is he mad because I told him
not to be friendly at work?
He can be so petty.
Mr. Jang Hyeondo
Why did you leave early?
You told me never to be friendly at work.
Still, you didn't even look at me...
It feels better not to look at you.
Don't you miss me?
But I see you every day.
Not by passing, with other people.
Not like that.
Even just in passing,
it's nice to see you regardless.
I don't like it.
My mom thinks you'll only last a month.
Your family thinks I'm just Jiwan's friend.
Jiwan has put off his decision on me.
And I can't be friendly with you at work.
Why does it have to be this complicated?
My love life has never been this complicated.
If I like someone, great. If not, it ends.
It used to be so simple.
So why is this so complicated?
So you're unhappy?
Yes.
I'm unhappy.
You want to end this?
I do.
I thought I could end it if I wanted to,
but just thinking about it terrifies me.
Not being able to take you to places,
not being able to do anything for you.
I hate all that.
But...
But even if things get complicated,
let's see how far we can go.
Your call is being forwarded to an automated...
Eunsu, why aren't you picking up?
Call me as soon as you hear this...