What are you doing here?
Who are you?
I am Baron Latos.
I have come to you for help.
It's 5:00 in the morning!
I must apologize for the intrusion,
but travel for me is very difficult
and I've come a long way.
I don't understand.
Perhaps you will after you've led me
to the basement room of this castle.
Very strange request.
This is my home.
Have no fear, Doctor.
Had conditions permitted, I would have
presented myself in the usual manner.
Well, it is most unusual.
I'll explain everything before sunrise.
Dr. Edelmann, do you believe
in the immortality of the soul?
Naturally, being a religious man.
Of the body?
Medical science refutes such a thing.
Just as it denies
the existence of vampirism.
It doesn't deny
certain physical aspects of it.
Cases have been recorded
in which the victims,
driven by some abnormal urge,
actually believed the blood of other people
was necessary to keep them alive,
became psychopathic killers
in order to obtain it.
These beliefs probably
upset their metabolisms,
induced fixations, lustful appetites.
Of course, the whole thing
is of a highly speculative nature,
particularly the supernatural aspect.
Do you doubt the supernatural?
I find it difficult to believe that a human
being can change himself into a bat,
or that by feeding upon the blood
of the living he can obtain eternal life.
But what has this discussion
to do with us, Baron Latos?
Perhaps a great deal, Doctor.
Shall we proceed?
The Dracula crest.
Yes, Doctor.
I am Count Dracula.
But I'm known to the outside world
as Baron Latos.
You see before you a man
who lived for centuries,
kept alive by the blood
of innocent people.
You ask me to believe that?
That's why I've come to you.
To seek release from a curse
of misery and horror
against which I am
powerless to fight alone.
According to the legend, a vampire
must return to his grave before sunup.
If you remain here,
how would that be possible?
Within this coffin is a layer
of soil taken from my native country.
That earth makes this my grave,
in which I must lie helpless
during the daylight hour.
Because a single ray of sunlight falling
on the vampire would destroy him.
Yes, Doctor.
The door was locked.
How did you get that in here?
Since you doubt the supernatural,
let us say that you were mistaken.
The outer door was not locked.
You're taking a great deal
for granted, Baron.
Proceeding on the assumption
that I would take your case.
Your reputation for helping others
made me certain that you would.
You could affect a cure?
There might be a way,
despite the dangers involved.
It would be a challenge
to medical science.
Accept that challenge, Doctor.
But decide quickly.
The dawn.
- Good morning, Nina.
- Good morning, Doctor.
Make a blood smear of this for me,
will you, please?
A Baron Latos will be in this evening.
I'll see him immediately.
Well, how are things coming?
Splendid, Doctor.
Increasing the humidity was a good idea.
The spores are multiplying
faster than ever.
Yes, we're making progress, all right.
Oh, the operation on
Johannes' leg proves that.
If we can produce the mold in quantity,
think what it will mean to thousands
of people all over the world.
We'll succeed, Nina.
And when we do, your devotion
to this experiment will be rewarded.
You'll be the first to benefit by it.
Nina?
Make a culture of this and prepare
an antitoxin as soon as possible.
All right, Doctor.
I am Baron Latos.
Dr. Edelmann is expecting me.
Baron Latos.
Miss Morelle?
What a pleasant surprise.
It's good to see you again, Baron.
You left Schvonheim just as
we were becoming acquainted.
I could hardly refuse the opportunity
to become Dr. Edelmann's assistant.
Now that chance has brought us together
again, I hope to see you quite often.
I've taken a chateau close by.
You're not here as a patient.
Unfortunately, the Doctor thought it
advisable that I come here for treatment.
Good evening, Baron. Come in.
Miss Morelle, it will be
necessary for Baron Latos
to have his appointments
during the evenings.
Yes, Doctor.
Sit down, Baron.
Thank you.
It appears that I may have
to alter my theories.
An examination of your blood reveals
the presence of a peculiar parasite.
A form with which
I'm completely unfamiliar.
It's possible that it may have something
to do with your problem.
Proceeding on the assumption that it has,
I'm having an antitoxin
prepared so that we can see.
Your new theory being...
That a pure culture of a parasite,
introduced into the parent bloodstream,
will destroy not only its own kind,
but themselves as well.
Sounds very promising.
Perhaps.
But we must proceed slowly.
These treatments will take some time?
Without doubt.
Meanwhile, your visits here
should be only at intervals.
On the nights and at the hours
which I shall designate.
Is that understood?
Quite clearly.
Then we shall start treatments tonight.
The transfusion.
How long will the Doctor be busy?
Some little time, I'm afraid.
I'm must see him at once.
I've come a long way.
If you'll just give him my name.
Talbot.
Lawrence Talbot.
Maybe he'll understand.
I can't interrupt the Doctor now.
He's giving a transfusion.
How long will that take?
Hour. Maybe longer.
I'm sorry, you'll just have to wait.
I can't wait!
There isn't time.
There isn't time!
Your next appointment
will be Thursday evening, Baron.
At about the same time?
Yes.
Good night, Doctor.
Good night.
Oh!
Baron.
Mr. Talbot was here to see you, Doctor.
- He was terribly upset.
- "Talbot"?
Lawrence Talbot.
He seemed to think
you'd recognize the name.
"Lawrence Talbot." No.
There was something tragic about him.
He had the look of
a man tormented by fear.
When I told him you were busy, he rushed
out of the house saying he couldn't wait,
there wasn't time.
Well, perhaps he'll come back.
Hello.
Just a moment, please.
It's Inspector Holtz.
Yes, Inspector?
Oh!
Very well, I'll be right down.
You'd better come along with me, Miliza.
Go to your homes, all of you.
This is no concern of yours.
We don't have to go home.
We know our rights.
That goes for you too, Steinmuhl.
Whenever there's trouble,
you're always on the front line.
Oh, good evening, Doctor.
Come right in, will you?
Go home!
If I find the person who started
the rumor we have a crazy man here,
I'll lock him up.
As a matter of fact, Doctor, we have.
He came in here a little while ago
and demanded that I put him in a cell.
To keep him from committing
murder, he said.
I did it to humor him.
But when he started raving,
I realized we had something serious
on our hands and sent for you.
Decent sort of chap, otherwise.
- Name of Talbot.
- Talbot?
You remember, Doctor.
The young man I told you about.
Come in, Doctor. He's in here.
Who are these people?
Get them out of here!
I didn't come here to
be put on exhibition.
Come, come now. Take it easy.
This is Dr. Edelmann.
He's come to help you.
Dr. Edelmann!
Yes. You wanted to see me?
That's why I came to Visaria.
In the hope that you could help me.
It's too late now.
What seems to be your trouble, my boy?
Do you believe that a man
can be transformed into an animal?
I believe anything can happen
in a person's mind.
This is not in my mind.
Doctor.
Have you ever heard of the pentagram?
The five-pointed star.
The mark of the beast.
When the full moon rises,
I turn into a werewolf,
with only one desire in my mind.
To kill!
Listen to me, Talbot.
There's no such thing as a werewolf.
It's a belief that
exists only in your mind.
Doctor, isn't there something you can do?
Not until morning, when this passes.
Bring him to me then.
Put him in my care,
and I'll do all I can for him.
Oh, I didn't hear you.
The Doctor will see you now.
Do you think he can help me?
He's done some wonderful things.
Then why has he kept me
waiting here all day?
Doesn't he realize that tonight...
Oh, I'm sorry.
I know he'll do whatever he can for me.
Good afternoon, Doctor.
Sit down, Mr. Talbot.
What have you got to tell me?
In your case, my boy,
diagnosis is extremely difficult.
But the examination you made
this morning, the X-rays.
Examination discloses one condition,
pressure upon certain parts of the brain.
This condition coupled with your belief
that the moon can bring about a change
accomplishes exactly that.
During the period in which
your reasoning processes
give way to self-hypnosis,
the glands which govern your
metabolism get out of control,
like a steam engine
without a balance wheel.
When this happens, the glands generate
an abnormal supply of certain hormones.
In your case, those which bring about the
physical transformation which you experience.
But explaining it doesn't help.
What can you do about it?
Operate?
A surgical operation to enlarge the cranial
cavity is a long and dangerous one.
Then there's nothing
you can do to help me.
There might be.
Come here, my boy.
Under tropical conditions,
which we have tried to duplicate here,
this hybrid plant, clavaria formosa,
produces a mold from which
we've been able to distill...
Well, a substance which possesses
the property of softening
any hard structure
composed of calcium salts.
Bone, for instance.
With this medium,
it might be possible without surgery
to reshape the cranial cavity
and thus eliminate the pressure.
You can do that now?
Can you?
Unfortunately, it will take some time
to produce mold in sufficient quantity.
Tonight, the moon will be full again.
What can you do to help me now?
Only what you did for yourself last night.
Confine you.
No, Doctor.
No.
I can't go through that again.
Talbot, listen.
Talbot. Talbot!
Talbot, come back!
Siegfried!
There are many caves along
the coastline here made by the tides.
There's still a chance
that he can be saved.
We must think of the danger
to Dr. Edelmann.
If Mr. Talbot has been swept
into the cave down there,
he's still under the spell of the moon.
We must wait till it sets.
When it does, if he's still alive,
he'll try to destroy himself again.
That's why the Doctor must time
his actions to the very moment.
If he can find him just as the seizure
passes, and his reason returns...
Perhaps he can persuade him
to want to live.
Here we work half a night
to get this thing rigged up,
and then he says, "We'll wait a while."
What's going on around here anyway?
That's Dr. Edelmann's business.
Strange business, if you ask me.
All right, swing me out.
Lower away.
Easy!
All right!
I might've killed you.
Why did you follow me down here?
To bring you back, my boy.
Back to a life of misery and despair?
I only wanted to die.
You want to die,
but instead you will live,
because God, in his divine workings,
has lead you to the very thing
which makes help possible.
Look about you.
The temperature and humidity
down here are ideal
for growing the spore-producing plants.
Before the next full moon,
we should have more
than enough to help you.
I wish I could believe that, Doctor.
You can, my boy.
But you must do your part.
You must want to live.
The Frankenstein monster.
That must be the skeleton of Dr. Niemann,
who revitalized him years ago.
As the story goes,
the villagers drove them into the swamp,
and they went down in quicksand.
After all these years,
the mud has brought them here.
Still alive.
He's indestructible.
Frankenstein's creation
is man's challenge
to the laws of life and death.
Doctor!
Dr. Edelmann!
Doctor, look here.
There must be a way
out of here into the castle.
History mentions an old torture chamber.
But its entrance was sealed up years ago.
He was made bit by bit, piece by piece.
The undying monster.
Triumphant climax of
Frankenstein's genius.
The heart that Frankenstein
gave him never died.
The spark of life is still there,
waiting to be revived.
Dr. Edelmann, this thing
destroyed Frankenstein.
It's brought death to all who have
tried to follow in his footsteps.
Is that poor creature
responsible for what he is?
It's a thing of violence to whom
death would be a merciful release.
Can man sit in judgment
over life and death?
The evil he creates, he can also destroy.
That would be murder.
Think what you're doing, Doctor.
To bring him back again, Doctor, would
unleash worse than murder upon humanity.
That helpless body
is man's responsibility.
Man's responsibility is to his fellow man.
Perhaps you're right, Nina.
Frankenstein's monster
must never wreak havoc again.
Baron.
I didn't hear you come in.
Please, go on.
You like it?
It breathes the spirit of the night.
They played it the evening
we met at the concert.
I'd forgotten.
Until I saw you again.
Perhaps I wanted you to remember.
I've never heard this music before,
yet I'm playing it.
You're creating it...
For me.
It frightens me.
It's beautiful.
It's the music of the world
from which I come.
It makes me see strange things.
People who are dead, yet they're alive.
Mine is a world without material needs.
It calls to me,
but I'm afraid.
The fear will pass as the music
becomes fixed in your mind.
It will make you long to be there.
Why do you stop?
Play the music again.
There's something Dr. Edelmann
told me to do.
Roll up your sleeve, please, Baron.
The music will come to you again.
My world is waiting for you.
Forsake the cross so that
you can join me there.
Your world is coming closer to me.
But I'm afraid.
It is a world without fear.
It is like the music.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
Oh, good evening, Baron.
Thank you, Miliza. That'll be all.
I feel that we're making progress, Baron.
This photomiorograph of your
blood reveals an odd condition.
One which I can't account for as yet.
What is it, Doctor?
A different species
of antibodies has appeared.
Why worry so long as the treatments
are proving successful?
If a doctor affects a cure,
he wants to know how he did it.
Which is of little concern to the patient
so long as he's being cured.
Day after tomorrow?
At the same time.
Then good night, Doctor.
Please go to bed, Miliza.
I'll finish down here.
I think I will.
Miliza!
Miliza! Are you all right?
The music is bringing my world closer.
Closer.
Doctor, Baron Latos...
He left here early
this evening, didn't he?
About half past 8:00. Why?
I...
Miliza and I were working.
What are you trying to tell me?
Come, speak up.
She seemed awfully tired.
Like a person in a trance.
In a trance?
She left me without saying a word.
I followed her.
She met Baron Latos in the hall.
They went into the garden.
And when he walked in front of the mirror,
I couldn't see his reflection.
I imagined that, didn't I?
Didn't I?
No, Nina.
Baron Latos shows no reflection.
Then he...
He's Count Dracula.
In trying to save him,
I've endangered the lives of all of you.
Then cast away the cross
so that you may join me there.
I must try to stop him
before it's too late.
But how?
Prepare for a transfusion at once.
You can't give another one so soon.
Do as I tell you.
If anything should happen to me tonight,
go into the old armor room in the basement
and burn what you find there.
What is it, Doctor?
You'll understand.
You must destroy it by fire.
Go to your room.
When you hear the music,
I will come to you.
I've been looking for you, Baron.
You remember that I was puzzled
tonight by the new antibodies?
Yes.
I know now where they came from.
They're from my blood.
We may be on the verge
of an important discovery.
So, to check my theory,
I'm going to give you another transfusion.
Now?
Immediately.
If this is the answer, we must see.
Doctor.
Dr. Edelmann!
Doctor!
He's gone.
Mr. Talbot!
- Miliza.
- She's all right now.
But what about him?
The evil I brought here
will never live again.
They tried to kill you, but they couldn't.
Frankenstein gave you eternal life.
Power which time cannot destroy.
The secret of immortality,
it will soon be mine.
Dr. Edelmann?
Go away. Leave me alone.
Dr. Edelmann, I have some coffee for you.
Go away, I tell you.
Dr. Edelmann, let me in!
Doctor.
Doctor, you're ill.
No.
I'm all right.
That'll make you feel better.
How much of the spore concentrate
have we ready?
Don't worry about that now.
We're making fine progress.
Answer me.
Is there enough for two operations?
No, there won't be for some time.
But we do have enough for one?
I think so.
Then I must operate
as soon as possible, on you.
- But Doctor...
- You were right, Nina.
I am ill.
It's impossible to know
what the future holds.
There, there, Doctor.
You mustn't talk like that.
I'll operate tomorrow, Nina.
Then you must operate on Mr. Talbot.
The moon will be full in a few days.
We can't let him suffer again.
But you... You've waited such a long time.
Then I can wait a little longer.
It won't make any difference.
You're worn out.
Why don't you get some rest?
I'm all right.
I know who you're thinking of.
I'm hoping we'll be ready in time.
I can't stand the thought of him
having to go through that again.
Don't worry, we'll have enough.
Why, it's wonderful, Dr. Edelmann.
What you've done would ordinarily mean
an operation of the most delicate nature.
This way, the dangers
of surgery didn't even exist.
We can expect some nervous shock.
He must be kept quiet.
Any exertion might undo everything
I hope we've accomplished.
We'll know in a few days, Miliza.
All we can do now is hope.
And pray.
We must think now only of Nina.
Every minute must be devoted to
producing more of the concentrate.
For her.
You're a fine nurse, Miliza.
You know perfectly well Mr. Talbot
should be asleep by now.
Sleep?
I'll have a lifetime in which to sleep,
when I know what lies ahead.
After what Dr. Edelmann has done
for you, only happiness lies ahead.
I wonder.
Please don't think that I'm ungrateful.
Time after time,
people have tried to help me.
Time after time, they've failed.
- If this fails, I...
- It won't fail, Larry.
You must believe that it won't.
I've tried to.
But when I face the night...
Try to see the night
as something beautiful.
Until the full moon turns it into
a thing of ugliness and horror.
Soon, you'll see it as everyone else does.
Restful, tranquil and serene.
Until that time comes,
I'll live 1,000 hopes,
die 1,000 times.
It will never be ugly to you again, Larry.
Believe me, I know it.
How do you know that?
My heart tells me.
Hello, Siegfried.
Dr. Edelmann!
Did you hear me call to you, Siegfried?
Why, no, sir.
I would have stopped for you if I had.
I'm certain you would have.
Don't worry about it, Siegfried.
What's the matter, Siegfried?
You act as though you were afraid.
Oh, no, sir.
Why should I be afraid?
Of the night, perhaps?
I'm not afraid of the night.
Your hands are trembling, Siegfried.
Are they?
Siegfried.
Yes, sir?
I believe I know what you're afraid of.
Do you?
You're afraid of me.
Of you, sir?
'Cause if you weren't,
you'd look at me, Siegfried.
Hyah!
See, you are afraid of me.
You're driving faster and faster,
so that you can get into
the village and tell the police.
Why? Why should I want
to tell the police anything?
Because you're afraid
I'm going to kill you!
Kill me? Doctor!
Yes. You've seen what's
happened to your old friend.
He doesn't want anybody
but himself to know about that.
No, Doctor!
I will never tell!
That's right, Siegfried. You never will!
Help! Help!
Help!
There he is! There he is!
This way!
It's your brother, Siegfried.
Is he dead?
There he goes!
Good evening, Inspector.
I'm sorry to disturb you, Doctor,
but I'd like to see Mr. Talbot
and everybody else in the house at once.
Certainly.
- Is something wrong?
- You'll know in good time, Doctor.
Now, please hurry.
Now, Inspector, what is it?
Your man Siegfried's been murdered.
Siegfried?
Murdered?
By the person who rode
into the village with him tonight.
His throat was torn open as though
by some enraged animal.
So naturally you suspect me.
I have good reason to.
But he hasn't been out
of the house for days.
Not to your knowledge, perhaps.
Have you been with him all evening?
Until an hour ago.
Well, the murder was only
committed 20 minutes ago.
And within the last five minutes,
we pursued the murderer
to these very grounds.
But it's impossible, Inspector.
Only the full moon affects Mr. Talbot.
The moon won't be full
again until tomorrow night.
Not only that, Inspector,
but Mr. Talbot has undergone an operation
which makes physical
exertion out of the question.
Running even a short distance,
much less from the village,
would cause serious complications.
A cerebral hemorrhage,
perhaps even his death.
I respect your word, Doctor,
but a murder has been committed.
It's imperative that I search
your premises immediately.
He's the man you want.
Are you gonna let Dr. Edelmann
talk you out of it?
That's enough, Steinmuhl. That's enough.
I apologize, Doctor,
but the man who killed his brother
is somewhere around here.
It's my duty to find him.
I shall hold you responsible
for these people until further notice.
Yes?
What are you doing here, my boy?
You shouldn't be up.
Never mind me, Doctor.
It's you I'm worried about.
You were with Siegfried tonight
when he went to the village.
I saw you.
I saw you when you came back.
Why didn't you tell Inspector Holtz?
After what you've done for me?
Why, you tried to help me.
And you want to help me now?
If I possibly can.
Because you suffered the tortures
I'm going through now,
you of all people will understand
what I'm going to say.
In trying to perform
the miracle of medical science,
I failed.
My blood has been contaminated
by the blood of Dracula.
My soul and mind have been
seized by some nameless horror,
a lust which changes me into the thing
that killed Siegfried tonight.
You wish to help me?
There's one way in which you can.
Say nothing to Inspector
Holtz of what you know.
Not to protect me, but to give me time.
Time to do for Nina
what I've done for you.
After that, this evil
thing must be destroyed.
You have my word that it will be, my boy.
But if I am unable,
you must do it for me.
Dr. Franz Edelmann.
Bonn University, cum laude.
What's going on here?
I was just on my way over
to your office, Inspector.
I want you to take a look at this.
I found it clenched in
Siegfried's left hand.
Dr. Edelmann killed him.
Be quiet, Steinmuhl.
You don't know what this means.
Neither do I.
It's obviously a matter
for the police to handle.
Is that clear?
It's clear Dr. Edelmann killed my brother.
Last night, you thought it was Talbot.
Tonight, you say it's a man who we all
have known and respected for years.
Good heavens, you're worse
than a gossiping old woman.
Go home. Go home.
Go home, all of you!
I'm sick and tired of this. Come on,
break it up. Break it up, come on.
Something's going on
at Dr. Edelmann's, I tell you.
What does Holtz have to say about it?
"This is a matter for
the police to handle."
It's a matter for us to handle,
unless we all want to be murdered.
He's right.
I'm for doing something about it.
Well, I don't know, now.
I'm with you.
The next few moments
will give us our answer.
It's the time we've all
been looking forward to.
You must put fear out of your mind.
Confront it with a belief
that the past is over with,
that a new life lies ahead.
A new life.
Stay here, please. All of you.
- But, Larry...
- No!
Not until we can be sure.
Doctor, it's wonderful.
Dr. Edelmann? Doctor!
That's it. That's it.
Now! Now!
I'll make you strong,
stronger than you've ever been.
I'll give you the strength of 100 men.
No, Dr. Edelmann.
No! You promised.
What are you doing here?
Why, I...
You were spying on me, weren't you?
No, I just wanted to find you.
I wanted to tell you that I...
You shouldn't have done that, Nina.
I want to see Dr. Edelmann at once.
You shouldn't have come here.
I don't like people who see
what they're not supposed to see.
- Doctor!
- He's gone mad.
Hello, Mr. Talbot.
You broke your promise to me, didn't you?
You told the police.
I don't like people who break
their promises, Mr. Talbot.
Get out! The Frankenstein monster!