Tell Ruth Hedeby when she's finished
with the meeting that we are
not shutting anything down and
that the case will remain open.
No, we are not shutting down and those people
who were given time off, will be called back
I will get backing and
the resources from
management once they see
what I have from forensic.
They have not found anything in Jylland.
The search of being called off
they have not found anything in Jylland.
send them back again
The search of being called off
requested local police to continue
to search for Emilie Zeuthen.
Coordinate with Lund, we shall give
them all the help that they need
tell Robert Zeuthen that we
have new information and
often to come in for a
briefing As soon as possible..
Asbjørn has requested backup,
they have traced the kidnapper.
Asbjørn, Brix here, What is happening.
Lund and Borch have traced
him to an old shipyard
just outside of town and
we are no our way now
have they captured him?
No, it does not sound good, they definitely
do not have control over the situation
what seems to be the problem
apparently they have been
locked in or something
the phone reception was not good,
so I'm not completely sure
what exactly had happened,
but we are rushing there now
hello anything
give me the black notebook, slide it
under the door, then you're free to go
he wants the book
give me the phone,
listen up, we do not have
the notebook for fuck sake
backup is on the way, listen
to me, turn off the engine
hello, HELLO!
I can't! You do it
you go ahead and come back to me
go on! We do not have time for this
drop the gun the gun.
Book.. gone...
the police and police intelligence
have traced the kidnapper to Jutland
right now it's incredibly
important that you keep a cool
head and get that meeting
with the heads of the party
ahh, Kamper... Kamper.
Kamper, I have to say, I just
heard about the meeting...
I'll do everything
to back you up
the Minister of finance will try her
best to discredit you, there is
no doubt that she has already attended
to influence some of the others
it's completely irrelevant
what she have done
this not going to be any meeting!
Right now we investigating
information that could
exonerates the government
of all wrongdoing
and you call me for this meeting
as member of the government you
are accountable to me and only me
and that's why you're
telling everybody here that
your incredible sorry that
you have wasted their time
but what is that information
we now have the witness that will
testify that it was Ussing that was
putting pressure on the prosecutor
that was responsible for the old case
but, what is it that you are saying?
What witness?
The witness is a trusted
member of Ussing staff
the police intelligence
Bureau is investigating it
now, I can't say more about
it now, is that clear
yes of course
I hope is not that guy Seifert
of course it's not him, do you
think we are complete idiots
everybody knows that he has been charged
by the police for stealing from Ussing.
Mogens! Everybody knows that he has been
charged by the police for stealing from Ussing
everybody knows that he has been charged
by the police for stealing from Ussing
while I guess it doesn't matter if..
No matter what, it still
needs to be investigated
I have asked PIB to..
Unless Emilie Zeuthen shows up in
live within the next five minutes
are we going to start the
meeting with or without you.
I'm going to check with
the Ministry of Justice
do that, I was just going
to propose the same
where is he, how could he get away?
I don't know, they're
still searching for him
you are right, Emilie Zeuthen
was not shot in the boat
have you found any signs of her?
She was not at the boathouse,
this searching his car right now
what the f.. is it then
that you have found?
The crime scene of Louise Jelby
apparently she was picked
up by her killer in a
black car when she was on
her way back from school
and then he drove her
out to an abandoned
shipbuilder where she was
kept captured and abused
and after that he apparently drove her out
to the harbor to make it look like suicide
and the kidnapper found
out about this place?
Now he's trying to figure
out who have done it
using an notebook that he
managed to get hold of
what notebook?
Well that was a boy who
wrote down all the license
plate numbers of cars
passing by that day
the kidnapper took the book from Borch.
Hedeby wants a briefing
what are you talking about? Where
did Borch have that book from?
You will have to ask Borch or Police
Intelligence bureau (PIB) about
there was a reason
I would like to explain.
I...
we have sent search dogs
through the plantation and
the beach, but the dogs lost
the scent at a stream...
He is no foot and he's injured
yes, but they believe that he
followed a stream leading back
to town through some wetlands,
and now it's dark and even..
I have not withheld information that
could have slowed down the investigation
let's get his blood back to forensics
to test his DNA, what about the car?
They don't believe that she was ever
in the car, the dogs did not react
okay let's go back to Copenhagen
if you can get anything out of that notebook,
I'm sure that would lead him to Copenhagen
I could not have done it
differently, do you understand
I have told you everything
what is it that you have been covering up?
I cannot tell you anything until it has been
cleared, but he would not have helped you.
I'm trying to explain
it's not a question of a single mistake
it's your relationship with Rosa
Lebech, her ex-husband who apparently
is leaking confidential information
from the Ministry of Justice
to the whole management
of the Zeuthen case
you have not been listening
to any warning signs
and instead of just letting the minister
of justice handling his own mess..
It's not the ministry of justice
that have been making any mistakes
you have been making the
Zeuthen case personal and
thereby jeopardizing the
whole party's credibility
you have to understand what kind
of situation you have put us in
we have a responsibility to all voters
and to the Zeuthen family
the party can not dispose of Prime Minister
well to my knowledge there has
never been a case of a Prime.
Minister surviving for very long
without the support of his party
the question is what kind of
party representing, if we don't
have more sensible things to
spend our time on than this
yes, our credibility is on the
line, and so is our future
our relationship with Zeeland
the foundation file financial rescue plan
but but you know me, you know
my views no matter what the.
Minister of finance have been telling you.
This is helping no one
you elected me because you trusted
me, that trust I need right now
unfortunately that is not going to
make Emilie Zeuthen come back to life
am I to understand that you
are not going to listen to
reason and thereby pushed
party into internal fraction.
Therefore I see no other reason than
to call for party meeting.. Mogens
would you be so kind to take a
seat so we can make some decisions
just a moment I just received new
information from my ministry.
I just got information from the
police, they have just found the
bag that was supposed to contain
the body of Emilie Zeuthen
it's apparently just to bag and
not the body of Emilie Zeuthen
it's quite clear that there's
only material damage
but that is definitely good news
and if we have no objections,
then I think that the
latest news have superseded
the purpose of this meeting
well I guess this is the best picture
the kidnapper got away and unfortunately that
no evidence suggesting that Emilie Zeuthen
was ever in Jutland
but the good news is that
she can still be alive.
Have Zeuthen been informed?
They the police right now
what happened at the meeting?
We need to get hold of PIB
that witness needs to be taken
seriously I need to know what Ussing
the witnesses being interrogated
by the PIB right now
but there's more to the case, the
police is accusing PIB of withholding
important information regarding
the old case from Jutland.
PIB claim that they knew
nothing about that case
yes I do not know what's going on
I believe everything should be okay again
with regards to the Minister of finance
and I would just like to not hold a grudge
we don't want any more trouble now
get hold of PIB I need a briefing right now
the sack had been transported
by the current from
the bridge out of the
harbour and into the fjord
we found the bag on 12 m of water,
the anchor made it go to the
bottom despite the positive buoyancy
of the rest of the material
as you can see the bullet
had gone through the bag
the caliber of the bullets
on the same as previous
a wish I could answer the questions
that this new evidence raises...
she's alive
the kidnapper was traced
to Jutland, but there's
nothing to suggest that
Emilie was with him
so for now the trail of
Emilie stops at the boat
we have intensified the search, but..
Nothing is certain
I will really like it when you against..
Get a hold of our chief
security officer and everybody
else who have competency in
that area and get them updated
no, we'll take care of the search now
I understand your frustration but you cannot
start interfering in the investigation now
we have wasted 48 hours since that bridge
we have not waste..
We were just about to tell our
son that his sister was dead
do you understand what I'm saying
I do apologize that we were mistaken
but you risk complicating
everything more by interfering
it's not the right way to go about it
of course there is an explication
as you know the girl was
found dead in that harbor
as part of the investigation
by the local police
uncovered and notebook
containing license plates
and as a routine we were informed cause..
You told me that PIB knew
nothing about this case
yes in hindsight that was a mistake
we did not know anything
about the case details
we were only interested in
the case since the Prime.
Minister's election campaign
car was in that book
what! Can you repeat
we were informed back then
because one of the numbers
in that book was the number
of your campaign car.
Of course we knew that the Prime Minister
had nothing to do with that case
I don't understand
it was during the last election,
your touring around the country
and somehow your cost license
number ended up in a kids notebook
we contacted the prosecutor he informed us
that it was suicide and we stopped looking
we had no idea that that information
was important until now
but then you found out that the
prosecutor was covering up
the case, wouldn't that notebook
then make a difference?
Is obvious now that the rest of the
numbers of great interest, mainly because
the car that was used by opposition
leader Ussing was also in that book
okay
it was wrong of me to tell you that we
did not know anything about this case
I apologize
what does it mean that
Ussing is in that book?
Now that we know that the prosecutor was
covering up the case and with the witness
that you have brought us, obviously
we are intensifying our investigation
hmm, as a suspect?
It's a possibility, but we are
primarily focusing on the kidnapper
he can't have much use of this book it
only contains license plate numbers
we know he's wounded, my
guess is that will catch him
soon and then we'll know
what happened to Emilie.
What did he say about Ussing?
Will he be investigated?
That's something that the police and
the PIB will have to take care of
in the meantime I'll like to shift our
focus back on the upcoming election and
am not going to throw accusations at
Ussing until we have more information
but you have to admit the
things the getting better now.
Lebech wants to meet up with you again
are you kidding me
it's too early, can you check up
on the arrangements for tomorrow
see you
thank you for your hard work Karen
is not that often I get a chance to
say it, but you are important to me
it's what I get paid for
I know but anyway
do you have a minute
no not really.
I'm going to the Ministry of
Justice to check up on Mogens.
I'm really sorry about
everything that had happened
I can understand if you have
lost your trusted in me
look, there's quite a lot of
need to get done for tomorrow
I forward I could keep our
private life and professional
life separate but I am
not a strong as you are.
I've had a lot of pressure on me
from my party and from my ex-husband
but it doesn't change my feelings for you
I need you to understand that.
She was at the bridge and the boat
was found in Copenhagen harbor
so that's where we start the search
but the police have already
expanded their search
they have more men searching
the harbor and the coastline
the police is basically everywhere
they have checked all the ships
so where have the police been
they have not been looking in all
the containers in the harbor
get them searched
is that realistic.. they are sealed
just contact the owners and tell them that
they will get refunded for the trouble
there are also legal aspects, not all
of the containers Zeelands and the
contents off the containers are the
properties of the individual owners
I get it started
I will contact our legal department
and get them to handle it
the board wants to have a meeting
you have to take care of that
when I got back, Carls..
Was watching the news
don't listen to what they say about Emilie
your mom and dad is looking for her
and if there's something that
you like to know, just ask us
but what if you can't find her
will find her
when?
Soon.
I've also been looking for her, I thought she
was in “the in between” but she wasn't there
what “the in between”
are you talking about
the room she goes to, when she
does want to listen anymore.
What is it that Emilie
doesn't want to hear?
When you arguing and ..
Lest go downstairs and get a cookie
I have packed the most basic things
then we have to wait and see
where he wants to sleep
any news
no, not yet.
Have Carl or Emilie ever talked about
something they call “the in between”?
No,
PIB continue to claim that
their protection off the Prime.
Minister and notebook had
nothing to do with our case
we need all the information now, they must
have a copy of those license plate numbers
the head of PIB is coming for
meeting tomorrow morning
have Borch told you anything?
Nope
do you have any news on the kidnapper
we cannot know how he got
your mobile phone number,
but we know he got back
to Sjaeland as a stowaway
and blood was found that matches his
okay, but nobody have seen anything.
No, but forensic test.
HI, don't turn on the heat
shows that it is 99% sure
that the kidnapper is the
biological father of Louise
HI, don't turn on the heat
shows that it is 99% sure that the kidnapper
is the biological father of Louise.
I've already started the
search, if the father is
unknown then we need to find
out more about the mother.
I'll keep you updated.
Okay
we can only hope for to get appeared
of time without subzero temperatures
otherwise will have to wait with bringing
them outside to the become spring
I made pumpkin soup if you like some.
You did not see it, close the door again,
the pictures from my ultrasound scan.
Let me warm the soup for you
no I don't want any soup, candlelight
or ultrasound pictures right now
okay, calm down I'm only
staying till tomorrow.
Did you talk to Mark?
Yes, he only told me that
he didn't know what to do
so I need to start thinking about
what's best for me and the baby.
I'll move in with a friend or I
will move back to my parents.
Mark will probably change ones he sees
the baby and you have your apartment
no, the apartment is not going to be ready
guy from the management office came
to survey the ceiling, he told us
there is asbestos, so the ceiling and
everything needs to be torn down
oh
it's going to be okay, if you could
manage to be a single mom then so can I
I don't think I managed
I thought that I could give Mark a proper..
Well I couldn't
it did not work with Mark's dad and me
so there was not much I could do.
Why did it work?
Anymore soup?
You would together and
then you got pregnant
I loved him
I love one before and
I broke it up with him to
even though it was him that
well, that's what happens
while I'm okay now
I have to answer this call
you can stay as long as you
want to and of course I would
like to have the ultrasound
picture on the fridge.
What.
Why did you stop me?
Your partner the guy
from PIB deserve to die
you can see that he was
covering up the case
where is Emilie?
I need your help Lund
we know you didn't bring her
to Jutland, is she alive?
There are 12 entries of
black cars in the notebook
from that day, one of them
picked up a small girl
I need the names and the ID numbers of these
12 people and then now take care of the rest.
No, I need you to surrender
and give us back Emilie
alive and then our promise
to solve the old case.
I'll call tomorrow and then I expect
to get the names and the ID numbers
you know I can't give you
that, don't you thing
that your daughter deserve
that we solve the case
your blood matches that of hers
I promise you that your daughters
killer will get his punishment
but you have to give me Emilie
I will get a copy of the
registration numbers
tomorrow and then I'll
get started immediately
okay?
Okay, but don't disappoint me
and you don't have to wait till tomorrow,
I have placed a copy on your doorstep.
We have stationed 2 offices
near Sarah Lund's house
in response to the
kidnappers visit last night
no thanks! I feel more
unsafe with your guys around
I can understand your point
of view, but you have
to understand that our
mission back then was
to protect the Prime
Minister ending up in the
tabloids just because his
car was in this book
how can you be sure that
the Prime Minister or
any of his staff were not
involved in this case?
It was his campaign car with chauffeur
and staff and everything and if
you think it was us who put pressure
on the prosecutor, you're wrong!
We fought that will be a
reasonable assumption
we are just as surprised about the
behavior of the prosecutor is you are
and my colleague Matias have been giving
you to correct information at all times
except for the small detail, that
you actually knew about the case
and that you grab the notebook
and I'm sure we would not have
been told about it unless we
found out about it ourselves
of course we would have told you
I just asked Borch to get
the notebook so we could
gain a clear picture, before
we handed over to you
of course you would
it's not Matias fault. Nobody could have known
that the notebook was important until now
so which one of these 12 cars is So
important that the prosecutor would
change the date of the girl's death?
You must know it, which one?
Which one? You must know
if we knew it we would tell you
what about Ussing? His any
of his cars on the list??
Yes, also a election campaign car
we are currently investigating his
relationship with Louise Jelby
but it might be an
unreliable witness we have
okay let's bring Ussing
in for questioning
you can do that but we
have act carefully, this
is a prominent politician
we're talking about
the girl was abused killed,
and then thrown in a harbor.
And if the only thing he wants in exchange
for the safe return of Emilie is justice
then we better get started
or how?
Yes
we have no clues to the
whereabouts of Emilie so
we cannot take your
sensibility into the matter
I made him a promise and I do
believe he will give us Emilie,
but we need to get started
now, he will call tonight.
We agree, you search the harbor
and we will take care parliament
no you can search the
harbor and we do the rest
with a good steady pace he
could have managed to get to
the Copenhagen harbor then
he would have had two hours
before he stole the car giving
him plenty of time to hide
the girl well, then it looks
like we're cooperating again
well, then it looks like we're
cooperating again you have to go
through everything again, somebody
must have seen something or camera
you have to go through everything again,
somebody must have seen something or camera
yes we are trying but it's difficult to
get access with all Zeuthen people here.
Brix is trying to do something about it
yeah okay what about Borch? Are you okay?
I know he fucked up, but it was him who got us
started again when we had given up searching
just call if you find something
it cannot come a surprise to you that there
were some things I couldn't talk about
don't be like that I've
tried to be loyal to you
confidentiality, I understand it
it meant something to me
between us
let's go
give me an update
the nursery is a job creation
project with about 100 employees
but with the stiff competition they are
about to close with debts in the millions
thank you
something wrong?
No, nothing
then there are rumors that Rosa
has dropped her backing of Ussing
any comments from Ussing?
I'm sure he will now
I do not want to comment on these rumors, but
if you have any questions on job creation.
Ussing: I'm standing with a glass of water.
Rosa: it was just...
we were asked, if we were willing
to take some additional questions
beyond the agenda, we don't have any
problem with that what about you?
As long as we get to talk about job creation
and the governments waste of tax kroner.
Rosa: you can borrow mine.
Kamper: thank you
I need to run it by my advices
that is some serious shit that you are
involved in, that is an unreliable witness
don't think you can win by
using these dirty tricks
as far as I understand
it's not only a witness.
I'll explain everything I can assure you
but you should look around for good
lawyer when I sue for defamation
is okay with us.
Ussing has been called back to Parliament
to help the police with the investigation
what a pity
now he doesn't want money,
he wants them to solve
an old case and why
should I wait for that
did you find anything.
Its a time-consuming process going
through alll those containers
then hire some more people
we're not missing any people, were still
working with some of the shipping
operators to get agreements in place, but
some of them are not very cooperative
just get done
excuse us for a minute
of course
I have talked with the board and they all
supported, but we are still without a CEO
share prices falling and
rumors are circulating...
if they have anything to say, they can say to me.
And then just do what I tell you to do
Robert
you get paid to do what I
tell you to do, so do it
there was uncalled for
here is your speech for the TV announcement
thank you.
I've been speaking with the
nanny and their teachers,
and none of them have heard
about “the in between”
maybe it's just a game they made up
Robert Zeuthen: Are They Ready?
Maja Zeuthen: Yes
the police called and asked us not to do it
no, let's go
you have the chance to
save the life of Emilie.
Zeuthen life, I'm sure your
voters will understand
I have already accepted
answering your questions,
as you are aware, there is a close
relationship between the old case that your
friend the prosecutor was in charge of
and the kidnapping of Emilie Zeuthen
I am deeply shocked but I had already
been question regarding that meeting
there was a witness present.
Thorsten Seifert claims that the meeting
was about to dead girl Louise Jelby.
Thorsten Seifert is completely untrustworthy,
I trust he's not the reason why we're here.
Do you recognise this girl Louise JelbyJ?
Sorry, no
on the 20 April 21/2 year ago
where you around Gudbjerg.
Havn, the town where Louise
Jelby was found dead.
Here is a list of occupants
on a hotel nearby under day
I was on the election trail, and
if he had done your homework,
you would have found out that I
was around their at the time
you drove a black car.
A BMW 3 series, it was up-served
on the stretch of the road where
Louise Jelby was picked up by a
black car, same place same time
I was likely at a election
meeting with my staff
likely!
Listen, a small girl was
tortured and murdered and your
good friend Peter Schultz
made it look like suicide
so for your own sake, I would suggest
that you try to be more precise
what exactly were you talking about
at that meeting with Peter Schultz
and don't give me any story about
exchanging University stories
we use this girl and one of our campaigns
what campaign?
A campaign for our foster care program
who are you?
Per Monrad, Political adviser
her foster care family was a glowing
example of the success of the
work that we had done in the
area and our foster care program
but then we were told that she
had committed suicide and
then that ruined our campaign
worth several million
we had to stop it all
before it even got started
hold on a minute, what had that to do
with your friend the chief prosecutor
I had heard that Peter was handling
the case and I just wanted
to make sure that part was not
relevant to the investigation
what did Peter say about the case
he told me that he could not talk
about the case, and I respect that
so that means you actually
did know that the girl
there is how it works, they find
somebody, I show up for the photo shoot,
I wouldn't be able to recognize her
if you showed me a picture of her
so you did not pick up that day?
Are you suggesting that I should
have killed some small girl.
I'm not suggesting anything
I have Ussing schedule
for that day right here
as you can see we had a meeting with the
Prime Minister in Esbjerg that day and time
does that answer your questions?
Then we would like to ..
No it doesn't, we need all the
details from both of your organisers
and everything relevant to
that day by the end of the day
and if we doesn't get that,
then will come back again here
with a search warrant and go
through everything in your office
thank you
the PR company confirms that they
used the girl for that campaign
how is it possible that
the PIB missed that?
They say they are making
a copy of the film now
you know anything about Ussing's private
life that we should know about?
Or is that also confidential
answer!
Ussing Got divorced from his wife
from Thailand five years ago
he has two adult children that
he doesn't see very frequently
he straight, he is sexually active,
anything else you would like to know
we are going to interview his
staff, admin, campaign managers
and then we're going to talk
with the Ministry of State
they must be able to confirm
whether his alibi sticks
Sarah
Robert Zeuthen: we hope that you will help
us get Emilie Zeuthen back home alive again
Maja Zeuthen: if anybody have seen
anything, then please contact us
she knows that we are looking for her and
will continue looking until we find her
information that will lead
to finding Emilie Zeuthen a
live will get a reward of
100 million Danish kroner
sources tell us that the amount is
close to what the kidnapper initially
wanted and is undoubtedly the largest
reward ever given in Denmark
I thought you had Robert
Zeuthen under control.
Kristoffer: it's going great, the media is all
over Ussing, nobody was to work with him.
Kristoffer: the parties
behind you, the Minister
of Finance and even Rosa
is asking for meeting.
Kristoffer: may be Karen
should arrange the meetings.
No, know why don't you take care of it
Karen needs to help the police.
Kristoffer: with what?
They want some information regarding
the previous election campaign.
Kristoffer: okay I'll arrange something,
Kristopher,
Kristoffer: yes.
I'm happy that you're back
and thank you for reminding me that
we shouldn't do things halfway.
We need to keep on doing that.
Kristoffer: yeah oh what
are you talking about
what is happening with Robert Zeuthen
we made a deal with the kidnapper.
Brix: Robert Zeuthen cannot be controlled.
Brix: our phone system have
gone down five times, everybody
thinks they have seen
something worth 100 million.
Brix: and arrested because
of complaints from Ussing.
Lund: Ussing, he was lying through his
teeth, we had to spell it out for him.
Brix: if he wins the next election,
our department won't have a budget.
Brix: keep me updated
hello
I am Matias Borch, we spoke on the phone.
And I'm Sarah Lund, we need to
get some information about the.
Prime Minister's schedule during
the previous election campaign
I understand, please have a seat.
Can you remember whether the Prime Minister had
a meeting with Ussing on 20 April that year
I have already looked it
up, the Prime Minister
did indeed have a meeting
with Ussing that they
and your hundred percent sure about that
if they had a meeting in Esberg
any chance that Ussing did not show up
no chance of that I would have remembered his
biggest opposition, I would have remembered
do you remember if they
there was anything strange
about them that they,
anything stood out?
No I'm sorry don't remember
what about the Prime Minister?
I'm just asking.
Did he drives around alone or
maybe he took a break in the car
is unlikely to have been
the Prime Minister's car.
No, that car is only available as part
of his official duties as prime minister.
We have to pay ourself during the
election campaign we drive around
in buses and in campaign cars and
he does not drive around by himself
I have to answer this call, Borch here
wait a minute, I found something, it
seems like the meeting was postponed
how.
Ussing did not participate in a
meeting with the Prime Minister?
Yes but only a few days later.
Ussing ask for a reshuffle of some meetings
is quite common during
the election campaign
I want to know what the reason was and
if there are any other meetings that was
reshuffled, who did it and any other
information regarding Ussing from back then
I don't have all the
information right here, then
then I have to go back
to the archives again
please go ahead, thank you
here's my card if you need to
contact me, thank you, bye
I got some information from the workers
bank, we need to talk to Ussing again
well then you need to join the queue
Robert Zeuthen: we're getting lots of
phone calls, the need to be sorted
Robert Zeuthen: but there's
got to be something there
Robert Zeuthen: what about Carl?
We just got home, I will come
over as soon as possible
Carl we drive over to the “the in between”
no
I know where it is, it's
over in the garage isn't it?
No
then tell me
is it in the basement?
Answer
I don't want to go up
to the “the in between”
what you mean by "up"
Carl, what you mean “up”?
Emilie told me not to tell anybody
show me that place, right now!
Did dad know that you are hiding up here?
We did not want to tell anybody,
we are just playing here
that's not Emilies iPad
hers is down in her room,
how is this one get here?
She told me she got it from the man
with the Cat, down by the fence
yes this is the same car that
Ussing was driving back then
but it can take several weeks for forensic
what are you doing here
no matter what it has to be later
the meeting that you claim to
being was postponed by yourself
okay and then what
that doesn't make me a killer
as you understand I was in the
middle of an election campaign
wouldn't have been able to move
around without somebody seeing me
we spoke to your chauffeur from back
then and according to the logbook
were you absent for several hours and
you were driving around this car
okay, that's a possibility
I have to leave now
we have interviewed your staff,
and nobody can verify your
whereabouts to you showed up in
your hotel at about midnight
please step aside so I can get into my car.
As the chairman of the
workers bank, did you
help your friend the
prosecutor out with a loan
what
you disappear from your election
campaign that they where did you go
we're talking several millions,
did he do any favours for you?
You have to answer the questions
you can contact my lawyer
you recognise the girl at the main road, you
picked up her and her bike and then what
if you have an explanation then
explain I don't have time for this.
Ussing you're not going anywhere this
car, we are bringing it to forensics.
You are insane, this is harassment
is just pure harassment
what the fuck do you think you're doing
you will be brought in for questioning
then you can explain there.
Asbjørn: it doesn't matter if you
solve the old case, she never
returned to the harbour, we do
not know whether she is alive.
Lund: what are you talking about
we got some pictures from an all camera at
the harbour and Emilie is not in the boat
that cannot be true, she
has to have been there.
Asbjorn: on looking at the pictures
now, the kidnapper arrives 03:54, alone.
Asbjørn: he passes by the card house 20
minutes later and enters the red van.
Lund: he must have dropped all
somewhere on the way there.
Asbjorn: there's no reason why
we should stay here, I will go
to the place in the North Harbour
where Louise's mother worked.
Lund: what is it?
Asbjorn: it a coffee shop
called “Morgen Fruen”
what
are you coming
where we going.
Mogens and a finance
minister on their way up.
Eggert confirms that she
was to meet up later.
Mogens: now they are rumours
that Ussing have been
involved in financial wrongdoings
with the prosecutor.
Headline: Ussing's car investigated in relation
with homicide case Mogens: now they are
rumours that Ussing have been involved in
financial wrongdoings with the prosecutor.
Mogens: now they are rumours
that Ussing have been
involved in financial
wrongdoings with the prosecutor
the police have questioned twice and
brought his cast to forensic investigation
I needed to find information requested
by the police please stop without me
thank you Karen
hello
I just want to let you know that
the party leaders are in euphoria
they say that they haven't been
such a great support for the
party since since the beginning
of November, and I right Brigit
it's just great, I can understand that that
witness was not completely wrong about Ussing
deeply sorry about our collision.
Mogens have been working very
hard to straighten everything out
so I hope that you don't bear a grudge,
I've also bought a little gift
it's a vintage port, I had
hoped to open it on election
night but with all the
things we have been through.
Birgit, just keep the Cork in
you will need it once I have won the
election and chosen my new government
it's all a mistake, Birgit
knows she was wrong
is not up for debate
the Prime Minister will no longer
have any confidence in you
and that can't be changed.
Kristian
I have informed the civil servants
at the Ministry of Finance
to make arrangement for you not
returning after the election
that's all, goodbye
it's okay Morgens,
I've spoken to the leaders of
my party and they all head
over heels even those that
were on the fence before
so that as it I've spoken to the
leaders of my party and they
all head over heels even those
that were on the fence before.
I've spoken to the leaders of
my party and they all head
over heels even those that
were on the fence before
we can give our support
for you as Prime Minister
but I thought we could go on and
haven't informal dinner now
now we should have a formal dinner, we are
through both politically and personally
not that we can't agree or because of your
ex-husband that leaks classified information
but simply because I didn't have
you support when I needed it
what is happening? I just
met the Minister of Finance
did you provide information to the police
yes, but there is something that strange
some files are missing
what happened with Lebech?
We are better off alone
are you coming with me
we need to get everything
out and once we have
done here in would continue
at the other location
they almost done or where the East terminal
but we have some issues with customs
I don't care, I.e. every
single containers searched
that's clear, I was just telling..
What did the police say, did
we get any useful calls
it's bit chaotic, I don't think the police have the..
Get all of them now I need answers
Robert, I know how he got in contact
with her and how he got the information
what
Emilie: hi and thank you so much
for the iPad I like it so much
mum and dad doesn't know that I
have my own profile on the net
and is profiled then never
got a find, they don't talk
to each other and they have
no clue what I'm doing
and thank you for the pictures
of the kittens they are so cute
I don't know which one I like the most
you can bring them with you once
they get bigger so I can see them
if you want to chat tomorrow
than ride on my wall, bye
excuse me, I spoken with the police
Emilie did not return to the harbour
they found some pictures from a camera
they think he might have
taken her somewhere else
or
the mother worked at the
coffee shop there is nothing
the whole area is closed down now
the only one here are the homeless
100% sure that you didn't see
this boat here three days ago?
Look, I sleep at night, So go
away and stop disturbing me
here are 200 kr now think again,
didn't you see anybody ever at all
there's only me around
here, and Mr T Jensen
oh yeah, then there is the Cat Man,
but you don't do anything about him
I think we should drive third
out there is nothing here
what cat men?
It's that psychopath living over there,
he thinks he owns the whole place
he tells us to stay away, but he
doesn't anyone rent than we do
he's not here, see if you can find anything
that was the clothing that Emilie
was wearing that night on the boat
winter boots, survival
gear, what's going on?
Look here
was that?
Container numbers, I think
there must thousands.
He can't have shipped her out as cargo
I thought we had an agreement
we do have an agreement, and
we're working on it and
if it's about the reward
we had nothing to do with
I don't give a shit about the reward, you
promised me that you would solve the case
I think we're close
I do follow the news, is not some
unimportant opposition politician,
they are screwing you over
again Lund, can't you see it
no they are not, but is
going to take some time
there was not 12 registration numbers
in that notebook, there were 13
somebody tore out a page of the book
before you handed it back to the boy
I think you need to have a
chat with your friend from PIB.
I'm sorry I only found out
about it now, that means
that I have to go out and
find out myself who it is
no, what car, give me the registration
number I promise you that...
what car is he talking about?
Did you tear out a page?
Is not true, he's lying
no it's true, look a page is missing
you can still see the imprint
that can't be true, it wasn't there
which one, what are you talking about
is the Prime Minister's car
but we know about that car,
you already checked it out
know there was the campaign car
this is the car assigned
to the Prime Minister