Grab him!
Come on kid. Out you come.
It's nothing, we're just
training with your dad.
Come on, we're waiting for you.
Sir... Don't hurt me!
Shut up and quit struggling.
Lam not going to do anything.
NO! NO! Please, don't kill me!
Alright. Good boy. Everything
is going to be Okay.
The bullet is lodged
behind the frontal lobe.
It's impossible to remove it
without damaging the rest of the brain.
In any case his chances
of survival are very little.
He won't survive more than 48 hours.
There's no point in cutting.
Let nature take its course.
It's a miracle he has survived this far.
One of the cops told me
that the shell misfired.
Otherwise the bullet
would have blown his brains out.
Has his family been notified? No one left.
His parents were killed, but he'll
be able to be with them very soon...
which is probably the best thing.
Hey! Have you seen that new nurse? Hot!
$500 I get her before you do!
You're on.
Don't worry. I'm here. Hang in there.
You need to fight... fight...
Superintendent!
Do you have any leads on the killers?
The inquiry is in hand.
What exactly were they working on?
That's classified.
Superintendent, superintendent...
Do you have any leads on the murder
of Inspector Samat and his family?
What a pain in my ass. What's
the news on Samat's kid?
He's still in a coma.
Make sure he's not left alone.
Understood.
Go ahead.
You can't come in here. This
is the intensive care unit.
His parents didn't want him on life
support. You have to turn it off.
Are you sure this is official?
Don't I look like I'm official?
Hold on! Give the kid a break!
Science has made so much progress
and miracles do happen. Tell him, Doctor.
If you turn it off, will he live?
No way.
Right. Then go ahead.
I'll take responsibility.
You can't do this. You'll kill him!
It's murder.
Turn it off. That's an order.
It's murder, no!
Don't touch me!
What does that mean?
I told you!
He's alive. It's incredible!
There's a problem.
Nurse.
Here's my card, call me if you have
any news about the boy.
Yes, it's bad news. Yes, exactly.
Don't worry little one. I'm here.
Hello. What the hell has happened?
Where's the kid? You are a bunch
of incompetent idiots!
Why didn't you warn me?
Adjan.
It's very bad isn't it?
His spirit is with us,
but he is between two worlds.
So that's it?
Don't you think I'm a bit
old to be playing nurse?
They're going to kill him.
Judging by his current condition
they wouldn't have to try very hard.
Adjan, be careful! I'm sure he can hear us.
The truth will cure him.
You know the secrets of the plants.
Only you can save him.
I will never ask anything of you...
if you won't do it for him... do it for me?
Then I get to go on holiday.
Thank you very much!
Long live holiday.
Know your past to build your future.
Know your body to open your spirit.
Nothing's changed?
He's ataraxic, his brain has been damaged.
He doesn't feel anything anymore.
No happiness, no pain...
You are about as fast as a turtle
and as powerful as a koala.
Training is not knowledge
and knowledge is not power.
Combine the training with the knowledge
and you shall achieve the power.
My art has become your art.
This evening I shall teach you
the ultimate technique.
The way which leads to death. This you
must use only if your life is in danger.
Hey, a beer!
Tea for two.
Lesson 956: A good fighter must know
how to receive like a buffalo.
Lesson 957: He must dodge like a mongoose.
And lesson 958: Strike like a tiger.
When you fight, you must neither dodge
nor reply until I tell you.
We will start with lesson 956.
Ok, who will I fight?
Adjan, they haven't done anything to me.
They will.
What? What did you say?
That they are all sons of bitches?
Lesson 956.
What did you say?
Think about the buffalo.
And lesson 957.
Lesson 958.
And our teas?
I think I prefer 958.
Master Adjan?
Yes?
Chanticha is sick. She wants to see Manit.
Hello Mom.
Manit, we have to talk
lam sick my little one. I will die soon.
I know that you understand
but you feel nothing.
This is not your fault. I will explain...
You have to know that your father
was a distinguished lieutenant.
He was investigating a vast network
of corruption within the police force.
But he didn't have the
support of his hierarchy.
He was starting to disturb
way too many people.
One evening they decided
to get rid of them.
They murdered all of his colleagues.
One by one, carefully.
Then they went to your house.
Who did this?
The investigation never found
the people responsible,
but for all these years
I have continued to search. Look in there.
Everything I have discovered is in there.
Press articles, pictures, witnesses...
I did what I could to save you.
I can no longer protect you...
lam so tired Manit.
Don't worry mother, I am ready.
Hello. I work as a nurse
at the General Hospital.
You asked me to inform you
if I ever hear of any information
about the little boy who
disappeared years ago.
Do you remember? Well I know where he is.
Do you know him?
No, I've never seen him before.
He doesn't look very sad.
Do you think it's him?
How the hell would I know?
The only photo I've seen
was when he was a kid.
Call the boss!
Sir... it's me. Yes...
he just walked past the car.
Yeah... just like that. I can't say really.
Looks like a peasant. Okay.
We will see if we can.
And?
We have to check
if he has a scar on his left temple.
If so, we take him to the boss.
Okay, let's go.
Where is he?
Hey, come here... Did you see this guy?
Sure? I'll be back.
Well, we had a deal. You
promised me an interview.
Yeah... we promised you an interview...
we keep our words right?
But it's just that we need to drag
it out a little bit... you know,
it's not that easy.
Okay come on Clara let's split!
Hey, where the fuck you
think you're going man?
Take it easy. Okay... how
much more do you want?
All you gotta do is give us a blow job,
for each and every one of us.
We'll tell you the greatest story
you need to know.
Yeah...
Sounds good?
By the way pretty boy...
we've got something for you too.
Stop it! No, no! Stop it!
Stop it! Leave him!
What's going on over here?
Who the fuck are you?
Manit...
Your friend is a kind of strange...
Who the fuck is this fool man?
Lamon, get this fool man, beat him up!
You wanted to speak with him?
Yeah.
Hey! The girl wants to talk with you.
All right...
These young people...
they've got nothing in their lives!
Okay-
They must be suffering!
I'm not sure about before,
but definitely now.
How can you do things like
that to human beings?
First you have to study anatomy,
then it's just a matter of training.
Okay guys, I'm out of here.
Thanks again Manit.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah, Okay. See you.
You have somewhere to sleep?
No.
You could crash at my place
if you like. I've got a couch.
- Which way?
- This way!
You don't know me!
My instinct never fails me.
Right... Sometimes people
are who they seem to be.
How come that you speak English so well?
If I told you, you'd never believe me...
Shower's through there.
It's a nice place.
Interesting?
I'm a journalist...
So you are honest?
Do you have an explanation for these?
I would have taken their ears...
but I didn't have a knife.
They were following me...
I didn't know they were cops.
Hey! Hey! Girls, where are you going?
Come here! Come here! Do you know this guy?
Never seen him!
You snore quite loud for a girl!
I didn't snore!
You have a dog?
I don't have a dog!
Well then I guess you snore.
Cheeky!
Sneaky?
No... Okay forget it! Actually I've been
looking through your friend's file...
Those are my mother's files.
Mother? Okay whatever.
Your mother she did a very good detective job
but there are more questions than answers.
Well that's why I'm here.
I'm trying to find all the answers.
I can help you.
We found him. He's with a journalist
who investigates gangs.
Well... I think we'll have to intervene...
How was I?
Marvelous as ever my beauty.
The first show is in 10
days I'm so nervous!
Because you are talented!
You're so nice
and I want to say again how grateful
I am that you are producing this concert.
I'm retired, I have got a wife
who sings like an angel
and I have the means.
Is it true? You don't feel any emotions?
Sometimes I get a bit hungry...
Smart ass... I read the medical report.
Oh yeah? Sometimes I think it might be
something of an advantage. You know?
It's a short cut.
Short cut, huh?
Police... come with us.
I'm not moving an inch.
I'm a journalist and this is an
illegal arrest. I know my rights.
Let go of me! Let go! Manit!
Where did you take the girl?
Fuck you.
That's not very nice.
Where?
8th district... Special force.
Well I'm gonna have to give them
a special visit then. Don't I?
Thank you!
Missed it...
Same floor...
Where is the girl?
I like you alright, don't make me hurt you!
Where? Where? Okay open the door!
Open the door! Thank you.
Okay open the door! Open the door!
Thank you.
Nice pants...
So where is the girl?
Fuck the girl!
Whoever you are, help me! Help me!
Who are you?
Depends!
I'm a cop.
It's not a very good reference.
Wait, wait! I'm not like them.
I've been onto these guys for months.
Those guys are working for the mob.
It's a real organization
and I almost had their leader.
I can show them to you.
Go on.
My father was onto them 20 years ago.
He had all their files. I can show you...
Holy shit! You don't fool around, do you!
Not for the last 20 years.
Never seen that before.
Well, I've never done it before...
Hey, come on, I'll show you the files.
He was my father. Butchered like a dog.
His throat was cut off
and a bastard cut off his tongue.
He was sent as an undercover
by his section chief
and I swear I will continue his fight.
Cool. Can you look up Samat...
Samat? Samat.
Wait, isn't this your...
Yes my father.
Holy shit! Just imagine:
Your father and mine...
and now me and you...
Look, I've set you free and that's great.
But I have got to finish what I've started.
Call some of your friends,
get them to do a clean up over here.
I'm gonna go find this girl.
Wait, wait. The girl?
Yeah!
I heard they were handing
her over to the Hyenas.
It's a girl gang.
The cops let them handle
all their dirty works.
Where I can find them?
I'll show them to you, you will get lost.
I found you okay didn't I? Leave it to me.
I can use their methods.
Okay-
Cool!
Come here I'll show you.
They should be here.
Hello guys, what did you get?
Excuse me sir do you know
the Khlong Toei neighborhood?
I do... yes.
Could you tell me how to get there?
Out of the question...
I don't want your death on my conscience.
Come on in, come in! We
have the best boxing!
Excuse me...
What do you want?
I have a friend...
Your friend is in here?
Yes!
I hope it's not the fat guy.
This is for white guys.
You see the fat guy with his gang?
He thinks he's Mike Tyson!
He's here because he hopes
to knock someone out.
Like if he was at Lumpinee Stadium.
It's going to cost him some money.
But he is ready to pay the price.
Just as long as he feels strong
and feels like a champion.
They all dream of being Thai boxers.
And you find guys ready
to take it, just like that?
Same guy has been around for 4 years...
Do you know where the Khlong
Toei neighborhood is?
Hey, he wants to go to Khlong Toei.
Well... if he wants to get
beaten up, let him go.
You're not from around here.
Neither are you.
The way you look,
you'll get the shit kicked out of you.
I'm looking for somebody!
Forget it!
Like you do with alcohol?
You really want to go there?
Yeah! You really want to quit drinking?
50 bucks and I'll take you.
3O
Deal!
You don't say much, huh?
No.
Carry on for 500 meters
and you'll know you're there.
You owe me 40 bucks.
Stop playing around and do your homework!
I don't want to mom!
It's amazing.
GO, go: Go'
Stop, stop!
You want some... Bitch!
It's not very nice.
Let her go!
Come and get her.
She's useless.
What?
Can I ask you something?
Asshole.
Shit! Hello?
I am working.
When?
Okay... start without me.
I'll be there in a minute.
Any problem?
Not really... just business...
we'll start again in two hours.
You heard?
I was on the extension.
You really can't help it, can you?
Professional instincts I guess.
Be careful.
Of course...
Is she dead?
It sounds like you're
talking about a sandwich...
You're real funny you!
Don't even think about it.
You're checking, I'm checking.
That must hurt... but not enough!
- Hi boss!
Hi girls. So where are we?
We got both of the little shits.
What the hell?
We didn't have any rope...
so we tied him with our panties.
That's what I love about you all.
You've got the initiative
of real bad bitches.
You... back to sleep...
Look at his left temple. Is there a scar?
Yeah, he's got a scar.
He's our man.
Right... enough talk. Kill them both.
Not like that.
Too quick and too noisy!
Get him!
Die bastard!
Let's go!
Manit, Manit, Manit!
Oh my god...
Manit.
You're suffocating me.
Thank God you're alive!
Oh I must because I can
feel you suffocating me...
Oh please forgive me for
taking care of you.
It's weird. You know, I
think I know their leader.
She's called Jessy Yiouchenko,
she's an opera singer.
She must have other strings on her bow.
Call the downtown police station
and ask to speak to Anada
You can give him my name.
Tell him what happened here
and ask him to check out this thing...
Now what?
Your place is on surveillance.
I carry on and you stay here.
No way! I'm coming with you
and you need my help.
It's out of the question... Okay!
I hang around and do nothing without...
Okay-
What did you say?
Okay, it's cool you can come with me.
That's it? Normally a
gentleman would have found
a thousand reasons why
I shouldn't put my life at risk.
You just say yes and that's it?
I'm gonna take a rest. I
feel a little bit tired.
I thought we were going to
finish the investigation.
I feel tired so I am going to have a rest.
I'm not tired.
Well you were asleep for
the whole fight so you've had your rest.
I was not asleep, I was faking it.
And why did you say that
I was used for nothing?
I guess I was faking it...
or something like that...
- You coming?
- Yes I'm coming.
What are you doing?
I'm comforting you... I
think you had a nightmare.
You know I have to feel sad in order
to be comforted, right?
I know you're never sad...
It must be terrible never to feel anything.
I don't know... maybe it's better that way.
In France I know a famous neurologist,
he's really good.
I'm sure he could do something for you.
Since your accident there
has been enormous progress...
that way you could be...
Normal?
That's not what I meant.
Don't worry about it, I
never feel sad, remember!
And tenderness?
Did you ever take a woman
in your arms and...
I can do that.
Sleep well?
Enough.
I have been thinking...
maybe it would be better
if you continued on your own way.
Okay-
Can you show me to this place?
You know what? Take a
fucking taxi, smart ass!
' Okay!
- Okay!
And Clara...
about last night...
hanks for that. It was cool.
Inspector Anada?
Yes this is Clara...
Manit has been kidnapped...
I'm waiting for you... five minutes, okay.
This is where you'll die.
But first, a couple of questions.
Answer them and we won't make you suffer.
Can I die somewhere else?
What?
It's ugly here. Somewhere nicer...
What is he saying?
No... this is a good place!
Oh my god,
I think I have fallen into the hands
of the most tasteless killers in Bangkok.
Shut the fuck up man!
Now you're gonna tell us
what the hell you're doing over here man!
Just this...
Oh shit man!
Are you guys cops or something?
No! Fuck off man.
Wrong answer.
Are you a cop?
Yeah... we're cops.
From the 8th? 8th district?
No man! Shit...
You're gonna take me to your boss
or you'll never walk again.
How man?
Shit, you broke my arm... shit man!
It's an automatic, you
don't need both hands.
You are not gonna win this, you know.
This is too big for you.
You're gonna end up blown away. Shit!
Shut up and drive.
We have to be quick we must find him.
I already put the details
of the car on wire
but if you really want me to help you,
you need to tell me more...
I've only know him three days.
You are a journalist...
you sense things... no?
Al I have is a file that his mother
left him before she died.
It contains documents
that could incriminate
corrupt cops concerning the
murder of his parents.
Now that is interesting. Where is it?
At my place... but there
must be police officers!
Look... you trust me so let's go get it!
These guys are screwing up
the whole goddamn system.
They must be found and eliminated.
I want to talk to Jessy.
Nobody talks to the boss.
I do not speak to the Fanky.
Anything else?
I work alone.
Alone?
Who the hell do you think has been selling
your shit for the last two last years?
And that goes for all of you.
Thanks to Jessy you are comfortably rich..
Without her network
what do you think you'd be able to export?
10 kilos?
With her you've got 5
tons a year out there.
What's the plan?
Tell your men. Find them and kill them.
Jessy wants their heads
on her desk in 48 hours.
If you want your money
the concert is still on.
Hey you like classical music, do you?
Not a lot.
Who's this girl singing here?
She's quite good.
I don't know man.
What's your first name?
Why?
I don't know just want to establish
a sort of friendship. I'm Manit.
Sanouk!
Well Sanouk, my friend,
you think I'm an idiot, don't you?
Let's start again. The lady singing
on this CD do you know who she is?
That's Jessy Yiouchenko or something man.
Go on...
If I talk, I'm dead man.
And if you don't you think
you're gonna get married?
She runs a network of heroin trafficking
between Thailand and South America.
How?
Thanks to the concerts.
The shit goes with the orchestra.
As she's famous and the shows run
by the embassies mostly,
there are no custom checks, you know.
And who's above her?
I don't know!
Well more pain is on its way I'm afraid...
Come quick we are after him!
We're coming!
Oh damn that feels good!
What's going on?
Get off!
I need your head!
And I need your balls!
We're Police! Police!
Freeze... Put your gun down...
Put your gun down.
It's done... We've got them.
I am asking you. What
do they want from you?
Do you understand me?
You won't get away with
causing all this trouble.
Do you know we've been watching you?
Do you.
If I had known I would
have brushed my hair.
Why do you speak in English?
If I told you, you'd never believe me.
Okay, English is fine...
But you'd better talk to me.
If you want protection just come up
with something... so trust me.
I don't want protection and trust has
to be earned not demanded.
True... but you are still
in deep shit anyway...
So are you. You have to clean out
your own stable first.
I'm the head of an anti-corruption brigade
and I'm fighting with all
my strength to uncover
and punish those who contaminate
the force because of what?
They insult the country.
My father said the same thing.
And he died for it, along with the rest
of the members of his section...
You wanna know why I'm here?
Not for revenge but for justice.
Fine, if you want to follow
your role, just do it.
And you know what?
If anything goes wrong I will arrest you
like the rest, even if your Samat's son.
To each his duty... and what about Simon?
He'll be busted.
So...
Mr. Simon Weber.
No one's called me that
in such a long time.
Or should I call you ex-French detective
Inspector Weber?
You can call me whatever you want...
I really couldn't give a shit.
I have an Interpol warrant for your arrest.
Don't you have a whisky also by any chance?
Your friends accused you of having
stolen 15,000 euros from drug traffickers.
With ice...
Personally I have nothing up against you
but you betrayed your oath.
If I betrayed somebody it was me, just me.
How about your wife?
Died.
Sorry...
Why? Did you kill her?
Smoking kills.
Assholes too...
Do you want me to get you out?
No, I have lots of questions
and I think the answers might be here.
Thanks for your help.
I don't like injustice... real one.
And I think you're special,
I like people who are different.
Okay, I'm out of here.
Hey!
I don't think you can
kill pain with more pain!
Hey Manit.
Anada
Clara and I have been
looking everywhere for you.
Well you found me.
Come on I'll get you out of here.
Let's go get Clara.
And what about Inspector Pitchai?
Don't worry I already talked to him...
Come on, let's go.
Cool
Clara just called.
She said she found out some really
interesting things about your family.
Something that could explain everything.
This will all be over soon.
It's not over yet...
You recognize this?
Yeah!
Come on let's go in.
When your father was killed his colleagues
did this for him to pay his respect...
You think you can get in?
I was able to get out!
Clara.
Get in!
Is that a gun?
Hey Clara, how are you doing?
You're alright? It's my friend Anada.
You wouldn't want another one would you?
How knows it might cure you!
I was the one who screwed
you on district 8.
Anada, enough!
You can never be too careful...
you prefer English...
Why is that? You're Thai like us!
If I told you, you'd never believe me...
Allow me to make the introductions.
Is that necessary?
I am Sanya Wurapong,
I was your father's superior.
I think it's nice for you to get to know
the person who made your life this way.
Shall I take a seat?
I feel this is going to be rather long
and very complicated.
I like your sense of humor.
Permit me to tell you a little story.
Once upon a time there
was this young inspector
whose boss sent him to
work with us undercover.
He was unmasked, questioned
and convinced to work with us.
So much so that we could lead his boss
to believe that he was dead.
Not too difficult to find a replacement...
I think you know the rest,
and now you come back
and stick your nose into
our business affair...
You know you're just like your father
before he turned vigilante.
He was doing his duty.
My father sacrificed his
life because of you!
Well... being a traitor must be
a genetic condition.
Hey cool it! I'm sure you understand you
can't leave here alive. You have to die.
You're too late... l am already dead.
Memories?
So far so good.
This scene won't be complete
without the final touches...
Ever thought about going
into the movie business?
Finish it Narai.
Have fun boys!
Sorry little boy...
Sanya!
Freeze.
How do you feel?
How do I feel? I feel like fucking shit!
I have got fucking holes in my legs...
I feel bad! I feel bad!
Welcome to the world of the living!
Your father would be proud of you...
Well, thanks for your help...
Good luck.
Thank you for coming to save me.
It's starting to feel like a full time job!
I love you...
Huh?
I love you.
Mr. Simon...
and Mr. Nicky!