Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Nightmare Teacher Team @ Viki
Nightmare Teacher
Episode 11
Yosan High School
It's time to wake up.
It was dark
dark?
An endless darkness in which
you don't know when it ends.
Hurt, jealous, angry that will never end.
Those kinds of feelings
And I saw Teacher Bong Gu.
I'm now remembering the
kids who disappeared,
and why they did.
A few days ago, I posted the names and photos
of the disappeared kids on the school feed,
and someone who knows them appeared.
If you're curious, go to
special class at 5th floor.
Is there a special class in our school?
Why haven't I heard about it even once?
If there was a special class I would
have already heard about it, right?
Something's fishy. Gives me a bad feeling.
Have you arrived?
I have, but what class
were you in second year?
Class 3.
Wow... You are in the same class with us?
I never said I was a kid.
What?
Special Class
Those kids..
They're the kids we saw in the photo
Well...
Is there anything wrong?
Hey, you guys...!
You guys made that weird feed or website or
whatever and threw off the school's atmosphere.
I'm sorry.
It wasn't done with bad intentions.
If our Teacher Bong Gu didn't tell us,
we wouldn't have known there
was a such a website.
Hey. And you, Kang Ye Rim.
Why are you hanging around with this kid?
Ye Rim is... I mean, the Class
President has done nothing wrong.
I was the one who dragged her into this and
I'm also the one who made the website.
Let's just let them off the
hook this time, Teacher Kim.
Teacher Han, I think you
are like a real angel.
Kang Ye Rim, Seo Sang Woo. You
guys won't do this again.
Also close that website.
Okay
But, since we can't just let this go past,
how about we end this with you guys
writing a reflection of a few sentences?
Thank you
Kang Yerim
Hey! Can't you hear?
Don't you feel tired?
To pretend to be kind and
live as a model student?
Don't be surprised
Special Class
Kids...
Why are you here?
The kids that were sitting here yesterday,
where did they all go?
Isn't it time for them all to go home?
Those kids... they aren't real.
You mean like you?
Huh?
Kang Ye Rim... you also aren't
being seen as the real you.
What are you teacher?
Just who in the hell are you?
That's what I wanted to say. Who am I?
What could be your reason
for looking for those kids?
Simply curiosity?
Or responsibility as the Class President?
Since we are classmates.
Is that responsibility?
Kang Ye Rim... I feel that you have
a different voice in your head.
Those actions you're doing
right now seem pretentious.
Is it a "kind-kid" complex?
Get out!
But still no matter how much I want to
talk to him, he might not be available.
This is 881...
I believe that I have a sense of
responsibility over those kids.
The kids chose what they wanted.
Also, they just received the results.
But... what about you?
I...
Kang Ye Rim, what do you really want?
I'm talking about the reason
you want to find those kids.
I am sick of it.
I don't know.
Isn't that why there's something
called a consultation?
The Mirror.
You don't know if you can find what
you're looking for in the mirror.
Also, just in case you're lucky
and find what you're looking for
and get the kids back...
You just have to be back before
all of the sand falls down.
What if I don't?
Then you'll just stay there.
Make your decision.
Will you go back into the mirror?
Or forgetting everything and
going back to the classroom?
I'll do it.
Contract completed.
Kang Ye Rim
Guys
Can't you see me?
Guys! Can't you see here?
Sang Woo. Seo Sang Woo, I'm here.
Seo Sang Woo. I'm right here!
Seo Sang Woo. Can't you see? Seo Sang...
Sang Woo!
Teacher Bong Gu.
Year 2 Class 3
Ye Rim & Sang Woo.
Kang Ye Rim
You.
If anything should happen to me
What? Looks like Teacher isn't
doing a consultation today.
-I really wanted to have a consultation from him.
-Me too.
Ye Rim! Ye Rim!
Did you see Ye Rim?
Where could she be?
Ah, Sang Woo. I heard that Ye
Rim received the consultation.
- Really?
- Yes.
Where are you Kang Yerim?
Seo Sang Woo.
Did you miss me?
Are alone here?
No. The unnies and oppas in the classroom
are scary.
Where is that place?
I don't know where this place is.
What should I do?
Unni, I see you every day.
Me?
I saw it everyday
You looking into the mirror.
You looked sad
I thought that it would be nice
if you could live happily
Living doing whatever you want
No. I am living happily
Lies.
You're not having one bit of fun.
It's like that
Unni, why do you study?
Why do I study? Because I want
to go to a good college and--
Then? What are you going
to be when you grow up?
What do you mean what would I be?
You're a coward. You're
wary of other people.
You don't even know what you're
going to be when you grow up.
Hey where are you going?
Ah. I like it
Okay, okay. Wife, I get that it's good, but
I do think it's better if you come down.
Sang Woo.
If you were going to die
tomorrow, what would you do?
What?
Mr. Seo Sang Woo, if you were going to
die tomorrow, what would you like to do?
I'm not sure. What would I do?
Ditch class and hang out with you all day?
Then what about you Yerim?
Pretty
What this, Kang Yerim
Me?
Ye..Yerim
What you wanted to do was this?
There's a lot more than this, but
let's just enjoy what's now.
Hey let's go together
There... the scary unnies and oppas.
Guys.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Nightmare Teacher Team @ Viki