[Scottish accent]
WELCOME, SIR.
WELCOME TO
THE IMMORTAL HILLS.
THANK YOU.
IT'S ALL BY WAY
OF MAKING YOU FEEL
RIGHT AT HOME, BOBBY.
MR. CHAIRMAN.
COME ALONG, SIR.
AFTER YOU.
THIS IS YOUR PLACE
NOW, YOU KNOW.
OF COURSE, IT
ISN'T AS IF YOU WAS
ANY STRANGER HERE, BOB.
YES, BUT SOMEHOW
THIS PLACE ALL LOOKS
DIFFERENT TO ME.
LIKE I NEVER
SAW IT BEFORE.
WELL, MAYBE I
NEVER HAD TO.
IT'S COLD AS
AN ICEBOX IN HERE.
THAT THING HASN'T
WORKED IN YEARS.
CEMENT, HOLES,
THE WET, YOU KNOW--
IT MAKES THE AIR
A WEE BIT CHRISTMASSY.
WON'T BOTHER YOU ANON
ONCE YOU GET DOWN TO WORK.
I'M NOT SWORN IN YET.
OH, THAT'S ONLY
FOR SHOW, SIR.
NOW, LET ME SEE IF
I'VE GOT THE LIST
OF COMMITTEEMEN RIGHT.
FIRST, CHAIRMAN
ROBERT KRAFT--YOURSELF.
A MR. HONEGGER,
TREASURER,
YOUR UNCLE GEORGE,
SECRETARY,
AND OF COURSE,
MR. TROWBRIDGE
AND MR. BATES,
MAKING 5 IN ALL, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
YOU CAN FIND ME
AT ANY TIME.
MY DWELLING'S STRAIGHT
ACROSS THE BOULEVARD.
OPPOSITE THE GATE.
MAKES IT NICE LIVING
SO CLOSE TO MY WORK.
NOW, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SEE THE SIGHTS, SIR,
GIVE THE ROOF A CHANCE
TO CATCH THE HEAT?
MM-HMM.
IF YOU CARE
TO MAKE A TOUR,
IT'S A BIT
WARMER OUTSIDE.
THAT'S QUITE A MAP.
OH, YES, SIR.
THAT'S A MAP
OF THE ENTIRE
CEMETERY DOWN TO THE
WEEST SPECK OF DUST.
HERE WE ARE,
AND HERE'S MY SHED,
WITH THE ROSE STONE.
AND THERE'S THE
GATE YOU COME IN.
YOU'VE KEPT IT
UP TO DATE.
THERE'S THE NEW
MAUSOLEUM ON
THERE ALREADY.
AYE. OH, YES, SIR.
THIS MAP'S GOING TO
BE A BIG HELP TO YOU.
SUPPOSE YOU GOT THE CUSTOMER
AND YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT GROUND
WE CAN SHOW HIM.
THIS IS WHERE
THE MAP COMES IN.
ONE LOOK, AND
QUICK AS A WINK,
YOU KNOW WHO'S WHERE
AND WHAT'S WHAT.
IT'S THEM PINS THAT
MAKES IT SO EASY.
THE BLACK ONES STAND
FOR THE ONES
THAT IS ALREADY THERE,
AND THE WHITE ONES
FOR THEM
AS HAS MADE
THEIR ARRANGEMENTS
FOR THE FUTURE.
NOW, FOR EXAMPLE--
HERE'S MY PLACE.
LOVELY, ISN'T SHE, BOB?
THERE. SUN IN
THE MORNING, BUT, UH,
IT'S THOSE TREES
THAT GIVE SHADE
IN THE AFTERNOON HEAT.
McKEE, YOU'VE
BEEN ON THIS
JOB NOW 40 YEARS, RIGHT?
AYE.
GUESS THE
COMMITTEE'S RIGHT.
HIGH TIME WE RETIRED YOU.
NOTHING TO WORRY
ABOUT. FULL PENSION.
YOU'LL DRAW THE SAME
CHECK EVERY MONTH.
I'M TO BE PAID FOR
NOTHING FROM NOW ON?
NO. YOU'RE TO BE PAID
FOR 40 YEARS OF DEVOTION.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING.
ANYONE IN MIND
TO REPLACE YOU?
OH, AYE, UH, WHY I HADN'T
A'GIVEN IT MUCH THOUGHT, SIR,
BUT, UH, WHY?
THERE MUST BE PLENTY OF
YOUNG AND HARD-MUSCLE TOUGHS
WHO WOULD GIVE THEIR
EYE TEETH FOR MY SHOES.
IT'S A LOVELY
PLACE TO WORK.
YOU'RE OUTSIDE
NEAR MOTHER EARTH.
WELL, LET ME KNOW
IF, UH, YOU FIND SOMEONE.
OH, AYE, I WILL.
YES, SIR,
THAT'S QUITE A MAP.
PARDON ME, SIR.
I JUST WANTED TO SHOW
YOU WHERE WE KEEP THIS
IN CASE OF EMERGENCIES.
NO NEED TO WORRY, THOUGH--
WE HAVEN'T HAD NONE YET.
[Bell rings]
OH, YOU EXPECTING
VISITORS, SIR?
NO, BUT THAT SOUNDS
LIKE STU DREXEL.
OH, AYE, DREXEL.
AND PRETTY BETH FERRIS.
THEY'RE PROMISED.
LOOKS LIKE
THEY'RE HITCHED.
HA HA HA. SHE FINALLY
CAUGHT ME, BOB.
BETHIE, MANY HAPPY
RETURNS OF THE DAY.
STU, YOU'VE PICKED
A GREAT HONEYMOON PLACE.
OH, MARRIAGE HAS MADE
ME CONSERVATIVE.
HOW ABOUT
IT, MRS. D?
CAN I CARRY YOU OVER
THE THRESHOLD?
I STILL DON'T THINK
IT'S SO VERY FUNNY.
I THINK IT'S POSITIVELY
AWFUL IF YOU WANT
TO KNOW THE TRUTH.
OH, BETHIE,
DON'T BE THAT WAY.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE?
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO GET A CEMETERY PLOT
FOR A WEDDING GIFT?
NOW BETHIE, YOU
KNOW POP NEVER MEANT
IT FOR A PRESENT.
IT'S JUST A FORMAL
LEGAL SORT OF THING.
YOU SEE, DAD LEFT PART
OF MY INHERITANCE
IN TRUST FOR WHEN
I GOT MARRIED.
ONE OF THE PROVISIONS WAS
THAT MYSELF AND MY WIFE
HAD FIRST-CLASS
ACCOMMODATIONS
HERE AT
THE IMMORTAL HILLS.
DOESN'T COST
US A CENT.
BUT WE HAVE TO
BUY THE PLOTS
BEFORE THE BANK WILL
LET ME HAVE THE CASH.
YOU KNOW DAD--
HE NEVER DID
CONSIDER ME MUCH
ON RESPONSIBILITY.
HE WAS A
VERY SMART MAN.
OH, AYE,
THAT HE WAS.
AND THOUGH A
BONNY BRIDE SHOULD
HAVE HER THOUGHTS
FAR FROM DOOM,
IT'S A LUCKY GIRL
WHOSE FATHER-IN-LAW
PROVIDES FROM THE BEYOND
FOR HER FUTURE.
ISN'T HE SWEET?
THANKS, SCOTTY.
BOB, GIVE US A
COUPLE NEAR THE
OLD MAN, WILL YA?
AND CALL OWENS
AT THE BANK
IN THE MORNING,
SO I CAN
CASH A CHECK.
I DON'T THINK
IT'S FUNNY AT ALL.
[Bell rings]
FROM THE LAST
ADMINISTRATION, SIR.
FOLKS GET
A WEE BIT ROCKY
WHEN THEY COME
OUT HERE SOMETIMES.
BEST TO BE PREPARED.
DOWN THE HATCH.
AGH.
THANK YOU.
MMM.
OH. OVER HERE.
THAT'S WHERE
THE DREXEL BUNCH IS.
AH, IT'LL GET SO YOU
LOVE IT OUT HERE, BOBBY.
IT'S A FINE AND GREEN
AND LOVELY PLACE.
A FINE PLACE TO SLIP AWAY
FROM THE CARES OF THE WORLD.
SLIP AWAY AND
LIVE A WEE BIT.
"AS RETIRING CHAIRMAN
"OF THE
IMMORTAL HILLS
MANAGEMENT COMMITTEE--"
GEORGE,
I HAVEN'T GOT--
"IT IS NOW MY
VERY GREAT PLEASURE
"TO ANNOUNCE THE
APPOINTMENT OF ROBERT KRAFT,
"PRESIDENT OF
KRAFT DEPARTMENT STORES--"
NOW GEORGE,
DON'T SHUSH ME.
YOU RAILROADED
ME INTO THIS.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE,
BOB. IT'S YOUR TURN.
LAST YEAR
WAS HIS TURN,
THE YEAR BEFORE
IT WAS MINE.
NOBODY REFUSES TO
TAKE THE CHAIRMANSHIP.
PARDON US, HENRY.
"PRESIDENT OF KRAFT--"
WHY?
NOBODY EVER HAS.
IT'S JUST
NOT DONE, SON.
WELL, CAN YOU GIVE
ME ONE GOOD REASON
WHY I SHOULD TAKE
OVER THE MANAGEMENT
OF A WHOLE
BIG CEMETERY
WHEN I'M UP TO MY NECK
IN MY OWN BUSINESS?
"AS RETIRING--"
HOLD IT.
OF COURSE I CAN.
TRADITION.
PARTICULARLY
FOR US KRAFTS.
YOU ALWAYS HARP ON
DIGNITY, HONOR, PRESTIGE.
WELL, HOW DO YOU
THINK WE GOT IT?
BECAUSE YOUR
GREAT GRANDFATHER,
YOUR GRANDFATHER
AND YOUR FATHER
SERVED ON EVERY
COMMUNITY PROJECT,
BOARD, AND COMMITTEE
THAT WAS EVER CREATED.
THEY SERVED FOR FREE.
BUT THEY DID IT
FOR BUSINESS.
THAT'S WHAT A FINE
FAMILY HAS TO DO
IN THIS TOWN.
AND YOU CAN'T
REFUSE TO DO IT
WITHOUT LOSING
A LOT OF RESPECT
FROM OUR CUSTOMERS.
AND ANOTHER THING--
IT'S JUST NOT DONE.
WELL, PASS ME OVER
UNTIL NEXT YEAR.
I'M UP
TO MY EARS.
BOB, DO YOU REALIZE
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
ONLY A FEW HOURS
A MONTH AT THE MOST?
McKEE, THE CARETAKER,
HANDLES EVERYTHING.
ALL YOU DO IS
SHOW UP ONCE A WEEK
AND SIGN THE CHECKS.
GEORGE,I'VE--
PROCEED, HENRY.
RAISE YOUR
RIGHT HAND.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT
BILL HONEGGER?
RAISE YOUR
RIGHT HAND.
"DO YOU, ROBERT KRAFT,
SWEAR TO DISCHARGE
"THE DUTIES AND
RESPONSIBILITIES
OF THIS OFFICE
"FAITHFULLY
AND COMPLETELY
"TO THE UTMOST
OF YOUR ABILITIES?"
I DO.
CONGRATULATIONS,
BOB. SEE YA.
THANKS,
MR. TROWBRIDGE.
THANK YOU,
UNCLE GEORGE.
UH, OK, MISS
LANE, YOU CAN PUT
THROUGH HIS CALLS NOW.
THANK YOU, MR. WATSON.
I'LL RING HIM FOR YOU NOW.
HELLO.
THERE'S A GUY NAMED
WATSON ON THE PHONE.
SAYS IT'S URGENT.
YOU KNOW HIM?
OF OLDS AND WATSON?
OF OLDS AND
WATSON. YOU KNOW.
OH, THE
UNDERTAKER. SWELL.
HELLO.
WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, MR. WATSON.
I'LL DO THE
BEST JOB I CAN.
AW, YOU'RE KIDDING.
WELL, SIR, UH,
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF IT MYSELF.
I'LL BE THERE
WITHIN AN HOUR.
YES, SIR,
THANK YOU.
WELL, WHAT
ABOUT THIS AD?
IT'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
I'M SORRY.
WELL, NOW,
CALL McKEE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GO
UP THERE EVERY TIME.
THIS IS DIFFERENT.
SOMEBODY PROMINENT?
STU DREXEL
AND HIS WIFE.
STU AND BETHIE.
NO.
HI.
HI, JESS.
McKEE, THIS
IS MR. JESSUP OF
THE  MILFORD HERALD.
HI. JESSUP, JESSUP--
OH, THE WEST SLOPE
BETWEEN THE PATTERSONS
AND THE FINDLEYS.
WHAT ELSE IS NEW?
YOU WERE MY BIG NEWS
FOR THE DAY.
"ASKED ABOUT PLANS
FOR THE COMING YEAR,
"KRAFT REVEALED
THE IMMORTAL HILLS
"WILL INSTALL
A DRIVE-IN BAR
"TO STIMULATE
ADDITIONAL TRADE."
I'M STUCK WITH
THE OBITUARY DETAIL.
BOY, IT'S
COLD IN HERE.
McKEE, LET'S GET
THAT HEAT ON BY
TOMORROW, HUH?
WE'D BETTER GET READY
FOR INTERMENT.
AYE, THAT WILL
BE DONE, SIR.
AND YOU BETTER
CHANGE THE DREXEL PINS.
BLACK INSTEAD
OF WHITE.
OH, THEY ALREADY
GOT BLACK PINS, SIR.
OH? WHO
CHANGED THEM?
WELL, NOW,
THE LAST I REMEMBER
WAS THE VERY DAY
THEY COME OUT HERE
TO GIVE YOU
THE ORDER,
AND YOU
STUCK IN 2 PINS.
YEAH, I GUESS
THAT'S RIGHT.
I MUST HAVE PICKED UP
THE WRONG COLOR.
HMM?
OH, NOTHING.
IT'S JUST A
LITTLE WEIRD,
THAT'S ALL.
WHAT?
WELL, THE KIDS
CAME OUT HERE
RIGHT AFTER THEY
TIED THE KNOT,
AND THEY BOUGHT
A COUPLE OF PLOTS.
STU WAS COMPLYING
WITH SOME
TECHNICALITY
IN HIS TRUST.
AND IT WAS ALL VERY CUTE.
WE HAD A COUPLE OF LAUGHS.
AND AFTERWARDS I JABBED
2 PINS IN THE MAP--
WHITE PINS, I THOUGHT--
JUST TO MAKE IT OFFICIAL.
AND I HEAR TODAY
THEY'VE BEEN KILLED,
AND THE MAP'S HAD THEM ON
THE BLACKLIST ALL THE TIME.
OK, SO WHAT?
NOTHING, IT JUST MADE ME
FEEL A LITTLE EERIE,
THAT'S ALL.
I THINK HE MEANS
HE MARKED THE
YOUNG COUPLE
FOR DEATH, SIR.
YEAH, I GUESS
THAT WAS IT.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
THE FEELING I HAD.
BOY, IT'S FUNNY WHAT'LL
GO THROUGH A GUY'S MIND,
ISN'T IT?
DO ME A
FAVOR, McKEE.
IF HE STARTS
FOOLING AROUND
WITH THOSE
PINS AGAIN,
BE SURE HE STAYS AWAY
FROM THE WEST SLOPE,
BETWEEN THE
PATTERSONS AND
THE FINDLEYS.
INDEED I
WILL, SIR.
HI, ANNIE, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING OUT HERE?
I HAD A LUNCHEON DATE,
BUT I WAS STOOD UP.
[Jeesup]
I KNOW A NICE LITTLE
PLACE DOWN THE STREET.
I JUST MIGHT
TAKE YOU UP ON THAT.
I WON'T
HOLD MY BREATH.
OHH.
GEORGE TOLD ME
ABOUT BETH AND STUART,
AND I JUST
HAD TO SEE YOU.
MADE ME THINK
HOW LUCKY WE ARE
JUST TO BE ALIVE
AND TOGETHER.
[Engine starts]
OH, ANN,
THIS IS MR. McKEE.
THIS IS MISS CRAIG,
MY FIANCE, ANDY.
MISS.
HOW DO YOU DO?
WOULD YOU BE
WANTING ME
FOR ANYTHING
ELSE, BOBBY?
NO, THANKS, ANDY.
BOB.
HMM?
WHAT'S WRONG?
OH, NOTHING. I'M JUST
A LITTLE DEPRESSED,
THAT'S ALL, BUT YOU'LL
TAKE CARE OF THAT.
ANN, I KEPT
WISHING WE COULD
KEEP OUR APPOINTMENT.
OH, RENDEZVOUS,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
YOUR GRAY FLANNEL
IS SHOWING.
ACTUALLY, DO YOU KNOW
WHAT MADE ME TURN AROUND
AND COME HERE INSTEAD
OF GOING HOME?
MMM.
WELL, I WAS DRIVING
ALONG, FEELING REJECTED,
AND THEN ALL OF
A SUDDEN I SAW YOU
VERY CLEARLY
IN MY MIND.
BOB, IT'S JUST THAT
YOU'RE TOO ATTRACTIVE.
AFTER ALL, PRESIDENT
OF A DEPARTMENT STORE
AND IN CHARGE
OF THE IMMORTAL HILLS.
IRRESISTIBLE.
I SAW YOU,
AND I HEARD YOU--
"LUNCHTIME, ANNIE."
THAT'S WHAT YOU
SAID DISTINCTLY.
"LUNCHTIME, ANNIE"?
WELL, I CAN DO BETTER
THAN THAT, I HOPE.
OH, YOU DID.
YOU SAID...
"I WANT YOU,
AND I NEED YOU" AND...
AND A WHOLE LOT
OF LOVELY THINGS
I'D BE EMBARRASSED
TO REPEAT.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW,
JUST ABOUT THE TIME
YOU WERE SEEING ME,
I HAD YOU IN MY MIND.
THAT'S AMAZING.
NO, I MEAN IT.
AND I DON'T BLAME YOU
FOR NOT WANTING TO REPEAT
WHAT I WAS THINKING.
OHH.
DARLING, WE BETTER
GO TO LUNCH,
OR GET MARRIED.
OR I CAN JUST AS
EASILY JOIN JESS
AT THAT LITTLE SPOT
DOWN THE ROAD
HE SPOKE OF.
WE REGRET THAT MANAGEMENT
DOES NOT PERMIT EXCHANGES
ONCE THE MERCHANDISE
HAS BEEN PURCHASED.
[Kisses]
THEN I'LL FRESHEN UP.
[Door opens and closes]
[Telephone ringing]
IMMORTAL HILLS,
KRAFT.
HI, CARL.
NO, TERRIBLE.
NO, I'M SORRY.
THE FUNERAL'S BEEN
CONFINED TO THE
IMMEDIATE FAMILY.
YEAH, ALL RIGHT, CARL.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
NO, NOT--
OH, ANN, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WHAT?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE ARE LUCKY TO...
LUCKY TO BE ALIVE AND...
WITH EACH OTHER.
COME ON.
[Music box plays
Three Blind Mice ]
[Gasps]
HEIGH HO
NOBODY HOME
EAT NOR DRINK
NOR MONEY HAVE I NONE
STILL I WILL
[Car approaches]
HEY, BOBBY.
BE HAPPY
HEIGH HO
AH.
I PICKED THIS
DREXEL STONE FOR CLASS.
FINE AND RICH
AND SWIRLY.
I'M A GRANITE
MAN MYSELF.
BOBBY! BOBBY!
I'VE GOT A SURPRISE FOR YOU--
YOU FOUND
YOUR REPLACEMENT.
OH, WELL, NO,
NO, NOT YET,
BUT I'M SCOUTING
THE COUNTRYSIDE.
THIS IS FAR SWEETER.
[Andy]
THIS IS WHAT I CALL
GETTING THINGS DONE.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD HAVE
BEEN AN EXECUTIVE.
[Both laugh]
UHH.
HEY, BEST TAKE OFF
YOUR COAT, BOBBY.
YOU'LL BE GETTING
OVERHEATED.
FAIRLY QUIET
THIS WEEK.
ONLY ONE PASSING.
NOW, IF YOU'LL
JUST SIGN THESE.
LET'S GET RID
OF THESE FLOWERS.
OH, AYE, THEY SMELL
A WEE BIT SICKLY.
I WAS HOPING
TO KEEP THEM
FOR THE BURIAL
THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU NEED MUCH HELP?
OH, NO. THIS IS JUST
AN AVERAGE FUNERAL.
THEY DON'T COME LIKE
THE DREXEL DOINGS
EVERY DAY,
THANK THE LORD.
McKEE, THIS BILL
FOR W. ISHAM,
WHAT IS IT FOR?
WHY, HE'S THE LAD FOR
THIS AFTERNOON, BOBBY.
OH, NO NEED
TO LOOK SO SAD.
WILL ISHAM WAS
THE SAME AGE LAD AS ME.
OH, THERE'S SOMETHING
I'VE BEEN MEANING
TO TELL YOU.
MIGHTY QUEER
IT STRIKES ME, BUT...
I WENT TO THE MAP
JUST AFTER
WE GOT THE NEWS
TO CHANGE WILL
ISHAM'S PIN TO BLACK.
IT WAS ALREADY BLACK.
LOOKS LIKE THERE
MIGHT BE SOMETHING...
CREEPY ABOUT THAT MAP.
CHANGING PIN COLORS
WITHOUT HUMAN
ASSISTANCE, NO LESS.
I CHANGED
MR. ISHAM'S PIN, ANDY.
YOU--BUT, BOB,
YOU HAVE NOT BEEN HERE
SINCE HE DIED.
JESSUP, PLEASE.
I KNOW. I CHANGED HIS PIN
BEFORE HE DIED, NOT AFTER.
JESS, IT'S BOB KRAFT.
CAN YOU COME OVER
HERE RIGHT AWAY?
NO, I'M AT
THE CEMETERY.
THAT MAP'S NOTHING BUT
AN OLD PIECE OF PAPER
HANGING ON THE WALL.
ALL YOU DO WHEN YOU
STICK PINS IN IT
IS TO MAKE HOLES
IN THE PAPER.
WHITE PINS, BLACK
PINS, SAFETY PINS.
IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE, SEE?
WELL, LOOK,
IT'S UNFORTUNATE
THAT IT WORKED
OUT THIS WAY,
BUT COINCIDENCE IS
A PART OF EVERYDAY LIFE.
SOME ARE FUNNY,
SOME ARE PRETTY ODD,
BUT THIS ONE ISN'T
EVEN GOOD ENOUGH
TO MAKE THE BACK PAGE
OF THE SHOPPING NEWS.
THAT'S ALL IT IS,
BOB--COINCIDENCE.
YEAH.
YOU'RE RIGHT, JESS.
THANKS.
THAT'S OK.
SOMETIME WHEN I'VE TIED
ON A REAL HEAD-BENDER,
YOU CAN DO THE
SAME FOR ME.
WHAT'S YOUR TROUBLE?
WELL, NOTHING,
BUT I'VE...
BEEN THROUGH
ALL THIS BEFORE.
THE GRASS AND THE QUIET.
[Faint clang]
AND THAT SOUND.
I NEVER KNEW WHAT IT WAS.
IT'S THE SOUND OF A NAME
BEING CUT INTO A HEADSTONE.
YEAH, I'VE-I'VE HEARD
OF PEOPLE WHO THOUGHT
THEY'D BEEN THROUGH
THE SAME BIT BEFORE
IN THEIR DREAMS.
I THINK IT'S EVEN
HAPPENED TO ME.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
IF I TOLD YOU
THIS HAPPENS TO
ME REGULARLY,
EVER SINCE
I WAS A CHILD,
SOMETIMES AS OFTEN
AS EVERY OTHER WEEK?
I'D SAY YOU
WERE SENSITIVE
OR EXAGGERATING.
"3rd-FLOOR SPORTSWEAR--
$9,280 GROSS."
COMPARED TO $8,500
AT THE SAME DATE LAST YEAR.
HMM.
BASEMENT SPORTSWEAR--
[Bangs desk]
I'M GONNA CALL
BATES AND HONEGGER
AND TROWBRIDGE
RIGHT NOW,
AND TELL THEM
I'M QUITTING.
DON'T WORRY, GEORGE.
NOTHING DRASTIC WILL
HAPPEN TO THE STORE.
MY MIND'S MADE UP.
YOU MEAN MIXED UP.
I'VE LIVED IN MILFORD
ALL MY LIFE,
AND I CAN'T
REMEMBER ANY MAN
WHO EVER LET THAT PLACE
GET THE BETTER OF HIM.
WHY, WHEN I
WAS CHAIRMAN,
I'LL BET I STUCK
THE WRONG COLORED PINS
IN THAT THING
A DOZEN TIMES.
IF I RAN OUT
OF ONE COLOR,
I-I USED THE OTHER.
YOU'VE ONLY BEEN DOWN
THERE A COUPLE OF TIMES.
GEORGE, I PUT BLACK
PINS IN THE MAP
FOR THE DREXEL COUPLE
THE DAY THEY WERE KILLED.
NOW, I DIDN'T THINK ANYTHING
OF IT AT THE TIME.
AND THEN I TOOK A WHITE PIN
OUT OF THE MAP,
QUITE AT RANDOM,
AND I PUT A BLACK PIN
IN ITS PLACE,
AND TODAY I FIND OUT
THE OLD MAN IT BELONGED TO
DIED DURING THE WEEK.
[Laughs]
BOB, THAT'S TERRIBLE.
FOR HEAVEN'S SAKE, BOB,
EVERYBODY LOVES
A GHOST STORY.
WHERE'S YOUR SENSE
OF HUMOR?
YOU DON'T REALLY
BELIEVE THAT STUFF
YOU'RE TELLING ME,
DO YOU?
NO.
BUT I STILL THINK
I MAY BE LEARNING SOMETHING
ABOUT MYSELF.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
OH, I THINK I'LL JUST TAKE
A RUN OUT TO THE CEMETERY.
WHAT FOR?
SOUNDS LIKE
IT MIGHT BE FUN.
AFTER ALL, I'VE BEEN
TRYING TO FIND SOME WAY
TO WIPE OUT OUR
COMPETITION FOR YEARS.
[Laughs]
GOOD NIGHT, GEORGE.
[Door slams]
WANT TO TAKE MY CAR?
ALL RIGHT.
[Andy]
WON'T BE
BUT A MOMENT, SIR.
[George]
NO, DON'T BOTHER, McKEE.
I THINK I'VE GOT IT.
OH, THAT'LL
BE ALL, McKEE.
IS EVERYTHING
ALL RIGHT, BOBBY?
WE'LL SEE
YOU LATER, ANDY.
WELL, THE PLACE
HASN'T CHANGED A BIT
SINCE I WAS CHAIRMAN.
A FEW MORE PINS
IN THE MAP.
BLACK ONES.
WHITE ONES, TOO.
SIT DOWN
AND RELAX, BOB.
I THINK I CAN GET
THIS WHOLE THING
CLEARED UP FOR YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
I'M GOING
TO CONVINCE YOU
THAT THERE'S NOTHING
OUT HERE
FOR YOU TO WORRY ABOUT.
GEORGE,
LET'S FORGET THIS.
UH, BOB.
I SAID I'M JUST GOING
TO CONVINCE YOU.
WELL, GEORGE,
SUPPOSE YOU TOOK HENRY
TROWBRIDGE'S WHITE PIN OUT
AND PUT A BLACK ONE
IN ITS PLACE
AND TOMORROW MORNING
HE TURNED UP DEAD.
NOT A CHANCE.
WELL, I KNOW
NOT A CHANCE,
BUT SUPPOSE BY SOME
WEIRD COINCIDENCE
IT HAPPENED.
NOW, IT'S HAPPENED TO ME
3 TIMES ALREADY.
I DEAL STRICTLY
IN FACTS, SON.
I DON'T GO FOR
THIS COINCIDENCE BUNK.
BUT IF HENRY TROWBRIDGE
EVEN LOOKS A LITTLE
PEAKY TOMORROW,
YOU CAN RESIGN,
AND I'LL BACK YOU UP.
NOW, HENRY TROWBRIDGE--
LET ME SEE
IF I REMEMBER.
GEORGE, I JUST MENTIONED
HENRY AS AN EXAMPLE.
NOW, YOU'RE NOT
GONNA USE HIM.
WHY, HENRY'S AS GOOD
A CHOICE AS ANYBODY,
CONSIDERING HE DIRECTLY
PRECEDED YOU
AS COMMITTEE CHAIRMAN.
WAIT A MINUTE, GEORGE.
YOU BETTER LET ME
PUT THE PIN IN.
IF YOU DO THE HONORS
AND NOTHING HAPPENS,
IT WON'T BE QUITE
AS CONCLUSIVE.
BY ALL MEANS.
LET'S NOT DIVERGE FROM
THE ESTABLISHED PATTERN.
BUT I'LL HAVE YOU KNOW
I WAS NO SLOUCH
WHEN IT CAME TO PINNING
THE TAIL ON THE DONKEY
WHEN I WAS A KID.
UH, NO REFLECTION ON HENRY.
GO AHEAD, BOB.
YOU BETTER CALL HENRY
AND TELL HIM WHAT WE DID.
HE'D ONLY THINK
WE WERE KIDDING.
NO, HE'D BELIEVE YOU.
THEN HE'D CALL
MY PHYSICIAN,
AND HE'D RESERVE A NICE,
QUIET ROOM FOR ME
AT PROVIDENCE HOSPITAL.
LET'S KEEP THIS
QUIET, MY BOY.
HENRY CAN'T COMPLAIN.
AFTER ALL, IF HIS TERM
HAD RUN A WEEK OR SO LONGER,
HE MIGHT BE HAVING
THE WILLIES INSTEAD OF YOU.
[Laughs]
[Door closes]
HELLO, MRS. TROWBRIDGE,
THIS IS BOB KRAFT.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING UP SO LATE?
UH, NOTHING SERIOUS.
UH, I JUST MEANT
TO CALL HENRY EARLIER,
AND, UH, IT
SLIPPED MY MIND.
UH, PUT HIM ON,
WILL YOU?
OH, IF HE'S WATCHING
A MOVIE AND ENJOYING IT,
UH, ASK HIM TO CALL ME BACK
DURING THE COMMERCIAL.
NO, NO, BOB.
JUST HOLD ON
AND I'LL GET HIM.
HE'S UPSTAIRS
READING IN BED,
BUT I'M SURE
HE'S NOT ASLEEP.
WELL, I HATE
TO DISTURB HIM.
YOU JUST HOLD
THE WIRE, BOB.
[Clock ticks]
[Heavy breath
from telephone]
HELLO, HENRY?
[Sobs]
OH, HE'S...
HE'S NOT BREATHING, BOB.
I'VE GOT TO CALL A DOCTOR.
I UNDERSTAND.
I'LL HANG UP
RIGHT AWAY.
[Click]
I'M...
TERRIBLY SORRY.
HEIGH HO
NOBODY HOME
EAT NOR DRINK
NOR MONEY--
WAIT HERE.
THIS WON'T
TAKE LONG.
GOOD MORNING.
HOW DO YOU DO, SIR?
WELL, I DON'T
UNDERSTAND IT.
JESS SAID HE'D BE HERE
IN 20 MINUTES.
[Man]
I'M SURE HE'S ON HIS WAY.
LIEUTENANT CLAIBORNE.
SO THAT'S IT, HUH?
IT'S SURE BIG ENOUGH.
THERE ARE THE
BLACK PINS, EH?
WE'RE, UH,
PARTICULARLY CONCERNED
WITH THESE 4.
ISHAM, AND
THE DREXEL COUPLE
AND NOW TROWBRIDGE.
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT,
MR. KRAFT.
YOU SAY THAT EVERY TIME
YOU STICK A BLACK PIN
IN THE MAP,
PEOPLE TURN UP DEAD?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL, GO AHEAD,
LIEUTENANT.
YOU THINK I'M A CRACKPOT,
AND I HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT.
I JUST WANT TO PROVE IT
BEYOND A REASONABLE DOUBT.
"STUART AND ELIZABETH DREXEL.
"D.O.A. EMERGENCY,
RECEIVING HOSPITAL.
"RESULT OF HIGHWAY COLLISION.
"WILLIAM ISHAM,
CAUSE OF DEATH--
"CEREBRAL HEMORRHAGE.
"HENRY TROWBRIDGE--
CORONARY THROMBOSIS."
WELL, THE RULE IS THIS--
WHERE NO EVIDENCE
OF HOMICIDE EXISTS
ON INITIAL
INVESTIGATION,
THE MATTER
WILL BE DROPPED.
INVESTIGATED
AND FOUND NOTHING.
SORRY.
[Door opens]
JESSUP.
WHAT'S NEW,
OR SHOULD I SAY REAL?
NOTHING LIKE MURDER,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE AFTER.
I'M SORRY BOB
SAW FIT TO DISTURB
YOU, LIEUTENANT.
NO HARM DONE.
WHAT DO YOU
MAKE OF IT, JESS?
I KEEP TELLING
HIM IT'S JUST
COINCIDENCE.
YEAH.
IF I WERE
YOU, MR. KRAFT,
I'D TAKE A
WEEK OR 2 OFF,
TAKE IT EASY.
YOU'LL FORGET
ALL ABOUT IT.
IF YOU'RE GONNA
USE THIS STORY,
KINDLY REFRAIN FROM
MENTIONING MY NAME.
I KNOW.
LIEUTENANT
CLAIBORNE, WITH AN
"E" ON THE END.
[Door opens and closes]
BOY...
DIDN'T THINK 4 DEATHS
COULD APPEAR SO FLIMSY
TO A POLICEMAN.
YOU NEVER SHOULD HAVE
CALLED THE POLICE.
CLAIBORNE'S ONE
OF THE BEST.
ANY OTHER GUY
MIGHT HAVE LOOKED
FOR A BIG HEAVY BOOK
TO THROW AT YOU.
YEAH.
MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
MAYBE THAT THING'S DANGEROUS.
REALLY DANGEROUS.
OR MAYBE THE ELEMENT
OF DANGER IS IN A MAN.
IN ME.
BOB.
IS THERE SOMETHING
DIFFERENT ABOUT ME, JESS?
I'M REALLY BEGINNING
TO WONDER.
HEY, BUDDY,
IF THERE IS ANYTHING
TO THIS MAP BIT,
DON'T GO BLAMING IT
ON NAMELESS FORCES.
MAYBE SOMEBODY'S
TRYING TO SCARE YOU.
COULD BE YOU GOT
AN ENEMY OR 2?
SOMEBODY USING
YOUR DESK, GEORGE?
OH. HE CAME
IN TO KEEP ME
COMPANY, DARLING.
THAT WAS VERY
SWEET OF HIM.
OH, DARLING,
YOU MUST BE DEAD TIRED.
I'M ALL RIGHT, ANN.
NO SLEEP AND THEN
TO HAVE TO GO BACK
OUT THERE AGAIN--
I'M ALL RIGHT!
THERE'S NO CRIME
IN NEEDING
A GOOD REST.
GEORGE, I'VE GOT
SOME CORRESPONDENCE
TO TAKE CARE OF.
I'VE ALREADY
TAKEN CARE
OF YOUR MAIL.
AND I TOOK THE
LIBERTY OF MAKING
RESERVATIONS FOR YOU.
FLIGHT 33
LEAVING FOR
MIAMI AT 5:45.
MY PAL SANFORD
OWNS ONE OF THE
FINEST HOTELS
ON THE BEACH--
GEORGE,
THANKS ANYWAY.
THERE'S NOTHING
I'D RATHER DO,
BUT I CAN'T
POSSIBLY GO NOW.
BOB, I GAVE
YOU MY WORD
THAT IF ANYTHING
HAPPENED TO HENRY
YOU COULD RESIGN.
I TALKED TO CHARLIE
AND BILL HONEGGER,
AND THEY UNDERSTAND
COMPLETELY.
IT'S ALL FIXED, SON.
THE SITUATION'S
CHANGED.
UNTIL THIS THING'S
CLEARED UP,
I'M NOT ABOUT
TO RESIGN.
OH.
NOW, WILL YOU
TELL THE OTHERS?
ASK THEM TO
MEET ME HERE IN MY
OFFICE 7:30 TONIGHT.
AWFULLY
SHORT NOTICE.
THE COMMITTEE
CAN'T JUST IGNORE
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
I GUESS
YOU'RE RIGHT.
DARLING.
ANN, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO SNAP AT YOU.
NOW, WHY CAN'T
YOU RESIGN?
WELL, BECAUSE...
POSSIBLY SOMETHING
REAL, UNREAL--
I DON'T KNOW--
IS WAITING
TO KILL ONE OF US
EVERY TIME I JAB
A BLACK PIN
INTO THAT MAP.
BOB, IF YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT
HENRY TROWBRIDGE,
THE POOR MAN DIED
OF A HEART ATTACK.
HEART DISEASE
IS THE COUNTRY'S
NO. ONE KILLER.
MAYBE NOT
IN MILFORD.
OH, BOB, YOU CAN'T MEAN
THAT THAT MAP
IS LITERALLY
KILLING PEOPLE?
NO, ANN,
MAYBE IT
ISN'T THE MAP.
WHAT ABOUT
THE OTHER DAY?
YOU SAW ME,
YOU HEARD ME--
"LUNCHTIME, ANNIE.
I WANT YOU. I NEED YOU."
BOB, I WAS
OBVIOUSLY TRYING TO
BRING A LITTLE--
A LITTLE ROMANCE
INTO OUR VERY DULL
AND DISMAL LIVES.
NO, ANN, DON'T TRY
TO DENY IT NOW.
I DO DENY IT.
BOB, I LOVE YOU. I'M--
I'M NOT IN ANY SORT
OF OCCULT THRALL TO YOU.
HEY.
CAN'T YOU TAKE A JOKE?
ALL RIGHT, THEN,
I WAS LYING, TOO.
DOES THAT BRING YOU BACK
TO REALITY AGAIN?
BOB?
I THINK WE BETTER
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF...
OF THOSE PLANE TICKETS.
GEORGE'S MR. SANFORD
COULD BE BEST MAN.
THE OFFER'S
AWFULLY ATTRACTIVE.
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
ANN, IF YOU'RE
GONNA CRY,
DO IT SOMEPLACE ELSE.
[Door slams]
NOW, BOB,
IT'S REAL SIMPLE.
WE'RE WILLING
TO PLAY
BALL WITH YOU.
IF YOU WANT TO
REMAIN CHAIRMAN
OF THIS COMMITTEE,
WE WOULDN'T
THINK OF TRYING
TO DISSUADE YOU,
'CAUSE WE HAVE
CONFIDENCE IN YOU.
FULL CONFIDENCE.
ALL THE CONFIDENCE
IN THE WORLD, BOB.
NOW, ALL WE WANT
BEFORE WE
BREAK THIS UP
IS A PROMISE
FROM YOU,
MR. CHAIRMAN,
THAT BEFORE YOU
TURN IN TONIGHT,
YOU GO OUT TO THE CEMETERY--
NOW, LET ME FINISH.
YOU GO OUT THERE
AND CHANGE MY
WHITE PIN TO BLACK,
CHARLIE'S AND GEORGE'S.
JUST AS SIMPLE AS THAT.
AND THEN GO HOME
AND GO RIGHT TO BED.
NO, SIR.
YOU'RE NOT
THE COMMITTEE, BOB.
YOU'RE ONLY
OUR CHAIRMAN
WITH THE DUTY
TO CARRY OUT THE WILL
OF THE MAJORITY.
WE FEEL THAT YOU
SHOULD DO AS BILL SAID,
BECAUSE IT'LL PUT
AN END TO THIS BUSINESS
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
OTHERWISE,
WE'LL DO THE RESIGNING
RIGHT HERE AND NOW.
WELL, LET
ME SLEEP ON IT.
LET'S ALL SLEEP ON IT.
I DON'T THINK
YOU PEOPLE REALIZE
WHAT MIGHT
BE INVOLVED HERE.
MOTION DEFEATED.
GOOD NIGHT.
WELL, YOUR DEVOTION
TO THE PRINCIPLE
OF MAJORITY RULE
MOVES ME DEEPLY.
OK.
THEN GOOD NIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, CHARLIE.
HERE GOES NOTHING, GEORGE.
[Knock at door]
WHO IS IT?
[Andy]
IT'S ME, BOBBY.
OPEN UP.
I SEEN YOUR CAR LIGHTS
FROM MY WINDOW
DRIVING THROUGH THE GATES,
SO I COME RUNNIN'.
YOU NEEDN'T HAVE
BOTHERED, McKEE.
YOU PUT IN A FULL DAY.
NOW, I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
N-NO, NO.
B-BOBBY, PLEASE.
BOBBY, LISTEN.
WHEN YOU LOCKED
AND BOLTED THIS PLACE,
I SAID TO MYSELF,
"NOW, THERE'S A MAN
WHO KNOWS HIS BUSINESS."
THAT'S WHAT I SAID.
"HE MAY NOT KNOW
EVERYTHING BEHIND IT,
"BUT HE KNOWS
WHEN A THING'S
TO BE FOOLED WITH
"AND WHEN IT'S
TO BE LEFT ALONE.
"THERE'S NOTHING
TO FEAR WITH A MAN
LIKE BOBBY KRAFT
"AT THE WHEEL."
THAT'S WHAT I SAID.
WELL, THAT'S FINE. NOW,
YOU RUN ALONG HOME
AND DON'T WORRY
ABOUT A THING.
NOTHING'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO YOU.
N-NO. PLEASE.
BOBBY, LOCK THIS
DOOR AGAIN AND
SEND YOURSELF HOME,
OR ELSE, WHO CAN ANSWER
FOR WHAT MAY HAPPEN
TO THE WHOLE MISERABLE
LOT OF US?
WE'LL HAVE TO BE
OPEN SOMETIME.
IF I DON'T DO IT,
THEY'LL GET
SOMEBODY WHO WILL.
GOOD NIGHT, ANDY.
GOOD NIGHT.
[Telephone ringing]
ANDY, GO HOME.
[Man]
HELLO?
IS THIS THE IMMORTAL
HILLS CEMETERY?
WHAT DO YOU WANT, JESS?
BOB, WHY DIDN'T
YOU ANSWER ME?
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
ALL OVER TOWN FOR YOU.
I'M CALLING
FROM YOUR PLACE NOW.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
AT THE COTTAGE AGAIN?
HAVEN'T YOU HAD ENOUGH
FOR ONE DAY?
JESS, I THINK I'VE DONE
SOMETHING TERRIBLY WRONG.
FOR THE LOVE OF PETE,
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WELL, WE HAD A MEETING
OF THE CEMETERY COMMITTEE
AFTER CLOSING TONIGHT.
BILL HONEGGER,
CHARLIE BATES,
AND GEORGE, EVERYBODY.
AND THEY VOTED
TO MAKE ME
COME OUT HERE
TO THE CEMETERY
AND STICK BLACK PINS
IN THE MAP FOR EACH
OF THEM,
JUST LIKE IT WAS
SOME KID'S NIGHTMARE.
SO I DID IT.
JESS, THERE'S
A BLACK PIN
IN THAT MAP
FOR CHARLIE BATES
AND BILL HONEGGER
AND GEORGE.
AND IF ANYTHING
HAPPENS TO THEM,
TO ANY OF THEM,
IT'S MY FAULT,
NOBODY ELSE'S.
NOTHING'S GOING TO
HAPPEN TO THEM, BOB.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I THINK THEY DID YOU
A BIG FAVOR.
I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF A COINCIDENCE
INVOLVING 3 PEOPLE
DYING ALL AT ONCE.
BY TOMORROW AT THIS TIME,
THIS WHOLE BIG WORRY OF YOURS
WILL BE NOTHING
BUT A LOT OF HOT AIR.
YEAH.
WELL, I HOPE
YOU'RE RIGHT, JESS.
I GUESS THERE'S
NOTHING FOR ME TO DO
BUT SEE THIS THING
THROUGH, HUH?
I THINK I'LL CHECK ON 'EM
MYSELF AND SEE--
[Click]
BOB?
HONEGGER, BATES,
AND GEORGE.
6-6-6.
[Line ringing]
[Man]
DESK.
LIEUTENANT CLAIBORNE,
PLEASE.
HOMICIDE.
THIS IS HOMICIDE.
SGT. GREER.
LIEUTENANT CLAIBORNE,
PLEASE.
NOT HERE.
CAN I TAKE A MESSAGE?
SERGEANT, UH,
THIS IS BOB KRAFT,
KRAFT DEPARTMENT STORE.
OH, SURE.
WAIT A SECOND.
WAIT A SECOND
AND I'LL CHECK FOR YOU.
UH, MR. KRAFT,
ARE YOU CALLING
ABOUT POLICE MATTERS
OR IS IT JUST
SOMETHING PERSONAL?
WELL, UH, IT'S A LITTLE BIT
OF BOTH, SERGEANT.
TRY HIM AT
ADAMS 1-3-1-1.
THANK YOU.
[Busy signal]
ADAMS 1-3-1-1.
BILL HONEGGER,
ADAMS 1...
[Man]
DESK.
YEAH, HOMICIDE.
YES, SIR.
[Sergeant]
HOMICIDE.
THIS IS BOB KRAFT SPEAKING.
I CAN'T GET THROUGH
TO THAT ADAMS NUMBER.
SO?
CLAIBORNE'S AT THAT NUMBER
AND IT'S IMPERATIVE
THAT I SPEAK TO HIM
RIGHT NOW.
WELL, SIR, UH--
JUST A SECOND, SIR.
I THINK HE'S REPORTING
IN ON ANOTHER LINE.
I'VE BEEN TRYING YOU,
BUT YOUR LINES ARE BUSY.
HANG UP AND I'LL CALL
YOU BACK RIGHT AWAY.
[Telephone ringing]
SOMETHING HAPPENED
TO BILL HONEGGER.
HELLO?
IT'S JESSUP.
JESS, UH, I'M EXPECTING
A CALL FROM CLAIBORNE.
HE, UH--HANG UP,
CALL ME BACK IN 10 MINUTES.
CLAIBORNE'S WITH ME.
LET ME TALK TO HIM.
HE'S NOT HERE NOW. HE'S--
WHAT'S WRONG, JESS?
BILL HONEGGER'S DEAD.
SOON AS I FOUND OUT,
I ROUTED CLAIBORNE
OUT OF THE SACK
AND FILLED HIM IN ON
THE WHOLE WILD STORY.
WE WERE OVER AT HONEGGER'S
IN 10 MINUTES
WITH 2 SQUAD CARS DETAILED
TO COVER CHARLIE BATES
AND YOUR UNCLE.
HOW DID HONEGGER GET IT?
HE DIDN'T.
THAT'S THE TROUBLE.
WHAT?
POOR GUY JUST
DROPPED DEAD.
NOTHING OUT OF
THE ORDINARY?
BATES? CHARLIE BATES?
THEY FOUND HIM
IN HIS APARTMENT.
SAY IT.
NO HOMICIDE.
JUST STOPPED BREATHING.
GEORGE?
GEORGE, YEAH...
I CALLED AND TOLD HIM
ABOUT HONEGGER
BEFORE I LEFT
FOR CLAIBORNE'S.
BY THE TIME
THE POLICE GOT THERE,
GEORGE HAD ALREADY LEFT.
THEY'LL FIND HIM, BOB.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE WAITING FOR
WORD ABOUT GEORGE.
LET ME KNOW.
[Door opens]
WELL, BOB,
I SEE YOU FOLLOWED
OUR WISHES TO THE LETTER.
COME ON, NOW.
I'LL DRIVE YOU HOME
BEFORE YOU CATCH PNEUMONIA.
YOU 3 MEN MADE
A TERRIBLE CONTRIBUTION
TO THIS TOWN
TONIGHT WHETHER YOU
MEANT TO OR NOT.
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE,
UNCLE GEORGE.
I'M STAYING RIGHT HERE.
WELL, I'LL--
I'LL ADMIT THAT, UH...
WHAT WITH, UH,
CHARLIE AND BILL
GOING SO SUDDENLY--
AND HENRY
AND ISHAM
AND BETH AND STU.
STOP LOOKING
AT THE MAP.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT IT.
I'M LOOKING AT YOU.
WE'RE BOTH WAITING,
AREN'T WE, UNCLE GEORGE?
WAITING TO SEE
IF YOU ESCAPE.
ESCAPE DYING?
NOBODY ESCAPES
THAT, MY BOY.
THE ONLY QUESTION
IS HOW LONG?
THE ONLY QUESTION IS
DOES A MAN DIE
ON HIS OWN TIME
OR ON THE MAP'S?
SO FAR, EVERYONE'S
BEEN FORCED TO CONFORM
TO ITS SCHEDULE.
EVERYONE BUT YOU.
THAT PUTS ME BACK
ON SCHEDULE.
MY OWN SCHEDULE.
IF IT MAKES YOU
FEEL ANY BETTER.
LET ME TELL
YOU SOMETHING--
FROM NOW ON,
IF YOU WANT TO SEE ME,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
COME DOWN TO THE STORE.
I WON'T MAKE
ANOTHER SPECIAL TRIP
ON YOUR ACCOUNT.
THE NEXT TIME
I SEE YOU, GEORGE,
WE'LL BOTH BE
RIGHT HERE.
[Engine starts]
[Man]
DESK.
HOMICIDE.
THIS IS ROBERT KRAFT
OUT AT IMMORTAL HILLS.
CLAIBORNE SPEAKING.
LIEUTENANT,
MY UNCLE JUST LEFT HERE.
I THINK UNDER
THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
IS PUT A MAN ON
TO WATCH OVER HIM,
NO MATTER HOW RIDICULOUS
THE SITUATION
SEEMS TO YOU.
THANKS A LOT,
MR. KRAFT.
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF IT
RIGHT AWAY.
HE'S WEARING AN OVERCOAT
OVER HIS ROBE AND PAJAMAS.
WE PUT A DESCRIPTION
ON THE WIRE
QUITE SOME TIME AGO.
THEN YOU DO THINK
THERE'S DANGER.
SERGEANT,
KRAFT, GEORGE M.,
DRIVING EAST
ON BUNKER HILL.
PROBABLE DESTINATION,
MANOR APARTMENTS...
WE'LL HAVE YOUR UNCLE
SAFE AND SOUND
IN 10 MINUTES,
MR. KRAFT.
YOU'LL HEAR FROM ME.
[Telephone ringing]
[Line ringing]
ARE YOU SURE YOUR UNCLE
WAS OUT THERE TONIGHT?
YOU DIDN'T JUST
THINK YOU SAW HIM?
[Bob]
I TOLD YOU
HE JUST LEFT HERE.
THAT WAS 2 HOURS AGO AND
NO SIGN OF HIM ANYPLACE.
PUT OUT AN ALL-POINTS
AFTER THE FIRST HOUR.
HE'S NOT ON THE ROAD
AND HE'S NOT HOME.
HOLD THE WIRE,
LIEUTENANT.
[Car engine idles]
[Door creaks]
[Door slams]
[Bob]
YOU BETTER COME OUT,
LIEUTENANT.
HE'S STILL HERE.
[Hangs up phone]
WHERE HA'E YOU
BEEN ALL THE DAY?
RENDAL, MY SON
WHERE HA'E YOU
BEEN ALL THE DAY?
ANDY!
SOMEONE
I BEEN OUT HUNTIN',
MOTHER
MAKE MY BED SOFT,
MAKE MY BED SOON
FOR I'M SICK--
ANDY!
McKEE, I'M GONNA
BURN THAT STUFF
IN THE GREENHOUSE
IF THIS HEATER DOESN'T
WORK BY TONIGHT.
BOBBY, IT TOOK A WHOLE
LIFETIME OF COLLECTION
FOR ME TO GET
THE WHOLE CABOODLE HERE.
AND, SEE HERE,
YOU HAVEN'T EVEN
TOUCHED YOUR FOOD.
MAN, YOU'VE GOT TO EAT
IF YOU WANT TO KEEP
ABOVE THE GROUND.
THERE.
IT LIGHTS FOR ME,
BOBBY.
OF COURSE,
I CANNOT ANSWER
FOR WHAT HAPPENS
AFTER SUNDOWN.
BETTER WAIT
IN THE CAR.
IRRESISTIBLE, HUH?
AREN'T I CRAZY?
COMPLETELY.
I'LL NEVER CHANGE
I'M AFRAID.
ANNIE, UH,
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
BOB, PLEASE.
I TAKE IT BACK.
WHAT?
THAT DAY IN THE CAR--
I DID SEE YOU
AND I DID HEAR YOU.
I REALLY DID. I SHOULD
NEVER HAVE DENIED IT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
ANNIE.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
YOU HAVE A PARTY
NAMED JACOB MITTEL
SOMEPLACE ON THE MAP?
M-I-T-T-E-L.
THE IMPORTER? SURE.
YOU KNOW HIM?
YEAH.
WE CONTACT THE FRENCH
DESIGNERS THROUGH MITTEL.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
HE'S IN PARIS NOW.
BETTER STRIKE
HIM OUT.
JAY?
GO AHEAD.
HOW DID HE DIE?
HE ISN'T DEAD.
AT LEAST NOT YET.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING,
MR. KRAFT.
YOU'RE THINKING THAT
WE TRICKED YOU INTO
KILLING JACOB MITTEL.
WELL, YOU'RE 100
PERCENT RIGHT, SO
TRY TO RELAX, HUH?
THIS ONE'S
ON THE POLICE.
YOU SEE, JACOB MITTEL'S
IN THE PRIME OF LIFE.
NO PREVIOUS
MAJOR ILLNESSES,
NO RECORD,
LIFE EXPECTANCY
EXCEPTIONALLY GOOD.
HE'S IN PARIS WITH
ALL THAT OCEAN WATER
TO PROTECT HIM
FROM THIS MESS.
UP UNTIL NOW,
ALL THE DEATHS
HAVE BEEN CONFINED
TO THE LOCAL AREA.
IF IT STRIKES SOMEBODY
ON ANOTHER CONTINENT,
THEN WE'VE REALLY
FOUND SOMETHING.
I KNEW I SHOULD HAVE
GOTTEN RID OF THOSE PINS
4 DAYS AGO.
EVEN THE MAP.
THE WHOLE THING. OUT.
WHAT I WANT TO KNOW IS
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO TELL THE D.A.
IS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THESE DEATHS?
WE GAVE THIS CASE
A REAL FULL-DRESS
INVESTIGATION, MR. KRAFT.
QUESTIONED YOU AND
ALL THE OTHER SUSPECTS
AND WITNESSES
UNTIL THE POINT OF COMEDY.
FOUND NOTHING.
NO MOTIVE,
NO OPPORTUNITY,
NO SUSPECT, NO CRIME,
NO WEAPON.
EXCEPT 7 PINS WENT IN...
AND 7 PEOPLE DIED.
NOT ONE--7.
WHO PUT IN THOSE PINS?
YOU DID. ALL 7.
OTHER CHAIRMEN AND SO ON
HAVE BEEN PUTTING PINS
IN THAT MAP FOR YEARS
AND NOTHING HAPPENED.
BUT...
WITH ME...
IT ISN'T IMPOSSIBLE
FOR A CERTAIN KIND OF MAN
TO BE ENDOWED WITH POWERS
THAT NOBODY EVER DREAMED
HE COULD HAVE.
A LOT OF SCIENTISTS
CLAIM THAT.
MAPS AND PINS
CAN'T KILL ALONE,
THE POWER OF A HUMAN BRAIN
HAS TO BE BEHIND IT.
LIKE IN THE INDIES, I GUESS.
THOSE VOODOO DOLLS
YOU HEAR ABOUT.
WITCH DOCTOR STICKS PINS
IN THE THING
UNTIL THE GUY IN QUESTION
IS JINXED INTO DYING.
OF COURSE, I-I KNOW
YOU DIDN'T MEAN
TO KILL ANYBODY.
I HAVE TO GET BACK.
YOU'LL HEAR FROM ME
THE MINUTE WE GET WORD.
I THINK I BEST BE
RUNNING ALONG, TOO.
BOB...
I THINK SO.
[Door closes]
[Crickets chirp]
I DESTROYED THEM.
SOMETHING IN ME
KILLED THEM.
SOMETHING IN ME.
BUT I-I COULDN'T
REFUSE THE JOB.
NOT A MAN
WITH MY REASONING POWER.
POWER...
IF I HAVE THE POWER
OF DEATH
USING THE BLACK PINS...
THEN I MUST HAVE
THE POWER OF LIFE
USING THE WHITE ONES.
[Crickets chirp]
[Low rumble]
[Coughs]
[Telephone ringing]
THIS IS THE CEMETERY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
[Woman]
THIS IS ROSEMOND MITTEL.
ROSEMOND,
I DON'T--YES.
CAN'T YOU HEAR ME?
ROSEMOND MITTEL.
JAY'S WIFE.
ROSEMOND. YES.
I JUST RECEIVED
A CABLE FROM PARIS.
CAN'T YOU HEAR ME?
YOU JUST RECEIVED A CABLE
FROM PARIS, FRANCE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'LL READ IT AGAIN.
"REGRET JACOB W. MITTEL
DIED IN...
"HOTEL ROYALE.
BODY AWAITS DISPOSITION.
"SIGNED AMERICAN EMBASSY,
PARIS, FRANCE."
HE DIED THERE.
DIED IN PARIS, FRANCE.
[Click]
GOT IT.
JACOB W. MITTEL.
IMPOSSIBLE.
HE CANNOT BE DEAD.
WHAT? WHAT?
YOU STILL THINK
THAT THING'S THE KILLER?
OR YOUR OWN PUNY POWER,
MR. CHAIRMAN?
THE ONLY POWER YOU
OR THAT MAP EVER HAD
WAS ME,
AS FAR AS KILLING GOES.
YOU--YOU MARKED THEM
FOR DEATH, MR. CHAIRMAN,
BUT WHO DID THE DEED?
ANDREW McKEE.
OH, ANDY, WHY?
YOU AND YOUR
HIGH-AND-MIGHTY COMMITTEE
TURNING OUT A MAN
WITH 40 YEARS OF SERVICE
ON THE GROUNDS.
40 YEARS.
I TOLD YOU, ANDY.
A FULL PENSION.
IT ISN'T A'CASH THAT
KEEPS A MAN GOING ON,
THAT KEEPS HIS FEET
ON THE GROUND,
AND KEEPS HIM ON
THE JOB TILL THE
LORD MAKES HIM QUIT.
THE LORD...
AND NOBODY ELSE.
THIS IS MY
HOUSE, MY LANDS,
MY ACTIVITIES.
AYE, IT'S BECOME
A LONG DARK ROAD
TO PUT THIS GUN
TO YOUR HEAD, BOB.
ANDY, WE NEVER TRIED
TO TAKE ANYTHING
AWAY FROM YOU.
AYE. I MADE SURE OF THAT.
I SNUCK UP ON EACH
ONE OF THEM IN TURN
WHEN THEY WAS ALONE
AND HELD THEM FAST, LIKE SO,
UNTIL THEY WENT.
AYE, EVEN BIG OLD GEORGE,
YOUR UNCLE,
LEFT AS EASY AS A BABY.
BUT...
THAT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
WHAT HAPPENED TO MITTEL.
MITTEL'S DEAD.
WILL YOU STOP THAT
CONFOUNDED TALK, MAN?
THAT MAP'S NAUGHT
BUT A DOODAD, YOU FOOL.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO FEAR HERE.
[Faint clang]
[Clang gets louder]
THAT MAP.
ANDY, TALK ABOUT
SOMETHING ELSE QUICK.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
YOU'RE FINISHED
WITH TALKING.
FINISHED YOU ARE,
WITH MAPS, AND PINS--
BLACK AND WHITE.
TALK ABOUT
SOMETHING ELSE, I SAID.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
RIGHT NOW. TALK ABOUT
ANYTHING ELSE.
NOW!
[Clang]
WHY?
BECAUSE I CAUSED YOU
TO KILL THOSE PEOPLE.
ANDY, YOU BETTER GET THIS
STRAIGHT RIGHT NOW.
YOU HEARD
THAT LIEUTENANT.
IT'S POSSIBLE
FOR SOME PEOPLE
TO HAVE THINGS
INSIDE THEM
THAT MAKE OTHER
THINGS HAPPEN.
NOTHING IS IMPOSSIBLE
FOR A MAN LIKE THAT
IF HE THINKS ABOUT
IT HARD ENOUGH.
I KNOW YOU, ANDY--
YOU'RE NO KILLER.
I MADE YOU DO IT.
YOU THOUGHT ME
INTO KILLING THEM?
[Clang]
THEN THEY COULD
ALL BE BACK.
ANDY, I NEVER KNEW IT.
HOW DO YOU ACCOUNT
FOR THAT?
THAT NOISE.
CAN'T YOU HEAR IT?
[Clang]
ANDY. ANDY, STOP IT.
THERE'S NOBODY.
AAH!
[Andy]
THEY COULD ALL BE BACK.
STOP.
THAT MAP.
I PUT THEM INSIDE.
THEY'RE COMING.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE STUCK IN
THEM WHITE PINS, BOBBY,
BUT NOW IT'S TOO LATE.
TOO LATE.
I ONLY KILLED 5.
YOU GAVE ME ONLY 5.
NOT THE YOUNG
DREXEL COUPLE.
GO AWAY. GO AWAY.
LEAVE ME ALONE.
GO AWAY. GO.
SAVE ME, BOBBY.
[Door bangs]
HE'S DEAD,
LIEUTENANT.
ALL RIGHT.
FORGET THE
NORMAL PROCEDURE.
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
EXHIBIT A.
HE REALLY DIDN'T NEED IT.
THEY DIED OF FRIGHT FIRST,
JUST LIKE HE DID.
YOU'RE FORGETTING
ABOUT THOSE 7 TRIPS
TO THE MAUSOLEUM, LIEUTENANT.
7 BODIES, 7 TRIPS.
THEY HELPED.
LIEUTENANT, UH...
JACOB MITTEL, UH,
DIED IN PARIS?
NO, THAT WAS
A PLANT, MR. KRAFT.
MITTEL'S ALL RIGHT.
SORRY WE HAD
TO PUT YOU THROUGH THIS,
BUT IT WAS
THE BEST WAY
TO MAKE McKEE
COME OUT IN THE OPEN.
MRS. MITTEL STAYED UP
ALL NIGHT AT HEADQUARTERS
WAITING FOR US
TO CALL IN.
OUR RADIO CAR
IS POSTED JUST OUTSIDE.
WE SIGNALED HER
TO PHONE YOU
AND TELL YOU THAT LIE
ABOUT HER HUSBAND.
AM I GETTING THROUGH
TO YOU, MR. KRAFT?
WELL, NOT QUITE YET.
WE WATCHED HIM, BOB.
HE ACTUALLY MANAGED TO--
UNEARTH ALL 7 OF THEM.
WONDER WHAT
GOT INTO HIM.
IT WAS THOSE
WHITE PINS.
HEH.
IT WAS.
[Crickets chirp]
ANNIE, I'VE LOST
MY OVERCOAT.
OH? WHERE? WHICH ONE?
I'LL GET IT.
NO, NEVER MIND.
[Sighs]
I THINK I CAN
FIND IT MYSELF.