And people looked like they were
interested in what I was saying...
Hi, Orfeo.
- Happy New Year...
- Hey, Bruno! It's been a while!
- How are you?
- Fine. How did you spend Christmas?
Working all night, as usual.
You call this life?
Santa left a present for you.
Really?
Hey...
Absinth!
Thanks, Bruno. If I had any power
in this film school I'd give you...
-...the highest grades in every discipline.
- I know.
It's for her.
Do it, Orfeo...
The camera you see here,
my dear students...
...is the same one with which
your principal, Gustav Olinsky...
...fiilmed every one of his movies.
Behind this hatch...
...the history of cinema was imprinted...
...with a photochemical process.
- Hi! - How are you? - Fine.
- Hi... Aki! - Yo, Richard, how are you?
- How was your Christmas, Matteo?
It was like every holiday:
I ate a lot and drank too much.
- Hi, Aki!
- Here you are, Bruno!
- Didn't see you in class.
- Yeah, we just arrived.
- The trip was horrible.
- Did you come with Ozu?
- Yeah, he'll be here soon. He wanted
to call home before, you know...
- Ciao.
- Scusa.
- Oh... - Yo! - Yo...
Calavera...
- How are you? - Fine, and you?
- Me too.
- Any news about your grandmother?
- Mh... well... you know, she...
- I hope your aim improves.
- Hi.
- Leilou, forgive me for before.
- Don't worry.
- But now I'm stealing her away from you for a while.
- Of course.
- Fine with you? - Okay, see you later.
- Okay.
Excuse me, Mr. Olinsky.
I wanted to talk with you about something.
Something regarding the fiilm archive.
- So tell me, what's the problem?
- You see, I'm having an hard time making ends meet.
And I was thinking that if started
working in the archive again...
...I'd be able to pay...
at least a fraction of the college funds.
You're the student that
lost his family in an accident...
...a while ago, right?
- Yes. - Countess Orsini became very
worried about you, since that happened.
- She cares about you a lot.
- Yeah.
Well then, welcome back
to the archive, Marquez!
Thanks, professor Caligari.
Olinsky.
Silence, please. Thanks.
A lot of you dream of becoming a director.
The different roles will be decided with a test...
...I'm about to propose to you all.
In the next 10 days you'll have to submit...
...a photographic excercise...
...which will allow our dear teachers
to evaluate your dedication,...
...your sensibility, your technique
and your personal style.
So, a single photo for each theme...
...which will be submitted with a fake name...
...and which will be evaluated by the faculty.
Only I will know the authors' names.
How much time do we have for each photo?
Since its Monday, you'll have
to submit it Wednesday morning.
Time.
- Hello, Calavera. How's it going?
- Hey...
- Fine. - How have your holidays been?
- Hm, fine.
- Did you miss me?
- I'd say so!
Uhm... Elena is throwing a small
party for her birthday this evening.
Really?
No teachers, only a few friends.
- Yes, but... I dont think I'll come.
- Why not?
- I've got to work at the archive.
- Can't you start tomorrow?
- We'll all be there, it'll be fun.
- Yeah...
- Okay.
I'll tell Elena you won't be there.
Okay.
Here you go, youngin'.
Thanks.
Countess Orsini, Professor Olinsky told me that...
...you worried about me because
of the accident involving my family.
Well, I wanted to thank you.
It's something that saddened me a lot.
Didnt you get the data from Astolfi?
- No, I'm going now. - Ah.
- Well, let's hope that old fart
won't give you any problems.
Its a real pleasure to have you back in the archive, you know?
Thanks.
Mister Astolfi?
Mister Astolfi? It's Bruno Marquez.
I'm the student in charge with the archive.
I don't want to annoy you,
but I have to get all the data you have.
Bruno Marquez...
You look more dead than alive.
- How's the food in the mess hall?
- Well... it's not bad.
Kinda disgusting, eh?
- You can come back on friday. Okay?
- Okay.
Thank you.
Poor Astolfi... since his son died
he's not the same anymore.
Drink it. It'll make all your ghosts go away.
Ah!
Orfeo, is that true that Caligari
fiilmed all his movies...
...with this camera?
- Yes, that's right.
All his creativity was imprinted here.
Don't keep us on our toes, Lucia.
Can we see it now?
Of course, Gusta, We tought
a little wait would have...
...whetted your appetite.
Right, Athanasius?
May I?
The very first edition of Kircher's
"Ars Magna Lucis et Umbrae"!
- It's wonderful... - Incredible!
- Wonderful, Lucia!
What's up?
- Did you see it, too?
- What are you talking about?
There was a boy near the shelves,
pointing at something!
I'm the only one here.
I thought you'd like to see me
and I didn't go to the party.
Okay, it's just that you
scared me. Sorry.
- Did you drink something?
- Absinthe.
I bought a bottle for Orfeo
and we drank some of it.
- That explains your visions.
- Yeah.
Can we get out of here... please?
Yessir, Captain Calavera!
I don't get why you always
have to call me Calavera!
Your skin is so pale...
Calaveras are marzipan skulls...
...that the kids eat in Mexico City...
...during the "Day of the Dead".
I'm making you a compliment!
- Elena.
- Hi! We missed you yesterday night.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
They told you the reason, right?
- Sure, don't worry.
- Here. I got... I got something for you.
- Oh thanks, you didn't have to.
It's wonderful! - Yeah...
I see you're aware of my taste
for the macabre.
Well, I know we like the same things.
- You know, we could work together...
Iike writing a script, or... - Yeah!
- Yeah?
- Interesting.
- Oh, you think so? Thanks... er... bye.
- See you soon.
And this last one is from
some guy named "Calavera".
I wanted you to know this class level...
...and what your classmates have submitted.
Now, I think this is a way to get
better for the next theme.
Death.
- What happened?
- Arianna, I saw him again. - Who?
The boy from the archive. In the woods...
I went to take pictures of animals...
...and he was there. - Are you sure?
- I swear! I saw him!
- You have to believe me!
- I'll start to eat.
Okay, I'm coming.
Listen, come to my room after you're
done with the archives...
...so we can speak a bit. Okay?
- Okay. Later.
Calaverita? She's not there.
- How do you know about Calavera?
- It's not like a big secret.
- Did she tell you where she was headed?
- She's in the dark room together with June and Richard.
This afternoon she was struck by inspiration...
...while you were working in the archive.
Hey, your photo was really fantastic.
Now we'll open up the back of this Bolex...
...and I'll show you the various mechanisms.
As you can see, its design
is simple and compact...
It's easy to handle and to shoot,
just like an AK-47.
- Now let's open it...
...so I'll show you all
the various functions.
The incredible ease of use makes this camera
really useful to shoot documentaries...
"At two o'clock in my room!"
You hold it with your hands, like this.
Please everybody, pay attention.
May I?
You can come, but don't even
breath until I say so.
Ah! Got it.
Do you recognize this cave?
Yes. They call it "Well of Death".
It's an hour's walk from the school.
In the woods, behind Mrs. Orsini's house.
- Thank you.
- Bruno!
- If you want to bring a girl there,
I know loads of better places.
Do me a favour. Come with me to that cave.
- Bruno, I'm REALLY trying to believe you, but...
- Please, you have to come with me.
To see if there really is something there...
...and it's not just me going crazy.
Listen: I promise you...
...that if we go there and find nothing,
I won't touch the subject anymore. Okay?
Why can't you go alone?
Because I trust you...
...and I'm scared.
He pointed at something in this direction.
Wait!
- He was there.
- Where? - Here!
What is that?
It looks like some kind of helmet.
- Damn...
We're done for today.
Fear.
- Since the week is about to end,
you'll have one more day...
...to take your picture.
Please, I would like to talk
with the student nicknamed "Calavera".
We both know you found
the object, Mister Marquez...
...but you got something
that belongs to this school!
...and I think its absurd that
you hid it under your bed!
- It's not there anymore, professor.
- What?!
I don't know... somebody took it.
Those tools are extremely important!
- Important for what, professor?
- This is none of your business!
Find the thanatoscope, Mister Marquez,
or you will be thrown out of this college.
Do you have any idea on who stole it?
No, I don't.
But I'm going to be honest with you:
I'm in big trouble.
Caligari told me that if I
don't find it, he'll kick me out.
- Tell me, did you have other visions today?
- No.
- But, did you see? That stuff about
the cave was true. - Yes, it was true...
I gotta go. I have to get some
old movies at Astolfi's place.
Astolfi?
And Caligari... and Countess Orsini...
I see you like hanging with all
the school's freaks, Calavera...
Yeah, right... I'm Calavera after all.
- The thanatoscope is back with us.
- What, the thanatoscope?
"With us"? Wasn't it...
Does Ermete know about it?
So, where is it?
One of our students accidentally found it.
But I think he wanted to steal it.
- Gustav, talk to Ermete about it!
- This is really preposterous!
Mister Astolfi?
Mister Astolfi? It's Bruno Marquez.
I came to get the data, as we agreed.
Hello.
I never agreed to anything with anyone.
Expecially not with the
worst student of our school.
- You're pulling my leg, right?
- But of course I'm just kidding.
Come inside, my boy.
Here.
Can you take a look to this photo, please?
Mister Ermete?
Mister Astolfi?
Where did you get it?
It's a picture of a tool I found the other day...
...in the "Well of Death".
The Well of Death... I see...
- Where is it now?
- I don't know.
- Somebody stole it from my room.
- When? - This morning.
- Darn...
- Mister Olinsky called it...
- "Thanascope".
- Thanatoscope! Did Olinksy see it?
Yes... or no... I can't remember now. You see, I...
- You have 10 seconds to get out of here.
- What? - 9.
- But...
- 8.
- What did I say? - 7.
- Can you at least give me back... - 6.
- Give me back my photo.
- Scram!
You woke up early!
Hi. Morning, Leilou.
What's up?
Did you use a butchered lamb... for your photo?
- Me?! - Yeah.
- A lamb? - Yeah.
As far as I know, only two people
like dead animals here.
You and Aki.
Forget it.
- Hi...
- Calavera!
Listen, I've got to tell somebody
what's happening to me...
...or else I'll go crazy.
Can you come to the library with me?
Believe me, Arianna. There's too
much strange stuff happening!
First the vision, then the cave.
And the chest, the theft, the lamb!
- Why are we in the library?
- Because now I'm sure.
If we search together, I'm sure we
can find out what a thanatoscope is.
- A what?
- A thanatoscope.
That lantern-thing we found.
I think Caligari knew about it.
Astolfi is trying to rebuild it. So...
Read.
"It's a mock-up, done with ancient drawings...
...of tools created by Girolamo Fumagalli...
...by the end of the XVII century,
which seems to have magical features."
"For many, the thanatoscope was
the first step in the direction...
...that brought, centuries after,
the invention of photography."
- It's over?
- It's over.
Look!
- Orsini! Like the Countess!
- The school's owner? - Yeah!
When we printed that book...
...I didn't know what a thanatoscope
was at all. Neither did I know its origin...
...or what it was for. I only knew it existed...
...so I decided to put it in the book,
but only as random trivia.
Some time after I found some references...
...in an ancient manuscript
and realizing its importance...
...i decided to publish a book
focused on the tanathoscope itself.
On its dark powers and naturally
on its inventor, Girolamo Fumagalli.
During my research I stumbled
onto the original thanatoscope...
...built by Fumagalli itself and used
in a German expressionist movie...
...about his life, which was never completed.
I found out that the objects from
the movie set were all auctioned...
...by UFA studios itself.
So I sent Gustav Olinsky to buy them all.
Bundled with the thanatoscope
and all the other instruments...
...there also was the script of that movie
which was cancelled so abruptly.
Well, Olinsky went mad about that script...
...so I decided to produce the movie.
I had Fumagalli's entire lab rebuilt
from the ground up.
Olinsky was the director and
Astolfi the cinematographer.
Fumagalli was a Jesuit. He had been
a disciple of Athanasius Kircher...
...a man who lived in the 17th Century...
...who was held in great reverence
among alchemists.
Fumagalli was a true genius.
He discovered that in the human eye...
...images are quickly imprinted on the retina...
...and therefore they could be captured.
Snapshots from a man's life can be preserved...
...and survive death and decay.
The "tool" used to capture the
pictures was a human being...
...who was forced to stare at a composition.
Istant death was caused
by rupturing the occipital bone.
Carpem mortis aspectum...
...per oculos tuos!
Carpem mortis aspectum per oculos tuos!
"I'll capture death through your eyes."
To capture the pictures you had
to extract the eyeballs...
...and extract the contents of the
retina with a peculiar instrument.
That's what the thanatoscope did:
It projected the pictures
imprinted on a retina...
...on a thin glass sheet
which was imbued...
...with a photosensitive liquid.
That way you were able to keep the
pictures forever, through all times.
Fumagalli called this
procedure "Thanatography".
However, while he was going wild
with all his experiments, he was captured,...
...tried and sentenced to death.
The shooting of our movie was halted too,
because of a death...
...caused by the thanatoscope.
Astolfi's son, Sebastiano,
was Olinsky's assistant...
...and his girlfriend acted
as the experiment's guinea pig.
To shoot a scene, Sebastiano
put the killing mechanism...
...right on the girl's head,
sure that the safety lock was on.
Howerver, inexplainably, during the shooting...
...the mechanism suddenly sprung up,
killing the girl istantly.
That night Sebastiano took the thanatoscope...
...and hid it along with everything else...
...and committed suicide, by jumping
out the window on the last floor.
Since then Astolfi,
unable to cope with the pain...
...has been living like a hermit
in the attic where his son died.
Er... would it be possible to take
a look at all the data about that movie?
Everything that was shot
is kept in our archive.
Oh...
It can't be...
It's him...
He's trying to tell me something.
He wants to tell me something.
Sorry, I should've believed you.
Calavera...
It's Sunday!
Why don't you try to relax a bit?
Let's get back to sleep.
Yeah...
Astolfi is trying to
rebuild the thanatoscope...
I saw it with my own eyes!
- I saw the copy!
- So what?
Well, I think he has the original...
I think that...
-...the one who stole it from
my room gave it to him. - So?
So it might be used again!
We have to stop it!
- Where are you going now?
- Follow me.
- Good morning, Orfeo.
- Bruno Marquez!
- Are we bothering you?
- No, no, come in!
Well, I know that both you and
Ms. Niccolodi have the keys to all the rooms.
- Hm? - I need the Astolfi one.
Can you give it to me?
- Hm...
- Well... I tought that you could...
- Well, you know.
- Now... I... can't.
Believe me, Orfeo.
It's really important to me.
I'm really sorry, but I can't do that.
But if by chance somebody entered here...
...and took the third key in the first row...
Third key... first row...
I wonder... what would happen.
- Hey! -Hello!
- How's it going, pal? - Fine.
- Did you meet Arianna?
- Yes, at the entrance with Leilou.
- Do you have your picture for tomorrow?
- Yes, it's ready, I just developed it.
- Fantastic. See you tomorrow then.
- Good Night! - Bye!
Orfeo! Orfeo!
Orfeo!
In this photo we can see a certain use,...
...even if it's not all that well done,
of field depth.
Mr. Marquez!
What does this photo represent for you?!
Well... I tried to describe fear...
...using everything I had at hand, professor.
Destiny!
Ms. Niccolodi, do you know where Orfeo is?
He went to the city.
He had to buy some replacements.
- Do you know when will he come back?
- That's up to him, Marquez.
You know Orfeo well.
It's raining a lot.
The road must be blocked. Maybe he's going
to sleep at his brother's place.
Countess Orsini!
- What's the matter, Marquez?!
- They killed him!
Orfeo is dead! They used him
for... a thanatography!
Now calm down! You're panicking.
Astolfi wants to re-enact
the rituals... and I'm sure....
...that crazy Caligari is lending him a hand.
- Caligari?
- Professor Olinsky, Countess!
Should I take it as a compliment,
Mr. Marquez?
This is the end of your job at the archive!
Another misstep...
...and I'll send you back to your
grandma's home immediatly!
Come on, hand me the keys.
Give me back the archive keys, Mr. Marquez!
It's too bad I'll have to inform
your classmates...
...about the disturbing
mental state you're in.
Marquez!
Elena...
...please tell Ms. Niccolodi...
...to gather all the students
in the Main Hall in an hour.
- Something happened?
- No. Not yet.
Ermete? It's me, Gustav.
What do you want?
Can you let us in for a moment?
We're looking for something. Can we?
It's just a few minutes.
May I ask you what you
were doing, Ermete?
I was rearranging stuff. You know,
I collected too much crap over the years.
Mr. Marquez...
You all know this is a small community...
...Iike a big family. The reason why
I gathered you all here today...
...is to inform you of a rather grave matter...
...which unfortunately involves
one of your classmates...
Mr. Marquez.
Every one of you knows about
the tragic death of his parents...
...which occurred some months
ago because of an accident.
So, I ask everyone in this class
to be sympathetic to him...
...because I'm sure every one of you
understands his fragile state of mind.
Thanks for your attention.
Ari...
- What happened?
- Today I went to see Countess Orsini...
...and I told her... that Astolfi
was trying to repeat the experiment.
And I moronically accused Caligari...
...to be... his accomplice...
...and... to have killed Orfeo.
-But Caligari was there and he heard everything.
- Bruno...
I'm not... I don't have any
mental illness, believe me.
And then... he tried to make me look
like a joke... in front of everybody.
I'm not confused...
due to my family's passing.
Yeah, he played dirty.
And... what are the others saying?
You can guess it...
- Elena wants to know if there's a way to help you.
- Of course.
She's so kind.
Leilou noticed you act strangely...
...but you always act strangely, so...
- What about Arianna?
- Arianna... is so worried about you...
I really missed you a lot.
- We only met yesterday.
- No...
For me it was... a lot longer ago.
Do you still have the key to Astolfi's room?
What key?
Bruno!
What happened to you?
I don't know.
I was... I was running
and... somebody hit me.
- Did you go get the key?
- Elena... - What?!
- They killed Elena... - Listen...
-...and somebody else...
- In the theater!
- Stop! Bruno! Bruno!
What are you doing Bruno?!
We're working here!
You still don't know
what the red light means?
Oh, sorry, Calavera...
Caligari asked us to go soft on you...
- He told us of your problems.
- Stop it, Lou.
Let's go.
So, you threw the key away...
...then you waited for me to be
asleep to go get it back?
- No, it didn't go this way!
- If you think that by acting this way...
...you can earn my trust,
you're dead wrong.
- No... Iisten to me...
- Bruno Marquez...
You have to swallow one of these
after breakfast and another after dinner...
It's for your mental health.
Try to sleep more at night.
I have a class right now.
You wanna clean yourself up a little or would
you rather stay in your room to see dead people?
I think I'll take a shower
and change my clothes.
Don't forget the pills.
Bruno, it hurts me to see you
in this state. You have to recover.
Okay.
You wouldn't believe everything
Caligari said, right?
No, of course not.
Don't worry. Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm alright. Just a bit tired.
- Did you guys meet Elena today?
- No, we don't have the same classes.
Did you notice if there was somebody
else missing this morning?
- Ah... Matteo!
- Yeah, Gunter was missing too.
- Why? Did something happen?
- No, nothing.
Gunter?
- Hi...
- Bruno, what do you want?! - I'm sorry...
It's just that... I didn't see
you in class and I wanted to know...
-...if you're alrlight.
- Oh... well I've got the flu.
- Take care, okay?
- Okay, thanks.
Matteo?
The student Matteo Danese has
been granted a permission...
...to absent himself from lessons
to take a picture of the old factory.
Who signed it?
Dr. Elena Montenegro. Oh, look!
It says she's accompanying him.
- Hey, chill out, man...
- Damn...
Oh, I forgot, you're the one that...
Sorry.
- How are you, crazy-boy?
- I'm fine.
You almost gave me a heart attack.
Are you going back to your room?
Yeah.
I'm going to the studio.
I'm bringing these little wonders to Aki.
- Cool stuff, uh?
- She'll like them a lot.
This school is unluckily overrun by bugs.
- Aki loves it, though.
- Well, see ya.
Get some rest.
See you tomorrow.
Wow... they're the biggest ones
I've ever seen here at school.
Richard has been nice to you.
I thought he only cared about Elena.
Ozu...
Aki...
The nickname of this author is Murnau.
- Ah!
- Calavera...
The boy who has issues...
Hey...
- You know where Ozu and Aki are?
- They must be sleeping as usual.
- They're always late.
- With today's theme
the exercise is complete.
The evaluation criteria will be
on both artistic and technical sides.
The teachers will rate them and,
depending on this, every one of you...
...will get a role in the
shooting of the shorts.
Truth.
What's happening, Mr. Astolfi?
Every last imprisoned soul
will be set free.
They will finally rest in peace.
What are you talking about?
A perfect thanatography...
They will be freed by creating
a perfect thanatography.
- What's this?
- This will save Sebastiano.
But Sebastiano is dead, Mr. Astolfi!
Death is just a transition.
It's the price we have to pay for our sins.
It's also the only way to obtain...
...a perfect thanatography...
...a picture which freezes
the exact moment of death...
...the one in which you suddenly realize...
...your unavoidable end.
To obtain it you need two victims...
...to stare at each other in the eyes
in the exact moment of death.
The thanatoscope allowed Fumagalli
to continue his cursed experiments...
...after his death, through
the hands of others...
It's like his spirit possessed them...
...to complete the work
he started four centuries ago.
- This... this is ridicolous!
- Not if Satan will get what he deserves...
Everything will come to an end and,
freed from the curse, every one of them...
...will overcome death and
be free for all eternity.
- Where is Orfeo?
- Only by dying can someone be reborn.
You killed him.
- Where do you think you're going now?
- To the studio, to end this...
...once and for all.
Arianna! Arianna, it's all true!
Astolfi did it!
No, Arianna... no!
Arianna!
Arianna! Calm down.
I'm with you now! Don't be scared!
Calm down! You don't have to...
Leilou? What do you want to do?
- What are you doing?
- Don't worry.
No, no, please.
Did you go crazy?
Stop it!
Stop it, Leilou.
- It's a bad joke...
- Shh!
Keep your eyes like that, okay?
You won't feel pain, Calavera.
I promise.
Why do you want to do this
horrible thing to us?
Your contribution will be invaluable.
Thanks to you,
my short will be fantastic!
And when I'll show professor
Olinsky what I have done...
...the director's chair will be mine.
He was so kind to me when he found out...
...I was the one to get the
device from your room...
He didn't even scold me.
Instead, he showed me how to use it.
Isn't it wonderful, Bruno?
He told me that if I was able to include...
...a thanatography in my short,
it would become the best one for sure.
And if I refused...
...he'd understand that...
...but he would have asked somebody else.
I couldn't refuse.
I tried so many times.
- You know, don't you?
- Don't do that, Leilou.
This is just... madness.
Please...
I beg you...
Free us.
This time I will succeed.
Choking is the best way...
...to capture the exact moment of death.
I'll capture your death through Bruno's eyes.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry, dear.
But this is my chance.
I knew it would happen here...
...and now I can finally
put an end to all this.
I know what you want, Fumagalli...
I know what you were looking for.
So, let's do it.
Listen to me, Bruno: when I'll be dead...
...you'll have to finish the process...
...or else my sacrifice will be in vain.
I have a drawing in my trouser's pocket.
It shows how the device works.
Follow it carefully...
-...and do everything that needs to be done.
- Wait!
- We have to destroy those devices!
No! Once you have obtained what you need...
...there will be no more reason to destroy them.
It will be the end, Bruno.
Who said it would end?
Don't do it.
It's absurd!
It's absolutely useless!
- Mr. Astolfi!
- This will be the perfect thanatography.
Imago mortis...
...per oculos tuos.
What's happening?
Nothing.
Do you see anything?
No.
What were you going to do
for the "truth" theme?
Nothing.
- Nothing?
- Mh.
Oh...
Subtitles translated by: Kiavik