Please, let me out of here.
Let me out of here!
Let me out of here, God damn it!
Let me out of here! I don't want to die!
Give me the key! I don't want to die!
Let me out!
Give me that key, you bitch!
Miriam! Miriam!
Give me the key! God damn it!
Miriam!
Genie knows you're hiding.
Miriam?
Come out.
Come out, wherever you are.
Genie's out of the bottle.
Miriam?
Miriam.
Come out.
Come out, wherever you are.
Miriam. Miriam!
Anybody hurt?
Jesus fucking Christ.
I don't believe it. We could have been killed.
You okay, Jay-Jay?
This is so screwed up.
- Can't we pull it out?
- It's a hunk of steel, Holly.
- Oh, I'm cold.
- It's going to get a lot colder.
- There's no signal up here.
- Great. That's just great.
We can't haul it out.
Can't even sit in the damn thing.
- So...
- So, what?
- We walk.
- Walk?
Walk where?
You don't even know where we are.
If we follow the road down,
we can get to the highway before dark.
Get the chance of a lift
and maybe a cell signal.
We do not want to be out here at night.
You do what you want.
I'm staying with the truck.
Okay.
Take it easy, Karen.
I'm not tramping through the woods
in these boots.
- Baby, come on.
- They were $500, okay?
Shit.
You realize this is the last time
we're going to be doing this?
What? Dying of exposure?
You know what I mean.
We've been camping here
since we were kids.
Hey, I got it. Lord of the Rings.
It's a gay allegory.
Bug, is this more
of your Lord of the Rings bullshit?
In which the addictive pleasures
of the one ring must be destroyed
in the fiery and, I think it's safe to say,
vaginal crack of doom.
It's still bullshit.
Where are we?
Wherever we are, we're not going
to make it to the highway before dark.
Look how the road loops.
If we cut through the forest, we save miles.
Jesus, how much further?
- Shouldn't we have hit that road by now?
- How should I know?
Oh, great.
Now we're going to be swimming home.
We gotta just keep going.
Jesus, it's creepy out here.
It's getting really cold.
- I can't go on.
- Me neither.
What the hell is that?
You must have just set off
some kind of motion detector.
- It's not on the map.
- How can it not be on the map?
Hello?
Careful. It could be electrified.
I guess not.
Did it occur to you
there might be a gate somewhere?
It's breaking and entering.
It's okay. It'll just be for the night.
Looks deserted.
- What the hell is this place?
- There's got to be a phone here.
Hello? Hello?
Looks like it's completely sealed up.
Hello?
Don't do that. It gives me the creeps.
Looks like a ventilation duct.
With a big skylight.
- We're in. Come on, guys.
- In? I don't wanna.
Jay, come on, this is crazy.
Look, if we stay out here
we're going to freeze.
Okay, let me think about that a second.
It's got to be 30 feet down.
What's up, little sister? You scared?
That's big sister to you.
- Don't fall.
- Thanks for the advice.
- What's happening down there?
- She's almost down.
I'm down.
I'm going to try to get to the front door.
Did you hear something?
Jay?
Jay, are you okay?
Here.
- Give me a hand. I'm going down there.
- Right.
Oh, my God!
Jay?
Jay!
Jesus!
Christ. You scared the shit out of me!
Come on, you got to see this.
Jesus.
- They're going to say that we did this.
- Josh, it's going to be okay.
Come on, let's get out of here.
All right. They got the lights on.
Come on, Karen.
Okay, Karen?
You go first.
Oh, shit.
Look out!
- Dude?
- Are you okay?
Yeah, I'll live.
Shit.
Okay, Karen.
Karen?
- Karen?
- Where's she at?
She's gone. I can't believe she's gone.
- Where's Karen?
- Bad news.
What happened to you?
- We have to leave this place right now.
- Why?
Don't go down there.
Holy shit! Who the hell did this?
Oh, great.
We're trapped in a blood bath
in the middle of the mountains.
No, guys.
I think they did it to each other.
There'd be blood. Look at all the blood.
Someone else did this,
they'd have tracked blood all over.
Which means, it's not like we're dealing with
some psychopath kind of thing here, right?
Yeah. Just a routine "people go crazy
and butcher each other" kind of thing.
We're out of here, now.
How exactly?
Karen?
It's a prison. A goddamn Supermax.
Baby, please.
Karen?
Karen!
She was out there a minute ago.
- Karen!
Karen?
- Where's Jay?
- I thought she was with you.
Jay.
- Jay?
- Jay, where are you?
Jay!
Jay?
Over here.
What the hell?
What is it?
- Jay?
- I don't know.
Oh, shit.
Is that a guy in there?
They've got a guy in there.
- What's that in his stomach?
- It's to feed him. To keep him alive.
Looks like some sort of experiment.
You can't experiment on a person like this.
- Shit.
- What?
I know where it is.
- What, Josh?
- The key to the front door.
Josh, messing with the bodies
is a really bad idea.
You got a better one?
- How do you know it's the key?
- I don't.
I'm not going to move her.
I just want to take a look.
- Shit.
- What?
It's not the key. It's something else.
Okay, look. We find a ladder.
A bookcase. Something.
We pile it under the skylight and we climb.
- Looks like she...
- Don't, Josh!
- It's stuck.
- Oh, God.
- The hell with this.
- Josh, no!
Holy shit! It was stuck in her throat.
- What, what, what, she swallowed it?
- She tried to.
But why would she do that?
Guess she didn't want anybody leaving.
- It's the wrong key.
- You don't know that.
Damn it!
- Oh, Jesus.
- Whoa.
It was probably just a short.
Water getting in somewhere.
Or the grid going down.
Fuses. There's got to be fuses
in the basement.
Guys.
When I first got here I turned on the lights.
So who just turned them off?
Oh, great.
Let's just scare ourselves to death.
Shit.
- Jay, come back!
- Jay!
It's okay.
It must be some kind of auxiliary power.
- What are you doing?
- Opening the door.
- He's a human being, Holly.
- Jay, I have a really bad feeling about this.
Look at this guy.
Looks like a goddamn electric chair.
They're monitoring his brain.
His brain works?
He's not dead. He's in some sort of coma.
How do you know he's not just asleep?
People who are asleep... wake up.
- Shit!
- Oh, my God!
- What the hell was that?
- Electroconvulsive therapy.
What?
Why?
What's that on his forehead?
- An eye.
- A tattoo.
Shit.
- It's that guy.
- What guy?
The guy that bit his tongue off.
When he was a kid.
Then he killed his family.
It was like ten years ago.
Okay, we're leaving now.
But they killed him.
I mean, they killed him.
I'm sure they killed him.
- They executed him.
- So it's not the guy.
You okay, Jay?
Jay, it's not the guy. How can it be?
When I first came in I saw something.
- What?
- It was near the bodies.
It was severed, bitten off.
A tongue.
Why didn't you tell us?
Okay, enough.
Let's just get the hell out of here.
What the hell is going on here?
This is money, guys. Millions of dollars.
- Lock it.
- He's not going to hurt you, Holly.
I want to see you turn the key.
- Okay. We prioritize. First...
- We get the hell out of here.
Second, we get the hell away from here.
Third, we forget we ever came here.
We find the generator.
There must be a lower level.
We climb. Through the air vents.
We saw the duct on the roof.
- There's a grill on it.
- We can get it off. At least try.
Our flashlights are dying.
In about an hour, maybe less,
they're going to be dead.
We're going to be stuck here in the dark.
How do you know it's a generator?
What if it is the grid?
They're not hooked up to the grid.
All the juice they'd be sucking down,
they'd have the FBI out here in a week.
He's right.
Out here in the sticks, the Feds
are tipped off to high consumption.
Guys cooking meth,
guys growing marijuana with UV.
They all use generators.
What they were doing here
was underground.
There's gonna be a generator to run all this.
A big one.
Maybe there's a way out.
Okay.
Josh, are you sure about this?
Josh?
You ready?
- What's that smell?
- Smells like shit.
- That's weird.
- What?
Gauge says the tank's still half full.
Probably just the gauge.
Something's in here.
Got to be a switch here somewhere.
Something just came in.
Josh?
- Someone...
- Someone, what?
Someone switched it off.
Holly, open the door!
Josh, you're hit!
Oh, my God!
Open the goddamn door!
- Be careful!
- Get me out of here!
- It's gonna be okay, Josh.
- Help!
- Be careful!
- You can't leave me in here!
- Josh!
- Oh, please hang on.
I can't stop the bleeding.
The wound's too deep.
Get me out of here.
Help!
No.
Get me out of here!
- Come on, Josh.
- Josh.
There's no pulse.
Oh, my God, my brother.
Get me out of here!
You fucking maniac!
- I'm going to kill you! Fuck you!
- No!
No!
Why?
My brother.
Be careful.
- What was that?
- Nothing.
It's nothing. He can't get out.
Please.
Please!
Thanks.
We get out through the air vents.
That duct on the roof.
Better get Jay.
Jay.
- We're getting out of here.
- We're going to get the police
and we're going to tell them
what happened here.
Jay.
I'm okay.
How do they kill them, Bug?
Who?
Murderers.
Trust me, Jay, this guy is going
to get what's coming to him.
In California, lethal injection.
Anesthetic. First, the anesthetic.
Then the muscle relaxant
which stops the guy breathing.
Then the drug that stops the heart
and then the doctor pronounces...
But what if the doctor's been bought?
What if the murderer's heart's still beating
but the doctor said it stopped.
You're talking about the guy in the tank?
They wheel him away,
and now they have a body to play with.
Well, why not just grab a homeless person
or do a deal with an asylum?
And there's the family.
Don't they want to bury their kin?
He killed his kin.
It's coming loose.
It's four hours till sun up, dude.
Sun or no sun,
we're still going to be in the dark.
You know, we should go.
Bug and Peter are waiting for us.
I'm staying.
I want to know why my brother died.
Confronted with the possibility that
this is not, strictly speaking, a dream state,
lucid or otherwise, we are...
We are faced with...
Miriam! Miriam!
...occur when calcium is admitted
through voltage-sensitive membrane...
...recourse to a nerve agent
as a means of inducing coma
was taken only after a considerable debate.
You got it, dude?
I can feel the air moving.
...decision to use electroconvulsive therapy
was taken without,
in my opinion, without proper consultation.
It is since the adoption of electroshock,
as a means of punishment
that the phenomenon,
I can't think of a better word,
have become so difficult to contain.
Dr. Gregg...
...then tried to break
into the observation room.
We took the decision to wake him up,
but we couldn't.
It was impossible,
as though he were in some sort of a trance.
There's a junction
with a duct going straight up.
- You reckon we could climb it?
- I think so.
I'll go get Jay.
Jay?
Jay, you in there?
Jay, sweetheart.
Do you believe we have a soul, Holly?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
When we were kids, me and Josh,
we used to put these playing cards
on top of the bookcase in my room,
so that if I was really floating around,
I could see what was up there.
Floating around?
There was this period
where I used to have these dreams
and I would sort of just float up
out of my body.
- Were you scared?
- No.
It was beautiful. I felt so free.
There are people that would do anything
just for the chance
to float up out of their lives,
even for just a second.
Some people, they try so hard and it's like,
no matter what they do
they never get a chance.
Josh.
He was always in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
He wasn't bad. He was making it work.
He was pulling it together.
He...
He really was.
Orin Kiefer. He was in a cell for 15 years.
Before that he was in asylum.
Before that he was in hell.
Mother. His mother,
she used to scour his mouth.
I don't want to hear it.
- To stop him from singing, she...
- I don't want to hear it!
Can you imagine being seven years old
and wanting to do that, and then doing it?
Jay.
At San Quentin they had him
in a 10 by 12 cement cell,
with no windows,
locked down 23 hours a day.
- Look, we're getting out of here.
- Don't you see what I'm saying?
Can you imagine how attractive
the thought of floating away would be
to someone forced to live like that?
We're out of here.
They've been studying him for years,
starting with the Stanford Research Institute
remote viewing program.
Remote viewing. What's that?
The National Security Council,
the Defense Intelligence Agency, the CIA.
They all kicked in funds.
Project codename: Sun Streak.
What's remote viewing?
It's where you see things
when you are not really there.
- Oh, like a form of clairvoyance.
- A form of bullshit.
Yeah, it's bullshit, but the CIA spent
over $70 million doing research.
- They officially shut it down in '95.
- Why?
Leaks, embarrassing revelations.
It's all in here.
They brought Kiefer into the program in '99.
They thought he was a freak of nature.
They could do
whatever they wanted with him.
They were drugging him, making incisions,
rewiring his brain.
They put him in a coma.
They used electroshock therapy
to control him.
Control him? The guy's strapped in a chair.
Peter.
Peter?
Peter, are you okay?
Talk to us, dude!
He wouldn't have left without us.
Oh, shit. The cellar door's open.
Bug, don't. Maybe it wasn't Peter.
Down here.
Peter?
- Peter, are you down there?
- It's okay.
- Everything's okay.
- Peter?
Peter?
My flashlight's dying.
Peter, please.
- Shit.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Shit.
No! No!
Please don't hurt me.
Get away from me. Please!
Please! Stay away from me.
Son of a bitch!
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Peter?
The psycho's dead.
It's over.
It's going to be okay.
Come on. Come on. Shit, come on!
Come on, Peter, it's okay.
We're going to get out of here.
Okay. It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, let's go. Come on. Come on.
Peter?
Run! Run! Run!
Come on, hurry up!
Quick, get in the room!
- Holly, open the door.
- Holly!
- Open the door!
- Holly, please!
- Please!
- Open the door!
Open it!
He's gone.
Listen.
- No!
- Josh!
- No, Jay. No! Let him go!
- No!
- I got to get out of here!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Bug. Don't.
When Peter fell asleep
something happened to him.
He went nuts, is what happened.
He attacked the psycho and went crazy.
- He dreams. People walk. Sleeping people.
- He dreams them.
- Dreams through them.
- Oh, boy.
Come on, Jay, don't tell me
you believe that bullshit.
I saw the files.
Maybe there's a way
to keep a person at the brink of death,
- suspended outside the body.
- Unable to pass over to the other side.
Unable to come back.
My God.
You're serious.
- Was Peter asleep when you left him?
- Maybe. I guess, but...
Look, we watched him.
He bit his goddamn tongue off.
I mean, that's going to wake you up, right?
- Not if you're in a coma.
- Peter's not in a coma.
Come on, Jay, it's autosuggestion.
A response to this freak.
I mean, we all know the story of how he lost
his goddamn tongue, and so now we're...
I saw a tape. There was this guy.
He was a scientist.
He said he couldn't wake him up.
I think he's talking
about the man in the basement.
Maybe that's what happened to Peter.
Oh, this is crazy.
- We find him.
- We what?
We find Peter, and we tie him up.
What the hell are you talking about?
Didn't you just see what I saw?
He's like a total psycho maniac.
He's quiet now.
When he's not dreaming, he's quiet.
- I saw a ladder in the basement.
- No way.
We are not opening that door!
For all we know,
he's on the other side wide awake.
How long can you stay awake?
An hour? A day? Two days?
What happens when you fall asleep?
Okay. Okay.
So, let me get this straight.
You think that if we fall asleep,
this guy's soul,
- something gets into...
- Gets into, tunes into, I don't know.
Incubus.
Say what?
A demon that enters into your sleep.
It's what they call it.
Jesus.
Demons now.
So, if you're right,
and I'm saying "if" to make it perfectly clear
that I'm not buying
into this bullshit for a second.
If you're right,
all we've got to do is open that door
and get the hell out of the way
while this guy uses Peter to...
Free itself.
We can test it. An experiment.
We tie one of us up
and whoever that is gets to...
Fall asleep.
- This is bullshit.
- So you won't mind trying it.
Funny thing, I'm not that tired anymore.
Anyway, what difference
is it going to make?
- It's not going to help us get out of here.
- Wrong.
If we're right, when he stops dreaming,
Peter stops walking.
For how long, Jay?
Look, duration of cycle.
The last one was about...
twenty minutes.
Enough time to get the ladder
from the basement.
It won't work.
If this thing is inside Peter
how do you know
it's going to get inside one of us?
Maybe it'll leave Peter.
Like it left the psycho
when Peter fell asleep.
You don't know that.
Bug, we don't know anything.
Okay. Just so long as
we're not opening that door.
So, who wants to have a nightmare?
It can't be Bug. He's too strong.
It would be too risky.
You're the smallest.
The weakest.
You wake me up as soon as...
As soon as anything happens,
you wake me up.
I promise.
Her teeth. We need a gag for her mouth.
This is going to be really uncomfortable.
Holly. Holly. Holly, wake up.
You did good, Holly.
Holly? Holly?
She can't breathe! Holly?
- Holly, just keep calm.
- She can't breathe!
Get it off! Get it off! Get it off!
Oh, my God!
No!
She's trying to kill you! Holly, stop.
No! Bug, stop!
- You're killing Holly.
- No!
It's not Holly! It's Kiefer!
She was... She was going to kill you.
We have to leave.
It's what he wanted.
To go over.
Whatever it is out there, we find it
and we rip its fucking head off.
Come on.
The ladder, it was right there. I know it was.
It's Peter, Jay. What are we going to do?
Kill him.
Bug?
- It's Peter.
- Guys!
Go!
No!
Oh, God!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Bug.
It's me,
Peter,
your friend.
Peter. Peter.
No. Oh, God.
Oh, Bug!
Bug! Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- Jay-Jay.
- Oh, God.
Jay-Jay.
I'm coming.
Coming to get you, girl.
Dreaming about being inside you, girl.
Don't you want to play?
When I want you
And all your charms
All I have to do is dream
Dream, dream, dream
Hey, Jay-Jay?
Jay-Jay.
Jay-Jay!
Don't you be playing with me, Jaybird.
You think you're getting out?
You're going straight to hell.
Jay,
please
don't leave me.
Got to help me.
Jay.
Please.
Jay-Jay.
Kill me.
Please.
Miss, what the hell went on in here?
Hey.
I'm glad you're okay.
What's the matter, girl, cat got your tongue?