These days Girls are accepting Fb requestst
for celebraty photos than our original photos
recently i uploaded my photo as profile on
fb i didnt even got one like
Dude take a good pic at this location i will
stand here
are you mad dont you get better location than
this
Come on dude....
ok
Smile     some left    more smile  ya  like that   ya ya   ready  dont move
Ahhh
What happend
carry on
uh uh take it
ya ya taking just wait...
heeeee
Dude are you kidding me
I saw someone behind you
where,,,,,,what the hell u seen here
Something behind you ah ah
Check it dude nothing is here
Come on dude just one photo
ok yah sorry
hum
make it fast
teja what happend ,,,,,,,,,,        there is someone behind
you
what u saw their
there is something behind you
right behind you ohhh my god
their is no one teja
trust me their is some one behind you
no one is there dude come,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,,, on no no no there
is someone behind you
nothing  is there see
what the f*** man
ohhh Shit
"mobile ringing"
wait not alone
Screaming
wat the hell is it
I think it willl kill us
we are dying today
No no i dont want to
it just going to kill usss
for sure it will kill us
Nothing like that dude i dont want to die to this f*** wierd  thing....
ahhahh   the ringtone has stopped lets take
our mobile and run from this shit.............