Hyde, Jekyll, Me
Episode 14
[Robin]
- Robin.
- Hi, Doctor Yoon.
- I'm here.
- Okay.
Can I come up right now?
Yes, come on up.
Okay.
As of today, balloons are
strictly forbidden.
The marble.
There was a marble.
Robin has figured it out.
Lee Soo Hyun is...
Doctor Yoon Tae Joo.
How about doing it like this?
You said that you're not very
susceptible to hypnotism, right?
Is it really Doctor Yoon Tae Joo?
He just pressed the doorbell.
- Robin?
- Yes.
Is it you?
Are you Lee Soo Hyun?
Come on in.
Have a seat.
Would you like a cup of tea?
Yes, please.
You're saying that you remember
Goo Seo Jin's memory of the kidnapping?
Yes, I only remembered parts of it before,
but I remember pretty much everything now.
Doctor Kang told me something before.
That I was created by Seo Jin because of
the trauma he received from being kidnapped.
Which means that his kidnapping
was how I got my beginning.
But Seo Jin rarely ever talked about
what happened to him.
Because he and I have spent
all these years as enemies.
Then what you're remembering now is
something that you had no recollection of?
Yes.
From what I've been able to tell
he hasn't been able to completely forget
the trauma of what's happened
and still retains some of those
memories.
- Yes, but what does that mean?
- It means...
when he was taken back to the warehouse
and had to relive his kidnapping incident
all his old memories came
rushing back to him...
and it seems that he wasn't
quite able to handle that.
So that's why he passed those
memories onto me...
Yes, that's right.
He's gone back into hiding.
I'm not sure... if those memories
are even worth hiding from.
- Excuse me?
- Ah...
Granted, it's different for
Seo Jin and I.
Since I have no way of knowing how these
memories are perceived from Seo Jin's end.
What is it that you've remembered?
That's...
It's a bit of a mess.
Parts of the memories are very clear,
but other parts are very fuzzy.
Okay, then let's get them
all out in the open.
Let's see if we can get you to remember
everything that happened that day.
The reason why you came to be...
and why Goo Seo Jin has disappeared.
Hypnosis?
He's suggesting hypnosis.
Okay, he's going to start the hypnosis.
Shall we get started?
I need you to focus.
I'm going to count to three.
One.
Two.
Three.
Robin?
You don't think he's
really hypnotized, do you?
December 25, 1992.
It's Christmas Day.
You are at Wonderland Park.
- What are you doing right now?
- I'm standing around.
- Where?
- In front of the Ghost House.
- Shall we go inside?
- No.
- Why not?
- I'm waiting.
- Waiting for whom?
- A friend.
- Why?
- Because he told me to come.
- To the Ghost House?
- He's there.
- Your friend is there?
- Yes.
- I'm going inside.
- Okay.
Go on in.
- And you'll soon be kidnapped, right?
- I'm being dragged away.
Are you sure he's not
really hypnotized?
- You're being dragged away?
- Yes.
- With your friend?
- Together?
- Yes.
No, that's not right.
Seo Jin was dragged off first, and
Soo Hyun grabs onto the kidnapper.
Soo Hyun asks the kidnapper
why he's dragging Seo Jin away.
Soo Hyun continues to cling onto the kidnapper
even after being shoved and kicked away.
'Mister, please don't do this
to Seo Jin!'
That's where things start to differ.
Between your memories...
and my memories.
Don't you agree?
Yes, that's right.
You're wondering how I
know all this?
That's because...
- You are...
- I'm...
I'm your friend...
Lee Soo Hyun.
I had my doubts...
but how can this actually be true?
We've got him!
Get in there!
Ha Na, stay here where it's safe.
I've been wanting to meet with you.
I wanted to resolve everything.
All the resentment and rage that
I've been tormented by all these years...
But the thing that angers me
the most...
is that even though I've so desperately...
been waiting for this
exact moment all my life...
Why is it that I'm having to speak to
Robin, whom you're hiding behind...
instead of saying this
to your face directly?
Soo Hyun.
Lee Soo Hyun.
Goo Seo Jin?
Come quickly!
We're heading up right now,
so block all access to the elevator!
The police have the outside surrounded.
They just heard our whole conversation,
and they also know that you're Lee Soo Hyun.
Shut up.
It isn't going to end like this.
It's the police!
Open up!
Lee Soo Hyun, open the door!
It's all over now.
Just accept it.
This could be our last chance to talk.
The first and the last time...
that we'll get to talk face-to-face.
Lee Soo Hyun, open the door!
I think we're going to have to
break through the door.
- Call 119 for backup.
- Yes, sir.
- Call 119 immediately.
- Lee Soo Hyun, open the door!
First, I'd like to apologize.
I sincerely apologize.
For what I did to you
and for all the years that I've lived my
life without remembering the past.
Apologize?
This is your idea of a sincere apology?
Apologizing to you wasn't
my only purpose for coming here.
Then you're waiting for me
to apologize back?
- I have nothing to apologize to you for.
- No.
- I came to resolve something.
- Solve what?
The young kids you and I once used to be
after having been hurt and left abandoned.
And our lives that got
destroyed after that incident.
But in order for that to happen,
we both need to know...
the real truth behind
what happened that day.
What happened?
Why did it turn off?
Director Goo?
Director Goo!
- Is 119 on their way?
- Yes, they're on their way right now.
- So you really didn't know?
- Know what?
You didn't call me
out there on purpose, right?
- You weren't in on it too, right?
- In on what?
Your father.
You didn't know that your father
was the kidnapper's co-conspirator?
Don't make me laugh.
- That never happened.
- Are you sure?
No, it didn't!
Stop trying to make up stories.
You're actually implying that
my father was the culprit?
- I'm saying that we were victimized.
- Victimized?
Victims?
Who gave you the right to
call yourself a victim?
You ran away that day, and
you haven't lost anything in your life
so how can you be the victim?
Because none of us wanted
that to happen!
You and I both... experienced something
that neither one of us wanted to.
So...
you're saying that my father is responsible
for everything that happened?
No.
My father has never abandoned me.
The only person that abandoned us...
was your father.
Open the door!
Lee Soo Hyun, open the door!
- So what is it that you want?
- We were just little kids.
Just two little kids who were abandoned
by none other than our own fathers.
No, that's not true.
- Not me.
- It's okay to admit it.
Even if you admit it and accept it...
both of us ultimately survived
in the end.
No matter how difficult it was,
and torturous it may have been...
isn't the fact that we're both still alive
what really matters?
And more importantly, the
lives we both still have left to live.
What a joke.
I'm sure you just need an excuse
to carry on with your life.
There's no evidence to prove
that my father did any of those things.
You're just going off of
what you think you remember.
And for me to trust any
of those memories in your head?
You are just too untrustworthy.
All you did was manipulate
the memories in your head.
So that you can just run away again.
To be honest, there are times
when I still doubt myself.
Because just like you said, I
wonder if I'm just fabricating something
in my head for me to hide behind again.
Because I've spent my whole life
blaming and doubting myself.
That's why I want to verify it
beyond the shadow of a doubt.
Give me the answer that I seek.
You weren't in on it?
- And you really don't remember?
- No, I don't remember.
That is my honest answer.
This is your final warning!
Open the door!
Lee Soo Hyun!
I think the time for our
face-to-face conversation is over.
Doctor Kang is here.
Go find her.
Doctor Kang... is here?
- Is 119 not here yet?
- What's the status on 119?
- They've just arrived in the lobby.
- Tell them to hurry and get up here!
Doctor Kang.
Get him!
Lee Soo Hyun!
He's headed down the emergency
stairwell. Block him!
Stop right there!
Lee Soo Hyun!
He got on the elevator from the
fifth floor, and he's headed down.
He's still in the building.
Freeze!
Slowly get down on the ground,
and place your hands on your head.
You're all familiar
with this song, aren't you?
You're all...
familiar with this song, aren't you?
Keep up the good work.
Wait... what are you even
saying right now?
How could you have lost him!
- It was the song.
- The song?
- What song?
- The song he used during our hypnotherapy.
He must've used the song
to hypnotize us in some way.
He's right, we couldn't even
move a muscle.
Director Goo!
Doctor Kang.
Are you okay?
Are you hurt anywhere?
Why did you turn off the wire?
You promised you wouldn't do that.
What if something happened to you?
- Oh my, I guess love knows no bounds.
- How did it go?
Um...
He got away.
We're canvassing all surrounding areas
and now that we know who the culprit is,
we're going to send out an APB...
- We're focusing everything...
- Doctor Yoon Tae Joo is Lee Soo Hyun?
Seo Jin, I really am sorry about this.
Wow...
I should've picked up on it since I'm better
at noticing things than most people.
The truth is,
I had a gut feeling about the guy.
Anyway, I'm so relieved to hear
that Doctor Kang is still alive and well.
It's all my fault.
I jumped the gun too early.
When I found out that Doctor Yoon Tae Joo
was really Lee Soo Hyun
I thought that the mere fact
that both of you were still alive
was enough to forgive each other
and mend your relationship.
But you didn't know about the piece
of memory that I had forgotten.
Lee Soo Hyun is in the exact
same boat.
He's selectively erased any parts of his
memory that he couldn't bear to accept.
As it is with anyone, the greatest pain
you feel are those that you allow to fester.
What you've done is turned that pain
into self-blame
and Lee Soo Hyun turned it into
feelings of rage and revenge.
As for the matter of Soo Hyun's father,
I haven't been able to verify it yet.
Soo Hyun vehemently denied it,
and I'm only going off of my memories.
- But what if it turns out to be the truth?
- Then it'll become very dangerous.
For him to admit and accept the truth now...
He's already gone too far for that.
Even though his start
may have been accidental
he's still a criminal now,
and his life is already ruined.
- He now has nothing else left to lose.
- No.
There is still one thing left.
He still has one weapon left
that he can use to attack you.
You have to stop him from that.
Come in.
I was told that you need to
get your blood pressure tested.
- Are you Jang Ha Na?
- Yes.
I know I must've caused you
a great deal of trouble lately.
- Thank you for everything.
- No, not at all.
If anything, I'm just
grateful that you're safe.
And I'm even more grateful that
you've remained by Seo Jin's side.
- Doctor Kang has been found?
- Yes!
Director Goo, Robin, and Ha Na have
pieced together all the clues
and they came up with the plan
to solve everything!
They've even figured out that
Doctor Yoon is the real Lee Soo Hyun.
What? Yoon Tae Joo?
Doctor Kang's pupil?
Yes, the police have issued
a nationwide arrest warrant for him.
His face has been known everywhere,
and there's nowhere for him to escape to.
- I'm sure he'll soon be captured.
- And also...
- Director Goo hadn't disappeared.
- What?
What does that mean?
He tricked us?
Yes, that's what it means.
I actually feel pretty disappointed.
But don't you remember
what Doctor Minsky told us?
That Director Goo's disappearance
was the most important sign.
Yes, he did say that.
He said the danger would've been if he
continued to keep disappearing like that
but since he never actually disappeared,
there's no real threat of any danger.
I'm begging you, Chairman Goo.
Your constant desire to send him overseas,
and locking him up in a hospital...
Please stop saying things like that.
Secretary Kwon,
you really are starting to sound...
Director Goo.
Even though it was only for
a short moment...
I think I'm actually
able to understand you now.
I've been putting my trust and
faith into Doctor Yoon all this time...
but the moment that I realized
that he really is Lee Soo Hyun...
I felt like I couldn't trust anyone
anymore.
I felt so stupid and pathetic for
all the things that I had believed in...
and it made me feel like I'm clueless
when it comes to knowing who people are.
But in your case...
it was your father, and
the closest friend that you had.
And to know that
it was your friend's father...
Had I been in your shoes
I don't know if I would've been
able to survive like you had.
You've done... really well for yourself.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Having someone in the room with me
while I left Robin a message...
I never would've even imagined it.
I finally met with Lee Soo Hyun.
And we were also fortunate enough
to safely rescue Doctor Kang.
Even though we weren't
able to capture Lee Soo Hyun
now that we know who he is,
we should soon be able to capture him.
Thank you.
I sincerely mean that.
Even though we only
accomplished half the goal
we still wouldn't have been
able to do it without your help.
But there's one thing
that I'm still unhappy about.
And that's the fact that this is the only
way for the two of us to face each other.
The marble.
There was a marble.
I think I know who Lee Soo Hyun is.
Lee Soo Hyun is Doctor Yoon Tae Joo.
Was it really difficult?
What is it?
What are you dreaming about?
Your father was
the kidnapper's co-conspirator.
We were just little kids that were abandoned
by none other than our own fathers.
No, that's not true.
You both experienced a living nightmare
that's tough to handle.
Do you think Seo Jin was the only one
who wanted to forget?
I'm different.
I'm different from Goo Seo Jin.
That can't be true.
[A nationwide APB issued for
kidnapper, Lee Soo Hyun.]
The culprit responsible for the kidnapping
of Doctor Kang Hee Ae
and for the kidnapping of
Wonder Group's Goo Seo Jin
has been identified as Lee Soo Hyun.
So the police haven't caught him yet,
and he's on the run?
Yes, it sounds like it. What if
he threatens my sweeties again?
The phone you are trying to reach
has been turned off...
Robin, it's me.
Can you please call Woo Jung?
She's very worried about you, and
it worries me to see Woo Jung so worried.
So please make sure to
call her back, okay?
Isn't that what you were
going to do yourself?
- Yeah, but why...
- Why do you think?
I'm trying to stake my claims.
His real name is Lee Soo Hyun,
and he's 33 years in age.
He's a US citizen, and there
aren't any records of his adoption.
He's just listed as the son of Yoon Sung Mi,
a Korean-American immigrant.
Then the reason why we couldn't find anything
on him was because he's a US citizen?
Yes, that's correct.
During Doctor Kang Hee Ae's tenure
at Johns Hopkins Hospital back in 2011
they worked together in
the research program for two years.
It's estimated that's when he started to
formulate his revenge plans on Lee Soo Hyun
and it was with that purpose in mind
that he intentionally approached Doctor Kang.
He came to Korea with Doctor Kang
in 2013 when she made her return
and he secured his position at
Hankyeol Hospital as its resident professor.
After confiscating Lee Soo Hyun's computer
and having searched through it
it's been noted that he ran a search on
Goo Seo Jin on a daily basis.
As you can also see, all the key search words
are also related to Goo Seo Jin.
- So he carefully premeditated his plans?
- Yes, that's correct.
What else have you identified?
There are actually two office spaces
that are listed under his name
so we're searching nearby
both those places.
But we haven't been able to
locate him yet.
Something odd that we've noticed
upon checking through his call logs
is that he doesn't have any friends.
He doesn't have any friends,
or anyone else that he keeps in contact with.
The only people that he's been
in recent contact with are Goo Seo Jin,
Jang Ha Na, and Ahn Sung Goon.
With only those three on the call list,
the rest is pretty obvious.
Thus, with our current bit of information,
we can only rely on the tips that comes in.
First, we must secure the safety of
Goo Seo Jin, and Jang Ha Na's surroundings
- and the kidnapper...
- Jung Man Shik.
Yeah, and he's at
Taeyang hospital, correct?
Call and alert the hospital.
The chances are pretty high that
he'll be targeting there next.
Yes, sir.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
What was that all about?
Lee Soo Hyun, the guy on
the wanted list...
I guess he may be targeting the hospital,
so they want us to stay alert.
- He needs to be taken for his CAT scan.
- Okay, hang on.
Can you please lower
your face mask?
I said, I need you to lower
your face mask.
What's taking so long in there?
Here he comes.
We had to give him some sedatives due
to an adverse effect that he had to the dye.
- Leave him to get some rest.
- Yes, I understand.
During the life I've led
since the kidnapping...
I've really endured a lot.
But...
I didn't think that I'd be able to
endure ever having to see you again...
So I tried to make an effort
to never see you again.
I was simply...
going to let you rot away
for the rest of your life in prison...
for the crime of murder that you're not
aware of as a price for your sins.
But I don't think that's going
to be enough.
That's not enough of a price
for your sins.
What?
They're sure that it was Jung Man Shik
that went in for the scan
but it was the scan technician
who came back out.
It seems Lee Soo Hyun was hiding
in the scan room.
That's why I made the phone call
for them to keep a close eye on him!
They couldn't recognize that it was
a different person
just because of some bandages
on his face?
What if he used hypnosis on them?
If he hypnotized them
like he did to us the other night
then they would've been
rendered helpless.
That was that post-hypnotic response
or whatever that he did to us.
Don't you remember?
'You're all familiar
with this song, aren't you?'
Was that a universal hypnosis
signal or what?
Every single person is susceptible to it!
Then... we've just been had again?
At this point, doesn't it seem right
that we submit our letter of resignation?
But I'm going to maintain my position,
and I vow to capture him with my own hands.
Lee Soo Hyun...
kidnapped Jung Man Shik?
I'm sure it was because he wanted to
verify the story I told him.
Yes, he's completely obsessed with you.
Now that he's got Jung Man Shik
we have no way of predicting
what he'll do next.
Which makes me want to tighten the level
of security for you and Jang Ha Na even more.
- How would you like to proceed with that?
- No, it's okay.
We've already got a
tight security system in place.
Yes, I figured you would already
with your amount of money and power.
But the one I'm really worried about
is Jang Ha Na.
- Where is Jang Ha Na staying right now?
- At my house.
I see... What?
I'm saying, we're living together.
Ah... I forgot that you two
had a budding relationship.
Yes, I see.
We'll take care of things on our end,
so no need to worry about us.
We just won't
step foot out of the house.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Are you still asleep?
Are you... not feeling well?
I need you to go out to get some
porridge and hot beverages.
- Why? Is Ha Na ill?
- She has a fever.
I have all the medication here,
so go out and get some food.
Yes, sir.
You're awake.
Are you feeling really sick?
Should I call for a doctor?
No, it's okay.
It's just a little exhaustion.
Just stay down.
Your temperature isn't too high.
What was it that the doctor
told you?
Keep the body warm
once all the sweat dries off...
I've got the warm barley tea
right here...
Keep that held in your hands.
I'm sorry.
I'm sure you were feeling
just as nervous as I was last night
and I didn't even think about
how it may have affected you.
And top of it all... I'm sure you must've
felt quite shocked about Doctor Yoon.
I was wrong.
I should've taken care of you better.
Eun Chang?
I'm actually glad you called.
Starting today, Leader Jang won't be
coming into work for a while.
- Yes, it's because of the culprit.
- Hand me the phone.
Manage by yourselves at work, and call
Secretary Kwon if you have any problems.
Carry on.
Director Goo.
You can't go into work for a while.
I'm being serious.
- Why not?
- Because Lee Soo Hyun....
just kidnapped our kidnapper.
I've got the house under tight security,
so just stay inside.
There's no need for you to worry.
Get some rest.
This is the first time I've taken
any time off in years.
And like I said...
I want to do the things that
my heart has been wanting to do.
Let's take our time...
and do them all together.
By any chance...
last night...
No, never mind.
11:50 PM...
7:40 AM...
Almost eight hours...
No, I did the right thing.
What I did was right.
Ha Na is sick.
Were you not aware that
she's sick?
If you had known about it,
then you definitely should've told me.
You know that, don't you?
She's sick?
- Robin?
- Ha Na!
Are you sick?
Have you taken any medicine,
or eaten anything?
I took some medicine earlier, and had
the porridge Director Goo brought me.
Figures Goo Seo Jin would do this.
Just stay in bed, and I'll be right back.
Young Chan, it's me.
Can you go grocery shopping for me?
I need beef, abalone, a bottle of red wine...
and all sorts of fresh fruit.
Yes, like strawberries.
Okay, thanks.
Robin?
What are you doing?
Did you see the message that Director Goo
had left for you yesterday?
Rule number one.
While you're with me, any mention of Seo Jin,
Goo Seo Jin, Director Goo, or the Director...
will not be allowed.
Rule number two.
The next 12 hours belongs to
me, and me only.
I know it's night, but either sleep less,
or take a nap during the day.
I want all your attention during my hours.
What else?
Don't laugh.
That's rule number three.
I still don't agree with what you said.
So don't think that
you can just glaze over the issue.
Because I'm going to wait
until I get the answer.
I'm sorry for having
fallen asleep on you last night.
I know that you came to me last night.
And thanks to you, I slept really well.
Then why are you sick?
It upsets me that you're sick.
Don't you think it's actually odd
that I haven't even been sick once?
Ever since I've been back in Korea
I don't think there's been a single
peaceful and uneventful day.
I almost died several different times
and every one of those times, you
appeared out of nowhere and saved me.
So why don't we...
both get some rest?
Come with me.
- Did you spray something on?
- Huh?
- Why do you ask?
- Because you smell like roses.
It's okay.
So go on and tell me.
My father...
what happened that day...
Did you conspire the
kidnapping together?
What did you just say?
Say it again.
What? Who did you
say was your co-conspirator?
My father is not that
type of a person.
He passed away while
he was on his way to come save me.
He's not someone who'd do
such a thing with an asshole like you!
It's okay.
I just want the truth.
- No.
- What?
- I said, it's not true.
- What's not true?
You have to choose your
answer wisely.
Your life isn't the only thing
that's hanging on the line anymore.
I'm being honest, it's not true.
Tell me exactly what it is
that you're saying isn't true.
- What happened back then...
- Tell me what you're referring to!
I'm saying...
that we didn't conspire together.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
My father...
- had nothing to do with it?
- That's right.
My father...
- wasn't your co-conspirator?
- That's right!
My father...
- wasn't in on any of it?
- That's right.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Are you sure!
- Yes!
That asshole!
- A tip?
- He bought medical supplies at a pharmacy.
Detectives Kim and Detective Lee
went out to investigate the tip.
- To where?
- Gangdong District.
Cotton gauze, and senefol,
which is an antiseptic.
He also bought compression bandages,
and other dressings.
- Seeing those purchases...
- It's to treat injuries.
- It must be for Jung Man Shik.
- It would seem so.
Then it must mean that
he hasn't killed Jung Man Shik.
According to Goo Seo Jin,
Lee Soo Hyun is trying to verify something.
But what is it that he's trying to verify?
- By any chance, was it this guy?
- Yes, this is him.
- This was the guy.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm positive.
- Great, thank you.
There's no need to be scared.
It's not time for you to die yet.
We have...
a great deal of things
we've yet to do.
- The express bus terminal?
- Yes.
He bought a laptop from a express
bus terminal in Sangdo earlier this morning.
- The use of his credit card was alerted.
- He's openly using his own credit cards?
These are Lee Soo Hyun's known
whereabouts for the past two days.
He was spotted at a pharmacy
in Kangdong two days ago.
Then he was spotted at an
express bus terminal the next morning.
Then at a convenience store in Ahnsung.
Next, at a gas station in Iksan.
Then at a restaurant in Daegu.
And finally, we traced him at a
convenience store in Busan this morning.
As you can see, the path shows
that he's traveling southward.
We've been able to trace his path
by his use of his personal credit cards.
But I'm sure that he's aware we'd be
able to trace his whereabouts like that.
Don't you think that's strange?
And why do you think
he's continuing to travel south?
I doubt that he even
has any connections down there.
Detective Jang, head down to Busan.
We've already requested for local backup.
We'll just have to wait and see.
- Busan?
- Yes.
His last whereabouts were
traced down to Busan.
- Can you think of why?
- No, not at all.
- What is all this?
- What do you mean?
- My fridge is filled to the brim.
- Ah, that?
Robin asked me to go
grocery shopping for him.
- Why?
- He's actually a pretty good cook.
It seems he cooked a huge feast for Ha Na
when he found out that she was feeling ill.
Yes, Chairman Goo.
I'm headed over to the house right now.
Yes, Director Goo seems to be holding up
much better than we had expected.
I'll call you back and
let you know how he's doing.
What was that?
Let's have dinner.
Have a seat.
You're not going to sit down?
Is this... what I think it is?
Are you doing this
because of what Robin did?
No, it's not like that.
I just thought we could have
dinner together.
Secretary Kwon is heading in.
You said you felt like
you were dreaming, right?
When you had first
found out about my illness.
It's like a dream to me, too.
The times that I spent with you as Robin
are like dreams that I'm unable to remember.
But you remember those times.
You remember the events in my dreams
that I'm unable to remember.
I want to remember them with you.
- How?
- I want you to tell me about them.
The things I say to you
when I'm Robin...
and how it is that
I make you laugh and smile.
And also, how it is...
that I show my love for you.
The power must've gone out.
Don't worry, it'll be back on soon.
You and I...
we still have some truths
left to uncover.
[Without an invitation,
and without permission...]
Subtitles by DramaFever