Ju-On is the curse of a person
who died with a deep grudge.
This grudge is accumulated in the place where
that person lived and becomes its "Karma".
Whoever gets in contact with this curse
loses his life and a new curse is born.
This noon at around 12:10...
in the prefecture Suginami, Tokyo,
in the residence of Yoshieki Matsuoka...
the corpses of Yoshieki, his wife Mariko
and their son Takashi had been found.
Mr. Matsuoka, Mariko and Takashi had lost
pints of blood because of exterior injuries.
Numerous wounds on the dead bodies...
Foul play is suspected in those deaths.
In the afternoon of the same day
the investigations were...
It seems to happen in
the night of the 21st...
Until further details should be revealed,
every piece of evidence of this case
suggests a crime of passion.
Matsuoka, as their neighbors
have described, was...
Ju-On: Girl in Black
Yes, yes.
That cruel family massacre.
I'm standing right in front of
the house where it happened.
It's so scary here!
What? Me?
Are you crazy? I don't do things like that.
But say: Do you come today?
[Tetsuya]
Hello.
So she DOES have a lover.
Shit!
What's that?
I don't hear anything.
But it's true.
Have you eavesdropped on your neighbor?
Definitely not.
So, how's your neighbor?
I've already seen her, she's really beautiful.
So what's her job?
She's a nurse.
Unfortunately, I think you don't
have a chance with her, Tetsuya.
That's not what I'm talking about.
She's really strange.
Yuko.
What's wrong with you?
Yuko?
Are you already on a first-name basis?
Hey, say:
That family massacre happened here, right?
The neighbor.
Yes, so what?
Maybe she's the culprit.
What?
No way.
Exactly.
It's possible that a lady in white was the culprit.
Right?
Yes, and in the hospital she...
had been molested by a doctor and then she killed him or so.
How scary.
We'll look after your apartment till
you're back from your part time job.
But don't do anything strange here.
Don't worry. Just go.
See you.
Bye.
Come here.
No, not in his apartment.
Why not?
Yuko?
Are you OK?
What?
I've heard a strange voice...
You just worry too much...
[Yuko]
Fukie.
Are you doing that nonsense again?
How's your mother?
She was here before, but she said,
she's still got work to do.
I see.
Your mother does work really hard.
You should really model yourself on her.
And now put on your pajamas.
Hey...
For how long do I need to stay here?
Well... I don't know that, too.
We don't have the results of
the follow-up examination yet.
What's wrong with me?
My body?
My head?
It can't be anything serious
if you're still feeling so good.
I know it.
I'm going to die soon.
I see. So...
She's now in an age where
children imagine such things...
So, please continue to look after her.
She's got accustomed to you, I think.
Yes, sure.
You can send her mother home now.
Call her when we've got the results
of the follow-up examination.
You may go now, Mrs. Yokota.
I'll call it a day.
Yes, have a nice evening.
Bye.
What?
See? There's nothing.
Sorry to wake you up.
Sleep tight.
Hello.
Yuko.
Are you on your way home?
Yes.
I'm on the way to my part time job.
I see.
Good luck!
Are you OK?
What?
Are you dreaming?
Sorry.
Would you please switch
supervising room 3035 with me?
What?
Fukie's room?
Do you still worry about it?
Well...
Fukie likes you most. She would be very sad.
Don't worry...
Fukie...
Stop that nonsense!
[Ayano]
Scary, isn't it?
These are hard times we're living in.
Maybe an accident...
Or was it a crime?
Oh... sorry...
Please stop at the next traffic light.
On this side?
Understood.
Don't you need to go further?
It's OK, it's not far from here.
Aya...
How is it?
Can I offer you a drink?
I need to go to work tomorrow.
Here, the money for the taxi.
Oh, never mind!
But it was me who called the taxi.
Then...
Is this really OK?
Yes, see you tomorrow.
But be careful, it's very dark.
Thank you very much.
You're even more dangerous!
Boss?
Please answer!
[Fukie]
Miss teacher!
Fukie!
Are you OK?
How are you?
It was just a light anemia.
Are you OK now?
Dad is here!
Fukie! How are you?
How was work today?
There was nothing important to do, so I went earlier.
Have you already eaten, Fukie?
No, not yet.
Poor thing...
Didn't they let you eat?
So, shall we go out for food today?
Fukie collapsed in school today.
Really?
It was just a light anemia.
I see.
So, shall we go to the steak house?
Or do you want Yakiniku?
No, we'll eat here today.
But you can cook tomorrow.
It's always the same with you...
What did you say?
Fukie.
With these hands you're going to kill that woman.
Fukie...
Would you please come, Mrs. Yokota?
You wait here, Fukie. OK?
There seems to be nothing wrong with her brain.
Then...
It seems to be a psychic problem...
A psychic problem?
Caused by stress in her familiar surroundings.
This happens often with children at her age.
OK, let's start, Fukie.
There's no need to be nervous.
Relax.
Take a deep breath.
Look at my hand.
And while you're doing that,
you'll listen to my voice, yes?
You don't need to talk.
Just answer within your heart.
Relax.
Imagine...
that you're floating on a big, big ocean.
Your body...
is sinking down in the ocean.
it's not difficult to breath.
You're feeling much lighter than before.
you're sinking deeper and deeper...
and you're getting close to
the bottom of this deep ocean.
And your memories...
reach back to a time when you were much smaller.
How old are you now?
I.. am... 5...
You're 5, yes?
What do you see?
A beach.
What are you doing there?
I'm swimming with mum and dad in the sea.
So you're swimming in the sea.
It's fun.
Let's return to a time
when you were even smaller.
You're now...
inside the womb of your mother.
What do you see?
What?
Relax.
Relax!
Fukie, answer!
Doctor!
Relax, Fukie!
Fukie!
Why didn't you give birth to me?
Would you please come, Mrs. Yokota?
We now have the results
of the follow-up examination.
This here...
is on the side of Fukie's mons pubis.
It seems to be a cyst.
A cyst?
This is a really rare case...
Within the uterus they still were twins.
But for some reason...
one of them absorbed to
other one and grew up alone.
But he became a cyst and remained
inside the body of the other one.
Her twin became a part of her body
and was born that way.
Inside of Fukie's body...
Inside of the born twin, in Fukie...
the other one subsisted...
and grew up until today.
Sister...
What is it?
I wanted to talk to you about something...
About Fukie?
[Yokota]
Have you seen Ma?
My little Ma.
She's black and very cute.
Don't you know her?
I can't find her.
Let's look somewhere else.
Fujie!
It's me, Yokota.
What?
I couldn't get you on the phone.
I'm coming in.
Have you drunk something?
Maybe it's an inappropriate moment...
May I turn the lights on?
Let me go!
With these hands you're
going to kill that woman!
[Mariko]
Do you feel anything?
I can't tell on the basis of this video.
What did the doctors say?
They said she has a cyst.
Maybe you should ask some experts.
And I'm not that good anyways.
But it just won't become better.
I feel so sorry for her.
I can really understand you, but...
The cyst within her...
I had another daughter
to whom I didn't give birth.
I think this is the curse of that child!
That's why you're the only one
who can help her.
Please!
Help me!
Hey, mother...
Can I go play with Ken today?
Hey, Takashi! Say hello first!
How old is he?
He's already going to elementary school.
Won't you take the elevator?
No, an old habit.
Mariko!
Do you have a problem?
Thanks.
It's all right.
Who was that?
The nurse who's looking after Fukie.
I see.
Sister...
I'm sorry.
We'll leave it for today.
What?
I need to restart from the beginning.
Don't say that!
There's no point in doing it today.
In three days...
I'll be back in three days.
Understood.
But come under all circumstances!
Let's start.
Look at her!
It's over.
In Fukie...
was another soul...
besides her own one.
As you've said...
it was probably the cursed soul
of that unborn child.
Please pray for her.
Mariko.
Thanks.
See you, sister.
Hello.
I'm coming.
Wait for me.
Who are you?
Fukie?
No.
You're not Fukie.
You've taken her place, haven't you?
and I've banished Fukie's soul.
Run away!
[Kiwako]
Fukie...
Sister...
I'm sorry.
Take care.
I understand.
You hate us.
You hate us, because you
weren't allowed to be born.
We'll end this now.
Ma...
Ma?