Ju-on: A curse born when a person dies
in a powerful rage.
It gathers where the dead person lived,
and becomes a “stain”.
Anyone who touches it dies,
and a new curse is born.
TOEI VIDEO and CELL Present
An OZ Production
The bodies of Yoshiyuki Matsuoka,
his wife Mariko and son Takashi
were found at 10:20 am today at
their home in Suginami, Tokyo.
Produced by Taka lchise
Co-Producer Toshinori Nishimae
All three victims appear...
to have bled to death from
multiple external wounds...
Ai Kago
Koji Seto
The police set up an investigative
team the same day...
and launched a full murder enquiry.
The incident occurred on the night
of the 26th or morning of the 27th...
Yuri Nakamura
Maria Takagi
Hana Matsumoto
Yuno Nakazono
Kane Tsugihara
Kuniteru Shigeyama
Ryota Matsushima
Masanobu Katsumura
...no sign of theft, it is thought
likely to be a grudge.
According to neighbors,
the Matsuokas were...
Original JU-ON Concept Created by
Takashi Shimizu
Written and Directed by
Mari Asato
JU-ON
BLACK GHOST
Yeah, the family massacre.
I'm standing in front of the house.
It's terrifying!
What? Me?
You dope! No way!
Anyway, you coming over today?
TETSUYA
Hello.
So she does have a boyfriend.
Shit!
What the hell!
It's nothing.
I'm telling the truth.
You always listen to your
neighbor's sex life?
It wasn't like that.
What's your neighbor like?
I've seen her. A total babe!
She's a pharmacist, right?
A nurse.
What a shame, you liking her and all.
That's not the point!
There was something weird about her.
Yuko wasn't like that before.
Yuko! Were you that close to her?
Hey. Remember that family massacre?
Your next-door neighbor!
What about her?
Maybe... she's the killer!
What? No way.
A delicate girl like her might
be the killer, amazingly!
Overloaded with work,
groped by doctors... Boom!
She snaps! Kills everyone!
Scary!
We'll watch the place until
you get back.
Don't do anything stupid!
We won't. Now get going.
Bye.
Stop it! Not here!
What's wrong with here?
Yuko?
You OK?
What's wrong?
I heard a weird voice.
You're imagining things.
YUKO
Fukie?
Always fooling around!
Where's your mom?
She was just here.
She's gone to work.
Your mom is a hard worker.
You should learn from her.
Shall I change your pajamas?
When can I go home?
I'm not sure. Your latest test results
aren't back yet.
What's wrong with me?
Is it my body? Or my mind?
You're so lively, I'm sure there's
no problem.
I know.
I'm going to die soon.
She said that?
Girls her age are very imaginative.
Well, take good care of her.
She likes you.
Of course.
Tell me when her mother returns.
I have the new test results.
Yokota-san, please come in.
Good-night then.
Good-night.
What is it?
It's nothing!
Sorry to wake you. Goodnight.
Hello!
Yuko!
Are you coming home now?
Yes.
I'm going to my part-time job.
Uh, right... Work hard.
Come on! What's wrong?
Not enough sleep?
Sorry.
Can you switch with me on Room 303?
Huh? You mean Fukie?
You can't still be worrying about that?
No, it's not that.
Fukie likes you the best.
She'll be heartbroken.
But...
Don't worry about it!
Fukie?
Stop messing around!
AYANO
Pretty wild, eh? Probably because
of the recession.
Is it an accident?
Or a crime?
Can you stop at the next traffic light?
Just in front of the light?
OK.
Isn't it a bit further?
It's OK. My house is hard to find.
Ayano. How about one more drink?
No thanks. I've work tomorrow.
This is for the taxi.
Forget it.
I was the one who called the cab.
You sure?
You really OK?
See you tomorrow.
Stay out of dark alleys.
Thank you.
I'm more worried about pervs
like you!
Boss?
Say something!
FUKIE
Miss!
Fukie!
You OK? I heard you fainted?
Her blood pressure was low, that's all.
You really OK?
Dad's here!
Ah, Fukie. You alright?
What are you doing here?
I needed something for work
so I dropped by.
Fukie, have you eaten?
Not yet.
You poor thing! Nobody's fed you yet?
Shall we go out to eat?
She fainted at school today.
Ls that true?
It's just anemia.
In that case, shall we go for a steak?
Or barbecue?
You'll eat here today, right, Fukie?
Why don't you cook tomorrow?
You never change!
What now?
Fukie.
You'll kill a woman with this hand.
Fukie!
Yokota-san, please come in.
Fukie, wait there please.
The results show the brain is
quite normal.
Which means...
The problem is psychological...
Psychological?
Your daughter's symptoms are
quite common.
Often from stress in the family
environment.
Fukie, let's begin.
Yes.
Don't be nervous. Relax.
Shall we try deep breathing?
Look at my hand.
Keep looking at my hand
while you listen to me.
Yes.
No need to say anything.
Respond in your mind.
Relax.
Now, Fukie, imagine that you are
floating on a wide, wide ocean.
Your body is sinking into the ocean.
But your breathing isn't difficult at all.
In fact it's just as easy as now.
You're sinking deeper and deeper.
Until you approach the deep ocean floor.
Your memory too is going back to
your early childhood.
How old are you now?
Five... years... old.
Five. What can you see?
A sandy beach.
What are you doing on the beach?
Swimming... with mom and dad.
Right, swimming.
It's fun.
Now let's go back to when you
were even younger.
You're inside your mom's belly.
What can you see?
What's wrong? Relax...
Calm down...
Calm down!
Fukie, it's alright now.
Fukie! Fukie!
Why didn't you give birth to me?
Yokota-san, please come in.
Yes.
The new test results are back.
Can you see this?
Next to Fukie's uterus.
It's probably some kind of cystoma.
A cystoma?
It's a very rare condition.
There were twin fetuses
in the mother's body.
For some reason, one twin absorbs
the other and grows.
The other one remains
as a cystoma inside its twin.
In other words, twin sisters...
Born in the one body.
Inside Fukie?
It's thought that the born twin, Fukie...
Nurtures the unborn twin inside her.
Sis.
What is it?
I need to talk to you about something.
Is it about Fukie?
YOKOTA
Have you seen Ma?
My little Ma? He's dark and cute. No?
No.
Can't find him anywhere.
I'll look elsewhere.
Ayano. it's Yokota.
Ayano! Ayano!
Ayano.
What's wrong? Why didn't you
call in sick?
I'm coming in.
Have you seen a doctor?
You don't look good at all.
Can I turn on the light?
Ayano!
Stop it!
You'll kill a woman with this hand.
MARIKO
Can you feel anything?
Not from a video.
What does the doctor say?
A cystoma in her stomach.
A medical specialist is treating her.
I don't see how I can help.
But she's not getting any better.
I feel so sorry for Fukie.
I understand, but...
The cystoma in poor Fukie.
It's her unborn little sister.
It's probably cursed.
You're the only one who can heal her!
I beg you. Use your powers!
Mom, can I go play at Ken's house?
Takashi, where are your manners?
How old is he?
He'll start elementary in the spring.
I'll help.
You won't get the elevator?
No. it's an enclosed space.
Mariko!
Are you alright?
Thank you. We're fine.
Who's she?
She's the nurse taking care of Fukie.
Really.
I'm sorry, Kiwako,
but I can't do it today.
I'll come back another time.
Don't say that!
It's impossible today.
I'll come back in 3 days.
OK.
But promise you'll come back.
I promise.
Let's begin.
Quiet! it'll come to you.
It's finished.
There was another spirit...
Living inside Fukie.
As you said, probably the cursed
spirit of the unborn child.
You must hold the proper rites for her.
Mariko!
Thank you.
See you, Kiwako.
Hello?
I'll be over soon. Wait for me.
Who is this? Fukie?
Fukie?
No.
You're not Fukie.
You've switched!
You tricked me into casting out Fukie!
Run!
KIWAKO
Fukie.
Kiwako.
I'm sorry.
I know what's going on.
You hate us, don't you?
You begrudge me for not giving
birth to you.
Let's end it now.
Little Ma!
Executive Producer Kazuo Kato
Produced by Taka lchise
Co-Producer Toshinori Nishimae
Original JU-ON Concept Created by
Takashi Shimizu
Cinematography by
Shin Hayasaka (J.S.C.)
Art Director Shimpei Inoue
Music by Gary Ashiya
Edited by Yoshifumi Fukazawa
An OZ Production
TOEI VIDEO and CELL Present
Written and Directed by
Mari Asato
C2009 TOEI VIDEO/CELL