[Suspenseful music plays]
[Music continues]
[Birds chirping]
[Footsteps approaching]
Ada?
[Ada running]
Come on!
[Chuckles]
Come over here!
[Groans]
Come here.
Get off me!
Why?
'Cause I said!
Ain't anybody else gonna see.
Tsk! Not here!
But I'm already hard.
[Sighs]
Come on!
No! I said no!
[Groans]
Fine.
[Panting]
Why is your skin so hot, anyway?
Better go finish up the
why is your skin so hot, anyway?
still.
Better go finish up the
Wait.
Still.
I ain't got time for games.
Wait.
Back there, then.
I ain't got time for games.
You sure?
Back there, then.
Yeah.
You sure?
Come on.
Yeah.
[Suspenseful music plays]
Come on.
[Birds chirping]
[Clattering]
[Wheel rumbling]
[Moans]
[Fire crackling]
[Suspenseful music plays]
I swear your skin feels
different.
Really?
Different.
Well, it ain't.
Really?
[Chuckles]
Well, it ain't.
Just drop it already.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
Just drop it already.
[Birds chirping, dog barking]
Ada?
You come here.
Now, bodey got something to tell
you.
We're gonna be joined.
You.
Well...
We're gonna be joined.
When?
Well...
Next full moon, it'll happen.
When?
If she's been true.
Next full moon, it'll happen.
Got the papers?
If she's been true.
[Chirping continues]
May I go to the pit?
I'd like to pray on this.
Best go with her.
I-I'll go later.
Tell everyone to come on for
dinner after you've finished.
[Breathing heavily]
[Birds chirping]
[Chirping intensifies]
[Gasps]
Dawai?
What?!
Ow!
Shit fire!
What you doing?
Aah.
Nothing.
[Breathing heavily]
[Chuckles]
Oh...
The candles need lighting.
You're supposed to come on
the candles need lighting.
for dinner.
You're supposed to come on
Oh, is something -- something
for dinner.
good happening?
Oh, is something -- something
Bodey asked pa for us to be
good happening?
joined.
Bodey asked pa for us to be
Aah!
Joined.
Well, that's -- that is good
aah!
news.
Well, that's -- that is good
Bodey?
News.
He'll do right by you.
Bodey?
Want to listen to some music?
He'll do right by you.
I'll play you your favorite.
Want to listen to some music?
Can't.
I'll play you your favorite.
Got to tell everyone before it
can't.
gets late.
Got to tell everyone before it
Tomorrow?
Gets late.
Yeah, tomorrow, then.
Tomorrow?
So, you'll come for dinner?
Yeah, tomorrow, then.
I don't know.
So, you'll come for dinner?
I-I got...
I don't know.
I got things need tending to.
I-I got...
So...
I got things need tending to.
I hope you do.
[Birds chirping]
[Crank squeaking]
[Country music plays]
[Sighs]
You get to everyone?
Yep.
Anyone say they ain't coming?
Dawai's the only one that
anyone say they ain't coming?
seemed to be on the fence.
Dawai's the only one that
[Scoffs]
Seemed to be on the fence.
Figures.
[Scoffs]
You ain't spending no more time
figures.
down there, anyway.
You ain't spending no more time
I'll do what I want.
Down there, anyway.
You will do what bodey tells
I'll do what I want.
you to!
You will do what bodey tells
Now, that's the way it is.
You to!
You best get used to it!
Now, that's the way it is.
Whatever.
You best get used to it!
You got something you want to
whatever.
say?
You got something you want to
Oh, I'm just all up in knots
say?
is it.
Oh, I'm just all up in knots
Oh.
Is it.
You're dripping, then?
Oh.
Come a little late, though,
you're dripping, then?
ain't it?
Come a little late, though,
Let me see.
Ain't it?
Why? It's gross.
Let me see.
Come on, ada!
[Birds chirping]
You got that 'shine ready?
What's going on?
We got people coming over.
Bodey asked to be joined to your
we got people coming over.
sister.
Bodey asked to be joined to your
About time.
[Clears throat]
I want to, uh...
I want to thank you all for
coming.
Today I give away my only
daughter to be joined to
today I give away my only
bodey jenkin...
Daughter to be joined to
To continue in the ways that we
bodey jenkin...
hold sacred.
To continue in the ways that we
And I thank the pit with all my
hold sacred.
heart for making it so.
And I thank the pit with all my
I raise this jug of 'shine for
heart for making it so.
all to taste who believe.
[Dog barks]
I'd like to say something.
Bodey, you're getting a good
one.
I can tell you that.
One.
[Insects chirping]
I can tell you that.
Wish you all the best.
Eat up, all.
[Country music plays]
[Laughter]
No!
Do you need any help?
Just this little redheaded
do you need any help?
one.
Just this little redheaded
He's a biter!
One.
No biting!
He's a biter!
[Laughter continues]
No biting!
Don't bite!
[Laughter continues]
There we go.
Don't bite!
They're meaner than they look.
There we go.
Yeah, I'll bet.
They're meaner than they look.
[Laughs]
Yeah, I'll bet.
Shit.
[Laughs]
Shit?
Shit.
Well, jessaby, you must be real
shit?
happy.
Well, jessaby, you must be real
Shut the fuck up, you retard.
Happy.
Jessaby!
Shut the fuck up, you retard.
I want to talk to my sis
jessaby!
alone.
I want to talk to my sis
All right.
Alone.
[Country music plays in
all right.
background]
[Country music plays in
Don't.
Background]
Don't what?
Don't.
You keep your mouth shut.
Don't what?
I know.
You keep your mouth shut.
They're gonna test you, and
I know.
you better blame it on somebody
they're gonna test you, and
else.
You better blame it on somebody
I don't care who.
Else.
I ain't letting bodey take after
I don't care who.
pa 'cause of this, you hear?
I ain't letting bodey take after
We'll talk about it later.
Pa 'cause of this, you hear?
No, we won't.
We'll talk about it later.
You're on your own.
[Insects chirping]
You and sustin's all happy
now, but if she'd been fooling
around, you're gonna have to pay
up.
Around, you're gonna have to pay
Tsk.
Up.
Well, don't you worry your
tsk.
pretty, little head about it.
Well, don't you worry your
She was dripping today.
Pretty, little head about it.
Just means she ain't been
she was dripping today.
caught.
Just means she ain't been
She'll pass.
Caught.
Now leave it alone.
She'll pass.
Was your brother sad?
Now leave it alone.
About what?
Was your brother sad?
He'll be asking someone to
about what?
join him soon, won't he?
He'll be asking someone to
Want me to mention you to
join him soon, won't he?
him?
Want me to mention you to
Could you?
Him?
Take your grandpa a plate.
Could you?
It's cold.
Take your grandpa a plate.
Yeah, well, it'll have to do.
It's cold.
It's nasty, though.
Yeah, well, it'll have to do.
He won't complain.
It's nasty, though.
What was your brother all tore
he won't complain.
up about earlier?
What was your brother all tore
He's just being his ass self,
up about earlier?
as usual.
He's just being his ass self,
He don't care for bodey?
As usual.
He -- he just don't want him
he don't care for bodey?
horning in on things is all.
He -- he just don't want him
Like what?
Horning in on things is all.
I don't know.
Like what?
He wasn't making much sense.
I don't know.
Huh.
[Insects chirping,
dog barking]
Grandpa?
I got you some food.
Huh?
You've been sleeping?
[Strained] Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Are you hungry?
Mm-hmm.
I thought so.
Let's get you some air.
Either you're getting fat, or
let's get you some air.
I'm getting weaker.
Either you're getting fat, or
[Chuckles]
We had everyone over to
dinner tonight.
[Chirping continues]
Dinner tonight.
Bodey and I are gonna be joined.
[Chirping continues]
I should have seen it coming
bodey and I are gonna be joined.
already.
I should have seen it coming
Not like there's anybody else
already.
could have asked.
Not like there's anybody else
I know who the next jug face is.
Could have asked.
[Suspenseful music plays]
I know who the next jug face is.
It's me.
It's mine.
I don't even know why I told
you.
Not like you can help.
[Door creaks]
[Insects chirping]
Here we go.
[Chuckles]
What's wrong with you?
Has anyone ever said no?
About what?
Being joined?
Is that why you're so quiet?
It's a woman's job to have
is that why you're so quiet?
babies.
It's a woman's job to have
You got to be joined to do that.
Babies.
Is that all I'm good for?
You got to be joined to do that.
It's an amazing thing,
is that all I'm good for?
bearing babies -- something no
it's an amazing thing,
man will ever get to do.
Bearing babies -- something no
Once bodey gives you a little
man will ever get to do.
one, you'll be beside yourself.
Once bodey gives you a little
You'll see.
One, you'll be beside yourself.
What if I can't?
You'll see.
Oh...
What if I can't?
Pit will make it right.
Oh...
It always does.
Pit will make it right.
Has the pit ever taken a
it always does.
baby?
Has the pit ever taken a
Yeah, sure has.
Baby?
Gonna check on that possum.
Yeah, that's what.
All right.
Now don't speak to nobody.
Just get what you need, and
now don't speak to nobody.
that's it, right?
Just get what you need, and
[Birds chirping]
Morning, sustin.
What you got?
I got half peach, half apple.
They're both hot sellers
right now, I'm telling you.
[Cans clang]
Right now, I'm telling you.
Can't help you with that possum,
[cans clang]
though.
Can't help you with that possum,
That ain't for sale.
[Country music plays]
♪ not my brother's, any others ♪
♪ your heart ♪
♪ i broke... ♪
all right.
♪ I broke... ♪
Thank you so much for coming in.
All right.
You have a good day.
Thank you so much for coming in.
[Door beeps]
You have a good day.
♪ taking licks and karate kicks
[door beeps]
to every inch of my face ♪
♪ taking licks and karate kicks
♪ but I'd do it all again
to every inch of my face ♪
to get my way ♪
♪ but I'd do it all again
♪ i tell myself each day
to get my way ♪
that it was worth it ♪
♪ i tell myself each day
♪ lately, I've heard
that it was worth it ♪
some real disturbing news ♪
♪ lately, I've heard
you finding everything all
some real disturbing news ♪
right?
You finding everything all
Yeah.
Right?
♪ ...Talk of this mean, old
yeah.
town ♪
♪ ...talk of this mean, old
let me know if you need any
town ♪
help.
Let me know if you need any
♪ you've been getting
help.
aro-o-und ♪
♪ you've been getting
♪ don't play me, sweet baby ♪
Aro-o-und ♪
♪ oh, baby ♪
♪ don't play me, sweet baby ♪
[Birds chirping]
Do any good?
Pack of three.
Make them last.
[Sighs]
[Urinating]
[Pounding on door]
Don't forget the laundry.
I know!
Must be nice...
To know who you'll be with,
finally.
Oh, right.
Finally.
All that he talks about is
oh, right.
you now.
All that he talks about is
Is that so?
You now.
How many kids you think
is that so?
you'll have?
How many kids you think
Mama says we need five or six to
you'll have?
keep things going real good.
Mama says we need five or six to
We'll have as many as the pit
keep things going real good.
wants, I reckon.
[Sighs]
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Gasps]
It's right.
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Ada?
Eilen.
Run.
[Water gurgling]
Eilen!
Oh, God!
[Panting]
Eilen?! Where's eilen?!
Where is she?!
Eilen?!
[Crying]
Oh! No!
[Retching]
[No sound]
[Horn blows]
Dawai said nothing?
Not to me.
Hey...
You're down there all the time.
You seen him making one?
No.
Just his normal stuff.
I ain't make no jug face.
I swear.
The pit ain't spoken to you
at all?
No.
[Birds chirping]
Have all the families meet at
the house at dark.
[Crying]
I'm sure you all now know
that eilen jenkin was -- was
taken today.
That eilen jenkin was -- was
Where's the jug face?
Taken today.
Dawai, do you swear that the
where's the jug face?
pit did not guide your hand to
dawai, do you swear that the
make a new jug face?
Pit did not guide your hand to
[Clears throat]
Make a new jug face?
Well, when it does, I don't know
[clears throat]
that it did or not.
Well, when it does, I don't know
I just wake up feeling funny.
That it did or not.
And I did feel funny yesterday.
I just wake up feeling funny.
But I didn't fire nothing.
And I did feel funny yesterday.
All right, now -- now dawai
but I didn't fire nothing.
is gonna search his place again,
all right, now -- now dawai
and if he does not find a
is gonna search his place again,
jug face, well, then, we wait.
And if he does not find a
We wait until the pit guides its
jug face, well, then, we wait.
hand to make another.
We wait until the pit guides its
My daughter's gonna roam
hand to make another.
these woods, shunned forever.
My daughter's gonna roam
Who knows how many others will
these woods, shunned forever.
be taken 'cause of this idiot?
Who knows how many others will
Where are you?!
[Panting]
[Gulping loudly]
Hooo!
Tell me where it is!
Please! I'm begging you!
Just tell me where it is!
I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna do it!
I swear I'll do it if you don't
tell me.
[Knock on door]
What?
It's me.
[Insects chirping]
All right!
Come to check on you.
I want to be alone.
Thought you hated 'shine.
[Sighs]
I do.
You found it yet?
It's got to be around here
you found it yet?
somewhere, right?
It's got to be around here
Don't!
Somewhere, right?
[Radio plays in background]
Don't!
I might have left my knife in
[radio plays in background]
there.
Let me do something with this.
What is that?
What?
It's a...
Never noticed it before.
I didn't -- I didn't really
never noticed it before.
want you to see that.
I didn't -- I didn't really
Thought we swore we'd never
want you to see that.
have secrets.
Thought we swore we'd never
Yeah, right, we didn't, but
have secrets.
I -- please, don't!
Yeah, right, we didn't, but
Please!
When did you make this?
[Sighs]
Couple weeks back.
I ain't told nobody 'cause ain't
couple weeks back.
nobody got a baby right now.
I ain't told nobody 'cause ain't
You think it means something?
Nobody got a baby right now.
I don't really know.
You think that's what the pit
wants?
There ain't no baby, so how
could it?
Right.
Could it?
That's...That's what I come to.
Makes my head hurt.
[Sighs]
[Chirping continues]
If I were you, I'd think on
it real hard, and maybe you'll
see the face again that it
showed you.
What if a face I see ain't
the right one?
Never been wrong before, have
you?
[Door opens]
Come in here.
[People talking on television]
Where you been?
I was out, walking.
Where's pa?
He's over at the Jenkins'.
I don't think you'd be too
scared out there in them woods
yourself.
Scared out there in them woods
Must have been an awful sight.
Yourself.
It was.
Must have been an awful sight.
I'm gonna go to bed.
It was.
I ain't done with you.
I'm gonna go to bed.
What?
I ain't done with you.
Go in the bathroom.
What?
No!
Go in the bathroom.
Go.
No!
[Sighs]
Go.
Go!
[Sighs]
I want to see.
Go!
See what?
I want to see.
I want to see if you've been
see what?
fooling around, before you shame
I want to see if you've been
all of us.
Fooling around, before you shame
Now drop your drawers.
All of us.
I'm fine.
Now drop your drawers.
I swear!
I'm fine.
Get them off and sit your
I swear!
butt down.
Go on. Open up.
Open up.
Mm-hmm.
Do you want me to burn you?
[Whimpers]
All righty.
[Screams]
Stop!
[Cries]
Now you do as I say.
I ain't kidding around here!
[Whimpers]
Further!
You little slut.
No, I'm not. I'm not.
I swear!
Who is it?
It ain't nobody!
I swear!
I swear it ain't nobody!
Get on the floor!
Aah!
Mama, please!
Give me your hand.
Please, no, no, mama!
No-o-o-o!
Aah!
Now tell me who it is!
I was just playing with
now tell me who it is!
myself.
I was just playing with
I swear! I swear!
Myself.
I swear!
I swear! I swear!
No!
I swear!
I swear on the pit!
No!
I promise! I promise!
I swear on the pit!
It ain't dawai?
I promise! I promise!
No!
It ain't dawai?
[Panting]
No!
[Cries]
[Panting]
Well, I hope you're right.
[Cries]
I surely do.
Well, I hope you're right.
Clean yourself up.
I surely do.
[Door closes]
Clean yourself up.
[Crying]
[Knock on door]
Hey, darlin'?
[Crying] What?
Come on. Roll over.
[Sniffles]
She tell you?
She did.
I believe you.
Oh, let me see your hand.
She shouldn't have done that.
You know, this is all gonna be
she shouldn't have done that.
over, and you're gonna be on
you know, this is all gonna be
your way to a happy life with
over, and you're gonna be on
bodey.
Your way to a happy life with
What's wrong with her?
Bodey.
Nothing. She's fine.
Don't worry. You're safe.
Don't even try to hold this
over me.
There is one thing, though.
Over me.
Go to sleep.
There is one thing, though.
I'm pregnant.
Go to sleep.
And I know it's true, 'cause I
I'm pregnant.
got one of them tests from town.
[Wheel rumbles]
Let it be known.
No!
He's all we got!
Sustin, please.
The pit has spoken.
It is an honor to be chosen to
the pit has spoken.
be with it in this world -- you
it is an honor to be chosen to
know that -- for without the
be with it in this world -- you
blood, the waters of the pit
know that -- for without the
would heal no one.
Blood, the waters of the pit
And so, we do what we must.
Would heal no one.
Bodey...
And so, we do what we must.
Go on, son.
Bodey jenkin...
Today, you will pass from this
world into its.
Do you give yourself to it?
World into its.
Yes.
[Crying] Mama...
[Crying] It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
[Crying]
[Gagging]
Go now with your hearts
beating strong and know that our
pact continues.
[Panting]
Grandpa!
Oh!
Oh.
How long you been like this?
[Mumbles]
Are you finished?
One...Two...Three.
Up.
Put your hand up.
Watch your head.
[Groans]
[Birds chirping]
[Sighs]
[Chirping intensifies]
[Panting]
No! What do you want?!
Do you know what I am?
You're one of the shunned.
Then, you know you must stop.
I don't know what you're
then, you know you must stop.
talking about.
I don't know what you're
No! Please don't hurt him!
Talking about.
Plea...
No! Please don't hurt him!
It is he who hurt me.
Plea...
He hid a jug face, same as you.
It is he who hurt me.
I forgave, but...
He hid a jug face, same as you.
They did not.
I forgave, but...
They won't forgive you, either.
They did not.
They did this to coops?
They won't forgive you, either.
Poison.
They did this to coops?
Whose jug face was it?
Poison.
His wife's.
Whose jug face was it?
What if I don't want to die,
his wife's.
though?
What if I don't want to die,
I have a baby inside me.
Though?
You must.
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Birds chirping]
[Record scratches]
[Door opens]
Who's there?
[Country music plays]
♪ everybody wants to make... ♪
you sure are drinking a lot
for someone who don't have a
taste for it.
For someone who don't have a
[Sniffs]
Taste for it.
I don't know what I had against
[sniffs]
it.
I don't know what I had against
It's treating me -- treating me
it.
just fine.
It's treating me -- treating me
You want a sip?
Just fine.
I need to talk to you.
You want a sip?
But you ain't up for it, I'm
I need to talk to you.
thinking.
But you ain't up for it, I'm
Everything's all right.
Thinking.
It turned out just fine, didn't
everything's all right.
it?
It turned out just fine, didn't
Yeah.
It?
[Music continues]
Yeah.
[Door opens, closes]
[Birds chirping]
Ada? Ada?!
What's wrong?
Is pa inside?
I don't know.
Can I see?
[Door opens, closes]
Pa, I need to talk with you.
It'll have to wait.
I got to see the corber.
I'm sick.
What?
How long?
A week, maybe.
[Panting]
You think the pit will heal me?
If we ask it, it will.
What if it's too soon?
That ain't how it works.
It could still be mad.
It ain't.
We give it a life when it wants
it ain't.
it, and it heals us when we need
we give it a life when it wants
it.
It, and it heals us when we need
It's been like that since we
it.
first survived the pox.
It's been like that since we
Now come on.
First survived the pox.
We'll be back.
[Birds chirping]
Strip down...
All the way.
It's gonna work, right?
Don't be scared.
We got to trust in it.
Sit down low.
Get it all over you.
We...
We come to ask for help.
My boy jessaby is sick, and we
we come to ask for help.
ask that you heal him so he can
my boy jessaby is sick, and we
serve you better.
Ask that you heal him so he can
Dawai!
Serve you better.
Ow!
Dawai!
Help.
Ow!
Aah!
Help.
And we thank you for all the
aah!
years you kept us well, and we
and we thank you for all the
pray to be chosen.
Years you kept us well, and we
[Suspenseful music plays]
Pray to be chosen.
Stand.
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Water gurgling]
Stand.
I think I feel it.
Pa!
Come on up here.
Come on.
Aah!
No.
Ah!
Ada?
[Birds chirping]
You out here?
I thought I heard you.
Ada?
Ada?!
[Horn blows]
Ada.
[Crying]
Hey.
Huh?
You all right?
Jessaby's been taken.
It's all my fault.
Loriss?!
What?
[Crying]
What's happening?
I heard the...Horn.
Whose blood is that?
Ada didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Jessaby was sick.
So, we went to the pit.
No.
It ain't never done this
no.
before!
It ain't never done this
The sacrifice didn't take?
Before!
Something ain't right.
The sacrifice didn't take?
The pit wants me...
Something ain't right.
And my baby.
The pit wants me...
Baby?
And my baby.
You know that jug face you
baby?
got in there?
You know that jug face you
I'm pregnant.
Got in there?
[Vehicle approaches]
There she is.
Dawai?!
What did you do?!
Pa! No!
Pa, no!
Stop hitting him!
Pa, stop it!
Pa, get off him!
Stop hitting him!
Please, please, stop hitting
pa, get off him!
him!
Please, please, stop hitting
[Groaning]
Him!
He's gonna pay for the deaths
[groaning]
he caused!
He's gonna pay for the deaths
[Panting]
He caused!
What the fuck did you do?
[Panting]
I --
what the fuck did you do?
tell us!
I --
I lost it -- the jug face.
Tell us!
I looked everywhere. I did.
I lost it -- the jug face.
And then, when I couldn't find
I looked everywhere. I did.
it, uh...
And then, when I couldn't find
I made another from...
It, uh...
[Panting]
I made another from...
...The person I had in my head.
[Panting]
Motherfucker.
...the person I had in my head.
Both my girl and boy are dead
motherfucker.
'cause of you!
Both my girl and boy are dead
Oh!
'Cause of you!
I'm sorry.
Oh!
Get your ass up!
I'm sorry.
Get up!
[Insects chirping]
[Groans]
Now, because of what dawai
has done, it's only fitting he
now, because of what dawai
be next.
Has done, it's only fitting he
Once it takes him, he'll choose
be next.
the next Potter.
Once it takes him, he'll choose
You got anything to say?
The next Potter.
I'm real sorry. I am.
You got anything to say?
Hope you all know that.
I'm real sorry. I am.
Well, you'll have plenty of
hope you all know that.
time to think on it, as you walk
well, you'll have plenty of
these woods forever, shunned
time to think on it, as you walk
like those whose deaths you
these woods forever, shunned
caused!
Like those whose deaths you
I know...
Caused!
And accept it.
Grandpa...
I got to go.
Now, someone might not come to
check on you for a couple days,
now, someone might not come to
till they figure out what's
check on you for a couple days,
going on.
[Voice breaking] I love you.
Dawai?
Dawai --
no!
Shh! Shh-shh-shh!
No!
We're leaving now.
Shh! Shh-shh-shh!
We got to hurry.
We're leaving now.
What? No.
We got to hurry.
You want to die?
What? No.
It doesn't matter.
You want to die?
It's all right.
It doesn't matter.
This will make it stop.
It's all right.
And then you and your baby will
this will make it stop.
be safe, then.
And then you and your baby will
I ain't gonna have your blood
be safe, then.
on my hands, too.
I ain't gonna have your blood
You got any 'shine left?
On my hands, too.
Uh...Yeah, I got a couple
you got any 'shine left?
jugs.
Uh...Yeah, I got a couple
Get something to put those
jugs.
in.
Get something to put those
Why we need these?
In.
For money, unless you got
why we need these?
some stashed around here nobody
for money, unless you got
knows about.
Some stashed around here nobody
No.
[Birds chirping]
You think they've noticed?
Probably.
[Breathing heavily]
What's wrong?
I just...Get this bad feeling
what's wrong?
in the morning.
I just...Get this bad feeling
Oh, right.
In the morning.
Hand me that jug face.
Oh, right.
Well...
Hand me that jug face.
Dawai, give it here.
Well...
Nothing's gonna take my baby.
[Jug clatters]
[Vehicle approaching]
Oh, make him stop.
Make him stop, dawai!
Hello.
We need a ride into town?
[Country music plays on radio]
[Bell jingles]
Can I help y'all?
We need to speak to your pa.
Yeah, sure -- one second.
[Door opens]
Can I help you?
We got something for you.
♪ ...With a smile ♪
We got you some more 'shine.
Y'all ain't supposed to be
here till next month.
Yeah, but this is special.
Here till next month.
Look. Show him.
Yeah, but this is special.
[Sniffs]
Look. Show him.
Smells the same.
[Sniffs]
It's real strong!
Smells the same.
Head peeler!
It's real strong!
I don't think so.
Head peeler!
Look.
I don't think so.
I think we're gonna need to
look.
stick to our original agreement,
I think we're gonna need to
all right?
Stick to our original agreement,
I'm gonna have to pass on this,
all right?
okay?
I'm gonna have to pass on this,
No, wait!
Okay?
Look. I'm real sick.
No, wait!
We need the money so I can see a
look. I'm real sick.
doctor.
We need the money so I can see a
My pa, he don't believe in them.
Doctor.
I'm scared.
My pa, he don't believe in them.
Please!
I'm scared.
All right.
Please!
Oh, thank you, thank you!
All right.
Y'all wait right here, and
oh, thank you, thank you!
I'll get you some money, okay?
Y'all wait right here, and
Y'all thirsty?
I'll get you some money, okay?
You want something to drink?
Y'all thirsty?
Yeah, that'd be good, thank
you want something to drink?
you.
[Door opens, closes]
Here you go.
Thank you.
He sure is out.
He's been through a lot.
If there's anything else you
he's been through a lot.
need, let me know.
I don't mean to pry, but my dad
said you need a doctor.
I know where there's an ob/gyn.
Said you need a doctor.
Hmm?
I know where there's an ob/gyn.
A baby doctor.
Hmm?
I saw you with the pregnancy
a baby doctor.
tests the other day.
I saw you with the pregnancy
No, no, no, I'm not.
Tests the other day.
Oh.
No, no, no, I'm not.
I'm sorry. I just assumed.
Oh.
Aah!
I'm sorry. I just assumed.
You okay?
[High-pitched screeching]
[Gasps]
Aah!
Help me!
What?
I don't know.
I think she's having a seizure.
She needs a doctor.
No doctors.
No, no, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
[Moans]
Please don't tell your pa.
You need help.
The people where we're
you need help.
from -- they want to hurt us.
The people where we're
She's telling you the truth.
From -- they want to hurt us.
I'll make sure you get your
she's telling you the truth.
money, then.
I'll make sure you get your
[Panting]
What'd it show you?
It took pyer.
Then, you do see through its
it took pyer.
eyes.
It's punishing me.
Who was that?
How they doing back there?
We have to help them.
You can't get in the middle
we have to help them.
of these people.
You can't get in the middle
There's some weird shit going on
of these people.
in the woods out there, and we
there's some weird shit going on
don't want any part of it.
In the woods out there, and we
You understand?
Just rest yourself.
It ain't no good for you to be
wound up like you are.
This is taking too long.
Wound up like you are.
Well, they said they'd bring
this is taking too long.
the money.
Well, they said they'd bring
Let's go.
The money.
We'll try somewhere else.
Let's go.
Get up! Come on!
Okay.
That's what I figured.
I needed to be calling you.
Those two came in here.
They tried to sell some of your
those two came in here.
moonshine.
They tried to sell some of your
Oh, shit!
Moonshine.
What?
Oh, shit!
Pa's here!
What?
Ada?
Pa's here!
Ada?!
Ada?
Keep your voice down!
Ada?!
Ada!
[Truck door closes]
How dare you?!
Aah!
You think you can just turn
aah!
your back on us?!
You think you can just turn
They don't care about you out
your back on us?!
there!
They don't care about you out
We're all you got!
There!
And I know what you've been
we're all you got!
doing now.
And I know what you've been
It's plain as day!
Doing now.
There ain't nothing going on
it's plain as day!
between us!
There ain't nothing going on
I told you!
Between us!
Oh, he's good enough for you
I told you!
to run off with?
Oh, he's good enough for you
Then, he's good enough to get in
to run off with?
your pussy!
This is for bodey.
Aah!
And this is for eilen.
[Groans]
And this is for my wife.
[Yells]
I'll do her.
Aah!
[Screaming]
Got to start listening, ada.
Back before, they'd have killed
you for less than this.
Your pa, he's gonna work this
out, though -- what needs to be
your pa, he's gonna work this
done for the best of all of us.
Out, though -- what needs to be
[Sobbing]
Done for the best of all of us.
What's that mean?
[Sobbing]
I'll let him explain.
What's that mean?
[Screams, sobs]
I'll let him explain.
What is wrong with you?
I'm pregnant.
It ain't much of nothing.
She was only two months in.
Well, I shouldn't have beaten
she was only two months in.
her like I did.
Well, I shouldn't have beaten
You did what was right.
Her like I did.
And we don't need another dawai
you did what was right.
walking around, no way.
And we don't need another dawai
You sure it's him?
Walking around, no way.
Well, whose else would it be?
How you doing?
[Sighs]
Why didn't you tell us?
I wouldn't have put you up there
why didn't you tell us?
and whupped you like that.
I wouldn't have put you up there
I couldn't.
And whupped you like that.
She's ashamed, like she
I couldn't.
should be.
She's ashamed, like she
I can't believe anyone would lie
should be.
with a fool like that.
I can't believe anyone would lie
It's not dawai's.
With a fool like that.
Then, whose is it?
It's not dawai's.
It's jessaby's.
Then, whose is it?
What'd you say?
It's jessaby's.
Why else do you think we took
what'd you say?
all them walks together?
Why else do you think we took
Hey! Stop!
All them walks together?
Loriss!
Hey! Stop!
Is what you say true?
Loriss!
Don't you lie to your pa!
Is what you say true?
I loved him.
Don't you lie to your pa!
Ugh!
I loved him.
Get her out of here!
Ugh!
Shit!
You tell corber we'll pay him
shit!
whatever he wants.
You tell corber we'll pay him
Oh!
Whatever he wants.
[Crying]
Oh!
Oh, that's right.
[Crying]
We'd already arranged for you to
oh, that's right.
be joined with him.
We'd already arranged for you to
But he probably won't even want
be joined with him.
your sorry ass now!
But he probably won't even want
[Sobbing]
Your sorry ass now!
Ah!
[Sobbing]
[Growls]
Ah!
You don't make a squeak!
[Growls]
[Door slams]
You don't make a squeak!
[Panting]
[Groans]
Maybe we shouldn't even tell
corber.
He'll just say she's ruined,
anyway.
I can't believe she'd do this.
Anyway.
I can't --
I can't believe she'd do this.
woman, will you shut your
I can't --
mouth and let me think?!
Woman, will you shut your
[Both sigh]
Where you going?!
To the pit.
[Birds chirping]
Grandpa?
Where is he?
I need to speak to the shunned
where is he?
boy right now.
I need to speak to the shunned
You were right!
Boy right now.
Is that what you want to hear?
You were right!
[Chirping intensifies]
Is that what you want to hear?
How do I stop it?
[Chirping intensifies]
You know.
How do I stop it?
Isn't there some other way?
You know.
It's not of this world.
Isn't there some other way?
Come on and do it.
It's not of this world.
I'm sitting right here.
Come on and do it.
What you waiting for, you old
I'm sitting right here.
pit?
What you waiting for, you old
I'm sitting right here.
Pit?
I ain't scared of you.
I'm sitting right here.
I used to be scared of you.
I ain't scared of you.
Everybody's so scared of you.
I used to be scared of you.
I ain't scared of you no more.
Everybody's so scared of you.
So, come on.
I ain't scared of you no more.
Dawai, did you do it?!
So, come on.
What?
Dawai, did you do it?!
You been fucking my daughter?
What?
No!
You been fucking my daughter?
No, I ain't never...Touched her.
No!
I ain't never done it with
no, I ain't never...Touched her.
nobody.
I ain't never done it with
I swear.
Nobody.
Did you know she was
I swear.
pregnant?
Did you know she was
Was?
Pregnant?
You mean, she ain't no more?
Was?
You are no longer with child.
You mean, she ain't no more?
Why do you resist?
You are no longer with child.
I don't know.
Why do you resist?
[Pit chirping]
I don't know.
What?
[Pit chirping]
It's awake.
What?
Well, who do you think it
it's awake.
was?
Well, who do you think it
[Screams]
Was?
[Jug face clatters]
[Screams]
Aah!
[Jug face clatters]
[Pit screeches]
[Horn blows]
[Birds chirping]
Why are you still alive?
Where's sustin?
It took him.
I don't know why, but it did.
No!
This whole thing is 'cause of
you!
I-I'd trade places with him
if I could.
You are so dead.
If I could.
Stop it! It's not his fault!
You are so dead.
It's because of me.
Stop it! It's not his fault!
It was my jug face.
It's because of me.
I hid it.
It was my jug face.
What?
I hid it.
I found the jug face that
what?
dawai made a few days ago...
I found the jug face that
And it was mine.
Dawai made a few days ago...
I got scared, so I buried it in
and it was mine.
the woods.
I got scared, so I buried it in
The one he couldn't find?
The woods.
I'll take you to it.
Give it to him.
Aah!
You selfish, little bitch.
Look what all you done.
You almost ruined us, 'cause of
look what all you done.
what?
You almost ruined us, 'cause of
'Cause of your dirty, little
what?
secret?
'Cause of your dirty, little
Tomorrow, you're gonna make this
secret?
right in front of everyone!
Tie her with dawai.
What about our agreement?
The pit wants what it wants.
[Pit rumbling]
[Birds chirping]
[Grunts]
I'm sorry.
I'd have tried to save my
baby, too.
It ain't quite fair, is it?
[Sighs]
I reckon they'll do me in after.
Probably.
I don't care.
Tired of them, anyway.
Sleep tight.
[Birds chirping]
[Insects chirping]
[Chirping intensifies]
What are you doing?
Coops wants you to go.
Wait.
Leave while you can.
What about dawai?
He must stay.
They'll kill him.
Go.
Ada, please, just go!
If I give myself, will dawai
ada, please, just go!
be spared?
If I give myself, will dawai
Yes.
Be spared?
I'm staying, then.
Yes.
No, you ain't!
I'm staying, then.
You ain't staying.
No, you ain't!
Go.
You ain't staying.
Ada, go.
Go.
Hey, where you all going?
Ada, go.
Come back here.
Hey, where you all going?
Take her.
Come back here.
Hey!
Take her.
Come back here!
Ada, I want you to go.
I want you to go somewhere, and
you live a life.
You can do anything.
You live a life.
You can go to town.
You can do anything.
I am doing this for you.
You can go to town.
I don't want you to do this
I am doing this for you.
for me.
I don't want you to do this
It's what I should have done
for me.
in the first place.
It's what I should have done
[Insects chirping]
[Mumbles]
I can't bear it.
I love you.
[Sighs]
[Birds chirping]
Who let her go?
She ain't going anywhere.
Are you ready to give yourself
she ain't going anywhere.
to the pit, once and for all?
Yes.
The pit gives, and the pit
takes away.
It is an honor to go be with it,
away from this earthly plane.
I hope you are satisfied with
our sacrifice.
We understand that the pit wants
what it wants.
If you have got anything to say,
let it be known.
[Crying] I just want to say
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry for those who died
'cause of what I done.
And I'm sorry to those left
behind.
[Gurgles]
[Birds chirping]
[Up-tempo country music plays]
♪ Hey, baby,
what's going on?
♪ got a sneaking suspicion
that something is wrong ♪
♪ got a whole lot of time
to kill ♪
♪ and I know
you've got some secrets
you've been wanting to spill ♪
You've got some secrets
♪ well, I lie awake,
you've been wanting to spill ♪
and I'm thinking through,
♪ well, I lie awake,
and I knew long ago
and I'm thinking through,
that I'd stick with you ♪
And I knew long ago
♪ I know
that I'd stick with you ♪
I'm not your only fool,
♪ I know
'cause I vowed long ago
I'm not your only fool,
that I'm sticking with you ♪
♪ heard some discussions
that are bringing me down ♪
♪ and I know from the gossip
it's all over town ♪
♪ not in my nature
to walk out and quit ♪
♪ might look okay,
but I'm feeling like shit ♪
♪ well, I lie awake,
and I'm thinking through,
and I vowed long ago
that I'd stick with you ♪
And I vowed long ago
♪ I know
that I'd stick with you ♪
I'm not your only fool ♪
♪ I know
♪ decided long ago
I'm not your only fool ♪
that I'm sticking with you ♪
♪ well, I laid awake
and thinking through ♪
♪ every night I'm up
and feeling blue ♪
♪ well, I know
I'm not your only fool ♪
♪ but I vowed long ago
that I'm sticking with you ♪
♪ 'cause I vowed long ago
♪ I knew long ago
that I'm sticking with you ♪
♪ and I vowed long ago
that I'd stick with you ♪
♪ long ago
I learned I'm sick of you ♪