Ta-da!
An acceptance letter? You passed?!
I, Irie Kotoko, safely
passed the Medical School Nursing Department test!
My reward for working so hard was...
Of course, my long-desired date with Irie-kun.
People say that couples  who ride the boats in this park will break up.
What?
What are you going to do?
You've already gotten into the boat.
Why didn't you say anything before we got on?
If you knew you shouldn't have...
Because you wanted to go on this kind of date?
With me.  On a boat.
What do you mean?
For me, I would never go on   a date like the one you planned.
But since you stayed up all night planning this date,
I wanted to do at least part of it.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to believe in this  ridiculous curse and get off the boat?
Irie-kun.
Or...
Subtitles brought to you by the Mischievous Kisser Team @ viki.com
Tonan University Medical School
So cool!
Hello.
Finally, my first step towards becoming a nurse  will start here.
Moreover,
Irie-kun's medical department  and my nursing department -- right next to each other...
Oh, found it.
Nursing Department  Lecture Hall 2
202. Nursing Department.
Okay.
Good morning!
Who is that?
That's right. I don't know anyone here.
Then to top it off, everyone is  three years younger than me…
Excuse me.
Alright, alright.
By any chance...are you new?
Oh, she's cute.
Ah, yes.
I just transferred from the literature deparment.
Really?
Transferring part way through college,  you must really want to be a nurse.
True.
I'm Ogura Tomoko, nice to meet you.
I'm Irie Kotoko, nice to meet you too.
Good morning.
Today's the start of a new semester.
To practice as nurses, we will begin exercises.
I will give you groups of five within the class.
Cooperate closely with your team members.
Well then, I will read the names.
-First, Naoko Saiki.   -Yes.
Ah, its finally starting!
Wait for me Irie-kun!
To suit Irie-kun, I will become a legitimate nurse.
Scalpel.   - Here.
-Sweat.   -Okay.
In Surgery
Good work.
As to expected from Dr. Irie. The operation was a great success.
Yeah, we got closer thanks to you being a nurse.
I didn't do much...
From now on and forever, stay by my side and support me, please.
Okay.
Irie Kotoko.
Irie-san?
Kotoko-san?
Yes! I will always go and support you!
What are you doing dazing off already in the first semester?!
Please be more careful.
Please excuse me.
We're together in team 2, ok?
Really?
That's a relief!
Mischievous Kiss 2   Love in TOKYO
Kotoko, I will introduce you to the other members of our team.
Yes.
Everyone.
This girl is the new member.
Wow, what a pretty guy.
What imposing members...
This is Irie Kotoko-san.
Nice to meet you, I'm Irie Kotoko.
I found my big dream, so I came to enter nursing.
Please take care of me.
I am Shinagawa Marina.
Big dream?
Well...
Is there a boy you like in the medical department or something?
Bull's-eye? Same with me!!
I also came here in order to marry a doctor in the future!
Marina!
Throw away those frivolous thoughts of yours.
Don't get into this profession with such feelings!
I like men that are smart and have money!
In the future, I will give birth to a child  with an excellent DNA.
As if such a guy could exist!
You're so bothersome!
Not everybody's an enthusiastic nurse like you Keita!
You just want to try if for fun!
You're the over-enthusiastic one!
Okay okay, you both calm down. Okay?
These two are always like this,  don't worry about it okay?
This hot-blooded boy is Kamogari Keita.
I am aiming to become Japan's number one nurse.
To help restore the lives of patients!
Even if you are young, that is really splendid.
Hey. Irie? Theres no relation to that Irie right?
What are you so startled about?
Are....are you a man?
How mean.
I'm a woman inside.
I am Kikyo Motoki. Please take care of me.
Moto-chan is fine.
Moto-chan.
You aren't related to the medical department's Irie, right?
The medical department's Irie?
What?! That amazing person in  the medical department, Irie Naoki?!
Irie Naoki? I've heard of him...
Right?!
He's extremely good looking and he's a genius!
I must meet that perfect gentleman soon...
How cool must he be?
How smart must he be?
Moto-chan also created a fan club for Irie!
I am also a member!
There's no other man that can live up to my expectations!
Wait a minute.
There were rules!
You can't look at him like that!
What? It's the same.
I'm not as irrational as you.
My feelings for Irie-san are more pure.
A love that can't happen.
What did you say?!
"Love" is equal for everyone.
But...
Irie-kun is already married, right?
How do you know?
It's a rumor! I heard a rumor!
That's right!
Listen...
If I could only be married to Irie-kun.
According to the rumours it seems like  his wife is in the same year as him.
It is unforgivable!
What kind of woman would Irie-kun be willing to spend his life with?
She must be a beautiful, smart woman, of course!
She's the one I resent the most.
Nursing Seminar Room
Well then, I will measure your blood pressure.
Hey, today after school, why don't we go to Irie-san's house?
Let's go, let's go! Tomoko, you'll go too, right?
Moto-chan, to pinpoint where his house is you're really persistent huh?
Isn't that expected?
As president of the fan club, I must spy on his wife!
What? Come to my house?
I know, right?
What should I do!? I'm Irie-kun's wife!
But, if they found out....I can't stay here anymore.
I will have a hard time those three years not to get found out by those three in hiding Irie.
How pitiful, I am.
Hey!! How long are you going to be putting air in?!
What?
Look! The color has change, hasn't it?!
But hey, don't get too angry or your blood pressure will rise!
Who was the one who angered me?!
The next one will be fine, okay?
I didn't want to be in the same group as you…
Why not?
It hurts, it hurts! Stop, stop!
You're stopping the blood flow to my hand!
That's because, I can't hear Keita's pulse!
What?
You...
have the stethoscope placed wrong.
Do you have some kind of special reason?
I'm sorry! One more time.
Stop fooling around! What would you do if I were an actual patient?!
Don't get so angry! I only failed once...
Nope, this was your third failure.
No, isn't it the fourth?
To be exact, the sixth time.
If you're aiming to become a nurse  for frivolous reasons that's wrong!
They aren't irresponsible feelings!
I want to be Irie-kun's support!
What? Why would you want to be Irie-san's support?
That's because...
Because...
I'm Irie-kun's wife!
What are you talking about?
Kotoko, that's awesome!
Don't laugh!
I understand. You're just saying that, right?
Then, I'm also Irie-san's wife!
Moto, even if...
Excuse me.
Irie-san!
Kotoko!
What?
You left this behind! Mother told me to deliver it to you.
Then, bye.
Irie-san!!
Ko-to-ko!
See! I told you, it was true.
What did you hear about Irie-san?
I'm sorry! I wasn't planing to lie!
I couldn't tell you guys.
Now I will no longer survive in this nursing department...
Hey, it's okay. You don't need to apologize.
I'm not angry at all.
Because if you are Irie-san's wife,
we don't have a reason to give up anymore, right?
I thought Irie-san was someone I would not be able to reach, but
it seems like we have some hope.
Right!
Seems complicated...
Irie-kun!
Move over!
So from now on I will become a good wife to Irie-kun.
Watch closely.
I did it!
Kotoko, I'm begging you.
Leave it to me.
I established strong friendships with our team,
and, even through the tough times, I had a fulfilling college life
but the greatest challenge still awaits us.
Medication Intramuscular Injection
Injections should be given about three fingers down  from the shoulder.
Right here at the center of Deltoid muscle.
Oh, snap! I'm not good at giving injection.
When you inject it in the right position, you will see the green light.
During the injection, the blood...
Everything is clear up till this point, right? We shall now begin practising injections.
Please practise hard since the test will be next week.
There'll be a break after everyone in the group has made a successful injection.
Yes.
Alright, we'll be the first.
So let's do it!
This feels totally the same...
Well, let's hurry and finish this up then go for lunch.
Well then, Keita, lend me your arm.
What?
Oh, Keita you've a nice arm.
Will you be okay?
It's okay, it's okay.
Then who will do it?
I'll do it!
It's okay, though.
You're not scared?
Not at all.
Syringe.
Yes.
Subtitles brought to you by The Mischievous Kisser Team @ Viki.com
How does it feel?
It's Tomoko's dream.
Marina-chan, you're skilled.
All done.
Then, last is Kotoko.
Yes.
Do it proper!
Right! Irie Kotoko will go!
That is my shoulder!
Here.  -It's here.
Are you okay? -I'm fine, I'm okay.
There's an idiot who gives an injection with her eyes closed?
Well...it's scary to look at an injection...
Don't just leave it there!
Hi-yah!
Still not done?
It's only us now, right?
I'm starving!
This time, surely!
Hey!
What can't you get it right?
Pinch with your fingers and go to the raised muscle!
I understand but it goes wrong when I try! Sorry.
How many time do you have to be told to understand?!
Because of you, our team is always last.
If you feel bad, you should help us organize
a get-together with Irie-san, right?
Well, that...
Seriously, I can't believe it.
Irie-kun!
Irie-san!
Kotoko, if you're going to be like that,  please don't come to the same hospital I am in in the future.
Well, I think she'll first have to pass the national exam...
You should do something about it!
It's impossible for her to become a nurse  if she carries on like that.
What do you mean "impossible"?
You're a genius right? You should do something about it.
I didn't become a doctor just for her.
If she doesn't have the ability to become a nurse, that's that. It's not my problem.
She's your wife, right?
If you're bothered, you can do something about it.
Sorry for taking up your time.
He's cool!!
What's up with him!
Are you alright with him saying that?  What did you get married for?
Face? Status?
It's okay. Just calm down. It's okay with me.
Besides, it's the truth.  It's mutual knowledge, so I'm used to it.
Irie-kun doesn't go easy on me.
It's not that!!
Husband and wife should encourage one another,
and do all the things while holding one another!
That's the way you can be together for life!
Encouraging one another, together...
Keita has a really ideal image of marriage, right?
But, that's great.
What?
Because you don't seem to be very loved by Irie-san.
That's wrong...!
Can I really become a great nurse like that?
Furthermore...
Thanks to you, our group is always last
If you feel bad, hurry up and organize a get together with Irie-san.
And they say that...
Irie-kun doesn't even like things like get-togethers...
Tears...onion...
It hurts.
Kotoko-chan, what's wrong?
Are you crying?
Well, the road to being a nurse is really tough.
That's right.
You've tread into unfamiliar territory just for Naoki.
You're so admirable, Kotoko-chan!
Okay then.
I will tell you a story that will make you happy.
In fact, the land that Papa has in Hokkaido.
There is a village that doesn't have any doctors.
Working at a large hospital is nice, but
wouldn't it also be nice  to work at a small clinic, just you and Irie?
Only the two of us?
That's right.
You would be thanked by all the villagers
and at night you would be enveloped by a sky full of stars.
Give me a break.
Naoki, you're back already?
Yes.
To cut off your wild imagination.
That kind of nurse who can't give an injection.  Please don't put just the two of us together.
But Kotoko-chan has been putting effort  both into being a wife and a student!
Oh Irie-kun, today's dinner is your favorite beef stew!
I'm gonna make a lot so you can have it tomorrow too!
I don't need dinner for tomorrow.
Eating out?
Yeah.
We're  having a dinner party.
Wow, it's rare that you're attending!
How many people is it going to be?
Well...6~7 people.
Where?
Shibuya.
So it's Shibuya.
What's the name of the place?
I don't know!
I'm not even interested.
6:59 p.m. we are all here. Let's go in.
- Have you been here? - No.
Welcome!
I've a reservation for 7pm under Funatsu.
Sorry for the wait.
Your companions are this way.
Right through here.
Wow, what a coincidence!
Tounan University's medical students right?
We're second years from the nursing department!
It's alright if we're together right?
We're okay right, everyone?
It sounds like it'll be fun!
What a coincidence right, Irie?
Kotoko!
Oh, Irie-kun what a coincidence.
What coincidence? This was your doing isn't it.
It's just coincidence.
Ah!! That's why you called me last night.
I thought it was weird when you asked  about tomorrow's restaurant.
Well, everyone please sit down.
Please sit!
Here you go, Irie-san!
Thank you.
-Here you go. -Thank you!
Marina-chan, your such a considerate person.
Is that so?
I always do this so…
You're so feminine.
Wow, she's that refined.
She doesn't even do that in front of us.
She changes so much in front of men, right?
Sorry for the wait,
this is the house special beef.
Looks delicious!
You're good in cutting, aren't you Tomoko-chan!?
At times like this you can see who really likes cooking!
I don't particularly enjoy cooking...
- I like cutting meat. - What?!
That's why I applied for nursing.
That way I will be able to cut as much as I like, right?
But, nurses can't use scalpel at someone's body, right?
Yes. That's right.
No way?!
Then, I can't hold a scalpel forever?
I even made a scapel with my name  to commemorate getting in.
What's wrong?
Although she has the image of an angel...
You really can't judge a book by its cover, right?
Irie-san! You're too close!
You're heavy!
What did you say?!
What?! Doesn't he look like he's having fun?
And with a woman on top of that.
He's a energetic person, your husband. Although he's married...
Irie-san is always so popular.
Funatsu-kun, since it's such a good opportunity, you shouldn't pull a long face.
Why don't you talk to the girls?
No, I'm not interested in those.
Don't say such things!
Look, aren't there many cute girls? Right?
Well, Funatsu-san!
Here you are!
Is it alright if I sit here?
It...it's alright.
I'm Shinagawa Marina, nice to meet you!
I always thought that I should try speaking to you once.
What are your hobbies?
Reading medical books.
Then, what do you do on days off?
I read medical books.
Do you not go out at all?
I do go out sometimes.
Where do you go?
I'm go to look around the whole country or go into national museums.
I see.
Then...see you.
Wait wait wait wait wait!
What?
Try talking a bit more? He's just shy!
Stop joking.
Even if he's smart I don't want a boring guy like him!
It looks like she left.
Anyways, Marina doesn't seem  too compatible with Funatsu-kun.
Should I bring somebody else for you?
How about...that girl?
That girl seems compatible with you, what do you think?
What do you think?
Marina-san.
Marina-san is good.
Weren't you cold to her earlier?
I'm always like this in front of girls I like.
My heart races non-stop like this, see?
Really!
Don't tell me Funatsu-kun fell in love with Marina at first sight?!
Wait, Kotoko-san!
What are you going to do, Marina?
But Funatsu-san can't beat Irie-san.
It's natural he can't be the first!
Damn it!
It's always like that.
It's always Irie, Irie, Irie! There are things Irie can't do to!
Remember it well I will win against Irie!
And then take back your words just  now and go out with me!
You got it?!
Do you get it!?
We got it, you're being scary.
Kamogari Keita!
What is it?
You know what...
I've been wanting to say this from before but,
even though I appear like this, I'm older than you!
In fact, by three years.
Three years...you know, three?
So?
So...
-Quit doing that! -That hurts!
You always keep nagging me!
Ah, that's cold.
What are you doing?
It spilled.
You did it!
Haha, I'm sorry.
Wipe it clean...
Okay, it's wiped.
No matter what I say, you still act like a klutz.
If you're older than at least act like you are.
What'd you say?!
Ouch, that hurts!
Hey.
Hey!
Don't fall asleep in a place like this.
Ah, Kotoko fell asleep.
Ko-to-ko.
Not working.
She totally drank herself to sleep.
Should we get Irie-san?
No, its fine. I'll send her back.
I haven't drank, and I've got a car.
Irie-san is here anyway, so shouldn't  we leave it to him?
It's ok, he's enjoying himself anyway.
Kotoko fell asleep?
Irie-san. That's right.
Sorry, I'll take her back.
Kotoko! Hey, let's go home.
Hey!
Hey, Kotoko, let's go home.
It's fine.
I'll send her home.
Who are you?
Kamogari Keita from the nursing department.
Always being troubled by your wife.
And so?
I'll send her back safely,  so go enjoy yourselves with the girls there.
You don't care about your wife anyway, right?
Shut your mouth.
Whether I care about Kotoko or not has nothing to do with you.
Outsiders should mind their own business.
What did you say?!
Chuu!…
Injections, what are they?
Why can you do it so easily?
You awake now?
Ah, it's Irie-kun.
Kotoko, let's go home.
Yes!
I guess I have no choice.
Irie-san.
Oh, Kamogari.
Don't refer to Kotoko as this person.
What happened...that you're like this?
I don't like him... Irie Naoki.
Irie-kun.
What is it?
Sleep talking huh.
Chu...
Not injections again?  (kissing sound "chu" sounds like "chu-sha" for 'injection')
Keita Kamogari.
Nursing Practice Room
It's me again!
I'm cursed.
Why? It's not even a real injection.
It's just putting the model on your arm. You're exaggerating.
Idiot.
No matter how protected it is!!! And the syringe is in  Kotoko's trembling hands!
You don't know that horror!
It's alright, it's alright!
Since then, I've practised countless times  on the arm of the dummy!
Just leave it to me?
The test duration is 15 minutes.
Please start.
Yes!
Well, first...
Pinch with your fingers and raise the muscle.
Yes!
That's my arm alright.
Oh, I'm sorry.
-Calm down! -Yes!
Then…I'm starting.
Okay.
-It hurts! -What are you doing?!
I pricked myself...
Put this around your hand!
Kotoko!
-Hey! -Kotoko!
Hey, are you okay?
Pull yourself together!
She's totally unconcious!
Sensei, I'm going to take her to the sick room.
-Please do so. -Should I help too?
It's alright, I can handle it alone.
Let me pass!
Make way!
Quickly make way. Let me pass, pass!
That was Kotoko, right?
What's wrong with her?
And who's that person?
Doctor, a patient!
There's no one here.
She's so peaceful. Makes me want to faint too.
Seriously, seeing this person's sleeping foolish face...
What are you going to do from there?
You again?
I haven't done anything.
Are you kidding? Who would do that with her?
It didn't seem that way to me.
This person, I heard you carried her here after she collapsed.
Thanks for the trouble, all for this person.
Since I'm here it's enough now.
Please go back.
I was going to even if you didn't tell me to.
Kamogari...
You already know right...
That she's married to me.
Don't get an unneeded interest in her.
I would be...
I know now.
I care for Kotoko much more than you do.
I'd treat her better than you do.
Is that so?
Subtitles brought to you by the  Mischievous Kisser Team @viki.com
I'm going on a vacation with Irie-kun in summer!
I don't remember ever saying I'd go.
Let's all go out and have fun!
Irie Naoki!
Then why don't you just go back with Kamogari.
Why did it end up like this.
This drama is a work of fiction
I mean what I said to you.