Ju-on: A curse born when a person dies
in a powerful rage.
It gathers where the dead person lived,
and becomes a “stain”.
Anyone who touches it dies,
and a new curse is born.
TOEI VIDEO and CELL Present
An OZ Production
Produced by Taka lchise
Co-Producer
Toshinori Nishimae
Akina Minami
Hiroki Suzuki
Mihiro
Aimi Nakamura
Marika Fukunaga
Chie Amemiya
Akiko Hoshino
Takuji Suzuki
Tsuyoshi Muro
lchirota Miyakawa
Original JU-ON Concept Created by
Takashi Shimizu
Written and Directed by
Ryuta Miyake
JU-ON
WHITE GHOST
FUMIYA
CAKE SHOP NICOLA
ISOBE
Hello.
Anyone home?
Delivery from Cake Shop Nicola.
Your Christmas cake.
I'm tied up right now.
I'll be right there.
Right.
Uh, excuse me?
The price for the family size is...
I'm tied up right now.
I'll be right there.
Are you OK?
I'm coming in.
Uh, you OK?
Hold on!
I'm tied up right now.
I'll be right there.
KASHIWAGI
Here we are, Miss.
Miss!
That'll be 12 million yen.
Just joking!
You don't want me to drop you
at the school gate?
Getting a taxi to school is
asking to be bullied!
Why can't a man take his daughter
to school?
Today's cram school,
so have dinner before me.
Take a day off from cram school.
Don't be silly.
It's Christmas Eve.
You can't keep Santa waiting.
Santa doesn't exist.
He does.
Where?
Here!
Bye.
Take care.
What's this?
There's something on my bag.
Must have been that customer
this morning.
Sorry!
Yuck! it's disgusting!
Sorry.
Bye.
Akane!
Merry Christmas.
What the hell is this?
Sheesh!
Message from dispatch center.
Yes! Car number 12.
Kashiwagi-san. Where are you?
Uh, right now I'm...
Hold on!
Don't give me a booking now.
I'm just about to go home.
The police were just here.
The police?
They want to talk to you.
About what?
I don't know.
Something about
a customer this morning.
A customer this morning?
Kashiwagi-san?
OK. Tell them I'll be back
as soon as I can.
Roger. Thanks.
AKANE
SAKURADAI HIGHSCHOOL
Akane.
What's wrong? You OK?
I'm fine.
Kashiwagi-san!
We've got a favor to ask you.
It's not moving.
Don't take your finger off!
Have you really got special powers?
Special powers?
Since you were small,
you saw and heard things, right?
What a let down.
Maybe we're calling the wrong person?
You're the one who suggested a celeb!
But not Jun Matsumoto, not him!
What about Okada then?
He's still alive! Someone dead,
a dead person!
How about Kashiwagi-sari's dad?
Mayumi!
He passed away, right?
He's just missing.
Ls that right.
Sorry.
It was 7 years ago.
Shall we give up?
Yeah.
Ouija board, Ouija board.
Stop!
I'm not doing anything!
Mi.
Ra.
Mirai?
Like mirai, the future?
Maybe a person's name?
What is it, Akane?
Akane!
Kashiwagi-san!
She won't pick up.
Maybe she's mad at us.
Huh? Why?
Because we talked about her dad.
She said it was OK.
What?
I forgot something.
I'll just go and get it.
Hurry up!
ISOBE
Please come in.
Wow! it's great!
Nice, eh?
Well, it's not bad.
Mom, the garden's huge!
Granma, look, this is your new home.
Shall we see the garden?
Uncle, it's awesome. Hurry up!
I'm coming.
Where's the bathroom?
Through here.
Roomy enough?
Yes, it's wonderful.
Hey, don't you think it's too cheap?
I think something happened here.
Something?
Maybe someone died here.
You really have no sense of humor.
I want this room!
OK, it's yours.
This is a good room for you, Atsushi.
Right.
It's quiet.
You'll be able to study here.
This time, you must pass
the legal exams.
Atsushi will have the upstairs room.
Right, dad?
We just looked at it.
It's really quiet.
Granma.
Voila! it's finished!
Careful! You'll squash it!
Uncle.
What's wrong?
CHIHO
AMANUMA POLICE STATION
I'll be right there.
Are you OK?
Fumiya!
Chiho.
Here.
Merry Christmas.
Well, open it!
Cute, huh?
Sorry.
I know how excited you were
about tonight.
We can go out to eat another time.
Christmas at home isn't bad either.
Blow out the candles!
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas.
Let's eat!
Are you OK?
I should rinse.
It's fine.
MIRAI
Akane?
Akane.
Thanks.
Shouldn't you be in bed?
I'm fine. The fever's gone too.
All thanks to this.
Sorry I kept it all this time.
Give it back when you're better.
But it really worked eh?
Like magic! I can see why
it's your good-luck charm.
Granma.
That's Atsushi's basketball.
He'll get mad again.
Hello.
Sorry about that.
Are you OK?
I should be going.
It's OK. Stay a little longer.
It's better if someone else is here.
But your uncle's here.
That's the problem.
You're joking?
Did you tell your mom?
Why not?
I can't. Because we live together.
Was he always like that?
He suddenly changed when we moved here.
And...
When I get out of the bath,
my underwear is gone.
It wasn't me. Granma did it.
You should go now.
But...
Mirai, this house!
Stop it, uncle.
Stop it! Stop!
Mirai!
Akane!
Granma! Granma!
Akane! Akane!
Sit down.
I'll help you with your homework.
I'm OK.
That's not true, is it?
You're sweating.
What the hell?
What's wrong with you?
Let go! What's up with you?
Granma!
YASUKAWA
AMANUMA POLICE STATION
You still here, Kawabata?
Did you hear?
Chikada's had another baby.
He's pretty virile for his age.
I'll be right there.
What are you listening to, Kawabata?
Kawabata?
Yasukawa-san?
The family massacre in Nishiogi?
It was 7 years ago.
What does it have to do with that tape?
The killer committed suicide.
After killing the whole family,
he hanged himself.
He recorded that tape as he died.
One of the detectives...
named Makabe...
Worked overtime transcribing the tape.
Next day, back at the station...
Only the tape was there.
Makabe was gone.
I called him many times,
but he never answered.
I had to go looking for him
at his home.
Makabe was dead.
Hanged himself in the bathroom.
You think it was because of the tape?
What was on the tape?
Yasukawa-san.
A voice.
The same voice I heard?
No, another voice. A child's.
Where are you going?
I'm going to burn it.
Ls that necessary?
I already threw it away once.
I dumped it 7 years ago.
On a mountain many miles away.
There's no way it could be here.
Don't get involved.
Don't ever get involved.
NISHIOGI FAMILY MASSACRE
FAMILY OF MURDERED
CRIME COMMITTED RD EVENING?
ELDEST SON MISSING
NO SIGN OF STRUGGLE INSIDE
DECAPITATED
Come quickly.
ATSUSHI
EXAM RESULT: FAIL
Just confirming our order.
Yes, one family size cake, please.
Thank you.
The cake will arrive tomorrow morning.
I didn't know he was that stupid.
His mock exam results weren't
good apparently.
I wasn't told.
I told you.
You did not!
You're his mother.
You have to watch over him.
I'm sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
You're not his real mother anyway.
What's so funny?
Nothing.
What is it?
No thanks.
How long will it take him
to pass the exam?
How much money
have we spent on him?
It's so humiliating.
What will other people think?
It's always “other people”!
You're no better!
A baby at 16, crawling back home
after all that heartbreak.
I didn't want to have a baby!
I had a million other dreams!
So why didn't you get rid of it then?
How many times did I ask to!
I'll be right there.
Come quickly!
I'm scared.
Come here.
Miho-san. I think grandma needs you.
I'm tied up right now.
I'll be right there.
Are you hungry?
Shall I make something?
Miho-san?
What?
That hurts! Stop it! It hurts!
No! No!
Have you got any plans for Christmas?
My daughter's in 4th grade
at elementary.
I haven't got her a present yet.
What do girls that age like?
I'll be right there.
Come quickly.
I'm scared.
Come here.
I'm sorry.
I'm home!
“l'll be home late.
Go ahead and eat.”
Are you home?
Mom?
Akane.
I'm sorry!
Executive Producer Kazuo Kato
Produced by Taka lchise
Co-Producer Toshinori Nishimae
Original JU-ON Concept Created by
Takashi Shimizu
Cinematography by
Koji Kanaya (J.S.C.)
Art Director Shimpei Inoue
Music by Gary Ashiya
Edited by Yoshifumi Fukazawa
An OZ Production
TOEI VIDEO and CELL Present
Written and Directed by
Ryuta Miyake
C2009 TOEI VIDEO/CELL