What did you wish for
l wish
we could be together forever
What about you?
Me too
lf your mom and Yoo-jin's dad are together
then you'll be brother and sister
lt's a good thing too
Mom, is my dad...
...Yoo-jin's father?
Sorry, J un-sang
Let's get married today
J un-sang and Yoo-jin
...are brother and sister
Good
J un-sang, let's get married
Lord... Forgive me...
Yoo-jin!
Yoo-jin! J ung Yoo-jin!
This is what happened
that's why they...
Sang-hyuk!
J ung-ah,
where's Yoo-jin!
Don't you know where she is?
What about J un-sang?!
Sang-hyuk...
lt's important. lt's really important!
You know where they are, right?
You know, right?
Tell me, huh?!
l, J ung Yoo-jin thake thee,
Kang J un-sang as my lawfully
wedded husband
and promise to love and cherish
until death do us part.
l Kang J un-sang...
Take thee, J ung Yoo-jin as my
lawfully wedded wife
and promise to love and cherish
until death do us part...
Sang-hyuk.
Yoo-jin, let's go.
J un-sang!
Sang-hyuk.
You thought you could get married
by yourselves like this?!
You two can' get married. You can't!
l'm going to stop you.
You two
can't get married!
J un-sang
ang-hyuk, what's wrong with you?
Let go of me!
J un-sang. J un-sang!
Sang-hyuk!
J un-sang!
What are you doing here?
Sang-hyuk
looked for you and Yoo-jin.
So l told him that you were here.
Didn't he come by?
J un-sang:...
Where's Yoo-jin?
Hey, Lee Min-hyung!
ls something wrong?
l though nobody knew...
What?
l really thought
nobody knew...
What's come over you now?
What is it now?
And why are you dressed like this?
Hey...
did Yoo-jin go with Sang-hyuk?
ls that it?
Where are you going?
What's wrong with you?
Why are you suddenly being like this?!
l don't want you to marry J un-sang!
l was going to let you go.
But l couldn't bear
the thought of you marrying J un-sang.
l shouldn't have let you go to
J un-sang in the first place!
Break up with J un-sang.
You know that
l can't do that.
l'm not asking you to come
back to me immediately.
J ust first, break up with him.
lt'll be hard for you at first
but you'll be OK in time.
You can go back to the time
when J un-sang came back into your life.
You can forget about everything
and start over.
l can't do that!
Why can't you?!
Everybody's against it!
un-sang's mother, and your mother, too!
You know that everybody opposes to
you two getting married!
Nobody's willing to give you their blessing!
Sang-hyuk
l don't care...
l don't care
if nobody gives us their blessing...
l won't feel sad
Even if everyone opposes...
lt's OK with me.
lt doesn't make me sad.
lf l just have J un-sang's love...
l don' need anybody else's blessing.
The two of us...
No, Yoo-jin.
You can't marry him!
Yoo-jin, no...
Sang-hyuk!
Why are you being like this!
You were the one who let her go.
You're the one who said that
you wished for her to be happy.
Jin-sook, hold still.
Why are you suddenly being like this?
You were all right up to now!
Why are you suddenly being like this?!
You guys believe in me, right?
You trust me, right?
Don't ask me anything.
Please, don't ask me anything
and just trust me.
Please...
Did you know?
How did you find out?
Did your father tell you?
Yes.
l see...
Everybody knew, huh?
You didn't...
You didn't tell Yoo-jin, did you?
No, l didn't.
l couldn't.
How could l tell her that...
How could l tell that to Yoo-jin?
What will you do now?
What shall l do now?
lf l asked you to overlook it...
lf l told you that
l wanted to run away with Yoo-jin...
What would you do?
Will you let me run away ith her?
J un-sang...
Hey...
You still haven't heard from J un-sang?
No.
l'm sure he went to meet Yoo-jin.
l didn't think
J un-sang meant it
when he asked Yoo-jin to get
married right away.
Yoo-jin said they were going to the cathedral,
so l thought they were going to pray.
ls there a problem between them?
lt's too dramatic.
Getting married all of a sudden like that.
Sang-hyuk's reaction, too.
Don't you find everything strange?
Yes.
Yoo-jin!
Mr. Kim and l were just talking about you.
We were so worried about you.
ls J un-sang here?
He won't answer his phone.
J un-sang?
Didn't he go to you? He went to Seoul.
Really?
OK, J ung-ah.
l'll call again later.
J un-sang.
J un-sang!
J un-sang...
Mr. Lee's not here right now.
He hasn't left a message either.
She's waiting outside
Hello.
What brings you here?
Do you know
where J un-sang is right now?
Do you know?
What do you mean?
J un-sang's not at his office or at the ski resort.
He's not at his house either.
l can't get in touch with him.
l think
You know, right?
You know where he is right now,
right?
Yoo-jin.
Are you still seeing J un-sang?
l take it that l made myself clear that
l'm opposed to your marriage.
l told that your mother, too...
l'm sorry.
l know that you're against it,
but...
We can't break up.
Didn't J un-sang tell you
why l'm against it?
l see. He didn't tell you, did he?
Go home.
l have nothing to say to you...
Mrs. Kang!
Please...
lf you know, please tell me...
Please tell me
where he is right now.
l don't know.
And l think it' best that
you don't try to find out either.
Who's my father?
ls my father J ung Hyun-soo?
ls my father
Yoo-jin's father?
Yoo-jin came to see me.
She was looking for you.
l know how hard
it must be for you.
You know?
l see. You knew.
J un-sang, l'm sorry...
Putting you through so much pain...
l
l...really
...really loved Yoo-jin's father.
When l brought you up
No matter what,
you were his son, and...
Stop it!
Break up.
Break up right now.
lt'll just get harder if you drag it on.
lt'll just ruin you and Yoo-jin
and cause you pain.
lf you can't, l'll tell her.
l'll tell her myself.
l'll tell her myself
why the two of you
can't married.
No!
l'm going to tell her!
No, you can't do that.
You musn't let Yoo-jin know.
Yoo-jin...
She won't be able to endure it.
Make up your mind.
Will you break up with her?
Or shall l go and tell her?
J un-sang.
J un-sang!
J un-sang...
l'll break up with her.
Where were you...
Yoo-jin...
Where were you!
Do you know how worried l was?
l'm sorry...
You wouldn't even answer your
phone...
Where were you?
Something came up.
What?
Oh, it's nothing...
lt's something
you can't tell me?
No, it's not that...
lt's just a bit complicated...
l too care of it.
Then
l don't have to worry anymore?
Yeah...You don't have to worry anymore.
OK...
Well, you're back now. l'm OK ...
l'm OK now...
Shall we go to the sea?
Now that l think about it,
it's the first time to the sea...
You've never been
to the sea before?
No...
lt's the first time to come to the sea with you.
So this is
our first trip to the sea together.
That's right...
This is our first trip to the sea together...
And...lt's also our last trip to the sea together.
l'm going to bid farewell to her here...
Don't cry my love
We have more time
J ust stay by me like this a little bit longer
So that l can remember
l know even if you don't say
We were like that all along
lf my love
is equivalent to your happiness
l won't hesitate to let you go
l promise
l'll be back some day...
Promise that you'll be happy without me
The smell of the sea's nice...
The sky's so blue...
lt's nice, huh?
Yeah, it's nice.
Do you know what that is?
An airplane.
You know, huh?
Seeing an airplane
makes me want to go far away...
You, too, right?
l know even if you don't say
We were like that all along
lf my love is equivalent
to your happiness
l won't hesitate to let you go
l promise
l'll be back some day
You'll be happy without me
You've cried for too long
l can't be by your side anymore
l'm sorry
l can't take care of you anymore
l have to let go of you once again
l met you again after losing so much
Now l have to send you away again
l promise...
J un-sang, J un-sang! Look at this.
l gathered this much!
You're rich, huh?
lt's weird.
Why are there so many coins here?
l guess people who visited here in
the summer lost a few coins.
Oh, l see!
One ice cream cone, two, three...
No!
Give it to me.
Give it back! Give it to me!
lt's winter here...
But these coins are from the summer...
What shall we do with it?
l don't know...
Shall we gather some more
and buy a yacht?
A yacht?
Yeah, a yacht...
And...
We can sail out into the sea...
And never return.
l think
We'll return someday.
Time will pass...
And then the yacht will get old...
You'll get old...
And we'll be so tired that
we'll want to return...
Do you think so?
Wherever it is,
it's not good to go away too far.
l'll miss so many people.
My mom, Hee-jin, my friends...
l'l miss them so much that it'll hurt.
Yeah, you can't do that, right?
You'll miss too many people.
Right
Let's not hurt the people
that are precious to us.
Stay here.
OK? l'll be right back.
What about this?
l thought about using you.
l thought that it'd be a good idea
to have music critics on the show.
We'll have you,
and have a different critic
every other day of the week
from Monday to Saturday.
Carrying out a show
from a critic's perspective seemed
like a good idea.
Then who...?
We've already found one person...
Hello?
Do you have any recommendations?
And l think that we should carry out
the show a bit differently during the weekend...
You have a phone call.
Who?
Hello?
San-hyuk.. lt's me...
Yes,
hi J un-sang...
Will you come here
tomorrow night?
Yes.. l'll do that...
l'm sorry to trouble you every time like this...
Are you OK?
Yeah, l'm OK...
Actually, no...
But l'll be OK...
Oh yeah, Sang-hyuk.
Can l ask you a favor?
Of course.
What is it? Tell me.
l took some pictures
with Yoo-jin a few days ago...
l didn't think of it then...
l sent those pictures to Yoo-jin's house...
They've probably arrived by now...
Will you get rid of them
before Yoo-jin sees them?
J un-sang...
l don't want to leave anything behind
that Yoo-jin can remember me by...
Please, do that for me.
OK, l will. l'll do that.
l'll see you tomorrow.
What are you doing?
You waited for a long time, right?
Did you call someone?
Oh, yeah... To the office.
Where were you?
l went to buy something.
With the coins you collected on the beach?
Look!
l bought it for you with the coins.
So that we'll have
something to remember our trip by.
Let's make a lot of memories here.
So that we'll have a lot to remember.
This much!
l don't want to leave anything behind that
Yoo-jin will remember me by...
lt's nice, huh?
And...
This is my present to you!
What's this?
Turn it over.
ike you said, they flipped a coin like this
one to tell their future in the movies.
This is how you conquer your fate!
Flip it.
You'll get the answer you want.
lt's simple
J ust need a little money
No matter what happen next
Fate is on our side now.
Right?
Yeah...
l have some left over.
Let's go and take pictures.
OK, let's go.
Let me take some of you.
You already took a lot of me.
What's better? This or this?
Come here!
One, two...
Smile.
You're more handsome when you smile.
Get ready.
Excuse us.
Yes?
Do you have a room that we can use?
A room?
There aren't many people looking for
rooms these days
that l haven't cleaned up...
lt's OK.
How many rooms do you need?
Two...
One, please!
We're married.
l see...
Follow me.
lt's this room.
Won't it be too small?
lt's a bit cold.
lt'll start to get warm in a while.
Have a nice stay.
Thank you.
J un-sang.
To remember our first night together.
l'm just joking.
Get up...
lt's cleaner than l thought.
Me and my friends
went on a trip back in college and
we slept at a place like this.
There were about 20 people in one room then.
This is paradise
compared to then.
Oh, yeah!
l bought a toothbrush, too.
l bought one for you, too.
Where did l put it?
Here it is.
Do you want to wash up first?
No.. Later...
Yeah?
Won't it be cold
in the morning?
Yoo-jin.
My memory,
l remember everything
l remember the smallest things
when l close my eyes
You're far away at a place
where l can't reach you
Not being able to tell you that
l love you that l'll wait for you
l really didn't know
l didn' t know that
l would get to meet you again like this
l'll tell you now that
l still love you
l wanna love you forever
Will you still come to me if it's not too late...
l'll be back in a while.
You are with me forever
J un-sang
l'm not afraid of anything.
Anything...
Nothing scares me.
As long as you're with me.
You're awake?
What are we going to do today?
Get up quickly.
A pound of strawberries for just 1000 won.
What do you want to do?
What shall we do?
Tell me if everything
that you want to do.
l'll do anything you wish.
Anything?
Anything.
Come and get some strawberries..
3000 won for 2 pounds...
Why are you being so nice?
No special reason...
No special reason?
You're really acting strange.
lt's just for today
so tell me before l change my mind.
Really? So that's it, huh...
well, l can't let this opportunity slip away...
Hey! See the fish bread over there?
l want to eat that.
Can you buy for me?
But we just ate!
Still, there's room for a fish.
OK.
Wait here.
Hurry up.
Ma'am, how much is it?
iss, l'm sorry, but will you carry
this for me?
My house is over there. lt's just so
heavy...
Will you carry it for me?
Sure.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
1000 won for a pound of
strawberries.
Yoo-jin!
J un-sang...
What happened? lt's just so heavy...
An old lady
asked me to carry her groceries for
her.
lt took longer than l thought.
You were gone when l came back.
You should've just waited for me there
if l wasn't there!
lt's OK...
You found me
didn't you?
What if l'm not around...
hat if l'm not around to find you, then what?
Let's go.
You know what?
The day before,
a star fell off my necklace.
lt looked strong but it broke.
How come?
l think that's why
l got lost today.
l should go and repair it soon,
right?
oo-jin, can l have the necklace back?
Why?
l'll go and repair it for you.
You will?
This is for you
eturn it to me as soon as possible, OK?
OK, l will.
Come
You know what,
we fought for the first time today.
We did?
Yoo-jin,
l'm sorry l shouted at you before.
lt's OK. lt was my fault.
No, don't say that.
l'm sorry. l mean it...
You don't have to be sorry like that.
Still...
Then listen to my wish again tomorrow.
Don't you want to make it up to me?
lt's OK to fight from time to time.
l get to make a wish. lt's nice.
What shall l wish for this time?
un-sang, what shall we do tomorrow?
What shall we do?
Tomorrow...
Yoo-jin,
don' drift away when you're walking.
You get lost
because you drift away in other thoughts.
OK.
Don't get distracted
when you see something interesting in the street.
And you know that
you're clumsy, right?
Remember the hard time we had
when you lost the blueprint at the
ski resort last time?
Be careful not to lose anything.
Oh,
and you
have to learn how to say no to others.
Listening to every favor that
everyone asks of you
isn't always the best thing to do.
Sometimes you're being of more help
to the other person by saying no.
Do you understand what l'm saying?
And you...
Hey.
You're really acting strange.
You're acting like someone
who's going far away.
And!
Why do you keep on picking on my bad points.
Don't you have anything good to say about me?
Tell me my good sides.
You have none.
Really? l really have none, huh?
Really?
Yeah.
Yoo-jin...
l'm sorry...
Don't forget a thing.
Don't forget
even if l'm not by your side
My love
from the beginning to now
ls close by
but far away
l'll take care of you
Wherever you are
and whenever it is
Wait for me
until l come to you...
Wow! lt's heads!
lt means that we'll be together
forever and ever.
Even if l'm a bit late
Wait for me
until l come to you, until l do...
l'll take care of you
Wherever you are
and whenever it is
Wait for me until l come to you
We'll go back to the time
when we first met...
What are you doing here?
Where's J un-sang?
Did you see J un-sang?
Yoo-jin!
Where did J un-sang go?
Where is he?
J un-sang...
left.
Don't lie.
Why?
Why would J un-sang leave?
J un-sang...
lt's because of his mother...
She won't allow it no matter what...
She said she'd cut ties with him
if he married you...
He said
he couldn't hurt his mother anymore...
No, that's not possible...
lt's true...
That's why he said he had to leave you...
And...
He said he won't see you anymore...
He asked me to tell you that and left.
That's not possible...
That's not possible!
Honey.
Did Sang-hyuk call?
Why?
He didn' come in last night and hasn't called.
l don' know why he's being like this these days.
Do you think
it's because of Yoo-jin?
What if he's seeing her again?
Nothing like that will happen.
Don't worry.
Then do you know why he's acting like that?
Why on earth is he being like that?
Tell Sang-hyuk that
l want to talk to him when he comes in.
Gosh...
l remember the day
Hyun-soo got married.
You tried to drown yourself
right after he got married.
Do you remember that night?
You ran away from Choonchun
after that night.
So l thought that
J un-sang was my son.
Why'd you bring up the past for?
l don't want to talk about it.
Were you already pregnant
with him then?
Jin-woo.
l thought that
you tried to kill yourself just
over the fact that Hyun-soo left you.
But that wasn't it, huh?
ou were pregnant with J un-sang, weren't you?
That's why you tried to kill yourself.
l realized that out
after meeting J un-sang a few days ago.
Why didn't you tell me that
he was Hyun-soo's son?
You loved Hyun-soo so much.
Why didn't you tell him?
You wanted to hold on to him.
lf you told him that you were
pregnant with J un-sang,
he wouldn't have left you.
Do you know what the difference
between you and Hyun-soo is?
lf you love someone,
you believe everything that person tells you.
You loved me,
but Hyun-soo didn't.
That's the difference between you and Hyun-soo.
Yes?
You're home.
Since when did J un-sang know that
he' Yoo-jin's brother?
He found out
when his memory came back a while ago.
His memory?
Then he already knew
before the accident?
Yes.
How did he know?
Through who?
l'm sure
Mi-hee didn't tell him about his father.
l don't know.
l'm not quite sure about that.
The two of them...They've decided to break up.
l see...
lt was so hard for them
to get back together again.
lt'll be hard for them to accept the fac
t they're brother and sister.
Even l can't believe it.
l feel so sorry for them.
l shouldn't have let Yoo-jin go.
Even if she didn't love me...
l shouldn't have let her go.
Then she wouldn't have had to go through this.
lt
would've just been me that she resented.
l shouldn't have let her go.
l'll go to my room now.
OK. Good night.
Yes, good night.
But...
J un-sang and Yoo-jin...
There should be an age difference...
How are they in the same grade?
l'm not sure.
Anyway,
they're the same age.
Their birthday is only
two months away from each other's, too.
The two of them have a lot in
common.
Father.
Who is it?
Mother...
Mother, have some tea...
l'm not your mother anymore,
isn't that so?
l'm sorry.
There's no reason for you to be sorry
about breaking up with Sang-hyuk.
l didn't come here because of that.
l don't care about that anymore,
but...
Why are you still seeing Sang-hyuk?
Mother.
What does Sang-hyuk mean to you?
ls he someone who's at your beck and call who
comes to you when you need help
and who you can brush aside when
you don't need him?
ls that what he is to you?
l hear that you broke up with the guy
that l saw at the ski resort.
Well, l heard about your situation.
l was surprised, too.
But l won't allow you to meet
bSang-hyuk just ecause
you're going through a hard time.
lt's over
between you and Sang-hyuk.
Even if you were more than
ust brother and sister with J un-sang,
it's over between you and Sang-hyuk.
other, what are you talking about?
l was shocked to hear that
J un-sang is your brother, too,
but it's your father
that you should resent.
Don't involve Sang-hyuk
in your problems...
Mom
What did you just say?
J un-sang and l are what?
Will you...
Will you tell me once more?
You didn't know?
Mother...
What... What did you just say?