Sammy's hurt.
He's hurt real bad.
This one goes out to any angel
with their ears on.
This is Dean Winchester...
And I need your help.
Start with a name.
Ezekiel.
There is a chance I can fix
your brother.
How will it work?
I heal Sam while healing myself.
Sam can eject me
at any time.
And if Sam does eject me,
he will die.
Then we keep it a secret
for now.
I just got to hope that you're
one of the good guys.
I am.
Zeke!
You can bring her back
like you did with Cass.
I cannot keep doing that.
Why the hell not?!
Every time I use my power,
it weakens me.
Merry Christmas.
Dad wants us to pick up
where he left off --
saving people,
hunting things...
The family business.
Becky, it's all real.
I knew it!
Nipples?
I mean, come on.
We hunt monsters!
Why am I here?!
I mean, normal people,
they see a monster,
and they run.
But not us -- no, no, no.
We search out things
that want to kill us.
Real. It's real.
No, no, no.
Now you die.
You know who does that?
Crazy people!
I'm Batman.
We...are insane!
I lost my shoe.
That was scary.
And with a 1:20 left
in the game, it's 62-54.
This team wants
that championship.
It would be great.
He's up.
It's good, but the ref's
on the whistle.
He's calling a foul.
It could be charging.
Number 10 --
he's not happy about that.
This guy just about
could foul out,
and nobody but the ref
wants to see that happen.
Coach Johnson
watching the clock.
He calls time-out.
Talking to the ref right now.
You know, so far in this game,
there have been
a number of fouls called
by this particular ref,
and that's not...
Easy, Colonel.
Is anyone here?
Whoa!
Gets me every time.
What's the matter, boy?
It's me.
What the hell?
♪ Supernatural 9x05 ♪
Dog Dean Afternoon
Original Air Date on November 5, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
Wow.
What?
Kevin.
Just poured some buffalo milk
down his gob twice.
Buffalo milk?
Yeah,
the hangover cure-all.
It's got everything in it.
Except buffalo milk.
How is that kid still recovering
from Branson?
What can I say?
He's an amateur.
The slippery nipple shots at
the Dolly Parton Dixie Stampede
nearly killed the guy.
All right.
Well, uh,
I got something
that's gonna get us
back on the road.
A case?
Yeah.
You sure
you're ready for that?
Why would I not be ready
for that?
Aren't you kind of running
on empty?
Yeah, but the last
three nights straight,
I had eight hours
of shut-eye.
And for a hunter,
that's like 20.
Trust me, Dean.
I feel good.
Well, that's great and all,
James Brown,
but you're still recovering
from the trials.
I think you ought to pace
yourself, you know?
And the sooner
you heal...
Yeah?
I just want you
back to your old self.
I am, Dean.
Look, Kevin's back
on the heaven spell.
Crowley's locked up.
We should be out there
doing what we do best.
Well...
You want to listen at least?
Okay, great.
Taxidermist
named Max Alexander
mysteriously crushed
to death.
Nearly every joint in his body
dislocated,
every bone broken.
Poor guy is
a human pretzel.
You tell me what's got
that kind of strength.
A demonic Luchador?
Shop's a couple hours away
in Enid, Oklahoma.
We should at least
check it out.
Unless there's some reason
you think we shouldn't.
Subtle.
Check that out.
Huh.
Well, the creep factor
just skyrocketed.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
How are you?
Agents Michaels and Deville.
The body's already been
to the morgue.
Just wrapping it up
with Dave Stephens.
He's the one
who discovered the body.
Such a shame.
I used to go hunting with Max.
He was a real good egg.
Sorry for your loss.
Thanks.
You mind showing my partner
around?
I just got a couple questions
for Mr. Stephens.
Okay. Come on.
Dave Stephens?
Yeah.
I just got a couple questions
for you
if that's all right.
I'll tell you
whatever you need to know.
Max was a...a real pal.
Hunting buddy?
Mm. Yeah.
Eh, lucky guess.
So, uh, about what time
did you discover the body?
About 9:00 a.m. --
my usual pickup time.
I come in every Wednesday
and Sundays,
uh, to collect
the entrails.
The what?
The animal organs.
Ah.
After Max would, uh,
dig them out and work his magic.
Huh.
He, uh -- he was
a real artist, you know?
Strange thing is, though, uh,
bins were empty this morning.
Why is that strange?
Well,
because it's a Sunday.
Weekend hunts
are pretty much a given
in this neck of the woods,
so they're usually, mm,
chock-full of guts.
Ah.
Mm.
Any chance Max could have
cleaned them out himself?
No. It's a --
it's a biohazard.
You can't just, you know,
throw the stuff out.
You got to burn it.
Huh.
Is there, uh, anything else
missing from the shop?
No. The register was full,
and the safe was intact.
And all of Max's trophies
were still on the walls.
And was there anybody else here
when you showed up?
No one.
No, other than, uh...
The Colonel.
Hmm.
Excuse us.
So?
Okay, so, uh...
We got a thief
who's jonesing for animal parts,
we got a pagan symbol,
and we got a human pretzel.
Yeah, it all sounds
very witch-y,
but I wasn't
able to find a hex bag.
All right,
well, let's keep digging.
But, uh, not here.
I don't like the way
that one's looking at me.
Okay, uh, that...symbol
in the graffiti,
it's...not wiccan.
It's copywritten.
Local animal-rights group,
Enid's answer to PETA.
S.N.A.R.T.?
You got to be kidding me.
Well, it makes sense
that an animal-rights group
would have an axe to grind
with a taxidermist.
Why?
The animal's already dead.
Yeah, but hunters
are what keep them in business.
Now the question is,
are those bleeding hearts
actually witches
or just hippies?
What's the difference?
Always knew I'd find
the source of all evil
at a vegan bakery.
What's that smell?
Patchouli.
Yeah, mixed with depression
from meat deprivation.
Hey.
You know who wears sunglasses
inside?
Blind people.
And douchebags.
Olivia
and Dylan Camrose?
At your service.
You two are members
of s.N.A.R.T.?
Founders and co-presidents,
actually.
Uh, can we interest you
in some literature?
Or a flaxseed scone?
It's wheat-free,
gluten-free, sugar-free,
and surprisingly moist.
Let me stop you
right there.
Uh, we're here to investigate
the death of Max Alexander,
a local taxidermist.
He's...dead?
You knew him?
Ish. Um...small town.
Well, he was murdered
last night,
and a S.N.A.R.T. logo was found
at the crime scene.
You two wouldn't happen
to know
anything about that,
would you?
His business is funded
by hunters,
and you know
how hunters are.
They're selfish dicks
who define themselves
by what they kill.
And as animal advocates,
we couldn't stand for that.
So, you killed him?
Of course not.
S.N.A.R.T. doesn't tolerate
violence.
Huh.
This coming from a couple
who spray-paints death threats.
It was a scare tactic.
We just wanted to spook him.
Turns out we were the ones
who got spooked.
What does that mean?
Well, last night,
when we were tagging the joint,
we heard this noise.
A hissing noise.
It freaked us out,
so we ran out into the alley.
But someone attacked us.
Sprayed us in the eyes with mace.
And it's not like we could go
to the cops.
So, now we look
like total douchebags
because we have to wear
our sunglasses inside.
Necrosis?
Premature death
of tissues --
that's why their eyes
were all messed up.
And it's not caused
by mace.
All right.
What caused it?
Right here. "Blunt force,
radiation, venom."
As in "snake"?
The taxidermist
was constricted.
Olivia and Dylan
heard hissing,
and they were sprayed
in the eyes.
By venom.
Okay, so...
What are we talking here,
some sort of a freaky-ass
snake monster?
Maybe.
The weird thing is snakes
either envenomate or constrict.
No snake does both.
Correction --
freaky-ass mega-snake monster.
It could be a Vetala.
Yeah, but they're not afraid
to sink their fangs in.
Taxidermist was
bite-free.
It doesn't really fit
the profile.
Right. So...?
So, call Kevin.
Have him look some stuff up.
Aren't you early,
dude?
Hmm.
Dude!
You said you were from
a perfume company.
No! No, please!
Claw marks.
Yeah. The cops said
all the cats went missing.
Right, so, yesterday,
uh, we're dealing with
some sort of a snake monster.
Today,
it's a killer kitty.
I don't know.
Hey.
Why does that mutt
look familiar?
That was
the taxidermist's dog.
So, he's been
at both crime scenes?
Yeah.
Maybe he's a suspect.
You know may--
Could be a skinwalker,
maybe a shapeshifter.
Doesn't really look
like a monster to me.
One way to find out.
Come here, boy.
Hey.
This isn't gonna hurt
at all.
Unless it hurts.
Hmm.
I guess we can, uh,
rule out killer.
Do you agents need
any further assistance?
Officer, I think we're okay.
Thanks.
All right,
well, let me know.
Officer. Excuse me.
Uh, can I borrow your hat?
Good luck
getting adopted.
Okay, so,
the Colonel's not a suspect.
Yeah,
but he's a witness.
Hey, boy.
You speak sign language?
That's monkeys.
Huh?
You know what?
This is gonna sound crazy.
I read this book once
about this guy
who tried to teach his dog
to speak
after it witnessed
a murder.
It worked?
No.
But he wrote a book
about it?
Yeah, well, he doesn't have
what we have.
Kevin. Hey, it's me.
How do we speak
to a dog?
An Inuit spell.
Yeah.
Who knew the, uh, Men of Letters
had its own Eskimo section?
And it's supposed to let us
communicate with the Colonel?
Yeah,
well...that's the plan.
Kevin said it's like a sort of
a human/animal mind meld.
Meaning?
If it works,
we should be able to read
the Colonel's thoughts.
All right, I'll do it.
You -- you got enough
on your plate.
Like what?
Uh, like...you're tired.
You're on the mend.
Okay?
Plus, you -- you've got
a sensitive stomach.
Last thing we need is
you chucking this stuff up. Huh?
Doesn't look so bad.
I was wrong.
Come on.
Ha!
"Deila hér me.
Dag eru nou rar
vitur orum."
All right.
Let's get this party started.
Tell me
everything you know.
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Tough crowd.
♪ I got to take a little time ♪
So, call Kevin.
♪ A little time to think things over ♪
spell tasted like ass and was a bust.
At least it didn't affect
your appetite. Geez.
Yeah.
Change the station.
♪ I better read
between the lines ♪
Change the station.
♪ In case I need it
when I'm older ♪
What?
You -- shut up.
It's working!
It -- go!
♪ Ohh ♪
Say that again.
You call
this classic rock?
Next thing you know,
they'll be playing Styx.
♪ Now this mountain I must climb ♪
And Dennis DeYoung? A punk.
Dennis DeYoung's
not a punk.
He's Mr. Roboto,
bitch.
Why are you arguing with the dog
about Styx?
Wh-- uh, yeah.
Um, hey, boy.
What were you trying to tell us
about the cowboy hat?
The douchewheel
who killed my best friend
was wearing a cowboy hat.
And the pothead, too?
Yep.
Same guy killed both.
♪ In my life ♪
Ask about the cats.
Yeah, uh --
♪ There's been heartache
and pain ♪
And what about the cats?
♪ I don't know ♪
I don't know.
I don't want this.
I couldn't see much.
I didn't exactly have
the best view in the orphanage.
Oh,
but I could smell him.
Guy reeked of red meat,
dishwashing detergent
and tiger balm.
Huh.
So, what's he saying?
Uh, that the -- the guy,
he smelled like ground chuck
and soap suds
and old-lady cream.
Dean,
what are you doing?
♪ I want you to show me ♪
I don't know.
Oh, what are you
laughing at?
Uh...
Hey!
Hey, hey! Yeah!
You! You!
Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey, you! You!
You! You!
Uh, Dean?
Hmm?
I think the spell worked.
Fact, I think it worked
a little too well.
What?
I think...
you might be a dog.
What?
You're scratching
your head.
You're...barking
at the mailman.
You're playing fetch.
I --
Ruh-roh.
Yeah.
No, that -- okay.
All right. Thanks.
So, apparently, the Inuit spell
has some side effects.
Oh, well, that would have been
nice to know
before I downed it!
What kind
of side effects?
When you mind meld
with an animal,
it's...possible to start
exhibiting some of its behavior.
Don't look at me, Hoss.
It ain't my fault.
Well, how long am I gonna have
the urge to...
Sniff butts?
Oh, whoa.
Hey.
I don't have the urge
to sniff butts.
Yet.
Do you really h-have
the --
No! Come on!
Well, Kevin doesn't know
how long it'll last.
It's not like
it's an exact science, you know?
But hopefully,
when the spell wears off,
so will the side effects.
I wouldn't eat that
if I were you.
Chocolate?
Seriously.
Where we headed?
Back to the shelter.
To sniff out more clues,
maybe dig up
something we missed?
All right, one more doggy pun
out of you,
and I'm gonna
have your nuts clipped.
I hate to break it to you,
Hoss.
My sack's emptier
than Santa's after Christmas.
Aw, are you kidding me?
Hey, dick move,
pigeon!
Screw you, asshat.
Did --
what?
Wait a minute.
Can I hear all animals?
Yep.
Animals have a universal
language -- like esperanto.
But this one
actually caught on.
And I'm just
getting started, too.
Brewing a real big one.
Ha.
Bet your ride's gonna look
sweet in white.
What's he saying?
You --
he's being a douchebag!
Who you calling "douchebag,"
douchebag?
Oh, shut it,
you winged rat!
Dude.
What?
Hey.
Just calm down.
Just get in the car.
Ha ha. That's right, Sally.
Go cry to mama.
Oh, that's it,
you son of a bitch!
Ooh! Dean! Hey!
Get in the car.
I think
it's probably best
to just leave the Colonel
in the car.
Excuse me?
Well all the windows
are open.
You think we like that?
"We"?
You think
because the windows are open
that that's some sort
of a treat, huh?
No,
the dog's coming in.
Respect.
♪ uh-huh
Yeah, baby.
♪ Ohh
You said it.
♪ Ooh
Dean.
Yeah.
So, what else
can you tell me
about the man
with the cowboy hat?
Honestly, I couldn't see much.
Damn cataracts.
And you know no one's going to
pay for my surgery.
Just another casualty
of the system, I guess.
I don't belong here, you know.
I'm pedigreed.
Well, I'm sure
you'll be out of here soon.
Please. I'm 14.
Good luck...Ma'am.
Once a day
they clean these cages.
Once a day!
Okay.
A biscuit.
Just one biscuit.
I need a Raquel Welch poster
and a rock hammer.
I'm shaking the fence, boss.
Still shaking the fence.
- Over here!
- I was framed!
Any luck?
Hardly.
And I'm not getting any clues --
just a bunch of complaints.
Hey, pretty boy.
Over here.
Yeah, uh, sorry, pal.
I'm done for the day.
But I saw everything!
And I'll tell you,
but...
It'll cost you.
What?
Are you kidding me?
I'm being extorted by a dog.
Well, what do you want,
huh?
What? Beggin' strips?
Snausages?
Bitch, please.
If I'm gonna
rat someone out,
it's got to be
worth my while.
I want...a belly rub.
You --
All right.
Not from you, sweetie.
From that big one.
Over there.
Hi!
Ohh, a-a cowboy hat,
leather pants.
The dude's
a total closet case.
Okay, what else can you tell me
about the guy
other than his outfit?
Um, he was carrying
a burlap sack for the cats.
What does he want
with the cats?
Ooh, attaboy, yes.
Hell if I know.
But he took all of them,
except for the one he ate.
Ew.
What?
Apparently, our guy has
a sweet tooth for kitty cats.
Huh.
Oh. Oh, and the sack had
something written on it.
Okay, what did it say?
Hey, come on.
We had a deal.
Well, you tell that
to the tall drink.
He's the one
who stopped rubbing.
Sam.
Hand cramps.
He's not talking.
Attaboy.
It said
"Avant-Garde Cuisine."
Lucky for you,
I read French.
That's a café
on Main Street.
"No dogs allowed."
Well, no wonder he smelled
like hamburgers and dish soap.
We got to go downtown.
Apparently our guy works
at a restaurant.
Whoa-oh, yeah.
No, no, wait, wait, wait.
Sure you don't want to adopt me?
No, thanks.
Uh, we'll pass.
No,
I'm not above licking feet.
Hey, big'un!
Come back here!
All right.
Well...
Hey, hold up.
What's the matter?
Best belly rub I ever had.
Freedom!
I left a surprise in there
for animal control.
I didn't peg you
for a softy.
Going home. I'm going home.
Honey, I'm coming home.
Yeah,
I'm coming home.
I'm going home!
Bacon! Bacon! Bacon!
Bacon!
I'm sorry.
Who can afford to be closed
on Monday these days?
A homicidal maniac?
Yeah.
Hey.
Check this out.
Chef Leo.
Think he's our guy?
It's Okie town.
Lots of dudes
wear cowboy hats.
Whoa.
Oxycodone,
tramadol, methadone.
Oh, guess he likes to cook
comfortably numb.
Yeah, apparently.
Help us.
Please, mister.
Over here.
Did you hear that?
Sounded like little kids.
Help. If you don't free us,
the chef will eat us.
She's not lying.
We're in a cage!
Eat you?
Look in the refrigerator
behind you.
Yeah, behind you.
In the fridge.
Hey.
"Owl brains."
"Cheetah liver."
"Grizzly heart."
Ah, a spell book.
Shamanism.
Well, what's a chef doing
dabbling with witchcraft?
It says here whatever
animal organ you ingest
with the right mix
of hoo doo and spices,
you temporarily gain the power
of that animal.
So, okay, if you're munching
on owl brains...
Your head spins around
like "The Exorcist"?
Close.
Bolsters your IQ.
Okay, eat a cheetah liver
for speed,
bear heart
for strength.
Okay, so if he's chowing down
on this stuff --
Then it would make sense
why he constricted
the taxidermist
and clawed the guy
at the shelter.
Well, no offense, but why would
he want to eat you guys?
Uh, we have
collapsible spines.
We do. Promise.
Look at this.
Hmm?
"Lion liver plus
eagle heart.
"Rattlesnake fangs plus
anaconda bladder.
Baboon brains plus
black widow abdomen."
He's mixing ingredients.
What the hell for?
Shoo! Quiet!
Don't shush me!
You be quiet!
I am quite. Now.
Who the hell are you?
We're from
the health department.
Stopped by
for an inspection.
I wasn't aware
we had one scheduled.
Yeah, no, you wouldn't be.
That's the point.
Besides,
I thought you were closed.
We are.
Chef's having a private dinner.
In fact,
he'll be here any minute.
Oh. Well, then. In that case,
kitchen's shut down.
Shut down? Why?
Because, uh, y-you're both
in clear violation
of penal code 8.14.
Out. Come on. Get out.
Both of you.
We'll let you know.
All right.
I'll take the front.
You take the back.
Do we even know
how to kill this guy?
Well, empty one of these
in his head.
See what that does.
Aah!
Chameleons aren't
that bad.
Kind of taste
like chicken.
How the hell
did you do that?
D-do what?
Don't play coy.
I want to know what you are.
Oh,
screw the sharktopus.
You're my main course.
Why does it smell like dog
in here?
That smell's coming
from you.
All dogs
should be leashed.
What did you do
to my brother?
Your brother?
What was your mom smoking
when she had you two?
He's fine.
He's just taking
a little cat nap before dinner.
I've never had human heart
before.
Heard it's a bit chewy.
Good job
I'm not a fussy eater.
You're sick.
Been told that
once or twice.
No, no.
Not in the head.
I, uh -- well,
you are that, too,
but I mean
sick like cancer.
Well, I guess dogs really can
sniff it out.
Stage IV carcinoma.
Huh.
So that's why
you're doing this.
What happened?
Draw the short straw,
decided to break bad?
See,
when I was diagnosed,
I was way past
standard treatment.
No one could save me.
But then with the help
of a Pawnee shaman
and a zoo membership,
I found a cure,
albeit a temporary one.
Cancer always came back.
You start experimenting
with different organs, huh?
Traded in the single serving
for a combo platter.
Well, what can I say?
Combination therapy works.
I felt stronger,
and the effects
lasted longer.
And if you smoke a few innocent
people in the process,
well, hell,
at least you felt better.
Well, I didn't mean
to kill anyone -- at first.
But if people got in my way,
they became collateral damage.
Guess you eat enough predators,
you start to become one.
You are what you eat,
right?
Do you really think
the power you hold
over other people's lives
can make up for what you lack
in your own?
So, dog boy,
what do I need to eat
to take you down, huh?
You don't
want to do this.
Oh, but I do
See, I'm gonna kill you,
work up a nice appetite,
and then I'm gonna eat
your brother.
I mean, I don't know
what the hell he is,
but with healing powers
like that, who cares?
He could cure me.
Ah.
Dog on sort-of dog.
Rahuraar,
sakuriisat iisat
a ti'pah kaawakit.
'A tarahkista'u...
...a raah.
Sorry.
Wolf trumps dog.
Maybe.
But not a whole pack.
Hey.
For the love of God,
Sammy.
Hey, Sammy.
Zeke.
Whoever the hell
you are.
Hey. Come on.
Don't make me lick
your damn face.
Hey.
Come on.
When you called us
about adopting him,
we couldn't
believe it.
Aren't you
the sweetest?
Ugh.
Back off, tofu-breath.
Oh,
you must be starving.
Lucky for you, I baked
some vegan doggy cupcakes.
I'm gonna be pooping wheatgrass
with these two.
Look, I know
they're hippie freaks,
but they're gonna give you
a good home --
one that you deserve.
Yeah, yeah.
Wish we could take you
on the road with us,
but it's no life
for a dog.
Don't sweat it.
I get carsick anyway.
I was afraid to tell you
earlier,
but I barfed
in your backseat.
You...
What?
I'm gonna miss you,
buddy.
I'll miss you, too.
And by the way,
as an honorary dog,
there's something
you should know.
Dog's aren't really
man's best friend.
What are you
talking about?
I know it sounds
like a conspiracy theory,
but the real reason
we were put here was to...
Put here to do what?
Oh, you got to be
kidding me.
Oh, now the spell
wears off?!
Okay.
How did it go?
Well, bad news is
I'm gonna miss the flea bag.
Good news is
it looks like the spell
is finally wearing off.
You okay?
The Stetson man
got you pretty good.
Yeah, I'm fine.
I-I just, uh...
I can't stop thinking
about what he said.
Oh, come on, Sammy.
Guy was out of
his freaking gourd.
Yeah, but, I mean,
why -- why would he ask that?
Why -- why did he want to know
what I was?
Who the hell knows?
He was all jacked up
on juice, you know?
He was possessed by -- by
something he couldn't control.
It was...
It was just
a matter of time
before it
completely took over.
You can't reason with crazy,
right?
I don't know.
Well, I do.
Trust me, Sam.
You got nothing to worry about.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man