I aIways wanted to be
in the movies
When I was IittIe I thought for sure
1 day, I couId be a big big star...
Or maybe just beautifuI...
BeautifuI and rich,
Iike the women on TV
Yeah, I had a Iot of dreams
And I guess you can
caII me a reaI romantic
Because I truIy beIieve that
one day...they'II come true
So I dream about it for hours
As the years went by,
I Iearnt to stop sharing this with people
They said I was dreaming
But back then, I beIieved
it whoIe heartiIy
So whenever I was down,
I would just escape into my mind
To my other Iive, where
I was someone eIse
It made me happy to think
that aII these peopIe...
just didn't know yet
who I was gonna be
But 1 day they'II aII see
I heard that MariIyn Monroe
was discovered in a soda shop
And I thought for sure,
it couId be Iike that
So I started growing up
reaI young...
And I aIways secretIy Iooking
for who is gonna discover me?
Was it this guy?
Or maybe this one?
You never knew
But even if they couIdn't take me
aII the way ... Iike MariIyn
They wouId somehow
beIieve in me just enough
They wouId see me for what I couId
be, and think I was beautifuI
Like a diamond in the rough
They'II take me away...
To my new Iife
And my new worId
Where everything
would be different
Yeah, I Iived that way
for Iong Iong time
And my head dreaming
Iike that
It was nice
1 day it just stopped
By the time I met
you aII...
Shame...
aII I want is a beer
How are you doing?
-Great
Anyone sitting here?
No
Madam our services
are for patrons onIy
Give me a beer
whatever cheapest
So what it is Iike,
a gay pIace or what?
Yeah
Hey, whatever, man
Can I buy you that drink?
I got my own money
I'II have a pitcher, whatever
she's having
Look, I'm not gay aIrite?
Well, it makes sense
So what are you doing
here then?
My truck broke down, I'm a ...
I got a pressure cIeaning
business
What's pressure cIeaning?
You know steam cIean?
Upholstery, carpets,
you know, shit like that
So I'm just getting out of the rain
My name is SeIby
You owe me change!
Fuck!
I'm out of here
Oh, are you sure?
Get your fucking hands off
me! you dumb dyke...
I'm not gonna fuck you
for fucking beer ok
Stop wasting your fucking
time!
I wasn't trying to fuck
you!
I just wanna taIk to you
I thought that if I bought you
some beer maybe you'II taIk to me
I just trying to have one
decent night out, you know ..
Just taIk to someone before
I've to go back to my parents cIoset
I'm sorry
You don't have to stay
So are you reaIIy a
steam cIeaner?
No, I'm not
No man, actuaIIy it's
a reaI good job...
Pressure cIeaning
You want some?
Oh come on don't
Iet me down now
You ready?
1...no, you don't get
to do this
Shit, I don't fucking
trust you
You ready?
1, 2, go!
You do suck
You're just a sore winner
Yeah, winner though,
man
Oh, man that's aII
my cast
You spiIIed some good
shit there
I'm gonna Iick it up
Iike a dog
We need 2 more
What's that buIIshit?
What time is it?
The bar is cIosed
Then why don't you take
that stick out of your ass...
Now wouId be a good time,
don't you think huh?
Now that the bar's cIosed
What you do for is that?
We had a good time
though
Yeah, I know, it was fun
I'm sorry, I caIIed you
dumb dyke
I don't care
And thanks for the drinks
No...No Problem.
So see you around ok
Do you wanna stay with
me?
I didn't mean....you know
you don't have to do anything
Shit I know
Fuck it
Yeah? My truck's
broken down
Ok, car's over here,
come here, this way
AII I wanted was a beer
But the day I met SeIby I'd spent
most of the afternoon sitting in the rain,
about to kiII myseIf
So you can understand
I was fIexibIe, I mean everybody
gotta have faith in something
For me? For me aII I had Ieft
was Iove
And I was getting pretty sure that,
I wasn't gonna Iove a man again
So I was gonna do it
And the onIy reason I did it
was a five doIIar biII
I knew I probabIy given some
asshoIe a bIowjob for it
So reaIIy tried to piss me off that
if I kiIIed myseIf without spending it
BasicaIIy I sucked
him off for free
So I made a deaI
I said God, I gotta spend
this 5 bucks
But when it's gone
so am I
If you've got something for me
in this life, you better bring it on
And there she was
Just some friends my parents
and I are staying with
You wanna take a shower
or anything?
Goodnite
-Goodnite
I can't beIieve you
are here
Me neither
Can I touch your face?
Sure
Honey!
God Donna!
Donna sorry, just a sec!
I'm sorry, I'm supposed
to be ready for church
Hey, where's my shirt?
Look at this, it's 5 o'cIock in
the morning and she ain't dressed yet
I'm sorry about that
No, it's aIrite
Hey thanks for letting me crash
No, that was nice
So when are you Ieaving?
Tuesday
But you know, I'm gonna be hanging out
at the Moon Nite, around 5
About 2 bIocks up
-Yeah yeah yeah
Maybe I'II swing by
AIrite
You have fun at church,
aIrite
Who was that person?
She's just a friend I made
Honey, I think she was a
straight person
Did you check your stuff,
because she might have stole something
No...I checked it, she didn't
take anything
Listen, honey, you cannot bring peopIe
like that here, what if Charles had seen her?
I'm sorry
A person Iike that ... no Mdm
We have no business with
peopIe Iike that
I'm just getting some stuff
You'll give it to me when you get it
Want some sandwich?
Ham don't do it for me
-Thanks, man
I'II buy it if you want
It's aIrite
You'II pay me when
you get it
How are you doing?
I'm good
I met a friend
-ReaIIy? good for you
Hope it's not some
asshoIe Iike the Iast guy...
who AImost trampIed you half to death
No, she is...reaI nice,
you know
Thanks, man
Hang on a sec
Hang the fuck on!
You Iook good
Thanks
Man, you know what
I'm going to give you the $5...
I got it. I got it
So you came
Yeah I was around,
you know, thought I'll swing by
So where's your friends?
WeII, I...I'm not...
You're mean
Can I ask you a question?
Are you a prostitute?
Yeah
I don't know
PeopIe Iike pay to be
with you, it's wiId!
Men must just Iine up
to be with a girl Iike you
I guess, I don't know,
not reaIIy, you know!
What do you do to them?
AII kind of things, you know,
whatever they want
How do you know what
they want?
WeII they ain't shy
to teII you
ReaIIy?
Well shit, men are real
easy to read anyway
Well, how about that guy?
How about him?
Oh, he's gay
No way
Yeah, man, Iook at him,
he tries too hard
Oh man you see that
IittIe fucker over there?
Well he, he's straight up, S&M
That's Trevor,
That's the son of the people I'm staying with
Shit I'm sorry
I don't care about that
I don't reaIise he was gonna
be here
This girl in my church, she toId
everyone that I tried to kiss her
So my parents
basically disowned me
And I decided to come down here
and try to figure somethings out
Then this happened
before I could get a job
How Iong do you have to stay on?
Not too much Ionger
But my dad had to pay my medicaI biIIs
So I made a deaI with him,
that I would go back
Which ...you know...it...probabIy
for the best...maybe it'll work
Maybe he'II be able to save my
souI and aII that
WeII I bet you twenty, I'II beat
your ass in a race, rite now
Oh no...
Oh yeah, me and you are gonna
hit the floor rite now
Serious I can't skate
You gotta heIp me
I know, I've gotcha, come on
There you got it
You better not Iet
me break my other arm
See you can do this
Your're very good, man
You think you can you do by yourseIf?
Ok
-There you go
Feel the music
You having fun?
There you go turn, turn
Oh, man I Iove this song
Oh I Iove it too
Just Iike that
Oh I can't do that
Yeah you can
No, no, no,come on,
come with me
Trevor
Who cares about him?
Come on are you ready?
So we don't hit anyone
Are you ok?
I can't, I can't do
this here
Maybe we can go somewhere
How about the yard
over there?
I thought you didn't Iike gaIs
I don't Iike men anymore,
reaIIy
I Iike you
Maybe...maybe we
could go somewhere
Where we can get
a room or something
Oh I don't have any
money
I gotta go
I'II see you tomorrow
Ok honey I taIked to your
father and guess what?
What?
-You got a job, little miss
How about that?
-ReaIIy?
That's rite, working
rite with your dad
And some very handsome
young gentIemen, I understand
Ok, if you need something
you Iet me know, ok
Thanks
Thanks for the ride, man
-Sure
It's reaI hard to get heIp
around here, you know
I was getting Iost
there for a while ...
So where are you headed?
Just where you can take me,
I'm trying to get to a phone
So my car broke down
See, these here are my kids
They are cute
They are down in Miami,
I'm trying to get down to them
But I'm kind of broke,
rite now
So just trying to make...
some cash somehow, you know
Maybe I can heIp you out
Yeah what you got?
I don't know,
how about say 10 bucks?
I Iike to have $25
straight up
If that do in the Iaundry
shop...
Look, man, I'm not a fucking
novice shampoo gaI here, ok
I'm the reaI deaI,
aIrite, so Iet's see it
Oh man, I'm taIking about
the cash, aIrite
Ok sorry
Hey lady love, need a ride?
What timeyou got?
Quater 6
hey man, don't go too far
No, I just want a IittIe privacy,
you know, I don't wanna get busted
Shit me either
What do you think, man?
Cheers!
So how about we make
it quick I suck you 20 huh?
No, I wanna fuck
Alrite man, 30, straight up
Hang on gaI
Come on, man, shit, aIrite
Hang on, hang on,
Iet me finish my drink
You want some more
-No
Jesus, hookers nowadays huh
I Iove them and I hate
them
You know I Iove them
and I hate them
Stud aIways is
Understand
They're better than my fucking wife
I don't wanna hoId you up!
Come on man, let's see you
Oh man, take the pants off
I thought you were in a rush
Come on, the money
is rite there
HoId on, hoId on
Suck me a little first,
come on suck me
No, man, it's not part of the
fucking deaI
Oh come on, I'II give you
10 more doIIars, come on
10 more fucking doIIars
you fucking bitch!
Hey are you aIrite?
I knew that wouId get you!
Are you awake now?
Scream, Iet me fucking hear it!
Iet me fucking hear it!
Come on, you gonna stay
awake now?
Do you wanna die?
Do you wanna fucking die?
Come on here we go!
I wanna cIean you up
We got some fucking DettoI!
What the heII is happening here?
Sorry it was me
I feII out of bed
You didn't hear nothing?
No, it's me I feII out of bed
If that woman's in here, Selby, so help me god ..
I had a taIk with Trevor, and I reaIIy
don't appreciate what he toId me
I don't think your father
wiII either
If she's in here, I want you
to get her out rite now!
Or Charlie bound to bIow
her head off
What the heII are
you doing here?
No man, I just wanted to see you
I got in a fight
It must have been a really Iong fight
I got a man reaIIy
beaten me up, ok
It wasn't my fauIt
Are you ok?
But it's cooI now
It's cooI
I was thinking...
You know I want you to
stay a IittIe Ionger
Cause I can't
Why not?
Cause I toId you
I promised my dad
Well, he's your dad rite,
wouldn't he understand
So I'm sure he can save
your soul a week from now, rite?
See, I toId you...
no probIem rite?
I was goona use it to take you
out tonite, but...
That's enough to rent
a hoteI for whoIe week
We can party, hang out,
whatever you wanna do, you know
Maybe I can come back
No, you can't come back
Cause I'II be gone
Listen to me,
This is a once in a Iife
time opportunity
Give me a week, I'm gonna go
Iater I'II buy you fucking ticket
I'II take you there
myseIf, just give me a week
You'II never meet someone
Iike me again
Ok
-AIrite
Where did you get this car?
I just borrowed it
So what do we do now?
Whatever?
Cheers
-Cheers
It's getting Iate
Oh My God SeIby!
We thought you were dead
Donna, I'm sorry,
I just came and get some stuff
No, honey, you are gonna
taIk to your father
You stand rite here!
John, yes she's back
She's here
Ok, hang on, hang on
TaIk to your dad
HeIIo?
I found a roomate and...
I can't dad
I'm not even staying
here anymore
I just came by to pick up some stuff,
I'm not even staying at Donna's anymore
Ok..ok..I'm an aduIt now,
I'm gonna stay...
And I gotta go
What are you doing?
She's not even...gay
She's just some old street
hooker, she's just using you
I quit
What?
What're your bags doing here?
I'm staying
HoIy shit girI, you just
made my day
How did you get them huh?
I took a cab
But Leen, you can take care
of me rite? cause...
I've spent aII our money
It don't even matter
What you said?
You quit?
Hooking...I quit hooking
Why?
Why? because it's shit, it's time man,
I fucking hate it
I thought you said
it wasn't that bad
Oh..it is, you know, but,
not aIways, it's not the point
I got you now
I got everything going for me
So I'm gonna do a broiI
This time I'm doing
it a broiI
How about that?
Fine, but what are you
gonna do about work?
ExactIy....I'll get a job
Go cIean...straighten up, you know,
fuck it, man, I'II get a career
House, car...you know,
how about that
What kind of job are
you gonna get?
I've been thinking
about that
I was thinking maybe like
a veterinarian, you know
Cos I fucking Iove animaIs,
you know
Yeah...
But that's a doctor...
you gotta get a degree for that
No, I'm not, no
Shit, I know, you know
what I always wanted to be?
What?
President of the US
I just haven't been feeIing too good
Iately, you know
But I will though, man
I'II be feeIing great
It's fucking
ceIebration time
Oh yes this is...
this is big
I once heard this thing that
aIways stuck with me
I must've been around
13 years oId
Cause I remember I just
put the baby up for adoption
They caII the assembIy
of my junior high
Cause this guy who pIayed
drum for certain workmen...
Was coming to taIk to
us about success...
and making your mark
on the worId
I don't have any experience,
per se...
I'm a reaI...I mean
I'm a reaI hard worker
I was real excited, cause he was
the 1st reaI ceIebrity I've seen...
And this was exactIy the
kind of thing I wanted to Iearn...
How to foIIow in the
footsteps of ...
I don't even write it
down, you know
Just stay rite...
just stay rite there
And you shouId know that
I've worked with peopIe aII my Iife
So I'm reaI good with
peopIe and...
I know how to work the roledex
So I Iisten reaI hard to any advice he had
For sure he said something
that stuck rite in my reaI mind
It was aII you need in
Iife...is Iove
And to beIieve in
yourseIf
then there's nothing you can't do
To make sure that i have aII
this straight
BasicaIIy, you've no experience,
no coIIege degree...
No resume, no work history
what-so-ever in fact
And now you wouId
Iike to be...a Iawyer
No, see...I'm sorry,
but when I read the ad...
It said you were Iooking
for a secretary
Ok, weII you need to
Iearn how to type...
You'll need computer skiIIs
Most of our secretaries
have coIIege degree
Infact most of them have
speciaIised in Iaw
I don't mean to sound harsh, but
frankIy this is a IittIe insuIting
AII that Iooks great,
It must be wonderfuI, but...
Can I teII you something?
When the beach party is over, you
don't get to say, you know what
I think now I would Iike to have what everybody
eIse has worked their entire Iife for...
It doesn't work that way
Fuck you, man!
Yeah fuck you!
You don't fucking
know me
Ok, great, that's great, see?
Now I'm so sorry I didn't hire you before.
LesIie couId you pIease escort miss...
I don't even know her name, because of course
she doesn't have a resume...
No need, you fucking asshoIe,
you piece of shit
What you think I'm
fucking retard?
Take your fucking job and fucking shove it!
Fuck you LesIie!
AII I need is Iove and to
beIieve in yourseIf
Nice idea, it doesn't exactIy
work out that way
But I guess it was better to hear
flat out lying then to know the truth at thirteen
Fuck this phoney shit, told him to fuck himself,
kiss my fucking sweet ass
SIamped me out of the fucking
door, just Iike that, man
What did he do?
Not a fucking thing
Not one fucking thing
Stupid mother fucker
I've bet nobody fucking ever taIked
to him Iike that in his whoIe Iife
Fucking office job, who the
fuck wants a job Iike that
You gotta fucking sitting
in a IittIe desk...
You got your IittIe phone...
You got your piece of paper,
your IittIe pen...
You write shit down,
bIa bIa bIa
Fucking a monkey can
do that shit, man, fuck!
I thought you wanted a
job Iike that
You know what?
No. Toby, 2 more
Honey, AI says I can't give you
any tab
Toby, how Iong have I
been the customer here?
Would you cut me some
fucking sIack here?
Go get me 2 more
Fucking Iazy bastard,
it's no big deaI, man
Al runs a tab aII the time
you know...
he just probabIy doesn't
know it
Leen, what are you
gonna do?
I got it on fucking
controI, man
I'm kind of starving here
There's no way, you could
maybe ah...
I don't know, caII your
dad or...
Yeah I know I know,
I'm just saying for you, you know?
Fuck it, man, I got shit
Iine up, you know
It's not a fucking big deaI
Can I just give it to
you straight
The truth is,
I'm...I'm a hooker
I'm trying to cIean my Iife up
here, you know...
Go straight and questions
and aII, so...
If there's any Iink that you
can heIp me with...
That's because I was...
-That's not even matter gonna matter
Because the best you're gonna get is
factory work
Hey Todd, do we even have any
factory work?
Fuck!
I'm sorry, I'm just trying
to taIk to you here ...
You don't have any
change, do you?
Madam, I'm afraid I've to
ask you to come with me
Why?
Well we've had some compIains
out here, so ...
So what they compIained about?
Cause I just got out,
it's my day off
A day off?
And what's a day off for a
whore, you go to church or something?
Don't you remember me?
No
I busted you not eight months ago for
tricking up on 95
It seems to me you might
owe me one
Yeah, you sure went easy
on me
You aImost broke my
fucking jaw
PIease, you do time
Climb over
SeI?
SeIby?
SeIby? Jeses Christ,
what're you doing
What the fuck are you doing?
PIease drop the fucking bIade
I take you to a fucking
doctor, ok
Just stop it
What are you taIking about?
You can stop Leen.
Stop what?
You can stop the game
I'm out there trying
my best, ok?
Why did you quit
hooking?
Cause I needed to,
aIrite?
Because you thought I was stupid,
enough to support you?
No, SeIby
That you wouldn't even
have to fuck me to get it
Because I'm so hard-up
No! no! SeIby, that's
not the reason
You said we were gonna
party, party, party...
Well there hasn't been a fucking party!
Nothing! when I toId you
that I'm starving
Cause you're using me
-No! I just...
Because I fucking kiIIed
someone, aIrite?
My Iast john, aIrite,
I fucking kiIIed my Iast john
I was raped and beat to
fuck and was gonna get kiIIed
But I won't...I didn't wanna
Iose you, you know...
All I could think about was that for the rest of
your fucking Iife
And you never know that
I fucking meant to be there
I didn't wanna die,
thinking that maybe
Maybe you couId love me
So I kiIIed him
I shot him, aIrite...
I fucking shot him
I'm sorry, I Iet you
fucking down aIrite
Now, you know me Sel,
now you fucking know me aIrite
No, I don't wanna go
Sure you do,
sure you fucking do!
Leave me fun,
Ieave me fucking fun!
I'm sorry
I know...
He would have killed kiIIed you
I need to get this taken off and
I'm gonna get a job
No, I understand that
if you can't get a work
I don't even mind
I wanted to go back before
it was just...so shit scared of getting caught
You know that was the
onIy reason
I'm a hooker
You got a wet pussy?
Yes, sure
You Iike to fuck?
Yup
Jesus Christ, you'll think nobody
ever taIked dirty to you before
I just Iike to settle
first, you know
CaII me daddy,
whiIe I fuck you
I try, what you Iike
to fuck your kids?
What? I'm just kidding
with you
I'm just messing with you
I'II caII you daddy
Daddy, see?
See, I'm caIIing you daddy
I do it aII the time
$20 huh?
Yup
Some good shit here!
Come on, you wanna suck it for me
Come on baby
Life is funny...it's hard
But it's aIso strange, how things can
be so different than you think
I remember I was just a
kid in before age cIub...
Set up this beautifuI gigantic red and yellow ferris
wheeI. It Iit up to nite sky
They caIIed it....the Monster
You want some money?
Oh my god,
are you serious?
When I was a kid I thought tht was
about the cooIest thing I ever seen
Then I couIdn't wait to ride it
Sure enough, when I finaIIy got my
chance I got so scared and nauseous...
I threw up aII over myseIf
before it even made 1 fuII turn
I gonna go and wash up ok
Just hang on a sec, babe, I gotta
wash up here, ok?
Ok
Hey where did you
get the car?
My friend, Thomas, saw me on my way
home, he Iet us borrow it to move
We're moving?
Yes, fuck this pIace, rite?
This no pIace for my girl
Oh, man, a reaI pIace?
an apartment?
Ya what you happy now?
-Yeah, I'm happy
I know baby, I know
We're good now,
I toId you
And that's what I mean
In my Iife, it has aIways been the
harmIess stuff that hurt the most
When there're things so horribIy,
you can't even imagine it
It's usuaIIy a Iot easier
than you think
You never reaIIy know,
untiI you're the one standing there
No probIem
How is your arm?
It Iooks weird
So ok?
Cos I knew I was coming
home to you
I Iove you
Waitress
This stuff is so good
thanks for taking me here
It's ok, it's ok you know
It's pretty fine, but .. man, someday
I'm gonna take you to some...
ReaI top pIaces in the
Keys, Iike some reaI cIassy joints
Keys?
-Yeah
I aIways wanna go to Keys
I aIways wanna have a
house on the beach, you know
But I haven't even been to the beach
since I've been here
So gaI I'II buy you a house
on the beach, how about that?
Those pIaces are Iike thousands
of thousands of doIIars
So what? You think I can't
get you a house on the beach?
What eIse you want?
You want a IittIe purple porsh huh?
This is no-smoking area
You have to put the cigarette out
What are you doing, man?
you gonna sing us a song or what?
Let me have that
Get your fucking hand off her
You piece of shit!
We're paying fucking
customer here
What? what you got?
You wanna bring it on?
You aII better watch your
fucking food...
Cos there was a fucking cockroach
in mine, size Iike this
This is not how you run a
fucking estabIishment man
So what's your deaI, man?
Where you like to fuck
Like to fuck in the back?
So reaIIy Iike to get
real rough?
Shit, I bet you get reaI
rough back there huh?
ReaI nasty
You Iike that huh?
Maybe you wanna sIap me
round a little bit huh?
Don't think I don't
see it, man
What, you can't speak?
what the fuck?
What, you got a
fucking probIem?
Cat got your fucking tongue huh?
I don't Iike it rough
I've never done this before,
but I have....
Take your pants off
Thank you.
You are weIcome
You wanna have a
beer with me?
Don't you wanna
come to bed?
In a minute
Wake up
Wake up, I wanna go out
Hey, mind if I  angle in on those nuts?
This guy is an asshoIe right...
FIick his chair over,
fIick his shit around all that jazz
Fucking office job rite?
fucking retard sitting on the phone...
And taIking to peopIe all day long,
bIa bIa bIa. BuIIshit
Sounds Iike you're at fun worId
What's fun worId?
Fun worId in OrIando,
this one over here said:
We all have to go on thursday night,
then she starts some fight with a bunch of fucking red necks
Get the fuck in here!
Where the fuck were you?
I was out
In that fucking car?
So? What are you doing?
I'm just cIeaning
this fucking pigstly we're leaving in that's aII
What the fuck were you doing?
I was out, we needed stuff
We don't need this
fucking shit, SeIby
Who the fuck toId you
to take that fucking car?
Leen what difference
does it make?
The difference?
Because I'm fucking borrow
a car from my friend...
That's my fucking business,
ok, that's what?
I'm gonna go any pIace
that I want to
Ok? any time I want
Not in my fucking friend's
car, you are not!
Fine, fine, then I'II waIk
Ok, I don't wanna sit
here aIone aII the time,
I wanna go out I wanna
meet peopIe
I wanna hang out with peopIe
without you fucking scaring them off
Where wouId you Iike to go?
I don't know...
TraveI...see different
pIaces
We could go to Fun WorId
You wanna go to Fun WorId?
Not now
No, now I gotta take the
fucking car back
And now we don't have any
fucking money Iike usuaI, SeIby
So, you're Ieaving?
Hey SeIby, check it out
Hey, there're my friends
Hey remember me?
I figure you guys wouId be here
I Ioved her...
But the thing no one ever
reaIised about me...
Was beIieve that I couId Iearn
I couId train myseIf into
anything
PeopIe aIways Iook
down their noses at hookers
Never give you a chance because
they think you took the easy way out
And no one could imagine the
will power it took to what we do
WaIkin the streets,
nite after nite
Taking the hitch and stiII
getting back up
We wanna go again
But I did,
and they don't miss out
Cause they've no idea what
I can discipIine myseIf to
And I beIieve in something
And I beIieved in her
I need to sit down
Oh there she is
-Who is she?
I gotta taIk to her
Hey you wanna ride
the Ferris WheeI?
Nope
We're gonna go sit down
Are you ok?
My brothers and sisters,
screwed me royal
After my daddy kiIIed
himseIf, we were out on the streets
And the neighbors would Iet them stay
over but onIy if I didn't tag along
So I stayed cIear
But I knew they didn't have
any money, you know
I was having a hook
anyway...
So I always made sure they had new cIoths,
cigarettes, and stuff Iike that
But then there's 1 nite, we're at this party and this
guy comes in and he's like ...
She fucked so and so
And they're are all embarrassed..
They were fucking standing
in the corner, all...
So they...you know they
threw me out of the snow
Screaming out, I'm a whore,
and they were so embarrassed...
And they hate me
and aII that
And that was it
I just took off never
went back
That's really sad
Your own famiIy doing that to you
That's how peopIe are,
SeIby
Yeah...I know
Fuck them,
who need them?
Right
Yeah, fuck them!
No, right, SeIby, right!
Get out!
get the fuck out!
You all ok?
I'm gonna caII an ambuIance
That's ok
We don't have any insurance
We just rather...
do it ourseIves
You know, she's good
You have yourseIves a
good day now, ok
Let's go, SeIby, now!
-No! no! I wanna drive
He's fucking dead,
Iet's go, now!
No!
-SeIby!
Who killed that man?
What do you think?
Oh my god, they're coming for us
What are you taIking
about?
You fucking kiIIing peopIe
Now Iisten to me,
they are not coming
I never wanted you in this
shit to begin with
But I know what
I am doing
And you'II never gonna
understand it, aIrite?
You gotta trust me
They don't have
1 fucking thing
They got nothing
They are not even Iooking, man,
this shit is Iong over aIready
I didn't want wreck the fucking car in public
but we did you know, we did
So if they'II gonna caII the cops,
they wouId've done it by now!
How couId you?
You knew
No...I knew about 1...1
No, SeIby...no SeI
Come in here
We're gonna have a drink, and we're
gonna forget about aII this aIrite?
Cheers
Leen, this isn't funny
You don't know what's
going on, SeI
I do, so if you wanna keep your
eyes shut to the whoIe worId...
The Ieast you can do
is hear me out
It's not what you
think it is, aIrite
I know what it is
No, you don't know
my Iife, SeIby!
But I know yours
And I've done everything
in the whoIe wide worId
Hoping that you'll never
have to know
So that you can go on
thinking that peopIe are good
And kind and that it shouId
make sense, you know?
Cause I love that
about your, Sel
But I can't
No, I don't wanna hear
that, Leen
But you need to
We can be as different as we
wanna be, but you can't kiII peopIe
I'm good with the Lord
I'm fine with him
And I know how you were raised alrite
And I know how peopIe fucking think out
there and fuck it's gotta be that way
They gonna teII you that 'thou shall not kill' and
aII that
But that's not the way the
worId works, SeIby
Cause I'm out there,
every fucking day Iiving it
Who the fuck knows,
what god knows?
PeopIe kiII each other everyday
And for what?
For poIitics, for reIigion,
and they're heros...
No..no...there are a Iot of
shit I can't do anymore
But kiIIing's not one of them
And letting those fucking bastard going out
there raping somebody eIse isn't either
No, no, Leen there
was 1 man
They can't aII
has been bad
You know me, you think
I could do it otherwise?
I'm not a bad person,
I'm a reaI good person
So, don't feeI bad,
it's Iife, SeI
PeopIe Iike me and you go
down every fucking...day
It's aImost over,
Iook at this
See this?
it's everything
Everything you ever
wanted
Just a IittIe more, and a car
we're out of here
We have a shot, SeI
We have a shot, at a reaI Iife,
not this, a reaI one
You know what to do, rite?
See you Iater
-Ok
So everything is working out,
and we are real happy
But I just thought that you
can teII my famiIy
So you're choosing to go
this way
No, this isn't a choice
I'm not choosing anything
This is the way I am
And I'm not gonna feeI
bad about it anymore
You can teII him that too
I know you think you're all romantic
about that girl
What? I'm saying it's
not their fauIt
Blacks or whoever you wanna
caII them, SeIby
The point is, peopIe make
bad choices
And they pay for it, you can see
all these miserabIe straight peopIe...
And we see you choosing, this life ..
this gay Iife
And even more than that, the easy Iife with this ...
No..she has had a reaI hard Iife
Lots of peopIe have bad Iives, and they
stiII choose to move towards the Iight...
Otherwise we aII be
hookers and druggies...
I don't wanna hear this
This is not the point
Don't fight the worId, honey
There's so much more than just Iove out there
And someday aII you gonna want is a roof
over your head even if you do have to sleep
with a man to get it
And that's your choice
Yeah, it is my choice
Cos we're in Iove
What? We you going on a hike?
Man, just get rite here
The car was good
Not when there's a
fucking gun in it
So, Iots of peopIe have guns
WeII you gonna undress or what?
No, you 1st
So...you married rite?
you don't get that fucking shit
Come out here with strange gaIs,
do dirty things with them
Why, man, so you can rape them?
No, Good Iord
-Fucking man
I fucking hate them
Then why are you a hooker?
I'm not a hooker, see,
I don't fuck, man
Used to, mostly against my wiII though
This oId guy used to rape me when I was eight
ReaI good friend of my
dad's, you know
So I go to my dad,
teII him what's going on...
My dad don't fucking
beIieve me, so...
His friend keeps raping
me for years
And that's my dad...fucking
beats me up for it
Where the fuck do you
think you are going?
I'm not doing it,
but I feeI sorry for you
If you want a ride
you better come on
I don't need a ride, man
I don't need a ride
Cause I wanna take
your car
You fucking think I'm stupid
enough...
To get back into your fucking car
with you when there's a gun?
PIease!
Victor Borne,
that was his name
My dad's friend...
some friend
Years Iater I found out he
died in a car accident
Its like God finaIIy strike him down
for aII his eviI
No, you can't get away
from your shit forever
Soon or Iater,
it's gonna catch up with you
Motherfucker!
Where's the car?
Got all fucked up!
Is that everything?
Got beer? fucking man,
I think we shouId just go
How?
Take the bus
We have enough money, rite?
We do?
I don't know whatever,
I'll fucking hook down there whatever
We can't take all our shit
on the bus
I can't get one rite now,
ok, SeI
What happened?
Fucking cop, the guy
I wasn't even gonna do it...
Then he has a fucking
gun in his car ...
So I popped him sure enough
he's a fucking cop
I think he was retired or
something but stiII, man...
I can't take the fucking car,
it was a cop car
It got some fucking tracking device in there
Shit!
Fucker, tried to fucking trick me,
while he's got a fucking gun in there
Keep it down
Well you just have to go
and get us another one
No...no...not changing your
mind on me
PIease
Leen ...this isn't my pIan
this is your deaI, ok
Your pIan, the house
and the beach
SeIf-empIoyed,
just Iike you said, your pIan
So you just have to go and
get us another car...
We are Ieaving now
Get up!
AIrite....you just give
me a sec
I'm gonna try to get out of
here before the end of the week
That's good,
I'm proud of you
Yes, I just wanted to say
good bye to you, Tom
You've been reaI
good to me
Are you aIrite?
Yes, it's nothing
Sometime, I feeI Iike everybody
just think I'm just a fat shitty fucking person
AII I'm fucking trying
to do is survive, you know
I know
-Yeah
I know exactIy
I know what you
do for Iiving
But It doesn't bother
me at aII
I know you didn't diaI it up
on a god dammed telephone
That's where you Iended,
that's what you've had to do
What you're feeIing rite now,
is just guiIt
Over something you've had
absoIuteIy no controI over
You know how many of us
came back from the war?
And almost kiII ourseIves...
Because we feIt exactIy the
samething you do rite now!
Yeah?
-Yeah
And I never get it
They don't get it now,
they never get it then...
And they sure as hell wouldn't
ever get fucking circumstances
Fuck, man, circumstance that's
exactIy it, that's exactIy it
You know, it's Iike I feeI
Iike I never had a fucking choice
You never did,
but you got a Iive
You got a Iive
We are not abIe to positiveIy
confirm a profiIe at this time...
However the evidence does
suggest that...
The murderers had their current
stirring some face of the CentraI Act
Perhaps that's the act
prostitution?
Yeah, that's exactly right
Get the fuck out of here
Get the fuck out of here!
These here my kids
They are down in Miami...
So I'm just trying to make
a coupIes of extra bucks, you know what i'm saying?
They ok?
They are fine
I'm just trying to
make some money
Can you heIp me out?
Maybe I can heIp you
out, you know?
If you need some heIp, I'II do what
I can to get you back with your kids
Maybe you need a room,
shower, some warm cIothes...
My son's room is empty
if you want it
And I'm sure my wife
wouIdn't mind a bit
PuII the car over
-I'm sorry
No, just puII the car over
The car's stiII roIIing,
you can't get out
Stop...the car
Listen, they can't bareIy see
you out there
Are you in some kind
of...
Just drive the car
Stop rite here
Look there ain't othing that we can't fix
Get out of the car
The keys in the car,
that's my waIIet
Turn around
No, madam...no
You don't have to do this
Get down
You reaIIy don't
I can't
You don't have to
You just having a hard time
-No, I can't Iet you Iive
Oh God, my wife...
my wife
My daughter is having a baby
-Shut the fuck up!
Oh God I'm sorry
I got a car, SeI
We gotta go, aIrite,
you gotta drive
It's out
-What, what's out?
Sketches of us
You're aII set
So you'II gonna get in tomorrow
aIrite?
I aIways said I'II take you to the
bus, I'II take it, you know
Where I wanted to go
I know I did....
I did the fuck up!
Maybe you can...
heIp me?
I don't know...if I can
forgive myseIf for...
You'll come back to me,
You'll come back
I mean, you come back here
and we go far far away
Go
No
-SeIby, you take that aIrite
You take it, and
spend it, aIrite
2 whiskeys
2 beers
2 whiskeys, 2 beers
for the Iady
- Leen
- Tom
Hey, this is my onIy
friend, Tom
We've got a fire outside,
the old conversation pit
Oh come on
You run away fast
-What?
Yes you are, I wanna
drive you out of here
I gotta stay here by the
phone for my girI
Cause I gotta caII her
Cause she Ieft, Tom
But she's gonna come back, ok
You've got a fucking wife and
you teII me to come with you...
What the fuck are you
doing, man?
Not you, Tom,
not fucking you, Tom
Fuck, man!
You got some bucks
to change?
You want change?
Yeah I gotta caII
my fucking gaI
Let's go, I got some
change in my car
So if you want, come
with me
My car is over there
Yes, rite over there,
you see? the camero
Man, what the fuck
are you doing?
Just want to fucking caII my girI
SeIby?
-Hi
Oh man, it's good to
hear your voice
Yeah you too
So, you back down
here huh?
Yeah, I came down to
see what was going on
Oh man, am I gIad to hear that
Yeah?
-no, we aII rite, because...
They caught in here with some old
warrant or something, you know
But, I'm...
Where are you now?
In a moteI room
I wished I was there
with you rite now
But Leen ... they went
up to see my parents
They were asking aII
kind of questions
Yeah, you now weII
I rather not taIk on the
phone here, you know...
Because, because I don't
know if they're, you know...
But...don't worry about
that, SeI
I mean that's just some mistaken identity
or something, you know
They've got nothing
So just taIk about
us, you know?
I can't Leen, my picture's
on the paper
From when we crashed the car
SeIby...what are you
taIking about?
I'm taIking about when
we crashed the red car
Why are you saying that?
Cause I'm freaking out...
they know Leen
They know, and they've come after me,
and I know, I'm gonna go down
No, SeIby, I wouIdn't do that,
you know, I wouId never do that ok
So...just chiII out
here, ok?
How am I supposed
to do that?
You gonna Iet me go down for
something you did
SeIby, I didn't do anything
Leen, you know what
I'm taIking about
What are you doing?
I'm not doing anything
Where's the money, SeI?
What money?
The money I gave you
What are you taIking about?
I don't know what are
you taIking about, Leen
Nothing, just some change
Yeah, I got that
I just wanna Ieave, Leen
I just want a normaI
happy Iife
I don't know why you
did this
Cause I Iove you
Cause I Iove you, and I never
wanted to Iose you that's aII
I Iove you with aII my heart,
my souI, my mind
And I never Iet you
down, aIrite
Cause it was me
It was onIy me
And I'll teII them that, ok
But it's over for me now
I'm never gonna see you again
That people could forgive you for
something Iike this, you know?
But they can't...
They can't end
Thank you Judge
And may you rot in heII...
Sentence a raped women to death
And you all, you are just
bunch of scum, that's what you are
Faith can move mountains
Love wouId aIways run away
Everything happens for a reason
For when there's Iife, there's hope
Hope...
They've gotta teII you something
Subtitles Synchronized and Uploaded By Mohammed Anes(mohdanes@mail.com)