I
What are you doing?
Not up here.
Get back down there.
Jesus. Morons.
Hey, do you think
you could speed it up?
I got another load of sheets
coming from county hospital...
in one hour.
You! I'm talking to you!
You, come on!
Jesus.
Hey, move it! Move it!
Yes, sir.
Good morning,
Mrs. Frawley.
Good morning, dear.
You're looking good
today, Sherry.
Hi.
Good morning.
You ought to watch
yourself, dear.
Let me help you
with that.
Take care
of number one.
Don't let the
pressure get to you.
What do you think
about the new girl?
Lin Sue?
Oh, she's OK.
If you're
not careful...
you'll end up
like me.
I'll keep that
in mind.
I wonder where
the boss found her.
I wish she'd go back to whatever
sewer she crawled out of.
Let's get that
second boiler working.
Do you understand me?
Watch that pressure gauge!
What are you doing?
I'm fixing the boiler!
Coming through!
Back off now.
We're coming through.
Steady now.
You better tighten
the belts.
What?
The belts--tighten
them with clamps...
so we can get
a bigger load in.
Now, steady.
Come on.
We're way behind.
Ow!
What are you doing?
Watch out!
- Aah!
Aah!
Stanner!
Sherry!
Sir! Yes, sir!
Ow!
Holy shit,
what was that about?
Goddamn sons of bitches.
These two idiots
almost killed Sherry.
Damn it!
Jeez, I'm sorry.
Are you OK?
Moron! You could have
killed her!
It's nothing. I'm OK.
Sherry.
You may need stitches.
No. I'm OK now.
Mr. Gartley, sir.
Do something.
Get 'em back to work!
Work 'em like
there's no tomorrow.
You boys with that
piece-of-shit icebox...
get it out of here! Move!
Deliver on time,
or you'll lose our business.
Move it!
Stanner, time's a-wasting.
Tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick.
Ha ha ha!
It's all right,
George.
You know,
life's a bitch...
then you die.
Get 'em back to work.
Yes, sir.
We're behind schedule
as it is, goddamn it.
Yes, s--
I got deadlines,
George.
Never enough time
around here--never.
You heard the man!
Let's go! Move it!
Don't look at me!
You, get back to work.
Come on, get back to work.
Get back to work.
Come on,
work with me, ladies.
I
Good morning.
Good morning,
officer.
- How are you?
- Have a nice day.
Shit...shit...shit.
Got the address?
It's 1216 Lake...
or is it 1218?
It's over there.
Oh, fuck!
What did I miss?
Shit!
Hey!
Idiot, what was that?
Hey, what was that?
Hey, idiot,
I'm talking to you.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
No, I'm talking
to the other idiot.
What was that? What?
Can't you drive?
Move the truck.
Sir, we're just
delivering an icebox.
I don't give a fuck...
if you're delivering
a pizza to the Pope.
Move the fucking truck.
You looking
for trouble, asshole?
That's Officer Asshole
to you.
Move the truck...
and then we'll
talk, OK?
OK.
Sorry about
your hand, Sherry.
Boss, you're not kidding.
This icebox is hot.
All right, Mr. Gates,
it's time to talk.
It seems that your driver's
license has expired.
Watch out!
Shit! Uh!
Oh, I'm really
sorry, officer.
Jesus!
Get this goddamn thing
off of me!
Shit!
Numb nuts! Jesus!
Ow!
Are you OK?
Frawley! There's no time
for daydreaming.
I've got another load
coming in.
Now, both of you,
back to work!
Ow!
Bring the ratchet.
Oh!
Aah!
Oh, God!
Aah! Oh, God! Help me!
Help me, please!
My God!
Please, help!
No!
Aah!
Hell's bells, Adelle!
Shut it off! Aah!
I don't know how!
Aah!
It won't shut off!
Shut it off!
Aah!
It won't shut off!
No!
Aah!
Goddamn!
Uh! Uh!
Get back!
Mrs. Frawley!
Oh, my God!
Jesus! Oh, God!
Aah!
Out of my way!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh, Frawley!
You stupid old bitch!
Always getting in the way.
Goddamn it! Goddamn it!
Goddamn it!
Now, what's that for?
Reckless driving...
illegal parking...
blocking of
a public street.
Come on, pal.
Give me a break.
What do you want?
Insulting an officer...
or being an arrogant,
ignorant son of a bitch?
Since when
is that a crime?
Help me, boss!
Aw, you broke
my damn watch.
I'm all pooped out.
Officer Hunton, come in.
Damn it.
You're a moron.
Officer Hunton,
come in.
Officer Hunton.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, Molly,
what have you got?
Good morning, Johnny.
How's your day so far?
Oh, my day's peachy,
Molly. What's up?
We've got a death
at the Blue Ribbon Laundry.
It's a bad one.
Sheriff Hughes got called away
to an urgent meeting.
I need some help.
What's going on, and how many
did you take this time?
Right side up. Come on.
All right, Molly, I'm on
the way. Thanks a lot.
Oh, my God!
No!
Sherry, it's OK.
Get away from me!
Her worries are over.
Holy shit.
Hello.
Is Mr. Gartley here?
Mr. Gartley
is unavailable.
I'm Stanner.
I'm the foreman.
Mr. Stanner...
I'm, uh--
I'm Officer Hunton.
Can you show me...
what happened,
Mr. Stanner?
Do I have to?
Yeah, you have to.
She's down there.
I--I can't look at it again.
It makes me sick.
She's down there. I can't.
I'm sorry. I can't look at it.
Yeah, right,
you can't look.
Run a loose shop,
cut corners--
what do you expect?
People get hurt
or killed, right?
And then he can't look.
No, he can't look at it.
Oh.
Hell of a mess,
huh, Johnny?
You know,
me and my old camera...
were doing this...
long before you even
came to this town.
Never did
get used to it.
Yeah, right.
Oh.
Um...pictureman...
make sure I get
some copies of that.
Like always.
Have I ever
let you down?
Yes.
Oh...shit.
I feel like
it's all my fault.
I just wasn't
strong enough.
I tried to help her.
I tried to pull
her free.
OK, it's all right.
It's all right.
Excuse me.
It's OK.
Ex--excuse me.
I know how you feel.
Have you seen
that machine?
It makes me
sick to my stomach.
These will help.
Mrs. Frawley
used to take 'em.
Oh, keep the bottle.
Thank you.
Annette Gillian.
Uh, John Hunton.
How do you do?
Hi.
Oh, poor Mrs. Frawley.
Oh, God!
Hey, what's going on?
Nothing, Johnny.
We're here to settle
a safety issue.
What's the emergency,
anyway?
There's been
a slight accident...
with a speed ironer.
Let's go in.
If the safety features
on this machine...
meet state
and local standards...
then you may resume
operation.
Yes, thank you,
Judge Bishop.
OK, Martin,
start her up.
Stand clear, boys.
Let's start
with the safety bar.
When I lift this up...
the machine
should stop. Uhh!
Put it down,
it should start.
What is your conclusion,
Mr. Martin?
Well, I'll tell you,
Judge Bishop...
the safety bar seems to
be working fine.
Then I declare...
that this was a case
of accidental death.
This inquest is closed.
I know what you
think of my work.
Look, there's no such thing as
empirical truth...
in theoretical
parapsychology.
If you saw seraphims
and cherubims...
falling out of the sky,
singing HallElujah...
you wouldn't believe it.
You want proof,
right?
Oh, you'll
never change.
You haven't
eaten much.
What? You're not
feeling well?
There was
an accident today--
the worst one
I've ever seen.
Messy?
So how long
is it now...
you've been chasing
corpses?
14 years.
Oh, man, 14 years.
You know,
you need to spend...
some more time
with the living.
Ha ha ha!
Jesus, you sound
just like Sandy.
Sandra
really loved you.
Whatever.
Uh, I just--I just
got to hang in there...
and get my 20 years in
so I can retire...
and get the fuck
out of this town...
before I turn
completely numb.
Yeah, well, uh,
you know, Johnny...
you really do
need to get a life.
I got a life.
What I need
is a beer.
Come over if you want.
I don't suppose...
you know anything about
industrial laundries?
You know, I used to work in an
industrial laundry...
when I was an
undergraduate at Berkeley.
Get out of here.
I did, man.
Really?
Yeah, sure.
Well, look, do you know
that machine...
they call
the speed ironer?
Oh, man, yeah.
It's called a mangle.
A mangler?
Mangle.
That's the one.
It mangled a woman
this morning...
Oh!
Over at Mr. Gartley's
Blue Ribbon Laundry.
It...
There was hardly
anything left of her.
No way. No way, man.
That can't happen.
You've got
a safety bar.
If someone's feeding
the machine...
and get their hand
underneath...
the bar snaps up...
and turns the damn
thing off.
Right.
Well, that's
how I remember it.
Yeah, it's got
a safety bar...
but it happened anyhow.
Oh, God. Man,
what a way to go.
I hated
that machine.
Oh, fuck me!
I can't do this!
Well, it is
what it is, right?
Johnny, don't.
I mean, you can't--
What? A woman's dead, Mark.
It folded her like a sheet.
They carried her out
in a basket.
Whose ass
is on the line?
Nobody's ass
is on the line.
Gartley owns Judge Bishop.
Judge Bishop
owns the sheriff.
I mean, it's all dirty.
It's all dirty.
Yeah, but why are you
fighting it, man?
I mean, wake up.
I've been in this town
long enough to know...
that there's some
strange shit going on.
It's always been
narrow-minded...
and corrupt.
Hell, they used to
burn witches...
just 10 miles from here.
This puritanical ethic
is still hanging over--
Look, don't start
with the sprout-breath...
political mystical
bullshit, Mark.
I'm not in the mood
this evening. Thank you.
The woman's dead...
and that machine
is running right now...
all right, like nothing
happened--business as usual--
6 miles from here--
6 miles.
Oh, whatever.
Now, what the hell
are you...
supposed to do
about it, huh?
Have a beer.
That's what I'll do.
You're what?
You're gonna take
the sins of the world...
on your shoulders?
It's your fault?
I mean, you have to
live a little.
You can't just
take everything in.
Yeah, you're right.
Come on.
Just live a little.
You're my brother-in-law,
I love you, man.
You're going to get a
goddamn nervous breakdown.
Alright.
I'm worried
about you.
You want some yogurt?
I got some yogurt.
Is it whole-wheat?
Granola? I got granola.
Yeah, is it organic?
No.
I
Are you OK?
I wish I could
go home.
- Aah!
Aah!
Move away!
Move away from there!
Do something!
- Aah!
Shut that damn thing off!
Inside.
Help!
I'm sorry.
Chaos abounds,
my dear.
You'd better
get used to it.
Like I told you,
there's no free lunch...
no sirree, Bob, not in
this lifetime. Uh-uh.
Ha ha!
Still, life must be better here
than on the streets, hmm?
Here, the predators
are few.
The benefits are many, hmm?
Hmm? Mmm.
For I am a generous man.
I...am a man
of my word.
Now, then...
why don't you
go in there...
and freshen up for
your Uncle Billy?
Go on now. Draw
your bath. Skedaddle.
OK.
Shoo.
Shoo. Shoo fly.
Would you like to come in here
and keep me company?
Uh!
Lin Sue, Lin Sue...
you sweet...
young woman.
I'll tell you...
the one thing worse
than the devil within...
is the devil
without.
Save my seat.
Hello.
Yeah.
What?
What? What is it?
There's been another
accident at the laundry.
A steam hose broke loose
on that machine...
burned three women.
One of them
is at the hospital.
Shit.
Hey, can I come with?
Hey, Pascal...
how you liking
public service?
Oh, you know.
Can you tell me
what room...
Annette Gillian
is in, please?
Room 132.
Thank you.
Annette!
Remember me?
I'm Officer Hunton.
Oh, I thought
you were the doctor.
Well, go get
a goddamn doctor!
Wh-where is he?
Where's the doctor?
Oh, God!
What took you
so long?
That's it. Take it
easy, Annette.
Take it easy.
Annette, Annette,
take it easy.
This is going to take
the pain away, huh?
No pain allowed
in this hospital.
There we go.
There.
That's it.
Ooh.
What do you want?
- Ooh.
- I'm Officer Hunton.
I'm here to ask Annette
about the accident.
I don't think
she's up to it.
I don't think I want
a second opinion.
Annette, what happened?
We was running sheets...
and the ironer
just blew up.
Mr. Stanner said
there must have been...
a surge from the boiler
or something.
I don't know.
Has anything like this
ever happened before?
It all started
happening when Sherry...
cut her hand on
one of the clamps.
On the mangler?
Yeah.
Was there blood?
Well, I mean, did she
bleed on the mangler?
There was blood
everywhere...
and then later...
Mrs. Frawley...
I think she's had enough.
She needs some rest.
Annette,
thank you very much.
Sherry Ouelette--
Mr. Gartley's niece...
just out of
high school.
Mr. Gartley watches
her like a hawk--
has all her life.
Won't let her have
any boyfriends...
or go on dates.
You know, it's almost
like that machine...
had tasted blood
and found it liked it.
Don't women get funny
ideas sometimes?
Thank you very much,
Annette.
You'll be fine.
Bye-bye. Thanks.
Come on.
Annette, I just
wanted to ask--
Mark...
come.
Safety inspector
barely had time...
to check the machine.
They railroaded that
inquest through.
Said, "Everything's OK.
Put those kids
back to work."
And then, kapoom--
three women burned...
one kid's disfigured
for life.
Now, that's against
the law in my book.
So, what do you
think? Mark?
What?
What's going on...
in that jelly-roll
head of yours?
Nothing.
Right. That would
be a first.
Barry!
Was that
Mrs. Ellenshaw?
Yeah.
Take it easy, man.
Right. You, too.
Hey, man...
why don't you
come on over?
There's something
important...
I want to show you.
Six-pack of beer?
No. Come on.
Are you hungry?
No. I'm going
to bed.
No, come on. It's really
important. Come on.
Ah, what the fuck.
Cold beer, huh? Is that
all I'm good for?
You really know
how to hurt a guy.
That's no way to treat
your brother-in-law...
but I suppose
you'd follow me...
to the ends of the earth
if I asked.
That's right, man.
I'd follow you to the ends
of the earth, man.
Come.
Where?
Frazer's GoldEn Bough--
check it out. You
might learn something.
"Frazer's GoldEn Bough--
"The definitive work
on magic...
and the occult."
Check it out.
Have you considered
the possibility...
that the machine
may be haunted?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yes, Mark. Yes.
That's the first thing
that popped into my mind.
No. Play along with me.
Maybe "haunted"
is not a good word.
Let's say "possessed."
Possessed?
Yeah. Yeah, man.
Possessed.
Possessed?
Yeah! Possessed.
By the parrot demon,
right?
OK, OK.
I'll tell you what
we're going to do, Mark.
We're going to grab
that bad boy by the throat...
shove a couple cloves
of garlic up his butt...
and that will be
the end of it, right?
- [Chuckles]
- Man, this stuff is for real.
I'm serious about this.
I mean, check it out.
This stuff is for real.
Look, if you just
look in here...
I mean, everything
is pointing--
Mark...check it out.
First there is God...
then there's country,
and then there's the law.
All right?
The rest is bullshit.
OK?
This is bullshit, Mark.
Reality, bullshit.
Bullshit, reality.
This is bullshit.
Aah! Help!
Whoa! I got you.
I got you.
Aah!
It's OK.
It's OK. Shh.
It's all right.
You'll be OK.
Bring her up here, George.
But, Mr. Gartley,
she's hurt, sir.
Mr. Gartley,
she needs a doctor.
She needs help.
My finger!
Bring her to me.
All spells
can be reduced...
to simple
common denominators.
European spells...
mention the hand
of glory...
and that's
real trouble.
Look, spells need
a catalyst--
either herbal
or human or both.
The answer
is in that book.
Just go for it!
- Uh-huh.
- Carry on. Come on. Come on.
Read on, man.
Uhh, belladonna,
hand of glory...
blood of a virgin!
Ha ha ha!
Now, that's supernatural.
Supernatural is a really
misleading word, man.
Witches, demons,
spirits--
all part of nature.
Like, um...OK, well...
a demon is a kind of energy like
electricity...
or fire.
Sometimes it gets
out of control...
and people get hurt.
Thought you might
want something to eat.
Thank you.
The most powerful spells...
always incorporate
belladonna.
What is
belladonna?
The hand of glory,
or deadly nightshade.
The plant?
Yeah. And the most
common ingredient...
in all these spells...
is, uh, the blood
of a virgin.
You must admit...
the way Annette
describes Sherry...
she sounds the type.
Oh, come on.
Come on.
Go with the flow.
Think of
the possibilities.
- Could be fun, huh?
- Yeah, uh.
All right.
Hey, Mark,
tell you what.
I'll run
right on over...
to Sherry Ouelette's
house, OK?
Knock on the door.
"Sherry? Hi.
"My name is
Officer John Hunton.
"I'm with the police
department here...
"and I am
investigating...
"a laundry machine...
"with a bad case
of demon possession...
"and I need
to examine you...
"to determine...
whether or not
you're a virgin."
Right?
Mmm...mm-hmm.
Huh?
Mark, I could
just see my report.
They would
tar and feather me...
and run me out of
this town on a rail.
You think so?
Ha ha ha!
That sounds like...
a whole lot of fun
to me.
Oh, yeah!
Oh, boy!
Why don't we just go over
there and talk to her?
Do it for me.
Come on.
Johnny?
Johnny, I got
that info for you.
Yeah, Molly,
go ahead.
Let's see.
Sherry Ouelette--
parents died
in a car accident...
on 7-10-83.
William Gartley
is her legal guardian.
Is that it?
Yeah. Who's picking up
the tab...
for my overtime?
Take it out
of my pension.
You're the best,
Molly.
You got that right.
Oh, man.
So who's going to
pop the ques--
You don't
say a word.
Right? Not a word.
Far out.
Gothic.
Who is it?
Sherry? Hi. It's
Officer John Hunton...
from the police
department.
- Hi. Remember me?
- Hello.
Mm-hmm.
I'm here to ask you
some questions...
about the accidents that
have been happening...
at the Blue Ribbon
Laundry.
Are you
a policeman, too?
No. I'm
a theoretical--
Um, this is
Mark Jackson.
He's a student...
an observer.
Then I guess
it's all right.
Thank you.
It won't take long.
I
Is your uncle here?
I'm alone.
Oh, hey,
look at those.
They're beautiful.
Look at that
little face!
Are they yours?
No, they're not
really mine.
My uncle says
they'll be mine someday.
Um...
Sherry, I'm really
sorry to disturb you...
at a time like this.
I just have
a few questions. OK?
OK.
It's OK?
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Now, Annette said that
you cut your hand...
on a clamp.
How did that happen?
Getting out
of the way...
of that icebox.
These two guys
lost control.
I guess it...
it hit the feed belt.
On the mangler?
Yeah.
Then it bounced off
and almost hit me.
Did this icebox
hit the safety bar?
I think it did.
There were bright
sparks everywhere.
What, sparks like
a wire had been cut?
I saw a big flash...
like lightning
or something.
That's it, then.
There it is.
I really loved
Mrs. Frawley.
Shh.
She was like
a mother to me.
I tried to help her.
I pulled as hard
as I could...
but I was too weak.
It's OK.
Hey, Sherry, Sherry.
Sherry. Sherry...
you're a very
brave young woman.
OK?
Sherry, I just want--
Mark!
The icebox
hit the safety bar.
That's it.
Thank you very much.
Bye-bye. It was
a short circuit.
That's all
there is to it.
Let's go.
Mark! Mark!
Sherry,
are you a virgin?
Excuse me?
What is this?
Just get out!
Just get the hell out!
What did I tell you?
I'm right!
I'm right.
She's definitely
a virgin.
Jesus Christ!
I can't believe
you did that--
What? Talk to
a little girl like that.
God! Have fun?
Shit, I hope
you had fun.
It's not a question of fun.
I know I'm right.
Shut up, goddamn it.
No more about virgins,
alright.
I'm right.
What are you--some
kind of pervert?
Doesn't matter
whether I'm a pervert...
What is this?
Oh, Christ.
What the hell is going on
at Mrs. Smith's house?
I don't know.
Whatever it is...
you stay the hell
out of it, alright.
There he is!
Stop him!
Mark! Mark!
Stay in the car.
All right.
You stay in the car!
All right!
Hey, Steele...
what is this?
Hi, Johnny.
It's really bad.
The boy's suffocated.
It's Barry Ellenshaw.
Been missing all day.
Mrs. Smith just learned
10 minutes ago.
I found that icebox...
when I got here
this morning.
He never got
in any trouble.
He'd no more play...
in a refrigerator
than...
All right.
The boy's dog was barking
outside the icebox.
That's why
I had a look inside.
Oh, Barry.
Suffocated, poor kid.
He's been missing
since 11:00 this morning.
Come on, honey.
Rest in peace, Barry.
Barry Ellenshaw--
oh, man.
Poor kid.
Hell of a shame,
huh, Johnny?
Get him out of here.
Stand back there.
Stand back.
No! No!
No! No,
Maryanne. No!
Barry!
Stop! Oh, my baby!
Stay there.
No!
Barry!
It's not my fault.
I had nothing
to do with it.
It was here when
I came home from work.
What? It's not yours?
No. I don't know
where it came from.
Hey, Johnny...
come have a look
at this.
Wait a minute.
What? This is
the son of a bitch...
that almost hit Sherry?
After it hit
the mangler.
Transference.
It's transference
of evil.
Oh, bullshit.
Evil. Bullshit.
Easy.
What?
Shit.
It's all right.
It's all right,
little baby.
It's all right, baby.
Come on.
Aah!
Jeez!
Let go!
Aah! Aah!
Are you all right?
Yeah. I think so.
Oh, shit.
Jesus H. Christ.
A hammer--
you got a hammer?
It's in the garage.
Ow!
Miserable piece
of dogfuck!
Goddamn you!
Oh, oh, God.
God!
Jesus Christ!
Lend not thy sight
to idols...
nor make gods
of thyself!
Nice work, Johnny.
I always knew
you had it in you.
Where did you learn
to do magic tricks?
That was the first ghost
I have ever seen.
Thank you, my boy.
Just when you thought
you'd seen it all...
life bites you in the ass.
See you later, Johnny.
I'll be waiting for you.
What the fuck
was that?
Jesus Christ.
Get that thing
out of my sight!
And burn it...
then bury it.
Drive a fucking stake
through its heart.
I
So, what do you
think now, hmm?
Do you know
any priests?
No, man. Do you?
No. I knew
a rabbi one time.
They'd think we're nuts.
We are nuts.
It's our play, Johnny.
It's up to us.
Why don't we just
get some dynamite...
and blow the shit
out of the pig?
Brute force isn't
the answer, man.
I mean, a demon
may be trapped...
in that piece
of machinery.
There's a chance
it could get out.
It would love to get out
and love to kill.
Oh, good. Good.
Virgin blood.
That's the key.
It's got to be.
The trouble is,
there's many...
different kinds
of demons.
I mean, I don't know what
we're dealing with here.
It could be in the
cycle of Bubastis...
Pan, Dionysius.
You following me?
No...but go on.
I have to isolate
the exact cause.
We have to make sure...
that we use
the right ritual...
because the rites
of exorcism--
I don't know
if you understand...
but the rites
of exorcism...
that's really heavy stuff.
That's like controlled
nuclear fission, in a way.
I mean, we make one mistake,
that's it. We're dead.
We're destroyed.
I mean, if you ask
me, this is...
just an act of
random possession.
It's got to be.
Hey, Mark.
I got to do
some thinking.
Oh, Johnny...
listen, man,
don't worry, OK?
I'm with you 100%,
man, OK?
All right, Mark.
That's a relief, man.
100%.
That's real reassuring.
Belladonna,
demonic possessions...
Oh, I'm having fun.
Hey! I'm with you, man.
There are stranger things
in heaven and earth...
John Hunton, than are
dreamt of in your philosophy.
Ha ha ha!
Hey, Johnny,
what do you know?
Not much, Charlie.
Just going to the morgue.
Whew. Not much.
Barry, Barry, Barry,
it's been a hell of a day.
Fix you up
in the morning.
He's a brave kid.
He put up
a hell of a fight.
Broke his arm
in six places.
It was suffocation, right?
Mr. Hunton...
we've been expecting you.
You've come to see
Mrs. Frawley.
Yep.
She was a real challenge.
I had practically
nothing to go on.
Hardly recognized the parts--
the ones that came in.
You look at her now.
I think I did
a pretty damn good job...
considering
the raw materials...
I had to work with.
Can you keep a secret?
I had to fill up
her body with--
I hate secrets.
OK.
- OK?
- Yeah.
- You need to be alone.
- Right.
You've come to do
some thinking.
Thank you.
I'll be in my office.
OK. I'll call you
if I need anything.
She's headed to the
cemetery in the morning.
Until then,
she's all yours.
Good. Thank you.
Oh, her personal
possessions?
- They're right here.
- Great.
That's all
they brought in.
Thanks.
Cherry tomato?
No, thank you.
Thank you. Bye-bye, now.
Oh, Jesus.
I
You won't mind,
will you?
Jesus, I got to
get a life.
Boo! Gotcha!
Very funny.
She looks...pretty good,
don't she?
Oh, yeah.
She looks great.
Johnny. Johnny!
Do you want to
come downstairs...
and finish off
that gin game...
we started
three years ago?
I've still got a drop
of that old Irish whiskey.
You know,
I get the feeling...
you don't like me anymore.
No.
It's my job I don't
like anymore.
Oh.
Well, it doesn't
matter much anyway.
You won't have to look
at my ugly mug...
around here much longer.
Why?
Don't tell me...
you're moving out
of this hellhole?
Oh, something
like that.
The doc says
I'm going fast.
I'm being
eaten up...inside.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Ah, don't be.
We all have to
go sometime.
Johnny, you and I--
we share the same ghosts.
To forgive is divine...
especially if you can
forgive yourself.
Oh, did you get pictures
of that icebox?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm off down
to the darkroom now.
What was that?
What?
That ghost.
We live in strange
times, Johnny--
very strange times.
I'll have the photos
ready later tonight.
Come on by.
I'll be
waiting for you.
You know,
I'm 50 points up...
on you in that game.
I've got an ace
up my sleeve...
I'm dying to play.
You know
where to find me.
You don't want
to lose...
to an old hack like me.
Shit.
Fuck.
God! God! God!
God!
What are you doing?
Where the hell
is Gartley?
He's out of town.
Yeah, right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Come back here!
Hey, stop!
Goddamn it,
he's out of town!
Get your hands off
of me...
you lying sack of shit.
You want to go downtown?
Boys! Boys! Boys! Boys!
All right. Knock it off.
Get out, George.
I'll deal with you later.
Come in, Mr. Hunton.
I've been expecting you.
So sorry I missed you earlier.
You know, Stanner tells me
you're quite the detective.
A regular Sherlock Holmes
of the dead, hmm?
Why don't you
shut that thing down...
before somebody else
gets hurt?
What, am I
going to have to...
shut you down?
Tsk tsk tsk. I wouldn't
do that if I were you.
Mmm. Bad career move.
Are you threatening me?
Is that a threat?
Go on, threaten me.
I'll shove
them crutches...
up your moldy ass,
you fucking clown.
Ha ha ha!
I like that. Threaten?
Uh-huh.
No, no, no. Threaten
is far too...kind a word.
This goddamn machine
tried to kill me!
Aah!
Breaking and entering
is a serious crime, of?cEr.
Perhaps I should have
you arrested, hmm?
Yeah. OK.
Ok. Hey. Yeah.
Have me arrested.
I'm going to shut
you down...
you sick son of a bitch.
I will not have you
tamper with my affairs.
I'll have you suspended!
Hey, all your
powerful friends...
and all your money...
don't mean shit
to me, Gartley.
Ha ha ha!
My power has nothing
to do with money.
Power is energy.
Power is motivation.
Power is what
holds things together...
when they would
rather fly apart.
It's a complex world
out there, sporty.
Many things you
do not understand.
But...understand this.
There's a little bit
of me in that machine...
and a little bit of
it in me.
We are the lifeblood
of this town.
Gartley, what are you
talking about?
We all have to
make sacrifices.
You're right.
Everything has its price.
Yeah. Yes, it does.
Well, do come again.
This has been delightful.
And, uh...drive
carefully, won't you?
Fuck you!
What?
I
That S.O.B.
He thinks he's going to
shut down our machine.
Ha ha ha!
Well, sir, I've been
thinking...
maybe it should be
shut down.
Yeah...how long you
worked here, George?
15 years.
15 years. Well, you're--
you're practically...
part of our little family,
then, aren't you, hmm?
I assume you'll be helping us
run this town, hmm?
I've known that machine
since I was a little boy.
My daddy bought it.
Best business decision
he ever made, I'll tell you.
My God, Mr. Gartley, sir.
That--that machine
killed your daughter.
Look what
it's done to you.
Yeah. Sacrifices, George.
We all have to
make them.
Hell, boy. You could say
that machine out there...
made me what I am.
Mr. Gartley, if
you're not going to...
deal with it,
then maybe I should.
Oh, don't
be a fool, George.
Don't throw away
a bright future here.
I'm worried.
I'm worried, uh...
it's been troubling me.
Well, George, let your own
conscience be your guide.
Good evening, Martha.
Bill. Bill Gartley.
Sorry to call so late.
Let me speak to
the good sheriff...
won't you, Martha?
Thank you.
Evening, Hughes.
Now listen...
I'm having
a little problem...
with one of the boys.
Yeah. That's the fellow.
That's right.
Now you deal with him.
Yeah, good.
Fuck him.
John?
What?
Take some time off.
There's no case here, son.
Take a vacation!
OK, Mr. Gartley.
Now you're suspended,
Officer Hunton.
Hey, how much is he
paying you, Hughes?
OK, pal.
You're terminated!
And kiss that
pension good-bye.
How are we feeling,
my dear, hmm?
Strange.
I'm getting sick.
Are you ready for bed?
Yes.
No! No.
There's something
I must show you.
Come.
Aah!
Must be here somewhere.
Aha! Yeah.
My baby daughter's
death certificate.
Her passport to hell.
She was only 16.
Hmm. Well, survival
of the fittest...
is the way of things.
I mean, surely,
my child...
you must have noticed
how Rikers Valley...
is so ideally perfect, hmm?
There's something
I want to show you.
Just a moment here.
Ah! Ah.
This...is my contract--
my deal...
with the beast--
the beast in the machine.
What's happening to me?
My child...
there's a little
piece of you...
in the mangler...
and the essence
of it in you.
You're one of us now.
My signature.
See? Hmm?
Oh. Understand now?
Do we?
Hmm?
See?
Welcome to the club.
Oh, precious.
Fuck!
I've been studying, man.
Virgin's blood.
Definitely virgin's
blood. It's got to be.
Now, look.
A little holy water,
a smidgen of Eucharist--
that ought to do it.
Then we'll read
some LEv?t?cus to it.
Strictly Christian
white magic.
Listen, I'll tell you
the truth.
I was really worried...
about that hand
of glory--belladonna.
That's black juju.
Strong magic.
Hey, Mark?
I looked down...
this son of a
bitch's throat.
Holy water ain't
going to do it.
Yeah, well, a demon
conjured up...
in conjunction with
the hand of glory can--
I mean, that could eat...
a stack of Bibles
for breakfast...
but we don't have to
worry about that.
Thank God.
All right.
Yeah. I hope you're right.
I know I'm right.
I don't.
We got to go
talk to somebody.
Come on.
Hold up!
Damn it, hold up!
I
I don't know
about this, George.
What the hell
took you so long?
I'm sorry.
Are you sure we're doing
the right thing?
Yeah. Now, don't start
arguing with me now.
Go over there,
cut all power...
and pull the breakers.
I'll start
on the feeder.
Sherry?
What are you doing here?
I have to see my uncle.
That's not a good idea.
He's very upset.
I can't work here anymore.
The police came
and asked me questions.
I got to speak to him.
Police. That figures.
Just don't go up there.
He's busy.
Lin Sue's with him,
isn't she?
Sherry, go on home now.
I have to talk to him.
Oh, oh, oh. I'm caught!
Mr. Stanner!
I'm caught!
Help me! Aah!
Mr. Stanner!
The fuses! Jesus!
Aah!
Mr. Stanner!
Aah! Turn it off!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Aah!
Mr. Gartley!
Aah! Oh, help me!
Help me! Oh, please!
Please!
Do something!
Do something?
I'll do something.
I'll dance,
that's what I'll do.
I'll do a little
dance for you, Sherry.
Oh, God. Mr. Gartley!
A little jig.
I need your help now.
We're running out
of time. Come on.
Please! Please! Aah!
Uncle Bill, please!
Move like there's
no tomorrow.
We're on the clock.
Aah!
Do it! Do it!
I can't!
Do it now!
Oh, Christ.
I can't, George.
Do it! Aah! Do it!
Do it! Do it!
Christ!
Do it!
Very good, children.
Come here to
your Uncle Bill.
Sherry! Sherry!
I used to have all...
the time...in the world.
Damn her. Damn her.
Hey, hey. Hey, man...
where the hell
we going?
We're going to
go talk to an old man.
Oh, no. What
the hell is this?
No. Take me back.
Joey, stop!
Don't argue. Just do it.
I was just drinking
my tea, and...
you're all right.
Hey, you'll be OK.
You're going to be
all right.
You'll be OK.
Thanks for coming and
visiting me, Johnny.
You made an old man
very happy.
Just breathe.
Downstairs...
in my office.
Present for you.
You have to
exorcise your demon.
Don't let it
possess your soul.
Oh.
Argh!
Aah!
Shit!
I
Jesus!
Oh, man.
It wasn't your fault.
I was driving the car.
Accidents happen.
People make mistakes,
but they carry on.
Johnny.
Take a look at this.
This is my present.
"Maryanne Gartley...
"daughter of
William Gartley...
"was killed at...
"the Blue Ribbon
Laundry yesterday...
"when she apparently...
"fell into the new
speed ironer.
"She died
on her birthday.
She was 16 years old."
There's Maryanne.
"Sarah Krandel...
"was reported
missing yesterday...
"when she failed
to show up...
at her 16th
birthday party."
That's Sarah.
"Suzanne Bishop
still missing.
"Suzanne Bishop...
"daughter of
Judge Bishop...
"was reported
missing yesterday.
"She was last seen...
at her 16th
birthday party."
"Lois Hughes...
Chatterton..."
Well, these are all
the rich people...
the old money--
the people
that want nothing...
need nothing more...
Power. Power.
What is this?
Wait a minute.
Everything has
its price.
The price of power...
Gartley said
something about...
No, Gartley said...
that we all have to
make sacrifices.
Human sacrifices.
Sherry?
Jesus Christ.
Hi. Sherry? This is
Officer Hunton.
Mr. Stanner's dead.
I just went
to see my uncle.
Um, listen, Sherry.
I want you to stay inside.
I want you to stay
in the house.
Lock the doors.
Stay in the house.
You'll be safe...
as long as you stay
in the house.
What's going on?
How old are you,
Sherry? 16?
Really?
OK. Stay inside.
Do what I told you, OK?
I'll explain everything...
when I get there.
I'll be there as
soon as I can, OK?
The mangler got
the foreman.
Today's her birthday.
She's 16.
It's her birthday?
We're running
out of time.
Happy birthday,
my child.
Surprised to see
your Uncle Bill?
What do you want?
Why, you, of course.
Leave me alone.
Ohh...
aren't you going to
blow out your candles?
Come on.
Go ahead, Sherry.
Make a wish.
I wish you were dead.
Ha ha!
No doubt about it...
girl's got
true Gartley spirit.
Uhh!
Oh, what a waste,
but then...
we all...
have to make sacrifices.
Heh heh!
Now, now, now.
Uh, no!
Oh, I'm so sorry
it had to be you...
but I must
not be selfish...
when I make
my decision...
so it's time...
to turn in
your dance card.
Heh heh!
I do hope you'll accept
my apology...
but I must choose
between you and me...
and of course,
I choose...
me.
Come, darling.
We're running
out of time.
Stop! Stop!
We haven't got time, Mark.
I have to rehearse.
We haven't got time!
All right. Fuck!
OK, I'm going to read.
Now, I might read
from the Latin...
I might read
from the English...
but I'm going to
read anyway.
OK, this--this--
this, my friend,
is holy water.
Holy water. Fine.
When I give you the signal,
you take this...
and you sprinkle it
on the machine...
and you say, "In the name
of the Father...
"the Son,
and the Holy Ghost...
"Get thee from this place.
Thou art unclean."
OK, this is the host.
You break the host.
OK. OK. The host. Alright.
You put it on the machine.
You repeat the incantation.
Oh! The hand of glory--
Now we don't have to
worry about that.
Shit. Get in the car.
Get in the goddamn car!
You always do this to me!
Wait up!
I
God of all machines...
God that meshes
good and evil...
accept this blood
of my blood...
because I am
signing off--
payment in full!
See you later, Sherry.
Sherry!
No!
Piss off!
Get on out.
You've got no right!
You have no right!
Oh...
Agh!
No right!
No right! No...
Aah!
God!
Goddamn you!
You miserable piece
of dogfuck!
How dare you!
No!
So this is
the price of power?
This is the price
of power?
Ugh! No!
No! No! No!
No!
Here's the truth,
Gartley. It's done.
No! No!
No!
Lin Sue.
Aaah!
Lin Sue!
OK? Stay with me.
Trespassers!
Lin Sue!
My Lin Sue!
Off the clock.
Out of time?
Argh!
My God,
who art in hell...
cursed be thy name...
Why, you lying
son of a b-b-b--
Fuck you.
Stay back!
What do you
want me to do?
Help me.
OK, when I point to you,
you take the holy water...
and sprinkle it
in the machine...
and you say, "Glor?a ?n
ExcEls?s sp?r?tu omn?bus."
Omn?bus.
OK, all right.
Glor?a ?n ExcEls?s
sp?r?tu sancto omn?bus.
Then you put the host in.
- Repeat the incantation.
- Alright.
Glor?a ?n ExcEls?s
sp?r?tu sancto omn?bus.
In the host!
Aah!
In the name
of the Father...
the Son,
and the Holy Ghost...
get thee from this place!
Thou art unclean!
Holy shit! This
ain't working! Shit.
[Reading in Latin]
Our Father,
who art in heaven...
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done...
on earth as it is
in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread...
and forgive us
our trespasses...
Trespass against us...
and lead us not
into temptation...
but deliver us
from evil...
for thine is the power...
and the glory forever--
...sight to idols...
nor make gods
of thyself...
for the land will
vomit you up...
for defiling it...
as it vomited up
nations before thee!
Amen, goddamn it!
Look! Yeah!
We did it!
Huh? We did it!
We did it.
Ha ha ha!
It's dead!
Uhh! Oh, man.
Now I know where you get
your flaky stomach from.
Let me take
one of those.
I don't do drugs, man,
but I need this.
You OK? Really?
What's in this?
I don't know.
They're antacids.
I got them
from Mrs. Frawley.
Belladonna?
You got these
from Mrs. Frawley?
The hand of glory?
I think we may be fucked.
Aah!
Oh, God!
Oh, what's this?
Aah!
- Oh, shit!
- Oh. Oh.
Oh, God!
No! Aah!
Run! Run!
Mark!
Out! Get out! Out!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Do you know
a way out of here?
No! No!
Run! Run! Go!
[Sherry screaming]
We're fucked!
Oh, God!
No! Ohh!
No! John!
Mark!
It--it won't open!
If I walk
through the valley...
of the shadow of death,
I fear no evil.
Aaah!
John! No!
Johnny!
Mark!
No! Mark!
No!
Come here!
What are you doing?
Let go! Save yourself!
It wants me!
Over my dead body!
Are you crazy?
No, I'm a policeman.
But it wants me!
It wants me!
Sherry!
Sherry! Sherry!
Jump!
Leave her alone,
goddamn you!
Leave her alone!
No! Goddamn you!
Aah!
[Sherry gasping]
Ugh!
I
Sherry's all right.
She's lost
a lot of blood...
but she'll recover.
Thank God.
Mind telling me
what happened?
Yeah, I do mind.
Can I go see her?
No.
She's resting.
Maybe tomorrow.
OK. Thank you,
doctor.
Thank you.
Tomorrow.
Morning, officer.
Have a nice day.
Dearest Johnny...
in this envelope, you'll
find vital information...
that may save your life.
The old-timers in
Rikers Valley had a saying--
beware of people
with missing parts.
There's a piece of each
of them in the demon...
and a dose of the demon
in each of them.
"Faithfully yours...
J.J.J. Pictureman."
Herb!
I've got a big load of sheets
coming within the hour!
Now, get a move on!
Come on, ladies!
Move it up!
There's never enough
time around here!
I'm not running
a charity here, Herb!
Tell them to get their
lazy asses in gear!
Sherry?
You heard the boss!
Keep moving!
I