...
Is it on?
Whenever you want.
We're right in the middle of
the industrial site of Chamfors.
This is where they found the child.
Building 1.
We've got permission
to make this movie.
As a medical archive in favor
of the pediatric ward of
the hospital.
There you go.
She lived there.
She wasn't raped, that's for sure.
It looks more like common abuse.
Malnutrition, dehydration,
mild hypothermia.
The hole allows the person to
do one's needs without standing up.
The infection on the wrists proves
she was chained.
How did she escaped?
Lucie doesn't tell a thing
about what she went through.
What's that? Orange juice?
Yes.
Is it for her?
You're her mom, now?
Well yes, she got no one else.
Don't worry, Anna, these gentlemen
are really nice people.
Okay.
Do you know why we show you this movie?
Yes.
Why do you think we need you?
Because...
you want to get the people
that did those things to Lucie
Yes, Anna.
Lucie wants that too.
You must catch the bad people.
What else did she say?
You talked to her for hours...
She's afraid.
Does she tell you any thing else?
Not much more.
What does she remember?
She doesn't know who it is.
Sometimes she thinks she remembers something,
sometimes she doesn't.
What do you think?
Do you think she will remember?
It was dark and she couldn't see well.
She doesn't remember.
Come in.
Lucie Jurin didn't come down for lunch.
Lucie?
Anna!
Don't tell anyone, please?
I won't.
It wasn't me
it wasn't me
it wasn't me.
Calm down.
Do you want to sleep with me?
Anna?
15 YEARS LATER
Give it back!
Stop it, both of you.
Damn!
Your girlfriend can barely write
a sentence.
Stop, I said.
You're the worst!
Don't touch me.
By the way, it's none of your business.
What do you know?
You don't know what love is.
You don't even have a boyfriend.
And? Are we gonna eat breakfast or not?
Yeah, yeah.
You're getting on my nerves.
I hate you.
CHAMPION 100 METRES BUTTERFLY
So that's what you decided, huh?
Well, it's my life isn't it?
Smartass...
Did you talk about it with your mother?
Yep.
And what did she say?
She's more pissed about her low water pressure.
She's not happy with either situation.
Are you happy?
What? It's all good here!
"What? It's all good here!"
All done.
Good job, honey.
Here.
A gift.
Awwwww, Gabrielle.
Gross!
This little guy got stuck
in the main pipe.
This guy was causing our low water pressure.
Toss it in the trash.
Yeah, I'm being gross
but now that it's fixed we can replant the Azealeus.
Did Antoine talk
about his big plans?
Actually I was just asking him about what
you thought about it.
No, you wondered if she was pissed off.
Be quiet, it's none of your business.
I'm trying to help my brother.
You can't help your brother whose a visionary that's for sure.
Antoine?!
It's enough of an expensive school
to drop out after only being there for 3 months!
Definitely not if you pay in advance.
TA-DA!
Marie, you really need to butt out!
She think she's a swimming celebrity!
Are you planning to make this a habit of yours?
The school?
Keep in mind that you wouldn't have graduated
if we hadn't paid extra!
What do you mean?
I made it!
Oh-ho? "Made it" with a C average?
C'mon remind me that it's about 8 grand to push you through wasn't it?
After each trimesters! But it wasn't skin off your nose was it?
Aren't you tired of being such a pain in the ass? You little shit!
Well listen! This school is a lot more work
I-I.. wanted to go study something I really like.
Just get your law degree
Law?... Studying law is not my thing...
Laws open many doors!
The problem is he wants to go and live with his girlfriend
Minerva!
You know laws is not my thing!
Whatever, Antoine!
As if anything is "your thing!"
For a week there you wanted to be a Pastry Chef, remember?
Someone's just got served!
Is that Minerva?
Lighten up on your brother.
He always picks on me!
So what? Cool it, it's the weekend
Take a break.
You work in the factory or something?
Dad?
Stay here, don't move!
Don't move!
Sit down!
So, you how old?
...18.
Do you know what your parents did to me?
Why did you do that to me?
Why?!
It's them.
Lucie?
It's them, Anna.
You sure?
They've changed, but it's definitely them.
Are you positive?
It's been 15 years!
You can tell it's them from the papers?
I CAN TELL!
Then we'll call the cops.
There's no need to.
What?
I did what I thought was right.
You did WHAT?
What I had to do!
We said you'd just observe them.
I'm sure they were the ones!
I knew I should have come along, what have you done?
Don't you believe me?
Where are you calling from?
From the house.
From the house?
Yes.
What's the address there?
Lucie, give me the address!
I did it...
Look!
It's me, Lucie, It's me!
Calm down. It's me!
She's in there.
She's in the house.
I know.
She hurt me more than usual.
Stay right here.
Where are you going?
I have to go and take a look.
She's still in there.
I have to go!
She's in the house.
Look at me, I have to go and take a look.
Wait for me.
She hurt me worst than usual
I'm coming, Lucie.
What am I going to do?
I'm almost done.
Got anymore shotgun shells?
They're gone, you won't be needing them.
Maybe we should get moving?
Yeah!
She'll be back soon.
C'mon.
They'll know that we did this
Cause you phoned me from here.
I don't care.
I know.
Really, I don't!
You'll care if they lock you up.
What are we going to do?
Stay still.
You're hurting me!
Sorry.
What are we gonna do, Anna?
Are you okay?
Is this making you sick?
Do you smell this?
The foul stench?
I smelled it every day
Every time she would bend over me I'd smell that. Everyday.
Do you understand?
It smelled different when she hit me.
Look.
It's them.
What are you doing?
Will we ever be free from this?
Yeah... Sure.
Please, if you wanna live be quiet.
Anna, what are you doing?
Are you okay?
Yes.
You didn't answer?
I didn't hear you.
I thought she was here.
No.
You finished? Then let's go.
Not yet, let's clean up.
When we're done we go!
Yes, get dressed.
Lucie!
Open the door!
I can't it's locked!
Open up!
Quickly!
What do you want?
Leave me alone.
l killed them all!
Even the children!
I even killed the children!
Calm down! Calm down!
Get away from there you little whore!
I'm gonna kill you!
Sorry.
It's not my fault.
Where are you?
Anna, I know you're there!
ANNA!
I'm coming, Lucie.
What's your name?
Gabrielle...
I'm coming, Lucie!
You have to help me, Gabrielle.
Why is she doing this?
I think she heard us.
We have to move fast.
Please, call an ambulance.
For my children...
Come on!
I'll get you as far as the wood
Then you're on your own.
No! Stop!
Stop! Lucie!
Why did you helped her?
She didn't do anything, Lucie.
She was the one who hurt me!
A LOOOT!
And you want her to live, huh?!
So, you have never believed me?
Enough!
So you think I'm insane too?
Just like the doctors.
Did they ever do anything for me?
Beside say I was crazy?
You're just like them.
It's over, Anna!
They're dead.
They won't hurt you anymore.
Stooop!
Nooooooooooooooooooooooooooo!
Why are you calling me? Huh?
I haven't heard from you in over two years
And now you call?
Yes.
I'm angry at you, Anna.
I'm not gonna lie, I'm furious with you.
Mama...
You trying to make me feel guilty?
No.
Don't you think I ever feel bad?
Don't you think I'm not thinking about
All everything and the way I've raised you?
No, mama, that's not it.
What is it then?
I wanted to talk to you, for real.
So you wake up one day and
You decided you're missing your mother?
Anna, you okay? You're not in trouble are you?
No, mama I'm fine!
Are you sure? Where are you?
Far away.
You have a place? What do you do for a living?
It's okay, Mama... I'm fine.
So tell me, are you still with her?
No!
My God! She's still influencing you.
She's still running your life! I can tell.
Mama?!
Anna, she's worthless, she's a slut.
You need to break free of that witch!
Don't stay with her.
Anna?
Anna, you there?
Don't move.
I can't help you...
Don't be afraid..
Calm down.
Rest well.
Forgive me.
I'm so sorry.
Stop it!
Who's the girl on the couch?
Who is it?
Lucie...
Lucie who?
Lucie Jurin.
And you?
And?
Anna Assaoui.
We're trying to reach the Belfonds for hours.
The phone's off the hook.
That should never have happened.
Can you tell me what went on here?
What are you doing here?
Lucie Jurin escaped from us 15 years ago.
Correct?
Right.
Back then we were disorganized.
Gabrielle shouldn't have let her escaped
After 15 years the girl found her.
I'm impressed by her tenacity.
But in the end Lucie is just a victim.
Like all of the others.
It's so easy to create a victim, young lady.
So easy.
You lock someone up in a room with no light.
Soon he begins to suffer.
Then you feed that suffering.
Slowly, methodically, systematically.
Coldly for a long time.
You then witness your subject
Going through several mental states.
The mental trauma starts to break them...
And that small easily opened cracks.
Make them see things that don't exists in our world.
Your friend Lucie what was her vision?
Did she see anything?
Not even one monster?
Things that wanted to hurt her?
A dead girl.
There you go.
The girl you found Sarah Dutreuil.
She saw insects. Cockroaches, everywhere.
They were crawling all over her, she would rather
Chop off her own arm than to go through that.
People ignore the existence of suffering.
That's how our world sees it.
Yet everyone's a victim.
Martyrs are very rare.
A true martyr is a special person.
They're exceptional beings.
They withstand paralyzing pain, young lady
They survive total depravation.
They carry all the sins of the world.
It's their sacrifice
They transcends themselves completely
Do you understand?
They're transfigured!
Longsheng Province in 1912.
She didn't believe in God.
She stole a hen
And it costs her dearly.
In the photograph you can see she's...
Still very alive. Look at her eyes.
Jouans Lussac, 1945.
This woman was a grocer.
She slept with a German.
Back then the French were sensitive.
So she had to pay.
Look at her eyes... She's still alive.
1960, a hospital in Birmingham.
Just an ordinary young housewife
An atheist.
Riddled with terminal cancer
Morphine had lost its effect for her.
Her eyes tell the story.
This one was beaten up by her husband.
Jealousy...
This one just spent 9 hours
In the wreckage of her car.
This young leukemia patient
Is dying. The pains gnawing.
This woman has a rare disease.
She suffered for nine hours.
Look at their eyes. Look.
All of them. Do you hear me?
They were all alive when these
Pictures were taken.
No one can tell me that the
Concept of materydom
Is an invention of the religious!
We've tried everything.
Even with children.
And it has been proven that women
Are much more responsive to
Transfiguration.
Yes, young women.
That's how it is!
Lucie: Anna?
Lucie: Are you there?
Anna: I'm here.
Lucie: Anna?
Anna: Yes, Lucie.
Lucie: Why are you never afraid?
Lucie: Sometimes I'm afraid.
Lucie: You're not like me.
Lucie: I didn't go through what did.
Lucie What do you have to do to
Stop being afraid?
Anna: Just let go...
Lucie: Do you think so?
Anna: Just... let go.
Lucie: If I can't do it,
will you be there for me?
Anna: Yes.
Anna: I miss you.
You're not afraid anymore, Anna.
You're not afraid anymore...
It will be okay, Anna.
It will be okay.
The suffering is almost over.
There's one stage left.
The last one.
It will be okay.
You don't have to defend yourself anymore.
It's okay, Anna.
Is she still holding up?
Yeah, it's amazing.
Michel!
What is it?
Just now. When I went to feed her.
A few minutes ago.
Are you sure?
Like I said...
I've never seen an expression like that.
She's liberated, completely liberated.
Her face is like...
Miss, her eyes...
She doesn't see what's happening around
Her anymore.
But is she still...
She's still alive.
Have you seen it, then?
The other world?
Yesterday afternoon in this very
House
Around 12.15...
Anna Assaoui became a martyr.
Let us take a moment to pay our
Respect.
Anna Assaoui is an exceptional being.
In our 17 years of research.
She's only the fourth to have reach this stage.
And the first, yes, the first...
To have reported what she has seen.
Between 12:15 to 2:30
Miss Assaoui has clearly
Seen what comes after death.
You heard correctly.
Her state of ecstasy
Lasted for 2 hours and 15 minutes.
It was not a near-death experience.
What she experienced was an
Authentic martyrdom.
At 2.30 she left that state.
And at 3:05 she spoke.
At this very moment she is still alive.
But no longer communicating.
Miss heard her testimony.
And this testimony...
Will be shared within a few moments.
Miss...
They are waiting.
I'm coming, Etienne.
So there IS something?
Of course.
Was it clear?
Like crystal.
And precise?
I see no other interpretation, Etienne.
Thank you, Miss.
Etienne?
Miss?
Have you ever try to imagine
The other world?
Are you okay?
Well, have you?
No, I...
Keep doubting, Etienne.
martyr:
noun
From the Greek word ''marturos''
Witness