0
00:00:07,000 --> 00:00:17,000
(please select 2nd audio track
to enjoy AC3 Dolby Digital 5.1)

1
00:01:04,931 --> 00:01:08,196
[Boat Whistle Blowing]

2
00:01:08,301 --> 00:01:11,236
<i>[Boat Whistle Blowing]</i>

3
00:01:35,862 --> 00:01:40,162
Honey?
Come on over here, sugar buns.

4
00:01:42,569 --> 00:01:45,595
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>This machine just called me an asshole.</i>

5
00:01:45,705 --> 00:01:48,833
<i>♪♪ [Rock]</i>

6
00:01:48,942 --> 00:01:51,433
♪♪

7
00:01:51,544 --> 00:01:55,446
<i>[Male Singers]</i>
<i>♪ The video game says "Play me"♪</i>

8
00:01:55,548 --> 00:02:01,612
<i>♪ Face it on a level</i>
<i>but it takes you every time on a one on one ♪</i>

9
00:02:03,423 --> 00:02:06,950
<i>♪ Feeling running down</i>
<i>your spine ♪</i>

10
00:02:07,060 --> 00:02:13,021
<i>♪ Nothing gonna save your one last dime</i>
<i>'cause it owns you ♪</i>

11
00:02:15,468 --> 00:02:18,767
<i>♪ Through and through ♪</i>

12
00:02:18,872 --> 00:02:22,000
<i>♪ Who made who</i>
<i>Who made you ♪</i>

13
00:02:22,108 --> 00:02:26,374
<i>♪ Who made who</i>
<i>Ain't nobody told you ♪</i>

14
00:02:26,479 --> 00:02:29,846
<i>♪ Who made who</i>
<i>Who made you ♪</i>

15
00:02:29,949 --> 00:02:32,076
<i>♪ If you made them</i>
<i>and they made you ♪</i>

16
00:02:32,185 --> 00:02:35,552
<i>♪ Who picked up the bill</i>
<i>and who made who ♪</i>

17
00:02:40,593 --> 00:02:42,720
<i>♪ Who made who ♪</i>

18
00:02:44,297 --> 00:02:47,198
<i>♪♪ [Continues Indistinct]</i>

19
00:02:50,203 --> 00:02:52,171
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>I knock.</i>

20
00:02:52,272 --> 00:02:57,904
- Huh?
- Jesus Christ!
Do you know how to play this game?

21
00:02:58,011 --> 00:03:01,947
- Sure.
- Then why don't you make your last draw?

22
00:03:06,386 --> 00:03:10,083
<i>♪ Satellites send me pictures ♪</i>

23
00:03:10,190 --> 00:03:12,124
<i>♪ Get it in the eye ♪</i>

24
00:03:12,225 --> 00:03:16,059
<i>♪ Take it to the world</i>
<i>Spinning like a dynamo ♪</i>

25
00:03:17,897 --> 00:03:21,594
<i>♪ Feel it going</i>
<i>round and round ♪</i>

26
00:03:21,701 --> 00:03:26,968
<i>♪ Running out of chips</i>
<i>You got no line in an eight-bit town ♪</i>

27
00:03:27,073 --> 00:03:29,041
[Motors Whirring]

28
00:03:29,142 --> 00:03:32,305
<i>♪ So don't look down, no ♪</i>

29
00:03:32,412 --> 00:03:36,041
<i>♪ Who made who ♪</i>

30
00:03:36,149 --> 00:03:39,141
<i>[Loud Whirring]</i>

31
00:03:47,360 --> 00:03:50,761
<i>♪ Who made who ♪</i>

32
00:03:50,863 --> 00:03:54,230
<i>♪ Who made who ♪♪</i>

33
00:03:56,202 --> 00:03:59,763
- [Woman] The bridge is going up!
- [Man] It can't be.

34
00:03:59,872 --> 00:04:02,500
Stop the car!

35
00:04:06,379 --> 00:04:08,711
What the fuck?

36
00:04:26,432 --> 00:04:29,697
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Look out.</i>

37
00:04:31,571 --> 00:04:34,563
[Screaming]

38
00:04:42,982 --> 00:04:45,075
What the hell?

39
00:05:10,843 --> 00:05:12,970
Wow! Far out!

40
00:05:15,415 --> 00:05:17,747
[Man Screaming]

41
00:05:22,488 --> 00:05:24,718
- [Screaming]
- [Brakes Squealing]

42
00:05:27,593 --> 00:05:29,561
[Screaming]

43
00:05:49,115 --> 00:05:51,606
- What is this shit?
- <i>[Man] That's impossible.</i>

44
00:05:51,718 --> 00:05:56,246
- The light's green.
The crossbars never went down!
- Huh?

45
00:05:56,356 --> 00:06:00,087
Shut up, you goddamn
stupid asshole!

46
00:06:00,193 --> 00:06:02,354
Can't you see we got
a situation here?

47
00:06:33,192 --> 00:06:36,923
<i>[Man #1] Did you get Mickey Mantle</i>
<i>over to the baseball game?</i>

48
00:06:37,029 --> 00:06:39,827
You go on and joke
all you want.

49
00:06:39,932 --> 00:06:44,130
But he hit three balls over the fence,
and one must've gone 250 feet.

50
00:06:50,710 --> 00:06:54,646
- <i>[Man #1] Holy God. Look at that thing.</i>
- <i>[Man #2] I'll get it.</i>

51
00:07:08,594 --> 00:07:13,258
- Handy, you son of a bitch.
I thought you was in Texas.
- No, that was last week.

52
00:07:13,366 --> 00:07:16,164
You like that, huh?

53
00:07:16,269 --> 00:07:18,237
Yeah, that's some rig,
all right.

54
00:07:18,337 --> 00:07:21,238
Give her a big drink.
I gotta have some coffee.

55
00:07:21,340 --> 00:07:23,433
Right.

56
00:07:37,924 --> 00:07:39,824
- Hey, man.
- Handy!

57
00:07:39,926 --> 00:07:44,329
- This damn thing!
- What's the matter, hon?

58
00:07:44,430 --> 00:07:47,263
This thing was working just fine
a few minutes ago.

59
00:07:47,366 --> 00:07:51,302
Now I can't get pea-turkey on it.

60
00:07:51,404 --> 00:07:55,204
You wanna bring me a light coffee
when you get done jerking on that thing?

61
00:07:58,911 --> 00:08:00,845
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Robinson?</i>

62
00:08:02,949 --> 00:08:06,316
- Robinson, get in here, boy!
- I got eggs on.

63
00:08:06,419 --> 00:08:08,979
I don't give a lady bug.
I want you in here now.

64
00:08:09,088 --> 00:08:13,855
<i>Wanda June, shut off that radio,</i>
<i>mind them eggs for Billy.</i>

65
00:08:19,966 --> 00:08:22,093
<i>[Games Beeping]</i>

66
00:08:27,540 --> 00:08:30,008
Your mama!

67
00:09:02,074 --> 00:09:04,338
[Hose Clicks Off]

68
00:09:29,335 --> 00:09:31,997
[Screaming]

69
00:09:42,415 --> 00:09:45,441
<i>Steve Gayton, Mr. Hendershot.</i>
<i>Duncan Keller's had an accident.</i>

70
00:09:45,551 --> 00:09:47,712
[Hendershot]
Oh, "shitsky"! What happened to him?

71
00:09:47,820 --> 00:09:50,118
He got diesel in his eyes.
I'll be damned if I know how.

72
00:09:50,222 --> 00:09:53,817
Is that all?
Flush his eyes. Leave me alone.

73
00:09:53,926 --> 00:09:56,053
<i>Got some talkin' to do</i>
<i>in here.</i>

74
00:09:56,162 --> 00:09:58,995
<i>I gotta wipe everybody's ass</i>
<i>around here.</i>

75
00:09:59,098 --> 00:10:03,296
Shitty job, but I reckon somebody's gotta do it.
Ain't that right, bubba?

76
00:10:03,402 --> 00:10:06,997
No, no. Let me
get this straight now.

77
00:10:07,106 --> 00:10:12,476
You want me to work for nine hours,
and only clock in for eight?

78
00:10:12,578 --> 00:10:15,342
I know you been to college, boy.

79
00:10:15,448 --> 00:10:17,780
Uh-uh, screw that.

80
00:10:17,883 --> 00:10:19,783
<i>Not this kid.</i>

81
00:10:19,885 --> 00:10:23,844
You know what that star means, don't you?
You ain't that obtuse, are you?

82
00:10:23,956 --> 00:10:25,787
On parole, boy.

83
00:10:25,891 --> 00:10:30,157
Either your ass belongs to me
or it belongs to the state of North Carolina.

84
00:10:32,865 --> 00:10:36,528
You got one hell of a racket goin',
don't you?

85
00:10:36,636 --> 00:10:41,573
Here. Put that back in the rack
for me on your way by, would you?

86
00:10:44,377 --> 00:10:46,845
<i>Thank you, bubba.</i>
<i>[Laughing]</i>

87
00:10:50,116 --> 00:10:52,846
Oh, shit!
[Laughing]

88
00:10:53,452 --> 00:10:57,912
<i>[Man] Wanda June, honey, you want me</i>
<i>to get that cup of coffee myself?</i>

89
00:10:58,024 --> 00:11:01,152
Bill?

90
00:11:02,428 --> 00:11:05,761
Billy, gettin'
out of hand in here.

91
00:11:05,865 --> 00:11:08,925
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>You ain't talkin' about me, are you, honey?</i>

92
00:11:12,538 --> 00:11:15,769
Jesus Christ!

93
00:11:15,875 --> 00:11:19,072
[Knife Whirring]

94
00:11:19,178 --> 00:11:23,547
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Hey, those eggs comin' Pony Express or what?</i>

95
00:11:24,850 --> 00:11:28,047
Just a minute, sir.

96
00:11:29,055 --> 00:11:31,819
[Screaming]

97
00:11:36,462 --> 00:11:41,126
[Screaming]
It's biting me! Make it stop biting me!

98
00:11:41,233 --> 00:11:44,293
- What is?
- The knife! The knife!

99
00:11:44,403 --> 00:11:47,531
<i>Quick, a rag.</i>
<i>Somebody get me a rag.</i>

100
00:11:47,640 --> 00:11:50,131
That knife go rabid on you,
sweet thing?

101
00:11:50,242 --> 00:11:54,804
Well, it turned itself on,
and it bit me.

102
00:11:54,914 --> 00:11:58,042
- Short circuit, maybe.
- <i>[Wanda] There it goes again.</i>

103
00:12:03,022 --> 00:12:05,456
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>It's on again.</i>

104
00:12:07,526 --> 00:12:10,825
<i>It's still goin'. Look at that sucker.</i>
<i>Nail it.</i>

105
00:12:13,332 --> 00:12:15,493
<i>[Games Beeping]</i>

106
00:12:26,445 --> 00:12:30,074
<i>[Beeping Continues]</i>

107
00:12:55,207 --> 00:12:57,368
- [Gasps]
- Now what?

108
00:13:04,316 --> 00:13:07,114
<i>[Loud Beeping,</i>
<i>Whirring Noises]</i>

109
00:13:32,511 --> 00:13:36,242
<i>[Crowd Cheering]</i>

110
00:13:37,449 --> 00:13:40,418
Come on!

111
00:13:43,088 --> 00:13:44,988
Safe!

112
00:13:50,763 --> 00:13:53,561
Come on. Sodas.
I'm buyin'.

113
00:13:57,303 --> 00:14:01,330
<i>[Boy]</i>
<i>You guys gonna help me pick this stuff up?</i>

114
00:14:06,412 --> 00:14:09,245
<i>[Boy]</i>
<i>Uh-oh, no sodas.</i>

115
00:14:10,850 --> 00:14:12,841
- [Rumbling]
- Huh?

116
00:14:12,952 --> 00:14:15,182
[Groans]

117
00:14:15,287 --> 00:14:20,088
- <i>[Boys Laughing]</i>
- [Groans]

118
00:14:20,192 --> 00:14:22,251
- [Rumbling]
- [Groans]

119
00:14:22,361 --> 00:14:24,921
What the hell?

120
00:14:26,532 --> 00:14:29,399
[Boys Screaming]

121
00:14:29,501 --> 00:14:32,959
[Rumbling]

122
00:14:39,411 --> 00:14:42,107
- [Rumbling]
- Oh, shit!

123
00:14:45,718 --> 00:14:48,482
Coach? Coach?

124
00:14:50,022 --> 00:14:51,785
You okay?

125
00:14:55,561 --> 00:14:58,121
Come on, Coach.

126
00:15:14,079 --> 00:15:17,981
<i>Bobby, look out.</i>

127
00:15:18,083 --> 00:15:20,916
[Screams]

128
00:15:34,500 --> 00:15:39,597
[Man]
♪ One step at a time, sweet Jesus ♪

129
00:15:39,705 --> 00:15:44,039
♪ That's all
I'm asking you ♪

130
00:15:44,143 --> 00:15:47,806
♪ One step at a time
sweet Jesus ♪

131
00:15:47,913 --> 00:15:49,938
♪ That's all
I'm asking... ♪

132
00:15:50,049 --> 00:15:52,711
Might as well give up
on that, sugar pie.

133
00:15:52,818 --> 00:15:56,754
I ain't been able to get diddly-squat
out of it past half hour.

134
00:15:56,855 --> 00:15:58,948
Must have a broke antennae
or somethin'.

135
00:15:59,058 --> 00:16:02,459
<i>[Radio]</i>
<i>Our firsthand information...</i>

136
00:16:02,561 --> 00:16:05,325
So, how far are you goin'
up the road, sugar pie?

137
00:16:08,467 --> 00:16:11,061
Depends on how long you can keep
your hands to yourself.

138
00:16:11,170 --> 00:16:14,071
What's that, sweet thing?
I didn't quite catch it.

139
00:16:15,975 --> 00:16:18,273
I said,
I don't really know.

140
00:16:18,377 --> 00:16:21,107
Just driftin', huh?
[Laughing]

141
00:16:21,213 --> 00:16:26,150
- Yeah, I know what it's like.
Been drifting for ten years.
- <i>As far as we can tell...</i>

142
00:16:26,251 --> 00:16:29,311
When I started this business
about eight years ago...

143
00:16:29,421 --> 00:16:31,719
Shh, shh.
I got somethin'.

144
00:16:31,824 --> 00:16:34,452
<i>[Radio]</i>
<i>...Before our microwave facilities broke down.</i>

145
00:16:34,560 --> 00:16:39,395
<i>Reports of strange occurrences</i>
<i>are pouring in over the wire services.</i>

146
00:16:39,498 --> 00:16:44,367
<i>We will have further bulletins as they come</i>
<i>in, but let me repeat this urgent message.</i>

147
00:16:44,470 --> 00:16:48,406
<i>If you are on or near a major highway,</i>
<i>get away at once.</i>

148
00:16:48,507 --> 00:16:52,068
<i>Get away</i> at...
<i>[Static]</i>

149
00:16:52,177 --> 00:16:57,114
- Shit!
- Whoa! What's wrong, sweet thing?

150
00:16:57,216 --> 00:17:00,549
Pull in there, and if you don't
get your hand off my leg...

151
00:17:00,652 --> 00:17:04,213
you're gonna be wiping your ass with a hook
next time you take a dump.

152
00:17:04,323 --> 00:17:07,190
I never heard no talk
like that when I was a boy.

153
00:17:08,727 --> 00:17:12,322
What the hell you doin', girl?
What's the matter with you?

154
00:17:21,340 --> 00:17:25,401
Lordy! Lordy, girl!
You gone crazy or somethin'?

155
00:17:25,511 --> 00:17:27,706
Did you hear anything
that man said?

156
00:17:29,915 --> 00:17:33,783
Are you...
are you on somethin'?

157
00:17:33,886 --> 00:17:35,979
Jesus!

158
00:17:36,088 --> 00:17:38,613
<i>Wait a minute. Wait a minute.</i>
<i>Wait a minute.</i>

159
00:17:38,724 --> 00:17:42,319
<i>Don't you go walking</i>
<i>away from me like that.</i>

160
00:17:42,428 --> 00:17:45,522
You come back here, girl!
You come back here! You listen to me!

161
00:17:45,631 --> 00:17:47,826
Eat my shorts.

162
00:17:47,933 --> 00:17:50,834
Sometimes I think this world forgot
what good manners is.

163
00:17:50,936 --> 00:17:55,100
<i>I give you a ride in my brand-new car,</i>
<i>and look at the garbage...</i>

164
00:17:55,207 --> 00:17:57,107
comin' out of your mouth.

165
00:17:57,209 --> 00:17:59,939
- [Engine Revs]
- And you know what I think?
It's that damn TV.

166
00:18:00,045 --> 00:18:03,640
Look at what that stuff does.
You're losing your immortal soul!

167
00:18:03,749 --> 00:18:08,209
- [Engine Revs]
- <i>Whole goddamn civilization...</i>
<i>[Continues Indistinct]</i>

168
00:18:12,791 --> 00:18:14,884
It ain't newspapers
gonna save this world.

169
00:18:14,993 --> 00:18:17,655
It ain't TV.
I'm tellin' you here and now...

170
00:18:17,763 --> 00:18:19,663
- far as all that's holy, holy...
- <i>[Engine Revs]</i>

171
00:18:21,266 --> 00:18:24,633
It ain't full yet!

172
00:18:34,079 --> 00:18:36,047
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>What is wrong with this?</i>

173
00:18:36,148 --> 00:18:39,379
"The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want."

174
00:18:40,986 --> 00:18:44,183
- <i>Jesus Christ, what the hell happened here?</i>
- <i>I don't know.</i>

175
00:18:57,669 --> 00:18:59,796
What in the Dickens
is goin' on around here?

176
00:18:59,905 --> 00:19:01,805
<i>[Billy]</i>
<i>That's a damn good question.</i>

177
00:19:01,907 --> 00:19:04,102
- <i>[Man] That was your rig, wasn't it, Handy?</i>
- <i>Yeah.</i>

178
00:19:04,209 --> 00:19:07,144
- <i>[Man] Then who was driving it?</i>
- I don't know.

179
00:19:07,246 --> 00:19:10,477
But he must've been
a hot-wire champion.

180
00:19:10,582 --> 00:19:12,413
[Man]
Hell's bells.

181
00:19:33,138 --> 00:19:37,404
- We gotta get some gas.
- That's good, 'cause I got to go to the ladies'.

182
00:19:37,509 --> 00:19:41,707
- Can I come in and watch?
- No, you cannot come in and watch!

183
00:19:41,813 --> 00:19:43,576
Ouch. Shoot.

184
00:19:55,327 --> 00:19:57,227
- Did you see...
- What, honey?

185
00:20:02,067 --> 00:20:04,035
Never mind.

186
00:20:21,220 --> 00:20:24,212
- Oh, Jesus!
- [Screams]

187
00:20:31,330 --> 00:20:33,798
- [Fly Buzzing]
- <i>Curt?</i>

188
00:20:37,803 --> 00:20:39,964
Curtis?

189
00:20:40,072 --> 00:20:41,972
Is he dead?

190
00:21:16,942 --> 00:21:19,809
<i>Great God.</i>

191
00:21:24,216 --> 00:21:26,480
<i>[Engine Revving]</i>

192
00:21:26,585 --> 00:21:28,849
<i>[Revving Continues]</i>

193
00:21:40,932 --> 00:21:42,900
Hey! Hey!

194
00:21:43,001 --> 00:21:46,835
<i>I need some...</i>
<i>I need some help</i> ov...

195
00:21:50,175 --> 00:21:52,075
Hey!

196
00:21:56,481 --> 00:22:00,542
Curtis, I don't like this!

197
00:22:07,326 --> 00:22:09,226
Shit!

198
00:22:10,929 --> 00:22:13,159
Curtis!

199
00:22:20,505 --> 00:22:23,303
<i>Are you dead?</i>

200
00:22:24,543 --> 00:22:26,511
Shit.

201
00:22:31,516 --> 00:22:33,450
[Coughs]

202
00:23:12,324 --> 00:23:15,691
- [Engine Revving]
- [Screaming]

203
00:23:15,794 --> 00:23:19,093
Curtis!

204
00:23:19,197 --> 00:23:21,961
Get in!
Get in right now!

205
00:23:22,067 --> 00:23:24,763
[Engine Revving]

206
00:23:26,004 --> 00:23:28,973
Go! Go! Go!

207
00:23:30,675 --> 00:23:32,609
[Screams]

208
00:23:38,817 --> 00:23:41,786
[Curt]
No! The other way! The other way!

209
00:23:41,887 --> 00:23:43,878
[Connie]
Oh!

210
00:23:43,989 --> 00:23:45,889
[Curt]
Jesus Christ, honey!

211
00:23:45,991 --> 00:23:50,257
You stop that yelling!
You know I can't drive when you shout at me!

212
00:23:50,362 --> 00:23:52,990
[Engine Revs]

213
00:24:11,483 --> 00:24:14,213
<i>[Hendershot]</i>
<i>Boy, ain't this a ton of shit.</i>

214
00:24:17,823 --> 00:24:20,451
You do what I said
with his body?

215
00:24:20,559 --> 00:24:25,622
Got him downstairs, sure. Pretty crispy,
Mr. Hendershot. What happened?

216
00:24:25,730 --> 00:24:27,960
Fucked if I know, bubba.

217
00:24:29,267 --> 00:24:31,167
Fucked if I know.

218
00:25:05,770 --> 00:25:08,170
<i>♪♪ [Musical Note]</i>

219
00:25:27,826 --> 00:25:29,726
♪♪ [Musical Note]

220
00:26:16,007 --> 00:26:17,497
Yo!

221
00:26:17,609 --> 00:26:19,509
Vroom-vroom.

222
00:26:25,550 --> 00:26:28,246
<i>[Woman]</i>
<i>So, anybody in there?</i>

223
00:26:28,353 --> 00:26:31,151
Nope, not now.

224
00:26:33,758 --> 00:26:36,318
You're cute.

225
00:26:36,428 --> 00:26:38,328
[Laughing]

226
00:26:38,430 --> 00:26:40,955
Yeah? Am I?

227
00:26:41,066 --> 00:26:43,626
Not that cute.

228
00:26:43,735 --> 00:26:46,499
Well, maybe I'll grow
on you.

229
00:26:48,640 --> 00:26:52,337
<i>[Woman]</i>
<i>Look at that. There's nothin'.</i>

230
00:26:52,444 --> 00:26:57,040
<i>You ever see that much nothing</i>
<i>at 10: 15 in the morning, hero?</i>

231
00:27:05,223 --> 00:27:10,024
- <i>Name's Bill.</i>
- <i>Hi, Bill. Brett.</i>

232
00:27:40,258 --> 00:27:44,490
<i>[Radio Indistinct]</i>

233
00:27:44,596 --> 00:27:48,589
<i>Although our microwave relay</i>
<i>was knocked out at 9:00 this morning...</i>

234
00:27:48,700 --> 00:27:52,227
<i>this frightening mechanical revolt</i>
<i>appears to be occurring everywhere.</i>

235
00:27:52,337 --> 00:27:55,431
<i>New York, London,</i>
<i>New Delhi, Moscow, Peking.</i>

236
00:27:55,540 --> 00:27:59,271
<i>The reports we have</i>
<i>are all the same.</i>

237
00:27:59,377 --> 00:28:02,278
<i>Machines apparently operating</i>
<i>by themselves...</i>

238
00:28:02,380 --> 00:28:06,009
<i>or under the direction</i>
<i>of some agency we don't understand...</i>

239
00:28:06,117 --> 00:28:08,210
<i>are going on</i>
<i>a homicidal rampage.</i>

240
00:28:08,319 --> 00:28:10,719
<i>Whatever is happening...</i>

241
00:28:10,822 --> 00:28:14,622
<i>[Continues Indistinct]</i>

242
00:28:24,002 --> 00:28:27,961
<i>[Siren Wailing]</i>

243
00:28:28,073 --> 00:28:31,736
<i>[Wailing Continues]</i>

244
00:28:32,510 --> 00:28:36,469
[Siren Wailing]

245
00:28:36,581 --> 00:28:38,481
[Radio] Some cities are waking up
more slowly than others.

246
00:28:38,583 --> 00:28:41,143
Only one thing is completely
certain this morning...

247
00:28:41,252 --> 00:28:43,277
<i>and that is no machine</i>
<i>is to be trusted.</i>

248
00:28:43,388 --> 00:28:45,288
<i>Unplug all</i>
<i>electrical appliances.</i>

249
00:28:45,390 --> 00:28:48,416
<i>If you have a truck</i>
<i>or car...</i>

250
00:29:12,650 --> 00:29:16,484
<i>♪♪ [Ice Cream Truck Jingle]</i>

251
00:29:16,588 --> 00:29:29,433
♪♪

252
00:29:53,992 --> 00:29:56,187
♪♪ [Ice Cream Truck Jingle
Continues]

253
00:30:32,864 --> 00:30:34,991
[Motor Revs]

254
00:30:49,214 --> 00:30:51,239
Let me tell you right now,
boy and girl...

255
00:30:51,349 --> 00:30:55,513
this beautiful American Truth Way bible
with gilt edges and color pictures...

256
00:30:55,620 --> 00:30:57,611
can be yours
for just $9.95.

257
00:30:57,722 --> 00:30:59,781
Wait, before you say anything,
let me tell you something.

258
00:30:59,891 --> 00:31:02,325
<i>This bible has everything</i>
<i>in it...</i>

259
00:31:02,427 --> 00:31:06,420
<i>from the creation of this beautiful world</i>
<i>of ours to the fall of mankind.</i>

260
00:31:06,531 --> 00:31:09,898
Look, Duncan, just hang out
a little longer, all right?

261
00:31:10,001 --> 00:31:12,561
I gotta find my boy.
Christ knows what's goin' on out there.

262
00:31:12,670 --> 00:31:14,570
Look, man,
you can't even see!

263
00:31:14,672 --> 00:31:16,572
I can see just fine.

264
00:31:16,674 --> 00:31:20,132
I don't wanna pop you one.
You keep yappin' at me, I'm gonna.

265
00:31:21,679 --> 00:31:25,979
- <i>[Billy] Duncan? Duncan?</i>
- [Man] What's he doin'?

266
00:31:26,084 --> 00:31:28,712
- You really goin' after Deke, man?
- Yeah.

267
00:31:28,820 --> 00:31:33,257
How many fingers do you see?
Eight, twelve?

268
00:31:33,358 --> 00:31:37,089
So I got a little double vision,
but it's clearin' up.

269
00:31:37,195 --> 00:31:39,891
I gotta find my boy!

270
00:31:39,998 --> 00:31:41,898
I gotta!

271
00:31:42,000 --> 00:31:46,596
Anything could be goin' on out there.
Christ's sakes!

272
00:31:46,704 --> 00:31:50,800
You leave without punching out...

273
00:31:50,909 --> 00:31:54,072
and you ain't never gonna
have to punch out again, bubba.

274
00:31:54,178 --> 00:31:56,612
Good.

275
00:31:56,714 --> 00:31:58,614
You leave me alone,
you fat fuck!

276
00:31:58,716 --> 00:32:01,014
Yo!
Leave him alone.

277
00:32:02,320 --> 00:32:04,379
Or what?

278
00:32:04,489 --> 00:32:07,390
Or I'll knock
your teeth in... bubba.

279
00:32:08,960 --> 00:32:10,928
<i>[Engine Revs]</i>

280
00:32:24,943 --> 00:32:28,276
<i>[Billy]</i>
<i>Duncan, look out.</i>

281
00:32:31,282 --> 00:32:33,011
<i>My God.</i>

282
00:32:38,656 --> 00:32:41,318
- <i>[Engine Revving]</i>
- It'll give you protection in time of danger.

283
00:32:41,426 --> 00:32:43,758
It'll give you health
in time of sickness.

284
00:32:43,861 --> 00:32:47,024
It'll give you Leviticus...

285
00:32:50,101 --> 00:32:52,535
Oh, sucker!

286
00:32:56,074 --> 00:32:59,043
Son of a bitch!
Outta my way!

287
00:32:59,143 --> 00:33:01,737
[Muttering]

288
00:33:01,846 --> 00:33:04,007
I'm gonna tear 'em up,
boy!

289
00:33:12,490 --> 00:33:15,425
Where the hell are you goin',
you truck son of a bitch?

290
00:33:15,526 --> 00:33:17,994
Get back inside,
you idiot!

291
00:33:18,096 --> 00:33:23,534
Goddamn it, you snotbag!
Come on!

292
00:33:23,634 --> 00:33:29,197
<i>[Man] You scumball.</i>
<i>You wanna rock and roll with me, puss bag?</i>

293
00:33:30,541 --> 00:33:33,009
<i>Right here, you prick.</i>

294
00:33:33,111 --> 00:33:36,205
You lowdown scumball!
I got...

295
00:33:43,554 --> 00:33:47,115
- Get outta the way, you asshole!
- [Shouts]

296
00:34:36,541 --> 00:34:41,979
This is Bubba Hendershot at the Dixie Boy.
Anybody read me? Come in.

297
00:34:42,080 --> 00:34:44,378
<i>Come on in, Rusty.</i>

298
00:34:44,482 --> 00:34:46,950
No one.
No one in the cab of that motherfucker.

299
00:34:47,051 --> 00:34:48,780
Horse pucky!

300
00:34:48,886 --> 00:34:51,411
What are we gonna
do now, huh?

301
00:34:53,558 --> 00:34:55,458
I don't know.

302
00:34:55,560 --> 00:34:58,188
This is Bubba Hendershot
at the Dixie Boy.

303
00:34:58,296 --> 00:35:00,856
Goddamn it, Rusty,
come on in, boy!

304
00:35:00,965 --> 00:35:04,492
Spread it on the ground
next to him.

305
00:35:04,602 --> 00:35:08,800
Hurry up, man,
he's startin' to draw flies.

306
00:35:14,812 --> 00:35:16,973
What the hell
you doin' in there?

307
00:35:17,081 --> 00:35:20,244
Changing.
That salesman had his hands all over me.

308
00:35:20,351 --> 00:35:23,286
And he's dead now.
I don't like the smell of him on me.

309
00:35:23,387 --> 00:35:25,719
<i>I don't like it.</i>

310
00:35:25,823 --> 00:35:28,883
[Chuckling]
Jesus.

311
00:35:33,131 --> 00:35:36,532
For Christ's sake, don't just stand there.
He's dripping over my floor.

312
00:35:36,634 --> 00:35:39,831
- Get him outta here.
- Come on, man.

313
00:35:43,708 --> 00:35:46,939
What the hell are you guys lookin' at?

314
00:35:48,679 --> 00:35:50,579
- Nothin'.
- That's right. Nothin'.

315
00:35:50,681 --> 00:35:53,514
Then go look at it
somewhere else.

316
00:35:57,288 --> 00:35:59,722
[Chuckles]
Okay.

317
00:35:59,824 --> 00:36:02,918
[Engine Revs]

318
00:36:20,178 --> 00:36:23,079
[Engines Revving]

319
00:36:32,523 --> 00:36:36,357
<i>[Truck Horns Honking]</i>

320
00:36:37,461 --> 00:36:39,554
[Honking Continues]

321
00:37:28,613 --> 00:37:33,641
Most of them goddamn things
got no right to be runnin' through this depot.

322
00:38:10,388 --> 00:38:12,822
[Connie]
Where are they going, Curtis?

323
00:38:12,923 --> 00:38:15,687
I don't know.

324
00:38:15,793 --> 00:38:17,852
Greensboro, maybe.

325
00:38:17,962 --> 00:38:20,453
Maybe Charlotte.

326
00:38:21,999 --> 00:38:24,194
Why?

327
00:38:24,302 --> 00:38:26,793
Don't know.

328
00:38:29,740 --> 00:38:32,140
Try the radio again.

329
00:38:35,079 --> 00:38:37,343
<i>[Radio Static]</i>

330
00:38:41,285 --> 00:38:43,185
<i>[Radio Off]</i>

331
00:38:43,287 --> 00:38:46,313
- Look out!
- [Brakes Squealing]

332
00:38:51,829 --> 00:38:55,287
I think I just loaded
my pants.

333
00:38:55,399 --> 00:38:58,562
Curtis? Curtis!

334
00:38:58,669 --> 00:39:01,695
<i>It's comin' after us.</i>

335
00:39:19,290 --> 00:39:22,384
Get going, Curtis!
It's gonna bump us!

336
00:39:32,903 --> 00:39:37,203
<i>[Connie]</i>
<i>Why is this happening?</i>

337
00:40:00,865 --> 00:40:03,663
Hang on!

338
00:40:08,105 --> 00:40:10,335
[Screaming]

339
00:40:13,778 --> 00:40:17,077
Curtis, I never should've
let you drive again!

340
00:40:21,185 --> 00:40:23,085
<i>[Connie]</i>
<i>Curtis.</i>

341
00:40:23,187 --> 00:40:27,089
Make him stop bumping us!

342
00:40:39,170 --> 00:40:42,162
[Brakes Squeal]

343
00:40:48,779 --> 00:40:52,943
- Curtis, what is going on?
- I don't know!

344
00:40:56,854 --> 00:41:00,620
But I know we can call the police
from that truck stop up there.

345
00:41:36,193 --> 00:41:39,219
Oh, my God!

346
00:41:40,931 --> 00:41:44,662
When we get to that truck stop,
everything will be all right.

347
00:41:44,768 --> 00:41:47,532
Oh, yes!
[Laughing]

348
00:41:47,638 --> 00:41:51,802
- [Shifts Gears]
- What are you doing?

349
00:41:51,909 --> 00:41:54,400
You see that gap?

350
00:41:54,512 --> 00:41:58,107
The next time it comes around,
I'm gonna shoot right through it.

351
00:41:58,215 --> 00:42:01,776
No, you don't!
They'll gang up on us and squash us!

352
00:42:01,886 --> 00:42:06,721
- I can do it!
- So we can be inside where they are?

353
00:42:06,824 --> 00:42:10,055
What do you think's gonna happen to us
if we stay out here?

354
00:42:12,530 --> 00:42:14,430
I'm scared.

355
00:42:18,302 --> 00:42:20,202
Me too.

356
00:42:20,304 --> 00:42:24,502
Billy, come here
and look at these fools.

357
00:42:26,110 --> 00:42:29,568
- <i>[Man] Now what?</i>
- They're dead.

358
00:42:29,680 --> 00:42:31,875
- Maybe not.
- Hey, don't go out there.

359
00:42:31,982 --> 00:42:34,644
- Don't, Joe.
- Eat this.

360
00:42:34,752 --> 00:42:38,210
Hang on tight.

361
00:42:54,738 --> 00:42:57,798
<i>[Truck Horns Honking]</i>

362
00:42:59,910 --> 00:43:03,437
<i>[Connie]</i>
<i>Curtis, I'm scrunched up.</i>

363
00:43:03,547 --> 00:43:08,007
<i>Where are you going? Will you get me</i>
<i>outta here? I'm caught in this seat belt.</i>

364
00:43:08,118 --> 00:43:10,643
<i>I'm stuck.</i>
<i>[Shouting Continues]</i>

365
00:43:10,754 --> 00:43:13,450
<i>I told you a thousand times,</i>
<i>"Watch out."</i>

366
00:43:13,557 --> 00:43:16,185
<i>Curtis, will you help me?</i>

367
00:43:16,293 --> 00:43:20,195
Watch that thing, will you? That thing
looks sharp. Will you watch that thing?

368
00:43:20,297 --> 00:43:22,697
<i>He's not my Curtis.</i>
<i>Where is my Curtis?</i>

369
00:43:22,800 --> 00:43:26,201
Shit! I'm sick of this shit!
You goddamn asshole!

370
00:43:26,303 --> 00:43:29,329
Curtis, will you help me?
Help me!

371
00:43:29,440 --> 00:43:33,774
<i>[Connie Screaming]</i>

372
00:43:35,980 --> 00:43:40,383
<i>All right, bubba.</i>
<i>Stick this one up your home sick.</i>

373
00:43:43,187 --> 00:43:45,314
<i>[Hendershot]</i>
<i>Fuckin' truck's to be dee-po'ed.</i>

374
00:43:45,422 --> 00:43:48,016
That one's dee-po'ed
for sure.

375
00:43:48,125 --> 00:43:50,559
<i>[Hendershot]</i>
<i>Reload me, Joey. Reload me, boy.</i>

376
00:43:58,402 --> 00:44:01,997
<i>[Hendershot Laughing]</i>
<i>I want that shit, bubba.</i>

377
00:44:02,106 --> 00:44:04,506
- Connie, run!
- [Screaming]

378
00:44:08,646 --> 00:44:11,809
Oh, honey, you're bleedin'
like a stuck pig.

379
00:44:11,915 --> 00:44:16,352
- Where'd you get that stuff?
- We got a whole bunch...
- Shut up, Joey.

380
00:44:16,453 --> 00:44:20,116
Found it in my Christmas stocking, bubba.

381
00:44:21,725 --> 00:44:24,751
Get inside.
Come on, let's get inside.

382
00:44:50,020 --> 00:44:52,181
[Gasps]

383
00:44:56,694 --> 00:44:59,060
[Crying]

384
00:45:22,786 --> 00:45:25,220
How are the lovebirds?

385
00:45:25,322 --> 00:45:28,052
Heart rates are slowin' down
a little, I think.

386
00:45:28,158 --> 00:45:29,887
That's good.

387
00:45:29,993 --> 00:45:32,518
Mother's helper?

388
00:45:34,598 --> 00:45:37,829
A girl hitchin' her way to Florida
needs some protection.

389
00:45:37,935 --> 00:45:40,961
<i>Yeah?</i>
<i>That's what you're doin'</i>

390
00:45:41,071 --> 00:45:43,938
Yeah.

391
00:45:44,041 --> 00:45:49,502
That's what I was doin' before every machine
went into maximum overdrive.

392
00:45:53,884 --> 00:45:56,250
[Crying]

393
00:45:57,955 --> 00:46:00,253
I'm scared.

394
00:46:09,867 --> 00:46:13,394
If I put my arm
around you...

395
00:46:13,504 --> 00:46:16,098
would you stick me
with that thing?

396
00:46:17,875 --> 00:46:20,844
You don't stick a person
with a straight razor.

397
00:46:20,944 --> 00:46:23,310
It's more like...

398
00:46:25,415 --> 00:46:27,542
And I wouldn't.

399
00:46:38,462 --> 00:46:41,022
- Okay?
- Mmm.

400
00:46:45,002 --> 00:46:47,698
Holy crow!

401
00:47:33,150 --> 00:47:35,050
Joey?

402
00:47:35,152 --> 00:47:37,586
Yeah.

403
00:47:37,688 --> 00:47:42,057
Get up here.

404
00:47:42,159 --> 00:47:46,061
Tell me, man,
does he really got a lot of firepower...

405
00:47:46,163 --> 00:47:48,927
<i>down in the cellar?</i>

406
00:47:49,032 --> 00:47:51,899
You heard him tell me
to shut up, didn't ya?

407
00:47:52,002 --> 00:47:54,630
<i>Come on,</i>
<i>this is serious.</i>

408
00:47:56,073 --> 00:47:57,904
He's got a lot.

409
00:47:58,008 --> 00:48:01,910
- Grenades?
- <i>Well...</i>

410
00:48:02,012 --> 00:48:04,276
Flame throwers?
Rifles? What?

411
00:48:06,984 --> 00:48:09,077
You're gonna get us
in an awful lot of trouble.

412
00:48:11,321 --> 00:48:15,621
In case you didn't realize it, buddy,
we're already in trouble.

413
00:48:17,394 --> 00:48:19,294
Talk to me, Joey.

414
00:48:22,165 --> 00:48:25,657
Everything.
He's got everything.

415
00:48:25,769 --> 00:48:27,794
Now leave me alone, Billy!

416
00:48:30,707 --> 00:48:32,902
Holy shit!

417
00:48:34,711 --> 00:48:38,374
- You think he stole all this?
- No, I think he bought it.

418
00:48:38,482 --> 00:48:42,543
- That's what a guy like him does.
- Buys things.

419
00:48:42,653 --> 00:48:46,589
Buy cheap and sell dear.
It's the American way.

420
00:48:46,690 --> 00:48:49,215
[Screams]

421
00:48:49,326 --> 00:48:54,059
<i>[Hendershot]</i>
<i>Jesus Christ palomino. This is cute, isn't it?</i>

422
00:48:54,164 --> 00:48:56,826
<i>You find any money on him, bubba?</i>

423
00:49:00,337 --> 00:49:04,364
I don't know what to make of you, boy.
You're bright. I know you are.

424
00:49:06,009 --> 00:49:08,170
You keep on being obtuse.

425
00:49:08,278 --> 00:49:11,372
We don't wanna steal anything.
We just wanna get outta here alive.

426
00:49:11,481 --> 00:49:15,645
You messin', bubba,
where you hadn't ought to be messin'.

427
00:49:15,752 --> 00:49:21,156
Sometimes even college boys don't learn
their lessons till they had their chops busted.

428
00:49:21,258 --> 00:49:23,954
You know what's goin' on outside, huh?
You blind?

429
00:49:24,061 --> 00:49:28,964
You tell little road twitch
about your illustrious career?

430
00:49:29,066 --> 00:49:33,560
He's a bloodthirsty criminal.
A regular John Dillinger.

431
00:49:33,670 --> 00:49:35,365
Goddamn you.

432
00:49:35,472 --> 00:49:39,033
Couple of Charlotte cops caught him
in this little bitty grocery store.

433
00:49:39,142 --> 00:49:43,442
Sack of money in his hand.
Thumb up his ass. Big grin on his face.

434
00:49:43,547 --> 00:49:47,347
- You wanna get outta here,
one call, I get you out.
- Who you gonna call?

435
00:49:47,451 --> 00:49:49,646
The North Carolina
state police?

436
00:49:49,753 --> 00:49:53,746
I don't wanna play any goddamn games
with you. I just wanna get the hell outta here.

437
00:49:53,857 --> 00:49:56,052
I'm warnin' you, boy.

438
00:49:56,159 --> 00:49:58,650
No, I'm warning you.

439
00:50:04,601 --> 00:50:08,503
This thing's over,
your ass is grass.

440
00:50:10,440 --> 00:50:14,501
Grass, you hear me?
Joey?

441
00:50:16,513 --> 00:50:20,540
Goddamn you, Joey!
I told you to keep an eye on them keys!

442
00:50:20,650 --> 00:50:23,619
I owed a guy some money.

443
00:50:25,455 --> 00:50:28,652
I was about 20 at the time.

444
00:50:28,759 --> 00:50:31,421
Not real bright
about most things.

445
00:50:31,528 --> 00:50:33,996
- Hey, it's all right.
- No, it's not.

446
00:50:37,567 --> 00:50:40,900
You know what gets to me?
Is the stupidity.

447
00:50:44,608 --> 00:50:47,600
Cops put that spotlight on me,
and I just froze like a rabbit.

448
00:50:47,711 --> 00:50:51,044
Hey! Hey!

449
00:50:54,084 --> 00:50:56,109
It's all right.

450
00:51:11,401 --> 00:51:16,100
<i>[Truck Engines Revving]</i>

451
00:51:51,741 --> 00:51:54,005
[Giggling]

452
00:51:56,713 --> 00:51:59,841
- [Brett] I'll tell you one thing.
- [Billy] What's that?

453
00:51:59,950 --> 00:52:03,647
You sure make love
like a hero.

454
00:52:25,008 --> 00:52:27,135
Wow.

455
00:52:27,244 --> 00:52:29,144
Look at that light.

456
00:52:29,246 --> 00:52:32,613
- <i>[Brett] You know what I think?</i>
- <i>What?</i>

457
00:52:32,716 --> 00:52:35,014
<i>I think it's the comet.</i>

458
00:52:36,353 --> 00:52:39,186
<i>We've been in its tail</i>
<i>for almost 12 hours.</i>

459
00:52:39,289 --> 00:52:41,917
<i>If it is that comet</i>
<i>that's making everything go crazy...</i>

460
00:52:42,025 --> 00:52:44,994
<i>then all we gotta do is stay alive</i>
<i>for the next seven days.</i>

461
00:52:46,830 --> 00:52:48,855
No problem.

462
00:52:52,903 --> 00:52:54,837
[Sighs]

463
00:53:05,148 --> 00:53:07,708
- I got an idea.
- Hmm?

464
00:53:18,495 --> 00:53:23,523
- Can you sail?
- A little. Hobie cats and things like that.

465
00:53:23,633 --> 00:53:26,761
Mm-hmm, good deal.
I used to crew the big ones.

466
00:53:27,904 --> 00:53:30,600
Sailboats. No motors.

467
00:53:30,707 --> 00:53:34,040
- No motors?
- Uh-uh.

468
00:53:34,144 --> 00:53:38,103
- Where would we go?
- I've been thinkin' about
this place called Haven.

469
00:53:38,215 --> 00:53:41,946
It's an island about,
about six miles off the coast.

470
00:53:42,052 --> 00:53:46,751
There aren't any motor vehicles allowed.
None whatsoever.

471
00:53:46,856 --> 00:53:49,950
- None?
- Uh-uh.

472
00:53:50,060 --> 00:53:52,051
You know...

473
00:53:52,162 --> 00:53:56,258
you are not only a hero...

474
00:53:56,366 --> 00:53:59,267
you are a genius.

475
00:54:05,742 --> 00:54:08,142
<i>♪♪ [Rock]</i>

476
00:54:08,245 --> 00:54:21,955
♪♪

477
00:54:23,827 --> 00:54:26,295
[Rumbling]

478
00:54:30,834 --> 00:54:33,803
The whole goddamn world's
goin' tits up.

479
00:54:33,903 --> 00:54:37,771
They can't.
We made them!

480
00:54:37,874 --> 00:54:40,707
Look, you've gone and hurt yourself.
Come on, sweet thing.

481
00:54:40,810 --> 00:54:43,005
Don't you "sweet thing" me!

482
00:54:43,113 --> 00:54:45,206
- Wanda June baby...
- They can't!

483
00:54:45,315 --> 00:54:49,183
We made them.

484
00:54:50,920 --> 00:54:55,380
You can't!
We made you!

485
00:54:58,895 --> 00:55:03,855
<i>Where's your sense of loyalty?</i>
<i>You pukey thing.</i>

486
00:55:03,967 --> 00:55:07,164
We made you!

487
00:55:07,270 --> 00:55:11,536
We made you!
We made you!

488
00:55:13,643 --> 00:55:15,770
We made you!

489
00:55:15,879 --> 00:55:19,679
- We made them! We made them!
- Hey! Hey!

490
00:55:19,783 --> 00:55:24,049
<i>[Truck Horns Honking]</i>

491
00:55:33,496 --> 00:55:37,899
Oh, God, not the dark!
Please, God, don't...

492
00:55:39,703 --> 00:55:42,831
Oh, I'm scared.

493
00:55:42,939 --> 00:55:45,874
Please don't leave us
in the dark.

494
00:55:50,347 --> 00:55:54,647
<i>[Spoons Tapping Cup]</i>

495
00:55:54,751 --> 00:55:57,948
<i>[Man]</i>
<i>Man, stop with them damn spoons.</i>

496
00:55:58,054 --> 00:56:00,045
It's safer
than the jukebox.

497
00:56:00,156 --> 00:56:02,056
I like spoons.

498
00:56:05,161 --> 00:56:08,824
Man, this is one piece of shit!
Shit.

499
00:56:10,467 --> 00:56:13,766
Damn trucks ain't never
gonna let us out of here.

500
00:56:13,870 --> 00:56:17,931
[Giggling]

501
00:56:23,480 --> 00:56:25,971
- [Dishes Rattle]
- Ahh! [Giggling]

502
00:56:27,650 --> 00:56:31,518
- Place your bets.
- <i>I don't usually play for peanuts.</i>

503
00:56:31,621 --> 00:56:34,920
- Come on.
- Hmm.

504
00:56:35,024 --> 00:56:38,221
- I gotta eat.
- Deal, woman.

505
00:56:41,131 --> 00:56:43,031
Hit me.

506
00:56:46,603 --> 00:56:49,470
There's lots less
of 'em.

507
00:56:49,572 --> 00:56:54,669
<i>[Billy]</i>
<i>Yeah. Looks like they're runnin' dry.</i>

508
00:56:54,778 --> 00:56:58,077
I think they're
pushin' 'em in back.

509
00:57:00,183 --> 00:57:03,414
Maybe tomorrow
it'll be our world again.

510
00:57:03,520 --> 00:57:06,546
I don't know.

511
00:57:06,656 --> 00:57:09,090
Was it ever?

512
00:57:09,192 --> 00:57:11,319
I hate those
fuckin' trucks.

513
00:57:11,428 --> 00:57:13,328
I never did like trucks
anyway!

514
00:57:13,430 --> 00:57:16,297
- <i>[Groaning Sound]</i>
- Holy shit!

515
00:57:16,399 --> 00:57:20,199
- <i>[Groaning Continues]</i>
- <i>[Curt] What was that?</i>

516
00:57:20,303 --> 00:57:24,034
<i>[Brett] Oh, God.</i>
<i>That's that bible salesman I rode in with.</i>

517
00:57:24,140 --> 00:57:27,200
There's some guy
out there?

518
00:57:27,310 --> 00:57:30,939
<i>[Bible Salesman]</i>
<i>Sweet Jesus, help me.</i>

519
00:57:31,047 --> 00:57:35,381
<i>Help. Help me.</i>

520
00:57:35,485 --> 00:57:38,977
<i>[Groaning Continues]</i>

521
00:57:39,088 --> 00:57:41,682
[Gasps]

522
00:57:43,293 --> 00:57:45,989
- Let's go get him.
- No, you don't!

523
00:57:46,095 --> 00:57:48,689
You let those other big, strong men
go out and get him.

524
00:57:48,798 --> 00:57:51,289
<i>[Trucker]</i>
<i>I didn't sign on here to be no hero.</i>

525
00:57:51,401 --> 00:57:54,165
Yeah.

526
00:57:54,270 --> 00:57:57,467
Wait a second, man.
Wait up!

527
00:57:57,574 --> 00:58:01,305
It's like the old joke.
You can't get there from here.

528
00:58:01,411 --> 00:58:04,380
We gonna stand around
and listen to him do that?

529
00:58:04,481 --> 00:58:07,575
There might be a way
to get to him.

530
00:58:41,551 --> 00:58:44,679
<i>[Trucks Rumbling Overhead]</i>

531
00:58:51,728 --> 00:58:55,664
<i>[Rumbling Continues]</i>

532
00:59:03,573 --> 00:59:07,634
Now, that shower drain runs
into the ditch where that guy is.

533
00:59:07,744 --> 00:59:10,235
- Will we fit?
- One way to find out.

534
00:59:10,346 --> 00:59:13,144
- You boys are crazy.
- <i>[Connie] Curt.</i>

535
00:59:13,249 --> 00:59:17,310
<i>Curtis. Curtis.</i>

536
00:59:17,420 --> 00:59:20,878
- What are you doin'?
- I'll be right back.

537
00:59:20,990 --> 00:59:24,255
- You ain't goin'!
- There's a man layin' hurt out there.

538
00:59:24,360 --> 00:59:27,625
There's gonna be a man layin' hurt in here
if you don't quit this foolishness.

539
00:59:27,730 --> 00:59:30,995
- If it was your man out there,
you'd want someone to go.
- Well, it ain't.

540
00:59:31,100 --> 00:59:34,866
- You're not going.
- I'm going.

541
00:59:34,971 --> 00:59:39,965
- Don't make me a widow
on my weddin' day, Curtis.
- Okay.

542
00:59:40,076 --> 00:59:42,601
No reason why
we can't scoot across.

543
00:59:42,712 --> 00:59:47,376
- <i>Pick up your feet and try not to shuffle.</i>
- <i>I can handle it.</i>

544
00:59:47,483 --> 00:59:51,852
<i>[Hendershot] You boys are just crazy</i>
<i>as a couple of rats in a plugged-up shithouse.</i>

545
00:59:51,955 --> 00:59:54,515
And you, sir,
are without a doubt...

546
00:59:54,624 --> 00:59:58,287
one of the biggest fuck heads
I've ever met in my life.

547
00:59:58,394 --> 01:00:03,297
Wish me luck.
You ready? Let's do it.

548
01:00:34,697 --> 01:00:37,029
Good thing that one
was out of gas.

549
01:00:37,133 --> 01:00:40,466
What makes you so sure
that it was?

550
01:00:40,570 --> 01:00:43,038
I don't think we need to worry
about that right now.

551
01:01:22,679 --> 01:01:24,579
Man, you ready?

552
01:01:24,681 --> 01:01:26,706
One, two, three.

553
01:01:35,558 --> 01:01:38,789
Bombs away!

554
01:01:46,002 --> 01:01:49,938
- Think it'll hold?
- Fucked if I know.

555
01:02:11,094 --> 01:02:13,324
- You okay?
- Yeah.

556
01:02:13,429 --> 01:02:17,160
- Wanna grab that bag?
- Thanks.

557
01:02:17,266 --> 01:02:21,168
Jeez, this sucker
weighs a ton.

558
01:02:21,270 --> 01:02:23,500
<i>Oh, boy.</i>

559
01:02:29,712 --> 01:02:31,612
Great smell, huh?

560
01:02:31,714 --> 01:02:34,410
You okay?

561
01:02:34,517 --> 01:02:37,384
Yeah, uh-huh.

562
01:02:41,457 --> 01:02:43,755
Wonder how many people
have peed in this.

563
01:02:49,265 --> 01:02:52,166
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.

564
01:02:52,268 --> 01:02:55,203
How's it taste?

565
01:02:55,304 --> 01:02:58,000
[Laughs]

566
01:03:06,716 --> 01:03:08,877
Oh, shit.
Hey, I'm sending you a friend.

567
01:03:08,985 --> 01:03:11,954
<i>Oh, shit.</i>

568
01:03:12,054 --> 01:03:14,215
<i>Get out of here.</i>

569
01:03:56,199 --> 01:03:58,099
Mister?

570
01:04:25,828 --> 01:04:30,094
[Screams]

571
01:04:30,199 --> 01:04:33,760
- <i>Help me.</i>
- How?

572
01:04:33,870 --> 01:04:36,634
Pull me. Pull me!

573
01:04:36,739 --> 01:04:38,707
I can't.
You're too heavy.

574
01:04:38,808 --> 01:04:42,539
<i>Get me out of this ditch,</i>
<i>or by Jesus...</i>

575
01:04:42,645 --> 01:04:45,239
I'll kill you.

576
01:04:50,586 --> 01:04:52,611
Ahh! Shit!

577
01:04:52,722 --> 01:04:55,555
What a great time!
Wish I could do that every day. What a blast.

578
01:04:55,658 --> 01:04:59,924
<i>[Deke]</i>
<i>Bill. Bill. Help me, Bill.</i>

579
01:05:00,029 --> 01:05:02,054
- Jesus Christ, that's Deke.
- Who?

580
01:05:02,164 --> 01:05:04,758
Help me.

581
01:05:04,867 --> 01:05:07,062
- Come on.
- <i>Please, help me.</i>

582
01:05:11,073 --> 01:05:14,565
- Stop! Stop pulling me.
- He's dead.

583
01:05:14,677 --> 01:05:18,113
- <i>[Deke] No, he isn't.</i>
- <i>He's dead.</i>

584
01:05:18,214 --> 01:05:20,944
<i>He's dead.</i>
<i>He's dead.</i>

585
01:05:21,050 --> 01:05:25,111
I'm going, I'm going!

586
01:05:27,456 --> 01:05:31,688
- Bill, you okay, bud?
- <i>Yeah, I'm okay.</i>
<i>Move your ass, for Christ sake.</i>

587
01:05:39,769 --> 01:05:41,669
Okay.

588
01:05:43,706 --> 01:05:47,506
All right.
Let's go.

589
01:05:47,610 --> 01:05:49,669
Bill?

590
01:05:53,316 --> 01:05:57,082
Bill, is my dad okay?

591
01:06:00,356 --> 01:06:02,290
Come on.

592
01:06:06,295 --> 01:06:08,422
Let's go, partner.

593
01:06:10,666 --> 01:06:14,124
<i>[Connie]</i>
<i>I think that truck got 'em. That's what I think.</i>

594
01:06:14,236 --> 01:06:17,171
I think they're dead.

595
01:06:17,273 --> 01:06:19,173
No, they're all right.

596
01:06:19,275 --> 01:06:21,607
- Then where are they?
- There they are!

597
01:06:21,711 --> 01:06:23,611
<i>They just came out.</i>

598
01:06:23,713 --> 01:06:27,843
<i>[Hendershot]</i>
<i>That ain't no salesman. That's Duncan's kid.</i>

599
01:06:27,950 --> 01:06:31,545
- <i>[Truck Engine Revving]</i>
- Go! Go!

600
01:06:38,494 --> 01:06:40,052
Yeah!

601
01:06:40,162 --> 01:06:44,155
[Laughing]
Yee-haw!

602
01:06:44,266 --> 01:06:46,257
- <i>[Man] Way to go, Billy.</i>
- <i>Attaboy.</i>

603
01:06:48,170 --> 01:06:53,130
<i>You ain't gonna be satisfied until</i>
<i>you get 'em right in here with us, are you?</i>

604
01:06:53,242 --> 01:06:56,609
Cigar, Joey.

605
01:06:56,712 --> 01:07:00,273
<i>[Joe] Mr. Hendershot,</i>
<i>did you see how he nailed that big sucker?</i>

606
01:07:00,383 --> 01:07:04,615
You okay?
How'd you find the kid?

607
01:07:04,720 --> 01:07:06,620
Bill, where's my dad?

608
01:07:09,158 --> 01:07:12,559
Dunc got scrubbed
by one of them big boys out there.

609
01:07:12,661 --> 01:07:16,620
- <i>Tough break, kid.</i>
- You unbelievable shithead!

610
01:07:23,739 --> 01:07:25,639
Is it true?

611
01:07:28,344 --> 01:07:32,747
Is it true?

612
01:07:32,848 --> 01:07:35,646
Yeah, it's true.

613
01:07:39,355 --> 01:07:43,883
No. No.

614
01:07:43,993 --> 01:07:46,655
Hey, hey, hey.
No, no, no, no.

615
01:07:46,762 --> 01:07:49,629
Hang on.
Hang on, Deke.

616
01:07:49,732 --> 01:07:51,632
Mr. Hendershot?

617
01:07:54,737 --> 01:07:57,467
Just a little lesson in manners
from the road twitch.

618
01:07:59,508 --> 01:08:02,966
- [Sobbing]
- Hold on, Deke.

619
01:08:15,791 --> 01:08:18,157
[Snoring]

620
01:09:06,175 --> 01:09:09,633
- <i>[Knocking]</i>
- <i>Bill. Bill.</i>

621
01:09:09,745 --> 01:09:12,714
Bill, you gotta wake up.
There's something out there.

622
01:09:12,815 --> 01:09:16,046
Come on, Bill, wake up. There's something
out there. You gotta see this.

623
01:09:16,152 --> 01:09:18,052
Come on, wake up.

624
01:09:35,771 --> 01:09:39,036
Come on.
It's right up here.

625
01:09:56,292 --> 01:09:59,125
What the fuck
is goin' on here?

626
01:10:06,969 --> 01:10:08,960
Now what?

627
01:10:52,748 --> 01:10:54,648
<i>Holy God.</i>

628
01:10:54,750 --> 01:10:58,083
<i>[Hendershot]</i>
<i>All right.</i>

629
01:10:58,187 --> 01:11:00,121
All right, Goddamn it!

630
01:11:20,609 --> 01:11:23,169
You want a war...

631
01:11:23,279 --> 01:11:25,179
- <i>you got one.</i>
- I wouldn't do that.

632
01:11:25,281 --> 01:11:28,944
- Shut up, bubba.
- Shit! Down, down!

633
01:11:32,388 --> 01:11:37,325
How do you like that chickenshit?
[Laughing]

634
01:11:37,426 --> 01:11:40,725
- [Machine Gun Firing]
- <i>Keep your heads down.</i>

635
01:12:11,493 --> 01:12:13,927
[Growling Sound]

636
01:12:17,633 --> 01:12:21,364
- What the shit's goin' on, man?
- It stopped, man.

637
01:12:41,757 --> 01:12:44,157
You sons of bitches!

638
01:13:09,084 --> 01:13:13,214
- <i>[Steve] Wanda, no.</i>
- Sons of bitches!

639
01:13:13,322 --> 01:13:15,950
Wanda, no!
Let go of me!

640
01:13:16,058 --> 01:13:20,518
- We made you! Can't you understand?
- <i>[Steve] Wanda, no.</i>

641
01:13:20,629 --> 01:13:24,258
You can't do this!
We made you!

642
01:13:24,366 --> 01:13:27,164
- [Machine Gun Fire]
- Wanda!

643
01:13:37,112 --> 01:13:41,105
<i>Wanda. Wanda.</i>
<i>That's Wanda June out there.</i>

644
01:13:41,216 --> 01:13:43,946
That's Wanda June!

645
01:13:44,052 --> 01:13:47,579
- Deke, Goddamn it,
you're gonna get killed. Stay down.
- It's right there.

646
01:13:47,689 --> 01:13:52,183
- <i>If it wants to waste us, it will.</i>
- <i>[Honking]</i>

647
01:13:56,432 --> 01:13:59,196
[Honking Continues]

648
01:14:02,638 --> 01:14:06,404
<i>[Honking Continues]</i>

649
01:14:08,444 --> 01:14:10,605
Now what is it doing?

650
01:14:10,712 --> 01:14:13,476
It's Morse.

651
01:14:13,582 --> 01:14:16,278
- <i>Bullshit.</i>
- No, really.

652
01:14:16,385 --> 01:14:19,445
I should know.
I got a merit badge in it this spring.

653
01:14:19,555 --> 01:14:21,455
<i>What's it sayin', kid?</i>

654
01:14:21,557 --> 01:14:24,890
<i>[Honking Continues]</i>

655
01:14:24,993 --> 01:14:27,461
Gimme a pen.
I can't keep up with it.

656
01:14:40,108 --> 01:14:44,044
[Honking]

657
01:14:44,146 --> 01:14:47,240
<i>[Brett]</i>
<i>Incredible.</i>

658
01:14:47,349 --> 01:14:49,579
- <i>They want us to feed 'em.</i>
- <i>Feed 'em?</i>

659
01:14:49,685 --> 01:14:53,519
Fuck 'em. Let 'em starve.
Half of 'em's out of gas already.

660
01:14:53,622 --> 01:14:55,522
Let 'em starve.
It won't take long.

661
01:14:55,624 --> 01:14:59,082
<i>[Honking Continues]</i>

662
01:15:01,697 --> 01:15:04,894
<i>Can't fill 'em anyway.</i>
<i>We ain't got no power.</i>

663
01:15:07,302 --> 01:15:10,863
- <i>Aw, shit.</i>
- There's your power.

664
01:15:10,973 --> 01:15:12,873
How'd they do that?

665
01:15:12,975 --> 01:15:16,502
I'll be damned.
I'm gonna turn on the pumps.

666
01:15:16,612 --> 01:15:20,480
I hope none of them left home
without their American Express cards.

667
01:15:22,518 --> 01:15:25,316
[Brett]
Bill, wait.

668
01:15:29,424 --> 01:15:31,824
Wait.
You can't do this.

669
01:15:31,927 --> 01:15:35,920
It's not a good idea. It's like
Neville Chamberlain giving in to the Nazis.

670
01:15:36,031 --> 01:15:38,727
I gotta show you something.
Come here.

671
01:15:38,834 --> 01:15:41,234
Okay, now you see
that one?

672
01:15:41,336 --> 01:15:44,032
- <i>Yes, I do.</i>
- <i>Now, look, here's the way I figure it.</i>

673
01:15:44,139 --> 01:15:46,039
<i>The big guys,</i>
<i>they're heavyweights.</i>

674
01:15:46,141 --> 01:15:49,133
They crash in here, they're gonna break
through the floor and end up in the cellar.

675
01:15:49,244 --> 01:15:51,303
But that bastard,
ain't no reason...

676
01:15:51,413 --> 01:15:55,577
why he couldn't call in a truck full of Napalm
and hose this place down.

677
01:15:55,684 --> 01:15:59,381
- Just take care of yourself, okay?
- What are they gonna do?

678
01:15:59,488 --> 01:16:01,513
Run me down?

679
01:16:01,623 --> 01:16:04,615
That'd be like a junkie
trying to run down his connection.

680
01:16:11,166 --> 01:16:13,691
[Sighs]

681
01:17:20,335 --> 01:17:22,530
All right, you bastard.

682
01:17:24,139 --> 01:17:28,337
Tell all your friends
the main line's open.

683
01:17:28,443 --> 01:17:32,209
I got the best shit on the east coast,
practically uncut.

684
01:17:34,383 --> 01:17:36,317
You got that,
fuck face?

685
01:17:41,523 --> 01:17:45,823
[Engine Revs]

686
01:17:58,473 --> 01:18:01,169
<i>[Bell Ringing]</i>

687
01:18:03,345 --> 01:18:05,745
<i>[Bell Ringing Continues]</i>

688
01:18:05,847 --> 01:18:07,940
This could be
a very long day.

689
01:18:27,135 --> 01:18:31,265
<i>[Male Singer]</i>
<i>♪ I'm a rolling thunder, a pouring rain ♪</i>

690
01:18:32,974 --> 01:18:36,603
- <i>♪ I'm comin' on like a hurricane ♪</i>
- All set, big guy.

691
01:18:36,712 --> 01:18:40,773
<i>♪ My lightning's flashing</i>
<i>across the sky ♪</i>

692
01:18:40,882 --> 01:18:45,478
<i>♪ You're only young</i>
<i>but you're gonna die ♪</i>

693
01:18:45,587 --> 01:18:49,079
<i>♪ I won't take no prisoners</i>
<i>Won't spare no lives ♪</i>

694
01:18:50,258 --> 01:18:54,319
<i>♪ Nobody's putting up a fight ♪</i>

695
01:18:54,429 --> 01:18:58,991
<i>♪ I got my bell</i>
<i>I'm gonna take you to hell ♪</i>

696
01:18:59,101 --> 01:19:02,969
<i>♪ I 'm gonna get you</i>
<i>Satan get you ♪</i>

697
01:19:03,071 --> 01:19:05,335
<i>♪ Hells bells ♪</i>

698
01:19:06,975 --> 01:19:09,307
<i>♪ Yeah, hells bells ♪</i>

699
01:19:10,512 --> 01:19:14,004
<i>♪ You got me ringing</i>
<i>hells bells ♪</i>

700
01:19:14,116 --> 01:19:16,584
- <i>[Truck Horn Honking]</i>
- <i>♪ My temperature's high, hells bells ♪</i>

701
01:19:16,685 --> 01:19:20,086
Shut up, already!
You ain't doin' so bad here.

702
01:19:20,188 --> 01:19:23,123
There!
Suck on that!

703
01:19:28,797 --> 01:19:30,992
I'll take over now.

704
01:19:33,735 --> 01:19:37,398
Thanks.

705
01:19:37,506 --> 01:19:40,407
I hope they choke on it.

706
01:20:05,300 --> 01:20:09,634
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>Satan's comin' to you ♪</i>

707
01:20:09,738 --> 01:20:13,936
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>He's ringin' them now ♪</i>

708
01:20:14,042 --> 01:20:18,604
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>The temperature's high ♪</i>

709
01:20:18,713 --> 01:20:22,979
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>across the sky ♪</i>

710
01:20:23,084 --> 01:20:27,521
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>They're takin' you down ♪</i>

711
01:20:27,622 --> 01:20:32,025
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>They're draggin' you around ♪</i>

712
01:20:32,127 --> 01:20:36,393
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>gonna split the night ♪</i>

713
01:20:36,498 --> 01:20:41,629
<i>♪ Hells bells</i>
<i>There's no way to fight ♪♪</i>

714
01:20:44,673 --> 01:20:47,870
<i>[Bell Ringing]</i>

715
01:20:49,878 --> 01:20:51,778
Sorry, guys.

716
01:20:53,348 --> 01:20:56,010
If was fun while it lasted,
but we're all out.

717
01:20:56,117 --> 01:20:59,143
[Trucks Honking]

718
01:21:01,323 --> 01:21:04,554
[All Trucks Honking]

719
01:21:18,373 --> 01:21:21,604
What?
What do you want?

720
01:21:32,053 --> 01:21:34,578
- [Honks]
- What?

721
01:21:34,689 --> 01:21:37,283
- What's it doing?
- I don't know.

722
01:22:42,390 --> 01:22:44,654
Hey, Billy.

723
01:22:44,759 --> 01:22:47,523
Hey. Billy!

724
01:22:47,629 --> 01:22:49,529
Come on.
I'll take over here.

725
01:22:49,631 --> 01:22:51,758
He's all done, man.

726
01:22:51,866 --> 01:22:55,302
- They don't understand.
- What's that, Billy?

727
01:22:55,403 --> 01:22:58,497
How it is
to get tired.

728
01:22:58,606 --> 01:23:01,131
How a man gets tired.

729
01:23:02,944 --> 01:23:05,208
Why should they?
Come on.

730
01:23:05,313 --> 01:23:08,407
If you need any help,
you call me.

731
01:23:08,516 --> 01:23:11,679
I will.
Come on, man, let's go.

732
01:23:13,822 --> 01:23:15,847
We've been puttin' stuff
down in the cellar.

733
01:23:15,957 --> 01:23:18,255
The kid said there's
a big sewer pipe down there.

734
01:23:18,360 --> 01:23:21,989
He couldn't get in because of the wire
and shit, but we can use it to get out.

735
01:23:22,097 --> 01:23:24,657
<i>[Engine Revving]</i>

736
01:23:27,902 --> 01:23:30,530
<i>[Handy]</i>
<i>Looks like the coffee break's over.</i>

737
01:23:30,638 --> 01:23:33,573
His master's voice.

738
01:23:33,675 --> 01:23:37,611
- Go on, Billy. Go on in and lay down now.
- All right.

739
01:23:49,724 --> 01:23:52,522
It isn't the comet, you know.
It's a broom.

740
01:23:52,627 --> 01:23:55,528
- What?
- Broom.

741
01:24:01,436 --> 01:24:06,203
Imagine you're a,
you're a race of aliens, right?

742
01:24:06,307 --> 01:24:11,574
And you're looking for
a new place to live.

743
01:24:11,679 --> 01:24:13,579
Say you're looking
for a planet.

744
01:24:13,681 --> 01:24:17,617
Like you and I, you know?
Like we looked for a new place to live?

745
01:24:17,719 --> 01:24:19,778
<i>A new house or something.</i>

746
01:24:19,888 --> 01:24:22,789
So here's Earth.

747
01:24:24,192 --> 01:24:28,356
Only it's like
this big ol' house...

748
01:24:28,463 --> 01:24:30,727
and it's kind of polluted.

749
01:24:34,269 --> 01:24:36,328
<i>Dirty and smoky.</i>

750
01:24:36,438 --> 01:24:39,066
Grease on the walls.

751
01:24:39,174 --> 01:24:41,074
Soot in the chimney.

752
01:24:43,711 --> 01:24:46,373
- And they send in...
- Shh.

753
01:24:46,481 --> 01:24:49,917
Their interstellar
house cleaners.

754
01:24:50,018 --> 01:24:52,418
Send in their broom...

755
01:24:56,958 --> 01:24:59,188
sweep us all up.

756
01:25:00,895 --> 01:25:03,022
That's what it is.
It's a broom...

757
01:25:03,131 --> 01:25:08,068
<i>using our own machines</i>
<i>to sweep us right off.</i>

758
01:25:23,485 --> 01:25:26,682
Hey, mister!
Mister!

759
01:25:30,258 --> 01:25:32,158
<i>Come over here.</i>

760
01:25:42,170 --> 01:25:46,334
- How ya doin'?
- I'm tired and I'm scared.

761
01:25:46,441 --> 01:25:48,341
I got us a plan.

762
01:25:51,813 --> 01:25:56,113
- [Curt] Come on with that thing.
- Son of a bitch!

763
01:25:59,521 --> 01:26:02,422
We ain't never gonna get out of here,
are we, really?

764
01:26:02,524 --> 01:26:04,754
Whoa!
Cool it, champ.

765
01:26:04,859 --> 01:26:06,850
Little peep business
to take care of.

766
01:26:06,961 --> 01:26:09,361
Something you wouldn't understand.

767
01:26:11,099 --> 01:26:14,967
Now, when I say "run,"
you run, okay?

768
01:26:15,069 --> 01:26:17,970
- What you gonna do?
- Don't worry about it. Just run, okay?

769
01:26:18,072 --> 01:26:19,972
What you gonna do?

770
01:26:23,711 --> 01:26:27,545
- Run!
- [Machine Gun Fire]

771
01:26:33,788 --> 01:26:35,847
<i>[Brett Laughing]</i>

772
01:26:35,957 --> 01:26:39,518
<i>I ain't never seen a hero</i>
<i>with his ass in the air like that.</i>

773
01:26:44,732 --> 01:26:47,758
- Hi, babe.
- <i>[Bullets Ricocheting]</i>

774
01:26:59,480 --> 01:27:04,543
I bet there's spiders down there.
I hate anything with more than four legs.

775
01:27:04,652 --> 01:27:08,554
I can't do this!
Oh, don't drop me now!

776
01:27:08,656 --> 01:27:13,025
<i>I'm delicate.</i>
<i>I'm just gonna keep...</i>

777
01:27:13,127 --> 01:27:17,655
<i>[Connie Chattering Indistinct]</i>

778
01:27:17,765 --> 01:27:22,725
Oh, my God.
Look at me. I am a mess!

779
01:27:25,240 --> 01:27:28,368
<i>[Connie]</i>
<i>Dang. I wish we could get out of here.</i>

780
01:27:38,019 --> 01:27:41,455
Holy shit!

781
01:27:41,556 --> 01:27:44,116
- Stay down.
- Oh, my Lordy.

782
01:28:46,654 --> 01:28:49,316
Jesus is coming
and He is pissed.

783
01:29:07,308 --> 01:29:11,244
- Can we get outta here?
- Yeah, I think it's time to get out of here.

784
01:29:11,346 --> 01:29:13,644
Let's go, gang.

785
01:29:47,915 --> 01:29:52,477
Oh, my God.
That son of a bitch is goin' up, isn't it?

786
01:30:02,330 --> 01:30:06,733
- God almighty!
- Come on, let's go.

787
01:30:06,834 --> 01:30:09,302
Come on, go, go, go!

788
01:30:35,163 --> 01:30:39,998
<i>[Truck Engine Revving]</i>

789
01:31:03,391 --> 01:31:07,122
- How far, Bill?
- To the marina?

790
01:31:07,228 --> 01:31:09,219
We're close.
About a half a mile.

791
01:31:09,330 --> 01:31:11,230
<i>[Voice Over Speaker]</i>
<i>Humans here. Humans here.</i>

792
01:31:11,332 --> 01:31:14,301
Humans here.
Humans here. Humans here.

793
01:31:14,402 --> 01:31:17,269
<i>Humans here. Humans here.</i>
<i>Humans here.</i>

794
01:31:17,371 --> 01:31:20,101
<i>Humans here.</i>
<i>Humans here. Humans here.</i>

795
01:31:20,208 --> 01:31:23,666
<i>Humans here. Humans here.</i>
<i>Humans here.</i>

796
01:31:23,778 --> 01:31:26,303
This is for my dad,
you loudmouthed son of a bitch.

797
01:31:35,189 --> 01:31:37,350
I don't want this
anymore.

798
01:31:43,130 --> 01:31:46,156
♪♪ [Ice Cream Truck]

799
01:31:48,369 --> 01:31:50,929
- <i>[Curt] I got him.</i>
- Curt!

800
01:31:51,038 --> 01:31:53,370
<i>[Connie]</i>
<i>Curtis.</i>

801
01:31:54,942 --> 01:31:57,934
♪♪ [Ice Cream Truck]

802
01:32:12,793 --> 01:32:15,921
Hurry. Come on,
get in the boat.

803
01:32:22,236 --> 01:32:25,694
That's it right there.
That's the one I was thinking about.

804
01:32:25,806 --> 01:32:29,037
<i>[Curt]</i>
<i>We better hurry up. It's getting light.</i>

805
01:32:53,601 --> 01:32:57,059
Come on,
hustle, hustle!

806
01:32:57,171 --> 01:32:58,934
[Brett]
Bill, where's Brad?

807
01:33:12,119 --> 01:33:15,213
[Engine Revving]

808
01:33:16,390 --> 01:33:19,382
<i>[Screaming]</i>

809
01:33:25,600 --> 01:33:27,158
Adios, motherfucker!

810
01:33:28,703 --> 01:33:31,831
<i>[Cheering]</i>

811
01:33:54,128 --> 01:33:56,926
Brett, mother's helper.

812
01:33:59,700 --> 01:34:03,500
<i>[Deke] Come here.</i>
<i>Somebody help me with this thing.</i>

813
01:34:06,307 --> 01:34:10,004
<i>♪ Who made who</i>
<i>Who made you ♪</i>

814
01:34:10,111 --> 01:34:12,011
<i>♪ If you made them</i>
<i>and they made you ♪</i>

815
01:34:12,113 --> 01:34:15,708
<i>♪ Who picked up the bill</i>
<i>and who made who ♪</i>

816
01:34:17,051 --> 01:34:18,814
<i>♪♪ [Continues Indistinct]</i>

817
01:34:18,919 --> 01:34:22,047
<i>[Deke]</i>
<i>You think we're gonna be all right?</i>

818
01:34:22,156 --> 01:34:24,716
<i>[Billy]</i>
<i>Deke, I know everything's gonna be all right.</i>

819
01:34:28,062 --> 01:34:31,520
<i>♪ Who made who</i>
<i>Who ♪</i>

820
01:34:31,632 --> 01:34:34,499
<i>♪ Who made who</i>
<i>Who ♪</i>

821
01:34:34,602 --> 01:34:37,093
<i>♪ Yeah you ♪</i>

822
01:34:42,309 --> 01:34:44,743
<i>♪ Ain't nobody told you ♪</i>

823
01:34:48,015 --> 01:34:50,279
<i>♪ Who made who ♪♪</i>

824
01:34:52,386 --> 01:34:56,755
<i>[Connie] Curtis, when do we get</i>
<i>off this boat? You know I get seasick.</i>

825
01:34:58,559 --> 01:35:02,495
<i>I think I'm gonna whoops my cookies.</i>
<i>[Groans]</i>

826
01:35:08,969 --> 01:35:18,002
♪♪

827
01:35:23,984 --> 01:35:27,647
<i>♪ She was a fast machine</i>
<i>She kept her motor clean ♪</i>

828
01:35:27,755 --> 01:35:31,521
<i>♪ She was the best damn woman</i>
<i>that I'd ever seen ♪</i>

829
01:35:31,625 --> 01:35:35,994
<i>♪ She had the sightless eyes</i>
<i>telling me no lies ♪</i>

830
01:35:36,097 --> 01:35:39,157
<i>♪ Knocking me out</i>
<i>with those American thighs ♪</i>

831
01:35:39,266 --> 01:35:43,225
<i>♪ Taking more than her share</i>
<i>Had me fighting for air♪</i>

832
01:35:43,337 --> 01:35:46,898
<i>♪ She told me to come</i>
<i>but I was already there ♪</i>

833
01:35:47,007 --> 01:35:50,602
<i>♪ 'Cause the walls start shakin'</i>
<i>The earth was quakin' ♪</i>

834
01:35:50,711 --> 01:35:56,047
<i>♪ My mind was achin'</i>
<i>We were making it and you ♪</i>

835
01:35:56,150 --> 01:35:59,278
<i>♪ Shook me all night long ♪</i>

836
01:36:01,689 --> 01:36:06,683
<i>♪ Yeah, you</i>
<i>shook me all night long ♪</i>

837
01:36:07,862 --> 01:36:10,831
<i>♪ And knock me out</i>
<i>and then you ♪</i>

838
01:36:10,931 --> 01:36:15,732
<i>♪ Shook me all night long ♪</i>

839
01:36:15,836 --> 01:36:21,934
<i>♪ You had me shakin' and you</i>
<i>shook me all night long ♪</i>

840
01:36:23,144 --> 01:36:25,044
<i>♪ Yeah you shook me ♪</i>

841
01:36:26,747 --> 01:36:28,908
<i>♪ Well you took me ♪</i>

842
01:36:56,410 --> 01:36:59,072
<i>♪ You really took me</i>
<i>oh, you ♪</i>

843
01:36:59,180 --> 01:37:02,411
<i>♪ Shook me all night long ♪</i>

844
01:37:04,351 --> 01:37:10,290
<i>♪ Ohh you</i>
<i>shook me all night long ♪</i>

845
01:37:11,826 --> 01:37:17,162
<i>♪ Yeah, yeah, you</i>
<i>shook me all night long ♪</i>

846
01:37:18,632 --> 01:37:24,264
<i>♪ You really took me, you</i>
<i>shook me all night long ♪</i>

847
01:37:25,606 --> 01:37:29,167
- <i>♪ All night long ♪</i>
- <i>♪ Yeah you shook me ♪</i>

848
01:37:29,276 --> 01:37:33,110
- <i>♪ All night long ♪</i>
- <i>♪ Yeah you shook me ♪♪</i>

