It's sent.
Yeah.
I already sent it.
It'll arrive today or tomorrow.
Sorry. Just keep it a bit.
Yeah, just a few days.
It's docile. No worries.
Yeah, don't worry about it.
You can feed it anything.
Wait, no meat!
If there's a problem,
I sent a pistol, too.
I'll pick it up soon.
Sorry. Bye.
I need you to sign here.
Thanks.
Thank you very much.
Open it up.
All right.
Kenichi.
Kenichi!
A zombie, eh?
Don't see these much.
I've never seen one before.
Care instructions...
Feed fruit or vegetables.
Never provide meat
as it may turn feral.
If there is a risk of bodily harm,
dispatch it with the pistol included.
Well, what should we do with it?
We can't keep it here.
We have a storage unit in town.
Take it there.
It's just a few days.
My friend will pick it up soon.
Lock it up.
Make sure it's locked.
Damn it.
Hey, now!
Had enough?
Mr. Teramoto...
I hear you're keeping a zombie here.
You can't bring
something like that into town!
It's a misunderstanding.
I know it looked suspicious,
arriving like that.
It came from a former employee.
It'll just be a few days.
But a zombie is a zombie, right?
But this one is almost human.
Well, it's a carrier,
but its virus count is low,
so it's not fully developed.
Even so, the responsibility
is on my shoulders!
I know. I know.
You're a doctor and all.
I know you know a lot.
But things can go wrong.
I know.
If something happens...
Here.
I'll take care of it with this.
That's not safe.
Put that thing away somewhere.
Sorry.
I won't hesitate to call the cops.
I understand.
Sorry for the disturbance.
Unbelievable.
What a bother.
Isn't it going to work here?
I had to lie.
You three can handle it.
This is too colorful.
From the missus.
Change into them.
Have you heard?
Heard what?
Well, why would a zombie
be delivered here?
It's from Sasaki, a friend of the doc.
He's a shady character.
He was saying something
about making zombies
into a new business.
What kind of business?
He's making them pets.
That's dangerous.
Zombies have levels.
The lower the level,
the more human they are.
Oh, so ours is a low-level one.
Yeah, and so are you.
Don't compare me to a zombie, man.
Okay, start scrubbing here.
Care Instructions
Hey.
Listen.
You need to use water.
Water.
Understand?
Here, I'll show you.
Like this. Here.
Well?
Got that?
Sorry.
Since Rudolf guided the way
Santa Claus was able to deliver
presents to all the children.
The end.
More!
Hey, just give it something rotten.
Whatever's spoiled.
All right.
Oh, yeah.
Don't give it meat.
Got it.
Good work.
Now, now, Kenichi!
Hey! Get back here!
Get back here!
Hey!
Good morning.
What?
Check this out.
Well?
Sexy, eh?
You moron.
What? It's sexy, right?
It's a zombie.
You said it's mostly human.
Well...
That's true, but...
Good work.
See you tomorrow.
Bye-bye.
Good morning.
It's dried out.
Be careful!
See you later!
Good morning.
Kenichi!
He was playing by the pond and...
Kenichi, answer me!
Bring him back!
Bring Kenichi back!
Do it! Do it!
Bring him back!
You're a zombie, right?
You can do it.
Now, hurry.
Hurry!
Stop!
Don't!
Kenichi.
Kenichi!
Ah, um...
I want to apologize.
I...
thought that...
Do you need a hand with something?
Hey!
Stupid thing!
Die!
Kenichi, get over here!
The Zombie Virus:
Testing and Diagnosis
Kenichi!
Kenichi, wake up!
What's wrong? What happened?
Kenichi, come on! Kenichi!
Kenichi...
Is he a zombie?
No.
I think he's just in shock.
It's a kind of allergic reaction.
What will we do?
What will happen to him now?
He's still a child.
The process takes a few years.
I'm sure they'll have
a new treatment by then.
Good work.
Well, see you tomorrow.
Cast
Ayaka Komatsu
Makoto Togashi
Riku Ohnishi
Taro Suruga
Tateto Serizawa
Takaya Yamauchi
Toru Tezuka
Crew
Executive Producers: Yoshinori Kumazawa
Kazumi Satake
Producers: Kenichi Yoshida
Yasushi Utagawa
Screenplay: SABU
Line Producer: Asuka Matoba
Cinematographer: Daisuke Souma
Lighting Designer: Akiyo Miyoshi
Sound Recordist: Koji Yamada
Special Makeup Effects: Taiga lshino
Hair and Makeup: Chieko Naijo
Costume: Keiko Okamoto
Post-production Producer: Manabu Shinoda
Editor: Naoichiro Sagara
Script Supervisor: Aika Muramatsu
Sound Effects: Keisuke Shibutani
Casting: Toshie Tabata
Assistant Director: Jun Shiozaki
Production Coordinator: Koji Hotta
Production Company: dub inc.
'Miss ZOMBIE' Film Partners AMUSE
SOFT ENTERTAINMENT INC. dub inc.
Subtitle timing, editing and additions by famitsu1 Special thanks to
ikeda69 English translation by 'unknown' (many thanks whoever you are)
©2013 'Miss ZOMBIE' Film Partners