I can see ghosts.
No matter what happens,
I'll protect you.
Why is my father here?
It appears that your dad was murdered.
You killed Bong Pal's mother. It wasn't
enough, so you killed his father.
You've met his father before?
It was at a temple
five years ago.
He asked me to give something to his son.
He also asked me
not to show it to anyone.
That is very important to Bong Pal.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
I will come back soon.
Wait for me, Bong Pal.
You don't look so good.
Have some tea.
[Episode 15]
Monk Myung Chul.
Did you know about it, by any chance?
What do you mean?
The detective came by.
He asked me about Professor Joo.
He said...
that Professor Joo Hye Sung is
connected to my father's death.
Bong Pal.
Professor Joo Hye Sung is not human.
Accurately speaking,
an evil spirit is inside his body.
An evil spirit.
The same evil spirit that came
out of your body a long time ago.
What's wrong?
I just feel dizzy.
I will use the bathroom.
That evil spirit has been
hanging around you and Hyun Ji.
Hyun Ji?
She has what he whats.
- What is it?
- A weapon.
The weapon that was used to get rid
of that evil spirit in your body.
Do you remember?
That weapon... was broken.
It was.
But it seems like your mother
made another one for your sake.
Bong Pal, your mother
had a very strong soul.
So much so that it shocked
even the shamanesses.
- My mom?
- Yes.
Some say it was a gift, but to
your mother, it was a nightmare.
She decided not to accept the gift.
- Why?
- She was pregnant with you back then.
She wanted to raise
you like a normal person.
The gods were angry.
Among them, the evil
spirit was also there.
- It was rejected, so...
- It tried to posess my body.
Yes.
That's when the misfortune all started.
I eventually got rid of
the evil spirit from your body
but your mother made another weapon
just in case it tried to harm you again.
- With all her energy.
- My mom.
But... how did Hyun Ji...
Your father came looking
for that weapon at the temple
and it seemed like
Hyun Ji also came to pray.
Your father was being chased
by the evil spirit at that time.
He was frantic and asked her
to look after the weapon.
But she got into a car accident
on her way to give it to you.
The weapon got lost in the middle
and your father was back
to being chased again.
My mom, my father, and Hyun Ji.
- They all got hurt because of me.
- No. No, Bong Pal.
It's not because of you.
It's because of that evil spirit.
Where are you going?
I need to go to Hyun Ji.
[My Love Bong Bong]
The person you are trying
to call cannot be reached...
Hyun Ji... are you okay?
Hyun Ji...
Where is the item
you're supposed to give me?
Young lady.
Professor Joo, you're...
You remember.
It's best to bury bad memories.
Excuse me!
What brings you here?
- Is Hyun Ji home?
- She's not home right now...
- Didn't she go out to meet you?
- She hasn't returned yet?
Is there something going on?
No.
Young man! Young man!
- Never mind.
- Seriously!
It's not him.
You need to move more quickly.
You're not careful at all.
Don't you know
the fundamentals of a stakeout?
Is this necessary, huh?
What are we? Detectives?
Didn't the monk tell
us to watch over him?
And when did you ever listen so well?
You know, you're not as
bright as I thought you were.
We need to score points with the
monk if we want to work with Bong Pal.
Why do you think he asked us to do this?
It's because this person
is dangerous to Bong Pal!
He must've seen us as very
strong and reliable colleagues
to give us something
so important like this to take on.
- Ah.
- Ah?
I get it.
Isn't that him?
Right?
He's... he's loading
something in the car.
Let's follow him.
Let's go.
Hyun Ji! Hyun Ji!
Hyun Ji.
Right, the alarm went
off 30 minutes ago.
We started the search and rescue.
We'll catch him soon.
Don't worry so much.
I'll call you right away
if something comes up, so go home.
Bong Pal! Bong Pal!
Goodness, hello.
What's going on here?
That bastard...
took Hyun Ji.
Goodness.
Oh my dear Buddha.
Oh goodness.
Is your daughter Kim Hyun Ji?
She is currently missing.
- Are you okay?
- Senior.
- Did you talk to the employees?
Yes, I think he planned this all along.
He gave them time off a few days ago.
And they know nothing about Professor
Joo. His cell phone is also turned off.
It'll be hard to track him.
What should we do?
Compare Park Ji Hoon's
and Professor Joo Hye Sung's DNA.
Tell everyone this is an emergency.
He hasn't gone too far.
Yes, sir.
Who went to his mother's house?
The local precinct agreed to cooperate.
They're probably there by now.
Hey, be quiet.
- What in the world is he doing?
- I don't know.
He seems very suspicious.
Seeing how he's changing
cars this late at night.
It's always the good-looking
ones that surprise you.
He's taking something out.
Hyun... Hyun Ji!
What are you doing over there?
Nothing.
Is this your car?
Yes. Why do you ask?
You can't park here for
two days without a contact number.
Hurry up and remove it.
I got so many complaints
because of this car.
- Just go.
- Hurry up and remove it.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I told you to just go.
Why do you keep bothering me?
- What the heck?
- What are you doing? Let's go!
What the hell!
This worthless piece of crap!
Bong Pal, don't worry so much.
That punk won't be able to touch
Hyun Ji until he finds the weapon.
Why... is he so
obsessed with the weapon?
He can completely possess you
once that weapon disappears.
Me?
It's because your mother's energy
has been handed down to you.
That's why he's been lurking
around you for 10 years.
Yes, Senior Il Rang.
What did you say?
Where?
Okay.
Senior, that camera is useless.
It's been broken for a long time.
The students did not get
a good look at the license plate.
Tracking him won't be easy.
If he planned this as well, then he
probably has an escape location too.
Call all of Professor Joo's contacts
and check all the streets and cameras.
Yes, sir.
Bong Pal.
Let's go back home. You guys too.
- Yes, sir.
- Bong Pal.
- Go without me.
What about you?
I have to find Hyun Ji.
By what means?
How are you going to find her?
I can't sit around and do nothing.
He's after you.
You're the one who is in danger.
Then what about Hyun Ji?
- I'll find her.
- This happened because of me.
- I have to do something.
- Bong Pal.
We'll stay with Bong Pal.
Don't worry.
[Joo Hye Sung]
[Kim Hyun Ji]
- Senior.
- Yeah?
- Did you find something?
- Yes, I checked the cameras
and there were several shots
captured of Professor Joo's car.
We're in the process of
searching for it right now.
We should be able to get its
location in a couple of hours.
Let me know as soon
as you get the results.
Yes, sir.
Hello.
Monk, you can't stay here.
Go over there and we'll let you know if
we get any information on Professor Joo.
- She's here.
- Hello.
Please sit over here.
Just a moment please.
Who is that person?
Professor Joo Hye Sung's mother.
Let's go.
Did Hye Sung kill all those people?
We're still investigating.
It's true.
I heard what happened on the way.
How...
I know this is very difficult for you
but please help us so the investigation
can move along as quickly as possible.
I'm not sure if I can
be of any help to you.
What was the last thing you
talked about with your son?
I don't know.
I understand.
- Senior Il Rang.
- Yeah?
Did you say
Professor Joo headed to the right?
Yes, he went to the right.
Professor Joo is looking for
the item that Hyun Ji has.
And Hyun Ji got into a car accident
trying to give me that item.
Then that item is probably in Seoul.
That's right.
Why did he come all the way here then?
I think he's trying to lure us.
He probably went to Seoul.
- You fixed it?
- That's right.
Who am I? We can use
this for 10 more years.
What should we do? Where do we go?
Should we just head straight to Seoul?
The detectives said that
he was prepared to run away, right?
Yeah, why?
- Don't you think he scoped out the area?
- Probably.
Then...
Hey, where are you going?
Hey.
What are you doing?
Are you searching for the destination?
I'm sure he already erased it. I swear,
you're slowly turning into an idiot.
Of course he erased it.
The destination can be deleted from the
screen, but it's still on the hard drive.
If I do this right, I can even
find out where he went a week ago.
It worked! I found it! I found it!
- You found it.
- It's the coordinates.
Somewhere in Gyungdo or Euido.
If I input the coordinates here...
Ta-da.
Just who are you?
Bong Pal, come quickly!
These are the current destinations.
That's the school
and that's the hospital.
Where is that?
I think this is Guil-dong.
I'll look for it.
Ah, Guil-dong is where
that empty warehouse is!
It's the perfect place to hide a body.
Do you think Hyun Ji is there?
Let's go for now.
Thank you.
I'm sorry that I couldn't help you.
Not at all. I'm thankful
that you even came.
I'll escort you home.
No, I'll just go by myself.
Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Can we talk?
I'm sorry.
- I have nothing to say.
- No, it's fine.
I'm not doing this so I can
get an apology out of you.
Then...
There are some questions
I want to ask about your son.
I told the detective everything.
I won't know anything
even if you ask me.
You can tell me what you
couldn't say to the detective.
When did it start?
When did your son change?
I know there is an evil
spirit inside your son's body.
When did it start?
Hye Sung is who he is because of me.
You brat! You're just like your mother!
I told you not to look at me like that!
- Don't look at me like that, punk!
- Hye Sung, run! Stop!
Please stop!
Why are you crying?
Should I help?
Leave me alone! Go away!
Go away!
Should I save you from hell?
How about it?
You have to save your mom too.
Don't you think so?
Mom?
Mom.
Kill him, kill him, kill him!
Kill him!
Hye Sung... Hye Sung!
Someone help!
Someone has fallen!
I should've taken better care of him.
He wouldn't be what he
is now if I had done that.
I'm home.
Mom.
Mom!
- Can you give me the number and address?
- Gosh, it's really hot today.
Why are there so many reports
on a hot day like this?
- Yes, I understand.
- So many reports.
No kidding.
By the way, who is that kid?
He came back from school
and his mom moved without him.
- Did you call her?
- I did.
She's coming.
Ever since that day,
Hye Sung started to change.
He went to live in
the dorms at his middle school.
And he only called me once in a while.
It's all my fault.
I made him that way.
I'm to blame.
It's for one day.
Why did Mom pack this much?
It will be hard to carry this around.
Now you're up.
I've been waiting for so long.
Why are you doing this?
If you have your memory back,
you would know.
Don't blame me.
You shuld blame the man who
gave you the item and his son.
They put you in hell
for the last five years.
If you hadn't gotten that item
we wouldn't have met this way.
Don't you think so?
Are you scared of me?
No, I'm not scared of you at all.
Good.
Do you know what's scarier
than just feeling scared?
It's being found out
that you're actually scared.
See? You're already shaking.
What are you?
You're not human, are you?
Not sure. What am I?
Am I human or not?
Depending on your answer
I will be human or not.
Where is... that item?
That is very important to Bong Pal.
If you remember,
please tell me, okay?
What is it?
You still don't remember?
Then I will help you remember.
- Hello?
- Mom.
Is this Hyun Ji? Hyun Ji!
- Mom!
- Hello? Hyun Ji!
What do you think?
Do you remember now?
You'd better remember.
If not
your loved ones will die one by one.
Here!
Hyun Ji.
Hyun Ji!
- Hyun Ji!
- Kim Hyun Ji!
[Myungsung University]
As a boy, he probably wanted
to protect himself from
the guilt from killing his dad
and feeling distant from his mom.
His hatred made
the evil sprit come to him.
The spirit used the boy's open wound.
Do you think that professor
might still have his humanity?
Not at all. They're one body now.
Then what should we do now?
Where is the stuff I gave you?
Ah, hold on.
If I think about how hard it was to
make this all the way out here...
Wow, it's great work.
Thank you.
I really hope
this has the power of divine spirits.
When you're not equipped
to borrow the power of divine spirits
you won't be able to walk.
Do you want to
not be able to walk forever?
You nag so much
that I might just do that.
What is it that you're going to do?
I have to finish
what I couldn't 18 years ago.
What?
I will finish him.
How are you going to do
that without weapons?
Only you will end up dead.
I will have the power of divine spirits.
If I don't finish him,
Bong Pal will be in danger.
Bye now.
I hope you get married again.
I will go now.
You'd better not do anything stupid
if you care about your mother.
Get out.
Bong Pal, is it true
that the man is here?
Yes.
- Did you call the police?
- They should be on their way.
Bong Pal, I will go in by myself.
- You stay out here.
- No, I won't.
It happened because of me.
I will finish it.
You two stay here.
Excuse me, sir.
The subway has stopped running.
Sir, I said we're closed.
Please leave.
There are buses outside.
Take the bus.
It hasn't been that long
since he was here.
Bong Pal!
Hyun Ji!
Kim Hyun Ji!
Bong Pal.
- You didn't see her?
- No.
If she's nowhere to be seen...
Is this really the right place?
This is the right place.
Then maybe she's mistaken about
the location since it's been five years.
If not, it's a mystery.
I can't believe
she vanished without a trace.
Five years ago? Five years...
If it happened five years ago,
we're at the wrong place.
If Hyun Ji came to
this station five years ago
this wasn't the same station then.
What do you mean
this wasn't the same station?
It means that
there was a fire five years ago.
They closed the station then
and rebuilt this station instead.
He's right. There was a fire...
- Then where is the original location?
- It's that...
It may be near Exit Two.
This feels very spooky.
Wait. We should wait for the police.
- That's right.
- Isn't it?
True. You're right.
Bong Pal, be careful.
You too, Monk Myung Chul.
You're no longer needed.
I will let you rest now.
Hyun Ji!
I was going to come find you.
Thank you for coming to me first.
Do you know how long
I've been waiting for this moment?
If I hadn't been
driven out of your body...
this wouldn't have happened.
Wait a little bit.
You and I will become one body.
No, you can't!
Bong Pal!
You evil spirit,
you're up to no good!
Bong Pal, Hyun Ji.
Are you two okay?
Hyun Ji, get Bong Pal out of here. Hurry!
I won't let you do that.
Will you really kill me?
Then you're killing this man too.
It means that you're taking a life.
Sure.
If I can end you, I shall do that.
Don't kill yourself over this.
I will end you today, you evil spirit.
You bastard!
This is why I told you
not to kill yourself over this.
Now this is really over!
You bastard!
Monk Myung Chul. Are you okay?
Hyun Ji.
The weapon... the weapon...
You stop that!
Monk Myung Chul.
It's done. It's done.
Bong Pal. Bong Pal!
Hyun Ji, find the weapon!
It's the only thing
that will stop him, Hyun Ji.
Monk Myung Chul!
[Let’s Fight Ghost]
Is Hyun Ji leaving?
Why do you exorcise, Monk Myung Chul?
Do you know why I was against
you exorcising when I found out?
It was because I could see
hatred in your eyes then.
- You remember these people, right?
- I killed them.
You can't see the world right
when you have so much anger in you.
What is this?
She may be a con artist.
Not all ghosts are bad.
Perhaps they just want your sympathy.
I said get lost!
Can you really do the job?
It's up to you.
Isn't this place
a restaurant for rice soup?
I'm Goo Dae Hyung, a sophomore
in the Physical Education department.
Making others happy makes you happiest.
[My love Bong Bong]
Hello, seniors.
I'm a freshman, Kim Hyun Ji.
I'd appreciate your guidance.