Well, my friend,
this is an unexpected pleasure.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
How do you do?
I wouldn't disturb you,
but the friend I spoke to you about...
is leaving town tomorrow to supervise
some new excavations in Egypt.
He was most anxious
to see your collection before going away.
- May I present Mr. Galatalin.
- Why, this is a great pleasure.
I've heard so much about you.
How do you do?
Follow me, gentlemen.
My children would become conceited
that so distinguished a critic...
has thought them
interesting enough to review.
Splendid.
Joan of Arc. Beautiful.
It's a pity to race through
such an exhibition.
And here is Voltaire.
One might almost expect him to speak.
I wonder what he'd say
after all these years.
You would be astonished.
He is more difficult now, to those
in authority, than even the records show.
He is a very stubborn person, I assure you.
- Stubborn?
- Unbelievably.
For days I argued with this fellow...
before getting him just as I wanted.
But always, I triumphed.
And few people triumphed
over Monsieur Voltaire.
And here, gentlemen....
Here is something that pleases me...
although of no historic importance.
It was done because
I love to model children.
Note, gentlemen,
the line of the shoulder and--
You have no right to hide such genius
in a side-street museum.
You are very gracious.
These things have some merit,
I suspect, but this....
Will you come this way,
gentlemen, please?
This, I'm convinced, is fine.
- Marie Antoinette?
- Yes, sir.
Beautiful composition.
Even those delicate veins
and the texture of that flesh.
I never saw anything more exquisite.
But, tell me, where did you begin
to model in wax?
In my native country, at first, as a hobby.
- He has a great reputation as a sculptor.
- You are very kind, sir.
However, I was commissioned
to come to England...
and with the completion of my work,
I turned my mind to these...
because it seemed to satisfy me more.
I felt I could reproduce the warmth
and flesh and blood of life...
far more better in wax than in cold stone.
If you will grant me the privilege...
I'd like to submit your work
to the Royal Academy when I get back.
Royal--
You will have won
the undying gratitude of all of us.
Is that not so, Marie Antoinette?
I regret that I have not the time
to give to your exhibition now...
but I'll worry you more when I get back.
It will always afford me
the greatest pleasure to welcome you.
I must apologize again for coming
and disturbing you at this late hour.
It was a great pleasure, I assure you.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
- And I'm very grateful to you.
- Not at all.
Thank you for your visit
and your encouragement.
- Good night, lvan.
- Good night.
My masterpiece, my Marie Antoinette.
You heard what this man,
who is very celebrated, said of you?
Yes, of course. You would say that.
You always told me so, of course.
Hello, there!
Hello.
What are you doing here so late?
I came for some books. I'm trying
to straighten out the accounts.
I don't hope to impress you
but we haven't a farthing.
That is unfortunate.
You're right, it's unfortunate.
*15,000 it's cost me,
and you say it's unfortunate...
as though I spilled soup on my vest.
Your money may be very well invested,
one never knows.
Something important may come of all this.
Something has got to come of all this.
- The rent on this place isn't paid.
- ls that a fact?
No, I'm lying to amuse myself.
Now, look here. I have an idea
that will get us out of all this.
You and I have absolutely no money,
but we have got this.
- Fire insurance.
- Yes, insurance. That's our way out.
You know that a fire in this place
will give us *10,000?
A fire?
Is this your idea of humor, my friend?
I want the money back
that I've thrown into this rubbish heap.
You're asking to burn these people?
- You are asking to destroy all--
- I'm not asking you.
- I'm telling you.
- You think I'll permit this?
You've got to permit it.
Whose fault is it
if people don't come here?
Yours. All this artistic nonsense.
The museum at Walston Lane
does well enough.
And why? Because they have
Jack the Ripper, Burke and Hare...
the Mad Butcher...
the Demon Barber of Fleet Street,
things that people pay to see!
And they are welcome to them.
To perpetuate such scoundrels
is to celebrate their crimes.
What do think I'm in this for?
A match. A cigar stub, even...
and you and I have *10,000
to divide between us.
You are insane.
No, I'm not insane. Not at all.
Let me show you
how easily it can be done.
Wait, you!
Anything new, Doc?
Nothing we didn't tell you this afternoon.
The coroner confirmed our opinion.
It was suicide.
Gee, that'll make a swell story. Come on.
Hello, is that you, Tim?
I'm sorry, but I've got to have that tonight.
I've got to have it.
No, I tell you, I need it right away.
Who's on the gate down there?
Joe? Then you can get it out, all right.
I'll send a truck right down there.
The harness bull's okay.
I straightened it out this afternoon.
New Year's Eve ain't what it used to be.
This is only the second one tonight.
Times sure are tough.
What happened to this one?
Husband slapped her full of lumps.
Said she talked too much.
What's that?
Embalming fluid. It makes them jump.
Ain't that just like a woman?
Always has to have the last word.
As I live and breath
and wear spats, the prince.
You've been doing experiments
with Scotch and soda again?
Where did you get that news item?
From a little bird?
Have a pleasant vacation?
Charming. More delightful people crippled.
That's fine.
Consider yourself crippled financially.
See if you can jar your friends loose
for enough to eat.
Meaning what?
You're a sure bet
to place in the bread line.
There's no room on this rag
for the purely ornamental.
You're easy on the eyes
and pretty conceited about it.
Is mama's dumpling getting tough?
I'm through clowning, Florence.
You're all washed up. Get out!
What do you mean? It's New Year's!
We still get out a newspaper.
Ever thought of that?
- ls it my fault if nothing happens?
- What do you mean, nothing happens?
Look down there!
Out of that insane mob,
you say nothing happens?
There's a story
in every person down there.
Do I circulate among them and say
"Would you tell me the story of your life?"
Getting newspaper stories
is none of our business.
You're through. Get out.
Go on, get out.
You're fired unless you bring a story
for the next edition!
Even if it's only
a new recipe for spaghetti!
I thought I told you to keep out of here.
I won't bother you, but I'm all in.
My nerves are all shot.
Your nerves aren't the only things
that'll be shot.
You've been smoking again.
Give him a bag.
Thanks.
Come on.
And understand this...
you get nothing
until you show me something.
The next time you talk
out of turn you'll have bad luck.
- Understand?
- Thanks.
Happy New Year!
Hey, Miss Dempsey.
Wonder how they'll settle the heavyweight
argument while you're around.
Hello, sweetheart. How's your sex life?
So you're in again.
Hey, Jim, call out the riot squad.
- How's every little old thing?
- Fine.
You're the first reporter here in two hours.
- You people been seeing the old year out?
- I'm people which the old year saw out.
- I'm fired.
- No kidding.
I gotta make news if I have to bite a dog.
Hey, Kelly.
Oh, my gosh, even he walked out on me.
I've got a story for you.
You know the Joan Gale girl?
She committed suicide yesterday.
I read about it last year.
Yeah? Maybe she didn't commit suicide.
- She may have been murdered.
- No kidding? Any suspects?
- You know George Winton?
- Old Howard Winton's cub?
- That's him.
- They don't suspect him?
Don't they?
He's down at the Tombs right now.
- lf you're stringing me, old timer....
- Why should l?
- They were sweeties till last month.
- What does that prove?
Nothing. Only she may have tried
to blackmail him.
You know, such things have happened.
Anyway, he was in her apartment
a few hours before she was found dead.
- Saved, one job.
- The press room for yours.
- Wait till I give you the rest of the dirt.
- Make it snappy.
They've ordered an autopsy over
at Bellevue immediately. Go there.
- Don't give this to anyone else.
- It's yours.
Thanks!
Fresh kid!
- Feeling tough?
- Rotten.
]That's too bad, sister.
I have a case of jitters
that will cop the Pulitzer Prize.
If they don't hurry up,
they'll have another corpse on their hands.
Bring in number seven. The Gale girl.
She's a very interesting case.
When I was called, the girl had been dead
for possibly three or four hours.
My examination clearly showed
that she died of laudanum poisoning.
I thought at first it might have been
an accident. An overdose.
Her eyes indicated
that she used narcotics frequently.
- What was the police theory?
- Suicide.
- Leave any message?
- No.
That's why I thought it was an accident.
- Are you in charge of the case?
- Yes, sir.
Who got the information about Winton?
Everyone knew they were living together.
But he was playing around
with some other twist.
Winton was in bad though
because he left before she folded up.
If she committed suicide with laudanum
she probably took it in its true form...
and we'll find it in that
or very close to that state.
If someone gave it to her,
it would be diluted.
- But how could he give it to her?
- ln a cup of coffee or a glass of whiskey.
- That's possible.
- The Gale body is gone.
- What are you talking about?
- Absurd!
What do you mean? The body is gone?
Just that. It's vanished.
Gone. Disappeared.
You mean to say someone stole the body?
We found the slab empty
and the window to the alley was open.
Come on.
Boy, and he asked for a story.
Is his face red!
Bryant, 2626.
- Hello.
- Hello, slug.
Kill that Winton story for this.
Joan Gale's body was....
Not John Brown's.
Joan Gale's body was snatched
from the morgue two minutes ago.
I'm here now.
Yeah, there were nine or ten witnesses.
No, they didn't talk. They're pretty stiff.
No, dope, not drunk. Dead.
Get out of the Tombs and get to Winton.
I'll have Harry write the first flash.
A cow does that, and gives milk besides.
Send Harry in.
- How do you do? I'm from the Express.
- Yeah?
I don't want to talk to you.
I know you people. You'll try to crucify me
for something I didn't do.
Anything you print about me,
you've got to prove.
You know you're innocent
till you're proven guilty.
That's fine.
But while I'm proving my innocence...
you people will uncover
every petty kid trick I ever did.
You'll write editorials
about every cocktail I drank.
Anything that any normal person
might have done...
will have a sinister meaning if I did it.
It'll be a lot easier if you come clean.
Let's get down to cases.
- When did you see this girl last?
- ln the afternoon before--
- Why didn't you tell that to the police?
- They didn't give me a chance.
We had a couple of drinks.
She was all right. She seemed happy.
Do you remember what she said?
What did you talk about?
She laughed
and she said we were being very silly...
that we didn't care for each other anymore
but we needn't hate each other.
- Said she wanted us to be friends.
- Was that all?
No. We planned a trip.
I was sending her to Bermuda.
- You weren't going with her?
- No.
- Why didn't I take her away somewhere?
- Let's get back to the case in hand.
They ordered an autopsy
and found her body had been stolen.
No.
What are you trying to do to me?
- You're working with the police--
- I'm trying to help you...
if you're on the square and I think you are.
- Why are you telling me a crazy lie, then?
- That happens to be the truth.
- But who'd steal her body?
- That's what they'll ask you.
- Come on, time's up.
- Be right with you.
Keep a stiff upper lip, kid.
I think you'll come out okay.
Go ahead, I'm listening.
The whole thing sounded
on the up and up to me.
Poor guy's too scared to lie.
I think he's getting a raw deal.
Ain't that a shame.
Nice little chap, wouldn't harm a fly.
Everyone picking on the poor little fellow.
If he was unknown,
they wouldn't have pinched him.
He's George Winton
and they're playing it up.
It's a Roman holiday for every editor
in New York.
Why the goose pimples?
If he was someone like me,
you'd be trying to hang him.
I wouldn't be trying, beloved,
I would hang him.
All that gaga
about that body disappearing....
Eight bodies have been stolen in New York
in the last 18 months.
Isn't it more reasonable
to hook this up from that angle?
And ruin a perfectly good story?
Don't be silly.
I think this kid's entitled to a break.
- He's getting it. He's front page.
- You give me a pain.
I'm glad to hear it.
Since when did you start crusading
for justice?
This mug with all the money
has had two or three nasty affairs.
He's kept out of print,
because his grandfather was smart.
He couldn't have stolen the body from jail.
Don't think he'd be sap enough
to do the job himself, do you?
I hope they give him the works.
Even if he didn't kill her,
he's responsible for her death...
and they can fry him any time
without making me sore.
- I won't work on it from that angle.
- You won't?
You were pretty tough about
Judge Ramsey, a while ago.
They didn't prove anything against him.
Except that he disappeared
when things got too hot.
Or was killed by someone afraid of him.
- He took a run-out powder.
- That's got nothing to do with this case.
- Can I handle this my way?
- You cannot.
I'm still editor of this newspaper.
You said I was fired. Well, I quit!
- Give the assignment to somebody else.
- Wait a minute.
No, I'm through!
Come here, sob sister.
All right. Go ahead.
Do it your own way.
On the square,
if you'd seen that kid down there...
I'm not holding for him,
maybe he is a dirty pup, but he's scared...
and so kind of dumb and worthless.
If he is, we'll give him away
as a bridge prize.
Come on, beat it.
It's 5:. 00. You need some sleep.
- There's another point.
- Sleep on it. We'll get it tomorrow.
Here's your portrait.
- Which one is me? The horse?
- Get out of here.
If my curiosity is not too great...
would you mind telling me
what animal you are designing?
One of the Athenian girls
for the bacchanal.
It would be interesting to know
where and when you studied anatomy.
It doesn't seem so bad to me.
What is wrong with it?
Anatomy.
Heaven forgive you.
You must have studied
with a sideshow of .
I'm sorry, sir. I'll change it.
The reason I wanted to work with you
was to learn about that.
And this fellow.
Look what this cobbler is doing.
What is this?
Are you so beautiful that you make
everything in your own likeness?
It's a mercy of Providence
that this fellow cannot hear.
Anatomy.
A great sculptor.
And I am barred.
Look.
Look at these claws.
If I had those hands of yours...
I would show you the meaning
of what you are trying to do.
All those beautiful things
that were destroyed...
I could restore.
It is a cruel irony
that you people without souls...
should have hands.
But go on, go back to work.
It is useless and hopeless
to talk to such people.
Who is it?
Got it? Is it completed?
Yes, sir, it's ready,
but it's pretty heavy and I'll need help.
Come in here. Help Professor Darcy.
And hurry.
The figure has yet to be mounted
and dressed.
And now, my friend,
you are to see something...
that one truly can describe as art.
Professor Darcy doesn't try to keep
freedom and sketchiness in his work.
He is an artist.
His figures are realistic, lifelike.
He works at home, hours when
such people as you are loafing.
- Shall we open it?
- Yes.
Exquisite. Almost as beautiful
as the original.
Someday I hope to have you restore
Marie Antoinette.
I'd be glad to, Mr. Igor.
Take her in. Dress her for the opening.
I think I'll have something to tell you soon.
You have done well,
and I too have something for you.
Thanks.
Hello?
Hello! I was just thinking about you.
Yeah, I was, too.
No, I haven't forgotten.
I won't have much time,
we'll have to eat someplace close.
Let's go to that little Bohemian place.
- All right, I'll meet you in the lobby.
- At 12:00.
Bye.
Who was it? Penny ante?
- Why?
- I just wondered.
Did he invite you to lunch,
or did you invite him?
I don't want to offend you
but it's none of your business.
- I don't interfere in any of your affairs.
- I don't have any affairs.
- What do you mean?
- I don't think you could have a real affair.
I don't think you could care for anyone.
I've been in love so many times,
my heart's calloused.
But I never had one with dough.
This love-in-an-attic isn't my idea of a way
to spend a pleasant afternoon.
I don't agree with you.
All right, you raise the kids,
I'll raise the roof.
I'd rather die shaking cocktails
and bankers...
than expire in a pan of dirty dish water.
Would you?
He can look like a gorilla
and have no manners...
but he must have dough, plenty of dough.
You think money is the only requisite.
It just happens that the poor people
are happier.
Then marry Ralph.
You'll be the happiest couple in the world.
I wish you wouldn't be
so sarcastic about him.
He's the sweetest kid I know.
What are you laughing at?
I just imagined you telling
a landlady some day...
you didn't have the rent,
but Ralph was awfully sweet.
I haven't noticed
any multi-millionaires running after you.
I met one last night.
All the money this side of Peoria.
- Did you? Where?
- ln the can.
The hoosegow! Mrs. Winton's little boy,
of the Park Avenue Wintons.
- Discharge?
- Yeah.
How are you, Mr. Winton?
When I say I'm happier to see you
than I ever was to see anyone...
it comes from the heart.
- How are you, Mr. Gates?
- Splendid, my boy.
- What have you been up to?
- Not a thing.
- I hope your father accepts that.
- ls Dad here?
No. We talked to him long distance today.
- Was he pretty sore?
- He wasn't exactly overjoyed.
What did he say?
He said to get you out of trouble,
then hire someone to punch your head off.
- Have you had lunch?
- No.
Come on, we'll get something to eat.
- Hello, Florence, how are you?
- Fine. Thanks.
I'm awfully sorry,
I've got to disappoint you.
Don't worry. She'll get used to it.
Disappoint me? Why?
I won't be able to go to lunch with you.
What's happened?
The old man is awfully anxious
to open on schedule.
All of the advertising
announced it for tonight.
What are you doing here?
There are no visitors allowed.
- You'll have to leave.
- I'm from the Express.
I don't care where you're from.
I said, "No visitors allowed."
You might get some good publicity,
if you'll--
We're opening tonight.
You shall have the pleasure then.
You don't understand, if you....
Ralph.
Are you going to stay out there all day?
The old man's pretty peppery.
I'll see you tonight.
All right.
I'm awfully sorry.
I was just explaining about....
- What's the matter, sir?
- Nothing at all, my boy.
I should like to meet your friend.
Why, certainly, sir.
Charlotte, Mr. Igor wants to meet you.
Why, certainly.
Mr. Igor, may I present my fiancée,
Miss Duncan.
- Charlotte, Mr. Igor.
- I'm delighted to meet you.
- Professor Darcy.
- How do you do?
If you will forgive this poor,
crippled stump, my dear...
I am very happy to know you.
You'd be amused if I were to tell you
that I knew you before you were born.
Before this terrible thing
happened to me...
I made a very beautiful statue.
And, my child...
you are that figure come to life.
How?
I wonder, sometime, would you pose
for one of my sculptors...
who does really excellent work?
Why, yes, I'd love to.
Thank you.
...see you tonight at the opening.
- Of course, I plan to come.
- You'd be welcome at any time.
I crave nourishment.
Come on, moonstruck. Let's get going.
So long, see you in jail.
- Good-bye, Mr. Igor.
- Good-bye. I'll see you tonight.
I assume I shall have the privilege
of having her pose for me.
- That was my plan.
- Thank you.
I'm going to leave you.
I've got to get to the office.
- But what about lunch?
- I'll have it for supper.
Hello, light of my life!
Well, Prussic Acid. What's on your mind?
I want to see the original pictures
of Joan Gale.
Dig into the morgue and send up
all the art you have on Joan Gale.
Why so mysterious? Spill it.
So you can tell me I'm wrong?
Don't be silly.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
I am right! I know I'm right.
No one would suspect it.
You don't sound right.
If you wisecrack while I'm talking,
I'll crown you.
Go ahead, wise guy. Spill it.
There's a wax museum opening
on 14th Street.
Don't that call for an extra.
I asked you to keep it shut.
You can't blame a guy
for getting breathless with that scoop.
You poor baboon, you can guess the rest.
Wait a minute.
No kidding. What's your idea?
I got a look at that dump a while ago...
and if they don't have a wax figure
of Joan Gale, then I'm crazy.
- We'll grant that.
- What?
What of it? Where do we go from there?
Does this mean anything to you?
Joan Gale's body was swiped
from the morgue.
Did you ever hear of such a thing
as a death mask?
I used to be married to one.
And it came to life and divorced you.
I know that.
My idea is this: Somebody swipes
the body, takes the impression...
makes a mold, produces a wax figure,
peddles it to the old skate there.
Work that up into a comic strip
and syndicate it.
- You go to....
- What's that?
Let it go.
Come down to earth.
Would they dare to do that?
Wouldn't they know
it would be recognized?
Shake your head, you'll be all right.
All right, mastermind.
Something's cockeyed about that joint,
I'll find out what.
By the way, another pet theory
of yours just blew up.
- What?
- That innocent Judge Ramsey...
that you were sure got bumped off,
has been located in South America.
- No kidding?
- Almost certain.
I'll still bet I'm right,
and let you write your own ticket.
- That settles everything.
- Yup, everything settled.
Good.
- I'm glad they didn't hold you.
- There's no case against me.
A clumsy thing,
but nothing to worry about.
- lf I can do anything for you....
- I know I can always depend on you.
- What do you think is the best time?
- I'll let you know.
- So long.
- See you later.
- I hope, soon.
- Good-bye.
Hello?
Don't swoon. This is the voice of
the New York Express broadcasting.
I'm awful glad you phoned.
Thank you for trying
to cheer me up last night.
If you're grateful, you can prove it.
And do yourself a good turn too.
About 8:30 p. m., you be in your car at....
Good evening.
The history of these figures
becomes more interesting, perhaps...
when I tell you
that the originals were destroyed...
twelve years ago, in London, in a fire...
and were reproduced only after years
of arduous toil.
To reproduce the figures destroyed,
I had to train men for years...
to do the work that I could no longer do.
The results, you see here tonight.
Ladies and gentlemen, here is
one of the classic examples of chivalry.
Sir Walter Raleigh,
spreading his cloak in the mud...
so that Queen Elizabeth
might walk dry-shod.
This group represents
His Royal Highness, Le Duc D'Angouleme...
Ieader of the French nobility...
praying before the remains of the victims
of the Battle of Quiberon.
And next, we see
the ill-starred Maximilian...
established as Emperor of Mexico
by Napoleon lll.
Upon the conclusion
of the American Civil War...
Napoleon withdrew his military support...
Ieaving Maximilian to the mercy
of his rebellious subjects.
The figure lying in the bath is Marat...
one of the most bloodthirsty
leaders of the French Revolution.
He perished at the hands
of his mistress Charlotte Corday...
who was inspired to the deed
by her fanatical devotion to her country.
This my friends, is Napoleon,
Emperor of the French...
whose overwhelming ambition
swept him to world power.
Here we see him after his banishment
to St. Helena by the English.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
on the right here...
we have a figure of Peter the Great.
- Hello, Ralph.
- Hello.
- Are we late?
- No.
- Pretty dress, have I seen it before?
- Yes, I think so.
- Thank goodness that's settled.
- Pay no attention to her.
I'm so excited to see all these things.
- Mr. Igor.
- Yes?
You're sure of that? You're quite sure?
- I'd know him anywhere.
- Keep track of him.
This is the most important thing
of my life.
That'd be easy.
I wish....
- My little Marie Antoinette.
- Good evening, Mr. Igor.
- It's kind of you to be present.
- All these things are beautiful.
They are.
- Too bad the audience was so poor.
- I wouldn't be too disappointed, Mr. Igor.
The people are tired from the festivities.
My boy, I think you're right.
Everybody is tired out tonight.
And now that I've seen my doors open
in a new country...
I begin to realize I'm a little tired myself.
- Call that fellow in, I'll close up for tonight.
- Yes, sir.
I might have felt a little discouraged.
But now, everything seems
just as it should be.
You know, to find even one person who
appreciates my beautiful children here...
- changes everything for me.
- I'm glad.
You're very beautiful.
Thank you.
You must come sometime in the morning
when there is no crowd about...
and I can give you more of my time.
Good evening, Mr. Igor.
I've just been admiring your works.
Properly lighted,
they're even more impressive.
Yes. At first I despaired of ever achieving
the same results I did abroad...
and then lighting came to my rescue.
I was particularly interested in that group.
Yes, that one is very fine. Its grim tragedy
seems to fascinate everyone.
- Yes, and that other one, that Joan of Arc.
- That was the most recently completed.
- lt arrived this morning.
- You did that yourself?
No. Never since these hands were burned
have I created anything.
- I only direct the work of others.
- Who did it?
Professor Darcy.
- He has been my hands for years.
- You are very generous, Mr. Igor.
But I don't deserve any credit.
I only carried out your instructions.
Good night.
It's getting late. I better be going.
- Good night.
- Shall we go?
- All right.
Thank you for coming.
Good night, my dear.
- Good night.
- Ready, Florence?
You two go without me. I've got a date.
No fouling in the clinches!
Winton!
Follow that man down the street!
And no questions.
We're on the trail of hot news.
- What's this all about?
- I might as well tell you.
That man is connected
with the robbery at the morgue.
I don't want anything
to do with this matter.
- Even if it gives you a clean bill of health?
- Not even then.
The police should handle this. If you've
suspicions we'll go to the police.
And let every rag in town
grab a red-hot story?
- Drive me around the corner and wait.
- I don't want to mix in this.
Then you can go to a warm place,
and I don't mean California.
- All right. What do you want me to do?
- I told you what to do.
Drive out of sight of the house.
I want to get a closer look at the place.
That's nonsense.
- I figure you're yellow.
- No, I'm not.
- I feel that someone's been watching me.
- Nobody's watching you.
You're yellow and your nerves are shot.
I'll do nothing to help you
until it's delivered.
- Get that through your head.
- All right.
- I'll phone.
- Not on this phone, you fool.
Go outside and call.
All right.
Well, buddy, what's the stall?
- I'm waiting for someone.
- Yeah, for who?
- I don't think it concerns you.
- Cut out the bluffing.
We've been following you,
and you've done very suspicious things.
- Now, what are you doing here?
- What have I done?
You had a visitor at your apartment
this afternoon.
Not the kind of a person
I'd expect you to entertain.
Winton!
- Hello, Express.
- I found the body!
- What are you talking about?
- The body of Joan Gale!
Trying to outsmart the police?
The body of Joan Gale is packed in the box
in the basement!
- Are you giving me this straight?
- Take a look for yourself.
Let's take a look.
You, stop!
You cover the house, I'll get the other bird.
Come on.
Open this door.
Take it easy.
- It's down there in the basement.
- Wait a minute.
You boys go upstairs.
- It's not here, it's in the basement.
- Keep quiet.
Let's have a little light.
- See what's in there.
- Yes, sir.
Can you give me a description
of this person you saw?
Not a very good one, I guess.
It wasn't like anything human.
It hobbled and swayed like a monkey.
And the face, from the glimpse I got
of it was like an African war mask.
- You mean he was colored?
- I don't know.
But he made Frankenstein look like a lily!
- Nothing in there.
- ls there a rear entrance?
- I couldn't find any.
- Let's take a look.
Look, that's the basement.
- You find anything upstairs?
- Just a lot of paper and junk.
See if you can find a back entrance.
Let's take a look at the basement.
Just a minute, you.
- This is the place.
- Shut up!
Come out of there.
There's no one in here.
There he is now.
Turn on that light.
There it is. You'll find
the body of Joan Gale in this box.
- Get that hatchet and open this.
- Yes, sir.
- I don't want to see it.
- Stay where you are.
What I wouldn't give for a slug of gin.
So that's your corpse?
Of all the things!
There's your corpse.
I've done nothing.
You've no right to arrest me!
- What's the charge against me?
- Shut up.
Here it is.
Come here.
Come on, spill it.
Who is it that owns this layout?
- I don't know.
- You don't know anything about it?
No, sir. I just know
there was man named Worth.
- Worth?
- Yes, that was his name.
That's my bootlegger's name!
A heavyset fellow, with a broken nose?
Yes, that was the man.
I hope he delivered the stuff
I paid him for this afternoon.
I told you it was a bootlegger
you saw at my place.
- Take this fellow in.
- I've done nothing.
- I even refused to deliver stuff for him.
- Come on, let's go.
Are you trying to give us
the runaround here?
I want two of you boys
to work the outside.
Don't let anybody in or out.
Florence, I don't want to leave her--
What're you doing? Put it back!
No, this is my percentage.
You guys are going to get yours.
I found this dump.
- Yeah.
- Whatever.
- Junkie?
- Yes, peddling.
Hold up your hands.
A classy turnip. Must have dipped it.
They tell me
your managing editor is poison.
It takes a sturdy person to look at him.
The season's best catch is waiting.
I guess I'll breeze.
Wait a minute.
You want to talk to that junkie, Captain?
No, it's all right.
Lock him up. He'll talk soon.
- What do you think this is?
- What?
- Looks like a watch.
- Yes, but do you know whose watch?
- We don't know anything about it.
- Judge Ramsey's. That's all.
- Where did you get it?
- Took it off the junkie.
Well, I'll be....
- Bring him in. Here's your chance.
- Oh, boy!
Come in.
That yours?
Wait. Get me to the office and step on it.
- You like taking chances, don't you?
- Why?
- You go in for dangerous things.
- Darned if I don't!
Slow down!
I said the office, not the cemetery!
I never knew there were women like you
in the world. You're game and decent.
And so determined to live that I'll take
a taxi if you don't watch where you go.
I've only known you 24 hours,
but I'm in love with you.
Doesn't usually take that long.
I forgive you.
You were in a tough spot when we met.
- No, I'm crazy about you.
- That's what caused it?
You don't believe me. You think
I'm just talking. Will you marry me?
- How much money have you got?
- Heaven knows. A lot.
That being the case, I'll take it up
with the board of directors.
Listen, aviator. Here we are.
Hold everything, I'll be right back.
- Mitt me, kid. I've got a classic.
- You here again...
Iike an evil spirit to mar my happiness.
I've got a story,
but I won't tell you what it is.
- Every time I tell you, it goes haywire.
- What do you mean?
You start out after murderers and
bring back three-for-a-dime bootleggers.
You start out to solve murders
and break up crap games.
You're stupendous. I'm for you.
You're wonderful.
You're always razzing everything I do,
but this time I'm in.
Go on, girl. Tell your troubles to a cop.
I don't feel like talking.
Is there any art on Judge Ramsey?
Don't tell me you suspect Judge Ramsey
of stealing the body.
I'm gonna make you eat dirt,
you soap bubble.
I'm gonna make you beg for somebody
to help you let go!
You may be the world to your mother
but you're a....
Let's get them some coffee, they've been
in there with that junkie all night.
Go on, talk.
You found that watch in a taxicab
three months ago. Is that right?
Yes, sir. I got in the cab
and it was laying there on the floor.
Where were you going
when you got in that cab?
I don't remember. Not very far.
- You remember what day that was?
- No, sir. About three months ago.
- Remember what kind of a cab it was?
- No, sir, just a cab.
- Didn't happen to be going to Worth's?
- No, sir. I'm sure it wasn't there.
You used to go to Worth's place a lot.
What makes you sure it wasn't there?
Well, maybe, it was. I don't remember.
You've got to do something for me.
I can't stand it anymore.
I can't! Please.
He's beginning to break.
He'll talk pretty soon.
I think we got him, Chief.
He's been begging all night.
I never saw a junkie hold out so long.
Ralph?
I beg your pardon. Is Ralph here?
I was looking for Ralph.
No!
Mr. Igor, I'm so glad you're here.
I don't know why
but I was a little bit afraid.
Afraid? Poor Hugo is quite harmless.
My little friend, you've honored me
by accepting my invitation of last night.
No, I wanted to speak to Ralph.
We had a silly little argument last night,
and I said something unkind--
Oh, you children. You happy children.
You've quarreled,
and now you'll be friends again.
That's exactly as it should be.
Never let any stupid misunderstanding
come between you.
- lt was really all my fault.
- Let him think it was his fault.
You must be stern with him before you
forgive him, especially if it was your fault.
Now I understand
why he was so gloomy this morning.
- Then he's here?
- Yes, down in the workroom.
- I'll call him for you.
- No, please, don't bother.
- I think it'd be better if I surprise him.
- As you wish, my child.
- Just go straight ahead.
- All right, thanks.
Ralph?
Ralph, are you there?
What's the matter, my child?
Are you frightened?
I thought you said Ralph was here.
I came to tell you that I was mistaken.
I've sent Otto to find him.
I hope this little glimpse behind the scenes
will interest you.
This is the birthplace of all my creations.
Let me show you.
I don't want to put you
to the trouble, Mr. Igor.
No trouble at all, my child.
This is the strange, vicarious pleasure
that remains for me.
To see others enjoy the beauty
I used to create.
- My footing is none too secure.
- Please, let me help you.
Help me, my dear...
you'll help me to give back to the world...
my masterpiece.
Marie Antoinette.
No!
Hey, you. Wait a minute.
- You can't park here. Get it out of here.
- Okay, brother.
- I have to park the car. I'll be right back.
- Make it snappy, I might need you.
- Hey, Ralph!
- Hello, Florence.
- Gee, am I glad to see you.
- First time you've said that.
- Have you got a key?
- I just came down to open up.
- What are you doing here?
- After news, as usual.
What are the chances for me
to slip in and look around?
You better wait
until the old man gets here.
I'll tell you a secret. I like the old gent.
I'm doing a special Sunday magazine--
- I don't think I can--
- lt might help him a whole lot.
The old man was depressed at the opening
last night. This might cheer him up.
Hurry up.
Thanks.
All right. I'll talk. I'll tell you what I know!
Ramsey was murdered
because he looked like Voltaire.
Do you hear?
Because he looked like Voltaire.
You want to know what became of him!
He's a statue. A silly wax statue.
You killed him!
Come on with the rest of it.
No, I did not.
It was lgor at the Wax Museum.
You were in on it. You worked for him.
The only thing I did
was keep track of a man named Worth.
- He runs the place where you arrested me.
- You lie!
No. It was lgor at the Wax Museum.
You'll find your judge embalmed in wax!
He's a statue of Voltaire,
with the other corpses!
I tell you, the whole place is a morgue.
Do you hear? A morgue.
My child, why are you so pitifully afraid?
Immortality has been the dream,
the inspiration of mankind for ages.
I am going to give you immortality.
Please, I haven't done anything
to hurt you.
I have no desire to hurt you.
You will always be beautiful.
Think, my child, in a thousand years,
you will be as lovely as you are now.
- Come.
- No!
Let me go!
Your face...
was of wax.
- You fiend.
- My Marie Antoinette.
- You must not say that to me.
- You fiend!
There was a fiend, of that you can be sure.
There was a fiend.
And this is what he did to me.
You did this.
For 12 years, 12 awful years...
this terrible living dead man...
with these burned hands and face
has searched for the fiend.
Now the account is closed.
He is here!
Charlotte!
Don't be afraid, my dear.
In a few minutes,
the container will have filled with wax.
And when it overflows,
your beauty will be preserved forever.
Here, go down there quickly.
- I'm getting out of here.
- We'll go down there and help them.
- What can I do?
- I don't know, we must do something!
Come on, boys. This is it.
They're down there. Quick!
Through the center.
Try it again.
Stop where you are!
Take them away!
- You've got the other papers bleeding.
- Now I'm going to scramble this egg.
- Now, Poison lvy, was that a story?
- You had a million dollars worth of luck.
Listen, stupid, could I do anything
that would meet with your approval?
You could. Cut out this crazy business
and act like a lady. Marry me.
- Marry you?
- That's what I said.
I'm gonna get even with you,
you dirty stiff.
I'll do it.