[Idol Drama Operation Team]
[Script Reading Day]
[Before filming the drama,]
[the staff calls the members]
[to coordinate with one another]
[Whoa~]
[Writer Somi arrived first]
[Serious Somi]
[Same aged friends]
[Sohee and D.ana arrive~]
Welcome~
[As Sohee & D.ana arrive]
D.ana, please sit here.
[Full serious mode comes out]
Sohee...
[Blurred vision for a 17 year old]
Over there.
- Is that right? - Yes
[Somi is into role playing]
You just have to listen to me.
I don't think so.
[Tsk!]
I'm in the CEO's seat...
[You make no sense...]
[Back to checking the script]
- You checked the script already.
- I'm doing it now.
[Like test day at school?]
I said I'd do a little, but I didn't.
- Look at this. I'm ready.
- Earlier...
You know? Just doing the action?
Just underlining everything...
I'm like that.
The page just gets messy.
[Good at underlining]
Trying to look good.
[Time to read the script]
[is approaching]
[Writer Seulgi has arrived]
Role of Kang Seulgi.
[Moon Byul has arrived]
You posted some things on your script?
I guess so~
[feat. post its]
- I'm sorry~
- You came, YooA?
I ran over.
[Rushed over from "Music Bank" rehearsals]
You finished your rehearsal?
You have to go back then?
- After this?
- Afterwards...
[Bbang Dduk rushes over to her seat]
Su-Jeong.
[PD] [Main Writer] [Drama Writer]
[All members and staff have gathered]
- You all read the script? - Yes.
- How was it?
It was sad.
[Seven writers felt sentimental]
[from reading their own stories]
As I read the script,
I reminisced and thought a lot.
Then I fell asleep...
[What?]
You really fell asleep?
- It was really fun.
- Yes, seriously.
Everything we talked about
was included.
It was cool that it all came together.
[Before we get started]
In addition to the members,
[Empty seats?]
two more actors are coming today.
[Two empty seats]
[The guest stars are?]
Who are they?
[Special actors enter]
Whoa! Teacher.
[Who is it?]
[Who's the teacher of]
[Idol Drama Operation Team?]
[Warm welcome]
[Joyful round of applause]
[The acting teacher for the members]
[as well as the matchless actor,]
[Jang Won-Young, has arrived]
[A week before the reading,]
[he became their acting mentor]
[A big picture for the acting rookies]
[Teaching them through fun activities]
[to bring our their emotions]
[Improvising to bring out their own characters]
[Teacher Jang, the big time actor]
[Completely satisfied with the class]
An unexpected class...
It was a meaningful time...
I love you, teacher.
[A love confession? Random Somi]
[Then]
I think it would be great
[Leader Moon makes the request]
if you came out in our drama.
[Though Teacher Jang looked helpless]
[he agreed to appear in the drama]
[And]
[One more special guest]
[who surprised the members]
[Can't believe it]
[Chung Ha has arrived]
[The I.O.I member who]
[gave off a fresh charm]
[Cute cute]
[The one who made our hearts race]
[The first I.O.I member]
[to make a solo debut]
[Captivating the hearts of men]
[with her pure and feminine charms everyday]
[Welcome to Idol Drama Operation Team]
[Role of Director Jang]
[Role of Kim Chung Ha]
Have you been well?
[Special guests have brought up the mood~]
Director Jang~
[PD begins the script reading]
We'll briefly read over the script.
I'm nervous.
[Fidgets]
[Dazed~]
[Nervous about the first reading...]
We'll read it from the beginning.
[#. Girls are nominated]
[for first place at "Music Bank"]
[The Girl Next Door wakes up late]
[and rushes to get ready]
Su-Jeong, wake up!
We're late!
What do you mean...
[Showing her acting skills]
It's already morning.
You said you'd eat jokbal before.
[Jokbal in the morning?]
Oh right! My jokbal.
[Su-Jeong loves jokbal in the drama]
I couldn't resist eating it last night.
[Doing a good job]
Just one bite.
Wake up, YooA.
We're late.
[Good start amidst concern]
- What time is it? - Wake up, Somi. We're late!
[#Great expressions]
[#Not acting, but reality]
[Proud]
[Smiles]
Sohee is still sleeping, but above her,
[The highlight approaches]
we can hear Director Jang's voice.
What are you doing...?
What are you doing? You're still not awake?
[Jang is able to fall into character]
[Goosebumps...]
Do you think you can win like this?
Your attitude is all wrong!
What are you doing right now?
Girl's Generation would already be
at the salon by now~
[Can't help but admire]
[Respect]
The line is so funny.
[#. "Music Bank" Rehearsal]
On the way to "Music Bank."
The "Music Bank" PD will be played
by actor, Shin Hyun-Joon.
[Special actors appearing as]
[cameos for "Flower Road"]
[Shin Hyun-Joon and EXO?!]
The girls silently rejoice
in front of the door.
They look at the sign on the next door,
which says Jeon So-Min.
[Starting to get nervous]
[Her appearance is confirmed]
[Starring as their senior]
She's done with rehearsals, right?
Should we knock?
[Jeon So-Min's line]
Who's making that noise outside my door?
[Cold]
The Girl Next Door?
[Role of a feisty senior]
Is that why you chatter like them?
That's right. You're a first place nominee?
We'll work hard today.
We want to become singers
[Seulgi is good at everything]
who can act well, too.
It'll be hard, right?
Of course. It's difficult.
It's not easy to be like me.
I'm not sure if you can do it
just with effort...
[Suddenly]
Right? We can't get over it.
We always envy and respect you.
We will work even harder~
[Scene after meeting Jeon So-Min]
Will we be like that
when we meet our juniors?
- I almost died holding my tongue.
- I'm old, too.
A bit stronger.
[Puts in emotions]
I'm old, too.
[Relieved!]
[Moon Byul is doing well]
The others have cute roles,
but I think it'll be good if
Moon Byul's role balances that out.
[Also Moon-crush in the drama]
Sounds good.
Oh, turn on the monitor.
[Continuing the reading]
Miss A went on stage.
[#. Envying Miss A, who are on TV]
Suzy is so pretty.
Why did my mom raise me like this?
I still get negative comments.
"She's a celebrity?"
They call me,
"Bbang Dduk."
[At the first meeting]
Fans call me Bbang Dduk.
[Su-Jeong misinterpreted]
[the nickname that fans gave her]
They might be saying that with bad intentions.
Now, it's a term of endearment.
It sounds like "Our Bbang Dduk."
[Is that how you felt?]
[Came to like the nickname]
[Staff inserted various sides of her story]
[Cute]
Do I need to lose weight?
They say fat woman haven't won the lottery yet.
[#. Officially unfolding the story!]
[Unveiling their past]
How annoying!
Are we rabbits?
[Dieting is their biggest struggle]
Let's order food.
Okay. Let's order jokbal! Jokbal!
[Jokbal is the best]
What are you going to do about him?
Don't worry.
I have an idea.
[Director Jang comes into the practice room]
[Nags more than a mother]
What are you doing right now?
Your best isn't even good enough.
You call this dancing?
[Wait for us, jokbal]
[Moon Byul's hardcore acting beings]
- Unnie!
- Moon Byul.
What are you doing?
I feel gassy...
Oh my... You must be kidding me.
[Totally my taste]
[Laughs]
You were like this last time.
I'll run to the pharmacy to buy medicine,
so wait here.
[So funny]
[His impersonations never fail]
A girl group that's gassy...
You should be embarrassed.
[#. Members finally get jokbal]
The moment they take a bite.
What are you doing?
[Director and CEO enter]
Can't you see the CEO is here?
The CEO will be played by actor Im Won-Hee.
[Recruited after filming]
["Strong Woman Do Bong-Soon"]
[Just hearing about the cast]
[excites them]
[What's their fate...?]
You ordered jokbal?
If you weight more than 50kg
at the monthly evaluation, you're out.
[The story D.ana shared at the meeting]
[was put into the script]
We're allowed to leave once
we meet that target weight.
What if you can't?
If we can't, they kick us out
during the monthly evaluations.
If you weight more than 50kg
at the monthly evaluation, you're out.
[Members immersed by realistic script]
Why? You don't want to leave?
Then don't eat!
You eat jokbal, pizza, and chicken, and
do everything you want?
How do you want to perform then?
Is that being a celebrity?
Don't make others suffer,
and just quit!
[Seriously saddened]
[#. They exercise because of his scolding...]
I'm saying this because I'm struggling,
but can we eat a little bit?
You're saying that right now?
Yes.
[Unreasonable character]
[Moon robot?]
Fine... I guess you'd say that.
You have to say that last line
as if she's pathetic.
[Giving immediate feedback]
[as they read the script]
"I guess you'd say that."
[Got it]
[#. Upon Su-Jeong's wishes]
[she's given a hamburger]
I'll only eat half. Just half.
As soon as she takes a bite!
[That moment]
[Director Jang's silhouette]
[comes in like a ghost]
[These sad hunches are never wrong]
[But this situations sounds so familiar]
What do we do?
What if he comes?
[YooA wrote this!]
They just make us diet.
One day, I just really wanted to eat a hamburger.
I was eating it on the second floor,
while looking outside the window
our recruiting team leader walked down the street...
[Saw the recruiting team leader]
[through the window]
[Goosebumps]
[YooA contributed a relatable story]
I got really scared,
so I picked up the burger...
and I ate it in a bathroom stall.
[Just like YooA's story, Moon Byul and]
[Su-Jeong hide in the bathroom]
How much longer...
[What are you saying...]
[You don't have to be that quiet...]
[Too absorbed by the script]
[Cuteness overload]
Let's exaggerate this part.
[Not missing the cute ad-lib]
[by adding it in the script]
[Nice nice]
[#. Director Jang and his friend]
[come into the bathroom]
[Don't know they're hiding]
- The CEO was so angry. - Why?
[Nervous] They got caught
ordering jokbal behind our backs.
What were you doing
when they were eating jokbal?
One of the members was pretending to be sick.
I could see through her,
but I just left.
[He's actually on their side?] Why?
[We didn't know, Director!]