: Dispatch, Unit 16,
non-injury accident involving
two cars at intersection
of Pacific Coast Highway
and Metzger Road.
Millie, six five two
eight three seven five,
Belinda Richards, Caucasian
female, Malibu, California.
No wants or warrants, unit 32.
Unit 32, Dispatch.
I'll be giving her a
verbal warning, 10-4.
No warning ticket, 32?
Uh-uh, too young, too cute.
Ha ha, 10-4, 32.
Dispatch, Unit 16,
non-injury accident
involving two cars
at intersection...
I'm not gonna give
you a ticket, miss.
Just make sure you
fix that tail light
first thing in
the morning, okay?
I will, officer.
Thank you.
Dispatch, Unit 12, 10
minute personal, Roger.
Dispatch, Unit 32.
Dispatch, Unit 32, please.
Dispatch, 32, come in.
Come on, you 911375-
Dennis, I have told you
four times, time for bed.
Say good night.
Good night princess, sleep well.
Dennis, you heard
your mom, let's go.
Come on.
Mommy, I like
to stay downstairs.
We'll see.
Good evening.
Tonight's top story is
William Henry Glazer.
With an update, Maureen.
The Los Angeles
Sheriffs Department
continues in its search tonight
for escaped mental
institution patient,
William Henry Glazer,
formerly of Chatsworth.
Glazer is wanted for
questioning in connection with
the so-called canyon slayings,
the home break-ins and
brutal knife slayings
of five separate Los Angeles
Canyon area residents...
Do you know where that other
carton of cigarettes went?
Glazer, here, is
25 years of age,
just under six feet
tall, and heavily built.
When last seen, he was
wearing a light beard.
Anyone seeing a man
matching this description
is asked to call the Los
Angeles Sheriff's Department
at 654-1654.
That's 654-1654.
Citizens are warned not
to try apprehending Glazer
on their own as he is
thought to be armed
and extremely dangerous.
In other news from
around the south land today,
a man believed responsible
for 100 downtown burglaries
was arrested by city police
today in Los Angeles.
Is it getting worse
every day, or is it just me?
I don't think it's just you.
Do you need anything
from the store?
You kidding?
It's after 11:00.
Can't it wait till morning?
Well we need some
milk for breakfast
and I'm out of cigarettes.
I'll be right back.
Come on Lise, there's a
nut out there somewhere.
Why don't you just forget it?
Forget about it.
I'll be gone 10 minutes.
He isn't out there attacking cars.
For goodness sakes.
No, absolutely not.
You are not going
out for cigarettes.
Oh, come on.
You're not going
out for cigarettes.
- You're a slave to them.
- Phillip.
I mean it Lise,
you're not going.
This is driving me crazy.
Well then give
the damn things up.
Daddy, I can't sleep.
Well, you little phony,
of course you can't sleep.
You're kneeling on your pillow.
Get under the covers, come on.
That's a girl.
Now close your eyes.
You can't sleep with them open.
All right, I'm gonna
sit right here till
you get to sleep.
I don't want to see you blink.
Get down, get down from there.
Hey!
Get away. Get Away.
Get down, hey
come on down.
Oh, oh I'm sorry
Lisa, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have him
off the leash like this
but we were walking
around the neighborhood.
You know, that nut is
loose in Topanga somewhere.
Really?
Yeah, it was just on the radio.
A sheriff's deputy got
slashed all to hell
down in Malibu.
Wow.
And the guy who did it ran up in
the hills somewhere.
You know you, you really
shouldn't have to go out
tonight if you don't have to.
Oh, I'm just going to the store.
Yeah, well why
don't you send Phil?
Well, I'd rather leave
him with the kids, thanks.
Yeah, I can see your point.
All right, but be careful, huh.
Okay, night Norman.
Goodnight.
Lisa, you know if
I finish that drywall
tomorrow we should
be able to get the
guest bedroom painted by...
Lisa.
Lisa!
The 33-year-old
highway patrolman
was taken to Malibu
Emergency Hospital
with multiple knife
wounds to the upper
chest and face.
Hospital spokesman
say he is in surgery
at this moment and
declined to list
his condition.
Phillip's assailant
may have been
William Henry
Glazier, the escaped
mental patient.
He is wanted in connection
with the grizzly
knife slayings of five
Los Angeles Canyon
residents in recent weeks.
Witnesses to the
assault say the man
matching Glazier's
description was wearing
grey institutional
type work clothes
and escaped into the
Topanga Foothills.
The same foothills where
sheriff's department
officials are now
conducting an intense
foot and helicopter search.
KF...
All right, I sure need a ride.
Hey wait, wait!
What the hell are you doing?
Uh, carton of
Metropolitans please.
Metropolitans.
Regulars or longs?
Regular.
Did you hear about
that highway patrolman
getting stabbed up here?
Yeah, terrible.
Yeah, just down the road.
Should have seen
those cop cars boy.
I'll tell you, those
guys come down real fast
when it's one of their own.
Well, I don't envy
you having to work here
alone all night.
I'm not alone.
Yeah, well, I don't like guns.
Miss?
$11.39.
Oh, sorry, keep the change.
Thanks.
Damn it.
Oh, boy.
Stupid, stupid, stupid, stupid.
Oh.
Want gas?
Five dollars?
Five dollars.
Oh my god, oh.
It's okay, it's okay, m♪am.
He was in the
backseat with a knife.
He's the guy they were
talking about on the radio.
It's okay.
It's over.
Lets just call the cops, huh?
Lets just call the police, okay?
Oh my god.
Thanks.
Yeah, thank you.
I was so shaky I
didn't want to drive.
Are you mad at me?
Did you get your cigarettes?
No.
♪ “I Don't Care
About You” by Fear
I don't know, J.J.
Huh?
I said I don't know.
What's that?
I'm not sure of this.
We're a long way
from The Valley.
That's the idea.
Stop yelling-
We're here.
I don't know, J.J.
Man, one of these times
our luck's gonna run out.
How else am I gonna make any
money to beat The Bishop, huh?
You got any better ideas?
Hey man, that's a great score.
Hey, you wanna play?
Oh no, J.J., you'll
end up losing that
10 bucks you got cutting
Old Man Harrison's lawn.
Shut up, Zock.
I don't always lose.
How about it?
You want to play, ese?
Yeah.
Okay, ese, we'll play.
But I wouldn't want
to give you lessons
unless you want to
play buck a game.
Five game minimum.
No J.J., come
on, let's get out.
No Zock, it's okay. We're
just having a little fun. Come on.
Man-
Well, that's pretty steep.
All right, all right, yeah.
Yeah, a buck a game, five games.
Who knows, I might even win.
Damn.
All right, one more.
No, that's six bucks already
and I got to get
home for supper.
Hey, hey, come on, Zock.
- I gotta go.
- One more game.
Come on, this will
only take 10 minutes.
No, you keep losing.
Come on, it's all right.
Now look, my
buddy's a little antsy
so, uh, why don't
we raise the stakes
a little bit, huh?
Okay, how much?
How about 25 bucks.
Are you out of your mind?
If you want to give away money
why don't you just
give it to me?
Okay ese, let me see if
I can cover it, all right?
25 peso, vato.
All right.
I got the bread, man.
Lets play.
Me first?
Totally.
Pleasure taking your money, ese.
All right, nice and easy.
All right, you got
it man, you got it.
All right, yeah.
17 chinga.
My homeboy.
Be my guest, ese.
Last chance J.J.,
you're never gonna make it.
Thanks for those
encouraging words
in time of need.
You have to beat 17,010.
Lets see what he can do, huh?
Don't get nervous, ese.
Hey dude, don't kiss him.
I remember now.
That dude's named J.J. Cooney.
He's the best, man.
The best who ever was.
You guys are getting hustled.
♪ “Let's Have a War" by Fear
17,220. He did it.
Boy, I don't know
what, what happened.
I guess I just
kind of got lucky.
Not even, ese.
Hey vato, your name Cooney?
Never heard of him, man.
Beat it, ese.
You're lucky.
Hey, get back here.
Hey, where you going?
I'm gonna sneak
in a couple games
with The Bishop.
I'm gonna hit level
13 today, man, come on.
I got to go J.J.
Hey J.J., don't you get it?
13th level doesn't even exist.
It's just a scam to get suckers
to spend their money.
It exists.
I hear some kid out in
Jersey made it twice.
Yeah, right.
Hey look, just give
me my cut, okay?
My mom will kill me
if I don't get home.
Why don't you
just come in with me.
Just for two or three games.
Yeah, which turns into 10 games,
turns into all night.
Look J.J., give me my money.
I mean it.
- You want your cut?
- Yeah.
Sure you don't want
to come in with me
just for two games?
Thanks, got to go.
Go, go all the way
to hell for all I care.
You know what J.J.?
You're nuts.
That machine's made you
into some kind of fiend.
J.J. hey, you
gonna play The Bishop?
Not even.
Come here, guys.
Mind if we watch?
I'm going to level 13 today.
Awesome.
Hi J.J., you gonna
try The Bishop again?
He's going all the way to 13.
All right.
Come here you guys.
Come on, J.J.'s playing.
Let go of me, man.
Sorry man,
next time.
Hey, lets go, come on.
Hey man, heads up.
Man, oh wow.
Get to level 13.
Greetings earthling.
I am the Bishop of Battle.
Master of all I survey.
I have 13 progressively
harder levels.
Try me if you dare.
You are on level one.
Lets begin.
♪ Mercenaries by
Negative Trend
You have just reached level 12.
Welcome.
Guys, be quiet.
Let the master concentrate.
Lets begin.
Oh no.
You are good earthling,
but not good enough.
I am the Bishop of Battle.
Master of all I survey.
I have 13 progressively
harder levels.
Try me if you dare.
Insert coin.
Totally awesome, all right.
I don't even think
level 13 exists.
Yeah it does.
I heard some guy out in
Jersey got to it twice.
Hey, later, man.
Hey, come on J.J., it's closing time.
Hey, where you guys going?
Hey, come on back.
I got some more quarters.
It's getting late, J.J.
Hey, come on.
Come on, I got
some more quarters.
Lets play another game.
Just one more game.
Sorry.
Go on home.
Who needs you talentless
clowns anyway.
Get out of here.
Bunch of lightweights.
Come on J.J.,
lets go get a pizza.
We'll sit and talk
like we used to.
Shine it, Pamela, I'm not
into that crap anymore.
Greetings earthling.
I am the Bishop of Battle.
Master of all I survey.
Welcome to level one.
Lets begin.
Come on J.J.
I gotta close.
J.J.!
What are you doing?
Come on.
Lets go, pal.
There's a whole big
world out there.
- You like girls, J.J.?
- I'm feeling hot man.
Come on, I'm feeling really hot.
Come on, lets go, lets go.
Let me just...
Now come on, J.J.
Plug it back in, man, I mean it.
Hey, Cooney.
Now we've been
through this before.
Now, tomorrow's another day.
All right?
I'm your best customer, Willie.
You shouldn't
treat me like that.
- I'm gonna get back at you.
- Go home, Cooney.
I promise you that, man.
I'm gonna get back at you.
Good. Bye.
You think I'm kidding?
I mean it, man.
This sucks!
Come on, that's baloney.
How do you expect to
improve your grades
when you spend all
your time playing those
damn machines?
Oh no, forget it J.J.
As of now, you're grounded.
From now on, the game room
is off limits, period.
Come on, Dad,
be a sport, will ya?
Short? Sport?
Take a look at this
report card and tell me;
is that sport?
Forget it, J.J.
- Dad, I got a deal for you.
- No deals, end of discussion.
You're grounded.
Grounded?
Are you kidding me?
No, I'm not kidding you.
Dad, I am at my
absolute peak right now.
Oh, come on.
Don't you see?
I am this close.
J.J., you're not
making any sense
to either of us.
You're what, close to what?
The 13th level in The
Bishop of Battle.
Oh J.J., that is just a game.
It's not just a game.
It is just a game.
If I don't make it now, I
might never make it at all.
J.J., it's time you
went in your room.
No, it's not worth it.
Listen to me, Dad.
I listened long enough.
No you haven't.
Hear me out.
Now look, give me a
week, a couple days even.
When I make the 13th
level on that machine
that's it.
- I'm gonna retire from the games.
- Come on, come on...
I've heard this all before.
Why don't you
listen to me for once?
I've listened
to you long enough.
No, you haven't.
There's gonna be no more,
no more stealing quarters.
No more late nights
at the arcade.
- No more any of that.
- Enough.
I've heard enough.
Go to your room.
- No.
- Yes.
- Go to your room.
- Why?
You always said that...
You sit there in that chair
and you make judgments on me.
You don't know
anything about me.
Goodnight, go to hell.
What?
Forget it, both of you.
J.J.
I hate the both of you.
Jerry.
Leave him alone, Adele.
It's for his own good.
Jerry, he's not himself.
♪ “Rise Above” by Black Flag
Good evening, Bishop.
I hope you're ready to lose.
'Cause tonight's my night.
Hello?
Mrs. Cooney.
Zock, is that you?
Yeah.
Do you know what time it is?
Yeah, is J.J. there?
Zock, he's asleep
and you should be too.
Yeah, well, me and
J.J. kind of had a fight
today and I had a
nightmare about him
and I couldn't
get back to sleep.
Oh Zock, honey.
He has been acting
kind of strange
the last couple days.
I guess I just want
to know if he got home
all right and stuff.
Yeah, he's here and he's fine.
I'm sure you'll
make up tomorrow.
Now you go back to bed now.
Okay.
Goodnight.
Sorry.
Bye.
Who's that?
Was that the Maxwell boy?
Um hum.
Good lord.
- Where you going?
- To the bathroom.
Jerry.
♪ “I Got Power” by Negative Trend
You have just reached
level 12, earthling.
Welcome.
Lets begin.
Told you tonight was my night
you son of a...
Sorry Bishop, your boys
aren't good enough
for me tonight.
I'll see you on level 13.
You are very
very good earthling.
You have just reached level 13.
Welcome.
Lets begin.
I beat you.
I beat you!
My god.
Welcome earthling.
I am the Bishop of Battle.
Master of all I survey.
Stay away from me!
Well, he's not there either.
Zock, can you think
of any place else?
The Game-O-Rama should be open
in a couple of minutes.
We could check there
if you want to.
I doubt he'd go there
if he was running
away, though-
- Lets go.
- Come on, gel: in the car.
Get in.
Let's get the key in the door.
All right, all
right, I'm opening it.
Oh, it's still closed.
Hey Willie, seen J.J.?
No, not since last night, kid.
All right, I'll open it up.
It's like you guys have
never played before.
Where the hell could he be?
We got to call
the police, Jerry.
Lets go.
What the hell is this?
Look what they
did to the machines.
Damn vandals.
I am The Bishop of Battle.
Master of all I survey.
J.J.
I have 13 progressively
harder levels.
He's got you.
Try me if you dare.
Insert coin.
I am The Bishop of Battle.
Master of all I survey.
I have 13 progressively
harder levels.
Try me if you dare.
Frank.
Are you all right?
A nightmare.
What was it about?
It was horrible.
I'm sorry, sorry.
It's all getting too extreme.
I think maybe I should visit
my local parish priest.
It's almost 9:00, Frank.
Blessed art thou among women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour...
You are asking,
Father, why we are
given so many signs of evil
and so few signs of good.
I can't help but
think that the entire
concept of good and evil
may be a fallacious one,
Your Eminence.
It's come to that.
God works in ways we
cannot understand.
is with him now.
He's in a better place.
You've been a good friend, Luis.
You're leaving?
Uh huh.
Where you going?
Well, I got about $78 in cash
and a credit card
with about $100
still left on it.
I'm gonna drive until
I can't buy gas anymore
and then I'm gonna stop,
get some kind of a job.
What are you, crazy?
Come on, Frank, everybody
has a crisis of faith.
You do, I do, the Bishop does.
Even St. Thomas did.
But it doesn't mean you stop,
pick up everything and go.
I respect your belief, Luis.
Respect my lack of belief.
ls all this happening
because of that
little boy's death?
You're really not giving
me much credit, are you?
What about the
family, my friend?
You're gonna leave
them with that
pitiful excuse for a
eulogy and then just go?
Think.
Think about what that
says to them, Frank.
Frank, you've been
their shepherd.
The least you can
do is wait until
their grief begins to dissipate.
Look, I don't care what
you really believe in.
All I know is those
people are in desperate
need of counseling.
You've become very
important to them.
They need you, Frank.
The well is dry.
What are you doing?
Frank, it's holy
water, it's blessed.
It's tap water and I need it.
I got a long drive
across the desert
and a car with no
air conditioning.
Adios, Luis.
Thank you.
Grocery store.
Hold up.
What?
They shot the kid.
They want the last rights.
Get an ambulance.
He's gone, Frank.
He's gone.
Get an ambulance.
Sit down, it's gonna
be all right, sit down.
I see only anarchy.
I see inexplicable,
unfathomable anarchy.
And I see people
ground up in the gears
of this anarchy.
I see people in anguish.
My biggest fear
is this is not the
work of the devil
because there can
be no devil if there is no God.
And if there were
an Almighty God,
he would never allow
such suffering.
I've come to believe
that we are living
in a great void, Your Eminence.
I've lost my faith.
What is it you want?
No!
There's no tracks
in that sand anywhere.
There's no strange
paint in those dents
on your car.
Nah, there's just no evidence of
another vehicle
around here anywhere.
You think I'm making this up?
No sir, uh, I think
that maybe you fell
asleep and went off the road.
Your car rolled over
and you got thrown out.
They say you got
a mild concussion.
I had one of them once myself.
Gave me the weirdest
dreams, like you.
You know, Father, in
the history of the church
only a few, very few
individuals have been
given a literal
sign, as at Lourdes.
That's why the word is faith.
You understand?
: Well, we're right
smack dab between
that hospital up in
Bisbee and Travis General
where you're coming from.
I'll have that driver just
take you on up to Bisbee.
No wait, wait...
Take me to Travis.
Now you did tell me
you were leaving there,
didn't ya?
That's where my parish is.
Yes sir, it's all right with me.
Travis.
Steven?
Huh?
What?
I heard it again.
Can rats get in
between the walls?
It's not rats.
It's the wind.
The branches need a trimming.
Go to sleep.
Just turn off the
violins, will ya, Bill?
This isn't the first
time this son of a...
the nitwit screwed up.
So his wife's expecting.
It isn't the issue.
The man's an employee,
he works for us.
He represents us.
I'll be damned if I'm gonna
let him embarrass us again.
Mommy.
We're on the line here, too.
What's pryidoxine hydrochloride?
God knows.
No notice...
- Am I eating it?
- Just give him two weeks severance
and get him out.
Look Bill, I'll be in
in a half an hour.
I want Higgins gone.
Jim Higgins.
You don't know
anything about this, Claire,
so don't start.
Jim used to be
your best salesman.
You know, Nancy's pregnant.
What's this with
the exterminator?
What's all this about?
We have rats.
I heard them in the walls
and later in the attic.
You didn't wake up.
Are they white ones?
Just go out and
buy a couple of traps.
I'll set them up tonight
and that'll be it.
Well, I just
figured you wouldn't
want to be bothered
with setting traps.
Look, we still want
the swimming pool, right?
What?
The swimming pool,
I take it we still want to put it in.
Oh yeah, Daddy, of course we do.
Well, we're going to, peanut.
But the way we're going
to is by not wasting
a lot of money on things
like cleaning ladies
twice a week and
shyster rat catchers
who come out and look for
droppings once a month.
We did agree that certain things
we're going to start
doing around here
all by ourselves,
didn't we, Claire?
If you catch the rat
can I keep it, Daddy?
I'll tell you what, sweetheart,
if Mommy says it's okay,
you've got yourself a deal.
Here you go.
Go get your books.
I'll wait for you in the car.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh no, honey.
You see anything?
Insulation.
Mr. Thompson has
two rats in a cage.
Who's Mr. Thompson?
Billy Noble's teacher.
One's named Annie, the
other, he's the boy,
he's named Pinto
because he has these
little pink spots all over.
Oh.
Billy says Pinto is this big.
Brooke, please.
Did you do it?
Yeah, tough job.
Took all of a minute and a half.
What's the trouble here?
No trouble.
Seems like we've had this kind
of trouble around
here for a month.
How would you know?
You're never around.
You're either traveling
or at the office or something.
I'm here now.
Steven.
Steven, you're not even here
when you're here anymore.
Do you know how
insensitive you've become?
You use a sledgehammer
most of the time
when just a word
or two would do.
There are people
who get things clone
and there are people
who don't, Claire.
Steven.
All our problems should
be solved so easily.
Steven, would you
please get rid of it?
What?
Would you please get rid of it?
Now?
Well, I am not going
to be able to sleep
knowing it's bleeding all over us.
I am not getting dressed
and going down -
- Steven please, please.
- Absolutely.
Yes m♪am, at your service.
Your hero humbly accepts
his thanks, by the way.
I can't find Rosie.
What'd you say, hun?
Rosie, she's gone.
You mean she wasn't in your room
when you woke up?
No and I'm scared.
Oh honey, she probably
just went out somewhere.
She never just goes away.
Sometimes she does.
Somebody got a problem here?
Rosie's gone.
Mama says she just
goes away some times.
But she doesn't.
Oh, this sink is all plugged up.
I'm afraid something's
happened to her.
Here let me do that, hun.
Excuse me.
Wasn't Rosie fixed?
Yeah, she was fixed
almost a year ago
but that doesn't mean
that she can't go out sometimes.
She wouldn't go out for that.
I know her.
Rosie wouldn't go
out for that at all.
Don't worry about Rosie, peanut.
She'll be back by the time
you get home from school.
We better hurry up,
we're gonna be late.
Oh, that's disgusting.
What is it?
Nothing to worry about.
Just some old rat hair.
I thought you said
it was a white rat.
I'm surprised that
little guy wasn't bald.
Rosie.
Kitty.
Kitty, kitty.
Rosie, come here.
Rosie.
Kitty.
Here, kitty kitty.
Rosie.
Rosie?
Oh...
Kitty?
Rosie?
Oh great.
Rosie.
Hi Rosie, come here.
Rosie?
Come here, kitty.
Ow.
Come here, Rosie, come on.
Won't you come here?
Rosie?
You all right, honey?
Come here kitty, come here.
What's the matter?
Rosie?
You all right?
Baby, I'm gonna catch you.
Oh.
Come on, Rosie.
Oh, oh.
Okay, bye.
Hi honey.
You have a good day?
Pretty good.
Billy was lying about Pinto.
He's only that big.
Did Rosie come home yet?
Did she?
No, she didn't, honey.
Can I go to Cindy's
after I change?
Sure ya can.
You have to be home
before it gets dark. All right?
Okay.
Mommy!
Look what Rosie did!
Honey, wait for me.
What is it, honey?
Look.
Why would Rosie do that?
What's wrong, Mommy?
Oh.
Oh my god.
Why would Rosie do this, Mommy?
I don't know, honey.
Choosey's okay.
Honey, why don't we go over...
Mommy.
It's all right honey.
It's all right.
Why don't we, uh, go
over to Cindy's now.
Okay?
The wires have
been gnawed through.
That's what caused
the flickering light.
But aren't wires
inside pipes or something?
Look at this.
Didn't seem to
bother this fella.
You mean it bit
straight through the pipe?
A rat can do that?
I've seen a seven
pound rat squeeze through
a quarter inch
crack under a door
without exhaling, Mrs. Houston.
I've seen them living
in mud huts along
the river like beavers
and nesting in trees
like eagles.
I've seen 'em as big as
a medium size dog
and as small as a big June bug.
I'm no longer surprised at
anything I see a rat do.
Very special animals.
They're horrid
animals is what they are.
This one is big and horrid.
You saw him?
Well, I saw his eyes.
He was, uh, looking at me when I
was underneath the house.
How long have
you been on vacation
or wherever?
Oh, we haven't been anywhere.
But your little
girl has been away?
No, Why?
Well it's obvious your
pest has been working
at this for several weeks.
How come you didn't
notice until today?
Well, that wall was
perfect yesterday.
That happened sometime
during the night.
I think you better
show me the cabinet
he was into downstairs.
oh, my god.
That, madam, was not done
by your average rodent.
I've never seen that
kind of destruction.
Steven, look what
this thing has done.
It's worse than we thought.
My name is
Keefer, Mr. Houston.
You've got an unusually
aggressive visitor, sir.
- I've never seen anything like...
- You know that it's killed Rosie
and I found her under the house.
Apparently, my
wife misunderstood me.
I was under the impression
that we agreed I was
gonna handle this
problem by myself.
Steven you can't
handle this problem by...
How much do I
owe you Mr. Keefer?
Well sir, you really
don't owe me anything.
- Well then, thank you very much.
- Steven.
I apologize for having
wasted your time.
Steven.
Wait a minute.
Look, I'm not gonna
let Brooke sleep up in her room.
Wait till you see the
damage it's done.
Then she can sleep in the
bedroom next to our room.
Would you excuse us
please, Mr. Keefer.
I'm terribly sorry I
bruised your precious ego.
Get off my back, Claire.
I had a tough clay.
I had no idea it was so fragile.
We have a second rat,
I'll get rid of it.
You know what
Mr. Keefer said?
- He said he's never...
- You know what your problem is?
Seen this kind of destruction.
It's the same as 99% of
the people in this world.
Why don't we bring
in somebody who's
see this type of damage.
It never occurs to you
to do something yourself.
Will Rosie come back?
Well, you know what I think?
I think Rosie might
have gone to visit
some friends.
But will she ever come back?
I don't know.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Now you get some sleep now.
Tomorrow's another school day.
Good night.
Don't close the door.
I won't.
Good night.
Good night, Rosie.
I think we should
buy Brooke another cat.
A kitten.
It probably would be best
to wait until we get rid of...
Hello?
Mrs. Houston, it's Keefer.
Yes.
The reason I'm calling
is, well, this might sound
a little strange Mrs. Houston,
but there's this old book
I have from back in
Germany in the 1600s.
Tells about a thing called
the das Teufel Nagetier.
Das what?
Claire, who is it?
Das Teufel Nagetier.
I was going to tell
you about it today
but Mr. Houston didn't seem much
in the mood for listening.
Who is that?
It's late.
Well, what is this Das
Teufel, whatever it is?
It translates into
“the devil rodent".
It's a legend about
huge malevolent rodents
with unbelievable
cunning and strength
that terrorize certain
villainous individuals
in 17th Century Europe.
Claire, who are you talking to?
The problem is
according to the legend
Das Teufel Nagetier cannot
be destroyed, Mrs. Houston.
That's ridiculous.
Claire, who the hell is...
Who is this?
It's Keefer, Mr. Houston.
The reason I called
before is that I think
the problem over there may
be bigger than you realize.
What in hell are
you talking about?
We have rats.
I'll take care of them.
You won't.
Don't call again.
Everybody's got
their hand out Claire
and you're always
right there to fill it.
He told me an awful story.
Of course he did,
to scare you into
rehiring him.
Steven?
Steven.
Mommy, Daddy, I'm scared.
Brooke.
Mommy!
Brooke!
Brooke.
Are you all right, sweetheart?
Honey, honey, oh God.
Are you okay?
What is going on?
Oh God!
Mommy.
What is happening here?
Steven?
Come on, honey.
Mommy!
It's all right honey,
you just stay right,
I'm just gonna close the,
I'm just gonna close the door.
Okay?
See?
There.
Okay?
Mommy!
Oh honey, it's
all right, sweetheart.
They'll go back on.
They will, I know.
Rosie, see, see,
they went back on.
Now we'll just stay
right here and everything
will be just fine.
All right?
Steven!
What are you doing?
Steven, Steven,
you can't kill it.
What are you talking about?
Mommy, Daddy!
He's in the ceiling!
Honey, it's all right baby.
Here, stay here.
Steven!
You can't kill it!
You're gonna kill us!
Steven!
You're gonna kill...
Mommy!
Brooke, open the door!
What?
Come on baby,
honey, open the door.
It's Daddy, open the door!
Brooke, open the door.
Watch out.
No!
You'll kill her.
Watch out!
Mommy!
Help me!
Steven!
Mommy!
No, wait, you're
going to kill her.
I think it's trying
to tell me something.
What honey?
What, what's the
rat gonna tell you?
Bring baby...
Bring baby.
Hers.
Bring her baby back to her.
Oh.
Mommy, Mommy!
Bring it back to her.
No Daddy, please.
Please Daddy, she
just wanted her baby.
Please, Daddy.
Mommy, Daddy.
Daddy, where do you
suppose she's going next?