Night of the Demons 2 (1994)
OliveFilms Bluray Release.
Doesn't look like
anyone's home.
You mustn't give up
so easily, Albert.
We've come all this way.
Let's just see.
Hello?
Anybody home?
You know, I don't think
anyone's living here.
I'm so sorry. I didn't
mean to frighten you.
Oh, well...
We didn't think
anyone was home.
Oh.
Have you been saved?
Who, me?
We're here spreading
the good word.
Do you realize that the end
of the world is drawing near?
As a matter of fact, I do.
I was just about to
have a slice of cake!
Would you two like to join me?
Huh. Well, how kind.
Yes, thank you.
This is a big house
you have here.
Must need a lot of upkeep.
Not really.
Ooh, yum.
Well, I hope you're hungry.
I think...
we'll skip the cake.
Oh, don't be silly.
It's devil's food!
Mmm.
♪ I'm not a warrior ♪
♪ But I am a lover ♪
She's so beautiful.
Oh, turn around.
Please turn around.
Yes. Bingo!
Hey, come on, Kurt.
I paid for half of those.
Come on, you hog
them every night.
It's my turn.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
I was just bedazzled.
Jesus, Perry, you just now
getting out of the bathroom?
What the hell you been doing
there this whole time?
Spanking your monkey again?
Gee, how time flies.
You're the one with
the binoculars.
♪ When I steal
your heart away ♪
♪ I'll steal your heart... ♪
Damn it, Kurt, they're turning
out the lights already.
You can go first
tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night's the dance.
So?
They'll still have to take their
clothes off when it's over.
Bibi.
Yes.
The day after the party, the county
sheriff went in with his deputies.
They found the kids, or rather,
what was left of them.
Their bodies were chopped,
grated, sliced, and diced.
Totally toasted.
I'm talking ground round.
Terri!
Their relatives could
barely identify them.
But they did.
Every one of them.
Every one except Angela.
Angela?
The girl who threw the party.
They searched the
property over and over,
hi and low,
but never found her body.
They say it's because she
descended into hell,
body and soul,
and now she's
Satan's favorite,
sitting on his lap.
She's probably sitting on
his big spike right now.
There's some things that
you shouldn't joke about.
Go to bed, Mouse.
My name's Melissa.
All right, Melissa.
Go to bed.
Before I cut your tail off.
So this place, Hull House,
it still exists?
Oh, yeah. Right at the
end of Old Hull Road.
Every so often, some kids
venture out there on a dare.
Some of them come back
insisting that Angela
is still in the house
searching for her
missing party guests.
Some claim to have actually
heard the swooshing
of her long black
wedding dress
as it sweeps against
the mildewed walls.
Others claim to have
actually seen her,
now a demon floating through
the long dark hallways,
and some never
come back at all.
Oh, right.
Are you scared?
You wish.
Lights out.
Mouse.
Mouse, wake up.
Angela?
Am I dreaming?
No, you're not
dreaming, silly.
I'm right here, see?
Smile, sis!
Mouse!
Come on.
Terri.
En garde.
Coupè. Coulè.
Tiercè.
Touchè.
Who is it?
It's Father Bob, Sister.
Come in.
Good morning, Sister Gloria.
Oh, good morning.
I hope I'm not disturbing you.
Oh, no, no, no, no. Come in.
What can I do for you, Father?
Well, um, the reason
I stopped by is
I wanted to talk to you about
the school dance tonight.
School dance?
Yes, I thought it would
be a great opportunity
for the kids to, well,
cut loose for a change.
Cut loose?
Yes, you know.
Burn up some of that
youthful exuberance
by having the kids get more
involved in running the dance
and take some responsibility
for creating their own fun.
What do you think?
Well, Father, these
children are troubled
and the parents send them
here for discipline.
No, Sister.
No, Sister, their
parents send them here
in order for us to
help them adjust
in growing up with the
pressures of today's world.
What they need to learn
is responsibility,
not discipline.
But I've been running the
Halloween dance for 15 years now.
Precisely!
Now, all I'm asking is for a
little fresh input from the kids.
Input? Father Edward
would never have--
Father Edward is in
Somalia, Sister.
Now, if you'd like, I'm sure I could
arrange a transfer to his clinic.
Have you been
vaccinated for malaria?
St. Rita's is my home, Father.
Well, then, I'm sure
you'll make every effort
to make it a happy one...
for all of us,
including the kids.
Look, just work
with them, Sister.
Is that too much to ask?
Whatever you say, Father.
Good.
Hi, there.
You're Melissa, right?
Yeah.
Are you going to the dance?
Dance?
Yeah, you know, the
big Halloween dance.
Maybe I'll see you there.
I can't believe Mouse
is Angela's sister.
Yeah, well, after she wakes up with a
few more of those screaming nightmares,
maybe then you'll believe it.
Does she do that often?
Just about every other night.
What a freak.
Hey, Mouse is all right.
She's just had it a
little rough, that's all.
A little rough? Yeah.
So who hasn't?
Well, listen to this.
About a year ago her
parents received
a weird Halloween card.
It was homemade and
really creepy,
like, decorated with dead
bugs and dried blood.
It was totally disgusting.
Anyway, it was
signed by Angela.
They really took it hard.
Everyone tried to convince them
that it was just a really bad joke,
but they swore that
it was her signature.
That night, they both
committed suicide.
Suicide?
That's why she's here.
She's an orphan.
No shit.
She's a charity case.
Stop that vicious gossip.
Whatever the truth is about
Melissa and her family,
I want you all to show a
little bit more compassion
for her in the future.
Things are bad enough for
her without your abuse.
Hey, beautiful.
Tonight's the night.
I can't wait.
I had a dream about you.
You did?
Mm-hmm.
Save a little room
for the Holy Ghost.
Sorry.
Thanks.
You're such a gentleman.
And these are things you will need
to know when you are married.
Now, don't be shy, girls. I know that
this is an embarrassing subject,
but if one doesn't
ask questions,
one never learns, does one?
Yes, Teresa?
Sister, is it a sin
to kiss a boy?
I mean, if you really,
really like him?
A kiss is a sin
when it is an upper persuasion
for a lower invasion.
Yes, Shirley?
Sister Gloria,
is fellatio a mortal
sin or a venial sin?
Fellatio.
I don't think I'm
familiar with that term.
Could you please explain to the
class exactly what that means?
What's the matter,
Miss Finnerty?
Cat got your tongue?
Oh, by the way, boys,
Sister Gloria has
called my attention
to the fact that several
imaginative rumors
have been circulating throughout
the school
regarding a certain
local landmark.
Hull House.
Yes, Kurt, that is correct.
A typical urban folktale.
Folktales? Mm-hmm.
You can't write that stuff
off as folktales, Father.
Why not? Well, that stuff
really did happen.
It's a matter of record.
Well, of course, they
happened, Johnny,
but things happen everywhere.
Uh, excuse me, Father?
Yes, Perry, what is it?
Rather than blindly dismissing the
legend of Hull House completely,
perhaps it would be more constructive
to discuss demonic phenomena
from a religious perspective.
Perry, this is a
catechism class,
not Demonology 101.
Yeah, but demonology is part
of our catechism, Father.
Excuse me?
Well, the church gets its directive
from Jesus Himself, right?
Yes.
Well, He cast out
demonic spirits
no less than 26
times in the Bible.
Well, yes,
but why don't we discuss some
of Jesus' other teachings,
such as love for all mankind?
Father? Yes.
You mean the kind of love
we get from Sister Gloria?
Yeah, like on the tip
of her yardstick.
All right, boys.
That's enough.
Excuse me, Father. Yes?
I have been researching demonic
possession.
Well, therein lies
your problem, Perry.
You're wasting your time reading
the wrong kind of books.
Stick with this one.
Go ahead, laugh.
It won't be long before
somebody proves that
demonic energies
do indeed exist.
And maybe then, Father,
demonology will finally get
the kind of scientific
credibility it deserves.
Ah, yes, Perry, I'm sure it
will rank right up there
with astrology and
trance channeling.
And now my spirit guide
says it's time for...
math.
Open 'em up.
Jordan's got the ball!
He's charging down the line!
He's got it. He's got it!
It's 10, 9, 8--
It's going nowhere.
He's got only one shot.
He goes, shoots!
Oh, man.
Hey, butthead, what are you
looking for, a fat lip?
I want my book.
What book?
Come on, you know what book.
That's a rare text.
It cost me a
month's allowance.
What's the problem here?
Oh, the old sexorcist here thinks I stole
his precious little ghoulie book.
Yeah, so?
So what would
I want with a book?
Good point.
Perry, Kurt doesn't
have your book.
He can barely read a clock.
Thank you. Sure.
You guys think you're
so great just because
you're bigger, tougher, and
better-looking than everybody else.
I'm gonna show you that--
He said he doesn't
have your book.
I'm gonna prove
that demons exist.
Yeah, well, you're
living proof.
Look, why don't you go haunt
a house or something,
let us finish our
lunch in peace?
Whoa. Speaking of lunch.
Ooh. Check out
those headlights.
That's something that could
really brighten my day.
That's what I'd call
double trouble.
It's the kind of trouble I'd
like to get my hands on.
Oh, yeah?
So do it, dude,
unless you left your balls
in your other Calvins.
Just pay attention, junior.
You just might learn something.
From you?
Just watch the bouncing ball.
Looks like I caught something.
Yeah, or something caught you.
Sorry. Slippery fingers.
Name's Kurt. Ladies
call me Kingsnake.
Oh, really? I heard
they call you Inchworm.
Yeah.
Can I at least get
the ball back?
Who's stopping you?
I've got your ball.
Maybe we should throw
ice water on them.
Oh! Do you really think
that would stop them?
Nah.
Shit. Sister.
Hey, Kurt.
What in the holy name of
glory is going on here?
I asked you a
question, young lady.
What is going on?
I see.
Struck dumb by the
devil, are we?
I knew from the
get-go I was going
to have trouble with you,
Miss Shirley Finnerty.
Kiss off, you old tyrant.
We were just--
You are lucky, young lady,
that there are laws
that prevent me
from giving you the
punishment that you deserve.
In the old days, I would've--
Would've what?
Well...
I can see that you need time
to examine your conscience.
Therefore you will remain
in the dormitory tonight.
And that goes for your
friends here, too.
But, Sister, the dance!
Oh, hey, come on. We
didn't do anything.
We'll just give those
raging teenage hormones
a chance to cool down.
You old witch.
October 31st, 6:25 P.M.
I am in the sacristy of St.
Rita's chapel
preparing to conduct an
experiment of demon conjuration.
I've chosen the sacristy
for three reasons.
One, it is quiet.
Two, it is the likely
vortex of mystical energy.
Three, it's totally safe.
This sucks.
I have to set up for a dance
I'm not even invited to.
Isn't this some sort of
child abuse or something?
I'm gonna get a lawyer.
The Church is worth
lots of money.
I think we can get
rich off this.
Yeah, right.
Neil Diamond?
This stuff is fossil fuel.
This is Flintstones
top 10 countdown.
Ooh, you're right.
We're lucky we're not going to
old Gory's Jurassic hoe-down.
You said it.
Oh, Kurt.
Got a minute?
Who, me?
Yeah, Einstein.
Y-O-O. You.
Yeah, sure.
Barry Manilow?
I will be using texts from the
ancient Assyrian Necronomicon
as phonetically translated by the
professor Heinrich Hilmeister.
"Mi-halo shaitan
"ben-el shaitan
shakraf hu y'ra."
"Mi-halo shaitan
"ben-el shaitan
shakraf hu y'ra."
"Mi-halo shaitan
"ben-el shaitan
shakraf hu y'ra."
"Mi-halo shaitan..."
Who's there?
Perry!
Oh, thank God. Father Bob.
What are you doing in here
and why do you have
on my chasuble?
Don't be mad, Father.
I needed a safe place to
conduct my experiment.
Experiment?
Yeah, and it worked.
It worked better than
I could've dreamed.
I actually conjured a demon.
Conjured up a demon?
Oh, Perry.
Perry, I have given you
every chance I could,
but this obsession of yours has
gotten totally out of hand.
You're not listening
to me, Father.
I saw Angela. She's a demon.
The legend of Hull
House is true.
Perry... Father...
I saw her in the mirror.
Look, she attacked me.
I have scratches
all over my wrist.
She almost pulled me into
the mirror with her.
Silence.
Now, Perry, you have
desecrated the sacristy.
You have defiled
my holy vestments.
Not to mention the
damage you've done--
Father, haven't you
heard a word I said?
Yes, and I've heard
quite enough.
Now, go to the dormitory.
You're hereby grounded
until I decide otherwise.
No dance tonight.
Oh, come on, Father...
Go.
I'll take this.
I'll expect the rest of your
collection in my office tomorrow.
Drop it off before
your first class.
Whoa! Back off, Romeo.
Let's save some for later.
Later?
Now, listen, Shirley,
about this party.
You know, I really don't
think it's a good idea.
I mean, if we get
caught off campus,
Old Glory's really gonna
rip our head off.
Listen up, Inchworm,
this is gonna be the
party of the century.
Don't get me wrong. I don't
have a problem with it.
You see, it's Johnny.
Oh, yeah?
Well, if you can't even get
your best friend to a party...
Jesus, I can't believe
I actually let you
touch my breasts.
I didn't say that
I couldn't get him to come.
Here's your invite.
All the cute girls
will be there,
including Bibi and Terri.
If you ain't at the
pick-up by 8 with Johnny,
forget you ever knew me.
♪ Can you rise above? ♪
♪ Plant a little seed
and watch it grow... ♪
Oh, God, what was I thinking
when I bought this?
Bibi, you're not helping.
Who cares?
My world is over.
Well, mine isn't.
Bibi, hey.
I thought maybe you would want to
wear this to the dance tonight?
What are you talking
about, Mouse?
You trying to be funny?
No, I...
I'm not going to the dance.
You're not?
No, she's not.
You're good friend Sister
Gory grounded her.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
No. Hey, I appreciate it.
It's really pretty.
You think so?
Um, I made it in
sewing class and...
I don't know, but I could never
wear anything like this.
Sure you could.
No.
Sure you could, Mouse.
After all, it is Halloween.
Here, I want you to have that.
All right, look, B., this
is what we're going to do.
All you need to do is go to Father Bob
and explain to him what happened.
He's gonna have to let
us go to the dance.
Fat chance.
I just saw Father Bob
in the courtyard
and he looked like he was
ready to kill somebody.
Forget it. Come on, get up.
Better start getting dressed
if you want to look your best.
Ooh, for what?
A leisurely night in the dorm?
No, you dipshit, we're
going to a party,
and I ain't talking Sister
Gloria's stupid dance, either.
We're talking a real
Halloween party.
We're talking the sexiest guys
and the wildest
party games ever.
Yeah, right.
And I suppose that
you're gonna--
Zip it, lame-o.
Now, don't ask me how,
but I pulled some strings,
and I managed to get you
both on the A-list,
so don't wuss out.
And where's this party?
Outside the walls of
this penitentiary,
and that's all you gotta know
except for the fact that
Johnny will be there.
Oh...
Johnny?
Yeah.
Oh, could you get
Mouse to come?
Mouse?
Why do you want Mouse?
Why not?
Didn't Sister Gloria say
we should be nice to her?
I don't know, Kurt. She
didn't even say where it is.
Who cares where it is?
It's a party, man.
And wherever it is,
Bibi's gonna be there.
Bibi?
And anybody who's anybody
is gonna be there.
Twist my arm.
You think I'd have to?
♪ When I touch,
it makes me shiver ♪
♪ When I feel,
Hey, I don't know if we should
be doing this, you guys.
You're right, Mouse.
Why don't you just
go back to the dorm?
Terri, please.
Mouse, just relax.
It's a party.
Just stop worrying
for one night, okay?
It's gonna be fine.
Um, is it a costume party?
No, Shirley told us
to come as we were.
Hey, if Sister Gloria finds
out we're doing this,
we're gonna get in trouble--
Gloria's not gonna find out.
We'll be back before
the dance is over.
Shh. Car's coming.
Let's go, gang. We ain't
waiting here all night.
Everybody, this is Rick.
Hey.
Come here, sweet tits.
Kurt.
Say hi to Rick.
Hey.
Let's move it, huh?
Jeez, I don't want to be doing
time here for hauling jail bait.
Let's go.
Glad you made it, Mouse.
My name's Melissa.
So, uh, Rick?
Huh?
What school do you go to?
I'm currently enrolled at the
school of hard knockers.
Yeah, but, you know, I'm pretty
much into the entire student body,
huh, Shirl?
So you kids are all
troubled, huh?
How 'bout, you, Marcia?
What's your problem?
Actually, I, um...
I killed my parents.
Oh, yeah? Me, too.
All right.
Hey, wait a minute!
Wait a minute.
I'm a little lost here.
Which way do we go?
Right. Go left.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
Wussies.
Oh, God, no.
No, this is Hull House.
Mouse, I'm sorry.
Bibi, you tricked me.
No, Shirley didn't tell me.
Sorry, babe. The
Ritz was booked.
No. No, take me home.
I can't go here!
Would somebody shut her up?
Take me home! I can't go!
Shut the fuck up! Shut up!
Shut up, Mouse.
No!
Maybe we should discuss this.
Yes.
Nobody knew that it was here.
Overruled.
You didn't tell us the
party was at Hull House.
I didn't say it wasn't, did I?
Johnny?
Well, we're here already.
We may as well make
the most of it.
You know, something to
tell our grandkids about.
Here, Shirl.
Come on, Mouse.
You brought me here, Bibi.
Well, I didn't know.
Hey, come on, Mouse,
don't be afraid.
You're with us. Nothing's
gonna happen here tonight.
You know about my
sister, Angela.
Melissa, nobody knows for sure
what happened to your sister.
I mean, maybe she
just ran away.
Hey, look, if she wants
to stay here, fine.
Let her. Come on.
Wait a second. He did what?
You should have seen his face.
Oh, Angela!
Angela!
Come out, come out,
wherever you are!
Your party guests are here!
Shh! Come on!
This place used to
be a funeral home.
So what? Are you afraid
I'll wake the dead?
This is awesome.
♪ Close my eyes
and I'm lost ♪
♪ In a world
that's moving... ♪
Leave a little room
for the Holy Ghost.
Oh, God.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed are...
Real cute.
I don't think
Angela will mind.
There. Done.
What was that?
Probably just Rick.
He's a real scream, isn't he?
I'm starving. What
is there to eat?
Well...
Bibi's wearing candy pants.
Oh, yeah?
What flavor?
Um, cherry?
Mmm. Johnny's favorite.
Oh, come on, guys.
Do you want to take a walk?
You're not afraid
of Hull House?
You'll protect me, won't you?
Oh, yeah.
Hey, wait a second, you guys.
You're not gonna leave
me here alone, are you?
You're not alone.
Hey, don't go too far.
I have a big
surprise coming up.
Oh, I can't wait.
Hey, Shirl,
check this out, huh?
Found it in the old morgue.
Hmm? Whoa.
Think of all the dead bodies
that slept on this thing.
Oh, yeah.
Rick, check it out. Huh?
Shit.
What the hell?
Jesus, Rick, this paint sucks.
What do you want from me?
I stole the best I could.
This party sucks.
Why don't you go take
a little field trip?
Go do some sight seeing.
Hey, get out of here, man.
Rick and I will call
when we need ya.
Sure.
So, did you bring the
little fuzz ball?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, how cute.
Yeah, the perfect
little victim.
For pin the knife
on the sacrifice.
Kitty, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty.
What a dump.
Come on, Bibi.
Are you all right in there?
Serious, you had me worried.
Ooh, it's cold out here.
Yeah, well, I know a place
where we can warm up.
You gotta keep
your eyes closed.
Okay. All right?
Okay.
Cool, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Ow!
Wanna party?
Absolutely.
Hey, stop it!
Shh.
What?
Come on, stop.
Not here in the hallway.
You're so beautiful.
Somebody help me!
Woo hoo hoo!
Mouse?
Z-boy!
What's up, man? Hey, baby.
Happy Halloween, dude. Yeah!
Yeah, now. Hey, dollface.
Scared up another
party guest for ya.
Boo!
Well, you also scared
away our sacrifice, dude.
Ooh.
Hey, Shirl, you know what?
Who needs a cat...
when we got a little mouse?
Ooh, yeah, mama.
Yeah, who needs a cat?
Maybe we can find a virgin.
Mousy little mousy.
Mousy! Mousy!
Hey, what was that?
Olly olly oxen free!
It's time for the
big surprise!
Hey, come on. We don't want
to miss the big surprise.
Come on.
This is so romantic.
Oh, shit!
What the hell's going on?
Ah-ah-ah! Hold it
right there, hulk.
I don't think you want
to be doing that.
No, no, no, you just
shut the fuck up
and enjoy the show now, 'kay?
Wohaa!
Tonight, we gather in
the name of darkness,
and with this
consecrated dagger,
we offer this virgin lamb.
That's Perry's book.
Please accept her blood as
payment for the favors we seek.
Accept the purity
of her life force.
Feast on her virgin soul.
Please, accept our
humble sacrifice.
Amen.
No!
What do you think
you're doing, man?
Stop it! Stop!
Stop it!
Listen--
Johnny, stop.
Stop?
I'm just getting started.
No, didn't you
hear that scream?
No.
It was probably just
some stupid prank.
No, I don't think so.
Look here, Hulkster.
No pain, no brain.
No cavity.
It don't slice, dice,
chop, or peel, my man.
It's the all new
amazing Knife-O-Matic.
We like that, baby.
What's going on?
Dude, why didn't you guys
tell me it was a fake knife?
Jesus, what are you?
The joke inspector?
You ruined the prank, asswipe.
Oh, mama.
Look, we got us a little
miss prom queen here.
Yeah, back off, pal.
Oh, a tough guy, huh?
Tell me something, toughie,
is she as good as she looks?
You'll never know.
You're breaking my heart.
You're breaking it in two.
Just let me have a
little something, boy.
Woo!
What the hell is that?
Something's happening.
Yeah, I can feel it.
Really, I can smell it.
It's gross.
Smells like a little
teen spirit to me.
Teen spirit, my ass.
It smells like
Godzilla's butthole.
It was Angela! It was Angela!
She was standing right there.
I saw her!
Bibi, take me out of here.
Please!
Okay, honey. Come on.
Please! Please.
No, she was here!
She was standing-- I saw
her standing right here!
Melissa, there's nobody here.
She's here!
Holy shit, that is rank!
Hey, I don't know
about you guys,
but I say we get the
hell out of here now.
This place bites the big one.
Yeah, wait a second, you
guys, I've gotta go pee.
Terri, you can hold it.
No, I don't think so.
Not if she's riding in my car.
Well, come on. Just
hurry up, will ya?
Look, I'll go with her.
It's right there.
Well, I think I gotta
go pee, too.
There it is.
Make it fast, would you?
Don't worry.
What do you want?
Go on now! Get.
What?
Come on, let's
get out of here.
Girls.
Kids.
Damn.
Wait up for me, baby. Hey.
I'm ready for you.
Where you been? Hey!
Let's get the
hell out of here.
Terri, what's wrong?
Can we just go now, please?
Hey, we ain't going
nowhere without Z-boy.
Well, where the hell is he?
He went to take a leak. Did
you pass him in the hall?
No.
Okay, honey child,
I know you're up there.
Don't be playing no games
with old Z-boy, baby.
You can't get away from me.
Oooh.
Oh, no. Dear God, no.
No, no, no, no!
What are you doing? No!
Jeez, doesn't the fun
ever end in this place?
Z-boy. That dude always has
to have the last laugh.
Well, let's just see
how hard he's laughing
when he comes back here,
finds us all gone.
We can't just leave him here.
Hell we can't.
He got here on his
own, didn't he?
Well, he can get his ass home.
I'm leaving.
Z-boy!
Hey, Z-boy, we're
splitting, baby.
Fuck him.
Oh, yeah.
Damn it, Shirl,
would you move it?
Man, I have seen
enough of this place.
Come on!
Jesus, Rick, can't you wait more
than a minute for anything?
Yeah, that's funny, Shirl.
Thank goodness we're
out of there.
I know what you mean.
Relax guys. Come on, we just
passed the underground stream.
What?
The underground stream that
surrounds the property.
Everybody says it keeps
the demons inside.
Yeah, right.
We're safe now.
♪ Some say we're
in danger here ♪
♪ As long as we're
all strangers here... ♪
Sister Gloria.
Can I speak to you
for a minute?
Certainly, Perry. You know, I'm
always here for you children,
though Father Bob might
choose to believe otherwise.
I don't want to get anybody
in trouble, but I think--
Trouble? Don't be silly.
You're not going to get
anyone in trouble. Speak up.
I think some of our kids snuck
out to Hull House tonight.
What?
Look.
You see that road?
That goes to Old Hull Road.
Somebody took one of
my books, Sister.
A book on demonology.
Look at this.
I think they went to Hull House
to perform some kind of ceremony.
Who went out there, Perry?
Kurt and Johnny and a
couple of the girls.
Melissa.
♪ I'm busted ♪
♪ We're going through
a little piece of hell... ♪
Ow! Hey!
What's the big idea?
What's going on?
I saw-- You okay?
Bibi, what are you doing?
Where did you get this?
Just get rid of it, okay?
Just throw it out the window.
Bibi.
No, it's something that
I found at Hull House.
Just throw it out now, okay?
Okay, all right. Calm down.
Wait a minute. Give me that.
That's a nice little souvenir.
Shirley, I wouldn't
if I were you.
Why, is it gonna bite me?
♪ I keep dancin' ♪
♪ Two steps left of Hell... ♪
Good color on me.
Oh, yeah.
You all right?
Yeah, I guess I was just a little
more tired than I thought.
Melissa?
Bibi?
Shirley?
Mouse. Mouse, wait.
I had no idea what
Shirley had planned.
Honest.
Hey, it's not your fault.
I just hope she'll
be all right.
You want to stop up for a
little trick or treat?
Sure, I'll come up for
a little sticky treat.
Thank you, Sheriff.
I'm sure it's just
a false alarm.
One of our boys has a very
overworked imagination.
Thank you.
All right, the sheriff is sending
out one of his deputies.
If our kids are out there,
I'm sure they'll find them.
It could be too late
by then, Father.
Oh, Perry, I've had enough of
your Halloween shenanigans.
Now, you've desecrated
the sacristy,
and now, you must admit,
that if any of our kids
did go out to Hull House,
it was one of your ridiculous
books that gave them the idea.
Perhaps we should listen
to the boy, Father.
We should certainly be
thankful for his vigilance.
Well, Sister, there
is a fine line
between vigilance and
paranoia, isn't there?
Now, if you'll both excuse me,
I've had a rather long day.
I'm going to bed.
Very well, Father.
Come with me, Perry.
Hey, Mouse. Mouse, wait.
She'll be all right.
We'll talk to her
in the morning.
Whoa, the dance sounds
like it's rockin'.
Hey, you guys, check it out.
I don't see Sister
Gory in there.
The way the music's blasting,
I bet she had a heart attack.
Yeah, well, let's get a dance
in before she recovers.
You know, I'm not
much into dancing.
Me neither.
Hey, Kurt,
is it true they
call you Kingsnake?
Yeah.
Hmm.
All right, party on! Woo!
♪ Then she got locked away ♪
♪ Sweet temptation... ♪
Come on, Shirl.
Chill. I just want
to hit the head.
Keep my place warm, okay?
It'll be here.
Hi there, dollface. You're
looking pretty good tonight.
Just one little touch up,
and you'll be queen
of the ball.
Let me out!
Oh!
Oh, yeah, all right!
Thirsty?
Well, thanks for the dance.
You don't belong here.
Where have you guys been?
What's going on with her?
What's the matter, baby?
Don't you want
your sticky treat?
I'll take a little piece
of that, sunshine.
Stop this hellishness now!
Nice.
What are you doing, you freak?
Let go of my hand!
Oh, my God.
To the chapel.
Everybody, quickly!
Come on! Hurry! Get
to the chapel!
Let's go.
Come on, let's go!
Bibi!
Johnny!
I don't believe this.
Why is it happening here?
Oh, God, the lipstick.
What lipstick?
The lipstick that I brought
from Hull House.
You mean you brought
something out of Hull House?
Be quiet, Perry.
But, Sister, don't
you understand?
That lipstick must
be the conveyance
that brought the demons out
across the underground streams.
We'll deal with that later.
Johnny, go find Father Bob.
He's got to get over here and
give that boy his last rites.
Satan has taken his body.
Maybe we can save his soul.
Bibi, you get over to the chapel and
make sure everyone stays inside.
Okay.
Perry, you get over
to the chapel.
Where are you going?
To prepare.
Don't panic, okay?
One at a time!
One at a time.
Terri! Terri!
Bibi! Bibi, are you okay?
Johnny!
I can't find Terri.
They're probably inside.
Just go inside.
I'll be right back.
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Come on, you know you
want it as much as I do.
Kurt, we're just
getting acquainted.
Oh, yeah, but I'd like to
get way more acquainted.
Okay.
This is as far as I go.
Well, if I have to.
Oh, yeah.
That feels good.
Mm-hmm.
Oh...
Well, slow down, now.
You don't want to
strike oil too soon.
Hey, hey. Calm down, will you?
Oh, shit!
What a healthy,
strapping young buck.
How's about a
little head, tiger?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Shirley.
The most horrible
thing has happened.
It was Kurt! It was--
It's not so horrible.
Oh, my God!
What?
Shirley, what are you--
Father Bob, wake up!
Wake up, Father!
What?
What is it?
It's an emergency! Hurry!
All right, well, give
me a couple of minutes.
Please, Sister
Gloria needs you!
All right.
Don't cry, little one!
I'm back, and I'm gonna
take good care of you now.
Angela?
No, you can't be here.
You died.
No, I didn't.
I'm dreaming.
I'm just dreaming again.
No, you're not.
It is me, Mouse.
I'm flesh and blood
just like you, see?
I'm your flesh and blood.
Listen, Mouse, I was so scared
after what happened at
my Halloween party.
I had to run away.
I just couldn't
face Mom and Dad.
I knew you were miserable
when they passed on.
You must have been so lonely.
Oh, Angela, it was so,
so lonely without you.
Oh, it's okay now.
My little Mouse.
I've come to take you away
with me to a wonderful place
where you'll never
be lonely again.
I have lots of
great friends now.
They were all lonely once,
just like you.
You still love me,
don't you, Mouse?
Oh, Ang, I missed you so much.
All right, children,
stay calm.
What's that?
Holy artillery.
Do you have one for me?
Sister Gloria, I'd
like an explanation.
Did you give him the
last rites, Father?
Give the last rites
to whom, Sister?
Rick's body was gone.
Gone?
Bibi! Where's Bibi?
Sister Gloria, why are
you wearing that habit?
I have an Uzi, Sister,
holy water filled balloons--
What are you talking about?
An Uzi? Six rosaries,
a cross...
Mouse?
Why do you want Mouse
when you can have me?
Bibi!
Hold her.
Pour it down her throat.
Touchè.
Take her to the chapel.
She's gonna be all right.
Let's go.
Melissa?
Sister Gloria!
Come here, look!
Things are gonna be so
good for us now, Mouse.
Just you and me, the way it
always should have been.
Time to go.
Well, you coming or not?
Sister Gloria, would you please tell
me what is happening around here?
I can't find Kurt anywhere.
The demons have escaped from Hull
House and they've kidnapped Mouse.
Oh, Perry, don't start.
Now, I warned you
once tonight--
But he's right, Father.
I have seen Satan's work
tonight with my own eyes.
Look, I cannot believe
I am hearing this.
Sister Gloria, come here.
Now, I expect this
nonsense from the kids,
but you are supposed
to be a role model.
Father, look at the statue.
Oh, no.
Now do you believe me?
What?
Ugh. Perry, someone
vandalized the statue.
There are none so
blind, Father, as--
Oh, Perry, there are none so
annoyed as I am right now.
First of all, I get
dragged out of my bed
with a story about a boy
needing the last rites,
and now this.
Where do you think
you're going?
To Hull House.
Somebody's gotta save Mouse.
Not you.
Perry's right. I'm going, too.
It's my fault she's there.
You don't know what
we're dealing with.
Oh, come on! We're
losing time.
Father, give me the car keys.
You are not setting foot
off these school grounds.
Now wait a minute,
Sister Gloria.
If they want to go, I think
we should let them.
In fact, we'll all go.
And by the time this
evening is over,
the legend of Hull House
will be laid to rest forever.
Let's go.
Well, let's go in.
Get it over with.
And after we put an end
to this absurd prank,
we'll deal with whoever
instigated it.
Father, I thought the sheriff was
supposed to send somebody out here.
Perry, I'm sure they've
come and gone.
Come and gone? They probably didn't
get past the Donut King back in town.
They couldn't help us.
Not tonight.
Not in this place.
Melissa?
Melissa, are you here?
Shh! Perry, please.
This way.
Whoa, whoa, hold on a minute.
I agreed to take you all out
here on this wild goose chase,
but I will not spend all night traipsing
around some dusty old mansion.
Now if Melissa's here,
we will find her much more
quickly by splitting up.
We must stick together.
This house is a
portal to hell.
Thanks, Sister.
I really needed to know that.
Well, I'm going this way.
Who's coming with me?
Fine. I'll see you
all back at the van.
I'm gonna go with him.
Somebody has to protect
him from himself.
What? Shh.
It's close.
What the hell?
Where did it go?
Come along.
What happened?
It's nothing.
Nothing? We just saw--
It's the house.
The house is trying
to deceive us.
Bibi!
Johnny!
Sister Gloria?
What's that?
Relax, Perry.
I've heard the devil
described in many ways,
but never with a squeak.
Oh, my God!
There's your devil for ya.
He seems to have left his pitchfork
down in Hell, didn't he?
Father, that's the guy.
Hey, hold it right there!
Perry, that's enough.
No, Father, I need that!
I don't want to hear it!
Well, hello, Father.
Good evening, son.
Having a little Halloween fun here
at Hull House tonight, are you?
Oh, yeah.
Father, I have something
to confess to you.
Would you like to
hear my confession?
What? Now?
I broke the fifth commandment.
The fifth?
Thou shalt not kill.
You killed someone?
Yes, Father.
You.
Get out of here, Father! Run!
I'm heartily sorry
for offending thee,
and I detest all of my sins,
for I dread the loss of Heaven
and the pain of Hell!
Father?
Father...
Kurt?
Is that you?
Hey, J-boy.
Heads up. Want to
shoot some hoop?
He's dribbling down the court.
No one's near him!
He's got 10 seconds left.
He's going around.
Larry Bird shoots.
Nothing but net!
He's racking up the
points tonight.
Larry Bird's in the air.
Nothing but net!
Uh-uh! Penalty for traveling.
Hey, buddy boy, I thought
you'd be happy to see me.
Well, if you're not,
I can fix that, too.
No! Kurt, please!
Kurt's not here right now.
- 2 points!
- Time out, Kurt.
Oh, where's a ref
when you need one?
Technical foul.
Wrong! Field goal!
Oof!
Ah!
Come on, Johnny, let's go.
Where's Father Bob? Don't ask.
Batter up.
Come on, toughie. Come on.
Strike.
Perry...
You saved my life, man.
Jesus.
Holy water.
John, please.
Hang on, Perry.
Come on, man.
John...
Do you remember the
story of Abraham?
Willing to prove his devotion to the
Lord by sacrificing his own son,
his own flesh and blood.
I think that's Angela's plan.
I think she's
gonna kill Mouse.
Please, John, save Melissa.
Please.
Perry!
Perry...
Perry.
Boo!
Why, little miss prom queen.
I've got a little something
special right here for you, baby.
Woo hoo ha ha!
I'll give you a ride you'd
never forget, baby.
I like a rich bitch. No!
No!
Bitch.
When you say no,
I know you mean yes.
Leave a little room
for the Holy Ghost.
I don't think so.
Hi-ya!
Ah!
Spare the rod and
spoil the child.
Father Bob?
Oh, thank God.
Have you found Mouse?
Oh, yes, I know
just where she is.
Come, I'll take you to her!
Blessed are the hopeless!
The heirs of the Kingdom...
of Hell!
Ah!
Agh!
Well, well.
Look out!
Let's party here.
Let's go.
Melissa?
Welcome.
I'm so glad you could join us
on this very special occasion.
Oh, we really can't stay.
We've just come for Melissa.
We're taking her home with us.
Melissa?
Oh, you mean Mouse.
Well, I'm afraid you're
mistaken about that.
You see, Mouse is home,
and so are you.
Or hadn't you figured
that out yet?
This place is not a home.
Oh, but it is.
That's why I let you make
it all the way up here
to the inner sanctum,
the very threshold
of infinity.
A river of holy water
wouldn't help you now.
Abandon all hope.
Close shave, Angela.
Huh?
But no cigar.
Sister?
You think I need holy
water to beat you?
I've got all that
I need right here.
It's a little thing
called faith.
Faith?
Your faith is a joke.
Real faith can move mountains.
Your faith can't
even move a mouse.
If you really have
faith, prove it.
Trade places with her.
No, Sister, don't.
It's a trick.
Your life for theirs.
Come on, Sister.
Kick the habit.
Let them go and I'll do it.
Don't do it, Sister.
Mouse, her soul
has great power.
You will have all that power
if you chop off her head.
No!
Johnny!
Don't fuck with me, kid.
Bitch!
You have to earn
your power, Mouse.
Melissa...
remember your faith.
Now.
I order you.
I order you to kill her.
Kill her!
Now, Mouse.
Do it.
Now, Mouse!
No!
My name is Melissa.
You bitch!
Say your prayers.
Let's get out of here.
This room wasn't here before.
No, it wasn't.
The house won't let us leave!
Here, let's try these windows.
Angela.
Where are you going? The
party's just begun.
Oh, my God!
Here's a little taste of hell.
Run!
Do something!
Johnny!
Oh!
I hate you!
Let's go home, children.
Sister Gloria, are you okay?
Yes, we're all right.
We're all right, children.
Where's Perry?
What happened?
Everything is going
to be all right.
♪ I got nasty habits ♪
♪ I keep bad company ♪
♪ If there's something I want,
I just grab it ♪
♪ Honey, I don't say please ♪
♪ I play to win,
don't take no for an answer ♪
♪ I'm a rebel
without a cause ♪
♪ So if it's a good time
that you're after ♪
♪ Honey, I'm the man to call ♪
♪ I got nasty habits ♪
♪ I keep bad company ♪
♪ If there's something I want,
I just grab it ♪
♪ Honey, I don't say please ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ I'm just a
little bit crazy ♪
♪ But aren't we all? ♪
♪ Spend my life ♪
♪ Living outside
of the wall ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I got nasty habits ♪
♪ I keep bad company ♪
♪ If there's something I want,
I just grab it ♪
♪ Honey, I don't say please ♪
♪ Yeah, I got nasty habits ♪
♪ I keep bad company ♪
♪ If there's something I want,
I just grab it ♪
♪ Honey,
I don't say please... ♪