Indecipherable yelling
Dick.
How long was I out for?
Just about two days.
Do try to take better care of yourself…
Pennyworth.
Good ole Alfred.
So I guess...
Thanks.
It wasn’t me.
What do you mean it wasn’t you, I saw you?
I’ve been on league business for the past
several weeks. Barbara found you on your balcony.
So you’re saying I have a guardian
angel who knows where I live?
Super.
How’s your wound?
Fine. What’s this supposed to be, Bruce?
An open hand.
It’s… a long trip from the watchtower.
When were you going to
tell me about Barbara?
We had to convince the Joker
that she was dead.
But after? Well, Afterward she
had her own reasons.
You didn’t have to lie to me.
No, I didn’t. But I kept her secret because
that’s what Barbara wanted.
Imagine being where she was.
As far as she was concerned,
she did die that night.
I gave her time to find herself.
You seriously think that justifies
what you two did?!
I can and have made mistakes before.
Is that was Jason is? Just a mistake?
When Jason died I almost hung it up.
I was wrong, to try and
replace you so soon.
The truth is, you were right to
leave and I was upset.
You asking me to forgive you?
I don’t expect that. But I’m not going
to be around forever.
We both know Batman can’t die.
Batman won’t. But Bruce Wayne will.
When It comes, someones going to
have to take up the mantle.
There’s only one person I trust
to do that.
I got my ass kicked the other night.
You made a mistake.
I can barely stand on my own let alone...
You rushed in head first without
knowing your enemy.
You have a secret weapon, Dick.
Use it. You’re a detective.
It’s who we are...
It’s what we do.
You’re going to be way better at this life
than I ever was.
Justice league. This is Superman. We’ve got
a league-wide alert. Departure in 15 minutes.
I can’t stay.
I can’t do this alone.
You can. You’re my son.
Now grab your gear
and be a detective.
Have you seriously been
their the entire time?!
Short answer?
Yes.
Grab my gear and be a detective?
What?
I remember he was wearing
dog tags the other night.
"Accessing archived Footage”
Dick, he could have killed you.
I screwed up. Got cocky.
Won’t happen again.
Oracle, Isolate text.
Slade wilson? Oracle, cross-reference the
name “Slade Wilson” with all American...
military personnel from the last 40 years.
- Barbara look I shouldn’t have...
- Dick I’m sorry, I...
“Match found”
S.H.A.D.E.? Never heard of them?
I have.
This is a high level encryption. This is
going to take at least an hour for us...
Got it.
What? You think I spent the last three
years crying in a closet somewhere?
Apparently not...
S.H.A.D.E. Super Human Advanced
Defense Endeavor.
They were the militaries first response to
meta-humans. They wanted to form their own
meta-army. This is some high level stuff.
Slade Wilson. Highly decorated from a young
age? So Deathstroke was an army Vet.
Not just a veteran. S.H.A.D.E. recruited
him for a meta-enhanced soldier project.
Codenamed: Team Seven.
They injected him full of drugs to increase
his brain performance.
Dramatically improved his reflexes,
pumped him full of steroids.
Our government built Deathstroke.
And then lost control of him.
Team Seven’s Administrators.
These are the guys who built Deathstroke.
Looks like after S.H.A.D.E. fell apart most of these
guys left the military and set up shop in Bludhaven.
He’s been killing off his past.
And there’s only one man left alive.
Are you going out?
Barbara, Mayor Redhorn is the last man left
on that list. If we don’t stop Deathstroke
now… we may not get another chance.
You’re not exactly in the best shape?
It’s who we are.. it’s what we do, right?
Fine but I’ll be with you the entire time.
Oh, so I guess I’m calling you
Oracle for the night?
Yeah, I actually kind of like that.
I don’t care if they’re going to be upset. You
have to clear my appearances. All of them.
We’ve had this meeting with LexCorp on the books for months.
Airport, Step on it.
Is the plane ready? Who’s name did you book
the reservation under? Relax?!
You have no idea who you’re dealing with here!
You need to have eyes in the back of your head.
Hey, we just passed our exit!
Yeah, we had to go ahead and make a coupleof
changes in your itinerary Mr. Mayor. Sorry about that.
Would you kindly take your cellphone and toss
it out the window?
Thank you.
Got a trace on Redhorns phone! Looks like
he’s on his way out of town.
That’s my cue.
Be careful.
Never.