( cow moos )
( man speaking on radio )
( people chattering )
Exactly what
Pastor Kingsman said--
you take a--
off the turnpike, six miles on--
- He doesn't know.
- I didn't think so. ( giggles )
What's it called--
the first road? Lime Road?
- Old Lime Road.
- Rebecca, help your dad out
here.
Rebecca.
I think we're lost.
- Sorry, Dad.
- Okay. All right.
- Wendy: I saw these before.
- Saw what?
This. It all looks the same.
I don't know.
If you took the right,
left at the right--
- Mary: You can't even hit me
back.
- Wendy: --at the right barn.
Or was it the left, left
at the right barn?
Mary: Do you remember
when he took the wrong exit?
- Rebecca: Right?
- Mary: We ended up going...
- Dan: No, no, that's not--
- Wendy: Twice.
- No, that's not true.
- He did it twice.
- It was not properly marked.
- Mary: He did it twice.
- Wendy: You circled twice.
( Dan chuckles )
Dan: Okay, ha-ha.
Listen, this is--
- that was the right barn.
- ( Wendy sighs )
I'm pretty sure
that this was the right road.
Rebecca:
Well, I mean,
it's not that I don't trust your
keen sense of judgment, Captain,
but why don't we just
stop and ask?
( man speaking on radio )
Wendy:
There's an idea.
Come on, ask, ask.
( all chanting )
Ask, ask, ask, ask.
Ask, ask ask.
Dan: I'm gonna go in here
and check it out.
- I listen to my family.
- Wendy: Wrong turn.
Is there-- is there--
is there a fellow there?
Christopher:
Oh, my God.
( Mary mocking )
( all chattering )
Wendy:
That's enough.
Dan:
Whew!
Hallelujah!
Wendy: All right,
there is a word I like to hear.
Let's be saying it
when we find out where we are.
Oh, that's nice.
Isn't that pretty?
For the tenth time
that we've seen it today.
I know.
Sorry, Dan.
I'll go up and check.
- Okay, Christopher.
- Wendy: Take the boy.
- Let's go.
- Dad.
See you in a minute.
Wendy:
Good luck.
Something tells me
this town won't have a mall.
( scoffs )
A mall?
Come on, I'll settle
for indoor bathrooms.
- ( flies buzzing )
- ( dog barking )
- ( horse snorting )
- ( chimes tinkling )
Hello?
Hello! Anyone here?
Hello!
Excuse me.
You folks looking for something?
Sorry. Yeah, we saw
your farm here and--
You lost or something?
Well, to be honest,
I think we may be a little lost.
There's a gas station a couple
miles back the way you came.
You can get a map
from them.
Okay. I was just-- I was just
looking for a town called Stull.
I think we took a wrong turn
a mile or so back.
So we'll get out of your hair.
Sorry for having bothered you.
You wouldn't be
the new pastor, would you?
Well, actually, yes.
How did you know that?
Well, Pastor Kingsman asked me
to keep an eye out for you,
make sure you're okay.
I'm just so glad
that you made it, Pastor.
I was starting to get
a little worried.
Your moving truck passed by
a couple of hours ago.
Oh, that's good to hear.
I know my wife will certainly
be happy to hear that.
Are we far from town?
Oh, no, no, not at all,
just a couple of miles or so.
I'm Pastor Dan Bramford.
Nice to meet you.
This is my son Christopher.
Christopher.
Oh, got a good grip
on you, boy.
Yeah.
I'm-- I'm Mason.
Nice to meet you.
I'll just--
I'll just bring my truck around.
You can follow me.
Okay, that's great.
I told you
we weren't lost.
- ( sheep bleating )
- ( cowbells dinging )
( dog barking )
Hey! Honey!
Welcome to Stull!
Wendy: Oh, no.
You gotta be kidding me.
Give me five.
I got you here.
You did it.
- I hate to say I told you so.
- ( laughs )
- All right.
- He's gonna come by with the
truck
and pick us up,
show us into town.
( sheep bleating loudly )
Oh, my God, what the hell
is that guy doing?
I don't know.
Oh. Oh, yuck.
Well, that is just not
appropriate
for you to see.
- Christopher: Eww.
- You, too.
- In the car. In the car.
- Come on, guys.
( car approaches )
- Are you folks ready?
- Yeah, we are.
I'll just drive right up there
and wait for you.
Thank you, Mason.
All right, kids just got
their first taste of the
country.
We won't need
these anymore.
Dan: It's not as small
as you thought it was, Rebecca.
- Mary: This is Main Street?
- Christopher: What's that?
- Dan: Ice cream?
- Christopher: Look.
( chuckles )
Christopher wants to go there.
( birds chirping )
- Dan: Is that us?
- ( Wendy chuckles ) I think.
- Is that us right there?
- This is--
- Is that it? Oh!
- Are you kidding me?
- That's it.
- Dan: Oh.
- Wendy: Can you believe it?
- Ma'am, I'm sorry
I didn't get a chance to meet
you
back at the farm, but I'm Mason.
Oh, I'm Wendy.
- Wendy: This is gorgeous.
- Oh my goodness.
Mason:
I'm glad you like it.
I'm just glad I showed you
where it was.
Wendy:
Oh, my.
Can you-- what's--
it's amazing.
Um, hi. Hi.
Excuse me.
( chuckles )
Wendy:
Be careful.
Becky-- uh, Rebecca.
It's okay, Dad.
You can still call me Becky.
It's-- it's really nice.
Yeah.
Big change.
I know that you are gonna
make the most of it.
Wendy: Excuse me. Hi.
Thank you.
I gotta go
help your mom.
I-- I'm sorry.
Can you help me?
I'm so confused.
Where are the movers and--
Let me help you.
I don't know
what's going on.
Did the movers just leave
everything on the ground?
No, no, no, they were nice
fellows.
We just figured
you didn't want any strangers
traipsing through your house.
Some fellows from church
came by to help.
- Pastor Kingsman.
- Oh, Pastor Bramford.
- How are you?
- Good. Good.
I thought you were a mover.
I'm so sorry.
Well, today I'm a mover.
Who knows what I'll be tomorrow?
I know I speak for everybody
when I say
we're awfully glad you're here.
- Thank you.
- Well, I think six states,
three children,
countless rest stops--
- I think no one's happier than
we are.
- I expect that's true.
- Here, Dan.
- Sure.
- Fragile.
- Yeah, should we?
- Dining room?
- Dining room, gents.
- Kingsman: All right, let's go.
- You be the captain out there.
Captain, I know.
Thank you.
( chuckles )
Oh, yeah. Excuse me,
I think that goes into the
living room.
Thank you.
Hi, sweetheart.
- Hi.
- Can you believe it?
Um, kitchen.
Thank you.
Okay.
- Can you believe it?
- This place is so nice.
- Christopher: This place is
huge.
- I know, right?
- Mom, can I pick out my room?
- Well, yes, after your sisters,
'cause they're older than you,
so they get first choice.
- First choice?
- Wendy: First choice.
- Wendy: Second choice.
- Dan: Hey, girls, Christopher,
please say hello
to Pastor Kingsman.
The man responsible
for all of this.
Oh, well, I wouldn't say
I'm responsible.
I think a higher power
called you to our little town.
Well, certainly.
Thank you.
It's nice to meet you, girls.
- Nice to meet you.
- Go. Get up there.
- Christopher: Stop pushing me.
- I'll help.
Stop.
- I like the window in here.
- This room is cool.
Christopher:
I saw it first. I call dibs.
Mary:
You heard what Mom said.
I'm older than you.
I get first dibs, kiddo.
Christopher:
Second dibs.
Mary: Second's better
than the third, you weirdo.
Christopher: What?
You didn't get the crappy third
one.
( birds chirping )
( door creaks )
Damn it.
Let me guess.
Yep. Mine.
( mouse squeaking )
Mom!
Oh, thank you so much.
This is incredible.
Everybody's so-- so sweet.
- And this kitchen is amazing.
- Well, I'm glad you like it.
I'm not much of a cook myself,
so I have to take your word for
it.
- That's not your handiwork?
- Oh, no, no, no.
- That's-- that's Mrs. Gordon's.
- Oh.
She-- she's pretty famous
for her cakes around here.
- Looks delicious.
- They're good.
Yeah, melt your tongue
right off.
So, Dan,
what do you say
we rip the Band-Aid right off
and get you up
on that pulpit tomorrow?
- Oh. Oh. Oh.
- Wendy: Oh my goodness, Dan.
- I'm not sure that I'm ready.
- Kingsman: I know it's quick,
but folks are anxious
to meet their new pastor.
Well, you know,
he's got big shoes to fill.
- I'm sure they're gonna miss
you a lot.
- No, no, no.
I've been here a number of
years.
They're about ready to see me
move on.
- No. ( chuckles )
- I'm looking forward to
retirement.
I think it's about time
we had some new blood around
here.
- Oh.
- Well...
- Come on, sweetie.
- Kingsman: What do you say?
- Rip the Band-Aid right off.
- ( chuckles )
- Huh?
- All right.
( insects chirping )
How's the sermon going?
Oh, fine. Good.
The usual battle.
How are the girls?
They're good.
You did the right thing,
you know.
The house is perfect.
I'm almost finished unpacking
downstairs. It looks so good.
I'm glad
you're happy with it.
I think moving is always
hardest on the children.
- Yes, I know.
- The new school, the new
friends.
They'll adjust.
You know they will.
I think they're gonna like it.
It's not like we had
that much of a choice.
- No?
- No.
- We have a bigger boss.
- Oh.
He called you to be here.
As long as we're together,
that's all--
- Nothing else matters.
Rebecca:
I'm going with two years.
What, too little?
10 years.
10 years?
Are you kidding me?
No, they live
for about 45 days.
The stronger ones can live
a little longer, like 60 days.
10 years--
they'd have grey hair.
Yeah, I guess 10 years is kind
of
a long time for an ant to live,
huh?
Yeah.
Rebecca, do you think
I'll make friends here?
You kidding me?
You? Mr. Personality?
Of course you're gonna
make friends.
Think about how much
a big city slicker kid like you
knows
compared to these guys.
- Mary, honey.
- ( knocks )
- Guys.
- Mary: What?
- Dan: Are they here?
- Mary, come here, please.
- Put that away. Turn off the
light.
- Hi. Here.
It's our first night here and I
just
wanted to say a little
something.
Come on.
Hey.
A big change for us.
And your mother and I
would like you to know
how much we appreciate
the love and support
that each one of you has given
us
on our journey.
I think we had a great life
in the city,
but I believe the Lord
has called us here.
He didn't call me.
Okay, all right,
He called.
Okay, put our hands together.
Heavenly Father, thank You
for protecting us
on our long journey.
Please, we ask You
to watch over us and guide us...
( continues indistinctly )
( thunder crashing )
- ( thunder crashes )
- ( shrieks )
( roaring )
( screaming )
( gasps )
( church bells ringing )
Wendy:
Wait up for us.
( organ playing )
Dan:
Oh, good morning.
Wendy: Good morning.
Good morning.
♪ While I draw
♪ This fleeting breath
♪ When my eyelids
♪ Close in death
♪ When I rise
♪ To worlds unknown
♪ And behold Thee
♪ On Thy throne
♪ Rock of Ages
♪ Cleft for me
♪ Let me hide myself
♪ In Thee.
Good morning, friends.
Good morning.
Now before I get started,
I promised Mr. Roberts
that I would mention that we
still need a few volunteers
to help us set up
for tomorrow's summer festival,
so if you have
a little extra time
and want to lend
a helping hand,
please see Carl
after the service.
Please be seated.
I have spent a lot of years
here with you
and I would like to believe
that through all those years
we have built a community
of love and faith.
I would also like to believe
that we have learned
to trust each other.
Now trust is
a very funny thing.
It requires absolute belief
in one's soul, a complete faith.
But it's different than faith.
Trust also obligates
the person that is being trusted
to do the best he can.
And so I am asking you
to trust me
one more time
as I prepare to leave you.
Today we welcome
the Bramfords.
- ( applause )
- Pastor Dan,
his lovely wife Wendy
and their three beautiful
children
have all consented
to join us.
And I trust
that you will show them
the same love
and compassion
that you showed me
so many years ago.
The Bramfords
have made a great sacrifice
to be here with us.
So let us welcome them
with open hearts
- and open arms.
- ( applause )
Pastor Dan, your people.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Pastor Kingsman.
- And good morning, everyone.
- Good morning.
First of all I would like
to thank you
for welcoming my family and I
into your lives.
When I first received the offer
to become your pastor
here in Stull,
my wife Wendy and I
were unsure--
unsure about
moving a family
halfway across
the country,
unsure about
leaving behind
a life that we had come
to know and understand,
unsure about
a new adventure.
But in times
of unsureness,
in times of great decision,
I put my faith in the Lord,
that He would provide for us,
that He had a plan for us.
I think my faith
was like a rock.
I was reminded of
Matthew, chapter 7, verse 24,
which I would like to read to
you
this morning.
( clears throat )
"Therefore whosoever heareth
these sayings of mine
and doeth them,
I will liken him
unto a wise man
which built his house
on a rock.
And the rain descended
and the floods came
and the winds blew
and beat upon that house.
And it fell not,
for it was founded
upon a rock.
And everyone that heareth
these sayings of mine
and doeth them not
shall be likened to a foolish
man
which built his house
upon the sand."
( all chattering )
Wendy:
So nice to meet you.
Dan:
God bless. Thank you.
Wendy:
Thank you.
Not really your scene, huh?
What?
This whole thing.
I saw you inside.
You weren't singing.
And then you left
during the sermon.
I could say the same for you.
Sounds like you were paying
more attention to what I was
doing.
Well, maybe,
but that's just 'cause you were
so obviously not into it.
Yeah, you're right.
I'm not much into singing
and just not big
on the whole sermon thing.
- No offense to your dad.
- None taken, trust me.
I saw you and your family
when you got into town
yesterday.
I take it y'all met Mason.
Oh, Mason?
He's the farm guy?
Yeah. Yeah, the farm guy.
Okay, so then you were
the guy with the lambs and--
Technically they're sheep.
Wow. Well,
you clean up well.
Maybe I'll see you around
and show you the town.
Yeah, cool.
Yeah, that'd be awesome.
( clicks tongue )
"You clean up well"?
Idiot.
Wendy:
I have a hard time believing
that your boxes are unpacked
and your room is clean.
- ( music playing over
headphones )
- Huh?
Mom, stop. I'm hungry.
Do we have any food in the
house?
You're hungry?
Yeah, there's a little
something.
I'm sure you can make do.
- And my boxes are unpacked.
- Uh-huh.
- But define clean.
- Exactly what I thought.
You know I hate
living in the mess, honey.
Relax. It's only been a day.
They're just boxes.
- Breathe.
- I'll breathe when you help me
out.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, we are definitely
gonna need an escape plan.
I swear, if she brings up
unpacking
one more time, I'm gonna kill
her.
- ( Rebecca giggles )
- I'm serious. We need a plan.
Okay, like you mean the time
that we told Mom
we were going to Sonia Rosen's
house to sleep over,
so that we could see
the Stone Roses?
Yeah, we probably should have
told
Sonia Martin about that plan.
- Somehow I got blamed for that
one.
- You did not.
I got it way worse than you.
I was grounded for, like, two
months.
Remember? Because I should
have known better.
- Yeah, you should have known
better.
- ( Rebecca giggles )
Hey, what are you eating?
I'm starving.
Just peanut butter and jam
I found on the counter.
Mm, sounds appetizing.
Um, I would not do that
if I were you.
Mom said we're saving that
for after dinner tonight.
It's our first family dinner
in the new home,
blah, blah, blah.
Oh, please.
No, seriously, dude, you know
how Mom gets about that shit.
None for me, thanks,
but when Mom kills you,
- I'll take your purple sweater.
- Fine.
Mm, so good.
( coughing )
Are you okay?
( Rebecca gasps )
Mary!
Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
- Are you okay?
- What was that?
I have no idea.
Eww.
Oh.
I can't believe
this came out.
- I know.
- Holy shit.
- ( knocks on door )
- ( gasps ) Fuck.
Hi. What are you
doing here?
I told you I was gonna take you
around and show you some stuff.
Oh, yeah.
I just didn't know
you meant today.
Is today bad?
No. Come in.
What happened?
You have no idea.
- Who puts a tooth in a cake?
- Tell me about it.
It cut the crap
out of the roof of my mouth.
This is one of
old Mrs. Gordon's cakes.
A nice lady,
but she's almost 95.
Let's just say you're lucky
this is all you found.
Lucky?
There. No more cake.
So are you ready to go?
Um...
Just go, Becca.
I'm fine. Go. Escape.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. I'll be fine.
A little weirded out,
but I'm fine.
Okay.
Bye.
Rebecca:
So, not that this hasn't been
great,
it has,
but is there anything
to actually do in town?
This isn't exactly
the big city.
I know it's not the big city,
but there's gotta be something.
Noah:
There really isn't anything to
do.
Rebecca:
Well, I mean,
could you give me a chance
to figure that out for myself
maybe?
Please?
Fine.
So how long
have you lived here?
I don't know.
A long time.
I guess
you're used to it then--
the whole country thing.
No, you never really
get used to it.
You just sort of adapt.
I wasn't exactly thrilled
about moving here,
but it's kind of nice.
- Afternoon.
- Hello.
I should probably
get you home.
What?
I thought
we were having fun.
It's not that.
It's just it's getting late.
I don't want your parents
worrying.
Rebecca:
Oh, please.
- ( tires screech )
- Noah.
Noah, Pastor Kingsman
is looking for you.
Tell him I'll be there
in a few.
He wants you now.
I've got to go home.
Home?
You live with Pastor Kingsman?
- ( horn honks )
- Noah.
I'll explain later.
Are you gonna be okay
getting home, young lady?
Yeah, sure.
( footsteps )
( knocks on door )
Kingsman: Noah.
Noah.
Has the choice been made?
I know you're probably
scared right now.
But you can do this.
You're prepared for this.
You can do it, son.
I'm not your son.
And you have no idea
how I'm feeling right now.
You're right.
I wouldn't pretend to know
how you're feeling.
But you knew
this day was coming.
And there can be
no mistakes-- none.
Humble yourself
before the Lord, Noah.
We are His servants.
We are here to do His will.
We should not question
what is beyond our
understanding.
Put aside your weaknesses,
and He will give you strength.
Do not get close to them--
to any of them, to her.
Here.
Who is it?
The younger sister-- Mary.
( sighs )
- Wendy: Was it delicious?
- Dan: It was delicious.
Christopher:
Yeah, it was delicious.
Oh, hi, honey.
Look, I left a plate for you
in the oven.
How was your day?
Did you have fun?
Rebecca has a boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend.
Well, I sure hope not.
You've only known him a few
hours.
- Where's Mary?
- Wendy: She's upstairs.
She hasn't been
feeling well all day.
Oh, yeah, no problem.
Don't worry about it.
You're welcome for that plate
I left for you in the oven.
Oh, you think that's funny,
do you?
- ( insects chirping )
- ( clock ticking )
( knocks )
Ooh, wow,
you look like shit.
Thanks. I feel like shit.
How's your mouth?
Eh, it's okay.
How was your date
with Romeo?
Fine, until that weird
Mason guy found us
and told him to go home.
Guess where home is.
He lives with Mason?
Pastor Kingsman.
What?
Yeah, exactly.
It was weird.
Nice but weird.
Okay, why don't you start
with the nice?
I don't think I can stomach
the weird just yet.
( birds chirping )
( sheep bleating )
( bleating loudly )
( gasps )
( birds chirping )
You do know we have
two separate rooms now, right?
Sorry. I was just so tired.
I didn't feel like...
Walking all the way
down the hall.
Oh, you poor thing.
All that flirting with that Noah
guy
must have really taken a toll on
you.
Ha-ha.
You feeling better?
Eh, a little bit.
But I've got to get out of this
house.
So come on, get up.
Let's go into town,
check out the boys.
I need a little fun.
- Wendy: What are you doing?
- Dan: No, no, it's good.
Wendy: Oh, no, that doesn't look
very good at all, actually.
- Dan: Easy now. Easy.
- Rebecca: What's with all the
cookies?
Well, they are supposed to be
for the festival,
if your dad doesn't ruin
them all.
Hey, easy.
I'm trying my best.
Honey, yuck.
( chuckles )
Don't give him
all of your mistakes.
- No, no, this is not a mistake.
- He is gonna get sick.
So are you sure
you're gonna make it?
Yeah, I'm fine.
It just hurts to eat.
- Okay, but I want to get out of
here.
- I know.
- A masterpiece.
- I'm watching you. That looks--
I'm gonna go to the park
with Pastor Kingsman.
That sounds like
a really good idea, honey.
Yeah, a pastor needs to be
with his people.
Oh, can me and Mary
go to town too?
'Cause we want to walk around
a little bit.
So nobody's gonna
help me out at all?
- No.
Fine.
Take your brother.
And get him something
other than a cookie to eat.
All right, come on then.
Let's go.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Out of here. Out of here.
All right, you girls,
make yourself useful.
- Help people out.
- Okay, Dad.
- Woman: Hello.
- Hello.
- Hello, Pastor.
- How are you?
- Dan: Nice to see you.
- Woman: Hello to you too.
- Want to help her out?
- Christopher: Hi.
Mary:
Hmm.
Okay. Not bad.
He's kind of cute.
10 seconds.
It took you 10 seconds
to find your mark.
It's a gift.
- ( balloon squeaks )
- ( gas hissing )
( girls whispering )
Hi.
What are you doing?
Well, I'm Mary
and this is
my sister Rebecca.
- Smooth.
- Shut up.
( hissing )
So have you
lived here long?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Why are we hiding?
We're not hiding.
- Well, maybe a little bit.
- ( both chuckle )
You want
to get out of here?
Actually, there's something
I'd like to show you.
- Right now?
- Yeah. Is that cool?
Yeah, sure.
Let me just go tell Mary.
Okay.
What, is that
your kissing both?
- No.
- He's really cute.
Um, I think
he just asked me out.
Nice.
Can you cover for me?
Well, I can,
but it's gonna cost you.
All right, fine. At least one
of us is doing all right.
All right, thanks.
- Hey.
( water running )
( wings flapping )
Noah:
Is it weird?
Rebecca:
Is what weird?
Noah:
Moving away from it all,
away from your home.
Rebecca:
My parents seem really happy.
I think they were tired
of the city.
Noah:
What about you?
Rebecca:
Me? I'm fine, I guess.
I mean, it's different,
but it's okay.
Noah:
Just okay, huh?
Rebecca:
So where are we going?
- Noah: You'll see.
- ( Rebecca chuckles ) Okay.
So you brought me
all the way out here
to show me
an old rusty tower?
This is so much more
than an old rusty tower.
Really?
- Yeah, really.
- ( chuckles )
I want to show it to you,
but if you're scared...
Oh, you think that rickety old
ladder
that climbs, what,
100 feet in the air
is too scary for me?
Please.
Rebecca:
Come on.
What, are you chicken?
Rebecca:
Come on.
( wind whistling )
( metal creaking )
Rebecca:
Oh, my God.
This is beautiful.
I told you.
This is where I come when I want
to get away from everything.
It's kind of special to me.
Well, you weren't kidding.
It's amazing.
Noah: And you can see
everything from up here.
Makes you feel like
there is a world beyond here.
Rebecca:
There is a world beyond here.
You know what I mean.
Thank you, Noah.
For what?
For taking me here.
I can see
why it's so special to you.
I'm just glad you like it.
So are you gonna stay
here in town?
What do you mean?
I live here.
No, I know you live here,
but I just thought
since your dad's retiring
and everything, maybe you--
My dad?
Pastor Kingsman.
Kingsman's not my dad.
He's not your dad?
But you live with him.
Sorry.
It's none of my business.
No, it's fine.
When I lost my family,
Kingsman took me in.
He's strict,
but he's a good guy.
I get the feeling
he doesn't want us hanging out.
Why would you say that?
Well, that whole thing
with Mason
was a little weird yesterday.
And us hiding
from him today--
I just-- I feel like
he doesn't like me.
It's not that.
He's just being protective.
He's not so keen
on the whole dating thing.
Oh.
So this is a date?
I-- I--
I'm just kidding.
Who is that?
What?
There's a guy down there
watching us.
Where?
We should go.
Why? Who is it?
I don't know. We should just go.
We shouldn't be up here.
( door creaking )
Did you think
I wouldn't find out?
You were gonna betray us-- all
of us.
I will not let that happen.
So I just have to put up
with this shit?
My God, Noah, you've seen it.
You know what it's capable of.
Why can't we stop it?
It is God's will.
We are His servants.
We must do
everything we can--
You're a fucking liar.
Stop being such a child!
Yes, we've been lied to.
Yes, we've been told stories--
stories of angels
that will come down from heaven
and slay the demons and send
them to hell and protect us all.
There are no angels!
There is only us.
You know what needs to be done.
And I need to know you'll do it.
There is no other way.
I just wish there was something
I could do to save them.
Do your part.
( laughing, chattering )
Wendy:
Oh, goodness. Hello.
Mom, I'm gonna
head off, okay?
Oh, you like that,
don't you?
All right, well, you can go play
with the other kids.
- Okay, Mom.
- Don't go too far.
Dan:
Check in with us.
Wendy:
Mm-hmm.
I think we should do this
in the backyard.
Hello. How are you?
We're neighbors.
It's so nice to meet you.
- Wendy: Hello.
- Dan: Hi. Nice to see you.
Wendy:
Well, aren't you handsome.
- Dan: Hi.
- Wendy: Hi there. Hi.
( all chattering )
- ( bell dings )
- Yeah, I got it. I got it.
Woman:
You did it. Awesome.
Would you like some popcorn?
Crowd: Ooh!
Dan:
Was that you?
Christopher: Dad, you should
try.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
( chattering )
- Christopher: Dad, please.
- You do it. Let him put you...
- In the tank?
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Oh, really?
- Come on, come on.
- Mary: So do you see him
anywhere?
- Rebecca: Who?
Oh, don't even.
You know who. Noah.
No, but he said he was coming,
so I'm not worried.
So what do you guys think?
Well, it's not totally lame.
( chuckles )
Yeah.
Um, are there some cool games
or something?
Yes, sure. Come on.
Mary: All right,
let's see what you got.
- ( Rebecca laughs )
- Nice. That was not even close.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
Mary: Nice.
Oh, you guys
really suck at this.
Shut up, Noah.
You're taking all the fun out of
it.
And aren't you the one that's
supposed to be winning us a
prize?
- Maybe he just can't throw a
ball.
- Well, that's true.
- Let me show you something.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Oh.
- Holy shit.
Maybe-- maybe he can.
I don't know.
Man:
Let's just take a seat.
- I'm good. Thank you though.
- No? No?
- Mary: I'm also good.
- Noah: Thanks.
- Cute.
- ( bell dings )
Rebecca:
Let's see what you got, Mary.
Oh, I'm not--
I can't follow that.
I'm kind of thirsty. You guys
want
to grab something to drink?
Oh, that sounds good. I want one
of those pies I keep seeing
around.
- Of course you do.
- Shut up.
Mary: Do you see them?
They look so happy.
- They just fit right in here.
- I know. It's kind of perfect.
Man:
Thank you.
- So what can I get for you
kids?
- Do you have pie here?
- We sure do.
- Mary: Can I have one?
What about you?
What would you like?
You? Anything to drink?
We'll have three
lemonades, please.
All right, well,
I guess I'm having lemonade.
Hey, are you okay?
What? Yeah.
Here you go.
Thank you.
- You guys want to go?
- Yeah.
♪ Kansas
♪ In the springtime
♪ Where the sun shines
♪ Every day...
( vomiting )
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Are you okay?
What happened?
I'm good. I thought I was
feeling
better, but I guess I'm not.
- Thank you.
- You don't look good.
No, no, I'm good.
I feel better. I threw up.
- I'm gonna take you home.
- No, no, you guys are having--
No, Becca, you guys are
having a good time.
I feel fine.
Seriously, I'm gonna go--
I'm gonna take you home.
Becca, I'm gonna go
find Mom and Dad.
- I'm good. I just want to--
- Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm good.
You guys have fun.
♪ Kansas
♪ In the springtime
♪ Where the sun shines
♪ Every day...
( people chattering )
( bell dings )
( laughing )
( water dripping )
( panting )
( grunting )
What? Why the fuck
are you doing this?
I-- I don't know
what you want,
but please just--
just let me go. It's fine.
♪ Sun shines every day...
♪ I've been wondering
♪ What's the other
♪ Kansas in the springtime
♪ Kansas in
the springtime, oh... ♪
( Mary panting )
What?
What is this?
What are you doing?
Shit. Oh, God.
What is that? What the--
what the fuck are you doing?
( Mary whimpering )
Please. Help!
( sobbing )
Please, God.
Please help me.
Mary:
What are you doing?
What the hell is this?
Help!
Please, God, help me!
Please. Oh, God.
Oh, God.
( sobbing )
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
Please help.
I don't know what this is,
but can you-- can you--
can you please
just untie me?
I didn't do anything.
Oh, please.
Please, I didn't do anything.
( music continues playing )
( Mary crying )
( coughing )
With my blood,
the gate is open.
This is Your servant, Lord.
We commend her immortal soul
to Your everlasting care.
Mary:
What's happening?
Kingsman: Her body may become
the vessel for His work.
- In her death, may we have
life.
- Please. Please.
- In her suffering...
- Help!
...may we have peace.
Somebody please hear me!
Amen.
Come forth
and claim your offering.
( Mary sobbing )
No. No.
No. No. No!
- Woman: Shh.
- Man: Shush.
Woman:
Get your sweater.
Man:
Let's go, honey.
Woman: Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Woman: Jimmy, Jimmy,
shh, shh, shh.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, now.
No, now.
- Woman: Hey, everybody, come
on.
- Man: Shh.
Kingsman: Dan.
Dan, Wendy.
Honey.
- Mary, what's wrong?
- What happened?
Wendy:
What happened to you?
- She was sitting by herself.
- What?
Sweetie, go get your sister.
We gotta go.
- Dan, we need to go.
- Christopher: Becky!
- Dan: Tell her--
- She'll be all right.
Just get her home.
Get her to bed.
- Wendy: Honey.
- Honey, are you all right?
Are you okay?
I have to tell you something.
What?
- Becca. Becky.
- What?
I think Mary's sick.
Mom wants you.
What happened?
I don't know.
She doesn't look good though.
Come on, let's go.
Noah:
I understand. Go ahead.
- Wendy: Come on, you guys.
- Rebecca: What happened?
- Wendy: What happened?
- Dan: Honey.
Wendy: She was supposed
to be with you.
Dan:
She's not feeling well. It's
fine.
She'll be all right.
She's just not feeling very
well.
Wendy: All right, sweetie.
Let's just get her upstairs.
Watch your brother.
Rebecca:
Hey, let's watch TV.
( phone rings )
Hello.
Dad, it's for you.
Um, okay.
Wendy: Come on, sweets.
Almost there.
Hello. Oh.
( clock ticking )
Dan: Is there any way
we could do it tomorrow?
( TV playing )
Okay. Understood.
Okay.
Wendy:
Who was that?
I have to go to the church.
What, now? What for?
I don't know.
Kingsman said
that he needed me.
Wendy: At this hour?
You can't go now.
He knows
your daughter's sick.
Yeah, he said
that it was important.
- Honey, I don't--
- How is she?
She's not well.
She's sweating a lot.
She doesn't have a fever.
I don't know what it is.
Dan: Okay.
It shouldn't be long, all right?
( squeaking )
Hello?
Pastor Kingsman?
( squeals )
Dan:
Ahem.
Pastor Kingsman.
Are you okay?
I had to get you away
from there.
It needs time.
Not much,
but it needs time.
Dan: I'm afraid
that I'm not following.
I don't know
what needs time
and what I'm supposed
to get away from.
Yes, Dan, you are.
You are following.
You are following His will.
You are a good man, Dan.
You are such a good man.
And I am so sorry.
I'm so sorry
that this has to happen
to your family, to you.
Oh, your poor daughter.
She is so young.
What-- what are you
talking about?
God give us strength
to do what must be done.
( sighs )
Have faith.
This is His will.
( Dan gagging )
Have faith.
Have faith, Dan.
( church bell ringing )
( distant dog barking )
( TV playing )
Mom, I'm gonna go
check on Mary.
Yeah, good. Good.
Thank you.
- ( knocks )
- Mary.
Mare.
Mary. Mare.
Mary! Mary!
Mary. Mary.
Are you okay? Mary.
Mom! Mom.
- Mom.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- Mary, honey.
Mary. Oh, my God.
You've got to help me.
Christopher!
Sweetie, sweetie, get up.
Christopher! Get up,
Mary, sweetie.
Christopher, call 911!
- Wendy: It's okay.
- Rebecca: Go!
It's okay.
Christopher, go!
Come on, sweetie.
Oh, my God.
Whoa.
( beeping )
Oh, my God. Mom.
- Wendy: Whoa.
- Mom, Mom.
- Honey.
- Mom, what's happening?
Wendy: I don't know, baby.
I don't know. I don't know.
Christopher!
Sweetheart.
- Rebecca: Oh, my God.
- Get her to the bed.
- Okay.
- Help me. Help me.
Rebecca:
Oh, Mary.
Come on, baby.
Christopher!
( beeping )
Sweetie.
- Mom.
- Both: What?
- The phones are all dead.
- What? What are you talking
about?
Christopher: Mom.
I need you to go to the church
and get your father. Go get your
father.
- Christopher: I want to go too.
- Okay, take your brother.
- Okay, let's go.
- Go. Go. Hurry. Hurry.
( quietly ) Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Becca, wait up.
Come on.
Becca.
We've got to go.
Come on, we need
to get Dad.
I can't run as fast as you.
Just don't leave me.
I would never leave you, okay?
We just-- we gotta get Dad.
Christopher:
What is that?
Rebecca: I don't know.
Come on, we gotta go.
Come on.
( distant dog barking )
Over here.
Christopher: Dad!
Dad!
Christopher:
Open! Dad!
Rebecca:
Dad, are you in there?
( twig snaps )
What are you doing here?
Move.
Dad?
Wait here.
Dad!
Oh, my God, Dad.
Dad, are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Dad.
Noah.
- Dan: Kingsman.
- Rebecca: Are you okay?
What?
- It was Kingsman.
- What?
Where's your mother?
She's-- she's at home.
Mary's--
We have to go.
We have to go now.
- Are you okay, Dad?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Look. What are those?
They're on every house.
Dan:
Jesus. What--?
We need to get home.
Mary?
Honey?
Mary. Mary?
Mary?
Sweetie?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my-- Mary.
( roaring )
( Wendy screams )
Get away.
( screams )
( beeping )
Dan.
Dan. Dan.
Dan!
Rebecca:
Wait here.
- You can't go there. It's too
late.
- What are you doing?
Dad. Dad. Dad.
You can't go in there, Rebecca.
Please trust me.
- What are you doing, Noah?
- You're here for a reason.
- Get off me!
- You have to go now.
- God damn it. Noah.
- It's too late. You can't save
them.
Let me go, Noah.
It's too late.
You can't save them.
- Please get in the car.
- Dad!
Noah:
Rebecca, please get in the car.
( door creaking )
Hello?
Wendy.
Honey.
( Dan gasps )
( whimpering )
Mary?
Honey?
Mary.
( roaring )
- Start the car! Go!
- Dad.
- Start the car!
- Dad, what's going on?
- Is that Mary?
( car engine starts )
- Go! Get in the car!
- What?
- Christopher: Dad.
- Get them out of here. Get
help.
Get help. Go, go, go!
- Get in the car!
- Daddy, you have to come.
- Dan, get in the car.
- No. No.
- Dad!
- ( tires screech )
Rebecca:
Daddy!
What are you doing?
We can't leave him there.
We have to go. You have no idea
what that thing can do.
Christopher:
Dad!
( tires screech )
Whatever this is,
please let it leave my daughter.
In the name of Jesus Christ
our Holy Savior,
please be rid
of my daughter.
( snarling )
Leave my daughter!
Mary?
Honey?
( snarling )
Dad!
( sobbing )
( gasping )
( roars )
- Christopher: Mary, no!
- ( tires screeching )
Stop the car.
We can't.
Stop the car now.
That's not your sister.
Stop the fucking car now.
- ( tires screech )
- Why are you stopping?
Don't stop.
Keep going.
- Noah: Rebecca.
- ( car door slams )
Listen to me.
She's not your sister anymore.
What the hell
does that mean?
What does that mean, Noah?
What's going on?
Christopher:
Get in the car.
Please get back in the car.
I'll tell you what I know, but
you
have to get back in the car
right now.
What?
You're part of this?
Oh, my God,
you're part of this?
Rebecca, please
get in the fucking car!
You were chosen.
Chosen?
Yes. You, your whole family.
You were chosen.
We all were.
I don't understand.
We aren't meant to.
My whole family was brought here
just like yours.
You come here and you think
it's fucking perfect,
and then you're fucked--
you, your whole family.
That's just what happens.
If they even knew I was
telling you any of this--
Who is they?
Pastor Kingsman?
Kingsman is just the keeper.
He is just doing
what he was asked to do.
This place is a doorway,
and on the other side is evil.
We were picked to be a part
of this great, big plan
that we have no control over.
All I know is that once
the doorway is open,
we have one job,
and one job only-- to shut it.
I'm sorry.
I'm trying to save you.
Please trust me.
You have to get back in the car
and we have to go right now.
( gasps )
Get in the car!
- Christopher!
- Help!
Help! Help!
- Christopher, she's coming.
- Help!
She's coming, Christopher!
What are you doing?
Christopher!
No! She's coming,
Help! Help!
Let me in!
Please.
Help!
Please let me in!
Help! Help, please!
Please help!
( roars )
( screaming )
( banging )
( Christopher whimpering )
Rebecca:
What are we gonna do?
Noah:
Just keep looking.
Oh, God.
There she-- there she is!
Noah:
Christopher is inside.
Rebecca:
Oh, my God.
Is he gonna be safe
in there?
I'm sorry,
but you can't stay here.
Please.
Why?
Why won't you help me?
I'm sorry,
but you have to leave.
- Please. No. No!
- I'm sorry, but you have to
leave.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Please. Please.
- Please no!
No. Please.
Please, no, don't do this!
- I'm sorry.
- You can't put me out there!
( tires screech )
( coughs )
Christopher.
Chris, I'm sorry.
Come on.
Come on, get in the car.
- Rebecca: Come on, come on.
- ( Christopher panting )
Rebecca:
Hurry. Okay.
Go. She's coming! Go!
( tires screech )
It's okay. It's okay.
We're gonna be okay.
You're safe now.
You're safe.
Where the hell
are you going?
Noah: We have to stop
the bleeding.
Rebecca: Oh, God.
It's okay, Chris. It's okay.
It's okay.
( tires screech )
- Leave the car running.
- What?
If it comes, you have to
promise me to leave.
- Christopher: Rebecca.
- But, Noah--
- Please promise.
Noah, I promise.
Please just don't leave me.
( Christopher moaning )
It's okay.
You're gonna be all right.
Okay. It's okay.
( Christopher moaning )
It's okay.
( engine stalling )
( engine stops )
- Shit.
- What's happening?
- ( Christopher whimpering )
- No, no.
No. No.
Christopher! No.
No! No.
Christopher, get away!
- Rebecca! Rebecca!
- Christopher!
- No, Noah! No!
- Noah: Come on!
Christopher! Christopher!
- Christopher!
- Christopher: No!
No! Becca!
( crying )
( screaming ) No!
Rebecca: No!
Christopher!
No! Christopher!
Stop it!
Get off of him!
( Christopher whimpering )
Christopher!
Rebecca: No!
( Rebecca sobbing )
Rebecca:
Christopher!
No.
I have to keep you safe.
I know a place. It's safe.
We can hide there till morning.
Where?
( thunder rumbling )
In here.
( thunder continues )
Oh, my God.
- Why are you doing this?
- I'm sorry.
He's doing what God
has asked us to do.
We must close the gate
and end this,
or else darkness
will subdue the light
and the world
will become his.
It's the way it's always been.
There is no other way.
We must close the gate.
( Rebecca gasps )
( Rebecca whimpering )
( roaring )
( gurgling )
( screaming )
( creature roaring )
( birds chirping )
( sheep bleating )
( dog barking )
( flies buzzing )
♪ Don't cry
♪ This won't hurt
♪ At all
♪ You are all I want
♪ I've waited patiently
♪ My love
♪ Hold tight
♪ Let me breathe you in
♪ Touch the blade to skin
♪ It is time
♪ Close your eyes
♪ Forever more
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear
♪ Scream out
♪ If you dare
♪ My love
♪ But your God
♪ Won't come
♪ Not this time
♪ For this fate
♪ You can't outrun
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear
♪ But your God
♪ Won't come
♪ Not this time
♪ For this fate
♪ You can't outrun
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear
♪ There will be
♪ Nothing left
♪ To fear.