Forgive me.
Ok
Which of you nuns
violated my first commandment?
You do not steal from Chavo.
No.
Did you steal from Chavo?
You can tell me, mother.
I won't hurt you.
Yes or no?
No.
Now, you!
Did you steal from Chavo?
No? You lie to me ?
- You lie to Chavo?
- No.
Hey-hey-hey-hey!!
Where d'you go?
Where are you going?
Come here.
Take her.
For your troubles.
Thank you.
Let's go.
From Father Bernardo.
Nice.
Go ahead. Pick the one you want.
It's on the house.
You want the special?
Very good.
I go get her ready for you.
Will you hurry up and stick this bitch?!
Got a guy waiting to pay
triple for this holy piece of ass.
- Who knew nun pussy was in such demand?
- I told you for the last time.
She can't handle anymore.
- Use a different girl.
- No, no, no.
He already knows that she's a real nun.
Not just some filthy street whore dressed up like one.
- I can't help you.
I pay you good money
to do this. So do it!
I may be a lot of things
but I'm no murderer.
Fine.
I'll do it.
That motherfucker Padre Bernardo...
God bless him.
You think that's funny?
Come, laugh with me.
Damn!
Another one.
You dont care how much
you pay for a nun...
Get rid of them. Now.
I was certain God came to me.
He said: I have a better purpose in life.
God didn't talk to you.
It was just a bad reaction
about that shit in your body.
- What did God tell you.
- He told me to kill.
- To kill who?
- All  who sin against him.
God told you to start going
around killing people?
Shit.
You must have been tripping badly..
Because, see, I gave you the good stuff.
He wanted me to go away.
To purify my mind
only with his words.
Only then could I be prepared
to do his vengeance
Here they are.
For you.
If you're going to be doing the Lord's work...
You'll need the Lord's tools.
Careful, hey, they are loaded.
What else did God tell you?
He told me He was going to test me.
To see if I was worthy
to take on his mission.
- What kind of test?
- I would have to show no mercy.
Even to someone who
show mercy on me.
Everyone?
Bless you, Father.
Goodbye, Carlitos.
Bueno Suerte.
Carlitos!
You have a customer over here.
Carlitos?
Let God, who has enlightened every heart...
...teach you to know your sins
and trust in his mercy.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
It's been one day since my last confession.
What sins troubles you so much
that you must return after one day?
Just business as usual at our monastery.
The nuns carried the dope.
Bikers and priests were counting the money.
No one was to know that death was about to
make an appeareance in this house of God.
Stranger killed the priest?
Patience, padre, I'm getting to the good part.
The stranger leaned in and whispered into his ear.
This must have put the fear of God into him,
because all he could say was,
Carlitos.
And that's all the stranger needed to hear.
The stranger pushed the priest into his chair..
..turned and walked away.
But the priest had one more hail Hail Mary up his sleeve.
He reached for a gun...
Bang... Bang...
Bang-bang.
- Priest killed the stranger?
- No.
Stranger killed the priest?
What happened to the priest?
Four shots.
Forehead...
Sternum...
Shoulder...
Shoulder.
Sign of the Cross.
What happened to the stranger?
Came in like a demon,
then vanished like an angel.
Bullshit. I've heard nothing of this.
How do I know it's even true?
Who the fuck are you?
Who sent you? Talk to me!
Who the hell are...
Some nutjob is running around
whacking priests left and right?
Why the hell am I paying protection every month
for when you people can't protect a goddamn thing?
Stop your worrying.
You are still alive, aren't you?
Don't give me that. I fucking
used my men, for Christ's sake.
- How do I know I'm not next on his list?
- I said we take care of it.
Hello? Hello?
Bullshit! Ther's a goddamned vigilante
running around whacking priests...
...and all they can tell me
is they'll take care of it?
Take care of it how?
Like they took care of Father Bernardo?
Where is the world coming to when a man
of the cloth can't even do God's work?
It's a goddamned shame.
Bernardo was a good earner.
May God have mercy on his soul.
- Hello. How are you?
- There's something wrong. You can look at it, please?
- What a shit hole!
- Penny, watch your mouth!
- But it is.
- Come here.
What?
- That's for the attitude, little missy.
- Dad!
I can fit my finger in your radiator.
It's busted.
Hey man, let's take a little bit of this.
They won't miss it.
That's how people get killed.
I was only kidding anyway.
I'm going to see what Rigo doin.
You do that.
Just miss my friends, you know.
I could be on the beach, at the ocean...
- Look at all this sand you have out here.
- Hey, Kick-Stand?
What?
Come check this shit out.
- Wonder who they are.
- Where's Dad?
- Ladies!
- Get your hands off her!
Stanley!
- What happened?
- I was just fucking around with my buddy.
Your buddy?
Why are you crying?
It's okay. Come.
Come, come.
- We do not want any trouble
- Trouble? Do we look like trouble?
- So you are a bunch of nice guys.
- Yes, yes. We are very very nice guys.
But ... we do have a problem
when people come to our establishment
and they dont want to pay respect.
I do pay respect.
Do I look a puta?
- No!
- He called me a puta, no?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, he called you a fucking whore.
Why you trying to pay
me with puta money?
Want to see the puta?
There she is.
Show him a puta, guys.
You know, you could...
You could grow some balls.
Be a man and go over there and
save her from the bad guys.
I won't stop you. I promise.
Come on, you can do it. Go!
Be a man.
Go! Save her!
Hello.
I'm sorry about your daddy.
Guess I'll have to be your papa.
You're cute.
- Chavo, phone call.
- Who is it?
- It's him.
- What does he want?
He wants to talk to you.
- How does he sound?
- He sounds serious.
I come back for you, mami
- Stop! Stop!
- Come here, bitch!
Chavo's Repair. You wreck'em,
we don't give a shit.
Father Bernardo is dead.
And so are Lobo and Chinaco.
It was a goddamned massacre.
They took nothing. No money, no drugs.
It was strictly personal.
Round up your men and
get the word out.
Orale jefe, we have a surprise for you.
And she's sweet. We checked.
Ain't that right Kick Stand?
Sho'nuff.
- Would you like to pop her cherry?
- Yes.
I do...
But I can't.
We have work to do.
Muchachos... We are in the
middle of a holy war.
And besides, my mama always said to me.
"If you want a sweet nice ripe peach...
...you have to wait a while, falling under the tree.
Until it ripens and it's
nice and good and sweet.
My papa said: "Blacker the
berry, sweeter the juice."
That's what he said-- Hey!
Chavo? What are you doing?
You're talking about my mama at the same time
as your dirty stinking motherfucking father?
I didn't say nothing.
Hey! Chavo!
You ever talk again about my mama, I'm gonna
blow your dick off and beat you to death with it!
- Chavo, I didn't say nothing!
- Never talk about my mama!
If anybody else wants
to talk about my mama...
...be prepared to lose his dick!
- Rigo!
- Yes.
- Do you like this one?
Do you want me to give her to you?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Give her to him.
Not now. Go away. Leave me alone.
Shit!
Hello, Chavo.
You done a great job
taking care of my place.
I am. I made you a lot of money.
Listen up.
There's a vigilante on the streets.
going around and killing the bad guys.
In case you guys forgot, we are the bad guys.
Alright. Anybody comes through
that door, I want to know about it.
Understand?
Go! Go!
Alright, alright, I'm on it !
My hat.
In witness pleasuring one another in God's house.
That kind of blasphemy will not
be tolerated in my church.
- Father Carlitos is there. And he is scared.
- Good.
Why don't we just call the police
and let's them take care of it?
Believers didn't ask for any help.
When Moses came down from the mountain
and asked ask then who is on their side.
They responded by taking arms
the name of the Lord.
Slayed all who oppose the Lord.
Spared no one.
Are you ready for this?
Are you ready going with guns blazing...
...and shooting up a church
and killing more priests?
I'm not ready for this.
You know what they did to us.
You know what they would do to others like us.
They must be punished, Angelina. They must
be punished by the hand of true believers.
Look at me.
How am I supposed to be the hand of God,
if I can't even hold my own hands still?
All I can think is going back
at the monastery, in my filthy cell...
...where they can stick a needle
in my arm and I can forget.
Mother Magda told me you died.
I did die.
I was dead.
When I was in death's arms,
the Lord spoke to me.
Giving me his calling.
One I wasn't ready for.
One I'll have to prepare for.
- What did the Lord say?
- It wasn't words.
It was intense emotion of being alive
one that spoke to me.
How did you escape death?
The Lord sent an angel to guide me
back to this Earth to protect me.
- Like the way you're protecting me now?
- Yes.
Now that we found each other,
We will be whole again.
There is no easy road to become a nun.
It is not a life of refuge
from the outside world.
It is a life of sacrifice.
When times become unbearable,
we take comfort in knowing...
...that the sacrifices that we make
are made in the name of the Lord.
Jesus Christ.
When you pass through those doors,
you will be born into a new life.
You'll enter with nothing and you will be
absolved of sins without questions.
We do not ask nor do we speak
of our past lifes upon entry.
To make a closer union
with the crucified Lord...
You will be submitted to...
exercises and tasks in humility.
If you question these trial,
you do not belong with us.
To be obedient in all
things until death...
...for the love of God.
Is to be perfect nun.
You want me to take care of it?
No.
I am in the mood for a good jerk-off story.
- I'll take it.
- It Could be the priests's killer.
The Good Book is all the protection I need.
May God who has enlightened every soul..
..teach you to know your sins
and trust in his mercy.
Forgive me, Lord,
for I'm about to sin.
I'm not the Lord, he only works through me.
Now tell me what is so heavy on your heart..
..you must come to confession
at this unearthy hour?
I'm not here to confess any sins.
I'm here to commit them.
You must have balls in steel to come to my house.
Do you know who your dealing with?
How much money comes through this church?
Kiilling a couple of thugs and a priest
is not going to stop anything.
- You have no idea what you're up against.
- Just tell me who you work for.
and you won't have to suffer the
same fate as your brothers.
I work for the Lord.
He is my sheperd!
Make yourself comfortable.
Fuck.
Is always the same.
Go around.
Is nothing sacred any more?
Don't you cover up.
It's alright. It'll take a minute
Right back.
- I need a room.
- By the hour or by the night?
- By the night.
- That will be 30 dollars, cash.
Alright, that's thirty.
Lucky room number seven.
Thanks...
Jesus...
Halfbreed.
That's you.
- You good?
- Yah.
How can you get to count everybody's
money, including your own?
What's your problem?
You want to count my money?
- Nah, man. I'm just saying.
- Count it.
- No, that's alright. It's good.
Rigo.
Go handle to your business, man.
- Chavo's repair. This is Rigo.
- Get me Chavo on the phone. Now!
Ok. Ok.
- Carlitos too?
- Those bastards killed him in his own church.
- He should have prayed harder.
- You need to put an end to this, right now.
OK.
If you want us to track down this hellraiser,
it's going to be double the regular price.
- I don't have that kind of money.
- Hey, Padre, don't fuck with me.
I've already lost two men
in your holy war.
Besides, I know Jesus has deep
pockets for this kind of shit.
If you want double the pay, then
I want all this done in half the time.
Meet Mother Magda at Carlitos his church.
She is expecting you.
Carlitos...
That didn't sound good.
This way.
Hey-hey-hey. No-no.
You guys stay here and make sure
we don't have any unwanted visitors.
- What do you think?
- They're dead alright.
You can stop them. Make them pay.
You know, you're not exactly the forgiving type, Magda.
You know, turn the other
cheek, love thy enemy...
And all that other
bullshit you preach.
Listen, you brute. They called me
up from my monastery to fix this.
And I expect it to be resolved
as soon as possible.
I heard you the first time, OK ?
I know, I know you want it fast.
You want a miracle.
That's your business.
But by the looks of things,
your business is not doing very well.
Now. Are here any witnesses?
Sister Mary was the first one
to alert us of the situation.
- Then get her ass in here.
- This won't do any good.
Sister Mary took a vow of silence 20 years ago.
I keep her around just because she knows
how to keep a big mouth shut.
We'll see about that. Bring her.
Who did this?
Who killed these men?
OK.
I am going to ask you one more time nicely.
If you do not want to talk, I'm going to let
Kick Stand take over the questioning.
Who killed these men?
OK. It's your choice.
I'll be right back.
Mary, tell me what you saw now.
Mary what did you see?
It's alright. You can talk.
I won't tell anyone.
Just between us.
Mary, they are going to come back here..
.. then I can not stop them.
What did you see?
Kick Stand, get your dick over here.
Now!
Who killed them, Mary?
You know who it was, don't you?
You've seen them before, haven't you?
What did they look like?
Kick Stand, go to work.
I'm gonna nail you harder than
they nailed Jesus to the cross.
Kick Stand, enough.
It was a nun.
- With guns.
- A nun?
Looks like one of your
penguins flew the coop, Magda.
- What kind of guns did she have?
- Big guns.
I looked into her eyes
and saw the devil in them.
So what are we going
to do now, boss?
Well, first we're going to round
up the troops. And then...
...we are going nun-hunting.
Halfbreed! Quit fucking around!
Get up here!
We're looking for a nun.
A nun with big guns.
You mean, "big guns" like in big tits?
I said guns.
You better wisen up or you're
gonna end up here in a pine box.
Get the word out on the streets.
Hey, Kick Stand, go check that out.
What about her?
She is a nun.
Yes she is.
Are you a killer?
No, no, no. Not this one.
I don't think she can even hold a gun
much less shoot one.
C'mon. Let's go.
Be back for you later.
Oh, my prodigal daughter returns.
When they didn't find your body in Valambrosa
I thought perhaps it was you causing all this trouble.
And now that I see you here before me,
I know, I know my words are true.
The only thing you're shooting
up is in your arms.
I knew you wouldn't last
a week outside of here.
Are you looking for someone?
Well, take a good look at him.
God punishes those who
fail to serve his will!
- A delivery from Magda.
- What the hell am I suppose to do with her?
I thought we were done
with this nun bullshit.
Magda said to give her to Chavo
and when he is finished with her
just throw her out with
the rest of the trash.
- Put it in that booth.
- Alright.
Nice rack.
- Hi, Chavo.
- Hello, love.
Hey, Kick Stand. Go tell Beverly
to bring me some beers, please.
Come with me.
Just like I remember.
- Will you dance for me, Mamacita?
- Of course.
Come on, come here.
Thanks, Beverly.
Listen, if you see a crazy chick like that,
you shoot first and ask questions later.
That's Chavo's orders.
- Halfbreed, would you like a beer?
- What the fuck you think, bitch? Yeah.
I think God is trying to tell me something.
Everywhere I go, I see nuns.
What the fuck you
yapping about, Beverly?
The girl in the picture. I saw one checking in
at the Palms Hotel, last night.
Really dirty looking one too. Might've
had, I dunno, a drinking problem.
You saw this chick, a nun, checking
in that piece-of-shit motel last night?
I was with Butch. Ask her,
she'll tell you the same thing.
God help you if you're wrong about
this, Beverly, God fucking help you!
God...
- What do you want? I'm in the middle of something.
- I need you to wake the fuck up and pay attention.
Yeah, well now that you got my undivided attention,
What the fuck is so important you need
to wake me up in the middle of the morning?
It's four o'clock in the afternoon, you stupid bitch.
- Did you checked in a nun, last night?
- No.
Beverly, you fucking cunt!
I'm gonna kick your fucking
ass when I get off the phone!
Leave her the fuck alone,
you red nigger. Jesus.
I didn't checked her in last night.
I checked her in this morning at 3AM.
Butch, now is not the
time to fuck with me.
Room seven.
I checked her in myself.
Don't let that fuckin' bitch leave.
We're on our way.
Is she dead?
No, but Beverly saw a nun checking
in to that Palm Motel last night.
I want to see this little hellraiser myself.
Kick Stand, you get over there.
You bring her back to me, alive.
Go.
You let me leave now.
I won't have to kill you.
In case you haven't noticed,
I'm the one with the gun.
You do not have to go through this.
There are no sins unforgivable by God.
- If you just ask for his forgiveness.
- What do you know about sins?
Are you even a real nun
or just some whore playing dress-up?
I've taken my vows and was ordained
at my church in the name of the Lord.
You worship whores are so high and mighty.
Who are you to preach?
What do you know about
half the sins you condemn?
- I too am a sinner.
- What are your sins, my precious sister?
- I am a fornicator
- Big fucking deal.
Half of you penguins are
getting poked by the preacher.
That may be true.
But, my sins of the flesh...
are that of the fairer sex.
Get back on the bed, bitch.
Shh....
We will sin today.
And ask for forgiveness tomorrow.
Such is the beauty of the faith.
- I thought that you...
- You thought, you thought? You thought wrong.
You said I can be forgiven.
You want to be forgiven?
Ask for it. Come on, come on!
- Ask for it! Ask for it!
- Please... please...
- Please...
- Shh....
I absolve you...
It's ok...
of all your sins.
But there's no penance
for the hellbound!
- Where the fuck have you been all day?
- Over at Titty Flicker's.
They got this new girl over there.
Man, I'm telling you: She is it!
She wears this nun outfit. Makes your
dick just pop out of your pants.
You've seen a nun
at the Titty Flicker club?
Yeah...
- How long has she been there, asshole?
- Papa said she just stopped there.
Get the fuck out of my face!
- What now?
- Butch is dead.
That nun worked over real good.
Chavo's going to be pissed.
Sorry, boss. But I got bad news.
Butch is dead.
- Bloody mess over there, man.
- Goddamn, that bitch is crazy!
Prospect said there's a nun
over the Titty Flicker right now.
Come on.
- Tity Flicker's.
- Hey, man, it's Halfbreed.
- I bet that you're looking for that nun.
- Tell Papa Chavo's on his way.
Yeah, I'll get that bitch cleaned up.
- Now what?
- Chavo's on his way.
- And...?
- And, get that bitch out of the booth...
and clean her up before he gets here.
What's the matter, Halfbreed?
Not now, bitch.
Wake up!
And put your clothes back on.
My heart will not allow
me to wait any longer.
I pray to the Lord, He
will safely reunite us.
If not in this world,
then in heaven above.
♪I've got the joy, joy, joy,♪
♪joy down in my heart...♪
♪Down in my heart.♪
♪I've got the joy, joy, joy,♪
♪joy down in my heart...♪
♪Down in my heart to stay.♪
♪And if the devil doesn't like♪
♪it, he can go fuck himself...♪
♪Go fuck himself.♪
♪And if the devil doesn't like♪
♪it, he can go fuck himself...♪
♪Because Magda is here to stay.♪
Get your filthy hands off me.
Where's Angelina?
She is just playing at the Titty Flicker
theater with some old friends of yours.
Killing me is not going
to make things right.
Kick Stand, go tell Papa
to bring in a nun.
Hello again, killer.
I know you're not the
nun I'm looking for.
But, I do believe you have
something to do with this.
- Papa, leave us alone for a while.
- Gotta take a dump anyway.
Look! The nun!
Put the gun down, nice and slow.
Now walk!
Who the hell are you?
Fucking bitch!
No, no, no, calm down.
Get off her.
I'm not touching her. It's okay.
Come on.
Are you okay?
- I will be.
- No, no, no ...
No, no.
No! No, no, no.
Everyone?
No. I'll take care of it myself.
Father...
Are you ready to take on this new
mission in the name of our Lord?