Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick
"Yotsuya Kwaidan."
- Good morning.
- Hi.
Kosuke's behind us.
Sorry about last night.
I was held up.
I'll make it up to you.
Hello.
"Kosuke Hasegawa - In."
- How do I look?
- Mean.
"Yotsuya Kwaidan, The Play"
5 and 4. Odd number.
Dealer rolls! Place your bets!
Hello, Sir.
Yes?
What's that scent on you?
Is it blood?
Borrowed money should
be returned.
But some people
forget to pay it back.
A loan from a blind masseur
is taken lightly.
I'm not a noble samurai
like yourself, Sir.
For me,
I can only depend on money.
True, I am a samurai.
But without money or rank
I feel like I'm in a dungeon
without sunlight.
Mister.
How about a good time?
Not a bad idea...
Look at your debauched face.
Asshole!
Give it back to me!
Lovebirds.
It's mine.
A patron gave it to me!
Give it back to me!
Sir.
Who's your new woman?
When I'm with you
time passes in the
blink of an eye.
Leaving so soon?
If I'm not home before Father
he'll never let me
leave the house.
If you had a comb
like this...
I'd always be with you, Iwa.
My daughter wants to
marry you but
I won't leave my family fortune
to you.
Since her mother died
I've raised her on my own.
I won't let a sleazy man like you
have my precious daughter.
Take this money and forget Iwa.
I know all about you.
Did years of unemployment
rot your morals?
You and your shifty
friends con people.
You'd even kill for money!
How despicable!
You give samurai a bad name.
Shame on you!
What amuses you?
You think I'm worth so little.
You're incorrigible.
You brute!
Nobody's listening to
your nonsense!
You useless old fool!
How dare you...
Ah...
You'll catch a cold.
Is your father still missing?
It's already been a month.
Poor Iwa.
You must feel miserable.
Oh, Iemon.
I'm sure he's out
there somewhere.
Maybe he got held up
by some important business.
It breaks my heart to see
you so sad.
But don't worry.
I'll ask around for you.
Iemon.
When I'm with you...
I feel that I can cope.
I wish I was with
you all the time.
Iwa.
Do you mean that we should
get married?
Yes.
That is my wish too.
But your father hasn't
given his approval.
Right?
As he has no sons to
continue the family's line,
he should be happy to have a
successor.
Being the head of this household
might help you
find employment.
Starting a family...
Is that happiness?
I guess so.
For you, too?
Maybe.
What's funny?
You'll catch a cold.
This is unbearable.
I'm not worthy of you...
I'm so sorry.
Oh, God, sorry!
Sorry. Are you OK?
I'm fine.
Let's have a break.
It's break time!
- Here.
- Thanks.
You OK?
Kayo, can you fill in for me?
But...
Please.
Okay.
I'll do my best.
Iwa.
I know that you resent me.
That's not true.
Since we got together
2 years ago
I've never brought
any money home.
"I gave you a baby boy."
"Even though I've been sick
since his birth."
"I'm the one who works"
"and prepares the meals."
It's written all over your face.
You in here?
Here, it'll relieve the pain.
No, thanks.
He kicked you
even though it's a rehearsal!
Never mind.
What do you see in him?
How are your wife and kid?
Good?
We have our ups and downs...
You look happy.
Don't be deceived.
Men are easily tempted.
Just to be clear.
Married men don't interest me.
You're direct.
Keep your mind on the job.
Sometimes I wish that the play
was my real life.
I don't.
This is unbearable.
I'm not worthy of you!
I'm so sorry!
Women really are something...
So you know all the lines!
Yes, just in case...
You're so prepared!
Thanks for that.
Is your back OK?
I'll get changed.
You alright?
Yes.
I believe you're Mr.
Iemon Tamiya.
And you are...?
I'm a nanny at Mr. Ito's
residence for his girl, Ume.
My name is Maki.
Would you accompany me
to the Ito mansion?
It would be in your interests
if you came.
Master Kihei Ito
wishes to speak with you
in person.
I'll leave it to you,
Grandfather.
Alright.
Ume, I'm happy for you.
Sir, step this way please.
Thank you for agreeing to come.
I apologize for bringing
you here like this.
What can I do for you?
What a shame a good
samurai like you isn't employed!
I can tell that
you're a good samurai.
I'd like to propose that you
become part of the Ito family.
I wonder if you'd agree to be
Ume's husband.
But I have a wife and a child.
Besides Ms. Ume appears
to be quite young.
She's sixteen.
With clue respect I must decline
your proposition.
I find your honesty
very gallant.
Ume is certainly
childish at times
but at 16 she's mature enough
to be a woman.
She saw you one day
when she was in town
and she can't shake you
from her mind.
She lost her parents
at a young age.
She's so dear to me I'd
do anything for her.
But Ume has never asked
anything of me.
Until now.
Until she fell in love.
Love...
Yes.
I know your position,
but please consider my offer.
Mr. Tamiya.
You deserve a life
worthy of a samurai.
If you marry my Ume
it'll be easier to
find employment.
Your wife will understand.
A samurai's wife would
encourage her husband's career.
There's nothing to worry about.
We've figured out a plan
to make things go smoothly.
Let us handle it.
May I come in?
Miyuki, I'm clone for the day.
I'll see you tomorrow.
See you.
Miyuki.
I'd love to have a talk with you
one clay.
I got into acting because I
was inspired by you.
Oh.
You're quite gutsy, aren't you?
Thank you.
I'll be going.
See you.
See you tomorrow.
It's OK now.
Miyuki, are you in here?
The car's here.
"Miyuki calling."
What's wrong?
Hi.
I just came here for
some shirts.
Oh.
You want to shower?
Why so nice?
Coz you dropped by, Kosuke.
We have a day off next week.
Got any plans?
I'm going to Izu.
Work?
I was invited by some
producers I worked with once.
As soon as I'm done
I'll come by.
I'll be waiting.
That's a lot of pasta...!
Want some?
"Home Pregnancy Test."
"Negative."
Welcome home.
How do you feel?
Iemon...
I wish I was...
It's not decided yet but.
I might be offered
an official position.
Is that true?
If Father was here...
he would have been happy!
You can wear this when
you report for duty.
It's our family crest,
a ying-yang insignia.
Where there's light
there's shadow.
Where there's shadow
there's light.
All elements in the universe
throughout eternity
have a light and a shady side.
What is it?
There, there.
Iemon, he's smiling
at his daddy!
Dear boy!
Ms. Maki came all this way
to bring me a gift.
Please thank her.
Let me express my thanks
for my husband's good fortune.
I appreciate
Master Ito's generosity.
I hope he'll continue
to support Iemon's career.
Thank you so much.
I'll pass it on.
It appears that
your husband is preoccupied
with your health.
So Master Ito acquired
some medicine abroad and
he wanted to get it to you soon.
Have one packet a day.
I don't deserve
such expensive medicine...
Not to worry.
It's for your husband.
We hope he'll perform to the
best of his ability on the job.
And that depends on
your good health.
Thank you very much.
Iwa, we have no reason
to reject their generosity.
I don't know how to thank you.
Look at that darling baby!
What did you give her?
Don't worry, it won't kill her.
But...
Gentlemen usually
despise things that are ugly.
Are you in pain?
There, there.
Does it still hurt?
There, there...
Welcome home.
I nursed Ichinosuke
a while ago but
he got sick and threw up.
I wonder if it's the medicine...
Are you saying that it's poison?
No, I wouldn't!
I've taken the medicine
for 2 days now but...
What?
I guess it'll start
working soon.
It was so expensive!
You have to finish it or
it'd be disrespectful
to Master Ito.
It is generous of you to
be so concerned for my health.
You troubled yourself
to get me medicine.
I'm so fortunate.
Tell Master Ito
how grateful I am
for his kindness.
That was the last packet.
Thanks, everyone.
Let's finish for the day!
We'll have a clay off tomorrow.
And we'll resume rehearsals
at 2 pm in two days.
Kayo.
Kosuke will stay over tonight so
I won't need a ride tomorrow.
OK.
If there's any change
let me know.
In that case I'll call you.
Good.
Sorry, I'm still in Izu.
Oh.
It's not your fault.
Bye.
See you...
Me or her...?
I love you.
If it's true
marry me.
We'll get married and
move to America.
There's no reason for you
to work as an actor.
You can help Dad
with his business.
He owns many restaurants
and buildings.
Acting is all I've known
since childhood.
I won't...
I won't let Miyuki
have you back.
About Iemon...
What would have made him happy?
Nothing.
See you tomorrow.
Hey, you.
I'll have to ask you
to come a little sooner.
Sorry.
It's his fault.
Uh...
Miyuki!
What's going on...?
Miyuki?
Hi, there.
I'm not worthy of you...
I'm so sorry.
What?
I'm not worthy of you...
I'm so sorry.
What are you saying?
Let's sleep.
You need a doctor.
Let's go.
I can sleep it off.
No, you can't...
We're going.
I can't find our baby!
I know he's in there.
I looked all over but
I couldn't find him.
What...?
You know how important this play
is for us.
We need some sleep.
Or do you want to
make love?
That's enough!
I'm not worthy of you...
I'm so sorry.
Go away...
I'm not worthy of you...
No, it's OK...
I'm so sorry.
I'm not worthy of you...
Stay away!
I'm so sorry.
Hello.
You're early today.
Listen, everyone.
We can't find Miyuki
so we'll use an understudy.
Let's get ready, everyone.
Fill in for her.
Very well.
Thank you.
"Miyuki Goto - Out."
When I'm with you
time passes in the
blink of an eye.
Leaving so soon?
If I'm not home before Father
he'll never let me
leave the house.
If you had a comb like this...
I'd always be with you, Iwa.
It hurts...
Oh, God...
It hurts.
Good evening.
It's Takuetsu, the masseur.
Ms. Iwa.
How are you tonight?
It's kind of you to visit but
I'd prefer to be alone
this evening.
Iemon will be home soon
and he'll want his supper.
Mr. Iemon?
I wonder if he'll
come home tonight.
Takuetsu...?
Ms. Iwa!
How dare you! Stop it!
I've desired you, Ms. Iwa
for a long time.
Let me go!
Beautiful Ms. Iwa...
I said let go!
Forget your husband.
You see, Mr. Iemon...
He knows about this.
He said I can have you.
I guess Iemon wanted
a better life.
Samurai can be...
quite heartless.
For a better life
he sacrificed you and the baby.
He'll live in a mansion
with a pretty, young girl
as his wife.
Ah..
Ms. Iwa...
Ms. Iwa!
Ms. Iwa.
Ms. Iwa...
Filthy animals.
I caught you fornicating.
Sir, this isn't what
you promised!
Iemon!
Masseur.
I saw you.
You tricked a married woman
into a shameless affair.
And you're a wife who
let herself be tricked.
It's immoral.
I had to punish you both.
Iemon.
You're mine and mine only.
What's wrong?
Ume.
Iwa...
You've done me wrong.
Iemon.
You demon!
Ume!
There's nothing to worry about.
We figured out a plan
to make things go smoothly.
You're so undignified...
I think you've already
been in hell, Iemon.
For the pain
you inflicted on me!
What the hell...!
There wasn't even a breeze.
It flew from over there.
OK, where is his head?
Well sir...
We can't find it.
What do you mean?
Thank you.
"Kosuke Hasegawa - Out."
He's late again.
OK, that's good.
Come downstairs.
See you down there.
Miyuki.
Kosuke isn't here.
Do you know why?
No. He worries me.
Do you know anything?
No, I don't...
This play...
Make sure it goes ahead
no matter what.
Director!
Is he here?
No.
The police?
Miyuki.
If we're done early tonight
how about...
a drink?
Well?
If we're done early
you should go home.
Too bad!
Ebizo ICHIKAWA.
Ko SHIBASAKI.
Hideaki ITO.
Screenplay by Kikumi Yamagishi.
Directed by Takashi Miike