Sarah.
Same dream.
There's smoke.
Someone takes her hand.
She's running.
The same man
comes towards her.
Jay Prescott with some
cool morning sounds,
and enjoy it while you can...
...because it's gonna be
an unreasonably hot one
later in the day in LA,
going up to 95 in the Valley,
92 in the Basin and upper to 70s
- in Santa Monica and the beaches.
- Hello?
- And now, appropriately enough...
...here's Yvonne Murray
with "Burning Up."
Hello?
Ms. Julius?
Sorry, wrong number.
Remember who the ninth circle of Hell
is reserved for.
Hmm.
- Morning!
- Morning.
- So, what do you want for breakfast?
- I don't have time.
I got an early class.
Close-up--
his eye gleams
like volcanic lava.
Sarah stands transfixed
like a deer
in a car's headlights.
Sarah? Why did you
name your character Sarah?
I don't know.
- More dreams, huh?
- Yep.
I'm not getting any sleep,
but it's gonna make a great film.
I wonder if Orson Welles
dreamt "Citizen Kane" first.
We're in a huge cathedral with gargoyles
all over, mixed with religious icons.
Mm!
- Mark!
- Mm.
- I want you, Maggie, right now.
- Mark, I can't.
Come on,
let's go back to my place.
- I'm-- I'm dying without you.
- Mark, this is the age of safe sex
and sex with you on any level
is not safe.
Come on, Maggie.
Why won't you give us a chance, huh?
I'm crazy about you, but I'm not
gonna let you shine me on forever.
I'm not, I'm just concentrating
on my script right now.
Yeah, right, the script.
Come on,
this is really important to me.
I just can't let anything distract me.
Okay.
Okay, I see.
I just hope I'm still around
when you decide to get distracted.
Give me a break.
Ugh.
It's cloudy and misty...
- Joannie, ah!
- Bud!
Hey, Bud, it's not a speedway,
you know?
- Sorry.
- Come on, people.
We got good news, we got bad news,
we got all kinds of news.
- Go ahead, Tina.
- Okay, first,
- we lost our editing space again.
- Oh, no!
You know,
they stick us in the library,
then the biology lab,
and now the music room.
Yeah, how come it's always
the film department that gets shafted?
What do you have to do
to be taken seriously around here?
You gotta learn
how to kick ass, man.
Yeah!
Well, we are a novelty item.
Every new department
has to make a splash
to get on the map.
And that's the good news because
Toby's come up with a great idea.
- Go ahead, Tobe.
- Yeah, Toby!
Here's our new idea.
We do an all-night horrorthon.
- Ugh.
- No, this is a terrific idea.
An all-night horror show.
They're big grossers.
Hey, gang,
I got a better idea.
Why don't we put on a play?
We'll convert the old barn
into a theater, huh?
- Please.
- Is there an inherited gene
for obnoxiousness?
- Yeah.
- These are the future writers
and directors
of the American cinema.
It's the "Police Academy" syndrome.
Hey, hey!
There's more social relevance
and character development
in "Police Academy 5"
than in all of Ingmar Bergman's
cinematic smorgasbord.
Bergman's fleshy ambiguities,
as one critic said...
- I believe he did say that.
- No, no, no.
Joannie, how would you know?
Your favorite film
is "Escape from Witch Mountain."
- Shh!
- Hey, hey, hey, fellas!
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
What makes you think
people are gonna pay six bucks
to see some crappy old movie
they wouldn't even rent for 99 cents?
Because you can't see "Mosquito"
at home
in 3-D what's it--
what's it called?
- Project-o-Vision.
- Right.
Nor can you watch "The Stench"
in authentic Odor-o-Scope.
- Aroma-Rama.
- Oh.
Noseguards given at the theatre.
You could use those in lots of movies.
Right.
Or "The Amazing Electrified Man"
- in...
- Shock-o-Scope.
And that's why
they're gonna pay 10 bucks.
See, every one of these pictures
was originally released
with some kind of a promotional gimmick.
Yeah, which
we're gonna recreate for our audience
- only with improvements.
- So, on the one hand,
- it'll be a total goof.
- And on the other hand,
we're gonna scare
the living shit out of them.
So, how do you vote?
Oh, there might be
enough money left over
for some of you to do your own
little experimental film.
- Bingo!
- I'm in.
Hmm.
Maggie?
We're voting.
Yep.
Welcome to the house of ushers.
Wow.
The old Dreamland theater.
It was a live theater
for a long time
before they converted it
to a cinema.
- Toby, it's great.
- Yeah, isn't it?
Kind of sad we're gonna be
its swan song.
They're tearing this place down
in three weeks.
Three weeks?
Are you crazy?
We can't get this festival ready
in three weeks.
Yes, you can
because I am here to help you.
Malcolm Mnesyne
at your disposal
- so to speak.
- Hi, Dr. M.
Hello, Tony.
I'm Toby.
Yes, yes, of course you are,
dear boy.
My cargo is outside
and it will require all of you
to bring it in.
I'll be waiting center stage
where I belong.
Thanks a lot for coming, Dr. M.
- Who the hell is this guy?
- Dr. M's Movie Memorabilia shop.
He's got everything we need
for the festival.
Now, what you see here
are the priceless relics
of a bygone era of showmanship.
I refer not to myself,
but to the contents
of these crates,
which I have stored
and lovingly tended
since my own youthful days
as manager of a movie palace
very much like the Dreamland.
We had theaters in those days,
not like these cine-, omni-, multi-,
whatchama-plex things today
with 29 screens
the size of postage stamps.
And we had fun.
The ballyhoo,
the giveaways,
the bullshit.
I could tell you stories.
The point is we put the butts
in the seats where they belong.
And they loved it.
Now, what you guys got
in your festival
are turkeys
and not fresh turkeys either.
But here I am
the master chef
of showmanship
to teach you
how to turn those withered turkeys
into a memorable
moviegoing feast.
So, step right up
and we'll all get started.
♪ Well, Saturday night at 8:00 ♪
♪ I know where I'm gonna go ♪
♪ I'm gonna pick my baby up ♪
♪ And take her
to the picture show ♪
♪ Everybody in the neighborhood ♪
♪ Is dressing up
to be there, too ♪
♪ And we're gonna have a ball ♪
- ♪ Just like we always do... ♪
- Hey!
♪ Saturday night at the movies ♪
♪ Who cares
what picture you see ♪
♪ When you're hugging with your baby
in the last row of the balcony? ♪
♪ Ah, there's Technicolor
and Cinemascope ♪
- ♪ A cast out of Hollywood... ♪
- Shit!
♪ And the popcorn
from the candy stand ♪
♪ Makes it all seem
twice as good ♪
♪ There's always
lots of pretty girls ♪
♪ With figures
they don't try to hide ♪
♪ But they never can compare ♪
♪ With the girl by my side ♪
♪ Saturday night at the movies ♪
♪ Who cares
what picture you see ♪
♪ When you're hugging with your baby
in the last row of the balcony? ♪
♪ Another Saturday night
and everything is groovy ♪
♪ Me and my baby,
we're going to the movie ♪
♪ It don't matter
if the show is very scary ♪
♪ We'll have a mai tai
in the balcony ♪
♪ We buy the popcorn
with plenty butter ♪
♪ And not a single word,
any that we utter ♪
♪ We go inside and take a seat... ♪
♪ And start to share
our body heat ♪
♪ Saturday night at the movies ♪
♪ Who cares what picture you see... ♪
♪ When you're hugging with your baby
in the last row of the balcony? ♪
Stop. Stop it!
Son of a gun.
All right, Leon, for the test,
- use the magnolia blossom.
- No, no,
- use the ambrosia.
- Yeah, yeah, something nice, okay?
- Okay! What odor pellets do we got?
- Okay, we have fish smell,
- locker room, road kill...
- Mm-hmm.
...fart plain, fart stale,
- dead dog.
- Dead dog!
And locker room!
Oh, boy.
- Whoo!
- Ugh! Ah, shit!
- Dead dog, dead dog!
- Blech!
Leon, you son of a bitch!
- Tina, go!
- Oh, God!
I look like
a fucking snow cone.
Shape up, soldier.
♪ Saturday night at the movies ♪
- ♪ Who cares what picture you see... ♪
- Voila.
♪ When you're hugging
with your baby ♪
- ♪ In the last row of the balcony? ♪
- Okay, hit it!
♪ Saturday night ♪
- ♪ At the movies... ♪
- I like it!
♪ Who cares
what picture you see ♪
- Vroom!
- Stop it.
Vroom.
So, what are we gonna do
with the rest of this stuff, huh?
Dr. M said to store everything back here
until after the horrorthon.
Hello, what do we have here?
"Warning, do not open."
He didn't say anything
about a film.
Why does it have
a warning sticker on it?
It's probably a nitrate print.
Old movies were filmed on stock
- that was highly flammable.
- Yeah, sometimes they used to explode
when exposed to the air.
Knowledge entails risk.
Boom!
- What is it?
- I don't know.
It doesn't look very long.
- Wanna run it and find out?
- Why not?
Oh, must be a private eye flick.
Yuck, get the Visine.
We got a great cinematic mind
at work here.
Yeah, eat your heart out,
- Spielberg.
- I think this is funny.
Nice nose.
I am the possessor.
The possessor,
the possessor,
the possessor.
You said that.
I am the possess--
the possess--
possess--
possess...
Oh, no, he's gonna do it.
- I don't believe it.
- Yes.
- He's gonna dolly up his nose.
- Yes, yes.
Come into...
my head.
- I'd rather not, thanks.
- Come into
my head.
Come into...
She's coming to.
Are you okay, Mag?
Yeah, Mag,
how many fingers I got up?
Will you move back
and let the girl breathe?
- What?
- I'm okay.
What was that movie?
Whatever it is,
it bites the big one.
No, no, no, really, what was it?
- I need to know.
- I don't know, but if it's that scary,
maybe we should show it
in the horrorthon.
Well, I'm not sure of all the facts,
but it's called "Possessor."
It was made by a guy
named Lanyard Gates.
He was, like, the head guru
of this film cult back in the '60s.
They used to drop acid
and make these weird
avant garde movies
of each other
staring into the camera
picking their noses,
stuff like that.
- You knew him?
- Oh, I bought into his rap for a while
until I actually saw
one of his films.
It was ludicrous.
The audience laughed it off the stage.
"Possessor" was his response.
How do you mean?
He didn't like
being laughed at
so he shot all of "Possessor"
except for the last scene.
When he showed the film,
he played the last scene live on stage.
He murdered his family
in front of the audience.
- What?
- Set fire to the theater,
locked the doors.
A lot of people were killed.
I always thought the film
went up in smoke, too,
but I guess
a fragment of it survived.
I think we should just turn it over
to the police.
- Yeah.
- Not a good idea for the horrorthon.
It's a total bummer.
I mean, who wants to see a film
where a guy really goes berserk
and kills his entire family?
- Mm.
- Exactly.
Back to Dr. M.
- All right.
- Really.
- Mom?
- Oh!
You scared me.
You all right?
Have you ever heard of this guy
named Lanyard Gates?
No, I don't think so.
Why?
Because we found
this film that he made, "Possessor."
Mom, I think that this is a man
that I've been dreaming about.
It's really weird.
Maggie,
I want you
to quit this festival.
I'm gonna get some tickets for us
down at the agency
and we'll go away together,
just the two of us.
What are you talking about?
I can't just take off like that.
Well, sure you can.
We never tied ourselves down
before.
And if these dreams
are starting again--
Mom, I'm not
gonna run away, okay?
I mean, I can't run away from something
that's inside of my head.
I know it sounds
completely off the wall,
but there's something
happening here
that I've been looking for
all of my life.
It's almost like
it's psychic or something.
Does that make any sense?
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Oh,
just every once in a while
I realize that you're all grown up
and I miss that little girl
you used to be.
That little girl
who used to need me so much.
- I gotta get to bed.
- Yeah.
- Good night.
- Good night, sweetie.
- Hello?
- The ninth circle of Hell
- is reserved for traitors.
- Who is this?
I am the possessed,
the possessed,
the possessed.
- Oh, my God.
- Soon, I will be the possessor.
I want her.
- I want her!
- No!
Well, then why don't we talk?
I'm in Dreamland.
And bring your nasty little gun
in case I turn my back again.
Coming soon
justice, retribution,
and death.
The film they tried to stop,
but couldn't.
Fifteen years in the making.
No.
No, Lanyard.
Lanyard.
Good-bye, Suzanne.
Stop!
Lanyard, you know I'll do it!
♪ Scary, scary movies ♪
♪ On the silver screen ♪
♪ Aliens, maniacs, tarantulas,
and brainiacs ♪
- ♪ And everything in between... ♪
- Why are you going?
I got through the horrorthon
and look at me!
Look at me!
- Here's your official horrorthon kit.
- Thanks!
It contains your Project-o-Vision
3-D glasses,
your Aroma-Rama noseguard.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Whoo, hoo, boo!
- Give me two.
- Have a great night.
You're gonna love this horrorthon.
Ooh, awesome head, man.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
What time
does the first show start?
Check the shock clock, ma'am.
When it screams,
a feature beams.
Sign the fright form, please.
In case you die of a heart attack,
it means we're not responsible.
No! Don't sign it!
Think of your families,
your mommies, your daddies,
- and Toto at home!
- Excuse me,
- it's time for his injection.
- Ah, no!
Not the needle!
I'm sorry, Nurse Ratched, I'll be good!
- Thanks.
- Two, please.
Mark, hi.
- Hi.
- Well, hi, Maggie.
Fancy meeting you here.
Enjoy the show.
Maggie.
Will these films be as shocking
as "Possessor," Sarah?
Two, please.
Hey, lady, where are you going?
Whoo!
♪ Let's all go to the lobby ♪
♪ To get ourselves a treat ♪
♪ Little things to eat ♪
♪ A popcorn can't be beat ♪
♪ The sparkling drinks... ♪
All right, come on you guys.
Help support our film fest.
We are broke.
We can give you these T-shirts for $20.
Come on,
two T-shirts for $20.
make your boyfriend buy you one.
Don't let him be cheap tonight.
Come on, you're a high roller.
Come on, spend 20 bucks.
What do you want,
a large, a small?
No, you guys need a large.
This is a horrorthon.
- Yeah! Ooh, wah! Yeah!
- You're gonna be all night, okay?
Whoo!
Bring on the boos!
Come on, you've got two fives,
he's got a 10.
All right, come on, just spend
all your lunch money right here.
Come on, let's do it!
What in tarnation
could've done this, doc?
There's nary a drop of blood left
in any of my sheep.
Beats me, Skeeter.
Wait a minute.
Look at this large puncture wound
in the back of her neck.
Are you sure that's the neck?
Gross!
- I'll be right back.
- Somebody just...
- I'm gonna get some popcorn.
- ...stuck a big needle
or something in them
and just sucked the blood out.
Oh!
Someone or something.
Got the whole dang flock.
Even Effie.
Say, you don't think
there's any connection between this
and them underground tests
the Army's been conducting out here,
do you?
It's our army out there, Skeeter.
If we were in danger,
they'd have warned us.
- Toby.
- Hey, Mag.
I know this sounds
really crazy,
but I think I just saw
Lanyard Gates.
- Gates?
- Yes, I'm sure it was him.
He's older
and his face was burned,
but I'm sure it was him.
The guy from the "Possessor."
"Possessor"?
Maggie, all we saw was an eyeball
and a bad haircut.
How could you recognize anybody
from that?
I don't know how I knew
but I'm telling you it was him.
I just-- I know it.
Well, Mr. Davis did say
this guy Gates's body
was never officially identified.
He said it was a big fire
and the bodies were burned
beyond recognition,
- so maybe he could--
- So maybe he's still alive.
I mean, like, he could be just lurking
somewhere in this theater
just waiting to attack us!
- Sounds a little paranoid.
- This is great.
God, Toby, what a great movie
this would make!
We gotta find this guy.
Maggie,
maybe we should call the police.
Oh, yeah, right,
they come right on down here,
"Hello, officer, hi.
There was this guy
and he made this movie 15 years ago
and he, like, killed all these people
and everything
and we think
he's at our film festival,
blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah."
All right.
Look, somebody's
gotta watch the booth.
- I'll take a look, okay?
- All right.
Hey, be careful.
Wait.
What-- what's that, Skeeter?
I-- I don't know,
but whatever it is,
it's getting too close!
Oh!
Get it off!
Skeeter, oh, God!
Skeeter!
Now, tell me
this whole thing again.
And spell it out for me
this time.
- I'm simpleminded.
- And you're ugly, too!
The radiation...
...from the underground atomic tests
stimulated the mosquito's growth
far beyond its normal size.
Latimer, you're a very good vet
and a very pretty lady.
But a mosquito capable
of that kind of destruction
would have to be
as big as a house.
- Excuse me, Lieutenant, sir.
- What is it, Corky?
We got an emergency
over at Fielding's Pond, sir.
Folks over there
are saying that big larva
are breeding in the water.
Yeah, well, we got people
breeding in the balcony!
...here sooner,
we could've gotten them all at the pond.
We got all but one?
Yes, ma'am,
but that's the mother.
If I'm right
and she comes back here,
then maybe we--
we've got a chance.
Say, Doc...
Boo!
Ow.
Mark! Damn it, you scared me.
- Are you okay?
- Mm.
Well, if I was a 10-ton mosquito,
I wouldn't waste all my time
sucking through all them sheep.
No, sir.
I'd head straight for the blood bank.
Okay, Corky, go keep a lookout.
If you see anything coming,
holler loud and clear.
You got it, sir.
So, uh, tell me,
is there a, uh, Mr. Latimer?
Not yet.
Is there a Mrs. Bradley?
Yeah.
She lives in Kansas.
Bakes apple pie.
- I call her Mom.
- Whoo!
Hey, no tongues!
No tongues!
Careful, Jim.
The female mosquito
is the dangerous one.
Just thought I should let you know
what you're in for.
Thanks for the warning.
Mayday, Mayday!
Come on, bugs.
I saw the thing up in the sky!
It's bigger than ever
and it's headed right this way.
Holy cow,
get Washington on the phone pronto.
It's picked up the scent
of the plasma.
Its proboscis is aimed right at us!
Send the Air Force,
Mr. President.
Don't forget the Army, Navy,
and the Coast Guard.
How about the police dogs
while you're at it?
We need every plane, tank,
and battleship
you've got, Mr. President.
This is one hell of a bug.
Thank you, sir.
God bless you, too.
I'm scared, Lieutenant.
Yea, though I walk through
the valley of the shadow of death...
I will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever.
- Jim, it's leaving!
- Amen!
Yahoo!
Nothing fazes it.
We'll have to drop the A-bomb.
No, Jim, that's what started
all this trouble in the first place.
Five, four, three,
- two, one.
- Everybody, under the desk!
Whoo!
Five, four, three...
Bye-bye!
Go, baby, go, go!
What the?
It's dead.
Wow, incinerated beyond belief!
- Thanks, guys.
- You're welcome, Corky!
We're safe this time, Jim.
There may be a next time.
And a next.
Do you know
how many species of insects
there are in this world?
Mankind must learn
to be ever watchful.
I know one thing, baby.
From now on,
I'm gonna be watching you.
Amen.
So, let me get this straight,
this guy Gates,
like, come back from the dead
to show some flick he made and, like,
walked up to the movie theater
and bought a ticket like that?
Am I getting this right
or am I just delirious?
I didn't say
that he came back from the dead.
Right, right, but, well,
this Sarah thing-- run that by me again.
He called me Sarah.
Maybe he thinks I'm his daughter.
Oh. Oh, so Gates
has a daughter named Sarah?
- Yes!
- And we know this how?
I don't know, Mark,
but I kn-- ugh.
You're pissing me off.
Well, enjoy your little joke?
- What?
- Locking me out of the theater.
I had to climb down the fire escape
and into the side yard.
I fell in a trash bin.
I twisted my ankle while climbing
the barbed wire fence,
outrunning
a very pissed off Doberman.
And now if you'll excuse me,
I have to change reels.
Toby, I didn't do anything,
I swear it.
- Oh, yeah? Well, who did, then, huh?
- Don't look at me.
- Maybe it was him.
- Who?
- You-- you mean Gates?
- It could be!
Oh, so Gates came back from the dead
to lock Toby out of the theater.
Oh, yeah.
That's real cute, Mark.
Come on, Maggie.
I'm only fooling around.
Great, why don't you fool around
with Joy, then?
Get out of here.
- How many?
- Just one.
- Hi.
- Did you have a nice break?
- I'm really sorry. Thanks.
- Yeah. Later.
- Great, there you go.
- Thanks.
Two popcorns, please.
What's up, player?
Don't ask.
The prisoner will stand.
There being no legal cause
why a sentence
should not be pronounced...
Your Honor,
the defense would like the court
to consider the fact...
Joy, what's the story?
Hey, I tried to save it for you,
but you were gone for so long.
- ...the court would be lenient.
- Hey, man, you're in my seat.
It is the judgment
and sentence of this court...
Eat shit, asshole.
...that for the crime
of murder in the first degree...
You wanna repeat that, pal?
Huh?
I said eat shit, asshole.
And may God have mercy
on your soul.
Whoo-hoo!
Ooh, nice shot, dude.
Oh.
Isn't Mr. Davis here?
He's backstage.
Will you tell him I need him?
What for?
Every one of these buttons here
represents a wired seat down there.
They're supposed to go off
in automatic sequence,
only I don't know
how to set the timer.
So in the meanwhile, I'm gonna
have to zap everybody manually.
That's fascinating, Bud.
I'll tell him.
- Tell me...
- Tell him, then.
...what do you know
about erythrocytes and leukocytes?
Say, aren't those the red and white
corpuscles in the blood?
Very good, Vernon.
I have created a third corpuscle--
the "magnecyte."
Theoretically, it can regenerate
the blood cells
even after severe trauma,
any trauma.
Even electrocution.
I get it.
You want to inject me
with this corpuscle
to see if I can survive the chair,
is that it?
Exactly.
There's this mystery in her own life
that she hasn't solved yet,
which--
Sarah, wake up.
Your life has been a dream.
You are possessed.
Mark!
Sorry!
- What are you doing here?
- I just came to talk to you.
Hey, listen, you remember
that guy Gates?
I can prove that he was here.
When we were gone,
he came into the box office
and he left a message
on my recorder.
Listen. Shit!
Shit, I must've smashed it
into the door.
Tina was here.
I bet she saw him.
Cheryl, did you see
where Tina went?
- Check with Bud. He might know.
- Great.
It's time, Vernon.
I'm ready, Warden.
So long, Vernon.
Adios, Big Gil.
Warm it up for me,
Vernon.
Anytime, Maxie.
Hey, Vernon,
whatever they tell you, don't sit down!
I'll keep that in mind, Otis.
Vernon, when you get to heaven,
will you tell my ma
I said hello?
I ain't going to heaven,
Bobby.
But I'll sure be glad
to say hello to your daddy.
Mr. Davis?
Hey, that mosquito gag
was great.
Hey, Bud, where's Tina?
Jesus, you almost made me
zap the third row.
Cheryl said
she was up here with you.
Well, she's looking for Davis.
Check backstage.
Hey, you'll need this.
Thanks.
Sauté the sucker!
Fry him!
- Fry him!
- Make mine medium rare!
Fry him! Fry him!
All right, kids,
here comes Dr. Zap.
Any last words?
See you later.
And away we go.
Bingo!
Boop!
Attention,
hemorrhoid sufferers...
You, sir, have just received
the Ted Bundy award.
Yes!
Ah, this is fun.
I like doing this.
Boo!
Bud needs you.
And by the way, so do I.
Your lip, it's peeling.
Nerves.
How about a quickie
right here
with just that little screen between us
and public exposure?
Everybody always wonders
how I get those straight As.
I keep telling them
I do lots of extra credit assignments.
My God,
he's still breathing.
Mm!
What can we do?
Get Washington on the line.
Pronto.
I don't see him.
Shoot.
I see you.
Wow, Maggie.
Maggie, check this out.
Tina, you scared me.
Are you okay?
Mm-hmm.
Shh.
Audience.
Right, um,
what are you doing up here?
Securing the mosquito.
Hey, listen,
did you see anybody
come into the box office
after I left?
Mr. Davis.
Where'd he go?
He just left.
Damn it.
Well, maybe
I could still catch him.
Tina should start eating better.
She looks like shit.
Bye.
- How's the movie?
- Too scary for me.
I need some popcorn
to calm me down.
Thank God it's not fattening.
And a Milky Way, too, please.
- Joannie!
- Cheryl!
I am not having any butter
on my popcorn
and you can get me a diet Pepsi
so it all balances out in the end.
Yeah, that's exactly where
it's gonna balance out-- in your end.
He must be able
to change his appearances.
- Who? What?
- Mark!
Now we're gonna have to walk
- all the way around the building.
- Shit.
Yeah, who did you say
could change his appearances?
Gates.
I saw him buy a ticket.
But Tina just said it was Davis
who came into the box office.
Now, she wouldn't have let Gates in
unless she thought he was somebody else,
somebody that she knew.
So, obviously,
he must disguise himself.
Oh, no, wait, no disguise
looks that real that close up.
Maybe.
Wait a minute.
Hmm, this is Davis's car.
That's his briefcase.
He must still be inside.
Maggie, who are we looking for,
Davis or Gates?
If Gates is walking around
disguised as Davis,
that probably means
there isn't a Davis.
- I'm gonna go find--
- Wait, wait, hold it, hold it,
let's just cut to the lot
like Toby did, remember?
- What do you mean? There's a fence.
- So we'll climb it.
- But there's a barbed wire fence.
- Maggie, we'll fly over it, all right?
Will you just trust me?
Wait, Mark, Toby said
he got attacked by a guard dog.
Babe, any guard dog
that Toby can handle,
Mark can handle, too, okay?
Come on.
Hey, Tina,
have you found Davis yet?
Oh, yes.
Hey! What the--
Hey!
This is cute, Tina,
but I have a cue in five minutes.
Oh, okay.
Very kinky.
What do you-- oh!
What's going on here?
Tina! Mm!
Mm!
Stop right there, man.
Hey, Bobby,
get a load
of this crazy cat.
Yeah, bird brain.
We're addressing you.
Whoo!
Well, Bud,
you'll get a charge out of this.
Watch the panel.
The lights will go on
in the following order--
red, blue, green.
Or is that green, blue--
oh, I forget.
But the important light
is that yellow one.
When it turns on, Bud,
so do you.
All right, big guy.
Come to papa.
Hey, he's got Ritchie!
Let go of Ritchie, man!
Richie!
Oh, my God, what happened to him?
He fell off this fence
and there was this Doberman.
Yeah, forget about that,
all right?
No big deal.
Whoa, this is a job
for Nurse Joannie.
- Hey, I'm fine.
- Bend over.
He's coming this way.
Kiss me, Dick.
Kiss your what?
- All done.
- Have you guys seen Davis?
No.
Let's go talk to Bud.
Give me a hand.
- Watch the candy counter.
- I love it.
No, Vernon.
Have you heard, Peggy?
I'm high voltage these days.
Always been high voltage
to me, Vernon.
Pucker up, baby!
Well, well.
- What do we have here?
- Burn him dead!
Burn the guy dead!
It's great!
They're eating it up in there!
I know, I cannot believe
the stunts actually worked.
- And now that we are alone.
- Um, sure.
Come on!
Come on, darling, run!
Be happy, Dick,
and remember me.
But--
What the hell's going on?
This is not scheduled.
Wow.
Leon, this is weird.
Was all this
supposed to happen?
No, I don't think so.
Okay, okay, we've gotta turn the lights
back on.
What?
I don't know from lights.
- That's Toby's department.
- This is a blackout.
There are a thousand people
inside there, Leon.
They'll riot.
The band!
- Good idea.
- Where are they?
- The green room. Okay.
- Let's go.
- Now, what the hell was that?
- I don't know.
Don't let go.
You might fall down the st--
Shit.
Shit!
I'll get him. Mark!
Talk to me.
- Are you okay?
- Fine, fine!
Just don't step on my hand!
Oh, jeez.
I'm gonna go talk to Bud.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we hope to be off auxiliary power soon
and get back to the movie.
Meanwhile,
let's bring out the band!
♪ There's trouble ♪
♪ My heart is heavy ♪
♪ With sadness ♪
♪ Massah told me
you're going away ♪
♪ To chant revival
in a cozy church ♪
♪ On Pocomania Day... ♪
Bud?
Bud.
Sarah.
- Oh, my God.
- What, no kiss for daddy?
- Who are you?
- Oh, that hurts.
There's so great a wound
as an ungrateful child.
I'm not Sarah.
I'm not your daughter.
I'm not your child.
Oh, yes.
Think.
An altar, a sword,
Mommy dearest.
The fire,
a gunshot.
And now it's time
to join your mother.
No!
Sarah.
Sarah!
Oh! Hey!
Hey, hey!
Maggie, what's the matter?
Oh, my God.
Gates just tried to kill me.
He killed Bud
and maybe Tina and Davis, too.
Toby,
he's my father.
I remember.
I remember the whole thing.
Wait, Maggie.
Shit.
My, my, my.
And what could you two be doing
all alone in the dark?
Come on,
let's get out of here.
♪ So then come,
come and turn your roller ♪
♪ Hot, we hot,
yes, we cold in the water ♪
♪ Come on this
and mice of the sea ♪
♪ Then taka-taka
on your tambourine ♪
♪ Beat the drum pass,
word to your mi ♪
♪ One more thing
I want to let you know ♪
♪ There's a meeting here tonight... ♪
Toby,
it's not a screenplay
that I've been writing.
It's my life.
My unconscious
has been trying to make me
relive my past
so that I would remember it.
I'm Sarah Gates.
I'm not Maggie Butler.
Suzanne's not my mother,
she's my aunt.
My mother's name
was Gloria.
My father killed her
the night that he showed "Possessor."
He tried to kill me, too,
but Suzanne stopped it.
She shot him
and she saved me
and I don't know,
somehow we got away.
She changed our names
and our identities
to protect me.
From Gates?
Well, his body
was never found,
so nobody could ever prove
that he was dead.
She never knew
when he'd come back.
Now he's here.
Why, Maggie?
To finish the film.
And to kill me.
God, Toby.
My brain is just,
like, reeling.
Hey.
Hey, I'm here for you, Maggie,
all the way.
Come on.
Let's get
the lights turned on, huh?
We gotta call the police.
Okay,
but let's do this first, huh?
Well, down the rabbit hole.
- The rabbit hole?
- And into Wonderland.
That's a little humor there.
It's the only way
to get to the circuit breakers.
- Whoa!
- Toby!
Are you all right?
Toby!
Toby, where are you?
Toby?
Mr. Davis!
Mr. Davis?
Toby?
- Sarah.
- Tina?
Tina, is-- is that you?
Tina!
Sarah.
Oh!
Stop!
Stop. Please.
Stop, please!
Welcome home.
♪ On Pocomania Day ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
Okay, we got our lights back on.
Let's get on with the show!
Whoo!
Who are you?
I'm Toby.
Or-- or nearly Toby.
You'll have to forgive the...
sloppy craftsmanship.
Actually,
it takes hours every morning
to prepare the perfect Toby
for the world to see.
In truth, I've perfected
the quick transition
from face to face.
Of course,
I have to borrow their faces to do it.
You might say
I'm "multidentical."
Now, with a little nip here
and a little tuck there
I become "multisexual."
Nothing new about that, huh?
And as you've heard with the help
of electronic voice harmonics,
I become Tina,
the class bimbo.
I can look like
anybody I want to.
It's one of the few advantages
of not having a face.
- Then you're not...
- Your father?
No.
Lanyard Gates is dead.
Died in the fire
15 years ago.
If you're Toby,
why are you...
Why am I going to kill you?
Is that your question?
- Why are you doing this?
- Oh!
Good question.
Same answer, actually.
See,
I was caught
in that fire, too.
My mother
was in Lanyard's so-called film cult.
We were sitting
in the front row
when your Aunt Suzanne
shot Lanyard
and set fire to the theater.
You, luckily, got out.
We, unluckily,
did not.
My mother died.
I lost most of the flesh
on my body.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, are you?
Well, that makes it
all right, then!
Here, I'll just let you go.
You're sorry?
Look at me!
This is your work!
Don't like it, huh?
You don't have to look!
Don't look!
Don't look at me!
I was a child, too, Toby!
You were a child?
Good.
I was a child.
We were all children.
Nobody was a child like me.
Nobody.
Shall I describe the--
the years of surgery
I went through, huh?
The skin grafts,
the prosthetic pieces.
I had to glue on my face
all through school
every day of my life
so the other kids
wouldn't scream.
Nobody saw me coming, huh?
Here, I'll show you
how it works.
Now, the first thing we do
is we cover up
these fried egg eyes
with contact lenses.
Lovely.
Toby.
Ah.
Now a new nose.
There.
- Please stop.
- Then we prepare a face
to meet the faces
that we meet.
A lovely chin.
Yeah.
It's my Scarecrow in Oz face.
Cute, huh?
You're crazy.
What,
this just dawned on you?
That's great.
And I'm the one who's crazy.
Can't say I've lost
my sense of humor, can you?
Toby.
What are you gonna do?
Mm, here's my plan.
I've thought it out
with geometric logic.
I'm going to recreate
that showing of "Possessor"
only this time,
it's going exactly as planned.
And maybe that way,
things will be different.
Maybe,
then my mother won't die...
and I won't be burned.
And everything will be okay.
That makes perfect sense.
Yeah, it does, doesn't it?
- Yuck!
- Oh, pee-yew, what is that?
Hmm, I don't know.
Could be swamp gas.
Well, it doesn't smell like
swamp gas to me.
Well, it's not me.
I'm not so sure.
Well, whatever it is,
it's getting worse.
Yuck.
Mark, if you keep this up,
you're gonna have to hire
your own private nurse before long.
There you are,
you son of a bitch!
Oh, no.
- I wanna go home now.
- Hi, Joy.
Look, I'm sorry,
but Maggie had some problems
and I had to help her out.
Maggie? What, are you
obsessed with this bitch or what?
God, I knew you didn't have any brains,
but I thought you had some taste.
Why don't you just cool out?
Why don't you just
shut your little mouth, you little slut?
And as far as Maggie goes,
I saw her leave here
with that little film nerd.
- What's his name?
- Toby?
Yeah, that's right, Toby.
I caught them in the dark
and they were going at it.
They were hot and heavy.
And you wouldn't believe it,
they're on their way to his house.
You're full of shit.
Hey, asshole!
Oh, no.
Uh-oh.
- You got a problem?
I said you got a problem?
- No, do you?
- He hit me. Kick his ass!
- Kick his ass!
- Uh-uh, wait, wait, wait,
wait a minute,
this boy's been getting beat up all day.
- You want him, you gotta go through me.
- I don't hit chicks. Now back off!
You don't hit chicks?
You swear to God?
I ain't never hit a chick
in my life.
That's all I wanted to know.
Rad!
- I could've done that.
- You bitch!
- Oh, my hair!
- Punk-ass blonde bitch!
- Get your sorry ass out of here.
- You're messing with my hair!
- It's not your hair anyway!
- I'm gonna bust your butt, bad boy.
God damn it!
- I got you, wimp! You ain't shit!
- Oh! He's going for the side door!
I can't believe
she went to Toby's house.
Toby and Maggie,
are you crazy?
- You believe that dumb bitch?
- You guys know where Toby lives?
48 Crescent Road, apartment 7-3
about five blocks away.
Believe it.
She's the world's authority
on Toby D'Amato.
- Use the side door.
- Right.
Oh, my God, my stench cue!
I'm late.
Almost time.
Lanyard Gates
began "Possessor" at midnight.
and we will follow
in his footsteps.
Wait, I forgot
the other member
of the original cast.
- Ta-da!
- Mom?
Sarah, Mom.
Mom, Sarah.
Maggie, forgive me.
Hey, sure, why not?
All she did was murder your father,
destroy his life's work,
and then lie to you
your whole life.
Sure, say a couple of Hail Marys
and forget the whole thing.
Maggie, he was giving you acid.
I had to get you out.
Liar, liar,
face on fire, face on fire!
Toby, don't do this, please!
- Toby!
- Lanyard Gates was crazy!
I am rubber, you're glue.
Everything that you're saying
bounces off me and sticks on you!
- Toby, no!
- Sticks on you!
Sticks on you,
sticks on you, sticks on you.
Oh.
Half an hour to midnight.
I still have
a little time to kill.
Hmm.
Where the hell
have you been?
- Get the odor pellets.
- Okay. Which one goes first?
- I forgot.
- Body odor.
- That's disgusting.
- No, it's not B.O.
It's body odor
as in the odor of a dead body.
Oh, much better.
Anyway, I wanna get back
to what I was saying.
Yeah, just hold that thought, okay?
I gotta take a leak first.
- We've got a cue coming up.
- We got five minutes.
Hey! Hey!
Let me out!
This isn't funny!
Oh, shit!
No! Please, no!
Took you long enough.
- I had some gas.
- Spare me the details.
Anyway,
what do you think?
- About what?
- Toby.
Does he like me?
Like you?
What's wrong with your voice?
You sound so weird.
- I got a frog in my throat.
- Sounds like a crocodile.
Anyway, I need to know.
I mean, I'm walking around
madly in love with this guy
and he just acts like
I don't even exist.
You're impartial.
What's your opinion?
Is he shy or what?
Look, I've got my own problems.
Just leave me alone, all right?
Men.
Admit it,
you fucked up.
Don't you-- I got--
I got problems of my own here!
Don't you--
don't you talk about love to me!
We're gonna make a movie here!
Come on, baby.
Wait, it's getting stronger.
Ooh, my nose is burning!
Well, I don't know
what you're doing,
but I'm getting out of here.
Good idea.
Let's head for camp.
My lungs are burning!
Hey, my legs won't move!
I can't see!
Just a normal life
filled with normal happiness.
Hmm, normal sadness.
Normal family stuff.
Normal kids of my own.
Do you know
how amazing normal stuff seems
when there's no chance
you'll ever have it for yourself?
And whose fault
was that, huh?
Whose fault was that,
nasty Suzanne?
Nasty Suzanne
and her nasty gun.
Bang, bang
went nasty Suzanne.
went her nasty gun.
Well-- well, not this time,
Ms. Pretty Skin.
Go ahead.
Go ahead, try it, huh?
No, huh? No.
I am so glad
I cast you in this part.
If you don't stop it soon,
there's no telling
what might happen.
Hmm, I fear you are right...
Better get Tokyo
on the line, pronto.
Who the hell are you?
I'm a friend of Toby's.
Is he here?
If he was here, he'd be dead.
Look at this place.
You say
you're a friend of his?
I ought to kill you.
Maybe that'd make me feel
a little better.
What did he do?
What the hell did he do?
Jesus Christ,
what the hell didn't he do?
The guy's
a goddamn lunatic.
Should've thrown his ass out
six months ago.
Yelling and screaming
all night long
at the top of his lungs.
Never let anybody in the place.
Oh, I only wonder why.
- Look at all this shit.
- What?
The goddamn smell.
I mean, it's just--
- Oh, my God.
- it was like some chemical smell.
I had to break
the goddamn door down to get in here
- because the tub overflowed...
- Oh, no.
...and it flooded
the apartment downstairs.
You know--
you know what he's got in that tub?
He's got-- he's got things
that look like human skulls
and-- and body parts.
Probably some-- some kind of
Jack the Ripper or something.
Ah, son of a bitch.
What are you doing?
Just say yes.
Toby!
Anyway, that's what
I gotta say about him.
Yeah, look at that.
The guy can't paint either.
Isn't that
a real piece of crap there?
Hey! That's Gloria Gates!
I did a picture with her.
You're a director?
Hey, listen,
you're a director?
I-I'm an actor.
You wanna take a picture or résumé?
Well, how about we do lunch?
It came from outer space.
We know that now.
We must be ever vigilant and never rest.
Keep our eyes on the heavens
or the stench will--
♪ Let's all go to the lobby ♪
♪ And have ourselves a treat... ♪
...into the shelter.
This place can only be avoided
if we can get to the--
- Come on!
- Boo!
I am the possessor.
- Who put this junk on?
- Where's Toby? Do something!
- Do what?
- The projection booth!
Yeah, it stinks,
doesn't it?
Ooh, I hate this movie.
Yeah, thumbs down
on this movie.
Ooh, I hate this movie.
Hate this movie! Ugh!
- Get this movie off the screen!
- Hey, fix your makeup, dude.
Yeah, yours is a bitch, too.
Get it on!
Get on with this movie!
Okay.
Okay, this should stop it.
- It's not stopping.
- Cheryl, make it stop!
What do you want me to do,
stick my hand in it? Stop!
Sweet, dreamy Sarah.
You've stolen my heart.
Oh, what have we here?
Oh, I hope I got your size.
And you thought Iron Maiden
was a heavy metal band.
I am so glad that you have finally
remembered everything
because, you know,
with-- without memory,
there can be no retribution.
Open up!
Shit.
Ah.
- Lovely.
- No.
Now, are we finally ready?
Can we shoot this thing?
Lights.
- Camera.
- Toby.
- Action.
- No.
No, Toby.
Help me, please!
Please help!
He's gonna kill me. This isn't a joke!
- Help me! He's not kidding.
- Yes, yes, yes.
- I was gonna kill the wench.
- Please, this is real!
- But not, dear friends...
- This isn't a joke! Please!
- without the approval...
- This isn't a joke!
...and the approbation of you,
my audience.
- My heart, my soul...
- No!
my sustenance.
So, so, shall we kill her?
Or, or shall we spare
this maiden?
- Toby, please stop!
- Show mercy
- to the tender virgin?
- Please, Toby, no!
No!
- No? No?
- No! He's going to kill me!
Yes! Yes!
All right, then.
Then the fatal stroke
shall fall
exactly at the stroke of midnight.
Shall we count it down together?
Thirty seconds to go.
Are you ready?
All right! Thirty,
29, 28,
- 27, 26,
- No!
25, 24, 23,
- 22, 21, 20,
- Don't!
- Maggie!
- 19, 18,
- 17, 16,
- Mark!
15, 14, 13,
12, 11, 10,
nine, eight, seven,
- six, five, four,
- Ah!
three, two, one!
No! No, you're ruining it!
You'll ruin it!
No! No!
You're ruining it! No!
...and that's all I know.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'll see you
in a little while, okay?
Okay.
I was a pretty lame hero,
I guess.
No, you were great.
God, you looked just like Indiana Jones
coming down that wire.
More like
George of the Jungle.
Did you hear me?
Another movie.
Everything is a movie to me.
Yeah, well, let's--
let's make the next one a comedy, okay?
Would you hold me?
♪ Scary, scary movies
on the silver screen ♪
♪ Make me shake, make me sweat,
you know the kind I mean ♪
♪ Scorched hairs, nightmares,
the innocent possessed ♪
♪ Raging fires, vampires ♪
♪ Creepy crawly, bug-infested eyeballs
from outer space ♪
♪ Corpses come to life ♪
♪ Schizophrenic maniac
attacking with a bloody knife ♪
♪ Inside his creepy coat he's got
a blade that's two feet long ♪
♪ Pierces through his lovely wife,
he bids the bitch, "So long"... ♪
I love it.
♪ Scary, scary movies
on the silver screen ♪
♪ Aliens and maniacs,
tarantulas and brainiacs ♪
♪ You know the kind I mean... ♪
I still have a little time to kill.
♪ Dudes with buzzing chainsaws,
massacred the place ♪
♪ Sleepwalking on a coffin,
corpse's bloody face ♪
♪ Bloodsucking insects
hanging from a rope ♪
♪ Gotta read a ten
on the Shock-O-Scope ♪
- ♪ Ah, bad ♪
- ♪ We're talkin' bad ♪
♪ We're talkin' rad ♪
♪ We're takin' mad, mad scientists,
Frankenstein's brains ♪
♪ Schizophrenic general
and his paranoid plan ♪
♪ Zombies throwing masquerades
make me scream and yell ♪
♪ Monsters big as houses,
demon lords from hell... ♪
Die.
♪ Scary, scary movies
on the silver screen ♪
♪ Aliens and maniacs,
tarantulas and brainiacs ♪
♪ You know the kind I mean ♪
♪ No fakin',
I'm shakin' ♪
♪ 12:00 midnight
on the shock clock ♪
♪ Wanna scream so bad,
but I can't even talk ♪
♪ Head is spinning faster,
Pounding hearts aflutter ♪
♪ So damn scared
I'm s-starting to s-s-s-stutter ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Scary, scary movies
on the silver screen ♪
♪ Make me shake, make me sweat,
you know the kind I mean ♪
♪ Heart screams, all the dreams,
sharp fear of dread ♪
♪ Zombie on the left,
stuck behind my bed ♪
♪ Scary scary movies,
making me obsessed ♪
♪ Love those scary movies ♪
♪ Scary, scary movies,
man, they are just the best ♪
- ♪ Scary, scary movies ♪
- ♪ Huh! ♪
- ♪ Huh, huh, huh! ♪
- ♪ Scary, scary movies... ♪
- Whoo, yeah!
- ♪ Scary, scary movies ♪
- ♪ Shock-O-Scope ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
A human skull.
♪ Now you're talkin'... ♪
Probably some--
some kind of Jack the Ripper.
♪ But you can't come in... ♪
Get Washington on the phone, pronto.
Nerves.
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ This is scary... ♪
Warning-- do not open.
Ow!
♪ Pocomania Day ♪
♪ So then come,
come and turn your roller ♪
♪ Hot, we hot,
yes, we cold in the water ♪
♪ Come on this
and mice of the sea ♪
♪ Then taka-taka
on your tambourine ♪
♪ Beat the drum pass,
word to your mi ♪
♪ One more thing
I want to let you know ♪
♪ There's a meeting here tonight ♪
♪ So, come and dine, ah ♪
♪ Come and jump with me ♪
♪ And make me feel all right ♪
- ♪ So, think it over ♪
- ♪ Over before you go ♪
♪ Think it over before you walk away
and leave me here ♪
♪ To jump revival in a lonely way ♪
♪ On Pocomania Day ♪
♪ Think it over
before you go ♪
♪ Think it over before you walk away
and leave me here ♪
♪ To jump revival... ♪