Go on, do your prayers, Eddie. Go on.
God bless Mama and Daddy
and the farm. Amen.
- Mama.
- Mmm-hmm?
- What's wrong with Daddy tonight?
- Nothing, Eddie.
You mind me and you go
right to sleep, you hear?
Will it be all right?
Should I be afraid?
Tom Harley. Open up, Tom.
It's me, Clayton Heller. Tom.
Please open the door.
For God's sakes, Tom.
Open up, please!
It's after me, Tom.
It's gonna get me.
God in heaven, Tom.
We can't just sit here.
We have to, Ellie. This has
nothing to do with us.
What kind of a Christian
are you, for God's sakes?
- You got to help me, Harley!
- Tom.
- Mama.
- See to the boy.
Tom, it's gonna get me if
you don't open the door!
For God's sake, please help me! Tom.
Why doesn't Daddy let the man in?
- Please open the door!
- He can't, baby. He just can't.
Get away from my door.
- Get away from me and my family!
- Tom, please!
You got to help me, Tom.
It's coming. I didn't kill that girl.
I don't know nothing about that,
and I don't want to.
They said I did, Tom. But I didn't.
Now, I'm sorry. I am. But I can't
risk my family for you, Clayton.
Now, I got my shotgun here.
Get away. Get away
afore I have to use it.
Gypsy, ready? Ready?
Pick it up. Come here. Come on.
All right, ready? Go get it.
Come on.
Now, young man, come up here.
- I thank you. What've you been doing?
- Playing with Gypsy.
Mmm-hmm.
That's good.
You know something?
When I was your age,
your great-grandmama
used to wash my hands.
And she was so old that the skin on
her hands was thin as tissue paper.
It felt so good.
Guess what?
Last one in the house will get the
privilege of washing the breakfast dishes.
Get out of town.
Come on, Gypsy.
- Not at the table, Billy.
- But he's awful hungry, Daddy.
Put it in the bowl.
- Is it story time?
- I reckon.
Wait. I got to get something.
- Daddy?
- Hold on.
- I made you a present.
- You did?
I like presents.
Oh, well. Now, this is something.
It goes around your neck.
This is something special.
- You really like it?
- I love it.
You don't have to wear it every day
or nothing. Just when it strikes you.
Give me a hug. I ain't
never taking it off, punk.
All right, now, wait a minute.
Once upon a time,
there was this scruffy old man,
and you know, he was one of
them yes-and-no kind of guys.
So anyhow, he was very proud
'cause he had this very clever son,
and he knew that one day,
this son was gonna grow up
to be something very special.
So, and one day...
Really, Tracy. You know, Joel is a
great guy once you get to know him.
Honey, get me a beer.
So how much further is
it to the cabin, Steve?
About 50 miles.
Why do you always have to
carry that stupid rifle with you?
'Cause you never know what you're
gonna find in the jungle, yo.
- Sorry.
- Thank you, klutz.
Okay, come on.
- Let her rip.
- Now?
Get the potatoes, kid.
Sweet potatoes.
Come on, get it over there.
- Wait, Steve, pull over.
- What?
- I want to take a picture of this.
- These people can get pretty weird, Trace.
We heard a story a couple years
ago about a guy who killed his wife
and ate her just to get
rid of the evidence.
- Yeah.
- That's disgusting.
No, the cops found, like,
her foot or something in this big pot
with all these carrots and onions.
It was like foot stew.
You know, I think this
was the guy, too.
This was the guy.
Get a few more of these. Here you go.
Get a few more of them, boy.
All right, here we are.
- Where?
- Downtown Bradley Mountain.
Cabin's the next stop.
Just a few miles from here.
- Kimbo.
- Yeah?
Help me out.
This is your last chance to shop, lady.
Breathe deep. The air is clean.
- You guys are animals.
- Civilization is behind us.
No, Gypsy!
- Hook shot.
- No, Gypsy.
- Whoa! Nice dog.
- No.
Gypsy!
Made a friend there
already, huh, Joel?
Gypsy, no.
Check out this kid's glasses.
We're talking Coke bottles.
Jesus.
- What? All I said was...
- We heard you, man.
Come on, Scratch. Let's do it.
- What's your name?
- Billy. This is my dog Gypsy.
Hey, Gypsy. How're you doing?
Hey, Gypsy.
Come on. I thought we were gonna
get everyone settled in first.
Listen. If you want to stay here and play
with the vegetables, that's fine with me.
I'm going.
Fetch, boy. Go get it.
- Come on, Gypsy. Come on. Come on.
- Yeah. Good dog. That a boy, Gypsy.
Come on.
Come on, Joe.
- Come on, Jimmy Joe.
- Shut up.
- You shut up.
- Stop it.
You young ones just
stay put now, you hear?
Yes, sir.
- What's that?
- It's a camera, stupid.
Yeah, it's my camera. See?
Hey, can I take your picture?
There you go.
Good afternoon, Mr. Wallace.
What do you know today?
No more than I did yesterday.
Honey. Honey.
- Do you have any beer, sir?
- No. No liquor.
- Hessie, look.
- What?
Jimmy Joe, you give that here.
Jimmy Joe gots the ball
and won't give it up.
Give it here. Give it.
Come on. Give it.
Jimmy Joe, you done bad.
Y'all know what settles
on bad ones, don't you?
- Pumpkinhead.
Y'all stop.
There ain't no Pumpkinhead.
- What about old Mr. Foley?
- He moved away.
Uh-uh.
Pumpkinhead got him.
Teared off his head
and drank all the blood.
- Did not.
- Did too.
Shut up, Hessie!
"Keep away from Pumpkinhead
Unless you're tired of living
"His enemies are mostly dead
He's mean and unforgiving"
Stop it!
- Stop it!
- "Bolted doors and windows barred
- "Guard dogs prowling in the yard"
- Pumpkinhead. Pumpkinhead.
"Won't protect you till you're dead
"Nothing will, from Pumpkinhead
So keep away from Pumpkinhead"
- Stop it!
I mean, well,
you've got him pretty scared.
- Pumpkinhead.
- All right.
Get in the truck. Come on.
Hey.
Come on.
Here you go, Billy.
I was just about to
say something myself.
- That'll do it for you, Mr. Wallace?
- That and my feed.
Damn, I left it up at the house.
Give me a couple of minutes. Will you?
I ain't got it. I'm due back now.
Suppose I drop it off right at
your door? How'd that be?
Be there before dark.
Billy, bring Gypsy inside
out of the sun for a while.
Yes, Daddy.
- Got to admit, he's pretty good.
- He's a jerk.
Yeah, but he's a talented jerk.
Nah.
He's just a jerk jerk.
Billy, I want you to stay right
here and mind things, okay?
I got to fetch something
up at the house.
- Yes, sir, Daddy.
- Then we'll take us a little ride.
Do you have to encourage him?
Maggie, he's my brother.
Be a good boy, now.
- You man enough?
- Go for it!
Gypsy, no.
Little boy?
- Are you okay?
- Little boy?
What?
Gypsy!
No!
Jesus.
- Don't move him.
- He just came out of nowhere.
- Is he all right?
- He's cold.
It's gonna be okay, Billy.
All right, keep him warm.
Keep him warm.
- It's gonna be okay, little boy.
- Oh, God.
- Hey! Stay here.
- We got to do something.
You're gonna be fine.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
We stay, I'm fucked, man.
Is that what you want?
It was an accident.
I almost hit him myself.
Yeah, but I've been drinking.
They'll fry me.
You got to help me, Scratch.
- Call an ambulance.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hurry!
- What are you doing? What are you doing?
- Get in the car.
- Get in the car. Get in the fucking car.
- No, we can't just leave him.
Damn it.
Joel, get back here!
Where the fuck is he going?
- Forget Joel.
- Forget... Fuck.
It'll be fine.
Everything's gonna be okay.
- Come on.
- Chris, did you get through?
- No phone.
- What about that guy at the stand?
He's gone, he's gone, he's gone!
Oh, God. Get to the cabin.
There's a phone over there.
It's all right. Chris.
Take care of her...
- and I'll stay with the kid.
- Yeah.
Go help Chris with Maggie,
and I'll stay with the kid.
- Are you sure?
- I'll stay with him. Go! Go!
It's okay, Maggie. It's okay.
Go.
Billy?
Gypsy.
Billy.
Billy. Billy, Daddy's here.
It's okay.
Nobody saw him. It was
an accident. Can I help?
- Okay, Maggie, come on.
- Come on, Maggie.
Maggie, come on. Listen. Just get up
to the cabin and get on that phone.
I'm right behind you.
- I just stay on this trail?
- Yes, stay on the trail.
Did you call for help?
Jesus. This is crazy.
Damn you!
Jesus, he just ripped the
phone cord out of the wall.
What?
I'm going back. I'm gonna
drive to the nearest town.
You're not going anywhere.
- Hey!
What's up, man?
Chris, please.
Joel was in another accident a couple
of months ago and a girl was hurt.
He's on probation right now.
If the police find out about it,
- he could go to jail.
- They're not gonna find out about it.
Look, man, I'm real sorry about that,
but that little boy down
there needs our help now.
Joel,
just give me the keys, all right?
- You okay?
- Yeah. Go.
He wouldn't stop.
It's gonna be okay.
Once upon a time,
there was this old man,
and he had a very, very special son.
- Daddy.
- Yeah, baby?
- Hey, are you okay?
- Steve! Steve!
Hey, Steve, let us out, man!
We're in here!
Oh, man. I just don't believe this.
I'm not going to jail
for a fucking accident.
- Come on, Steve! Damn it!
- Come on!
Just look, the kid's father showed up.
He took the kid away.
Now, I think everything's
gonna be okay.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Did you tell him what happened?
- I told him it was an accident.
- And?
- And he just looked at me.
- What do you mean, he just looked at you?
- I don't know.
Don't lie to me!
He looked at me like
he wanted to kill me.
Looking for your pa.
- Hey! Bunt!
- Sir?
- Fetch your grandpa.
- Okay.
Grandpa, Pa wants you.
Mr. Harley's outside with the feed.
You go on out and unload
the feed. I'll be out directly.
- Here's what I owe you.
- Keep it if you can help me.
I'm looking for an old woman.
She lives somewhere in
the mountains hereabouts.
Some folkses say as
how she's got powers.
I never heared of no such woman.
Mr. Wallace. Please.
I can't tell you what I don't know.
- Bunt.
- Sir?
- Get over by the house.
- But you told me to do this first.
You do what I told you,
boy, and you do it now.
Okay.
- What killed him?
- City folks run him over.
- Left him.
- I'm sorry about your boy.
You got to tell me. She's the
only one that can help him.
- Like I said, I'm sorry.
- You got to tell me, God damn it!
She can't help him. All she can
do is take you straight to hell.
Now, you go on home. You go
home and you bury your boy.
Hold it!
Mr. Harley, I heard you
talking to my grandpa.
I know who you're looking for.
- What's your trade?
- What?
Her name's Haggis.
She's up on Black Ridge.
Get in back.
No way.
You got to show me. Get in back.
Okay, but I'm only going part way.
That old woman scares
the piss out of me.
Stop it! Stop the truck! Stop!
This is as far as I go.
You keep on straight.
Follow this road till
you can't no more.
You come to a cabin, that's her.
Who are you?
Ed Harley. I thought...
Afraid raising the dead
ain't within my power.
This is...
This is all I got.
This is everything.
Nothing I can do for him.
- When I was young...
- I said, there's nothing I can do.
- I saw it.
- What?
What do you want, Ed Harley?
Say it.
Say it! Say it!
When I was young,
folks used to talk about you.
Said as how you knew things.
Said if a man had been wronged,
he could come to you
and you'd called upon this
thing in that man's name,
and that man, he'd be avenged.
What you're asking
got a powerful price.
They killed my boy.
They run him over and they left him.
Ever hear of Razorback Hollow?
There's an old graveyard
way back deep in them woods.
Mountain folk used to bury kin
in there, kin they's ashamed of.
Bring a shovel.
The thing you're
looking for is in there.
Bring it back here.
Some things I got to do to it
before it'll be any use to you.
- That graveyard... How will I know...
- You'll know, Ed Harley.
You'll know.
Leave the boy.
God.
When we get out of here,
Joel's gonna be carrying his
balls home in a knapsack.
Remind me never to
piss you off, Tracy.
I'll tell them it was my fault,
that it was my bike that hit him.
The worst they're gonna give
me is a slap on the wrist.
No.
Look, I'm really starting
to worry about Maggie.
Bring it here.
- What is it?
- It's what you wanted, Ed Harley.
For each of man's evils,
a special demon exists.
You're looking at vengeance,
cruel, devious,
pure-as-venom vengeance.
Give me your hand.
You can go now, Ed Harley.
Now it begins.
What'd you do, Daddy?
Well, fuck it. Let's just kidnap
Chris and Tracy and go to Mexico.
Guys.
You got to do the right thing,
and you got to do it now.
They killed our boy, Lynn, honey.
Now they're gonna pay.
Maggie.
Here. Look.
Look, Maggie. Look at it.
You always found your
strength from this.
Well, find it now and come back.
I need you.
Steve. Steve.
Yeah.
It's okay. I'm sure the
boy's gonna be fine.
I'm sure his father's
taking care of everything.
Steve! No!
Help! Steve! No!
I'm always fucking up.
My whole life, one big fuck-up.
But it stops now.
- Help me! Help me!
- Maggie!
- Maggie, what happened?
- It's killing him!
Lock the door.
Steve!
If those scum hurt my brother,
I'll rip their fucking hearts out. Steve!
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee...
Maggie, whatever you saw
out there, it wasn't the devil.
It was!
- There is no such thing.
- There is! I saw it!
Oh, man, be okay, Steve. Be okay.
We're gonna find him, man.
They should be okay, right? I mean,
they took the gun and everything.
God is the only thing that can
stop what's out there, Kim.
Just in case God doesn't show.
Oh, God, Steve.
Cabin, man! Come on!
Jesus.
- Joel!
- You all right?
- There was something at the window.
- What about Steve?
We couldn't find him.
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know.
We've got to get
the hell out of here.
We're not going
anywhere without Steve.
- Maggie, we don't know what's out there.
- Steve is out there.
She's right. Now, come on.
We're gonna find him.
Maggie, wait!
- Here, help me!
- Maggie!
Tracy!
- Maggie! Maggie!
- God damn it! Tracy! Wait!
- Did you see something?
- I saw something. I don't know what...
- Just stay close, okay?
It'll pass, Ed Harley.
- Let it finish.
- No, you got to stop it.
It's what you wanted.
No! Not like this! Not like this!
I see it. This is wrong.
Nothing I can do.
It's got to run its course now.
What did you think? It'd be easy,
neat and clean and painless?
- You're a fool.
- If you won't help me...
If you don't help me,
then I'll do it myself.
I'll do it, I'll do it myself.
You'll fail, Ed Harley.
You'll fail and you'll die, too.
Then I'll die. Then I'll die!
And pay the final
price all the sooner.
God damn you. God damn you.
He already has, son.
He already has.
Maggie!
No! No!
I'm the one you want!
No!
- Oh, my God, Joel. What's wrong?
- It's got Kim.
- What's got her?
- It's a thing.
- What thing, man?
- It's a thing! I don't know! It's a thing!
- Kim! Kim! Kim!
- Come on, man. Come on, man.
Tracy, come on!
Kim! Kim!
- Joel!
- Oh, my God.
Kim!
- No.
- No!
No!
Joel, come on. We got to move, man.
Come on!
Help us!
- Hello?
- Why is this happening?
- I don't know!
- We got to move. Let's go.
- Help! Somebody help us!
- Help!
Help us!
Anybody in there, please?
There's something after us.
Please!
Where's Steve at?
Don't be mad.
- I'm cold.
- Come on.
Steve's dead.
Come on, man.
Come on.
Tracy.
Shit. It's locked.
Okay, just get back.
Empty your hands, son.
Get away from here.
- Go on. Get.
- Look, mister.
We got something chasing us.
We just want to use your truck, okay?
- Please.
- Get off my land.
Don't make me have to shoot you.
- Please. We just need your help.
- I can't help you.
You folks is marked.
Marked? What do you mean, marked?
Joel. Joel, no. No, Joel,
you don't know if it's dead!
It's dead.
Joel!
Come on.
- Come on.
- What is it?
I don't know! But whatever it is, it's
not gonna get us. Do you hear me?
It's not gonna get us! There must
be somebody that can help us!
Come on!
Bunt, get away from that window.
Grandpa, you sure that thing
ain't gonna hurt the animals?
It only kills what it was
called upon to kill.
Them, and whatever gets in its way.
Our animals will be fine.
You get away from that
window, and you get to bed.
Help! Help us!
Get to bed like I told you. Now.
For God's sake, please.
Help us! Come on, man! Let us in.
Damn.
- Bunt?
- Go back to sleep, Hessie.
- What you doing?
- Nothing.
Okay.
If I tell you, you got to promise
not to tell nobody. Not a soul.
- I won't.
- Cross your heart.
- Now swear.
- I swear.
Spit.
I'm gonna help those folks, Hessie. I got
to find out if it's real or just a story.
Grandpa will whip you
good if he finds out.
He ain't gonna find out.
Be careful.
Of course I'm gonna be careful.
Hey.
Shh.
Come on.
- It's you.
- Did you get a look at it?
- What's it look like? Is it big?
- Who are you?
- Man, what's going on?
- I'm trying to help you, for Christ's sake.
My name's Bunt. I live
in this house here.
How come nobody answered
the door? Didn't they hear us?
They can hear you.
They ain't allowed to help.
They ain't allowed to let you in.
They can't get involved.
- What do you mean, man?
- A man back there said we were marked.
We can't talk about this here. Come on.
I know a place that might be safe.
Come on.
I know where we can go.
Come on. Come on.
Ain't it neat?
About 40 years ago, they tried to
start a congregation up around here.
Didn't work out, I guess.
I figure it's a holy place,
so it might not like it here.
Come on.
Come on. Watch out.
Bunt. What do you know about
that thing that's after us?
It's some kind of demon.
Before tonight I didn't believe it.
I thought it was just something that
they made up to scare the little kids.
But when the sun went down, my grandpa
fetched the whole family together.
And he told us that some outsider
folks had done something real bad.
He wouldn't say what. He just said
that Pumpkinhead was
gonna be out after them,
and that we better stay
inside till he got them.
- Pumpkinhead?
- That's what it's called,
'cause it comes from the old
pumpkin patch graveyard.
- Well, do you know why it's after us?
- No, ma'am.
But you must have done something bad.
See, according to the legend, if one
man does something bad to another man,
it's got to be something real bad,
something like killing...
Then that other man can have Pumpkinhead
conjured up to take revenge.
The kid at the stand.
What? What?
There was an accident earlier.
One of our friends hit a
little boy with a motorcycle.
Where?
At the fruit stand a couple
of miles down the road.
Gosh almighty. Billy Harley.
You know? You heard about it?
I took his...
I saw his pa, Mr. Harley, this afternoon.
I took him somewhere.
- Well, was his son okay?
- I can't say for sure.
But if that thing's hunting you,
I suppose not.
Oh, my God.
- Your friends, where are they now?
- They're dead.
Do you know the spot
on Bradley Mountain
- where people park their cars?
- Yes.
- Can you take us there?
- Uh-huh.
I think it's here now.
Go!
Go! Move it!
Wallace! Wallace! Open up!
Wallace, open up! Wallace!
We got to stop it!
We got to stop it, or it's
going to kill them all.
Open up or I'll blow the
goddamn thing off the hinges.
Lose it, Harley.
You get away from here.
Get away from me and my kin.
This way.
Stay here.
- No.
- Stay here.
Chris!
Chris.
Come on. Please.
Come on.
Ma'am, you got to get up.
Come on. We got to go.
Please. We can't stop it. No one can.
Somebody can.
- Mr. Harley.
- Come with me.
Mr. Harley,
it's Pumpkinhead. It's real.
Now.
Come on.
Get in.
Get in the house.
Do you wanna live?
You Okay?
Yeah.
Thanks to you.
I'm gonna go outside
and talk to Mr. Harley.
I want you to stay here.
Mmm-hmm.
Mr. Harley?
Mr. Harley.
It was an accident.
He's dead.
Nobody saw him until it was too late.
Can't you stop this?
Can't you call it off?
Nothing can call it off.
But I'm gonna send it back to
whatever hell it come from.
You old dog.
Mr. Harley?
Mr. Harley, are you okay?
Chris.
Kill me.