My friends live in the monster's house.
My friends, who I love like my own life.
Friends who saved my life.
Also, at the monster's house,
the monster lives too.
Why is Tae Ha here? Just why?
Myeong, why are you here...
Let's go somewhere else. This
isn't the place to talk.
Don't you be mistaken,
I can't even sleep well
worrying that you'll harm me.
A kidnapper would do anything.
You say it's meaningless?
No If you're a human being
you can't say such things.
Because of your meaningless
deeds, I've been living in hell.
Do you know that?!
You should try knocking.
I knocked twice.
This reminds me of when you used my
makeup in secret and I found out.
You hid the lipstick behind
your back and denied it.
When did I do that?
You did when you were a kid, that's why there were
no secrets as you had it written on your face.
Why did come here at this late night?
To see Da Hae. I thought she was in here as
I heard her voice. I guess she isn't here.
What Da Hae's voice? Oh yea, while we
are talking, let me ask you something.
Ma'am, how much do you know about Da Hae?
Who should be asking who? You're
the one who brought her in.
I'm sorry I couldn't come
when you were released.
You must've had a reason, so it's okay.
Come out of Goong Rak Won. Everything happened
after the noodle master came to the orphanage.
You going to Masan, me seeing you there and even
today. Everything is connected to that place.
So stop now. It's dangerous for you.
My parents were killed
right in front of my eyes.
Being burnt to death at that.
Noodle Master, Hwa Jung Tae
is the one who did it.
I have the nightmare every time I close my
eyes. I haven't had a good nights rest ever.
The person who killed my parents are in front
of me, how can I pretend not to see him?
I've come to far. I can't stop now Tae Ha.
Right now, I'm doing what
I am supposed to do.
Did you see Yeo Gyeong?
No.
Go met her. Guilt won't
go away from avoidance.
It grows imaginably.
Also, I don't know why you came her,
but I would like it if you
don't come there anymore.
I'm leaving.
You can't handle that.
That person, he isn't someone
you can handle by yourself.
There are times to fight even if you know
you'll lose. This has become like this to me.
It's not just losing,
You could end up dead!
Thank you for the advice.
You've come.
This dough isn't done by one person.
You have to put the hot water over the buckwheat mix
and knead fast in order to avoid getting burned.
You are working very
hard even at this hour.
The more I get to know you the
more of a mystery you are to me.
Having a conversation with the
noodle master as a mere errand girl.
Going in and out of Madan Go's heart.
You are very interesting,
I don't why you're saying that, but
it's better than not being fun.
What is this?
Blueprint of Goong Rak Won.
There is a secret room inside the
noodle master's office. Get inside.
Are you sure?
It's half the size of the
noodle master's office.
There has to be another place.
Who knows? The reason you're
here might be in there?
Did I just get suspended?
Since we don't have assigned cases, suspension
seems right... without a dock in pay.
Who cares if we come to the Special
Investigative Team? There's nothing to do.
Detective Kim... as for Goong Rak Won...
Why don't you stop doing the work
that doesn't help our group?
If you continue to dig the suspended
case, you'll be the only one to suffer.
On top of that, you're part of the
Special Investigative Team, Prosecutor.
If you touch Criminal Investigative
Team case, you'll hear an earful.
I see a nail sticking out.
How can I just ignore it?
Whether we rip out the root,
smash it or do something.
That's right!
Rip out the crime and catch the criminals.
Prosecutor.
Prosecutor Chae, have you eaten?
I have.
Let's go eat noodles!
I said I just ate.
That's why, let's go eat noodles.
Prosecutor.
It's an order! Let's go eat
noodles, Prosecutor Chae.
Prosecutor Chae Yeo Gyeong.
It's nice to meet you.
I'm So Tae Seop.
You're curious why I called you, right?
More than that, this feels uncomfortable.
You look like him. Your eyes, nose,
and lips. You look just like him.
May I speak informally to you?
It's embarrassing speaking formally
to my younger brother's daughter.
Younger brother's daughter?
Professor Chae Il Hwan,
isn't he your father?
Do you know my father?
He was a lieutenant under me. He joined the army reserve and
became a professor at the Agency for Defense Development.
I went into politics.
You've grown up well. Your
father will be very proud.
Keep it.
It's better you carry that than me.
Let's have a bowl of rice soup together.
When I miss your father, I'll call you out.
Thank you.
You... Do you know Doggoo?
That guy... he's a thug.
He has his own business and helps
out with the foundation...
He seems quite busy.
If you dig, wouldn't some
interesting things come out of him?
I was ordered to stop investigating
into relevant matters.
Since it's a Criminal Investigation Team case, it's hard
for the Special Investigative Team to get involved.
Does it make sense to pick and choose precinct
and divisions in catching a criminal?
What do you think about that?
You were alive.
Since you didn't call, I
thought you forgot about me.
Did anyone follow you?
The Noodle Master? He
hasn't come by lately.
He had me for 3 years so
he's probably sick of me.
How long have I known you?
8 years.
I still don't trust you.
Why should you?
Noodle Master?
He's busy with Goong Rak Won these days.
I worry that he won't want to
get into politics this way.
Didn't I write you a scenario?
Just don't miss a word and just act your
part. Then everything will work out.
And I wasted three years.
There will be a talk show for
the next spring programming.
Over the air broadcasting.
Why? What's the matter?
About what?
You're being watchful of me right now.
Did you enjoy the rice soup?
What did he say?
That's right. That must be right!
Our prosecutor... she's still got it!
We met, I ate the rice soup.
He gave me some advices, so
I was all ears. Satisfied?
Do you know which line our
prosecutor is connected to?
Prosecutor General, Deputy Inspector... everyone climbed
the ladder holding onto Senator So Tae Seop's line.
- So? - For the new recruit
to eat with that person...
Autobahn... smooth road ahead...
Just... We just ate the
noodles, that's all.
Stop reading into it for no reason.
I don't think it was just that.
The materials that we asked
for but got ignored about.
Over a bowl of soup and rice...
everything came pouring in.
The Goong Foundations current
fund isn't so great.
Who cares if other people's money keeps coming
in? It's not like we can use any of it.
Goong Rak Foundation's money line is Goong
Rak Won. But since it's starving itself...
there's no way.
Wait a little bit more.
Once I get back the management
rights, I'll assist once again.
It will be hard to stand three months.
That's enough. It's already in the works.
So fascinating.
There's not even a safe. Where would
all that money be stored away?
Never mind yourself with it. You
do your work right, CEO Lee.
Wow... I work like an ox. I'm
disappointed if you say that.
My tears are coming out.
Bring in Park Tae Ha.
I've done this much...
If you can't bring him in, aren't
you the one with a problem?
Daebak Money, Loan
What the?
Hey...
It's unbelievable.
Did you guys promise to have
an orphanage reunion here?
What about Doggoo?-He...
Doggoo?!
Hey, do you know how many more bowls of rice he's had than you
(meaning older). Don't disrespectfully call him "Doggoo."
Who do you think Doggoo is!
You go there too?
I'm a VVip there! Haven't
you seen in dramas?
Tell him to come see me.
Look at the way he's talking.
Who are you to tell me to tell him that?
Hey, do I still look
like a pushover to you?
Don't be like this.
You'll never be my match until
the day you die, Cheol Doo.
It's Doo Cheol, I said!
Who the hell are you guys?! Huh?!!!
Senior Patrol Officer Kim...
I'm a sergeant now, Cheol Doo.
I'm from the Supreme Prosecutor's
Office, Special Investigative Team.
Fraud and breaking the moneylending law...
For the charges of forging official documents,
we'll conduct a search and seizure. Begin.
- Stop.- Hey.
You guys stay here.
We'll arraign you as reference witnesses.
Tae Ha?
Oh, my goodness...
Are you really Tae Ha?
Why are you here?
It's nothing to with me.
I will be leaving first.
Tae Ha.
[Prosecution]
[Prosecutor Chae Yeo Kyeong]
Sorry. You waited a long time, didn't you?
Do you want coffee?
No, I'm fine.
I called you here because
you were at the scene.
Not as Prosecutor Chae Yeo Gyeong, but
right now as your friend Yeo Gyeong.
You didn't change at all.
You look nice.
How... have you been?
Just here and there.
I'm living well using
what I learned in there.
Work is fun, and I think
I'm finding my place.
I want to save money and
purchase a heavy equipment.
I won't live in lap of luxury, but
I won't let my family suffer.
- Tae Ha.- Don't be sorry.
If you say that, the past six
years become meaningless.
Don't say "Thank you" either as it was
for myself, but not because of you.
Don't cry either.
I've grit my teeth and endured until now
Case number 1994-Gohap-5021..
Let's stop it.
I think I wasn't thinking well.
Investigating past incidents
won't change anything.
My father killed your parents.
And I was just paying that debt to you.
We're a tragedy that can't be avoided.
Let's stop here, Yeo Gyeong.
From now on, I am
Prosecutor Chae Yeo Kyeong.
I am not your friend anymore,
so listen to my words closely.
If someone orders someone else to kill
a person, that's abetting a murder.
Even if the statute of limitation has expired,
it can't be ignored as if it didn't happen.
Changes?
There is.
That person...
who made our lives like this. That person,
Even if we can't send him to jail, we
reveal to the world his real face.
I'm going to completely destroy him.
But if we stop now, your
six years and my six years
Everything will become meaningless.
That...
I will never meet him.
Yeo Gyeong.
Doggoo and Good Rak Won's Noodle Master Han Jung
Tae had something to do with that incident.
I'm going to investigate that side first.
Once I get high enough,
I'll run into that bastard someday.
Do you not know what I'm saying to you?
It's dangerous and that you would get hurt!
Are you scared of that?
I am not scared.
From now on, "sorry" and "thank you"
will not be said.
Also, I will not show up in front of you.
Also, next time,
don't ask me to stop.
Park Tae Ha that I know,
he never runs away.
He fights all the way for
what he believes is right.
That's you.
I'm finished interviewing
the reference witness.
You can return now.
There's so much more...
Look at you working hard.
My heart breaks everytime I see you.
How much more would it cost
to hire another dishwasher?
They're just killing you.
Isn't something a bit weird?
What do you mean "weird"?
Look over there. A parachute
falls from the sky...
I'm talking about the soup.
There's a lot of soup left nowadays.
Especially the palace
pheasant buckwheat noodles.
Really? I'm busy making side dishes.
How would I know?
There's often more than half of the soup left.
Some customers even just eat the noodles.
Hong Chun Yeo! Hurry up and get over here!
Aren't you going to get ready for early lunch?
I got you, so stop calling me!
Always calling me,
My name will get worn down.
Noona Da Hae!
Has our Gil Yong come?
I did!
Why don't you greet me?
-It was good not seeing you.-Eesh.
You two, follow me.
Quickly!
You're in for a real treat.
Look, this is Hwayangjeong
the king used to eat.
Wow, this is so good. So delicious!
Ah, right?
Our Da Hae needs one too.
Then, for you to get prettier...
here's Chongpomukjeon.
Isn't it good?
We should eat more.
Has it been about 3 years since
you wandered about here?
What do you mean wander about?
I'm not a rat.
I confidently deliver vegetables.
You haven't been coming recently.
Well... I've other things
going on, that's why.
Did you miss me?
I should just!
Who are you?
I'm the vegetable deliverer, Go Gu Ra.
I mean, Go Gil Yong.
See me, Hong Chun Yeo.
Madam, I didn't invite him
in on purpose... well...
You use the same room as Kim Da Hae, right?
Pardon?
Oh, of course.
That girl always snores so much.
From now, tell me
everything Kim Da Hae does.
What's the reason?
Don't ask, just do as I tell you.
This is a secret between just you and me.
You understand?
Yes, I understand.
Potager.
- What?- Can I taste the broth?
Why? To cure your hangover?
Did you drink?
What are you doing?
You said not to act like I know you.
Except for when talking
about work-related things.
The after-taste as subtly bitter.
This is why the customers haven't
been finishing the soup.
You knew too?
For noodles houses or soup specialty restaurants...
it's essential to check on the broth.
If you just pay attention
a little, you can tell.
There's no problem with the other broths.
The palace pheasant buckwheat
noodles indeed has the problem.
What should we do now?
Since we know the problem,
we should solve it.
You said that if I don't touch nor hurt your
belongings, you said you wouldn't touch mine.
Is Goong Rak Won included in that?
It's not yours yet.
Your ability to learn
quickly is still slow.
After being threatened by
you, I thought long and hard.
Should I give up now or see how it unfolds?
Guess what I decided on?
Whatever your decision,
You can't protect Goong Rak Won.
Look at you.
You looked down on me your whole life.
Goong Rak Won became like this
because of your sabotage.
- Sabotage?-Giving up
operation of Goong Rak Won
doesn't include giving up
the role of Noodle Master.
Nowadays, you act like you've
let go of Goong Rak Won
and offering it up to its demise.
It is sabotage.
Listen closely.
The reason why it's in this state is
because you don't have the ability.
Before you blame others,
take a look at yourself.
If you don't have the skills,
hand over the operating rights.
Don't blame on the innocent person.
You want me to wave flag
and give up, right?
Wake up from your dream.
I'm going to fill up the remaining
three months and endure.
If you throw in the towel now, I'll
let you be in charge of the kitchen.
But if you don't give up,
there will be nothing left
in your hands after 3 weeks.
Remember.
Kim Da Hae!
Why are you so surprised?
Look at you widening your eyes.
Say what you want to say, instead
of beating around the bush.
Isn't it time to promote her?
She works hard and has talent.
I do feel a bit uneasy about her
being Madam Seol's connection, but
I know you're interested in her.
Isn't that right?
It's too early right now.
Think about it.
I've decided already.
If Madam Seol agrees, I can promote her.
If we're going to promote her, wouldn't it
look good to all agree on this decision?
I think it's fine.
The palace pheasant buckwheat noodles... you use
the pheasant sauce along with fish and meat sauce.
These guys are playing hookie
whenever you get a chance.
Hey, Laborer.
Yes!
Can a laborer touch the jars or not?
I'm not allowed to touch them.
What Goong Rak Won is most
careful about is sauce thieves.
Half of our recipe lies in these sauces.
If you don't want to be mislabeled as a
thief, don't even lay a finger on these.
- Understand?- Yes.
And you, kiddo...
Hey, where is fish and meat sauce?
Where is it?-Are you ignoring me
(literally chewing my words)?
- In the storage. We keep
them separate.-Am I gum?
Hey! Aren't you going to stop there?
Stop while I'm saying it nicely.
One, two, three.
The Noodle Master takes special care of the fish
and meat sauce storage. No one else can go in.
Even the potager receives
necessary daily allowance.
You're treating your
senior way too easily...
What?
Hey, hey, hey... This isn't right...
Please stop!
Stay back.
Crazy bastard!
What are you doing right now?!
This is a deadly sauce.
It's something human shouldn't be eating.
Can't you stop?!
Stop.
You saw it too, Noodle Master.
He's destroying all these
precious stone pots.
Step away.
Noodle Master!
Quick!
For noodles, a stone pot is its life.
No matter how well the dough was made,
if the sauce tastes bad, you
can't make tasty noodles.
Right now now, the ten year
old fish and meat sauce...
and the ceramic jars made out of special soil
from Mount Taebaek... you destroyed them all.
Convince me why you had to destroy them.
If you can't convince me,
you'll have to pay for it.
This ceramic jar isn't made
out of the special soil.
Instead of using red lead glaze, they
used traditional glaze to fool you.
Because the jar isn't made out of the
special soil, the jar can't breathe.
Since the sauce can't breathe and is trapped inside the jar, it has
changed to bitter and sour taste rather than its intense taste.
This is the reason why the
customers leave left overs.
Fish and meat sauce taste changed?
Yes!
Check then.
Taste it right now.
He's right.
It's bitter and sour.
Polishing the outer surface and letting it
receive sunlight doesn't do everything.
That's why I broke them.
So they can breathe.
Check the rest of the fish
and meat sauce thoroughly.
Pay special attention to taking
care of the ceramic jars.
Yes, I understand.
Da Hae,
you knew it too?
I thought it was strange as
there were so many left overs.
I didn't know.
What an embarrassment.
I'm sorry.
Why should you be sorry?
It was my fault for not paying attention.
It's not your fault.
The Noodle Master switched all the ceramic jars
for the fish and meat sauce two months ago.
You opposed that. This is the
jar that was switched then.
The thing you just said,
don't say it anyone else.
If that leaks out, we're finished.
He knew I changed the ceramic jars.
Just by looking at the texture and shine.
What is with this cold atmosphere today?
What's the matter?
The election is over now.
National Election Committee started
investigating violations in election laws.
Many will get tangled and head for jail. You
should prepare for the Special Election.
If we let this chance go, then we
will have to wait four more years.
I'm okay, but I'm not sure if you are okay.
I have to get Goong Rak Won back.
That's my priority.
That's right. Ha Jung Tae, the
man, is no use for the election.
But it's different for the Noodle
Master Ha Jung Tae of Goong Rak Won.
You must hold on to the
Noodle Master position.
Everything will be over
the minute you let go.
Tell me your plan.
Deciding on districts, staff, campaign office,
campaigners, working the ground... it's all useless.
You just need to received the nomination.
With the nomination, you'll receive money.
Then people will gather. So...
you can put on a gold badge, right?
That badge... it only weighs 6 grams
and is plated gold only worth $35.
But the minute you put that on, you'll be treated like a
Minister and become an independent constitutional institution.
You can't give up.
Anyhow, this might be the last chance.
How can you be so easy?
Ma'am.
I couldn't bare to see
you two from blushing.
Wow, you were coming on strong.
It's the job of a PR Director.
Straightening out his clothes.
PR Director?
Wow, she moved up fast. How many times
did you do PR to get the director title?
I receive corporate director position
proposal from time to time. It's no big deal.
If you received a proposal,
you would've gone there.
No matter how big Goong Rak Won may be, it wouldn't
compare with a big corporation. Don't you think?
You're about 165 cm?
Pale skin, medium hair length.
I see both a lady and seductress
in your face. Totally his style.
I feel offended.
Stop.
Should I make you even more offended?
Including you, this is the fourth time.
So, enjoy as much as you can while you have the chance.
You'll get pushed over by number five in an instant.
I know you're tempting him
to get into politics.
I'm warning you. Noodle Master, no,
Good Rak Won... don't shake it up.
If you continue to shake things
up, I won't leave you alone.
Do you understand?
Yeah... is this a gangster or something?
Gangster?
Are you scared of gangsters?
I'm scarier.
Director Do, you can go now.
She has no guts. She's useless.
She's nervously pissing all over the place
at one word out of my mouth. What PR?
Say what you want to say.
Stop your sarcasm.
Politics? Do it if you want to.
You're not someone who'd
listen to me if I said no.
I don't care as long as
Goong Rak Won runs well.
But
don't think about coming
back after you fail.
I won't accept that.
Look at you curse me.
The best thing is for you to make noodles.
The worst is to get into politics.
There's no in between. Choose one.
You can't imagine having both?
Let's live positively.
Even when I see my husband playing
with another woman, I'm still smiling.
How much more positive do I have to be?
That's killer!
Congratulations on your third election win.
This is all thanks to you, Noodle Master.
You have to support me now.
My heart is all in, but...
I don't know how to support you so that
people would say I supported you well.
Do you know, Noodle Master?
Right around your sixth election win,
would you be able to support me easily?
You realize that the only senator who's been
elected six times is Senator So Tae Seop, right?
What do I need to do to meet the very
important six times elected senator?
They say the beacon does not shine
on its own base. It's really true.
Wasn't it Moo Myeong?
He's much closer to him than I am.
So pretty.
How could noodles be this immaculate?
It's called Yeonah noodles.
I added lotus extract in
the flour to knead it.
The broth is made out
of mushrooms and dashi.
You can say it's one of the best of the
monk noodles that you like so much.
They call it monk noodles because
it makes the monks smile, right?
Yes.
It's my good fortune that I met you.
If you hadn't come to the temple to
rest, how could I have ever met you?
I went to the temple to pay my respects
and I met the noodle buddha.
Have some.
How's your body?
Yes, I'm all better now.
I feel bad asking you to
make noodles all the time.
Just tell me.
I'll set up a nice noodle
restaurant for you.
You're a bit late.
I got into Goong Rak Won.
What?
Why would you work for someone else when
your skills aren't lacking anything?
I have always respected the
Goong Rak Won Noodle Master.
I would feel even worse
calling you up in the future.
Don't worry, if you call
me, I'll come anytime.
Ma'am.
Father just fell asleep.
You don't need to go in.
But still, since I'm here already,
I want to see his face...
From now... You don't need to come here.
You... I'll promote you as a noodle maker.
A noodle maker?
You'll get busier.
I feel bad being selfish.
I'm okay, I come here as I like it.
For now, focus on work.
Now that I've made you a noodle maker, if you fail and get
back to working as a laborer, we'd both be embarrassed.
I'll call you to the separate living quarters
when I need you again. Let's do that, okay?
Hey! Tae Ha! Are you alright?
Ugh! Why did they take an innocent person?
What a hassle. They come and turn things upside
down whenever they want to. These jerks.
Hey, we're not illegal.
We're doing legal business.
Do you remember Myeong?
The one who came to the junkyard fight?
Myeong?
Myeong... Oh, that guy? The
one who took you away?
Ignore him even if you run
into him at Goong Rak Won.
Also, tell Doo Cheol that when he sees
him, don't act like he knows him.
Why should I do that?
Shouldn't the one who has to
poop look for an outhouse?
Myeong has evil connection
with the Noodle Master.
His identity can't be revealed.
He'll be in danger.
If you're that worried, you go
in yourself and protect him.
How can you take yourself out of it
and tell someone else to do that?
I don't know. You take care of it yourself.
I'll go in!
I'll go to Goong Rak Won.
But instead, keep it a
secret, you and Doo cheol.
Instead, I've a favor to ask of you too.
She's like my daughter,
so take care of her well.
If it seems dangerous, you've to block it.
Can you do that?
She's like a daughter,
then why is she here?
Ugh, this punk. You're
digging into my wound.
Oh, kiddo!
We'll open soon. I have to go soon.
Stop pretending to be so strong.
Park Tae Ha. Kim Da Hae. Greet each other.
Hello?
Yes!
He will be working in there
too, so be nice to each other.
I brought him to greet you.
Since I greeted already, that's it right?
She has a bit of a temper.
I know!
You know?
Yes.-How though?
I didn't put any lipstick either.
Sun glass! It's well?
The one that I gave you.
It should be well.
It's been a while.
Yes, it's been a while.
Come in.
Noodle Master.
Have a seat.
The fish and meat sauce incident...
We were able to avoid the worst.
I wanted to thank you.
It's no big deal.
Anyway... you must have a huge network.
What do you mean?
Your connection with
Congressman Choi and...
I heard you're close to
Senator So Tae Seop...
I met him a few times
at the Buddhist Temple.
He specially likes my noodles.
So Tae Seop... I would like for him to
come in here. Can I ask you this favor?
Yes. Well, it isn't that hard.
Great. Quickly, let's set a date.
Yes.
I've a condition.
Condition?
Promote me into the Noodle chef.
One more thing. I must appear in
all the broadcasts you're in.
If this condition is met, then
I'll bring So Tae Seop in.
That's the same thing as asking
me to raise you as the successor.
Your request is quite extreme in exchange
for a bowl of noodles for the senator.
Your goal isn't to serve him
noodles to begin with, right?
Another goal?
I've already revealed my intentions to you.
It's my goal to be your successor.
If you open up your heart,
I'm ready to do anything.
Whether that be noodles or politics.
If Madam Seol knew this he would pass out.
I'd like to show her the image of
one of her own betraying her..
I'm not anyone's person(side),
I merely met Madam Seol
prior to meeting you.
I'm not switching sides but merely
choosing an owner for the first time.
Myeong, you know that I'm being
suspicious of you, right?
Please be more suspicious of me, then only
after that, you'll start believing me.
If a single word said here today turns out to
be false there will be grave consequences..
Myeong, you can't handle me.
I don't do things I can't manage.
The thing I'm best at is scaring people.
Once the person is scared, he starts to be
generous and is easier to negotiate with.
But it doesn't seem to be working on you.
Should I act like I'm scared?
I like your courage. The courage
to make a deal with me.
I'll take that as a compliment.
On promoting you as the Noodle Chef...
let me think about it.
Yes!
Why did you change your
mind all of a sudden?
I was impatient. I thought this
chance would never come again.
That's why I came here.
To come under me, you need
to uphold some rules.
First, don't judge things for yourself.
I'll do the judging.
I order you and you do it.
I understand.
Second betrayal, lying, and other
motives will not be allowed.
If something like that happens
then you'll pay the price.
I'll keep that in mind.
Third don't bring your father's
info up until I allow it.
I'll let you know when you prove that
you're my guy, will you till do it?
Yes, I'll.
Follow me.
This person will drive,
you've the license right?
Yes!
I'm going to bring a guest.
Please make the preparations.
Please go inside.
Let's stop now. That's enough.
Clean out Secretary Ha's room.
Someone else is going in.
Were you testing me?
Things that cost a dollar
I'll buying with ease.
Even if it's defective it's
only cost me a dollar.
But starting with something costing $10,
you try to be choosy. $100, $1000...
It's human nature to chose more
carefully when the price is higher.
From now on, I'm going to
invest a lot into you.
It's a given that I test you.
I'm not a product.
You are a product. And you will
become my most expensive product.
You'll look good in suit.
What are you doing?!
Have I not told you the trash needs to be recycled and
clothes go separately. Have I told you this before or not?
Who's stuff is it?-Secretarty Ha.
I'll throw away the trash and
burn the rest so you can go.
This is something I've to do...
If you throw something you weren't supposed to,
are you going to take responsibility? Hurry go!
Just go! Just go.
These people... they don't
have basic civil mentality!
I...feel burdened.
I'm doing this to make you feel burdened.
That way, you'll do your best.
Good work. It's this room. You must be
tired, so from now on, you stay in there.
Yes, sir.
DNA Parentage Test Report
Client 1 (Ha Jung Tae),
Client 2 (Kim Da Hae)
This is proof that client 1 (Ha Jung Tae) and client 2
(Kim Dae Hae) are biologically related. DNA Testing Center
Master: God of Noodles