[Episode 18]
No... Tae Ha...
No!
What are you doing not taking care
of the Prosecutor first, punk?
Yeo Gyeong...
Go to the hospital first.
I'll go after I wrap up here.
Doggoo, you a**hole...
how is that you're here?
Pil Seung... did you get a fake eye?
How did you see to it that you think
it was okay to mess with a prosecutor?
Listen to me carefully.
Don't ask nor try to figure it out.
Just disappear.
Whatever the Noodle Master says
to you, you shouldn't come out.
If you show your face, I'll kill you.
Got it?
If I don't find work, I'll
starve to death all the same.
Tens of gold badges (Assemblymen)
are tangled in this and
a Prosecutors' Office Special
Investigative Team is twisted in it.
If you get involved thinking, "Something's
gotta give," then you'll be shredded to death.
Eat this money and get
your feet out of it, okay?
You can't even handle me alone. Understand?
Come in.
Sit down.
I'll tell you the reason I called you here.
Noodle Maker Kim Da Hae is especially
generous to you, Noodle Chef.
Is there another reason
why you approached her?
What are you saying?
TV appearance issue and also the
noodle master position issue...
I believe you're behind
it all, Noodle Chef.
Are you showing concern as an adviser?
Or are you concerned as her father?
You knew?
It's an open secret. Everyone
knows, but pretends not to know.
Don't influence Da Hae. Distance
yourself and don't get close to her.
If you're saying that as an
adviser, I can't do that.
Noodle Maker Kim Da Hae has the talent to lead Goong
Rak Won. I'll stay close to her and help her.
If you're saying this as her
father, I can't do that either.
Adviser, you don't have the right.
Listen to me. Don't make this any bigger.
Now, I'll tell you the reason I came here.
Vacate your office.
This office... There's no reason for a
mere adviser to occupy this office.
I'll give you three days,
so wrap things up here.
Also, please don't come in
and out of the kitchen.
I won't accept the kitchen being
used for your political ambition.
You act as though you've
got the whole world.
If Goong Rak Won is a small world,
you're not wrong in saying that.
If I captured enemy territory,
I should reap the spoils.
You're my spoils, Adviser.
You said you had a name you had to
recover for your father's sake, right?
I also have names I need to recover.
When I recover those names, something
very interesting will happen.
I don't need spoils.
I'll destroy everything.
Three days.
Take everything.
I'll throw whatever is left
away in the trash can.
Why not sleep more?
You didn't faint from the
injury, but from exhaustion.
Everything's a mess.
We were lucky. Both you and I.
It's the Noodle Master, right?
If he finds out they
failed, he'll try again.
There's no guarantee you'll
be as lucky next time.
I have you. Stop them again.
Yeo Gyeong.
I should show them what happens if they mess with a
prosecutor. They keep trying because I let it slide.
I'll sweep them all away...
Oh, so dizzy...
Sleep some more. I'll say
until you fall asleep.
ID, Park Tae Ha.
Is the Prosecutor alright?
How about you?
Are you worried?
You almost got a hole on your side.
Wouldn't I be worried?
Everything is good with you except
your focus. How disappointing...
Did the Noodle Master really
order my father to kill people?
That's right.
I don't think he said it in so many words.
But isn't going to the extent of giving drugs
to a drug addict and handing him a knife
the same as ordering him to kill?
Tae Ha, if you're not going to kill
the Noodle Master, come out of there.
Noodle Master, that punk... he
ruins people by riling them up.
You, too, will be used like your
father and will be abandoned.
I can't leave yet.
Why? Because of that cocky friend of yours?
I came in because of my friends at first. But there's
someone else I need to protect besides my friend.
Please take good care of Yeo Gyeong.
Noodle Master
Hyungnim... let's get out
of this at this point.
Doggoo
Ha Jung Tae speaking.
Hey, Ha Jung Tae, how are you?
Don't hang up, punk. I
have something to say.
From observing your behavior yesterday...
you must be quite desperate, huh?
Yesterday?
Kang Gil Seung and his gang... they dug up a
hole and buried their heads like ostriches do.
There's no use looking for them.
This is my last warning.
The reason I didn't kill you is because
I didn't want to make Da Hae an orphan.
If you mess around again, I'll
go in to Goong Rak Won again.
You're really dead then. Got it?
What happened to your face?
I fell drunk.
You drink without money?
See if you're missing anything.
Thank you.
Go.
What's going on?
I think the Noodle Master
senses our relationship.
It's because you dropped our photo.
No, you might have given
it to him yourself.
Are you saying I sold you guys out?
How did you see the photo?
The Noodle Master showed it to me.
Right in front of my eyes.
Why are you still by his side?
I know the reason why you came. But the
reason for your staying here is inexplicable.
Get out of here. That's the
only way I can trust you.
When everything is over, I'll
leave on my own two feet.
Whatever kind of revenge
you want, do it fast.
The way I see it, you and Yeo
Gyeong are both in danger.
Worry about yourself. I
can take care of myself.
Don't be so sure. Yeo
Gyeong said the same thing.
Go see Yeo Gyeong. Bye.
Hospital Room 203
Are you looking for someone?
Chae Yeo Gyeong...
Patient in room 203 was discharged.
Shouldn't you stay in the
hospital for a few more days?
I don't have that kind of time.
How about the thugs?
Well...
Myeong
I told them off so they'd understand.
So, don't look for them.
Only sparks will fly if you mess
with the fire that's going out.
Let the attackers who
attacked a prosecutor go?
From the looks of it, I think they
were going to stop at kidnapping you.
But if you corner them like crazy,
they'll come carrying weapons next time.
When their own lives are on the line,
who cares if you're a prosecutor?
Focus on the Noodle Master.
You sent in the witness
application, right, CEO Lee?
He said he was ready to testify.
So, I sent it in.
If you don't need it, we'll
just say it never happened.
This... Can he testify for sure?
A change of heart happens
so quickly in a person.
I can't guarantee it. But
I think he'll do it.
Keep it for me. I'll summon him soon.
Wow, playing prosecutor is so fun.
What will you do now?
Hyungnim...
What's wrong? Looks like you
were eating stolen food.
Oh, Prosecutor Ahn, what brings you here?
I'm Prosecutor Chae Yeo Gyeong.
Ah... Prosecutor Chae. Had I known how beautiful you are,
I would've responded to your subpoena ten times over.
In any case, looks like we'll be seeing each other quite a bit.
I couldn't connect the Noodle Master with Aide Park alone.
I have to bring you into it in
order to arrest the Noodle Master.
Are you speaking Russian?
Hey, you translate.
Did you stick a log in your ear?
Assemblyman. You can choose
one of the two options.
First, I'll arrest you in violation of the tax
law and will wrap up the case by fining you.
You'll hurt your image, but
you can keep your gold badge.
If you insist on being stubborn, I'll arrest you the
minute the Temporary National Assembly Session adjourns.
Be ready to serve a minimum of three
years to a maximum of five years.
How can you say such a cruel thing?
Is there any other way?
No, there isn't.
Number one.
I have a condition.
Sell out Noodle Master Ha Jung Tae.
I'll pay you a lot for him.
Let me think about it.
Speak.
Prosecutor Chae Yeo Gyeong...
Yeah, I heard she came to work today.
You'll have to suppress her.
There's plenty reason for her dismissal, but
looks like they're blocking it internally.
You're the one who caused all the problems.
Why are you whining to me for your
inability to take care of it?
You joined me offering lots of
money to Goong Rak Foundation.
I gave you more shares in the Foundation compared
to Goong Rak Won. I can't even ask for this favor?
If you're asking me a favor,
show me how much you care.
You have cash stored away in
your personal deposit box.
Assemblyman!
I apologize.
If I touch my customer's money, I'm dead.
You know this.
That's why everyone wants to wear the
gold badge. If you put on a gold badge,
it's not embezzlement if you touch that
money. It becomes investment for your work.
For now, bring it to me and
let's talk next time we meet.
Must you even eat my bone marrow?
People who haven't tasted
meat only want meat.
One must eat even the bone marrow to say
that you've tasted everything. Understand?
Anyway, please clean this up first.
So dark. I hate to see this.
What are you doing?
You're here. Good timing.
This sofa is too big for
our living quarters.
What living quarters? Didn't
you say in three days?
I changed my mind. Since it's come to this,
I wanted to take care of it quickly.
I'm going to destroy the secret room.
Oh, my goodness... Even putting a rotating door... You made
such a big deal. How odd. Are you filming a spy movie?
The corporate credit card for the
Noodle Master will be discontinued.
Also, what else... Oh, yeah...
I fired all your men.
Ugly guys dressed in dark suits
don't look good around here.
Also, what makes you think there's
a terror threat at Goong Rak Won?
To hire more than ten security guards
and bodyguards? Don't you think so?
You're having so much fun. So much fun.
Does it look like it?
What should I do? I shouldn't
be so transparent.
Do you know how I feel?
I feel like I'm on cloud nine.
It's so great, so great. Such an ecstasy.
Keep floating on cloud nine.
I'll make you fall from there.
Oh, my gosh... Aigo... so scary. What should
I do? I'm so scared that I'm about to cry.
Be careful.
That moron... he'll do anything
to get back what he lost.
Go Gang Sook... she's a scary woman.
She placed a mat for me to sleep on
in a spot where her father died.
She wants me to have a
nightmare or something?
Should I look for a place
for you to stay outside?
That's what Go Gang Sook wants.
If I leave here, I'll never be
able to get back to Goong Rak Won.
- Secretary Park.
- Yes, Noodle Master.
Does it look like I'm
finished to you as well?
I do see that circumstances aren't good.
It will change soon.
After I'm nominated and become a Assemblyman,
I'll put everything back the way it was.
The person who smiles
the widest right now...
will be the one who'll cry the most then.
Why are you revealing this to me?
The palace pheasant buckwheat noodles. My father
perfected it, but Noodle Master stole it.
Is this about the Noodle Master?
It's not like that.
Come in. There's something
I want to say to you.
I have a favor to ask you.
Please oblige me.
Noodle Master... so that he
can't do any more wrong...
Please stop him.
Stop getting hurt yourself.
Promise me. Hurry.
Go to sleep. It's late.
Please sign the release form.
If you want, I can get you a bodyguard.
I'm okay.
Assemblyman.
You're here.
Put it away.
And the classified document?
K120-17: Corruption in the National
Security and Defense Industry
- The original?
- The original... I'll give it to you after the nomination.
That's a fair deal.
What is it?
Answer sheet to the candidate evaluation.
It's the same as wearing a gold
badge starting today for you.
Your district... Doesn't even
a corpse get elected there?
- Review that and do well in your evaluation.
- I understand.
And... until your
nomination is confirmed...
just breathe. Nothing
else will be tolerated.
If you do something like messing with Prosecutor
Chae like last time, you're finished.
- I'll keep that in mind.
- You'll find out soon.
You'll experience yourself why perfectly normal
people go crazy just to wear a gold badge.
I only focus on the future of our nation...
and happiness of our people...
I'll solely focus...
Solely focus...
An exiled king must live like this.
She made sure you can't go anywhere.
I can go anywhere except for the kitchen.
Do you know who you are if you can't
go into the Goong Rak Won kitchen?
An outsider. You're being treated
like an outsider, Noodle Master.
I just let her have it for the time being.
All I have to do is get it back.
How? In what way?
I listened to you and took my hands
off of Goong Rak Foundation.
I'm shaky without any strings to hold
on to. Will you just stand and watch?
The cruelest revenge is to bring misfortune when
she thinks she's reached the happiest moment.
Tell her to be happy to
her heart's content.
She doesn't have many days
left until she's miserable.
Give me Goong Rak Won
shares as you promised.
I should at least hold on
to that to feel as ease.
I told you. My nomination comes
first and shares comes after that.
Noodle Master!
Don't be confrontational with me.
What will you do if even I
turn my back on you? Wait.
I never break a promise I made.
Do you know who Prime
Noodle Chef Moo Myeong is?
He's the bastard who ruined the banquet.
I found him. The bastard
who ruined the banquet...
I mean, Choi Soon Seok. I found him.
Choi Soon Seok.
He came into Goong Rak Won
targeting you from the get-go.
To revenge his father's death, he hid
a knife with him. That's Moo Myeong.
His medical records from the time he
was stabbed by Secretary Hwang...
The banquet guest list he stashed away...
It's all in there.
Invitation List
But how do you know about this, Madam Seol?
I held Moo Myeong's hand and...
was going to chew you out, Noodle Master.
We were accomplices.
Are you Choi Soon Seok?
Not Moo Myeong. Ha Jung
Tae's son, Choi Soon Seok.
You're Kim Gil Do.
Gangnam San 323-37.
Right here. The spot where you're
standing is where you were born.
Seongbukdong 387-18.
So Tae Seop's house where you
committed your first murder.
And Gangwondo Bongpyeong Yupori 802-2.
You killed my father and even my mother...
And that wasn't enough. You stole my
father's name and life altogether there.
And again here! This is where Choi Soon
Seok took away everything Kim Gil Go had.
At a place where you were born!
Shut up!
If I was going to kill you, I could've
done it a hundred times over!
Do you know why I let
you live all this time?
To take away everything you've got.
Ha Jung Tae... bore a monster.
It's not over yet.
There's one more thing I'll take away.
So, anticipate.
The thing you'd never want to lose!
I'll take it away ruthlessly.
Jung Tae...
Look at your kid. To kill me...
he appeared in front of me
as someone just like me.
Ha Jung Tae...
Wait a little longer.
I'll send your son to your side.
Oh, my gosh! This is so nice!
We can even record our show here.
Why did you want me to come?
I'm sure it's not to show
off your restaurant.
Go live?
Yes, the viewers can participate and...
Moreover, it's something new.
It is, but as a cooking show...
It takes too long to cook and...
there exists variables.
Is Senator So Tae Seop well?
Yes.
He mentioned you at times, Hyeon Jeong.
Come by our Chi Meon Restaurant
with the Senator some time.
It would be nice to have
Adviser Ha Jung Tae as well.
Sure, I'll work on it.
While we're at it, let's make it big.
You must make sure Adviser Ha
Jung Tae appears on the show.
And this production didn't come from me.
You started it, Hyeon Jeong.
Do you understand what I mean?
I'm not a child.
You have to keep your secret,
too, Prime Noodle Chef.
That's the only way things will proceed.
Hasn't he gone crazy yet?
It must be hard to endure
with a clear head.
Adviser Ha? Why do you ask me that?
Aren't you guys buddies
these days, Madam Seol?
I heard you two go around stuck
to each other. Isn't that true?
What nonsense you speak!
I plan to promote Prime
Noodle Chef to Noodle Master.
It hasn't been long since
he became an heir.
The Noodle Chef position has
been vacant for three years.
You must be more serious about
the Noodle Master position.
If I leave the noodle
master position vacant,
I don't know when Ha Jung Tae that
moron would come running for it.
Since I've closed the casket,
I'm trying to hammer it shut.
The Prime Noodle Chef can't
become the Noodle Master.
Why not? Are you starting to hurt
seeing me doing whatever I want to?
Prime Noodle Chef... he's
doesn't have sense of taste.
He lost his sense of taste.
How can he be Noodle Master when he
can't taste anything? Don't you agree?
Is that true?
Why would I lie over something
that can be easily found out?
If the Clan finds out, his place
as the heir is in jeopardy.
So, stop acting in vain.
He's like Beethoven. He's really amazing.
Don't you think so?
Without sense of taste, could
he make such delicious noodles?
Isn't he just like Beethoven?
Madam Go!
Madam Seol, listen up, okay?
If your string got cut off, just stay put.
Don't go around causing ruckus
with your mere 10% shares.
Goong Rak Won is mine!
Don't you understand?
If you don't understand, just memorize it.
Memorize!
Please put it on this end.
Right here.
Watch out for the floor.
Father, it's where Kim Gil
Do's desk used to be.
He signed your name here.
I took it from him.
It's where Kim Gil Do's glory used to be.
He obtained it through your
name and your secret recipe.
I got rid of it all.
And this is...
where he was born and grew up.
I'll destroy it completely, so that
he can't even dream of coming back.
Wait a little longer.
Just a little longer.
It's not a legal matter. It's a matter of
enforcement. As far as enforcement is concerned...
With issues like these...
Steal, change, imitate.
I don't have to work at
creating an original.
I can just steal, change, and imitate.
Did they change my car, too?
Forget it.
Is today the candidate evaluation for
the Special Election nomination?
Yes, Prosecutor.
Some reporters must've shown up.
Probably quite a few.
Do you want to go look?
Candidate Ha Jung Tae.
I'm nomination candidate Ha Jung Tae.
The great noodle master of Goong Rak Won...
You must be a little nervous.
There's no one who hasn't had a bowl of noodles
at Goong Rak Won over the candidate evaluation.
Think of how you served noodles. Relax.
Thank you, Chairman.
Shall we begin?
Who'd call you a political
novice, Noodle Master?
As if you've been in office
for about three terms...
your easy confidence,
attitude of conviction...
and persuasive communication skills...
Also, down to earth speaking manner...
Most importantly, making
people feel comfortable.
You're born with it.
You're generous in your compliment.
If you trust me and follow, there
will be good things down the road.
I'll be trusting you.
Long time no see, Senator
and Noodle Master.
What's going on?
I request you to accompany me in
regards to Congressman Choi's case.
Why now of all times?
Why here of all places?
We have reporters here and looks like you'd be watchful of
others since it's candidate evaluation day for the nomination.
I believe I picked good timing.
I deny your request to accompany you.
It will become a little noisy.
Go follow her... before it gets louder.
Noodle Master, what's this about?
Prosecutor Chae, one word please!
- Will this affect the nomination?
- Will it matter?
One word please!
Please say one word! Please!
There must be something.
Please say something.
Will you keep your promise?
Ha Jung Tae... how long has he
been in the interrogation room?
Going on seven hours.
Hold onto him a little longer.
He's probably going crazy.
We saw Senator So Tae Seop and he knows
we're trying to involve Congressman Choi.
They're probably worried just about now.
The answer is out there already. Wouldn't
they call when their meeting is over?
If you testify, she'll let you
get away with paying a fine?
That's what she says, but I can't trust
anyone at the Prosecutors' Office.
Some give their hearts and even
let them slap their cheek...
Men who got screwed over...
can fill up a truck.
She said she'd dig up to the
end if you don't testify?
So I was thinking... if the
Prosecutors' Office looks into it,
wouldn't it eventually lead
to Goong Rak Foundation?
I'm afraid you might be
hassled if she continues.
That shouldn't happen, seriously...
So I was wondering...
If the charges against me are dismissed,
wouldn't it both benefit me and you?
You go and testify.
Don't let it affect Goong Rak
Foundation and stop at your level.
Instead, sell out the Noodle Master.
What happens to Noodle
Master's nomination then?
I'm sure he put in everything he
had and bought the nomination.
Did I ask him to put everything in?
He did it happily.
Call the Special Investigative
Team and wrap it up.
Live people should live
and dead should die.
Yes, Congressman Choi.
You made the right decision.
You can go home.
Did you get what you wanted?
Somewhat. How about you, Noodle Master?
Not even a scratch.
Noodle Master.
Congressman Choi is here to see you.
Congressman Choi?
The results of the candidate evaluation for the
Special Election will be announced today, right?
Yes.
You must be nervous.
I remember the first time I walked into
the Chi Meon Restaurant 30 years ago.
I barged in trusting the secret recipe to
the palace pheasant buckwheat noodles.
That mophead became me today.
How I would turn out in
30 years from now on...
will be determined today.
You ask if I'm nervous?
Honestly, more than 30 years ago...
I'm nervous today.
I'm being summoned by the
Special Investigative Team.
After meeting with the Special Investigative Team,
even the most powerful conglomerates or congressmen
don't end well. That place was
set up to catch people like us.
Even Doggoo who accepted
money got his case dropped.
They can't accuse you of
crime for losing money.
Noodle Master.
Don't blame me.
What are you talking about?
In life, things happen that
goes against how you feel.
Well... It's not like things would
work out just because I want it to.
Let's get together for some soju later on.
Thank you for the noodles.
Breaking news: Korea's Freedom Party nominates Professor Lee Gun Shil.
Goong Rak Won's Noodle Master Ha Jung Tae unexpectedly denied nomination.
I got rid of the indigestion
I had for ten years!
I don't need Tums.
I didn't think request to accompany
me would deny him the nomination.
The splinter in my finger is
much more painful than a sword
stabbing another person.
What if they get screwed for
embracing the Noodle Master?
This is why politics is scary.
When is Congressman Choi being summoned?
Tomorrow.
You don't know when he's going to
change his testimony. Don't relax yet.
Okay.
Anyway, how far will you dig Noodle Master?
Violation of Foreign Exchange
Transactions Act? Tax laws?
Also, murder and soliciting murder...
I'll add to it.
Do it right if you're going to do it. There will be
bigger opposition more you try to let him have it.
Tae Ha.
Noodle Master.
Want to grab a drink?
Yes.
I know you killed my father.
But I won't kill a man like my father did.
Instead, your downfall...
I'll witness it up close.
Do you know this?
Your daughter... she asked me to stop
you from committing more crimes.
But I know I can't do that.
Stopping you from committing more crimes...
Only you yourself can do that.
It's me, Senator.
Did you get some sleep, Noodle Master?
Thanks to you, I slept well.
I'll give up the nomination.
Regarding this matter, I won't be
bothering you in the future, Senator.
You make me feel so bad.
But I won't go to jail.
I gave up my dreams and
sacrificed Goong Rak Foundation.
I don't think jail is fitting.
I'd like to see you with Congressman Choi.
Please be our mediator.
Well, that's not hard, but it won't be
easy to dismiss the Prosecutors' Office.
It will be a small amount, but
I'll express my gratitude.
If you go as far as this,
I can't ignore you.
Let's meet together.
Won't we come up with a solution
if we put our heads together?
At my house?
Sure, let's do that.
Geez, Prosecutor Chae, I
feel so bad about this.
Something urgent came up today.
I won't be able to show.
Look, Congressman Choi. If you break your
promise this way, I won't just stand back.
Oh, my, scary...
I'm getting goosebumps all over.
It's not like I can show it to you.
Alright then. I'm busy, so...
CEO Lee, it's me.
The person who sent in the Witness
Application, can I meet him?
I'll be waiting.
♪ There's still regret,
but not very much... ♪
I need to know how much more it'll
grow, so I can figure out the size.
♪ The days that still remain... ♪
♪ are passing by ♪
Geez, the Noodle Master has no sense...
♪ When I walk this path... ♪
I'll drive. Secretary
Park can take a break.
Give me the key.
I'll go with you.
You do what you're told.
I'll be the judge always.
Please think it over once more.
Welcome, Noodle Master.
Have a seat over here.
You made the right decision.
This isn't the only election.
While trying to do well...
Things like this happen. Can't
we try to be understanding?
I apologize for making your worry.
Geez, scared me. I have a weak heart.
But... don't you have something to give us?
Geez, man...
Of course I should give it to you.
My life depends on your
word, Congressman Choi.
It's all for mutual benefit.
And even if they get voted in,
some people die afterward.
What do they call it? Oh, right, "Vacancy."
They call it vacant when the position is empty.
What I'm saying is you'll have that type
of opportunity, so don't be too upset.
Is that so?
Since you're sure about
testifying, I'll believe you.
First, I'll proceed with the basic
investigation. Your name is...
Hwang Seong Woo.
Your title at Goong Rak Won?
Goong Rak Won Noodle Master Ha
Jung Tae's Executive Assistant...
and Goong Rak Won's operations manager.
Which crime committed by the
Noodle Master would you testify?
Soliciting murder and
numerous embezzlement and corruption.
Also forgery of documents and...
I'll testify regarding assault,
blackmailing and other crimes.
You still haven't quit smoking?
I smoke seldom when I feel frustrated.
Are you going to smoke?
Gil Do, don't do it.
I'll put it back.
Then...
- One.
- This never happened.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
One.
What's with the mood all of a sudden?
Is something wrong?
Two.
Kim Gil Do!
- Three.
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
There just opened up a vacancy.
Will it be okay if I fill the empty spot?