- Busy night?
- Four customers!
Oh~oh, a record!
- Will you count it for me?
- I always do.
Thanks...
Good night!
Have a good morning.
Hm...
Please, please, stop it!
Please dont!
You don't have to do this.
God, Jimmy, you're late again.
I told you I got class.
- Who are you?
- My friends call me Duke,
Jimmy couldn't make it,
he send me to pick you up.
What'd you mean,
he couldn't make it?
Come on, you can ask him yourself,
I know him from the salvage yard.
Hey, we even put in a new starter.
Listen...
Good as new.
What's the matter?
Come on, I gotta get back.
Okay.
Do you mind
if I listen to music?
Whatever.
You know you might have
to give me directions,
I didn't write it down
what Jimmy told me.
Okay.
- How do you know Jimmy?
- We're friends.
He's a great kid.
You know he's always
bragging about you?
I can't say blame him...
I gotta tell you, I think you're
the prettiest girl I've ever seen.
Thanks.
If I had a girl like you,
I guess I brag too.
What the fuck are you doing?
I just wanna see your pretty face,
you got nice skin.
You don't have to touch it.
You haven't talked very much,
I'm not trying to rape you.
I'm sure you don't act like that
when Jimmy touches you, huh?
You're not gonna be
a stuck-up cunt, are you?
Don't tell me you're another one
of those fucking cunt's.
Turn right here.
I better walk you up
to the door, huh?
I'm alright, thanks.
Mom.
Mom, are you here?
Jimmy, it's me. Look... um, some
weirdo picked me up in your truck...
and drove me home and... and I wanna
make sure you're not dead or something.
Call me.
You know, I can see you
through the door.
It's me, Duke.
You remember me?
I just give you a ride home.
What'd you want?
Oh, you left something in my car,
I thought you might want it back.
What?
Your ear-ring.
I'm not gonna open the door.
Quit foolin' around,
open the door.
- No.
- All right, hey, I tell you what...
I just leave it out here,
at the porch for you, alright?
You can get it later,
how'd that be?
That would be great.
All right then,
that's what I'm gonna do, superstar.
See you later.
Please God, no...
Go ahead and press it,
I won't pay over-time.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Don't worry about me, I'll...
huh, take care of this for you.
Get in.
Hey.
- What's the matter?
- Sorry.
Forget it.
- Long night?
- Work was okay, but...
I think I must've
dozed off or something,
I had this fucked-up dream.
- Was I in it?
- No.
There was like... this creepy guy,
who picked me up from work...
drove me home, dragged me into
the basement and killed me.
Oh, man...
that's so weird.
- I had this crazy dream too.
- No shit! Really?
You and me, we...
we were getting it on, right?
And here's the weird thing.
Jen, shows up... and she went like:
Yeah, I always wanna do it with a girl.
- And, huh...
- Right.
So lame, I can't even believe
we're having this conversation.
Well... I know Jennifer,
your best friend.
I just think we should at least
ask her, if she'll do that.
You want me have sex
with your best friend?
Did you not with my friend?
Okay, let's not go there.
You wanna come in?
- My mom's home.
- Figures.
- Jesus mom, you scared me.
- Oh, no kidding?
You gonna open the door,
or you want me to?
- Wait.
- What?
Don't open it.
- Hi. Jimmy.
- How are you, Kate?
- How you doin'?
- I'm great...
That's a smokin' blouse
you're wearing today.
Well, thank you.
That's a very nice compliment.
You know it almost makes me think,
I should take you out
instead of your daughter.
Hello... get a room!
Yeah... well,
I'm gonna go wait in the truck.
Are you late for class again?
Mom...
You know that Jimmy is kind enough.
to come and get you every morning,
because you can't be bothered
to get your drivers licence,
the least you can do
is to be ready.
None of your buisness.
You're 19 years old, the agreement was
that'd you stay here, while you...
Blah... blah... blah...
blah... blah...
Have a nice day!
Whoa... whoa, whoa.
- Can you... huh, you push the truck?
- Why, what about this shit?
What? You don't have a drivers license,
how you gonna jump-start the truck?
Please.
Thank you.
Hurry up, put some ass into it.
Push harder!
- Was that enough ass for you?
- That was a lotta ass, baby.
You know that's all the ass you gonna
get until you get the starter fixed.
Through me is the way,
into the woeful city.
to the eternal world.
Through me is the way,
among the lost people.
Justice moved my locken maker.
Divine power, the supreme wisdom,
and abiding love made thee.
Before thee,
things created stay eternal,
and my eternal lasts!
Appending all hope
thee who enter.
- Oh'oh...
- Sorry about that.
Um... we're about
outta time anyway...
Please don't forget,
you know that 3 page report on
escrows is due for tomorrow.
I'll see you then.
Watch?
Watch this.
Come on.
What you doing?
Let's go.
Fuck you.
- I'll just carry you.
- Okay.
What's that for?
How about a... picnic under
the bleachers, something like that.
Somebody might see.
So? That makes it exciting.
Sounds like we got company.
I thought
that's what makes it exciting.
- Huh, some one's up there.
- Yeah, no shit.
- Will you check it out?
- I just did.
Please.
Claire...
you're acting crazy today.
I know, I'm sorry.
No... no... no... no!
Hello?
Is there anybody down there?
Mom?
Mom you in there?
Turn the light on.
What the hell you're doing down here
in the dark? Who are you talking to?
I lost something down here.
I was just looking for it.
I guess I'll get it.
- Hello.
- Hey, what's up?
Hey Jimmy.
Sam and I playing basketball tomorrow,
and I thought maybe you could bring Jen.
Yeah, I guess.
Yeah, Jen told me
she liked basketball.
Hey Jimmy, are you okay?
- Huh... yeah, why wouldn't I be?
- No reason.
So... huh, see you
at the basketball court tomorrow.
- Yeah, okay, see you.
- You'll bring Jen.
- Bye.
- Will you bring Jen?
Are you ready for this, James?
This ball in that hole.
- Let's go... do it... do it...
- I'm doing it right now, ready?
- Alright... here we go.
- Ohh...
- That's, man!... Gosh...
- Calm down man, it's just a game.
It's uncalled for, I wanna
play basketball here.
- So, huh, Jimmy had a dream last night.
- Oh yeah? Let's hear it.
You me and him had a 3 way.
No...
Hey, guys you're ready? I'm gonna
teach that boy a lesson of humility.
Alright, let's see it.
Yeah...
I won't play
with you no more.
Just get some training
and come back.
- Hi, baby.
- Nice dream, Jimmy.
- What's your name?
- You told her?
Oh yeah, you should tell Sam.
I think he might like to hear it.
Ready?
No.
Show me how to do it,
and you push it.
Alright, well... uh,
this pedal is the clutch.
You put your foot on it,
push it down,
when I tell you to,
let her go.
That's what you've been doing
this whole time?
Hm, pretty cool, huh?
Learn something new every day.
Come on, Sally,
put some ass into it.
Hey, what did Jen say about
my dream when you told her?
She thought it was funny.
Funny like... how? It's disgusting,
or like... that might be kinda cool?
If you wanna fuck Jennifer,
then just do it,
I'm not stopping you.
Pop the clutch.
Oh come on, give me a little
more credit then that.
I mean...
I would never cheat on you.
But if you want me to,
I mean here,
I would do it right now.
Because that's how much
I love you.
Are you retarted?
Take me home... God!
Mom?
Mom, are you there?
Yes I'm here,
I'm just getting dressed.
Okay.
Jeez mom, nice outfit...
what'd you got
a hot date or something?
He's somebody I met at work.
He... huh, worked there
something over a year.
What?
So, can you... huh,
get yourself up...
and... huh, to class
in the morning?
I guess...
Because there's some possibility,
that I may be spending the night.
Okay, I get it.
Well, have a good night.
And be careful... okay?
'Cause I worry about you,
in that place all alone.
Okay.
I will...
Thanks.
Bye.
Have fun on your date.
- Hey Gertie.
- Hey.
- Busy night?
- No, it's been dead.
Oh, good...
I didn't get any sleep last night.
I'm ready to do lull.
Don't let Cleatus catch you,
he said he might stop by later.
What's he gonna do, fire me?
- Yeah.
- I wish.
- See you.
- Bye.
Hello?
If anyone is over there?
I'm gonna press the alarm.
The police are gonna come.
Not yet.
- It's okay, it's alright.
- He's in there.
It'll be alright,
we'll get 'em.
Alright Claire,
what this guy look like?
Okay... he had red hair.
And he was... I guess he was
like... huh, average hight...
Um... he... huh...
he was wearing this like
gray jacket, and...
and he said he worked
at the salvage-yard, so...
I did get it stained...
I...
What?
Claire, are you high?
No.
From time to time, you don't...
smoke a little weed,
do a little extacy?
- I just think you'd... huh...
- What am I supposed to say?
I used to buy it off of you
in the parking-lot,
before you became
Captain ass-hole.
All right, alright,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Alright... let's move on.
Would you get the TV
and the VCR for me?
There's someting
you'd wanna see.
Alright.
That's you, right?
- Yeah.
- Sleeping.
That's you waking up,
walking across the store,
and getting into a fight
with yourself.
I don't understand.
I felt it.
Look, he had red hair, okay?
He...
He worked at the salvage-yard,
he.. he had a funny name..
- I don't remember it...
- Duke Desmond?
- You know him?
- Yep, yeah...
I shot him death last week.
Everybody in this town
seams to know that, but you.
- He's dead?
- Dead and gone forever.
I'm loosing my mind.
Look...
it's not surprising...
you're having night-mares
about this guy.
It's been all over the news.
We found some kid cut up...
in the back of his own
pick up truck.
I'm sorry,
come on, I'll take you home.
Let's go.
You look pretty tired.
Why'd you go ahead lay down
and get some sleep?
I'll wake you up
when you get home.
Thanks.
What the fuck?
God!... No!
Not you!
Shut up!
Well, let me guess...
That one, right?
How did I know that?
This just isn't happening.
This isn't for real.
Well, how would you know
what wasn't for real?
Look.
You want me to tell you?
'Cause all of this
is bull-shit.
You, me, everything,
it's all made up.
The only thing that's real,
is what you feel.
The only thing that's real
in this whole world,
"is what... you... feel"...
when I cut your head off.
Mom! Mom!
No! No! No!
Shut up!
Don't! No, please, don't hurt me.
Let go of me, please!
Please, don't hurt me.
This is not real.
This isn't really happening.
This isn't happening.
This isn't happening. No!
It isn't happening!
Please God, no!
This isn't happening!
No! No...
Please, please, God...
God...
No!
No... no... no!
Don't hurt me.
Please don't, Please...
Please. Please. Please!
Good... morning.
What the hell's
the matter with you?
Through me is the way
among the lost people.
Justice moved my locken maker.
Divine power, the supreme wisdom,
and abiding love made thee.
Before thee,
things created stay eternal,
and my eternal lasts!
Appending all hope
thee who enter.
Sorry about that... We're about
out of time for today.
Yes, Claire?
You gave this lecture yesterday.
Well, how would you know?
You weren't even here yesterday.
Where're you going?
What the hell's the problem?
I've been to your house,
your work,
looking for you,
I've waited.
Okay... you're not crazy.
You know I'm here to listen,
just tell me
what the problem is.
I'm seeing stuff, Jimmy.
Like what?
Like people...
killing me.
And... and it isn't like...
I just see it,
I... I feel it too...
it's like... it's really
happening to me.
The weird thing is... okay,
I saw a picture of the guy
who keeps attacking me.
Well, that's weird, right?
I saw a picture of the man,
after I imagined him.
What if there's something
with this guy, you know?
I mean... maybe he's a ghost
or something?
The sheriff said
he was a serial killer...
and was shot to death.
Claire, what the fuck
are you talking about?
- Well, maybe he's a ghost?
- Bitch, are you crazy?
What?
Oh... just great!
I so cannot deal with this.
Fuck you!
Honey.
Wait, please.
I didn't mean
to call you the "B" word.
Go home, Jimmy.
It's just... I didn't know
you'd be talking about some...
serial killer ghost shit.
- Go...
- Just... just... let me help you.
You know what, I... I'll help you,
just... I wanna help you.
Just stop walking down the street,
like you're some kinda kook.
Hey, fuck you, Jimmy!
You don't even believe me.
I do believe you.
There is a ghost.
Oh, I'm sorry, it's just
the funny face you just made, I...
I... I do really think
there is a ghost.
- You're just such an ass-hole.
- I'm... I am an ass-hole...
huh... you just made me laugh,
with your funny face.
There really is a ghost,
come on...
- Fuck you!
- Come on.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
- It's closed.
- Can I help you?
- God, you scared me.
- I'm sorry...
if you're here for the...
huh, bibel-study,
it's at 3 o'clock
this afternoon.
Um, actually, we wanted
to talk to a minister.
- He is out.
- Ask him.
But he's a janitor.
He works in the church,
that's pretty close.
Um...
I don't know if you can help me,
but...
I'm seeing ghosts.
Well... a ghost,
just one...
His name is Duke Desmond.
Duke? You sure?
Don't look at me,
I... I haven't seen any ghosts.
- He went to this church.
- But he died, right?
- Yeah, the cops shot him.
- Fantastic.
Hm, that's all you needed to hear.
You ready to go?
He had us all fooled, but there's...
talk of Jesus and salvation.
I guess the devil works
in mysterious ways these days.
Hiding in plain side.
Oh, but you don't have to
worry about him though, huh...
- He wont hurt you.
- That's because he's dead, right?
Because he's in hell.
Wait... one more thing,
you know where he lived?
Hm...
This is it.
This is where he lived.
Yeah, it looks like
a psychos house, it's a dump.
Can we get out of here?
It's kinda deserted.
Okay, great, even better.
Can we please leave?
Don't... even think about it.
What? I thought you didn't
believe in this stuff?
I don't, it just... this place
gives me a bad feeling.
Like what?
Like you know, when you get
kinda nervous... and...
some butter-flies going
through your stomach, and...
You know this place makes me
feel like taking a crap.
Crap.
Okay, well,
I guess you stay here, and...
I go look around.
Hello?
Is anybody here? Huh...
I need to use your restroom.
Jimmy.
Come on.
Hi, I need sheriff Miller?
- This is him.
- Sheriff Miller, it's Claire.
Look... um, I'm in a cabin,
out on route 16.
I... I think Jimmy come in to get me,
and I think he might've gotten killed...
- and I need somebody to come.
- Whoa, whoa, woman.
Hard for me to tell you
what's going on Claire, but...
we're gonna find out
soon enough.
Who are you now?
Where'd keep your
old news papsers?
Is it for a specific class?
- It doesn't matter.
- Actually it does.
- It's philosophy of antiquity.
- Who's the professor for that?
What is your deal, lady?
Just tell me where it is.
Shh...
this is a library.
Did you find
what you were looking for?
Claire.
Look out!
Oh my God, Claire,
what's wrong?
Close the door.
Are you okay?
Come on, let's go
in the other room.
Come on.
It's okay,
I'm gonna call the police.
- It's okay.
- No, I already talked to the police.
I'm telling you, I... I think
there in on it, I do...
No, it's okay,
I'm your best friend.
I'm here,
I will take care of you.
I promise,
nothing's gonna happened.
You're in a safe place, okay?
Okay?
Here.
Come here, sweety.
I called the police,
they're on the way.
It's okay, calm down.
It's okay, Claire,
you're save.
Duke Desmond, don't move!
Hold your positons, I got him.
Okay, okay...
You got me officer, you got me.
I found that boy in your truck.
Why'd you do it?
Come on man,
what'd you want me say?
I don't know...
Okay, okay, cowboy.
I tell you...
- We're gonna meet with a lawyer.
- What?
You know about them?
I can't resist 'em, man, they're
controlling me with something.
What the hell
you're talking about?
Like I'm getting radiosignals
put into my head, man.
That's how they
must be controlling me...
they put a piece of medal
in my head or something, man...
and it's telling me
what to do.
I can't help it
when I do this shit.
They make me do this, man,
they've taken contol.
Come on, man, don't tell me
you're on of them or something?
- Hey.
- Hey, you wanna come on in?
She was quite upset.
You wanna see her?
Alright...
Push the clutch down.
Come on, come on.
Claire! I need your help.
I need you to help me.
Help me, Claire.
Mom?
Claire! I need your help.
Claire, come down to
the basement, I need you.
Mom?
You have to come down
to the basement, Claire.
Please, don't make me
go down there, mom, please.
Claire, come down here
and help me, please.
Claire, I need help.
Hij komt voor mij nu...
I'm in pain.
Come down.
Help me!
Please, somebody help me.
Mom?
What're you doing down here?
Mom, please hurry...
we have to get outta here...
He's coming...
We've got to get outta here...
We can't get outta here.
Don't you get it?
You got to relive
what you did,
again and again...
But why are you
doing this, mom?
Stop calling me that.
- You're not my daughter.
- Yes I am, I'm Claire.
Claire is dead.
Because you killed her.
Because you killed her,
and Duke!
I didn't do anything.
You want me to tell you?
Shh...
You wanna know the secret?
I shot him death last week.
Dit alles hier is zever.
- You, me... all of it.
- Duke is dead, right?
- Because he's in hell.
- I'm not, Duke.
Please... I didn't kill him...
Appending all hope
thee who enter.
The only thing that's real,
is what you feel.
- Because he's dead, right?
- Because he's in hell.
I didn't do anything, please.
Please...
I didn't do it!
I didn't do anything!
I haven't done anything.
Please, God, help...
Gute nacht?