Fixed & Synced by bozxphd. Enjoy The Flick
Former New York socialite
Judith Case and John Raymond
are joined by Satan in unholy wedlock
before a live altar, a nude red head.
Self-ordained sorcerer,
Minister Anton LaVey
presided at
the San Francisco ceremony.
As the worst man looks on,
the blessings of Lucifer
and Beelzebub are invoked.
The elaborate rites smacked
of publicity because next day,
the bride and groom secured
a conventional wedding license.
Two days in LA to go on
my dark tour. David has to handle it.
Two days!
Cannot believe I agreed
to this shit.
Chlo, you wanna hit off this J?
No, I'm good, thanks.
Hey, will you open
a fucking window?
LA, spread your legs.
So tired, I can barely get high.
Too dark.
Keeps burning
through that memory, Chlo.
You guys are like
a fucking Apple commercial.
Devil face.
Oh, my God, that was so KISS.
Knights In Satan's Service.
KISS worshiped pussy, not Satan.
- Hey, don't we all?
- I hate that word.
What? Seth said it, not me.
Hit him anyway, Chlo, they love it.
Where the fuck are we?
Good evening, Los Angeles.
And we are officially lost.
Damn it.
The arrow shows Flower.
Is this Flower?
No, this is Santa Fe.
Hey, should we get back
on the highway?
Are you sure you had the GPS on?
I don't know, do I?
Nope, 'cause I'm an idiot.
Ah... ha-ha, there she is.
Welcome back, Kim.
I'm sorry, you call her Kim?
Don't ask.
Okay, hello to you, too.
Junkies and whores.
Welcome to La La Land, darling.
Right, there it is.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Yes.
Elise Stevens.
Two nights, right?
Yeah, and specifically
requested room 204.
Laney Gore bled on the floor in 204.
- That's the shit, bro.
- So the shit.
Who the hell's Laney Gore?
One of many surprises
we have in store.
!' Play nice.
I am playing nice.
Laney!
- Oh, my God.
- Wow.
- Smell that asbestos.
- Oh, wow.
Nice. What a shit hole.
Oh, my God. Look at this.
Seth, I think
this is where it happened.
- Matches the photograph, right?
- Yeah.
Hey, this isn't a suite,
it's a dump.
Why did we pay an extra 20?
Room 204.
Laney Gore slit her throat here.
- What?
- Yep.
1972. One of the early sisters
of LaVey's Church of Satan.
Check out the bloodstains
like wet paint.
Oh, my God. It is the same.
David, look.
Yeah. Fucking awesome.
Hey, why are we here
and not Coachella?
Because Chloe's my best friend
and you're on her leash. Okay?
- And you're on mine, bitch.
- You wish, bitch.
Hey, you guys
really want to stay here?
- Yeah.
- Darling, this is why we came.
Right?
- Yeah.
David, are you okay with this?
- He can't hear you.
- He's sleeping.
Get back here!
Oh, my savior.
Nice neighbors we have.
Yeah, this place
is a squatter's paradise.
You get a needle at check-in.
Anything?
I thought I felt something
a while ago, but...
Yeah. Well, maybe that
was just Milton Bradley
- pocketing your 20 bucks.
- I felt something.
- I swear to God.
- Ask it something.
Hello.
Who are you?
Are you Laney Gore?
What do you decree?
"What do you decree?"
Hey.
Oh, my God, Seth,
you're totally doing that.
I'm not.
What do you want? What do you want?
What do you want?
"B"
"BJ."
Oh, my God, it's like
we're thinking the same thing!
Seth! You little fucking prick!
Fucking goth troll.
- Yeah, my goth troll.
- Bullshit.
Come on, it's cool.
It's not cool,
nobody's taking this seriously!
Okay. Sorry, your bullshit
Satanic tourism,
- I have to take this seriously?
- It's not Satanic tourism,
it's about understanding
the dark natures.
Wow, that's very
Aleister Crowley of you.
You know what? Fuck you, David.
If you didn't wanna do this,
why'd you come?
To get a BJ.
Hey, I've got that
department covered.
Oh, do you?
If you guys are gonna
shit around all weekend,
maybe we should just
blow this whole thing off
and go to Coachella.
This isn't bullshit for me, okay?
I mean, would it kill you, David,
to open your fucking mind
and be a free spirit?
I swear to God, I can't deal
with this frat-boy shit!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Tension release.
We'll have our coffee.
And from now on they'll behave.
Come on, it's Spring Break.
Come on, LA for two nights,
and then Coachella, right?
Look, we're on board.
Our minds are open.
Yeah?
So... you tell me. What's the plan?
All righty.
- Everybody get together.
- Mm-hm.
- Come on!
- Ow!
- Cheer up!
- Yeah.
- 'Kay? This is where Satan lives.
- Okay. This is happening.
Oh... Cute.
Check out the cross, it's kick-ass.
It's cool.
Oh, my God.
We love your look.
They're friendly.
Hey!
Uh... Dude, uh, we're trying
to find the Sharon Tate house...
Fuck off.
Yeah, well, fuck you, too!
Colossal waste of time, take two.
Sick. I'm gonna use this
as my screen saver.
Color-tone the shit out of it.
Hey, did we ever find out
where her house is?
Go suck cock, bitch.
David, no.
Yeah, go suck
the devil's cock, bitch!
Oh, my God. Good one, Dave.
- Fucker loogied all over my window.
- Welcome to LA.
- No shit!
- This city sucks.
All right. First ones here.
Only ones here.
Sorry, why are we not at a
taping of Two and A Half Men?
Chloe, can you keep his negative
energy away from me, please?
And, David, that shitty show's
been canceled.
Just like the photos.
Insanely awesome.
Oh, my God. Were people
really murdered here?
Bloody and cold.
Seth, we got to find a way
around the back.
Yeah.
Can you get the hell
out of the way?
Dick.
Wow, Dave,
you're just an asshole magnet.
Yeah, no shit. I'm here with you.
Oh, my God. Dave, do you ever
get tired of being wrong?
Oh, you gotta be
- fucking kidding me.
- Mm-hmm.
All right. Yeah.
They came this way about ten PM,
up the hill, to the backyard.
Big-ass hill. Jesus,
what were they? Sherpas?
Why'd they do it?
Manson thought some record
producer that fucked him over
was still living here.
He was actually the target.
Wrong place, wrong time, eh?
On steroids.
Slit her stomach open.
- She was fuckin' pregnant.
- Seth!
Oh, my God, it's so pretty.
I know,
that's what makes it so creepy.
Seth, get a picture of us.
Chloe!
- I don't want to.
- Chloe.
No. Fine.
- Say "Charlie."
- Charlie.
Yep. Totally worth it.
1641 Cahuenga.
Okay.
So, now we're touring porn shops.
Nah, dick,
they just don't advertise.
Call me a dick again, Seth...
Dude. Dave.
You gotta chill, bro.
He's right. You need to chill.
Chlo, do you know how much shit
we're missing right now?
It's almost over.
I'm just saying.
She's your cousin. Okay?
I barely tolerate her
and I don't like Seth.
- David.
- Seriously.
They don't even offer gas money.
Oh, my God, will you guys
fucking grow a pair?
Seriously. Hell, fuck.
Oh, I have a pair, Morticia.
Big pair.
Blow my fucking mind.
Oh, how spine-tingly awesome.
Seth, check it out.
Mmm... incantations.
Check it out.
How wet are you right now?
Oh.
That's rad.
Boo!
- A bad hand-job.
- Good one, Dave.
- Is it real?
- It's mummified.
Taken from the body
of a convicted child murderer.
Killed a ten year-old girl
back in Modesto in '85.
Satanic Panic.
Cases like this all over
Southern Cali, right?
The Panic was a myth.
This asshole was a killer
and a pedophile.
Satan had nothing to do with it.
Yet, here he is,
on display in your shop.
- Yo, how much?
- Not for sale.
What about this?
- You know Coptic Greek?
- I can read.
You need the accent
for the incantations.
It wouldn't work for you.
Asshole.
Well, I guess you're not
ready for the Dark Embrace.
You see his tattoo?
Yeah, upside down cross.
Very original.
Out.
Yeah, yeah. It's cool.
- Now, fucker!
- Or what?
Are you gonna
spill some pig's blood on me?
No, just cut your fucking heart out.
Hey... Place is horseshit.
All right. Let's go.
Poser dick fucks. Shop sucks.
Well, that went splendidly.
I'm gonna burn this place on Yelp.
Enough of this shit.
We're doing the Starline Tour.
Dave at the wheel.
- I hate your van, Dave.
- It hates you.
I'm serious, it was like a shrine.
It had goats' eyes
and dried intestines.
Oh, my God. Are we still
in that little Satan shop?
It's a sacrificial circle.
They give gifts to Lucifer,
in turn, he grants power.
Wow. Goat eyes and pig balls.
The gifts that keep on giving.
We should head back there.
Follow him and see where he goes.
Probably back to his mom's basement.
Seth's right. We should follow him.
- What, are you serious?
- Come on, it'll be fun.
I guarantee
it'll lead somewhere dark.
You can't just tail someone
for fun. There are laws.
Yeah, talk to Google about that.
Nancy Drew did it all the time,
nobody gave her shit.
I'd say we're more like
that Scooby gang
with this piece-of-shit van.
Dude, I paid 1,200 cash with
140,000 miles in that engine,
- and it kicks your fucking goth ass.
- Such a piece of shit.
Insult that van one more time,
we will have serious words.
Maybe we should just check out
and head to Coachella.
Oh, Chlo, stop being a bitch.
She's not a bitch... she's lame.
Hey, that asshole had a blade on him,
who knows what those people are into.
I thought he lives
in his mom's basement?
It doesn't mean he's not a wacko.
Hey, Chloe, come on.
The guy's a total puss.
Oh, with a devil shrine
in the back room?
Yeah, well, one devil shrine
does not a douchebag make.
Honestly, these people probably
circle-jerk to Marilyn Manson
- and call it a day.
- Okay, let's put it to a vote.
Who wants to follow numbnuts
to his little tree fort
of demonic possession?
Yeah!
- David.
- What?
Babe, I'm sorry, I love you,
but I need a little excitement.
Chloe, you're out-voted.
Terribly sorry.
Yay, we're going spying!
Yes!
Hey, if you don't wanna go,
we won't go.
David's right, you owe gas money.
- Oh, my God.
Yo, here.
Thank you.
Fucking peer pressure.
Come here, darling.
Tongue!
Use your tongue.
David. David.
They're heading out.
Hey, guys, they're heading out.
Oh, that fuckin'
bald-headed piece of shit.
Fucking bald motherfucker.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey, he's gonna
get away! Come on.
Yeah, the hell they are.
Go, go, go, yo, yo, yo!
- Hey, don't lose him.
- Floor it, Dave!
Floor it, Dave!
He just ran the red.
Hold on, I'm blowin' through it.
Yeah! No fear! No fear!
Yeah, that's right, bitch,
I know how to tail.
They're in the right.
Right, right, right.
- Turning right.
- I see him, grommet.
Seth, he sees him.
I think they're headed
towards the coast.
Yep, that is exactly
where they're going.
Dave, I find myself apologizing.
This van actually does kick my ass.
Dude, it's a stealth fucking fighter.
God, I'm loving their black tint.
Maybe they're vampires.
Ha! No shit, right?
- How much fun is this?
- Yes!
Hey, yo, not to spoil
the moment or anything,
but does anyone know what the fuck
we're gonna do once we stop?
That's what makes it
so much fun, Dave.
- No idea.
- Okay.
Yo.
Dude, don't let them get away.
- I got 'em. I got 'em.
- I think we're in Malibu.
Posh Satanists.
Yeah. They probably
have a fuckin' reality show.
This is exciting.
I'm, like, gonna pee.
Okay.
Now this feels like trespassing.
Let's go back.
David! David, kill the
headlights, they're gonna spot us.
Fuck you, man. I can't see shit.
No, he's right. They'll spot us.
Damn it.
- Fuck, it's dark.
- Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck.
- Damn, it's dark.
- Fuck.
You know,
I'm gonna drive us off this cliff,
I swear to Christ.
You're doing a good job, babe.
Oh. Check out this house.
Of course it's a shit hole.
- Pull over.
- All right, all right.
- They will see us.
- No, we're too far away.
All right, from here we walk.
Seth, there's a flashlight
on the floor.
Got it.
Shh, quiet.
Seth!
Hey!
I feel like we're trespassing.
This is wrong, guys.
Stop being a buzz kill.
Yeah. Hey, we'll just take
a little peek
and then we'll head out.
I mean, come on, you can't
tell me you're not curious.
- Shit.
- Are you okay?
Are you okay?
I ripped my fucking
stockings! Cow shit...
It's not funny, dickhead.
- It's a little funny.
- Elise, it's hot.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Take you down right here.
- Piss off.
Shh! Get down, fucktards.
We should get a little closer.
Is that the cumball from the shop?
Yeah, that's cumball, all right.
- He had a knife on him.
- My God, I told you.
- We should get closer.
- No.
- Yeah.
- Come on. Come on.
- Let's do it. Let's go.
- All right. All right.
Oh, my God.
What are they playing?
Satanic rage.
Oh, my God.
Hey, Satan's children,
are you doing ecstasy?
- Must be a rave.
- Satanic ecstasy.
Can you see in there?
David, I can't see shit.
- Let's go in the back.
- Yeah.
- David!
- All right, all right.
Shit.
Robes. They're wearing fucking robes.
Shh!
Just when it couldn't get
any more pathetic.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the world's worst Latin class.
No shit, right, what the hell
are they doing?
They're summoning
the spirit world.
You see the elemental signs
on the wall?
Are they written in blood?
- Magic marker.
- Good one, Dave.
I have my moments.
Oh, nice.
- Very nice.
- Seriously?
Hey, that's the freak
from the back room.
And probably the leader, right?
Yeah.
Oh... shit!
Boobs. We have boobies!
Okay. Now I'm starting
to understand the dark powers.
- Seriously?
- Sorry.
Oh, my God. David.
- Elise, what are they doing?
- I don't know.
- David.
- What the hell?
My God, David,
they're gonna cut her!
- We have to do something!
- Hey, Chlo, it's cool.
No!
Hey!
Hey, leave her the fuck alone!
- Shit! Go, go, go.
- He's got a gun!
Go, go!
That's it, a fuckin' gun!
Shit, they're shooting
at us! Run! Run, run, run!
Chloe, hurry up. Come on, run!
- Come on, come on.
- Shit!
Get in! Get in!
Go, go, go!
Did they follow us?
No. I think we're okay.
Jesus Christ!
What the hell was that?
Grommet,
tell me you got that on video.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck! Fuck, I dropped my phone
back there.
I dropped my fucking phone!
- Dave, we gotta go back.
- The hell we do.
Yeah, dude.
You'll get another one.
Yo, yo, there's some
serious viral on that shit.
They tried to shoot us.
Yeah. Well, we were trespassing.
Are you really
taking their side right now?
No, asshole,
I'm just pointing out the obvious.
If anything, they'll find
your fuckin' phone
and report us to the cops.
Good, we can tell the cops about
their sacrificial massacre.
Okay, you guys.
Did anybody see them cut her?
- No, but they were going to.
- How do we know that?
The whole thing
could have been for shits.
David, the girl was scared.
I'm not saying that she wasn't.
I'm just pointing out
the fact that we don't know
the whole story.
God.
Shit.
Elise.
Elise, your phone.
- Hello?
- Elise?
No. Who's this?
My name's Alice.
I think I found your phone.
That's her there, right?
Yup.
Morning.
You okay?
There's no one else here.
Just me.
How'd you know to call us?
Elise was the last call.
Is that you?
That's me.
Do you live around here?
- I got it before they did.
- Oh. Cool.
If you want a reward,
I can give you...
I want the magic word.
Please.
And video's intact. Thank you.
Um... I'm surprised
you didn't delete it.
It wasn't my concern.
So what the fuck was this last night?
Seth, shut up! God.
- We were all there.
- You shouldn't have been.
Fair enough.
But it's good we were, right?
Because whatever
fuckin' virginal sacrifice...
- It wasn't a sacrifice.
- Then what was it?
You wouldn't understand.
Try me.
It was an excommunication.
They were kicking you out?
Why?
Because I wouldn't do
what they wanted.
See ya.
Wait, Alice.
Do you need any money?
- 'Cause I can...
- No! No, no. It's fine.
Well, do you need
a ride anywhere, 'cause...
Chloe.
- I already asked her that.
- It's okay. I'm leaving tomorrow.
Where?
Bakersfield, maybe.
You sure you don't need anything?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Who knew Satanists liked
iced cafe mochas?
She never said she was a Satanist.
- No, just a groupie.
- I'm so curious now.
What do you think
they wanted her to do?
She's barely legal with no home.
Do the math.
She did have nice titties.
She's all ratchet. Okay?
Girlfriend needs to get a bra.
You guys are just
so fucking nice, aren't you?
She's just a kid,
probably some homeless runaway.
Chlo, we all have our issues.
Oh, fuck you, Seth.
She was cool enough to call and
give your fucking phone back.
She didn't even want money.
Yeah, what she wanted
was a place to crash.
You could read it all over her face.
Well, so?
Would it have been so bad
to help her out?
Chloe, for all we know,
she could've been
some little crackhead.
Wow!
For so-called "free spirits",
you guys come up
really fucking short.
Whatever that was.
Chloe.
I'm sorry. I'm a total bitch.
Megabitch.
Yo, there she is.
David, look,
she has nowhere to go.
What?
She's waiting for the bus.
She's so not waiting for the bus.
She said she's heading out
tomorrow, and so are we.
It's one night.
The place is a shithole.
Could she really
fuck it up any more?
Guess we could at least offer.
All because you goth snobs
didn't want to see
Two and a Half Men.
Will you drop it, please?
- Come here, baby.
- Uh-uh.
Alice. Hey.
This is Laney Gore's room.
Yeah.
- What, Laney got naked.
- So fucking full of shit.
No. Laney was totally naked.
No.
She was still in her underwear.
There was blood all over the walls.
Right there.
She tried to make a star
with the blood.
- Why?
- She needed a door.
Took a razor and started slicing
through her skin.
Wait. I thought she slit her throat.
That's what most people think.
The truth is,
is that she cut her wrists.
Took her almost five minutes,
and then she tried
to bathe in her own blood.
- Why'd she do that?
- She wanted to be worthy.
- She wanted to be welcomed.
- Into hell?
Didn't know it was so hard to get in.
Hell isn't a place.
It's a beautiful confusion.
And there's pain.
Okay, uh...
No offense,
but you kinda weren't there.
So... how do you know
it took her five minutes
to cut through her wrists?
Jesus.
This is from back when I was 13.
- I was in a bad place.
- A lot of us were.
- Are you Satanic?
- Seth. Jesus fucking Christ.
I don't believe in organizations.
I believe in finding my own path.
That's not what LaVey believed.
LaVey was a fraud.
Most of them are.
I believe in the power
and reward granted unto Him.
Power not of this Earth.
Just like you.
There's a difference.
I believe in the one, true God.
So do I.
I... didn't mean
to bring down the party.
No. It's okay. Sucks anyway.
This is what happens
when we let Seth buy the beer.
Yo, El Brazo, God boy.
Aw, dude.
Now it's a party!
Wet t-shirt,
taking it back to '87!
To Laney Gore.
Laney Gore.
And now we chug!
I don't like this.
♪ It's a crying shame ♪
♪ It's a suicide ♪
♪ What you do to me ♪
♪ Like a .45 ♪
♪ When your finger
pulls that trigger ♪
Come dance with me.
♪ You got me feeling fine ♪
♪ When I see you there ♪
♪ Standing in the door ♪
♪ Makes it perfectly clear ♪
♪ What I've been living for ♪
♪ Yes indeed ♪
♪ Nothing left to say or do ♪
Seth. What the fuck?
What the fuck?
Hey, what the fuck?
♪ You got me feeling fine ♪
♪ Got me feeling fine ♪
♪ Hey, yeah ♪
♪ Red lips, fingertips ♪
♪ A velvet glove
that always fits ♪
No!
I can feel her.
I feel Laney.
We tried to summon her.
- We used this.
- She's beyond that.
We can reach her.
I can show you how.
What do you mean?
She means she can summon. Right?
I can do a lot of things.
I just need willing others
to help me.
We're willing.
- No, we're not.
- Chlo, come on.
Don't you want to know
where she went?
- She's dead.
- There's no death.
Just transition. I can show you.
Take my hand.
No. This we don't record.
All are welcome.
Laney wants to show us something.
Something beautiful.
Chloe.
And these four be here with me.
And now we travel
from flame to flame.
I see it.
I want to share.
No, they are not like the others.
They're of the humble.
They want to.
- Oh. Hey!
- Shit.
What the...
- Yo, what are you doing?
- David, shut up.
Don't tell me to shut up,
she's fuckin' up the walls.
Awesome.
- Alice, are you okay?
- She's drunk.
- Oh, shit.
- Oh! Oh, shit!
- Chloe, she's just drunk.
- She only had one beer, Dave.
Can you please get her some water?
- Hey"
- Alice: Don't you see?
She found the door.
Laney's with him.
All are welcome.
Oh, my God.
It's beautiful.
Whoa! Hey!
Oh, my God. David.
- Oh, fuck.
- Fuck.
It's okay.
We all made the choice.
We're joined now in the circle.
Yeah, the fuck we did. Out.
Don't you see? He wants us.
Just like Laney.
We'll all be summoned.
And I'm the first.
I'll guide us through the darkness.
Through the labyrinth.
Alice, you need to leave.
I know.
I'll see you soon.
Yeah. Yeah, no, I...
I really appreciate that, Jay.
No, no, no. We just, uh...
we just got off to a late start.
Be an extra day.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, no, it's perfect.
It's perfect.
All right, cool.
We should have never
brought her in, I swear to God.
They said if all checks out,
we'll be cleared in two days.
I don't wanna wait two days.
We should have never picked her up.
We should have never...
All right, Elise,
you made your fucking point!
All right, I talked to my cousin.
We can crash at his place
in the Palisades.
There's a key under the mat.
- Where's the Palisades?
- The fuck if I know.
I want to leave.
Elise, we don't have a choice
right now.
- Says who?
- Says the LAPD.
All right? It's either the
Palisades or the Scooby van.
Um...
Where's the bathroom?
It's, uh, last door on the left.
Elise.
Oh, God.
How long you really think
we'll be here?
Who the hell knows?
I mean, they still have to
interview everyone
from that goddamn house, too.
This is so fucked.
Whole lotta fucked.
Elise?
Elise, are you okay?
Chlo. Chlo. Chloe, hey.
Hey. Hey. Hey. You're okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're okay.
Police?
No, my mom.
Hey.
No, we're still in LA. Just...
No, just decided to stay another day.
No, no. It's fine. Don't worry.
I don't know yet.
Yes. We will.
Yes, I promise.
Did you tell her what happened?
I still don't even know
what happened.
Offerings.
She said she would be the first,
and the rest would be summoned.
We all made the choice
and grabbed her hand.
Chloe, she didn't know
what she was saying.
Look.
A couple of days
and we're out of here.
All right? We'll forget this.
Forget this?
How do you erase that
from your fucking mind?
- Chloe.
- She slit her own throat!
She died right in front of us.
Yeah, Chloe, I know.
I was there, too.
Look.
Another day,
and we'll be on the road.
All right?
Might even make the last night
of Coachella, God willing.
Chloe.
Elise, forget it.
No. I want to know
why she did it.
I want to know where she is.
She's not gonna tell you, she's dead.
I wanna know.
Come here.
Oh, that's cute!
David?
Really? Who's the asshole?
- What the fuck?
- What the fuck, my ass.
What the hell
is your problem, Seth?
- I didn't do this.
- You're such an asshole.
- It's not funny, Seth.
- Fuck you. I didn't do shit!
Dave was the one in here, not me!
Dude, don't even
try that shit with me.
What the fuck?
Motherfuckers!
David, no.
What is this?
We don't even know
if it was them.
Yeah? Who the hell else
would it be?
Sick pieces of shit.
Let's just call the police.
David, let's call the police!
- I don't feel well.
- Shit.
- Hey!
- I don't feel well.
- David, stop!
They're not even open!
Fuckers!
Yo, there he is.
Hey!
- Shit.
- David!
Fuck! Jesus.
What? You want this?
David, no!
You think this shit is funny?
Breaking into my place?
Fuck you, man, I don't even know
where you live!
Bullshit!
- Fucker! Hit him again.
- David, no!
I repeat,
why'd you break into my place?
I didn't.
What'd you do to that girl, man?
- What?
- Alice!
- What'd you do to her?
- Nothing.
Nothing? She just slit
her throat in our hotel room
for no apparent fuckin' reason.
She said you made her do things.
Is that why you kicked her out
of your little bullshit cult?
You don't know what the fuck
you're talking about, man!
You got rid of her because
she wouldn't go along
- with your twisted shit!
- We wouldn't go along with hers, man!
We kicked her out
because she was too hardcore.
Even for us.
You broke my fuckin' nose, man!
What the hell's gotten into you?
What?
The fucker tried to slash me.
So you break his nose?
You should've
put it through his brain.
Goddamn it, we're already
in enough trouble,
we don't need any more!
- Chlo, don't get my fucking...
- Seth, shut up!
What is happening?
Fuck! Chloe!
Chloe. What is going on?
Can we get out of here please?
I don't really feel well.
I just want to
get the fuck out of here.
Can we get the fuck out
of here please? I feel sick.
Okay.
Hey, does anyone understand
that we are part
of a police investigation?
We can't leave town.
I wanna go. Can we go?
- Yeah, we can.
- Jesus!
- We can.
- No, we can't.
Okay, the police say
we can't go anywhere.
I don't care what they said.
Something happened in that hotel room
and it's still fucking happening
right now.
It's like we're marked or something.
You feel it. I know you do.
- I feel it.
- Come on.
- No. We have to leave.
- It just hurts a little bit.
Fucking look at her.
We can call the cops
in Boulder if you want.
Let's just grab our things and go.
Right now.
Jesus Christ.
Come on.
Fine.
- David, I'm gonna be sick.
- Hey, it's okay.
It's not okay, I'm gonna...
David, we need to pull off somewhere.
All right.
Shit.
Do we even know
where we're going?
I don't see a gas station.
- What about up here?
- Chloe, there's nothing!
Oh, shit. Dave, pull over.
- What?
- No, you gotta pull over now.
Damn it.
- Now! Pull over now.
- All right.
Hey.
Elise!
Are you okay, Elise? Are you okay?
Oh, my God, you're freezing.
I feel hot. I need to get
to the bathroom.
No, no, no. We'll find you
somewhere else...
No, I don't want to go
anywhere else. Can you...
Are you okay?
What?
It hurts.
Oh, my God.
It hurts!
Chlo, is she okay?
Uh... Yeah.
It's okay. I'm right here.
- We need to get her to a hospital.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
- What?
Seth, stop.
Just give her a minute... Seth!
No.
Elise! Elise, it's me.
What?
Where is she?
Where?
I don't know.
Seth, will you help me?
- Elise!
- Seth.
Calling 911. I need to call 911.
Oh, God, oh, God,
oh, God, oh, God.
911, what is your emergency?
Hi...
My friend's in trouble.
She's missing.
We need your help please!
Hello?
Where are you, again?
We are... We are... Just...
David, where the fuck are we?
Santa Fe in South Los Angeles.
We're at Santa Fe
in South Los Angeles.
Please, my friend, she's in trouble.
Please. We need your...
Hello?
Hello? Operator!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I don't know. I have no bars.
There's no signal.
Hey!
Elise!
Seth!
I'm on the third floor,
I don't see her. Elise!
- Elise!
- Okay, just...
Just stay where you are.
We're coming, okay?
Elise!
Come on. Come on.
- Seth!
- Elise!
Shit. It's closed off.
- Over here...
- Guys! Where are you?
Please!
Seth!
Wait, wait. I hear her.
Oh, God.
Sounds like she's in pain.
Elise!
Wait.
Yo, guys!
- Seth, wait for us.
- I'm coming!
♪ It's a crying shame ♪
♪ It's a suicide ♪
♪ What you do to me ♪
♪ Like a .45 ♪
♪ With your finger,
pull that trigger ♪
♪ Looks like mine ♪
♪ You got me feeling fine ♪
Sorry.
Chloe! Help me!
Chloe!
Is that you?
Seth!
Seth, Seth.
Seth, are you there?
Shit.
Help! I'm burning!
Oh fuck!
I'm fucking burning!
Seth!
Oh, my God.
David.
David, David, your face.
Oh, my God.
Shit.
No. No. We need to get out of here.
David, we need to
get out of here right now.
We need to go.
We need to go. Come on.
Come on, David!
Dav... David?
David!
Chloe!
Help me!
Stop.
- Chloe.
- David!
Chloe, I'm right here. Chloe.
- Chloe.
- Come find me.
Please.
Laney wants to show us something.
Something beautiful.
Follow me.
Chloe.
Can you help me?
Help!
Help me, please!
Somebody!
Please help!
Help!
Please, someone come...
Don't stay! Leave!
Stop! Don't! Go!
Please leave town right now!
Don't go!
Don't! Don't bring it back!
Please! Please!
No. No! No!
Hell isn't a place.
It's a beautiful confusion.
And there's pain.
Oh, my God.
Don't you see him?
Chloe.
No!
It's me.
You're already dead.
You fucking...
Don't be afraid.
- Always been here.
- He's already here.
You died.
You're dead.
Oh, my...
We're all dead.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God, please no.
Forever.
No!
What the fuck?
Oh, God, please.
Please, God!
No!
We're dead.
David!
David. David.
No.
No!
Oh, my God, make it stop.
Make it stop. Make it stop.
Make it stop.
Come with us.
Are you coming?