ALL THAT IT EXISTS
Is it worth TO DESTRUCTION
SEED
STATE LAW:
A prisoner,...
sentenced to death
by electric chair,
who survives three
jolts of,
15,000 volts each,
for 45 seconds,
must be set free.
That you have done well.
I-I can not believe what I just saw.
This is my last time.
I do not ...
- I wrote many letters to all of your complaints.
You get an entirely new job.
I promise you.
That you have done well.
You did your job.
Right, I ... I did my work.
He is!
You see him?
It is the serial killer.
Do you hear what I say?
Stop the bus!
Everyone, from the bus, now!
Stop! Listen.
He is.
Do you not?
Can anybody hear me? It is him,
you see him?
You see not about who I am?
What are you doing?
... No!
Do not.
Stop the bus!
Give me ...
Give the baby to me!
Come on, give the baby!
My God!
SUFFERTON Murderer GEVAT!
666 MURDER IN 6 YEARS
Worst SERIAL KILLER
EVER IN THE U.S.
MAX IS THE SEED
SUFFERTON killer.
SEED WILL executed
BE BY ELECTRIC CHAIR
SEED'S TERRORIST
1973-1979
DETECTIEVE Matt Bishop
HERO BY JUDGMENT OF SEED
We have post, boss.
- Hopefully the right.
Yet not as far as I know.
I do not know how many letters I wrote.
And how many calls I have committed.
Nothing.
No approval
the new electric chair.
We have him next week, boss.
I know. It must happen with the old.
Fantastic.
I'll let him know.
Any last wishes, Seed?
Want a priest speak?
Some meal?
What is this?
- I do not know.
Are you sure this is our prisoner?
- Yes, most certainly.
Why would a guy who masses
people killed,
important to find rats?
He tries to tell us something.
It succeeds at anything.
It looks like someone's pet.
Damn.
Sick bastard.
My God, you know that there
a missing child in the street 14.
Damn.
This is some sick joke.
PROOF
My God.
What are you saying?
What does this mean?
You're right.
This street is not indicated.
Never mind.
I hunt a lot in this neighborhood.
I know this area well.
Are you a little tense?
Is it?
- Yes.
Gwen Dennis Road.
Here it is.
Please.
She took her good toegetakeld.
They should have fought back.
- Is it really?
When it was classified?
The dates are met.
Please!
Let me go!
Come in here to bother you
hell can murder!
Let me go!
Please!
If you still have that
ten dollars that you need me?
I have ten dollars.
We should all put together $ 50
for those who begin this bastard.
It's so damn dark here,
this upcoming me.
How many houses are here?
The moon is almost there, then there is some light.
- If it is not raining.
Understood.
What is that?
God, that's disgusting.
Jesus.
Look at her.
ONGOING LOS SERIAL KILLER?
POLICE IS DIFFERENT TIMES
Murderer succeeds TOE AGAIN
What do you think about Bishop?
We had it to Ward should leave.
I would not want to be Ward
with Bishop drive.
He lost control a bit.
He does not talk a lot, eh?
It's like I said ...
We talked to Ward should leave.
He is closely involved.
Best a tense atmosphere.
Let us hope that this track is real.
Okay, guys, be careful.
We do not want heroes.
We want him down.
Flynn and Jeffrey,
you occupy the area.
Ward?
- Sir?
You got the point.
- Got it.
Forward!
Search the floor.
Find the basement.
I inspect the top.
What is that?
Herpak yourself, Ward.
Damn!
Come on, where are you?
Simpson?
Damn!
Damn, Jeffrey.
Flynn!
Damn it, Jesus.
Come out of the car!
Forward!
Come out!
Get up!
Forward.
Come on!
I can murder you on the spot!
Seed, this is your big day.
We go a day without geet equivalent of them.
You will be someone's bitch tonight.
Come on, get right!
Something to remind us.
I am even enjoying this.
Security!
CHILD LIVES ON ACCIDENT VURIG
JONGEN LUCK TO SURVIVAL
OF FIRE
Help me!
DIRECTOR OF PRISON SUFFERTON
Execute
Got something to say?
Would you excuse not to
the families of the victims?
Okay, listen ...
we should postpone this execution.
And you know that.
This chair can not.
We have standards here, I have standards.
Calm down.
- Remember the last time?
It was the fourth July!
- Calm down!
We execute him tonight.
Tonight!
You said last time was the last time.
You promised it.
Do your job.
- Do my work.
Do my damn job.
External signs are present.
Heartbeat present.
It is over.
We wish you a
horrible sight saving.
And you ask to leave the area.
Thank you for your arrival.
He is dead, eh?
Of course.
We are three failures,
we have a problem.
We are not more than three attempts allowed.
- Can you assure me ...
damn that my position is protected here?
That means that we get him to
the hospital should bring.
And he continues to live as a freak, blind
and fried brains.
Parker.
Confirm that he is dead.
MEDICAL CERTIFICATE
DECEASED
You buried him alive, man.
And everyone knows that!
Just remember, ...
that karma is a bitch.
And I can not wait until
it takes you to graze.
Seed?
Please.
Lots of butter.
Can I have something for you, honey?
Look at what we?
A movie about vampires.
But ...
it's boring.
That is regrettable.
I go to my room, I think.
Good night.
- Good night.
OUTPUT
HOLY BIBLE
I could not sleep.
- Me neither.
Why not?
A nightmare.
About what?
Well, Em, guests
which I work together ...
did a very bad thing.
And I stopped them, while I could.
What have they done?
They took the law into their own hands.
And now we are criminals.
And you?
I had a dream ...
about an alligator on
hunted me through the house.
Have you caught it?
No, I woke up.
Well.
Want to hear something funny?
I had a dream ...
I ate a giant marshmallow.
And when I woke up,
was there on my pillow geknabbeld.
Have you dreamed of something else?
I had a dream where ...
you die.
Baby.
Nobody comes in here ...
before forensic here.
Damn!
6 VICTIM OF SEED imitator
TIMES OF A YOUNG MAN ...
FOUND IN A FIELD.
Imitator?
LONGER BE FOUND
'Do not panic'
Bishop.
What do you want, Davis?
I want you to do this correctly.
If these murders continue to occur,
will the public know that it is Seed,
and the department will address.
We had never been so may bury him.
Okay, we had him alive
may be buried.
Then you had him in the forehead should shoot,
and to ensure that
he remained underground.
But you did not. So you must find him
and murder him.
And I want you begraafd him,
so he never comes back.
That bastard has five good agents murdered.
Your best friends ...
- Five good cops, my agents.
But he was unarmed, unprotected ...
I had to kill him?
- That I had done.
Do not worry about the right to do so.
Just that you're a cop.
I will make sure.
SEEM RISES AFTER 6 MONTHS
SEED'S DEATH
DENY POLICE blur
WHO IS THE imitator?
58 BE FOUND
30 Missing
Paragnost SAG SEED
'ALIVE AND WELL'
I FEEL THE PRESENCE OF A POOR
It scared ME
Executed.
Detectieve Bishop.
Yes, Davis, I have four agents needed.
16 hours per day, ...
that my family in mind,
until this is completed.
No, I do not send them to their mother.
My child is attending school, so.
Do not worry.
I care for it.
Inside.
Sir?
- What?
This video tape is found.
We had not seen him first.
We just found him?
- Yes, sir.
Okay, thanks.
This is my house.
The son of a bitch.
Sandy?
Emily?
Asshole.
Seed!
Seed, it's Bishop.
Come out!
What do you want?
Seed!
Sandy, can you hear me?
Are you okay?
Does he hurt you?
We do what he wants, okay?
Whatever he says, do we.
Emily, that means:
Mr yes or no sir.
Nothing mispeuteren, understood?
Darling.
Does he hurt you?
Are you okay?
Seed.
What do you want?
Seed, I'll do anything you want.
What do you want me to do?
I'll do anything you want,
my family just doing nothing.
Come here.
Come get me.
Listen ...
I could shoot a bullet through you,
but I did not, remember?
Come on, man.
I'll do anything you want,
my family just doing nothing.
Okay? What do you want?
He wants you to suicide.
- What?
He wants you to shoot yourself.
Do not!
He killed us.
- No, come here.
Take the gun and shoot me down himself.
That is the deal.
But do not touch it.
Seed, they had nothing ...
They had nothing to do with
what happened to you is.
They have done nothing wrong.
Come here and kill me.
That's what you gotta do.
You need to come here and murder me.
They have nothing ...
They have done nothing wrong.
Please, come here.
Come here to kill me!
Please, do not hurt them!
I beg you!
Okay, I beg you!
Come here and kill me, asshole!
Come on!
Oh, God!
Bastard!
Okay, I'll do it!
Papa!