official site FastDrama
(Lovers in Bloom)
(Episode 99)
- Grandma! - Yes? My gosh, you're back,
Grandma, look at this,
Mr, Tall gave it to me as a gift,
- Do you want one too? - What?
What is this?
Gosh, he's so mischievous,
Woo Ri, you should go brush your teeth,
Okay, Mom,
- Goong Hwa, you're back, - Yes,
- You two looked so lovely earlier, - Sorry?
Goodness, you were piggybacking her in front of all the neighbors,
You saw that, Mom?
Of course, Didn't you do that so everyone could see?
Mom, that's enough,
All right, I should go to bed,
Goodnight, Mom,
Goodnight to you too,
- Have a good sleep, - All right,
Bo Ra, you should get some rest too,
And you don't have to greet me when I get home, I'm younger, you know,
You're her sister-in-law,
- She's very concerned about you, - Gosh, whatever,
Don't be, You two should go to bed,
Goodnight, Goong Hwa,
- Goodnight, - Have a good sleep,
What's wrong? Is Bo Ra feeling sick?
She seems to have a fever, so I wanted to freeze some wet towels,
Shouldn't she go see a doctor?
We'll wait and see first,
I think this will make the fever go down,
I guess I woke up all of you,
Go in, and get more sleep, Mom,
All right,
He keeps going back and forth,
It looks like he'll stay up all night,
Bo Ra, this won't do,
Let's go see a doctor,
I said I'm fine, It's just a fever,
We have some fever reducer pills, Do you want some?
I don't like taking medicine,
You should sleep, Su Hyuk, I can't sleep if you stay up,
I shouldn't have piggybacked you like that,
We should've just come back home,
I said I liked it,
I started having this fever before that anyway,
You didn't need to bring this,
I heard drinking warm milk can be helpful when you can't fall asleep,
It's probably you who can't fall asleep, not me,
But still, I went all the way to the substation,
How could he leave like that without eating my lunch box?
Gosh, I knew it,
He looked so cold-hearted when I first saw him,
Why don't you help me get over him?
Do you have a lingering affection for him by any chance?
Why would I? That's nonsense, Why would I be missing him?
- He's handsome, - Gosh, How can you smile like that?
Then should I cry instead?
I'm just saying that we shouldn't talk about him anymore,
You saw that we're over at the substation,
You saw how he acted with your own eyes,
Then you should at least stop going on patrol as partners,
I'm worried because you work with him all day long,
I'm sure that makes it hard for you to get over him,
Seriously, you're worried for nothing,
He'll be transferred to the headquarters soon,
Is that right?
I think that's a good thing,
So don't worry about me anymore,
I'll never be foolish enough to shed tears because of a man,
I swear on my lovely daughter, Woo Ri,
I swear,
It's over, Completely,
You're home,
- Why are you out here? - Nothing much,
Why didn't you come home early, eat dinner with us, and get rest?
You know how my work is,
Ju Young seems to like you so much,
I like him too,
My goodness, You look so weary,
I should tell Mother and get you some herbal medicine,
That's not necessary,
Get some for Dad, I don't need that,
But you do, Do you even eat your meals regularly?
Yes, I do, Please don't worry, Mom,
We're home,
- You're home, - Hi,
Did you hear that?
He called her "Mom",
I didn't mishear that, did I?
"Mom"?
It's a good thing,
Tae Jin grew up without a mother's love,
You should be relieved if he feels the similar affection from Mother,
What if my mom had seen that?
Tae Jin,,, Unbelievable,
Hey, Look how Mother treats Tae Jin,
She wakes up early and makes breakfast for him,
She sits beside him and has a nice chat with him,
She waits for him to come home without going to bed,
If I were Tae Jin, I would've become affectionate for her too,
When I saw him like that,
I felt sorry for him and felt like I was going to cry,
Even so, he calls his own mom "that woman", How could he?
It's because he's deeply scarred,
I'm sure he'll come around some day too,
When will that be? Mom is going to leave soon,
But she'll come back,
How would you know if she'll come back or not?
They tore down our restaurant,
How can we be sure if they will just let her leave?
What if something bad happens to her?
If you're that worried, you should at least call her often,
(Wanted List)
What's wrong with you?
Is it because you worry about me?
Why else would you act like this?
Do you still have feelings for me by any chance?
You said you no longer care about me,
Mr, Cha, you're acting odd,
Officer Moo is a police officer,
We're trying to catch a bad guy,
You said gender doesn't matter when it comes to police work,
Do you like Officer Moo by any chance?
(Studio Office)
Double check the concept,
and come up with some designs and catchphrases,
Let's eat some carbs first,,,
so my brain can work properly,
Is it already time for lunch?
You don't even check your meal time,
Are you getting spoiled by your mother and wife?
Let's go out,
Oh, my, Why are you two coming in together?
We met out front,
Mom, why did you come here?
I know you couldn't sleep well last night,
You didn't even sleep last night, but you left without eating,
Why wouldn't I be worried?
I told Bo Ra to stay home, but she left too,
You heard that she has a full schedule today,
Did you even eat lunch?
We were about to go out to have some hangover soup,
But didn't you bring us lunch?
Well, yes, But it'd be better for you to eat hot soup,
Eat this later, and go have lunch,
We'll stay here until you're back,
She's right, You must be hungry,
Why didn't you eat yet?
Then we'll go and have lunch,
- See you later, - See you,
- Let's go, - See you,
Is everything okay with your family?
What problem would happen to us?
Your family members must be at ease now,,,
since the trouble has gone,
Well, yes, They're all doing fine,
Is Officer Moo doing all right?
I hope she'll get back together with Tae Jin soon,
- I don't know about that, - To tell you the truth,
my husband also wants Tae Jin to get back with her,,,
Please, forget it,
Pardon?
Please, forget it, They're over already,
Goong Hwa has gotten over him,
No way, It's not that easy to forget someone you love,
She's very confident and smart just like me,
She wouldn't cling on to someone she broke up with,
She's not that kind of person,
She's always clear about how she feels,
Is that so?
Tae Jin is so tender-hearted and considerate,,,
that he can't bear to watch other people heartbroken,
He seems very cold-hearted to me,
Tae Jin isn't cold-hearted, I'm not saying this because he's my son,
I mean, he's my son now, isn't he?
I'm not saying this because he's my son,
but he's such a nice person,
It's rare to find a man like him these days,
I hope Officer Moo knows that,
Whatever, Hope for their reunion as much as you want,
We've decided to give up on him,
I don't even want to know about him anymore,
Is that true?
Yes,
Ju Young said that she's a very talented cook,
I know that you don't like the idea,
but kids don't give up until they give it a try,
So let Hae Chan learn to cook for now,
- But it must cost a fortune,,, - It's free,
Ju Young already told her about Hae Chan,
Still, I can't let him take the lessons for free,
Gosh, Ju Young introduced him to her,
He said she's like his sister-in-law,
Sister-in-law?
In fact, she's Officer Moo's sister-in-law,
Come to think of it, Officer Moo is so foolish,
There's no man like Tae Jin,
She can't find anyone like him in the entire country,
She should've been more patient and waited longer,
Well, I think I should go now,
Oh, my, What brings you here?
I came here to talk to Hee Jin,
Is that so? Then have a nice talk, I'll go home,
Ms, Oh,
Yes? What is it?
I'm sorry about what happened before,
Don't say that, I should be the one who should apologize,
See you later,
Hee Jin, how did it go with your landlord?
Oh, that? Our landlord hasn't said anything yet,
I guess your landlord is a nice person,
I thought something bad might happen to your restaurant,
Dad, I didn't mean to tell you this,
Tae Jin didn't tell you anything, did he?
About what?
Some thugs came and tore down the restaurant,
What did you say?
It turns out that it was the son of the man my mom is living with,,,
who sent the thugs to do that,
Mom visited me not long ago,
She said she'll leave that family and go abroad,
They tore down this place because she met us,
I'm not sure if they will let her go without causing trouble,
Dad, what if something bad happens to Mom?
Please let us know if there's any side dishes you crave for,
Seonny will prepare everything for you,
My gosh, Seonny,
Okay, good,
What should I post though?
Is there an easy-to-make dish that looks romantic?
Meatballs?
Is it too common?
Chili pepper fritters? No, no,
That's too labor-intensive,
That's right, I can't make Seonny work too hard,
Is there anything I can do to express my feelings for her?
The cutie-pie of the team is here, everyone,
That guy, Mr, Park,
always barges in whenever I'm trying to take my chances with Seonny,
Hey, did you guys have another feast for lunch?
I can easily take care of your leftovers if you have any,
People don't change, right?
Gosh, people die when they change suddenly,
Hello?
Yes,
Yes, this is Officer Moo Goong Hwa,
Pardon me? You have information about a case of murder?
(Restricted Caller ID, Record)
Then would you be able to meet us here?
No, let's meet somewhere else,
Somewhere else?
Sure, Yes, I know that place,
Yes, I'll see you there tomorrow, then,
A murder case,,, It must be the golf lounge case, right?
Isn't it obvious?
No, let's meet somewhere else,
Somewhere else?
If you walk along the main street from the substation,
you'll see an intersection, Do you know the cafe there?
Did he tell you who he is?
No,
You'll probably find out when you meet him,
He told me to come alone,
Of course you should meet him alone,
We'll hide and watch you,
We've done things like this so many times, you know,
By the way, it's very strange,
How did he call your number?
Could he be someone who knows you well?
Officer Moo, someone is here to see you,
Hello,
- You must be the chief, - Yes,
Please take good care of Officer Moo,
By the way, who are you?
I'm a friend of hers,
- I see, you're her friend, - Yes,
What brings you here?
You're almost done for the day, right?
I'll wait outside, Come out when you're done,
Then have a good day, everyone, Goodbye,
He looks familiar,
Get ready to leave for the day, Go on,
Wait, Chief,
It's getting chilly, How about we go for some hot mudfish soup?
- Gosh, I don't want to, - I know a great place,
- Cha Tae Jin speaking, - It's me, Let's meet,
I must see you today even if you're busy,
Honestly, I can't understand,
I'm tall, and I'm quite handsome too,
I'm also very rich,
And there's more,
I like you a lot,
and I love Woo Ri as if she's my own child,
Wouldn't you say I'm perfect husband material?
You won't be able to find any men who fit all the criteria,
So why are you being so foolish?
When you see a good guy, you must snag him,
You're right,
It's strange that you're readily agreeing with everything I said,
You always surprise me after being like this,
Mr, Jin,
Be honest with me, You liked that I picked you up,,,
in front of Cha Tae Jin earlier, didn't you?
Women seem to like things like that,
Showing off a new boyfriend in front of an ex-boyfriend,
I really liked Tae Jin a lot,
My feelings for him were sincere, and I'm a faithful person,
I can't jump into something new right away like this,
And I don't even want to,
I'm sorry,,,
if I confused you in any way,
Woo Ri grew up without a dad, and she likes you so much,
I guess I didn't want to take that joy from her,
- Officer Moo, - I told you,
Woo Ri said that she wants you to be her dad,
But I have no interest in becoming your wife,
It means that all of this will only end up hurting Woo Ri more,
I don't want her to end up being hurt like that because of me,
So even if she calls you in tears,
I don't want you to coddle her anymore,
Like you said, we're family now,
Please do it for me,
Go ahead, You said you wanted to tell me something,
Jin Dae Gab, that man,
is much more dangerous than you think,
You might get in huge trouble if you underestimate him,
Why did you have to tell me this in person?
Why? Are you afraid that I might make your life difficult?
Right, You may end up in a difficult position because of me,
So? Did you want to warn me to behave myself?
No, you don't need to worry about me,
Do whatever you want,
But do not let your guard down,
Chairman Jin is capable of doing anything,,,
if it's for achieving his goal,
Haven't you lived your life just like that?
It seems to be the case according to my investigation,
When it came to money, you didn't care whether people died or not,
You were known as a godmother among loan sharks,
Tae Jin,
Don't come to see me again with these ridiculous excuses,
Actually,
I want you to stay far away from my family,
That's the best thing you can do for us,
Mom, why are you sitting out here?
Tae Jin isn't home yet, you know,
Mom, please, He's not a small child,
I'll wait for him, You should go in,
What if you catch a cold?
Tae Jin broke up with that girl, right?
Yes, that's what he told me,
I ended up repeating what I did to you,
I made him break up with the woman he likes,
You're still awake?
Why didn't you tell me?
About what?
Hee Jin told me,,,
that Chairman Jin's son sent some thugs to vandalize her restaurant,
Dad,
We never know what other things he may do to us,
And now, your mother has even told him that she wants to end it,
She came to see Hee Jin and told her,,,
that she'll be abroad for a while,
so it looks like she's made up her mind to leave him,
I'm worried, I'm concerned about you,
but I also hope that nothing bad happens to your mother,
I think it'd be better if we don't,,,
I'm on my way to meet Officer Moo right now,
What did you say?
You keep avoiding me, What choice do I have?
I have to find a way to save my own life,
I found out that she is,,,
the dead police officer's wife,
Stop it right now unless you want to die!
Wait until I contact you again,
Mole, come out,
Sweetie,
Hey, you're here,
Have you been waiting for long?
- It's okay, I just got here, - Did you?
What would you like to drink?
We just wasted two hours waiting for him,
Do you mind if I go home first?
Today is my third child's birthday,
Sure, Please go ahead,
Okay,
Officer Moo, good job,
- Please send my congratulations, - Okay,
See you later,
It didn't seem like a prank call,
If he's really an informant, he'll call you again,
If not, he might be poking around,
He sounded like he used a voice changer,
I don't think he's just an informant,
Then what?
If he calls you again, call me immediately,
Don't do anything alone, It's dangerous,
You understand me, right?
I got it, You be careful too,
Don't worry,
(Open the door,)
Dad,
You knew about Do Hyun, didn't you?
- Yes, I did, - So,,,
how does Officer Moo feel about him?
Jae Hee told me,,,
that she's not interested in Do Hyun,
Why can't you answer me?
- Is it that she likes him too,,, - No,
Goong Hwa likes someone else,
What?
Are you saying that Do Hyun,,,
is crazy about a girl who likes someone else?
That stupid brat,
All right, Who is he?
He's a police officer she works with,
A police officer? What's his name?
He's Inspector Cha Tae Jin who works at her substation,
Cha Tae Jin?
Did you just say he's Cha Tae Jin?
Dad,
He's Cha Tae Jin?
Cha Tae Jin,
Dad,
You're going to give all this to your son?
No way,
This is just the beginning, Jin Dae Gab,
What are you doing here?
Do you want to have a drink?
I heard that it's Cha Tae Jin,
The man whom that girl, Moo Goong Hwa, likes,
Is that why you tried to hook Do Hyun up with her?
Were you worried that your son might marry a single mom?
- You're right, - What?
Why? Is something wrong about that?
It's been a while since we were on the same page like this,
I didn't like it either,
I didn't want Tae Jin marry a girl like her,
I guess you're determined to take this to the end,
What's there left for us to do? We're already over,
We don't even need to get a divorce,
It'll be over when I pack my stuff and leave this house,
So are you planning to pack your bag and leave?
Who says you can do that?
Do you think I'll just watch you leave?
Until I kick you out of this house,
you'll never be able to leave,
Like father, like son,
Do Hyun said the same thing to me,
He said as long as you want me here, I can't leave you,
What are you going to do with me?
Are you going to kill me?
How are you going to stop me when I walk out on my own feet?
You will never be able to stop me,
Do Hyun, I really don't think this is right,
I had a crush on Bo Ra for over 10 years,
I endured the humiliation your family gave me because of that,
But look at me now,
Bo Ra doesn't care about my broken heart because she doesn't like me,
I'm sure that it's the same for Officer Moo,
No, The more aggressive you get, the more uncomfortable she must be,
Shut your mouth,
You know well,,,
that she loves Cha Tae Jin,
I said, shut your mouth!
That woman will never look back on you,
So please come to your senses,
You're wrong,
I know that she will love me one day,,,
because I'll make it happen at all costs,
Gosh,
Thank you for your hard work,
- Hello, - Hello,
Officer Moo stepped out to buy something,
- Please wait upstairs, - Okay,
Thank you, I'll do that,
- Please come this way, - This way please,
- Hello, - Hello,
- He's here again, - I know, And he's even drunk,
- Where is Mr, Cha? - I think he's in the rest area,
Gosh,
Oh, boy,
We see each other often lately, Inspector Cha Tae Jin,
Officer Moo said you guys had broken up,
I want you to stop confusing her,,,
by using the fact that you're her partner as an excuse,
Please act like the gentleman you always are,
You haven't changed,
- You're still a coward, - What did you say?
Do you think a coward like you can be a good match for Goong Hwa?
I don't think so,
Goong Hwa is more righteous than you think,
and she's a police officer,
So you better come to your senses,
(Lovers in Bloom)
Who's the friend of Officer Moo that came to see her?
Officer Moo, were you two-timing Mr, Cha?
Don't you think that is out of line?
I think something happened to Mom,
Her face turned pale, and she ran out frantically,
Let's do as you said,
Get out of my house,
I'll make sure to catch that jerk, Mole,
So please let me investigate the case with you,
There was a murder in our jurisdiction a little while ago,
and your father is helping the suspect, Mole, hide,
It's none of your business,
Where is that jerk right now?