[Labored Breathing]
[Light Switch Clicks]
[Footsteps]
[Breathing Continues]
[Lighter Flicks]
[Flame Whooshes]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Coughing, Panting]
Pete!
Oh, my God!
[Grunting]
Pete! Pete!
Wake up, Pete!
Don't worry.
I'm gonna get some help.
[Panting]
[Camera Whirring]
You have to help us!
We've been in a car accident.
My boyfriend
is hurt really bad.
You're not from
around here, are you?
What? No. No, I'm not.
My name is Lisa.
Please help us.
Pete is unconscious.
Okay. Wait here.
I'll get the keys
for the ambulance.
- What do we have here?
- [Nurse]
A car accident.
Take him to
Operating Room number... 2.
I'm Doctor Anderson.
What happened?
There was a deer
on the road.
We didn't see it in time.
Pete lost control
of the car.
Next thing I remember,
I was lying on
a muddy field, bleeding.
Was Pete awake
when you left him?
No. No, he wasn't.
What were you doing around
here so late at night?
Nothing.
We're just on a holiday.
Just driving around
the country.
We thought that it would
be nice to see the border.
Is Pete going to be okay?
Uh, yes.
Everything's going to be fine.
Don't you worry.
I've asked the nurse to
come over as soon as possible
to take a look at this cut.
This is
a mental institution.
It's forbidden
to walk around
in the hospital.
We have many dangerous
patients here.
It's for your own safety.
Please stay here.
[Thunderclap]
[Light Buzzing]
How is Pete?
No news yet.
Pete is still in surgery.
Let's have a look
at that wound of yours.
Come with me.
[Door Squeaks, Closes]
[Latch Clicks]
Please sit down.
Let's get some light.
[Sighs]
Yeah, I think it needs
a couple of stitches.
You have
lots of films there.
Yeah, we have a few.
It's our hobby.
[Man Screams In Distance]
[Gasps]
What was that?
What?
That screaming.
That was nothing--
nothing out of the ordinary.
I have been here so long,
I don't recognize
those screams anymore.
Let me see.
It's 1974.
That means
I have been here...
25 years.
This must be an old hospital.
[Winces]
Yes.
Over a hundred years old.
Are there
many of you here?
Just a few
on the night shift.
But more come
in the morning,
'cause we have almost
a hundred patients here.
It's ready.
It's not much to look at,
but you're not
bleeding anymore.
[Thunder Rumbling]
I'm going to see how
your boyfriend is doing.
I'll be right back.
You can go down
to the break room and get
yourself a cup of coffee.
[Groans]
[Thunderclap]
[Sputtering]
[Sighs]
[Thunderclap]
[Chuckles]
-[Distant Scream]
- [Switch Clicks]
[Distant Voice]
Help! Help!
[Distant Whimpering]
[Distant Panting, Crying]
[Clattering]
[Whimpering]
[Grunts]
[Heavy Breathing]
[Gasping]
Kill me! Kill me now!
Didn't I tell you it was
forbidden to walk around
in here?
It would have been
my responsibility if something
had happened to you.
Well, I-I didn't know.
I heard a voice--
We have many murderers
and rapists in here.
Death isn't the worst thing
that could happen to you.
[Faint Whimpering]
I came to tell you
the operation was a success.
Everything's
going to be fine.
When can I see him?
Straightaway if you'd like.
But I'd advise against it.
He's still sleeping.
Maybe you should think
about sleep yourself.
You look tired.
-[Man Whimpers, Mutters]
- [Banging On Door]
What's-- What's wrong
with his eye?
It's missing.
Another patient gouged out
his eye and ate it.
Come along.
I'll get you a room
for the night.
I would rather
check into a hotel.
You can't get out of here
until the morning
when the bus comes.
We're a long way
from the city.
There's a raging storm outside.
The telephone lines
have been cut.
And besides, a taxi wouldn't
come here anyway.
Nurse, prepare a room
for her on this floor.
I think Room number 7
is available.
Good night, Lisa.
Tomorrow's a brand-new day.
[Thunderclap]
[Nurse]
I don't think that works.
Good night.
Could you please
leave it open?
It feels strange
sleeping here.
Stay here no matter what.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Thunderclap]
[Lightbulb Shatters]
[Camera Whirring]
[Clicks]
- [Growling]
- [Distorted Voices Echoing]
- My eye! You ate my eye!
- [Screaming]
[Thunderclap]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
[Door Creaking]
[Door Thuds]
[Gasps]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Thunderclap]
[Gasps]
Pete.
[Grunts, Panting]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
Didn't you lock the door?
[Nurse]
I can hear her!
She's in the basement!
[Panting]
What are you doing?
Come here.
You missed her.
You imbecile!
[Camera Whirring]
Oh, my God!
[Gasping, Choking]
[Coughing]
Lisa--
[Gasping]
- Lisa.
- Pete.
What have they done?
Lisa, you have to kill me.
No.
[Grunting]
[Stammers]
They are insane.
[Gasping]
They will never stop.
Please. It hurts!
I can't take it anymore.
Please end this now.
I can't.
I'm gonna get you out.
No! No!
[Gasping]
[Sobbing, Choking]
No. Save yourself.
Look at me, baby.
I'm gonna die anyways.
If you love me,
you'll do it now!
Please!
Just do it, baby.
[Sobbing]
Just do it.
[Sobbing, Muttering]
[Panting]
I can't do this!
It's the only way.
[Stammers]
I love you, baby.
I love you too.
[Ax Clatters On Floor]
[Sobs]
[Crying]
Brava! I was right.
I felt it immediately
when I first met you.
You're a natural-born
killer.
Are you ready
for your grand finale, Lisa?
[Panting]
Stop.
Please.
Oh, don't worry.
You're going to be a big star.
[Man]
Cut!
[Whirring Stops]
Cut, cut, cut.
What happened?
The production designer
didn't do her job properly.
You can see a reflection
of the camera in the mirror.
Anna!
- Do we have to do it again?
- Yes.
What's wrong?
You didn't fix the mirror.
You can see the camera in it.
Put something on it,
and do it quickly.
We haven't got all day.
What time is it?
Almost 5:30.
Is there time
for a smoke?
Yeah, sure, sure.
Okay. Chop-chop, people.
Get to work.
You're doing really well.
This is gonna be great.
Thank you.
This film is gonna be like
a Saw or a Hostel
kind of thing, you know.
Well, I hope
there'll be many sequels.
Yeah. I have
some ideas about that.
Silent Creek II: The Beginning.
Well, none of that
prequel stuff.
I mean,
something that gives me
more work.
Well, I'm not really sure
if your character's
gonna stay alive after all.
[Groans]
We might have to do
an alternative ending.
That was excellent,
right?
Yes, Bruce.
I think the classic
Christopher Lee approach
is the way to go.
Absolutely.
So you're happy then.
Let's keep going.
Well, I was thinking
that maybe we could do
a couple of takes...
where we take it easy
a bit, you know?
Not overdo it so much.
Mmm, I don't think so.
I think this is
the way to go.
Believe me, I know how
to create an unforgettably
evil character.
You're looking at a man whom
even Sam Raimi couldn't convince
of his acting technique.
And that boy's
got a vision!
Yeah.
I suppose you're right.
We should stick to the genre.
I'll see you in a bit, Bruce.
How's it going?
Good.
Yeah. I think this is
gonna be fine.
Yeah, I'm sure it will.
The setting's great,
but we could have shot this
in L.A., you know.
But shooting it here
is just as well.
This location is awesome.
This is the actual place
where the murders took place.
It's ready. It's free.
This would have cost
a fortune in L.A.
Well, the walls
and the ceiling,
they're perfectly decayed.
You know, actually,
I was thinking we should
get a couple of angled shots.
You know, just to do
the place justice.
Yeah, I suppose you're right.
I still think it's wrong.
I know that hospitals were
a bit run down in the '70s,
but they weren't as bad as this.
It's a film.
It's the Soviet Union.
Anything
could have happened.
It's set in Finland.
[Scoffs] Whatever!
Same thing. No one cares
about the tiny details.
They're interested
in the bigger picture.
Anyway, it's a horror film,
right? Anything happens.
Yeah.
Whatever. It's your film.
Your name, your problem.
Look. How long
till we can continue?
About 10 minutes.
You've got five.
What's up with these Finns?
Why's there always
problems with them?
Not enough California sun
and vitamin "D."
Yeah. Too right.
Lisa though--
She's easy to work with.
Yes.
I'm just gonna go
listen to some more praise.
What's he smiling about?
Fucking dickhead.
Yeah. I mean, doesn't he realize
that the film is total crap?
Yeah.
And what the fuck was up
with that nightmare scene?
He's making up these
extra scenes all the time.
I wish
I'd fucking known this.
You know, I would have been
the boom operator for
the next season of Idols.
Mmm.
Yeah.
And even that
would have been better
than this shit.
Yeah, and we'd get paid
on time.
You know, if he still
hasn't paid us on Friday,
I'm leaving.
¶¶¶¶ [Stereo: Rock]
¶¶¶¶ [Man Singing]
Powder fix.
Please spread it on evenly.
I've got my close-up shots soon.
Somebody's got to look good
in this film.
Okay. So let's stick
with the same foundation
you had on this morning.
Yeah. It's stayed on
pretty well.
Sit down.
I can't reach
if you're standing up.
Speaking of reaching,
I was once in a film...
with Michael Douglas,
Kathleen Turner
and Danny DeVito.
It was a black comedy.
And all the actors--
all of us--
were playing practical jokes
on each other throughout
the whole shoot.
One day, we were in this
very small, hot studio.
Well, at the end of the day,
I hit the showers.
I knew DeVito
was right behind me.
Then I remembered this
absolutely disgusting joke
he played on me.
Now, I'm coming out of
the shower and I'm thinking,
payback time!
Me, Bruce-- six-point-two.
Danny-- four-point-
absolutely nothing!
Mmm.
I take the showerhead.
I put it all the way
at the top of the shower.
And then I leave,
looking back
and see DeVito go in.
[Chuckles]
I was pissing in my pants
with laughter--
this image of him
jumping up and down
to grab that showerhead.
Did DeVito get you back?
[Chuckles]
No.
It was just a short gig for me.
Just a couple of days
of filming.
Have you been doing
a lot of acting
in big Hollywood films?
Oh, sure.
I was in James Cameron's
Pariah II.
I've been in a bunch
of Steven Seagal films.
Steve is a close
personal friend of mine.
He's helped me with my acting.
I even know a couple
of Finns. I was a corpse
in Renny Harlin's Prison.
But this is something else.
To think that they're making
a film about something...
that actually happened
30 years ago on this
exact location.
Yeah, it's pretty freaky.
I read about this...
Dr. Anderson,
how he started to call himself
"The Auteur"...
because he was fascinated
with French film directors
from the '70s.
You know, like Godard
and Truffaut.
Although he filmed,
tortured and killed
his own patients for real.
Ha!
I don't think that's part
of the French New Wave!
I can't understand
why anyone would want to make,
let alone watch, snuff films.
[Scoffs]
What's the difference between
a snuff film and Big Brother?
People secretly want
to watch other people
behind a closed curtain.
They want to see
someone's other side,
the side they normally
don't see.
I think he was
basically good.
Nobody could be that bad.
And that's
what fascinates me
about this character.
I plan to portray him
as being this touching
and misunderstood man.
I know what
the audience likes.
Believe me.
[Panting]
Do you like that?
Yeah.
You want me
to keep going?
Yeah.
Then I want something too.
What?
I want a sequel.
You're gonna be a star.
[Panting]
Yeah.
Get ready to scream!
[Screaming]
Cut! Yes!
Excellent, people.
Good work. Good shot.
Darius--
[Clicks Tongue]
Very good. Very good.
Right. Let's move on.
Next scene. Next scene.
[Line Beeps, Clicks]
Hey, Jerry, it's Steven
calling from Finland.
Hi, Steven.
How you doing?
I'm good, thanks.
How are you?
You in L.A.?
Well, you know us producers--
always working.
Actually, I'm at
the studio right now.
I'm having a meeting
with the studio executives
about your film.
Everybody's really
ramped up about it.
Okay. That sounds great.
Listen. I'm a little bit
worried that there's a problem
with the funding.
Is everything okay?
No, no.
There's no problem.
Everything's in order.
Don't you worry.
Okay. Good. Because the Finnish
crew said they would quit
if there's no money by Friday.
There will be.
I'm on it.
Look, um, I gotta go now.
The meeting has started.
Call you later. Bye.
Okay. Bye.
[Woman Giggling]
Is this all right,
Jerry?
A little bit lower,
darlin'.
All right.
[Groans]
We'll start recording
the background sounds
at the other end.
[Sighs] I don't think
it even matters what
we're doing in here.
This project will never
see the light of day anyway.
I can't believe he decided
to dub the whole soundtrack
later on.
Yeah. With those actors.
Good luck with that.
[Scoffs]
Like that would work.
Hey, listen to this.
Yeah, just a moment.
[Whirring]
[Water Dripping]
Yeah, that sounds great.
And... rolling.
[Indistinct Voice, Distant]
- Did you hear that?
- Hear what?
Did you hear
someone talking?
No, I didn't hear a thing.
Do you still hear it?
No. Not anymore.
Maybe it came from upstairs.
Hey, what's that?
I don't know.
Looks like
a sealed room.
You know it can't be.
The only place we can't
get in is the attic.
It is a room,
and there's a light on.
That's impossible.
Hospital's electricity
has been cut off.
Yeah?
No. It's been cut off
for a long time.
For years.
Something's wrong.
Let's go and get the others.
Hey, hey.
Is this
what I think it is?
We've found them.
The Auteur's snuff films.
We've found them!
How is this possible?
Didn't the police take
all the films in the '70s?
Yes, but they found
a small storage room
next to the coffee lounge.
He had hidden a small
snuff library behind some
other legitimate films.
And if I have it right,
the whole hospital
was turned upside down.
Yes, but they didn't find
these ones.
The police were suspicious
because they couldn't find
the darkroom...
where the films had been
developed, let alone where
they would watch them.
During the investigation,
the authorities compared
the list of the patients...
with those
of the natural deaths
that occurred...
during the senior
physician's time.
The records showed that there
should have been more victims.
But there was
no hard evidence
until now.
[Lisa] Are you sure
we should do that?
[Woman] I agree.
We should call the police.
[Man] Oh, come on!
Let's see what it is.
It might be nothing.
Steven, don't turn it on.
I sure as hell
am not watching anything.
It's insane.
You don't have to watch
if you don't want to.
- You can leave.
But I'm gonna to stay.
- Why?
We are making a film based on
these snuff films, people.
A film about the man who's
responsible for all of this.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity...
to see what material
he really produced.
Do you really want to let this
opportunity pass you by?
This is the best
preproduction research ever.
Stay or leave. I don't care.
I'm gonna watch the film.
[Gasps]
[Woman Whimpering]
[Gasping, Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Woman Whimpering]
[Muffled Screaming]
[Blow Lands]
[Screaming, Sobbing]
[Sobbing Continues]
[Coughing]
That is fucking sick!
I've had enough.
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Hammering Continues]
[Panting]
[Darius]
Wow. That was hard-core.
Let's go out for a smoke.
Steven, what are you doing?
What does it look like?
I'm gonna watch
another film.
Suit yourself, man.
I'm leaving.
[Soundtrack Popping]
[Man Gasping]
[Gasping Continues]
No! Please!
[Screaming]
Oh, my God!
[Screaming Continues]
[Screaming Continues, Louder]
I can't believe it.
How come no one
ever found them?
It makes me sick
just thinking
about it.
[Man]
If you ask me, Steven's
getting a bit too excited.
This is seriously fucked up.
We should call the police.
No, I don't think
we should call them
just yet.
Why not?
Well, if we call them now,
they're just gonna come
and shut the place down.
We can say good-bye
to our film and our pay.
I don't care
about that.
I can't afford to walk away
from this film.
I'm flat broke, and this is
my ticket to better jobs.
What difference is it gonna
make if we wait a while?
These things happened
30 years ago.
We'll call them when we've
finished shooting.
We'll do that.
I need some rest.
I'm getting to bed.
Good night, guys.
Good night.
[Sniffling]
What's wrong?
Mari, what's wrong?
I'm totally messed up.
Really scared.
Don't think about it anymore.
Everything's all right now.
[Exhales]
[Breathing Heavily]
Okay, guys!
I have a change of plan.
I've got a new vision.
We're gonna shoot
the torture scene
in the boiler room first.
[Anna] The set is not ready.
Well, I'm sure you can
sort that out.
What's this?
Don't worry.
You'll be like
the original scream queen--
Jamie Lee Curtis in Halloween.
Okay, right.
Fifteen minutes, rehearsal.
Get your shit together.
Lisa, Bruce,
are you ready?
I'm ready.
Let's try to do this
in one take.
I hate retakes
of a scene like this.
It ruins your concentration.
Yeah, well, we'll try,
Bruce, okay?
So, camera?
We're ready.
Okay. Right.
Let's do this, people.
Sound?
Rollin'.
Camera?
- Rolling.
- Slate up.
Okay,
and remember, Lisa--
with feeling.
And action.
[Gasping]
[Muffled Shouting]
Boom shadow.
I can see it
in the background. Cut!
Just wasting film
here, morons.
[Bruce]
I'm telling you, in Hollywood
a mistake like this...
would cost tens of thousands
of dollars.
Time is money.
Could you please move
somewhere else, Klasu?
I can't.
There's no room.
Why don't you move the
fucking lights for once?
You move your ass, Finnish boy.
[Shouting In Finnish]
What?
What the fuck did you just say?
"What the fuck
did you just say?"
Come on, guys. Cut it out.
We can't move the lights.
The room's too small.
Move the fill
closer to the wall.
Klasu,
can you fit there?
I guess I have to.
[Steven]
Okay, good.
Let's take this from the top.
Chop-chop, people.
Sound?
Rollin'.
Camera?
Rolling.
Slate up.
Action.
[Gasping]
Pull harder.
Pull harder, Bruce.
It doesn't look
fucking real. Anna,
do you have a lighter?
[Muffled Shouting]
Bruce, take this lighter.
Burn her ear.
-[Lighter Flicks]
- That's it. Yeah.
[Screams]
No, no, no!
Do it for real!
The hell you will!
Steven, what the fuck?
Yeah, maybe that's not
a good idea, Bruce.
Sorry. Um--
We'll just do
the suffocation after all
and maybe add some blood?
Anna, could you
do that for me?
But, Bruce,
that was good work.
Okay. So let's go again.
Take three.
Sound?
Rollin'.
Camera?
Rolling.
Slate up.
And action.
¶¶¶¶ [Stereo: Pop]
Lisa, this was
an excellent day.
You got some great material.
Good. I noticed
you were on fire.
Ah. You too.
You know, I'm telling you,
you have a great career
ahead of you.
With your talent,
you really should
consider moving to L.A.
[Lisa]
Really?
You think so?
Definitely.
Would you
help me getting
started there?
Of course.
I have plenty of contacts.
That sounds exciting.
I'm ready for anything.
[Whirring]
What you doing?
I'm listening to the background
sounds that we recorded
in the basement yesterday.
What about them?
I thought I heard
something down there.
[Whirring]
Maybe we caught it on tape.
[Tape Rewinding]
[Whirring,
Volume Increases]
[Faint Clang]
[Distant Screaming]
There.
Did you hear it?
Yeah.
What the hell is that?
Play it again.
[Tape Rewinding]
[Whirring]
[Faint Clang]
[Distant Screaming]
[Tape Recorder Clicks Off]
I don't know.
[Whirring, Rewinding]
[Whirring]
[Clattering]
Hmm.
[Gasps]
God!
Who knows what secrets are
hidden behind this door.
We'll never know.
None of the keys fit the lock.
It's a strong door.
We wont be able
to break it down.
It's like they say
in the movies--
Some doors
should never be opened.
[Heavy Breathing]
Steven!
[Coughs]
Stop it.
Stop it!
Fucking asshole!
I told you to stop!
You sick fuck!
Get the fuck out of here!
And stay the fuck
away from me!
Fucking bitch!
[Grunts]
- Ahhh!
- [Gasps]
[Scream Echoes]
[Gasps]
[Sighs]
[Distant Laugh]
[Distant Grunt]
[Scream Echoes, Faint]
[Film: Man Grunting]
[Grunting Continues]
[Groaning]
[Whirring]
[Grunts]
[Groaning]
[Screaming]
[Door Opens]
Time for work, guys.
Come on. Let's go.
Get your stuff.
Wake up.
We haven't got all day.
[Door Closes]
[Groans]
[Breathing Heavily]
[Screaming]
Fucking cut!
It just doesn't
look real enough, okay?
You need to put in
more energy, okay?
Feel your character.
Action.
- [Screaming]
- Cut! What the fuck
is this, Bruce?
And you, scream.
He's cutting you open.
From the top.
Camera. Action.
Fucking cut!
Cut! Cut!
You bunch
of incompetent fucks!
What the fuck
is wrong with you? Huh?
Do any of you
have any fucking vision?
Do you know how to make
a fucking motion picture?
Mike! Darius!
Where did you leave
your skills? L.A.?
Bruce, you're
a fucking professional actor.
You're acting like
a wet pile of shit.
Sort it out. Fuck!
This script
I wrote last night.
This is the new fucking film.
This is what I'm
gonna be remembered for.
This is the fucking masterpiece.
Wrap your heads around that,
the lot of you.
And will you fucking
Finnish film school fucks...
from whatever fucking
unpronounceable town
you came from...
go back there and learn
your fucking skills?
Fuck!
Fucking fucks!
[Lisa]
Hi, guys.
What's up?
[Erno]
It turned out
we're having a day off.
Mr. Visionary
went ape shit.
[Darius]
Steven's been
acting strange all morning.
No idea
what's wrong with him.
And Bruce got really upset.
Well, you don't
hear me complaining.
I'm fine having a day off.
Me and Erno bought this
for the wrap party,
but... fuck it.
Should I check up
on Steven?
No. Let him sulk.
He'll be all right.
Just let him clear
his head for a minute.
There's nothing to worry about.
- We'll get back to work
tomorrow morning.
- [Clanging]
[Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
Ah. Tallyho.
[All]
Tallyho, bitches!
[Man Screaming]
[Electricity Sizzling]
[Screaming Continues]
[Sizzling Continues]
[Sizzling]
[Screaming]
[Projector Stops]
Fuck!
¶¶ Looking for the others ¶¶
[Speaking, Indistinct]
¶¶ Searching every room
in the base ¶¶¶¶
Hey, where you going, Mari?
I'm going to bed.
Okay. Good night.
Come on. Don't go.
We'll play
Spin the Bottle.
I'll take a rain check.
What's wrong
with Spin the Bottle?
What if someone sees us?
No one's going
to see us.
Trust me.
[Camera Whirring]
[Snores]
Bruce.
Bruce, wake up.
Steven,
what's going on?
- Good. You're awake.
We need to start filming.
- At this time of night?
What is this?
We'll redo the scene
from yesterday.
- I know what was wrong
with it now.
- What?
We should have
shot it at night.
I know what to do now,
and we'll be back
on schedule tomorrow.
I'm glad to hear that.
I was a bit worried.
Okay. Well, come
to the same room. We'll
get it over and done with.
Don't forget your costume.
See you in five.
Ah, good morning,
I guess.
Ah, you're
already tied down.
Well, I'm ready to go.
Good. You're already here.
So, this is how it goes.
We're gonna shoot you
from behind that observation
window over there.
Everybody's there waiting.
This is the tool
that you'll kill her with.
[Whirring]
It's one of those
fake tools. You know? See?
[Whirring]
That's good.
So it goes like this.
You come in.
The camera's
gonna follow you.
Walk up to her.
Look into her eyes.
Deliver your lines.
Press this hard
into the top of her head
and kill her.
Sure thing.
Cool. Right.
I'll go and see
if we're ready.
Hey, Darius.
Everything cool,
Darius?
Okay.
So here you go.
Ready when you are,
Bruce.
[Whirring]
[Camera Whirring]
Let's ventilate
your thoughts a bit.
[Chuckles]
[Whirring]
[Screaming]
-[Whirring]
- [Screaming]
Cut the cameras!
What's gone wrong?
She's bleeding!
Steve, what is going on?
She's hurt!
Cut the camera!
Cut it, Steve!
[Doorknob Rattling]
Cut! Cut! Cut!
I don't know
what's happened!
[Whirring]
Mike! Darius!
Is anybody there?
I can't see!
I don't know
what went wrong!
She's dead!
[Yelling, Indistinct]
I'm gonna take a shower.
Oh, I hate going in there.
It's so far away.
You want me to come with you?
We could go together.
No. It's all right.
See you in a minute.
[Camera Whirring, Stops]
[Camera Whirring]
Hello!
Is someone there?
[Man On Stereo]
¶¶ Killing time
Killing time ¶¶
¶¶ I'm goin' down
down, down, down ¶¶
¶¶ Killing time
Killing time ¶¶
¶¶ I'm goin' down, down
down, down, down ¶¶¶¶
Hello.
Is anybody there?
Guys, I know.
Hospital, night,
girl in a shower.
Come on and stop it.
¶¶¶¶ [Stops]
- Steven. What's going on?
- Mari, get out!
Get out of there!
Steven's gone mad!
Get out! Get out!
He's gone insane!
[Mari Shuddering]
Rise and shine, Bruce.
Bruce?
Morning.
Already here?
Some of us
never left.
Have you
seen Mari anywhere?
No. We just came. Why?
She went
for a shower last night
and never came back.
Hmm. Maybe she
found better company.
Guess so.
Have you seen Steven?
No.
[Sighs]
I haven't
seen anybody.
I couldn't
find Bruce either.
Where is everybody?
I'd bet my money
on finding Steven
in the theater...
with all those
sick films.
Yeah.
Wait.
Look at this.
Let's do what it says.
I don't want to see
any more of that shit.
What the--
Steven.
Let me go.
We are ready.
The camera is rolling.
Slate up.
- I said slate up!
You know what to do!
- Oh, my God.
[Crying]
Scene 16, take one.
Steven!
Steven, let me go.
Action!
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Grunting]
[Crying]
Don't be jealous, guys.
You all have a role
waiting for you in this film.
Sorry, Lisa.
There's no sequel for you.
Steven. Let me go.
Steven.
Let me go.
[Crying]
I'm sorry, but Steven
is not here anymore.
[Whimpering]
There's been a rewrite.
[Whimpers]
Steven.
You can call me
The Auteur.
No. No! No!
No! No! No! No! No!
No! No! No!
No! No!
No! No! No! No!
No! No! No!
[Screaming]
Oh, my God!
[Screaming Continues]
Oh, my God.
[Gasping]
[Screaming]
[Laughing]
[Darius]
He's fucking insane.
We can't stay here.
[Darius]
We should stick together
and wait for the police.
I can't get through.
There's no signal.
How? The phones
were working
perfectly well before.
I think we should get the hell
out of here right now.
[Lisa] I agree.
Are you ready
for the final act?
I fixed this camera
just for you people.
So you better pay attention.
I had a little disagreement
with Bruce on how his role
should be played.
I hate overacting.
I think we need
to cut it down a bit.
No! No!
Steven, you can't kill me!
I'm your male lead!
No, Bruce.
You were the actor playing
the part of The Auteur.
But I'm the real deal.
-[Saw Buzzing]
- You're going straight
to the cutting room floor!
No!
No! Oh, no!
- [Screaming]
- [Laughing]
-[Laughing Continues]
- No! No!
-[Bruce]
Oh, no!
- [Vomiting]
[Engine Grinding]
[Grinding]
[Erno]
Come on.
I swear to God,
if I catch that fuck--
We must go on foot.
Erno, get out.
Let's go.
Shit!
Guys, I can't find Mike.
Come on.
What?
Mike.
Mike!
We have to find him.
Where have you looked?
Wait. You're not seriously
planning on going in there?
We must find Mike
before something
happens to him.
Bullshit!
That's fucking crazy.
There's one man in there.
If we stay together,
we'll make it.
No, we won't.
I've felt it ever since
we found those snuff films.
And then I heard it
on Erno's tapes.
There's something down there,
and it ain't no man.
Just shut up.
The line has
to be drawn here,
no further.
We're gonna make him pay
for what he's done.
Now, let's go.
Please, Klasu. Come on.
Can't you see?
This is like a bad movie.
I ain't coming.
Please, you must.
You go.
I'll be fine.
Well, I'll be sorry.
Come on, man.
[Lisa]
Mike.
Mike!
What the fuck? Anna.
[Exhales]
[Camera Whirring, Stops]
[Clicks]
Mike!
Mike.
[Lisa]
[Sighs]
[Banging]
[Gasps]
We heard banging.
It's just the window.
Where is he?
Let's keep
moving, guys.
[Distorted]
Klasu.
Come on, you fuck.
[Groans]
[Camera Whirring]
[Whirring Continues]
Mike?
Hey, guys. Up here.
What the hell?
Look.
What's this?
[Darius]
What is this? Who made this?
It's not handheld.
It's got dolly shots
and lights and everything.
[Whirring]
[Lisa]
Steven hasn't made this.
He's in the shots.
And the camera is moving.
[Whirring]
Are you ready for your
grand finale, Lisa?
This is my footage.
I shot this.
Stop.
It's the scene that kept
going wrong because of your
reflection on the mirror.
- Wait a minute.
- [Whirring]
[Whirring Stops]
Skeleton Crew?
What happened
to Silent Creek"?
It's us.
The Skeleton Crew--
it's us.
-[Darius] What the hell
you talking about?
- Look at us.
We are
the Skeleton Crew.
This is about us. All of it.
Don't you get it?
We're in a mental institution
in the middle of nowhere.
Phones stopped working.
People are going missing
one by one.
And Steven has gone mad
and has started
killing people.
- I wanna see how this ends.
-[Erno] This is
a fucking joke.
When did this happen?
You got
to be fucking kidding me.
[Camera Whirring]
I can't see anything.
Is there a camera
hidden in the wall?
No. There's
nothing there.
Somehow we're
inside a film,
a horror film.
That's why things
have gone like they have.
I went all lezzy with Mari,
and I'm as straight
as an arrow, for God's sake.
People are going missing
one at a time.
The phones and cars
are not working.
And Steven has turned
into this... serial killer.
Are you out of your mind?
Think about it.
How come we found
the original films
all of a sudden?
How come the police
didn't find them
30 years ago...
when they blew
the whole hospital
to pieces?
How has Steven managed
to kill two people...
without anyone hearing
or seeing anything?
Come on.
[Anna] There will
be more killings.
Remember the rules
of horror films.
The group is being killed
one by one in the weirdest
ways possible.
There's always someone
who survives.
Like the main character.
Well, sometimes.
[Camera Whirring]
[Stops]
- [Grunting]
- Don't bother.
It won't open. I tried.
I don't even know
how I got in here. I--
I remember
going to bed.
Then I woke up in here.
I saw you sitting
over there, and--
There's no way
out of here.
If it hadn't been for you,
I'd be out of here by now.
Really?
Well, find a way
out of here now.
[Squeaking]
[Switch Clicks]
Mike, how do you
like my light?
- Steven.
Steve, is that you?
-[Steven] No.
There's no Steven here.
Klasu, I thought you Finns
could handle your liquor.
Fuck you, Steven.
Let us go.
You've had your fun.
No. Not yet.
We need to play
a little game first.
What the fuck is this?
Hey. Hey, Steven, this
isn't fucking funny anymore.
Get down here
and open this door.
I want out of this hole.
Shut up.
You're wasting your time.
He's insane.
- Mari and Bruce are dead.
- What?
That dickless fuck
killed them.
Yeah, you hear me?
You're a dickless fuck!
Get down here,
and I'll rip
your fucking head off!
Calm down, Klasu.
I'm on your side.
All these years
the lighting guys have
been fucking you around.
"Move over there.
The lights are going here."
"There's a boom shadow
on the wall."
Well, now it's time
for you to get
some payback.
And I know you want it.
Don't let your people down.
Rules are simple, gentlemen.
The one who wins, walks.
[Camera Whirring]
[Groans]
[Grunting]
[Both Grunting]
[Groaning]
[Squishes]
[Groans]
- [Whirring Stops]
- Cut. That's a wrap.
Excellent.
You fuck.
Let me go now.
Next scene.
No.
Open the fucking door.
Just wait a while.
We have
to light you up a bit.
[Whirring]
What are you doing?
Open the fucking door!
[Grunting]
Just a warning.
Things might get
a little bit hot.
- I'm gonna fucking kill you!
- Get ready for your close-up.
[Panting]
Fuck. Shit.
[Grunting, Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
Hey, guys, listen up.
Klasu is really messed up.
You've got to find him
right now.
I'll stay here by the monitor.
If I see Steven,
I'll let you know.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Speaker Whines]
Steven!
[Steven]
Can I have
your attention, please?
I have
an announcement to make.
The following scene
may be unsuitable
for a young audience.
It contains violence
and bad language.
Thank you.
I almost forgot.
The crew in the attic
may experience
some loud noises...
that may also be hazardous
to their health.
[Chuckling]
[Whirring]
[Panting]
Fuck!
[High-pitched Tone]
- [Tone Grows Louder]
- [Grunting]
[Screaming]
[Tone, Whirring Stop]
[Steven Laughing]
This isn't gonna work.
Shit. We can't get out.
- Let's go to the basement.
- Are you crazy?
We are in
a horror film, right?
So we must play
by the rules
if we want to survive.
Everybody keep moving.
Lisa, step aside.
Let me lead the way.
In here. Let's go.
Shit. It's a dead end.
You're getting us nowhere.
Follow me.
Ah, shut up.
Watch your step.
Stop it. We know you like
to be the main character.
I get that.
But will you just
shut the fuck up?
I'm just trying
to get us out of here--
So... it seems he wasn't
the star of the film
after all.
Stay away from us,
you sick fuck.
Do we have a winner?
I think
I'll save you for last.
I want that bitch first.
[Whirring]
[Screams]
Anna, don't run.
[Lisa]
Wait.
Hey.
Let me go.
I'm gonna die anyway.
I won't leave you.
We'll make it through this.
I swear.
No. He can
come and go
as he pleases.
We're safe nowhere.
I want out
of here, please.
Trust me.
It's easy for you to say.
You're the main
character here.
I'm not.
[Lisa]
Hey, wait!
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Grunting]
[Camera Whirring]
[Rumbling]
[Screaming]
[Whirring]
[Whirring Stops]
Thank you, Darius.
That's a wrap.
What? Check the gate?
There is no second take.
[Thunder Rumbling]
-[Clanging]
-[Saw Revving]
Anna!
I'm sorry, Lisa.
I have to try this.
Please forgive me.
[Saw Buzzing]
[Laughs]
Whoever wrote this script
should have his ass removed.
[Buzzing]
[Saw Revving]
[Panting]
[Grunts]
Oh, my God.
[Light Buzzing]
-[Squeaking, Clanging]
- [Panting]
[Buzzing]
[Grunting]
[Door Squeaking]
[Screams]
Oh, my God.
Lisa.
Anna.
What has he done?
Lisa.
[Crying]
You have to kill me.
No.
I'm hurting.
I'm hurting bad. Please.
I can't take this anymore.
Do it before he comes.
- No. I'm gonna
get you out.
- [Screams, Cries]
Look at me.
I'm gonna die anyway.
If you care for me,
you'll do it... now.
- I can't do this.
- It's the only way.
[Crying]
[Anna's Voice]
Somehow we're
inside a film.
[Klasu's Voice]
Can't you see?
This is like a bad movie.
[Anna's Voice]
The Skeleton Crew--
it's us.
[Bruce's Voice]
Are you ready
for your grand finale, Lisa?
[Anna's Voice]
Lisa, you have to kill me.
[Pete's Voice]
[Steven]
Cut.
You can call me
The Auteur.
[Ax Clatters]
[Whirring]
[Body Hits Floor]
No! No!
You're not gonna ruin
my film, you stupid bitch.
Finish the scene.
Finish it!
- [Clicks]
- You're the one
with no sequel.
Anna.
Did you really think
you could kill me?
In this film,
I have the final cut.
No, you don't.
[Clicks]
I can fuck up your film.
[Gunshot]
[Camera Whirring]
[Labored Breathing]
[Lighter Flicks]
[Flame Whooshes]
The director's cut.
Lights.
Camera.
Action.
¶¶ They lie about the pain ¶¶
¶¶ Truth on their empty faces ¶¶
¶¶ And they stay awake ¶¶
¶¶ For you ¶¶
¶¶ To be safe ¶¶
¶¶ Saints keep breaking ¶¶
¶¶ But entirely holding
their own ¶¶
¶¶ Never giving in ¶¶
¶¶ They've hidden
all their sins ¶¶
¶¶ Deep down within ¶¶
¶¶ Undergone everything ¶¶
¶¶ For you ¶¶
¶¶ To be safe ¶¶
¶¶ Saints keep breaking ¶¶
¶¶ But entirely holding
their own ¶¶
¶¶ Never giving in ¶¶
¶¶ Godforsaken ¶¶
¶¶ And doomed to bare their ¶¶
¶¶ Souls ¶¶
¶¶ And even if they find ¶¶
¶¶ What divides them
from grace ¶¶
¶¶ They keep on breaking ¶¶
¶¶ And even if they were ¶¶
¶¶ Reprieved from their pain ¶¶
¶¶ They keep on breaking ¶¶
¶¶ Still pure in their hearts ¶¶
¶¶ In their acclaims ¶¶¶¶
[Man]
Aw, mate,
that really sucked.
Weren't even
any fucking tits.
[Heart Pounding]