Dr. Weiss says
that it's perfectly normal
to dream about it again
from time to time.
I mean, after all,
dreams are one way
that our minds deal
with frightening experiences.
I know.
See, what's why Valerie-
That's why Dr. Weiss says
that your sister has problems,
you see.
She's never been able
to release her-
I know.
He told me all about it.
Thanks.
Do you want me
to make an appointment?
Maybe you should talk to him.
Morn, I'm okay.
It was just
the same old dream.
Courtney, you're
gonna be late for school.
Coming!
Are you sure you're all right?
Mom, I'm fine.
I really am.
You be careful now, okay?
Remember I love you.
I love you, too.
Bye.
H'
Courtney!
- Hi.
What were you looking at?
A dead bird.
Ugh. You are so weird sometimes.
Is your mom still buggin' you
about your makeup and stuff?
She just picks
on the weirdest little things.
Man, sometimes I wish
she would just-
Fall into a black hole?
Yeah.
Oh, I love this song.
# I wanna be your
Tokyo convertible I
# I wanna have fun with you a'
# I just love going
through the motions I
# I wanna be your
Tokyo convertible I
# I wanna have fun with you a'
# I just love going
through the motions I
# I wanna live
in the love lane I
Oh, look! Look, it's him!
Who?
Matt Arbicost.
Isn't he the one you like?
Well, yeah, we had lunch
a couple of times.
Oh, God. Talk to him, Courtney.
He likes you.
He told Darcy Williams
he thought you were cute.
- Really?
- Yes! Hi, Matt.
Hi. How's it going"?
Fine. How are you?
All right for a school day.
You doing anything after class?
Um-.
We're practicing with our band.
Courtney's in it with me,
Sheila Barrington,
and Sally Burns.
You should come over.
It's a lot of fun.
Yeah, it's a lot of fun.
I'll try to make it.
My garage, four o'clock.
Bye.
See? I told you he liked you.
You know, you haven't gone
with anybody since junior high.
I know. I'm just kinda-
Shy. I know.
Listen, we'll-
We'll invite him up to,
uh, Sheila's dad's place
this weekend.
Well, I haven't asked my mom,
so I really don't know
if I can go.
You have to go.
I know.
Gee.
# I'm not the kind
who's never satisfied I
# I know where my bodies lie a'
# Most in the ground
that I have gained a'
# Doin' the push aside a'
# 'Cause Pm not one
who says 'if only' I
# There are things I'll never do
and I accept the facts a'
# There are things
I'll never see a'
# And I can understand a'
# There are places I'll never go
and I can live with that a'
# But I can't live without him I
# If only I had him
my life would be better I
# If only he knew
then we'd be together I
A' If only I had him #
# I like the way he talks a'
# And the things he does
and says a'
# The way he dresses
in that understated way I
# And every time I see him
I just wanna die a'
# 'Cause he's the one
I said 'If only' I
# If only I had him
I'd feel so much better I
# If only I knew one way
or the other I
A' If only I had him #
# If only I had him
I'd feel so much better I
# If only he knew
then we would be together I
A' If only I had him #
'I Clapping]
- [ Laughter]
Matt. I didn't know
you were coming over.
Courtney invited me.
Guys, I even got
the drum roll right.
Well, I think I'll get
something to drink.
Does anybody want anything?
Yeah, could you get me a Slice?
Sure.
Perrier, please.
H'
I like your music.
Thanks.
Would you like to do something
this weekend?
Sure.
But-.
But what?
Well, I was gonna invite you
someplace.
Well, invite away.
Um, so Sheila's dad just bought
this new condo...
Yeah?
And, well, all of us were gonna
go up for the weekend
and hang out and practice.
Sounds like fun.
Are her parents gonna be there?
No.
Bad, bad girl.
Not us!
You must be thinkin'
of some other girls.
No. I'm thinking of you.
Thanks for comin' by.
Thanks for inviting me.
You're welcome.
Uh, I'll call you tonight.
Great. Okay.
- Bye.
See ya.
Well? Is he coming? Hm?
- I think so.
- Yahoo!
- Yeah!
- He's hot!
Oh, I know what Courtney's
getting for her birthday.
- Oh, man, he is so hot.
- A boyfriend.
Mom?
Mm'?
Mr. Harrington 'gust bought
a brand new condo
at the desert club golf course.
Mr. Harrington?
Sheila's dad?
Mm.
Must be really hot out there
this time of year.
See, Sheila and Amy and all of-
I talked to one
of Valerie's doctors today.
He said that she
was talking a little bit.
I think we'll drive down there
this weekend and see her.
It's just Sheila invited
the band
up to the condo this weekend,
and I would really like to go.
So you don't wanna see
your sister?
Well, sure, but, well, Amy,
Sally, everyone's going,
and we need to practice
for the dance.
Well, I don't know.
I'm gonna have to think
about it.
I'm sorry, Mom. it-
it slipped.
Honey. It's an old plate.
That's not it.
It's Sunday's my birthday,
and I don't wanna go to
a mental hospital.
Oh, honey.
I forgot it was your birthday.
Oh, I'm- I'm so sorry, honey.
Hey, look,
we'll stay here at home.
You can invite some of your
friends over here, okay?
But all my friends
are going to Desert Springs
to Sheila's for the weekend,
and I wanna go.
Why can't-J?
Can't we go to Valerie's
some other weekend?
Well, I- I suppose. I-.
See, I- I don't know
Sheila's parents.
Oh, they're great.
Except they're a little strict.
You really wanna go, don't you?
It'll be the greatest
birthday present
in the whole world.
Well, all right.
I suppose a 17-year-old
is old enough.
Thanks, Mom.
You're so great.
Thank you.
I just wish you could come
a little earlier on Saturday.
I've gotta do this thing
with my family,
but then I'll come up
in the afternoon.
It's like a prison.
First you do your time,
then you're set free.
I know.
I just wanna see you.
Are you still on the phone?
Uh, hold on.
Uh, I- I'm getting off.
It's almost 11:30
on a school night.
Okay. I'm off.
I really gotta go.
Okay. Bye.
Okay, see ya.
Yeah. See ya tomorrow.
h'
Hi.
Courtney! Courtney!
He's coming! Courtney!
Courtney!
Valerie?
Courtney. Courtney.
Don't go.
Where?
Don't go all the way.
Rock and roll never dies, babe.
Courtney, now are you sure
you're all right?
You look tired to me.
Morn, I'm okay.
Okay, but you be careful now.
This is a long trip.
Mom, don't freak out.
I'm just going away
for a weekend.
Have a nice birthday, honey.
- Bye.
- Come on!
- Whoo!
Yeah!
Good-bye, Mrs. Bates!
- Bye!
# Well, it's nine o'clock
and I'm ready to rock a'
# My motorcycle's out of hock' #
# Jump on back
and hold on tight I
# We're gonna ride this rocket
into the night a'
# Don't let go a'
"Stop m
'l Laughs 1
- Quit.
- All right!
Amy, Courtney,
Sheila, come on down.
It's the ultimate slumber party
weekend,
and you girls just won two days
and two nights of no parents,
do anything you want to,
good time
on the slumber party weekend!
Whoa'.!
Yeah!
This is gonna be so fun!
- Whoo!
- So fun.
I can't believe you're serious
about going to Mills.
I mean, I would never go
to girls' college.
Hey, Courtney,
where'd your sister Valerie go?
Um, Humboldt.
Geez, why didn't she
just move to Siberia?
No wonder she never comes home.
Sally, what are you reading?
This really weird book
I found underneath
my brother's mattress.
“Hot, Wet, and Wild"?
Oh, my God, I gotta see this.
Wait 'til I'm done, piglet!
Oh, come on!
God, you're so selfish.
# Don't let go a'
# Hold on tight a'
# Hey, baby, squeeze me a'
# Don't let go a'
# Hold on tight, baby a'
h'
[Gasping 1
Courtney?
Courtney, are you okay?
She's gone.
Who's gone?
Valerie.
What were you dreaming about?
Valerie and Matt.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Yeah, save it.
Well, it doesn't look like
anybody lives here yet.
I know.
Hm.
Gimme my shirt.
Hey, let's
set up over there.
Well, now I know
why you invited us here.
Why?
You wanted us to help you
unpack your dad's stuff.
No!
- You get more than that.
- Help yourself.
Hey, Sally,
you and I can stay in here.
Looks “Hot, Wet, and Wild" to me.
What? What?
Shit!
My brother's been up here...
again.
[Laughing 1
Your brother?
Oh, Sheila, your brother
is such a pervert.
Hey, it runs in the family.
- Oh, did they hurt you?
- Ooh.
[Laughing 1
Can you believe that doll?
Oh, Sheila's family is so weird.
You're telling me.
Did you see its mouth?
Oh, I know.
What are you doing?
Some people have wine cellars,
my dad has a booze closet.
Bingo.
We are gonna have
so much fun tonight.
Man, these are killer corn dogs.
Some day we are gonna be
in movies and rock videos
and everything,
because my song
is gonna be a hit.
Hear, hear.
Yeah, a million years from now
when you finish writing it.
Hey, I'm gonna finish it
this weekend for sure.
Sheila!
- Why not?
- All right!
I'm not driving anywhere,
and, besides, the men
won't be here till tomorrow.
Won't your dad get mad?
- Oh! No.
- Whoo!
He'll think my pervert
brother did it.
Besides, it goes great
with corn dogs.
Oh, you sick-
Twisted, twisted woman.
Gum.!
Oh, look, this is a neat movie.
Oh, I love this song.
Turn it up!
Whoa'.!
# Speakin' in tongues
and got nothin' to say I
I 'Cause I'm Iivin' at night
in Hell's Cafe' #
Do you think they'll be pissed
at us for comin' early?
You are so uptight.
I'm not uptight.
Look, I'm telling you,
these girls will love it.
Don't you think we should've
at least called first?
They might not even be here.
- Look, dummy, the lights are on.
- So?
That doesn't mean they're here,
brilliant.
# Look up and I start to sway a'
# I drank too much
in Hell's Café I
See? I told you they
were here already.
We lucked out.
# Here's to my troubles a'
# Pour some more wine I
# Tell me a story a'
# Make it quick this time a'
# Tell me something
I've always wanted to say I
# Tell me all about you
in Hell's Cafe I'
Sheila!
You Jerk!
I'm all wet!
# Damn, I'll meet ya
in Hell's Café. I
# If you should ever come
to Hell's Cafe' #
# Be not concerned with
the price you must pay a'
# Have yourself
a good jug of wine I
# In Hell's Café
we always have a good time I
"Ooh!
-8hh!
'GOd!
I didn't know girls really did
this stuff.
It's because we're dead.
This is heaven.
Whoo!
# In Hell's Cafe' #
You are so weird.
Do you know what you look like?
What?
You look like a big chicken.
Bwaak! Bwaak, bwaak, bwaak,
bwaak!
Sheila,
did your dad say anything
about this house being haunted?
[Laughing 1
No. Did you guys lock
the back door?
I thought you did.
- No.
- Ooh!
Shh!
Quiet. Quiet.
Ooh.
Sheila, be careful.
Who knows who's out there.
Shh.
Ah!
Oh, T.J., you ass!
You know, you girls better
learn how to lock the back door.
That wasn't funny, Jeff.
You really scared us.
Hey, we thought
it was hilarious.
Especially that weird dance
you girls were doing.
You saw that?
- Yeah.
- We're busted.
- Smoke!
- 'Em!
Smoke 'em!
0w!
Oh, yeah.
Ooh.
Oh! Oh!
Sally, are you asleep?
Mm-hm.
Oh! Oh yeah!
Oh! Harder, harder!
Do they always make
that much noise?
Oh! Ooh!
Yeah.
The more they do it,
the louder they get.
Practice makes perfect.
Oh, oh. Mm. Mm.
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Oh, God. You're fantastic.
I know.
h'
How do you want it?
Oh! You killed Valerie!
Valerie.
Oh. I've had Valerie.
I'm tired of Valerie.
I just wanna make love to you.
I am you and you are me
until we go all the way.
Hey, baby.
Love the one you're with.
You're with- You're with-
You're with-
There you are.
I wondered what happened to you.
Courtney, are you okay?
Amy, I feel horrible.
It's just a hangover.
Everybody's got one.
No, that's not it.
I've been having really
horrible nightmares
about that stuff that happened
at Trish Craven's when I was 12.
I thought you were over that.
Yeah, me, too,
but I keep dreamin' about this-
this really weird guy.
And last night,
he was in bed with me.
I think you should have
some juice, have some toast,
and you'll feel a lot better
after you eat something.
Last night, in my dream,
he killed Valerie.
I mean, it was real.
I could feel him.
I could feel him breathe on me.
You know, I read
a doctor's report once
about something called
subconscious projection.
He kissed me and it was real.
Courtney, it's the kind
of dream you have
when you drink too much.
Oh, my God.
Cannon ball! Whoa!
Hey!
You rogue monster.
Chill out, man.
T.J., man!
Shit.
Hello. Sorry.
Do you want an egg?
I can fix you one.
No thanks.
Water's great.
Let's skinny dip.
No way.
Oh, you girls are so uptight.
I mean, they looked to me like
they were into it last night.
Didn't it look that way to you?
Huh? Huh? Didn't it?
Yeah, T.J., but we're sober now.
Apparently you're not.
Amy, pass me some juice.
Sure. Darling.
Thank you.
What's wrong, Courtney?
You got a hangover?
Oh, yeah, I guess I do.
I had the worst nightmare
last night.
So did I.
Come on, stop it.
Can't believe how much
my head hurts.
Oh, I can fix that.
How?
All right, stand up.
Come on, over here.
What are you up to now?
- T.J.
- All right, now just relax.
Okay-
How does that feel?
Feels okay.
Oh, Lord, heal this thy poor
lamb in her hour of need.
T.J.!
- T.J., calm down.
- Satisfy this wench.
- T.J., stop it!
- T.J.!
Give her what she knows
she wants.
T.J., calm down.
- T.J., get your hands off her!
Stop it!
Baptize! Oh, demons be gone!
Oh, God.
Come on!
- Come on!
- T.J.!
- Come on, help.
Give us a hand, 1'.J.!
[Gasps, coughs 1
You drowned her!
Leave me alone!
Courtney-
- Leave me alone!
Courtney- Courtney,
you're gonna be fine.
- Shh, shh.
- You're gonna be fine, honey.
- You just swallowed some water.
- Shh, shh.
Here. Here.
Uh, sorry about that.
Shh.
How's your headache?
Jerk!
Shh.
Hi. How's the hangover queen?
Hey! Little better.
Oh, I felt so bad this morning
I wanted to go home.
I can totally relate.
I've wanted to go home myself
this whole entire day.
I mean, my face is turning into
one big pimple.
It's really embarrassing.
Sally, I don't see a thing.
Oh, you may not see it,
but it's there.
There's one.
It's just lurking
just below the surface.
Sorry.
It's all right.
I can deal with it.
Hey, the guys are serving lunch
down by the pool.
- The guys are serving lunch-
- The guys. Come on.
Why don't you come down
and have some lunch with us?
- 'Kay.
- All right?
Quit it.
Ooh, loosen up.
Good Lord, what is this?
- A book.
- I know that, Sheila.
I mean, where'd you get
this thing. Look at it!
Sally swiped it from her dad.
"Hot, Wet, and Wild?"
T.J., come on.
Give it back.
What is this shit?
If your mother knew...
"His burning lips seared her
rose of a mouth while his...
...pulsating tool
drove deep into the confines-"
Oh.
"Gently, his hand caressed her
melon-like-"
Ah!
What's wrong?
My burger's weird.
Looks like the same old
kangaroo meat to me.
Way too much ketchup, though.
Mm. Here's a chicken sandwich
if you want it.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Whoo! Baby!
Baby, shake it!
MTV, here we come!
Whoa!
# No bad news,
they just want fun a"
# Someday soon
they'll have it all I
# Now there is no time to stop a'
# Gotta get right to the top A'
JWhy #
# Why do we want more?' #
A' Looks so cool
when it's not yours a"
# Love like them
you just want more I
# You tell me it's not enough a'
# But can't you see it's
only love a'
JWhy #
# Why do you want more?
Quit it! Quit it! Stop!
JWhy #
# Why do you want more?' #
"Heathcliff lay still,
his passion spent."
You in the mood yet?
Ah, not now.
"The hot, nubile bodies
of the girls
entwined about his massive form
like sun-warmed ivy."
And now?
Mm.
[Laughing 1
Something in the refrigerator
attacked you?
Yeah, I know it sounds
totally stupid,
but it looked just like-
a chicken.
Oh.
Come on.
Hawk, hawk.
Is this the offending bird?
Courtney, honey, you probably
just opened the door too fast,
and it fell out.
Oh, I can do it. Hey.
Are you sure
you're feeling okay?
Not really.
I've been feeling really nervous
and... weird.
I can't get that dream
out of my mind.
You think maybe you
hit your head
when you fell in the pool?
- Uh-uh, I don't think so.
- You know what it was?
It was all that booze
we had last night.
I've been feeling kinda edgy
myself today.
You know, you should try
to relax.
Take a hot bath.
Yeah.
I guess I've never had
a hangover like this before.
Yeah, and I bet you never drank
a whole case
of French champagne before.
Yeah, well.
I'll try to chill out.
So thanks for saving me
from the crazed chicken.
Bye.
# I want a silver Caddy
with a landau top I'
# I want a sugar daddy
with a candy shop I
# I want a lot of things
that money can't buy I
# But what I want most
is a pie in the sky a'
# What I want most
is a pie in the sky I
# All I want- a'
Sally! Would you come upstairs?
Something's going on
in the bathroom.
- Courtney, what's the matter?
- Please.
Well, yeah, sure. Okay.
Courtney! What are you doing?
Uh, well, I- I tried to turn
'em off before
and I- I couldn't turn 'em off
because-
they weren't on.
Courtney,
what is the matter with you?
Come on, I'm your friend.
Talk to me.
Hey, are you on drugs
or something?
Oh, God, I wish I was, Sally.
I mean, so many weird things
are happenin' to me.
Hey. Hey, I know what you mean.
The weirdest things
are happening to my face.
I mean, I have got
the fastest growing zit
I have ever had
in my entire life.
I mean, look at this thing.
I mean, is this the grossest
thing you've ever seen?
I'm gonna go get
some more Oxy 10.
I mean, it hurts like hell.
[ Gasps 1
Sally?
Courtney, what's wrong?
What's going on?
Sally's in the bathroom.
She's dead!
She's what?
She's dead.
You gotta believe me.
You gotta believe me, Matt.
You gotta go up there.
She's dead.
Okay, okay, okay-
She's in the bathroom
and she's dead!
- Okay_
'l $obs ]
What-? What's goin' on here?
What is this, a joke?
T.J., you didn't give her any
of your drugs, did you?
I think your sweetheart's
been takin' too many diet pills.
Hey, she's ruining my weekend.
Hey, shut up, man.
This whole thing
is Sheila's fault.
I mean, she's the one
that opened the champagne
and who knows what else.
See, you're just getting
uptight again.
You're uptight.
Smoke your head.
Courtney should go see a shrink
if she can't loosen up.
Would you guys chill out?
Please?
God.
I'm not crazy.
I'm not. I saw it.
And I heard him laughing.
He's in this house somewhere.
Courtney, it's okay.
I believe you saw something.
Have any of you heard anything
or seen anybody else strange
around here?
No.
Only Courtney.
Very funny.
Now, where is Sally?
I've looked all over for her
and I don't know where she is.
Great, man.
Oh, fuck you.
She probably
just went to the store.
All the cars are still here, T.J.
This is getting too stupid.
For once in your life, T.J.,
won't you just shut up?
God.
I mean, maybe, just maybe...
there is a psycho
running around here.
Courtney, why don't you
go lie down?
Okay?
I'm gonna go call the cops.
Oh, God. Anybody got any tranqs?
Who turned on
the trash compactor?
Well, I don't know. It was-
It was on when we came in here.
Probably just some old bones.
Now, let me
get this straight.
You saw Sally's face
explode in the bathroom,
but you haven't seen her since,
dead or alive.
And you think that she's
in the trash compactor,
but you're afraid to look,
right?
Yes.
When did this happen?
Uh, about three hours ago.
Did you see her?
Was her face intact?
Well, the last time I saw her
was about two o'clock,
but she was okay then.
No!
Go away, you're supposed
to be dead.
Is this Sally Burns?
Yes.
Christ, where have you been?
Uh, I just went to the store
to get some more Oxy 10
and, well,
I- I met this outrageous guy.
He was such a babe and, um, I-
Did I do something wrong?
You freaked out your
little friends here.
And you wasted about 200 dollars
of the taxpayers' money,
but you didn't do
anything wrong.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I don't know what kind of drugs
this one is on and I don't care,
because I don't wanna have
to deal with
her mother and father
and the fancy lawyers.
But I'll tell you brats
somethin':
If you jerk my chain in my town
I'll rip your lungs out.
Come on, Krueger.
Denny's is holding our booth.
I'm on my way.
Y'all have a nice day.
- What is the matter with-?
- I don't know. Courtney just-
Courtney needs some time alone.
I'm sorry. I'm- I'm sorry.
I must be just goin' crazy.
Do you wanna go home?
No, right now I just-
I'm so tired I just don't wanna
do anything.
Okay?
Matt, we're gonna go get
something to eat. Okay?
Yeah, we're starved too, huh?
All right.
I think we need to stay here.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
H'
Ready for a surprise dessert?
Dessert?
Happy Birthday, Courtney.
Wow!
I'd sing Happy Birthday to you
but my singing
would gross you out.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Gotta take a big breath.
No, I'm just gonna look at it
for a while.
It's too pretty.
Aren't you gonna make a wish?
I've already got my wish.
Hey. Hey, this is supposed
to cheer you up.
Matt, I don't know if I'm
going crazy or what.
You must think I am
the weirdest person
in the whole world.
No. No, I think you're a very
sensitive person,
but something bad happened
to you when you were little
and all the excitement
from your crazy friends
brought it back
a little while today.
You know what happened
at the Cravens'?
Yeah.
The Cravens are really
good friends with my parents.
And I know you and your sister
helped kill the murderer
and that's a really heavy trip.
Yeah, and he's dead.
Isn't he?
Yeah, they're dead.
I know, I know.
Hey, I have musical ability.
T.J., show them-
T.J.! Yeah!
Whoo!
H'
Matt, um, I've never-
Gone all the way.
Come on, baby!
Let's rock and roll!
No, you're a dream!
You're a dream!
This look like a dream to you?
Does it?
Come on, baby!
We're gonna rock and roll!
Just you and me, honey!
Just you and me!
Whoo! Yeah!
- Oh.-
- Yeah!
That was awesome.
Hey, hey, did you hear
something?
He's here!
He's in the-
- Oh my-
- Shit.
Yeah! Yeah!
Back off, punk.
It's party time, kiddies!
Die!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Well, try again!
Hello, you have reached
the Desert-
Shit!
No! No!
No!
- Oh, my God.
- Come on!
Run! Run!
He got me!
Oh, my God!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Asshole!
Come on! Come on!
Courtney. Courtney,
where did this guy come from?
I don't know.
I was dreamin' about him
and then all of a sudden
he was there killing Matt.
I know, I know, I know.
It's okay.
He was there and he was real.
All right, that's it.
We should make a run for it
in my car.
The keys.
Oh, God, Amy,
they're on the kitchen table.
We've gotta go back and get 'em
and Sally might just be-
I know. I know, I know.
What about T.J. and Sheila?
Well, we'll pick 'em up
if we see 'em, okay?
Look, honey, they're probably
a million miles away
from here right now.
Let's just make sure
we get out, okay?
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
All right?
Come on now.
Let's go.
All right, it's okay.
My God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
On, Sally.
Sally, can you hear me?
It's Jeff.
Come on, Sally, please.
Oh God!
God, we gotta go.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, God.
- You guys ready?
Yes.
All right, one, two, three, go!
Come on!
My God!
Hurry!
Lock the doors!
Come on, come on!
Lock the doors
lock the doors!
I can't believe this.
Goddamn car!
Don't panic! Don't panic!
Oh, God. Thank you.
This is dedicated
to the one I love.
God! No!
Come on!
Jeff! Jeff!
Okay, okay, I gotta stop. Stop.
Oh, God!
Oh God, there's lights.
Come on, T.J.
Come on, please.
Just a little bit further.
Please, come on.
Come on, honey.
Oh! Oh, come on, baby.
Come on. Oh!
We're here!
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Oh! Oh, my God!
Open the door, please!
Answer the door!
Oh, my God!
Please!
Come on! Never mind.
Come on!
Damn kids.
It's okay, it's okay.
I'll get the phone.
Desert Spring.
Police department, please.
Police emergency.
Hello, um-
Calm down, missy.
This is Courtney Bates
and we're at the Desert Club
condo number two
and we're being attacked
by a horrible man.
I don't wanna hear
this stuff anymore.
No, no, Officer Krueger,
it's not a joke.
Listen to me, listen to me.
He's real and- and he's really
trying to kill us.
He's already killed Matt
and Sally
- and now he's trying to-
Don't cal! back.
Okay-
He told us not to call
back again.
We'll just stay in here
till it gets light
and then... we'll sneak out.
Did you hear something?
I thought I heard something.
Jeff?
Now, it's time for the fun part.
# I love to jam it
to the floor a'
# Let these wild stripes roar I
# Well, I'm an inch
off the ground I
# Speakers all around, baby I
# Baby, do you like my sound?' #
# Let's buzz A'
# I got a very large amount a'
# In a Swiss bank account A'
# I got a penthouse at the Ritz a'
# I bought it with my hits a'
# I got a castle in Spain' #
# A Lear jet plane, baby a'
Amy, Courtney,
I know you're in there!
I can hear you! It's Sheila!
I can hear you!
- Sheila?
- Sheila's out there!
# Got so much money
it's a shame I
# Let's buzz A'
Coming! He's coming!
Oh my God!
# Let's buzz A'
Let's buzz a while!
# Strong constitution
and a will to match I
No, no, no!
# And those
thousand dollar wines I
# Go right down my hatch' #
# Well, I will rock you
in the cradle a'
# Till you scream for more,
baby I
# Tell me what you
waitin' for? I
Oh, God, he's out there.
# Let's buzz A'
No!
# Ah, let's buzz a'
# Well, let's buzz a while I'
# Let's buzz A'
# You say 'why',
I say 'because' I
# Let's buzz A'
Oh, my God!
# Yeah, you say 'why',
I say 'because' #
# Let's buzz A'
Come on!
Yoohoo! I'm home.
He's gonna kill us!
Boo!
I can't get no...
...satisfaction.
# Well, I'm Iookin'
for a real good place to go I
# I've been movin'
to the radio I
# I said I'd pick you up
about a half past eight I
# My love for you is killing me
and I can't wait I'
# I'm gettin' so excited
when I think of you a'
# My heart's a poundin' faster
at the things we'll do I
# My body starts a shakin' now
get you here I
# Like a little kiddy grinning
from ear to ear r
# I can't stop loving you a'
# I won't stop until I do a'
Shh.
# Can't stop loving you 4'
# I won't stop until I do a'
Amy! Amy!
Don't let go!
Courtney, please. God!
Courtney!
We rock!
And roll.
Courtney, here I come.
# My love is like lightning,
gonna strike you down I
# Don't be so frightened,
better get on the ground I
# I'm out of control, baby,
as you can see I
# You better hold on tight,
'cause it's you and me I
# I can't stop lovin' you a'
Well, she broken my heart
and made me cry,
so don't you know,
she had to die?
She had to die.
# I can't stop lovin' you a'
# I won't stop till I do I
# Well, my temperature's risin' a'
Ooh. Oh, yeah.
Oh, come on, baby.
Light my fire.
You bet I will.
# Can't stop loving you #
# I won't stop until I do #
# Can't stop loving you 4'
# I won't stop until I do a'
How many bodies are there?
H'
I love you.
# I love to jam it
to the floor a'
# Let these wild stripes roar I
# Well, I'm an inch
off the ground I
# Speakers all around, baby I
# Baby, do you like my sound?' #
# Let's buzz A'
# I got a rather large amount a'
# In a Swiss bank account A'
# I got a penthouse at the Ritz a'
# I bought it with my hits a'
# I got a castle in Spain' #
# A Lear jet plane, baby a'
# So much money
it's a shame S'
# Let's buzz A'
Let's buzz a while!
# Strong constitution
and a will to match I
# And those
thousand dollar wines I
# Go right down my hatch' #
# Well, I will rock you
in the cradle a'
# Till you scream for more,
baby I
# Tell me what you
waitin' for? I
# Let's buzz A'
# Ah, let's buzz a'
# Well, let's buzz a while I'
# Let's buzz A'
# You say 'why',
I say 'because' I
# Let's buzz A'
# Well, you say 'why'
I say 'because' a'
# Let's buzz A'
Buzz a while
# Well, it's nine o'clock
and I'm ready to rock a'
# My motorcycle's out of hock' #
# Jump on back
and hold on tight I
# We're gonna ride this rocket
into the night a'
# Don't let go a'
S Oh, no, no A'
# Hold on tight a'
# Hey! The sky is clear
and the stars are out 4'
# I'm tired of work a'
# I wanna twist and shout a'
# I wanna take you down
to the record hub a'
# And show you everything
I got a'
# Don't let go a'
# No, no!
# Hold on tight a'
# Don't let go a'
# And don't let go a'
# Well, the joint is jumpin'
to a rockin' show a'
# The band is playin'
every song I know a'
# And when it's over,
gonna take you home I
# And rock you, baby,
all night long a"
# Don't let goa'
# No, no!
# Don't let go a'
# Hold on tight a'
# Don't let goa'
# Hey, baby, squeeze me a'
# Don't let go a'
# Hold on tight, baby a'
A' Oh, don't let go #