Toei Co., Ltd.
SNAKE WOMAN'S CURSE
Screenplay
Fumio Konami and Nobuo Nakagawa.
Producers
Kaname Ogisawa, Tadayuki Okubo.
Production Design
Hiroshi Kitagawa.
Director of Photography
Yoshikazu Yamasawa.
Assistant Director
Atsushi Mihori.
Music Shunsuke Kikuchi.
Set Design Masao Ishii.
Script Supervisor Sumiko Nakao.
CAST
Seizaburo Kawazu.
Yukie Kagawa Sachiko Kuwahara.
Shingo Yamashiro Kunio Murai.
Ko Nishimura.
Shunji Sayama.
Akemi Negishi Chiaki Tsukioka.
Tamae Kiyokawa Mariko Ko.
Hideo Murota Akiken Sawa.
Special Appearance Junzaburo Ban.
Tetsuro Tanba.
Directed by Nobuo Nakagawa.
In the early days of the Meiji Period,
in the remote countryside
of northern Japan,
where deep mountains
face the desolate Sea of Japan,
the village of Onuma had
not yet been westernized.
Even if the people had wanted to fish,
there were no ports
a fishing boat could use.
Villagers could survive only
by farming the meager soil.
The Onuma family, who owned the land,
were breaking the farmers' backs.
Come on.
Landlord! Please, landlord!
Sir, please!
Landlord!
Please don't repossess my field!
Please! Master!
I will work harder than anybody else.
Please!
Yasuke, it's dangerous! Stay away.
Please, landlord.
Without the field, I can't live.
Please.
Please say something, master!
Please! Landlord!
I'll pay off my debt.
I will definitely do it.
Please don't take away my field!
Sir! Please!
Father! Father!
- Please! Sir!
- Father!
Landlord!
I can't live if you take the field!
Father!
Landlord!
What happened, Father?
Father, are you okay?
Father! Father!
- Are you okay?
- What's going on?
- Father.
- Yasuke?
- Yasuke? Hang on!
- Are you okay?
- Yasuke? What happened?
- Father!
Hang on, Father!
Yasuke?
Landlord.
Please.
Don't take the farm.
Father.
Sutematsu.
Thank you.
It's late. Please go home.
Please take care.
Thank you.
Please say hello to Matsugoro.
Yeah.
My father will be shocked.
Take care.
He isn't well yet.
Why did you let him work on the farm?
That was stupid.
My mother and I tried to stop him.
So foolish.
Sutematsu.
- When I feel jealous,
- Give me candies!
- I have a hard time,
So I make a rice dumpling for the Buddha.
Asa.
Kamekichi, do you have an errand?
I'm going to the next village.
You're working so hard.
By the way, how is Yasuke?
Thank you for asking.
Last night he slept well.
Well, I guess it was a bad day yesterday.
What's wrong?
Okay, I'll put you under hypnosis.
Hypnosis?
Yes. Hypnosis will control
the threads of people's minds.
The threads of minds?
Don't worry. Close your eyes.
- Relax.
- Like this?
Yes.
Are you ready? Relax.
I'm hypnotizing you.
You're feeling...
When I feel jealous,
I have a hard time.
So I make a rice dumpling for the Buddha.
Kamekichi! Idiot!
Thanks for your help.
Poor bird. You're hurt.
Sue! Sue!
Asa! Asa.
Trouble. Father is in trouble.
- Hurry!
- Father?
- Yasuke!
- Father!
- What happened, Father?
- Do you need water?
- Father?
- Let me go!
- What did I do?
- Father?
After you get better, we will.
- Let go.
- Yasuke.
I might die tomorrow.
I have to see the landlord
and ask him something!
I will ask him about you.
- Sue. Sue.
- Yasuke. Calm down.
Please wake me up. Please.
Are you all right? Father?
If I die, you can't pay back the debt.
I have to ask him a
once-in-a-lifetime thing:
Ask him about the debt.
Father?
- Yasuke?
- Here's his medicine.
- Father.
- Yasuke, take the medicine.
Father.
I... Even if I have to eat dirt,
for the master.
Landlord.
Please excuse me.
Please.
- Father!
- Yasuke!
- Father! Father!
Hang on.
- Father!
- Yasuke!
Father! Father!
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Father.
From now on we'll try to help you.
Please let us know.
Yasuke passed away.
May he rest in peace.
This is your condolence payment.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Yasuke said that,
even if he had to eat dirt,
he wanted to work for you
until he was dead.
He was worried about the debt.
Regarding that problem,
I need you to return the farm.
But...
- It'll make us...
- Don't worry.
Sue will work in my main building.
Tomorrow morning,
we'll teach you how to weave.
You two will work
to repay the debt.
We will tear down this place immediately,
to reclaim land here
and plant mulberry trees.
You have to prepare for it.
Do you understand that?
Landlord.
- Do it.
- Yes.
You guys, too.
- Heave-ho!
- Do it.
- You, too.
- Heave-ho!
Do it harder!
Heave-ho!
Harder!
Take it all away.
Sue, come here.
Sue. This is best for you two.
Let's go.
There you go.
Come on.
Yes.
Hey, it's not like they're going to Hell.
Eh, Sutematsu?
It might be worse than Hell.
Sutematsu!
What are you doing?
Get back to work!
It's a snake! Kill it!
No, don't!
Because of the interest,
Yasuke's debt has increased substantially.
From now on, you two will work to repay it.
Do you understand?
It will take ten years.
During that period, of course,
I won't pay you any salary.
But since I'm giving you free food,
you'll need to work hard.
Takeo, take them away.
Sure.
Hey, Sue, listen.
Now, do you understand?
Sue.
If you think that working here will be
easier than on the farm, you're mistaken.
Yes.
It's so hot!
It really is.
If you have any questions,
or if others are bullying you,
you can ask me anything.
Okay?
Kuzu, she's new here.
She'll teach you, okay?
Good luck.
You will work there.
Listen, if you have any questions,
or if others are bullying you,
you can ask me anything, okay?
- Not okay!
- Kame!
1. WAKE UP AT 4 A. M.
2. WORK FROM 5 A. M. TO 9 P. M.
3. NO CHATTING AT WORK
4. TAKE CARE OF YOUR TOOLS
Whatever the weather, I keep weaving...
I keep weaving...
Weaving woman don't sleep...
don't sleep...
Oh, no!
You're doing it the wrong way.
You're hopeless.
IF YOU WORK HARD,
YOU CAN ENDURE SHORTAGE
AND DISCOMFORT
Don't slack off! Do it faster!
Carrying only one is too slow.
Carry one more!
I can't see you work so sloppily.
I mean it.
Kame! You don't need to help her.
It can't be helped.
Sue.
You're doing great, aren't you?
What happened? You broke it!
Be careful.
You, hitting on another man
so soon after your husband died!
You're like a cat in heat!
Hey, Tora, watch out.
Yes.
Red, red, red pepper is so hot.
Heat, heat.
Tora, thanks for helping.
- Sure.
- Sue, that's a bad cough.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Didn't your husband have the same illness?
My shoulder hurts.
I'd rather become sick and die.
Well, Mino and everyone,
I'll take care of the rest of it.
Please take your baths.
Are you sure? Thank you.
I appreciate it.
It's so hot.
Sue. Take care.
I remember the sky
I saw this afternoon.
Red, red, red pepper is so hot.
Heat, heat.
Asa.
Mother!
Is anything wrong with you?
You look pale.
I'm all right.
You've become really thin.
Your work is hard, isn't it?
It's hard. But I'm still young.
It's tough for you, isn't it?
I'm okay.
Look.
Eat some of these and get well.
Can I take this many?
We can't eat it every day,
but sometimes we manage.
Thank you.
I will give some to the other girls.
They'll be happy.
That would be nice.
Anyway, keep working hard,
and you'll get promoted soon.
Take care, Mother.
Thank you.
I'll visit you again.
Sue.
How dare you steal them!
You sneak thief!
Please give her a break.
- Please.
- Kame, stay away.
Hey! You must apologize to her.
- Hey!
- Saiji.
You sneak thief.
Starting tomorrow, you'll work outside.
I can't let a dirty thief
stay in the house!
I was wrong. I'm sorry. So sorry.
That's enough!
The village mayor is coming.
Ma'am, the mayor is coming.
Welcome, Mayor.
- Hey, Kame.
- Please come this way.
Good.
Thanks for coming on such a hot day.
No problem.
Please.
Thank you.
Congratulations, my young master.
The village mayor came today
to talk about your bride.
Congratulations.
You're jealous, aren't you?
Young master won't act so filthy any more!
Are you sure?
You idiot.
- Snake! Snake!
- What happened?
Saiji, kill it.
Yes.
Please stop. Don't kill it.
Help it. Please help it.
- Please don't kill...
- Stay away.
Please.
What's the meaning of this?
I feel so sorry for it.
It's ominous.
You know how important today is.
Are you trying to insult our Onuma family?
No, I'm not.
- I just...
- No excuses!
Snake woman!
- Please forgive me.
- Don't touch it!
Sue!
It's so ominous. Hey, bring salt!
- Salt!
- Salt. Yes.
Get her out of here.
Hurry.
Go.
Lay her down now.
Are you okay?
It's terrible.
We should call a doctor immediately.
You idiot.
You don't have to call a doctor.
Sue.
Hang on.
It's a lot of fun.
If you cheat a geisha.
You'll have bad luck
for seven generations.
Of course, it was fun.
You'll have bad luck,
as they're all cats.
It was so fun to get a lot of watermelons.
I know, I know so much about it.
I knew everything from the beginning.
It's a beautiful day today.
Congratulations.
What about me acting as a go-between?
Ideal son-in-law?
Thank you for everything.
Good. No problem?
Of course not.
Right, Masae?
It really is a wonderful offer.
If her lips are thick,
she is compassionate.
The relationship between husband and wife
would be very deep.
Your young master is so sweet.
You'll dote on the bride.
Your ear seems stiff and turned-up.
It means you'll make a lot of money,
and your business will go well.
It's so lucky.
Do you guys know who I was?
I was a soldier in the
Satsuma gun-fighters.
This is the proof.
This stuff here.
When I was in the gun-fighters...
I carried the gun like this.
What a lucky man...
is Mr. Wakamatsu.
Shoot!
Sue.
I brought you food.
Why don't you eat some?
Sue.
Asa.
What did you say?
Say it again.
Asa.
Whatever the weather,
I keep weaving...
Every night I have to work late.
I'm really exhausted.
What the hell are you talking about?
Stop complaining.
Get back to work now!
Asa.
There's trouble!
Your mother is in trouble.
Hurry.
Come with me.
Where are you going?
You'd better come back soon.
Mother.
Mother, are you all right?
Dead.
I'm going to join your father.
No.
Please don't die.
Sue.
What?
What did you say?
Asa.
Mother.
- Mother.
- Sue.
Sue!
Hey, I feel sorry for Sue.
Me, too.
Same here.
- You scared us.
- Hey, what are you doing?
Stop!
Hey!
Don't!
Stop it.
Please.
Honey?
What's going on?
You're alone, finally.
I want to die.
I'd rather die.
You lost your mother and father.
I understand how you feel.
Hey, cheer up.
I'll be with you.
I heard that your mother
was driven to her death.
Damn it.
If you keep working there...
Someday, I will get you out of that house.
I have a huge debt.
I don't know when I can get out of there.
Hey, whatever happens...
I will marry you.
When the summer holiday arrives,
let's meet here.
Asa, I have something to tell you.
Asa, I need your help.
I want you to visit the wholesaler in town
and give this letter to him.
Yes, but...
Don't worry about the old man.
Please start getting ready now so you
don't have to come back late at night.
- Please.
- Sure.
Please don't.
Shit.
Asa! Asa!
Please don't!
Stay quiet.
Wait.
Asa.
Please don't!
Idiot!
Asa.
Please don't.
Young master!
Asa. Asa.
Please don't do this. Please.
Asa.
- Asa!
Hey! You go that way!
Kame, you go this way.
- Asa!
Asa!
I found Asa!
- You found her?
- We found her!
Asa! Asa!
Asa! Asa! Are you okay?
I guess she escaped.
Lock her in the shed for a few days.
- Yes.
- It'll serve as a warning.
Takeo.
It's you who's responsible
for failing to supervise.
That's why she escaped.
You need a tight leash.
Yes.
Asa.
Whatever happens, I will marry you.
You have to hurry up.
- Hey, watch out!
- Yes.
You've all done a fine job.
I'll give you a bonus.
- Tami.
- Yes.
It's your day off today.
You can go anywhere you want.
- Mino.
- Yes.
Thank you very much.
- Iku.
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Yoshi.
Thank you very much.
- Fuku.
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Saki.
Thank you very much.
- Ume.
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Tome.
Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Haru.
Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Sayo.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Asa.
You stay.
After all, you might escape again, right?
What kind of look is that?
First of all, we can't afford
to give you a break,
as you're only a new worker here.
Do you understand that?
Go and clean up the mosquito net.
Yes.
When you're done with that,
polish all the lamps.
Yes.
Asa.
Be patient.
Don't worry. Okay?
Forget about what that old hag said.
Do you know what I mean?
Now close your eyes.
I'll put you under hypnosis.
Are you ready?
Look this way. Close your eyes.
Now you're ready.
Good. Hypnosis will disentangle
the threads of your mind.
When I feel jealous,
I have a hard time...
- Kame!
- Yes.
When I feel jealous,
I have a hard time.
Are you Sutematsu?
Yes.
Asa won't come.
What?
I'm sorry, but they didn't let her out.
Why?
When she left for the town on an errand,
she tried to escape.
What? Escape?
That's ludicrous.
She tried to escape
without telling me anything?
I'm not sure if I should say this.
Please tell me whatever you can.
This occurred to me afterward.
It was the day the lightning hit.
When Asa went on an errand,
I saw the young master.
He was secretly heading
for the mountain from the back door.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
From that day on,
Asa stopped talking,
as if she became another person.
And then,
later that night, when we brought her back,
Asa squinted at the young master
with such a terrible look.
I might be wrong.
Being carried in a palanquin,
I felt as if I had become a monkey.
- I was sold somewhere.
- Hey, dance with me!
So I work in the rest of my life.
Please don't, young master.
- Asa.
- Please don't.
Stay quiet.
Ouch! Damn it.
Please don't.
Asa, you're ruined.
You can't get married to Sutematsu.
You're not a virgin anymore.
You're ruined.
Shit.
Asa.
Wait.
Asa. Asa.
- Asa.
- No!
Let's go, Mother.
Hurry, Mother.
Hey, baby, have a good night's sleep.
You'll enjoy staying at Shinagawa Inn.
Asa.
That day, when the lightning hit...
Tell me what really happened.
Hey.
Tell me the truth. Honestly.
The guy who just left, did he...
Son of a bitch.
Why the hell didn't you resist the guy,
the goddamn son of a bitch? Why?
I asked young master not to do it.
I hate him.
I hate young master.
Idiot.
What young master?
What landlord?
You can't call him that.
You should have killed him.
Why didn't you resist
until you really killed him?
I can't live any longer.
I'd rather die.
Hey, look at them. So hot!
A thousand degrees hot.
This is called "rabu-scene", isn't it?
No. "Labu-scene."
Love scene in English.
Love scene.
Hey, Sutematsu.
You have to buy me a drink.
You promised me that.
Come and do your love scene later at night.
Let's go.
- Love scene!
Love scene! So hot!
Asa.
Mother.
I'm ruined.
I feel sorry for Sutematsu.
Everyone's dead.
I can't live anymore.
What can I do?
Come here.
If you come, you'll feel better.
If you come, you won't suffer.
What happened?
It's scary.
What's going on, Kamekichi?
- Can you hear that?
- What?
- What can you hear?
You're scared like a girl.
- It's scary!
- You're a coward.
Are you really a man?
- I'm scared!
- Be quiet.
I went to the toilet outside just now.
- And...
- And?
And something tripped me.
What was that?
It was too dark to see it clearly.
It was squishy, something squishy.
- Squishy?
- Yes.
When I looked carefully,
it seemed like a human being.
- A woman!
- Woman? Really?
You're kidding again, Kame?
It's true.
So I asked, "Who are you?"
But she didn't reply.
Do you remember
the newspaper article sometime ago?
About the girl who shaved her hair,
cut her throat,
and tried to commit suicide?
The girl was like seventeen years old.
She was deceived by some guy.
She was pregnant.
She cut her throat with the razor,
but she couldn't kill herself.
The blood was pouring from her cut throat!
Hey.
Asa isn't here.
- Asa?
- Yes.
Takeo?
Takeo.
What's going on?
- Snake!
- Snake?
There is no snake.
You're half-asleep like a kid.
What the hell?
Rats again?
Damn it.
Asa.
Asa. Asa.
Who's there?
Asa!
Asa! Asa!
The bride is coming!
Come on!
You look really beautiful.
Takeo?
Let's go to the ceremony.
What a lucky man is Mr. Onuma.
What a lucky man.
You'll prosper increasingly...
in the future.
What a lucky man...
is Mr. Onuma.
You'll prosper increasingly in the future.
Hey, where the hell do you think you're...
Stop him!
You did a terrible thing to Asa!
I'll beat you to death!
What the hell are you talking about?
Get out of here!
You bastard!
What the hell are you doing?
Sutematsu!
- Come any closer and I'll kill you.
- Sutematsu, don't!
Stop him!
Hold him.
You can't do it.
Damn it!
This way!
Where did he go?
Damn it.
- You guys search that way.
- Yes, sir.
We'll go this way.
Come, hurry!
Matsugoro.
Your son forgot
that he was just a tenant farmer.
He put up a fight with me.
I'm so sorry for what my son did.
He escaped into the mountains.
- Please forgive us.
- Shut up!
Police officers,
please comb the mountains.
- We'll arrange it right away.
- Please find him.
- Landlord.
- Shut up!
You guys look for him
at the base of the mountain.
- Yes, sir.
- Please forgive us, landlord!
Landlord!
Hurry!
Come this way!
The crazy man from last
night, was he caught?
No, not yet.
It was a special day for you.
You were frightened, weren't you?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
It's unjustified resentment.
Takeo didn't do anything wrong.
What's wrong?
Here you go.
I don't want it anymore.
Take it away.
But you should eat.
I told you I didn't want it!
Didn't you hear that?
Your mother seemed very terrified.
I'm scared.
Well, she was just nervous.
Don't worry.
She will get better soon.
- Kinu, come here now.
- Yes.
You've gotten so tense.
You're so cute.
You smell good.
What's the matter?
You...
Young master.
Please don't do this.
Please don't do this to me.
Young master,
please don't do this to me.
Darling!
Takeo, please stop acting
like a new bridegroom,
and start working harder.
What are you doing?
She is a snake!
Snake woman! You!
Father!
Takeo. Don't get rough with her.
Let me go!
Saru? Kame? Is anyone near here?
You snake!
Anyone?
Shit! Snake!
Kinu.
I'm not scared anymore.
I'm fine with you being some monster.
Don't tell me something so terrible.
Please don't do things like that anymore!
Otherwise,
I'll return to my parents' place.
Sorry. I apologize.
Is your burn all right?
Yes. But it's itchy.
- Would you scratch it?
- Sure.
- Is it here?
- Yes.
Honey, are you okay? Honey!
- Help!
- A snake!
Please don't!
Help!
- Hey, what's going on?
- Anybody?
- Please help me!
- Hey! Is anybody here?
- What are you doing to me?
Hang on, young master.
- Let me go!
- Young master!
Young master!
What are you doing?
I'll kill anybody who gets in my way.
Young master.
Please don't do this.
- Please don't do this.
- Help me.
Please don't do this to me.
Young master.
Please don't do this.
Please don't do this to me.
It's an order from the police commander.
Please come to headquarters immediately.
That's it.
Police commander?
What good is the police?
It's just plain rude. Go.
Yes, sir.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Commander.
How can you believe these rumors?
Mr. Onuma, why don't we talk quietly?
It's rude.
If you're acting like that, Commander,
I will ask the prefectural
governor to fire you.
We're just asking you,
in compliance with the law.
I want you to answer my questions.
What good is the police?
Don't patronize me,
bragging about law and order.
First of all, you reported
that your son died of illness.
I also heard that he committed suicide.
That's ridiculous.
The doctor proved that
he died of heart failure.
Regarding that,
I need him to come here as a witness.
Commander.
Are you interrogating me?
Not at all. But...
I'm asking you in person, as a commander.
I have nothing to hide.
Summoning me here!
You won't get away with it.
Second, you reported that Yasuke's wife
died of lung disease.
It was lung disease.
All of her ancestors died of lung disease.
The death of one or two tenant farmers
has nothing to do with me.
So you insist that you have
nothing to do with it?
They were working for you.
She died in your house.
Do you think you can
take their lives so lightly?
Commander.
Your point is...
you're doubtful about
the cause of Asa's death.
You're not sure about why Yasuke died.
You're suspicious of me, aren't you?
The lives of one or two tenant farmers.
They're the same as worms.
Worms wriggling in the rice field.
- What the hell?
- Mr. Onuma!
- What's the matter with you?
- Commander!
Damn it!
Mr. Onuma! What happened to you?
I know we can't be together.
Though I want to say good-bye to you.
Why doesn't one of us
try acting as a medium?
Any volunteers?
Who do you think can do it?
I think Kame can do it.
- Right.
- Kame can do it.
You can do it, Kame.
No, I can't.
I'm scared.
If I act as a medium,
dead people appear, right?
No, I don't want to.
Kame, you're a man, aren't you?
You can't use hypnosis now!
- Do it! Do it!
- Please don't.
Excuse me, priestess.
I've used hypnosis. Can I do it?
This will be "Hypnosis versus the Medium"!
Hey, Kinjo! Kinjo!
Please begin.
I know we can't be together.
Though I want to say good-bye to you.
It's coming! It's coming!
I'm begging you.
My soul becomes like this.
Please don't forget about me.
When you can finally see
me, please talk to me.
Young master.
Please don't do this.
I can't live anymore.
That's Asa's voice.
- Really?
- Asa?
I want to die.
Asa.
Why did you die, Asa?
- I'm scared.
- No! It's creepy!
- It's a snake!
- A snake?
Shut up!
Listen up, everyone.
When dawn breaks, burn away
all the mountain forest around here.
Burn the snakes.
Kill them all!
Shut up!
Masae. Masae!
- Saiji.
- Yes, sir.
Drive nails into the shed,
and lock it up so no one can enter.
Yes, sir.
We'll stop weaving.
We'll fire all the weaving women.
- Landlord!
- Do you understand?
It's too sudden.
We'll all have a lot of trouble.
Shut up!
Are you against me?
Get out of here.
- Get out!
- Landlord, please.
We're very poor,
and can't survive if we have to go home.
- Please.
- Landlord!
Your people can survive
drinking water and eating anything.
Please don't say that, landlord.
We'll work day and night,
as much as possible.
- Please let us work.
- Shut up! Stop it!
- Please.
- Kame, you're fired, too!
- Get out of here!
- Landlord!
Get out of here! Now! Get out!
- Please let us work!
- Get out!
Get out of here!
Masae! Masae.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.
Landlord.
Even if I have to eat dirt,
I'll pay you back.