How are ya, Doctor?
Hello, Harry.
Hey, Charlie.
Hello, Dr. Brewster,
Mr. Stanley.
How are ya?
Say, are those all
the passengers you had?
Just the four.
You didn't
put anybody off at
the wrong station, did you?
We're here to meet
a friend of the Caldwells,
a Count Alucard.
There was
no Count on this train.
All customers.
Say,
there was a lot of stuff
in the baggage car
that might
belong to your Count.
Thanks.
We'll take a look at it.
All aboard!
Well, does this look
as though
he's come to stay for
just a couple of weeks?
No, it doesn't.
I wonder
what's become of him.
He's probably coming by car.
Don't worry.
He'll show up.
"D-R-A-C..."
What are you
mumbling about?
Nothing, nothing.
Just a silly idea hit me.
Well, if there's no Alucard,
there's no need of
our waiting around here.
I've got to get
back to the office.
Is that you, Matthew?
Yes, ma'am, Miss Kay.
This is Matthew.
I brought the trunks
and the boxes,
but Mr. Frank said
the Count didn't
come on the train.
Oh.
Well, put them
in the guesthouse
as I told you.
Oh, yes, ma'am,
but I have to have some help.
They're amazingly heavy.
Then get some of
the other boys to help you.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
Thank you, ma'am.
Come on, Sam. Come on.
Matthew's back
from town.
Oh, did the Count come?
No, not yet.
If you only had a phone,
Frank would have called
after the train arrived.
Believe me, if I still
lived here, I'd have one,
even if I had to
string the wires myself.
There are other
means of communication.
Oh. Please, Kay.
No lectures on
metaphysics tonight, huh?
You should allow your mind
to explore the unknown,
Claire,
then you wouldn't
laugh at telepathy.
I know Count Alucard
will be here tonight,
without benefit of telephone.
Oh.
He probably missed the train
and will come down tomorrow.
I must run in
and see Dad a minute
before I dress for the party.
See you later.
You do not know
why you came here tonight.
It was because
I wished you here.
Well, why?
Isn't Count Alucard...
I wished you here
to warn you.
The Angel of Death hovers
over a great house.
I see it in ruins.
Weeds, vines growing over it,
bats flying in and out
the broken windows.
But I want to know
of Count Alucard.
Is he coming?
Do you hear me?
Do you hear me, Queen Zimba?
"Alucard" is not his name.
You must stop him
before it is too late.
Stop him before
death comes to Dark Oaks.
Tell me if he is
coming tonight.
I see you
marrying a corpse,
living in a grave.
I see...
Queen Zimba!
Uh, Stephen!
This excitement
over Kay's Count
has worn me out.
If you'll all excuse me,
I'll let Stephen
take me upstairs.
Good night, Colonel.
Good night.
He's holding up
very well.
Good night.
Good night, Colonel.
Well, Father,
I'm afraid we'll have
to do this all over again
when Count Alucard
does come.
I'm afraid so.
I hope you're not
too tired, Father.
No, I feel fine.
Now, you run along and dance.
Stephen will
help me upstairs.
Good night, children.
Good night, then.
Good night, Father.
Good night, Colonel.
Good night.
I'll smoke a cigar
before going to bed.
That'll be all
for now, Stephen.
Yes, sir.
Kay, you're worried
about something.
I wish you'd tell me
what it is.
Wouldn't you be upset
if you gave a reception,
and your guest of honor
didn't appear?
Is that all?
Isn't that enough?
Yes, I suppose it is,
but I rather thought
you might be worrying
about that old Hungarian gypsy
you brought back with you.
I understand
she died tonight.
Queen Zimba?
"Queen"?
That old swamp cat
with a cabin
full of dried lizards
and stuffed toads?
It's good riddance,
if you ask me.
How did you know
she was dead?
That sort of
news travels fast.
One of the farmhands told me.
He also said
you were there when she died.
I'd hoped
no one knew that.
Why?
She died of a heart attack.
Certainly, your being there
could have no bearing on it.
Oh, they'll ask questions.
What was I doing there,
and what brought on
the attack?
And if I told them,
no one around here
would believe it.
What do they know of
these occult matters?
Blind fools.
Kay, I think it's about time
I talked to you frankly.
We're not blind,
and we're not fools.
We're just plain,
sensible people
that refuse to be fooled
by a lot of supernatural
nonsense.
"Nonsense"?
Exactly.
There's no magic
in dried lizards
and dead chickens.
Ever since you met
this Count Alucard
in Budapest, you've changed.
I hardly know you.
Kay, let me take you away
from all this morbid business.
A six-months' honeymoon,
a year, if you like.
We won't
come back here until
you've overcome
some of these strange ideas.
I'm sorry.
"Sorry"?
Does that mean
you're breaking
our engagement?
Oh, no.
You mustn't even think that.
Then what is it, Kay?
There must be some reason.
Of course
there's a reason, Frank.
Since we were kids,
there's never been
anyone in my heart but you.
You know that.
But, well...
Don't ever doubt me, Frank.
No matter what happens,
believe in me.
Believe
that what I'm doing
is best for us both.
Has it anything
to do with Alucard?
I see.
I'm afraid
there's something
I must tell you, Kay.
Alucard is an impostor,
a fake.
How can you say
such a thing?
I wrote
to Senator Manfield.
His reply informed me
that Count Alucard
is not known at
the Hungarian embassy.
You must be very proud
of that bit of snooping.
I only did
what any man would do
to protect the girl
he intends to marry.
Miss Kay!
Dr. Brewster,
is there anything I can do?
No, no.
You stay here.
Keep the party moving.
Father!
Get some water!
Looks like
the Colonel fell asleep
and dropped his cigar.
That's what started the fire.
Yeah, that's
probably what happened.
There's no evidence
of asphyxiation.
His heart might
have stopped beating
before the fire.
He might even have
died in his sleep.
He looks as though
he were literally
frightened to death.
It's purely a reflex
of the facial muscles.
Doctor,
what are those two marks
on the throat?
They don't look like burns.
Come, Claire.
I think you'd better go.
Announce Count Alucard.
Explain that I came by motor
and was delayed.
I'm sorry, sir,
but Colonel Caldwell
died tonight,
and the family
isn't receiving.
Announce me!
Yes, sir.
Central,
I called Professor Lazlo
at Muirfield University
about a half an hour ago.
Will you please
check the call for me?
This is Dr. Harry Brewster,
228. Thank you.
Hello?
Yes, this is Harry
Brewster speaking.
Fine, thank you.
Why, I called to find out
if you know anything about
a titled Hungarian
family named Alucard.
A-L-U-C-A-R-D.
Alucard? No.
I'm sure there
is no such family.
The name is not Hungarian.
Well, can you tell me,
is it possible
there's a Count Dracula
still living?
Dracula?
I'm sure there is not.
History says
the last Count Dracula
died in the Middle Ages.
Why do you ask?
A certain Count Alucard
is visiting a friend of mine.
I happened to notice that
the name spelled backward
is "Dracula". (CHUCKLES)
It made me curious.
That is strange.
According to
the legends of my people,
the last Count Dracula
became one of the undead,
a vampire,
and was finally destroyed
in the 19th century.
I am considered
somewhat of an authority
on the subject.
I know, Professor.
That's why I called you.
If this man is an impostor,
why should he assume that name
over all others?
Oh. He wouldn't.
Not if he were sane.
In Transylvania,
the name is associated
only with evil.
I advise you to be
very careful of that man.
Well, from your tone,
I gather
you don't entirely
disbelieve the legends
of the former Dracula.
In my research,
I have uncovered data
which I cannot
entirely disprove.
I do not say I believe,
but in honesty,
I cannot say I disbelieve.
I repeat, be very,
very careful of that man.
I will, Professor.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye, sir.
You will find this will
a comparatively
simple document,
owing chiefly to
the fact that you two girls
are the only living kin
of Colonel Caldwell.
It divides the entire estate,
cash, securities and
all evenly between...
Pardon me, Judge Simmons.
May I ask the date
of that will?
August 24th.
It was made
on the occasion
of Miss Claire's attaining
legal age and responsibility.
Then there's a will
of a later date.
There's no
important difference
between them, Claire.
There's a mighty
important difference
for you, Kay.
According to this,
you get nothing
but the plantation.
Claire gets
all cash and securities.
It's properly witnessed
and can't be disputed,
but I can't imagine
what your father
was thinking of.
It's the way I wanted it.
To divide the estate otherwise
would have meant
selling the plantation.
I love Dark Oaks,
and hope to live here always.
But, my dear child,
it takes real capital
to operate
a plantation of this size.
I wouldn't worry
about that, Judge.
I think Colonel Caldwell
knew what he was doing.
Oh. Oh, I see.
Well,
I'd offer my congratulations,
but this hardly
seems the proper time.
That seems
to end the matter.
I'll start the legal machinery
in motion at once.
In fact, I'll start it today,
if the clerk's office
is still open.
Goodbye.
Oh, don't bother, Claire.
I'll find my way out,
thank you.
Goodbye, Judge.
I can't understand
how you've been able
to get along without servants.
I take it that none of them
have returned since
that night.
No,
but I'll arrange for others
if I find I need them.
Well, of course,
you'll know what
you want to do.
Come along, Claire.
Let's leave these two
alone for a while.
I'll see you again
before I leave.
I'm so terribly
sorry for Frank.
I'm afraid he's living
in a fool's paradise.
"A fool's paradise"?
Yes. I'm certain
Kay doesn't intend
to marry him.
Well, what's the trouble?
Count Alucard?
She couldn't marry him.
There's something, well,
repulsive about him.
The way he came in
the night Father died...
Oh, I don't know.
I understand he left
almost immediately.
At least that
was decent of him.
Yes, but...
I'm positive
Kay's been seeing him
more or less secretly.
Why do you say that?
A couple of nights ago,
after I had gone to bed,
I heard them talking
in the hall downstairs.
Somehow,
I didn't like the idea,
and I went to
the head of the stairs
to make sure.
And?
Kay was alone
in the lower hall,
but she was
looking up at me as if...
Well, as if she'd
been caught at something
she wasn't very proud of.
I see.
Did you mention it
to her?
Yes,
but she pooh-poohed the idea,
said I probably was dreaming.
I let it go at that,
but I wasn't dreaming.
I hadn't been asleep.
Hmm.
That does sound strange.
Have you been
in the guesthouse
since the night
your father died?
No, but surely,
you don't think
Count Alucard...
I don't know what to think.
He couldn't be living in town
without my knowing it.
I'd like to take
a look at his belongings,
if he hasn't taken them away.
He couldn't have
done that alone,
they were too heavy.
This might be
a very good time.
Two large chests,
as well as the trunks
came on the train.
I don't know
what's become of them.
They were put in here.
That's strange.
They're not in there, either.
Well, it may not be ethical,
but there are reasons why
we ought to find out more
about the Count.
Well, he didn't have
any handbags.
I don't like it,
Claire.
He can't be traveling around
with only the clothes
he's wearing.
See what I meant
about Frank and Kay?
I don't like it, Claire.
I don't like it one bit!
You've got to leave here
and go back to town,
and the sooner, the better.
You sound as if
I was in some kind of danger.
I'd rather not go into that,
but I insist upon
your leaving.
You can go in with me
and send for
your things later.
Well, I can't leave Kay alone.
If I'm in danger,
she must be, too.
I'm going to make
one last attempt
to persuade her to leave.
If she won't...
Well, if she won't,
I want you to join me
in swearing out
an insanity complaint
against her.
An insanity complaint?
Are you serious?
Kay's my sister.
Claire,
everybody's in danger here,
Kay more than anyone else.
If she won't
leave voluntarily,
then we've just
got to force her.
Yes, but she'd be
arrested, put in an asylum.
I'd never do that to her.
Claire, don't you see?
We've got to protect Kay
from herself.
Yes, what is it?
You remember me,
don't you, Mr. Kirby?
Yes, of course.
You're Colonel
Caldwell's daughter.
Sorry to hear
about your father.
Thank you.
Uh, may we come in?
We want to be married.
Married?
Yes, of course.
Come right in.
Ma! Cecilia!
In a few moments, my dear,
you will become
Countess Alucard.
Everything has
worked out as we planned.
This house is ours.
No one else has
any claim on it.
I like old houses,
and I like your countryside
and the swampland.
It's very different
from your homeland.
That is why I like it.
My land is dry
and desolate.
The soil is red with
the blood of 100 races.
There is no life
left there.
Here, you have
a young and vital race.
You've spoken of your people,
but I want to know more.
Their legends,
their mystery,
their gifts.
Perhaps someday,
we may return there.
As I have told you, my dear,
ours will be a different life,
without material needs.
A life that will
last through eternity.
I'll see who it is.
I told you not to
come here again, Frank.
I'm sorry.
Please, Kay.
I've got to talk to you.
Kay, I must know
what this is all about.
I know that you and Alucard
are meeting secretly.
I followed you tonight
I don't know where you went,
because I lost you, but...
We went to Mr. Kirby's.
We were married.
"Married"?
No.
No, you couldn't have!
I told you before,
we were married tonight.
You'll save us all
a lot of unpleasantness
by going back
to town with me tonight,
and taking
the first train out
in the morning.
I'm afraid
I do not understand.
Then I'll make it clear.
You're going back to
town with me tonight.
In the morning,
you'll take
the first train out.
Kay will have
the marriage annulled
and if you try to stop her,
or show up in this
part of the country again,
you'll be jailed!
Kay!
Frank!
My boy!
Harry.
Harry, how did I get here?
Did you bring me here
from Dark Oaks?
No, you came alone,
about a couple of minutes ago.
What's happened, Frank?
Harry.
Harry, I've killed Kay!
It's all mixed up,
but I know I shot her twice.
Harry, am I insane?
Could I have shot
through Alucard
and killed her
without hurting him?
Tell me what happened.
Well,
I shot right through him.
I shot right through him!
Kay screamed and fell,
and he just stood there.
Just stood there,
staring at me.
Just staring at me.
You don't
believe that, do you?
Nobody will.
Yes, I believe you.
Have you got
your revolver?
I dropped it in the drive.
But you haven't told me,
just what happened?
Kay and Alucard
were married tonight.
I know. I followed them.
Well, didn't you try
to stop the wedding?
A tree smashed my car,
and I lost them.
Then I went back
to Dark Oaks,
and I found them there
and got in a fight with him.
He got me by the throat.
It was like one of
those crazy nightmares
where you can't move,
or struggle or...
I had no more
strength against him
than a baby.
He just threw me aside.
Then I fired.
The bullets went through him
without even hurting him,
and...
And killed Kay.
What did you do then?
I don't know!
I just seemed to be
running and falling and...
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know anything
except I found myself here.
I don't even know
if it's real!
Maybe it's a nightmare,
or something.
Just rest yourself
for a while, Frank.
We'll find out
just how much of it happened.
Here. Drink this.
Lie down, Frank.
May I inquire
what you are doing here?
I was about to ask you
the same question.
Tonight, Miss Caldwell
and I were married.
I am now master
of this house.
You see,
you owe me an explanation.
Well,
I came here to see Katherine.
The door was open,
she didn't answer my call,
and I thought
I heard somebody
here in the cellar.
I, too, thought
that I heard someone
in the cellar.
Come.
Dr. Brewster, what on Earth
brings you here
this time of night?
I hope nothing's happened
to Claire.
No.
No, she was worried
that something
had happened to you.
I'm sorry.
Count Alucard and I
were married tonight.
Yes,
so the Count told me.
It was the way
we wanted it,
quiet and alone.
That's the way
we're going to live, Doctor.
You see,
I'm engaged in some
scientific research.
It will take up all
of our daylight hours.
And we'll have
no time for social life.
We want you to
explain this to Claire.
And to Frank.
I'm fond of Frank.
But, of course,
he must never come here again.
I'd like you to tell
all our friends not to come.
If Judge Simmons has
papers for us to sign,
tell him to bring them
in the evening.
Katherine is
going to assist me
in my research.
I see.
Well, there doesn't seem to be
any more for me to say,
so, if you'll pardon me,
Katherine, I'll be leaving.
Good night.
Goodbye, Doctor.
And say goodbye
to Frank.
Perhaps I should emphasize
some of Katherine's wishes.
When I came to Dark Oaks,
I was not graciously welcomed.
Now, the position has changed.
I am master.
Anyone who enters here
without my permission,
will be
considered a trespasser.
Good morning, Sarah.
Will you set
another place, please?
For Mr. Stanley,
he slept on the couch
in the office last night.
There's nobody
in there now, sir.
There's
a blanket on the couch,
but no sign of Mr. Frank.
Why didn't you put him
in the spare bedroom?
No wonder he never
stayed for breakfast.
I'll just take coffee
this morning, Sarah.
- Good morning, Sarah.
- Good morning, Judge.
It's Judge Simmons, Doctor.
Give Sarah
your hat and coat, Judge,
and come in
and have some
breakfast with me.
I'll keep my coat on.
I can only stay a minute.
Quite a rain we had.
Yes, started about 4:00.
Claire isn't here yet?
No.
No, I expect her
any minute, though.
I was up most of the night
studying that
insanity complaint
you got out against Katherine.
What did you decide?
Well, if I didn't know you,
I'd be suspicious
of your motives.
You have no evidence
of insanity, Harry.
The fact that
she wants to live alone
at Dark Oaks may be eccentric,
but that's all.
And her infatuation
for this Count,
even if he's an impostor...
Well,
that may be bad judgment,
but it certainly
couldn't be
construed as insanity.
They were married
last night by Kirby.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Katherine's like a niece
to me.
You're wanted on the phone,
Judge Simmons.
It's Mrs. Simmons, sir.
She says it's important.
You better take it
in my office, Judge.
Oh, yes, thank you.
Thank you. Yes?
Yes, dear.
What?
Yes.
Well, I'll go right over
to the courthouse.
Goodbye.
Frank Stanley
surrendered to the sheriff
a while ago.
Told some sort of a story
about killing Katherine.
That's not so, Judge.
I know.
He came here in
the middle of the night
in a delirious condition
and told me the same story.
I gave him a sedative
and I drove out to Dark Oaks.
I talked to Katherine,
and that was long after
Frank said he'd killed her.
Oh!
Well, you'd better come over
to the courthouse
and tell them that.
Sarah?
Professor Lazlo
is arriving here
from Memphis on
the morning train.
He's spending
a few days here.
You make him comfortable,
will you, please?
Yes, sir.
Morning, Bob.
Good morning, Richard.
Come in.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Morning, Coroner.
Where's Frank, Sheriff?
The deputy's fetching him.
We're all going
out to Dark Oaks.
I don't think
that'll be necessary.
Dr. Brewster says
that Frank is insane.
I talked to
Katherine and her husband
after Frank was
supposed to have shot her.
What?
Well, I'm going to
Dark Oaks, anyway,
and talk to them myself.
No need to go
until evening.
Katherine and her husband
will be away all day.
Yeah?
Where will they be?
Well, I don't know,
but they told me
to tell Claire
they wouldn't be at home.
I'm going to take
Frank out there, anyway.
Maybe he'll come
to his senses
if we make him
go over the ground
like he covered it
in his confession.
I wish you
wouldn't do that, Sheriff.
Frank has had a shock.
What he needs is
complete relaxation.
Frank Stanley has
confessed to murder.
I have to act on it.
It won't hurt him to
ride out there with us.
I give you my word
that it will.
That's too bad!
But money and position
don't rate him
any better treatment
than anyone else from me.
Did he act crazy to you,
Dr. Peters?
No, can't say
that he did.
A little irrational,
maybe, same as anyone
after committing murder.
Hmm.
You can come along
if you like, Doc.
If everything's all right,
I'll turn him over to you,
forget all about
the confession.
Now,
that ought to be all right.
Funny that they'd leave
the door open.
Anyone here?
Suppose you tell us
where you were
when you shot Katherine,
and where she and
her husband were?
There's nothing to
worry about, Frank.
Go on. Enact the scene
just as you think it happened.
It was in the library.
I seem to remember
running out there
and dropping
the gun in the driveway.
Are you sure
you didn't drive off
in your car, Frank?
Oh, no, no,
I couldn't have.
Because I remember
a tree fell on it
earlier in the evening
while I was
following Kay and Alucard.
About what time was that,
you remember?
It's all so mixed up.
I just don't know,
but I'm sure
I went out that way.
Well, come on, Frank.
Suppose you'd show us
just where.
I was here,
but I don't remember
anything after that.
Remember this, Frank?
I think
we'd better go back
to the office, Doctor,
while you do some explaining.
Kay! Kay, my darling!
Good evening, Doctor.
Has Professor Lazlo
arrived?
Yes, sir. He's been here
all day, in and out.
Can I fix you
something to eat, Doctor?
The professor's
had his dinner.
No, thanks.
Professor,
I'm glad to see you.
I heard about
the tragic events
of last night.
And I called at the courthouse
several times this afternoon,
but they wouldn't
let me see you.
Step inside.
Thank you.
The sheriff believes
that I'm an accessory
after the fact
in the murder of Katherine.
And I can't say
that I blame him.
Why?
He can't believe that
I spoke to Katherine
after Frank shot her.
And because
I urged him to keep away
from Dark Oaks until tonight,
he thinks I intended
to hide her body
during the day.
But he didn't arrest you?
No.
No, he questioned me
most of the day,
but he's not quite ready
to hold me.
Then, you didn't tell him
what we believe?
Well, the chances
of convincing
a hardheaded sheriff
that we were
dealing with a vampire
seemed pretty slim.
Very.
And yet, I am satisfied
that such is the case.
Alucard is
undoubtedly a vampire.
Probably a descendant
of Count Dracula.
Are you sure we're not
allowing our imagination
to run away
with our common sense,
Professor?
Can you suggest
any other explanation
for the events of
the past few days?
No.
Neither can I give
a lucid explanation
of a vampire.
Mmm-hmm.
Broadly speaking,
a vampire is
an earthbound spirit
whose body comes
to life at night
and scours the countryside,
satisfying a ravenous appetite
for the blood of the living.
This it does by drawing it
from the throat of its victim.
That's a nauseating thought!
They're supposed
to be immortals,
no doubt?
Uh, practically.
So long as they return
to their graves
before sunrise.
Between then and sunset,
they remain in a, sort of,
uh, cataleptic state,
during which
they can be destroyed
by two different means.
At night, however,
they are invulnerable.
You mean you actually believe
that Frank shot
through Alucard
without hurting him?
Bullets would have
had no effect on him.
Well,
it's strange to hear a man
of science like yourself
calmly admit that
he believes in
a superstition so fantastic.
I could spend
days citing proof
that it is not
mere superstition.
My own homeland in
the Carpathian Hills,
where Count Dracula lived,
is sad testimony to its truth.
What was once a happy,
productive region,
is today, barren waste.
Villages depopulated,
the land abandoned.
Maybe that's why he left there
and came here to
a younger country,
stronger and more virile.
Of course.
And he will fasten
on it and drain it dry,
just as he did his homeland.
Unless...
We can find his grave
and destroy him in it.
His grave?
He was buried in Hungary,
wasn't he?
Yes, but you will find
that one of the chests
he brought
contains a layer of soil
from his birthplace.
That constitutes a grave.
Are you serious?
Rest assured
he has it hidden
in some safe place
and returns to it
just before sunrise
every morning.
And our job
seems to be to find
that chest with him
in it, and destroy him.
That won't be as
simple as it sounds.
The vampire can assume
very many different forms
at will.
Sometimes,
it appears as a bat,
sometimes, as a werewolf,
and sometimes,
as a small cloud
of swirling vapor.
In this way,
it can move unseen
among its enemies,
learn their plans
and be in a position
to outwit them.
You are
very brilliant, aren't you,
Professor Lazlo?
Perhaps too brilliant
for your own good,
and that of Dr. Brewster.
You're right.
I am here
because this is
a young and virile race,
not dry and
decadent like ours.
They have what I want,
what I need, what I must have.
Do you suppose
that I would allow
any mortal to stand in my way?
Here, drink this.
Thanks.
This doesn't leave me
much room to go on
disputing your theories,
Professor.
How in the world
did you drive him away?
I showed him this.
A simple cross!
It would take too long
to explain why
they fear it, but they do.
Keep this and
wear it at all times,
especially in your sleep.
Dracula has you
marked for death.
Not only me,
but unsuspecting people
in this district,
who'd never believe us
if we tried to warn them.
We must find some way
to destroy him
before it's too...
Excuse me, Doctor Harry,
but it's Mrs. Land to see you.
Something's happened
to Tommy, Doctor.
Put him here.
I sent him to my sister's
on an errand tonight.
He was gone so long,
I finally went after him.
Will you get my bag,
Professor?
Certainly.
I found him lying
beside the road,
just like this.
He talked a little,
but he didn't make sense.
He acted like
he was scared foolish.
And then he said something
about a foreign man in a fog,
but there wasn't
any fog tonight, Doctor.
I noticed those wounds
on his neck, too.
What are they?
Small animal bites?
No, I don't think so.
We can fix that very easily.
Sarah?
Yes, Dr. Harry?
Why don't you make
Mrs. Land a cup of tea?
You go along with Sarah,
Mrs. Land.
Yes, sir.
Tommy's going to be all right.
He's had a bit of a shock.
I want him to stay here
until he regains
consciousness.
I'll call you.
Thank you, Doctor.
Dracula's first victim.
It's starting fast.
Tell me, does that mean
that Tommy's in danger
of becoming
a vampire himself?
No, unless Alucard drained
so much blood from him,
that he died.
Well, what about Kay?
She died from bullet wounds,
and yet, you implied
that she would
become a vampire.
Yes, but her case
was different.
Her background was...
I know, morbid.
She'd gone overboard
on the subject of
the supernatural,
black magic and the like.
Exactly.
And I rather
believe that Miss Caldwell
may have made the transition
from choice.
No one could choose
a thing so loathsome!
Don't forget,
the girl was morbid.
That often
means thanatophobia,
fear of death.
And Alucard could
promise her eternal life.
Eternal life
at such a price?
Why do you think
she is a vampire?
The dirt which I understand
had been thrown
into her grave...
Who else would have done that
except Alucard, Dracula?
But then that means
we have to destroy her
as well?
That should be
relatively simple.
Her sister could
order her cremation
while the body is
still in the morgue.
Perhaps you're right.
Hello. Oh, hello, Claire.
I was just about to call you.
No, I think that'll
be perfectly safe.
Professor Lazlo
and I will stop by
and pick you up.
Oh, it's no trouble.
Besides, there's something
we want to talk to you about.
All right. See you
in a few minutes then.
The sheriff's office
just called her.
They say that Frank is
still a bit irrational,
and insists upon seeing her.
While she's there,
she can leave orders
for Katherine's cremation.
Oh, Sarah?
Mrs. Land?
Unfortunately,
I have to run along.
I think in a few minutes,
it'll be perfectly safe
to take Tommy home.
Don't you worry about him.
He's going to be all right.
Thank you, Doctor.
Frank?
Frank.
Kay.
No, it can't be.
Yes, Frank, it's Katherine.
No. No, you can't be Kay.
Kay's dead! I know,
I killed her. I saw her fall.
I was with the sheriff
when he found her body,
and she was dead.
She was dead! I saw her!
You see me now, too.
Yes, but...
Do you doubt
your own eyes?
It is you. It is you,
Kay, and you're alive!
But what is it, Kay?
You seem to be cold,
like death.
You seem to be Kay,
but there's
a strange difference.
It's almost as if
I didn't know you.
Does that mean
you no longer love me?
I'll always love you.
Enough to spend
the rest of your life
with me?
But...
But you're married, Kay,
you're married to Alucard.
I don't love him, Frank.
I never did.
But you're married to him!
I had to, Frank.
It was part of the plan
I told you about
in the garden.
I asked you to
have faith in me then.
I beg you to have
faith in me now.
I don't understand.
Count Alucard
is immortal.
Through him,
I attained immortality.
Through me,
you will do the same,
and we will spend
eternity together.
Are you serious?
Do you expect me to believe
anything so unreal?
How else can you
explain the fact
you shot through him
without hurting him?
How else could I be here?
Why, I can't explain it.
It's so incredible!
Perhaps you'll understand
when I tell you
Count Alucard's real name
is Count Dracula.
Count Dracula?
You mean the Hungarian
who's supposed
to have become...
Don't use that word, Frank.
We don't like it.
Say, rather,
that we are "undead."
"Immortal."
Do you mean
you deliberately planned this?
You married him
so you could become a...
So you and I could
attain immortality, yes.
But even if
it would work,
do you expect me
to agree to anything
so fantastic?
You have no choice.
I've taken the first step
while you were sleeping.
No. No, I can't do it.
I've already told you,
you have no choice.
Frank, isn't eternity together
better than a few years
of ordinary life?
Yes.
Yes, I suppose it is.
There's one thing
you must do while you're still
in your present form.
What is that?
Destroy Dracula.
Destroy Dracula?
But how?
There is one advantage
all humans have over us.
You can move about
in the daytime. We can't.
We must return to
our graves before sunrise,
or we're destroyed.
But how can I keep him
from his grave?
You don't have to.
You can destroy him
in one of two ways.
Either drive a stake
through his heart,
or burn his grave
before he reaches it.
You must do this,
Frank, for us.
Well,
Miss Caldwell!
It got so late,
I didn't think you were
coming in tonight.
Oh, I thought you
might have told Frank,
and I didn't want
to disappoint him.
I don't suppose
we're allowed
to see him, too?
Sheriff says no.
Find out if he knows
where Count Alucard
keeps himself during the day.
I'll try.
Third one on your left.
Hello, Frank.
Hello, Claire.
It's nice of you to
come after everything.
I can only stay
a few minutes. I...
I just wanted to tell you
that I know it was
an accident.
That makes me feel better.
Kay understands, too.
I'm sure she does.
Oh, I know it,
I know it, because she...
Would you think
I was losing my mind
if I told you
that Kay has been here
to talk to me?
Oh, I'd be more likely to say
you'd been dreaming.
Yes,
yes, I guess you're right.
I was dreaming.
You know,
they'll never convict
Stanley of that killing.
No?
No.
He's as nutty
as a filbert.
He's been back there
for a long time,
talking to some dame
who wasn't there.
First, he talks in his voice,
then he answers in
the woman's voice.
Did you... Did you hear
anything that was said?
That'd be a swell way
to spend a rainy evening.
Eavesdropping on some goof
talking to himself
in two voices.
Some fun!
Dr. Brewster's doing
all he can for you, Frank.
All he can do is
get me out of here
on an insanity plea.
That shouldn't be hard.
You mustn't even
think such things.
Why not?
I can't be sane.
I really believe
Kay came here to talk to me.
If that's not crazy, then I...
When are they going
to hold the funeral?
We haven't been
able to contact
Count Alucard so far.
Do you happen to know
where he stays during the day?
Why during the day?
It's an unpleasant trip
out there at night,
and there's no phone.
Why should anyone
think I know?
Well, you said
you saw him meet Kay
on the road once,
and I wondered
if you saw where he came from.
I'm sorry.
I don't know anything.
I suppose you'll be
burying her at Dark Oaks?
Yes, I think so.
At least her ashes
will be taken there.
Her ashes?
Yes.
I'm going to leave
an order for her cremation.
But you can't do that.
You can't do that, I tell you!
She isn't dead, I know!
She came here
and talked to me!
You can't cremate her,
she isn't dead!
It would kill her!
I won't let you burn her
now that she's immortal!
You mustn't
excite yourself this way.
You've got to
reconcile yourself to
the fact that Kay is dead.
But she isn't!
I know...
I know she isn't dead!
Stanley, let her go!
But she isn't dead,
I tell you!
All right, Frank.
I think you'd better leave,
Miss Caldwell.
But you must
listen to me.
Frank,
try and get some sleep.
Good night, Frank.
Kay?
Kay!
Did you hear what she said?
They're going to cremate you.
Yes, I heard. That means
Dr. Brewster has guessed
the truth.
We may have to
eliminate him and Claire.
Oh, no. No,
not your own sister.
She's no longer my sister
when she interferes with me.
But if they cremate you...
They won't find me.
I'll go to Dark Oaks tonight.
But we'll never be safe
as long as Dr. Brewster's
alive.
Our first worry's Alucard.
If I could get out of here,
I'd start hunting for him.
I'll get you out,
but you won't have
to hunt for Alucard.
I know where he can
be found in the daytime.
Where?
Remember
the old drainage flume
near the edge of the swamp?
Yes.
That's the place.
But be sure
you don't get there
until after
the sun is up.
Didn't I tell you
to get some sleep?
I couldn't go to sleep.
I was talking to someone.
Yeah.
Well, she's gone now,
so, I'll just douse
the lights.
I'll wait for you
at Dark Oaks,
in the playroom
Claire and I used
to have in the attic.
I'll unlock the cell
and bring you a gun.
There is very little doubt
in my mind
that Kay has
visited Frank in his cell,
and I'm afraid for one
very definite purpose.
What purpose?
Didn't you tell me
that she and Frank
have always been in love?
Ever since
they were children. Why?
Well,
it's an unpleasant thought,
but there are cases on record
where the living
have voluntarily joined
the ranks of the undead
in order to consummate
what might be called
an "unholy alliance."
You can't be serious,
Professor.
Why, such a pact
between Kay and Frank
is unthinkable!
Perhaps.
But so long as there is even
the remotest possibility,
and I insist there is,
we must arrange
for immediate cremation.
Otherwise, she will destroy
her own soul and Frank's.
Frank!
Get back!
Stay away from me.
Stay away from me!
Frank! Frank Stanley!
What happened?
Frank Stanley just escaped!
Look out for him,
he's armed.
Get after him! But if
you have to shoot, do it!
What happened, Mack?
How'd he get out?
I don't know, Sheriff.
The keys were on
the desk as usual.
And now they're gone,
and so is Stanley.
I tried to stop him, but...
Did you have anything
to do with this break,
Dr. Brewster?
Certainly not!
We are as anxious as you are
to keep him locked up.
More so.
Did you hear him
do any more talking
to that girl?
What girl?
Katherine Caldwell.
Katherine Cald...
Oh, it's some kind of
a crazy trick Stanley pulls.
He pretends to be
talking to some girl.
First in his voice,
then in hers.
What is this,
some trick you put him up to
so he'd sound crazy?
Did you listen in
as we asked you to?
Yeah.
But it was too crazy
to bother about.
For instance?
Well, the girl's voice
said something about
getting him out of jail.
That wasn't
so crazy, was it? He's out.
That's right.
Hey, I never thought of that.
Do you really think
there was someone
in there with him?
Never mind that.
What else did he say,
however crazy it was?
Well, she said something
about meeting him
at Dark Oaks,
in some kid playroom.
I know where it is.
What else?
Oh, some crazy stuff
about killing Count Alucard.
Did he say "kill him,"
or "destroy him"?
Come to think of it,
I believe he did say
"destroy".
Uh...
"Shove a stake through him,"
or something.
"Shove a stake through him"?
Yeah.
We're dealing with a madman.
Obviously.
Did he say anything
that would give us an idea
of where he expected
to find Count Alucard?
Yeah, but that really
was crazy.
She said
something about a swamp
with a drainage tunnel...
I know
where that is, too.
Good.
We'll get right out there,
and warn Alucard
before Frank gets there.
You'll not warn him
if we have to lock you up
in your own jail.
What's that?
There's a lot to this
you don't understand,
Sheriff.
If you doubt it,
just let's go over
and take a look
in that morgue.
What's the morgue
got to do with it?
Oh, never mind.
It's all becoming
as plain as day, Professor.
It has been to me
for some time.
Well, then let's go take
a look at that morgue.
Okay.
The coffin is gone,
corpse and all!
Of course.
You sound as if
you expected it.
We did.
What's your part
in all this?
How do you know in advance
what's happening?
We'd better get out
to where Alucard is hiding.
We'll try to explain it
to you on the way.
I thought you weren't
going to warn Alucard
about Frank.
We're not.
But we may have to save Frank
from the Count, and from
his own madness.
Gentlemen, the farther we go,
the crazier you sound.
Well.
It is seldom
that my enemies
are so accommodating.
How did you learn
where to find me?
I know all about you.
You're not Count Alucard,
but Count Dracula,
one of the undead,
a loathsome thing,
surviving on
the blood of the living.
Well,
there'll be no more blood
of the living for you,
because I'm going
to destroy you.
If you had
learned more about me,
you wouldn't have come here
until after sunrise.
Now, it is not I that
is going to be destroyed.
Put it out!
Put it out, do you hear me?
You stay here, Jack.
This is one thing
we didn't foresee, Doctor.
How could we?
I don't get it.
What's happened?
To maintain his existence
among the undead,
Dracula had to be
back in his coffin
before sunrise.
Frank prevented it,
as you can see.
You mean, that's all
that's left of Alucard?
Look at the ring
on his hand.
It bears the Alucard seal,
just as on his luggage.
Well, assuming it is Alucard,
or Dracula, or whoever
he calls himself,
where is Frank Stanley?
He's still wanted for murder.
Do you still think
that Frank killed Kay
deliberately?
Look, Doctor,
I'm only the sheriff.
I'm not the judge.
It's my job to bring him in,
and the court to decide
he's guilty.
Of course, but I think
our testimony
will have some bearing
on their decision.
Undoubtedly.
But the main thing
to do now is
to find Frank,
and I think I know
where he is.