What?
What is it?
- Go back to sleep.
Hey you're alive. I'm hanging up.
- I think I did something.
Yeah.. You did, you woke
my ass up at four in the morning.
I think.. Something bad.
- Where is your inhaler?
In my bedroom.
Good.
Here's what you're gonna do.
You're gonna hang up the phone, you're gonna walk to the bedroom,
take a hit off that thing and go to bed.
Mason?
Someone call the Police.
- Call the Police?
Shit, Mason.
I think you can handle it.
So what are you gonna do?
Use my inhaler.
And go to bed.
Good, buddy.
Breating in bed
I'm gonna do my part
and I'm gonna go back to sleep.
See, it's like teamwork only
I don't do anything. Get it?
Okay?
You're gonna be alright.
I'm gonna be alright.
JZD&J
INSURANCE.
You're late.
Did you hear me?
Where have you been?
I'm sorry.
Well that's real nice of you Mason
but it's not helping. You know why?
Because I got 6000 phonecalls that
have to be made by the end of the week
and an employee who can't get his ass to
work on time, even though he lives two blocks away.
Shit, I'm sorry.
I guess I'm just tired from someone
waking me up in the middle of the night.
See how that can make a guy
cranky in the morning Mason?
Okay then.
You okay?
Get some sleep finally?
Good to make some calls?
Okay. Good.
Then get to work, you crazy bastard.
Yes, I believe I can help
lower your rates by 20%.
Let me ask.
Have you, or anyone in your family
ever been in a car accident?
The rates are fixed and they
stay the same for the life of the plan.
Yes mam.
Can you.. please hold.
She's pretty.
Who is she?
She is..
Nobody.
Then you have a good imagination.
What are you doing?
Huh? Oh.. just..
Eating potatoes.
You want some?
Amber.
Picked a really nice spot here.
It's like a middle school inside.
Feel like I should smoke a cigarrete
and make out with an eighth grader.
Anyway. What did you say your
name was again?
I really like your drawings.
I.. I don't draw. I sketch.
I'm a painter.
Looks like it's gonna rain again.
Get in the car man!
What the hell are you doing?
Get your ass in the car, man.
Seriously bro, you're a grown man.
Invest in an umbrella.
So hey Mason.
Are we heading to the apartment?
Or we'll just sit right here.
Hey Mason, whats up?
You remember Christie? She was a year
ahead of us. I hired her today.
Brought her on for 20 cents
less than you. The bitch.
She's got fakes now, so you might
wanna start drawing her.
Come on Mason.
It's pouring out there.
We're having a conversation!
I'm really getting
sick of this shit Mason.
No mam.
We only handle annual and
bi-annual schedules.
What?
I'm sorry.
I'm not familiar with that.
Yeah, I'm gonna have to
check with my supervisor.
Can you please hold?
So you're from Kentucky.
- I've been here for almost three months.
You're awfully far from home.
Hey Mason, what's cooking?
Yeah, tell me about it.
Nah, that's a great plan.
I actually got one for my grandma.
True story.
Can you hold on for one second.
Can I help you?
I need to do an R27.
So?
I'v never done one.
Hold on.
JZD&J
Absolutely, he's at his desk,
just let me transfer you there.
What is it you need?
How to do an R27.
What am I, the guy you ask that?
I just..
- Hold on.
Yeah, absolutely, it's a..
Please go away.
It's called an R27.
I can set you up an account...
I just had a look for you
and it looks like I can save you...
It rained.
I should have been a weather girl.
My superviser says I'm
not cut out for sales.
Isn't that great?
I've been here under than a week
and already she's giving me these
'You're not right for this job'-talk
So I'm not the milk man.
Six sales a day.
I'm still learning.
I spit in her drink.
Her coffee,
I spit in it.
Which is really immature, but it
was just sitting there and i was just,
You know I really want to be good at this,
I really do, but,
It's just not fair for someone
to treat someone that way.
So what do I do? I go and act
like a teenager, and I just do
something really stupid.
And now I feel like this.
She probably deserved it.
Sir, we are an auto
insurance company.
No. Sir,
We don't do life insurance.
No, we just...
Okay.
Just think of it like make-up sex,
without the awkwardness.
..or the sex.
Thanks.
What can I say,
I'm a great guy.
Besides, I know your routine,
I can tell when it's time to move on.
There's a whole ocean out there
for you to dip your rod in. Carpe Diem.
So whatever.
It was just $10.
Hey you know, why don't we go
play some ball later this week.
Lunch hour at the court.
Like old time sakes.
You can work on your jumpshot.
I don't have a jumpshot.
- That's exactly my point.
She is calling me all the time,
she wants me to meet her parents, Look
I just think there should be an agreement,
Some sort of conversation between the two parties.
Because until then, you should have
the opportunity to entertain other options.
Does she know that?
God no, what are you kidding?
She would never agree to that.
Not about the other options.
Come on.
So I fired that chick
Christie already.
Why?
She showed up late for
work her first three days.
Anyway, it doesn't matter,
she has a boyfriend.
Have you..
Hired anyone else recently?
Mason, I hire people all the time.
No, I mean like..
Girls.
Someone's on the prowl huh?
Lemme think.. no.
But I'm not the only one
that does hiring. Why?
Nothing.
Nothing huh.
Alright, an office romance.
That can be a tricky thing.
Shit, I've had my wings cut in
that nasty web quite a few times.
Fortunately it doesn't matter.
Just shoot the damn ball. You're
never gonna get better unless you practise.
I don't want to get better.
And therein lies your problem.
Mason! Hey!
Wait up.
Hey.
-Hey! I missed you today at lunch.
Yeah, I..
- Do you always walk home? Don't have a car?
Oh. A nature thing, I get it.
What are you doing this weekend?
Nothing.
Are you going to the
'end of the promotion'-thing?
Because I was thinking about
going, you should go.
You're very.. Happy.
That could be because somebody
got all her numbers today.
I got all my numbers.
You know what that means Mason?
Coffee is safe again?
- No, it was only one cup, didn't touch the pot!
It was surgical strikes Mason.
Surgical strikes.
So anyway, now that I have conqured
my current job, what should I do next?
I was thinking feminist or astronaut.
Probably feminist.
I'm afraid of heights.
What does a feminist do?
Mostly just bitches about stuff.
Heh, I dunno.
Oh! Maybe ninja!
I've always thought there aren't
enough girl ninjas in the world.
I love that word by the way.
Say it! Ninja!
C'mon Mason say it!
Ninjaaa.
Ninja Mason, Ninja. Say it.
- Ninja.
Doesn't that sound great?
You know what you get?
You get a Karate chop!
That's gonna bruise.
I've been practising.
Seriously, I just think it'd be nice
to have a job that makes you feel good.
Um, I live here.
Okay.
Well, gee Mason.
Thank you for walking me home.
Perhaps you would like to come in
and have some coffee or something, look at my art?
Great.
Alright I'll see you later.
Thank you.
For the umbrella.
Oh yeah. Of course.
These things are pretty rare in this
town, but if you look hard you can find one.
Probably shouldn't get mine wet.
You suck at this game, you know that?
Stop whining.
Brings a sack to a party?
At least he's not wearing his backpack.
Guys, just play the game.
You alright buddy?
Do you have..
any water?
Mason, you're at a party, if you
want water you don't have to ask.
That was a lucky kill.
Two in a row?
Is that lucky?
It was one! You killed yourself
the second time! Blew yourself up!
It was him.
It was you.
(you didn't kill anybody!).
Guess who!
I always hated that game.
As soon as the other person
hears your voice, it's over.
I want to create my own game where
no one has to say anything, just guess.
You came.
- Yeah of course I came, I told you I would.
Are you getting ready to leave.. or?
That's real cute!
Real cute.
I hate these people.
Then why'd you come?
Not for them.
Look!
Look at all of this.
This is so beautiful.
It's cold.
- Oh, quit.
It's so worth the view.
No pain no gain Mason.
This is..
Nice.
See?
I told you.
Look you can see Lower Hurst Park from here.
I used to go feed the ducks there
when I was little. It was amazing.
I think that's the phone bank.
Oh yeah, you're right.
And look, there's your apartment.
If I had a view like this..
You look out of my window
and all you see is bricks.
You should paint this, Mason.
I dont.. do scenery.
Just people?
Like uh..
Like the girl in your sketches?
Sorry.
It's really none of my business.
We all have a history.
If I told you my life story,
we'd be here for the rest of the night.
But um..
You're not..
.. painting anyone right now, are you?
No. Noone.
You know we could walk from here.
Maybe you should just take your own coat.
Bat cave?
Can I..
Yeah sure.
They were my first.
All the great Jazz albums.
Is that what we're gonna do?
Only with bigger brushes.
Are you calling me fat?
They're postcards.
They're awesome.
Did you make them
for someone special?
Am I doing this right?
Is there something I should be doing?
Just..
Be you.
Hey buddy!
Whatcha doing?
Didn't see you leave last night.
Everything okay?
Fine.
I knew that sketch pad would do
you good, best $10 I ever spent.
You wouldn't believe how long
those assholes stayed at my house last night.
Next time we're doing it somewhere else,
let Senior management pick up the tab.
I gotta go.
Eat.
Why don't you come eat in
my office for a change?
My grandma was a dream reader.
It's true.
My whole family is practically gypsies.
Did you know that in Romania, they
still have whole tribes of gypsies.
It's crazy! They just, you know..
Ride around the countryside on wagons,
drawn by horses. Campfires, the whole thing.
Wouldn't it be great to be just,
you know, free?
Free to what?
Just do whatever.
Just to.. go. You know.
It wouldn't even matter where.
Let me see your hand.
Why?
Let me see it!
I want to see if your life line
matches up with your health line.
If it does, that usually means
you're gonna get married.
Are you doubting my gypsie blood?
No.
- Well you better not be.
I could put a hex on you.
I think hexes are more
for witches than gypsies.
You just made a joke!
You big phoney.
Did you just call me a witch?
So, you get her naked yet?
It's not like that.
Well if would be
if I was painting them.
Seriously buddy,
it's a good scam you're running.
Chicks dig the quiet
artsy guy.
Hey what about this one?
I don't think that's Jazz.
You barely looked at it.
There are not a lot of
soprano saxophones in Jazz.
Oh yeah smartypants? Wanna see
how much you really know?
Soft Hits.
Smooth jazz.
Smooth jazz isn't jazz.
How is it possible that you of
all people are a snob about something.
No, Buddy Holly didn't give
out a live album in 1962.
Because he died in '59.
That's a good one,
it's like a weather report on crack.
Yeah, as long as it's not 'smooth'.
I don't get it.
Guess you don't get Jazz.
Listen. That redhead.
She's still working here?
Haven't seen her around.
Ducks!
Look at all of them, aren't they great!
You gotta spend more time outdoors, really.
It's my new-years resolution for you.
Can't believe you lived here your
whole life and not once come down here.
Man, these ducks are
seriously fatter than I remember.
Look at that little kid
feeding those fat freezing birds.
I used to do that when
I was little. I made them fat.
I did that.
Come on.
Don't I get to see
what you're working on?
No, there's rules.
You can't see it
until it's finished.
Yes, I've been very understanding
when it comes to that part about painting
but I think that I deserve to
see a first draft.
It's not that.
This is the next one.
Who said there was going
to be a next one.
Mason, do you think that
pictures capture peoples souls?
Indians thought so.
Not all of them,
but mostly.
I wonder what
they would think of this.
You trying to steal my soul Mason?
Yeap. These ducks sure are fat.
You got turkey right?
Yes.
- Then the damage is already done.
Get in the middle.
Get them all.
Can you jump?
Are you like a dolphin?
Oh it's on your head.
I'm sorry!
...that same movie released.
There's this old theater
in the neighbourhood where I grew up.
It played these great movies
like 'Casablanca' and 'Rear Window'.
I used to go every day after school.
I'd watch them over and over again.
We should go sometime.
I've never been to a movie.
I'm sorry, did you just say never?
Even like, with your parents?
So who did you make
the postcards for ?
What?
Let's do the next one.
I just have
a hard time getting into it.
That's part of the point.
Jazz isn't about accessibility.
It is more
difficult to relate to.
It's not friendly or neat.
Only the finest musicians can play it.
Masters. People who have devoted
themselves to studying the theory of music.
The Rules.
And then they get together, as a
craft, and break these rules that they value.
It's decadent and carnal.
All at the same time.
I think that's probably the most
words you've said to me in one sitting.
I like Jazz.
- And I like coffee.
And I can't believe
you don't drink it.
When we go in here, just do what I do.
We'll try to sell you....
Where were you going?
Can we talk about it?
What?
No, I.. I just..
Can't figure out what colors to use
for the shadows on your arm.
So we're not gonna talk about it.
Okay.
So, why didn't you use the blue?
Because it will pull
focus from your eyes.
What about the orange?
Too close to the tan of your slip.
Does that matter?
Yes..
It's all about contrast
To accentuate some parts
good enough to hide others.
So they can't be noticed?
So they won't draw attention.
Now I know
why you like to paint.
Why?
Because you relate to it.
That's what's great about you.
Contrast.
I kind of envy that.
You shouldn't envy me.
That's me.
Hold your damn elbow in.
Line yourself up.
And remember to follow
all the way through.
You're still a great painter.
So contrast, huh?
I can see that.
Some would call it manic,
but contrast works too.
Oh come on, you've always been a bit
manic. But you've come a long way since.
I'm proud of you.
Contrast.
That's right.
Just like your paintings.
I'm telling you.
Chicks dig them.
Remember little Jessica
from outdoor ed. ?
She went nuts when she saw
those postcards you used to paint.
She stole one.
Yeah.
She went nuts!
The teacher had to go through all
of her stuff and found a pair of my underwear.
I'm telling you, that chick was a freak.
I wonder what she's doing now.
Sorry. Berkley, they are
looking for you for the one o clock.
Hello babe.
Conference room three.
Isn't she the cutest
thing you've ever seen?
God I love being the boss.
We'll work on your shot later.
Can I leave early today?
Why, you need some primping
time before you go out clubbing?
I'm kidding.
Do what you need to do.
And people say
I'm not a nice guy.
They don't actually say that.
So, are you gonna tell me where we're
going or do I have to push you in a puddle?
I really like Christmas.
It's the second week of December.
- Oh! You know what we should do?
We should go to the
mall and sit on Santa's lap.
And have our picture taken and
tell him everything we want, and
watch the really angry moms with
their screaming kids.
No elves.
Mason, are you afraid of elves?
Like ghouls.
- That is like the cutest thing ever!
Oh wait. I have something for you.
What is it?
It's your gift, Mister.
You have to wait until
Christmas to open it.
You'll ruin the surprise.
They're bus tickets.
Bus tickets?
And there's two of them.
They are open which pretty
much means we can go anywhere we want to.
Like my gypsie kin.
Do you like them?
Thank you.
- You're welcome!
Close your eyes.
- What ?
Just close your eyes.
Okay.
Let me guess.. Mason?
Step down.
- Okay, stepping down.
Just the one?
Two.
What do you think?
For the next painting?
You look like...
A Jazz player?
A Jazz singer.
Whatever. I like it. What's the point of
being a model if you can't live a decadent life.
What do you think?
Beige or true brown.
Never ask a girl if she
wants to be painted in Beige.
The answer will always be the same.
Oh! I'll be right back.
Are you okay?
I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to...
It's okay. I'm just..
just..
I just get
startled easily.
Was that me?
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Just..
No more elves.
No more elves. Promise.
I'm sorry.
Mother.
If she finds lipstick on a glass
in the sink then she's too much for me.
It's like she's looking for this shit.
It's like commitment, basically.
Are you still painting
that 'contrast' girl?
Yeah you must be, you're doing so well.
You're hitting your numbers.
No more middle of the night phonecalls.
Not that I mind bro, but
it can kill the moment from time to time.
If you know what I mean.
At the buzzer!
.. and fouled.
Do you think I can bring her?
What are you talking about?
Bring her where?
To Christmas dinner.
Do you think I can bring Amber?
C'mon buddy. Do you
really think that's a good idea?
I'm trying Berkley.
And I know that. It's just..
It's a big thing, you know,
This Christmas dinner.
I want you to be happy.
Why don't you just come have dinner with us.
That way you're not setting yourself up for..
Expectations.
I don't know.
This one's.. different.
This one's special.
They are not special.
They are just girls, Mason.
You should remember that.
Look, you're a grown man.
If you want to invite somebody..
Just think about it. Okay?
I mean you're really doing well.
I went and saw my mom.
You went to the cemetary?
I didn't know
you ever went out there.
I don't.
Well that's good.
Take a page out of my book
and don't dwell on the past.
You think people go to hell?
Are you asking me if I think
your old man is going to hell?
I don't know man.
No way.
Mason I'm not coming out.
What are you talking about?
I don't know what kind of ideas
you have about this, but I'm really a shy girl.
You don't have to
if you don't want to.
Okay..
Promise you'll never
tell anyone about this.
Is this good?
It's beautiful.
So Miles will play all over that area,
in different lounges and bars.
One time this young bass player
got the opportunity to work with him.
To play with
the master himself.
This kid looked up to Miles his whole life
and was so excited about playing with him,
That he practiced these really
hard bass lines. He was great.
He just went off on stage with Miles.
So when they were taking a break,
he walked up to him at the bar.
And he asked him:
'How do you think I did?'
Miles said; 'You were great, kid. you and
me should hire a bass player and go on the road.'
I don't get it.
You know, because bass players
usually just do easy..
And he was like all..
- Wait.. Hold on.
I'm working on your shoulder.
I'm sorry.
How come I never got
to see your lifeline.
You never asked again.
Maybe I should've.
Then maybe I would've been
able to understand your ways.
What ways?
You're just very secretive,
not so much your art, but you
definitely have.. boundaries.
Maybe secretive isn't the right word.
You're an enigma.
Well.. Like you said. Contrast.
I hate these power surges.
Isn't rain supposed to be better for
electricity, like a hairdryer in the bathtub?
That's one of the little ones, right?
The postcards.
This was his favorite.
Who's favorite?
We should keep working, we're almost finished
- Mason, who's favorite?
We're very close to being done.
- Mason, wh..
I didn't mean..
- It's..
Late.
They were for my father.
He.. sent them all back.
He didn't want them.
Is everything okay?
Do you want to have Christmas
dinner at Berkley's with me?
All I have is peanut butter.
That's fine.
Did you just sniff that?
If there was a nuclear explosion, all that
would be left would be peanut butter and cockroaches.
It's fine.
I'm just gonna put it on some bread.
It's cold.
Hey can I..
..can I borrow some socks?
The floor is freezing.
I have apples too.
I didn't know if
you wanted me to put the..
What are you doing?
I was looking for
some socks. It's cold.
Last night was...
Let's finish the painting.
Okay.
I got my bonus this week.
I hit all my sales.
I haven't done that all year.
That's really great.
Berkley said our floor is leading.
That's a first time for him.
What's next?
- Hey..
I don't get to see whats next?
You know the rules.
Listen.. I have this idea..
For one of the sketches..
- No.
What?
I just...
I'm halfway through this pose.
I'm the one that's gonna have to do all these poses.
- You're not the artist.
I'm sorry.
- Forget it.
Look, why don't you come up with the next one.
- Just.. forget it. Okay?
Are you mad?
How many girls have you sketched?
Before me.
What?
How many Mason?
I want to know.
I don't.. I don't know.
You don't know,
or you don't want to say?
Why are you doing this?
- I'm feeling a little vulnerable right now, okay?
I don't..
Normally..
I don't normally do that.
- Well me either.
I'm sorry.
I just need some time.
Why?
- It's not you. I just need to think.
Are you still coming to Berkley's dinner?
I need time to clear my head, okay?
Damn rain.
Maybe you should call her.
She's probably just running late.
Maybe I should go outside,
Maybe..
She forgot the address.
Mason, do we really have to do this?
Okay. We'll wait.
Why did you even invite him?
Please. Ten minutes ago you
were telling me to be nice.
That's different.
Oh I get it, in front of him it's
one thing, but when he's not here it's another.
That's not fair!
- What's not fair about it?
You know what? I could've
been in Vancouver, with my family.
So you're not having fun?
Is that what this is? Fun?
Is this entertainment?
- You better watch yourself.
What is it Berkley?
Do you even know?
Do you really want to know what this is?
It's called friendship.
It's about him having one person in his life
that is the same asshole to his face that he is to his back
And it's about me being the only
damn guy who gives a shit about him.
That's not friendship.
That's charity.
Oh is that right?
- Yeah.
It's him being your pet.
You know what?
To hell with this shit.
I hear Canada
is nice this time of the year.
What?
- Get out.
You can't be serious.
- Get. Out.
Listen to yourself.
I cooked this whole damn meal.
Happy Christmas.
Hit the road.
You're sick!
- And you're still here.
You think it makes you a better
person because you invite him over for dinner?
Or that you talk to
him for five minutes at work?
If you wanted to help him,
You would get him help.
Put some coal in my stocking.
You're using him.
No no honey. The only
one I'm using is you.
Drive safe!
That wasn't about you bro.
She's a bitch, what can I say,
I don't have a more concerning phrase.
I couldn't find Amber.
- You know what? Enough of this Amber shit.
I'm gonna smoke this, then
we're gonna go back and have a nice dinner.
She couldn't be lost.
She was at your party.
She was what, she was here?
Mason, you can't
keep doing this to yourself.
Maybe she thought we
were meeting at my place.
Do we have to go through this again?
It's because you went to the
damn cemetary, that's what it is.
You can't keep setting yourself
up for rejection like that.
I have to go find her.
- Mason, calm down.
Don't touch me!
What are you..
Where have you been?
- Can I come in?
I'm sorry, I'm...
I'm sorry.
I just couldn't do this there.
- Do what?
I can't. I think we got confused.
What are you talking about?
I think you want me to
be something that I can't be.
What do you mean?
Why can't I see the next pose Mason?
Because there are rules..
- What rules? What does that even mean?
Why are you doing this?
Why are you doing this to me?
Am I some kind of replacement?
Who are you trying to get over?
What are you talking about?
The sketchbooks. Filled with
copies of the same poses.
How do you think that makes me feel?
Who are they Mason?
Where is it?
Poses. You had
me at all the same poses.
Where is it?
It's the last pose..
Why is it ripped out?
- Where is the other one?
WHERE IS IT?!
You should have never...
Why did you do that?
No one sees them before they're done.
You can't leave now.
Sit down.
Just keep sitting.
Mason, please don't do this.
- You should have just listened to the rules.
Mason, Mason.
- Shut up! Shut up!
You knew that there were rules.
I wanted you to be the one.
I'm sorry!
What's going on here?
Shut up.
Everybody just relax.
Just another damn power outage,
the emergency lights are gonna come back..
You see? There's nothing to worry about.
- I need help.
What the hell are you doing?
It's alright. He's alright.
Come here.
What's the matter with you? huh?
You trying to get us both fired?
Are you out of your mind?
Showing up to work late is one thing.
Showing up to work like a psychopath
is another. Into my office.
What the hell happened to you?
Look at me.
Where's your inhaler?
Where is your inhaler?
Come here.
What am I paying you to stand
with your thumb in your ass?
Is he alright?
- Close the door!
It's the last time Mason,
I swear to god.
She went through my things.
I don't give a shit. I told you,
you have to deal with your own bullshit problems.
She found out about the others.
- What others Mason?
What the hell are we talking about here?
The waitress?
The one that would come up to your apartment
and let you paint sexy pictures of her?
Or.. who was before that, maybe
it was her huh? The..
The Spanish one. The poet?
Or maybe it was the girl you
met in the laundry room, that chick Korean.
Don't you get it?
You pathetic little shit.
None of them. Are real.
They don't exist. You made them up,
you always make them up. It keeps you happy.
But Amber..
- Amber who? Contrast girl?
The one who works here? the one that
was at my party? Why have I never met this girl?
Did you ever stop to think about that?
You ever see anyone smile at her? Talk to her?
Seen anyone move out of her way? Hold the door for her?
But I killed her!
I've never seen hands covered in blood Mason.
But I've seen hands covered in paint.
Must've seen yours like that
a dozen times.
No, it's real.
- You didn't kill anyone Mason!
Your dad did.
A long time ago, and I wish that he hadn't.
I wish that they had fried his ass 20
years ago,
So this still wasn't an open wound for you,
but I'm not God Mason.
I got problems of my own, you know?
What am I gonna do?
You're gonna take another hit off that thing.
You're gonna go get cleaned up,
and you're gonna calm down.
What are you going to do?
I'm gonna take a hit.
And get cleaned up.
And calm down.
I'm gonna stay right here and
take care of a little business, okay?
None of them are real?
None of them are real buddy.
How can you tell the difference?
Yeah whatever,
that's not my problem.
How the hell am I supposed to know?
You're the doctor.
Just send someone over here
as soon as you can.
I heard there was some
excitement down here this morning.
Yeah you know, damn power outages.
- Right...
Hey whatever. He's harmless.
He just has problems.
We all got problems.
That guy needs help.
I know.
Did you catch the game last night?
Are you kidding? I stopped
watching when Drexler stopped playing.
So how's life up on the
third floor treating you?
I was happier when I worked
down here for minimum wage.
Your manager salary isn't
worth this shit they put you through.
Tell me about it.
Actually, that's why I came down here..
One of my girls didn't show
up for her shift this morning..
Her mom called me up looking for her.
- Her mom?
I guess she didn't
come home last night.
Hate it when we're damn babysitters.
Anyway.. I'm sure this is the last
conversation you want to have right now, but
I've seen your severely troubled friend
talking to Amber a few times.
Maybe you could ask him
if he's seen her.
What did you just say?
She's pretty.
Who is she?
She is..
Nobody.