(HEART BEATING)
MALE NARRATOR: This is
the beat of a human heart.
Sit very still and listen.
Is your heart beating
in this same rhythm?
You are experiencing
the heartbeat of a dying man.
And it is with death and dying
that we concern ourselves.
What happens
at the point of death?
What happens afterwards?
(HEARTBEAT FADING)
What happens after death
to someone who does not
choose to stay dead?
Someone like Morella.
(SNORTING)
Ma'am, I have to get back
to Boston.
Oh, yes, well,
leave the trunk here,
will you?
I'll have one of
my father's servants
carry it in.
Yes, ma'am.
Giddap.
(CREAKING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Is anyone there?
Father?
(SCREAMING)
(RATTLING)
Who are you?
Father?
What?
It's Lenora, Father.
You are my father.
Yes.
Oh.
What do you want here?
Shocked? Disgusted?
No.
Are you all alone here?
I was. Until you came.
Father, I came to see you.
Very well,
now you've seen me.
Are you content?
That's all?
That's all you have
to say to me after
26 years of separation?
Father, I came
all the way from...
I know.
I know
you don't love me, Father.
That you put me
from your life,
except for 21 years
of board and tuition money.
But I had hoped
that we'd enjoy
one brief visit together
before I left
your life entirely.
I have no way of getting back
to Boston at the moment.
May I stay?
Do as you wish.
Morella, my beloved wife.
Your murderer has returned.
(DOOR OPENING)
(SCREAMING)
Get away from her.
Oh, Father,
has she been lying
here all these years?
You hear me?
Why did you come here?
Don't touch me.
I'm not a helpless baby
this time.
I'll go when I choose,
when I...
Oh, my God. My God.
Why did I come here? Why?
Try to understand.
Oh, I understand.
No, you understand nothing.
You understand nothing.
When she died,
I died with her.
All that remained of me
was this walking corpse
this shell,
this ghost of flesh.
She was my life.
And I killed her.
That's it, isn't it?
Yes!
Oh, no.
No, she thought you did.
She said so on her deathbed.
She was so young.
So alive.
To die just a few months
after giving birth to you.
She couldn't accept it.
I hated you.
Oh, dear God,
how I hated you.
I wanted to kill you.
I went into your nursery
and I took you out
of your cradle
and I almost hurled you
out of the window.
I wish you had.
What?
(CRYING)
(COUGHING)
You're ill.
I have a few months
left to live.
We're both dead now, Father.
I'm sorry.
In my 26th year,
my father is finally
concerned about me.
Did you ever stop
to wonder, just once
in all those 26 years,
"Where is my daughter?
What is she doing?
Is she happy?"
No.
Why should you wonder that?
After all,
I'm only your child.
I'll be leaving very soon.
Lenora.
No, no, no.
Forgive me, forgive me.
Forgive me.
No, no, no.
How long have you
been alone?
I don't know, Lenora.
Go on, please.
What happened then?
Well, there's not much
more to add.
Came as no surprise to me
that my marriage
ended in failure.
I'd failed before
in my relationships with men.
Many times.
I cannot give, you see.
Yes.
How did she die, Father?
How did she die?
Well, there was this party,
and I knew that she was
too weak to withstand
the strain of it.
Yet she insisted.
She had to have this party.
She had to dress up
in her finest gown.
Dance and sing.
Less than an hour
after the party had begun,
she collapsed.
I picked her up in my arms
and I carried her up
to her bedroom.
I put her on her bed.
Her face was white.
Oh, dear God, how white.
She was enraged, furious.
Even dying, she was enraged.
"It was the baby,"
she said.
She swore
she'd avenge herself.
"It was the baby." She kept
saying it over and over again,
"It was the baby."
And then,
before even the doctor
could arrive,
she was dead.
Why did you not bury her?
I did,
but I could not
leave her there.
I could not.
The thought of imprisoning
her beauty in a box of...
Putting her underneath
the ground.
I was deranged
and insane with grief.
I only wanted to kill myself.
I almost did kill myself,
a dozen times.
I never know
what kept me from it.
No, I could not bury her.
And now?
There's no reason
not to do it now.
Will you stay for a while?
Please.
I know it's too late
to make amends,
but perhaps together
we can find some sort
of an answer.
Perhaps.
Then you'll stay?
You really want me to?
Yes.
And you've come home at last.
MORELLA: At last.
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
Help me!
Go away. Leave me.
(MOANING)
Lenora, what is it?
What can I do?
Lenora, what's wrong?
Lenora!
(SOBBING) Oh, no.
How I envy you.
Sleep.
Now you are released.
(GASPS)
(MOANS)
Come back, Lenora,
come back.
(MOANING)
Lenora?
Morella. Oh, my God.
Where is Lenora?
What have you done to her?
All these years
I've waited to return.
I've waited to avenge myself.
(HEART BEATING)
MALE NARRATOR:
And what is it that happens
just before death
which leads inexorably
to that death?
Our second tale provides
one roguish answer
to that question.
In the story of a man
who aided a cat.
The Black Cat.
(LAUGHING)
(SINGING)
(CAT MEOWING)
(SLURRED)
Hey, why don't you watch
where I'm going, huh?
(HUFFS)
(BREAKING)
ANNABEL: Montresor?
Montresor?
Come down here.
(MEOWS)
And keep that beast
away from me,
or I'll kick his head in.
I want some money.
There is none, Montresor.
"There is none, Montresor."
Always lying, it's a fact.
As if I wouldn't know
you had more nest eggs
than a chicken.
Get away from me,
you repulsive creature,
and stay away from me!
Oh.
Where's my money?
There is none, Montresor.
All right.
(MUMBLING)
(SOBBING) Oh.
Montresor.
If you don't
give me the money,
I have to find it myself.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, I know where it is.
I know.
(CAT MEOWS)
Oh.
(PURRING)
If I ever catch you again,
you mangy, insufferable brute,
I'll tear your head off!
(MEOWS)
By the root!
(RATTLING)
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, you won't bite me.
Give me my money.
There is none, Montresor.
You haven't worked
in 17 years.
Well, you...
Has it been that long?
Oh, stop your silly tactics.
What about your sewing money?
We need that for food.
Food!
That's exactly
what I want it for.
I drink my food!
Give me the money.
(GRUNTING)
Thank you for
looking into your heart.
Well, we'll starve now.
That's all we have.
You've got a lot of money
hidden all around the house.
I don't care.
He was so romantic, once.
I said get out
and stay out!
(STAMMERING)
You pig, you dog!
How dare you throw me out!
(CRASHING)
If I only had a pistol...
If I had a pistol...
(LAUGHS)
I'd probably sell it
and buy myself more wine.
Oh, but, really,
after all I've done for her,
she should have given me
more money.
There's just no gratitude.
Sir, would you help a veteran
of the Revolutionary War?
Out of my way.
(SPITS)
Oh, pardon me, ladies,
but could you spare a coin
for a moral cripple?
Disgraceful.
(LAUGHS)
(COUGHING)
You got some money
for a dying man?
Go sleep it off.
(COUGHS)
No gratitude.
Hey, I want money!
Scum!
Dirty moneygrubber.
Just no gratitude.
(MUMBLING)
(WHISTLES)
(CHUCKLES)
Top of the morning, everybody.
My, what a nice bunch
of gentlemen.
Look. Look.
(MURMURING)
Beautiful.
One moment, please.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Quiet, everybody.
And as we promised before,
a treat for everyone.
A demonstration in expert
wine tasting by none other
than Mr. Fortunato Luchresi
himself.
(ALL CHEERING)
As you know, gentlemen,
Mr. Luchresi is,
without doubt,
the foremost wine taster
in the civilized world today.
Huh?
(ALL CHATTERING)
That's nonsense.
I can tell
the taste of any wine
just as well as you can.
MAN: Liar!
If we may proceed.
I said I can tell
the taste of any wine
just as well as anybody!
Let's throw him out.
(CLAMORING)
Afraid to try me, huh?
You coward.
You poseur.
I say
call the police!
(CLAMORING)
One moment. Please.
Sir, unless you're intent
on mere rabble rousing,
you have just made
a most grave
and serious accusation.
An accusation
which I am prepared
to follow up with action.
That is, if you care
to take the risk.
We will take the risk.
Oh?
Oh, yes, yes.
And my name
is Fortunato Luchresi.
At your service.
Montresor Herringbone.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Bring on the wine.
(SIGHING)
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
Ah.
(EXHALES)
(INHALING DEEPLY)
Pinot noir, Burgundy.
Clos de Vougeot.
Vintage, 1838.
Quite passable.
Correct.
(CHUCKLING)
Come on, give me more.
Don't be so stingy.
Burgundy, Volnay, 1832.
It's from the better slopes
of the vineyard.
It's very good.
Correct.
I don't believe it.
Bordeaux, cabernet,
Chateau Margaux.
Vintage, 1837.
A bit heavy for a Margaux.
CHAIRMAN: Correct.
(WINE POURING)
Chateau Petit Village,
1828. It's very good.
Correct.
(MURMURING)
Well.
I must say,
you seem to know
your wine, sir.
I should, I should.
However, I feel I must comment
on your most unorthodox method
of tasting.
What?
Well, the accredited procedure
is, of course, to partake of
a small mouthful, like this.
(MUFFLED)
Whoosh it around
in the mouth like that.
And then inhale like this.
(INHALING)
Thus releasing the aroma.
You do it your way
and I do it my way.
(BELCHES)
(STAMMERS)
(MUMBLING)
(HICCUPS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SLURRED)
Sauvignon.
It's very good.
Who's that
Knocking at the door?
Am that you, Sam?
Please, sir, couldn't you walk
just a bit more upright?
(HUMMING)
Who's that
Am that you, Sam?
(LAUGHING)
Please.
Who's that
Hey, why don't
you sing with me, Sam?
My name is not Sam.
But sing with me.
Who's that
(SHUSHING)
(STAMMERING)
I know the way.
Follow me.
(MEOWS)
Here I am,
young and handsome.
I want you to meet
a friend of mine.
A very good friend of mine.
The best friend I ever had
in the whole wide world.
What was your name, friend?
Luchresi. Fortunato Luchresi
at your service, ma'am.
I am Annabel Herringbone.
I was just trying
to help my friend home.
(LAUGHING)
He had too much to drink.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Well, no, really,
I must be going.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Thank you.
Come on, sit down, friend.
Sit down.
You live in the city,
Mr. Luchresi?
Yes, yes, I do,
Mrs. Herringbone.
(CAT MEOWS)
My, what a lovely cat.
Well.
You like cats?
I adore them, yes,
I have several
of my own at home.
(SNORING)
He's resting.
Yes, he's...
I think he's ill.
(MOANS)
(MONTRESOR GROANS)
(MEOWS)
(GRUNTS)
I tell you this.
With women,
you have to assert yourself.
Let me take my case,
for instance.
I tell my wife
to give me some money.
I want to go out
for the evening.
Well, sir, it used to be
that she gave me trouble,
argued with me,
and tried to withhold
what was rightfully mine.
Now, she just gives me
all the money I ask for,
and I can stay away
the entire night
doing exactly as I please,
which happens to be drinking.
Since when?
Since when. Huh?
Seems to me...
Since that day I went to
that wine sellers' convention
and met...
He assisted me home,
and I...
I introduced him to my wife.
Goodnight, my treasure.
Goodnight, beloved.
Let me look at you again.
Until tomorrow night,
heart of my heart.
Oh.
(CAT MEOWING)
Good evening, dear.
(STAMMERING)
You gave me such a start.
Why?
I didn't expect you
home so early.
You didn't?
Well, I just thought
it would be nice
if I came home early
and we spent some time
together, but I see
you've already gone to bed.
Oh, yes, I was very tired.
Exerting yourself?
Exerting...
(SIGHS)
I had a very strenuous day.
And a more strenuous evening,
I assume.
I beg your pardon?
Isn't it a little too late
to beg my pardon?
I don't know what you mean.
You lie!
You dirty, faithless,
little trollop, you!
You lie!
(GASPING)
So you know?
How long
has this been going on?
Long enough for me to realize
that our marriage, Montresor,
is a farce, it's a mockery.
You can no longer wound me
with your cruelty.
I have found,
at long last, love.
How touching.
Mock me if you will,
but this is the end.
You and I are finished.
I'm gonna leave you and become
Mrs. Fortunato Luchresi.
You are?
Congratulations.
Good afternoon,
Mr. Herringbone.
How very nice
to see you again.
And how nice
And how well you look.
Thank you.
Same to yourself as well.
Come in.
Thank you.
Come in, please.
After you.
Thank you.
And how nice of you
and Mrs. Herringbone
to invite me for dinner.
Oh, we're enchanted
to have you, sir.
Most delighted,
I assure you.
Please.
Thank you.
(CAT MEOWING)
Ah, the cat.
The cat,
what a charming fellow he is.
Yes, isn't he?
Yes.
Is Mrs. Herringbone about?
Oh, yes. She's very,
very busy
preparing our dinner.
Oh.
May I offer you
some sherry?
Oh, I'm delighted,
so delighted.
Amontillado.
That's correct, sir.
Ah, but what an Amontillado.
(CHUCKLES)
A wine to conjure memories
of tastebuds in transport.
I'm terribly happy
you like it, sir.
To your health.
And to yours, sir.
Thank you, sir.
A draft from paradise.
That it is. That it is.
Let me fill your glass.
Oh...
Look, mine is always empty.
Well, I cannot resist.
That I've noticed.
I beg your pardon, sir?
No, nothing, nothing.
To your long life.
And to your long life, sir.
(MUTTERING) Right now,
I have a better chance
than you have.
You spoke, sir?
No, no, nothing.
Let me fill up your glass.
Well, just a bit more.
Where did you
get this...
(YAWNING) Pardon me,
this excellent wine?
Oh, I've had that
in my cellar for
a long, long time.
Oh, indeed.
Yes, I was saving it
for a very special occasion.
Oh, today?
Yes, sir.
What occasion?
Surely not my presence.
That's part of it.
And what is the other part?
Your death.
(THUDDING)
(SCRAPING)
FORTUNATO: What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Give you three guesses.
Surely you can't mean to...
Wall you in, yes.
But, why?
Ask your treasure,
your heart of hearts.
What?
Ask Annabel!
Annabel?
Annabel.
You killed her.
You notice everything,
don't you?
Help. Help!
(SOBBING)
Please, let me go. Help!
Don't make so much noise.
I don't like it.
You're insane.
That may be,
but very clever.
The way I put that drug
in your Amontillado
with the consummate skill
of a Borgia.
And this whole arrangement.
They'll never find you
behind this wall.
You can't mean it.
Never.
Haven't I convinced you
of my sincerity yet?
I'm genuinely dedicated
to your destruction.
Help! Help! Help!
What kind of a man
are you, anyway?
Make love to my wife
and doesn't even talk to me.
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
That's an excellent jest.
We'll have many a good laugh
about it in the future.
I will, I will.
God.
Oh, for the love of God,
Montresor.
Yes, for the love of God.
Nice professional job.
She must hide it
in here somewhere.
(DINGS)
Eureka!
Everybody,
back to the counter.
Montresor is buying again.
(ALL CHEERING)
Come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Gentlemen,
let's have a toast, huh?
To my precious wife,
without whose money
this most splendid evening
would be impossible.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Where she is now,
she won't need it anyway.
Knocking at the door?
Is that you, Sam?
(SINGING)
(CAT MEOWING)
(CAT MEOWING LOUDLY)
(BANGING)
(SCREAMS)
No! No!
Give me back my head.
(CAT MEOWS)
Keep that cat from my head,
will you? Will you?
Keep that cat from...
Give me back my head!
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHS)
(HISSING)
(SHOOS)
Go away.
I said go away.
Mr. Herringbone?
Yes.
We knocked,
but no one answered.
The door was ajar,
so we looked in.
Then when we found the house
in such a state...
Such a state.
Oh, yes, I...
I remember I was searching
for something last night.
We thought perhaps
there'd been some trouble,
so we came right in.
Are you all right, sir?
I'm all right.
We've received a report
from a Mr. Wilkins.
He's the bartender
at the Red Lion Tavern.
You know Mr. Wilkins.
He claims you spent
a rather large amount
of money last evening.
Well, it's my own money.
Can't I spend my own money?
Further, that you said
something to the effect
that your wife
wouldn't need the money
where she is.
Might I ask, sir,
where your wife is?
She's gone.
She left with her lover.
I don't know
where she is,
nor do I care.
Are you ill, sir?
No, I...
You don't happen
to have a little whiskey
on you, boys, huh?
No, sir.
You see, I have
had hallucinations lately.
(LAUGHING)
Been drinking a little bit
too much last night.
I see.
Do you mind, sir,
if we search the premises?
No. Where do you
want to start?
I think the cellar.
Cellar.
Oh, are you coming down,
Montresor?
Did you hear anything?
No.
Well, I didn't think so.
Well, here we go, gentlemen.
Yes, come on down.
I think I'll drink
a little less
in the future.
Now he decides.
Shut up.
What?
Nothing, nothing.
I just keep mumbling.
I had too much to drink.
We had better make
a thorough search.
Search?
Don't you find
everything all right
and in order?
Go ahead,
search everything you want.
I don't care.
ANNABEL: Montresor,
what a thing to say.
FORTUNATO:
Naughty, naughty, Montresor.
Keep quiet.
(ANNABEL HOOTING)
ANNABEL:
Right behind here,
Mr. Policeman.
ANNABEL AND FORTUNATO:
We're right behind the wall.
Right behind it.
Are you blind, Mr. Policeman?
(FORTUNATO HOOTING)
FORTUNATO:
You're not paying attention,
Mr. Policeman.
You're getting cold.
This way.
Now are you satisfied?
What do you think,
I buried them down here?
(CHUCKLES)
ANNABEL: That's exactly
what he did. Exactly.
Where would
I have hidden them?
Under this floor?
Or maybe in that wall?
Look. Look how solid it is.
Look at it, look.
(CAT WAILING)
What in the name of God.
You can hear it, too?
Hear it?
What's behind there?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Well, we'll see.
(CAT MEOWING)
(CAT SCREECHING)
(HEART BEATING)
MALE NARRATOR: What exactly
is it that occurs
at the moment of death?
Especially to a man
who in that moment
is not permitted to die.
As in The Case
of M. Valdemar.
CARMICHAEL: There is no pain.
No pain.
CARMICHAEL: You are at peace.
Mind and body,
at peace, entirely.
Yes.
Then listen to the sound
of my voice.
Carefully. Pain vanished.
Mind and body
in a state of peace.
You understand this, Valdemar?
I understand.
Then sleep. Sleep.
Sleep.
When my hand passes
across your face, waken.
Are you all right?
Perfectly, my dear.
The pain, it's gone?
Vanished.
What is your finding,
Doctor?
Well, you seem to be
in good condition.
Seem to be? But I am.
Oh, come now,
admit the truth of it.
Mesmerism works. It works.
I've never doubted
that it works, sir.
Only its advisability
in certain cases.
It would certainly seem
be advisable in the case
of Mr. Valdemar.
Or would you have me suffer
untold agonies of pain
in order to observe
strict medical protocol?
Ernest.
Oh, my sweet Helene.
Forgive me, both of you,
for my most untimely
sense of humor.
But this is a joyous moment.
Smile! Come,
let us drink.
Let us drink to mesmerism.
The ministration of the gods.
I'm sorry.
I can't drink to that.
Then drink to the health
of my beautiful wife.
To the very good health
of you both.
And to Mr. Carmichael.
Sir.
How blessed
to be free of pain.
For that part, sir,
I'm truly happy,
please believe me.
It's for the other aspect
of mesmeric influence
that I feel concern.
Which is, Doctor?
Perilous toying
with the human mind.
But, my dear Dr. James,
what is perilous about it?
Mr. Valdemar has received
nothing but advantage
from its applications.
And, as we all know,
he is dying of
an incurable disease.
I wish you'd stop...
Helene, Helene.
The issue
must be acknowledged.
Within this skull,
as well you know, Doctor,
there is tissue
which is dying,
even as I speak.
I am physically doomed.
I do not say this out of
bitterness or despair.
However, there is one favor
I would ask.
To escape a pitiful
and painful decline to death,
through the auspices
of Mr. Carmichael.
Would you deny him this,
Doctor?
No, sir.
And yet, you know,
he will accept nothing
for this blessing,
save some trifling favor
on my deathbed.
Sir?
Favor, Ernest?
I should not even
have mentioned it,
it's so slight.
No, please, I want to know.
Well, my dear,
it's simply...
You tell them, sir.
You can explain it
so much better than I.
Mr. Valdemar has consented
to be mesmerized
in articulo mortis,
which is to say...
JAMES: At the point of death!
I fear it sounds
more dreadful
than it really is.
What does it mean?
Ernest, why?
To ascertain, madam, just
how long the actual moment
of death can be forestalled.
A momentous experiment.
Momentous.
Monstrous would be
more the word.
Sir, I appeal to you,
withdraw this offer.
The deathbed is no place
for lunatic experiments.
My dear young friend,
what can it matter
whether I die
10 or 20 minutes
beyond that point
when I should die anyway?
What could be less important?
I owe this gentleman
a great deal. A great deal.
I could not dream
of refusing him
such an insignificant request.
As you say, sir.
I fear I must leave now.
Oh, so soon?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Goodnight, Doctor.
Thank you for attending.
My dear, show our friend
to the door, will you?
Yes, of course.
A bit more wine,
Mr. Carmichael?
Oh, thank you.
Elliot, this experiment...
Do everything in your power
to dissuade him
from it, Helene.
I've no proof
that it's dangerous,
no proof whatever.
Only sense that it might be.
What is it, Elliot?
Why is it since
that man entered our life,
I can't think, I'm uncertain?
Oh, he helps Ernest.
I can't argue with that.
He seems to relieve him
of all pain.
To see him suffer
is more than I can stand,
but at the same time...
You distrust Carmichael?
Yes, I do.
Still it's true,
he asks for nothing.
Perhaps he asks for nothing
because he desires everything,
including you.
You can't be serious.
You haven't seen him
looking at you, then?
Yes, but surely...
Of course, I have
no right to say this, really,
for I, too, look at you.
Elliot, please.
You know how I feel.
I love my husband,
I respect him.
No more than I do.
I know that.
So let us think of
nothing else but Ernest
and our respect for him.
Goodnight, Helene.
Goodnight.
Ernest.
Hmm? Oh, yes, my dear.
Won't you reconsider?
Regarding the experiment?
I fear him.
You fear Carmichael?
But, my dear,
think of the pain
he spared me.
If only you could see
the change in him
when you're under
his control, Ernest.
All the fawning ceases.
He no longer calls you
Mr. Valdemar,
it's just Valdemar.
He tells you what to do,
what to think.
Please, my dear, no more.
Let us forget it.
It is established
and of no importance.
What is important is you.
I wish with all my heart
that following my death
you would marry
our good Dr. James.
How...
No, no, no, please, my dear.
Let me finish.
I know that there
is a bond between you.
All honorable.
I know that, too,
and I love you both for it.
But I am going
to die soon, Helene.
And it would make me
very happy to know
that you would not be alone.
That you would marry again.
Oh, my dear. Your happiness
means more to me
than anything, anything.
But I refuse to die
until that happiness
has been assured.
(WEAKLY)
It approaches,
does it not?
No pretense, please.
It approaches.
No, my dear, no sorrow.
I am content, believe me.
Did you inform Mr. Carmichael
as I requested?
He is below, sir.
Then fetch him,
if you will.
Quickly. Quickly.
Have a care, sir.
So, the time has come,
Mr. Carmichael.
It will be to you, sir,
I promise.
No more than sinking into
a dreamless sleep.
Best to hurry,
Mr. Carmichael.
Oh, no despair,
I implore you.
It is peace I go to.
Freedom from
this ghastly pain.
Your hand, Doctor.
I charge you this
upon your soul,
watch over my Helene.
Swear to it.
I swear to it.
Rest easily, sir.
I do now.
With all my heart,
I thank you
for having added
to my life one great,
sweet measure of devotion.
(SOBBING)
You may proceed,
Mr. Carmichael.
Look at the turning wheel.
At the changing of the colors.
And sleep.
Deep, deep sleep.
Your body losing
all sensation.
Your mind enveloped
in darkness.
Nothing can disturb you now,
as you drift ever deeper
into darkness
and sleep, sleep, sleep.
Valdemar.
Do you hear me?
It is my voice.
I hear.
Are you asleep?
I am asleep.
Valdemar,
raise your right arm.
Lower it.
Is there any pain?
No pain.
I am dying.
(SOBS)
Please, do not wake me.
Let me die.
I will not wake you,
Valdemar.
Deep, deep sleep,
from which
there is no waking,
unless I say.
You understand, Valdemar?
I understand.
You may examine him now,
if you wish.
(BLOWING)
Do you so fear me?
I have but released
your husband from
his pain once more.
Would you have had me
do otherwise?
No.
Then do I
personally offend you?
Please, Mr. Carmichael,
not now.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
Valdemar,
return to your sleep.
Return to your sleep,
Valdemar.
I command you!
Stop it!
Valdemar, do you hear me?
Do you hear
the sound of my voice?
Are you asleep now?
VALDEMAR: I have been asleep,
but now I am dead.
(GASPS)
You are asleep, Valdemar.
No.
Yes, yes, yes,
you do but sleep.
Raise your right arm.
Raise it, Valdemar.
I command you!
Raise your right arm!
He does not...
He is dead.
(SOBS)
Yes, he is dead,
but still aware.
Release him.
Release him?
Valdemar, do you hear me?
I hear.
Tell me, where are you?
Darkness.
Stop it!
That will do,
Mr. Carmichael.
Where, Valdemar? Where?
Stop it!
End the control! End
the control, Mr. Carmichael!
No.
Valdemar,
tell me what you see.
Your surroundings,
what are they?
That will do,
Mr. Carmichael!
No, are you insane?
Do you not comprehend
the import of
what has happened?
His body is dead
but his mind lives on,
controlled by me.
Which control will now end.
Let him die!
No!
Be gone!
VALDEMAR: Where am I?
What place is this?
I see only darkness.
People, multitudes of people.
No! No!
(SCREAMING)
No!
Valdemar, be still.
Help me.
Be still, Valdemar.
I will let you go
when I am finished.
Your whiskey, sir.
Leave it there.
(VALDEMAR MOANING)
Get out!
Valdemar.
Valdemar,
do you hear me?
Be still. Be still.
VALDEMAR: Release me.
Release me.
Give me peace.
Be still!
Let me go.
I will release you
when I am ready.
Good evening, Doctor.
Good evening.
Is Mr. Carmichael upstairs?
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Come.
I promise you
an end to it, Helene.
How?
Come.
Now, tell me this.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
What can I do for you?
I'm here to order you,
Mr. Carmichael...
I beg your pardon.
Not request, but order.
You will end
the mesmeric control
immediately.
Will I, Doctor?
You will.
And how do you propose
to enforce that order,
Dr. James?
With this.
You wouldn't dare.
Do you choose
to take that risk?
If you kill me,
Valdemar will remain in
the same state indefinitely.
Perhaps forever.
No.
I shall count to three,
Mr. Carmichael,
then I shall kill you.
Elliot.
You must be
out of your mind.
One.
No.
Two.
Elliot, no.
I want you to hear
something first.
Nothing from you, sir.
Did I say it was from me?
If you will, come with me.
Valdemar, tell them
what you told me
just now about Helene.
I do not wish for her
to marry Dr. James.
I wish for her
to marry Mr. Carmichael.
No.
You heard him, madam.
But he's under your control.
The words were
given to him by you.
That is a lie.
Is it?
Yes!
Elliot, please,
you must leave now.
What?
I want you to go.
But don't you understand?
That was not
your husband speaking.
It was his voice.
But not his will!
I don't know that.
Helene, in the name of God.
Elliot, please go.
There's nothing more
to be said or done.
I just want you to go now.
Very well, but I shall
be back, and God help you
if you do her harm in any way.
Well, madam?
I believe Dr. James
is quite correct.
It is not my husband
who would have me marry you.
You heard him
with your own ears.
It was not him.
However, I will make a bargain
with you, Mr. Carmichael.
I'll marry you
upon the stipulation
that you set my husband free.
I need make no bargains
with you, madam.
What?
You will marry me
in any case.
No, no, Mr. Carmichael,
not unless you end
his torment.
Edicts, Madam?
Orders from you?
Allow me to enlighten you.
I am in command here.
You will do as I say.
Or I will leave Mr. Valdemar
exactly as he is, and never,
do you understand me, madam,
never let him go.
I've coveted you
these many months,
waited for you,
hungered for you,
and now you shall
be my wife.
I shall not ask.
I shall take
what I desire.
Your body and your soul,
if I demand it.
I've heard enough! No!
Stop it! Let me go!
Let me go, you're hurting me!
Help! Help me!
Let me go!
(SCREAMING)
(KEY HITS FLOOR)
No!
(SCREAMING)
Helene! Helene!
Elliot.
(BOTH EXCLAIM IN DISGUST)