[SQUAD 38]
[This program contains virtual
and product placement advertising.]
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
Sung Il... Hey.
What did we do so wrong?
What did we do?
We were just trying to make a living!
But this isn't something that...
Don't be like that.
Please help me out, just this once.
You know we're right.
From now on...
I don't think it should
be our call to make.
We are public officials.
You jerk. You think that, as long as we
follow rules, everything will be okay?
Let's not get ourselves into trouble.
I have to get my pension.
Min Sik!
Are you in there?
Min Sik! Hey! Min Sik!
Wake up! Min Sik!
[SQUAD 38]
[EPISODE 1]
Did you register for that?
Oh... okay, thank you, thanks a lot.
Mapo and Yongsan areas seem
to be having lots of problems.
- Do your work.
- Oh, yeah.
[SECTION CHIEF KANG NOH SEUNG]
No, the section chief has been
really busy these days. Just look at him.
He has a lot on his plate.
In April?
Even if you declared bankruptcy
that doesn't mean you're exempt
from paying taxes.
Yes, everything is computerized
and you have to pay your taxes. So we...
Section Chief Baek, I think we'll have
to search the house right away.
In this series, we look at the skills
you need to write formal academic...
Section Chief Baek!
And you'll have the chance to listen...
Huh? What?
What?
Ms. Kim Eun Sook's house.
I think we need to search her house now.
Yeah? Now?
What time is it?
Oh, okay then.
Guys, let's get ready to go.
- Okay.
- Yes.
I'll call you back.
I was really into those
English lessons just now...
[TAX COLLECTION: "WE'LL CHASE YOU
TO THE END AND COLLECT!"]
We're from City Hall!
Is Mr. Jo Bong Gi here?
Hey! I don't have a penny!
Do what you want!
- Sung Hee, let's hurry up.
- Okay.
You're Mr. Jo Bong Gi, right?
We're here to collect on your taxes.
Go back, go back.
Let's speak in the office
for just a moment.
What is there to talk about?
Step aside! Step aside!
I said step aside!
This maeuntang is delicious.
I'm going to head out. I'll be back.
I'll get going. I'll be back, Mom.
- Did you fart?
- No, it wasn't me.
Oh, my head!
I'll be back, Mom.
- No wonder he didn't say anything!
- It was him!
- Thank you.
- Thanks, good night.
It reminded me of the old days.
And so, I just wanted to have some
jjajangmyeon with you, Section Chief.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
- Enjoy.
- Yes.
Sung Il, they ran an inspection
on me yesterday.
Those punks in Yeouido grilled me hard.
They asked me why the amount
in arrears isn't decreasing.
Section Chief.
How much is our city aiming
to collect in taxes this year?
182.5 billion won.
And how much did Team 3 collect?
We...
I'm sorry.
What's that look on your face?
Did I offend you?
No, no. You didn't.
People always tell me that I look angry,
even when I'm not doing anything.
About that 182.5 billion won...
Let's say borough office is going
to take care of 100 billion won.
So we have to collect 82.5 billion won.
If we divide that amongst Teams 1,
2 and 3, it's 27.5 billion each.
The amount that Section Chief's Team 3
collected in the first half of 2016
is 7.5 billion won.
20 billion won remains.
What are you going to do about this?
I said, what are you
going to do about this?
I...
I'll work harder, sir.
You should work harder.
You should work very hard.
Hurry up and eat.
Yes.
I wonder how you could
be eating that right now.
I think I should eat after
I finish collecting taxes, sir.
Why? You should eat first.
No, no...
I think I should
finish my job first, sir.
Geez. How stupid!
What am I supposed
to do now? You fool!
Did you all eat?
- Yes.
Do you want some coffee?
No, thank you.
Sung Hee?
Yes?
On our list, who owes
the greatest amount in arrears?
Hey, you. You should have checked
the balance before you sent it!
What are you going to do now? Huh?
What's the matter?
Are you a child?
How could you get scammed?
His name is Ma Jin Seok.
He owes 520 million won in local taxes
and 5.25 billion won in federal taxes.
He's on our blacklist.
Okay.
We investigated him a little bit
and uncovered that list.
We slapped a travel ban on him
and cut off all of his credit cards.
Still, he's not flinching.
It says he lives in Cheorwon, Gangwon-do.
But that's not his actual home, right?
What's his real address?
He lives in those Premium Apartments
in Cheongsam-dong.
I heard that apartments in that complex
go for about 1.5 billion won per unit.
Okay.
I think...
that
we'll have to search
his house right away.
So everyone, let's get ready to leave.
- Okay.
- Yes.
Sung Hee, take these documents with you.
Hey hey, Sung Il.
Yes, sir?
Why?
What's wrong?
Do you...
have...
five million won?
Five million won?
No, I don't...
Why, why, why? Why do you need that?
I got scammed.
You got scammed?
Not just me.
Chief Director Yoon, Han, and Jo.
We all got scammed.
Oh, so that's what all the commotion
was about. What's going on?
What am I supposed to do now?
If my wife finds out, I'll be a dead man.
How could you get scammed?
Come on, Brother...
You won't know how I'm feeling
until it happens to you.
At that moment,
you have no idea that it's a scam.
He's so good at talking
people into things.
There was really nothing
that I could do.
Geez, you...
I have to leave now. Let's talk later.
And don't worry too much about your wife.
She won't kill you. You're her husband.
I'll off. Let's talk later.
- We should make it quick.
- Okay.
How could that happen?
Director Ahn could have fallen for it.
But Director Yoon doesn't seem like
the type to get in this kind of trouble.
You know, he questions everything.
Hey, Director Han's wife got scammed too.
Innocent and foolish people
get scammed all the time.
How could they get fooled like that?
Section Chief is the most innocent
and foolish person here.
Are you crazy?
No, sir.
Getting scammed at least once is okay.
It teaches you where you stand.
That's how it was for me.
Where is everyone?
Our team went out for an arrest warrant.
And Team 3 is out on location.
Whose house are they searching?
They need an entire team for that?
I'm not sure about his name.
Of all the people Team 3
is responsible for
I was told that he has
the greatest volume owed in arrears.
What?
Oh, President Jung.
I told you this already.
I told you I can multiply
that dollar amount, by 20.
Why won't you trust me?
Yes.
Hold on. I have another call.
Wow!
Long time, no talk.
How have you been?
What?
Ma'am.
Where is my cell phone?
It's right here.
Yes?
Hey. Why don't you answer your phone?
I called you a bunch of times.
Why? What's the matter?
People from City Hall
are coming to collect taxes.
What?
This is it, right?
Yes, it's the top floor.
The public officials are here.
They're all here.
Let's go.
What is it? What's the matter?
They're going to block us.
The news got out.
We're from the City Hall.
Please step aside.
No visitors allowed.
Okay, I got it.
He said that they're
in the lobby. What do I do?
Okay, listen. Listen carefully.
Hide any valuables at all
that are in the apartment.
What if they find it?
What do I do then?
Don't worry about that.
Just do what I tell you.
It's going to get dark soon.
It's illegal to search
the house after sundown.
Okay? Just hide everything.
And wait until the sun sets.
I'll be there soon.
This is obstruction of justice.
Step aside, everyone.
I told you guys to leave.
[KANG HO JOONG]
Let's just break through them.
I just said, all of you, step back!
- Did you just hit me?
- Step aside!
This one.
- In the oven. In the oven.
- In the oven.
In the microwave. The microwave!
Sung Hee, quickly! Quickly!
In the toilet, the toilet.
Sofa, sofa. Sofa!
Ma'am, lift this mattress.
Lift it up. Lift it.
Lift it up more, won't you?
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
Is anyone there?
I'm from City Hall.
Where are you from?
- I'm from City Hall.
- City Hall?
Why did you come here?
This is Mr. Ma Jin Seok's house, right?
Okay, you can come in.
I got the door open.
When you go in there
you should search closets,
washing machines, and cabinets first.
That's where they hide the valuables.
- Okay.
- I got it.
Use as many confiscation stickers as
possible. We'll be auctioning this stuff.
- Yes.
- I got it.
Excuse me!
Hello.
I'm from Sungwon City Hall's
Taxation Department.
It looks like Mr. Ma Jin Seok isn't home.
What's your relationship
with him? Wife...
What?
Oh... Yes.
Didn't you get divorced?
You guys still live together,
after getting divorced?
Are you aware that your husband,
Ma Jin Seok, has failed to pay
520 million won in local taxes,
and 5.25 billion won in federal taxes?
That comes to about 5.77 billion won.
That's his business.
About the 520 million in local taxes...
He seems to be very rich.
Why wouldn't he pay his taxes?
Be quiet. Hurry up.
We'll be searching the house and
formalizing this as distressed property.
- Start it.
- Okay.
Excuse us.
Well...
Here, search this sofa.
Section Chief.
- Take them all out.
- Okay.
Put the sofa back together.
Those are all fake. Imitation.
Even if you take them,
you won't be able to sell them.
Okay, I understand.
There's nothing in there.
Do you usually
wash these in the washing machine?
There it is.
Wow, she really scattered
everything, everywhere.
Take them all out.
Excuse me. Can I have some water?
Okay.
Thank you.
The ones that have stickers on them,
we're putting up for auction.
If you don't want them revoked,
pay your taxes.
What are you guys doing?
Hey.
Why didn't you answer your phone?
I didn't get any calls.
You got no calls?
Do you see this?
I didn't buy you a phone for you
to check the time. Right?
- Mr. Ma Jin Seok?
- Yes.
We're from City Hall,
of the Seowon Taxation Department.
We're conducting a search on your house,
because of your delinquent tax records.
Isn't it illegal to search
a house after sunset?
It's dark outside.
What are you doing in my house?
Ma'am!
What are you doing?
Come here.
Who told you to give them water?
Isn't this my water?
This is expensive water, Ma'am.
Why are you giving them
my water, without my permission?
I'm sorry, President Ma.
Geez...
Ma'am.
How much do you earn, per month?
- 1.8 million won.
- 1.8 million won?
Drink that.
If you drink all of that,
I'll give you another one million.
What do you think?
Let's give it a try.
I would do it if I were you.
- Excuse me.
- Wait a second. What are you doing?
You stay out of this.
Are you going to drink it
or are you not going to drink it?
You said that you have
a kid to send to college.
Hurry up and drink it.
Quickly, drink it.
- Ma'am.
- Don't drink it.
- I'm okay.
Hey, you.
Can you see where you stand?
This is money.
Money looks something like this.
When you stick these on
you feel like you're doing
something amazing, yeah?
Huh?
You're not...
This Madam, and you guys, are all same.
You guys give up everything,
for a little bit of money.
Here. Take this.
Take this. You guys laid it out
for me very nicely.
Take these too.
Hey! Take some of that too!
Take it! Why aren't you taking it?
What in the world are you doing?
You don't even pay your taxes.
You can't waste your money like this.
- We'll teach you a lesson.
- A lesson?
What in the world is this bastard saying?
- Bastard? You better watch your mouth.
- You better watch your mouth.
You think that the law is on your side?
Is that you why have the nerve
to say something like that?
Okay. Let's just say, for fun,
the law is on your side.
In that case
the seven buildings in Dangjin
that I gave to my younger brother.
The four apartments in Gangnam
that I transferred to my Mother.
And 30,000 pyeong of land in Yongin
that I transferred to my fake divorcee.
Why couldn't you seize them from me?
You knew that they were all mine.
Why couldn't you seize them?
- Hey, you.
- You clearly knew those are mine.
Why couldn't you seize them?
- Don't be like this, Mr. Ma!
- Why not, huh?
Listen to me.
The law likes money too.
The law is for the rich.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
Okay, I got it. So stop it,
and step aside please.
Stop what?
Did I force her to do that?
She said she would do that.
Geez, that's gross.
- Are you okay?
- Ma'am!
If you spill it, that's a foul.
Do you want to start over?
She's your mother's age!
What are you doing?
She is not my mom.
And how could I stop her?
You stop her if you can, you beggar.
Who are you calling a beggar?
I can't take this anymore.
- Hey, stop it.
- No, no, no.
- Hit me, you bastard.
- Don't!
- How old are you, you jerk?
- Don't do it.
Don't talk down to me like that!
What in the world is he saying?
Bring me your
birth certificate! Bring it!
Birth certificate? Here you go.
Hey! Let go of me!
Here, take a look at it.
What are you doing?
What are you?
Jin Seok!
Yes?
Where is Section Chief Seo Il
from Team 3?
Chief Director Ahn is here.
Section Chief Sung Il.
Yes.
Baek Sung Il, how many years have you
been working in the Taxation Department?
It's been eight years, sir.
Eight years?
It has been a while.
Why did you do that?
Eight years, you've been on this job.
I'm sorry.
Tell Chief Director Ahn to come in.
Where are you going?
I thought you told me
to get Chief Director Ahn.
Chief Director Ahn is coming in.
The intercom...
Baek Sung Il.
Yes?
Let's do it right. Okay?
Yes.
Investigate it thoroughly and refer back
to the disciplinary committee.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
You haven't gone home yet?
No, not yet.
What did they say?
You know, the obvious stuff.
The disciplinary committee?
So, Section Chief...
You should control your temper.
Usually, it isn't a problem.
But sometimes, you get...
I don't want to be like that either.
But it's not that easy.
I have to pick up my daughter.
I'm going home.
You should head home too.
We'll share the blame.
Then, they won't suspend you! So...
- Dad.
- Yes?
I study really hard. I don't even sleep.
But why are my grades always the same?
Huh? Why do you think that is?
- Maybe other kids are studying harder.
- Geez, stop eating!
And, don't answer me so carelessly.
Why aren't my grades getting better?
Only three kids are doing worse than me.
But all three of them
are on the taekwondo team.
They even missed a day of testing.
What's wrong with me?
What I think is that...
there are too many
geniuses in your class.
- Really?
- That's right. It's not your fault.
They're just too smart.
There's nothing you can do about that.
I'm in the same boat.
I always work very hard,
but my team is always behind everyone.
And my salary stays the same.
You're like that too?
Of course.
Oh, it's because I take after you.
That's right, it's okay.
Oh, my.
Geez. Are you okay? You're all wet.
Ji Eun, are you okay?
Oh, Ah Jung?
- Is she your friend?
- Yes, we're in the same class.
Are you okay?
We meet again.
I guess you don't have a car.
Why are you walking,
out here in the rain?
Geez... you're soaked.
I'm sorry.
No, actually, I can't just say sorry.
That's not enough.
Let's go.
Geez...
Oh, my.
I thought these were 10,000 won bills...
I almost made a mistake.
Is this enough?
Take it. This is enough
for dry cleaning, right?
Thanks, but it's okay.
Take it back. Let's go.
Really? I guess I don't
have a choice then.
Let's call it even.
Your punch, and my splash.
Okay?
Oh.
And
when you have a chance, buy a car.
She must be tired from studying all day.
Why do you make her walk?
Aren't you embarrassed,
in front of your own daughter?
You know, there are many cars out there.
All it needs is four wheels to be a car.
I'll get going. Bye, kiddo.
Dad, are you okay?
Honey.
What do you think about
getting another car?
Don't you think it would be
better for Ji Eun and Mom?
Are you picking a fight?
Geez, I'm very tired.
It would be nice to have a car.
Go to sleep.
Oh, that's right.
I have to send an e-mail.
[BALANCE: 5,008,200 WON]
[POST LISTING]
[LOOKING FOR CAR AROUND
FIVE MILLION WON]
Brother.
Hello?
Hello. I saw your post
on the car swap website.
- Yes, yes.
- You're looking for an Avance MD?
Yes, that's right.
I have to sell my car
as soon as possible.
I'm hoping that we can
work out a price together.
How much do you want for your car?
It's a 2012 model, and it has
just over 50,000 kilometers on it.
I was thinking around eight million won.
But I need to get rid of it fast,
so I'll sell it for five million won.
Really?
You're going to sell it
for five million won?
Yes. I think I could give it
to you for five million won.
But... why are you selling it so cheap?
Is there a problem with the car?
There's nothing wrong with the car.
Well... Are you not
satisfied with the price?
No, no, that's not it.
It's not a million or two million won.
You're telling me you're going to
cut the price by three million won.
I guess that's it then.
Keep looking for other cars.
I'm hanging up.
Oh, well.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
Hey, guys...
2012 Avance.
Five million won.
He says he's going to give it to me...
for five million won.
Isn't that too cheap? Is that okay?
Is it a direct deal?
It should be okay
if it's a direct deal, right?
I think you should check it out,
but it should be okay.
Five million won for a direct deal.
I think it should be fine.
That's right. You need to
see the car first though.
Yes.
Yeah, right... Right?
Okay.
Yes, hello?
Yeah, then...
Can I take a look at the car first?
Oh, I'm sorry sir...
Why? Did you sell it already?
No, no.
Not that. Something came up.
I think my Brother will be there.
Oh, really? So what should I do?
He's going to show you the car,
so you can check out anything you need.
I... borrowed some money from him...
I'm going to ask you to not bring up
the price around him, and whatnot.
Oh, what's so hard about that?
Okay, then. So should I call you
after I take a look at the car?
- Yes, that would be okay.
- Okay.
I'll call you after I see the car.
- Sir, is this... Direct deal?
- No.
- By any chance, this car...
- Oh, yes.
- I should take a look at the car.
- Yes, go ahead.
You haven't been in any accidents, right?
Of course not.
You could go see a mechanic later.
No, no, it's not that
I don't trust you. I'm just checking.
Yes, thank you.
- Great, thank you.
- Sure.
Let me call somebody.
Okay.
Yes, hello?
I just saw the car.
Do you like it?
I like it very much.
Actually, will it be possible
for me to buy the car today?
I'll tell you my bank account number.
Bank account number?
Are we not meeting in person?
I'm quite far from there. It might
be hard for us to meet in person.
You checked out the car, right?
Yes, I did. But we have to take care
of the papers and stuff, right?
My brother has the car registration
and the contract.
I think you should
check it out for yourself.
- Oh...
- Yes.
Oh...
Yes, then. Let's do that.
Send me your account number then.
I'll send you the money right away.
Welcome. Select your option.
Watch out for any scammers
impersonating financial officials.
Enter the amount to transfer.
The following amount will
be taken from your account.
If the following information is correct,
please press "Continue".
If not, please press "Cancel".
Your transaction has been completed.
- The number you have dialed...
- Why isn't he answering his phone?
The phone has been turned off...
How could you get scammed?
What a pity.
At that moment,
you have no idea that it's a scam.
He's great at talking people into things.
Oh, wait! Stop!
Stop, stop!
What happened?
Where's your Brother now?
What?
The owner of this car. I talked to him
on the phone. Where is he now?
What did you say?
What are you talking about?
I'm the owner of this car.
- But...
- This is my car!
What? What are you...
Hold on. Wait a minute! Wait!
What's the matter now?
- Hello?
- Did you...
get your car keys?
You're not buying
some cheap t-shirts here.
Are you a fool?
You should have seen the person
before sending your money.
How could you be so naive, at your age?
From now on, don't do any
direct deals for cars.
Buy your cars at the dealership,
and buy your clothes at the store.
But, sir. Sir?
That money... Hello? Hello?
That money is very important to me.
I saved it up for my daughter.
You can't do this.
I... I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have done
any direct deals online.
No... Hey, no. You're young.
You can't do this to me!
Hey you. Give that money...
Give that money back, you punk!
You must be very angry, our naive mister.
I should at least give you
some of the money.
That man won't give you the car.
So don't make a fuss over it.
It will only make you look bad.
You can take the same taxi you took
to get there, to get home.
[DEPOSIT: 14,500 WON.
BALANCE: 22,700 WON.]
Have a safe trip.
Thank you for your money, sir.
And don't curse too much.
It's not good for your mental health.
Geez!
The phone has been turned off...
Yang Jung Do.
Come out.
After the IMF in 1997,
Korean minds had been changed.
All money.
They'll do anything for money.
Like dogs.
They say money, their religion. Money,
their parents. Money, their friends.
You're a rich lady
if you have a Hermès bag.
And you are the boss
if you have a Mercedes-Benz S class.
I'm leaving.
Since the world spins this way
a person like me can get discharged.
My teenage years were filled with bravado
and my 20's were
filled with stubbornness.
And now, in my 30's,
I live by conning people.
Conning people is very simple.
Once, I thought,
why would people fall for this?
Surprisingly, the answer is very simple.
It's because our world is simple.
50,000,000 Koreans are hoping
for the same one thing.
Money. Even if they can't
have it all, they want money.
Jung Do.
Someone told me to give this
to you when you got out.
People judge others based on money.
They shouldn't see how they look.
They should look on the inside.
Focus on EQ more so than IQ.
That's the real swindler.
If you can do that
everything in this world
will work the way you want it to.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever.
This is Manager Choi Chul Min
from Omega Savings Bank.
Did you apply for a loan?
Recently, the Korean Bank
reduced the base rate
from 1.5 percent to 1.2 percent.
So we came up with a new loan program
that matches the low base rate.
1.2 percent?
How can I get that loan?
They are the ones who received
money from our President.
When you get out,
you have to scam them all.
It seemed like life
was being hard on them
so the President and I treated them well,
with nice meals and stuff.
But when the President and I had to
come here, they completely ignored us.
The President wants to
teach them a lesson.
Let's beat them up, Jung Do.
We should check
on your loan eligibility.
To do that, I need your financial
and banking information.
8988-2674.
The address is Hangangno,
Yongsan-gu, Seoul.
[SAE AN INTERNET BANKING.
SECURITY LEVEL HAS BEEN INCREASED.]
What is this?
Yes? This is Korean Restaurant Dam.
- Hello, I want make an reservation.
- Oh, yes.
We'll be having about 50 people.
- Whose name should I put this under?
- Dae San Securities.
Do you have a premium menu available?
We have the "Royal Table".
It's 90,000 won per person.
- Would that be okay?
- Yes, okay.
500,000 won reservation fee?
Okay. I'll send it now.
Okay, thank you.
It appears that you're eligible
to borrow up to 30 million won.
But since your credit score is low,
you'll need to have a cosigner.
50 Royal Tables?
How much would that be?
How do I get a cosigner?
It's not that hard. If you have
five million won in your account
we can send you the money today.
What is this?
He sent five million
instead of 500,000 won.
You posted a watch for sale online?
Yes, I did.
One americano please.
You listed that at seven million.
I was wondering if we could negotiate.
I think that might be difficult.
Oh, no? I'll take it for
seven million won then.
When can I get the watch?
Oh, okay, okay.
Just a moment ago, I made
a reservation for 50 people.
I sent five million won
instead of 500,000 won by accident.
That's my company's money. Could you
send back 4.5 million won please?
Isn't that the watch that
President Wang gave to you?
- Hello?
- Yes, I'm on my way to send it.
Can you send it
from a convenience store?
If you send me the tracking number,
I'll send you the money right away.
Okay, thank you.
This is Manager Choi Chul Min
from Omega Savings Bank.
I've gotten my account
up to five million won.
[WHEN YOU TRANSFER MONEY,
WATCH OUT FOR SCAMMERS.]
My Father said he sent
a package just now.
- It's right here.
- Oh, yes. Thank you.
[SAE AHN BANK WITHDRAWAL:
FIVE MILLION WON]
Where's the package that
I just dropped off? Give it back to me.
- Your son just picked it up.
- What do you mean? What son?
I'm going to go crazy!
What in the world are you doing?
You jerk. Are you kidding me?
You bastard. What's going on?
Geez.
Hey, Mi Joo! Why did you
leave me your car?
I searched everywhere for you.
Geez, you. Aren't you happy to see me?
- Ji Eun, Ji Eun.
- Why are you here so late?
I'm running out of breath.
It's pouring. Let's go.
[BAEK SUNG IL,
CITY HALL SEOWON TAXATION DEPARTMENT.]
Yes, are you ready?
Okay, send it now.
Don't answer carelessly.
Why are my grades always the same?
Only three kids are doing worse than me.
But all three of them are
on the taekwondo team.
What's wrong with me?
I think...
There are too many
geniuses in your class.
Really?
Hey.
He deleted that message.
Let's dig some more into Baek Sung Il.
We meet again.
I guess you don't have a car.
Why are you walking in the rain?
- Yeah?
- I saw your ad online
I was wondering if you
could sell it to me.
It's a triangle scam this time.
You know how people
sell used stuff online?
Seller. To the seller, I'm going
to disguise myself as a buyer.
To the buyer, I'm going
to disguise myself as a seller.
So we're just going to take
the money from them.
Something urgent came up.
I don't think I can be there.
- Oh, really?
- I think you should show him the car.
I'm just going to ask you to not
discuss the exterior of the car.
Yeah, I get what you're trying
to say. I'll do that.
Okay. Should I call you after
I take a look at the car?
- Yes?
- I just saw the car.
- What do you think?
- I like it very much.
Can I buy the car today?
Hey punk. Give me that money!
Give that money back right now!
We did file a report, but it seems like
getting the money back will be hard.
I apologize.
We don't do direct deals here.
Why would we do
direct deals at a dealership?
Mister.
Can I borrow your lighter?
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by DramaFever
[SQUAD 38]
I'm Cha Jae Won from National Tax Service
Investigation Intelligence Division.
The rich are queen ants,
and the lawmakers are worker ants.
You are a solider ant.
You're the public official.
Baek Sung Il is the soldier ant.
Why are you attacking your queen ant?
Who are we supposed
to collect taxes from?
The poor ones. Collect taxes from them.
They listen to us well.
Excuse me.
Who are you guys?
Hey, do you want me to get him for you?
Can you do that?
You.. You bastard. Are you smiling?