TOEI PRESENTS
Ghost of Oiwa
Planning by Yumi Kanbe
Screenplay by Tai Kato
Photography by Osamu Furuya
Lighting by Giichi Inoue
Art Design by Choshiro Katsura
Music by Nakabai Takahaishi
Starring:
Tomisaburo Wakayama
Tosho Sawamura
Sentaro Fushimi
Yoshiko Fujishiro
Jushiro Konoe
Directed by Tai Kato
- All-purpose elixir!
- Most efficacious!
Cures all ills!
Hello, Tamiya.
Which is it,
gambling or women?
- Your wife not back yet?
- Bastard!
Naosuke, there aren't any
customers here.
You shut up!
You're a retainer of the
Tokugawa shogunate.
The government pays your wages.
Your runaway wife is from a
ruined samurai family.
Hey, medicine man!
What's it good for?
It's time to give her up.
Naosuke...
you know why Oiwa ran
away from me?
I killed that man in the den
last December.
She didn't want to have a...
murderer for a husband.
But mark my words:
I'll get her back.
I'll never find another woman with
such a beautiful body.
Huh, what a thing to say!
What are you doing here today?
Oiwa's father brought her sister to
the masseur's place.
I'm waiting here...
for him to come back.
Employee's Entrance
Would you please put your
thumbprint here.
Osode, now you're indentured,
Do as your master tells you.
Father, I'll work as hard as my
salary demands.
How dare you?!
It's not a difficult position.
She only has to tend the toothpick stall
in the temple precincts.
And these women?
That's our other business.
But we keep them separate.
Excuse me.
Go inside, dear.
Change this rag for one of ours.
I'll bill you for the kimono later.
You can start work at the stall
right away.
Yomoshichi! Yomoshichi...
we're due back by now.
If I miss this chance,
I won't see her for a year.
- How stupid!
- Who's stupid?
You are! You just don't get it.
I know you're keen to see the
one you're betrothed to.
But our lord departs for the fief
after a year of duty in Edo.
That's tomorrow.
You need to prepare.
You go on ahead.
I have something important to tell her.
But she's not at home.
Oiwa said she went to the
masseur's place.
Where's that?
I don't know.
- You are stupid!
- So what?!
That idiot sent Oiwa's sister to
work at the masseur's.
Oiwa sure is beautiful,
but her sister's even better!
I'd choose the sister!
- You can buy her tonight.
- Eh?
That massage parlour is
a whorehouse.
A whorehouse?
Yes, at night they massage
something else!
Shall I ask them to reserve
her for you?
No, thank you.
What? You're going back?
Why shouldn't I?
But she'll want to see you.
- It's too late now.
- You fool!
Yes, I know I am.
You won't even listen?
You won't try to help?
- You're a coward!
- Stop it!
Naosuke, if that dotard
refuses again...
I know. Leave him to me.
Be on time.
Naosuke! Naosuke!
We have a customer!
I'm busy. You go alone.
Our master will be furious.
Give up, man!
Father!
Father, please help me out.
I'll not have the likes of you
calling me 'father'!
Please... just hear me out.
There's no point!
Even if you won't listen,
Oiwa is still my wife.
I want her to come back immediately.
My daughter will have no murderer
for a husband.
What did you say...?
I was considerate enough not to
have you arrested.
Begone with you!
Are you all right?
I'm sorry.
Where's your hairpin?
Maid...?
I'm terribly sorry.
You're not hurt?
I'm not going in.
Please, come in.
I'll go see what they want.
Hey... that new girl is mine.
I'll go home, after all.
OK, Go.
I will!
I'll bring her here now.
What now?
Go on, go home.
When I'm good and ready!
Then how will you pay back
this money?
- I never agreed.
- It's in the contract.
Do as she says!
No violence!
You can't force her.
She just needs persuading.
Anyway, she has a client
waiting upstairs.
Come on!
Hey! What about me?
The men upstairs paid
one gold piece.
He who pays more,
goes first.
All right, then...
There's two gold ryo.
She's mine.
What shall we do?
He paid more.
They can't complain.
Then it's decided!
Stop it!
Not here. In there.
Please let me go!
Once I get going,
there's no stopping me.
You monster!
I'm already betrothed.
That sounds like Osode!
Ouch! Don't bite me!
You bastard!
You coward!
I'll get him!
What's going on?
- Close the door!
- Yes!
How dare you?
We're very sorry.
We paid for her,
so she's ours.
Osode, my darling!
Prepare some 'moxibustion'
for me!
Something with a bite!
Who are those men?
One of them is engaged to her.
- Which one?
- The one in white.
Damn him!
You, come back!
Please wait one year till I return.
When I come back next year,
I'll get permission to marry you.
I fell for that wench!
I really love her!
I'll never give her up.
Osode is mine!
Thank you.
- Is this yours?
- No, it's Yomoshichi's.
Well, I'll be damned if I'm going
back up there!
Getting along well, are they?
I'll take it.
I'll go have a drink. If you're not ready,
I'll go back alone.
It's Naosuke...?
Listen, Oiwa...
Is this Osode's father?
Osode was forced to entertain
a client tonight.
That cur, Takuetsu!
I'll go with you.
You stay here.
Mother... mother,
please protect Osode.
Treacherous dog!
You cowards...
- Prepare to die!
- I curse you!
That's him. He's the one...
He's dead!
- Mr. Tamiya!
- Husband!
- Who killed him?
- Two young samurai.
Your father killed the one wearing
this white robe.
The other made the head cut
that killed him.
He took Yomoshichi's body with him.
I will seek revenge.
Revenge for my father-in-law.
Wife, this is no time for
us to be apart.
I want you back.
Osode, in order to throw
them off the track,
you protect yourself by moving
in with Naosuke.
You can't be serious?!
Since we're partners,
I'm obliged to help out.
I will do whatever it takes to protect
your sister-in-law.
A year has passed...
Having the baby has spoiled
her beauty.
How can we raise a child
in this poverty?
She's been bed-ridden
since she had it.
Your dream to be promoted
in the ranks...
may end up as just a dream.
I want money so badly...
One good bribe and I'd get
the position I want.
Who's that lass?
A pretty girl?
Tell us. Who is she?
None of your business.
A neighbour.
They just moved in.
Not only that. She certainly
had her eye on you.
Tamiya, how much do you earn
making umbrellas?
The money doesn't matter.
My wife demands... that I revenge
her father's murder.
Tamiya... I know you wanted Oiwa
to die in childbirth.
Don't say that here!
once or twice in his life,
at a minimum!
Excuse my intrusion...
Your new neighbour wishes to pay
his respects to you.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Oiwa, how do you feel today?
I'll prepare your medicine.
How come he knows the
new neigbours?
Your new neighbours,
the Ito family
Thank you for inviting me.
In order to further our
acquaintance,
we'd be honoured to have you
over for dinner tonight.
# Oh, how I long to build... #
# a teahouse so very fine. #
# A place to await the boat, #
# which goes both upstream... #
# and downstream, up and down. #
# 'Tis a fine day in Kisarazu, #
# but Edo is wreathed in cloud. #
# Now a man, to be fair,
to be just, #
# is handsomely browned by
the harsh sun. #
- If you'll excuse me.
- Thank you for coming.
You shouldn't get up.
Since I've been sick, my husband has
nothing to wear when going out.
I should at least finish off
this jacket.
You are such a good wife, Oiwa.
I only wish he appreciated you.
Don't say that.
Once I fully recover,
he's bound to change.
Then he can seek revenge for
my father's murder.
Maid...
I beseech your favour.
Mr. Tamiya,
I know this is a sudden offer,
but we'd like you to accept these.
Mr. Tamiya,
please look at my daughter.
Since she ran into you last year
at the temple,
she fell deeply in love
and became ill.
We searched for you and finally,
today...
Thank you for your offer...
but I have a wife and child,
both officially registered.
We understand.
If money can resolve your problem,
I'll offer whatever is needed.
I didn't hear you enter.
How are the neighbours?
Your hopes of promotion will
end up as just a dream.
I need money.
I could buy a worthy position.
If money can resolve your problem,
I'll offer whatever is needed.
Oiwa... give me money!
Money!
- We don't have any!
- Yes... you do.
Where are you going?
I need to get out and drink!
Please don't.
You'll wake the baby.
I know you have some.
Hand it over!
You've saved some secretly.
I would never do that.
Please don't...
You obstinate bitch!
All right, I'll pawn something.
Please, don't!
This is worth something.
No! That's the only thing I have
of my mother's.
Get it off!
Please... take this kimono instead.
I don't want this rag!
This mosquito net will sell.
No, please don't!
He'll get bitten by mosquitoes.
Drive the bloody things away.
That's your job!
- You're too cruel!
- Let go!
Please don't!
You stupid, obstinate bitch!
All right, Oiwa.
You'll never let go, will you?
No matter what I do.
It's all right. There, there...
Laundry, Alterations & Repairs
Naosuke, are you in?
Can you go out?
I was planning on going fishing.
Want to come?
Fishing...?
How's my sister?
Is she any better?
She's at home.
How's the baby?
They're both home.
If you're worried, ask Kohei to tend
to your sister today.
Hello?
Coming.
Some of those flowers, please.
- How about these?
- They'll do fine.
That'll be 16 copper pieces.
Thank you very much.
- Hey, Naosuke...
- What?
You still haven't bedded Osode,
have you?
She always carries a dagger.
She puts it to her throat and
says she'll kill herself.
She's not much use to me dead.
- Is Kohei there?
- Yes, I'm here.
- How's your mother?
- No change.
Can you go and see to my sister?
I'll stay with your mother.
All right, then.
Thank you.
Mother, just a little bit more and we
can buy your medicine.
Tamiya - if you really want to
get rid of Oiwa,
why not kill her?
That way, Osode will be all alone.
Then I can easily have her.
A simpleton's solutions are
always simple.
And you're always right,
aren't you?
Listen, Naosuke...
one's reputation affects one's
promotion prospects.
I need a strong reason,
one for which she'd deserve death.
Hey, Naosuke...
What is it?
Bodies...
A lover's suicide, is it?
More like lovers put to death.
Probably an adulterous affair.
A samurai's wife had an affair
with a servant.
A rumour soon spread.
They were nailed to a board
and tortured to death,
their bodies thrown into the river.
Little fellow, it's such a lovely
jacket she's given you.
Let me do it.
Such a lucky boy!
Look, he's smiling.
He takes after his father.
Please send my gratitude to your
master and mistress.
This potion has been in the family
for generations.
It is especially good for
your complaint.
I'm much obliged to you.
- Be careful.
- Sorry.
This testimonial says it's
good medicine.
Take it.
Will you go and thank the
neighbours for me?
Is that necessary?
Yes, you really should.
Kohei?
Will you wear this?
Are they still painful?
I bought you this.
For your fingers.
Ointment
Husband!
I'll go next door.
Stop!
You'll regret this!
Hand it over.
What are you talking about?
You know what I mean.
You still refuse?
What do you mean?
This is what I mean.
Forgive me.
I have no money to buy medicine
for my mother.
Don't try to deceive me...
Please - forgive him.
You stay out of it.
Even a helping hand should be
loyal to his master.
You're an insolent, disloyal cur to steal
your master's goods.
Hurts... does it?
Stay back!
Takuetsu...
you watch him while I go out.
If he tries to escape,
kill him with this sword.
Mr. Tamiya, the medicine which I had
my maid give your wife... the thing is...
She's going to take it.
It is a ghastly poison.
We lied to her.
That poison will destroy her face.
It's all my doing.
I did it for my daughter.
The poison will make her
as ugly as sin.
Then you'll hate her.
That is what we want.
I know how dreadful it is.
But I love my daughter.
It breaks my heart that she cannot
have the one she loves.
Thank you.
Mistress, what's happening?
What should I do?
What's wrong?
Why are you in agony like this?
What on Earth is going on?
You're so beautiful. If I were a man,
I'd never leave you alone.
Maid, will you stop it?!
- I'll tell Mr. Tamiya!
- No! Don't!
Mother!
Has father finished?
Oume, despite our efforts,
you must also do your best.
You should be decent and modest.
Mr. Tamiya is a samurai,
you understand?
Mistress, was the medicine effective?
You had me very worried
there for a while.
Frankly, I was quite startled!
Mistress, how do you feel now?
Mistress?
Madame? Where are you?
You shouldn't use such dirty water.
My face suddenly felt like
it was burning.
I couldn't breathe.
But now... I feel better.
I'm relieved to hear it.
Is the baby sleeping now?
Ma'am... your face!
What about... my face?
No, I mean you recovered
so quickly.
That medicine is very effective.
I still feel a little dizzy,
but I do feel better now.
The lamp is out.
Takuetsu... would you go and get
some oil, please?
- Hurry, please.
- Certainly.
Mr. Tamiya...
She took the medicine?
How about her face?
You knew it was poison?
No! Please stop!
Takuetsu, go and mount her.
Don't be silly!
Then I can divorce her.
You have a woman.
Are you refusing me?
You still say no?
All right, I will.
If you don't do it...
you know what'll happen.
Hold out your hand.
Don't fail me.
- I'm back.
- Thank you very much.
I'll bandage it.
Thank you.
I've never read your palm before.
This line looks bad.
If you don't get rid of it,
your sufferings will never cease.
How can I change something
I was born with?
By severing the line between
you and your man!
How insolent!
Mistress!
Have you lost your senses?!
No, Madame.
I'm very serious.
While you pledge your all
to Mr. Tamiya...
you no longer reside in his heart.
No! Don't!
Forgive me. I'm so sorry.
Let me explain...
Your husband told me to do this.
What? My husband put you
up to this?
If you don't believe me...
look at your face in the mirror.
Do it now.
My face...?
Is this... really me?
This horror?!
What's happened to me?
Oiwa - your husband and Ito,
your neighbour, are responsible.
They said it was medicine.
It was actually poison.
He schemed to have me commit adultery with you.
Both want to get rid of you,
then that shopkeeper's daughter can
marry your samurai husband.
How vicious a plot!
They intended to kill me.
While I still draw breath,
I'll have my revenge.
Curse them!
No! Not like this.
You're too crazed just now.
You'll worsen your illness.
Calm down first.
Yes, I must look neat.
I must comb my hair and
blacken my teeth.
Takuetsu, would you be so good as to
bring my teeth-blackening things?
You really shouldn't.
You've just given birth.
That doesn't matter.
Bring them now!
# How the bamboo hedge... #
# has now grown to become... #
# as untamed as the grass is wild. #
# Even when sheltered by an eave, #
# the wild grass will ne'er
deign to wither. #
You're bleeding!
Takuetsu!
Stay right there!
I've caught you red-handed.
Now you and Oiwa have to die.
If you must kill someone,
kill him.
Yes, I forgot...
He's still in the cellar.
You must have heard everything, eh?
That's good... very good.
Put them down.
Come on. Hurry up.
Coming!
Good morning.
What's wrong?
My son still hasn't returned home.
I'm getting worried.
That is unusual.
He's not a child -
no need to worry.
But it's not like him.
Sit down here.
You scared me.
How did you get in?
Kohei is in the back.
Really? He's here?
- Yes, it's him all right.
- Really?
Oiwa, are you better now?
How's the boy doing?
Oume, sorry to have kept
you waiting.
Show me your face.
Who's there?
Oh, it's you, Naosuke.
Tamiya, you're a real shrewd one,
aren't you?
Chop off my head and I'd still live!
What do you want here, Naosuke?
You should know... hush money.
Are you sure?
Husband, some money.
Tamiya, you can trust me:
I'll never mention this to a soul.
You can count on me.
There's just the two of us here.
No need to hide anymore.
We're married now.
Oume... turn around and let
me look at you.
Yes, husband.
We will always be together...
forever...
Oiwa! Go to your grave!
What have I done?!
What's wrong with you?
Big trouble!
Where's your master?
He was tired,
so he went back to his room.
Tamiya! Why are you carrying a sword?
Mr. Tamiya, please! No!
Give me the medicine...
For rent
Where is Takuetsu?
Where is his lady stall-keeper?
- I don't know.
- Yes, you do.
You're choking me!
He went to Yotsuya,
but had some trouble there.
I hear he's working in Fukagawa.
Fukagawa, you say? Good!
It's filthy. What is it?
A tortoise shell comb.
That's a good catch!
Excuse me, can I get a light?
Sure. Here you are.
It's been a while.
It is a rare and good chance to find
you here, Tamiya Iyemon.
I must extract vengeance for my
sister-in-law, Oiwa.
That's what I should say!
But how've you been?
Since then...
I lost all chance of promotion.
Everything goes against my wishes.
Where do you live now?
In a temple in Honjo.
To ward away the evil luck
that dogs me.
It's freezing outside!
It must have been cold out.
I didn't catch much,
then it started to snow.
The only thing I did get was this.
Put it in the basin.
I'll wash it.
It's excellent quality;
it should fetch a good price.
It's unusually cold today.
That'll do it.
I need something hot:
warm up some sake.
I tried to buy some,
but our credit has run out.
The gods haven't deserted us.
Look, I can sell this.
Where did you get it?
The river, like always.
This used to be my mother's comb.
My sister, Oiwa, had it.
Well... there must be many
similar ones.
You must promise never to sell it!
All right. As usual,
I'll do whatever you say.
The rice and soup are hot.
Come have dinner.
Look - not much of a catch.
It'll fetch a good price.
I'd better do it now.
What are you doing?
A hand grabbed me!
This is my sister's undergarment.
Naosuke! You told me my sister was
punished for adultery.
This comb and these clothes
are all my sister's.
I don't believe she did it.
Tell me the truth.
Hey, masseur!
Naosuke, are you truly protecting me?
Of course I am.
Actually, I'm the only one...
Good evening.
Thank you for calling me.
It's you!
It is...!
How have you been?
Yes... quite a surprise.
- A long time.
- Indeed.
It's a small world.
A man has to be careful.
Anyway, let me begin.
That comb!
You know something?!
I can never forget it.
It was Oiwa's.
What happened to her?
- She was murdered!
- By whom?
Her husband - that samurai, Tamiya.
I shudder to remember it.
I can't stay!
This was Oiwa's kimono!
Tell me everything!
Osode! I'll tell you the whole story.
Takuetsu! Stop!
Forgive me. Help!
Takuetsu, I need to ask you.
Osode, I'll tell you everything.
Listen to me.
Osode!
I missed you so much.
I'm so happy.
I really missed you.
What's the matter? Tell me.
Listen... My father has given
his consent.
Even my mother was happy about it.
What's upsetting you?
I'll never leave you again.
Yomoshichi?
My God! What have we done?
I've told you everything.
Now kill me.
One failure in life is enough
for me. Do it!
No, I've got one more thing
to ask you, Naosuke.
Eh? More questions?
Where is Tamiya Iyemon,
the man who killed my sister?
I can't tell you that.
Even outlaws have a code.
Osode, the very cause of my failure is
that I truly fell in love with you.
Now he's found you again,
it's no use.
I'm beginning to regret all
the things I did.
But... evil men have no regrets.
Do it! Kill me now.
Naosuke, prepare to die!
Enough jokes!
Naosuke - you'll not stake your life
for a chance?
Hmmm? A chance for what?
For your love, Osode.
Yomoshichi!
I'll stake mine.
Let's you and I together kill Tamiya.
Either of us could survive,
or we both might die.
Let us fight!
Trust our lives to our swords.
I like that. Let's do it!
Stop haunting me!
Stop this agony!
Give me the medicine.
Tamiya, give me the medicine.
I'll give you this!
It always starts out like this!
Iyemon Tamiya! I've come to avenge
my father and sister.
I have joined her quest!
All right... I understand.
Why are you here?
I refute you,
and take the side of Osode.
Interesting... you'll regret it.
I'll send the three of you to hell.
Come on!
Protect Tamiya!
Stop running away!
Go back and get them.
Osode, you're mine now!
All mine!
Osode!
The final cut!
Osode... do it.
Hurry!
Naosuke... this life had nothing
good in it...
Elder sister!
Dearest sister!
The End
Translation by Stuart J Walton
Timing by Lord Retsudo