[Whooshing]
[Boy laughing]
[Click]
SEAN: Uhh...
Uhh!
Oh!
Ohh!
Ohhh...
[Sobbing]
Oh...
Ohhh!
[Exhales heavily]
-You eaten anything?
-No.
TITO: What is this, a picnic?
We got 10 minutes to go.
[Click]
[Choir singing]
Punch me out, man.
MAN: You got it.
SEAN: Any word
from the LAPD lntelligence?
If there is such a thing?
LOOMIS: Not yet, sir.
Of course not...
because we're a covert
antiterrorism team...
that is so secret...
that when we snap our fingers,
nothing happens!
[Beeping]
SEAN: Sheriff's department?
Airport police?
WANDA: Still waiting. Interpol
insists he's in Tripoli.
Yeah, well, you trust...
you trust that
billion-dollar satellite, OK?
I'll trust a $10 snitch
at this point.
TITO: Sean. Look...
SEAN: What?
TITO: Why don't you just give
'em a little break, OK?
We'll take a break
when the case breaks, OK?
CHORUS: Hallelujah!
Hallelujah!
Hallelujah! Hallelujah!
Hallelujah, hallelujah!
[Hallelujah Chorus continues]
CASTOR: I never really enjoyed
the Messiah.
In fact,
I think it's fucking boring.
But your voice...
makes even a hack like Handel...
seem like a genius.
CASTOR: Hallelujah!
Hallelujaaaaah!
Ah!
[Hallelujah chorus ends]
SEAN: Victor,
when we put this thing to bed...
you can brand
the Fourth Amendment on my butt.
Thank you.
KIMBERLY: Sir. Excuse me.
Your wife is on line one.
TITO: Sean!
A jet was just chartered.
Anderson Airfield.
Guess who paid the bill in cash?
Pollux Troy.
SEAN: Put one of our people
on that plane.
TITO: Wait! We still got no sign
of Castor.
Pollux doesn't fly
without big brother.
Now, come on.
POLLUX: You're 26 minutes late.
The casing didn't fit, right?
I told you Dietrich
would try to pawn off...
some cheap shit
North Korean plastic.
CASTOR:
Casing fit like a condom.
You didn't deviate from
the plan, did you? Pollux?
POLLUX: How long do you want me
to sit here twiddling my thumbs?
I paid for the jet.
Saved us some time.
That's what the boys are for--
to hide our famous faces.
If I didn't love you so much,
I'd have to kill you, bro.
I hate it
when you call me bro.
You guys are paid to protect
him from everybody...
including himself.
And stay away from downtown
on the 18th.
It's gonna be
a little, uh...smoggy.
[Chuckles]
WINTERS: Okay, my passengers
are here. I gotta go.
CASTOR: Let's go.
Let's go. I'm bored. Let's go.
WINTERS: Here you go.
Bravo.
Would you like anything else
once we're airborne?
Oh...a peach.
Sit. Come here.
Mmm.
You know,
I can eat a peach for hours.
Um...come here.
If I were to send you flowers...
where would l...
No.
Wait. Let me rephrase.
If I were to let you
suck my tongue...
would you be grateful?
Oh.
[Tires screech]
PILOT: There's someone
on the runway.
[Siren]
CASTOR: Get off of me!
[Tires screeching]
CASTOR: Archer.
WINTERS: FBI!
This is a very big gun.
Fly the fucking plane.
Come on. That's it.
Come on, let's go!
TITO: Don't play chicken
with the goddamn jet!
Come on!
He's got Winters! Goddamn it!
[Tires screeching]
All units, pin 'em in!
Close in on 'em!
CASTOR: One of yours, Sean?
[Gunshot]
Shit!
[Tires screeching]
SEAN: Out! Come on!
Let's go! Go!
TITO: Goddamn it, Sean!
CASTOR: Take off now.
-Fly!
-I can't!
Fly, bitch!
All units locked and ready.
Follow Archer's lead.
[Alarm sounds]
CASTOR: What the fuck
are you doing?
PlLOT: There's an engine out.
We gotta stop.
[Gunshot]
[Sirens]
Aah!
LOOMIS: Aah!
CASTOR: Pollux!
POLLUX: Uhh! Uhh!
Uhh!
[Glass breaking]
Aah!
Cas!
SEAN: Secure the hanger!
[Clattering]
[Loud click]
SEAN: Berkley, down!
SEAN: Down!
[Clicking]
SEAN: Give up, Castor.
Your time's up.
CASTOR: Better hit me, 'cause
you only got one bullet left.
SEAN: So do you.
Well.
We've got something in common.
We both know our guns.
SEAN:
What we don't have in common...
is that I don't care if I live,
and you do.
Sean...
that hurts.
You're not having any fun,
are you, Sean?
Why don't you come with us?
Try terrorism for hire.
We'll blow some shit up.
It's more fun.
-Shut the fuck up.
-Watch your fuckin' mouth!
I'm gonna unleash the biblical
plague "Hell-A" deserves.
But I'll give this shithole a break
if my brother and I walk.
Bullshit.
I see.
You think I'm bluffing?
Maybe I am...
but then maybe I'm not.
More importantly, what would
you do with me locked up?
You'd drive your wife
and kid crazy.
How is your daughter, anyway?
Is she ripening by now,
your darling Jamie?
Your little peach, is she ripe?
Whoo! I'm ready!
[Click]
OK.
Please, man, don't shoot me.
[Sobbing]
I'm scared, Seany!
[Laughing]
Well, I think you better
pull the trigger...
'cause I don't give a fuck!
[Singing] I'm ready!
Ready for the big ride, baby!
Unhh!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
TITO: Well, Sean, looks like
Elvis done left the building.
SEAN: [Sighs]
[Sighs]
JAMIE: It wasn't my fault!
Why won't you ever be
on my side?
EVE: I am always
on your side...
but you have to give me
a chance.
SEAN: Now what?
[Sighs]
She was suspended again.
Kid made fun of her clothes.
She started a fight?
JAMIE: Right, Dad,
don't even ask me what happened.
SEAN: OK. What happened?
Oh. I see.
JAMIE: Not like you would
believe me anyway.
Jamie, look, it's not easy, OK?
I mean, look...
you change the way you look
every week.
And the way you act?
Who are you supposed to be now?
I'm supposed to be me.
Not like you have a clue
who I am anyway.
[Door closes]
EVE: I have to work tonight.
I called to tell you.
I was on hold for 10 minutes,
and I couldn't wait any longer.
I got him, Eve.
It's over?
It's over.
Oh, Sean.
I'll make it up to
you and and Jamie, I promise.
I'll put in for a desk job...
and I'll do counseling,
sit down, talk about Mike.
I'll do it. Anything you want.
I just want you.
Well, good, 'cause
that's what you're gonna get.
You happy?
I think so. Yes.
[Laughing]
Oh, thank God.
MAN: Hold on.
What is all this?
KIMBERLY:
Sir, the ClA sent this over.
SEAN: Didn't know they catered.
Send it back.
No, wait.
How about, uh...
What about to Anderson...
Montgomery, Berkley...
Pincus...Gianelli...
Winters.
[Sighs]
How's Loomis?
TITO: He's gonna need
a little surgery, but, uh...
he'll be OK.
What's up?
Special Ops.
They want a word.
Aw, forget it.
I don't have the time.
HOLLIS: Better make time, Sean.
Recovered from the jet wreckage.
Found in Pollux Troy's
briefcase.
[Music plays,
woman moans with pleasure]
WOMAN: Ohh!
SEAN: Porcelain casing.
Thermal cloak.
Nerve gas
and biological payload.
HOLLIS: It's enough to flatten
a square mile.
Then, depending
on the prevailing winds...
the fallout will be
a tad worse...
than Gulf War Syndrome.
SEAN:
The biblical--
A biblical plague to L.A.--
Fuck! Aah! Where is he?
Where's Pollux Troy?
MAN: Why draw the schematic if
you're not gonna build the bomb?
POLLUX: What, is it a crime
to exercise the mind?
- l'm interested in bomb--
- l won't say another word
until l see my brother.
VICTOR: Any progress?
I need about 10 minutes
alone with this guy.
Ah, give it a rest. You got Castor.
Just go home.
[Sighs]
Look, we're not gonna evacuate
the city on your hunch.
Look, I know Castor too well
for this to be a hunch.
You know what?
Just run the goddamn bureau
any way you like.
[Sighs]
HOLLIS: I could put
an agent in his cell.
Maybe Pollux will let it slip.
SEAN: Oh, come on.
He's a paranoid sociopath.
The only person he'd talk to
is his brother, and he's dead.
HOLLIS:
There is one other possibility.
[Beeping]
Oh, God!
You're keeping him alive.
HOLLIS: Relax, Archer.
He's a turnip.
[Sean groaning]
What if you could walk
into Erewhon prison...
and give Pollux
a nice big brotherly hug...
as Castor Troy?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
MALCOLM: Let me try.
Malcolm Walsh.
I run the bio cover unit
for Special Ops.
-I know who you are.
-But not what I can do.
Physical alteration.
Augmentation.
HOLLIS: Dr. Walsh
can alter the likeness...
even the voice
of a government witness.
MALCOLM: I think you'll
recognize this patient.
We had to build
your friend Loomis...
a whole new ear from scratch.
What we're suggesting for you
isn't a permanent transplant.
Just a temporary trade.
Come here.
With new anti-inflammatories,
healing takes days, not weeks.
Your blood types won't match,
but Pollux won't know that.
Height difference is negligible.
Skin pigment, eye pigment,
both almost identical.
We'll use laser shears
for the hairline...
microplugs for body hair.
We'll do an abdominoplasty...
take care of those, uh,
love handles.
But all that's the easy part.
Here's the real science.
This is a state of the art
morphogenetic template.
The inside is modeled
on your skull...
The outside exactly like Troy's.
Then we fit his face on top.
Not a replica,
but the real thing.
Then we simply connect...
the muscles, tear ducts,
and nerve endings...
SEAN: So you want to take
his face and mine--
HOLLIS: Borrow.
The procedure's
completely reversible.
SEAN: You think
that I want to do this?
No. No!
There's no one else, Sean.
You have lived and breathed
Castor Troy for years.
I'll get his gang to talk.
That's what I do!
What if you can't?
The bomb will blow.
And Castor Troy will win.
SEAN: Get out!
Go ahead. Wipe your ass.
TITO: Damn!
What the hell is that smell?
He shit in his pants.
Where's Dietrich?
SEAN: Hello, Sasha.
When was the last time
you saw Castor Troy?
-Who cares? He's dead.
-Answer the question.
I know my rights.
I don't have to answer shit.
You're right, but know this.
You're a convicted felon...
on probation
for harboring Castor Troy.
One phone call from me...
and your son will end up
in a foster home.
I understand why you would use
such a threat...
but you try to take him
away from me...
I swear to you...
I haven't seen him for years.
[Sighs]
SEAN: This reeks of you.
It's got your signature
all over it.
DIETRICH: Maybe, but you
ain't got nothin' on me...
and you know it.
Maybe so, but I can keep you
within city limits...
or I can talk
to your sister again.
She's right outside.
Only this time I'll be nice.
Hey, Sean...
how's your dead son?
Aah!
I don't know any--
OK. Something about the 18th,
but that's all I know.
TITO: Great. So we got a date.
Where the hell's the damn bomb?
Only Pollux Troy'll know that.
It's your call, Sean.
SEAN:
Does Lazarro know your plan?
HOLLIS: No.
This is a black bag operation.
Strictly off the books.
You can't tell Lazarro,
and you can't tell your wife.
Oh, God.
What are you asking me to do?
OK, let's see.
You're asking me
to break the law...
risk my neck...
and you're asking me
to put in the dark...
all the people
that love me and trust me.
I'll do it.
[Dog barking]
EVE: Sean.
Sorry I woke you.
I'm glad it's you
that woke me...
and not a phone call...
telling me
you won't be coming home.
But that's a fear
I can finally let go of, huh?
It's all right, Sean. It's OK.
I keep...
I keep wanting to move this...
over here, you know?
If it had only been an inch
to the left...
Mikey'd be alive.
And you wouldn't be.
Sean, things will get better
now that you're home.
The scar won't move,
but it will heal if you let it.
Everything will be better.
He's out of our lives.
Eve, if I told you
that I realized that...
that this thing
won't fully end...
until I did one last thing...
Eve, something vital.
OK, I know.
You're going back
on assignment again.
Just one last time.
Come on, Eve.
"I'm not going anywhere."
That's what you told me.
Oh!
You don't need me
to tell you what to do.
You never have, so go.
But go now.
Sean, I'm changing my mind.
This is a suicide mission.
SEAN: Yeah, I know. I know.
Well, you know,
maybe this doctor...
if he can do even half
of what he says he can do...
maybe it'll work. I don't know.
I become Castor Troy,
be in control.
TITO:
That's the part that scares me.
Doctor, I have something...
I have a scar that...
If you can put this back after--
after all this is over.
It's important to me.
It's like a reminder.
MALCOLM: Sure.
MALCOLM: Tito, please,
hold this for me.
Please.
OK, let's go.
Oh, God.
TITO: Oh, my God.
TITO: Are you OK?
Come on. Talk to me.
Fuck you! Fuck you!
-Fuck you!
-Sean!
Fuck you!
Sean, sit down.
Sit down. Sit down.
Sean!
Archer!
You're Sean Archer!
Sean Archer.
When this is over...
I want you to take this face...
and burn it.
I still sound like me.
MALCOLM: I've implanted
a microchip on your larynx.
It's fantastic,
but you better be careful.
Pressure, sharp blow...
even a violent sneeze
could dislodge it.
Just repeat what you hear.
CASTOR: Peach.
I can eat a peach for hours.
SEAN: Peach.
There's a scratchy tickle.
Mm-hmm.
Peach.
I can eat a peach for hours.
Once again.
Peach.
I can eat a peach for hours.
Perfect.
HOLLIS: Now, Sean,
six days until the 18th.
The clock's ticking,
and so's the bomb.
SEAN: Yeah.
TITO: You've got two days
to get Pollux to talk.
Either way, Miller comes in
and pulls you out.
You got me?
What's the matter?
SEAN: Face itches.
You all right?
Come on. Let's go.
Archer's going to be pissed when
he comes back and finds out.
WANDA: The guy is knee-deep
in Georgia swamp.
GUARD: You are now the property
of Erewhon prison...
a citizen of nowhere.
The Geneva Convention
is void here.
Amnesty lnternational
doesn't know we exist.
When I say your ass
belongs to me...
I mean exactly that.
This entire prison's
one big magnetic field.
The boots tell us where you are.
Six-twenty-one to population.
HICKS: Hey, hey, hey.
What's the matter, pal?
Don't you remember
the little people?
-Burke Hicks.
-Oh, yeah.
I busted...
believe Sean Archer
busted you...
for stalking
the U.N. Secretary General.
No. Archer framed me.
I had nothing to do with that.
Word was you got wasted.
You want to see what wasted
looks like, little man?
INMATES: Ooh!
Pollux.
GUARD: Out of the way!
SECOND GUARD: Central, there's
a disturbance in the population.
Go to lockdown.
Hold that lockdown.
DUBOV: Come on, you pussy!
SEAN: Watch your fuckin' mouth.
Watch your fuckin' mouth!
'Cause I'm Castor Troy!
Yeah!
I'm Castor Troy!
INMATES: Whoo! Yay!
Whoo!
I'm Castor Troy!
Yeah!
Whoo!
Aah!
Lock 'em down!
I stop the fights, not you.
That's two strikes
for you, Dubov.
One more,
you know where you're going.
SEAN: When I get out of here--
If you get out of here.
I'm gonna have you fired.
[Laughter]
[Monitor beeps]
[Castor gurgling]
[Moaning]
[Wailing]
Aah!
Unh!
CASTOR: Lars, it's me.
Believe it.
Someone...
They took...
switched my...
Some fucking c-c-c...
But it's cool.
We're gonna deal with it.
[Sobbing laugh]
Oh, yes,
we're gonna deal with it.
[Soprano sings opera]
MALCOLM: What's this about?
CASTOR: Dr. Walsh!
I was just enjoying some
of your greatest hits here.
Oh, I hope you don't mind.
I partook in
your groovy painkillers.
This is fabulous work.
This is--Oh!
Ha ha! Bravo! Ha ha!
Brav--fucking--o!
Oh, God. This is excellent.
Bravo.
Bravo!
What do you want?
[Clapping hands]
Take one goddamn guess.
POLLUX: I wish they'd play
those salmon spawning scenes.
I found them intensely erotic.
HICKS: Aw, that fuckin'
nature channel.
One more waterfall,
I'm gonna foam at the mouth.
POLLUX: It's like
they're begging us to riot.
Excuse me.
Not feeling very coordinated
lately, are you?
CASTOR: Look, bro...
you got to help me.
I am so fried.
If the psychos in here
find out I'm misfiring...
we're both gonna be dead meat.
Shock treatment?
What's the matter with you?
Did they operate?
I was in a coma.
Jesus, you're still
so fucking paranoid.
Aren't they giving you
your medication in here?
What was my medication?
Pollux, I hand fed you
those pills for years.
Vivex.
I haven't forgotten that.
It's just everything else.
It's my senses, my reflexes...
my memory--
it's like a tab of bad Quantrax.
I don't even know...
why that fucking yeti
jumped me yesterday.
Dubov?
You had a sex sandwich
with his wife and his sister...
the night he was sent here.
Guess that explains
why he's so upset.
Wow.
We're gonna blow up L.A., bro.
Ain't it cool?
Rub my nose in it,
why don't you?
Ten million dollar design...
and now those militia nut jobs
get to keep their cash.
So fucking unfair.
That bomb you built
does deserve an audience.
It's a work of art.
It belongs in the Louvre.
POLLUX: Yes, it does.
Oh, well.
Guess the L.A. Convention Center
will have to do.
What?
Thank you.
For what?
You are so fucking pathetic.
GUARD: You got a visitor.
Ooh-whee, you're good-lookin'!
You're hot!
It's like looking in a mirror,
only not.
SEAN: Troy?
Now, that is between us.
OK?
But you were...
In a coma?
Having your face cut off
to disturb your sleep.
Read the newspaper lately?
Aah!
You killed them?
Beats paying the bill, huh?
Come on. I mean, if a facelift
cost five grand...
See anything you like?
Tito.
I torched all the evidence
that proves you're you, OK?
So, wow!
You're gonna be in here for...
the next hundred years!
Now, I have got to go.
I've got a government job
to abuse...
and a lonely wife to fuck.
Did I say that?
Oh, sorry.
Make love to.
God, I miss that face.
Die!
Die! Die!
Aah!
WALTON: Sorry, Agent Archer.
No, don't you worry about it,
Mr. Walton.
Clearly, he's had
a traumatic childhood...
and, uh...Thank you.
[Car radio plays]
CASTOR: Look at this place.
I'm in hell.
I may never get
a hard-on again.
[Car radio playing]
INXS: Don't lose your head.
Oh, yes.
There we go.
Well, I suppose it was
only a matter of time...
before you forgot
where we lived.
Come on. Give me a break.
Every house in this block
looks the same.
Then I spotted you.
Eve.
My one and only Eve.
So how was
your vital assignment?
Which one was that?
How should I know, Sean?
Oh, oh, yes.
The out-of-body experience.
Yes, that one.
Where you going?
EVE: To the hospital.
CASTOR: No. No.
What's the matter?
-Sean, come on.
-Oh, what?
Quit teasing me. Stop it.
I'm still really hurt.
There are leftovers
in the fridge.
No, no.
I'm going to stay hungry
for you.
My peach. Gimme that tongue.
Sean, come on.
I can't believe
what you're doing.
Eve...
I hate to see you go...
but I love to watch you leave.
CASTOR: "Date night...
fizzled again.
"We haven't made love
in two months."
What a loser.
[Sighs]
[Music playing]
["Papa's Got A Brand-New Bag"
playing]
Got your e-mail, Karl.
That poem you sent me
was pretty kinky.
[Castor sighs]
The plot thickens.
Hang on a second.
I'll have to call you back.
You're not respecting
my boundaries.
I'm coming in, Janie.
Janie?
I don't think you heard me,
Jamie.
You got something that I crave.
MUSIC:
Papa's got a brand-new bag.
Clarissa left those here.
Well, I won't tell Mom
if you don't.
When did you start smoking?
You'll be seeing a lot
of changes around here.
Papa's got a brand-new bag.
Ah-ooh!
MUSIC: He ain't too hip now...
but I can do the jerk...
Come on, do the--
MUSIC:
You're doin' the twist...
Just like this.
POLLUX: Bye, bro.
Drop me a line sometime.
WALTON: Gonna be kind of lonely
with Pollux gone, huh?
SEAN: Pollux what?
That big-shit cop, Archer...
cut him a deal
for turning state's evidence.
Your brother's been released.
I'm Sean Archer.
There is a bomb
at the L.A. Convention Center.
I'm Sean Archer, and--
Ow!
[Singing]
AGENT: Sir, we just wanted you
to know--
WANDA: We're all really sorry
about Tito.
CASTOR: Oh, hey.
Shit happens, you know.
So is our star witness talking?
AGENT: Yeah, about what kind
of mustard he likes...
on his tongue sandwiches.
WANDA: If that bomb's out
there, we're almost out of time.
CASTOR: Hmm.
VICTOR: Archer!
You made the deal
with Pollux Troy.
That isn't like you.
CASTOR: Ah, well.
When all else fails,
fresh tactics.
Fresh?
Let me tell you my fresh tactic.
Everything to do with this case
goes through me, understood?
-Hmm.
-Good!
Thanks.
You're supposed to be snitching,
making me look good.
-Look good?
-Mm-hmm.
Seeing that face on you
makes me afraid...
my tiramisu
might come back up.
CASTOR: Well, think about me.
This nose, this hair.
This ridiculous chin.
[Sighs]
Brother, we're going straight.
Ooh, my goodness.
You exchange brains as well?
First, I need you to confess
to the location of the bomb.
What about our $10 million?
What about when I become
a hero for defusing the bomb?
What's that worth? Know that.
Thank you. Next question.
CASTOR: You're not the only one
in the family with brains.
POLLUX: No. Although now I am
the only one with the looks.
Touché.
[Sirens]
POLICEMAN ON BULLHORN:
This is an emergency evacuation.
[Sirens]
This is
an emergency evacuation.
COP: Go! Go! Move this way!
-Any ideas?
-Yeah. Run.
COP: Sir, it's protected
by a tamper switch.
It'll take us hours to bypass.
CASTOR: Evacuate your team.
No, but, sir, we can't disarm--
Leave!
[Singing] Dee dee dee.
Hallelujah!
Hallelujah, hallelujah!
[Singing] Ha-ha-ha.
[Beeping]
Oh, baby!
Ohh!
REPORTER: That was the scene
at the L.A. Convention Center...
where an FBI agent
became a city savior.
Sean Archer disarmed
a massive bomb...
just one second before
it was set to blow.
The apparent targets were
three Supreme Court justices...
scheduled to speak here today...
and anyone unlucky enough to be
within a mile of the scene.
We asked Agent Archer
if the FBI had any leads...
on who planted the device.
CASTOR: Well, that is
classified information.
But, if he's listening...
I wouldn't mind
giving him a message.
Interception!
Now our side's got the ball!
Sorry.
[Inmates booing]
[Applause]
CASTOR: Wanda? Everybody!
Hey, look, l...
I want to thank you...
for, uh...
enduring all these years
I was an insufferable bore.
[Laughter]
WANDA: Sir?
Did you just have
a surgical procedure?
What do you mean?
Well, was the stick successfully
removed from your ass?
[Laughter]
KIMBERLY: Sir,
the White House on one.
It's the President.
Oh, and your wife on line two.
Will you tell
the President to hold?
[Gasps]
Oh!
Oh, my God!
Sean, you scared
the hell out of me.
CASTOR: It's date night.
Congratulations.
Oh, big deal.
OK, I said, uh...
"Mr. President...
"l want the authority...
"and I want the funds
and the personnel...
"to take over the whole gamut
of global terrorism."
Right?
And he said...
"The next name on
my calling list is Lazarro."
And I'm telling him Sean Archer
writes his own ticket.
OK?
[Sighs]
What's the matter?
I don't know, Sean.
You just seem so different.
Hmm?
EVE: What is all this about?
This intimate
candlelight dinner?
Huh?
I'm supposed to forget
all the promises...
'cause you're going back
into the fray?
[Sighs]
If the top cop
in this country...
can't come home every night
to his wife...
then the hell
with the country...
because the only place
I'm going...
is upstairs with you.
GUARD: Exercise. One hour.
[Weapon clicking]
SEAN: How can l
get out of here?
HICKS: You can't.
How can I get these boots off?
They only take them off
in the clinic...
right before
they fry your skull.
Hey!
I'm out of cigarettes.
GUARD: Get back in line, Troy.
I said I'm out of cigarettes.
Ugh.
INMATE: Kick his ass!
HICKS: What the hell?!
That's not right!
Aah!
I need a light!
-Anybody got a light?
-All right!
Anybody got a light?
[Cheering]
[Sizzling]
MED-TECH: Bring the bastard
down before he chokes to death.
MED-TECH: Well, happy day.
It's Castor Troy.
SEAN: Wait. H-Hold it, hold it.
Can l, uh-- Can l have a light?
WALTON: You know,
those things can kill you.
[Laughs]
Get his boots.
[Snapping]
Dubov?
I didn't touch your wife.
And I didn't touch your sister.
But I know your wife loves you.
She's waiting for you.
So let's get out of here.
[Grunts]
WALTON: You're more
brain-dead than Dubov.
SEAN: Ow!
Unh.
Out!
Out.
GUARD: There they are!
Close the door
SECOND GUARD: Look out.
GUARD: Under fire.
We have men down in C-4.
GUARD: l got 'em.
Throw 'em down!
[Screaming]
Move!
[Alarms sounding]
DUBOV: Get down!
[Shouting]
SEAN: Dubov!
No!
Get out!
Aah!
Dubov!
Give me your hand.
Come on.
You can do it.
-Aah!
-No!
No! No!
No!
EVE: Sean?
Wait.
What are you doing?
CASTOR: Ah! I'm sorry.
Have a nice day.
Have a nice day?
What is with you?
Is his your way of
not dealing with this morning?
Yeah. Yeah, maybe.
Sean?
Sean!
I know it's hard for you,
but it's hard for me, too...
and we still have to go.
Happy birthday, Mikey.
He took our baby, Sean.
He took our little boy.
[Crying]
WANDA:
You turned your beeper off.
CASTOR:
Yes, well, my son's birthday.
WANDA: Well, here's
some poetic justice, sir.
Castor Troy's dead.
AGENT: He got killed
trying to escape from Erewhon.
CASTOR: Where's his body?
I want to see his body.
WANDA:
It hasn't been recovered yet.
It hasn't been recovered yet?!
Get the LAPD on this.
WANDA: Even if he's alive...
Castor isn't stupid enough
to come back to the city.
[Sighs]
You must--you must trust me.
He's already here.
[Car alarm chirps]
[Dialing]
WOMAN: County General.
How may I direct your call?
SEAN: Dr. Archer, please.
It's an emergency.
-And who's calling?
-Her husband.
NURSE:
Dr. Archer, call on line three.
SEAN: I know
this sounds crazy, but--Shit!
[Sighs]
Sean?
Eve. Listen carefully.
The man you think
is your husband, isn't.
Who is this?
Please, just listen.
Take Jamie.
Go to your mother's.
Don't tell him
where you're going.
Whoever you are,
don't call again.
MAN ON PHONE: Operations.
I need Victor Lazarro
immediately.
-Regarding?
-lnformation about Castor Troy.
MAN: I'll transfer you, sir.
CASTOR: Sean Archer here.
Who's calling?
Well, if you're Sean Archer...
I guess I'm Castor Troy.
Ah, yes.
WOMAN ON RADIO: This escapee is
considered extremely dangerous.
If you have any information
concerning the whereabouts...
of Castor Troy...
[Clicks off]
[Siren]
DIETRICH INTO PHONE:
You're goddamn right. Yeah.
This shit's so good,
it's gonna make your dick hard.
What?
Cheryl? Cheryl's a liar.
SEAN: Dietrich.
So you're still selling hops
and drugs...
to Cheryl and Phil Roy.
Ha ha ha!
Castor fucking Troy!
Ah, man. You scared me, man.
All right. All right. Ha ha.
You know, l never should have sold you
those bombs.
lt's my curse.
l can't say no to a friend.
SEAN: Can't say no to money.
-Yeah, that's my other curse.
-You drug dealer.
-What's the matter?
-What?
-Look like you fucked your mother.
Let's relax, huh?
DIETRICH: Hey!
MAN: Hey, Castor.
FITCH: I don't believe this.
Castor Troy!
ALDO: What are you doing?
Woo-oooh!
Wanna hit?
WOMAN: Hey, baby, remember me?
I'm your favorite peach.
SECOND WOMAN: I thought
I was your favorite.
FITCH: Look at this guy.
You look pretty good
for a dead guy. Hey!
DIETRICH: Let's go.
Here.
So what do you want to do?
You wanna leave the country?
SEAN: I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna get Sean Archer...
with your help.
OK.
Welcome home, baby.
Oh!
ALDO: How we supposed
to do that?
He's vulnerable at home.
FITCH: No. This is
Sean Archer we're talking about.
This isn't just some Boy Scout.
ALDO: Fitch.
Besides, his house is probably
alarmed up the wazoo.
SEAN: Code is 10-19-86.
That's his dead son's
birthday.
Don't it just break your heart?
Ha. That's brilliant.
But sick.
[Laughter]
ALDO: How is it that you know
so much about Sean Archer?
I, uh...sleep with his wife.
[Laughter]
Well.
Jesus Christ, this is great.
FITCH: So, once
we kidnap Supercop, then what?
Tiny...
surgery.
I'd like to take his--
his face...
off.
Yes.
Now, if you'll all
excuse me...
I have to use the...
Iittle boy's wee-wee room.
DIETRICH: Cas?
You want to take his...face--
Yes.
His face...off!
The eyes...
nose...
skin.
It's coming off!
The face...
off.
DIETRICH:
No more drugs for that man.
[Laughing]
I'm not me.
I'm me.
Not me.
Me.
Castor Archer.
SASHA: I thought you were dead.
SEAN: I'm not dead. I'm me.
No, look. What I'm
trying to tell you, Pollux...
is once we get the full
protection of the government...
to help us get rid
of our rivals, right? Then we'll be set.
Then maybe, just maybe
I'll get my frickin' face back.
Then I'll just have one jag-off
to take care of.
[Loud rock music playing]
[Music stops]
KARL: Hey, where you going?
Where you going?
JAMIE: Karl, stop it.
Maybe two. Hold on.
-Karl, stop it!
-Calm down!
JAMIE: My dad's gonna--Karl!
CASTOR: Happy hunting.
l'll catch you later.
Yeah, like Mr. Fuckin' lnvisible
gives a shit about you anyways.
-So fucking hold still!
-Calm down!
Now say you're sorry.
-I'm sorry.
-I didn't hear.
-I'm sorry!
-Mean it.
I'm so sorry!
CASTOR:
Dress up like Halloween...
and ghouls will try
to get in your pants.
Typical, Dad.
Some guy tries to rape me,
and I'm to blame?
CASTOR: This isn't you.
You haven't been the same
since Mike died.
Hiding behind
someone else's face...
hoping you wouldn't feel
the pain.
While we're talking...
do you have protection?
What, you mean like condoms?
Protection.
Next time,
let Karl take his pants down.
Slip this in his thigh...
twist it
so the wound won't close.
Now go on. Get out of here.
I am the king.
SEAN: Hmm.
Mmm.
Eve.
[Gasps]
SASHA: Aah!
Jesus! Cas, it's me!
SASHA: It's me.
SASHA: Cas...
Shh.
Come on.
It's me.
SASHA: Jesus!
Come on.
Don't you wanna talk?
SASHA: Only talk
I ever heard from you...
is "Suck my tongue,"
"Love your ass," and "See ya."
Take this filthy shit off,
put this on and get out of here.
No. I'm not going anywhere.
SASHA: Oh, really?
What do you-- What do you
expect me, after all this time...
just to--just to jump on you?
Is that what you expect?
SEAN: That's not what I meant.
SASHA: What did you mean?
Is this what you meant? That? That?
How about this?
Is that good, huh?
[Telephone rings]
CASTER: Sean Archer.
POLLUX: Bro,
I figured he might drop in...
on some of our old friends.
And if my eyes don't deceive...
I think this fellow's
beginning to enjoy being you.
Good.
SEAN: Look, look,
OK, look, Sasha.
What I meant is, uh, that
I'm not going anywhere...
until your brother helps me, uh, first.
[Sighs]
Cas...
if the FBI finds out
that you were here...
I'll lose my son.
Please, Cas, you just gotta go.
I've said and done some things
that made your life harder.
I know.
SASHA: How would you?
You left and never looked back.
l-- l just know.
Look, Sasha, I'm not
the same person you remember.
And for what it's worth,
I'm sorry.
-Nice looking clothes.
-Of course. They're yours.
Look, l know, l-- just like 'em.
That's a nice looking kid, too.
Yeah, of course.
He's yours, too.
[Guns cocking]
How old is he?
SASHA: Five.
Nobody knows he's yours.
I was scared someone would try
to hurt him just to hurt you.
Adam! Adam!
Don't play with those things.
They are
very, very dangerous, OK?
Now, come on, sweetie.
I want you to meet your father.
Look at him. It's OK. Say hi.
ADAM: Hi.
SEAN: Hi.
Michael.
Michael, Michael.
SASHA: Cas.
Cas.
Cas, you're scaring him.
Let him go.
What is the matter with you?
SEAN: Get down!
[Screaming]
MAN: OK, red team,
red team, break off!
SEAN: How'd you get so brave?
[Machine-gun fire]
MEGAPHONE: Come out now
with your hands up!
SEAN: Put these on.
SASHA: That's a good idea.
Listen to your music.
Come on.
MUSIC: Somewhere...
MEGAPHONE: We have a warrant
for your arrest!
DIETRICH: Cops.
DIETRICH: I hate cops.
SEAN: Come on, kid.
MAN: Move! Move!
Go left, left! First door to the right!
Go! Go! Move!
Go! Go!
MUSIC:
Someday I'll wish upon a star.
SEAN: Let's get out of here!
Come on.
SEAN: Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Come on, move!
My place is getting fucked up!
[Laughing]
WOMAN: Aah!
SEAN: Take him.
DIETRICH: Cas! Cas!
Give me the boy!
SASHA: Really?! Really? Come on!
Shit!
SASHA: Come on, come on!
Let's go! Go, go, go!
SASHA: Be careful with him!
DIETRICH: Don't be scared, OK?
MUSIC: Somewhere...
over the rainbow...
skies are blue.
MUSIC: And the dreams
that you dare to dream...
really do come true.
Someday I'll wish upon a star...
and wake up
where the clouds are far...
behind me.
MUSIC:
Birds fly over the rainbow.
Why then, oh, why can't l?
SASHA: Adam!
Adam!
DIETRICH: Get them out back.
Go, go, go!
MAN: Put the boy down.
SASHA: Honey, sweetie,
don't touch that.
It isn't nice!
I never want to see you do that.
DIETRICH: Aha!
They're like cockroaches!
SEAN: Hey! Drop it.
That's it.
Buzz.
DIETRICH: Hey!
Told him not to fuck with me.
[Cocks gun]
DIETRICH: Take the boy and go.
SASHA: Are you all right?
DIETRICH: Go!
SASHA: Hurry up.
DIETRICH: Hey, man...
we had some good times,
didn't we?
Ohhh!
[Castor Sighs]
CASTOR: I don't know
what I hate wearing worse...
your face or your body.
I enjoy boning your wife,
but let's face it.
We both like it better
the other way, yes?
So why don't we just trade back?
SEAN: You can't give back
what you've taken from me.
Oh, well.
Plan "B."
Let's just Kill each other.
Aah!
Sir, why are you so upset?
It's just Pollux Troy.
KIMBERLY: Sir, look,
you're on the cover of Time.
Listen. "ln a single week,
Agent Archer has ordered...
"a stunning series
of blitzkrieg-style raids...
"on the hideouts, staging
grounds, and safe houses...
"of our nation's assassins--"
VICTOR: Look, we're friends,
so I'll tell you face-to-face.
I don't give a damn if you are
Time's Man of the Year.
After last night's bloodbath...
I'm terminating
your war on terrorists.
CASTOR: Is that because
I'm getting all the kudos...
and you're not?
VICTOR: I don't know
where you get your intelligence.
Not from field agents.
Sometimes I think
you know too much.
Washington's starting to worry.
Justice wants a hearing.
They're concerned
about the constitutionality...
of your Gestapo tactics,
and frankly so am l!
[Sighs]
CASTOR: Uh...
OK, Victor, I'll give
the taxpayers a break...
but, uh...
I have something
I want to confess...
and I don't think
you're gonna like it.
I am Castor Troy.
Ahh--
[Sighs]
CASTOR: Kimmy. Kim?
KIMBERLY: Yes, sir.
Call the paramedics.
Lazarro had a heart attack.
KIMBERLY: Oh, God. Right away.
CASTOR: Thank you.
[Shower running]
[Dog barking]
Home.
[Shower stops]
Eve.
No, honey, please don't scream.
Don't scream.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Please. Don't, don't. Shh.
Just don't look at my face.
And the voice, don't listen.
EVE: I know who you are!
You killed my son!
SEAN: I did not kill our son.
Shh.
I'm Sean.
The last time I saw you
was in this room.
We had a fight when I said
I had to go away again...
and I spent the night
in Mike's old bed.
I'm tired, Eve.
The assignment was...
to enter a federal prison
as Castor Troy.
It's just fucking insane!
And a Special Ops surgeon
gave me Castor's face!
And then somehow,
Castor came out of his...
his coma and killed everybody
who knew about the mission.
But not before
transforming into me.
[Glass breaks]
I know you don't believe a word
I'm saying.
Well, here's proof, Doctor.
Your husband--me--mine--
Sean's blood type is O-negative.
Castor's is AB.
And I love you.
[Door closes]
CASTOR: Get some backup.
What a day.
You look tense.
CASTOR: I know I've been acting
different lately, strange.
But I've got a confession
to make, Eve.
You're not gonna like it.
Oh, Eve, I feel...
I feel so close to you.
I read your diary.
I know I shouldn't have.
I'm ashamed.
But I did.
I just want to be the man
that you deserve--
passionate, tender.
Victor Lazarro died today.
He had a heart seizure.
My mentor--gone.
First Tito, then Victor.
So what?
I hope this doesn't mean
I'm losing you.
EVE: Of course not.
You're the only family I've got.
[Dog barking]
Oh, God.
Oh, Sean.
SEAN: I was hoping
you'd come here.
Thank you for trusting me.
EVE: Right now...
I don't trust anyone.
SEAN:
Eve, where'd you get that gun?
EVE: I took it
from my fake husband.
SEAN: Put it down.
You know I'm Sean.
EVE: Do l?
Maybe Sean's already dead, huh?
SEAN: I'm moving very slowly.
I was thinking the other day, l...
I remember...
I once took a date out
for surf and turf...
not knowing
she was a vegetarian.
So she ate bread...
and, uh, broke her tooth
on a rye seed.
And we drove around
all night...
Iooking
for an all-night dentist...
and he was so drunk,
he fixed the wrong tooth.
[Laughs]
And it... when I finally
brought her home...
even though
it must've hurt like hell...
you, you, kissed me.
Oh...
Sean...
EVE: That man...
You know we've been living together
as man and wife for a week.
Yeah, l... I know.
Eve...
I put you in that position...
and... and l... l... l can never
make it up to you.
Well, you're damn well gonna try.
Let me look at that wound
before you bleed to death.
SEAN: With Lazarro out of the way...
Castor's the new acting director
of the bureau.
He's untouchable.
EVE: Not tomorrow.
Tomorrow he'll be
at Victor's service.
SEAN: Tomorrow.
That will be the day.
I want you and Jamie
away from there.
Give him a good excuse.
I can cover for Jamie,
but if I'm not coming...
he'll know something's up.
Besides, I'm the only one who
can try and explain the truth.
WOMAN: Excuse me, Mr. Archer.
May l help you?
MAN: Dr Levine to X Ray.
Sean, what are you doing here?
CASTOR: I'm so...
sorry, darling.
I just get so jealous, I mean,
wh-wh-what is a guy to think...
when his wife runs off
in the middle of the night?
EVE: That I'm a doctor
that's on call.
So please let me
get back to work, OK?
CASTOR: Sorry.
CASTOR: Lies, distrust,
mixed messages.
This is turning
into a real marriage.
SEAN: How's Adam?
SASHA: I took him
over to my cousin's...
until this thing blows over.
CASTOR: Where's Jamie?
EVE: That's what I'm wondering.
She stole $50
from my purse and took off.
SASHA: So what's the next move?
SEAN: This isn't your fight.
EVE: Come on, you're surprised?
Our daughter won't even
visit Michael's grave.
Think she gives a damn
about your boss?
SASHA: He killed my brother.
I won't let him take you, too.
Whatever happens...
I promise...
Sean Archer is off your back
for good.
PRIEST: My dear friends...
we are here to celebrate
the life of Victor Lazarro.
[Speaking Latin]
Amen.
[Birds flapping]
PRIEST: Amen.
[Choir singing in Latin]
ALTAR BOY: Somebody back there
asked me to give this to you.
[Bird flapping]
PRIEST: In peace now, let us
take our brother Victor...
to his place of rest.
[Birds flapping]
CASTOR: Ohm..
[Chanting in fake Latin]
CASTOR: lsn't this religious?
Ah...
Ah, yes.
The eternal battle
between good and evil...
saint and sinner.
But you're still
not having any fun!
Ooh.
Honey.
Come here.
Ahh...
And guess what.
Your daughter's on the way.
History repeats itself.
This is between us.
Leave them out of it.
CASTOR: No. You should have
left them out of it.
Your son was an accident.
I wanted to kill you.
CASTOR: But you took it
so personally.
Why didn't you just
kill yourself or let it go?
No father could.
No brother could either.
SASHA: Neither could a sister.
Hey, baby.
Sasha, what the fuck
are you doing here?
Gee, Archer, I guess I'm crashing.
You OK, baby?
Yeah. Thanks.
Sasha, baby, I'm Castor.
That's Archer.
SASHA: And I'm bored.
[Sighs]
Put the fucking gun down.
MAN: Why don't you put your guns down.
Whee!
What a predicament.
[Laughs]
Take care of our boy.
I love him so much.
Don't let him grow up
to be like us. Promise?
Yeah.
SASHA: See ya.
Mom?
Aah!
JAMIE: Mom!
SEAN: Jamie!
JAMIE: Aah!
Jamie, don't!
Aah!
Hello, Wanda?
Wanda, this is Eve Archer.
I have something crazy
to tell you.
CASTOR: It's a capital crime
to attempt to kill...
the next boss of the FBI, yes?
SEAN: Yes.
CASTOR: Ah, yes.
SEAN: And the penalty?
CASTOR: What?
SEAN: The penalty is death!
SEAN: Die. Please, God, die.
JAMIE: Hold it!
CASTOR: Aah!
Good girl, Jamie. Shoot him.
SEAN: Don't listen to him.
He's not your father.
Hear my voice.
I'm your father.
CASTOR: Use your eyes.
Shoot him!
SEAN: Don't listen to him.
CASTOR: This scumbag
shot your brother. Kill him!
Aah!
Clod.
CASTOR: No daughter of mine
would shoot so wide.
CASTOR: Dad, put the gun down.
Put it down.
Dad...put it down.
Now we're gonna find out
what's in papa's bag...
Peaches.
Say good-bye to papa.
Aaahhh!
Jamie!
[Siren]
EVE: Jamie!
EVE: Are you all right? God!
Sir, are you OK?
[Siren]
JAMIE: Will someone please
tell me what planet I'm on?
SEAN: Get down! Move!
[Ship's horn honks]
Stop! This is the police!
Stop immediately or we will be
forced to open fire.
Fire! Fire!
SEAN: Oh, shit.
Aah!
CASTOR: You're right, Sean.
I've misbehaved.
I need to be punished.
But remember, every time
you look in the mirror...
you'll see my face.
Aah!
Die!
CASTOR: [Singing] Ready...
Ready for the big ride...
Baby.
[Sirens]
Off of Pico in the middle
of the street.
BUZZ: You OK, Archer?
What did you call me?
He called you Archer, sir.
EVE: Sean.
They're bringing in their top
surgical team from D.C.
You're going to be OK.
[Siren]
DOCTOR: When you wake up,
everything will be restored...
just the way it was.
My scar.
The one near my heart?
This old bullet wound...
I won't need it anymore.
DOCTOR: OK.
Dad?
I'm sorry I shot you.
I've got something
to ask both of you.
This is Adam.
And he needs a place to live.
JAMIE: Hi.
My name's Jamie.
I'm Adam.
SEAN: Why don't you show Adam
his new room?
JAMIE: Come on.
EVE: OK.
INXS: [Singing]
You shot your mouth off...
Iike a kid who's scared
to have a heart.
Losing grip
of what really matters...
'cause you don't know
where to start.
You wake up in the morning...
with a starfuck for a friend.
The things you do
are so in tune...
with what you're gonna hate.
What's giving you
the will to live?
Is it looking for revenge?
The only life
that you've got left...
is hiding from the pain.
What must have happened
to your soul...
is skinning you alive.
The thing
you fear the most is love...
and that's buried deep inside.
Yeah.
So deep inside.
Don't lose your head.
'Cause I can't do the time.
Or can you pay the price?
The heart you're building
out of rock...
is turning into sand.
'Cause you never
took the time to think...
what it means to be a man.
You act like you got
the answer...
when the question's
never asked.
I've been to where
you're coming from...
but the postcards
weren't so bad.
The knife I carry's
been sharpened...
on the mouths
that won't keep shut.
I'll stab at you
in the darkness...
'cause I'm trying
to shed some light.
Your point of view's
so meaningless...
if you ever had one at all.
All you seem to care about
is who's gonna take the fall.
Who's gonna take
the fall for you?
Don't lose your head.
I can't do the time for you.
Can you pay the price?
Yeah.
Mama.
Don't lose your head.
'Cause I can't do the time.
Can you pay the price?
Don't lose your head.
'Cause I can't do the time.
Can you pay the price?
Don't lose your head.
You can't do the time.
No, don't lose your head.
You cannot pay the price.
If you can't pay the price.
Don't lose your head.
You know I can't do the time.
You ain't worth it to me.
Subtitles by ARAVIND B
[by_agentsmith@yahoo.com]