'In the year 2000BC,
'there was born
to the reigning Pharaoh of Egypt a son.
'For many years, the Pharaoh Men-ta
had prayed to the gods
'for this blessing
that came so late in life.
'At last he had an heir.
'And as he presented the child
to his rejoicing people,
'he felt strong, proud and secure.
'Men-ta faced the future
with pride and contentment.
'Yet evil men had already sworn allegiance
to Men-ta's younger brother, Almen-ta,
'who saw in the child, Kah-to-Bey,
an end to all his hopes of accession.'
(Crowd cheers)
'Men-ta was too absorbed in his child
and all he portended for the future
'to be aware of the dark clouds
already gathering,
'yet as he offered a prayer of thanks
given to the gods,
'invoking their blessings
in the years to come,
'tragedy was already preparing to intrude.
'For as he turned from the cheering
crowds outside his palace,
'the cold finger of death was soon
to touch the heart of his beloved.
'In the presence of his dying queen,
'Men-ta named his child Kah-to-Bey,
the next Pharaoh.
'Silently, the attending physicians
watched the life that gave him his son
'flutter into oblivion.
'The head slave, Prem,
bowed his head with the rest in sorrow,
'sharing Pharaoh's grief.
'The young queen
had given Pharaoh his dearest wish,
'an heir to the throne of Egypt.
'So the people rejoiced.
They sang and danced in the streets,
'believing that the gods
were smiling upon them all.
'Year after year, Pharaoh watched
Kah-to-Bey grow towards manhood.
'He devoted every moment to the child
who was destined to succeed him.
'He lived only for his son.
'So engrossed was he in the future
'that the past and the present
became of no account.
'He was deaf to the warning voices
of his advisors.
'And while Men-ta dreamed,
'Almen-ta continued to scheme
against the throne.
'Soon he was exhorting his followers
to violence.
'His secret army grew
and, finally, struck.
'Men-ta and his guards
were hopelessly outnumbered.
'The slave Prem fought valiantly to
protect his beloved master, but in vain.
'Not one of the royal household
was to be left alive.
'This was Almen-ta's decree.
'But before the murderous onslaught
claimed the final toll,
'Men-ta exhorted Prem to try to escape
to the desert with the young prince.'
Prem! Take Kah-to-Bey!
Take him! Take him!
'These men were the sole survivors
of the holocaust.
'Like Prem, they were slaves, determined
to lay down their lives for their prince.
'Along the first few miles
of scorching desert sand,
'they were sustained in the belief
that Almen-ta's treachery
'might yet recoil upon him.
'Perhaps one day Kah-to-Bey
might return to his rightful place
'on the throne of Egypt.
'As they trudged on,
the slave Prem must have prayed
'for some future bloodbath
of vengeance.
'But the gods had laid their plans.
'Almen-ta was to rule many years
before he came to a traitor's death
'and Kah-to-Bey was not to live
to see the final overthrow.
'The slaves' faith in their leader Prem
never wavered.
'Prem would guide them
out of the desert wilderness.
'They never doubted him.
They would follow him into eternity.
'But they lacked provisions -
'very little water amongst them
'and practically no food.
'Gradually, the desert enclosed them.
'And, one by one,
they fell and perished.
'Overhead,
'death hovered.
'And waited.
'The gods seemed determined to reserve
their favours for the usurper, Almen-ta.
'As all hope started to fade,
'even Prem's massive strength
and resolve to save his young prince
'began to waver.'
(Wind howls)
‘In the teeth of fierce desert storms,
'the few survivors carried Kah-to-Bey
towards his last resting place.
'As he lay dying,
'Kah-to-Bey presented to Prem
'the royal seal of the Pharaohs.
'With reverence,
Prem covered his young master's body
'with the sacred shroud.
‘In the language of the Pharaohs
'Prem recorded the time and the place.'
‘In the year 1920,
'an expedition financed by a wealthy
industrialist, Stanley Preston,
'and led by the distinguished
archaeologist Sir Basil Walden
'set out to find the tomb of Kah-to-Bey.
'Their return to the base at Mezzara
was now more than a month overdue.
'Speculation as to their fate
became news headlines.'
- Ah, Mr Longbarrow...
- Please, gentlemen, not at the moment.
- Ah, Mr Preston.
- You're Longbarrow.
Yes, I saw you arrive.
I must apologise...
Hey, you boy. See to my luggage.
What's the number of my suite?
I’ve arranged all that. There is only
one suite available, Mr Preston,
- but I have secured it for you.
- How do you do, Mr Longbarrow?
- Why didn't you meet the boat?
- Your cable arrived half an hour ago.
- As you expressly desired...
- Mr Preston?
- Yes?
- Have you any news of the expedition?
- I’ve only just arrived from England.
- Our readers would like your view, sir.
- Your readers?
- I represent the Cairo Evening Sun.
Ah, well now, gentlemen,
you can tell your readers we are
most concerned about the expedition.
My own son Paul is, as you may know,
a member of Sir Basil’s party.
I came here to ascertain
what's being done to find them.
Isn't that so, Barbara?
- Yes, Stanley.
- Is your son an archaeologist, too, sir?
He is indeed. A very brilliant boy.
Oh, this is my wife.
How do you do?
I don't know whether you are aware, but
I’m holding a press conference tomorrow.
- Have you arranged that?
- 10 o'clock sharp.
- Sharp?
- I don't want you to be kept waiting.
- We just arrived. Where is it being held?
- At the Restoration House.
- The what?
- It’s a place of Sir Basil’s.
It’s where all the curios
and things he finds are brought...
- I see.
- ..to be sent to the museums.
Mr Preston, sir,
just one photograph, please?
Oh, right. My dear?
- Thank you, sir.
- Not at all.
See you tomorrow, gentlemen.
Where's this suite of ours?
Perhaps if you would allow me.
After you, Mrs Preston.
- I would like to make one point clear.
- Yes, Mr Preston, sir.
- I don't like being ignored.
- I can see that. Quite understandable.
My general impression is that the press
are more interested in Sir Basil Walden.
- We can very soon rectify that, sir.
- If you are my press representative,
you'd better improve on this guff
I’ve been reading back in England.
Without me, there is no expedition.
- I don't think you quite understand...
- I only understand results.
Oh.
Thank you very much.
- Hm, not as bad as I expected.
- I’m so glad it meets with your approval.
Very pleasant, Mr Longbarrow.
More light?
Oh, certainly, Mrs Preston, yes.
There is a good view from here.
You can see the desert quite plainly.
What about the bathroom?
I’m afraid there's no bathroom as such.
I’m sure there's a wash basin.
At least there should be.
Shall I ascertain?
Yes, there is a wash basin, Mr Preston.
I’m afraid there's no convenience.
So sorry, Mr Preston.
Did you, ah, have a nice journey,
Mrs Preston?
Quite pleasant, Mr Longbarrow.
Naturally, our thoughts are
with those poor men in the desert.
Our son Paul, Sir Basil, Harry Newton -
what a nice young man he is.
- Yes, indeed, isn't he?
- I hope and pray they're all right.
I’ve got £12,000 tied up in this
that says they've got to be all right.
And this young girl, Sir Basil’s
assistant. What's her name?
Claire de Sangre, Mrs Preston.
She goes on all his expeditions.
- They say she's a brilliant linguist.
- How many search parties are looking?
- Three, sir.
- Double that. Right away.
- Very good. It is siesta time...
- Don't give me any excuses.
Just you go and wake them up.
I intend to get things moving fast.
- Get along with you.
- Very good, sir.
Is there anything I can get for you,
Mrs Preston?
Yes, you can order me some beer.
Make sure it's cold.
Very good, sir.
- Anything you want?
- Nothing, Stanley.
Yes, you can see the desert from here.
How the devil did
that fool Walden get himself lost?
(Wind howls)
No chance of water from there, sir.
The sand's choked everything.
How long do you reckon, sir?
This? It could blow itself out
by the morning.
You can never tell in the desert.
I’ve given you all a rough journey.
Don't blame yourself.
We've had bad luck.
Uh-huh.
Can't put it all down to bad luck.
We started on the wrong day, according
to Claire. Friday the 13th, wasn't it?
I remember Claire mentioned it
at the time.
- Sorry.
- No, I should have listened to you.
But that's in the past.
What about the future, Claire?
- We've still got one?
- Of course we have!
- Well, Claire?
- We'll find the tomb. It’s not far away.
What makes you so sure?
It’s the same feeling I had
when I told you the porters would desert.
And the traders' route out of Mezzara.
Yes, you said that would disappear.
You were right.
Hope the Derby's on when we get back!
I’m taking Claire with me.
I could be wrong, Harry.
If my reckoning hadn't gone adrift, we
should be on the side of the tomb now.
I’ve been trying to work it out. Allowing
for compass error or the storm or both,
we can't be more than a few miles from it.
The question is shall we go on
or shall we try to find the oasis
we left three days ago?
We've got just enough water to get back.
It’s your decision, sir.
No, Paul, it's only fair to put it to you.
If we go on,
we go farther away from the water.
Well, I think we should take a chance.
Harry?
I’m gambling on Claire.
Having predicted the disasters, it'd be
a pity to miss her one ray of hope!
We're all agreed, then?
I know we'll find the tomb,
and we'll survive the desert.
Well, this calls for a celebration.
One mouthful of water each, my hearties!
But when the desert is behind us
begins the real danger.
And some of us won't survive.
As you know, gentlemen,
the primary object of this expedition
is to prove my theory that the mummified
figure wearing the seal of a pharaoh
is not that of Kah-to-Bey,
but that of Prem,
the slave who received the seal
from the young prince when he lay dying.
If we find his tomb, we shall have proved
a point that's been debated for 20 years.
We believe that this is not the mummy
of Kah-to-Bey, but that of Prem,
the slave who buried him and was himself
buried as a pharaoh wearing their seal.
Records that have only recently come
to light refer to the Rock of Death.
And close by, we believe,
lies the tomb of the real Pharaoh.
Well, gentlemen, I hope I’ve been able
to provide all the information you require.
- Thank you, sir. Most informative.
- Any questions?
How many parties are out searching
for Sir Basil, sir?
Three at the moment. Three more today.
I’m sparing no expense to find him.
- And you won't spare yourself either?
- How do you mean?
- You will join one of the search parties?
- Yes, Stanley, of course.
Of course.
Well, gentlemen, if that's all, good day.
Thank you, sir. I wish you a safe journey.
I’m sure we all do.
- Thank you. Longbarrow!
- Yes, Mr Preston, at your elbow, sir.
I shall be joining one of the expeditions.
- So I understood, sir.
- See that it's the best equipped.
- With the best guides.
- Naturally, Mr Preston. Of course.
(Wind howls)
(Wind drops)
I think it's finished!
Claire!
You were right, Claire.
We're not far away.
"At this place died
my beloved prince Kah-to-Bey."
- Can you go on, Claire?
- It gives the year.
But I can't read the rest.
Well, this is it!
Shall we leave everything?
Yes, yes.
Just bring the guns and the water.
We'd better take the lanterns.
Bring them will you, Claire?
The lanterns, Paul.
Aaargh!
(Snarls in ancient language)
(Speaks in Arabic)
All right, Paul.
What was he saying?
He says that death awaits all who disturb
the resting place of Kah-to-Bey.
That tomb must be pretty near.
Ask him where it is.
(ln Arabic)
(Rants)
He says he's the keeper of the tomb.
His name is Hasmid Ali.
He says why should he reveal
the whereabouts of the tomb to us
when he and his family have guarded
the secret for centuries? Well...
(Small rocks fall)
Can you decipher that, Claire?
"Rest in peace...
"..Kah-to-Bey,
"my beloved prince."
Ah!
Your knife, Harry! Quick, your knife!
- Get me out in the air.
- Yes, sir. Steady.
(Horse whinnies)
Harry?
- What is it?
- I’m not sure.
Do you think our friend back there
is bringing some of his chums?
It’s more than likely.
- Wait!
- Let's go this way!
It’s your father!
- Hello, Father!
- Paul, my boy! Thank God I found you!
I’d almost given you up. It’s a great
moment. Wonderful to see you, Harry.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks, sir.
(Longbarrow)
Pity it's too dark for a photograph!
We arrived none too soon.
What happened to you?
Get some food and drink.
- Yes, Mr Preston.
- Get moving, man!
- How did you find us, Father?
- I met your porters. They deserted you?
- Yes.
- Lucky they did! We collared a couple.
They showed us where you were heading.
Then we stumbled on your tent.
I don't think you've met.
Claire de Sangre, Sir Basil’s assistant.
- How do you do? Where is Walden?
- Over here.
I’m afraid we had a bit of bad luck.
- Sir Basil has had a serious snake bite.
- Really? Is this the site of the tomb?
- We can't be sure, but we think it is.
- Well, is it the site or isn't it?
- Ah, Walden. How are you feeling?
- Not too bad, thank you.
Got bitten by a snake, I hear.
What's all this mystery about the tomb?
It’s no mystery. We think we found it.
We can't be sure until we've excavated.
I’ll show you what Sir Basil means.
Only watch out for snakes!
Oh, well, you can explain it to me.
We don't want to leave Sir Basil.
- How long will it take?
- I can't say without a proper survey.
I imagine the rocks are pretty thick.
We may need small charges of dynamite.
- That means sending back to Mezzara.
- We'll manage without dynamite.
Start your survey at sun up.
My porters are equipped to hack through
any thickness of rock you name.
- They're bringing the food and drink.
- Stay with them, man! Hustle them along!
What are those men doing over there?
Tell them to unload the equipment!
Come along there!
(Preston) 'l started excavating
'on the 10th of July, 1920.
'From the outset, we realised the work
would be arduous and dangerous.
'The heat was fantastic
'in the dark, cramped quarters
in which we had to work.'
We slaved on
through the broiling heat of the day.
"..heat...
"of the day."
There was always danger
of mutiny among the porters.
Twice I had to hold them at gunpoint.
"..at...
"gun...point."
Well, where's the body?
I want you all to understand
what happened.
Normally, as you know, the tomb
of a Pharaoh bears the necropolis seal.
And the tomb itself is
very much more elaborate than this.
Now theory is merging with fact.
The slave Prem buried his master,
sealed the tomb with rock.
- It was the best he could do.
- Is there a body or isn't there?
If you will contain your impatience,
Mr Preston, until I’ve finished.
In this canopic chest,
we shall undoubtedly find the urns
containing the viscera of the Pharaoh.
- Viscera?
- The heart and intestines.
- Harry, is your camera ready?
- Almost there, sir.
I think we're going to find one of
the earliest forms of mummification.
When a pharaoh was entombed,
a keeper or guard was appointed.
This position was handed down
from generation to generation.
Perhaps in this instance the keeper was
the madman we met in the cavern.
Possibly.
Some of the guards were dedicated men,
but many of them were villains
who rifled the tombs
that they were supposed to guard.
Hasmid Ali may have
discovered the tomb himself
or the secret may have been
passed down to him by his family.
Whatever he thinks,
he certainly seems to regard himself
as the keeper of the tomb.
Preserved in sand for 4,000 years.
Fantastic!
As you say, Mr Preston...fantastic!
The shroud of Kah-to-Bey.
And now perhaps you'd be interested to
know the meaning of these hieroglyphics.
Claire, you're better at this than I.
Will you?
- I’m sorry! I can't read the words.
- What do you mean, you can't?
- You're the language expert, aren't you?
- It’d be wrong to read them, Mr Preston.
- Wrong and dangerous.
- Is she some superstitious crank?!
Claire, I don't understand.
What's your objection?
The words refer to the Spirit of the Tomb
and the sacred words of life and death.
- Spirit of the Tomb? Camera ready?
- Always, sir.
I want a photograph.
First the shroud, then the body.
Right. Quite still, sir.
Walden, I want to get these
back to Mezzara as soon as possible.
Prem, the devoted slave,
who buried his master, Kah-to-Bey.
It is fitting that they should be together
after all these centuries.
One likes to think
they have found each other
on some celestial plane
and are watching our humble effort
to give them their place in history.
(Voice echoes) ..their place in history.
(Reporter) It’s good to see you've kept
your sense of humour, Mr Preston.
Any questions, gentlemen?
I understand Sir Basil Walden was taken
ill. Can you tell us about his illness?
I’m afraid I can't. Sir Basil was bitten
by a snake on his journey to the tomb,
but appeared to have made
a good recovery.
But I understand he's suffered
poor health for a number of years.
I arranged for him to go into hospital.
We're doing all we can for him.
Mr Preston, it appears from what you've
told us that a great deal of the credit
for the safe return of the expedition
goes to you.
Hardly fair on Sir Basil, I think!
It’s true I was fortunate enough
to stumble on them, shall we say,
- when they were at their lowest ebb.
- So sorry, Mr Preston.
With the help of my son, I arranged
for the return of this sacred thing,
this relic of Ancient Egypt.
Together, we brought it back to Mezzara
so that Kah-to-Bey can take his place
in the history of this great country.
Mr Preston, is it true a curse might fall
on members of the expedition?
Wasn't there some sort of warning?
We're not worried, gentlemen.
Neither are we superstitious.
But there was a warning.
Explain that.
Explain it?
We had a job to do and I feel that
Sir Basil himself, when he recovers,
will be the first to admit that
we didn't acquit ourselves too badly.
No, indeed not, Mr Preston.
Will you excuse me, gentlemen?
Sir Basil must have been moved
from the hospital within an hour.
- How do you know that?
- I went back.
The superintendent was unavailable.
Nobody would tell me
where he's been taken to.
This is Chief Inspector Barrani. He says
Sir Basil has been removed to an asylum.
The Mezzara lunatic asylum.
I propose to leave this day week.
Get Paul to help crate up
the mummy and the shroud.
- We can ship them out at the same time.
- We shall need a police licence, sir.
- Arrange it. It shouldn't be difficult.
- (Knock at door)
Come in.
Ah, Paul, come in, my boy. Have a drink.
Longbarrow, give him a drink.
- No, thank you. I’d like a word, Father.
- Any time, my boy, any time.
- Alone, if you don't mind.
- You have work to do. Get on with it.
Yes. Excuse me.
- Do you want me to go, Paul?
- No, that's all right, Mother.
- Sure you won't join me?
- Yes, quite sure, thank you.
That press conference went well.
- Very well, yes.
- What is it, Paul?
When did you first learn
Sir Basil had been sent to an asylum?
When? When your mother told us.
- Frankly, I’m not surprised.
- You're not surprised?
I must say, he behaved very strangely
on that return journey.
Of course,
he was in poor physical shape.
That may have caused
mental derangement.
It’s up to the authorities to decide
on the correct treatment. Not for us.
Who sent him there, Father?
Why, the hospital authorities,
I suppose.
- Did you send him?
- Look here!
Sir Basil is as sane as you or I! Someone
must have bribed the authorities. You?
Paul, we've always been very close,
but that doesn't mean
you can level these sort of accusations.
- There's no truth in what I’m saying?
- You are talking to your father.
If you're subjecting me to this
cross-examination, you'd better leave.
You wanted him out of the way. You hated
the idea of him stealing your thunder.
I’ve watched you taking
every advantage of his illness,
stealing credit for his work,
lying to the press and singing your own
praises so we're sick with embarrassment!
- How dare you!
- It’s sheer persecution of a sick man!
- And a great man.
- Oh, I know he's a hero of yours.
He certainly is!
And now he's out of the way,
your own star can shine more brightly.
Good old Preston. He saved the expedition
and found the mummy of Kah-to-Bey.
- Three cheers! Give him a knighthood!
- Get out!
He hasn't got your millions,
but he's worth ten of you.
Paul, please go.
Yes, I’m going to the asylum and
somehow I’m going to get him out of there.
That won't be necessary, Mr Preston.
I have to inform you that Sir Basil Walden
escaped from the asylum half an hour ago.
If he returns to the hotel,
I expect you to inform me.
Good night, gentlemen.
Inspector!
There's been a terrible mistake.
- This should never have happened.
- That is hardly my concern, Mr Preston.
- Your men are searching for him now?
- They are indeed.
- And if they find him?
- Escapees are treated as criminals.
It is necessary, you understand,
for the safety of the community.
- What will happen to him?
- That will depend on his behaviour.
- If he is violent, he may be shot.
- He won't be violent! He's a sick man!
In that case, he has nothing to fear.
- I will contact you when he is caught.
- Can I help you look for him now?
No, Mr Preston. This is a matter for
the police. I advise you to stay here.
I shall be in my room.
Any messages, contact me immediately.
I don't care how late it is. Immediately.
- You heard all that?
- Yes, everything.
Oh, Paul, how can we help him?
(Breathes heavily)
(Whispers) This way, quick. I help you.
I help you. Quick, quick.
(Bird caws)
Come. Come in.
Come in. Ah ha ha.
Come, come. Come.
Sit down.
Hee hee, sit down.
Ah ha ha!
You are Sir Basil Walden.
I am Haiti. I tell your fortune.
Haiti's the greatest fortune teller
in the whole of Egypt.
I look into the crystal so.
I see death.
You are going to die very soon.
But not the way you think.
Let me rest. Please...
- Give me somewhere to rest.
- You will soon be dead.
Then you can rest.
Death can be sweet.
Sweet death. I pray for it
because I am old and tired.
You pray because you are sick.
There is nothing left for you
but death.
My son, Hasmid.
Your son...
He will attend you.
The Spirit of the Tomb
will journey from death into life.
He will punish you
for what you have done him.
And one by one
the others will follow you.
It is in the crystal!
Help me, please...
It is in the crystal.
Soon the Spirit will move.
I see him now.
He is dead,
but he has the power to move.
And kill.
(Speaks in ancient language)
Death is coming.
Prepare yourself for death.
(Snapping sound)
Aaaargh! Aaargh!
(Sings quietly to himself)
Aaargh!
Aaaargh!
This is terrible news, Chief Inspector.
Terrible.
Yes, Mr Preston.
I imagined you would be very upset.
- Any idea who could have done it?
- No, I have no idea, Mr Preston.
As a formality, I shall have to ask you
to identify the body.
I’m afraid it is not a pleasant sight.
Well, Mr Preston?
It is Sir Basil, yes.
Who could have done it?
I suspect nobody at the moment. I was
hoping that you might be able to help me.
I? I have no idea.
- Your son perhaps?
- No, Inspector.
Are you aware of any enemies
Sir Basil might have had?
- Someone with a grudge perhaps?
- Nobody, no.
Strangely enough, the murder coincides
with the loss of the shroud
covering the body of Kah-to-Bey.
- The sacred shroud? It’s been stolen?
- It is not there.
The caretaker and the sweeper
have both been questioned.
Neither of them has even noticed
its absence.
Is there any connection between
the murder of Sir Basil and this?
Who can tell? You are returning
to your hotel, gentlemen?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
I shall be able to find you
if I want you.
- Good day, gentlemen.
- Good day.
A terrible thing. Quite terrible...
Have you made arrangements
for crating the mummy?
Yes, Mr Preston. I contacted the local
undertaker, a very excellent man. He's...
Good. We may be leaving earlier
than I thought.
I think there's a boat leaving
tomorrow night.
- Find out about available passages.
- Very well, Mr Preston.
I suppose
you've broken the news to Claire?
Yes, I did, but I thought I’d spare her
the ordeal of coming with us.
And you're blaming me, aren't you?
Yes, I’m afraid I am.
Why don't you accuse me of
murdering him and have done with it?
- I’m not accusing you of anything.
- Thank you.
But I don't see why you're so anxious
to leave Mezzara.
Sir Basil was virtually an employee
of yours and he's been murdered.
- You should stay and help the police.
- I don't need your advice!
- You saw him?
- Yes.
Barbara, I want you to pack your things.
We're getting out.
There's no point in remaining here
any longer.
I see. Do you feel
some kind of premonition?
- What do you mean?
- Do you?
- How long have we been married?
- 26 years.
Have I once given you the impression
that I’m subject to premonitions?
No, I don't think you were ever one
to indulge yourself in that way.
I was thinking of that strange man
they found in the tomb before you arrived
and his warning of disaster
to whoever violated the tomb.
- (Knock at door)
- Yes?
I trust you will pardon this intrusion,
Mr Preston... Mrs Preston.
What is it, Inspector?
Until I have finished my investigations,
I must request you to remain in Mezzara.
Why?
I may wish to call upon you
for further information.
I’ve told you all I know. As far
as I’m aware, Sir Basil had no enemies.
In my opinion,
this is the work of some local fanatic.
Fanatic? Why do you say that,
Mr Preston?
I’m using the term loosely.
Some maniac without motive or reason.
In any case, I must insist
on my rights as a British citizen.
I intend to leave as soon
as I can arrange a suitable passage.
In that case, I’m afraid you will become
the guests of the police department.
And in this event, I should warn you
that our prisons are not exactly
what I would choose for a holiday.
Perhaps you will be good enough
to reconsider your position.
Thank you, Mr Preston.
Good day.
It’s insufferable!
- What are you afraid of?
- I’m not afraid.
I’m merely concerned for the welfare
of the people in my charge.
- That includes you.
- That's very kind of you, Stanley.
But I don't really think you need
concern yourself on my account.
You see, I did not enter the tomb.
Harry, didn't you take a photograph
of the shroud when it was uncovered?
- Yes.
- Did you develop it?
- Yes, but I haven't run off a print.
- Could I see the negative?
Well, certainly. It’s in my hotel room.
Do you want to see it now?
- Yes, please.
- All right.
(Man shouts in Arabic)
Oh, there you are.
- Would you make a print, Harry?
- Yes, certainly.
I want to examine the hieroglyphics
in detail.
I have a feeling the shroud may hold
the key to Sir Basil’s murder.
When we first saw the shroud, Sir Basil
asked you to decipher the hieroglyphics.
Yes.
You said they referred
to the spirit of the tomb
and the sacred words of life and death,
but to repeat them might be dangerous.
Do you still think so?
Yes, they seem to imbue whoever uttered
them with some strange, mystical power.
I had the feeling
that if I spoke the words,
I would be animating some horrible thing
that might be uncontrollable.
- To bring something to life?
- Yes, and also to destroy.
I think we ought to remind ourselves
we're living in the 20th century.
On the other hand...
Yes?
Last night, just as I was packing up,
I looked through the window.
I thought it was my imagination
and at the time, I dismissed it.
But now I wonder...
(Paul) Go on.
I thought I saw the huge shadow
of a man walking in the alleyway.
If my imagination wasn't
playing me a trick...
(Bird squawks)
(Speaks in ancient language)
(Continues in ancient language)
(Carriage rolls by)
Aaargh!
Aaaargh!
Aargh!
Aargh, aargh, aargh!
- What's the latest news on the murder?
- Sorry, I’ve nothing to say.
Was Mr Newton present
for the opening of the tomb?
I can't answer any questions.
- Has Mr Preston heard the news?
- I’m about to tell him.
Is there a connection
between these murders?
Please, I’ve been very co-operative.
But I cannot speak
on Mr Preston's behalf. Excuse me.
It is terrible, Mr Preston.
Really terrible, sir.
What is it?
- Poor boy. How dreadful!
- We're getting out.
- But...
- Don't argue. We're getting out.
- In spite of our instructions?
- In spite of everything.
Do you think I’ll wait on some murdering
swine to get at me? Start packing.
Longbarrow, go down to the shipping
office and book the passages.
- Yes, sir.
- What about Paul and Claire?
- Longbarrow can book for them, too.
- Immediately.
- Mr Preston?
- Yes?
- What about me, sir?
- What about you?
Are you going to take me with you, sir?
All right. You can book a passage
for yourself as well.
Thank you, Mr Preston. I shall be very
glad to leave under the circumstances.
Also, it will be nice to see
the shady lanes, the old country again.
It’s been a very long time for me,
Mr Preston.
I... I must thank you
for your kindness in taking me.
- For heaven's sake, get out!
- Yes, sir.
Longbarrow,
there's no need to come back.
I’ll meet you down at the landing stage.
If we are lucky,
we can ship out immediately.
Barbara, tell Paul and the girl.
We must all leave here separately.
What about my few little things, sir?
- I’ll send your luggage on after you.
- Thank you, Mr Preston.
I told you to start packing.
I’m not going. Not until I know that
Paul and Claire are coming with us.
They can please themselves!
(Distant chanting of prayer)
Oh, Mr Longbarrow!
You must excuse me, Mr Paul.
I’m on an urgent errand for your father.
- What is it?
- Strictly between ourselves, sir...
Yes?
We're going back to England. All of us.
I’m so excited,
I...I can't stop trembling.
But we must be most discreet.
I’m just going to book the passages.
- No, not for me.
- Not, sir?
- Don't book a passage for me.
- Why not, sir?
Nor for Claire. Do you understand?
Oh, yes, sir.
I thought he'd do something like this.
- I’m going to have a word with him.
- I’ll be back in a moment.
- Father, I’ve just seen Longbarrow.
- What about Longbarrow?
I’ve told him not to book a passage
for myself or Claire.
That's your business. Your mother's
staying, too. You're in good company.
We're not doing ourselves any good
by running away.
What do you mean?
Someone or...or something
is trying to destroy us.
I believe it will find us wherever we go.
What do you mean by "something"?
We're dealing with a maniac.
Once we're out of this country,
we're free.
Do you honestly believe that?
Are you suggesting these murders
have something to do with the tomb?
I don't know.
Even the police are baffled.
But incredible as it may seem,
it's all we've got to work on.
You must be out of your mind.
You and your mother.
You're a fine pair, I must say!
Very well, Paul. Do what you like.
(Distant shouting and arguing)
My keys, please.
(Telephone rings)
Yes, Mr Preston. Very good, Mr Preston.
It’s no good.
He's still determined to leave.
It’s too late. I’ve just seen Inspector
Barrani talk to Longbarrow and I think...
Mr Longbarrow has
reluctantly informed me
that members of your party
intend to leave.
- Does this include yourselves?
- No, Inspector.
Your father perhaps?
- Inspector...
- One moment, please, Mr Preston.
I’m sorry.
The police have been asking me...
- You remember my instructions?
- Yes, I remember.
- May I have a word with you, Inspector?
- Certainly.
In private, please.
Look, Inspector,
with the greatest respect,
don't you think your insistence on keeping
us here may be endangering all our lives?
I have not yet come
to that conclusion, Mr Preston.
Two of your party
have been murdered.
I see no reason to suppose
there will be a third.
- Then what's the point in making us stay?
- I told you the point yesterday.
If I did not make it clear then,
I see no purpose in repeating it now.
Inspector, before leaving here,
I had every intention of writing out
a cheque for, say, £10,000?
If you will do me the honour of accepting
it, I will hand it to you personally
to be paid, at your discretion,
of course, to some good cause.
You are very persistent,
aren't you, Mr Preston?
- Don't for a moment see this as a bribe.
- I am trying very hard not to.
Think of it merely
as a gesture of goodwill.
Now, what do you say, Inspector?
Mr Preston, I think you must
begin to understand me.
I am not the hospital superintendent.
I must insist on your word
that none of you will attempt to
leave here until I give you permission.
Do I have your word?
- Very well.
- I will accept that.
I shall also want to interview you
later today.
Please be good enough to remain
in the hotel until I send for you.
- Longbarrow!
- Yes, Mr Preston.
- Damn, damn, damn.
- What happened?
I was prevented from leaving
by that blasted policeman!
- I’m sorry.
- Why do you say that?
I only mean I’m sorry
you didn't get your own way.
I know how you suffer
when this happens to you.
You must think I’ve let you down,
but they kept on firing questions at me.
And I lost my head. I’m not very good
at subterfuge, Mr Preston.
I’m wondering what you ARE good at.
I’ll give you one last chance
to prove you're not such an idiot.
Go down to that shipping office
and book me one passage, first boat out.
- We have been told very definitely...
- I know what we've been told.
Just do as I say. If you come back
without that booking, you're fired.
- Do you want me to go now, sir?
- No.
How late does the shipping office
stay open?
- Until eight o'clock.
- Go at 7.30. It should be dark by then.
If the police are watching the hotel,
slip out by the rear entrance.
Yes. It will be dark by then. I’ll...
Yes?
No, Mr Preston, I’ll talk to you later
when I get back.
Are you no longer going
to take me with you, sir?
No.
Oh.
Well, I...
I can't pretend that I’m not disappointed,
but I’m sure you know best.
If there is a ship
first thing in the morning,
they like the passengers
to be on board by midnight, sir.
Very well. Telephone me
as soon as you've booked the passage.
Yes, sir.
Why are you looking at me like that?
- I’m sorry. How was I looking at you?
- Accusingly.
What is there to accuse you of?
Is it your conscience?
No, I wasn't looking at you
in any particular way.
I was only wondering what it feels like
to have bought everything,
except the freedom
to come and go as you please.
And the ability to conquer fear.
Are you trying to frighten me?
I don't have to. And I’m sorry.
I really am sorry.
You will be returning to the hotel,
Mr Preston?
Yes, Inspector.
I presume you will wish to take charge
of Mr Newton's personal effects,
what remains of them?
- Yes, please.
- I will return them to you
as soon as I have had the opportunity
of examining them.
Inspector, have you any...?
I have no more idea than you,
Mr Preston.
No more and perhaps no less.
(Snoring)
(Alarm goes off)
Where...where's my glasses?
Where are they then?
(Loud snap)
Oh, dear!
Oh...
Oh, what a terrible thing to do!
Oh, dear!
I... Oh!
Oh, oh... Oh, dear.
Oh, my... Oh...
I’ll get those damn tickets!
I won't forget them.
Certainly not.
Excuse me. I’m...
Aaaargh!
Help me! Help me, somebody!
Help me!
Aaargh!
How long is he going to be?
- Sure you won't change your mind?
- Quite sure.
Don't worry about me. I’ll be all right.
I only hope you'll be able to get
to the boat and have a safe journey.
Don't forget you have to be
on board by midnight.
(Squawking)
- I must go. If I wait any longer...
- I understand.
As soon as I get back,
I’ll see about getting you out of here.
Yes.
- Well, Barbara...
- Goodbye.
- You have sufficient money, I think.
- Yes.
- Barbara, I...
- Yes?
Nothing.
- Do you want a gharry, effendi?
- There doesn't seem to be any about.
- Can you get me one?
- Yes, my brother drives a gharry.
He lives only two minutes from here.
I’ll get him for you, effendi. You wait.
I have to get to the landing stage.
I’ll give him £10 if he hurries.
I don't think my brother would accept 10.
He would want £20, effendi.
£20? Daylight robbery!
It is night time.
My brother does not like to work at night.
He has three wives who keep him
very busy. Did you say £20, effendi?
It can't be more than two miles,
the landing stage.
Oh, all right. £5 now,
the rest when he gets me to the boat.
Tell him to hurry.
I have to be on board by midnight.
Very good, effendi.
(Distant horn blows)
(Horn blows)
(Squawks)
(Speaks in ancient language)
(Continues in ancient language)
(Chuckles to herself)
(Clatter of hooves approaching)
(Sound becomes more distant)
(Loud miaow)
Aargh!
Aaargh!
No gharry, effendi.
As a police officer,
I can answer only to logic.
But as a man, I admit to many things
which are beyond my comprehension.
Do you mean supernatural things?
Perhaps. Who can tell?
Some people have seen ghosts,
so they say.
It has never been proved
that there are such things,
yet who can positively deny
their existence?
Some people believe in a blessing
from a priest or a curse from a witch.
Do you?
Yes.
We in Egypt have known
many tragedies
which have been attributed
for want of a logical cause
to the curse of the Pharaohs.
It is impossible for me
to disbelieve in these things.
There are now four dead people who are
beginning to gnaw at my conscience
and each of them entered
the tomb of Kah-to-Bey.
You three are the only ones left alive
and two of you entered the tomb
like the others.
I have no desire to risk your lives.
You are free to leave Mezzara.
I will say goodbye.
And may Allah go with you.
May I advise you as a friend to embark
at the earliest possible moment.
Well, Paul?
Running away isn't the answer.
I still believe that.
The sacred words of life and death.
Somewhere there must be a connection
between these words
and the spirit of the tomb.
There was also the keeper of the tomb,
this madman. What was he called?
Hasmid Ali.
Yes, he threatened us.
He warned us what would happen if
we disturbed the Prince's resting place.
According to Ancient Egyptology,
the keeper of the tomb has the power
to summon up the great spirit
to enact vengeance.
Who is the great spirit?
I think I know. Claire!
Claire!
When she comes back, keep her here.
Don't let her out of your sight.
(Squawking)
Oh, come in, come in.
Do not be afraid. Come in.
Come.
Sit down, please.
Some terrible things have
happened to friends of mine.
I want to know why they have happened
and who is responsible. Can you help me?
Four of your friends...have died.
- Yes.
- You want to know why?
Yes.
The crystal tells me
they have desecrated
the tomb of Kah-to-Bey.
- You wish to know more?
- Yes.
There are two other people.
You are one of them.
I entered the tomb.
I see in the crystal...
Yes, tell me.
It is too horrible.
You mean I’m going to die?
In a few minutes from now!
(Haiti laughs)
If you listen to me,
I may be able to save you.
But sit down first.
(Speaks in ancient language)
Those are the sacred words of death.
The ones you were afraid to utter.
How can these words have had
such power over the spirit of the tomb?
Go to the restoration house
and you will find the answer.
But first you will confront
the mummy of the slave Prem.
You will ask his forgiveness
for what you have done.
You will say to him...
"Oh, noble Prem,
sacred spirit of the tomb,
"I pray your forgiveness
"for my transgressions
against Kah-to-Bey
"and the desecration
of his resting place
"of which I am profoundly guilty."
Now say it in the language
of the Pharaohs.
(Speaks in ancient language)
(Continues in ancient language)
(Man replies in ancient language)
(Continues shouting)
Aaargh!
Kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
Claire! The words of death, say them!
Say them!
For God's sake, say them!
(Speaks in ancient language)
Only he who holds the shroud has
the power to destroy.
Quick! Take it!
Now, say the words!
(Speaks in ancient language)