(Groans)
(Drum beats)
Kada nostra, kada estra.
(Whispers) Kada nostra..
...kada estra.
Kada nostra...
(Drum beats)
(Drum beats intensify)
(Screams)
- Good morning, Father.
- Good morning, my dear.
- Oh, careful.
- Eh?
Oh, I'm sorry. You should know better
than to barge in here when I'm busy.
- Busy?
- Now, none of that.
When I'm on holiday
this is what keeps me busy.
- Mail, Father.
- I don't want to read it.
- There's a letter from Cornwall.
- I don't know anyone in Cornwall.
Yes, you do. Peter Tompson.
I'll open it.
Oh, Peter.
What's he doing down there?
Oh, Father, you're impossible.
You know he's got a job down there.
He's General Practitioner.
So he did.
What's he up to, then?
Well, why don't you read it
and find out?
- No, you read it.
- All right.
Ah...ah...ah...ah!
"Dear Sir James..."
A typical doctor's handwriting.
it's worse than yours, Father.
Oh, here. Give it to me.
Hm. "Just a brief line to inform you...
"For some time our village has been...
"beset by a number
of mysterious and fatal maladies.
"People have been dying off...
“Lassitude, no will to live...”
Well, this doesn't sound like Peter.
it's very rambling.
I wonder what's it's all about.
Well, we could easily find out.
"l desperately need your advice.
Symptoms can't be attributed to..."
- Find out? How?
- By going to Cornwall and asking him.
Go to Cornwall?
it's miles away.
Well, you can fish just as well
in Cornwall as here, Father.
Didn't your school friend...
What's her name?
Didn't she marry young Tompson?
- Alice? Mm.
- Ha.
I suppose your suggestion
that we should go to Cornwall
has nothing to do with the fact
that you'd like to see her again, eh?
Shall I pack your things?
I don't know why
I give in to you so easily.
And look up the train times.
I don't know why
I put up with you at all.
- I should have drowned you at birth.
- Thank you, Father.
I knew you'd understand.
- Come on, then. Come on, then.
- Whoo!
Oh, look, Father!
Look! A fox!
I've seen a fox.
Several of them, in fact.
I've no doubt your fox
looks very similar to all the others.
(Shouting)
Oh, they're hunting him!
Father, those men
are hunting that fox.
Men have always hunted.
For food, yes. Not for blood lust.
Well, can't you do something, Father?
I have not come all this way
to interfere with local customs
and antagonise the people
just to satisfy your sensitivity
about the welfare of wild animals.
Father, you must agree that...
Just because you are my daughter
doesn't mean I have to agree to...
(Coach man) Whoa, there!
Now what's happened?
- You, have you seen him?
- (Coachman) Who, sir?
- The fox, you idiot!
- No, I haven't, young sir.
I've been keeping
my eyes on the road.
Idiot!
Is it a fox you're looking for?
Well, my dear young lady,
that was the idea.
I saw him.
He was running that way.
You'll have to hurry to catch him.
He was running fast.
We'll catch him.
Never fear. Come on.
I have a distinct feeling you were not
telling that young man the truth, Sylvia.
Your distinct feeling is correct, Father.
Oh. Well, the fox will be grateful.
I doubt if the same can be said
for the young man.
I only hope you don't meet him again.
(Bell tolling)
- What is it, Sylvia?
- A funeral.
(Bell continues tolling)
(Horses approaching)
Come on!
- Come on then. Whoa!
- (Man screams)
(Dog barks)
Oh!
What the devil
do you think you're doing?
So the fox went that way, did it?
You'd better stay out of my sight,
young lady!
(Dog barks)
How horrible.
They should be reported.
I expect they will be, my dear.
And no doubt those your ruffians
will say it was an accident.
- Is there anything we can do, Vicar?
- Yeah, you can keep away from us.
Please, it was not our fault!
Leave us alone!
- But surely...
- I said leave us alone!
I know it wasn't your fault, my dear.
That was the poor lad's brother
in the coffin.
The Lord is punishing us
for our sins.
(Coachman) Whoa!
Oh, put the bags down there,
please, Coachman.
I'm sorry. The doctor isn't in.
- Alice?
- Who is it?
Alice, don't you remember me?
- Sylvia?
- Yes!
Oh, Sir James.
What a wonderful surprise.
Why didn't you let me know?
Well, come in.
Do come in.
Thank you.
- When did you arrive?
- We got here about half an hour ago.
Well, it’s nice seeing you again
Mrs Tompson.
- Oh, Father, call her Alice.
- Yes, please do.
Very well, Alice.
Hello, what's this?
It's nothing. it's just a cut.
- Well, I hope you're taking care of it.
- Oh, don't fuss so much.
Well, you can't be too careful
about these things.
Would you like me
to have a look at it?
It's all right.
My husband is a doctor.
Ah, yes. So they tell me.
- He is a very good doctor.
- Father is only joking, Alice.
Peter was his favourite pupil,
remember?
- Now, let me have a good look at you.
- No!
No, please don’t. I...
I look so untidy
Well, I don't know about that,
but you don't look too well to me.
- Are you eating enough?
- Oh, Father, really!
Don't take any notice of him, Alice.
Oh, why didn't you let me know
you were coming?
I'm so sorry.
You must think me very inhospitable.
No, not at all, my dear.
If it's inconvenient
we can always stay at the inn.
Oh, no. I wouldn't dream of it.
Of course you'll stay here.
It's just that I...
Well, the house isn't very clean.
Can I get you something?
Some tea?
We'd both love some.
Come on.
Kettle won't be a moment.
Hm. I suppose
there isn't anything stronger, is there?
Well, I'll ask,
but I don't expect...
Oh, don't worry.
I'll slip out later.
Well, where's that husband of yours?
Out on his rounds?
Yes, I expect so.
- Plenty of patients?
- Not as many as we'd like.
Oh, really?
There's been a lot of trouble.
What sort of trouble?
Oh, I...
I expect Peter would rather tell you
about it himself.
I'll see to the kettle. Excuse me.
You go and have a gossip
about your old school days.
I'll slip into the village
and see what I can find out.
All right, Father. Don't be long.
- Charlie.
- Aye, aye.
Will you have
a drink with me, Martinus?
Thank you, but I'll buy my own.
Beer, Tom.
I... I did my best for him.
I'm sorry.
- Wasn't good enough, was it?
- Apparently not.
What do you think it were, Doctor?
- That killed him?
- Aye, that killed him.
What was it that killed them all?
I don't know.
You don't know.
And you call yourself a doctor?
You won't let me find out.
If you let me carry out one post mortem.
It's no good cutting him up
after he's dead. It's too late.
- You're being ridiculous
- Ridiculous is it?
There's my brother lying dead
out there.
And twelve others like him. Twelve.
How long have you
been with us, Doctor?
Twelve months, isn't it?
That's one a month.
- Steady, Tom
- One a month.
Not a very good record, is it?
Are you trying to say
no one died before I came here?
At least we knew what they died from.
And if I was to tell you they died
from swamp fever or the plague
or some other nonsense,
would that make you happier?
- Yes, if it were the truth.
- Well, it wouldn't be the truth.
I'm not going to start telling
a lot of ridiculous lies
just to keep you people satisfied.
It's not good enough.
Oh, so we are not good enough
for you now?
- I didn't say that.
- it's what you meant, though.
Well, let me tell you something, Doctor.
You're not good enough for us.
Do you understand me?
You're not good enough!
- Ah, Doctor, there you are.
- Sir James!
- Good afternoon, gentlemen.
- (All) Good afternoon.
We've met before
in rather distressing circumstances.
May I now introduce myself?
Sir James Forbes, Professor
of Medicine at London University.
And this young man was
my cleverest and most able pupil.
I hope you realise
how lucky you are to have him here.
Landlord, see these gentlemen
have a drink with me, will you?
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Come on, Peter,
are you ready?
- Good afternoon, gentlemen.
- (All) Good afternoon.
- Sir James, what are you doing here?
- You've lost weight, my boy.
- Alice not feeding you properly?
- Yes, but...
- Aren't you glad to see me?
- You've no idea.
- Why have you come?
- You wrote to me.
It's very kind of you
to come all this way, sir.
I've just seen Alice.
She's not looking well.
Poor Alice.
I'm afraid she needs a holiday badly.
- You both do, by the look of you.
- Can't manage one at the moment, sir.
- You've no idea what it's been like.
- Well, we'll talk about it later,
without any of this hocus pocus
you put in your letter.
Ah!
That was an excellent meal.
You girls are to be congratulated,
eh, Peter?
Oh, yes, Sir James. Indeed.
Still, what I always say is,
cooking is a science and not an art.
If you get it right once
there's no earthly reason
why you shouldn't get it right every time.
Now, you girls run along to bed.
Peter and I will do the dishes
- But, Father, you can't...
- But Father, nothing.
You've had a long day
and I'm sure Alice is tired.
Yes, I am tired, it's true.
Good night, Peter. Father.
Good night, my dear.
It's so nice to see you again, Sir James.
Thank you, my dear.
it's nice to see you, too.
For you, Sir James?
No, thank you.
That's not the answer,
you know, Peter.
I know.
I wish I knew the answer.
First of all, we have to decide
what the question is, don't we?
This disease seems to be
more mental than physical.
Yes, but you were
a little obscure, Peter.
You said there was no attributable
cause for this mental affliction.
I'd like to Know a little more
about the symptoms.
- What about appetite?
- The patient show a loss of appetite.
Skin colour?
In every case a loss of skin colour, too.
- Reflexes?
- Retarding
Hm, like someone
in need of a holiday in fact, eh?
- You don't mean Alice, surely?
- Now, now, now.
Don't let's jump to any conclusions.
- What did the autopsies show?
- I didn't make any.
You didn't make any?
What's come over you?
It is not permitted to make any.
- Well, who stopped you?
- The villagers.
They don't want the bodies
of their love ones cut about.
What about the coroner?
Surely he supported your applications?
- There isn't one.
- No coroner?
This isn't London, sir.
This is a Cornish village,
inhabited by simple country people
riddled with superstition
and all dominated by a Squire.
He acts as coroner and magistrate,
judge and jury.
And who is this jack of all trades?
Hamilton, sir. Squire Hamilton.
Master?
Tonight. Tell the others.
They are not back
from the chase, Master.
Tell them to prepare
just as soon as they return.
I do hope you meet him, Sylvia.
He's such a charming man.
- Is he now?
- And so handsome.
- And rich.
- And unattached?
Yes. Yes, he is, as a matter of fact.
You're not trying to marry me off
by any chance?
Well, you could do a great deal worse.
He's got a lovely house
and a lot of money.
And what does Peter think?
He doesn't like him.
He thinks he's arrogant
and overbearing.
But he's wrong. He is wrong.
- Good night.
- Alice.
You're trying to tell me something else,
aren't you?
No!
No, I'm not, but I...
- I must go.
- What did you say his name was again?
Clive Hamilton.
Goodnight, Sylvia.
(Plate breaks)
I'm sorry.
Don't apologise to me, dear boy.
It's your Crockery.
Here, you'd better let me do the drying.
- I really do need a drink.
- Rubbish.
What you need
is an end to your worries.
So far we've nothing to start on,
nothing to help us at all.
I know.
We must have a body to examine.
We can't possibly work without one.
If you’re thinking
of applying for an exhumation...
Apply for nothing.
We'll dig one up.
- We'll what?
- Dig one up.
That lad they buried today will do.
Nice and fresh.
Then we might learn something.
- But we can’t just go out and start...
- We’ll do it tonight.
There's a full moon.
Couldn't be better.
We'll start off about midnight.
(Plate crashes)
(Door closes)
Alice.
(Dogs bark in the distance)
Alice!
Alice?
Is that you Alice?
Aah!
Wait a minute. I know you.
I know you!
(Panting)
(Man) Come on.
Oh!
Ah.
Oh, oh.
- Go away!
- (Horse neighs)
(Horse neighs)
(Screams)
Oh, no. No!
Hey, Tom. Get her off!
(Gasps) Oh, let me go!
Leave me alone. Oh, oh!
- (Man) Come on.
- Let go!
Let me go! Let me go!
(She gasps)
- Catch.
(He laughs)
(Sylvia gasps)
Oh!
(She sobs)
(Gasps)
What's it to be, lads?
Aces high?
(Men) Aces high.
Cut.
(Gasps)
Ten of spades, four of diamonds,
Jack of clubs
Jack of hearts.
- Let her go.
- (Groans)
King of hearts.
(Sobbing)
Very appropriate.
Don't... Don't touch me.
- Don't you dare touch me.
- Come on, little fox.
Go to ground.
Leave her alone!
(Gasps)
Get out of my sight, the lot of you.
Get out!
(Sobbing)
Miss Forbes...
I know that it is useless to ask you
to forgive my friends.
Such behaviour is beneath contempt
and beyond forgiveness.
I only ask
that you accept my solemn word
that I knew nothing
of what was going on.
How do you know my name?
The arrival in as small a village as this
of a beautiful young lady
and her distinguished father
could scarcely go unnoticed,
Miss Forbes.
My name is Hamilton,
Clive Hamilton.
Will you kindly take me home,
Mr Hamilton?
I fear you have not forgiven me yet.
Your fears are well founded,
Mr Hamilton. I have not.
Now, will you take me home
or do I have to walk?
Is there nothing I can do to persuade
you of my personal innocence?
Nothing.
I take it, then, I have to walk?
My carriage is at your disposal.
Unfortunately,
I can't leave at this moment
but I shall instruct
one of my young guests...
- Thank you. I prefer to walk.
- Miss Forbes, you can't walk.
You might be attacked, Miss Forbes.
I've already been attacked.
And it was here in your house.
Now, please open the door.
Thank you.
And tomorrow I shall go
straight to the police.
- Please don't do that, Miss Forbes.
- Why shouldn't I?
I am the Squire of this little community
and responsible
for the welfare of everyone in it.
Should any scandal attach
to my name,
the effect could be disastrous
for all these people.
I can't expect you to understand
why that should be.
I just ask that you believe it.
And what about those...
...your charming young guests?
Will you leave me to punish them
in the way I think most fit?
I promise they'll suffer
for what they've done.
Or would have done.
If it hadn't been for you.
Yes, that's true, I suppose.
Very well, Mr Hamilton.
I won't go to the police.
- This time.
- Thank you.
Are you sure you can find the way?
Thank you, Mr Hamilton.
Good night.
Please take great care
not to stray from the path.
There are tin mines under this land .The ground sometimes subsides.
Denver!
Everything is ready, Master.
. Ah.
. (Laughs)
Alice.
Alice!
(Gasps)
Good evening, Officer.
You just step up here a moment,
gentlemen, please.
I... I realise this looks...
it's a serious charge
you'll be on in the morning.
What charge?
Who might this gentleman be?
Sir James Forbes.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening.
What are you going to charge us with?
Body snatching I should think, sir.
I see.
Well, in that case I suppose...
you don't mind if we have a quick look.
I don't care who you are, sir!
Well.
What's going on, sir?
I don't know, Sergeant,
any more than you do.
Now, look, Sergeant, I need your help.
My help, sir?
Say nothing of what
you've seen here tonight.
Now look, Sergeant,
it doesn't need me to tell you
there's something very wrong
in this village.
All these young men dying
and now this.
Well, some people say
it is the marsh fever, sir.
Oh, marsh fiddlesticks.
In any case, it couldn't cause a body
to disappear into thin air, could it?
- No, sir.
- Well, then, will you help me or not?
I'd like to help you, sir. Really I would.
My boy was one of the first to go, sir.
Well, then, help me for his sake.
Very well, sir.
I'll withhold my report for 48 hours.
I dare not do more than that.
Thank you, Sergeant.
You won't regret it. I'm sure of that.
What are we going to do about this, sir?
We'll fill it in, make it look
as if it's never been touched.
We can manage this on our own,
Sir James.
Why don't you wait inside
where it's warm.
Thank you, Peter.
Yes, I will.
- Good night, Sergeant
- Good night, sir.
Right-ho, let's get on with it.
Sylvia?
Have you seen Alice?
She's not in her room.
Come in, Peter, and sit down.
- Sit?
- Please sit down.
I have some shocking news
for you Peter.
- What is it?
- Alice.
Then she was ill.
- I must go tell her.
- Wait.
- I have to see her.
- She's not here.
- Where is she?
- Control yourself, Peter.
She's not here.
Now, listen to me.
She's outside somewhere,
on the moors.
She's dead.
No.
Sylvia found her.
(Sobbing) No.
Oh, God.
Forgive me.
I killed her.
- That’s not true. You know it isn’t.
- Yes, it’s my fault.
- I should have known.
- That's nonsense, Peter.
If she's been struck by this disease,
it's no fault of yours.
Take me to her, wherever she is.
Yes, I will, Peter. I will.
But there's one thing we have to do.
We must find out about the disease,
find out what it is and destroy it.
You will have to let me
perform an autopsy.
- God.
- We have to, Peter.
And I shall need your help.
- I'm ready, Father.
- Yes, very well.
We'll ask the sergeant to come with us.
- Hey, Martinus.
- Heh?
Come on, wake up!
Come on, let's have a word with you.
(Screams)
No!
Extraordinary.
- No sign of rigor mortis.
- Hm.
When did she do this?
- Some days ago.
- How?
Piece of glass, I think.
She was rather secretive about it.
- Oh?
- It was a clean wound.
(Sighs)
Well?
It's not human.
- it's not human blood.
- Exactly.
She's been splashed
with the blood of some animal.
Do you think
she might have been attacked?
By an animal?
There are no external signs of violence.
None at all.
Then how did she die?
That's what we are trying
to find out, Peter.
How did she die?
Stop it!
I can't stand any more.
It's not a matter of what you can
or can't stand, my lad.
- it's the truth that matters, the truth.
- I'm telling you the truth.
- Look, Jack.
- Sergeant.
Sergeant.
Look, I was up there.
You saw me
so it's no use my denying it.
And she... And the body was found
right by me, all right.
But I didn't kill her. I didn’t kill her!
So you say, but you was drunk.
And so I'll go on saying,
because it's the truth.
All right.
What was you doing up there, anyway?
I told you. I'd just had a skinful.
I don't know why I went up there.
Just to get away from everything.
Are you sure you didn't see her?
- And follow her into the woods?
- No!
You'd had a row with her husband.
There's plenty who'll swear to that.
Now, I put it to you
that you wanted your revenge.
- So you saw her and followed her...
- No, I tell you, no!
- Is that the truth?
- Yeah, it is.
I'm sure of that, at least.
What do you mean by that, "at least"'?
What do you mean by it?
You wouldn't believe me, anyway.
You leave that to me to decide.
You saw something else up there,
didn't you?
What was it? What was it?
My brother.
- You saw your...
- My brother, yes. The one that's dead!
The one that's buried out there.
I saw him just as clear
as I see you now.
All grey, his eyes staring.
I saw him.
And yet I know he's out there,
lying in his coffin.
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
Peter, you'd better go up
and get some rest.
You've been on your feet for 24 hours.
I can't rest. I'll just go and make
all the arrangements for the funeral.
- (Knock at the door)
- Yes?
- Excuse me, sir.
- What is it, Sergeant?
The front door was open
so I took the liberty...
Well, what is it?
- it's young Martinus, sir.
- What about him?
You should have a word with him.
Oh, very well.
I did see him, sir. I swear it.
Everything I told the sergeant
is the truth.
I'm telling you, sir.
I did see him, sir.
I saw my brother.
Your brother is dead and buried.
I know that, sir.
Didn't I bury him myself?
But I saw him in his shroud.
- Standing, staring at me.
- How could you see him?
God only knows, sir.
But I saw him.
God only knows, indeed.
That's all, Sergeant.
You don't believe me, do you, sir?
On the contrary,
I believe everything you say.
Well, are you satisfied now, Sergeant?
No.
- You just heard the gentleman say...
- I know what the gentleman said.
But I'm the law here.
And I'm responsible for you until
I have made further investigations.
Put him in the cell, Constable.
(Gasps)
Father.
Feeling better, my dear?
Feeling well enough to talk?
Now, when you told me about Alice,
you said there was a man with her.
Did you recognise him?
No.
You remember the young man we saw
who was following
the funeral procession,
the one who shouted at us to go away?
Yes.
- He's been arrested.
- But it wasn't him.
But you said
you didn't recognise the man.
(Gasps)
Is it possible that the man you saw
was the man in the coffin?
It was, wasn't it?
But how?
Never mind how, my dear.
Just one more question
and then you can rest.
When we found Alice
was she in the same place
where you saw her with this man?
No, no she wasn't.
It was up by some old mine works.
I don't Know exactly where.
Well, I'll try to find them.
You go back to sleep.
No, I'll be getting up in a few minutes.
Thank you, Father.
Very well.
Ah, Peter.
- How is she?
- Oh, very much better.
She's talking of getting up.
Well, I feel like a stroll.
Care to join me?
Yes.
I want a word with the sergeant
so we'll call in on the way.
Where are we going, sir?
Up on the moors.
A breath of air will do us both good.
I didn't know this place even existed.
What did they mine here?
- Tin, sir.
- Tin?
Yes, there's a rich vein
runs under here sir, worth a fortune.
Then why has it been allowed
to fall into decay like this?
There was a lot of accidents, sir.
Miners killed and maimed.
They wouldn't go down there.
They said it was unlucky.
Old Squire was furious,
but he had to shut it down.
Has young Hamilton tried to reopen it?
Oh, no, sir, but then
he don't need the money.
- Where does he get his money from?
- I can't rightly say, sir.
He was away
when his father died in foreign parts.
The old squire left him the house
and a lot of unpaid bills.
When young Squire come back here,
he shut himself up there,
wouldn't see nobody.
Then suddenly he had a lot
of young people down staying there
and spending money like water.
It's creepy.
- They do say, sir, that it's...
- What do they say, Sergeant?
- That it's haunted?
- Well, how did you know that, sir?
It doesn't take much guessing, does it?
Come on, Peter, we mustn't leave
Sylvia alone too long.
Thank you, Sergeant.
(Knock on door)
- May I come in?
- Please.
Thank you.
What can I do for you?
At our last meeting
you made it abundantly clear
that my attentions
would not be welcomed,
that you would as soon
never see me again.
I appreciate your feelings
and the reason for them.
I wouldn't dream of imposing
myself on you, only...
Only I felt I had to come
and tell you how terribly sorry I was
to hear the news of your friend,
Alice Tompson.
I knew her, you know, not very well
but enough to realise
what a very fine lady she was.
Please accept my sincere condolences.
Thank you, but would they not be better
given to her husband?
I fear they would not be accepted,
Miss Forbes.
- Oh?
- Doctor Tompson doesn't like me.
You are not alone in your opinion of me.
I can't imagine that the opinion
of others affects you very much.
Oh, I should like to be popular,
of course.
I should be lying if I said otherwise.
But I realised long ago that
in order to be popular one must conform.
I find that too big a price to pay.
Conform?
Well, to the standards of conduct
dictated by convention.
I have my own standards.
I conform to them.
At least you are honest, Mr Hamilton.
Probably my only virtue.
(Laughs) I'm always honest,
even with myself.
I wonder how many people
can truthfully admit to that.
Not many, I agree.
I am becoming a bore.
I have taken up enough of your time.
Oh, I wonder,
could I impose on you
for a glass of water?
Oh, yes of course.
Unless you prefer sherry?
Please, I don't want
to put you to any trouble.
It's no trouble.
Do you believe in life after death,
Miss Forbes?
- That's an odd question.
- Odd?
To ask a stranger.
I was hoping that
you no longer considered me a stranger.
Very well.
Yes, I do believe in life after death.
Do you?
I'm sure of it, Miss Forbes.
- (Glass breaks)
- I'm sorry.
- Here, let me...
- Oh!
How clumsy of me. I'm so sorry.
It's nothing, really.
This should prevent
the risk of any infection.
You must think me a clumsy idiot.
I really do apologise.
One cannot be too careful.
There. Is that better?
- Thank you.
- A safety pin should hold it.
I have one in my bag.
Allow me.
May I say that I consider you
to be a very brave young lady.
Because of this?
Because of everything, Miss Forbes.
I'll see myself out.
(Drum beats)
(Drum beats intensify)
it's the Master. Open.
(Vicar) Man that is born of woman
hath but a short time to live
and is full of misery.
He cometh up
and he is cut down like a flower.
He fleeth, as it were, a shadow
and never continueth in one stay.
In the midst of life we are in death.
Yet, O Lord God most holy,
O Lord God most mighty,
O holy and most merciful Saviour,
deliver us not into the bitter pains
of eternal death.
(Drum beats)
O holy and merciful Saviour,
Thou most worthy judge eternal,
suffer us not at our last hour
for any pains of death
to fall from Thee...
(Bell tolling)
...for as much as it has pleased
almighty God in his great mercy
to take unto Himself the soul
of our dear sister here departed.
Vicar, may I ask a favour of you?
I am given to understand
that you have a fine collection of books
on a variety of subjects.
I wonder if you have any
on witchcraft or black magic.
If so, may I have the use
of your library?
- Come with me.
- Thank you.
Come in, sir.
No, no, please sit down.
Oh, hello, Peter.
Peter...
Have you ever heard of voodoo?
- it's a form of witchcraft, isn't it?
- Exactly.
It's practiced in the Caribbean,
in Haiti to be precise.
Please sit down, Vicar.
I find all kinds of witchcraft
slightly nauseating
and this I find absolutely disgusting.
You're not following
and there's no reason why you should
if I don't explain properly.
- Unless you would like to...
- No, I'm ignorant in these matters.
Oh, well.
Sylvia tells us that
she saw something on the moors,
something that was a man
and yet not a man.
Her description
was of a walking corpse,
the corpse of Martinus' brother.
Now...
...young Martinus also says
that he saw something on the moor,
something that he insists
was his brother.
But we know that his brother is dead.
We also know
that he is not lying in his coffin.
Now, what do you make of that?
That he was buried alive,
that he somehow freed himself
and he's out there.
But I've told you, Peter, I saw him.
And he was as dead then
as any corpse I have ever seen.
No, that's not the answer.
Then, what is?
What is the connection with voodoo?
Someone in this village
is practicing witchcraft.
That corpse wandering
on the moors is...
...an undead, a zombie.
It's incredible, sir.
How can you, a man of science,
believe that?
I have an advantage
over you there, Peter.
I spent the afternoon reading up
the subject in the vicar's library.
And it's all there.
It's all clearly scientifically stated.
And we have the evidence
of two sensible human beings.
What can be done?
About Martinus' brother? Nothing.
I'm thinking of Alice.
- Are you saying that Alice is...?
- Peter, I am.
I pray that I'm wrong.
But I’m going to watch over her grave tonight with the vicar until daybreak.
I'll come, too.
I’d rather you didn’t.
I think you need some rest.,
- I am rested, sir.
- Well, I'm...
If anything were to happen,
I'd rather you weren't there.
I'm coming with you.
Very well.
- Vicar?
- What?
I think you should go home now.
it's very late.
Dr Tompson and I will stay on.
- If you're sure.
- Yes, yes. Quite sure.
All right.
- Good night, Sir James.
- Good night.
(Drum beats)
(Drum beats intensify)
What happened?
- Who attacked you?
- I don't know.
He wore a mask.
We'll take you home.
(Drum beats)
I shall be all right now, thank you.
If you should need me...
Don't worry.
We won't hesitate to call you.
Thank you, Sir James.
We must get back.
This may have been a trick.
(Footsteps)
Zombie.
(Screams)
- Oh.
- Peter?
Peter, it's all right.
it's all right now.
You had a nightmare.
A nightmare?
Then, it wasn't Alice?
I'm afraid that part of it was true.
You fainted
and we brought you back here.
And Alice?
Reburied properly.
The vicar gave her absolution.
She will be at peace now.
Peace? Is there such a thing?
There will be, my son,
and with God's help
and the energy of your good friend,
I am sure of it.
Well, I must get back to my church now.
Thank you for your help, Vicar.
It is I who should be thanking you.
I shall pray for you both.
Would you care to tell me
about your dream?
It sometimes helps.
I dreamed I saw the dead rise.
All the graves in the churchyard opened
and the dead came out.
All the graves were empty.
In heaven's name, where are they?
What's happened to them, sir?
It is essential that none of the villagers
should know of this.
We must get these graves filled in
before anyone is astir.
Very good, sir.
Sergeant, I want another word
with your prisoner, young Martinus.
- You want to see him right away, sir?
- Yes, immediately.
He's got away, Sergeant!
Anyone can see that.
The question is how?
The question is, where did he go?
Has he joined the others?
- The others?
- You know what I mean.
But he's not dead, sir.
Not yet, Sergeant.
But he soon will be.
Did the prisoner
have any visitors yesterday?
- Well, did he?
- Er... No, sir.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, sir.
Well, only the squire, that is.
- What did he want?
- He wanted a word with the prisoner.
I didn't think there was anything wrong.
- What did they talk about?
- Oh, I didn't listen, sir.
I didn't think it would be right.
They just talked? Nothing else?
- No, nothing, sir.
- Are you sure?
Well, of course I'm sure, sir.
They just talked.
Oh, the Squire asked
for a glass of water.
For the prisoner.
He said he was thirsty so I got him one.
Where is it?
- The water?
- The glass!
I threw it away, sir. It got broken.
- Who broke it? You?
- No, the Squire.
And young Martinus out himself?
How did you know that?
Never mind.
Sylvia.
Sylvia?
- Yes, Father. Whats the matter?
- Oh, there you are.
Oh, nothing, I...
I was just getting
a little worried about you.
Why? I'm all right now.
I'm just clearing up.
- How's the finger?
- Fine, thank you. Almost healed.
I must get on.
Ah, Peter. I have to go out again.
I want you to do something for me.
Don't let Sylvia out of your sight
until I tell you it is safe to do so.
- But, sir...
- Please.
Believe me when I say she is in danger.
(Insects chirping)
- What can I do for you?
- We have met before, young man,
in somewhat disturbing circumstances.
However, I shall not
hold that against you.
Is Mr Hamilton in?
He's in but he's busy.
Good. Will you tell him
that I want to see him?
I've told you, he is busy.
I'm glad to hear it.
I, too, am a busy man.
But as I have found the time
to come all the way out to see him
I think that he could come out to see me.
Would you tell him that, please?
Well?
Yes, thank you.
- Are you being funny?
- No, I'm not being funny.
I'm just trying to remember
my manners.
I wish I could say the same for you.
My name is Forbes.
Yours is Hamilton, I believe.
What do you want?
I want to talk to you, Mr Hamilton.
In private.
Get out.
What do you want to see me about?
About Alice Tompson.
About young Martin us.
- About my daughter, Mr Hamilton.
- What about them?
And about many others
who should be at rest now,
at rest in their graves.
- What has happened to them?
- How should I know?
I don't know how but you do know.
You know very well
what has happened to them.
Are you mad?
I almost wish I was.
This business is so appalling.
Mr Hamilton...
Am I right in thinking
that you have spent a large part
of your life in the Caribbean,
in Haiti, to be precise?
And while you where there,
did you learn something
of the practice of voodoo?
You are mad!
No, I'm not.
But can the same be said of you?
Get out of here!
- I'm not going.
- Yes, you are.
Good night, Mr Hamilton.
Well, I'm ready.
(Insects chirping)
(Footsteps)
(Drum beats)
Kada nostra. Kada estra.
Kada nostra.
Kada estra.
- Kada nostra.
- What was that?
Nothing, Peter.
Come to me.
You will come to me.
- What is it?
- Some water, please.
Come and sit down.
Sylvia?
(Clock chimes)
(Door opens)
(Door closes)
(Footsteps)
(Grunting and groaning)
Aargh!
(Groans)
(Grunts)
Help! Help!
(Drum beats)
- Hamilton, where is he?
- I don't Know.
- Where is he? Where is he?
- I don't know.
- Do you want to burn to death?
- No, no, no!
- Where is he?
- He's in the mine.
(Drum beats)
(Sylvia screams)
Get to the mineshaft, all of you!
(Gasps)
Peter, look out! Peter!
Ohh!
(Hamilton screams)
(Sylvia) Hurry!
(Hamilton) Ah! Let me out!
(Screams)