Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Why aren't we getting it?
They're not doing a live broadcast.
Why not?
The opposition party protested.
They said it was unfair.
They must be nervous.
Call and find out.
The results must be in.
- This is a news flash
- There it is.
The results for the Chungbuk
party election are in.
Kim Gyeongmo...
Why aren't they showing the total
number of voters?
Be quiet.
- Shin Huiju, 421 votes.
- Please.
Jang Iljun, 803 votes.
- 803 votes? What does that come to?
- Jang Iljun is in 1st place.
Shin Huiju is in 2nd place.
- Kim Gyeongmo is in 3rd place.
- We won.
Are you sure?
We were 376 votes behind last time.
Shin Huiju is in 2nd place.
Jang Iljun! Jang Iljun!
Congratulations, honey.
Congratulations.
Congratulations,
it was a touching victory.
Thanks.
You made it through the tough part.
I'm proud of you.
This is just the beginning.
We have to figure out how to
beat Kim Gyeongmo now.
He's probably exhausted by now.
You can beat him.
I should.
Shouldn't you call Shin Huiju?
You saw her.
I think she's shocked.
Let's give her some time.
Ms. Shin.
I'm alright.
Go ahead.
How can this be?
Were the ballots rigged?
It's a difference of 6 votes.
I lost.
They rechecked.
You were so confident.
I was a fool to trust you.
I shouldn't have held hands with you.
That's upsetting to hear.
You were 1st place in Daejeon
and Chungnam.
Who knew Cheongam would go crazy?
Ms. Shin.
How about abandoning Jang Iljun
and going with Kim Gyeongmo?
What are you talking about?
You want me to break my promise?
Promises are made to be broken
once in a while.
Do you think I'm like you?
Stop yelling at me?
I know I play dirty, but doesn't
Jang Iljun also?
If I'm a blowfly, he's a gadfly.
Compared to that,
Kim Gyeongmo is a saint.
I'm saying this for your sake.
Why would a saint accept a fly?
That's my problem, so don't worry.
Baek Changi owes me.
Shin Huiju?
Yes. Get Shin Huiju.
No.
You know what she's like.
You have to get her.
If she merges with Jang Iljun,
it could be a tough race.
I asked her about it before.
She refused.
That's because she had
a possibility of winning then.
If they made a secret promise, as
we suspect, she can't win now.
She wouldn't break her promise.
People change, especially when
it comes to politics.
She held hands with Park Eulseop.
We have to do whatever we can.
You will be connected to the
voice message system.
She's not answering?
No.
Was the shock too great?
We have to accomplish the merge today.
Isn't it a bit strange?
Would she...
I only came because you were so insistent,
but I'm not feeling very well right now.
Let me get right to the point.
Did you promise to merge with
Jang Iljun after this party election?
Yes.
Did Mr. Park tell you?
Please reconsider.
I know you're desperate,
but don't make me pathetic.
I'm not a lying politician.
I know, but think about it.
Who is more honest?
Jang Iljun or me?
If you want a world based on
laws, principle and justice,
who should become president,
Jang Iljun or me?
Justice begins with keeping promises.
Think of the greater cause.
Didn't you hold hands with Park Eulseop
for that greater cause?
My offer is still valid.
I will make you
practical prime minister.
Don't be tied down by the little things.
Make a greater choice for the country.
Mr. Jang.
Ms. Shin, where are you going?
- Well...
- Let's go inside.
Isn't that a bit rude?
Let's talk inside.
Where were you going?
I was going to hear him out.
About what?
Fine, I'll be honest.
I don't like you.
You're good at lying and you're
crafty.
I'm not sure how much I can trust you.
I'm not sure if I should do my best
to campaign for you.
So, you want to break your promise?
Fine, I'll admit it.
I used tactics you don't like to
win this fight.
I started with nothing just like you.
We didn't have any assemblymen
or factions to support us.
I wouldn't have tried this hard if
I'd had everything like Kim Gyeongmo.
I could have been leisurely,
but I couldn't win like that.
You can't beat the opposition party
if you're like Kim Gyeongmo.
How can you be so sure?
A full tiger can't hunt.
Kim Gyeongmo lived in high society.
He was never hungry and even if he is,
he refuses to hunt.
He can be a good administrator,
but he won't win the election.
Are you saying it's alright to
do anything to win?
What you do after you win is important.
I understand you don't like me.
You were in mainstream society
from a young age, too.
However, we have commonalities, too.
We both grew up knowing what it's
like to be hungry.
If you don't like me, look
at my policies.
Are my policies closer to the country
you want or are Kim Gyeongmo's?
Now what?
I said I'd take care of that after
the party election.
We get our trust money back.
Let's talk about this later.
I can't worry about that right now.
What was that about?
It's nothing.
It didn't sound like nothing.
Do we have funding problems?
There seem to be some problems.
Kim Gyeongmo has plenty of funds,
but we never have enough.
I'm telling everyone I'll pay them
back after the party election,
but the trust money won't be enough.
Why didn't you say something?
Jang is allergic to money.
I couldn't tell him.
Don't worry.
Everything will be solved if he becomes
the presidential candidate.
What will you do before then?
Half the voters are in Seoul and
the metropolitan area.
- Discuss funds with me.
- Professor Jo.
Discuss it with me.
Keep it a secret from him.
Fine.
I understand.
I have three demands.
Go ahead.
Have your wife stay away from
the campaign office.
Why?
It doesn't look too good for her
to act like your advisor.
It doesn't fit Korean sentiments.
I explained that publicly several times.
She's my political companion.
What's wrong with her being
at the campaign office?
You're a woman and you're
running for president.
Why is my wife a problem?
It's because of past experience.
The current first lady abuses power.
My wife would never do that.
I can't accept that demand.
Is that so?
Second, make all decisions after
discussing them with me from now on.
No tricks or conspiracies
without my approval.
I have the right to ask as your partner.
I agree, but there will be unavoidable
situations where I have to decide.
If we were equal, there would be
no reason for a merge.
So, you can't accept that either?
What's the third?
Kim Gyeongmo offered me the
practical prime minister position.
What can you do for me?
That's not like you.
I didn't think you'd make deals
with positions.
Aren't you good at negotiating?
You can't accept any of my demands.
I could lie and agree to everything.
But I don't want to deceive you
right now.
It might work, but I could lose you
forever.
I really need you.
The negotiations are lasting long.
I'm getting nervous.
What if Shin Huiju doesn't keep
her promise to merge?
Stop saying things like that.
That must be him.
Mr. Jang, how did it go?
What?
Did she break it off?
I see.
Okay.
Ms. Oh...
He wants us to call a press
conference for a merge.
You...
I gotcha.
Right?
That was mean.
Oh, boy.
Is your sense of humor that low?
What?
He always makes everything sound
so unpleasant.
I gotcha.
Right?
I ought to...
Hey!
Come here!
We are announcing a merge to
make our country a prosperous one.
I resign from my candidacy.
I will support Jang Iljun.
Two young and energetic people
have joined forces.
We will supplement our weaknesses
and share our strengths.
We will win this party election.
Then, we will win the presidential
election and meet your expectations.
Vote for Jang Iljun as our
party candidate.
We will change your lives.
Jang Iljun and Shin Huiju announce a merge
Things have changed for the New Wave Party
I shouldn't have given
Jang Iljun any room.
He keeps shoving his way in
and changing things.
It's no use talking about the past.
The future is important.
How is this going to affect us?
It could have a large effect on
the Incheon party election.
You might not be first place.
But you have a lot of votes,
so you'll probably maintain the lead.
It was a mistake to give our votes
to Shin Huiju.
We have to deal with this merge
from now on.
Thank you very much.
You won't regret this.
Regrets aren't good.
We should all be careful.
Forgive me if I was rude to you before.
We're on the same side now.
We should get along.
That would be nice.
Hello, I'm the campaign director,
Lee Chisu.
Mr. Lee, I've heard a lot about you.
It's nice to meet you.
You're the top candidate for
executive secretary of the Blue House.
Oh, no.
I just do all the menial work
at the bottom.
We need people like you
for Mr. Jang to stand out.
Let's work together and do
a good job.
Thank you.
- Hello, I'm Jang Iljun.
- Vote for Jang Iljun.
We'll work hard.
Vote for Jang Iljun.
Take care of this first.
The world is running a green race
for green growth.
I will create 600,00 jobs with
my green new deal policy.
It's time for change.
Give a chance to the young people.
I will create a dynamic Korea!
I will take power with Shin Huiju!
Yeah!
Jang Iljun beat Kim Gyeongmo in the
Incheon party election after the merge.
However, Kim Gyeongmo took
the lead in Gyeonggi.
The voting rate is over 80%.
Both sides are criticizing each other.
With the final Seoul party
election remaining,
Kim Gyeongmo is in the lead by
2,300 votes.
The outcome still can't be predicted.
Congratulations on returning to Seoul.
Thanks.
Welcome.
For me?
You're so beautiful.
Will you go on a date with me
some time?
Any time.
I like younger men who are tall.
Be careful, he's a playboy.
Don't I get a bouquet?
Congratulations.
Thank you.
What about me?
I worked hard, too.
I'll give you a kiss.
Never mind.
Let's start the meeting.
Kim Gyeongmo has 22,969 votes.
You have 20,649 votes.
It's a difference of 2,300 votes.
It's a big difference in a regional
election, but not in Seoul.
How many voters are there in Seoul?
There are 16,000.
The voting rate is going up.
Up to 14,000 people could vote.
It means more younger people are
voting. That's good for us.
The merger of two young people
had a good effect.
The voting rate was 80
percent in Gyeonggi, but we lost.
It's because the party members unify.
It's about 8 to 2 for Kim Gyeongmo.
They even have buses to transport
the voters.
There are reports that
they're even buying tickets.
Have more people watch and
report to the election committee.
It will be forgotten after the election.
We need more people, too.
What are you talking about?
Do we have the funds to do that?
No.
We have to rely on volunteers.
Then we'll have to do that.
What about the press opinion?
It's a battle.
They're split right in half.
They're attacking you more.
Tell everyone I'll give interviews,
even if they're hostile to me.
Mr. Yun, finish the Gangbuk
development plan.
Mr. Gi, check the districts that are
advantageous and disadvantageous.
- Okay.
That's it.
Just a minute.
Mr. Lee, Mr. Gi.
Give me a report of the campaign
strategy and budget by today.
That's...
Isn't that too excessive a request?
Why is it excessive?
I have the right to know everything.
- But...
- Do it.
- Honey...
Seeing from Gyeonggi,
prospects aren't that negative.
The party members still
overwhelmingly support you.
2,320 votes...
Will I be able to maintain this lead?
Yes, you can.
You have to make the gap larger.
Too bad about the votes I lost
in Chungcheong.
Don't think about that anymore.
I'm sure Jang Iljun has weaknesses.
Do you have a plan?
No, not yet.
It's the Blue House.
This is Baek Changi.
You know how elections are.
Today?
Aren't you meeting Ms. Shin's
demands too much?
I have no choice.
She's my partner.
She's acting like she's in charge.
She's just like that because
she used to be a prosecutor.
Acting like a prosecutor.
She should be cooperating,
not investigating or interrogating us.
It's alright.
We don't have anything to hide.
She might not be flexible,
but people like her for her principles.
I beat Kim Gyeongmo because
she joined me.
We have to embrace her
even if we don't want to.
Okay, never mind.
About the party members.
How about meeting the president?
It worked in Gangwon.
I thought about it, but not now.
Why not?
I got a vote using a crippled
election as a weapon.
I won't get it now, but it would
be dangerous to get it, too.
Why?
I can't guess what he'd want.
He won't support me for no reason.
How are you?
Mr. Kim.
Good job.
- Have a seat.
- Thank you.
Our party election is very popular.
Everyone is talking about it.
I didn't expect Jang Iljun to
get so many votes.
Why did you want to see me?
What's the rush?
Let's have a cup of tea.
I want to hear about the election.
As you know, I don't have
time to sleep these days.
I know.
You can't have a leisurely
drink until it's over.
I see your pledge is the practical
prime minister system.
That's right.
Do you have a candidate?
there was someone I thought of,
but it didn't work out.
I'm still thinking about it.
Should I recommend someone?
How?
How about Choi Jeonguk?
Choi Jeonguk?
The First Lady's older brother?
He has a lot of political experience
and he's prudent.
I'm sure he'll support you well.
He was imprisoned for taking bribes.
He was pardoned.
All politicians have faults.
What is the vote difference right now?
About 2,000 votes?
How did it go?
I said how did it go?
He's going to think about it.
What for?
He should give an answer right away.
He can't give an answer right away.
The Seoul party election is soon.
He should decide quickly.
What are you doing?
Who are you calling?
As if you don't know.
Jang Iljun.
I'm telling you Kim Gyeongmo
is better than Jang Iljun.
Jang Iljun can't be trusted.
That's what you think.
Just give him one day.
Can't you wait a day?
Use this as expenses.
- Professor Jo, this is...
- What?
It's too much.
You have to think of the
presidential election, too.
This could become a problem.
Don't worry.
I made sure there won't be any problems.
Still, it's too risky.
They're spending a lot more than us
right now.
This isn't your first election.
If there's light, there has to be
darkness too.
Keep this an absolute secret.
First Lady, hello.
I'm sorry I haven't called.
Hon...
What is it?
Can I talk to you?
Is it something I can't hear?
It has to do with our children.
Does it?
Ms. Shin.
Okay.
I guess family matters come up.
I'll leave you for a while.
The president spoke to Kim Gyeongmo?
Yes, this afternoon.
The First Lady wants to talk to us.
She'll try to convince the President.
What's the reason?
She didn't say, but the President
has the most power right now.
Let's see him and see what he wants.
Let's think about it.
There's no time.
Kim Gyeongmo already met him.
We could be too late.
I don't know what the President asked,
but the First Lady wouldn't
have called us if Kim Gyeongmo said yes.
This is a risky deal.
We have to be careful.
Choi Jeonguk?
Yes, the First Lady's older brother.
The President is crazy.
Who's the person who made
the government like this?
It's because he was in the Blue House.
I quit being Prime Minister
because I didn't want to see that.
He wants me to take him in?
I can't accept this.
You should.
Mr. Baek.
You have to.
Are you crazy?
What will the people say if I
choose him as Prime Minister?
I can't have a corrupt person in
my government.
That's a later problem.
You have to win this election first.
Who do you think they'll ask
if you say no?
Jang Iljun.
All we have right now are
the votes of the party members.
If we lose those,
there will be no hope.
I can't do that even if I lose.
Even if you lose.
How can you say that so easily?
What about all those people
who supported you all this time?
- Do you know how much money was spent?
- Mr. Baek!
Expenses, salaries, meals,
promotions, labor, etc.
Do you think all that happens by itself?
Just remember this.
The minute you lose,
you can just leave.
But hundreds and thousands of people
will be disappointed with you forever.
Hi, Seongmin.
Are mom and dad in Seoul?
They came this morning.
Oh, no.
I have a favor to ask.
Dad's watch and tie pin are
in my desk drawer.
Why?
Are you crazy? The safe?
How important is the watch?
Grandfather gave it to father.
Why did you take it?
I have a girlfriend.
I wanted to show off.
I can't go home right now.
Can you put it back for me.
You're crazy.
What's the combination?
Okay.
You're asking for trouble.
This is Baek Changi.
Mr. Baek.
What can I do for you?
Have a seat.
What do you want?
I'm a little busy.
Don't be so stiff.
My life is messed up because
Shin Huiju joined Jang Iljun.
You're going to have to take me in.
I still have some power among
the conservatives in the party.
I know, but Mr. Kim doesn't like you.
I can't help you.
You saw his attitude last time.
That's his opinion.
You should help.
You can control him.
Why should I?
Did you forget?
You're the one who told me
about Ju Ilran.
That's it?
You're so naive.
Mr. Kim already knows about that.
What if I tell the press?
Look here, do you have proof?
You'll only be spitting on your own
face.
Go ahead, if you want to.
You...
Fine, I'll see what I can do.
Really?
But I have one favor.
A favor?
What is it?
Go to Jang Iljun's office and
say hello.
What?
What am I supposed to do?
What is Director Yu's picture...
What are you doing?
Who said you could open the safe?
Mom, it's not what you think.
We have to talk.
So, Seongmin knows the combination?
Don't scold him.
He was just trying to show off
to his girlfriend.
Then I guess he saw the picture, too.
I don't know.
He probably didn't.
He would have said so if he had.
He would have asked about it.
Mom...
I'm curious, too.
Listen carefully.
Forget what you saw.
You didn't see anything.
Mom...
Listen to me.
Nobody must know about this.
Not your father, not Director Yu,
not Seongmin, not Sebin.
Why?
I'm sure a day will come to explain
after the election.
Then, you'll also know why I told you
not to date him, but not now.
Don't ask any questions and
just listen to me for now, okay?
Do you understand?
Okay, if that's what you want.
Come in.
What is it?
Aren't you going home?
I think I'll have to stay up
all night tonight.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Do you have something to say?
Don't overdo it.
You shouldn't get sick.
Don't worry,
I don't have time to get sick.
Okay.
Good night.
Director Yu, what are you doing?
I just said good night to Mr. Jang.
Are you going home?
I'll only get a couple of hours
of sleep, but I want to see my children.
It must be nice to have a family.
- Yes. See you.
- Bye.
Hello?
Didn't you sleep yet?
Mr. Kim, what can I do for you
at this hour?
I couldn't sleep.
Let's meet.
Hello, Mr. Jang.
I know this place well.
Nobody else will come.
You didn't call me because you needed
someone to drink with, did you?
Maybe. Have a seat.
Do you enjoy politics?
I don't do politics for fun.
But it should be worth it.
I started later than you.
I can't seem to adapt.
I'm already starting to hate it.
Then you can quit and support me.
I've come too far to do that.
Too many people are making
sacrifices for me.
What is it that you want to say?
You know I went to
the Blue House, right?
You have a source there.
I'm sure you heard.
Yes. I was curious.
I wondered how much of a bind the
President would put me in.
The goal is Prime Minister.
Prime Minister?
Choi Jeonguk, the First Lady's brother.
Choi Jeonguk?
How can they want someone like him?
Right?
They don't want to
let go of their power.
Are you going to accept?
No.
I wouldn't unless I was crazy.
The problem is even if I refuse,
the offer will be made to you.
We are enemies right now.
But I don't think you're so low
that you'd accept such an offer.
You can't accept this offer.
Of course not.
I want to start my government,
not inherit corrupt people.
Do you mean that?
Of course.
If I accept that, the new government
will have a bad start.
Let's agree on this.
I will reject the President's offer
and any support.
Can you do that, too?
We can't abandon righteousness.
I agree with you completely.
Let's fight the President together.
- Mr. Gi.
- Yes.
How many suits do we have
against Kim Gyeongmo?
I'm not sure, but dozens including
what happened at district chapters.
Drop them all.
What are you talking about?
Why are you dropping the suits
instead of punishing crimes?
There was a request from the party.
What request?
They want us to refrain a bit.
Fighting amongst ourselves would
only do the opposition party good.
We can only drop the suits,
if they do the same.
They will.
Talk to them.
Yes, sir.
Wait a minute.
I can't agree to this.
You can't agree to forget about crimes.
This is why the same crimes
occur again and again.
If you abide by the law, the election
culture can change.
You're right, but go with me this time.
It's already been agreed to
by Kim Gyeongmo.
Do you believe him?
Jang Iljun betrayed you before.
How can you trust him now?
If he accepts this,
he will be just as burdened.
He's not that stupid.
He always does the unexpected.
I can't accept the President's offer.
I have to give an answer.
You can't do that.
Mr. Baek!
If you're going to refuse,
wait a little while.
You can refuse when Jang Iljun refuses.
- You're really busy, aren't you?
- Yes.
Go in order.
Dobong-gu, Gwangjin-gu,
Seongdong-gu, Seodaemun-gu.
Forget what you saw.
You didn't see anything.
Mom.
Listen to me.
Nobody can know about this.
Why?
I'm sure a day will come to explain
after the election.
Then, you'll also know why I told
you not to date him, but not now.
Everyone is working hard.
There are so many pretty women.
Mr. Jang, it's nice to see you.
Ms. Shin, you're here, too.
You're campaigning well these days.
I brought an orchid for you.
It's a very precious orchid.
I'm sure you didn't come just for that.
Well...
Can we talk?
This is the perfect spot.
What do you want?
Don't I get a cup of tea?
I was wondering if there was
anything I could do to help you.
Help me?
Think about it.
Shin Huiju merged with me first.
Then she merged with you.
I should go where she goes.
It's natural that I'm here.
You're really something.
Don't you remember what you did
to me with Ju Ilran?
You already forgave me for that.
Forgiving you is different from
accepting you in my office.
I know Baek Changi was behind it.
Go to him.
You shouldn't be here.
I came with good intentions.
Have a nice life.
He didn't call yet, did he?
Forget it.
Don't wait for a boat that won't come.
Get a new boat.
I really can't trust Jang Iljun.
You're making me nervous.
Listen to me.
Forget about Kim Gyeongmo.
Does he think he can win
without me?
Should we count the suits or
should we just say it's even?
We're busy.
Let's just settle it all at once.
Fine.
This is very uncomfortable.
Let's settle this quickly.
What are your intentions?
Are you really going to reject
the President?
What are you talking about?
Are you pretending or
do you really not know?
I guess you really don't know.
I guess you're not in a high
enough position to know.
Let's be fair this time.
No fouls, okay?
Does the word fair suit us?
That's true, but let's try to be
fair in the Seoul party election.
You can't beat me with your skills.
I stepped all over you 5 years ago.
Did you forget already?
You didn't use skills.
You used petty tricks.
I learned a lot.
Then you should be grateful.
I'll beat you with skills this time.
So you have nothing to say.
This is Baek Changi.
Did you do it?
Good job.
You can join me after the
Seoul party election.
Fight fairly with skills? You?
Everyone knows we merged.
We don't have to go everywhere together.
- We can split up to save time.
- Good.
Where should I go?
- This area?
- Here. I'll go here.
Get the strong areas.
I'll take the weak areas.
Okay, let's meet back at the
office at 10 pm.
Okay.
Be careful in the cold.
- You, too.
- Okay.
Honey.
You're going to have to cancel
the street promotions today.
I was just heading out.
Why?
Family matters again?
I'll go ahead.
The Blue House called.
They want to meet.
When?
9 pm.
What should I say?
I'll have to meet them.
Jang Iljun is going to the Blue House.
He's going to meet the President
at 9 pm.
How do you know that?
That's not important.
What will you do if he accepts
the President's offer?
He won't.
I trust him.
What if he does?
What if?
Then I will, too.
If he betrays me, I can't just
sit back and let him.
We'll both have to roll in the mud.
Even if Jang Iljun says yes first?
I don't know about the First Lady,
but the President is still on my side.
If we both accept, then he'll choose me.
How did you find out?
I cheated a bit.
[Blue House]
Hello, Mr. Jang.
How have you been?
It's nice to see you.
How about a handshake?
You've gotten stronger.
I'm shaking hands all day.
I know how it is.
You'll be shaking many more.
Professor Jo, you look well
for all the hard work.
Is it because you got a lot of votes?
It's a lot of hard work.
It should be over with soon.
Are the children well?
Isn't this a bit too much?
What?
You didn't say a single word.
We broke up, but we're not enemies.
Inyeong...
Did you...
Did you know my mom before?
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
I'm going in.
Wait.
Do you hate me that much?
No.
Then why won't you even look
at me?
Since that day...
I said everything I wanted to.
Let's not hurt each other again.
I'm asking you.
Seongmin, what happened?
What?
You didn't come home.
Mom's really mad.
Why?
Well...
Did you tell her about the watch?
No, but...
Okay, then.
I have to go.
Seongmin!
I was surprised to see what happened.
- That Ju Ilran woman...
- Oh...
You avoided the scandal well.
I thought Mr. Jang would have
to drop out.
It was all a lie.
Do you trust him?
Of course, I do.
I envy you.
I don't trust my husband.
I just need him as a partner.
You've lived together for 40 years.
Marital emotions get in the way
of political partnerships.
You'll find out when you live here.
What's most charming here isn't
a man or a woman.
It's power.
It's an erotic monster that steps
all over petty human emotions.
I like the fierceness of power.
Don't you?
I'm still lacking.
Choi Jeonguk?
Yes. What do you think?
Well...
I'm sure it burdens you,
but think about the reality.
You're a quick person.
I know it could put you in a bind.
The opposition party would oppose.
But you can do anything when
you first take power.
You have the most support of
the people at that time.
You made the same offer to
Kim Gyeongmo, too, didn't you?
Maybe.
Practical benefits or future burdens.
That's the choice.
Right.
Kim Gyeongmo is a gentle horse,
but he has no instinct to race.
You're different.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Translation by KBS World
Special thanks to KaKak
Transcriber & Timer: gleemonex
Fine-tuning: ay_link
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com