DOWNLOAD YOUR DUQA FILES FROM DUQA ACCOUNTS
http://thepiratebay.org/user/DUQA-TEAM/
http://www.torrentportal.com/account-details.php?id=798013
THIS SUBTITLE IS MADE BY DUQA
TO HELP THOSE PEOPLE WITH HEARING PROBLEMS
AND I HOPE IT HELPS ALOT
ENJOY THE MOVIE
BYE.
China
Long ago a mythic battle between good and evil
played out in ancient China.
The country was torn by civil war
with many kingdoms struggling for land and power.
But one king had a ruthless ambition
to make himself emperor by the sword.
The other rulers hired assassins to kill the king before he could conquered them all.
Kingdom by kingdom, his army swept away everything in its path
and anyone who resisted
and anyone who resisted met terrible fate.
The country was his.
He was now  the emperor of all under heaven.
He enslaved his conquered enemies and forced them to build his great wall.
When they were died or useless he had them buried beneath it.
The emperor's mystics taught him mastery of the five elements.
Fire, water, earth, wood and metal.
His power seemed without limit.
He was a master of millions.
But like the lowliest peasant he could not stop growing old.
He needed to defeat his last enemy.
Death itself.
One day news came of a powerful witch
who was rumored to know the secret to eternal life.
He ordered the General Ming, his oldest friend and trusted ally to find her.
The witch was named Zi Yuan and she was nothing like the general expected.
On the western border to the monastery of Turfan.
There was house the greatest library in the ancient world
and Zi Yuan was sure the secret to eternal life was here.
It was the long lost oracle bones.
A collection of all the mystical secrets of the ancient world.
The emperor's answer was here.
Along with other magic beyond imagining.
She casted the spell in Sanskrit in ancient language that the emperor did not understand.
The curse must never be lifted,
or the emperor will rise again to enslave all of mankind.
On that dark day there will be nothing and no one to save us.
You can run but you can't hide.
Fly Fishing.
Hm... one o'clock.
Ten o'clock.
One o'clock... ten o'clock.
One o'....
and this is won't be for girl nothing to do..
Buy on this!
Eve,  I'm home.
Mrs O'Conell is at Book Tree, said she'll be home for dinner.
Oh, great, cause we're having fish.
You don't take I catch nothing, don't you?
I had the at most convinced, Sir.
There's a hook in your neck, Sir.
Shall I fetch the wire cutters ?
Now savely abort the airship, with the Mummy finally vanquished, dashed,
slaped Scarlet into his arms.
Oh God, Scarlet.
I thought I've lost you.
For a moment that you did.
Bay didn't raise of golden sunlight,
are hero sealed the very reunion with the kiss of timeless passion.
Bay loved deeper and sure than ever.
Miss O'Connell
We all dying to know, is this Scarlet Tukiv character really based on you?
Honestly I can say she's completely a different person.
Anymore question?
Miss O'Connell.
Is your life today as exciting as it was before the war?
I wish my life with that exciting now.
- Will be any other book in this series?
- Do you believe in happy ending?
Isn't this place full?
Dinner at home.
- Every night.
Here's the retirement.
May we stay this happy forever.
Still no letter from Alex.
I sent him three in the last month.
What do you expect?
I turn forgiven this kid when he gets kicked
out the college needs more money.
I am sure he's just buried in his studies.
So how your reading book go?
Oh fine, thank you.
Until they asked me when will be another mummy adventure.
But you did promise the publisher third book.
I know,
but I spent my night staring at a blank page completely blot.
We can skip dinner,
and I could attempt to.....
inspiring you.
Upstair?
Oh, that so sweet of you darling.
I am going to sit at that typewriter
until something exciting comes up.
Thank you.
Oh, trout.
How lovely.
So happy found the hobby that doesn't involve guns.
Good, Wilson is back.
You're couple days late, professor.
Oh my dear fellow, thank you for your concern.
Are you thirsty?
Yes, please, thank you.
Look, when I saw you're standing up there,
I thought I was looking at your father.
You really are Rick O'Connell's son.
We hopefully after the day,
you've be known as Alex O'Connell's father.
How a powerfull face.
When I told my colleagues at the museum that you have
discovered the colossal, they were thrilled.
- Yeah, however...
- I know.
how I'm i going to get in  that tomb.
Don't let the baggage get you down.
It was you who discovered the Bembridge journal,
I'm with you to discover the emperor.
I have a complete faith in you, Alex.
Thank you, professor.
Thanks for believing in me.
That mummy...
here...
Filed mummy?
Cursed mummy.
Mysterious mummy.
Lick them mummy.
Rick, darling, where are you?
I am ready to be inspired.
Do you remember the time the mummy had me tied down?
And you came to save me.
And you...
...cut, no, you tore open the ropes, that's what you did.
Just he was about pulage his ...
Watch out!
Sir Collin Bembridge.
He went searching to this tomb seventy years ago
I have to notice this as warning.
Unfortunately this not death Bembridge can make us famous
Let's keep moving.
Look at that.
What is that?
Stop,
Alex, stay here.
Come on.
this gonna take just his territory and he known that by anyone.
Alright, good job.
All the warriors are facing into this point.
- It's for waiting nor of emperor.
- Where is he?
Is there thing some bloody grave robbers
pick to the prize to you?
No, he is still here.
See, this is a Feng Shui compass.
Okay, now. This.
Okay this is to north.
With the Feng Shui compass send me opposite direction.
Alright, we need the real one.
Alright, here we go.
Alex, it's me.
Are you alright?
Tell me have we found the emperor?
What is it?
It's totally the greatest finds since King Tut.
If he's awaken, all modest should despair
It's definitely him.
He even has his concubines to bury lie with him.
Selfish bastard.
Hey professor Wilson.
Will you come down and take a look?
Or you ... and so long we can talk?
Let's go, professor.
We got a lot to do.
First of all I'd just like to say you ..... during the war.
But I've been sent of you one last assignment.
I am afraid we've retired from the espionage game.
Haven't we dear?
Yeah, we don't do it anymore.
We finished. Completely done.
It's totally curiosity, what's
is the misson anyway?
We need you to carry of this ...
to Shanghai.
- It's a piece of eyes.
- It's the eye of Shangri-La.
If you believe the legend appoints
the way to the pool of eternal life.
It was ***** of China in 1940.
Now the government like return it to Shanghai museum
as a sign good faith the Chinese people.
And with your expedition field bring it naturally,
both of you.
Oh we'd be so flatterred.
But Rick and I, we made a promise to each other after the war,
that we would settle down.
That's right, dear.
We didn't... we...
Well I must say that I'm a little dissapointed.
Post of China is very dangerous.
There are a lot of factions would love
get the hand on the eyes of Shangri-La.
In lesser hand, the eye could be lost forever.
We couldn't let that happened, could we?
- No, it could be bad for the world.
- Terrible!
You know, she has a brother lives in China.
- Jonathan!
Yes, he owns a nightclub, if I'm not mistaken?
We have been meaning to visit.
We could drop and surprise him.
- In a while?
- Why not.
Does this mean we can count on you one last time?
Yes you, Princess.
And  Imhotep, may the bugger actually stay there.
Hi, can you buy drink for me?
Excuse me.
Alex, Alex, you back again.
Come here let me get you a drink.
Make that two.
Sorry Uncle John,
but I got a better offer.
No, Alex, no, look, listen.
Come here.
To put it on archeological term,
that's a tomb in which many pharaoh were laid.
Now listen, listen.
Just think about me for a moment, alright.
Your discovery will go public in few days, and your parents are sort to find out.
They are not gonna be happy that you drop out the school, and....
Be relax, Uncle John.
I'm here, they're long away away....
Excuse me, I have some excavation to do.
- You are in China
- Eve, Rick. What are you... this is so...
- Brother, we love to see you.
- I don't know idea if he was here.
- Who is here?
- Who?
Go away!
I'm gonna kill you, kid!
Not so fast,.
That's my... kid
- Mad Dog Maguire?
- Ricochet O'Connell!
Let's we get back, and have a good time!
Music.
- How long has it been?
- Egypt, '23 French foreign legion.
This guy can land a plane on anything.
Ricochet, he has handed out of my girl.
He's son or not son, I got to give my beaten.
Get away, Dad.
It's to much I really like you to teach him a valuable lesson.
His mother would be upset.
Very upset!
Wive now, and kid.
Things are a little bit different, I'm sure you understand.
Let me make it out to you.
I'm just surprised to see you here. That's all.
Alright?
I'm now here five minutes,
and I'm already put you in the fire.
- You going back to college.
- I think it's not gonna worth it.
You two show up told me what to do.
Who?
We should sit down and discuss this like a family.
No, thanks mom.
We haven't been a family a long time.
Hey don't you bring your back on me.
Alex.
Alex, come here..
Don't look at me like this.
- It is your fault.
- My fault?
You're the one always smothering and
you came in more five minutes and wipe at his nose.
Perhaps I was over compensating for the fact that you've
never took interest into his life.
His life
is my top priority.
How many time that I said that he could break his neck?
A little warmth encouragement for difficult night.
I am his father.
It's implied.
We spent entire life searching for priceless artefacts,
and one thing that most precious, we've lost.
We can't let Alex becomes
a stranger pictures on a mantle.
- We can't let it to happen.
- No we can't.
How can we fix this?
We need to do it together.
I think it's faster if we took a ricksaw.
It's Chinese New Year.
Don't you love this country has so many holiday and
drinking is mandatory.
I can't believe
we've got to see your first big discovery.
It''s so exciting.
Listen, I pick you up about one hour.
You're not coming?
No, no.
I have seen enough mummies to last a lifetime.
There is.
Oh, my darling.
Very impressive.
- When you get to open the sarcophagus?
- I have to wait to official red tape has been cut.
The words rest in peace mean anything to you too?
So mom,  why don't you stick around for next few days
then we can open it together?
I would like that very much, thanks.
Alex.
Won't you go and tell professor Wilson that we are here.
Just, don't wake the big guy up when I'm gone.
This is all...
Really really big stuff.
Whatever you say, Dad.
I guess mummy bring up the best to me.
Take a wrong turn in Cairo?
Sorry to interrupt.
- Roger.
- Professor Roger Wilson.
Hello Rick.
You know when Alex told me that you going to Egypt,
I just couldn't believe my ears.
Now I just .... tombs
in the name of preservation.
Congratulations on your latest discovery.
Alex deserves all the credits.
He's a heavenly kid.
He's a son I never had.
He's the only one we got.
So next time you send him on of your field trip
you give us a head up first ?
Yes, of course.
And now I believe you have something belongs to us.
What's that?
Oh, you mean this?
For you.
I knew I can rely on you two.
I am afraid your work is not done yet.
Mr.  and Mrs O'Connell,
I'd like to introduce you to a friend of mine.
General Yang.
Well, he's the man who find out Alex's dig.
We're in this together.
The eye belongs to Chinese people.
You can't do this.
So Roger, you're snake.
How much did the Yin and Yang pay it?
Enough to pull strings on the foreign office.
Make sure that it was you two who delivered the eye.
Turn around.
The eye contains the elixir from the pool of eternal life.
I let you to open it.
Mrs. O'Connell
No. You're going to use it to wake the emperor, aren't you?
And his terracota army.
At least that's the general's idea.
Raising an army of mummies is insane
Listen, Yang.
Time to open the sarcophagus.
Move.
Read the inscription.
Now!
Ancient chinese isn't my forté.
Here's some encouragement.
Wilson!
- Don't do it!
- No Eve, don't do it.
They just gonna kill me anyway.
The inscription says that only a drop of blood
from a person with a pure heart can open the Eye.
Your husband was right.
Only the pure heart who sacrifice themself for the one they love.
Open it.
You never called after our last date.
I don't have time for games. Alex
You know my name, but I don't know yours.
It's Lin.
You were one who explain me why you try to kill me?
We could do that or we could save your parents.
Wilson, you're son of a bitch.
Get with it O'Connell.
Once this touch his hand, the emperor will rise.
To rule again.
Finish him all.
Alex, please, don't!
It's not him
It's a eunuch.
It's a decoy.
Where the hell  is the emperor?
Stay!
No!
Here we go again.
Wait for me.
I'm coming with you.
Watch out!
The longer he awake, the stronger he get.
Open the gate!
Ya, ya, ya, I know.
You wanna drive?
- Why not.
- You're a woman who can drive the truck.
Hey pal, I'm sorry but...
Happy new year!
Hurry, honey!
Jonathan, get the back.
Sorry for the Rolls.
You guys are mummy magnets!
We have to turn you around!
Excuse me.
- Hey, we can use this.
- Give me that.
Oh ya, that's a better idea.
- Aim it to the emperor!
- Aim it to the emperor?
I'll try.
Fire!
Have we get them?
- Fire!
- What?
-Your ass on fire!
- My ass?
- My ass on fire!
Spank my ass!
Alright, here I come.
Give me your hand.
- Where are you going?
- Told me it's a shortcut.
I told you it was a shortcut.
Now they chase on us.
Give me your hand.
Here, you gonna need this.
- Don't wait for me.
- Where are you going?
Where is Rick?
Where do you think?
Come here Alex.
Get on the horse.
Get back, Dad.
Alexander Wilbert O'Connell!
You gonna get on the back this horse!
Get out the way!
We've to go back to help Rick.
Forget Rick!
Here they come!
I'll go after the emperor.
Trust me,
I got little more experience with the mummy.
And I have the only weapon that kill him.
OK 'll cover you.
Let's go!
- I think you were died.
- He missed.
Watch out!
Thanks Rick, will you pay the cab?
Does it look like  I have a wallet?
You know when I kill the emperor be too unblow my cover
and everything under control.
That exactly what we were thinking.
Oh yeah you could going and raise another mummy.
And this buggers got superpowers.
He got control over fire, water, and metal
and who knows what else.
- And you dig him up anyway.
- Hey you're not gonna pin this one on me, Dad.
Stop you two..
No one is to blame here.
- Wilson manipulated all of us.
I appologize for my parents.
But I, I thought we have through it well together.
Except we failed.
I'm sorry, we haven't been properly introduce.
- Who are you exactly?
- My name is Lin.
My family has watch over the emperor's tombs for centuries.
The emperor can not be killed.
Unless he's stabbed to the heart with this.
My mother put a curse on it long ago.
Well quickly we're meeting Alex.
- Sit.
- Down.
- What do you really know about this girl?
- Not much.
But after I help to know her to go on a little faith.
- Faith?
- Time is running out.
-You don't  believe the concept of personal space, do you?
If the emperor reach the Shangri-La,
and drinks from the pool of eternal life,
he will raise his army, and no one will be save.
But as I like to say this boy can be handsome forever.
Shangri-La is a crock.
We heard that's you used to say about mummies too Johny.
You did pretty well.
The gate way to Shangri-La lies in a mountain pass, high in Himalayas.
Beyond it, is a golden tower
Once the diamond is placed to the top,
it would point way to Shangri-La.
Yang still has the diamond.
And that he and the emperor will go.
She's right.
All the legends of the eye mention the gateway.
I look her Alex.
She knows what worth.
No just say that we were to believe you.
Could you guide us there?
Yes, I've been there once.
I remember the way.
Himalayas, it's flying with the plane.
I know just the Mad Dog for the job.
Well a selfrespecting pilot that would land on a valley floor,
But I don't have any self respect,
so I put you down half of the mountain.
Still it will give us advantage.
But no guarantee anyone will live.
I tell you to fasten your seat belt,
but it's to cheap to buy on it.
Why are you me laughing?
Here we go!
Nobody move, nobody move!
What is it goat awful smell?
The yak, the yak.
Delta. Tango. Alfa. to Ricochet.
Come in Ricochet.
Delta. Tango. Alpha. this is Ricochet.
Go ahead Mad Dog.
You know that Yang valley you told me to keep eye for.
He is just shown up.
Ricochet out.
Thanks Mad Dog.
That's all people.
Let's go.
- John, wake up
- What?
Here we go more than half way, we gonna camp there for the night.
Lin said as we leave as first life, we reach the gate by noon.
Did she happened to mention to know so much about the gateway?
No, not really.
Kind of mysterious.
She sadly manage to enchant you.
Come on Alex.
You obviously like her.
Mom, if been down there.
Clearly messing with your head.
What of secret that she's hiding here
just don't want to see you get hurt.
I appreciate that.
You know.
I had my faith share experience with the opposite sex.
Really?
How many experience that we're talking about?
You shouldn't ask a question if you don't want to know the answer.
OK mom?
Right!
Hey, Mom.
Sorry I blamed you guys for raising the emperor.
What is so funny?
My mother has an impression there's something between us.
I hope nothing romantic.
Well I have totally no chance for that.
We completely opposite in you and me, right?
You guard tombs, I raid them.
You like ancient knives, I'm man in guns.
Those in our bloods.
- Absolutely.
- Well, good.
Now you focus to take down the emperor.
I agree totally
Besides, you're not my type.
Of course not.
You don't like a woman who can knock on your back side.
Expression, kick my ass.
For the record, you didn't
That's not easy being me.
Maar ik denk dat het voor jou hetzelfde is.
If I met a girl like you, Geraldine.
Yeah, hard work, and you don't say much.
A litlle bit hairy, but I don't mind that.
There it is!
We found it!
The cape lake Shangri-La.
Go, girl, go, go!
Free!
Go Geraldine!
We free!
What you to do now?
Rob an arbery?
Have you ever seen a Walter P-38?
I have this peacekeeper.
Well, this is not the best size, Dad.
The best stamina.
You want power?
I get you a Thompson's submachine gun.
50 rounds a drum.
25 a mag.
Thommy is good, Dad.
But the kocking mechanism always jams.
Here, check out the russian PPS personal saw weapon.
Now this is the future right here.
You know experience is who wins today it's not all about the fire power.
Boys, if I may?
Have we a plan for the emperor?
Ya, we gonna hit high hard fast and smash him like a Ming vas.
An if it doesn't work?
We go to plan B.
Plan B!
You go upstairs, you blow that gold tower thing.
You laid it up the body sky high.
Dad, if explossion doesn't kill us, avalanche will.
You got a better idea?
I said we ambush in the long way drive with silencer...
We can finish him off with Lin's dagger.
Look, I am sorry I just don't for much your girlfriend's magic dagger.
She's not my girlfriend.
- You say that now. When I still don't trust her.
Well I do. She trusted my judgement. Okay?
Look kid. I put down more mummies than you.
- You put down one mummy, Dad.
- Yes, say mummy, twice!
Hand me the green wire.
Will you, please?
- Are you sure you know what you are doing?
- Of course I've done this a houndred times.
If the emperor places the eye pair, all will be lost.
Let's give 'em up a warm O'Connells welcome.
Fire!
We've got take out the bazookas!
Now!
Move, move, move...
Time to go to plan B, blow the tower.
Hey, I am not actually concern about the plan B.
Can we go straight to the plan C?
Just back, and go back.
I cover you up.
Okay, let it go!
Come on! Come on!
My last ones
Yeti!
Where are you?
I need you!
Yeti! Come now, quick!
Appearable snowman?
The Tibetan called them Yeti.
She speaks Yeti?
Why do I always have to save the day?
Get the other guy!
You can die slow or you can die fast?
Ya! I did it!
Oh, man.
I did it.
Time to retreat I think.
I'm in your team.
I'm a team player!
One for all, all for me, kind of thing?
The dynamite, always dynamite!
We should
get out of here..
Wow, back off!
Back of!
I hate mummies!
They never play fair.
Dad!
What are you doing?
Over here!
Over here, come on!
Shangri-La!!!
That's a diamond.
I can use a diamond like that.
Dad!
Avalanche!
Help!
Help me!
Please, help me!
I'm fine, and I'm still alive.
Help me please, somebody help me?
We're here!
Mom, we're down here!
Oh my god.
We've got to take them to Shangri-La.
Now it's an only chance.
We've made it!
The pool!
Thank you.
You must rest.
We'll take you into my chamber.
Well it's not everyone that gets the brother all from the death.
Is this Shangri-La?
I can live here.
Lots of opportunity
A casino.
Now rest them all. Thank you.
How can you get involved in all of this?
The emperor murdered the only man I've ever loved.
Lin's father.
I would have died too by his hand...
...if the Yeti had not found me and brought me to this pool.
How old is this happened?
Is is before the Christ?
How long you've got in this tomb?
Over two thousand years.
The emperor must never be allowed to reach the pool.
Or he will have the power to raise his army.
Once he becomes immortal, he can transform himself
into the most hedious creature ever seen.
I will check the first watch at the entrance.
I have no problem dating an older woman.
I'm afraid we can't be together.
Why?
Because I'm gonna live forever.
I don't want to watch you die.
So what? That's it?
You just gonna see the sideline for eternity.
My mother has mourned of my father for the centuries.
I don't know if my heart can bear it.
People can live in entire lifetime if one want.
I want my parents to live everyday.
Alex, your father is awake.
In up here.
If this is heaven, it is pretty good so far.
Nice to see something has never changed.
Go easy on him, he feels terrible.
I saw you laying there, Dad.
I've never been so scared in my life.
Well, I'm get used two of us.
You supposed to die.
You know you're Ricochet O'Connell, right?
You beat up us around but you still stand in the end.
I really never thought a world without you.
The truth is
I am just trying ...
I am just ...
I am trying to be a good husband and I am trying to be a good parent
and the truth is I've been dropped the both.
I've been a world greatest's son.
I know it's good cause I  rise a family.
Come here.
My boys.
Oh, no.
His power has been fully restored.
Time to go.
He is immortal.
Hey you three any shape something son of a bitch.
He is taking her back to his tomb ro raise his army.
- Is there any faster way down from here?
- The Yeti. No help.
But he's already on the air.
It will be too late.
Mad Dog have quite three headed lizards anyday in the week.
Let's go
Foreside, at nine o'clock.
Should I quit drinking?
Jonathan to Rick.
You've better get move on if you gonna be to the tomb.
Just back here as fast you can reinforcement, not sight seeing.
Here, Dad.
Lent me?
Nice.
The terracotta army is not indestructible until  they cross the great wall.
How it exactly we supposed send them of?
When the emperor build the wall he buried his enemies
underneath then curses souls to hold it up eternity.
Most of them the conquered soldiers.
I will call them to battle once again.
My mark on altar, rise an army,  that sounds like a plan.
Let's go.
- Alex. Where he go?
- Where do you think?
Open the gate of the past and free the souls of the wrong who he's damned.
In the name of the ancesters and rightious,
I sacrifice my immortality and that's of my daughter
so that you may rise this day.
Bring down the rough of the oppressed on his emperor and all who follow him.
I call of the hundreds, and the thousands,
that you may rise up and seize this moment
to take your victory
to take your justice.
And to take your revenge!
These  are
your good dead guys, right?
Zi Yuan sent us.
Do we speak English?
We're with Zi Yuan.
It's coming.
Welcome in twentieth century.
I really hate mummies.
Run!
Die you mummy bastard!
Die!
There's no call for the bad language.
Have you regret, darling?
None, not ever.
- You OK?
- Yeah, sure.
No problem
We had completely under control.
This guy ever won a trick?
Mother!
No!
Mother.
Hit this through his heart
You must still live.
My daughter.
She said, through the heart
Through the heart.
Enough tricks!
Where is your honor?
Fight like a man.
Devide...
and conquere.
Now you can rule...
...in hell!
Evening girls.
Looking well.
Good evening Mr. Maguire.
You dance great for an old lady.
Someone told me to stop living on the sideline.
Well you sounds like the smart guy.
He is.
sha'll we dash, and have another aventure.
why write about it when you can live it.
there is somthing incredibly romantic about vacwishing  undead.
even more ramantic doing it with you.
kiss me.
you don't have to ask me twice.
no,no don't touch it
whire you of to sir
some place where there is no mummies
step on it igot a plane to catch
yes sir
Ciao-Ciao Shanghai,
Peru, here I come.
BE AWARE OF BOGUS SITES AND LAMERS
DOWNLOAD YOUR DUQA FILES FROM DUQA ACCOUNTS
http://www.torrentportal.com/account-signup.php?ref=798013
http://thepiratebay.org/user/DUQA-TEAM/
I HOPE YOU ENJOY THE MOVIE
PLEASE SEED TO HELP OTHERS
BY
BYE