As we pass
our New York City street,
please turn your attention
to the sidewalk up ahead.
Screen goddess Marilyn Monroe
made her very last
film appearance
standing on that spot.
Studio old-timers say
her spirit has been
seen there on occasion.
Well, let's see if she'll
put in an appearance
for us this morning.
Oh, well. I guess
she's too bashful.
How did I let you
talk me into this?
Oh, stop complaining.
Look, we got these free
VIP tickets from my agency,
and, well, at least I think
my agency sent them,
but anyway, baby,
didn't you want to ever do
all those silly Hollywood
things that tourists do,
like Wax Museum
or the Graveline Tour?
I did them when I first came to L.A.
in one day.
I can't believe we're
here without the kids.
How'd we get roped
into this anyhow?
I think it was that
architect's prize I won.
Remember that swag-bag
they gave us,
the ones with
the sunglasses you liked
that Alice broke?
I think
they were in there.
I'm just not in the mood.
Can we please
go back to the hotel?
Well, come on.
I hear the bus.
Let's go.
We can
still catch it.
Come on.
Get some speed on it.
Henry.
Just hurry up.
You can do it.
My feet
are killing me.
Why did you wear
the stilettos?
All aboard.
Watch your head.
Uh, conductor, is it okay
if we take pictures?
Please go ahead.
We encourage it.
Oh, no, no, no.
Not of me.
Nobody wants
to take my picture.
Ah. Thank you.
Hey, I know that guy.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I met with him
when I first came out here.
He worked in a bunch
of freaky little B pictures
back in the '60s.
Nobody's hired him
in years.
Really?
All aboard.
Wait!
All set. And away we go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the magic
and the mystery
of Ultra Studios,
where movie dreams
are born,
bloom, blossom,
wither, and die away.
Through this fence,
why, you can see the most
infamous set on the lot.
The legendary
House of Horrors
from Desmond Hacker's
Hysteria.
Um, can we go inside?
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, it's not safe inside.
We only open it
for special occasions.
Well, we're special,
aren't we?
I mean, this is
the VIP tour, right?
Says VIP on the tickets.
All access.
Mm-hmm.
Well,
I don't know.
It's against
studio rules.
Oh, come on.
Oh, please.
We won't tell anybody.
Come on.
Well, if you're all sure.
Absolutely.
Yes.
Okay. Max, open it up.
Let them in.
I tried to warn them.
Hysteria!
Can we go inside?
Yes, yes.
You can all come in.
Ah.
Watch your step, please.
Looks like somebody's
been sitting here
a little too long.
Look at this guy.
Raah!
It's a shame they don't
take better care of this place.
Yeah. That's
typical Hollywood.
No respect
for its own past.
Hey, can we
go upstairs?
Oh, feel free
to walk around,
but don't touch
anything.
Some of Hacker's effects
may still be working.
Okay.
Hmm.
Present.
Did you hear that?
No, I didn't
hear anything.
It came
from up there.
Andy, be careful.
Huh.
Nothing there.
Yeah, whatever.
Are you here alone?
No. I'm with my husband.
That's a shame.
Because I'm here alone,
and I thought
if you were, too,
we might hook up.
Excuse me. We haven't
been introduced.
Leo.
Julia.
Hmm. Your husband's
a very lucky man
to have
such a beautiful wife.
I've always loved
tall women myself.
They're such a challenge.
You work
at the Egyptian Theater
on Hollywood Boulevard,
right?
Yeah.
I book the films there.
I thought
you looked familiar.
I'm Andy.
I'm a screenwriter.
I loved the Mario Bava
series you put on.
Black Sunday,
Blood and Black Lace,
all that weird Italian
Gothic stuff.
I wonder
what happened to him.
I mean Desmond Hacker,
the guy who made Hysteria.
No one would work
with him after a while.
There were rumors
of orgies
and satanic rituals
at night on his sets.
He made millions
for this studio,
and then one day,
they just barred him from the lot.
After that,
he disappeared.
Maybe this is him.
Whatever.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Let's try this one.
Aah!
Are you okay?
Phoebe, honey,
there you are.
Where were you guys?
We were back there.
Found this crazy room
with decapitated heads.
It was really cool.
So how do we get back
to the main entrance?
We don't know.
We all came in through
different directions,
thinking that
was the way out.
Okay, Mr. Tour Guide,
this has been a lot of fun
and everything,
but can you get us
out of here now?
Uh, I don't know
that I can.
You sure as hell
can, buddy.
Come on.
You got a passkey,
a walkie-talkie,
something.
Stop it. You're
just scaring him.
Now please. Just think.
Which of these doors leads
to the front of the house?
Well, it-- it's not
as simple as that.
Do you remember
the plot of Hysteria?
All the characters
gather in one room
to tell horror stories
to each other?
Well, this is that room.
Uh--
Desmond Hacker had it built
on a rotating platform.
Once his actors were inside,
they couldn't get out
until he released them.
I think someone's
trapped us in here.
Honey,
where's your phone?
Damn it,
where's my phone?
Shit. Here it is,
here it is, here it is.
Listen, I suffer
from severe claustrophobia,
so if this is a joke
or interactive whatever--
Just breathe.
You're in for one hell
of a lawsuit, mister.
I promise you that.
Enough of this shit.
We're getting out of here!
No! Don't, don't, don't!
That's studio property.
Fuck this studio!
You were supposed to take us
on a crummy 45-minute tour,
not suffocate us
in some torture dungeon!
Shit.
This is the door we came in!
There's got to be a way.
Oh, what the fuck!
Wow.
That was quite a trick.
I warned you
before you came in.
All the effects
in this house are real.
Then why did you
bring us in here?
Well,
I tried to warn you,
but you all wanted
to come inside,
see the famous
spooky house.
Oh, so scary.
Look, I think we should
just calm down.
I mean, they'll realize
we're missing.
The  tram bus
is parked outside.
Somebody will come spot it
and come looking for us.
She's right,
isn't she?
Yes, it's, uh, possible.
What do you mean
it's possible?
Well, it could
take them a while
to figure out we're inside.
And the studio closes
in a few hours.
Oh. It could be tomorrow
before they find us.
Maybe there's another way out.
How?
You remember in Hysteria,
the mad undertaker
forces everyone
to tell horror stories
to each other.
Well...
maybe that's what
someone wants us to do.
Reenact the movie,
in essence.
You think
someone's watching us,
like they saw us
come in here?
It's possible.
Oh, stop saying that.
"It's possible,
it's possible."
You don't have a clue
what's going on here.
Why do you hate me so?
I-- I'm a victim here
just like you are.
Look, I mean,
why don't we just try it?
We can't break our way out.
She's right. Let's just
tell some scary stories
and see what happens.
Oh. Oh, no.
They-- They can't
be just any stories.
They have to be
personal, true stories.
Desmond Hacker forced his cast
to tell their own
most horrifying memories.
All right. Who is
going to go first?
I will.
I'm an actress, so I
don't mind the spotlight.
Phoebe.
Honey, I don't think
that's a good idea.
No, it's--
it's all right.
Um, actually, I've had
some pretty terrifying
experiences recently,
and-- You know what?
Maybe it's good
to talk about them.
Baby.
When I first came out here,
they said I was
a Heather Graham type,
and I thought,
well, that was good.
I mean, she was cute
and likable,
I wanted to be
cute and likable, too.
After all, Heather Graham
couldn't get
all the Heather Graham
parts out there.
At some point
I stopped being
Heather Graham,
and I started being
a Sarah Michelle Gellar type.
Then I was Alicia Silverstone.
Oh, and then Mena Suvari.
Thanks.
Uh, yeah. No.
I'm right by the--
Are you ready?
Yes.
Excellent. Come on in.
Yeah.
Uh, excuse me.
I was wondering if I was
going to be seen soon.
What's your name?
Phoebe. Phoebe Kane.
I thought you knew me.
I've been coming
in here for years.
Yeah. Uh,
I'm really sorry.
You should never
have been called in.
This part's for a 22-
to 24-year-old.
I can play that.
I'm 22 to 24.
Uh, ha, I'm sorry,
honey, okay? Thanks.
Yeah. No.
Go on in now.
God.
Are my eyebrows too thick?
Is my nose too big?
Do I need collagen?
That's why they
look better than me.
Hmm.
I'm so glad you didn't fall
for all that "Plastic surgery
is bad for you" crap, Ms. Kane.
Really, it's nice
to meet a young woman
who can think for herself,
who can weed out
the media-controlled hype.
Thank you, Dr. Weissman.
I actu--
Oh. Dr. Larry.
My-- My patients
call me Dr. Larry.
Oh. Um, I've heard there
are some risks involved
in breast enhancement.
Well, in the early years...
out of every 10,000
plastic boobs,
there would be one or two...
bad apples in the barrel,
medically speaking.
Oh!
God.
But we've learned
from our mistakes.
Silicone is bad.
Gel implants are bad.
I wouldn't put those
things in my body,
and I won't
put them in yours.
Um, then how do you
make my breasts bigger?
Here.
With these.
These are made from
reprocessed human tissue
from cadavers.
You mean from dead bodies?
Oh, I know it sounds gross,
but it's completely natural.
You have to think of it more
as an organ transplant.
I mean, most of them
are done from cadavers.
Oh, like in car accidents?
Exactly.
And I guarantee,
you will feel
that the breasts
have always been
a part
of who you really are.
So...
are you ready
for the new you, Phoebe?
You feeling all right, Phoebe?
You want
to go ahead with this?
Good girl.
Gas her.
Count backwards from 100.
100...
99...
98...
97...
6...
5...
4...
3...
Huh. When's the next one?
20 minutes, Doctor.
Ah, jeez.
All right, let's go. Come on.
¶
Okey-dokey.
Implants ready,
Doctor.
All instruments
sterilized, Doctor.
Geronimo.
Nice.
Whoo-ee.
Ooh.
May I have a cigarette?
A double scotch.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Sponge.
Pail.
Stitch her up.
Get her out of here.
Get the next one in.
I think I'm ready
for my close-up now,
Mr. Spielberg.
Ow.
What the hell?
Must be the goddamn ring.
About a month
after Dr. Larry's surgery,
I got a call from my agent.
He was calling to say
I got cast in a film
based on a sci-fi
TV series.
I couldn't believe it.
I mean, they actually
wanted me
and not some other girl.
Action.
Jesus. Five years
inside that hellhole
prison on Mars.
Ohh...
Staring at those
other two planets--
Ohh...
...dreaming about it,
what it would feel like.
Ohh...oh...
Aah!
Oh, my God.
Cut.
Zack, what's happened, mate?
She fucking bit me!
Oh! I'm--
Christ, look,
I got a hickey!
It's big enough to have
its own area code.
Fuck!
I-- I guess I got too excited.
Are we going
to do it again?
You're a fucking wildcat,
girl.
Yeah!
Woo-woo-woo!
Phoebe, darling,
could you just
take it easy on him?
Yeah...yeah...yeah.
Oh...ohh!
Ahh...
Ahh.
Ohh...
Zack, can I talk to you
for a sec?
It's nothing heavy.
It's just...
I can't believe how my life
has turned around.
I mean,
I'm actually working now.
I bought new furniture
for my apartment
for the first time.
I've even got a sex life.
I know this sounds stupid,
but...it's all
because of my boobs.
Did you hear me?
Zack?
Look at the size of them.
I wasn't making this up.
They hurt like hell.
I know, baby.
I got your message,
but listen,
it's all taken care of
because I got bug spray.
Rose-scented,
and ta-da!
Look at the bed, baby.
Tropical
mosquito netting.
Mm...Oh, yeah.
Uhnn! Uhnn!
Oh!
What are you doing?
Oh, my--
Aah!
No! Oh!
You're not going
to cut it off!
Ohh! No!
No! No! No!
You okay?
Stay away from me.
What?
What have you got,
some kind of freaky
fucking nipple ring?
No! I don't know
what happened!
Oh, my God, I'm
as scared as you are.
I'm fucking out of here.
What?
Zack, please don't go.
Oh, my gosh.
What is going on?
Oh, my God.
Dr. Larry, open up!
I need to talk to you now!
Oh, excuse me.
Do you know where
Dr. Weissman is?
No, honey, I'm sorry.
He hasn't been in
for over a month.
A month?
There's been some other
girls looking for him.
Are you okay, honey?
No. I need to find him!
I have a medical emergency!
Don't you have any idea
where he could be?
Well, you could try the
research facility in San Pedro.
It's 11270 Wharf Front Drive.
Wait. But--
Oh, yeah, wait--
1127, 1127, 1127.
Can I speak
to Dr. Lucy, please?
Ohh...
Oh...my...
Dr. Larry.
Aah!
What are you doing
in there, Miss Kane?
You'll catch
your death of cold.
Who are you?
How do you know my name?
I'm Dr. Lucy,
and these are my colleagues:
Dr. Judith...
and Dr. Charlotte.
Are you going to kill me?
Kill you? Heh heh.
Whatever gave you that idea?
Because you killed
Dr. Larry.
His body's hanging up there.
He made the unfortunate
decision
to operate on himself,
and when he contracted
gangrene,
he asked...that his body be
used for scientific purposes.
I'm afraid
you'll be his last
but finest creation,
Miss Kane.
You know what he did to me?
My breasts, they--
Feed on human blood.
Yes, we know.
We designed them that way.
I don't understand.
Why would you do this?
We are men of science.
We've spent our lives
trying to find ways
to extend human existence.
I mean, why should
people grow old?
You could say
that we've been looking
for the Fountain of Youth.
We developed
an artificial breast,
but rather than
producing milk...
these breasts will
feed off human blood,
thus restoring
vital energy to the body.
Haven't you noticed
how much younger and sexier
you've been looking?
Yes, but I thought it was
just my new breasts.
It's a new you, Miss Kane.
But I don't want
a new me.
I want the old me back
without these bloodsucking
tits you gave me!
I'm sorry.
I thought you understood.
The operation
is, uh, permanent.
You mean I'm stuck
with these...things
for the rest of my life?
We all are, Miss Kane.
Whew.
Mmm.
Oh, man.
That's a fucked-up story.
Excuse me for saying.
I have to ask, though,
do they...hurt?
Your--
Your breasts, I mean.
Are they...hungry?
Why are you all
looking at me
like I'm some
kind of a freak?
I'm not. I didn't ask
for this to happen to me.
Uh, Mr. whatever your name is--
It's Andy.
Andy,
you're her boyfriend.
Have you ever seen these
vampire tits of hers?
No, she won't show me
her breasts.
Andy.
Even when we're having sex,
she keeps them covered up.
Well, it's the truth.
I mean, I just figured
it was part of your
fucked-up whatever.
I don't know
what I thought.
No, no, no, no.
Just admit it.
You wanted some pussy,
and you'd believe any
bullshit she told you.
Honey--
Maybe we should just
move on, huh?
Who would like to share
their story next?
This is insane.
We should be
shouting for help
or banging on the walls
or something.
You want to bang
on the walls?
Go ahead.
Oh, great.
So we just sit here?
If you're so impatient,
why don't you
just tell your story?
You know,
I don't think so.
I-- No offense.
I am not in a sharing
mood tonight.
All right.
I'll tell them.
We were in Japan.
I'd dreamed of going
there for years,
and finally
the opportunity came up
to go to an architect''
conference there,
and I thought if I--
if I brought Julia
that maybe we could...
...put a little fire
back in our marriage.
I could see
how unhappy she was.
She'd given up her own career
when we had kids,
and it seemed
like a good chance
to get away,
just the two of us.
He says all he want
to do now
is go fishing
and drink beer every day.
The last time
he was in New York,
we had to order him
a six-pack of Guinness
for every meeting.
You're funny.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
May I please borrow
my husband for a minute?
Please.
You said something about
just the two of us,
idyllic
Japanese holiday,
X-rated sex.
At my last count,
it's us, 40 guys
in business suits,
and no X-rated nothing.
I know,
but some of these men
are plugged into some
of the most lucrative
building contracts
in the Pacific Rim.
I've got your Pacific
rim right here.
Well, this could
get embarrassing.
Okay, you do
what you need to do.
I'm sorry.
I don't speak Japanese.
Do you speak English?
Uh,
my husband Henry
is in the other room.
He's the man
in the Ken Iwasaki suit.
Uh, Ken Iwasaki
is a Japanese designer.
Do you know his work?
Anyway, I helped Henry
pick out the suit
at Barney's in New York.
Do you know you can just bring
your dog into that store?
It's amazing. All these
expensive clothes,
and you can just bring
your big, hairy dog
right into the store.
God, what am I saying?
I'm babbling.
Um--
Oh. Forgive me.
I haven't introduced myself.
My name is Julia.
Julia.
Yes. Exactly.
Seishin.
That's your name?
Well, um, I should go.
My-- My husband's going to
wonder what's happened to me.
Jigoku.
Julia.
Julia? Are you there?
Yes.
I'm up here.
Just checking.
Ahh.
Oh, look.
Oh, God.
Look at that.
Jigoku.
What did you say?
What's that?
Just a word
I picked up.
I can't run
in these shoes.
You can run in them.
My God.
I've seen you run before
when there's a sale
at Barney's.
I'm coming.
Julia.
Oh!
There's a man back there
at the temple,
and he's hanged himself.
The cemetery by the temple.
She doesn't understand
a fucking word we're saying.
Can you tell her?
I'm trying, Julia.
There's only a few phrases
of Japanese in my guidebook.
None of them happen to be
"I just found a dead guy
at the temple."
Um, look.
I'm going to draw it.
There. Do you understand?
Dead. Man dead.
Man? Dead?
Yes.
I am very sorry
that you had to see this
on your visit
to our temple.
Please, who was he?
He lived and studied here.
He was a member
of our order.
I can't tell you
much more than that.
Julia.
Henry?
What is it?
Nothing. I just
had a bad nightmare.
Mmm.
It's okay.
Julia.
Julia?
Julia!
Hi.
Have you seen my wife?
You, uh, my wife.
She'll be back.
Don't worry.
Great. Thanks.
Have you seen this woman
anywhere? My wife.
Have you seen her anywhere?
No, you haven't seen her?
I just want to see
if my wife left a message.
Julia, where are you?
Hi. Is the, uh, head--
head monk-- is he in?
Shoes.
Oh.
Hello.
My wife
and I were here.
We found the dead man
up in the cemetery,
and now
she's disappeared,
and I can't find her.
I remember her.
Very beautiful.
I will pray
for her safe return.
All right, well, then,
can you tell me
what this means?
Where did you get this?
My wife drew it.
I'm sorry, but this is
a matter for the police.
I'll be happy
to speak to them for you.
I want you
to speak to me.
Do you believe in hell?
These are the chambers
of Seishin,
the monk
who hang himself,
the one you found.
Jigoku.
Jigoku?
These pictures
show the road to hell.
I'm afraid this is where
he's taken your wife.
You said
you love your wife.
How much?
She means everything to me.
I can't live without her.
Go back to the cemetery
where you found the man
hanging.
There's a cave entrance
nearby.
You must go inside.
You must get her
to take this prayer
and swallow it.
Swallow it?
Hurry. The longer
she remains in there,
the less chance
that either of you
will come out alive.
Julia?
Julia, are you in there?
Henry, where are you?
Julia?
Henry.
Julia.
Oh, stop, Henry.
Please, stop.
I'm lost.
Lost.
Julia!
You can't stop me.
I'm lost.
Swa--
Swallow.
Eat this.
Julia. Julia.
I can't believe you told our intimate
family details to these strangers.
Look, you've been under a lot of
strain these last few months.
I was sexually molested
by a dead monk
and dragged into the mouth
of Buddhist hell.
I'd call that more
than a fucking strain.
I think we should all
just calm down a little bit.
- What if we can't get out?
- I want to go home...
What if whoever's out there
won't let us go?
Are you kidding?
This whole thing is
a crock of shit.
Probably half the people
here are in on the gag.
What are you guys
talking about?
Nothing.
Can I have a cookie?
No.
Perhaps you'd like
to tell your story then.
Me?
I have only one
scary story to tell.
It's about the best friend
I ever had.
He was a great director.
Maybe the greatest.
His name was...
Stanley.
Leo Herschel.
You know, I--
I saw The Strangler,
and I thought it had
a wonderful setup.
I have to hand it to anyone
who can make a--
a psychotic killer
out of Bobby Driscoll.
What's your name?
I'm Stanley.
Nice to meet you.
He'd seen a low-budget
thriller I'd written.
It was about a teenager who
pretended to crash his bicycle
so older women
would take pity on him
and let him
into their homes.
Then he strangled them.
Most people thought
it was sick and depraved,
but Stanley thought
it was a work of genius.
Turns out we had
a lot in common.
Both our fathers
were doctors...
...we both loved jazz,
and, of course,
we both came to Hollywood
to make movies.
I'd seen Stanley's films.
The first two were good,
but the one at the race
track was brilliant.
People were already
talking about him
as the next Orson Welles.
Hold on a second.
I knew he was a genius.
And then I found out
that he played chess.
¶
There was a girl
I had the hots for
back in New York.
A real brainy type.
She dragged me
to a screening
at the Museum
of Modern Art.
I was just hoping to get
some pussy, you know?
My idea of cinema was
anything with Alan Ladd.
Then the lights went down
and the movie started.
It was a French film
by a guy I'd never heard of,
Jean Vigo.
And within five minutes,
the world changed forever.
The shot of a young woman
in her wedding dress
walking along the barge.
I'd never seen anything
so unbelievably beautiful.
I was at
that screening, too.
I don't know how long
we played that first time.
- We talked about everything-
movies, women,
18th century literature
and warfare,
Dr. Joseph Goebbels,
the Irish Republican Army.
Stanley knew everything
about everything.
After that, we started to
play chess together twice,
sometimes three times a week at his house.
Check.
Hey, Stanley!
Sorry I'm late, buddy.
Traffic was hell coming
over the hill from Ultra.
Hi, I'm Nina.
You must be Leo.
Stanley said
you'd be coming over.
What'd you bring us?
I have been starving
all day.
It's like an oven in here.
Stanley!
If you're such
a famous director,
why don't you have
air conditioning?
Sweltering heat's
good for you.
It opens your pores,
frees the inhibitions.
If my inhibitions were any freer--
For some reason,
I never thought of Stanley
as a ladies man.
Yet there he was,
kissing one of the most
incredible women
I had ever seen.
He never said
where he met her...
and I never asked him.
¶
I have a 90-page script.
They want me to cut
another seven pages.
It'll end up being a
trailer and not a feature.
Thank you.
This obsession
with length
is killing creativity
in American movies.
I have a secret
idea, though.
I wanna make a film...
that's 24 hours long.
One entire day
of celluloid.
Hmm.
I don't know.
You mean you follow
somebody around
with a camera
for a whole day,
shoot them while
they're peeing,
sleeping, fucking?
No, that's, uh--
That's not exactly
what I had in mind.
I'm not sure that
simply turning
a camera on
some daily,
mundane behavior
is necessarily
worthwhile cinema.
I disagree.
I think Leo's idea
is kind of brilliant.
Imagine if you filmed
someone dreaming--
really dreaming--
instead of just pretending.
You could actually capture
the essence of their dreams
on film....
like a firefly in a bottle.
Wouldn't that be wonderful?
Yeah, we could try
it out on you.
But I don't sleep, Stanley.
You know that.
I just take little catnaps.
Well, that's impossible.
Everyone has to sleep.
Not me.
I'm a dedicated insomniac.
Why don't you
sleep over sometime
and see for yourself?
What?
You mean like a--
Ménage à trois?
Come on, you're a man
of the world.
Real lady-killer.
You must know
about these things.
Nina.
What are you doing?
Look at poor Leo.
He doesn't--
He doesn't know that
you're teasing him.
Come here. Come here.
I have to keep
an eye on you.
You sure you wanna
make that move?
I should have known then
that something was wrong.
Stanley never made a sloppy
chess move in his life.
¶
After that, I didn't hear
from Stanley
for almost a month.
Troubling rumors started
to go around...
that he turned in
a half-assed draft
of a script to Dore Schary,
that he wasn't
returning phone calls.
It seemed like
he wasn't even leaving
his house anymore.
¶
Stanley!
Stanley's not here...
but you're more than welcome
to hang out.
He's not here?
He called and told me
to meet him this afternoon.
I'm sorry.
He had to fly to New York
to meet on some
World War I project.
Well, that's just weird.
I don't see him
for a month,
then he asks me to come
over and disappears.
Uh, I guess
I should take off.
No.
Please stay.
We can have our own party.
You could teach me
how to play chess.
You're kidding me.
You're with Stanley and you
don't know how to play chess?
We miss seeing you.
Stanley said you were
too busy to come over.
Well, that's odd.
I thought you guys
were too busy to see me.
Well, to tell the truth,
we barely left the apartment.
I was pretty surprised
when Stanley told me
he was going
out of town.
You know, this is the first
time we've been alone together.
I was just thinking
the same thing myself.
So, tell me, teacher...
what is the most
important rule
about playing chess?
Well...
I guess it's to...
trust your gut instincts.
But also...
to control your emotions.
Well, that sounds like
a contradiction in terms.
I suppose it is.
The winner is the one
to make
the next-to-last mistake.
Hmm.
You go first.
I give up.
Mmm...
I didn't care that Stanley
was my best friend.
I didn't care
that it was his house,
his bed...
his girlfriend.
I just wanted to fuck her
more than I'd wanted
anything in my life.
And I knew
nothing could ever,
ever come between us.
¶
I lost track of the days.
At first I told
the studio I was sick.
Then I said
I had family problems.
Finally, I stopped
making up lies...
and told them they could
rewrite my movie
any way they wanted.
It's from Stanley.
You wanna read it?
No.
He says
the movie's going well.
He thinks Adolphe Menjou
is a commie-hating psychopath,
which makes him
just right for the role.
He doesn't mention
anything about us.
Why should he?
Because I wrote to him
and told him
we were sleeping together.
What?
Are you crazy?
Why would you tell him that?
Because it's the truth.
Stanley's never lied to me, and I
don't intend to start lying to him.
I can't believe you'd just
blurt that out to him.
"The weather's fine and, oh,
by the way, I'm fucking Leo"?
He's gonna hate my guts.
Well, if he does,
he doesn't mention it here.
He just says
once the movie's finished,
he's planning
on staying in Europe
permanently.
At some point, Nina vanished.
I don't know when she left.
I just know that
one day she was gone.
I realized that I didn't
know anything about her.
My only contact
with her was Stanley,
and he was in Germany
never to return.
I knew then that
I'd lost them both...
forever.
Somehow I managed
to pull it together
and write
a few more movies.
People called them
minor classics
of anguish and despair.
They don't know
the half of it.
But I know I never
forgot about Nina...
or Stanley.
I hadn't spoken to Stanley
in almost 45 years,
but I still felt like
I had lost my best friend.
I was almost as shocked
when I got a phone call
from someone at the studio
a few weeks later.
He left very
specific instructions
that you and only you
should be shown this
after his death.
He also left this for you.
Oh.
Projectionist
will start the reel
and return
when it's finished.
¶
This is my inner sanctum.
I spent much of the last
40 years in these rooms.
Some people said
I was hiding from the world.
It wasn't the world
I was hiding from.
There's only two things
I regret in my life.
One is Napoleon.
I realize now that
I'll never live
to make my movie
of his life.
The other thing
I regret is you.
There's no excuse for doing
what I did to you, my friend.
You probably thought
that you betrayed me
by sleeping with Nina.
But that's exactly
what I wanted you to do.
Somehow...
I knew my life was in
terrible danger with her.
At first, I--
I thought it was...
just a bad case of love
or lust.
But when I let you win
that day at chess,
I knew something
was terribly wrong.
Yes. I knew it, too.
I had to get away.
An idea came to me.
I knew that if I left
you alone with her,
she might turn
her attentions to you.
So...
I lured you
to my apartment that--
that afternoon,
and then I left town.
It was a few years later
that I started noticing
these images.
The subject was a witch
who was accused of drinking
the blood of her lovers,
so that she could gain
immortality.
It couldn't possibly be her.
But then-- then I found
the final piece of evidence.
These--
These reels
of nitrate film were
in the national archive
in Prague.
They think it was shot
in what is now Czechoslovakia
before 1900.
These are the only copies
in existence.
You are the only person alive
who might understand.
I hope you can forgive me.
Stanley...
What is it
with you, huh?
You can't just say,
"I'm a total pig.
I fucked
my best friend's girl"?
You've got to invent
some totally insane story
to justify the fact
that you can't keep
your dick in your pants?
I take back
what I said before.
Your husband
isn't a lucky man.
He's fucking cursed!
What was in the box, Leo?
The roll of nitrate film.
Only it was completely
disintegrated,
or I could have
shown it to you
and proved what I said.
We don't need proof
that you're a pig.
You just shut up.
Hey, hey, hey.
Shut up.
Whoa, whoa.
Cool it.
Don't you all see
what's happening?
It's just like the movie.
He's right.
We're starting
to attack each other.
Pretty soon we'll be
killing each other.
Okay.
Everybody's gotta unwind.
Just sit down and chill out,
or we're not gonna
make it out of here.
Well, I guess I'll tell
my story then.
But I'm warning you,
it's pretty grotesque.
As opposed to what?
It's about my twin.
My father's name
is Vincent.
He was born in France,
just like my mother.
They both moved
to the U.S. in 1972
when my mom's family
bought a vineyard here.
Martine was my mother.
She grew up
in a very big family
where everyone had ten kids.
Thanks. Very nice.
He was the most beautiful man
she ever met.
I think a lot
of other women
said the same thing
about him.
My mom was a tomboy.
When she was a kid,
she got expelled from school
three or four times.
Ooh.
My grandparents said to her,
"You're like a wild vine.
Why don't you grow straight?"
Maybe I work harder
if you don't put so many
beautiful things
in my way, huh?
Very good.
Very good, indeed.
It doesn't seem right.
All this work,
and look how quickly it goes.
Oh, yes, if you guzzle it
like cheap beer.
Try sipping it,
and you won't drink
all the profits.
If we live long enough to
see the profits, you mean.
Oh.
What are we breaking
our backs here for
when we had perfectly good
futures back in France?
Who wants wine
from America anyhow?
Maybe you should be thankful
for a minute, Vincent.
Look around.
These vines
that surround us all
with beauty and--
and nourishment.
And someday they will make
you kids feel free.
Speaking of which,
when are we going to see
a grandchild, huh?
Soon, we hope.
We've pulled the goalie,
so we shall see.
If we could only get a few
shots between the goal posts.
The wine is gone.
I'll get another bottle.
Dr. Bender
to the mental ward...
The tests confirm it.
You're pregnant.
That is a relief.
Vincent will be very happy.
Yes, but, um...
I don't know
how to say this.
What-- What is wrong?
You have something else
inside you.
A parasite, I'm afraid.
Taenia solium.
It's a tapeworm
in your intestine.
You must have gotten it
from eating undercooked meat.
What is it doing there?
We have to get rid of it
before it hurts the baby.
Well, that's the problem.
The only way to treat it
is with massive doses of iron.
And in most cases, the treatment
causes pregnant women to miscarry.
I do not understand you.
You are saying I have to--
You have to let
the worm grow...
with your baby.
It's the only way.
So we began life together,
the worm and me.
We were both dependent
on my mom for food,
warmth,
our survival.
She carried both of us
in her belly.
This smells good.
Mm-hmm.
Delicious.
Mmm...
I hate to ask,
'cause it's so awful,
but I can't help it.
Go on.
You are my best friend.
Can you feel it
inside of you?
I mean, the worm?
I know there is something
in there with the baby,
some alien thing.
I don't feel it moving,
but I know it does.
I wish it were dead
and out of my body.
But I can't kill it
without harming my baby.
Ever since I can remember,
I always wanted more.
Like the little boy
in Oliver Twist
with his bowl out.
I know why
I was always hungry.
Because the worm
was eating all my food.
Just go away.
I am not hungry.
Come on,
a few bites.
It is miracle food.
I made it myself,
so it is a miracle.
Just go away.
This is stupid. You are just hurting
the baby when you don't eat.
Are you deaf?
I said go.
Why don't you go
have sex with one
of my brother's
wife instead, huh?
Bitch.
My parents must have fought
a lot when I was inside.
I said go.
Bitch.
I wonder if it
affected the worm.
Yes, the worm was eating
all my food,
but we were also sharing
the same space.
If I suffered,
then he suffered, too.
Neither one of us
could escape.
I guess--
No, I'm certain
that after a while,
the worm became my friend.
But to my mom,
he was born from poison.
He haunted her
day and night.
If only she could
have seen us then...
side by side...
she might have
loved him, too.
A parasite, I'm afraid.
I know there is
something in there with the baby.
You have to let
the worm grow...
with the baby.
Baby?
It's trying to kill
my baby!
Vincent!
My father left
when I was two.
He ran off with my mother's
best friend Annie,
if you can believe it.
I became a tomboy,
just like my mother was.
But she knew better
than to ask me
if I would grow straight.
In 1986,
Mom fell apart.
She had never
gotten over things.
And when my father
married her friend Annie,
she slipped away forever.
Jump inside.
Go.
First her family fires you
from the vineyard,
and now they blame you
because their daughter
is a nut case?
I swear to God,
sometimes I think
that Martine is having
a nervous breakdown
just to get back
at me.
Can I have some
pretzels, please?
Of course you can.
The bowl is right there.
You don't have to ask.
Vincent.
Natalie?
Open up.
We do not lock our doors
in this house.
What were you doing just now?
Why did you take
all of those pretzels?
I keep finding
these piles
of uneaten food
all over the house.
I had an eating problem, too,
when I was your age,
and it was really
awful for me
when I was in school.
So maybe,
if you wanna talk
about it,
then you won't have
to hide food.
Okay?
Looking back,
I can't really blame her.
My father never got
her pregnant,
so she was stuck
with me,
a stepdaughter
she did not want.
In any case,
I wouldn't stop stealing food.
I needed it for me...
and for my twin,
the worm.
Wherever he was,
I knew he must have
been hungry, too.
...problem, too, when I was your age.
I think you have a problem.
Why are you hiding
all of this food?
It quickly became war.
At first she said she was putting
me on a diet for my own good.
But soon I realized
she was trying to starve me
for being
my mother's daughter.
Why are you hiding
all of this food?
Are you just gonna
let her kill me?
Well, are you?
It's hurting.
Oh, stop it!
Oh, God!
Stop it!
There's something inside her.
My wife.
No, I am not killing
my wife.
She's--
There's something--
Yes! I don't know what she ate!
Oh, my God!
Please come quickly!
When they operated, they found
her intestines were riddled
with little,
bite-sized holes.
Is she...dead?
No.
But she's lost
all her taste for food.
She's an invalid now.
Never leaves the apartment.
Strange thing is,
my dad stayed
married to her.
He's cared for her night and
day for the past 25 years.
I bet he wishes
she had died.
Probably wish it
on each other.
That's marriage.
Not our marriage,
of course.
Oh, bravo.
Congratulations.
Oh, you were
all magnificent.
Better than I could
ever have imagined.
What do you mean?
Oh.
Truly twisted and horrific.
And the way
you each made yourself
the victim
of your own story,
that was the most
horrifying thing of all.
I've never had
better performers.
It's you.
You led us into
this torture chamber
so we'd each tell
our story
for your amusement.
Oh, hold on.
Hold on.
Don't get so excited.
If you hurt me,
you'll never hear
how it all turns out.
Don't listen
to him.
He's a lying
little freak.
For once I agree
with you.
I'm sick of hearing
this guy talk.
Hold on.
What's the end
of the story?
Well...
you each left out
the most important part.
You, Phoebe.
Everything they say
about Hollywood
and your life changing
overnight
is totally
and completely true.
I really don't think
I like the way
they lit me
for this interview.
Sweetie,
what do you think?
I think that Marilyn
is just a beautiful
sex symbol, icon--
Pretty smile, though,
don't you think, sweetie?
At least I still
have you guys.
My babies.
Oh, Andy,
as long as you
still love us,
that's all that matters.
Are you guys ready
for a refill?
Okay.
Oh.
There you go.
Much better now.
What's he talking about?
Phoebe, honey?
I don't know.
Andy, I would
never hurt you.
I love you so much.
Come here.
And you, Henry
and Julia?
Hi.
I love you.
Oh...
No, that's not possible.
I brought her out of there.
We both made it out.
And you, Leo?
And you...
sweet Natalie.
This is sick.
Sounds like
a real psycho child.
What a piece of work.
She poisons
both her parents
and sits here
eating pudding.
Let her eat.
She'll get the death
penalty for this.
Fresh air.
It was getting
a little stuffy in here.
Let's go.
I'm outta here.
Let's go. Come on.
Watch your step, Julia.
Where is he?
I don't see anything.
Just keep moving.
Where is he?
Look, there's a door.
Oh, my God, Andy.
That's you.
Nothing there.
Jesus Christ.
We're never going
to get out of here.
Look at me.
I forgot my badge.
That soundstage
that we just passed
is said to be haunted
by the spirit of...
well-known screenwriter
Leo Herschel,
who blew his brains out
in despair.
And if you look
to the left,
well, you may catch
a glimpse
of that lovely film actress
Phoebe Kane,
who died
of lethal injection
after murdering
her boyfriend
and draining
his body of blood.
Oh, and let's not forget
Miss Anjou...
who fed poisoned wine
to her father
and stepmother
and then slit her wrists...