Put your right hand over your heart.
Ready? Begin.
I pledge allegiance to the flag...
of the United States of America.
The cries of pain.
The shattered lives...
the devastation.
Maybe we as a people
have gotten too used to the wars...
that we have seen in the movies.
Because in this footage,
it becomes terribly apparent...
that there is
no triumphant music...
there is no victorious hero.
There is only the horrible
reality of human suffering.
This war isn't glamorous
or romantic.
It is rather a brutal reminder
of the violence...
that man is capable of.
And it leaves little doubt
in this reporter's mind...
that this war,
and perhaps all war...
is undeniably evil.
Take this down. That's a girl.
I split it in half,
so there's one for tomorrow.
That's a girl.
When California Governor
Ronald Reagan was asked today...
about his opposition to the proposed
expansion of Redwood National Park...
his response was- and I quote-
"A tree is a tree.
How many more do you need to look at?'"
In other news, censorship-
Hello. Yeah, okay.
Look, look, I 'm on the way.
I 'm on the bloody way!
Come on, son.
We gotta go. Come on.
No more logging!
Go home, murderers!
You're all murderers!
Get out of here!
This land isn't yours!
No more logging! No more!
You're murderers, all of you!
Don't deny it! You're killin' trees!
What do we got here, Burt?
They just keep coming back. How
are we supposed to do our job?
We're gonna have to go through 'em.
All right, you heard him.
Let's do it.
You're all murderers!
Do you know why we fall these trees?
To build houses.
Houses for families.
I don't give a damn about
you or your families.
Look, my wife is sick.
She needs medication.
And if she doesn't get it,
she's gonna die.
And you're making it impossible
for a man to do an honest day's work.
If your wife has to die
to save these trees...
so be it.
You-
Who's gonna save you?
You son of a bitch!
You okay? You okay?
Yeah. I-
He's got a gun!
Hold on! Hold it right there!
Everybody just calm down.
Let me take that.
- Come on. Come on.
- He hit me first.
- He started it!
- You're gonna go with me.
- Goddamn it! Can't a man work anymore?
- I gotta run you in.
- Daddy!
- It's all right, lad. It'll be all right.
We're gonna stay here until
we get the petition to save these trees!
Yeah? And what is that petition
made out of? Paper, you moron!
- Paper from trees!
- Not from trees...
that were around
before the birth of Christ!
No!
No! No!
No! Let him go!
I'll kill every one of ya!
I swear to God,
I'll kill every last one of ya!
Dad!
And the home of the free -
- - Brave - -
Mmm. Creamy goodness.
Should he be driving?
No. I'll drive.
It's the drugs that hold
Joey together.
- Right, burly man?
- Oh, yeah.
- Here.
- No, thanks.
Sam, see the nest
up there at the top of that tree?
Oh, yeah.
That's the nest of an
American bald eagle.
Hey, Captain. Hard to starboard.
I need to take a bio break.
- Me too.
- Aye, aye, mates.
- Here you go. One-stop shopping.
- Ew. Come on, dude.
It's dripping!
Ivan, you man the cannon.
Samantha steadies the aim.
Joey, look out!
Whoa.
- What the fuck was that?
- I think it was a dog.
- Really? I hate dogs.
- How could you hate dogs?
It's probably gone now.
Ladies' room to the right,
big boy.
- Jack, come with me.
- Sorry, babe. I'm afraid of dogs too.
Oh, you're such a chicken shit!
- Someone's giving you a hummer.
- What?
Your phone. Who's calling?
Uh, nobody.
Are you hanging in there?
Yeah, I guess. As long
as Jimmy's not around, I'm fine.
Hey, this is gonna
be great for you.
Yo, guys. Watch out
for booby traps.
- Watch out for what?
- Booby traps.
What? Where?
What fuckin' booby-
I've been hit!
Dude, you all right?
Ow, fuck!
Let me see. I gotta make
sure there's no glass in it.
Who the fuck were those guys?
I don't know, but we gotta
be careful out here, man.
The pot farmers catch us in their shit,
they'll chop our balls off...
and use 'em as fertilizer
for their crops.
Sounds like the perfect spot
for an outdoor music festival.
Ow! Jesus Christ, Samantha!
I didn't mean to.
- I didn't mean to.
- It hurts.
I could sew that shit
up for you, if you want.
What?
I have some needle
and thread in here.
Just run a lighter over it.
It's all clean.
- No, thanks, man.
- Do it, pussy!
- That shit will be sick.
- That shit's nasty.
- Do it.
- I'll do it.
Rambo style.
You're bleeding
and it's really deep.
We need to get
some disinfectant.
Go get me some of that whiskey.
Yes. Rambo.
Rambo! Rambo! Rambo!
Who's Rambo?
Okay. Do it.
Whoa!
I'm Rambo. I am Rambo.
Ah, fuck!
I can't watch, man.
I feel light-headed.
Yes!
My fellow Americans...
major combat operations
in Iraq have ended.
And the battle of Iraq-
You know, he's not just
the greatest American president...
he's just-
Wow.
- Asshole tried to piss on my head.
- It's sterile.
Yeah, thanks.
I'll get some medicine.
- Pee-pee party.
- You want to get high?
- Yo.
- Oh.
What's wrong with her?
She seems kind of damaged.
- Who, Sam?
- Yeah.
- She's going through some shit right now.
- Like what?
- Ivan didn't tell you guys?
- No.
She wasn't always so tweaky.
She just got out of
a really fucked-up relationship.
Oh, my God.
This ecstasy is really strong.
You're candy flipping.
We took "X" and acid.
Acid too?
You know that liquid stuff
that we put on our tongues?
That wasn't mouthwash.
Jimmy was her old boyfriend.
A rich, spoiled brat
who couldn't handle being dumped.
And apparently he wasn't used
to not getting his own way.
Samantha!
Jimmy? What are you doing here?
- Jimmy, please.
- Excuse us.
Jimmy.
- Are you fucked up? Are you fucked up?
- No. No!
- Did you give her shit?
- Fuck off, Jimmy!
You don't tell me to fuck off, pig.
What did I tell you, Samantha?
What did I tell you?
This cunt is bad news!
- Fuck you, asshole!
- Why are you so angry?
Why am I so angry?
Sam had never tripped before.
So when Jimmy flipped out, she lost it.
I ask you to stay.
You fuckin' leave.
I don't get it.
I fuckin' love you!
- I love you, Samantha.
- No.
You're making a fool of yourself.
You don't love me.
- Help!
- Drugs are killing this fucking nation!
- Somebody help!
- Destroying your brain.
Frying out!
I fucking love you!
Shit.
You break it, you buy it.
Jodie Foster was great in that.
Jodie Foster wasn't in that one.
Linda Blair was in The Exorcist.
Yeah, The Exorcist. The priest.
And the possessed demon was Regan.
Yeah, but it wasn't
President Reagan.
I could see how
you could get it confused.
Hey, beer.
- It has to last.
- Hey, where's Sam?
- She's inside.
- Go get her. Chop, chop.
- Chop, chop.
- All right.
- You heard him, man. It has to last.
Sam?
Easy, tiger.
Whoa, dude.
Yo, man, that's the truck!
That's the truck from-
Come on. Let's go.
- You sure are cranky.
- You keep talkin' shit.
The rednecks just
pulled up in the truck.
- What?
- The dude who threw the bottle at ya.
What's the matter with you, dude?
You got something stuck in your vagina?
Yeah, your mama's dick.
- What the hell is that supposed to mean?
- I don't fucking know.
Good morning, Spike. Coffee-
I wanna fucking
kill these guys, man.
You might not wanna
do that, bro.
There's three of us,
there's three of them.
I'm a lover, not a fighter.
Plus, it's a well-known fact
that rednecks love their guns.
That's the motherfucker
I hit with the bottle.
- Don't be a pussy.
- I enjoy being a pussy.
- We should just leave.
- Yes.
Hey, you toothless, redneck pig fuckers,
you want some trouble?
Huh?
'Cause my buddy here
was just wonderin'.
Who?
This-
This John Lennon-lookin' fella here?
He wants to fight?
- Thanks a lot, Joey.
- No problem. Bust a Jihad on his ass!
- Shh.
- Ivan.
- Whoa.
- What's going on?
Tell these guys
we don't want any trouble.
But your boyfriend here
is looking for trouble.
What do you expect?
- You threw a bottle.
- Hey, I thought that you deadheads...
believed in flower power
and shit.
Yeah, make love, not war.
Come on now. Just turn your scrawny
ass around and snuggle up to Yoko there...
- before you collect yourself a U.S.D.A.
- choice ass whoopin'.
- Stupid motherfuckers. Bring it on.
- You asked for it.
Oh! Not the knife, Muff.
Let's make us
some veggie burgers.
Whoa!
- Kick his ass!
- I'll kick your ass, bitch!
Come on, baby.
Let's kiss and make up.
Get off me!
Jesus, Muff. Settle down. Shit.
Holy shit.
What a pussy!
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Hello? Hello?
Samantha?
Samantha!
I know you're there. I know you're there!
Talk to me. Samantha-
I can't believe you'd fucking
do this to me. You're such a bitch.
- You are such a fucking bitch!
- Gus?
Goddamn it, Gus.
Get your ass out back...
and finish cleaning those grease traps
before those mangy dogs get at 'em.
- I fucking love violence!
- Shit, girl. Now I need another hit.
Goddamn! Ivan, your girlfriend is badass!
You know what I'm saying?
See that shit?
She got Clubber Lang on his ass.
- Who?
- Mr. T. Clubber Lang?
- Rocky?
- I pity the fool who don't know me.
- I didn't know you had that in you.
- You don't know shit.
I don't know why I stick it to you,
'cause you don't know shit.
Because I'm fine! That's why.
Gentlemen, there's a saying:
"Rome wasn't built in a day."
I got a little saying of my own:
Fuck Rome. This is America!
We can do whatever we please.
Some of you look a little worried.
Don't be.
We'll be out of here
first thing Monday...
and your precious little forest
won't be any the worse for wear.
Well, Mr. Baker, yours is certainly
an impressive enterprise.
Please call me Frank.
Well, it's just that... there's a couple
of concerns regarding, uh-
What, gate receipts,
profit sharing?
Fatalities.
Didn't some people die
at your festival last year?
I don't believe
we've had the pleasure.
Well, Mr. Baker, I'd like
to introduce you to...
Officer Buzz Hall, the town
of Carlyle's de facto peacekeeper.
De facto?
Our current fiscal crisis
doesn't allow for much of a staff.
Well, then you are
specifically Carlyle's finest.
Well, yes, he and Deputy Cooper.
Plus, there's a very strong park
ranger's force to help out with traffic.
Fan-fucking-tastic.
There are still some concerns however.
Buzz?
As I recall...
someone, uh, on drugs
was trampled at your festival last year...
when they couldn't get
to an exit.
A tragedy.
But I beefed up security this year.
I heard they're the ones
that did the trampling.
Well, then I can consider us lucky to have
you and yours to keep us safe this year.
De factoly speaking, of course.
What about the girl?
- What girl?
- The one who disappeared.
Buzz, you know how many kids
go runnin' off...
to follow the Grateful Dead
and whatnot.
- Jerry's dead.
- What?
Jerry Garcia is dead.
The Grateful Dead's no more.
She could have run off
with some other jam band.
Yeah. She could be, uh,
following the Phish.
Yeah, Phish broke up too.
Well, it concerned the folks
in Humboldt enough to shut you down.
That's why you're here in Carlyle,
isn't it, Frank?
- Buzz, can I have a word?
- Sure.
- How ya doing, son?
- Been better, been worse.
Uh-huh. Well, I know it. I do.
And I also know that this festival's
got your judgment a little clouded.
My judgment?
Now look-see.
What do you see?
I'll tell you what I see.
I see jobs, son.
And that's just the shot
in the arm this little lumber town needs.
Not all shots
are good for you, Mayor.
Buzz, I need to know something.
Can I count on you to help pull this off?
You can count on me
to do my job.
Just like I did yesterday
and just like I'll do tomorrow.
Is that a regulation length
mustache, Buzz?
Welcome to Free Love Festival...
where America's best and brightest
come to celebrate-
Freedom?
Yes, freedom to do
drugs-lots of fuckin' drugs!
- Yes!
- Speaking of which...
we have coke, we got speed...
we got a decent amount
of the purple hydro, buddy.
And we got some of these pills
Jade took from her mom's pocketbook.
Beer in the back. And
what do we got up there?
Looks like about
a half a sheet of acid left.
- That's it?
- You don't think that's enough?
Well, you see, Samantha,
we are professional drug takers.
Yeah, don't try this at home.
Sam, don't worry.
It's not just about drugs.
The Free Love Festival
is a really great concert...
where peace-conscious people
gather and talk about...
all the shit this government's
trying to pull, you know.
What the fuck
are you talkin' about?
She's talkin' about George W.
Going into Iraq...
and sucking the cocks
of all the corporate interests.
Thank you.
Shut the fuck up. George
Bush is the greatest.
The man's got balls.
Big Texas-size balls.
Probably the first man in history
to ever tell the whole world, "Fuck you."
I could do what I want,
and there ain't shit you can do about it."
George Bush is like the worst president
this country's ever had.
Yeah.
You're just saying that 'cause
George Bush hates black people.
You're absolutely right.
Whoa! What's that noise?
Ah, shit.
- What the hell!
- You okay?
Jesus Christ!
Dude, there's a fuckin' tree in the road.
Get outta here!
You're not wanted here!
This is the last time
I'm gonna warn you
commie, pinko bastards.
Joey, don't go near him.
I'm not.
It's the paper towel lumberjack guy.
Hold it, hold it.
Hold it right there, Dylan Riggs. Jesus.
- Holding on. Roger that.
- Step back, please, please.
This maniac just tried to kill us.
Dylan, what is your problem?
You could have crushed these kids.
They're my problem-
you and these rainbows.
This ain't their goddamn forest.
Goddamn it!
It's not your forest either.
You know, I could haul your ass in...
for felling this tree,
you crazy S.O.B.
This tree was tagged by the power company
on account of it's infested with beetles.
And I am subcontracted
to take it out.
Funny.
You picked today to do it, huh?
Get this tree outta here.
Clear it before I remove you.
All right, first of all, is anybody hurt?
We're fine.
But you're just gonna let him go?
What kind of backwards
fuckin' town is this?
This is my town, son, okay?
And I'd appreciate it if it were
treated with a little more respect...
from those that live here and from those
that are just passing through.
Sir, will you spank me?
My father never spanked me.
I'm in desperate need
of discipline.
You think it's a joke? Every year, four
or five of you kids get killed up here...
driving yourselves into redwoods
or get paralyzed sucking on nitrous...
or blow yourselves up
cooking meth.
You think you're invincible.
You're not.
Sir, I'm sorry
to make your job more difficult.
I was wondering if Methuselah
could direct us to the nearest paddy wagon.
We'll see what kind of a goddamn jig
you can do without your fuckin' legs!
All right,
why don't you guys get outta here now.
Or do I gotta search that van and see what
kind of trail mix you got hiding in there?
Would you like that?
Local problems?
Nothing we can't handle.
You just take care of your
end of things, Mr. Baker.
Oh, I will.
- Mr. Mayor.
- Call me Hal.
Hal, that's a beautiful pin you got there.
How do I get one?
You earn it, Frank.
It's gonna be
an interesting weekend.
That water felt so good.
Mmm, water's good.
I think I'm gonna go pick some mushrooms.
You wanna come?
No, I think I'm gonna
go lay down for a little bit.
Okay.
- I won't be long. Okay.
- Okay.
Hey, Mr. Rabbit.
Come here, little guy.
Mr. Rabbit, come here.
Come here, buddy.
What is this place?
It used to be
an old logging tunnel...
before these radical
environmental hippies blew it up.
When they were building
this place...
apparently 200 Chinese workers died
when they hit a gas pocket.
And they buried 'em
in a mass grave right over there.
Mr. Rabbit?
Don't worry, Mr. Rabbit.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
Who's that?
Is that you, Mr. Rabbit?
Ooh, chantrelles.
Ivan, look.
Whoa.
It's old Deuteronomy.
He's got a pimpin' fur coat, though.
- Pretty sweet.
- Where's your hooptie ride?
We didn't mean to disturb you.
I'm not disturbed.
This is not my forest.
You like some old-school hippie, like,
nature's for everybody and nobody owns it?
Yeah, you could say that.
But you better be careful
if you go out in these woods.
You never know
what you're gonna find.
- You mean, like, Bigfoot?
- No, he's not dangerous.
It's the traps the weed growers set
is what you better watch out for.
I told you motherfuckers.
- Knowledge.
- It's true.
People disappear
all the time out here.
- What do you mean? Why?
- Because of the weed.
Locals don't like anyone
fucking with their stash.
Hey, check it out!
Hello!
Come on down.
We're having an orgy.
- Bring beers.
- Dude, it's those redneck fuck holes!
- Ow!
- Whoa! Whoa! Duck and cover!
- Assholes!
- Go, go, go!
- Shit!
Tuck and roll if necessary!
Hey, dog. Come back here, man.
Worthless mutt!
I thought I told you
hippies to stay out of the forest.
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Hey, don't bogart all the coke,
my friends.
- I was kind of talking.
- You're always talkin'.
I was saying how happy I was
that everyone came out here.
I know things started
off a little weird, but
I think this trip's
gonna be a lot of fun.
- Amen to that.
- Yeah.
Know what I think would be fun?
If someone finds
that pot field that guy
was talking about.
Oh, yeah.
It's the lucid moments
that cut through the haze...
that make bringing Joey
along worthwhile.
I'm just glad that cop
didn't find my coke.
I don't know what I would
have done without it.
Probably speed.
Anything to keep you from eating.
- She's on the cokehead diet.
- Go fuck yourself!
- Baby.
- I would if I could.
- I'd fuck myself every day silly.
- I bet you would.
You're nuts, Joey.
Before you were talking about booby traps,
and now you wanna go into the weed fields?
I can get through 'em, sir.
I mean, bobbing and weaving
like stealth bomber style.
Bobbing, weaving,
tucking, rolling.
Necessary.
Necessary tuck and roll.
- Samantha?
- No, thanks.
- Just being polite. "I" man?
- No, I'm good.
Okay, more for me.
- You've had enough!
- There's never enough! Back up.
Come on.
Honey-
With that last toot, I'm gonna go
draw up some plans to find that wild ganja.
Jah, "Rastafaria."
You tired?
You wanna go to sleep?
You could have had some
if you wanted.
I want some of you.
Give me some of that.
I hope it doesn't get
too overwhelming.
All those people wasted.
It sounds like it could be a nightmare.
You gotta stop worrying, Sam.
You're just scared 'cause of
that bad trip you had with Jimmy.
Don't be scared.
Don't be a scaredy cat.
Anyway, you'll be straight,
and I won't do anything too mind-altering.
I'll, like,
smoke a little weed...
have a couple beers,
and that's it.
- All right?
- Really?
I promise.
I got a surprise for you.
Be right back.
Sam -
- Was her name -
- And for only one brief moment -
- She fell into my lap-
- Seems she had everything I wanted-
- In a girl-
- She paints her nails like my guitar -
- She played it
and that was the start -
- She danced like a wicked angel -
- She danced to the beat of my heart -
- Whoa, oh-oh -
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa -
- She told me you have pretty eyes -
- And I told her your eyes
were what I first noticed -
Then she said that's so cheesy -
- I told her it can't be all that cheesy -
- If it's true-
- She didn't like my music-
Ivan! Ivan.
Get away from me!
Damn. I'm just
getting some crunchies.
Did you see anybody strange around?
Yeah, there's weirdos
all over the place.
- He said he'd come right back.
- How long's he been gone?
- Since yesterday around 3:00.
- Excuse me.
Hold on. Well, if he's still missing
by the time the show's over...
I'll send someone out
to look for him.
My boyfriend's lost in the woods
and he won't even do anything!
Calm down. He's probably just-
Passed out somewhere.
Maybe if you told me
what kind of drugs he was on-
- Fascist pig!
- What did she call me?
Why won't you help her?
She thinks that he's lost out there.
I don't care if she thinks Mickey Mouse
is a goddamn kitty-cat.
I'm not going out in the woods hunting for
some hippie who got lost picking flowers.
He's probably in one
of these tents somewhere...
banging some other
big-bushed granola-eatin' broad.
How can I help you?
I think somebody's following me.
Buzz, you there?
I'll be right back. I promise.
- Buzz? Buzz?
- Yeah, go for. What's up?
We need you at the
north end of the river.
It's a bad scene, man.
All right, let him down.
Looks like the critters got to him.
Mighty big critters.
I guess I'll write up a report.
- Bring it down. Easy, easy.
- I got it.
Looks like an accident. You think?
Well, I don't think
he did this on purpose, Cooper.
Fuckin'-A.
I don't see any drugs.
Watch your feet. Watch your feet.
Where's Joey?
Come on. Come this way.
Come this way. It's a real fuckin' smash.
Beer! Beer!
Anyone know where
I can get some fuckin' beer?
- Nitrous.
Nitrous. Nitrous.
- Damn, girl. Watch where you're going!
- Sorry.
What's up? Where you heading?
Weed, shrooms, acid, "X"?
Shrooms, acid, "X"?
What the hell are you doing?
Howdy, Mayor. How's it hangin'?
Oh, do not give me nice, Buzz.
You just shut down half the forest.
And for what?
Because some fuzzy nudist
got himself strung up on a snare?
No, the body was attacked.
It could have been a mountain lion, a bear.
Or, uh, hmm, maybe it was Bigfoot.
There is a line of vehicles
stretching two miles back...
and they're aimed at that campsite.
And here are your instructions.
You are going to let them in.
You are gonna see to it that they are safe
and you're gonna keep it that way!
You, uh, want me to open the road up?
Come on.
And listen to an elected official?
Aren't you an elected official?
Just shut down the roads, Cooper.
And, uh, make sure the park rangers
know to not let anybody else in.
Hey, Buzz,
you think, uh, it could be...
Bigfoot, like he said?
Not unless Bigfoot
likes black jelly beans.
- You look funny this close.
- Don't I look funny from back there?
You always look funny. Strange.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit, I'm starting to feel it.
Samantha's gonna freak
if she finds out.
It's no big deal.
You only took a half a hit of ecstasy.
- It's not like you're shooting "H. '"
- I know.
It's a big deal to her, though.
She's gonna fuckin' know.
Don't worry, sweetie.
You know she loves you.
Really?
Does she?
Joey?
- Whoa!
- Sorry.
Uh, have you guys seen
Linda and Joey around?
Uh, Linda isn't in here, honey,
and, uh, we're gonna be a while.
Don't you know the golden rule?
I f the van is a-rockin',
don't come a-cock blockin'.
Do I look fucked up?
- Yes.
- How do you feel?
Well, I feel great.
That's all that matters.
- Linda?
- Samantha.
I didn't know where you-
Linda, can I talk to you
for a second?
Sure, sweetie.
Fuckin' amateur.
Look at you.
That's beautiful.
- I saw his car and I saw a cigarette butt-
- Jimmy's not here.
- Yes, he is here.
- No, no, baby, baby, he's not here.
Believe me, he's gone.
He won't get you.
Okay?
Linda!
Linda! Linda!
Come here.
I've got something to show you.
Oh, I wonder what that could be.
- Wait for me.
- But they said not to go into the woods.
Quiet down, Jesus!
Afternoon, Officer.
What can I do for you?
I was, uh, hoping
we might have a word.
There's been some trouble
I need to talk to you about.
You're not shittin'?
No, sir, I am not.
Festival grounds, north side of the river.
A flower child stepped in a snare
and got strung up in a tree.
Now, you wouldn't have any idea
who set that trap, would you?
You got a search warrant, Buzz?
No, sir, I do not.
But I can go get one.
I've been meaning to see what kind of crops
you got growing back there anyway.
I don't think
you understand, Buzz.
I don't hate 'em because they came here
for some goddamn concert.
No, I hate 'em because they ruined my life.
They made it
so people think that...
a goddamn tree is more important
than a human being.
And they took my wife.
And they took my boy.
I understand that.
It's just I got a...
dead body on my hands.
And I don't need another one.
Well, I didn't kill anybody.
I'm not saying you did,
but... I'm thinking, Dylan...
that I'm gonna have to lock you up for a
little while, just till the concert's over.
Now, it's for your own good.
Uh, or I-
You could show me
where the rest of those traps are.
Well, I guess I could do that.
But I still think
you authority types...
are protectin' the wrong people.
The government's got laws
that help corporations...
and activists.
Yeah, but who's out there
looking out for the little man?
Huh?
Well, some people say that the government's
looking out for the greater good.
Yeah? Well, that depends
who's in charge of the government.
You know...
Ronnie Reagan,
God rest his soul...
he had a theory
about jelly beans.
Yes, sir. He would keep
a big bowl of them on his table.
And he'd watch people
when they took some.
What would he watch for?
Well, he said
there were two types.
Those who reached in and grabbed a handful
willy-nilly and didn't care what they got...
and those who went in
with an agenda.
Those who were-how do you say-
more... tactical.
You, uh...
show Cooper the rest
of them traps, all right?
Stick around this weekend.
It'll be over before you know it.
Much obliged, Sheriff.
Cooper, Cooper.
Coop, you there, buddy?
Coop?
Go for Cooper.
I need you to come up
here to Ruby Ridge...
and collect some of Dylan's
hippie traps, and keep an eye out too.
I don't think he's gonna show
you where all of 'em are.
I'm gonna get you.
You're gonna get it.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Shit, if there was a trap,
I'd go, "Hell, yeah."
Oh, bud, you're scared of
titties if they're too big.
Yeah. Your mama's titties.
My mom has good tits.
You gotta admit that.
She does.
What do you say we play a little
hippie-hippie-bang-bang?
Linda!
Linda! Come here, girl.
Kitty, kitty. Here, kitty.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty-
Pussy! Pussy, pussy.
Come on, Linda!
Come on! Pussy! Good pussy!
Joey?
Joey, I'm here.
Joey!
Joey, I'm here!
Joey.
Joey? Quit screwin' around.
Joey?
I think we just found
the Garden of Eden!
You have just found
a weapon of mass destruction.
- Shut up.
- Okay, I can do that.
Oh, just like that.
- Ow! Fuck, I'm shot!
- What?
- Fuck!
- Oh, fuck!
Oh! I'm fuckin' bleeding!
What the fuck!
- Come on!
- Motherfucker!
It's paint!
They're shooting paint balls at us!
Baby white boy was gettin'
his penis sucked on.
- Let's go get a closer look.
- Shh!
Damn it! Hank!
I dropped my paint balls.
Where in the fuck are they?
They're not fucking here.
No shit, Sherlock.
Somebody's wantin' to play games.
Playin' a little hide-and-seek
with the big bad wolf.
Got you, bitch!
- Fuckin'-
- Get this freak off me!
I said come on, motherfucker!
Oh, fuck!
Hurts, don't it?
What the fuck's your problem, man?
Come back, girl!
I'm not gonna hurt ya.
I just wanna talk.
Shit!
Holy fuckin' shit! Help me!
My leg! Oh, fuck!
Please help!
Bears! Oh, bear trap!
Fuckin' help!
Oh, fuck! Please help!
Well, Nancy...
you know young people today.
No respect for anything.
Nancy!
What are you doin'?
Get out of here!
Come on. Bag huffer. Come on.
Come on, ass sucker.
Busted! Here you go.
Put your hands out. Put your hands out.
Fuck! I am startin'
to come down, though.
Maybe I didn't take enough.
Dude, quit bein' such a bitch.
Take some more. This is good shit.
It's not speedy at all.
Nice and clean. Make you feel very cozy.
I don't know.
Do we have anything to drink?
No. Come on, dude.
Just have some fun.
Finally. Just swallow.
Ivan.
- Sam.
- Hey.
Hi. I'm happy to see you.
Where's Linda and Joey?
I don't know. Maybe they're-
They're probably in there already.
- Look, it's Abe Lincoln.
- Aye, aye, sir!
Whoo-hoo! Funky town!
What's wrong? Come on.
Is it... starting to rain?
Make some room!
Step back, step back.
Step-Step out. Oh, my God.
All right, I need everybody
on this end to please exit the premises.
All right? I need that gate opened,
and I need you guys to move that way!
Please! Come on!
Fellas, let's go.
Jesus Christ!
Uh, Cooper, I need you to get over here
to the campground immediately.
And I need a body bag. Guys, what
are you doin' waitin' around here?
That's the door!
Let's go! Party is over!
Let's go, guys. Come on.
Move it out. Please.
Come on. Move out.
Watch out for the cars.
- Guys, please, let's move out.
- Major bummer, man.
The party's that way.
I know I said shut it down,
but I need that highway back open.
Please, sir, that's a fire hazard.
Please, put out the, um,
the fire on your head there.
I know. I know, guys. I'm sorry for the
inconvenience. There's always Burning Man.
- There's no makin' love in the woods!
- Sheriff!
Get your clothes on! No!
Sheriff, what in the goddamn
name of Judas do you think you're doin'?
- Shuttin' you down, Frank Baker.
- Fuck you.
Frank, I got two dead bodies out there
and a killer on the loose.
Okay? Thanks for
the wonderful party, pal.
But I got a job to do, all right? So please,
pack your shit and get out of here!
Fuck you!
Fuck you. Fuck you. Fuck you!
- Yeah, fuck me.
- Buzz kill.
- Real nice language, by the way.
- Fuck you!
Let's go, guys.
Bird! Bird! Bird, please!
Bird man! Hey! Hey! Come on!
Show's over, guys.
Get out of the costume.
Go! Move it!
- Jesus Christ.
- Fuck you!
No refunds! Get out of my fuckin' way,
you fuckin' dumb ass!
Party!
Get naked!
Take clothes off!
Rock it, George, man! Party!
- Party!
Party!
Shut it down!
I mean it!
Maybe you've heard
and maybe you haven't...
but there's been an incident
here tonight.
And I have lawfully ordered everyone
to vacate these premises a long time ago!
Right now, I am authorized-
If you won't leave,
I am authorized...
to call in any law enforcement agency
I deem necessary...
to have you forcibly removed.
That includes
the National Guard, people.
You will be arrested! Go home!
The show is over!
Leave, people!
And you, put your shirt on!
- Put your shirt on! Put your shirt on!
- No!
You think this is a joke?
It's not!
If you don't leave,
you will die!
Your sheriff thinks we have
a security problem, fine.
Let him send in
the National Guard.
Let him send in the motherfuckin'
marines for all I care.
Let me remind you
of one thing, Mr. Mayor.
We have a contract...
the cornerstone of
the American capitalist foundation!
You see, that's just the thing,
uh, Mr. Baker.
We do have a contract...
- Uh-huh. Fuck you.
- And, uh...
Let's just see what it says here.
- Uh, you are to provide a concert.
- Uh-huh.
Fuck you, Hal.
- And revenues owed this town...
- Uh-huh.
- By, uh, receipts from said concert...
- Fuck you. Uh-huh. Fuck you.
- Or out of your own pocket.
Uh-huh. Fuck you!
Excuse me?
No, I was talking to
somebody in the other room.
Uh-Uh-huh.
Well-
Well, you seem really busy.
Let me let you run, okay?
Where the fuck
do you think you're going?
Pig said that the show was over.
- So it's over. The show is over.
- No!
No! The show is not over!
So unpack your gear and get
the fuck back out there!
Say what?
There's a lot of people out there
who came expecting to see a show...
and I'll be goddamned if some
hick cop's gonna shut me down!
Well, what do you want us
to sing, Frank? "Taps"?
Yeah. I don't give a fuck
if you sing motherfuckin' "Kumbaya."
Just get the fuck out there.
We have a contract...
by the grace of
George fucking Washington...
you motherfuckin' fucking fucks!
Capisce?
Hey!
You wanna keep it alive?
Meet us in the forest, man!
- I n our forest!
- Fuck yeah!
God's forest!
Yeah!
Where's my fucking phone?
Hey, it's mellow, you guys.
I talked to 'em. Everything's cool.
What did they say?
They said it's gonna take hours
to even get to the highway...
not to mention Joey's got the keys,
and who knows where the fuck he is.
You didn't see him
at the concert?
- No. Linda either.
- We have to go find them.
Fuck that. I'm not goin' out there
with Chuck Manson on the loose.
- Dude, we can't just sit here.
- It's cool, honey. They'll come back.
No, it's not cool.
We have to do something.
If you wanna do something, you should
try the ecstasy. I highly recommend it.
Sam, just come over here
and sit down next to me.
I don't wanna sit down,
and I don't wanna run away from reality.
I just want to get out of here!
I'll run from reality
screaming gladly.
Plus, this dude said
the party's not over, not officially.
What are you talkin' about?
Some guys are thinkin' about
goin' in the woods, startin' a drum circle.
Here, babe.
You're stuck in bumblefuck,
you might as well party in bumblefuck.
Are you insane?
We're all insane, honey.
- Dude, what is your girlfriend's problem?
- My problem?
In case you haven't noticed,
people are dying around here.
Well, where are we
gonna go, honey?
Anywhere. Fuck!
Look. Without Joey
and without Linda?
Come on. Just come here.
Let's just be together.
Everything's gonna be all right.
And we'll go find...
Joey and Linda... at the party.
What?
You're fucked up too.
I'm not fucked up.
I'm just-
I'm just a little... fucked up.
Come on, babe.
Where are you going?
Sam.
Come on, Sam. Don't-
Fuck!
W-W-W-Whoa!
You leave me alone!
Fuck!
Ivan!
The goddamn problem is...
people just don't seem
to respect authority anymore.
Well, I respect you, Buzz.
That's not exactly what I meant.
Old Man Riggs.
My pops always said he was crazy.
I never thought he'd end up
killin' people though.
Yeah, he's a regular
goddamn Greek tragedy.
Wait, wait.
Clear.
Some people just like
jelly beans, pal.
- Get him off!
- I'm tryin'! I'm tryin'!
- Get him off me!
- Get out of the way, Buzz!
- Get him off!
- I can't!
I can't shoot a dog!
- Shoot him!
- No, Buzz! Shake him!
Get off of me!
- You're nice.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Shh!
Dylan Riggs!
Turn off the saw
and put your hands in the air!
You ain't gonna take
my boy again!
You're under arrest!
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Go get him!
Hang in there!
Ivan!
Jack? Jade?
No!
- Samantha?
- Ivan!
Jack and Jade, they're-
What's wrong with
your friend, Samantha?
He seems pretty fucked up to me.
What do you think?
You fuckin' asshole!
I thought hippies were supposed
to be nice little kooks.
He didn't seem that happy to see me,
not at all.
How could you?
- I love you, Sam!
- I hate you! You're sick!
- I fuckin' hate you!
- How could you say that?
Let him go!
Should I let you go,
you little bitch?
- I'm not gonna do-
- You're not gonna nothin'!
How could you pick
this piece of shit over me?
How could you leave me
for this piece of shit?
You're fucking crazy, Jimmy!
How could you kill my friends?
You're a monster!
What?
What are you talking about?
I didn't touch your friends!
He killed Jack and Jade.
What?
I didn't-
I didn't fuckin' kill anybody!
What makes you think
I could kill somebody?
Because you have a gun!
All right. What can I say?
I'm a big fan of Charlton Heston.
But I'm a Republican!
Sam, get out of here!
Get the hell out of here!
Get out of here!
Ivan!
Sam, go!
Well, there you go again.
Hank? Linda? Joey?
Somebody, please!
Help! Help! Somebody help me!
What-What was that?
Acid.
No! No! No!
No! No!
Truly improving.
Ronnie?
One, two, three, four!
Jesus.
California Department of Health Services...
prepared for the release
of thousands of mental patients...
many of them
violent extremists...
as new cuts to the state budget
are due to take effect.
Critics of the plan
blame Governor Ronald Reagan...
for slashing the funds
to mental health board rates...
the latest in a line of sweeping budgetary
changes-
The actor turned conservative Republican
took office last January.
Shh!
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh!
Oh, my God.
Jesus. Take it easy.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey, hey, hey! It's okay.
No one's gonna hurt you anymore.
- Give me your hands.
- You can't stop him.
You can't stop him. It's R-
It's Reagan.
Calm down.
No one's gonna hurt you anymore.
It's all under control.
It'll be all right.
- You're okay.
- It's Reagan. It's Reagan.
No one's gonna hurt you no more.
Shh!
How about we start collecting
some money from these bozos?
This ain't supposed to be free.
Nothin' in this world is free!
Ronald Reagan!
- Coop, you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine. Did you get him?
Dylan's dead.
But he's just the cleanup man.
Look, I need an ambulance.
And get me the park rangers.
Have 'em meet me by the campsite.
This is a manhunt now...
and Gus Riggs is our man.
Dylan's kid?
I thought they locked him up years ago.
Yeah, well, it looks like Reagan released
him and about a thousand other maniacs.
So lucky for us, he's back.
Who do you think he's after?
Hippies.
Nice puppies! Nice! Nice puppies! Nice!
Nice puppies!
Yeah. You okay? Buzz?
Cooper, I'm heading to Dylan's farm!
And, no, I am not okay!
Linda?
- It's gonna be okay, sweetie.
- I'm so happy to see you.
I've missed you.
Can we go home now?
Now, Patti...
you see what happens...
when you hang out
with the wrong crowd?
No daughter of mine
is gonna be hooked on drugs.
You're gonna break
your mother's heart.
Nancy?
Poindexter? Meese?
It's morning in America...
all over again!
Gus Riggs,
don't move a goddamn muscle!
Is this what you call
compassion and conservatism, boy?
Miss, you okay?
You hurt?
Cooper, you still standin', buddy?
I'm here, Buzzo.
What was that?
- Good! Got him!
- No!
- No! Don't shoot!
- Hold your fire!
These are God's creatures!
They're our friends!
- Oh, God!
- Okay, go ahead. Fire.
I got an injured girl here.
Looks like she's on drugs.
And, uh, a man down.
- No, don't leave me! Don't go! Please!
- Let go of my leg.
- Miss.
- Please!
You gotta let go of my leg.
Hey, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Easy, easy! Whoa! No, no, no, no!
Hey, hey, hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Give me the gun. Give me the gun.
What are you doin'?
Come on! What are you, crazy?
Sam was her name-
And for only one brief moment-
- She fell into my lap -
- Seems she had everything I wanted-
- In a girl-
- She paints her nails like my guitar -
- She played it
and that was the start -
- She danced like a wicked angel -
- She danced to the beat of my heart -
Jesus!
- She told me you have pretty eyes -
Look at this mess! Somebody's gonna
have hell to pay, that's for sure.
Jesus! This place stinks!
I'm goddamn fucked!
Hey, laughin' boy, come on.
Give me the... balloon.
Get out of here!
You okay?
You ever heard of
the trickle-down effect, Cooper?
I don't know.
It's when one big asshole goes crazy,
and the whole world goes to shit.
Hang on.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
Good.
What?
We went up to the field.
We didn't find Gus's body.
Shit.
Fuck you!
Yeah!
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
It's not about protecting
so much...
the fish and the Earth for their
own sake, or nature for its own sake...
but recognizing that nature
is the infrastructure of our communities.
And that if we wanna
meet our obligation...
as a generation,
as a nation, a civilization...
which is to create
communities for our children...
that provide them with the same
opportunities for dignity and enrichment...
as the communities
that our parents gave us...
we've gotta start by protecting
our environmental infrastructure-
the air we breathe,
the water we drink...
the shared resources,
the fisheries and the wildlife...
and the public lands
that enrich us...
that connect us to our history
and to our past...
that provide context
to our communities...
and that are the source
ultimately of our values...
and virtues
and our character as a people.
And I wanna talk about some of those issues
about the environment tonight...
but more importantly
about the impact...
of excessive corporate power
on America...
not just on the environment,
but on American democracy.
And I don't think...
there's any such thing as
Republican children or Democratic children.
I think the worst thing
that could happen to the environment...
is if it becomes a province...
of a single political party,
as it seems to have done.
But you can't talk honestly about
the environment in any context today...
without speaking critically
of this president.
This is the worst
environmental president...
that we 've ever had
in American history bar none.
And if you go to
N. R. D. C. 'S Web site-
the Natural Resource
Defense Council...
which is one of the groups
for which we work-
you'll see over 400 major
environmental rollbacks listed there...
that have been promoted
or implemented by this administration...
over the past four years...
as part of a deliberate
concerted effort...
to eviscerate 30years
of environmental law.
It's a stealth attack.
The White House has used...
all these kind of
ingenuous machinations...
to conceal its radical agenda
from the American people...
including Orwellian rhetoric.
When they want to destroy the forests,
they call it the Healthy Forest Act.
When they want to destroy the air,
they call it the Clear Skies Bill.
But most insidiously,
they have put polluters in charge...
of virtually all the agencies that are
supposed to protect Americans from pollution.
The head of the Forest Service
is a timber industry lobbyist...
probably the most rapacious
in history.
The head of public lands
is a mining industry lobbyist...
who believes that public lands
are unconstitutional.
The head of the air division,
E.P.A., is a utility lobbyist...
who's represented nothing but
the worst air polluters in our country.
The head of Superfund
is a woman whose last job...
was teaching corporate polluters
how to evade Superfund.
The second in command of E.P.A.
is a Monsanto lobbyist, and on and on.
If you go through all of
the departments of government...
that are relevant
to the environment-
the Department of Energy and Agriculture
and Interior and the E.P.A...
and even the relevant divisions of the justice
department-you'll find the same thing.
It's the polluters
who are running the agencies...
that are supposed to
protect us from pollution.
And a couple of weeks ago,
it was revealed in the New York Times...
that this character,
who's the second in command of the C.E.Q...
which is the Council
on Environmental Quality...
was in the White House
advising the president...
on the environmental implications
of all of his policies.
And as it turns out, he's an
American Petroleum Institute lobbyist...
whose primary job
over the past four years...
has been combing through
every federal scientific document...
and removing any
inculpatory information...
about the oil and coal industry.
And he has suppressed
12 major studies on global warming...
and altered hundreds and hundreds
of studies-Ronald Reagan-
of anything that is critical
of the oil or coal-
that says something connects,
you know, oil or coal to some bad-
Ronald Reagan-
scientific circumstance.
So his job is to lie-
Ronald Reagan-in public.
And, you know, there's nothing wrong
with having businesspeople in government.
It's a good thing if your objective
is to recruit confidence and expertise.
But in all of the-Ronald Reagan-
situations, as I show in my book...
these individuals-
Ronald Reagan-
have not entered government service
for the public interest...
but rather to subvert the very laws
that they're now charged-Ronald Reagan-
in order to enrich the president's
corporate paymasters.
And they've imposed dramatic and
catastrophic impacts on the American public.
Most of us don 't know it
in this country...
because we have an indolent
and negligent press-Ronald Reagan-
that has simply let down
American democracy.
Ronald Reagan. That's- And I-
You know, I'll just
tell you something about that.
The decline of American journalism
began in 1988...
when Ronald Reagan abolished
the Fairness Doctrine.
We had a law in this country that
required the press to behave responsibly.
And the Fairness Doctrine
was passed in 1928...
and said that the airwaves
belong to the public-
that the broadcasters
can be licensed to use them-
Ronald Reagan-Ronald Reagan-
Ronald Reagan-
Feel the vibration in
the jubilation, fool!
I can feel it! I feel.
God's kingdom government
and the son of Yahweh will return!
- Yahweh!
- Return from the-to overthrow the ruler!
Yes!
- Yes!
- Go on, Willis!
All right!
Whoo-hoo!
Destroy the wicked one!
- Go on, Willis!
- Destroy him!
For he who sayeth is a soothsayer!
Satan, get behind me
and pursueth the heathen!
Whoa to the soothsayer
who was the inducer of soot!
And yea to the one who prevail
over the temptation of evil!
Get your hand out of my pocket!
- Beelzebub and his herd of dark angels...
- That's some bullshit!
- Come and block off sleep in the night!
- That's some bullshit, Reverend!
- Behold, you heathen!
- Heathens!
Behold, my heathen,
because devil behind me!
- The blood of Abraham!
- Ecclesiastes!
Holy shit! Whoa!
Brother Eli!
Don't stop!
- Jacob!
- The man has spoken!
- Proverbs!
- Mary had children!
- Jehoshaphat!
- What's the word, Thunderbird?