You do realize why you're in this car,
do you not?
You've been tasked by Mr. Durant
to build a bridge.
Any man can lay track.
Am I correct?
Yes, ma'am.
Pretty near.
Then can you explain
why you've been spending
all your energy at rail's end
instead of at the bridge site?
That will be remedied, ma'am.
Thank you.
You heard what the lady said.
This the part where I tell you the men
don't like taking orders from a woman.
They don't have to like it.
No, they don't.
But if you're looking to get back
in Mr. Durant's good graces,
then pissing off the man
might not be the best tact.
Doesn't matter,
as long as we get this railroad built.
If you're not
careful, miss bell,
you're going to start
sounding like a man.
Right.
All right! Move your carcasses!
Step on it!
You lot, for the gorge,
make room for one more.
And as for the rest of you
jackanapes, I expect to be able
to walk a mile of rail
by the time I get back
from me lunch break.
Change the numbers all you want,
that ain't the problem.
56 men?
23.
And we've got another 46 coming in.
Another...
That's got to be Fleming.
The sentry?
You need to do something.
Bring me the long rifle.
There's too many!
They got the high ground.
If you keep them occupied,
we can loop back and try
and outflank 'em.
Damn it, I said bring me
the long rifle right now!
Get back.
He shot Fleming!
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Look at me.
I see you.
Damn, woman.
What's so funny?
Never thought I'd be glad
Mr. Toole made foreman.
Out early, home late.
Don't speak his name.
You know the rules.
Right.
'cause you live by rules.
I want you to feel something.
Damn, girl.
Give a man a minute
to raise his spirit.
You feel that?
That little bump?
You and me made that.
How you know?
Because I know.
Say something.
Elam Ferguson,
you look me in the eyes
and you tell me what you're thinkin'.
Don't you leave here
without saying something.
I can't.
See, I'm ask... asking you
to look... look inside your heart.
Inside your heart.
Sorry, Reverend.
I'm afraid it's empty.
Same as my wallet.
Hey!
All right now?
Reverend.
Cullen!
Could you...
Could you spot a fellow
traveler a drink?
Rye, barkeep.
- Be right with you.
- Carl.
Just the one.
You've got to read over a man today.
Oh, you have to ask
that harlot who threw me out.
You mean your daughter?
Yeah.
That sinning bitch
stole my church.
Yes, she's...
Your conduit to the Lord now.
You mind me asking
where you been bedding down?
I've been, uh,
been sleeping in the cemetery.
It's near freezing at night.
There's no cover.
Yeah, I find the dead a comfort.
What the hell?
You can bunk with me
until you get yourself settled.
Go on. Set him up.
Carl, set them... set them up.
What in the hell's going on?
Why aren't y'all men at work?
Turn around and get back on...
Mr. Toole.
You mind telling me
why these men ain't at work?
With all due respect,
we lost a man out there.
- A mate.
- That's right!
Then you finish your day's work.
Then you come back in
and drink to his memory.
We parlayed.
We all agree.
It's not safe.
It's about to get unsafe around here
if you don't get
your ass back to work.
I am afraid you'll
just have to shoot us.
That's right!
If we route South,
then we can bridge the river here...
And avoid the entire
issue of Sacred Land.
Yes.
At considerable expense.
Spend a few more pennies now
and keep your work force, Thomas.
Pennies.
We can't run from the Sioux.
If it ain't this gorge,
it'll be the next one.
- The men are afraid to work.
- Then we should find ones who ain't.
They believe that if the Sioux
won't kill them, perhaps you will.
Bullshit.
Of course. When logic isn't on
your side, resort to the profane.
All right, I'll give you facts.
Here, here, here.
May not be sacred,
but it's all Sioux territory.
We've already established what's
on this side of the gorge!
For once, let's be smart.
Reroute and show the men that we can
steer them out of harm's way.
The Indians' home's at stake,
young lady.
They'll fight us all
the way to the Rockies.
- If that's true, then we're lost!
- We turn tail first sign of trouble,
yes, we are.
You don't...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is your plan, Mr. Bohannon?
Fight 'em here, fight 'em now.
With what? That rabble?
Them's the ones we got.
They...
They won't even work for you.
You let me worry about that.
Just don't reroute this railroad.
Let me.
Thank you.
Your husband know about
what you told me earlier?
No.
Nobody knows but you and me.
Good.
I've spent my whole
life trying to get free.
Then here come a woman...
A white woman...
A married woman, spinning my head
saying she's got my baby.
I couldn't think of
nothin' to do but run.
Then it set with me.
And?
Any harm come to you,
I go weak in the head.
You are weak in the head.
All the gold eagles in the world
ain't worth a pinch of coon shit
if you can't use it to help
the folk that you care about.
Elam...
What are you saying?
You saying you care about me?
I love you.
I love you, woman.
I need you to take
these double eagles
and get yourself taken care of.
Taken care of.
You can't have no black baby.
Your husband will kill
it or you or both of you.
Elam, I used to be a whore.
If I want to get rid of this child,
I got my ways.
And you don't need to fear
for your freedom on my account.
♪ A prouder man
I'd walk the land ♪
♪ in health and peace of mind
♪ if I might toil
and strive and moil ♪
♪ nor cast one thought behind
♪ but what would be
the world to me ♪
♪ its wealth and rich array
♪ if memory I lost of thee
♪ my own dear galway...
I come to pay my respects
to Mr. Fleming.
He was a good man.
A poor end he was met with.
And he won't be the last, I'm afraid.
For Mr. Michael Fleming...
Um...
He didn't ask for what he got...
But he got it anyway.
Life ain't fair.
Ain't fair at all.
Hell, most of us here in this room
fought in a war
one side or the other.
We all seen men fall.
We prayed over 'em,
we drank over 'em.
But we did not quit.
The best way to honor
your friend is to carry on.
Finish this road.
Mr. Bohannon, Mr. Bohannon!
No disrespect intended,
but we won't die for your railroad.
Not on your life!
Your friend didn't have to die.
You best have a point.
We're all in the same position...
The Sioux don't look
at any of us any different.
They just aim to kill.
That doesn't explain why you're
interrupting a private wake.
We're willing to protect
the end of the rail
and the bridge site.
If the railroad give us guns,
we'll go out early and...
Give 'em guns?
Patrol for Sioux.
Mr. Durant ain't going
to arm no ex-slaves
and these men wouldn't
stand for it, neither.
Damn right.
Aye!
You best get yourself on out of here.
Then you ain't getting
no work out of us.
That's not a stand you want to take.
We aren't working, neither.
Not until you protect us.
We won't be sitting ducks out there.
Dammit, y'all, listen to me.
That road's going to get
built with or without you.
If y'all don't go to work,
it's you who's going to lose.
Now trust me on this.
You'll lose and it'll get ugly.
I'm sorry for your loss.
♪ 'Tis far away I am today
♪ from scenes I roamed a boy ♪
♪ and long ago the hour
I know, I first saw Illinois ♪
♪ but time nor tide
nor waters wide ♪
♪ can wean my heart away
♪ forever true it flies to you ♪
♪ my dear old galway bay
Hang him!
They are burning me
at the stake out there
and I had to come and find you?!
Thank you.
Yes, ma'am.
What are they demanding?
They want protection.
Well, we can't guarantee their safety
against the Sioux.
It's a hazard of the job.
More beans.
And the freedmen?
They want to be armed.
Give rifles to an army of ex-slaves?
No, no.
I won't allow it.
- That's what I told them.
- This is why we change the route.
Avoid sacred land.
Win the men back
by taking them out of harm's way.
You do that,
you'll lose this railroad.
At least get
the freedmen back out there.
They'll do what we tell them to do.
All evidence to the contrary.
Those Negroes...
Are the property of this railroad,
Mr. Bohannon.
Property?
Yes.
Most of the freedmen are criminals
that we bought their sentences
from the states where
they were serving time.
Bought them, bought me,
it's all beside the point.
They do not make demands.
I told you when you hired me,
this was a war.
Yes. And I expected you
to have a battle plan.
Well?!
Let me be clear.
I can't do anything
without your complete authority.
This is yours to deal with.
Then, yeah.
I've got a plan.
Hear you're holding
that railroad hostage, huh?
He'll use you as a sacrificial
lamb for them Injuns.
You worry about your people.
And I'm going to worry about mine.
Boys get themself killed
playing with guns.
They ain't never
going to see us as equals
till we holding the weapons they got.
Ohh.
I suppose everybody looks the same
once the maggots get to 'em.
Mm-hmm.
You'd be a vision
even if your whole body
were covered in them things.
Your beauty could never
be hidden from my eyes.
Are you drunk, Mr. Toole?
How did you know?
You always wax poetic
when you got a noseful.
Chitterlings again?
Yeah.
I had a hanking for them.
Just can't seem to get enough.
They're fattening you up a bit.
I like me a woman
with a bit of girth.
Oh, it's... it's strange
me wanting to eat so much
with me being so sick
in the mornings of late.
I'm sure it'll pass.
Give us a kiss, woman.
Mmm.
Mr. Toole...
I'm with child.
And it ain't yours.
I can't...
I can't lie to you.
You've been one of the most
halfway decent men I ever known,
but this... this child
belongs to another.
Does this mean you're leaving me?
Seems you've got your work
cut out for you, boss man.
It ain't nothing I can't handle.
Can you send a message
to the council bluffs office?
"Labor negotiations stalled." Stop.
"Work halted." Stop.
"Send 200 replacement workers
on the next available train."
Stop.
Got that?
All right.
There's gonna be bloodshed.
What you care?
You ain't no Freedman.
You sure as hell
ain't Irish or German.
I ain't cleaning up after your mess.
Nah. You'll just do whatever
Mr. Durant wants you to.
Won't you?
There is a storm brewing in town.
Oh, that's... that's a labor dispute
it appears to me.
Oh, more blood.
More bodies.
More coffins.
Heh heh heh.
Our jobs have never
been more secure. Hmm?
Can I tell you a...
A secret, Reverend?
War is coming.
Yet again.
And not this business of
workers sitting down on the job.
A real war.
Ahh!
Now is the time...
To see things clear.
We must decide...
Which side we are on.
Hmm?
Where do you think you're going?
Out of me way.
I'm gonna tell you this once.
You lay a hand on her,
I'm gonna kill you.
Oh, you can thrash me?
Fine.
You're not a real man.
Just so we're clear.
Puffed up. Big gun.
You can go to hell.
What kind of man are you?
Most of us would give
our life to be a father,
but look at you, huh?
You didn't even stay
by her side before.
And where are you now?
In the middle of town flexing
your damn trigger finger.
You're no father.
You're just a coward.
Good night, then, yellow belly.
Reverend?
You... you got any socks you want done?
Why don't you go to
the starlight, huh?
Get us a bottle.
What's a train doing here
so late at night?
Steel workers.
Coming in to take over for
thems who won't go out.
You're replacing the men?
Laying rail ain't
no scholarly business.
If the men don't want to work,
there's hundreds more
where they came from.
Now, you get us a bottle.
Whatever's left,
you keep.
You enjoying your view?
Matter of fact, I ain't.
Let's go!
The men think they
stepping off that train
and get jobs.
If they can fight,
they might just have them.
Boys are getting their ass kicked.
Let's get them, boys!
Don't do it.
You tell anybody else trying
to come out here what happened.
You hear me?
Get out of here!
Go! Go!
Go back where you came from!
Let me see.
What you got?
We're willing to go back to work,
under one condition.
Maybe you don't understand.
I could have another trainload
of workers here tomorrow.
We understand.
If the Negroes are
willing to put themselves
between us and the Sioux,
we're OK with them having guns.
Hmm.
Go get yourself some rest, Mr. Toole.
Proud of yourself?
Pride ain't got nothing
to do with it.
So that was the plan?
Now everybody's supposed to
get along happy ever after?
Not quite yet.
Now you need to get your
people back to work.
Ain't no sense having a horse
unless it's broke enough
so you can ride it.
Except we ain't talking about horses.
We talking about men.
Same principle.
You work for Mr. Durant now.
Same as me.
That means we're
the ones doing the riding.
Y'all got a choice.
You either get back to work...
Or go back to prison.
Says who?
Boss man.
Then we need to hear it
from the boss man.
You're hearing it
just as good from me.
I ain't hearing nothing
but some noise...
Coming from the boss man's flunky.
Look at you.
What you've become.
Get your ass up, boy!
Get him, son.
Get him!
♪
Aah!
Don't know if you're black,
don't know if you're white.
You're nothing.
You hear me?
You ain't nothing.
Get your ass up.
Get your ass up, boy.
Aah!
You bit me!
You're still my nigger.
Strike's over.
They gave in?
If the freedmen agree
to go back out, no conditions,
when the men sober up,
we'll give the Negroes rifles
and send everybody
back out to the cut.
But you said yourself
we can't capitulate to their demands.
Point is, we ain't.
I am not arming the freedmen.
You want this railroad built,
somebody's got to patrol that land.
Now, you gonna let me do this or not?
Well, if they want
to be Cannon fodder,
hmm, so be it.
But we have lost two days and 5 Miles.
Those men fought to
the death for their jobs.
We'll make up those
5 Miles in no times.
So that's it.
We move forward.
At what cost?
You're the one said
building this railroad
is the only thing that matters.
Being smart and rerouting
is not the same as being weak.
You and me's gonna have to
agree to disagree.
Yes. Because clearly it always
has to be on your terms,
doesn't it?
It don't work...
If there's any question about that.
Got yourself a real workforce now.
Mrs. Toole,
your husband has returned home.
Reverend, you leaving me?
Well, I see you've
bent the men to your will.
I suppose I played a part in that.
Yeah.
Is it true?
I mean, do you believe
you're at war with the Sioux?
Yes, sir, I do.
And now you have the men
to do the job.
I can't stay with you.
I respect that.
Rifle in your left hand,
cartridge in your right.
Join the line.
Arms distance, please.
You think this is unwise?
Probably.
But this is...
Barrels down, gentlemen.
But a necessary evil, Mr. Toole.
You're speaking of
yourself then, Mr. Bohannon.
Rifle in your left hand.
Cartridges in your right.
Congratulations.
All right, gentlemen.
The rest of y'all,
rifles in your left hand,
barrels facing the sky.
Finger off the trigger.
Take one cartridge in your right hand.
Sharp end is the business end.
Load that cartridge
into the cartridge port
on the side of your rifle,
business end first.
Now, on the order to make ready,
rack that lever all the way forward
and all the way back,
loading the round into the chamber.
And... make ready!
You dropped your round.
Pick it up.
Start again.
And... make ready!
Boss man coming through.
Hold your fire.
Boss man coming through!
Anything moves...
Shoot the shit out of it.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com