HAM EUN-JUNG
HWANG WOO-SEUL-HYE
MAY DONI
CHOI A-RA
JIN SE-YEON
BYUN JUNG-SOO
Written & Directed By
KIM SUN KIM GOK
WHiTE
Wow! "Pure" is better than ever
Now, we have 4 lovely angels
aiming for number 1
Who are they?
Let's call them out together
"Pink Dolls"!
I'm the youngest, A-rang
I'm the lead vocalist, Jenny
I'm in charge of dance and rap
I'm Shin-ji
I'm the team leader, Eun-ju
Please support us, the "Pink Dolls"!
Thank you. We came first
We'll work even harder
We love you, thank you everyone
We were just side-kicks
How annoying!
'Survival Challenge' is starting soon
Looks like "Pure" will be cast
We'll get another chance
She's so relaxed
Because she's old and experienced
She almost knocked me over
out there
No-one even visits our website
or uploads videos of us now
Another chance? As if.
We'll just appear on some
old pop show
This is what happens when
your agency is hopeless
Do you think it's the agency's fault
your ranking dropped?
Is that all you can think of?
Go turn it off
Yes
Do you think
they became stars easily?
They worked their asses off to
get to the top
We're moving tomorrow
Pack up their belongings
Yes, Mr. Choi
Let's go, girls
Really? We have to move again?
It better not be any worse
- Let's go
- I don't want to move
Let's look around
Wow! This is so cool!
What is this?
Where did she get the money?
The building was empty after a fire
The boss got it at a good price
Now all we need is a song & dance
Wait! Is it 2 people to a room?
Sure
Eun-ju! Leave it to me
It's okay, I can do it
If you say so
This rehearsal studio is really
something!
Why are you so shocked?
- I'm all right
- Sit down
So... How is it?
The girls are a handful, right?
You're the eldest & team leader
You have to control them
You used to be a back dancer
You knew it wouldn't be easy
Do you like the studio?
Yes, thank you
Don't thank me
Someone paid for it
His father owned this place
His father passed away in a fire
Anyway
Who do you think gave this place
to us?
Mr. Choi
He's gotten us this new studio
Now is the perfect timing
I don't even know his face
Eun-ju...
You want to
achieve your dreams too, right?
Don't think too hard about it
You've hit bottom, work your way
up now
What's that?
A music video?
The chorus is quite addictive
You've never heard it before, right?
There are tons of songs floating around
It's just another song with no owner
Okay... Are you sure?
Start working on it
Who cares who owns the song?
Finders keepers
- What do you think?
- It's pretty good
I will brush up on the original
Okay then
Mr. Lee's working on the arrangement
We'll have the MR tomorrow
Prepare for next week's showcase
Tell Sun-ye to come for the doubling
This showcase is our big break
It's our last chance to make it
The dance is a little strange
It's not even dancing...
Just gestures
So typical I knew the studio was
too good to be true
What is she doing?
Hey...
Eun-ju..
Do you like this dance?
Well... I think it's pretty good
The best part is
when you roll the neck
Best part?
She used to be a back dancer
She knows more about dance than we do
Why not just be a back dancer then?
Why come here and
raise our team's average age?
Debuting late
is nothing to be proud of
Jenny, A-rang
Watch what you say
I'm doing my best too
You're doing your best?
Talk about pathetic
Go and ask your sponsor to give us
more money to make up a new dance
That's how you can help us
I thought you went & meet him
to get us this great new studio
I thought
you'd finally come around
Eun-ju
I think you're wrong
That's not rolling
How can you roll the neck?
Eun-ju...
I think you're really pathetic
What do you think about when
you dance in front of people?
I'm going to die under that crowd...
That's what I think when I dance
I'm not going on stage with
this stupid dance
Hey! We have to rehearse!
Let's get started practicing then
Shoulders, chin
Karaoke room in an hour
- Eun-ju -
I love you, so I cry
I miss you, so I cry
My love who left me
That painful love
You left me, so I cry
Geez... What's with the sad face?
Is something wrong?
There are so many...
All these people were singers
Where are they all now?
Singers are just a seasonal act
Especially idols
Sun-ye
Why did you give it up?
Why do you think?
My bodywas hurt...
My heart was hurt too and
nothing worked out for me
Why?
Should I quit too?
Hey! Did they give you a hard time
again?
If you're going to keep that up...
Just form a group with me
What?
The LaLa Sisters?
Old pop specialists
A female duo
"White"... You're going to be
in a showcase?
Yes
I think it has potential
I've got a good feeling about it
Eun-ju
You've come too far to
give it up now
Let's just give it one more try
If it doesn't work out, then
we'll be the LaLa Sisters
All the journalists are here
Cancel?
Saved you from dancing at
school festivals & now, how dare you?
Get ready, girls
Sorry! My lesson finished late
I was just about to panic
Hurry up and get ready
Jenny, are you all right?
A-rang, don't keep touching your eye
You look fine
Shin-ji, don't get nervous
I'm going to perform
as though this was our last stage
We've already hit bottom
Let's get out there and perform
like crazy
People always said I was intense
Let's do it
Shin-ji, you too
Or we'll just lose to "Pure" again
This is it. Let's do it
"Pink Dolls"?
What brings them here?
This showcase sucks
Prepare for the doubling
1, 2, 3
Hot showcase! "Pink Dolls"
"Pink Dolls"
Shin-ji's power dance
I have some good news for you
Your online fan club surpassed
200,000
Bravo
- Take good care of the website
- Yes
You were asked to star in a film
but I turned it down
You can earn that money at 2 shows
Why waste 6 months shooting?
But I said yes to 'Survival Challenge'
Then we get to see Jun-ho?
Be quiet
That's not all
We're negotiating some
TV commercials
But there is a condition
Top of the Music Fever Charts
I think the 200th episode is perfect
It's around the time when
mid-terms end
Look at the time already
What's next?
The fitting session
Fitting? Let's decide
who'll stand in the center too
Center?
Yes
Don't we all sing a part each?
We still need a main vocalist
The original song was a solo too
The song's hard,
so it needs a good singer
The prettiest girl should be
in the middle
My ephidrosis is working up again
It's worse when I'm nervous
Hurry up
Do you think the center will go to
the best vocalist?
I guess so
It's your 2nd album, so the
song's important
Who told you to go first?
You're not even the main!
I think A-rang suits this style best
A-rang, stand in the middle
The center should be pretty
It's the 2nd album.
They should be sexy, not cute
Plus, the song's hard to sing
This time, Jenny Stand in the middle
Go with this
Okay! Setting number 2!
Jenny, get readyfor a solo shot
Not as loud as the center
Really good
Look daring
Okay, that's nice
Who sang this?
That's quite high
That's just the accompaniment
She's good
I didn't know
her voice was that high
Jenny, make it a little gentler
Can you raise it to a nasal tone?
I can still hear a head voice
Let's try it again
No-one's doubling, right?
I feel like
someone's singing along
Jenny, let's try it again Play
If hertone's that high,
it will drain out the other parts
Just play it
All she does is screech
The hook part's a solo too
It's the main single
You should divide it up a little
Why? I just want to give the
main voice more impact
If Jenny's too overpowering,
the other girls will drown out
Let them have other parts then
Give them the rap and hook
Eun-ju...
Sorry I was so mean to you
It's a little hot in here, don't you think?
Jenny, are you ready? 3... 2, 1, go!
Those girls are crazy
Wait... Where's Jenny?
In the studio, I guess
The boss is working her hard
You two go ahead and sleep
Jenny...
It's late. Rehearse tomorrow
Jenny..?
Jenny
Jenny?
Jenny!
Help! Help!
Is anyone there?
Help her! She's dying!
Eun-ju, it's not your fault
She was hallucinating from the
herbal medicine.  Keep smiling
Talk about trying to stand out
Ouch... My wrist hurts
Can you do the rest?
Yes, okay
5 mins left  Fans can enter now
What do you think?
About Jenny
She took that medicine all the time
for her ephidrosis
Why did it act up just now?
Don't you think it's strange?
I don't know. It's side-effects...
Why now?
Why did she experience side-effects
after she became the lead singer?
What are you trying to say?
Maybe...
Someone played a prank on her
Put something in her medicine...
Go to bed. We have to rehearse
group dance moves tomorrow
I guess it wouldn't be you
As we all know you're...
Really weak-hearted
Bad video of Jenny
You called me here to look at this?
I have a lesson tomorrow morning
Doesn't it look weird?
Maybe the flash went off
Or someone photoshopped it
It's all because of stress
Jenny was stressed out being
the main....
So she ate a month's supply
of medicine in one day?
I hope it's not related
Don't worry about it
It's just a bunch of young anti-fans
No... I mean "White", the song
Wow
You really have
that neck roll going
The neck roll's the best part
You all saw Shin-ji, right?
Okay then
We're going to set group dance today
Tomorrow, you'll dance in heels
Let's all try it
Shin-ji, you should be the main
I'll talk to the boss about it
Our music video's going to rock
Let's go
The first pose is different now
Do you think it's okay?
The new version's better
Let's all try after Shin-ji
The dance is after the chorus
I should be in the center
Why should you be in the center?
Can you sing? Can you dance?
Just stick to your own part
Let's try it 5, 6, 7, 8
Shin-ji, fill-in for "Pure"
Delete it right now!
Geez
What's with you?
Delete what?
Don't pretend you don't know
Delete it right now
Do you have proof that I did it?
You act tough & cool all by yourself
But you're nothing
You think you're so good
I've been nice to you, so you think
you've got nothing to be scared about?
If you don't delete it by tomorrow...
Stop it!
What are you two doing?
Yu Shin-ji, go outside
Dance all you want
There are photos of you all over
the web
I uploaded those pictures! I did!
What's wrong with you both?
She did it first
Some kind of chemical...
The doctor said the
pus in my eyes is side effect...
...from the cosmetics
See? There's something in here
In here
Here as well
She may trick Jenny, but not me
I know everything about cosmetics
Someone's the main vocalist,
the lead dancer...
I'm the pretty face
Why can't the pretty face
be the main?
We have to shoot tomorrow
Go to bed
I'm the main now...Look at my eyes
Eun-ju?
Yes, it's me
Eun-ju...
Don't tell the boss that I posted
the photos
She would've made me the
main vocalist anyway
You can't be the main
It's my song
What?
Do you want to be the main?
You're nothing but a back dancer
Cut! Okay!
Prepare the camera for the
main vocalist
You can be the main next time
I refuse to sing if I'm not the main
Then what do you plan to do?
Home shopping? A fashion model?
We're going after "Pure". We can't
have their old servant as the main
You're the sponsor's servant,
aren't you?
- Watch it!
- Boss
We're shooting in 5 minutes
- Shin-ji!
- Leave her
Idols can't walk off the stage
Balance your hips and legs
Then spin around
Do the motion in the hook intro
Your expressions are important
so keep your face in the frame
Okay?
Geez I've got a bad feeling
about this
A-rang, are you okay?
Want to postpone it?
No, we should do it
while we're on a roll
But Eun-ju...
It's hot in here, don't you think?
Okay, we're ready
A-rang,
please stand in the middle
Get into it more
Be lovely
Be sweet
Smile
Okay, that's good Keep going
Yes, you're doing well
She's just really exhausted
The negative reaction to cosmetic surgery
has resulted in auto nervous system shock
When can she get back on the stage?
She can't perform in her state
Now it's just the two of us
Shin-ji, you're really getting there
Anyone
who can roll their neck better?
Eun-ju...
Horrible video of A-rang
Hot, hot, hot...
It's so hot
I wrote down the lyrics from
the 2 videos
It's just a coincidence
It's so hot This studio...
There was a fire here, right?
People must've died too
I have to go
Look into it for me then
I'll call you
Don't you even know
how to say hello?
Do you practice all night too?
I bet
nobody knows that idols do that
Don't you agree?
Singing is a job too
I thought I just had to practice
I was so stupid
They formed "Pure" from a bunch of
girls who had just entered the agency
I wasted 8 years of my life
I'm sorry,
I'm going to be the main
Shin-ji, wait...
I have a bad feeling about this song
Let's postpone being the main
Why? Do you want to be the main?
I can't give it up
Especially for a back dancer like you
Stop it
Or your neck could dislocate
I'm going to be the main
Entertainment agency
10 deaths in fire
It was 15 years ago
A lot of people died
The owner, their sponsor...
That girl too
Is that her?
Name Jang Ye-bin,
18 years old at the time
She was the most promising talent
at the agency
They decided to make her the
main vocalist in "White"
She was really competitive
She had a reputation for being tough
Someone committed suicide
before this incident
Everyone blamed Jang Ye-bin
Someone died before the fire?
A trainee who used to be
a back dancer
One trainee, prior to the fire...
It was suicide
That means it was really competitive
Anyway, the main vocalist of "White"
who died because it was too hot...
Could only be one person,
Jang Ye-bin
Anything else?
The sponsor played around
with the kids
It's the same then and now
Jang Ye-bin became the main after
meeting up with her sponsor
Her first shoot after
becoming the main was cancelled
Cancelled?
There was an NG on the first day
They postponed the shoot The fire
occurred on the day of the re-shoot
How bad was the NG for the shoot
to be postponed?
She became the main but her
first shoot was cancelled
Then she died in a fire
And her voice is in the song
There must be an explanation
Jang Ye-bin didn't die in an accident
Someone did it
Do you think so?
This song entails some kind
of curse
No way...
Who's the main after A-rang?
Shin-ji?
Find the exit and escape from
the building
When the sensor sounds, men will
chase you. Run away from them, okay?
Okay, stand on the start line
Hurry up
Ready? Go!
She's running
Shin-ji is running away
A self-destructive variety show
'Survival Challenge'
Today is a Shin-ji special
Her mission is to escape from
the agency building
Trainees often want to run
Yes, being a star isn't always
glamorous
Sometimes you want to run away
Go and get her She's running
The door is locked!
Shin-ji is running away
Now she's outside of the building
The goal is within reach
Will she complete her mission?
An unexpected obstacle! Fans!
It's okay, she's just a little hurt
We're making sure it's kept quiet
The head choreographer
wants his pay...
Be quiet! Hello? Hello!?
What happened?
A spinal fracture
She's luckyto be alive
Are you all right?
We have to find out
what happened 15 years ago
Otherwise...
Next it could be me
Tell me what you're looking for
There's an NG somewhere on
this tape
What kind of NG?
Jang Ye-bin died the day that
the shoot was postponed
It must be related to the NG
Put in the moving pictures and
match the lyrics
What are you on about?
1 minute 14 seconds, 10 frames...
1 minute 57 seconds, 15 frames...
2 minutes 34 seconds, 10 frames
It's so hot in here
Okay, after this part....
What words comes next when joined?
What comes after these lyrics?
Geez
That doesn't make any sense
Can we start from the end?
There's no face
This is kind of scary
Wait
We looked at the
tape in reverse, right?
Yes
Can we flip it around?
I don't hear anything
Of course you don't
There must be a clue somewhere...
The chorus
How about the chorus?
What? The chorus?
It's the most important part of
the song
- Try it
- I don't believe this
Come on
Fine, I'll crank up the middle tone
Until it sounds like a human voice
There's no face...
That's the NG take
She wanted to cover up her
damaged face and shoot,
but it was impossible
That's why there were so many NGs
Why her face?
She's the main vocalist
Maybe someone poisoned her
make-up
Who would do something like that?
There must have been a lot of girls
who wanted to be the main
They would do anything to
become the main
Okay
So here's howthe story goes
Jang Ye-bin became the
main of "White"
The others terrorized her face
and the 1st shoot was called NG
But she wanted to continue
shooting
So the others set fire and burned
her to death
Is that right?
No, that's strange
Why?
They ruined her face already
Why set a fire?
She would've already lost the
main spot
To make sure, I guess
No
To undo the curse, I have to
find out who killed Jang Ye-bin
Everything is being repeated
If I keep going, l'll find the answer
What?
I'm in Jang Ye-bin's situation
The main spot will come to me
I will feel threatened
Then you should ask for help
Ask the boss...
If not her, then the sponsor
Why did you change your mind?
I guess...
I want to be the main vocalist too
I've come this far already
I should take it to the end
It's just the way it is
It was like that in mytime
It will continue in future too
"Pink Dolls"?
will they split up?
Did you think
I'd be old and ugly?
Life's really unfair, isn't it?
Please help me
Yes, I will
There's something I need to know
Please help me
Please
Our studio...
Did it belong to your father?
Yes
Relax a little
Do you want to know
how he died?
No
I want to hear about the trainee
that he fooled around with
You're really cute
She had white hair
I know We were the same age
She was talented
She wrote their songs,
choreographed the dances
Her name was Jang Ye-bin
I don't know her name
She hurt her face...
She lost the main spot
Then she killed herself
Maybe I shouldn't have said that
What else?
Come on
Hurry up
Jang Ye-bin wasn't murdered
She committed suicide
She must've really wanted to be the main
That's why she came to see my father
Just like you
The lights went out
I thought it was a crazy fan
I came and found her passed out
What's that?
It's probably a suicide note
How do you know that?
Jang Ye-bin
started the fire herself
Jang Ye... Who? Fire?
There was a fire here
15 years ago
A lot of people died
Eun-ju!
Sun-ye!
Sun-ye...
You're okay now
Deceased, Jang Ye-bin
Please forgive them
Rest in peace
My dance and song were taken
My face was damaged
I decided on suicide as
my last resort
It's so hot...
The moment she died...
She must've wanted to say that
Everything will work out now
I have a good feeling about it
Yes, boss
Yes, we're on our way
Mr. Choi transferred the money
just now
Eun-ju of "Pink Dolls" is back with
her hair dyed a shocking white
With her first solo single recording
& preparing for her music video shoot
next week, Eun-ju is extremely busy
Whether her first solo single can
bring her back to popularity
Whether she can overcome bad luck...
Everyone is curious to find out
"White"
is a huge success in Korea
Eun-ju's old photographs are
a big ssue on the web right now
"White" is working up a storm
"White" has done it at last
Within 2 weeks of the
music video and album release
She's caught up to a single album
of "Pure"
She will be battling it out for 1st place in
next week's 200th episode of 'Music Fever'
Everyone is curious to see whether
her solo debut will be
affected by the recent unfortunate
events of "Pink Dolls"
The patients have woken up
Yes, all 3 of them
Come on, let's go
Leave it, I can do that
I'm almost done
Give me 5 more minutes
Okay, hurry up then
I love you!
Wait a minute
Everyone, gather around
That's good,
but we need more energy in part A
I'm sure
you're all going to debut too
What do you think about when
you dance?
I think that I'm going to die dancing
in front of the crowd
Dancers, please do your best
Let's move, everyone
Let's wrap up
Eun-ju!
You dyed your hair
Does it look strange?
No, it's pretty
But it's really hot in here
Is it?
I'm cold.
The air-conditioner, fans...
"White"!
Can I do a short interview?
Yes...
Sorry, I'll be back
You seem close
She's an acquaintance..
Okay, why don't we begin?
How do you feel about your
solo debut?
It hasn't been easy for me
But I'm happy to finally make
my debut
I composed and choreographed
the song myself
I worked on developing a sexy,
provocative new side to "White"
I composed and choreographed
the song
The song has a complex story
I hope it will be loved
That's not true
I was never a back dancer
I debuted late, so I think people
made up stories about that
No-one hides that kind of stuff
these days
That was a hot performance
What's next?
A song of tears over an unforgotten love
Bang Seung-bae will sing it for us
'Sorrow'
That's it for the rehearsal
Stand-by
and we'll start in 30 minutes
Hurry up, please
"White"... Jang Ye-bin...
You expect us to believe that?
You all experienced it
I still can't believe it
There's no other explanation for it
Why not?
Maybe you poisoned us
A-rang, watch your mouth
Don't give me that
Do you think it makes sense?
Why would a trainee who's going
to debut meet a sponsor?
Don't pick a fight. It's all over
The police confirmed it too
Because they don't know this field
There are only 2 types of girls
that go to meet sponsors
A rookie back dancer
who wants to be a star
Or a cheap has-been whose
expiry date is approaching
Just like you
Call me if you run out of gigs
I'll see if I can find you
a spot as my back dancer
See you then
Maybe we won't see you again
What did I do wrong?
They're in shock
after everything that happened
This all began because they fought
each other to be the main vocalist
- Is that my fault too?
- That's enough. Stop it
You know it too
They never treated me with
any respect
To tell the truth...
I think
they deserve to be punished
Eun-ju...
We're here
You asked me
to drop you off here
Anyway, make sure you come first
"White" MR
"White" original song
"White" music video
Empty trash
Delete files?
"White" original song
Are you in the recording studio?
Did you delete it all?
Don't delete it! Stay right there!
Eun-ju,
should we do your make-up?
It's me
Haven't you had enough?
I'm starting to get scared too
Restore files
I need to check something
"White" original video
Look at that
Notice anything strange?
I don't know
Stop there
Play it in slow motion
The lips and song don't match
Especially there. You can't open
your mouth that wide at that pitch
Listen carefully
It's doubling
3 minutes left, 3 minutes
This way
Get ready. 3 minutes to go
Old pop show, songs of memories
Should we get the show started?
The other parts
are all doubling too
This song...
It's not Jang Ye-bin's voice
What if "White" wasn't Jang Ye-bin?
NG!
Let's look through the NG again
Rewind
I thought there was a suicide note
There was no name on it
That part was burnt
Why's it so hot in here again?
This is the studio. The hosts here...
Are you the CEO of their agency?
No, what's wrong?
I can't reach their boss
A-rang and Jenny have passed out
I think they're dead
What? Dead?
They drank poison to commit suicide
During the show...This is horrible
Dead? It's a live show!
Hey! Stop Shin-ji! Stop her!
You look so stunning
It's an important day today
Sun-ye
Excuse me
Eun-ju
I'm sorry about earlier
Where are you now?
I'm on my way
Listen to me, stop the car
You can't go and sing on stage
What?
You can't sing "White"
The curse isn't over
Stop talking about it
It's all over now
Eun-ju!
The song wasn't sung by her
"White" could be someone else
Don't do this to me
I'm the main now, got it?
I'm "White"!
Hello? Eun-ju!
What about the NG?
It's not moving according to
the subject
These grains are printed on the
film during emulsion
Speak so I can understand!
The film itself is damaged
Jang Ye-bin's face is fine
Then the NG wasn't
Jang Ye-bin's face
Now go to Eun-ju's video clip
I already am
If it's not over There should be
something in her clip
3 minutes 15 seconds,
10 frames Here it is
This is 'Music Fever'
Are you on your way?
Yes, we'll be there soon
We played
the MR in episode 199
We turned off the microphone
by accident
What? I heard all the vocals
It was nothing major
Can you check to see if the AR
and MR CDs were switched?
No way, I check it all the time
It's so hot in here, inside my heart
What's it saying?
Are you sure you found the right spot?
- It's right
Are you sure you didn't get confused?
- It's right!
If "White" wasn't Jang Ye-bin,
then who?
Whose voice is that?
What we know...They said it's hot
Did another trainee die in the fire?
The list of names!
Search this for me
What is this?
A trainee who poisoned themselves
prior to Jang Ye-bin?
Don't worry about that
A back dancer committed suicide
before the fire happened
"White" says it's hot.
The fire...
It's someone who died in the fire
Hello? Is that the studio?
We all heard it
Do you think a ghost sang it?
This is so strange
Hello? Hello? Hey!
Damn it
What did the girls drink?
Chemicals.
They poisoned themselves!
I know that! What did they drink?
Bleach...
The stuff you use to clean floors
Wait...
If you drink that, is it hot?
What?
Do you get hot if you consume
bleach!?
Of course it's hot!
It's 100% pure. It burns everything
from your throat to your stomach!
A back dancer poisoned herself
It's so hot in here, inside my heart
Stop looking
Hang on. Eun-ju's clip
It joins with the chorus of part B
Stop it
It's useless
It's a perfect match.
Let's join them
"White" was a back dancer who
drank poison to kill herself
She's not in the music video or
in the list of deceased persons
Stop it! We don't know her!
Wait
- Wait
- Stop!
Wait. I'm almost done l said stop!
I've got it
Here, behind you...
There, the "White" hair...
There's a ghost
A back dancer ghost
NG
Hello? Yes, Mr. Choi
It's Mr. Choi
Did you arrive? 1st place?
Why are you sweating so much?
It's a little hot in here,
don't you think?
It's a little hot in here
"White", 8 back dancers,
get ready
They're 8 in total, right?
Don't we have 9 dancers?
No, we have 8. Let's go
Do I have some time left?
3 or 4 minutes Make it quick
Do a good job. I trust you
Just think of it as your
last performance
You don't regret it, right?
It's not like I had any other choice
Besides...
I've come too far now
Give me a minute, please
I'll be out soon
We're totally stuck
We won't make it on time
We can't be late
Open the boot for me
Geez
Delete?
Delete request
unable to be completed
Update requests
The 200th episode of 'Music Fever'
Who will be 1st place on our 200th
anniversary? Nominees, come out!
"White", we're awaiting the
announcement How do you feel right now?
You must be
overwhelmed with emotion
Eun-ju?
Thank you for your support
I will continue to do my best
It's her first time being nominated
She's so nervous that I feel nervous
just standing next to her
Enough of the small talk
Let's see the results
Please show us
the graph for 1st place!
The votes have been all cast
Who will be awarded 1st place?
1st place...
Goes to "White"!
The queen of the 200th show!
Congratulations!
You must be so happy
Please tell us
how you feel right now
It's so hot in here right now
I can feel the temperature rising
Let's hear the 200th music queen,
"White" song and return
Give us the song!
I knew you'd come 1st
I'll call you
What was that?
What's happening?
Please stay calm
What was that?
Please turn on
Please stay calm
Calm down everyone
Can you go and save Eun-ju?
Help her, Mr. Choi!
Move!
Open the door!
Open up!
Eun-ju
Boss!
Eun-ju... sorry
Eun-ju!
Over here!
I'm here!
Eun-ju! No!
Eun-ju!
Around 4 p.m. this afternoon,
there was a fire
at 'Music Fever' studio
At the site,
popular singer, "White"
Choi Eun-ju is believed
to be still inside the studio
We will advise you once we have
more information
We have a report..
You're nothing but a back dancer
I told you not to stand out
How does it feel to be main vocal?
Let's see how far you can go with
that ugly face
Do not stand out
To: LaLa sisters Thanks... And sorry
Song chosen, "White"