Subtitles by Soompi TV
[Magic Bakery]
The painted maple bread originally
developed by Magic Bakery was copied
and is being sold by
Shinhwa Bakery with their capital strength.
[Final Episode]
After the story went public,
it's raised questions about the
high-handedness of big corporations.
How do you estimate your damage from it?
We used to have customers
in here like packs of dogs,
but now, as you can see,
there isn't so much as a fly.
Huh?
What are you doing, you fool?
It’s itchy.
I’m talking now.
Oops, I’m sorry.
I didn’t mean to be
rude to the viewers.
You can edit that part out, right?
Ah, yes.
- Please speak comfortably.
- Sure.
Good.
The decrease in sales is an issue,
but the biggest problem is that
Shinhwa Bakery claimed we copied them
so we’ve lost our credibility
with our customers.
Then do you have solid evidence that
Magic Bakery developed and launched
the painted maple bread first?
Yes.
Our painted maple bread was
featured in Gourmet Guide
before Shinhwa Bakery launched theirs.
So it was the bread featured
in Gourmet Guide.
If Shinhwa Bakery copied
and launched it,
they should have expected
this level of controversy.
I don't think that
they care much because
they believe small business owners
like us can't do much about it.
The first daughter of
Shinhwa Group said,
"You don’t have power,
money or a backer."
"Go ahead and try to do
whatever you want about it."
Ah, yes.
The next question is a little different.
I heard that the employees
of Magic Bakery
have a special background.
Can you tell me about it?
We met as cellmates
at Korea Women's Penitentiary.
We’ve lived together
like a family since then
and now we run Magic Bakery together.
It must be hard for you
to make that public.
Thank you for being honest with us.
Many people look at us differently
when they find out we’re ex-convicts,
but we're just trying
to live our lives to the fullest.
I hope that you all
can look at us generously.
Even though we're not perfect,
we make our bread in the safest
and most loving way,
more than anyone else.
It’s Soo In.
Soo In is there.
Soo… Soo In…
- You’re so mean!
- Jeez.
It’s only the bread we copied.
How could they turn it into arrogation?
How would they like to learn
what arrogation really is, huh?
Jeez.
We have enough troubles already.
Please behave yourself.
Hello.
What?
Okay, I’ll call you later.
What happened?
We have a problem, Joo Hee.
What’s the matter?
Our company website is
overloaded with complaints
and the public is demanding a boycott,
not just of Shinhwa Bakery,
but all Shinhwa Group brands.
Oh my.
What?
What should we do?
Huh?
Hello?
Is this Ms. Ma Joo Ran’s house?
Yes, it is.
Are you Ms. Ma Joo Ran?
Yes, I am.
What is this about?
This is Jongro Police Station’s
Criminal Department.
We need to investigate
you on allegations
of requesting the theft and destruction
of a vehicle by Lee Geun Ho.
I need you to come to Jongro Police Station
by 14:00 on March 6th.
If you disobey this summons, we'll have to
come to your home and take you forcibly.
The person you want isn't here.
You’ve got the wrong number.
Who was it?
Why do you hang up like that?
Huh?
I don’t know!
What’s wrong with her?
Our stock price is dropping every day
because of father’s detention.
The major shareholders won't stay quiet.
There will be a general
meeting tomorrow.
Both of us might get
kicked out of Shinhwa Group.
[Shinhwa Group Press Conference]
First of all,
I would like to say that
everything concerning
the painted maple bread
issue was my sole decision.
Since the entirety of this incident
was the result of my negligence,
I’ve decided to resign
from Shinhwa Group as of today.
Again,
I would sincerely like to apologize.
You’ve made a difficult decision.
You did a good job.
I don’t know how I’ve become
such a pathetic person.
I'm ashamed and miserable.
Anyone can make mistakes.
Don't be too hard on yourself.
That's how you used to talk to me.
When we studied abroad,
whenever I used to cry,
you would always comfort me
and say, "You'll be alright."
“We all learn"
"from our mistakes."
That's because you were a lovely,
wonderful friend to me then.
I always wanted to be a lovely,
wonderful woman to you.
Joo Hee.
Don’t worry.
I understand clearly now
that you'll never see me that way,
no matter how hard I try.
I'm leaving for New York today.
New Work?
Why?
I need a break and a chance
to get myself back together
so I can go back to being
the old Ma Joo Hee.
You can shake my hand, right?
[Shinhwa Group General Meeting]
After CEO Ma Do Hyun’s death
and the detention of
Chairman Ma Tae San,
our stock price has bottomed out.
The executives have decided
that we can no longer keep
the position of CEO open.
Accordingly, we'd like to have
VP Nam Woo Seok as our new CEO.
I’m sorry, but I can’t
accept this decision.
I'm sincerely grateful
to all the executives
who have put so much faith in me,
but I am a baker at heart
and not an executive.
I know that baking is my true calling.
Are you saying that you'd rather go back
to being a pastry chef
at Shinhwa Hotel than take
an executive position here?
No.
I'm going back to Paris
to continue studying
as a pastry chef for a while.
I’d like to suggest that
you hire a professional executive
instead of a baker like me.
I hope that you can establish a clean,
transparent corporate image
by incorporating the philosophies
of Shinhwa Confectionery's foundation,
Geobuk Bakery.
Before the CEO Ma came
to the prosecutor’s
office voluntarily,
he made a new will.
I’m sure that
he left everything to Moon Soo In again.
The beneficiary isn’t Ms. Moon,
but Mr. Nam Woo Seok.
What?
With the shares Nam Woo Seok
inherited from Do Hyun,
he moved Ms. Cha
and the other shareholders
to hire professional executives
and change our current management
in order to embrace Geobuk Bakery’s
corporate philosophy.
Do Jin came back to Shinhwa too.
How dare he?
Shinhwa Group isn’t
Shinhwa Group anymore.
I’m the only one of the Ma family
left in Shinhwa.
[The Fall of Shinhwa Group]
For thirty years,
I've lived only for the sake of revenge.
Now, after it's all over,
I finally regret wasting my life on it.
Sang Woo.
Do I look pathetic to you, too?
Is that why you never
appear in my dreams?
I’ll forget about the past
and I’ll live well with the children,
so you can stop worrying about me now
and rest in peace.
Thank you.
Please come again.
It's true there are always
ups and downs in life,
but when I first found out that
Shinhwa Bakery copied our bread,
I felt like I'd been blindsided.
I never would have imagined
such a crisis would make us so famous
that we'd sell out of bread every day.
You can't even read.
I had no idea you could be so eloquent.
Customers can hear you.
Oops.
Sorry.
We need to bake more
painted maple bread.
- Do we have dough left, *Unni?
- [*Unni: Older sister or older female]
Mi O asked you how much
painted maple bread
dough we have left.
Oh, I can bake two more batches.
Okay.
Just stop worrying.
Go tell him not to go.
I’m talking about Byeol’s father.
He's leaving for Paris.
Can you live without him?
I should go back to kitchen
and bake more bread.
Leave her alone.
She's already beside herself.
I don’t think she can handle it
if Byeol’s father’s leaves.
She'll make it.
You don’t need to worry at all.
What if they really break up?
If they’re meant to be,
they’ll meet again anyway.
Don’t worry too much.
I’m a philosopher.
My heart is
with you like this,
so put this ring on my finger
when you want to come back to me.
Young Wok and others couldn’t
come out to see you off
because the store's too busy.
They asked me to tell you sorry.
Is Soo In alright?
She's taking it pretty hard.
I feel so sorry for her.
Since you’re about to leave,
there must be a lot worrying you, huh?
Yes.
Please take care of mother and Byeol.
Don’t worry.
My Byeol.
Even if dad isn’t with you, you should
listen to grandma and grandpa
and get along well with your friends.
I’ll call you and
send you letters every day.
Promise me you'll reply.
Byeol, stop.
Don't cry.
Jeez, you're incredible.
Why didn’t you go see him off?
If you let him leave like this,
you’ll regret it a lot later.
If you ask me
what love is,
I say it’s
a seed of tears...
Don't sing that song.
It makes me want to drink.
Huh?
Why are you crying?
I don’t know.
I just can’t stop it.
Huh?
Are you back already?
Byeol’s father went early.
He left safely.
He said he’ll be back safely too,
so he wants you to take care
in the meantime.
I…
I'm going to go out for a walk.
It’s me, Soo In.
I just finished packing up
and I'm having a beer.
I thought about leaving you a voicemail,
but we won't be able
to see each other for a while.
I'm afraid you'll forget my face,
so I'm sending you a video instead.
I'm leaving for now because I thought
you'd be more comfortable
without having me near you,
but I’m not sure it’s
the right decision.
I'll look pathetic if
I change my mind now,
so I'm leaving.
But if you call me,
I’ll fly back to you right away.
So…
Don’t cry
and don’t get sick.
Take care of yourself.
Even though I'm not physically near you,
don’t forget that I
left my heart with you.
I love you, Soo In.
Why does the table look so empty?
Where is everyone?
Do Hyun...
Where is my Do Hyun?
Do Hyun…
He went to study abroad
for his doctorate.
Where’s Joo Hee?
Joo Hee resigned and went to New York.
She'll be back in a few years.
What about your father?
Father?
Father is…
How long
are you going to make him stay
in that cold place?
What does our corporate legal team do?
They just sit around and get paid.
They’re working on it day
and night to figure something out.
No matter how they work hard,
it’s pointless.
Father has been suffering
for a few months now.
The situation is bad.
Who is it this early?
I’ll go out to see who it is.
Whenever I think about father,
it drives me crazy.
He’s an old man in his seventies
and he's being confined like this.
Oh my.
No one could have dreamed his
later years would be like this.
You should come out.
Why?
They're from Jongro Police Station's
Criminal Department.
What?
Why are criminal
detectives at our house?
Did you make trouble again?
No, I didn’t do anything wrong.
What are you talking about?
I mean it.
- Come here.
- Get off me.
Get off me.
Are you Ms. Ma Joo Ran?
Yes?
Yes, I am.
You're under arrest for auto theft,
vandalism and obstruction of business.
What are they saying?
We've discovered that Ma Joo Ran hired
a detective agency to steal
and destroy a food truck.
A food truck?
I’ve… I've never done such a thing.
Don’t accuse the innocent.
If you cooperate with us, we can determine
if you're really innocent or not.
Wait.
- Ms. Ma Joo Ran.
- What's this?
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can
be used against you.
You have the right to an attorney.
Uncuff me right now.
I’m innocent.
How could you do this?
All of you!
I’ll sue you for defamation.
Oh my.
- Oh my.
- Honey.
- Honey, help me!
Mother!
Mother, save me!
Do we have a guest?
What's all this noise?
Oh my!
What did she do this time?
Yes, Lawyer Park.
Come to Jongro Police Station now.
Hurry up.
Are you saying that
you’ve never been to
Mori Detective Agency?
Yes.
I’ve never been there.
Mo... Mori?
I've never heard of it.
Come in and sit.
Ms. Ma Joo Ran said she
doesn’t know you.
What’s going on here?
She said she doesn't know us?
We took care of her
requests a few times.
Hey, hey.
You know her, right?
You really don't remember us?
What are you talking about?
I don’t remember you.
Do you know me?
This… is a truck.
I don’t care whatever you do,
just get rid of the truck.
I want it to disappear forever.
That's a piece of cake for us.
You know that we’re really good
at what we do.
Wait!
You should never let them know
that I was involved in this.
We’ve already confirmed that
you've had dealings with Lee Geun Ho
through his bank account.
Why don’t you stop denying it
and admit your crimes?
I’ll call my husband and a lawyer.
Let me use the phone,
please.
What… What’s going on?
Why are they here now?
I’m Moon Soo In.
You called me.
I called you because I found the truck
you reported was stolen.
Is this the truck you lost?
- Wow.
- Oh.
Yes, this is our truck.
Yes. this is the one.
Where is the truck now?
Ms. Ma Joo Ran here hired
a detective agency to steal
and destroy your truck.
It's already been scrapped.
My, my, my!
You tall nut.
I got you now.
Soo In.
It’s my fault.
I’m so sorry.
I must have been out of my mind.
I’ll compensate you ten times…
No, a hundred times
what the truck was worth.
Please… Please forgive me this once.
Please?
How dare you brag about your money now?
I’m not bragging.
I’m just saying that I want
to make it up to her.
Enough!
Officer.
We’ll never make a
settlement with her,
so let the law handle her.
Ms. Yoko.
Please save me.
I’m so sorry.
- *Sumimasen.
- [* "I'm sorry" in Japanese]
Sumimasen.
Yoko isn’t willing
to make a settlement at all.
Sumimasen.
Soo In.
We used to be family once.
I liked you a lot.
Please forgive me.
What will happen to her if we settle?
For the theft charges,
she'll still need to be punished
whether or not you settle.
In Ma Joo Ran’s case,
we have solid evidence
to prove her crime,
so she can’t avoid prosecution.
I’m the first daughter
of Shinhwa Group.
I'm the woman who donated $4 million!
Why are you doing this to me?
She’s really driving me crazy.
Forgive me, please.
Please.
It’s daddy.
You practically just went to work.
Why are you calling already?
Can you not work because you
miss your son so much?
That’s not why I’m calling you.
We have a problem, mother.
What?
Is it something at work?
Joo Ran was arrested for theft
and business obstruction.
Her case is being sent
to the prosecutor’s office.
Theft and business obstruction?
How was she involved in that?
She hired a private detective
to steal and destroy Soo In’s food truck.
What?
Dan Shim.
The weather is cold.
Why are you sitting out here?
Welcome back, lady.
It’s been a long time.
You seemed to have
aged while I was away.
Have you been sick?
I missed you.
I did miss you.
I missed you a lot, too.
He’s so cute.
He’s Do Jin’s son.
I hope my Do Hyun…
would hurry and have a son too.
He’s studying abroad now.
If you stay out here,
you'll catch a cold.
Let’s go in.
Even if I go in, there’s
no one at home.
They left me alone in this big house.
If I stay in all day long,
I don’t have a chance
to talk to anyone.
Why are you alone?
There are plenty of employees here.
They are busy with their own work.
They can’t play with me,
so I have to play alone.
I… want to be with you.
Can you take me with you?
Please?
Okay.
Come to my house with me.
I’ll take care of you from now on.
Yes, yes.
People say that there’s
always an ending to evil,
and this is how things will end.
You've suffered so much, my daughter.
You’re the one who had a hard time.
Let’s forget our grudges
and live comfortably from now on, okay?
Yes, mother.
Father,
you have no conscience
and no shame as a human being.
Your whole life, you've built up
a tower of avarice
you call success.
You're just a watchdog to protect
the house and eat dung.
You shouldn’t try to be a hunting dog.
The resentful wailing
and the blood of the people who were
hurt by it is too much to ignore.
Don't you see that, father?
You killed my father
and sent my mother to prison for it.
I lived as an orphan for thirty
years because of you
and you're saying you don't know
what I'm talking about?
You really don't know why I'm here?
I swear to God I've
never done such a thing.
I’ll teach you
what the real price is
for daring to attack me.
You'll end up caught
in the trap you set.
Still, I can’t stop it.
Your sins
killed Do Hyun!
Do Hyun.
I'm ready to
come to you now.
This bread is really delicious.
We have three left.
Thank you.
Bye.
Just a moment.
This bread was baked
by people who miss you,
so it has
all of their warmth in it.
This well-baked bread has
the warmth of everyone who misses you.
[One year later]
[Korea Women's Penitentiary]
Young Wok, where are you?
I’m busy now.
Go in first.
You'll be late.
Okay.
I'll meet you at the entrance
after my class is over then.
I’m here for the baking class.
I’m Moon Soo In.
I’m from Chuncheon.
For dereliction of duty and embezzlement,
I was sentenced to two years.
She passed out!
[Moon Soo In]
Hello.
I’m Moon Soo In.
I'll be teaching you baking
for the next year.
A few years ago,
I was sitting where you are now.
You were in prison like us?
Yes, I was in prison too.
I’m standing in front of you
as an instructor now,
but I was no different
from you in the past.
I thought I'd understand you
more than someone else,
so I decided to come teach here.
I hope we have a great time together.
I can’t let you keep faking illness.
I’m not faking it.
I haven't been able to sleep or eat.
Give me…
Give me… What is it?
A tranquilizer and
vitamins… and a tonic.
Give me a shot with those.
I think I'm malnourished.
That’s why I have a
headache and feel sick.
I feel like dying.
Look at my skin.
It’s ruined, isn’t it?
This is really the last time.
How much is the shot?
I’m the oldest daughter
of Shinhwa Group.
I'm the woman who donated $4 million.
Didn’t you see me in the news?
Man, I looked really
good in those pictures.
Hey.
No, no.
You screwed it up again.
You stink.
This is crazy.
I’m gonna get them all.
- Hey!
- Jeez.
Newbie!
Did you have a banana bag again?
I can't eat or sleep.
I need a banana bag at least.
I can't die in this rat hole.
You can’t sleep?
What are you talking about?
You?
She’s really crazy.
Hey.
Do you know how you slept last night?
Huh?
Do it!
That's how you slept.
That's what you looked like.
We’re the ones who couldn’t sleep.
I don’t snore like that.
I’m very sensitive.
I’m the first daughter
of Shinhwa Group.
I'm the woman who donated $4 million.
You saw me, right?
She's doing it again.
How dare you brag about yourself?
Huh?
We're the same here because
we both committed a crime.
We all eat together,
we all share the same blankets
and we all poo in the same toilet.
Hey.
Don’t brag about your past.
Aww…
- You’re so filthy.
- What?
Filthy?
I think we’ve been too nice to her.
She should learn who we are.
Let’s teach her a lesson.
- Bring it.
- Ok.
- What are you bringing?
I mean you.
- Come here.
- What?
- I told you.
What?
Cover her.
Trample her!
Come here.
Hey, you'll kill her.
Get off.
Easy, easy.
- Do it lightly.
- Inmate 2468!
Ah…
2468 seems to have a cold.
Hey
Are you… okay?
If you tell the guard,
you're dead meat.
Stand up.
Quickly.
Are you seriously sick?
No, I’m okay.
I got a shot, so I'm okay.
2468, you have a visitor.
Huh?
Finally.
- Get off me.
- Here.
- Get off.
- Be careful.
Open the door!
Who is it?
You cheating old woman.
How dare you come here?
Are you here to humiliate me?
Huh?
What a temper.
Sit first.
Ha! She’s so ridiculous.
So what's it like to live here?
Are you making fun of me?
Oh my.
I came a long way
to give you some advice
as a senior inmate.
Stop complaining.
Ha!
Hey.
In here, the smoked chicken is the best.
I deposited $50 for you,
so spend it on some food.
Help yourself.
Also, if you get in serious trouble,
there’s a prison officer
named Kim Yoo Jin.
I’m close with her.
Tell her about me
and she'll take care of you.
My real name is Kim Young Wok.
Stop being silly.
How is she?
Who are you talking about?
- You know, the one making bread.
- Ahh...
Soo In?
She's the new baking
instructor around here
for vocational training.
I came with Soo In.
Ha!
Soo In?
Volunteer work?
Jeez.
Hey.
Even the daughter of a millionaire looks
clumsy and dirty in a prison uniform.
You’re like a cat having hemorrhoids.
A cat having hemorrhoids?
I’m the first daughter
of Shinhwa Group.
I donated $4 million.
Who do you think you’re talking to?
How dare you?
Hemorrhoids?
Did you say hemorrhoids?
Stop it.
You'll get in trouble.
Shut up!
If you scream like this,
they'll drag you off to be punished.
I'm serious.
That means solitary confinement.
Whatever.
- They'll really do that to you.
- I’m done!
Are you?
Are you sure that you won’t appeal?
It can reduce the sentence…
It’s okay.
You don’t need to worry anymore.
So… How’s Joo Ran?
It's just like in the detention center.
She doesn't seem to be
handling prison very well.
You know her temper, father.
According to the prison officer,
she's healthy
and living relatively well,
so don’t worry too much.
Please visit her often.
She has no one else left but you now.
Yes.
Don’t worry and take good care
of your health.
What is this place?
We came to see Do Hyun’s father.
How could you come here?
She wanted to see you.
Why are you in there?
Come out quickly.
I can't leave now.
I have to stay here a little longer.
Thank you.
It must be difficult
to take care of a sick person.
I don’t know what to say.
The sins
I’ve committed against
her and Do Hyun…
I'm grateful I can pay
them back this way.
No.
You did nothing wrong.
It was all my fault.
Yes.
I only rushed forward
like I was deaf and blind.
After coming here,
I've finally opened my eyes
and ears to things.
I've committed a grave sin to you.
If I hadn't done such a thing,
you'd be living happily
with Do Jin's father now.
I've done the unforgivable
to you and Do Jin.
Mr. Chairman.
Yes.
Tell Jin Woo’s mother.
I’ll attend her retrial
and testify that I'm the one
who killed Jae Sub.
Are you serious?
I have nothing more to hide now.
Honey.
Your job is to eat, sleep and pee.
My job is to feed you, put you sleep
and do the laundry.
Right?
Yes, yes, yes.
I'll go get some diapers
and be right back to hug you.
Just wait for a moment.
My twins, father is home!
- My twins.
- Poong Geum!
Oh my...
Oh my God.
You didn’t tell me you were coming.
What brings you here?
We have something to tell
you and our brother.
Did something happen?
I have no idea.
Bow to brother and sister-in-law.
- Bow!
That's enough.
- Sit!
Why are you suddenly
visiting and bowing?
What’s going on?
Huh?
What is it?
One, two, three, four… A grand?
This is a lot of money.
How could you…
All three of us chipped in.
You still don't have a house
because you’ve supported us.
You have twins now.
You should at least stop
renting a room, okay?
He’s right.
We never knew you were living
in a residence hall.
When I was talking to
the sisters-in-law,
I mistakenly said…
- *Hyung! Being the first son isn’t a sin.
- [*Hyung: Older brother or older male]
You’ve sacrificed yourself to support
your siblings until now.
You should give us a chance
to return your kindness.
- Yes.
Please… Please accept it, Hyung.
You’re making me cry.
Thank you.
You don’t need to thank us.
It’s what we have to do.
- Everyone, stand up again.
- Stand up!
Let's bow again to our big brother
and sister-in-law
who have lived such hard
lives for our sake!
Bow!
You guys…
Really…
Thank you, brother!
Is he sick?
Why are you out here?
Why are you sighing so deeply?
Is something bothering you?
The more I think about it,
the more and more pathetic I feel.
Why do you feel pathetic?
I did raise my brothers well.
I agree.
Let’s look for a house tomorrow.
Don’t even think about it.
Huh?
Do you want to keep renting a room?
The house isn’t our priority now.
Hand in your resignation tomorrow.
Resignation?
Learn baking from Soo In
and open a bakery shop
with the money your brothers gave us.
Magic Bakery Number Two!
Magic Bakery Number Two?
You know how popular
our bakery is these days.
Reporters came to cover
our bakery a few days ago.
I’m not sure I can do it well.
For me and our twins,
you should do your best.
Yes.
Okay!
Let’s talk to Soo In first.
Huh?
It’s mother and father.
They seem very serious.
How many years it has been
since you were released?
Can you imagine how I feel
when I have to just
look at a woman I love?
I’m sorry.
Because of Soo In and Woo Seok…
I can’t do it first.
You and I aren’t young, Bok Nyeo.
If you keep delaying us for them,
we'll end up dead before we're married.
How could you say that?
I feel differently from last year.
I even get tired just
doing ironing lately.
There’s no guarantee that
I'll be healthy forever.
Don't be so childish.
I can’t control my anger.
I think it'll make me sick soon.
Even if I eat,
I can’t taste it.
Even if I see something good,
I don't feel anything.
You'll fuss and say I'm too greedy,
but that's who I am.
Mr. Park.
Mr. Park!
Byeol's grandfather
could really get sick.
I know.
We should do something.
Huh?
What do you want to say?
I went to Cheongju today.
I’m so tired.
Soo In went there to have a class.
Why did you go there, Young Wok?
I went to see the tall nut.
I deposited $50 for her.
Is she alright?
Hey.
She went berserk like a mad wild boar.
She looked just like one too.
It must've been quite a scene.
I should’ve gone with you.
By the way, why did
you call us all here?
Oh, that's right!
I forgot.
Mr. Chairman, please speak.
Mr. Chairman?
I'm the chairman of Park Yi Moon
and Shim Bok Nyeo’s wedding
promotion committee.
Park Yi Moon and Shim Bok Nyeo’s
wedding promotion committee?
Yes.
We should do something.
Father could fall ill from stress.
Let’s help them get married.
Darn it!
You bastard!
You only care about Shim Bok Nyeo
and not me?
I can't even sleep at night
because I'm so lonely.
Don't you pity me?
Jeez, you´re so silly!
Why am I silly?
I’m still young!
Young Wok, you have the man
with a hearing aid.
Even Mr. Hearing Aid got married
two weeks ago!
Calm down, Young Wok.
Yes.
After mother and father's wedding,
I promise that we’ll
get you married too.
Really?
Yes, of course.
Don’t worry.
Sit.
Sit down now.
Continue.
Oh, sure.
If we tell them to get married,
it’s too obvious that Byeol’s grandmother
would disagree.
That means we have to prepare
a surprise wedding.
- A surprise wedding?
Yes.
Let's make it a secret wedding.
Is that possible?
We'll lie to them and say we're taking
a family trip to Jeju Island
and we’ll make them get married there.
- That’s a good idea.
- I know.
What should I do with our twins?
It'll be too hard to take them too.
I can ask my mother to take care
of them for a couple of days.
Can you?
Yes, of course.
My mother loves babies.
Thank you.
Wait, just wait a moment.
Is it really okay to have a wedding
without Byeol's father?
I didn’t say anything wrong.
A son should attend
his mother's wedding.
We’re all their sons and daughters.
That’s right.
Byeol’s father will understand.
Yes, I think so.
[Jeju Airport]
The weather is great!
The air is great too!
It’s awesome.
The weather isn’t great.
It’s too cold.
Let's hurry to the hotel.
You've only complained
since we got on the plane.
This is our first family trip together.
Let’s have fun.
Family trip?
Yeah, right.
That's what you think this is?
The scenery on the way here was amazing.
Isn’t this too expensive?
It's our first family vacation.
We should spend at least this much.
Oh, yes.
Don't worry.
Do Jin helped out a lot too,
so there's no need to worry.
Thank you, Kang Ddang's father.
Please don’t.
You’ve helped me so much.
Did you just call me Do Jin?
Don't you know I quit Shinhwa Group?
Your rank is
inconsequential to me now.
Got it?
[Park Yi Moon and Shim Bok Nyeo]
Shouldn't we at least call Woo Seok?
My husband called him last night,
but he didn’t answer the phone.
Why didn’t he answer the phone?
I don’t know.
He's probably on a trip or something.
Jeez, you're making such
a big deal out of it.
What's all this?
They can sleep wherever.
What is all this?
It's like a kindergarten festival.
Don’t be jealous.
We’ll make your wedding
even more beautiful.
If you go back on your word later,
I won’t forgive you.
I wouldn't do that.
Everyone.
Your tuxedos and dresses
for tomorrow just arrived.
What kind of dresses are they?
We’ll be bridesmaids.
What about me?
I’m not going to be a bridesmaid?
Where’s my dress?
You didn’t get one for me?
Where’s mine?
Where is it?
A wedding?
What are you talking about?
You'd have disagreed
if we asked you to have it in Seoul,
so we set up a plan
to have a surprise wedding here.
Your dress and tuxedo are ready
and we asked a priest
to officiate the wedding.
We can't cancel it now.
They went to a lot of trouble for us.
Let’s just accept their kindness
and have a wedding tomorrow.
No!
No way!
Oh, then would you like me
to get married for you?
What?
You said you never would,
so I’ll be the bride instead.
Bride Kim Young Wok
will take the wedding march.
No.
No way!
Byeol.
You miss father, don’t you?
What about you?
Me?
I miss him too, of course.
Then let's go see father together.
Wow.
There are so many stars, Byeol.
The big star over there
is father’s star.
Then the baby star over there
is Byeol's star.
Then the pretty one beside father's star
and Byeol’s star must be your star.
Thank you for letting me in too.
Wow!
You’re a young lady.
Why don’t you put on makeup?
Wear lipstick at least.
Here.
You should look pretty
on a day like this.
Mother should be the pretty one today.
You’d better look pretty too.
What are you talking about?
It’s a secret.
Let's begin the wedding.
Enter the bridesmaids.
Next is the groom’s march.
Enter the groom.
Wow.
You look so beautiful, mother.
Don’t say that.
I'm afraid people will think I'm silly
for wearing a dress at my age.
Who would think you're silly?
You look like a bride in your thirties.
Are you making fun of
your mother-in-law?
Enter the bride.
Let's go in now, bride-to-be.
Hold on.
Enter...
the bride.
Huh?
Who is that?
It’s Byeol’s father.
What happened?
What do you think?
I called him to come back.
I couldn't let her get married
without her son here.
I did a good job, didn’t I, Soo In?
Thank you.
Long time no see, Ms. Moon Soo In.
- I can’t live without you!
- I can’t live without my woman!
I got it, I got it!
I got it.
It’s mine, it's mine!
It’s mine.
I'm getting married!
Look here.
I’m taking a picture now.
One, two, three!
Bye!
You’re getting married,
but you aren’t the only good one!
Poong Geum will introduce
me to a man too!
Gen, gen, gen!
I’m a gentleman!
How have you been?
How do you think I've been?
Have you been well without me, Soo In?
I tried hard to be
because you told me
to take care of myself
and not to cry or get sick.
Wow, you're so cold.
You haven't called me for a year.
You didn’t call me, either.
I didn't call you because if I had,
I would have missed you more
and come straight back to see you.
I had to be patient.
How do you think it was for me?
I missed you
very much.
Say it again.
I missed you
very much
each and every day.
Thank you... for missing me.
This ring...
Put it back on my finger.
[Courthouse]
All of the original evidence
submitted to the court
was found to be perjured.
According to Article 325
of the Criminal Procedure Law,
I find Shim Bok Nyeo not guilty.
I’m proud of you.
I’m so proud of you, Woo Seok.
Congratulations.
Jeez, you burned it again.
How long will it take you
to bake it properly?
Darn it.
Honey.
- Whatever.
- Please try it one more time.
One more time.
- You can do it!
- Okay.
You can do it!
- Fighting!
[Mina Cosmetics, Model Seo Mi O]
Thank you.
What is your name?
Seo Mi O, fighting!
[Silver Matchmaking Service]
[CEO Kim Young Wok]
Excuse me.
Yes, hello.
I’m here to apply for membership.
You don’t need a membership.
What?
You’re looking
at your destiny right now.
Don't you have filming today?
No.
To continue this good mood,
let's have a cheer before we start work.
Let’s start it.
[Magic Bakery]
One, two, three, four!
- Three!
- Four!
- Bang, bang, bang, bang!
- Bang!
[The world called them witches,
but we call them avengers now.]
I love you, Soo In.
[Our inspiring first meeting...]
[Woo Seok and Soo In’s
first shooting...]
[When we thought
it would be the end of our lives, ]
[but we laughed together]
[and cried together.]
[That's how we've become]
[mothers]
[sisters]
[brothers]
[and daughters]
[in a whole new family.]