I hope everybody's
ready to go out.
Have a good time tonight.
It's 8:00 pm, Saturday evening,
and it's still a hot one...
Detail, attention!
Present arms!
ID, please.
You're Sergeant White.
Please proceed.
I believe I will.
Thank you kindly.
Troops, attention!
Now I give you a great general,
a great friend...
"Fighting" Joe Campbell.
At ease.
Thank you all.
As you know, my official
retirement isn't until next week.
But this here, now,
tonight, with you...
...is my real retirement.
Because you and I have
known fear together.
Shed blood together.
Battled pain and suffering,
and all of their foot soldiers.
We know there is no
glamour in a sudden death,
and that no one
ever wins a war.
And it is that knowledge that
will bind us together forever.
That, and a love for this country
that no bayonet can pierce,
no bullet shatter.
To you.
Hooah!
Sergeant White here.
It's Colonel Kent, Brenner.
So you can drop the
cheesy Southern accent.
Hey, the only thing keeping me alive
is that cheesy Southern accent.
Look, I was just checking up on
my favorite my guest detective.
How you doin'?
Oh well, you know Bill.
I just love being undercover.
It's great.
I spent the last two weeks
smoking cheap cigars
and sweating my ass
off in that shitty houseboat.
Well, if you got any sort of time frame?
Yeah, I'm meeting Billing
tonight in the armory.
Then I'll arrest him on Sunday
when we make the exchange.
Then I'm going
back to Virginia.
Yeah, right. Well good
enough. Watch your back.
Thank you. I believe I will.
Oh, man...
Out of gas?
Yeah.
That's why I'm
looking at a flat tire
with a pair of pliers in my hands
instead of a lug wrench...
"Uh-oh, she's a captain".
Uh-oh, she's a captain.
This looks like the work
of ten chimpanzees.
Well, you just missed
the other nine.
They got bored.
Went for a beer.
I have a lug
wrench, can I try?
Well, if you don't, I'm
gonna drag you over.
Get the spare.
- Yes, ma'am.
Golly dang.
If you like pina coladas
and getting caught in the rain,
I will just have to
marry you, Captain.
You'll have to
take this in.
The spare's just a temp tire.
Won't be good for more
than thirty miles or so.
Where would if a fella got courageous
and wanted to send you,
a "thank you" notion,
a bob or a basket of fruit,
where might one
wanna find you?
Psy Ops.
How's that?
Psychological Operations.
I teach there.
What do you teach?
Mostly we fuck with
people's minds.
Damn...
There you go.
Genuine and made in the USA.
All you gotta do is give Dalbert
and me 100,000 each,
and you'll see them
guns on Sunday.
You'll get your money.
In time
I get the guns.
Now, you listen
to me, funny boy.
How do I know you're ain't
one of 'em, 'em Army cops?
Hey, I'm a freedom fighter.
Well, check it out Dalbert.
What'd I tell ya.
We got ourselves
Che fucking Guevara there.
What to do.
A freedom fighter!
Where's your
kooky red hat, boy?
Ain't never been a
freedom fighter worth it
if God ain't got him
a kooky red hat.
You listen to
me, stupid. . .
Dalbert, I think it's
one of 'em Freudian...
Hey, Dal-- Dalbert!
What?
You wanna hear a joke?
No!
How many of them freedom fighters
does it take to screw in a light bulb?
I don't know.
Hey, come on, man.
Relax, huh.
Well, he don't sound like
no criminal investigator to me.
No!
- No?
Well, you're
all right, pal.
I'm sorry about
what happened.
You know, we get a little jumpy
around here before an exchange.
So, we'll see
you Sunday then.
I'll be there.
Yeah, you'll be there.
All right.
Oh, unclench your ass cheeks,
Dalbert, the scary part is over.
Don't tell me. You
need your oil changed?
Nope. This is a token
of my appreciation.
These are strange chocolates.
They're bath products.
Bath products.
- Bath products?
Should I take a hint?
No. Of course not.
Bath products.
Everybody likes bath products.
Do you?
Yes, I do.
Well like, tell me what
you like about bath products.
I like the pink soaps.
and I like...
the skin softener,
and I like the bath beads.
Particularly like the bath beads.
Sometimes I draw a tub...
and then, ah, fill that tub with
skin softeners and bath beads,
Light a few candles.
Put on Coltrane...
Soak my troubles away...
Very good, First Sergeant.
I levied a non-two set
accusation of sexism at you.
And you took it three times
around the dance floor.
Not really.
I just dig bath beads.
Well, thank you.
Maybe I'll see you around.
Am I being dismissed?
Do you mind, terribly?
I have a ton of work here.
No.
I just came by
to give you that.
Thank you. You're sweet.
How's the tire?
Still rolling, ma'am.
I'm glad.
Goodbye, First Sergeant.
- Goodbye, Captain.
Having announced
his retirement,
Gen. Joseph Campbell is being
considered for the vice presidency.
Sources close to presidential
candidate Bill Post tell us
he's poised to select General
Joseph Campbell as his running mate.
Earlier this year, the General gave the
commencement address at West Point.
While it was meant to be
a non-partisan appearance,
it certainly played
like a stump speech.
Leading this country,
that is your destiny.
We'll be back for more in a moment.
Get way over to that car, okay.
And take it into the door.
Backing out.
Snagged.
- On what?
I don't know.
Let's take a look.
Paul Brenner!
Phone call for Paul Brenner.
What'd you say your name is?
- Frank White.
Brenner!
- You military?
- Yes, sir. I am.
Paul Brenner!
I'm a sergeant
at the post armory.
CID Agent Brenner!
...and locked out. The next thing I know,
you know, he's blasting away.
Oh, you military boys got stories more
full of holes than a target range.
Sorry, Pop.
It's Col. Kent at the base.
Is there a Brenner here?
- No.
I'm Brenner.
Thought you was White?
I'm both.
Skunked you, Chief Yardley.
Hey Bill.
No, man. It's over.
Billing's dead.
Okay. All right,
I'll see you there.
Thanks.
Hold on soldier boy.
I want you to tell me
about this Mr. Billings.
Soldier boy?
Okay, Chiefy,
if you have to know.
I was planning to arrest
him in the morning,
during weapons exchange.
But I guess he got wind
that I was part of the
Criminal Investigation Division.
See ya.
Good morning, sir. Where to?
- Urban Warfare site.
You have business there, sir?
- Yes, I do.
Very good, sir.
Hey, Bill.
- Hello, Paul.
What have we got here?
Tortured...
Raped...
And murdered.
Who found the body?
A bomb squad crew
doing exercises.
They called the tower.
Tower called me.
First on scene
was a PFC Robbins.
Is he a suspect?
- She. So I sincerely doubt it.
I have six of my boys securing
the scene. Nothing's been touched.
Oh, no...
What is it, Paul?
I met her the other day.
Damn...
What a shame.
Lovely. Lovely lady.
All right, let's see.
We got...
We got some rigor here.
Petechial haemorrhaging,
which is consistent with asphyxia.
Strangulation, you think?
I'm assuming that,
but there's no tear in the panties,
and no obvious sign of semen.
Is that hers?
- Yeah.
Why is she here?
HQ called her.
She's a rape counselor.
Name is Sarah Sunhill.
The victim doesn't need
counseling, Bill. She's dead.
Yes, but she's also a rape investigator.
She was on her way to an assignment.
She agreed to stay on for this.
- Aren't we lucky?
Get Forensics up
here from Fort Gillem.
Talk to Cal Seaver,
he's a guy I worked with.
Get a fifty-yard grid
around the body.
Make resin casts of
all the boot prints.
Let's see who was here and when
including these fall fine prints of you and hers.
We also need records.
Of Capt. Campbell's personal
and medical records, ASAP.
I already did that.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Ah, Sarah Sunhill, Paul Brenner.
Also, I want you to book a Sergeant
Dalbert Elkins at the armory.
He's the one who started the
arms deal I was working on.
She walked barefoot from
here to where she died.
Why do you assume that?
There's smudge marks on her heels
and the asphalt. Where did she live?
Victory Gardens?
- Where's that?
I believe that's off-post.
Yeah, well I
have to go there.
I'll call the Burford Police chief, I'll get a
court order and meet us out there.
No, that's Yardley.
I don't work with him.
Let's keep it within
the family, okay?
Whatnot, you can't
search her off-post house
without getting a
civilian search warrant.
Oh c'mon, Bill.
You need civilian authority.
Somethin' I forgot, protect Paul Brenner from himself.
Does she have
family here?
Of course.
I suggest you notify them right away.
Detail, Attention!
Present arms!
You're kidding, right?
Kidding about what?
Elisabeth Campbell, Paul.
She's his kid.
Oh, no.
I thought you knew.
- No, I didn't.
The General's daughter.
- Yeah.
What are you doing?
I feel queasy.
Well, hop on,
I'll burp you.
Drive the car, Paul.
I thought you said
you were queasy.
Drive the car, Paul.
Now, look.
I think I can help you on this one,
but I don't want it to be awkward.
Awkward? Now, why would
you think it would be awkward?
You're pouting.
This is not pouting.
Okay.
Sulky petulance, then.
- Wrong again.
This is just thinking
about Brussels, you know.
We'll always have Brussels.
Where?
- The capital of Belgium.
Why?
Why is it the capital,
or why will we always have it?
Why was she murdered?
Well, possible motives for murder.
Profit, revenge, jealousy, conceal a crime,
to avoid humiliation and disgrace,
- or plain old homicidal mania.
Right there in the manual.
Oh, boy...
- Yup.
Hello, we're here
to see the General.
Warrant Officer Paul Brenner, Sarah Sunhill.
Oh yes. I'm Captain Elby,
the General's aide.
Colonel Fowler, the General's
adjutant, will take you in.
Please wait right here.
He's cute.
Oh, please...
He probably practises his salute
in the mirror for an hour...
Please, come in, and
thank you for coming.
General, the CID
investigators are here.
Warrant Officers
Paul Brenner and Sarah Sunhill, sir.
Our deepest condolences, sir.
- Very sorry for your loss, sir.
Thank you.
Please be seated.
First,
I want you to know that you
have my full cooperation,
and the cooperation of
everyone on this base.
Thank you, sir.
You understand the time element?
The time element?
No, sir.
After thirty-six hours, the FBI will
send in a task force to investigate.
But, we prefer to keep
this an Army matter.
The General can keep a lid
on it through tomorrow.
Once the FBI moves in, the
media will be all over this base.
And my daughter's...
Captain Campbell's death...
They'll turn it into
a goddamn circus.
We'll do everything
we can, sir.
I'm sure you will.
Look, let me be blunt.
You're going to have to
decide on this one, Paul.
Are you a soldier?
Or a policeman?
I'm a soldier, sir.
I'm counting on it.
Sir, I met your daughter.
Really? When was that?
Well, ah, it was just a
coincidence. But, ah...
She helped me change a tire.
That, she could do.
She could do almost anything.
Her mother was the same way.
Fix a tire, bake a hell
of a Key Lime pie.
Speak five languages.
Extraordinary woman.
Two extraordinary women.
Goddamn waste.
Again, our deepest sympathies, sir.
And if there's anything else
we can do for you at this time...
Just...
Just find the
son of a bitch.
Yes, sir.
Sir...
When I enlisted
I was underage.
They sent me straight to Vietnam.
And you were
my commander.
You were a captain.
And I, I was so scared.
And one day,
when I was on watch,
You came by, and,
and you saw the fear.
You said that,
"Where are you from?"
And I said, "Boston".
You said, "Did you know that
last night the Boston Red Sox won,
against the St. Louis Cardinals
in the sixth game of the series?"
And then you
just walked away.
Well I knew, I knew then that
I was gonna get through it.
Boston lost that series.
- Yes, but I made it home.
We'll find the
son of a bitch, sir.
Mr Brenner...
I understand you have
special arrest powers,
Yes, sir.
But I'm going to ask
before you arrest anyone,
you notify me.
Why is that, sir?
We don't like our personnel arrested
by outside people without our knowing.
There are three ways
of doing things:
The right way, the wrong way
and the Army way.
See that, in doing it your way, Mr. Brenner,
you don't forget about the Army way.
Our job here at Psy Ops
is to panic the enemy.
To blunt his will to fight.
A psy-operator must know the
customs and habits of the enemy,
their current dissentions, anxieties
and fears, to determine vulnerability.
To engage the enemy, you
must know the enemy inside out.
You must fill him with fear.
And not just fear of dying.
Fear of grotesque wounds
is much more terrifying.
"Grotesque wounds".
I'll show you mine
if you show me yours.
May I help you?
Might I ask what you are doing
in Captain Campbell's office?
That depends on who you are.
Too comfortably ensconced
in her office, I might add.
Colonel Robert Moore.
Captain Campbell's commanding
officer here at Psy Ops.
And you are?
We're from the
Criminal Investigation Division.
Warrant Officers
Sunhill and Brenner.
And you're investigating?
The murder of Captain Campbell.
And now that we
know who you are,
we'll need to
speak to you, Colonel.
I just have a...
I have a meeting...
Something tells me, we can file
Colonel Moore under "last to know".
Are you married?
None of your business.
Right...
Well, she wasn't a hypochondriac,
she didn't dye her hair,
she didn't have oily skin.
And she keeps her method
of birth control somewhere else.
Or perhaps she required
her men to wear condoms.
Maybe you've heard that condoms are
in fashion again because of disease?
Nowadays you have to boil people
before you can sleep with them.
Care for a bath?
Oh, my...
This was one squared-away soldier.
Equally prepared for a military ball
or the next war in the jungle.
Liz, hi. Now, pick up.
It's Robert.
I haven't heard from you,
so call me, please.
Robert.
Surprise, surprise...
Paul.
Move aside.
Man with a gun.
There's nothing here. Let's go.
False wall.
This is it.
Oh, God...
What have we got here?
Ten bucks says these are not
the lost "Honeymooners" episodes.
Well...
How she died does appear
to be linked to how she lived.
All right,
what we need to do here is hold on
to these tapes until we need them.
We empty the house, send
this all to the CID lab,
padlock the house,
and we'll take our chances with this
with the local police staying out.
Is this Paul Brenner speaking?
It's Paul Brenner, the career Army
officer speaking, not the cop.
The evidence of her killer might be on
that tape. I don't have to tell you that.
This evidence here can ruin
the lives of everyone involved.
Including the General.
Now look, we take the tapes,
use them when we need them,
let CID do their job.
and keep all non-military
out of this. Okay?
Okay.
- Okay.
I'll call Kent.
All right. Here.
Thanks.
The phone's down. I'm gonna
go use the cell in the car.
Paul?
Paul!
Did you make out a face?
Yep, it was flat, steel and
used to clear snow.
Come on!
Did you marry ever that guy
you were seeing on the side?
Paul, this isn't exactly
the time to be...
Humor me. I'm near concussed.
Now, did you or did you not marry
the guy you were seeing on the side?
I was engaged to that guy.
I was seeing you on the side.
Fine...
So how is the boy Major?
Seemed a little annoyed the
last time I saw him in Brussels
with a pistol in his hand.
Make a hole!
Identification, please.
Are you working on the
murder case, Ma'am?
Yes I am, and
this is my father.
Please proceed.
What happened to you?
Went off-post without
civilian authority.
And my head paid
the price for it.
And there you go.
Per your request.
- Is this her entire record file?
That's it.
Come up with
anything yet?
Nope, just a preliminary
list of suspects.
Already?
Who?
Everyone.
Well, you ought to start getting alibis.
- Okay, how about you?
Home in bed
when the tower called.
Aha!
Oh, fuck off, Paul.
Where were you last night?
I was busy killing someone else.
I didn't have time to kill two people.
A likely story.
And you?
I went to the BOQ at 1900 hours,
I worked on my Neely case report until
about midnight and then I went home.
No witnesses.
Pathetic, the both of you.
Oh, you should've invited me to
your room, and we'd have an alibi.
I would rather be
a murder suspect.
Huh.
Don't encourage her.
By the way, Cal Seaver's here.
Ah, good.
Now look, Cal is the
best friend's I ever have.
But don't say anything
about his hair.
What's wrong with his hair?
He don't have any.
Hey, Cal!
Shouldn't you be
wearing a hat?
What the hell
happened to you?
Well, you know. Not everybody
loves me as much as you do, Cal.
This is Sarah Sunhill.
Hello.
- How are you?
The entire world walked
around this body, Paul.
There's gotta be
fifty boot prints here.
Have you found
the clothes yet?
Not yet.
I figured you want some more space
so I commandeered an empty hangar.
Good man.
Have everything
taken out there.
Is there any trace of
semen on the victim?
I ran it on ultraviolet,
I can't find any.
The coroner will run
vaginal, oral and anal swabs
and we'll know about
that in due course.
It is a strange rape.
- Yeah.
Why do you say that?
Oh, our guy wasn't just a rapist,
Excuse me.
he was a premeditated killer.
Observed it...
He set up ---uh, a rape kit.
Tent pegs and ropes, and used it.
- Yeah.
Well, there are no
signs of a struggle.
And she was strong woman.
I couldn't find a bit of
dirt under her fingernails.
And how did he hold a gun on her
and managed to tie the ropes?
Unless it was more
than one person.
What are those marks on her cheeks?
Those were tears, Paul.
The panties under the rope as if to
protect her neck from a burn.
I mean, what's a little rope burn if
you're going to kill someone with it?
Sunhill's good.
- Oh, yeah.
Sunhill has spoken.
Could you see the body
from here, Private?
No, but I saw
the headlights.
The headlights?
I hated that it was her.
You knew her, then?
No, but...
Captain Campbell was a...
She was real good
to female enlisted.
How so?
She organized meetings for us and...
See, there's a lot of shit,
I mean, there's a lot of stuff
if you're a woman in the Army to...
that you got
to put up with.
A lot of people don't
like it that we're here.
But Captain Campbell,
she encouraged us, and...
I'm sorry.
You're allowed to cry.
- No, it's all right.
It's all right.
Now, what about the
headlights that you ID'ed?
Didn't you think it was
someone coming home?
Or using the train,
or something?
Sometimes people go out
there in the middle of the night,
some nights to fuck.
Pardon my French.
But that's what I thought
the first time.
First time.
- First time?
The first time I saw the
headlights was at 0300.
They went away, then
they came back at 0330.
Then they went away again
and they came back at 0400.
Okay. Thank you.
What's goin' on, Bill?
What are you
doing here, Yardley?
You got a shitload of
explaining to do, son.
May I ask what is your
official business is, here?
And my official
business here, son,
is to ask you why there's a
bunch of MP's hauling furniture
out of an off-post residence
that belongs to a murder victim?
The family of the deceased,
Chief Yardley,
asked me to take charge of those
items and transport them here.
Sunhill, remind me to call
General Campbell and suggest
that I take charge of those
items and transport them here?
You got it.
Jesus, Paul...
You know what
you need, Chief Yardley?
Hope you don't mind, my saying?
Is a pair of them mirrored sunglasses
for you and the little one.
That'd really complete
the picture.
So...
Did you ever marry
Major what's-his-name with the gun?
Yes, I did.
Ha...
Congratulations. I'm extremely
happy for you, Sarah
and wish you both the
best that life has to offer.
I filed for divorce.
- Good.
Thank you.
Two club sodas, please.
Let's go boys, c'mon!
Now is the place to bet!
You should see her records.
And there's your boyfriend
from the General's house.
Valedictorian in high school.
Super athlete.
Speak West Point
like her Daddy dear.
Now, there's a guy who knows
how to have a good time.
Paul...
Look at me.
I think something
happened to her there.
Elisabeth Campbell was...
tops her class and
she all went to shit her sophomore year.
She barely got through school.
Senior year was better. She managed
to graduate and get a degree,
but she was never
quite the same.
I thought you hated places like this.
I do.
However, the murderer
may be in this room.
Sitting all smug and shiny,
until we walked in.
Now, maybe he's a little less
smug and a little less shiny.
And that's pretty cool.
Don't you think?
What about you?
Well, I hope Brussels wasn't
the last time you had a woman.
Oh, right. Here we go.
Yeah, I always thought
that you chose to avoid
a confrontation with my fiancé,
like I wasn't worth the trouble.
The man threatened to kill me.
I chose discretion.
It is the better part of valor.
Weren't you decorated for valor?
- Oh, please...
Sometimes you just gotta fight for
what you want.
That is... if you want it.
I received a Bronze Star for valor, Miss Sunhill,
for charging up a hill that
I didn't particularly need or want.
And besides, I don't remember getting
any encouragement from you.
Well, maybe I want you not to
accept my decision to break it off.
Maybe I wanted you
to take me away...
You're talking about telepathy
here, not communication.
You know, let's talk about
this next week, okay?
Fine.
Just one more thing.
- Is this next week, already?
You're such a goddamn
sharp detective, aren't you?
but you sure can't reach yourself
and sure as hell don't
know a thing about women.
You know.
You're very cute
when I'm mad at you.
However...
If you'll excuse me.
I'll take my anger
out on someone else.
Ridiculous behavior earlier, I'm sorry.
Well, we didn't exactly
let you see it coming.
Liz was, more or less, my protégé.
At least, I like to think she was.
We were...
Very close.
Please sit down.
Did you work together
on a daily basis?
Absolutely.
Did you...
...play together?
What a truly excellent question.
You see, here at Psy Ops,
that's one of the things we teach.
Threatening quietly.
Think of the echoes inherent
in those four simple words.
"Did you play together?"
Did you go out with her?
Did you fuck her?
Did you love her?
If you did, did you love her so
much that you murdered her?
I meant, did you play golf or
tennis or checkers, or something?
No, you didn't.
- No, I didn't.
So now, we both know we're smart guys.
Do you think I'm involved in this?
One way or another, yes, I do.
Then it would behoove me to
retain the services of an attorney.
I know a good one.
Two problems there.
First, the obvious.
There are no good ones.
Second, you're not
a civilian, Colonel.
You're in the Army.
You have no right to an attorney.
You have no right to remain silent.
And if you don't cooperate,
I may have to put you in jail.
And that would
make me feel bad.
You see what
you're doing here?
Hmm.
Looking for answers?
Of course, that.
But how?
You're trying to
make me like you.
And you know what?
It's working. I do.
But now, do you see
what I'm trying to do?
I'm trying to make
you like me, too.
Do you like me yet?
Why did you strangle her?
Wrong, sorry.
Not up to your standards.
Did you go to college?
What do you think?
I think you did not.
Why? Did I make a
mistake in grammar?
Of course, not.
Even if you were to, I wouldn't
be rude enough to point it out.
No.
You have this chip
on your shoulder.
A big one.
Makes you good at your
job, though, doesn't it?
I could imagine.
Holds you in good stead when you
see those commissioned officers,
those spit and
polish college types.
just waiting for you, you're
the scoundrel in the rumpled suit,
with a healthy
disdain for the rules,
just waiting to
bring them down.
Am I right?
Nah, I'm just here to
kick ass. Sleep till noon.
And you cover your
inadequacies with condescension
to the more robust
individuals around you.
How am I doing?
- Not bad. Robust, even.
When did...
...the event transpire?
0400, we think.
Hmm. See that? My quick
segueway back to the case.
Subtle as a chainsaw.
And where were you?
Snug in bed.
Witnesses? A wife, girlfriend,
roommate, hooker?
I'm divorced. I'm between girlfriends,
I live alone and I do not use hookers.
I actually have absolutely
no alibi whatsoever.
Does that make me a killer?
No. It makes you
lonely and unpopular.
Mmm, very good.
Condescending and clever.
No, thank you.
Okay, so you
called her machine.
You were very concerned.
What is this?
Jealousy, perhaps?
- Perhaps not.
Liz was my friend. I hadn't
heard from her in a couple days.
Okay, so, as her friend, did you
know anyone she was involved with?
You mean sexually?
Yes, sexually.
She was seeing someone.
A civilian.
A fellow named Yardley.
Police Chief Yardley?
No.
No...
Ah, okay.
The son.
His deputy.
Wes.
Yes, Wes. Yes, okay.
They've been seeing
each other, off and on.
For a few months...
Okay, so ah, it's obvious
you were very close to her.
We're trying to find
out what "very" means.
It means...
Very.
I was Liz's mentor.
There was a trust.
She was...
Yes, a passionate young woman
as well, she should've been.
But had I...
ever taken advantage of that?
I would have lost the trust.
So did I kill her?
Of course, not.
Did I love her?
I loved her very much.
Make of that what you will.
This is what made
him famous, isn't it?
Oh yeah, the Ledgeworth City riots.
The whole city was in chaos.
The General quelled it.
Then he brought in unarmed troops
and his little daughter.
Just to prove it was safe.
She looks terrified.
Excellent work.
I'm gonna head down to the morgue.
The report should be in.
You wanna come?
No, we'll be there.
I gotta talk to Cal.
Cal!
Coming.
So how's Moore?
Complicated.
Yeah?
Cal...
We got the dog tag
links back from the lab.
Partial prints belong to somebody
other than Captain Campbell.
Who's that?
Robert Moore.
Hello.
Smells good.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to ask you
a question, Bobby.
And the question is?
Why were you so stupid as to
leave your fingerprints everywhere?
- My answer --- you panicked.
- I teach panic, remember?
Yeah?
Well, obviously I didn't plan for things
to work out this way.
Define "things".
Look, Paul.
Can I call you 'Paul'?
I so enjoyed when you took
the liberty of calling me Bobby.
Here, I still assumed we're still
trying to outsmart each other.
Obviously, Paul.
I cannot tell a lie and say
I know nothing about all this.
I also, sadly...
cannot tell the truth.
And you think silence
won't save your ass.
My ass, as you so delicately put it,
is already in a sling, is it not?
You mean the sex tapes?
You're good...
Great question. Almost any answer
incriminates me, doesn't it?
Yep.
That's why I like it.
Yes, so let's cut the bullshit.
- Let's do that.
We both know I'm
pretty much destroyed.
Can you think of any
compelling reason
why Elisabeth should be
destroyed along with me?
Can you? I can't.
Paul.
I watched the two of you...
...on one of her tapes.
I don't think so.
You know, bluffing is the last
desperate act of the weak, Paul.
I'll not help you ruin that girl.
She's suffered enough.
Leave it there.
I'm all you've got.
Wrong again.
Hello, Captain.
Hello.
Capt. Goodson is with the
Judge Advocate's Office.
He's also my lawyer.
From now on, anything you
have to say to Colonel Moore...
I'll say to Colonel Moore...
Now listen, Brenner.
Don't think you
can bully my client.
You know, I'm done bullying.
You're under arrest, Bobby.
Conduct unbecoming an officer,
plus starter for [Art.] 134.
Disorderly neglect, accessory after the fact,
conspiracy, making false statements.
And...
Captain, you're on the
verge, marked for [Art.] 98.
Non-compliance with procedural rules.
Can I help you, ma'am?
Just taking another look.
- Go ahead, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Is it possible, the bag
with the victim's clothes,
was going to be
picked up by her killer?
or by a third party?
Five Charlie, do you copy?
This is Five Charlie.
Maybe she was here
for a secret rendezvous.
A tryst.
Maybe the rape fantasy
was part of the thrill.
We all know she had a predilection
for the gamier side of sex.
Is there anything to the argument
Elisabeth Campbell picked what
amounted to a nearly public place
because it presented an element of...?
Hold that bitch down!
Let me get in there.
This is the Army...
So you tell Brenner you don't
shit on your brothers.
Rape investigator, huh?
Want to know what
it feels like, huh?
Maybe. . .Maybe it'll make you
better at your job. Huh?
Number five.
- Got yourself a
colonel this time, huh?
Shut up Hawkins.
You were acting as her shrink,
were you not?
Were you not?
The Elisabeth I met
was bright and shiny.
The woman on the
tape was a different lady.
And there's a direct connection,
isn't there?
Isn't there?
Are you going to pull
my fingernails out now?
What happened at her sophomore
year at the Point?
You're a murderer or
an accessory to murder!
Either way you get
burned at the stake.
Nobody's going to bail you out.
It was awful.
It was awful. Go ahead.
What? She violated the Code?
She cheated, she lied, what?
Worse.
Drugs?
Rape?
Worse.
What's worse than rape?
When you find that out,
then you'll know
everything, won't you?
Tell me what the
hell happened, Bill.
Look, I'm sorry Paul,
but the MP claims he got a
radio call to leave his post.
I've got no record of that call.
Probably a dead end, but I'm taking it further.
I'm pulling up, talk to me later.
- She's fine, Paul.
- Who did it?
- I'm okay.
Stupid play, Elby.
Perky move.
Be sure to remember to take off all
identifying jewelry before an attack.
I don't know what
you're talking about?
I told you I was in
the "O" Club all night.
She's crazy, and you're crazy.
- You burned me.
- Sorry.
Sorry about that. You just can't
get good Styrofoam these days.
Okay, let's change the subject.
What can you tell me about
Capt. Elisabeth Campbell?
What about her?
She was raped and killed.
You know what rape usually is?
It's a woman who changes
her mind afterward.
Would you classify your relationship with
Elisabeth Campbell as an intimate one?
- You mean, was I fucking her?
- Yeah, that is what I mean.
Yeah.
I was...
But that's all I took it for
you know, just sport fucking.
I didn't think she's just
gonna run off and tell him.
- Tell who?
- The General.
The bitch told the General.
Why?
Because she's a freak and
that's what freaks do.
What about the General and Capt.
Campbell, were they close?
- No.
- Why not?
I don't know.
You like your dad?
My dad was a drunk, a gambler,
a womanizer. I worshipped him.
Yeah, well I think
I've said enough.
You cooperate, and maybe
we'll keep it out of the report.
You guys don't get it.
With Elisabeth gone, the General has got
a clear field to settle some scores.
And I'll be given the
opportunity to resign.
Maybe I can save my marriage,
or maybe I can't.
Oh great, there's a Mrs Elby.
And what does she do,
aside from waking up in the
middle of the night, screaming?
What do you mean,
settle some scores?
Okay! I told you,
I'm done talking to you.
Hey, we just got started, Elby.
I'll bring you up on charges
for the assault on Agent Sunhill.
See how you like four years of
sport fucking in a military prison.
Okay, dare me.
Go ahead, motherfucker, dare me.
Now, I'm going to ask
you one more time.
What do you mean
by 'settle some scores'?
Okay, okay!
When she was alive,
He couldn't touch her...
...without embarrassing himself.
He couldn't touch any of us,
because he knew
she would spill all.
All?
Meaning,
imagine what'd it look like?
the General's daughter banging
his entire male staff.
- Entire male staff...
- Yeah.
Yeah, everybody.
At least most of them.
What about the Sheriff's son?
No, that was just for show.
She was pulling along
this military train imaginable,
right up the chain, she went through
most of the General's immediate staff,
plus the staff Judge Advocate,
and people like me in key positions.
What about Col. Fowler?
Colonel Fowler once told me
he knew all about this.
And that I was
part of the problem.
I think he meant
that he wasn't.
What do you think
about this, Agent Sunhill?
I think it's insane.
Not really, Elisabeth once told me,
she was conducting a field
experiment in psychological warfare.
And that the enemy was Daddy.
- You okay?
- I've been better.
- God, Paul.
- I know, I know.
Most of these officers are married,
it's immediate grounds for court martial.
Their lives are over.
But I'll tell you this:
It's a helluva motive for murder.
How's it feel that our suspect
list is multiplying exponentially.
Well, at least we know the guys
who were on the tapes.
Yeah, a bunch of creeps willing
to risk it all for a piece of patch.
A piece of patch?
Sorry darling, I just
get back on the base
and it dredges up all my
old alpha male behavior.
Great, what's next, you're gonna do
ear-funnel and light your own farts?
- Maybe, after we see more.
- Oh, I can't wait.
Where is he?
- Bill, where's Moore?
- Oh, he was released.
What?
Restricted to quarters.
On whose orders?
On mine. It looked like he was
having a damn heart attack, Paul.
His lawyer came in
had a valid complaint.
Hey, you can't put an
officer in common lock-up.
He's a murder suspect, Bill!
Since when?
Since...His prints were all
over the goddamn tags!
Well, you never informed us
he was a murder suspect.
He was being held here
for conduct unbecoming.
Not murder.
I had no choice.
Bill?
Moore?
Moore!
I'm going in.
Oh, my God.
The organics on Elisabeth
Campbell came back.
There's no sign of rape.
- What are your thoughts on this?
- Apparent suicide.
Star pattern. Close contact
wound. And I don't buy it.
I'll do a UAV, check his
hands for gunpowder residue.
I'll let you know if I
find any inconsistencies.
Colonel Kent!
Yeah?
Were you aware of Elisabeth
Campbell's extracurricular activities?
How do you mean?
You know what I mean.
There were rumors, innuendo.
I always took it
as false bravado.
You know, soldiers bragging,
that sort of thing.
But there was more
to it than that.
Mr. Brenner.
As soon as you're
through here,
We'll convene at
the General's house
to coordinate the release
of the official findings.
What are you talking about?
Obviously, Moore was
overwhelmed with guilt.
We need to close up shop.
The General would
have it classified.
We'll release a statement
about Moore's guilt and suicide.
You don't understand,
Colonel Fowler.
This is my investigation,
and it's still open.
Who the hell do you think you are?
It's over.
Over!
You'd better start thinking about
your career, you understand me?
You'd better start
thinking about yours.
You're running a
lunatic base here.
You want to mess
with me, Colonel?
Let's start gouging away.
You've been warned.
Move out.
What are you
doing here, Yardley?
Shouldn't you be out
night-sticking the colored folk?
Wait in the car,
I want to talk to him.
Your son Wes,
we've got to speak to him.
Apparently, he was
involved with the victim,
but you neglected
to mention that to us.
He's on duty
when it happened.
His partner can verify that.
We got tapes of his
radio calls all night long
Just the same,
we'll be in touch.
Good night.
Asshole.
What is that?
The gods have smiled
on you, Paul Brenner.
Oh yeah, why is that?
Because this is a West Point
psychological report on Elisabeth Campbell
and pages from her medical file.
Pages we were never given.
Well, what does it say?
It says we're going to West Point.
Yes?
- Brenner and Sunhill, sir.
- Come in. Come in.
And talk loud.
Terrible thing for a shrink to lose.
Can't hear some my
patients half the time.
Of course, considering
some of my patients.
Maybe it's a blessing.
Col. Slesinger... Do you prefer
being called Colonel or Doctor?
I prefer Donald. And I'm assuming you
didn't fly here from McCallum to bullshit.
No, sir. It's what I
told you on the phone.
Yes, and I told you on the phone
that I can't talk about Capt. Campbell.
Nothing has changed.
- You were her psychiatrist?
- And a poor one, at that.
Well, she was at the end of her sophomore
year when she came to see you.
She was must've been about 20.
She was in a
serious depression.
I take it from your presence here,
Lizzie's in some trouble again?
Not now.
That's good.
Well, she's too
young to be dead...
She was strangled, sir.
Mock raped and then strangled.
Goddammit! Goddammit!
I couldn't help her.
I tried, but I couldn't unlock
her enough to trust me.
But you know what?
I still can't talk about her.
No, you can't.
But you're angry, yes?
Of course.
Sometimes when I'm angry
I talk to myself out loud.
Do you ever do that,
just sort of rant?
Yes, sometimes.
Or, if you were to rant...
and we happened
to be in the vicinity...
- Free country.
- That's my thoughts exactly.
She sets the place on fire,
our Lizzy does.
Top woman here.
Pretty as hell.
Outdoes most of the men
in the training runs.
At the end of her sophomore year-
- there was a big night exercise.
There must have been
thousands involved.
Lizzy got separated from her group.
Found herself with about
a half a dozen men.
A very dark night.
Not only were the
men unknown to her,
- but they were also
wearing camouflage.
They raped her
almost to death.
Raped her all night long.
Taking turns.
Stripped her.
Spread-eagled her.
Nailed her to the
earth with tent pegs.
Just had a
whale of a time.
Threatened to kill her
if she talked.
Tied her underwear
around her throat?
Yes.
Lizzy was hospitalized.
Treated for venereal disease.
Treated for pregnancy.
By the time I got to her,
she had gone away inside.
Never let me get close.
Who were these guys?
I need a name.
No. Sorry. Medical ethics.
I'm gonna finish
my work here.
I can't tell you
what to do, but...
You go back to my office.
The key's under the mat.
You would look
up Lizzy's files,
you might find an additional notation
there with a man's name on it.
It might be worth your while
to stoop. It's up to you.
Free country and all that.
Sorry I couldn't
be of any help.
Beginning our descent
to Fort Benning, ma'am.
Now, Ranger! Let's go!
- Female on the floor!
Female on the floor.
Capt. Bransford?
Uh-oh.
Yeah. That would be me.
What can I do
for you, honey?
Better yet, what can
you do for me?
Well, dear, you can ask
these other men to excuse us.
Yeah, that's a CID badge
you're looking at.
Looks like I picked
the wrong woman to "honey".
Hmm, that's right.
I'm Sarah Sunhill, Captain.
I'm a rape investigator for the CID.
We need to talk about
Elisabeth Campbell.
Right. Liz...
Liz and I were classmates
together at the Point.
Oh, I only have
just one question:
How scared are
you right now?
I'm sorry, Miss Sunhill. Is it possible
that you're in the wrong place?
Your heart's racing
a little faster.
There's a little ball in your
throat sticking under the arms.
- Yeah, I think that's enough.
- You can sit your ass back down.
I know you weren't the leader.
If you say so, Miss Sunhill,
but I really do not know what
in the world, you're referring to.
You're too weak
to have started it.
You're just a guy who's gotten
by on his smile and his charm.
Well, that's a good smile. But
you could never lead a rape.
Well, that sure is
good to know.
Elisabeth Campbell was murdered
thirty-six hours ago.
Staked out with tent pegs
and strangled.
So I'm gonna ask you that
question again, Capt. Bransford:
How scared are
you right now?
I was right here
on the post, lady.
But you were right there,
seven years ago on maneuvers.
You were right
there for the rape.
You can't prove shit.
That's not what
Dr. Slesinger's records say.
Yeah, okay. I went
to see Slesinger.
And I told him a story
that I had heard.
That's what his
records say, Miss Sunhill.
It was just a story.
Somebody else's story.
And that's it. Understand?
- What is that?
- What does it look like?
Well, it looks
like underwear.
Women's underwear.
Amazing scientific changes
in the last few years, Captain.
Won't you agree?
Amazing scientific changes
in the last few years, Captain.
Won't you agree?
I wouldn't know.
Certain fields?
It's been incredible.
- If you say so.
- Like DNA.
If it's there, it's there forever.
But then, you probably
already knew that.
Those are hers, aren't they?
I tried to stop it.
I did everything I could.
But they hated her.
They hated her so much.
They hated that she
was smarter than them.
they hated to be out there with
somewhere to squat to piss.
I tried to save her,
I did everything I could
but I couldn't
make 'em stop.
Who were the others?
It was my recon squad.
Their names are
in the yearbook.
Liz was my friend.
Thank you very much
Captain for your cooperation.
Someone from CID
will be in touch.
What are you doing?
What does it look like?
- What about the DNA?
- What DNA?
I bought those an hour ago.
So long, honey.
That's a positive match, right?
Yep, Paul. It's only a partial boot
print, but it's definitely Col. Fowler's
and it's right next to the body.
Good.
Good work.
Now look, we've only got
'til the end of the day,
then the Feds are
gonna be all over us.
Gotta go.
Hi.
Look, I got a lot on
my plate just now.
I just. . .I just want to thank
you for everything you did.
For what?
For leaving the medical
records in the car.
Now, did he instruct you to
give me the medical records?
Not in so many words.
But I think I
knew his wishes.
You know. Anything
that might help Elisabeth.
I'm sure you know
how much he loved her.
Not as much
as he loved you.
What do you mean?
Well, you know.
Something about the surprise way
that you came in that night,
the extra care he had
in making dinner.
What do you planning
on doing about it?
Not a thing.
Other than to tell you that
I'm sorry about Moore.
To ask you for your help.
Here, sit down.
What exactly do
you need to know?
I wanna know about the
recreation of the original rape.
I suppose that's
what it was.
Was it Moore's
idea to do this?
Think can cleanse her of her past?
- Oh, no. Jesus, no.
She thought it up.
He couldn't talk
her out of it.
I'd say, he thought so, so
bad that he killed himself?
Look, you and I both know
that's not how this happened.
And that's where they screwed up,
whoever did this.
Because, they didn't
know about Bob...
...and me.
Bob could no sooner
have killed himself.
I could pull a chicken
out of my hair.
But these are various
types, they don't get that.
You know, they
don't understand that.
Affairs of the heart.
Way beyond them.
Okay, so he staged this thing.
He tied her up. He then got
rid of her clothes, what?
Yeah, and he also had to make
the call to the General.
Play him the tape.
The tape?
General... Brenner.
Paul, come in, please.
Just wanted to
say goodbye, sir.
I'm driving back to headquarters
in the morning.
I'm leaving tomorrow, too.
I'm taking Elisabeth to Michigan,
- to be buried next to her mother.
Thank you...
...for everything you did.
I understand you're
still going into politics, sir?
Well, the jury's still out.
We'll see.
When you just thanked
me for what I had done,
what I wanted to say to you,
was I really didn't do anything.
At least, not anything right.
I did a lot of things
that were wrong.
You're not responsible
for Moore's death, Paul.
Any good investigator has
to follow his instincts.
I'd like to talk to you
about that, sir.
We all know that Moore did it,
then killed himself out of guilt.
Then we're all in agreement.
And I got thinking. . .
But what if, I was wrong?
What if it wasn't the same car three
times, but three different cars?
That's certainly an interesting theory.
But, what difference does it
make, since Moore is dead?
Probably none, sir.
It got me thinking
about your daughter,
and what she told
me. she taught.
"Mostly we fuck with
people's minds," she said.
Okay, then.
Thank you, Brenner.
You can go now.
- Tell me about the rape.
- But she wasn't raped.
It was just made to
appear that way.
The rape at West Point.
It was kept confidential.
- For the good of the Academy.
- And the Army.
And it was best for
Elisabeth, that way.
You were in Germany
when it happened?
Berlin. I was stationed there.
I came back as soon as I heard.
We flew all night.
And you went straight
there from the airport?
Of course.
No meeting first?
- Seems, Mr. Brenner is very well informed.
- It was in her psych records, sir.
It didn't happen that way.
George...
He's right.
The meeting did come first.
It was seven years ago.
The details get confusing.
It was nothing. Just a quick briefing
in a hotel near the Point.
General Sonnenberg.
He was very...
...sympathetic.
I want justice for my daughter.
I would give anything if this
had never happened.
But it did.
And I'm trying to tell you
the reality of the situation.
We'll never find them. Someone
we'll never know who did it.
But we do know this. . .
A co-ed academy is a good call.
And a necessary call.
Better one unreported
and unvindicated rape,
than to shake the foundations
of West Point.
To cast suspicion on a thousand
soldiers who did not gang-rape her.
One woman, that night.
All we have to do
is convince your daughter,
that she, the Academy,
the Army and the call of equality,
would be best served if she
just forgot about the whole thing.
These are the times
we live in, Joe.
He was right.
If it had gone public,
it would have permanently
damaged women in the military.
It would've destroyed West Point.
It was an untenable situation.
Is that what you
told Elisabeth?
Not in so many words, no.
She was in no condition
to understand that then.
I simply tried to tell her
that I loved her.
I loved her very much.
Daddy loves you.
And he's so proud of you.
Rest now. Try not to
think about it anymore.
Listen to me.
I only want what's best for you.
Trust me.
Do you? Like you always did?
Then don't ever think about
any of this again.
I know, I know. It's an awful thing.
A terrible, terrible thing.
But thinking about it won't help it.
So...
Close your eyes.
It never happened.
None of this ever happened.
Not my finest hour.
You were just doing
what you said.
Trying to protect her.
I did what I had to.
What I thought best
for everyone concerned.
Nothing else that
could've been done.
They never would have
found them, anyway.
- Here you are, sir.
- What is that?
The names of the perpetrators,
by associate Agent Sunhill.
Found with a
minimum of trouble.
Apple pie, sir.
That's just brilliant.
Each man will be
looking at 20 years, sir.
I think you'd
better go now.
Fine.
We'll just deal with the
phone call issue tomorrow.
If you prefer, perhaps
before your flight.
What phone call issue?
I have excellent
reason to believe
that Moore phoned you at 0300
hours, the night of the murder.
And why in the world would
he have done that?
Well, if I'm right, sir,
I think the whole recreation
of the rape was Elisabeth's idea.
God knows
why she did it.
Perhaps, because you
were going into politics.
She thought it
was her last chance.
But I think she got Moore to put her in
exactly the same position as the rapists did.
Seven years ago.
This time, you weren't in Germany.
And if I'm right,
she would've wanted you to see
firsthand what you covered up.
That never happened!
A gift from Moore's lawyer.
Dad, this is Elisabeth. I need to discuss
something extremely urgent with you.
You must meet me at the mount
site no later than 0330 hours.
I have an answer
to your ultimatum.
It's hard to argue with a recorded voice.
I'm sure it was part of her plan.
What does she mean
by 'an ultimatum', sir?
I gave her two options:
Resign her commission,
or agree to some sort of therapy.
If she rejected
both of those,
I would instruct the staff judge advocate
to investigate her misconduct
and draw up charges
for a general court martial.
I'm sure that must seems callous to you.
So you drove out
to the mount site.
Of course.
I needed an answer.
Here's the answer
to your damn ultimatum.
Jesus Christ...
Do you see what
they did to me?
Do you see?
Don't turn away,
you coward.
Come closer, get a better look.
See what they put me through.
What the fuck, do you
hope to accomplish?
There's a rope around my neck.
You can strangle me if you want to.
Just cover it up like you did before.
Have you gone
completely out of your mind?
It happened.
It happened!
I want to hear you
say it happened.
I don't give a damn what happened
to you seven years ago.
Whatever hurts you
makes me stronger.
The damage would not destroy me,
it makes me stronger.
You can't hurt me anymore.
- We're even.
- That's fine with me.
You never helped me!
Daddy, please don't go.
Come back.
Please...
Daddy...
You were in
the second car.
Which means Col. Fowler...
...must have
been in the third.
You couldn't expect a man
to deal with his own child.
She was screaming
such vituperations at him.
Of course not.
So he called me.
And he asked me to deal with it.
I went...
And I found her dead.
- You found her dead?
- Of course.
But you will never get me
to testify against the General.
What?
I've been by Joe Campbell's side...
...too many times.
Looked death in
the face with him...
...too many times.
I'll not back down now.
In God's name, what
are you talking about?
It wasn't like she
didn't give him reason.
- George, for Christ's sake!
- And when we realised...
...she was fucking everybody...
...from Bill Kent to Jake Elby,
it was too late for official action.
Colonel Fowler!
You'd have to ask for
all their resignations.
- Strangulation, you think?
- And then resign ourselves.
You need civilian authority.
What happened to you?
- You had no other choice, sir.
- You think I killed my own daughter?
- It'll die with me, Joe.
- You sorry son of a bitch!
- Bill, where's Moore?
- He was released.
Oh, my God...
Seaver...
- Cal, it's me.
- You arrest Fowler?
No, let me speak to Sunhill.
She's not here.
She got in an hour ago.
Then said she was going back
out to the crime scene.
She go out there, alone?
Sir, she took the big dog with her.
Capt. America himself.
Kent. It was his idea. He wants
you to meet him out there.
Of course he does.
Sunhill!
Bill, we've been through this
place, a dozen times before.
We're not gonna get
anything else out of this.
Paul?
Sure, sure...
Paul...
Think the three of us need to go back
to your office and talk.
I've always been in and out
towards that kind of guy.
Why don't we talk here?
That is, if we have anything
really important to talk about?
I thought you'd do your job. Pin it
on Moore then move the fuck on.
Oh, God.
But I forgot, you were the
nastiest rat in the shithouse.
Just goes to show you.
Why did you do it?
Why?
You tell me, you're the expert.
I think this is a woman...
Giving it out all over the post to
the one man who cared about her,
The one who's willing
to risk it all for her,
is the person she doesn't want.
And that's because
she couldn't want anybody.
See, I just wanted to
be with her, forever.
She owned my heart.
She tormented me.
She became my obsession.
So I followed her, and found her
out there on the range.
On display.
Elisabeth?
Get outta here, Bill.
Get the fuck outta here.
He'll come back.
I know he will.
You can't be around.
You'll ruin it all.
- What are you doin' out here?
- What's all this about?
My father send you.
Is that why you're here?
No.
- Did he send you to shut me up?
- No.
No...
Well, this time I won't be quiet.
This time I will tell everything.
About him, about you.
I'll tell your wife...
And I'll tell your kids...
Don't touch me!
Get your hands off me!
You repulse me! You're a disgrace!
You're not a soldier. You're not
even a man. You're just a fuck.
I fucked you!
Oh, Christ!
C'mon, Bill, let's get going.
Come on.
I'm all yours, Paulie.
Whoa!
Before you come closer,
don't you want to know
where you're standing?
- Where am I standing?
- In a minefield.
Ah, c'mon, Bill.
I buried some Bouncing Betties.
Anti-personnel.
Bye, then.
Oh, you're reasonably safe here, Paul.
but little Miss Can't-be-Wrong
over there...
She's deep in the hurt locker.
You remember
how the Betty works?
First man trips the primary,
mine shoots up,
the rest of the column
walks into the blast.
Heads are removed,
or limbs, whatever...
Backtrack the
way you came.
You know it's amazing,
what a load of shrapnel
do to flesh and bone...
- Sarah, you're fine.
- God!
Bang!
Scared you, didn't I?
You're an asshole, Kent!
Come on, Bill, it's over.
Yeah, it's over.
But not the way you think.
Detail, attention!
Present arms!
The human eye can distinguish
sixteen shades of grey.
A computer image processor,
analyzing a fingerprint,
can distinguish 256 shades
of grey, which is impressive.
The human heart,
mind and soul, however,
can distinguish an infinite number of
emotional, psychological and moral shadings.
In Psy Ops we deal with the blackest
of black and the whitest of white.
At ease, soldier.
Is Col. Fowler coming?
No, he's taking some much-needed R&R.
He's a good man, George.
A good man and a good soldier.
Sometimes the lines
get a little blurred but,
but when push comes to shove...
- He'll do what needs to be done.
- And what is that, sir?
Say Moore called him,of course.
And that I was never out there...
He'll do that for me,
even if it means his career.
Like a good soldier.
Nothing is gained
by my involvement.
A letter of commendation
will be inserted into your file.
In recognition of your
exemplary work on this case.
Remember when I asked you
if you were a cop or a soldier?
Yes, sir.
Well...
You're a soldier, Paul.
And a damn fine one.
General Campbell...
- You're wrong. I'm a rotten soldier.
- Oh? And why is that?
You really don't get it, do you?
The only mind Elisabeth wanted
to fuck with was yours.
And you still don't get it.
I've done nothing wrong.
You killed her.
What did you say?
Seven years ago,
in that hospital room.
When you told her to just
forget about it, you killed her.
Kent killed her.
No. Kent just put her
out of her misery.
I once asked Moore what
was worse than rape.
Now, I know.
Betrayal.
I loved Elisabeth,
but there were larger
issues to consider.
You traded her trust
for your career.
You made a deal,
didn't you?
You kept silent, and they
gave you another star.
You watch your
mouth, Brenner.
I'm gonna say
that in my report.
That you knew she was out there,
then you went out and talked to her,
and left her out there to die.
- You don't have the balls.
- Oh, you're wrong, sir.
Because that's just about all I have left.
You do that, you can kiss
your career goodbye.
I'm gonna have you
court-martialled, General.
Under Article 32 for conspiracy
to conceal a crime.
When this all started, I told you that
we would find the son of a bitch, sir.
I never expected that the
son of a bitch would be you.