Well, let's see what we´ve
got in this thing.
Hot dogs, beans, napkins
...oh wine!...
... coke, ...
... apples, ...
... 3 sandwiches, you pig...
Thank you dear,
I love you too.
Oh, what's this?
Looks like skipping stones.
Oh those are arrowheads,
I found those right outside
the front door.
You know this whole area
used to be Indian territory?
Come on to the picnic Shelly.
We might as well live like Injuns
as long as we're up here.
These Indians don't go
on picnics.Come on!
Would you be quiet,
I got her just where I want her.
Seven spaces in front of Boardwalk.
Okay, but you're missing
out on a good time.Come on!
Well, we're coming to have fun
and all she wants to do is play Monopoly.
Don't worry about it.
Hey.
I'm going to teach you
something interesting.
See this one?
-Yes.
... this is part of a hunting arrow,
okay?
And this used to fit on a larger
spear for hunting bigger game
like you know...deer.
How come you know so much
about Indians?
I'm an old boy scout.
It's my duty to know!
Besides, I grew up in this area,
you know I...
It's all I ever heard was Indian
legends and stories...
you  know, the whole bit.
You want to know something
interesting?
For a change, you mean?
You know this place we're staying?
It used be part of an
old indian burial ground.
Very sacred and holy.
Ooh, scary!
Well, is it cursed or something?
Yeah.
As a matter of fact, it is.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Don't worry about it.
You're only cursed by the evil
spirits if you violate the graves
of the dead...
... we're just going to be
eating hot dogs.
Besides, I'm there to protect you.
You?
Yeah.
You're going to protect me?
Yeah!
Hey!
Help me build a fire
for the hot dogs...
why don't you see if you can
find some wood.-Okay.
God ...
... this stuff must be 200
years old!
Here's your firewood.
That's as far as I go!
Ellen, look at this!
What is it?
It's an old Indian dagger.
God, it's in perfect shape.
Oh my!
What's it doing here?
Well, as far as I know ...
... when the medicine
man of a tribe died, ...
... they used to bury one
of his possessions with him...
... so he could have it
in his next life.
Oh, you mean we're having
a picnic over somebody's
dead body?
Yeah, but all that's left now
is Tinga.
The Indian spirit of the woods ...
... who watches over and
protects the medecine man's
grave for all eternity.
Oh hold me, I'm scared!
Go directly to jail, do not pass...Fuckin'...
Damn it, I hate this game!
Oh really?
Because you're losing now.
Oh, I'm sure. This game
is for fat old spastic people
that don't know any better...
... I can't do any damn thing.
I hate this lousy game.
Well, 20 minutes ago
you didn't think so.
Yeah, well that was different either...
That was different.
And why was that different?
I was winning.
Bruce?
Bruce, where are you?
Bruce!
Bruce has gone back to the
cottage without me.
Who's there?
Scotty? Scotty?
Scotty, is that you?
Please, who's there?
Answer me!
Scotty!
Scotty! Shelly!
Open the door!
Open up!
Sorry, I locked her out.
Yeah, Jeez.
Oh God. Who the...
I guess you should
get the door. Yeah...
Alright, alright!
He's dead, he's dead!
Who's dead? Bruce?
I saw him ...
... he was on the ground ...
he was all cut up.
Oh God. Are you sure
it was Bruce?
Did you see his face?
I was sleeping...
Ok, slow down.
...And I woke up
and then I started running...
Alright here's some coffee ...
See if you can make
any sense out of her, I can't...
It's ok Ellen, you were
having a nightmare...
you could've been completely!
Alright, listen. Maybe Bruce
is hurt. I'm going
to go outside and look for him.
I want you to take care
of her. Be careful.
I'll be back. You be careful.
Let's go in the kitchen
and get something to eat ...
... then we'll get changed,
then I'll bet you in 30 seconds ...
... Bruce and Scotty will come
through the door laughing
their heads off...
Don't worry about it.
Bruce!
Where are they?
They should be back by now!
Well, they're probably
rounding up the picnic
basket and the blanket...
that's all.
Bruce!
Hey, there's some food
on the stove.
Now you wait here, I'm going
to take a look myself.
No, please! Don't go out there.
I'm just going to step outside ...
... and shine the light
into the woods.
I won't go far.
Join us!
Oh, my God!
He's coming!
He's coming, Scotty!
Scotty, please, Scotty!!
Please, Scotty!
Scotty, please!
Scotty!
What have I done?
I saw.
Quick, ... , cellar ...
... gun! Hurry.
You got to get the gun!
The gun!
You have violated the
ancient ways!
... and so must die ...
to join...
Join us!
Die!
Bruce, Bruce...
Shelly ...
Let's go on a picnic ...
Scotty ...
and Shelly ...
You got anything good?...
We'll go on a picnic...