AVALANCHE
Main cast: Saeki Ideo
Edogawa Ranko - Kiritachi Noboru
Story by Osaragi Jiro
Writen by Naruse Mikio
Cinematography: Tachibana Mikiya
Music: Iida Nobuo
Assistant Director: Honda Ishiro
Third assistant director: Kurosawa Akira
Cast
Goro: Saeki Hideo
Yayoi: Edogawa Ranko
Fukiko: Kiritachi Noboru
Goro's father: Shiomi Yo
Goro's mother: Hanabusa Yuriko
Fukiko's father: Maruyama Sadao
Koyanagi: Mishima Masao
Keisuke: Ubukata Akira
Director: Naruse Mikio
‘Nadare' refers to the emotional crisis
experienced by Kusaka Goro.
Although Goro appears at first
to have his feet on the ground,
he falls eventually, pushed
by some sudden unknown force,
as if caught in an avalanche.
Today we all live in such
a precarious world that even
a person of strong will like Goro
can be carried away by this avalanche.”  -- Osaragi Jiro
That's enough for today,
Take this with you
I remember...there was
an airplane flying by then...
It's been a year already...
“We are in a Hotel in Nagoya...”
This way, we can make it clear
we are not hiding or running away
We also let your father know that we are here.
But...we can't do that.
Why?
Well, because...
You shouldn't think too much about it.
Aoyama is in Akasaka Ward, isn't it?
- I'll write it myself.
- Really? then go ahead
All we need to say is that we are staying in this hotel.
We can realize our wishes quicker
Think only about it.
Tomorrow my father will be here to pick us up
Father!
Goro, you're coming back?
Yes.  please apologise.
have you visited many places?
I've bought tickets already.
Do you have any luggage?
we don't have much luggage,
but could you pay the hotel for us?
That's not my business.
Keep in mind that you must pay
me back for the train fares too.
Such a good father he is!
Fukiko!
- Did Goro tell you where he went?
- No
- and he didn't tell you when he'll be back ?
- No, he didn't.
He never used to do such a thing.
your hair style is kind
of unusual, isn't it?
Today's Sunday. Why don't you go
somewhere with Goro?
He went out somewhere
but we don't know where
you're too nice.  he needs a little
more coaxing, Fukiko.
Maybe Goro is not happy with Fukiko, don't you think?
But she is a good girl
There's no question about that, sure...
We haven't seen Yayoi lately, have we?
- That's right
- She's still alone with her young brother.
We've got to do something for her future
Goro would've been happier with Yayoi.
Apparently they liked each other, you know
Tell me, Yayoi,  Am I that bad?
Yes, you are
You don't act like a man,
you act like a coward.
You say I'm a coward,
but I love you all the same.
Don't say that, please, I ask you.
It's not only my fault. It's yours too.
You haven't been fair to me either.
Why? Why do you say I'm not fair?
don't you recognize that you've never
shown me your real feelings?
That's not true
Yes, it's true.  I couldn't see
what was in your mind
I thought you hated me.
So I found you condescending
I wanted to tell you this.
We became too close....
I keep to myself feelings I hold dear.
That's how I was brought up.
Goro, it's too late now.
It's not too late!
- Let me go!  Please!
- I'll talk to my father!
What about Fukiko?  Poor Fukiko!
Welcome back.
Father and Mother went out to a party.
They'd be back around 9 p.m.
Really?
- And your dinner?
- I already have.
- Do you want to change clothes?
- I'll stay like this.
- Would you like some tea then?
- Yes
(I should really talk about it.)
(No, I can't do that)
(not to Uncle Kusaka...)
I really apologize
for what happened this time
You don't have to, Uncle.
To tell the truth, I was hoping
Goro would change his mind.
In fact, both Urako and I wanted
you to be his wife.
Me...? Really?
Yes, this is what
disappointed Urako the most
I know you won't like it,
but I have enough of this marriage.
What makes you say things like that?
Let me tell you this:
you are a man, so you should
act with responsibility.
I do feel responsible, Father.
After all, it was my fault.
But if we keep going like this,
sooner or later our marriage will end up in failure.
For her own good we shouldn't
let it happen even if it is cruel.
I made up my mind and want
to get out of this situation!
Well, in this world,
There is much to complain about.
and one cannot always
make out the way he wants.
You can ask anyone
Life is full of dissatisfaction
and discontent
To put up with it
is the everyday task of human.
What is it that you
don't like about Fukiko?
- Well...
- Can't you tell me?
It's not easy to explain...
It's not logical then...
is she not a good girl?
Even though Mother was against it at first
now she likes her
very much like me
I do think Fukiko is a good girl too
But I think it's not good
for her to go on like this
Well, I really don't understand why.
It's better to divorce now
than to make her unhappy later.
- Do you make her unhappy?
- I feel sorry for her
there's nothing I can do about it.
I can't pretend I love her if I don't.
It's about my own life!
What about her life?
you led her to believe
you were the man of her life
Don't you realize how
irresponsible all this is?
I look at it differently.
The way you look at it is wrong...
You are not alone but living
with others, in a society
Everyone has responsibility in society
Are you saying that we shouldn't do
what we believe is right?
what we believe is right
is taught by the society we live in
then living in jail or in this society are the same
- I refuse such a life.
- Shut up!
Who do you think you are
to show such an arrogance
A living being
Such a youngster you still are...
You cannot criticize me for being young
- Shut up
- No. I've had enough!
I'd be a coward if I don't live up
to what I think is right.
I do think about social responsibility,
but do I have to accept it even
when it is based on lies and deception?
That would be committing a sin!
I know I should have given more
thought before getting married
But is it all irreparable?
Suppose you are not Kusaka Goro
but an ordinary office worker
would you come up
with such a idea?
I know the life of an office worker.
I know also the life of those with money,
loveless couples who pretend to look
respectable but have lovers and mistresses
I don't like such lies.  I can't stand a married life in deception.
Well, isn't human life more subtle than that?
It is not a mathematical equation
I cannot bear listening to your selfish complaint.
But Father...
Some day, you'll understand what I'm saying.
It's a man's responsibility
to look after a frail woman.
and once you are married, it's a duty.
(A duty? Am I now
compelled to act like a coward?)
(Luckily I don't worry about money.
Why should I stay bound by old morality?)
(Things have changed since Father's times.)
(I should do what I think is right)
You shouldn't come to watch a baseball
game with such a weather
- Are you cold?
- No, I'm fine.
Nasty weather... Why did they invent
such annoying thing as a rain front?
Well, they didn't “invent” it!
- So are you going fine?
- Yes! I'm fine.
Fukuko is not expecting yet?
- Her name is “Fukiko”, not Fukuko!
- Oh, is that so?
Well, It's only names after all. Fukiko
or Fukuko, it doesn't matter.
Besides, I'm not her father myself.
Anyway, so no good news, eh?
No, not yet.
I'm starting to wonder if she's
capable of making a baby!
Ha-ha!  Are you kidding?
Well, she's always been healthy,
but she's just so skinny, you know...
Actually, skinny women
often are fertile. Don't worry!
- Oh, welcome!
- Hello.
Hello, Father.
What's happening?
Mother (-in-law) told me to show this to you...
What?
Oh, your hairstyle!
That's true, it's the first time...  very well...
- You look much better like that.
- You are joking
Come in, Koyanagi the lawyer is here.
We were talking about you.
Good day sir
Maybe you don't know, but he helped me
a lot for your marriage
Don't exaggerate, I was just involved
it's not easy with such a stubborn man like
your father... Fukuko, you know that
- Again!  It's Fukiko, not Fukuko!
- That's right, that's right.
first time she has this hairstyle
Kusaka's wife told her to show it to me
You look absolutely fabulous
Your husband must be thrilled
Please put out the laundry when the weather clears up.
can you prepare some sake and fish?
- Are you getting along well there?
- Yes.
With Goro's mother as well?
- She treats me very well.
- Really? That's very nice.
I'll help in the kitchen today!
then can you make that fish
you used to make often?
How was it...something "à la meunière"
Can you do it?
You know, Yokota, I don't like rich people
but I think Kusaka is different
Although he has a lot of money
He is a reliable man.
I see in his character some good sides of the old feudal times.
You are right,
he is different from the
common run of dirty moneymakers.
But first you didn't want to marry
your daughter to a rich family!
Well, after all Kusaka is a man
with a strong backbone!
Aren't you talking about yourself?
you are like a man
out of the Tokugawa era
If I was the Minister for Culture
I'd put you on display in a museum!
You'd put me in a museum,
then I'd put you in a zoo
Allo?  No, she is not here
No, Yayoi's gone to her cottage.
I see, thank you.
- What's the matter, Sister?
- What? Nothing.
Since you got here you
don't look like your normal self.
You see, Keisuke, I've been thinking...
Tell me. What is the meaning
of life as a human?
I don't know anymore if I'm happy
living in comfort like we do.
I think you are asking too much!
But listen, I heard a story about prisoners in Siberia
They say prison guards there pick up prisoners for fun
they make them dig and carry
the earth to somewhere else,
only to carry it back again to where
they dug it, day after day
And these prisoners are forced to repeat
this purposeless job over and over
until they get sick or go crazy.
There's nothing more cruel
than doing things without purpose.
It's the same thing for
those living a life without purpose.
Well, women can always...
...get married, right?
We say “it's settled”
when a woman is married off.
As if unmarried women were a nuisance!
what does it mean to be “settled”?
to submit your future to a stranger
you don't know if you can trust
Keisuke, who can possibly trust one man for the whole life?
Marital fidelity is not that simple...
- So you think you can live differently?
- Well, that is the problem.
(Yes, this feeling stopped me from being with Goro)
(I've always thought
I'll marry with Goro)
(And yet, I was not able to get over this feeling)
(Maybe this mean I'm a coward?)
Sister, I don't know if I'm wrong but..
- Wasn't it all because of me?
- What?
about Goro.
- Wasn't it because of my illness?
- You fool!
I wanted to talk to you about it
If I die, you'll have to perpetuate our name, right?
But who gives a damn about family anyway?
That's not the reason why I
don't get married.  You worry too much,
you should feel free to do what you like.
I'm not worried about those things.  I do live as I want.
Someone named Kusaka is here for you.
- Do you think it's Goro?
- Yes, maybe it's him...
I don't want to see him.
Why?
- Would you see him?
- Yes.
I told my father that I wanted to divorce Fukiko
I thought he would understand but he didn't.
After all he's got old ideas
I told him that's I'm sure about it and
that I'd be a coward if I didn't
Listen, Yayoi, we need to be strong
and think more about ourselves
You think too much about other people.
You always think about others,
but that's only to have clear conscience
We must not give in to such a easy thing, Yayoi!
A clear conscience is
needed to live in society!
You are a liar!
How are you doing?
- and Goro?
- He went to Kamakura
- Alone?
- No, with a friend.
Why didn't you go with them?
You stayed home last Sunday too.
But...
Is the friend one of his colleagues?
Well...  He only said the friend had a house there
- And mother?
- She's in her room.
I came back a moment ago too.  It was an excellent show.
Oh, the concert?
Mr. Tamura was thankful for
the bouquet you sent him.
Who is Mr. Tamura?
- The pianist!
- Oh, of course
You know, I've been thinking
about Goro..
I think I should take the matter more seriously
I've been too busy to pay attention to him,
but from now on I'll take it upon myself.
You shouldn't be the only one to deal with him.
That would be very nice...
You know, Goro is very smart
he knows so much about things
Well, times have changed!  Young people today know everything!
Yeah, that's it.
But they don't know how
to sort out their knowledge
Actually, they lack something important
They make up a good excuse
for every thing they do,
but they don't have principles
- But that is because...
- Let me finish.
This is a very important issue
I'm thinking about Goro's reckless character
Maybe it is just typical of his generation,
but I feel there is something
desperate about him
He knows his goal in life, but
he doesn't believe in it
Going to Nagoya with Fukiko, for example,
he knew  this was not needed
But we got over that issue already.
Well, you don't understand him...
Are you saying that
I don't understand my own child?
Excuse me but...
It's true, being mother is
more difficult these days.
You have been a great mother,
and I am grateful for it.
But still it's a difficult matter...
What makes you worry so much...?
Keisuke,
I might live for the sake of
my own happiness after all
We are able to live a life without worry,
and that is not
the case for most people
Beyond our happiness
the world is different
Here we can live happily, looking
at the bright light in front of us,
but there is a crowd out there
people left behind in darkness,
moaning and groaning...
But, I now think happiness can exist
only if we think about ourselves
and forget everything else...
Have you ever thought about all this?
Yes I have. in fact I have just now
in today's world, happiness exist
only by forgetting others' misfortune
(Goro may win me over in the end...)
Goro, Would you come
here during lunch break?
What ? I thought we could
eat together
I'll be waiting then.
Father, you have something on your mustache
- It's getting warmer these days.
- Yeah.
Are you going straight
to your office?
I still have some time.
- I think I'll walk a bit.
- I'll go with you then.
Why don't you get something
for Fukiko?  I'll pay for it.
- No, it's okay.
- Why not?
There's no need for it.
Father!
I changed my mind.
To buy her a gift, you must first
of all  have feelings for her
- Well, I...
- No more discussion!
I can't stand such
a heartless attitude
People who don't care making others happy
are the most despicable beings!
Father, which one is better?
You are the one to choose.
- What about this?
- You choose what you think is good.
Father!
Isn't this beautiful? Goro bought it for me.
Really?  That's very nice.
- Would you like some tea?
- Yes, please.
No, she's not back yet.
Do you know where she went?
What?  Kamakura?
Why do you look so sad?
I wish I could stay drunk all the time...
Listen, don't think about anything else when we are together.
Can you do that yourself?
when you are with me,
don't you think about Fukiko ?
Don't you feel pity for her?
Tell me, Goro.
I can think only one thing at a time
Let's change the subject.
That means...when you are with Fukiko
you forget about me, right?
That's what you think?
It's better that you forget about me.
Here we go again!
enough talking about it,
let's go dancing
Welcome back
Yayoi!
It's raining hard, isn't it?
The queen of diamonds...
Missed..,
This is my tenth try, you know.
Maybe I stop now.
Yayoi, please forgive us
We cannot find any solution.
You endure a lot, don't you?
Yes.... patience
I'd like to take time to think about it
How can you become happy
It's been our homework, my wife and I
We knew from the beginning
Fukiko was no match for you.
she's a passive and weak girl
If I told her to sit down,
she'd just sit down there forever.
She is so naive
If her husband cheated on her
she wouldn't believe it.
She'd even blame herself instead
She is like that. We can't be
harsh on her
You are like our own daughter, Yayoi
We've always thought of you
that way, and we always will.
Yayoi!
Goro, you are coming back home with me
Yayoi!  Yayoi!
Goro, let's go home
Call the chauffeur.
I don't.  You act like a coward!
Mind your language!
Don't forget I'm your father
- But Father...
- You are the coward.
You forced me to lie
in the first place.
I've told you that I didn't want to lie.
I know...
who has lied or who is responsible...
This is of no interest.
There is something more important
we need to talk about
You are smart and know many things.
But your knowledge is thin
like a piece of paper
Your head is stuffed with a bunch of thin paper
When you do something unreasonable,
you justify yourself with
this understanding of paper
this mentality of yours, I find it wrong
This is a lot worse than just cheating on your wife!
I think I am being sincere
I just want to do what I think is right
I want to be true to myself
I don't want to be a wise hypocrite like yourself!
Stop this paper thoughts
The misfortune of your generation is
knowing things without understanding them
You only "know" things
You're a stranger!  A stranger
to people like me!
Think as you like
but if you continue with
your immorality, I'll have to disown you.
I should remind you, that you would not be what you are now
without the wealth of the Kusaka family
Is that a threat?
No. compassion. I feel pity for you
Well, which one will you let go?
Your paper “truth” or my wealth!
All right, I'll be a liar then!
(No one suspect it.)
(Father thinks that
I am a different person)
(Fukiko, as usual, trusts me completely)
(She thinks we are off to enjoy ourselves today)
(And I am pretending
to love her until we die)
(even though in reality it's quite the opposite.)
(That's what Father wants)
(I can do that well.)
(He will say: “Oh, I knew it,
I knew Goro loved Fukiko!)
(Otherwise how could he possibly commit suicide with her?”)
(And he will grieve over our “beautiful” deaths!)
Fukiko, let's go back to Nagoya.
We can visit the same places and
stay in the same hotel and same room
But we didn't tell them
that we were going that far.
It's all right, we'll send them a telegram
I remember it all!
The temple...and that big tree over there too!
It's wonderful
I'm glad we came
The last time I was scared...
But it's different this time
(I thought the room was cleaner, but it's all right)
(I don't want any sentimentalism
in our double suicide.)
(This is just like any other business)
(except that you can do it only once in life.)
I'm going out.
I'll send them a telegram
Going by yourself?
Why don't you take a bath
in the meantime?
(Actually, I don't need to die with her.
Only pretending to)
(this way...  Fukiko will die happily)
(and no one will suspect murder)
(How come I didn't realize this earlier
and wanted to kill myself too!)
(Well, I haven't changed a bit!)
What's the matter?
- Fukiko, are you happy?
- Yes, I am.
If I ask you to die with me,
would you agree?
I am not kidding,
I am serious, Fukiko!
There is no need to ask me such a question.
I need your answer!
My answer is quite obvious...
So you will die with me?
But why do you say that?
You're not aware about it
but there's no way out!
Look. Now do you understand
that I'm not joking?
(She's almost convinced.
Let's play it well)
I am telling you the truth.
I can't go on anymore.
Why?
I cannot tell you. I also
don't want to tell you
But can't you at least talk to your father about it?
He can help you out.  You should really talk to him.
Oh, thanks a lot!  I never thought
you could give me advice!
I guess you don't understand my feelings.
I am sorry,
I will do whatever you tell me to do.
Well, I don't want to force you.
No, you are not forcing me.
I am all yours.
If you ask me to die with you, I will do it gladly.
(No, I must be strong!)
Is it because of Yayoi?
What?  What about her?
Maybe I'm wrong?
Yayoi has nothing to do with it!
Is that really so?
Stop crying!  People will hear us.
I was stupid...
I've been secretly worried that you loved Yayoi.
Please forgive me!
Stop crying, or people will hear us.  It's all right now.
I'm so ashamed of myself
I don't know what to do!
(What's going on with me?)
(Your head is stuffed
with a bunch of thin paper)
(When you do something unreasonable,)
(you justify yourself with
this understanding of paper)
(This is a lot worse than just cheating on your wife!)
(Compared to your wickedness, poor
people's misdemeanors are even beautiful!)
(I did not give in to Father.)
(This is different. Something
unknown changed my mind)
it was all a lie Fukiko
I don't want to die
I was only telling you a lie.
You know, I'm feeling better now.
Why don't you go for a trip somewhere.
Don't worry. For me it's better
we stay together quietly like this.
There's no use thinking about it..