Stock Exchange, this is Helicopter
123 Tango-Yankee on Vegas approach.
We're three miles out from landing.
Request permission to land.
Thank you.
123 Tango-Yankee.
Report landing assured.
Winds at south side
off helipad at 75.
Roger. Copy winds at 15.
We've got Mr. Brakus on board.
123 Tango-Yankee.
Signify tower when approaching pad.
Ah, Mr. jaquire.
So good to see you, sir.
123 Tango-Yankee to Stock
Exchange base. We're on final approach.
Roger, Tango-Yankee.
We've got you in sight.
Security is standing by.
Roger. Tango-Yankee out.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening, Mr. Brakus.
- Hi, Mr. Brakus.
- Lose it.
- Sorry, Mr. Brakus. I-
What did I say about guns?
They're unmanly.
It won't happen again.
Warriors fight here.
Get rid of it.
You're at 200 feet below
the surface of the earth...
where you, our special
guests, will witness
the deadliest of combat,
the highest stakes.
- It's a forum for gladiators!
- Mr. Brakus coming through.
Lust like in ancient Rome.
Not in Rome.
You are in Las Vegas!
It's My kind of town!
- Are you ready to rock and roll?
- Yea h!
Are you ready to rumble?
Okay. All right.
Welcome, welcome to the Coliseum,
ladies and gentlemen.
The greatest show under
the face of the earth.
The Coliseum.
That means the ultimate
in fighting competition with no referee...
no rules...
and open to anyone-
anyone with big brass balls.
For those of you that are here for
the first time, this is how it works.
Our finalists from
our preliminary
tournaments are privileged...
to challenge our stable
of modern gladiators.
Take a look!
They'd kill their mothers!
I'll bet on him!
Mean as cat shit!
What a bonanza!
Oh!
Now, if our challenger is successful
in defeating the first gladiator...
he will win $20,000.
Should he be successful
at the second gladiator...
he will win $50,000.
That's 50,000 big ones.
Now, if by some
divine intervention...
the challenger defeats
all three gladiators...
then he has earned the right to challenge
the supreme fighter...
for the ownership
of the Coliseum.
The ultimate warrior
who has never known defeat...
the master and owner
of the Coliseum...
the champion of the underworld...
Brakus!
Brakus! Brakus!
Yes! The betting cages are now closed...
so let the fights begin!
We have a spectacular
contest for you tonight.
The Coliseum's newest gladiator,
all the way from Paris, France...
Andre Mares!
The challenger, fresh from three
consecutive wins in the preliminaries...
all the way from
North Las Vegas...
Mr. Travis Brickley!
A 5 -to-7 underdog.
Paris, my ass.
Remember,
when the buzzer sounds...
there is only one rule-
There are no rules!
And you love it! Yes!
Fighters, take your corners.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Coliseum!
Andre!
- Go!
- Come on!
- Yeah! Come on!
- Yeah! Allright.
Sorry about that, Sinbad.
There's a new boy in town!
- Alex, you know what?
- Huh?
If he doesn't get it this time,
he'll get it on the next try.
Oh, I know it, Tommy,
but he's growing up so fast.
He made me promise that
if he gets his black belt...
I let him drive the car.
So? Let him drive the car.
Tommy, I've only got one car.
Look at him.
God, I hope
he makes it tomorrow.
Relax. He'll make it.
Yeah. At least he had
one of the best teachers in the world.
- Thanks, man.
- I was talking about me.
Walter, go to bed. Come on.
Oh, Honey, if you take your shoe off,
I can kiss your foot.
Hey, Travis.
What a hell of a fight.
- You killed my guy.
- Yeah, I did.
You took him like
Grant took Richmond.
- Thank you, sir.
- So tell me, how good are you, really?
I'm good enough to beat
any of your steroid freaks.
- Including that one.
- Open your mouth.
How long's it been since
you fought? About six months?
Mmm. Call him.
- Or are the fights fixed?
- Go ahead, then.
What, are you injured?
One or two punches right on the chin,
I believe you'd go right out.
You have a big mouth, boy.
And a big everything else.
So why don't you stop wasting time.
Put me in the ring with him.
Weldon, give him what he wants.
- You want Brakus?
- Yes, I do.
You got it.
- Black belt candidates.
- Sir!
Attention.
Present your papers.
Ready? Begin.
Break!
Point.
Yeah! All right!
I'm proud of you, Walter.
You taught that boy a lesson.
Now, it's showtime.
- I can do it.
- They're waiting on you.
Black belt candidates,
are you ready to break your bricks?
Yes, sir!
Ready? Begin.
Hyah!
- Oh.
- Walter?
- Yes,sir?
If you don't break,
you don't pass.
- You know that?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome.
Walter, come on.
Walter, are you gonna be okay?
Yeah, I'll be okay.
I'll get it on the next try.
- Cheer up, okay?
- Come on, Walter.
We gonna get lucky tonight.
My little ass-kicker.
Let's go make him feel good.
- Very happy to be here.
- Did you always know?
Now you stay here.
Make like a hat rack.
Mr. Brickley.
I blew it.
You look the same to me.
Hey, Walter, look-it there.
Hey, it's Dae Han.
He gave Tommy one hell of a fight.
Remember that?
It's only a violent sport.
- Thank you for that.
- Mmm.
Well, he'll be cool.
Now be his daddy.
- Walter Grady's daddy always be cool.
- Oh, yeah?
Mmm.
- Say hi to Tommy.
- Hi, Tommy.
In this tour
we hope to share...
the beauty and the art
of tae kwon do...
along with its power.
For KXRT Sports,
I'm Sue MacCauley.
Everyone, I would like
to propose a toast...
to those who have received
their belts today...
and to those who will
receive them tomorrow.
To the team.
Alex, why don't you say
a couple words?
Uh, years ago
when Walter's mother passed away...
I didn't know how
I was going to make it.
She was everything.
And it's tough to lose everything.
Son, today, all I wanted
was for you to make it...
to get your belt.
And you surprised me
by giving me much more.
The way you handled
your disappointment...
makes me prouder than
lever imagined, Walter.
You have become a man...
and I'm just so happy
to be your dad.
- To Walter Grady.
Out to Walter Grady.
Ten seconds left.
Nine, eight, seven-
He's driving up. He's in the paint.
Five, four, three, two-
He's going up!
- Buzzer shot! And he makes it.
- Oh!
All right, you guys. If I make it,
you have to wash my car.
If I don't make it,
you still have to wash my car.
- No! No.
- No way.
- Oh!
- Doesn't matter anyway.
- Where's your dad?
- Inside getting ready.
- Let's go.
- Bye, Mr. Lee. See you later.
- See you later john.
- See you, john.
Aah! Aah.
Hey, Alex!
Your sauce is burning.
Look at this.
You know, Walter, you have a great dad,
but he can't cook spaghetti.
Humor him.
He thinks it's my favorite.
- Hey, Alex.
- Coming.
- Hey, man, do I look good or what?
- You look marvelous.
New haircut, new shirt on-
My sauce.
- Hey, Walter?
- Yeah?
- Hungry?
- Always.
How does pasta Alexander sound?
Like you're trying to make up
for not taking me to dinner.
Could be some truth to that.
All right, Walter, I made a little extra
for Martha in case she's-
Dad, I gotta talk to you
about Martha.
What's the matter? You don't like her?
I thought you liked her.
Oh, yeah, she's great.
But she's not coming tonight.
Did she cancel?
I can't get another sitter this late.
You see, I called her
and canceled.
You what?
Dad, I don't need
a babysitter anymore.
Walter, you are 11 years old.
Dad, picture this scene.
A guy breaks into the house.
Martha freaks, runs screaming
into the closet, and I kick his butt.
Dad, you said it yourself
I'm a man now, and real men
don't need babysitters.
Oh, man.
I gotta pass, man. I got
no one to stay with Walter.
Great. I'll take 'em both out.
Yeah. All right, look.
This is not an option.
Travis is on his way over
here to drop off some
stuff before he goes
to his bowling league.
So you tell him to take you with him.
Understood?
Got it.
Okay. Hang this up.
Tommy, we're outta here.
- See you later.
- Stay away from the Playboy channel.
Travis, Dad said
I have to go with you.
Sorry, little buddy. Bad news.
Can't go bowling tonight.
Somethin' came up.
But you can't leave me here alone.
I don't even have a babysitter.
What if a serial killer
broke into the house?
- Get in.
- You sure?
Get in.
Thanks, Travis.
Put your seat belt on.
- Walter, there's somethin'
I gotta tell you.
But you gotta keep it
to yourself now, you hear?
You hear me?
I'm fighting tonight.
It's not the kind of fighting
that we-what we're used to.
At the Coliseum,
there are no rules.
Are you kidding?
Tommy and Dad would freak out if they
knew we were even going near that place.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Walter. What do you
mean, “we“? You're staying in the car.
Come on. You can sneak me in.
No can do, little buddy.
This'll take me a couple hours, tops.
Dad's not gonna
wanna hear about this.
And you're not gonna
tell him, Walter.
Might slip.
You're blackmailing me, Walter.
That's correct.
You are bad.
Thank you.
Take a good look
at this place, Walter...
'cause after tonight's fight,
it's gonna be mine.
Hey, Travis. Why don't you go in
the front door?
Got a buddy with me. I think it's better
he comes in this entrance.
Okay. Oh.
- Sparring partner.
- Yeah.
- Who's the midget?
- He's my manager.
- Look out for him.
- You got it.
Travis.
Showtime.
Wow.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight is a very special night.
We have a challenger.
Straight from a stunning victory
over Andre Marais.
Ladies and gentlemen, the challenger,
a member of the U.S. National Karate Team.
Give a big Coliseum welcome
to Mr. Travis Brickiey!
Right here. The fat guy.
Hey, smut!
The disco's upstairs!
BOO!
Ladies and gentlemen...
the ultimate warrior
who has never known defeat...
the master and owner
of the Coliseum...
the champion of the underworld...
Brakus!
Brakus! Brakus!
Now, remember,
when you hear the buzzer...
there is only one rule.
There are no rules.
And you love it! Yes!
♪  Fighters, to your comers.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Coliseum!
Come on!
Is that all you've got?
No.
You gotta stop it.
You gotta stop the fight.
Take it easy, kid.
Just part of the show.
In the tradition of the Coliseum,
you privileged few must decide:
Life or death.
Brakus! Brakus!
Does he live?
Or does he die?
Die! Die!
No!
Damn it!
- Payoff of the slots is better.
- Oh, yes. Whoo.
What's the matter, kid?
Need a ride somewhere?
What's the matter?
- I should've been back a long time ago.
- Oh, yeah. I know. I know.
Dad!
I don't know, Alex. Maybe
we should go to the police.
And tell 'em what?
We can't find our friend?
Tomorrow, when you park a car-
Yo, yo, yo.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I got a couple of men just cruised
through the front door here.
Hey. Guys. Can I help you?
- Are you the manager?
- Yes, Weldon Dardano.
We're looking for a friend
who fought here tonight.
Travis Brickiey.
There's gotta be some mistake.
This is a dance club.
Travis Brickley doesn't dance.
I said this is a dance club,
period.
Travis Brickley fought here tonight,
and we would like to see him.
A lot people come and go. Now, maybe
your friend was here, maybe he wasn't.
- This is bullshit.
- I'm sorry?
This is bullshit.
Look, guys, your
friend did fight here
tonight, but he is
no longer here.
- What are you saying?
- Well, he got his bell rung pretty good...
got his face messed up a little bit,
but he did walk out of here...
on his own two legs with some bimbo
with her tongue in his ear.
- Yeah.
- I put him in a cab and sent him home.
- I'm sure he'll be fine. Don't worry.
- Thanks.
- Pleasure.
- Yeah.
See you.
Finch.
What'd he say?
Everything is groovy. They
put Travis in a cab home.
He's lying, Dad. I saw it.
The big guy broke his neck.
Walter, maybe he
just got knocked out.
- Come on. Get in the car.
- He's dead. I know it.
Walter, he's not dead.
Now get in the car.
How you doing, Mr. Finch?
Never better johnny boy.
Never better.
Travis and a bimbo.
Let's take Walter home,
then go find Travis.
Where are you, Travis?
Tommy.
Back it up.
Tell that ambulance to back it up.
Tell that ambulance
to back it up.
So it was an accident?
We're investigating,
but it looks like that.
Thank you, Sergeant.
- Alex.
- Tommy. Tommy, what the hell happened?
We're lifting this thing now.
The police are saying
it's an accident.
Oh, Travis.
Tommy, we gotta do something.
He]!
Jesus! What is this?
They just pulled our
friend out of the river.
What do you want?
I want the man who killed
Travis Brickley.
I told you guys before, Travis walked
out of here on his own two legs.
Now the fact he went somewhere else
and got all screwed up is not my problem.
Yes, it is your problem.
My son witnessed
the whole thing.
Your son?
Your son the witness?
I got 20 witnesses.
I got 5O witnesses.
I don't like you guys very much.
Now get the hell out of here.
Did you kill Travis Brickley?
Easily.
Yeah.
Care to join him?
Ah, you son of a bitch.
Brakus!
Hold up, Brakus.
We don't make any money
like this.
- Clear the path. Let's go. Move it.
- Gus, get in here!
Alex, behind you!
Step aside, please.
Step aside. Let us through!
- Let"s go, boys.
- Where did you get the hat?
It was left to me in a will.
Lie down. How you doing?
Guess you're doing all right.
Behind ya. I'll get the car.
Eh, you're gonna have
a nasty scar there.
There you go.
It's the best I can do.
Shit.
That one who cut my face-
I want him alive.
The other one-
kill him and his boy.
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust. Amen,.
- Amien.
- Thank you all very much for coming.
Bye, Travis.
- Jammy.
- Hmm?
Bless you, sir. Bless you.
- They heard?
- Hmm.
The Lord be with you, jim.
Dae Han. Thank you for coming.
As your friend,
I share your loss.
Dae Han, it's so good
to see you.
Alex.
- How are you?
- Dane Han, this is my son, Walter.
I remember. You have grown.
Here. You go with Richard,
okay? I'll be with Dae Han.
- And the boy saw it happen?
- Yes, he did.
- Then it is also his tragedy.
- Yes.
- And the police?
- They're treating it as an accident.
Then let me help you.
Blood for blood.
I owe it to you.
I can't ask that
of you, Dae Han.
If not, what will you do?
- Excuse me. When are you on?
- H-Hi.
- When are you on?
- Oh, I can't do it, Alex.
Don't tell me that, Sue.
You know Travis was murdered. Come here.
L- Excuse me.
I'll be right back.
Honey, they shot me down.
I'm a sportscaster, you know.
I'm not an investigative reporter.
Well, if I'm gonna make
allegations like these...
I'm gonna have to go through
their proper procedure.
And without proof, well-
I don't have any.
Appropriate procedure?
Thirty seconds, Sue.
Honey, I gotta-l gotta
go on the air, okay?
Uh, we'll talk about this
later, all right?
A friend of mine was murdered,
and you're worried about your job.
Well, yes, I'm worried abut my job.
It's the only one I have.
But that doesn't mean I don't care
about what happened to Travis.
What, you think it's all about Travis?
What about Walter, Sue?
What do you mean, Walter?
You want me to tell my son
it doesn't matter what he saw...
because his word isn't
good enough for you.
- Ten seconds, Sue.
- Alex, please. Uh-Please.
Walter was there,
and that's good enough for me, honey.
And you know what else?
I couldn't care
less about your
appropriate procedures.
- Five, four, three, two-
- Don't do this. Please, Alex.
- [Buzzer Sounds
- Or your goddamn job.
It's been a busy day
in the world of sports.
Over there!
All right, there he goes. There he goes.
Come on, man. Step on it.
There were three of 'em,
Dad, in a big black car.
He's just a kid, man.
I'm going after them.
Alex, wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute!
Alex!
Walter, get down!
- Walter!
- Dad!
Come here.
Dad!
Freeze, asshole!
Stand up. I said, get up!
All the way up.
'Got him! 'Got him!
You wanna shoot me? Huh?
Shoot me now. Shoot.
No. No, I don't want to. No.
Punk.
You came into my house.
You came into my fucking house.
Dad!
Don't kill me, man.
Don't kill me.
Tommy, Tommy, Tommy. We'll-Tommy,
I gotta get Walter out of here. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
What do you mean
they vanished into thin air?
Brakus, there's no one
more surprised than me.
Find them. Bring me
the one who did this.
Do you understand?
Yeah, I understand.
I understand.
Fill 'er up.
- Tommy.
- Grandma.
Grandma?
I'll tell you later. Come on.
Grab your gear.
Come, meet my friends. Come on.
Grandma, I'd like you
to meet my closest friend.
- Alexander Grady.
- Hello.
- This is my son, Walter Grady.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you. Here. Let me help you.
- So she's the one who raised you, huh?
- Yeah, she's the one.
So, Grandma, I thought this would be
the safest place to come.
- You were lucky.
- Thank you for taking us in.
I think you should
talk to james.
- He's back?
- Two months.
- Who's james?
- I don't want to see him...
and I don't wanna talk to him.
He can help you.
- Who's james?
- Grandma, he can't even help himself.
- He needs you, Tommy.
I'm sorry, Grandma,
but it's too late for that.
Excuse me.
Who's james?
James.
Wake up.
Well.
Look who's here.
- What are you doing here, boy?
- James, Tommy's got trouble.
I said you could help him.
Just like old times, huh, boy?
Still runnin' to Ma
to fix your problems, huh?
- What did you say?
- Tommy, be cool.
- What did you say? Huh?
- Be cool. - Oh, come on.
Show me your stuff.
Let's see if you've learned
anything in the last 16 years.
I don't fight drunks.
Drunk? This is nothin'.
Right here.
Give me your best shot.
James.
I'll rip your fuckin' ears
right off your goddamn head!
Then I'll stick 'em right
where the sun don't shine...
so you can hear me
kick your butt.
Let's get out of here, man.
Can you believe this shit?
You damn-
- You son of a bitch.
- No! Don't!
Hey, hey! Hey! What's going on?
I'm gonna kick your-
- Let's get some cookies.
- Cookies? What-
- Cookies.
- Inside, Walter.
- Oh, come on. I wanna see this.
- Come on. Come on, you candy-ass!
Cut the crap James.
We're not kids anymore.
Come on.
Show me your stuff, boy.
If you've got any.
What is the matter with you?
James, I'm gonna
have to hurt you, man.
Pretty good. But you're gonna
have to do better than that, boy.
You got a little snap
in those kicks, ain't ya?
- Are you all right?
- Damn, that hurt. Ow.
What the hell was that about?
Come on. I'll take both
you bastards out.
Let's get him.
Mmm. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Oh.
Now.
Come on.
- You're out of your mind.
- Come on. I'll take both of you on.
You're out of
your goddamn mind.
Oh, to hell with you.
- Here, Walter. Grab some plates.
- Okay.
James ran with
a real bad crowd.
Always fighting for
the wrong reasons.
Then one day,
he just took off?
Went overseas to fight.
He left without
ever saying good-bye.
Took Grandma's life savings.
And I won't forgive him
for that.
I'm sorry.
Was he a good fighter?
We heard
he won some tournaments.
But then he had
a terrible car accident...
almost died.
And his life
pretty much fell apart.
Four, five, six, seven-
Ooh.
What's up, handsome?
How much longer are we
gonna stay here?
Oh, I don't know.
Till we're done training.
What's up?
I watch you training, Dad...
and I know either you're gonna kill Brakus,
or he's gonna kill you.
No one's gonna kill me.
I promise.
I saw him kill Travis, Dad.
I watched him die.
I know it, Walter.
And I have to protect
other people from Brakus.
It's like a war.
Like a war.
Are you afraid?
Yes.
Are you gonna help Tommy?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm gonna help the boy.
It'd be my pleasure.
Here. Here.
There's a dollar.
Give him that for a bowl of soup.
I know what happened to you
and what you think it cost you.
But the son who left me many years ago
in search of his manhood...
returned home a drunk
and self-pitying overgrown child.
You are a terrible example
for our people...
and a disgrace to your mother.
You have an opportunity now
to do something good.
Help Tommy or pack your bags.
Walter?
- Walter?
- Yeah?
Help me with the chicken feed,
will you?
Sure.
This is pretty cool.
Oh!
- Good morning, Mom.
- Good morning James.
- Where are they?
- Out back.
- Tommy, Alex.
- This is a private conversation.
Not on my mother's property
it's not.
You know,
I'm tired of your shit.
Tommy.
Ma told me about your problem,
sol came out here to help.
I know Brakus.
I've seen him fight.
How you're gonna fight him,
you must be prepared to die.
- You think I'm just a drunk.
- You are a drunk.
Yes, I am.
But I am one of three people
in the whole world...
that can teach you
to beat Brakus.
- You're full of it.
- Tommy!
- What?
- Remember the accident?
Yeah. So what?
Brakus was the car.
I was the accident.
Now, I can train you to beat him
if you're not too proud.
If you ever get past
the preliminaries...
you're gonna have to fight
with these things.
Pick it up.
Not with your hands. Like this.
All right.
Now let's see what you got.
- What do you want me to do?
- Attack!
Okay.
We got a long way to go, kid.
One of them.
Don't disappoint me.
Bring me Tommy Lee, alive.
- Go on in.
- Excuse me?
- Why?
- It's part of your trainin'.
- Oh.
- Come on, gentlemen. Let's go.
- Okay.
U h, Tom my, after you.
It's too hot. I can't breathe.
Tommy, I'll see you outside.
Alex, Brakus would stay...
even if it meant dying.
The sweat lodge is a church.
The heat drives the body temperature
way up like a fever.
Sometimes you may have
what the white men cal! Hallucinations.
We call them visions...
messages from the spirits.
Go ahead, Walter, Take it.
- What is it?
- It's a snake charm.
A snake can take a life
or save a life.
It's to protect you.
I don't get it.
Is this a riddle?
It's a symbol of courage.
Do you know what courage is?
Sure. When you're not afraid.
No, courage is not
the absence of fear.
It's doing what's right
even in the presence of fear.
Sometimes you just
gotta kick butt.
You men have done a good job.
But now I think you're ready
for a higher level of training.
So pack your stuff,
and you get a good night's sleep.
Then tomorrow
we begin our journey.
Easy Easy.
Come on. Let me see your hands.
Slow. Slow.
Okay, we've got 'em.
Come on in.
Come on.
Get the lead out, chief.
Let's finish this up, finally.
Get down, goddamn it!
ﬂames!
Move, and I'll pop her a third eyeball.
Now, all of you, get up.
Inside. Except you.
Mr. Brakus wants you for himself
- Gun.
- Inside.
Inside, please.
Mr. Brakus and Mr. Weldon Dardano
send their regards.
- Don't kill my son.
- It'll be clean.
Hurry up. I'm hungry.
All right. Turn around,
and down on your knees.
Run it all the way out
to the chopper.
You, too, kid. Come on. Let's go.
I don't have all day.
- What, are you deaf, tough guy?
- Courage.
Or you wanna take it in the face?
' Dad!
Where's Gus?
- It's about time.
- They're expecting four shots.
Don't you ever touch me!
- Hey, where's Gus?
- Takin' his sweet time now!
- I'm gonna go get him.
- No! We're outta here in 3O seconds!
- Acceptable loss!
- Like hell!
Can I, Mr. Finch?
Let me do it.
Blaze 'em!
Aw, shit!
I always told Gus
smoking would kill him.
Let's ﬂy!
All right. Take my hand.
Then Grandma. Come on.
Jesus!
Son of a bitch!
Grandma, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Enough!
I said, enough!
My, my. He is interesting.
I believe you two
have met before.
Tommy Lee, thank you
for joining us.
- Do you know why you're still alive?
- I really don't give a shit.
You challenged my invincibility,
scarred my perfection.
For that I will kill you
in the ring.
- Let's do it here, now.
- Excuse me. What-
What Mr. Brakus
was trying to say...
is that you're gonna have to
work your way up the ladder...
just like everybody else.
And when you're finished
with the gladiators...
and then Mr. Brakus
finishes with you...
the last thing through your mind
will be your ass.
Curtain's going up
in a few hours.
Show business is my life.
- Later.
- Get him to the Coliseum.
Poor baby.
Now, I realize that I didn't give you
time to study for this test.
But here it is.
How many of you believe...
that a martial artist could defeat
a world champion boxer?
How many believe yes?
How many believe no?
Okay. Well,
I say let's find out.
Ladies and gentlemen,
introducing...
our champion martial artist...
Tommy Lee!
And European boxing champion...
The Hammer!
Now, I thought The Hammer
was a rapper.
What do I know?
Now, remember, when the buzzer sounds,
there is only one rule.
- There are no rules!
- And you love it!
Yeah!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Coliseum!
Damn!
Ladies and gentlemen,
what an upset!
The winner, Tommy Lee!
A big Coliseum
round of applause!
- Tommy Lee.
- You lower the gate, now!
Work with me, man.
Work with me.
Tommy Lee!
Aren't we special!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next contest will begin shortly.
Just time enough to go potty
and come back and place your bets.
Now, this is gonna be
a long night.
Darling, I thinkyou may have finally
found a worthy opponent.
Ladies and gentlemen,
our second battle of the evening.
Tommy Lee versus the man who won
the gold in Olympic wrestling...
Stavros!
Come on! Come on!
Kill him! Let's go!
Tummy, some on'.
Tommy, come on'.!
It's not over yet!
Yeah! Come on!
BOO!
- Bring on the champ!
- Ladies and gentlemen...
in the tradition of the Coliseum,
we present only the best.
If you will, a big round of applause
for our winner, Mr. Tommy Lee.
Come on now. Let's hear it.
Tommy Lee!
Ladies and gentlemen...
according to the rules
of the Coliseum...
Tommy Lee has earned the
right to challenge me.
I have accepted.
Tomorrow night...
only one man...
will leave the ring.
I look forward to killing you!
Don't bet on it.
Yeah? Yeah? Who is it?
Open up, Sue. It's me.
Alex? Alex?
Oh! Oh! Oh, God, you're alive!
We'll talk about it later.
Yeah. Oh, God,
I was so worried about you.
- I've been worried sick.
- They got Tommy.
I heard.
He's supposed to fight Brakus.
They'll kill him.
I'm going in after him.
In the meantime, I need you
to take care Of Walter, all right?
- Of course I will.
- Dad!
What? Oh, boy!
What's the matter? It's okay.
- It's okay. It's okay.
- I don't-
- I don't wanna lose you.
- Hey. Hey.
There's no way in hell
you're gonna lose me.
I'm gonna go get Tommy, and then Tommy
and I are gonna come get you.
In the meantime, you stay here.
I'll know you're safe.
- I want you to do me a favor.
- What?
- Take care of Sue.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Here.
- Huh?
Grandma said this will
help you kick butt.
Alex.
I'm sorry that I let you down.
Come here.
You've got my boy-
You think I don't trust you?
I'll be back in a minute.
Hey, he saved my life today.
Let him tell you about it.
Tell her all about it.
It's easy money. The smart money's
gonna go on Brakus.
Okay? Believe me.
Put it all on Brakus.
- How much is there?
- $500,000, my dear.
Uh, counter, please.
Hey, tough guy,
Brakus says put this on.
Yeah. Did you order the, uh,
double security downstairs like I asked?
Okay, great. Thanks.
Through the roof! Yes!
Give me a little kiss. Thanks.
I ﬂew all the way in
for this fight.
Got myself a suite of rooms
if you wanna stop on by later.
Hell, bring your friend, huh?
Hey! Whoo-hoo!
Hey. Stranger!
You look like you're
a real stranger in these parts.
Where the hell are you from
anyway, huh?
- Houston.
- Houston. Houston!
Hey, blondie,
come on over here a minute.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I bring you the event
of a lifetime!
Firstly, our challenger,
vanquisher-
Vanquisher? He kicked the
shit out of three gladiators!
Mr. Tommy Lee!
And the ultimate warrior
who has never known defeat...
the master and owner
of the Coliseum...
the champion of the underworld...
Brakus!
I have waited a long time
for this, Tommy Lee.
The feeling is mutual.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the Coliseum!
- What do you want?
- Excuse me.
- I said, what do you want?
- What do I want?
Aaah! God!
Ah, son of a bitch! Ah!
- Hey, Han.
- Alex.
- So good to see you.
- G00D' to see you.
- You guys tryin' to mess up your clothes?
- How about you?
Hey, it's a rental.
Look out. Here they come.
- There he is, right there.
- Let's do it.
Ow!
That's it, Brakus.
Tear his head off!
Come on.
Get up, Brakus!
Hey, watch it!
- Oh!
- Watch out!
- You better watch it!
- Hey come on!
- Sorry, gentlemen.
- Private club.
Yeah! Yeah!
Now he's mad.
Now he's gonna get him. Get him!
How many?
All of them? All of them?
Where's Finch?
Get me Finch now, now, now!
How'd' you get in here?
Code red downstairs! Let's go!
- Move it! You!
- Come and get me.
- You've got a lot of balls.
- Come on.
Tommy! Tommy!
Tommy!
- Hey!
- Four more, Alex.
Okay. You get them.
I got Tommy.
The buck stops here, bucko.
You. I owe you.
Join your dead friends!
Tommy!
Yeah!
Yeah, yeah!
Tommy! Tommy!
Tommy! Tommy! Tommy!
Kill him! Kill him!
- No! No! No!
- Dead! Dead! Dead!
- Dead! Dead!
- Kill him! Kill!
Stay down... and live.
Tommy, look out!
Ladies and gentlemen-Ladies and
gentlemen, in
victory, the title...
and the ownership of the Coliseum
pass to the strongest.
The new owner and master
of the Coliseum...
Tommy Lee
W-Well, you see, the-the champ
is a little new to public speaking.
Believe me when I tell you,
you're gonna be seeing more of him...
right here at the Coliseum in the months
and-and the years to come.
Everybody, come on.
Give him a big Coliseum round of applause.
Mr. Tommy Lee!
Say a few things, champ.
Champ, say a few things.
Champ, this is it.
You gotta talk to these people.
Say a few things.
- Do it for me.
- Say something.
The Coliseum is closed.
What? Wait a minute.
Hey,wait a minute!
Wait! Hey, wait a minute, guys.
You need me.
You can't do this.
You gotta think this over.
This is not chicken feed.
This is 20 million dollars
a year, champ.
Think about this. You-
You'll be back. You'll be back.
You'll see, man.
Don't bet on it.