Ready? Okay.
Wishing and hoping
And thinking and praying
Planning and dreaming
Each night of his charms
That won't get you
into his arms
So if you're looking
to find love
That you can share
All you've got to do
Is hold him and kiss him
MY BEST FRIEND'S WEDDING
And love him
and show him that you care
Show him that you care
just for him
Do the things
that he likes to do
Wear your hair
just for him
'Cause you won't get him
Thinking and praying
Wishing and hoping
Just wishing and hoping
And thinking and praying
Planning and dreaming
his kisses will start
That won't get you
into his heart
So if you're thinking
of how great
True love is
And squeeze him
and love him
Just do it
and after you do
You will be his
Two and two, menu !
Brian, 22, immediately!
Guillermo!
Two pigeons! Right away!
''V. I.P.''
Very important tabIe right here!
Give me two grain!
- I'll take that poIenta!
- AIl right, Chef.
- This is the one I'm waiting for!
- Yes, sir.
I need that speciaI meat now.
Pastry, get ready. It's coming at you.
I will kill your family it you don't
get this right. I need this perfect.
Yes, sir.
I'm writing it up as...
inventive and...
confident.
- Did the chap from Newsday ever call?
- I'll check my machine.
Is this a reaI interview
or some cute guy...
- you're setting me up with?
- Please, Julianne.
I don't send you men anymore.
You have no idea what to do with them.
lt's Michael.
Jules, it must be months, huh?
l can't wait to talk to you.
l'm in Chicago at the Drake Hotel.
Call me. 4:00 in the morning,
whatever. We gotta talk. Bye.
- Who called? Man of the moment?
- No, the opposite.
It's my Michael. Michael O'Neal.
Sounds desperate to talk to me.
The wandering sportswriter.
Remind me about that one.
Sophomore year at Brown...
we had this one hot month.
But you know me.
I got restless.
So I get up the nerve
to break his heart...
and he gives me this look.
Then he said, ''The thing
that makes me want to cry is...
l'm losing the best friend
I ever had.''
At that moment,
I knew I tell the same way.
So I cried for maybe
the third time in my entire life...
kissed him...
and we've been best friends
ever since.
We've seen each other
through everything:
losing jobs...
losing parents, losing lovers.
We've traveled all over.
The best times of my life, maybe.
Drinking and talking,
even if it's just over the phone.
Go on. This is so moving.
Kindred spirits?
He's nothing Iike me.
He's Iike you actually, only straight.
I remember this one night
in Tucson six years ago.
He takes a razor out
ot this littIe shaving kit...
cuts his tinger, takes my hand,
does the same to me.
- I'm gonna be sick.
- He says, ''Swear when we're 28...
if we've never married,
we marry each other.''
We never talked about it again.
I don't know
what made me think of that.
You're about to be 28
in three weeks, right?
- How old is he?
- You think?
Desperate to talk.
Cheers.
''Digital Answering System''
''Play''
''Red''
- Good evening. The Drake Hotel.
- l'm calling for Michael O'Neal...
- but since it's so late--
- One moment, please.
Hello?
You've been enrolled
in the Obscene caller of the Month Club.
Hey, beautiful.
lt's so great to hear your voice.
l miss you. l've been
calling you for over a month.
l've been on a book tour.
- I figured you were out of town.
- My machine eats alI my messages.
Or you're just averaging 30 days
to return a call.
- lt's less when it's you.
- l have to ask you something important.
lf you turn me down,
l don't know what l'll do.
It I could just tell you
one thing first.
This is probably going
to hand you...
the biggest laugh
ot your adult life...
but I was thinking about you,
and l was remembering...
this unbelievably insane night
we spent in Tucson...
like a thousand years ago.
- You probably won't remember this--
- Are you kidding?
l think about that night
all the time.
You do?
But it's not why l called.
It's not.
l called because l met someone.
That's great.
You haven't really seen anybody
since that dingbat Jenny Lee, have you?
You don't understand.
I've never felt this way
about anybody.
- She's all wrong for me.
- That's a good start.
She's a junior
at the University of Chicago.
She's 20. Her name's Kim.
You're gonna love her. She's beautiful.
Her dad is this billionaire. He owns
the White Sox and some cable empire.
l've always been uncomfortable
around rich people.
- Sure.
- But they're not like that.
They're such wonderful people.
Salt of the earth.
So you've met her parents?
Jules, we're getting married
this Sunday.
- Hello?
- Michael--
It's Wednesday night.
How can you possibly
be getting married on Sunday?
Actually, it starts tomorrow.
lt's a four-day wedding
with all the traditional events...
and 10 milllon people
flying in from all over the world.
Aren't you working this weekend?
Is that responsible?
The Sox are at home and Sports is
letting me do a profile on Frank Thomas.
Wait.
What do you mean, irresponsible?
Taking off a weekend
to get married?
Jules, I'm scared.
- Maybe we shouId talk about this.
- l need you.
lf you can't come and hold my hand,
l'll never get through this.
Please come.
l can 't wait for you
to meet her.
''United Airlines''
Listen, Jules.
Let's stop for a drink.
You can take a later tIight.
I'm a busy girl. I've got four days
to break up a wedding...
steal the bride's teIlow,
and I haven't one clue how to do it.
He adored me
for nine goddamn years.
- I can see why.
- She has known him for five seconds.
Plus, she's got billions of dollars,
and she's apparently perfect.
So don't go feeling all sorry
for Miss Preteen Illinois.
l can't lose him, George.
I'm going to bring him back.
You give your hand to me
And then you say hello
l can hardly speak
My heart is beating so
And anyone can tell
You think you know me well
But you don't know me
No, you don't know the one
Who dreams of you at night
Wants to kiss your lips
Wants to hold you tight
l am just a friend
That's all l've ever been
- Can you believe l'm gonna do this?
- Not hardly.
This just makes everything
so perfect.
Since I've met Michael, all I've heard
is ''Julianne this'' and ''Julianne that.''
I've never had a sister.
I have this monstrous tavor
to ask you.
- Excuse me?
- My best friend...
shattered her pelvis line dancing
in Abilene over spring break.
- Be my maid of honor?
- What?
Shouldn't you promote a bridesmaid
or someone you've known longer?
My bridesmaids are my only two
temale relatives under the age of 40...
debutante sisters from NashvilIe
who are basically vengetul sluts.
My exit!
I have tour days
to make you my new best friend.
It's time for you
to force yourseIf to get personal.
- Do you like the color?
- I think it's beautiful.
- Isn't that perfect for her?
- absolutely.
This is going to be tighter.
You don't want those things to fall out.
- It's beautiful.
- I'm not hurting you.
I don't want her to trip,
so I'll take this up a tiny bit.
Would you rather the datfodil?
I thought the bridesmaids
all wore the same dress.
Not you. You wouldn't be comfortable
unless you were distinctive.
What else did he tell you?
You hate weddings.
You never go.
You're not up
for anything conventional...
or anything that's assumed
to be a female prlority...
including marriage
or romance or even--
Love?
Michael and I were a wrong tip
right from the start.
He said that too.
I thought I was like you,
and proud to be...
until I met rumpled,
smelly, old Michael.
Then I tound I was just
a sentimental schmuck...
like all those flighty nitwits
I'd always pitied.
It's funny, huh?
l need a cigarette.
George, how do you think I feel?
all she does is talk
about her and Michael's future.
- She's just so dreamy.
- Jules, pull yourself together.
I don't know if l can do it.
You want me to turn around
or something?
Not the person I was expecting.
I've seen you
a lot more naked than that.
Things are different now.
I guess so.
You look really good...
without your clothes on.
She's toast.
''Caution 2-Way Tratfic''
''Exit''
- Where is the honeymoon exactly?
- It depends.
It San Antonlo sweeps Sacramento,
we could start there.
''Chicago HiIton And Towers''
Or Phoenix. Or depending
on the Indiana-CIeveIand game--
Garden spots, alI.
A swing of maybe 40 degrees Fahrenheit
represents a packing challenge...
but there's tine tood and cocktalls
at a choice of Embassy Suites.
lt's his career. I'm supportive.
I've been everywhere.
I want to be with the man I love.
That's what makes it a honeymoon.
He's lucky. One woman in a billion
could put up with his shit.
The guy's a one-man festival
of idlosyncratic--
You've been introduced
to the symphonic range--
Of his snoring?
He says it's worse than ever.
You know that snartle one?
Now it's got this phlegm-rattling thing
happening behind it.
Earplugs work.
- What about--
- Cigars in bed? l broke him of that.
The bathroom's a swamp.
He wears Reeboks to dinner.
He likes action movies.
He reads over my Shoulder.
He loves karaoke bars...
- and I can't carry a tune.
- Really?
He sucks soup
through his front teeth.
That's a trademark move.
Don't touch that one.
But he sure can kiss.
It's been a whiIe.
I'm just gonna take your word on that.
After two weeks
of cataloging all his taults...
I made a command decislon
that changed my life.
I threw the list away.
He's not a baIance sheet.
He's Michael.
Loving him means
loving all of him.
Do you get nervous
in contined spaces?
It's sweet of you
to want to be protective...
but nothing ever could give me
one moment's pause about this marriage.
- Do you become hystericaI in confined--
- Except one.
You. You're always
in his mind....
this perfect creature
he loved for years.
perfection can get wearing
atter awhiIe.
I'm not kidding. I had to tace up
to my competitive drives.
believe me, I've got them.
Am I gonna be jealous of you
for the rest of my life?
- Our paths will keep crossing.
- Space. of course.
- He'll always talk about you.
- It's only natural.
The answer was so simple.
I was gonna predict that.
You win.
I've missed a step.
He's got you on a pedestal...
and me in his arms.
My God, it's the bride
and the woman she'll never live up to.
- Are you okay, honey?
- That would be us.
Did she say the wrong thing again?
That is so in character.
- I'm Julianne Potter.
- We'd be the vengetul sluts.
- You can just call us eager.
- Have you sized up the groomsmen?
- As maid of honor, you get first pick.
- Don't pick the short, hairy, tat one.
- He's mine.
- Kimmy's a virgin.
Is this Michael's Julianne?
I'm IsabeIIe Wallace.
My handsome new son
scarcely did you justice.
My husband says
to scoot you to the baIlpark...
so you can hang with Michael.
But tirst you have to meet
a lot of really old women.
That is, it you've absorbed
enough profanity.
Who ordered a beer?
- Let me heIp you with that.
- You unwittingly imply I'm cIumsy.
Sorry. l was confusing you
with somebody l used to know.
Julianne Potter, this is Hank and Eric
from Sport magazine.
- Nice to meet you.
- They kindly gave me a job.
- Hi, there.
- How do you do?
And this is Walter,
my father-in-Iaw.
Future father-in-Iaw.
''Comiskey''
Thank you.
lf he gives you any grlet,
come see me.
- And this guy you know.
- Papa Joe.
I told him to make you best man,
but he had to go with his baby brother.
Best-looking guy
in any room.
- Great to see you.
- That will do.
- Scotty, that will do.
- Sorry.
Remember, it is the duty
of the best man...
to dance
with the maid of honor.
Dance? You can't dance.
- When did you Iearn to dance?
- l've got moves you've never seen.
You're an imposfor.
What did you do
with my best friend?
''Chicago Tribune"
I'm stiIl your best friend.
You just haven't seen me
for awhiIe.
Some people might find
that kind of perfection boring...
- day after day, year atter year.
- That's what I thought at tirst.
How can you like someone
that perfect?
No potentiaI
for long-range IikabiIity.
But then, she does have
a few good traits.
- AlI right.
- Such as?
They got him.
When I hug her,
even in pubIic...
I don't have to let go
right away.
She lets me hold her
as long as l want.
- Batting second, the shortstop--
- What?
- Nothing.
- I forgot.
You and that yucky love stuft.
You always get like that
when it gets sentimentaI.
I do not.
When we were--
When you and l were--
- When we were--
- Together?
Did I, when--
- Yes.
- Yes, what?
You puIIed away when I tried
to hug you in pubIic.
I've changed.
I mean, I'm not the girl
that l once was.
Really?
Any reIationship over two weeks
I should know about?
This is not about longevity.
This is about...
being comfortabIe...
with the yucky love stuft.
all right.
And l am.
And it's wisdom born of pain
Yes, I've paid the price
But look how much I've gained
- If l have to
- Karaoke!
- I can do anything
- Where did you find this place?
The doorman told me.
And you are singing the song.
l am strong
l am invincible
l am woman
I didn't realize
this was a karaoke bar.
This is so great.
My two best girls.
- You toIks thirsty?
- Margarita.
- Blended, no salt.
- She wants it straight up.
- You?
- Amstel Light.
Two words for you.
Margarita.
Vespa.
Florence.
Me hanging on in the rain.
- I love Florence.
- And the guy with the thing.
Where was my pass?
- ''No, the pier is for tishing!''
- ''French kissing?''
- ''Fishing!''
- I've always loved Florence.
You Should take her there.
She's perky. She deserves a honeymoon.
''lt San Antonlo
sweeps Sacramento''?
You're off the road in September, and
when does taIl quarter start for you?
I'm not coming back senlor year.
Don't architects find a degree
sort of an asset?
I travel every week. Got coIlege baIl,
mofor sports, training camps.
l think the most important thing
is for us to be together.
Say, Pinky, l wanna hear you sing.
Come on.
Kimmy hates to sing.
She hates it.
all right, tolks.
Everybody...
my bride-to-be here
is about to kick some ass on--
What?
It will be tun.
No, she doesn't want to, Michael.
Leave her alone.
Come on.
Ladies and gentIemen...
Please give it up for the dazzIing
vocal styIings...
ot Miss Kimberly Wallace!
Come on.
l just don 't know what to do
with myself
Don't know just what to do
l'm so used to doing
Everything for you
- You suck!
- Planning everything for two
And now that we're through
l just don't know
What to do with my time
l'm so lonesome for you
It's a crime
Going to a movie
lf your new love
Ever turns you down
Come back
I will be around
just waiting for you
l just don 't know what to do
Like a summer rose
It needs the sun and the rain
l need your sweet love
l need your sweet love to ease
All the pain
That was just terribIe!
''Steakhouse'' ''Park'' ''Taxi''
- You won't be lonely without us?
- Desperately.
- Maybe we don't have to go.
- Your grandmother's dinner?
As bride-to-be,
she's got you on a technicallty.
I'd baby-sit you, but my loyaIty
is to the bride in her time of need.
- It's not really a time of need.
- If you're sure.
- ''Sure''?
- I'll stay with Michael it you're sure.
- Call me later?
- of course.
- Bye.
- Have tun.
Were you pretty shocked
when I told you?
Shocked? No.
A little.
A lot.
I tell oft the bed.
That expIains the thump.
You like her, don't you?
- I do.
- That's enthusiastic.
I mean, she's--
She's great.
She serlously
can't sing a note.
But to make that kind
of sacritice--
- What? Leaving schooI?
- all of it.
Putting her career on hold
to toIlow you around in this dumb job...
where you travel 52 weeks a year...
to places
like CoIIege Station, Texas.
- ''Dumb job''?
- It's not a grown-up job.
My job never bothered you before.
It doesn't bother me now,
but I'm not Kimmy.
Her tather owns the Sox
and cabIe sports.
I'm just surprised
it hasn't come up, that's all.
What?
The corner oftice with a view.
You in a nice blue suit.
Permanent Chicago address,
somewhat close to Mom and Dad.
Never.
She would never even think of that.
You don't know her.
- But Michael loves his job.
- Sure.
Bad games, bad pay,
bad towns, bad flights...
bad hoteIs, reaI bad food...
homeIess, rootIess, lonely...
your copy makes it
in one issue out of tour.
What's not to love?
Why would he trade that for running,
say, a piece of the public reIations...
at a powerful compIex conglomerate
like your father's?
- That's what my father and I discussed.
- l'm not surprised.
So do you think
he'd really accept?
Michael?
A job like that?
It would be the greatest thing
that ever happened to him.
Present company excepted.
This is what we do:
We make your dad a coconspirafor.
Michael does a favor for Walter.
Walter's reorganizing
his public relations...
and needs a brilliant guy
that he's close to...
that he can completely trust.
Then you beg.
'Michael, please do this for Daddy.
It's only six months.
lt would mean so much to me. "
- He'll see right through it.
- Only if he wants to.
At the end of six months...
he will be happy...
settIed...
successtul.
Wow.
You look beautiful.
Do you have a date later?
Never can tell.
Just the way you look tonight
Remember?
Okay, kid, you're up.
It's really my father
who needs the favor.
He's reorganizing some
ot the divislons of the company.
PubIic relations
is a reaI probIem area for him.
lt would only be
six months maybe.
- Or three or four.
- You knew about this?
I think you ought to Iisten to her.
lt's her life too.
You gonna tell me
that Walter thought this one up?
Why don't you start
by being honest one second.
I am being honest.
all of a sudden I'm supposed
to drop out of schooI...
forget my tamily,
forget my career...
- forget the things I had planned?
- Forgive me for screwing up your plans.
GIad I heard this
before it's too Iate.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- What am I supposed to do with my life?
I work in a low-paying,
zero-respect job...
which, unfortunately,
I happen to love.
- It sounds like a great opportunity.
- Does it really?
How come you never took
some seIlout estabIishment job?
I'll teIl you why,
because that isn't you.
- And it's not me either.
- lf that's the way you feel--
Damn straight that's how I feel !
Just come out and say it.
My job's not good enough.
I'm not good enough.
- I never said that!
- Yes, you did.
Great, Kim.
Two days before our wedding, you Iay
this on me. I'm supposed to roII over?
Fine. I'm an insensitive.
sexist asshoIe.
You're better oft without me.
You are so right.
l was so wrong.
We settIed this, and I reneged.
That just wasn't tair.
You have to forgive me and forget
this happened or I'll just die.
Please.
I'm sorry.
George and Werner are not in.
Brevity is the order of the day.
George, answer this, damn itl
l'm in a meltdown here!
She double-crossed me!
The little twerp groveledl
She's so wrong for him.
Michael and I are the same person:
self-absorbed and vaguely loveable.
We deserve each other.
l'm running out of time.
l'm completely out of sneaky ideas.
l have come to the end...
of my rapidly fraying rope!
Yo u have got to think of something!
- Cottee, anyone?
- That would be wonderful.
''The Drake''
This is very Marcel Marceau.
Now, relax. We don't want your face
coming off with it, do we?
What a hideous room.
Death by a mini-bar.
How glamorous.
You flew all the way here.
You hate to tly.
I have to go back this evening.
We have a tamily thing in the Hamptons.
You're butting in.
What I mean when I say
she's annoyingly perfect...
is that there is nothing annoying
about her perfection.
It is vuinerable and endearing.
And that is annoying as shit.
You like her.
lt l didn't have to hate her,
I'd adore her.
This is my whoIe life's happiness.
I have to be ruthIess.
He was in love with me
every day for nine years.
I can make him happier
than she can.
I am breaking her heart
in the short run...
but really doing her
a gigantic favor.
She would be so miserabIe tagging along
after this insensitive doofus.
Do you really love him...
or is this just about winning?
Serlously.
In the beginning,
it was mostly this prlor claim.
He belonged to me.
But now, when I'm with him...
he's just so wonderful.
How come I never knew that
when I could have had him?
It's amazing the clarity that comes
with psychotic jealousy.
George, believe me...
if he was feeling
what I'm feeIing...
then he would know how I feel.
It's horrible.
What?
Just tell him you love him.
tell him you've loved him
for nine years...
but you were afraid of love.
TeIl him you were afraid of love,
afraid of needing.
- Needing what?
- To belong to someone.
We alI are, sweetheart.
l'm sorry about that.
Tell him this is the worst, cruelest,
dumbest moment to do this to him...
but there it is.
He's got to choose.
tell him the actuaI truth?
Maybe not the actual truth.
Highlights.
Arms at your sides, Please.
- Good morning.
- I have to talk to you.
- You don't like the suit?
- That's not what I have to talk about.
One thing tirst.
Excuse me.
- Guard this with your life.
- What is it?
- The ring.
- Why are you giving it to me?
- l don't trust Scotty with it.
- I don't think--
Please.
You're practically
the best man anyway.
- Thank you.
- Open it.
will she like it?
- What did you want to talk about?
- What?
You wanted to talk
about something?
We've known each other
a long time, right? Twenty years?
Not that long, but a long time.
And in that time...
we've grown close.
Very close.
Do you know what I mean?
- I think so.
- Good. So do I.
So sometimes--
could you excuse us?
Sometimes...
peopIe think...
they know how they feeI
about each other...
but they don't...
until...
until they do.
I have a point.
- Am l getting to it?
- Why don't you?
Whatever it is you have to say
can't be that big a deaI.
''A big deaI'' is a relative term.
Who's that guy?
It's George. I've told you
about George. He's my editor.
What's he doing here?
You working this weekend?
- He's here to be with me.
- Why?
Because he's my friend.
He's my good friend.
My best friend these days.
You've been busy.
So all of this
has been about George?
I'm speechIess.
That's JuIes.
- Congratulationss.
What?
I told him, puppy. If we're engaged,
we Shouldn't be ashamed of it.
He's racing back to New York.
He just came in for a few hours...
to fuck me.
Takes a few hours.
God.
Give me your ring.
Give it to me!
When you ask a girl to marry you,
you have to give an engagement ring.
I can't believe you're doing this to me.
I've come all this way to heIp you.
- You're insane!
- For one day find me irresistible.
Stop it.
ls something wrong?
I guess it's just the way
you've always talked about George.
It always seemed...
seemed like--
- It sounded like George was--
- Gay?
Actually, yes.
Common misconception.
It is.
George likes to pretend
that he's gay.
And why would you do that?
I find it attracts women.
Indeed.
Worked for me.
Big time.
Right.
Oh, my God.
Race you to the altar.
- UnderpIay.
- Got it.
I'm JuIes' fiance, George.
Just in town for a quick pre-conjugal
visit, it you catch my drift.
I do.
- You're going to humiliate me.
- Only if I can.
Just one thing.
Stay away from--
George! Oh, my God!
- I don't know why I'm so carried away.
- Me neither.
It's so--
Against God's plan?
No! It's just wonderful !
It's so wondertul!
Mom!
- What?
- You have to meet George.
You must be
Kimmy's little sister.
Julianne's fiance.
They're going to be married.
- What's going on?
- Julianne's getting married.
- Why didn't you telI us?
- There hasn't been time.
I wanted to. I wanted
to shout it from the rooftops...
but Jules said,
''No, Pumpkin, no.
This is Kimmy's day.
Let's not take the attention
away from Kimmy.
Dear, sweet...
adorable,
chocolate-covered Kimmy.''
Those were her very words.
I think I'm gonna cry.
Me too.
This is so sweet of you
to come to our rehearsal.
I insist you stay for lunch.
- No, absolutely--
- Love to.
Love the bag, love the shoes,
love everything. Love to.
- Darling, what about your flight?
- Canceled.
I can tell you this now,
but I was very worried about you.
About me?
All those sfories that Michael told me
were hilarlous...
but all those broken reIationships,
all those men.
lt must have hurt going through so many
guys and never finding the right one.
She couldn't sit down for seven years
until she met teensy-weensy littIe me.
And the man of your dreams
was always there.
She's talking about me.
Yes, Darling?
- How did you and Julianne meet?
- George is my editor.
But, Poopy,
we met a long time before that.
Actually,
it's a very romantic story.
would you like to telI it,
Sweet Pea?
- It's private.
- Not anymore.
I first met Julianne...
in a mental institution.
Julianne was there visiting
some French chef...
she'd sent insane
with a bad review...
and I was there
visiting Dionne Warwick.
He thought he was Dionne Warwick.
- Who is Dionne Warwick?
- Sacrilege, darling.
She's Whitney Houston's aunt.
She's very good
on the Psychic Friends Network.
- Isn't she?
- Do you know the way to San Jose
There I was with Dionne.
His real name, by the way, is Jerry.
We were having a sing-along,
then suddenly...
breezing through the doors
from the shock therapy room...
I saw her.
A vislon in pink.
- You don't wear pink.
- She does.
Sometimes she does wear pink.
- You do.
- l do.
l said to Dionne...
''Dionne, who is this vislon?
Surely, she must be the understudy
to some fabulous Broadway star.
Look at her skin.
Who does her hair?''
- In that moment, I knew.
- We don't all need to know--
We do!
- I'm very curious.
- They do.
I knew...
that someday
we'd end up like this:
like some glittering...
Doris Day-Rock Hudson
extravaganza.
l said to Dionne...
''Dionne, I'm in love.
Could this siren love me?
Are the gods that kind?''
And Dionne turned to me,
opened her lovely eyes and said...
What did she say?
The moment l wake up
Before l put on my makeup
I say a little prayer for you
While combing my hair now
While wondering
what dress to wear now
I say a little prayer for you
Forever and ever
you'll stay in my heart
And l will love you
Forever and ever
We never will part
Oh, how l love you
Together forever
That's how it must be
To live without you
would only mean
Heartbreak for me
Go, Granddaddy!
l run for the bus, dear
While riding
l think of us, dear
At work l just take time
And all through
my coffee break time
My darling, believe me
For me there is no one but you
- Please love me too
- Answer his prayer
- And I'm in love with you
- Answer his prayer now
Answer my prayer, baby
Say you love me too
all right, now!
- Heartbreak for you, actually.
- You've made your point.
Get on your plane. I'll call at the turn
of the century when I've forgiven you.
- It never would have worked out.
- Because it was dishonest.
Difterent temperaments.
Look, tell him you love him.
Bite the bullet.
What will he do?
''Be Careful
Watch Your Step''
He'll choose Kim.
You'll stand beside her
at the wedding...
kiss him good-bye
and go home.
That's what you came here to do.
So do it.
George isn't my fiance, Michael.
It's been over for ages...
but he can't accept it.
I'd buiIt you up so much...
l couldn't let him lose face
in tront of you.
He could never stack up to the one man
I measure everyone against.
This is strange.
I gotta tell you, when you--
When you told me that you were
marrying George...
I got this really strange--
You were jealous?
Crazy jealous.
I'm sorry.
Can we maybe spend some time alone
this afternoon?
would that be aIl right?
I've been thinking a lot
the Iast coupIe of days, about us.
Have you?
- There are a lot of memories.
- It's more than that.
It's kind of embarrassing
to say it this way, but...
you've sort of been,
you know...
the woman in my life.
You've been the man in mine.
And I was thinking
this could be our last time...
alone together, you know?
Except for that hot aftair
we'll have twice a year.
Except for that.
I mean, you commit
to this wedding...
and then it seems
like there's this momentum...
and then you forget
you chose it.
You and I didn't--
In our reIationships
with other peopIe...
we didn't use
the word love a lot, did we?
Kimmy says
it you love someone...
you say it.
You say it right then,
out loud.
Otherwise,
the moment just--
Passes you by.
We don't even have a song.
Kimmy and I don't have a song.
Do you think that's a bad sign?
Someday
When l'm awfully low
And the world is cold
l will feel a glow
just thinking of you
And the way you look tonight
Is your dance card tilled?
I'd have to check.
I keep it on Powerbook these days.
Is that right?
With each word
Your tenderness grows
Tearing my fears apart
With each laugh
that wrinkles your nose
To uches my foolish heart
Excuse me.
- I thought Michael was picking me up.
- I said l'd drop you at the stag.
He's got a lot to do.
l'm the unotficiaI best man.
Ot course.
Kim said when Michael turned the job
down that there was no friction.
Friction? No.
Good.
I haven't caused a probIem,
have I?
You haven't. Nobody has.
Listen,
you're just a little bit early.
Actually, I needed
to make some phone calls.
- Is it possible to use your oftice?
- of course.
- At the end of the hall on the lett.
- Thank you.
Take your time.
E-mall.
''File'' ''New Letter'' ''Open'' ''Close''
New letter.
To: Eric Isaacson...
''Mall Out''
Senlor editor, Sport Magazine.
From: Walter Wallace.
You can do this. It's easy.
Just do it fast, get it over with.
It's like it never happened.
Eric, I need a tavor.
My daughter's
every happiness...
is in your hands.
I have offered Mike O'Neal...
my new son-in-Iaw...
a great opportunity...
in my company.
To his own detriment...
Michael will not...
accept our ofter...
while he works for you.
My daughter joins me
in this plea...
for your cooperation.
With gratitude, Walter.
''Do You Wish To Send?''
''Yes'' ''No''
Why would I send this?
He'd get tired.
''Save For Later'' ''Delete''
Save for later.
It's not like I'm sending it.
I'm just saving it
for a few hours...
till we come back here and...
Michael can see it.
Perfectly harmIess.
''Wallace Company''
Send out this, this,
not this, this.
That's it.
l'm holding tour or five e-malls
I wrote over lunch. Send those too.
- Yes, sir.
- Bye.
all set?
I can't believe this!
Did you try every key?
It's no big deaI.
She just gave us the wrong keys.
There's got to be a janifor
or a guard...
or a cleaning woman
or, you know, some kind of--
Somebody has to be in this building!
I need a brick.
What's the big deal
about getting this tile tonight?
- I'm up against a deadline.
- Me too.
- I'm getting married tomorrow.
- That's my point!
Everybody will be busy
with more important things...
and this is really my last chance.
If I could just get up to Walter's
oftice, they're by the computer.
Then I could just e-mail
those figures right out now!
Tomorrow's Sunday.
Nobody's doing business.
Monday morning, crack of dawn,
Walter will walk you right up there.
Give it up, kid.
Can't win them all.
Good night.
This thing mean
that much to you?
We'll use the phone
in your room.
Walter's probably not even asIeep.
- I'll drive you up there.
- Thank you !
We'll get the right key,
and we'll go back to the office.
If I fall asleep on the altar tomorrow,
you'd better be there.
I'll be there.
These are all from Eric.
This fax is from Eric too.
My wedding. You'd think my boss
would leave me alone.
Maybe it's Congratulationss.
What is it?
''Mike, I can't believe I'm doing this to
you on the night before your wedding...
but I think you need
and deserve...
to know what
you're marrying into.
I received the foIlowing e-mall
this afternoon:
'Eric, I need a favor.
My daughter's every--'''
IsabelIe, I need to talk to Kim.
- ls anything wrong?
- No, I'm just tired.
Please put her on.
Thanks.
could you give me a minute?
Please?
Excuse me, miss.
Are you locked out?
Just stepped out.
It's a no-smoking room.
It's a nonsmoking tloor too.
Maybe you could go down
to the lobby.
Why don't you have me arrested?
I mean it.
I am a dangerous, criminaI person.
I do bad things
to honest peopIe.
You can make a citizen's arrest.
I wouldn't struggIe.
It'd be like getting AI Capone
on tax evaslon.
Can I heIp you, miss?
Do you smoke, Richard?
Yes, I do, but--
It's a nonsmoking tloor.
But you know what?
You know,
my grandmother always said...
''This too shall pass.''
Thanks, Richard.
l want you to quit this shit.
It'll kiII you.
What happened?
It's over.
She denied it.
She said
I was crazy and paranold.
A bad combination.
There's a big...
brunch tomorrow morning
at her parents' house.
She said,
''How could I call it oft?
What am I supposed
to tell everyone?''
It's for the best.
It really is.
She was right.
I am crazy...
to tall for someone
I hardly knew.
I'm so gIad you're here.
Have you still got that ring?
I tried it on,
and it won't come otf.
Why don't we take a walk
or have some food sent up?
I just want to be alone.
Is that okay?
Sure.
Maybe I'll go back to New York
for awhile and hang with you.
Eric will understand.
Or we could go somewhere...
if you want.
''lt San Antonlo
sweeps Sacramento--''
I've never been to Texas.
''Brown''
You what?
- Can I try that?
- Sure.
- Excuse me.
- Good Iuck.
So this is your basic
call-off-the-wedding party?
I came here to confront everybody.
I won't sIink away like some coward.
Besides, she hasn't told anyone.
l don't know what I'm supposed to do.
There is a wedding at 6:00.
Have you changed your mind?
Do you want to marry Kimmy?
I made a decislon.
It's over.
I'll go tell them.
First,
do you think she's all right?
could you
check on her for me?
These are the most beautiful tlowers
I've ever seen.
How is he?
He's sort of wondering...
why you haven't told your parents
that the wedding's oft.
I don't know. I'm still hoping
for a miracIe, I suppose.
How could he think that
my father and I would do such a thing?
I only minored in psych,
you understand, but...
maybe Michael couldn't commit
to this marriage...
so he created...
a deIuslon...
produced an unconsclous,
psychosomatic...
manitestation of--
I'm better with food.
You're Michael.
You're in a fancy French restaurant.
You order...
creme bruIee for dessert.
It's beautiful. It's sweet.
It's irritatingly perfect.
Suddenly, Michael realizes...
he doesn't want creme bruIee.
- He wants something else.
- What does he want?
- Jell-O.
- ''J eII-O''?
- Why Jell-O?
- He's comfortable with Jell-O.
Jell-O makes him comfortabIe.
I realize
compared to creme brulee...
it's Jell-O,
but maybe that's what he needs.
I could be Jell-O.
Creme bruIee
can never be Jell-O.
You could never be Jell-O.
- I have to be Jell-O.
- You'll never be Jell-O.
TeIl your parents. lf you're waiting
for that ''do you take this man'' part...
- it's considered poor form.
- I love him.
Whatever deluslons
I drove Michael to...
there's truth
at the heart of it.
I want him to work
for my father.
I want to stay in schooI,
and I want a life of my own.
Please, tell him it's my fault
and I love him.
You're the only person
that I trust.
- I'll be right back.
- Thank you.
How is she?
- Knock it off!
- Yes, sir!
- I asked you--
- She admits that it's her fault.
Totally, completely,
inexcusably her tault.
Do you think
she still loves me?
Love is a strong word...
and I don't know that
I'm necessarily quallfied--
I guess I wouldn't be totally oft base
it I said that, in her way...
she does possess
strong feelings--
Sure, she does.
She's crazy about you.
You fill up my senses
Like a night in the forest
Like the mountains
in springtime
Like a walk in the rain
TeIl her I'll marry her
at 6:00...
it she'll still have me.
Please.
Like a sleepy blue ocean
I'll be right back.
Come love me again
What did he say?
He said...
''Marry me.''
Thank God you were here.
I got so contused.
It happens.
Got a minute?
What's up?
I have to say this quick or I'll
just have this massive coronary...
and then you'll never hear it,
and you have to.
This is, by far, the dumbest thing
l've ever done in my entire life.
So dumb, in fact, that I can't.
But I'm gonna.
What's wrong?
I love you.
l've loved you for nine years.
I've just been too arrogant
and scared to realize it.
Now I'm just scared.
I realize this comes
at a very inopportune time...
but I really have this gigantic
favor to ask of you.
Choose me. Marry me.
Let me make you happy.
That sounds like three favors,
doesn't it?
But--
- Lovely together.
- Aren't they?
That's our maid of honor.
She's from New York.
''Floral Design/Special Events''
Michael, wait!
Please! You'll never catch her!
Doesn't anybody
leave their car unlocked?
Nobody trusts anybody anymore?
A good Samaritan.
''Auto Memory Sforing''
There's just
Too little of
What the world needs now
''Bakery''
Come back here!
''Shy tendrils of russet pleasure...
began their unbidden journey.
She moaned.
The tonnage of years of anguish,
sacrifice, mingling with--''
It is not going well !
This is what comes of telling the truth
or even part of it!
- Getting what you deserve isn 't fair.
- Where are you?
I have stolen a bread van, and I'm
chasing Michael down Michigan Avenue!
This is all your fault!
I told him the truth !
I said that I loved him,
and I kissed him.
- This is what's happened!
- Jules, a question.
When you kissed Michael,
did he kiss you back?
What do you mean?
We were lip to lip!
Was there anything there leading you
to believe this chase will end happily?
That's beside the point.
We were interrupted.
- Who interrupted you?
- Kimmy! She ruined everything!
And Michael started chasing her
before he could answer me.
Michael's chasing Kimmy?
You're chasing Michael?
Who's chasing you?
Nobody. Get it?
There's your answer: Kimmy.
Jules, you are not the one!
Now, for God's sake,
the wedding is at 6:00 p.m.
You have a small, but distinct, window
of opportunity to do the right thing.
''Exit'' ''Canal St.''
all aboard!
Excuse me.
I have a confession to make.
Another contession.
Besides that I love you,
this is even worse.
The e-mall that Walter sent
to your boss--
I wrote that.
I'm the bad guy.
Are you crazy?
Are you completely insane?
l mean, Jules,
how could you do that?
It wasn't supposed
to get sent.
I just wanted you
to get mad at Kimmy.
God.
I have done nothing
but underhanded, despicable...
not even terribly imaginative things
since l got here.
I was just trying to win you...
to win you back.
But that doesn't excuse
any of it.
I'm pond scum.
Lower, actually.
I'm like the tungus that feeds
on pond scum.
Lower.
The pus that intects the mucus...
that cruds up the tungus
that teeds on the pond scum.
On the other hand...
thank you...
for loving me that much.
That way...
it's pretty fIattering.
Except it makes me tungus.
That part I knew.
God.
I'm glad you didn't get
on that train.
I came here looking for her.
- Why would she be here?
- This is where I proposed.
l had to cover a game in MiIwaukee,
and she saw me ott.
The train was starting
to leave and...
I jumped up on the step
and I heId the handIe...
and without...
a thought in my head,
I just shouted, ''Marry me.''
The train was puIIing out,
and she just suddenly screamed, ''Yes!''
Just once.
And bIew me a kiss.
It would've been
a nice wedding.
You can't believe
that you've lost her.
You will find her, and you'll look
into her eyes and see all that love.
I just hope that it's soon.
Or eIse l'd hate to be you at 6:00.
Just wait.
We'll spIit up.
You will go to every romantic place
the two of you have...
and I will go someplace brilliant,
and we'll find her.
We will find her.
Wallace egreglous residence,
Mandy speaking.
lt's Jules.
Have you gotten a call from Kimmy?
She slipped out, the little monkey,
during the commotion.
''Commotion''?
My sister was licking an ice sculpture,
and her tongue troze right to it.
And that's a commotion?
It's a sculpture of the David.
So Kimmy would be--
She's probably with Michael
doing the nasty.
Either that or crying in her nachos
down at Comiskey Park.
- Excuse me?
- l had this crank call...
from some guy who says he saw her
in the luxury box.
- Right.
- What would a bride be doing--
Can you bring my dress
to the church?
I have to pick something up
for the ceremony.
Don't forget to shave now.
Here we go.
Here's the hair dryer.
There we go.
It's going to be okay.
Please, no pictures.
''Federal Express''
I know you're in here.
The guard saw you come in.
Just leave me alone,
you bitch!
Who the hell
do you think you are?
- Cat fight!
- You came here...
pretending to be my friend,
and I made you my maid of honor!
Who asked you to do that?
You knew me what, eight minutes?
Michael trusted you,
so I trusted you.
You wanted to keep me close.
You didn't trust me for a second.
- I was right!
- of course you were right.
- But that's not my fault.
- You kissed him!
- At my parents' house!
- That's cold.
On my wedding day!
- Bitch.
- Tramp.
Shut up!
Now I love this man,
and there is no way...
I'm going to give him up to some
two-faced, big-haired food critic!
all right.
Okay, all right!
I kissed him.
I tried to steal him.
I lost.
He doesn't love me.
He loves you.
I haven't done much that l'm proud of
the last three days.
I'd like to take you
to the church...
so you can walk down
that aisIe...
and marry the man
ot our dreams.
Because he sure wants
to marry you.
So raise our glasses and wish Mike
and Kim every happiness...
for a long and happy life
together...
filled with happiness.
- I guess that's it.
- To the bride and groom.
Now let's hear from the maid of honor,
the lovely Julianne.
I had the strangest dream.
I dreamt that some psychopath was
trying to break the two of you up.
Luckily, I woke up and I see...
that the world
is just as it Should be...
for my best friend...
has won the best woman.
I didn't get you a gift.
However,
this is on loan...
until you two
find your song.
Someday
When I'm awfully low
When the world is cold
l will feel a glow
Just thinking of you
And the way you look
Tonight
Oh, but you're lovely
With your smile so warm
And your cheeks so soft
There is nothing for me
But to love you
Just the way you look
Tonight
- It's mine!
- I don't think so!
I got it!
Bye.
Hey, gorgeous,
having a good time?
Not particularly,
but I did what I came to do.
What? You split them up?
No, I said good-bye.
Good girl.
l'm proud of you.
Be prouder still
if you were dancing.
I have big plans for dancing.
Just give me 30, 35 years.
The misery...
the exquisite tragedy.
The Susan Hayward of it all.
l can picture you there sitting alone
at your table in your lavender gown.
Did l tell you
my gown was Iavender?
Hair swept up.
Haven't touched your cake.
Probably drumming your fingernails
on the white linen tablecloth...
the way you do when you're
really feeling down.
Perhaps looking at those nails thinking:
''l should've stopped...
my evil plotting to have that manicure,
but it's too late now. "
I didn't tell you
my dress was lavender.
Suddenly, a familiar song.
The moment l wake up
And you're off your chair
in one, exquisite movement...
wondering, searching,
sniffing the wind...
like a dapple deer.
Has God heard your little prayer?
Will Cinderella dance again?
And then, suddenly,
the crowds part...
and there he is:
sleek, stylish...
radiant with charisma.
Bizarrely,
he's on the telephone.
But then, so are you.
And he comes towards you...
the moves of a jungle cat.
Although you quite correctly sense
that he is...
...
like most devastatingly handsome
single men of his age are...
you think, what the hell...
life goes on.
Maybe there won't be marriage.
Maybe there won't be sex.
But, by God,
there'll be dancing.
Bond. Jane Bond.