(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
(Episode 10)
I'll go study abroad.
Thank you, Se Yun.
Thank you...
so much.
Why are you thanking me?
I'm the one who's thankful.
I get to study abroad with your hard-earned money.
I'm sorry,
Se Yun.
I'm sorry.
So you do have something you want.
Yes.
Hong Se Yun.
I need Hong Se Yun.
Grandpa.
You won't abandon me, will you?
Why would I abandon you?
You're my only blood relative in the entire world.
I won't do it again.
I won't do anything bad.
If you let me have Se Yun,
I can fix what I did wrong.
So please,
don't abandon me.
My child.
- Mom. - Yes?
Why are you crying?
When I was little,
when it was...
just you and me,
I used to get scared whenever the sun set.
I worried that you wouldn't come home from work,
and that you wouldn't...
pick me up from daycare.
Do you still remember things from when you were five?
I always told you to sleep first if I was late,
but you always cried, holding your knees to your chest...
whenever I was late.
I felt like if you left me,
the sun wouldn't rise,
I couldn't breathe,
and the entire world would end.
You felt the same, right?
Like you couldn't live without me. Right?
But if I go study abroad,
you'll be all alone.
You'll take down the laundry all alone like this,
and return to a house without me.
I won't be able to hug you like this either.
You and I...
aren't the only ones in the world anymore.
Even if...
I send you far away,
I can lean on your dad, Chul Soo,
Sun Hee, and Gang Hee.
You're the one I'm worried about.
You'll be alone...
in that faraway land.
Don't worry,
because I'll take your face,
your scent and your voice...
with me...
right here.
I can take you out whenever I miss you.
Okay. That's right. Good.
I'll take that.
Thank you.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
- Hello! - Mom!
Dad! Mother's here! So is Se Yun!
How did you come? You didn't even call.
I've decided to hold off on sending Gyung Hye...
to Hawaii.
Mr. Chairman. She cut up clothes at a shop...
and even physically fought with a shop employee.
People will complain about her abusing her status.
We must send her to Hawaii to avoid the storm...
Mr. Lee...
will take care of it.
- I'll do that. - If that was possible,
he would've prevented them from occurring in the first place.
Mr. Lee. My wife is secretly receiving psychiatric treatment.
Your duty is to make sure she doesn't make a sound...
outside of the house,
but you let things get this out of hand.
It isn't only to avoid the rumours, sir.
It would be of great help to her treatment to let her...
rest peacefully in a new environment.
Sir. You must send my wife to Hawaii.
Mr. Jang.
Have faith in Gyung Hye.
Dr. Kim.
Work harder on her treatment...
so that she can overcome her illness herself.
Yes, sir.
I'll do my best.
I'll be more attentive to her, sir.
Average people fear you.
You're in bad shape.
Get it together.
Don't sit there like that.
You look openly insane. It's frightening.
Apologize for what you said.
- Let go. - Apologize!
Let go. Let go!
That's right.
I'll get rid of everyone...
coming at me.
I'm going to live.
Gyung Hye asked me...
to hire Hong Se Yun as her personal shopper.
She plans to reduce...
the impact of the designer shop incidents.
If Gyung Hye and Hong Se Yun...
knew each other well enough that Gyung Hye would hire her...
as her personal shopper,
people wouldn't think Gyung Hye was abusing her status.
Although they had a physical altercation,
it will be buried as...
a minor argument, a misunderstanding,
and a mistake.
Do you plan to do as Ms. Gyung Hye wants?
Play, turtle
You look happy when you play
You and you
Everyone plays
- Good job. - You were great!
- You did great. - Nice.
He's better than you.
I should get going.
What's the rush?
Gang Hee will be here soon.
Wait until she comes.
Mom. Can't you sleep at home tonight...
and go early tomorrow morning?
I told my boss that I'd be right back.
What are they, night goblins?
It's not like you need to cook or clean in the middle of the night.
Mom, just stay over.
Woong, you ask her.
Don't go. Please?
Gosh. I'll see you on the weekend.
Why are you acting like you'll never see me again?
I have something important to tell you...
and the family this weekend,
so tell Gang Hee to stay home.
Okay.
Mom. What do you need to tell us?
You'll have to wait. I want to tell everyone together.
Wait. I'll go with you and get you a cab.
I don't need a cab. I can take the bus.
- Stay. You'll only slow me down. - No, no.
- I'll walk you. - See you this weekend.
- Clean up. - Okay.
- Get back safely, Mom! - Bye!
I said I'd take you. You're so stubborn.
It's still cold out.
Ask Gang Hee to dye your hair for you.
Do it for me when you're home this weekend.
Gang Hee is very careless.
She misses spots all over the place.
I'll cut your hair too, while I'm at it.
I really like hearing you laugh like this.
Do you remember when Gang Hee was born?
You lost your retirement fight...
and ran to the hospital all banged up,
but as you held Gang Hee,
you smiled like you were the happiest man on earth.
I felt like Gang Hee made you and Se Yun...
really my family,
so I adored her.
I'll bring Ms. Gyung Hye's food to her room.
I'll eat here.
Okay. Have a seat.
Miss.
Water kimchi.
Yes, Miss.
I'd like dark chocolate for dessert.
I hear it's good for reducing stress.
I understand.
You look good.
I'll eat well, sleep well, and smile often.
I'll keep doing that.
The VIP ultra-luxury goods project.
- Yes, sir. - It's not bad.
I'll call a meeting with the executives soon.
Prepare a presentation.
Thank you, sir.
You walked this path to work for 10 whole years.
Work is hard, isn't it?
Dad.
You don't have to worry about what happened yesterday...
at the shop.
I didn't tell your mom.
Good. If she finds out,
it'll just be yet another person who is upset.
Se Yun, are you really okay?
You must've been very upset.
Dad, I'm really okay.
Plus, it was worth it.
I got to have your special agujjim.
- Go in, Dad. - Okay.
Okay.
6 months docked pay.
Demotion.
Write a formal apology...
explaining exactly what it was...
that you did wrong.
Don't type it. Write it by hand.
You're getting off easy only because you were...
the best employee for three years.
Most importantly,
go to Ms. Eun Gyung Hye...
and get her to sign your apology.
I'm saying, get her to forgive you.
I think Friday will do.
Why do you need so much time?
- Go to her today and... - By Friday,
I'll pass on the list of clients that I handled,
their preferences, sizes,
favourite brands and other notables...
to my successor.
What...
What did you just say?
I said to go to the client and apologize, but what?
Your successor?
I'm the one who should receive an apology,
not Eun Gyung Hye.
So, what's this?
Are you saying you quit?
Yes. I'll pass on everything to my successor...
by this Friday, my last day.
I'll do that since this had been my bread and butter for five years.
I hope you'll treat me with respect during my remaining days...
as well.
What...
We didn't ship Gyung Hye off to Hawaii.
Things just got more complicated.
If there's a problem, there is always a solution.
You need to come up with that solution quickly.
I thought he said he'd call an executives meeting soon.
To discuss the ultra-luxury goods project...
If all the core executives complain,
Chairman Eun's hands will be tied.
Isn't that too dangerous?
It may hurt the company.
Chairman Eun is still strong.
He'll block the bomb we set off...
before the company is harmed.
Gyung Hye's succession...
is all that will be destroyed.
I thought you'd withdraw her shopping deposit,
but you doubled it instead.
Ms. Eun Gyung Hye, our VVIP,
is incredible magnanimous...
- and generous... - I hope the employees...
will not talk about what happened...
that day.
You do not need to worry about that at all.
Hong Se Yun said...
she'd resign just earlier today.
Once she's gone from the shop,
the incident will be forgotten.
Don't worry.
Hong Se Yun is resigning?
Yes.
So, please put in a good word...
with Ms. Eun Gyung Hye.
She won't have to worry about...
such unpleasant things happening here again.
Se Yun.
When is your last day here?
I heard you were quitting.
Is it because of what happened with Ms. Gyung Hye?
Not everything in the world happens...
because of Eun Gyung Hye.
If you'll excuse me...
Do you have some time now?
It won't take long.
Sorry, but I have plans.
Shin Hyuk.
You must be hungry.
- What should we have? - Let's have noodles.
- Eat. - Thanks.
Is it good?
Did you have a workshop nearby?
I wondered what was up...
when you suddenly asked me to lunch.
From what I learned at the workshop today,
if we're lucky,
I think we can get them to reopen Kkot Nim's case.
That's great. Good luck.
Don't give me lip service.
Take me to the movies.
- The movies? - I'll pay for lunch.
That's not all. When we get to the theatre,
I'll pay for the popcorn, squid, soda,
everything.
I'll pass on everything to my successor...
by this Friday, my last day.
Then let's go on Friday.
Friday? Wouldn't Saturday or Sunday be better?
Friday is good.
I want to eat yummy food and watch a movie...
that day.
(Letter of Resignation)
I got yelled at a lot by the higher ups.
Look at this. I look like a panda bear.
You caused the problem,
but rather than fixing it,
you're just quitting.
You know you're being mean to me, right?
So, don't go around badmouthing me...
or anything, okay?
I can't thank you for everything.
But still,
you worked hard.
What is this?
Let's go, Se Yun.
(Letter of Resignation)
(I quit because you treat us like garbage.)
Why that...
(I quit because I don't want to get cancer here.)
Hey! Why you...
Enjoy.
Why are you putting on so many sesame seeds?
Because I can do whatever I want.
Now that I gave her...
the letters of resignation I wrote over the past three years,
I feel like I pooped after being unable to for a month.
It feels so good.
Gross. We're eating right now.
Let's eat.
This is good.
It's awesome.
- Young Ae. - Yes?
Can you really just quit like this?
Because of me...
Ever since high school, you were the needle, and I, the thread.
That's true.
Designer goods make me sick now.
I'm going to change my field...
to something more for commoners and the general public.
Somewhere where I don't have to see arrogant jerks with money.
- Young Ae. - What?
- Sorry. - Why?
I'm going abroad to study.
You are?
It turned out that way.
My family wants me to pursue my dream before it's too late.
- Do you mean it? - Yes.
You need to find a new job, but I...
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
You really wanted to become a fashion designer.
Congratulations.
Brat. Thank you.
For what?
You're letting me have a fashion designer friend.
- I'm so happy for you. - Congratulations.
Designer friend. Cheers.
- What... Just eat. - Okay.
He must be drunk.
Miss, have some tea.
Why is my grandfather...
taking so long to decide?
What are you waiting for him to decide?
I said I wanted a personal shopper.
A personal shopper?
A personal assistant to help you shop?
Yes.
I recommended someone.
Whom did you recommend?
Hong Se Yun.
I want her.
Why someone...
you had issues with?
I want to teach her something.
- "Teach her"? - Just something.
He should've received the report by now.
It's too quiet.
The core executives...
received a report stating Gyung Hye is secretly...
receiving psychiatric treatment...
along with photographs.
Yes, sir. It was sent from a burner phone...
early this morning to all the core executives.
When is the executives meeting?
It is 10 days from now.
The picture...
must be completed flawlessly...
before that meeting.
(Resume: Hong Se Yun)
In order for the picture to be completed,
we need Hong Se Yun.
Gyung Hye was right.
There is something about her that you need to know.
Bring Hong Se Yun...
to me right now.
The person you have reached...
Your belly is big.
You ate a lot, didn't you?
How did you know I ate a lot?
Do you have a baby in there?
- It was so much fun. - I haven't watched a movie in ages.
People need culture in their lives. Don't you agree?
(Missed calls)
(Mr. Lee Jae Joon)
- You're popular. - I guess so.
Hello? I received a missed call...
Don't be late.
What is it? Is something wrong?
Se Yun.
Don't be nervous.
I plan to forgive you for what happened.
I came for an apology.
Did you...
just say "apology"?
If you weren't going to apology,
why did you call me here?
Don't do it, if it's too hard for you.
Your apology isn't all that important to me...
or to my dad.
Do you realize...
what great opportunity you're passing up?
Remember what you said when we ate here before?
You said a bloody hunting dog...
survived because of his love for food.
For the dog, it was food,
but for me, it's my family.
So, Eun Gyung Hye,
don't mistreat people.
"Mistreat"?
You're the one mistreating me.
How dare you talk to me that way?
I didn't come to fight you.
You can't fight...
with someone who doesn't understand you.
Shut it.
Do you think I'm afraid of you?
I feel...
sorry for you.
What do you have?
Money?
It looks like that is all you have.
That's why I want to teach you...
how that one thing that I have...
can drag you into the sewer.
Try me.
I'll teach you...
that there are people you cannot order around.
I'll make sure you understand.
Hong Se Yun.
How dare you...
How refreshing.
(Mr. Lee Jae Joon: Please call me.)
Hong Se Yun came to the house to see Ms. Gyung Hye once.
Ms. Geum knew that the shop worker with whom she had the altercation...
was her daughter.
(Mother: Geum Young Sook)
(Hong Pil Mok)
Se Yun.
Mom.
It's still cold out. You should dress more warmly.
Se Yun.
Ms. Geum.
Mr. Lee?
(Mysterious Personal Shopper)
You work for the owner of Winners Group?
What are you doing?
What are you thinking?
We have to send Se Yun abroad to study.
- She's going to study abroad? - Is that true?
Thanks to you,
- I had a great experience. - Please help me.
You said you'd help.
Schedule a meeting with Hong Se Yun.
I'll do whatever it takes to stop it.
I will not let her step foot in this house.