This is where I intercept
with the target?
Exactly.
Spare no one, Julia.
Or we die slaves.
Spare no one.
-Are we ready to go?
-She's a little nervous.
She's a little nervous.
You'll make a good martyr.
Spare no one.
Meanwhile, all of our comrades
will be getting killed one by one.
It will be worth it.
Nicholi, you have to be patient.
Your moment will come.
Now go. You have work to do.
-Spare no one, Julia.
-Or we die slaves.
-Are we ready to go?
-She's a little nervous.
You'll make a good martyr.
Now go. You have work to do.
-Yes?
-Turning the corner.
Okay.
Stop. Stop.
Get the fuck out.
I thought this was
the high-level security facility.
Well, it is. Why, you already in?
You're good.
-Let's go, send me the scan.
-There you go.
Thomas, make sure
the encryptions are right...
...I don't wanna get stuck
at that gate.
No, she's good.
Numbers are virtually the same.
Perfect.
That's what I'm talking about.
Let's do it.
Who the hell are you?
-Who the hell are you?
-Prep that arm.
There's a thing called the Geneva
Convention. I've got rights.
-You know about that, do you?
-You are fucking dead.
You are dead.
You are fucking dea--
Doc, you sure you
hit the right vein?
No vein there, it's lM.
Get that bag ready.
-Scary shit.
-Okay, you guys can leave, please.
Nurse.
Doctor.
He's going into anaphylactic shock.
Get me 2 c's of epi, right now.
We'll work on the airway later.
We'll have to transfer him.
He's a red wristband. We can't.
Well, we're gonna have to.
I don't have the facilities here.
-Under whose authority?
-Under mine.
I'll call an ambulance.
-Open the gate.
-We've got a flatliner.
We're transporting now.
Get him up.
All right, move it, move it.
Stop the vehicle.
Wait a minute. What's going on?
You're not a doctor.
Been away so long, it even
feels good to be stuck in L.A. traffic.
I hope my brother cut you
a good deal.
It was worth the trouble.
How many years were you
in the system?
For long enough
to know my way around.
So do you have any other skills...
...or do you just break people
out of prisons?
What kind of skills
are you looking for?
Do you know
what a little fat boy is?
Why would you ask a question
like that?
Jonathan Cold, ex-ClA.
Current freelance operative
specialized in covert operations...
...and nuclear-weapons intelligence.
I don't recall leaving my resume
with you people...
...but I'm impressed with the way
you've done your homework.
Who do you think employed you,
Mr. Cold?
You don't think I'd entrust
my freedom to my baby brother.
You're here because I wanted
you here, simple as that.
So, what's your day rate?
I can't believe you're safe.
Good to see you, brother.
Wait a minute.
Jesus Christ. That's Jonathan Cold.
God, I thought he was dead.
Who is Jonathan Cold?
He taught me everything I know.
-I had excellent help getting here.
-Expensive help.
Come on inside, Mr. Cold.
Get you the rest of your money.
No hurry. Mr. Cold's gonna be
staying around for a while.
A robbery in the Amsterdam
Diamond District.
Interpol believes a Chechen
resistance group is responsible...
...for this and a string
of other robberies across Europe...
...presumably to finance
their political goals.
Joining us is Dr. Richard Turpin...
...an expert on European terrorism.
Thank you.
Besides funding their operations
with daring robberies...
... what else do we know
about this organization?
A year ago, their leader,
Aslan Masklov, was assassinated...
...in what is believed to be
a CIA hit.
The group has intensified
its terrorist activities since...
...and vows vengeance
on the United States.
Good job getting my brother
out of that place.
Yeah, my pleasure.
What exactly does he want you
to do for him?
Well, why don't you ask him?
-You forget who's paying you.
-I made the deal with your brother.
If you have any issues,
why don't you take them up with him.
Don't get too comfortable.
Any movement?
Nothing yet. They're just waiting.
So tell me about your friend.
Well, he was my first handler.
One of the best operatives
in the field.
So why's he working
for the bad guys?
I'm not sure.
Rumor has it he turned tables, killed
six agents and then disappeared.
Now he's classified as a foreigner.
There's a shoot-on-sight
sanction on foreigner operatives.
-lf he's seen, he's dead.
-Exactly. So why is he here?
This isn't his style.
I'm gonna call Greer and fill him in.
-Greer.
-Stuart here.
Looks like we got a little party
going on.
Donovan just showed up.
Interesting. Have you heard
of any prison breaks?
Nope. But he had an escort.
Jonathan Cold.
Cold?
Are you sure? Intel says he died
last year in Prague.
Well, he's here,
and I'm pretty sure he's not dead.
You know him?
Yeah.
A long time ago.
Be careful. Dead or alive,
Cold is a dangerous man.
Should we alert
the Marshals Service?
-Let them know we found their man?
-No. Stay dark.
Donovan is only one piece
of the puzzle.
I wanna know exactly what they're
up to before we make our move.
Yes, sir.
Finally, we have reached
our targett
The great city of Los Angeles.
One more time, that's all.
One more.
Then we have enough.
And then everything changes.
It's big. See how much bigger it is...
...than the one your boyfriend
bought you?
But size isn't everything.
Believe me, I know.
Girlfriend, they'll hear
wedding bells looking at that.
Hands in the air.
Come here. Come here.
-Open it.
-I don't have the combination.
I can't.
How about now?
Come on. Come on. Do it.
Take a breath.
Now, one at a time.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Only two types of sales make the kind
of money I like:. drugs and weapons.
I hate drugs. You still interested?
Well, that would depend
on what's in it for me.
Two hundred K up-front.
Another 800 when the job is done.
-I'm listening.
-lf you were me...
...would you buy this?
-No.
-Why not?
Because there's only half
the schematic there.
It's a teaser from the seller.
That's right. You see,
in this business...
...the keys to the kingdom
is weapons-grade plutonium.
If you ain't got that,
you ain't got shit.
You'd be surprised how generous
the local nuclear test program is.
You just have to know who to ask.
I heard that.
Jonathan's in.
-lsn't that right?
-Yeah, that's right.
Need to talk to you.
Give us a minute.
Relax, James.
You're getting yourself all worked up.
I don't trust him. I want him out.
I trust money. He needs us
more than we need him.
Three years you've been gone.
Three years I've been
putting this deal together.
The people, the product.
All me, all me, all me.
I've risked my ass to get you home,
and it's still not enough?
-When do I get a say?
-You did good.
I'm proud of you.
But you didn't get me out. He did.
Cold stays.
They called. They wanna meet
tomorrow morning.
-We're not ready.
-They are.
Well, then. I guess we're gonna
have a busy night.
What is a common criminal
like James doing hanging out...
...with a Russian nuclear physicist
like Myshkin?
Okay, let's just say,
for argument's sake...
...that they're trying to build a nuke.
Where would they get
the plutonium?
There are two power stations
in Oakland...
...and a test facility in Pasadena.
Okay, the test lab in Pasadena
is a civilian facility.
Start there,
the security should be lighter.
Then find a list
of their new employees...
...and run backgrounds
through the grid.
I'm gonna take a walk,
so keep your cell phone on.
All right. Time to give it up, baby.
-Morning.
-Good morning.
Sorry, I was--
Much better.
Can't beat this weather,
can you, Mr. Macabe?
Better than Los Alamos.
Bet you're happy
you got transferred here.
-Every day.
-Have a nice day.
You too.
Keep moving.
Find anything?
Gun.
Please.
I thought we were all
on the same team.
I trust my men. No one else.
You know what, you can't
kill everybody you don't trust.
I owe you once
for bringing him back.
Won't ask twice.
Is that right?
Get his phone.
Follow me.
Yeah. Hey, Myshkin's here.
-Doctor, a pleasure as always.
-You said no guns.
No need to worry. Want me
to get you something to drink?
Where is my money?
Very well.
Business first.
I believe you have something for me.
I tell you, she is very delicate.
Based on the Mk-54 design.
But with 23 microprocessors
and eight charges.
Each precisely calibrated to fire
within two microseconds of the next.
Implosion causes the core to reach
critical mass and then....
Well, then...
...you know the rest.
Yeah, she should yield a 5-kiloton
charge. Just like you asked.
Small but powerful. Like the heart,
if you will.
A child can carry this.
Here is the rest of my test results...
...along with the rest of the plans.
They are all there. You can look.
Go ahead.
Then I guess we have a deal.
Gentlemen, thank you very much.
Brother, where's the password?
The ignition sequences are missing.
Without the numbers,
there's no boom.
Is this how friends behave?
It is only an insurance policy.
Please, I am not a stupid man.
The numbers.
When I get to my car, you will have
everything that you need.
I cannot spend my money
if I'm a dead man.
Go with James.
Thank you very much.
What?
You're a piece of shit, that's what.
That hurt. I did it for you.
You wanted...
...to get paid, right?
Oh, yeah, it's all about
the money, huh?
If these are the wrong numbers...
...it'll be interesting to see
what your next trick is.
Thank you.
Greer, it's Stuart.
Look, this is going down right now.
-It's good?
-lt is.
Give me the book.
Who you selling this to?
Since when do you ask questions,
Mr. Cold?
It's not your style.
You know what, you're right.
I don't know what got into me.
What if they try to screw us?
-They won't.
-What if they do?
It will make no difference.
They will all be glowing in the dark
in the end.
We are days away from
realizing Aslan's dream. Just days.
No more petty crimes.
No more blowing up buses.
We are ready to die,
and they are not.
-They're here.
-Copy.
We have an appointment.
No guns.
You first.
No deal.
Those two stay here.
Do you have the diamonds?
Where are the rest?
When we have the device and
the plutonium, you get a key.
Key to what?
A large safe-deposit box
full of diamonds.
A lot of diamonds.
Our friend, Mr. Cold,
ran a complete diagnostic.
It passed with flying colors.
Here's the rest of your plans.
Password.
Well, Mr. Macabe.
Looks like you're not exactly
who you say you are.
Who the fuck are you?
Where is she?
Who?
What's he got?
Yeah, be quiet, you bitch.
So where's my plutonium?
As I told you, we have to wait.
-How long?
-A day at most.
-Hey, look what I found here.
-Who the hell is this?
Maybe we should be asking you.
Were you followed?
-We're being set up.
-Hold it.
Who are you?
-I'm a reporter for the Times.
-Since when do reporters carry guns?
Directional mike,
telescopic zoom.
-You spooks are all the same.
-ClA?
-Please don't--
-Shut up.
How many of your friends
are out there?
Just shoot her.
You wanna live...
...you'd better find something to say.
What a silly girl.
Well, have it your way.
I'm disappointed, Jonathan.
I thought we had an agreement.
-Shit happens, you know?
-I don't give a shit.
-Get them.
-No. Nobody move.
They have seen us.
They know who we are.
They know what you're doing.
Nicholi.
Then you'd better get them.
Go. Now.
Stupid, stupid idiot.
I knew it.
Jonathan Cold.
Good to know you still have
the magic touch.
It's a shame you don't.
I mean, what was that, How to
Surrender to the Bad Guy 1 01?
You are my teacher,
O master of spook.
Apparently not.
You haven't learned a goddamn thing.
I'm in.
Get out of the way.
-Find the lever.
-What?
Shit.
Hold on.
Shit!
There are no brakes.
We're gonna have to jump.
What?
Jump.
Enjoy the ride?
Well, it's nice to be appreciated
anyway.
You want to tell me...
...what you and your new best buddies
are planning to do?
Oh, let me see.
Shoot you in the head and make
Vegas beachfront property.
Yeah. With your help.
Look, these guys have access
to the plutonium now.
You know what that means?
They could make a bomb right quick.
We don't have time for this.
I can't believe that
you are a part of this.
We work for the same people.
Just on a little different level.
You disappeared for six years.
You expect me to believe this bullshit?
Believe what you want.
I'll brief you later.
You can't just walk away, Jonathan.
-So, what do you want me to do?
-Whatever it takes.
Right now, that just means
getting out of here.
Try these.
-Where we going?
-The warehouse.
You know, back in the day,
one of the first things I taught you is:.
When you're on the run, never
go back to where you came from.
You're on the run, not me.
And I gotta find my partner.
Looks like he's been doing
his homework.
It's Macabe.
It's me.
He found him.
Yes, sir.
It's a bad day for you.
-Any idea who those Russians are?
-Well, that's a good question, isn't it?
For someone who's on the inside,
you don't know very much.
You think?
Look, why would they classify you
as a foreigner...
...if you still work with the agency?
Darling, you just need to
hang around me for a little while.
Let me get you up to speed.
You're a bit out of your league.
-Then help me understand.
-The agency...
...has four top-secret columns.
Those columns are dedicated
to doing work...
...that's probably considered by
many people to be immoral or illegal.
Nonetheless, it's stuff we have to do
in the interest...
...of the United States' security
all over the world.
I belong to one of those columns.
There's two people above me,
two people below me.
Nobody else knows about me.
Nobody but you right now.
So that means folks might try
to come and kill you.
I'm a senior agent.
Why wouldn't I know about this?
Well, what do you think
the agency's main m.o. is?
Disinformation.
That's right. What do you think the
greatest business in the world is?
-Drugs.
-And above that, there's war.
Okay, it's the same old
song and dance...
...but busting an international
arms dealer out of jail?
Placing nukes in the hands
of baby-faced fanatics?
I mean, come on.
This doesn't make any sense.
This is not exactly what you think.
I think you know me well enough
to know I couldn't have opened up...
...a coffee shop or something. So how
long you been watching these folks?
Two months.
We've been following him
since Philadelphia.
I think this is a bad idea.
It'll be worth it if Max has a lead
on the plutonium.
If it don't work, we'll
have to shoot our way out.
Fuck.
They're in.
Yes, sir.
Oh, my God.
Oh, Christ, Max.
Who did this?
Stuart, this place has been
compromised.
-We gotta get out of here.
-No.
I gotta find some information.
He left me something.
Listen to me. There's no time.
We gotta go.
I've gotta find it.
Stuart, gotta go. Now.
-Let's go.
-Just wait.
Agent Stuart.
Greer?
What are you doing here?
Pierson called me in.
-What happened here?
-Why don't you tell us.
No, don't do it.
What's he doing here?
He's helping me. Please, sir, just...
...put the gun down. I can explain.
You're lucky to be alive.
So, what exactly did Pierson dig up
that got him killed?
We're not sure.
Myshkin showed up last night
and Max and I got separated...
...and we came back here...
...and this is how we found him.
That's it?
Who's this guy down here?
Is he one of yours?
There's a leak within the agency. A
small faction is working off the grid.
We don't know why or what they're
after, but you may not be safe.
-Me?
-Look around, this was no accident.
Come on. I'll bring you in.
Debrief you on the way.
You're gonna trust him?
What the fuck are you doing?!
Go, go, go.
Move it, move it, move it.
You all right, man?
I'm good, but there's some people
up there that are no good.
Not doing too good up there.
-Did you get them yet?
-Not yet.
-But my people are on it.
-That does not sound very reassuring.
With the ClA after us,
we have to move up our time line.
I need my plutonium now.
Yeah?
You really gonna do it?
I need a place
to put this thing together.
-What kind of place?
-Metal workshop.
With a lathe and C4.
Something clean and discreet.
And we need protection.
I'm gonna need more. A lot more.
Don't you worry. We have vacuumed
half the globe for diamonds.
You will be well rewarded when
you complete your end of the deal.
Diamonds will be the only currency
worth anything for the next 1 0 years.
You will be a very rich man
in the new global economy.
Just be bloody sure I'm not here
when it goes off.
You get me my plutonium, I'll give you
1 2 hours to get out of town.
If Cold comes back, he's mine.
You just get me what I need.
I almost forgot. Again.
Mr. Macabe.
I'm sorry that it's so late.
No problem, Mr. Brown.
Everything has gone through.
The helicopter will be available
from tomorrow onward, sir.
-Okay. Thanks.
-Have a good evening.
And you.
-Yes.
-Are you alone?
Damn it, what is wrong
with using the lnternet?
Relax. Just checking in.
Do you have it?
I got one more run.
-After that, I'll have enough.
-Good. Where is it?
Well, it's not here.
-But it's safe.
-Get it ready. It's almost time.
Still broken, Mr. Brown.
Contact your seller.
-We'll be ready in four hours.
-Yeah.
Hey.
Go over my escape plan
if I were you.
Round up some men.
Get moving. We have no time.
-Can I talk to you?
-Talk.
I have a bad feeling about this.
I don't trust these men, Nicholi.
As long as we stay focused,
we'll be fine.
The timing is not right anymore.
The ClA knows what we're up to.
-Why don't we wait it out?
-There is no more waiting.
Who else wants to quit?
Nobody wants to quit, Nicholi.
But we don't want to get ourselves
killed before we push the button.
-We don't want to die like Julia.
-Julia, she sacrificed herself.
We vowed to be martyrs...
...not corpses without a cause.
There is no more time to waste.
I am finishing this.
With or without you.
Room 467, 6:.00.
Right.
Got four guys heading that way.
Plane's on the runway.
-Whenever we get there, it's ours.
-Good. Cool.
Are you ready to give up your home
to a bunch of lunatics?
Yeah.
Well...
...fuck them.
Once we get the key,
we waste them. Yeah?
-May I help you?
-Hi, I'm with the EPA.
-I have a meeting with Dr. Macabe.
-Well, Mr. Macabe's right down there.
If you hurry, you might be able
to catch him.
Thank you.
-Fuck.
-Hey, Billy.
Cold? I'd heard you were dead.
Devil didn't want me, Billy.
-Just didn't want me at all.
-Yeah, okay.
You know, I was thinking.
If you didn't wanna get found...
...you should leave the suburbs.
Yeah, well, the rent's cheap,
you know?
Listen, I was wondering if
you could do me a big favor.
Can you use all of your tricky-dicky
spooky talent that you got there?
Can you take a look
into my old company...
...check out some supervisors?
One named Greer, G-R-E-E-R,
and see what you come up with?
-That's it?
-Well, no, that's not it.
I got a few more things.
And if I do this...
...you won't kill me, right?
No, I don't kill people.
But you know what...
...I got something better for you.
Do this for me right...
...I'm gonna hook you into some
TS lntel that even you can't reach.
-A real lifesaver, you hear me?
-Okay. That's--
I'm gonna do that now.
Just give me a minute.
-Just takes a minute.
-Hey, man, I got all day.
Load up.
Follow me.
Someone's been busy.
Eastern Europe, Balkans,
Estonia, Chechnya.
On what's he been working?
Oil, gas, uranium.
He's guarding assets.
Well, he's been dark
for about two years...
...and then last year
he took over as the district chief.
Look, I need you to see if you can
check any e-mails in the last 72 hours.
Oh, yeah, sure. You mean his
personal, highly encrypted e-mails?
-ls that what you want me to do?
-Look, look. Just do it, okay?
And find out if the nearest nuclear test
facility is and if there's been any...
...cross-contamination with any
of his guys, stuff like that.
Oh, yeah. Sure. It's really--
It's very simple. Yeah. Okay.
I'll do that.
It's-- It might take me a minute.
Yeah?
All right, I'll be there.
Don't do it.
Throw the gun over there now.
-Look, I'm ClA.
-Who isn't nowadays?
Toss it.
Now.
Now where's the plutonium?
Oh, you bitch.
Son of a bitch.
Where the hell is it?
This guy's connected.
All black ops.
Chechnya, Balkans, Estonia.
Same.
Just like my old friend.
-Who else?
-Well, wait a minute, I got a hit.
Julius Macabe.
Employed eight months.
Top-level security clearance...
...plutonium disposal technician?
Yeah. Yeah, okay,
that sounds like fun.
-Yeah. What does the e-mail say?
-Look, I told you, I can't open it.
These guys are whales.
They're triple-encryption and blinds,
all sorts of shit. It would take weeks.
-I can't do it. I'm sorry.
-All right, okay. Give me an address.
All right, fine.
All right. That's about 1 0 blocks
from here.
Listen, Cold, I actually--
I got some bad news for you.
In putting together
all of these names, l--
Them showing
up in one locale like this...
...it's obvious that a cleanup team
is coming to hit you.
And these guys are-- They're the best.
Hey, wait. What about my bonus?
Get out of L.A. right away.
What the hell does that mean?
"Get out of L.A. now."
Oh, fuck me. This--
Yeah, this is Harry Brown
from Tishman.
I just wanted to check on my rental.
Very good. Thank you very much.
My man.
What's up?
Oh, excuse me.
The elevator's broken.
Yeah? May I use your phone?
Thank you.
Stairs?
It's gotta be in here.
Gotcha.
Oh, shit.
Room 667. Said he'd be here.
Who the hell are you?
Be quiet.
-Shit.
-Who the fuck is this?
He's dead.
Package is in the bathroom.
It's not here.
That's it.
-Where is it? Tell me right now.
-We can end this now if you want.
Not now, Nicholi.
You better not be
fucking with me, man.
-I kill you.
-Go ahead.
Sweep the hallway. Let's go.
Listen, if we retrieve this plutonium,
we can save the op.
You guys make it around back,
meet me in the center.
You're my team. Let's do this.
Make it right.
This isn't what it looks like.
I don't know her.
This is not--
It's not--
Hey. Check it.
Stupid bitch.
Dial 91 1, man.
-This is it.
-Where's my key?
-Where am I going?
-Sun Country Bank, San Diego.
-I wouldn't dilly-dally if I were you.
-Let's move.
Don't move.
Where's Sergey? Where's Fedor?
What happened? Nicholi, tell me.
-What's going on?
-Shut up and drive.
I thought you were dead.
-You all right?
-Yeah. Okay.
Yeah, just park it right there.
-Can you open the door, please?
-We're closed.
-Can you let me in? Please. Please.
-Let me in.
-Come on.
Please, open.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
My father's working late upstairs,
and my cell phone died.
Can you buzz him?
Please?
What's your dad's name?
Bob.
Where is the damn elevator?
Shit.
We detonate here.
So where would you detonate
a nuke if you were the Chechens?
Wherever I could inflict
maximum damage.
Listen, I found a credit card
receipt in Macabe's house.
It's for a dummy corporation
that he set up at the Vox and Billing.
-He's renting space there.
-What for?
If he rents space there, he has access
to the corporate helipad.
-And that's what you're talking about.
-Oh, yeah.
-Maximum damage.
-That's what I'm saying.
Best way to escape a small nuke
has to be in a helicopter.
It makes sense, but how did he know
they would come here?
I think there's somebody else.
Who you working?
I was supposed to be on James
and his people.
But we weren't supposed
to make a move...
...just report his whereabouts. Why?
-Who did you report to?
-Only to Greer.
There's gotta be another way
in here.
We did it.
In moments, we will be heroes.
Wouldn't want you to set that
until I'm safely out of here.
Ingenious, how you put this together.
You were a good choice, Nicholi.
Who the fuck are you?
Who do you think could
pull off a job like this?
Not you, not Aslan.
Me.
You are nobody.
I am everything to you.
You are here because
I put you here. I created Aslan.
I told him to detonate it here.
That's who I am.
You burn in hell, you pig.
-Step away from the device.
-Cold.
You don't know what you're doing.
I'm after the same ends as you.
You don't know who I work for
or who I work with.
Now step away from the device now.
Don't do anything else.
Don't move. Just do that.
You know I can still push this button
even with a bullet in me.
You're not a martyr, Greer.
You don't understand,
this has to be done.
Step away from the device now.
Check the security desk. There
should be a switch for the elevator.
-Shut it off.
-I can't.
If I touch anything,
it might go off.
So, what are we gonna do?
I just wanna get this away
from people.
I'm gonna see if I can get up
on the roof and in the chopper.
Okay, thank you very much
for everything.
-Thank you. Now get out.
-No.
Listen, it's too dangerous.
I really appreciate you coming.
See you later.
No.
Hang on.
We're probably gonna die,
aren't we?
How deep is it?
What?
How deep do you think
the water is here?
I don't know.
A thousand feet, maybe?
Well, that's good.
That's good.
I was hoping you'd say that.
All right. Open the door
and throw that bitch out.
What?
-Get it out.
-Okay.
-Do it now.
Are we gonna make it?
I wouldn't count on it.
Oh, Jesus.
Are we clear?
Well, it looks like we might be...
...but we could be glowing
in the dark for a while.
Now I just kind of wanted
to compliment you on a job well done.
Now, what do you mean by that?
Well, I mean, you did good.
We're both still alive, and you've been
a good student and a good friend.
-A friend?
-Yeah, a friend.
A friend.
First of all, I'm your colleague.
And secondly, "friend"?
After all that we've been through,
you're gonna call me a friend?
Normally when people
sleep together, they--
Look, what are you talking
about, man? Okay, okay.
All right.
Lover? Concubine?
Wizard of the three-night stand?
"Master of the three-night stand,"
that's really classy.
You know, I don't recall
there just being three nights.
Oh, whatever. You know,
as busy as I am, it's all a blur.
Now, see, I would stop there.
Because being your student...
...you taught me how to use
these chopsticks.
All right.
To friends.
I'm sorry, sir. I wasn't reachable.
Yes, sir, I am well and intact.
Well, thank you, sir,
but I was just doing my job.
The last time that I saw Cold,
he was in a helicopter with the nuke.
With all due respect, sir...
...in all my years of service
with the ClA...
...it's the most courageous act
I've ever seen.
Guess he had a change of heart.
Yeah. I'll have a report on Monday.
Sir?
The president?
Well, I would be honored.
No, sir.
Just a ticket for one.
THE END
Subtitles by: