1
00:00:39,540 --> 00:00:42,334
BLOOD OUT

2
00:00:42,335 --> 00:00:53,000
<i><font face="Vrinda" size=17>{\an2}
<b>SubText: NoRMITA.326</b></font></i>

3
00:02:11,380 --> 00:02:14,099
Got a meth lab...
explosive, highly toxic.

4
00:02:17,100 --> 00:02:19,940
Last report...eight inside,
all presumed armed and dangerous.

5
00:02:19,940 --> 00:02:21,817
Billy, Joe, you've got the back.

6
00:02:24,980 --> 00:02:26,620
Go.

7
00:02:26,620 --> 00:02:28,860
Hey, you guys wanna
play cops and robbers?

8
00:02:28,860 --> 00:02:29,895
Yeah!

9
00:02:43,780 --> 00:02:47,500
- Get down! Get down!
- Get down, everybody! Freeze!

10
00:02:47,500 --> 00:02:49,700
On the ground! Down! Clear.

11
00:02:49,700 --> 00:02:51,380
- Cops!
- Gun!

12
00:03:00,660 --> 00:03:01,900
Ohh!

13
00:03:01,900 --> 00:03:04,500
My leg! Ohh.

14
00:03:13,380 --> 00:03:15,450
Arggh!

15
00:03:43,820 --> 00:03:45,780
No, no.

16
00:03:45,780 --> 00:03:46,849
Freeze!

17
00:03:55,860 --> 00:03:57,339
No...

18
00:04:01,180 --> 00:04:03,091
Oh!

19
00:04:22,780 --> 00:04:24,338
No.

20
00:04:26,460 --> 00:04:29,980
Get me a medic now! Move it!

21
00:04:29,980 --> 00:04:32,335
Hang in there, sweetie.

22
00:04:33,340 --> 00:04:34,660
Damn you!

23
00:04:34,660 --> 00:04:36,969
Now! Move it!

24
00:04:52,300 --> 00:04:56,460
Yo, Mike, David called again
twice today. This is his number.

25
00:04:56,460 --> 00:04:59,020
Really? You know what?
I'm not interested.

26
00:04:59,020 --> 00:05:00,540
It's your brother
we're talking about, man.

27
00:05:00,540 --> 00:05:03,900
- He might be in trouble or something.
- Oh, David in trouble?

28
00:05:03,900 --> 00:05:06,060
Well, that would make
a change, wouldn't it?

29
00:05:06,060 --> 00:05:08,780
David's not in trouble.
He is trouble.

30
00:05:08,780 --> 00:05:11,089
Guys.

31
00:05:12,100 --> 00:05:15,060
Tough day today, but you did
a good job out there.

32
00:05:15,060 --> 00:05:19,180
We got a couple of guys down,
but no-one lost.

33
00:05:19,180 --> 00:05:21,180
Most importantly,
the dopers got shot down.

34
00:05:21,180 --> 00:05:23,660
You said no-one was lost.
How's the girl?

35
00:05:23,660 --> 00:05:26,970
I'm sorry. Collateral damage.

36
00:05:28,300 --> 00:05:29,900
It's just terrible.

37
00:05:29,900 --> 00:05:32,130
No-one wins in this, Michael.

38
00:05:33,980 --> 00:05:35,652
Everyone get some rest.

39
00:05:48,100 --> 00:05:50,568
Hey, give me a minute,
alright? What are you doing here?

40
00:05:52,100 --> 00:05:53,580
Can I talk to you?

41
00:05:53,580 --> 00:05:55,980
The one thing I asked you...
not to come here. One thing.

42
00:05:55,980 --> 00:05:59,660
Mike, please, man, can I just...
just for a second, please?

43
00:05:59,660 --> 00:06:02,060
What the fuck do you need?
One of your friends banged...

44
00:06:02,060 --> 00:06:04,060
- Just please...
- You need money? I can't help you.

45
00:06:04,060 --> 00:06:07,530
Could you please just come out with me
and talk with me for a second?

46
00:06:08,540 --> 00:06:10,380
Please?

47
00:06:10,380 --> 00:06:12,530
I'll see you outside.

48
00:06:39,180 --> 00:06:41,740
Hey. So what is it?

49
00:06:43,100 --> 00:06:44,580
What do you need, David?

50
00:06:44,580 --> 00:06:46,377
Look, uh...

51
00:06:47,380 --> 00:06:49,291
I'm getting out.

52
00:06:52,660 --> 00:06:56,180
How many times do you think
you can make me believe that, huh?

53
00:06:56,180 --> 00:06:57,977
I'm getting married too.

54
00:06:59,740 --> 00:07:01,860
- Look at her, man.
- Yeah, she's beautiful.

55
00:07:01,860 --> 00:07:05,091
Isn't she, though? Her name's Gloria.

56
00:07:06,220 --> 00:07:07,700
She cares about me, man.

57
00:07:07,700 --> 00:07:09,340
A lot of people cared about you, David.

58
00:07:09,340 --> 00:07:10,693
I love her, man.

59
00:07:14,300 --> 00:07:15,779
I'm gonna marry her.

60
00:07:18,460 --> 00:07:21,660
What do you want from me, huh?
What? You want my fucking blessing?

61
00:07:21,660 --> 00:07:23,780
You got it. Go marry her, do something.

62
00:07:23,780 --> 00:07:26,820
She won't marry me
unless I get out, you know?

63
00:07:26,820 --> 00:07:30,500
I can't do that alone,
blood out and all that, you know?

64
00:07:30,500 --> 00:07:32,809
Yeah, I know, more than you know.

65
00:07:37,980 --> 00:07:40,020
You're gonna give her Mom's ring?

66
00:07:40,020 --> 00:07:42,295
I am.

67
00:07:43,780 --> 00:07:45,293
Let me see that.

68
00:07:47,140 --> 00:07:48,900
Is this for real, David?

69
00:07:48,900 --> 00:07:52,460
I swear to you, man. I'm done.

70
00:07:52,460 --> 00:07:54,180
Do it for Mom, OK?

71
00:07:54,180 --> 00:07:57,500
You come stay with me, we'll get
you a job, I'll get you a place, OK?

72
00:07:57,500 --> 00:08:00,219
I gotta put up with your shit anyway.

73
00:08:02,660 --> 00:08:04,139
OK.

74
00:08:05,140 --> 00:08:07,140
I love you, man. Come here.

75
00:08:07,140 --> 00:08:08,619
I love you too, man.

76
00:08:09,620 --> 00:08:11,500
I'm not gonna let you down.
I promise, man.

77
00:08:11,500 --> 00:08:12,979
I'm not gonna let you down.

78
00:08:14,140 --> 00:08:17,735
Yo. We got a problem.

79
00:08:29,180 --> 00:08:30,818
Hey, hold up.

80
00:08:43,060 --> 00:08:47,020
- Yeah.
- Yo, kid, meet me at the spot.

81
00:08:47,020 --> 00:08:49,300
Come on, man.
Shit, can't you handle this?

82
00:08:49,300 --> 00:08:52,700
Of course I can, kid,
but Elias wants us both on this one.

83
00:08:52,700 --> 00:08:55,820
I guess there's some new crackers
he ain't vetted yet.

84
00:08:55,820 --> 00:08:57,620
It's five bills a piece.

85
00:08:57,620 --> 00:08:59,133
Five bills, huh?

86
00:09:00,140 --> 00:09:01,971
Shit.

87
00:09:03,220 --> 00:09:05,060
Just a quick pick-up and drop, right?

88
00:09:05,060 --> 00:09:07,369
That's it.

89
00:09:10,860 --> 00:09:14,460
Shit, alright. Fuck it.
Alright, I'll be there.

90
00:09:14,460 --> 00:09:16,610
Cool. See you, kid.

91
00:09:33,300 --> 00:09:36,258
- What's up, fool?
- What it is.

92
00:09:41,020 --> 00:09:42,900
So let's go. Where's this slinger at?

93
00:09:42,900 --> 00:09:44,891
Oh, fucked if I know.

94
00:09:50,300 --> 00:09:51,779
What the fuck is this?

95
00:09:54,740 --> 00:09:56,412
What the fuck is he doing here?

96
00:09:57,740 --> 00:10:00,660
We couldn't bring
ourselves to miss your funeral, bro.

97
00:10:00,660 --> 00:10:02,620
Anthony, step away.

98
00:10:02,620 --> 00:10:04,178
Step away.

99
00:10:10,700 --> 00:10:13,533
It seems like all your boys
have turned up to say goodbye.

100
00:10:14,900 --> 00:10:17,016
They don't look very sad to me.

101
00:10:18,340 --> 00:10:20,460
Well, nobody's sad when a snitch dies.

102
00:10:20,460 --> 00:10:22,580
I ain't no fucking snitch!

103
00:10:22,580 --> 00:10:26,700
So what you're saying here
is Stix over there is a liar.

104
00:10:26,700 --> 00:10:28,258
Stix?

105
00:10:30,940 --> 00:10:34,180
I seen you sucking up
to that fucking cop.

106
00:10:34,180 --> 00:10:36,180
No, he's my brother, man!

107
00:10:36,180 --> 00:10:38,410
Look, I needed his help
with something. That was it.

108
00:10:40,300 --> 00:10:43,260
I ain't no fucking pigeon, alright?

109
00:10:43,260 --> 00:10:44,898
I swear to you on that, Elias.

110
00:10:47,620 --> 00:10:51,020
I just want out, alright? That's it.

111
00:10:51,020 --> 00:10:53,860
OK, you want out?
That's it, it's done, you're out.

112
00:10:53,860 --> 00:10:57,260
Zed? It makes no difference to me.

113
00:10:57,260 --> 00:10:59,940
You're still a dead man.
You know the code.

114
00:10:59,940 --> 00:11:03,020
Look, I've been banging for you
since I was 12 years old, alright?

115
00:11:03,020 --> 00:11:04,860
I've done everything
you've ever asked of me.

116
00:11:04,860 --> 00:11:07,540
Man, I've taken care of your beef,
jacked for you, killed for you...

117
00:11:07,540 --> 00:11:09,860
everything you've ever asked of me.

118
00:11:09,860 --> 00:11:11,540
Man, my own mother died in my arms

119
00:11:11,540 --> 00:11:13,780
'cause of a bullet that was meant for me

120
00:11:13,780 --> 00:11:15,896
and I still didn't drop the flag then.

121
00:11:22,740 --> 00:11:24,380
You wanna jump out?

122
00:11:24,380 --> 00:11:26,300
Yeah.

123
00:11:26,300 --> 00:11:28,580
OK.

124
00:11:28,580 --> 00:11:32,580
You get past them boys and you go free.

125
00:11:32,580 --> 00:11:35,299
You don't, you die.

126
00:11:36,940 --> 00:11:38,980
No bullshit.

127
00:11:51,060 --> 00:11:54,820
Oh!

128
00:12:11,420 --> 00:12:12,500
Ohh!

129
00:12:31,420 --> 00:12:32,978
Are you next?

130
00:12:38,900 --> 00:12:40,731
Run, rabbit. Run!

131
00:12:57,660 --> 00:12:58,809
Blood in.

132
00:13:02,660 --> 00:13:03,979
Blood out.

133
00:13:29,340 --> 00:13:31,331
- Let me get this.
- Go ahead.

134
00:13:40,060 --> 00:13:43,860
Yeah. Hello. Uh-huh.

135
00:13:43,860 --> 00:13:46,738
Uh-huh. This is he.

136
00:13:47,740 --> 00:13:50,208
Yeah, yeah, Deputy Michael Savion.

137
00:13:53,980 --> 00:13:56,050
When...when did this happen?

138
00:13:59,100 --> 00:14:00,738
OK, I understand.

139
00:14:03,220 --> 00:14:05,370
I'll be there as soon as I can.

140
00:14:06,900 --> 00:14:09,050
You good, bro?

141
00:14:11,740 --> 00:14:13,220
It's David.

142
00:14:13,220 --> 00:14:15,500
He in trouble again?

143
00:14:15,500 --> 00:14:17,570
Yeah, it's more than that, man.

144
00:14:27,940 --> 00:14:30,500
Deputy Savion.
I got a call about my brother.

145
00:14:30,500 --> 00:14:31,980
Go through.

146
00:14:31,980 --> 00:14:34,140
You Savion?

147
00:14:34,140 --> 00:14:35,698
Uh-huh.

148
00:15:00,060 --> 00:15:02,300
Two shots, both entry, right?

149
00:15:02,300 --> 00:15:04,370
Yeah, one up close.

150
00:15:07,340 --> 00:15:09,500
Any shells?

151
00:15:09,500 --> 00:15:11,900
One in the wall right there.

152
00:15:11,900 --> 00:15:14,260
The other one's
probably underneath him.

153
00:15:14,260 --> 00:15:16,330
It looks like a.50.

154
00:15:25,460 --> 00:15:28,780
You said a .50-cal.
Are you talking about a rifle?

155
00:15:28,780 --> 00:15:34,060
No, no, no. No, it was short shells.
Probably a handgun.

156
00:15:34,060 --> 00:15:35,540
- A handgun?
- Yeah.

157
00:15:35,540 --> 00:15:37,020
You think gang-related?

158
00:15:37,020 --> 00:15:40,012
Oh, yeah, yeah, definitely gang-related.

159
00:15:41,020 --> 00:15:43,340
Look, uh...

160
00:15:43,340 --> 00:15:47,140
I just need to get your signature
here on this positive ID form

161
00:15:47,140 --> 00:15:49,180
and we can get back to work.

162
00:15:49,180 --> 00:15:51,460
You know, I'd greatly appreciate it.

163
00:15:51,460 --> 00:15:53,380
- Feathers, huh?
- Yeah, something like that.

164
00:15:53,380 --> 00:15:55,700
Yeah, yeah, yeah, feathers...
that's gang-related too.

165
00:15:55,700 --> 00:15:57,300
He's definitely a stool pigeon.

166
00:15:57,300 --> 00:15:58,900
You shitting me? Fucking listen.
Hey, hey!

167
00:15:58,900 --> 00:16:00,540
I'll tell you exactly what it is!

168
00:16:00,540 --> 00:16:02,019
I got it.

169
00:16:10,260 --> 00:16:12,620
Guess I'll get his personal effects
at the station, right?

170
00:16:12,620 --> 00:16:15,820
Yeah, yeah. Hardwick's
the lead detective.

171
00:16:15,820 --> 00:16:18,780
- Yeah, good to know.
- He'll call you in a couple of days.

172
00:16:18,780 --> 00:16:20,259
I'm sure of it.

173
00:16:28,620 --> 00:16:32,898
4..dash..861.

174
00:16:33,900 --> 00:16:35,572
What's the password?

175
00:16:36,580 --> 00:16:38,536
Thanks, bro. I owe you.

176
00:16:39,540 --> 00:16:41,019
Mike.

177
00:16:42,020 --> 00:16:43,578
What you got?

178
00:16:50,820 --> 00:16:52,580
- Gang tats, right?
- Yeah.

179
00:16:52,580 --> 00:16:54,700
You recognise any of them?

180
00:16:54,700 --> 00:16:57,168
Mm-hm, that one.

181
00:17:00,900 --> 00:17:04,660
RSAs. Aren't they the same suit
that runs out of Baltimore?

182
00:17:04,660 --> 00:17:06,537
Same gang, different set.

183
00:17:07,740 --> 00:17:12,180
OK, good. Nice work. Do a run on
the.50-cal handgun for me, will you?

184
00:17:12,180 --> 00:17:13,659
Got you.

185
00:17:39,580 --> 00:17:42,780
Hello. Hi. This is Michael Savion,
Deputy Michael Savion.

186
00:17:42,780 --> 00:17:44,500
I've called at least 15 times,
left messages.

187
00:17:44,500 --> 00:17:45,979
I've not got a single call back.

188
00:17:46,980 --> 00:17:48,460
Yeah, yeah, I understand.

189
00:17:48,460 --> 00:17:50,300
No. Excuse me.
Can you listen to me, please?

190
00:17:50,300 --> 00:17:53,220
I'm just simply trying to acquire
the status of the investigation.

191
00:17:53,220 --> 00:17:55,220
Can you please give me some information?

192
00:17:55,220 --> 00:17:56,780
But I...no, no, I...

193
00:17:56,780 --> 00:17:59,140
OK, yeah.

194
00:17:59,140 --> 00:18:00,700
Look, just tell him that Michael Savion,

195
00:18:00,700 --> 00:18:02,300
Deputy Michael Savion, called again.

196
00:18:02,300 --> 00:18:03,780
OK? Thank you.

197
00:18:38,140 --> 00:18:39,620
Excuse me.

198
00:18:39,620 --> 00:18:41,300
Oh, yeah?

199
00:18:41,300 --> 00:18:44,100
I'm looking for a Detective Hardwick.

200
00:18:44,100 --> 00:18:46,660
And what's your name?
Michael Savion.

201
00:18:46,660 --> 00:18:48,380
And what is this in reference to?

202
00:18:48,380 --> 00:18:50,060
The murder of my brother.

203
00:18:50,060 --> 00:18:52,060
OK, yeah, follow me.

204
00:18:52,060 --> 00:18:54,016
Thank you.

205
00:19:04,580 --> 00:19:06,696
Are we here?

206
00:19:08,060 --> 00:19:11,180
Whore was dumb enough to offer me
a blow job to let her go.

207
00:19:11,180 --> 00:19:14,300
- Well, what did you do?
- I let her suck my dick.

208
00:19:14,300 --> 00:19:15,620
Oh, man.

209
00:19:15,620 --> 00:19:18,100
Then I busted her for
attempting to bribe an officer.

210
00:19:18,100 --> 00:19:20,740
- That's ballsy.
- What?

211
00:19:20,740 --> 00:19:23,740
She swallowed the evidence.

212
00:19:23,740 --> 00:19:26,620
Hey, guys, who's Hardwick?

213
00:19:26,620 --> 00:19:28,258
Right there.

214
00:19:30,740 --> 00:19:32,740
I'm Hardwick.

215
00:19:32,740 --> 00:19:34,540
Why you so uptight?

216
00:19:34,540 --> 00:19:37,940
Deputy Savion. I've been calling you.
Hammond Sheriff's Department.

217
00:19:37,940 --> 00:19:39,460
Oh, yeah. Savion, right.

218
00:19:39,460 --> 00:19:41,740
Sorry I didn't get back to you.
I've been real busy.

219
00:19:41,740 --> 00:19:43,580
Yeah, I see that.

220
00:19:43,580 --> 00:19:46,460
You wanted to know about that banger
that got whacked a week ago, right?

221
00:19:46,460 --> 00:19:48,820
You mean my brother, right?
My brother who was murdered?

222
00:19:48,820 --> 00:19:50,540
Any leads? Anyone in custody?

223
00:19:50,540 --> 00:19:53,020
Best we could figure
was a member of a rival gang.

224
00:19:53,020 --> 00:19:56,020
Right. It's taken you, what,
a week to work that out?

225
00:19:56,020 --> 00:19:58,380
The case has been filed 'Unsolved', OK?

226
00:19:58,380 --> 00:20:00,860
What are you talking about?
You closed this?

227
00:20:00,860 --> 00:20:03,420
He was shot in the fucking back
by a.50-cal handgun.

228
00:20:03,420 --> 00:20:05,540
There's, what,
like, four in the fucking state?

229
00:20:05,540 --> 00:20:07,849
How hard is that to trace, guys?

230
00:20:10,860 --> 00:20:13,740
Look, sorry to hear
about your brother, alright?

231
00:20:13,740 --> 00:20:15,220
- Really?
- Really.

232
00:20:15,220 --> 00:20:18,380
But you probably know better than I do
what he was up to.

233
00:20:18,380 --> 00:20:20,780
A lifetime banger, slinging drugs
on the streets for years.

234
00:20:20,780 --> 00:20:24,260
Yeah, I knew what he was doing.
My brother, though, you know?

235
00:20:24,260 --> 00:20:26,780
Yeah, well, we look at it
like a problem solved, alright?

236
00:20:26,780 --> 00:20:29,020
Another low-life thug off the streets.

237
00:20:29,020 --> 00:20:32,540
Now, I don't know how you boys
handle things down in Mayberry,

238
00:20:32,540 --> 00:20:34,420
but here we don't lose sleep

239
00:20:34,420 --> 00:20:36,650
when the bad guys
do the dirty work for us.

240
00:20:39,740 --> 00:20:41,780
All of you,

241
00:20:41,780 --> 00:20:43,259
you're a fucking disgrace.

242
00:20:44,260 --> 00:20:47,172
- Disgrace?
- Fuck! Oh!

243
00:20:57,940 --> 00:21:00,180
What the fuck are you
doing to me? To a cop?

244
00:21:00,180 --> 00:21:02,569
Oh! Arggh!

245
00:21:07,020 --> 00:21:09,056
- Tough guy.
- Arggh!

246
00:21:17,700 --> 00:21:21,579
He waltzes in here...where the fuck
he think he at? Kansas?

247
00:21:31,300 --> 00:21:33,291
Savion.

248
00:21:34,620 --> 00:21:39,569
Whew! It's hot in here. You alright?

249
00:21:40,940 --> 00:21:42,498
Yeah.

250
00:21:43,900 --> 00:21:45,380
I'm gonna hold on to these

251
00:21:45,380 --> 00:21:48,372
till your sheriff in your
podunk town call for it.

252
00:21:49,500 --> 00:21:51,820
And I personally wanna thank you

253
00:21:51,820 --> 00:21:55,699
for staying here at
Hotel Central Lockup.

254
00:21:56,700 --> 00:21:58,820
- They look good on you, man.
- Yeah.

255
00:21:58,820 --> 00:22:00,300
But do come again.

256
00:22:00,300 --> 00:22:02,940
We'll always have this suite here
available for you personally.

257
00:22:02,940 --> 00:22:04,419
Yeah, I'll be back.

258
00:22:06,980 --> 00:22:10,768
You had your fun, you had a good time.

259
00:22:23,580 --> 00:22:26,333
You're a fucking joke, you know that?

260
00:22:33,780 --> 00:22:36,900
Fuck you very much,
Officer Sayvion...Savion,

261
00:22:36,900 --> 00:22:38,936
whatever the fuck your name is.

262
00:22:41,780 --> 00:22:43,260
- What about work?
- You kidding me?

263
00:22:43,260 --> 00:22:45,740
Still think I got a job
after what went down in there?

264
00:22:45,740 --> 00:22:46,600
That's not true, man.

265
00:22:46,700 --> 00:22:49,250
They'll probably just put you on a desk
till they get this sorted.

266
00:22:49,350 --> 00:22:52,380
You're probably right.
Can you imagine me behind a desk?

267
00:22:52,380 --> 00:22:53,980
- No.
- Yeah, me neither.

268
00:22:53,980 --> 00:22:55,460
I'll call you, man.

269
00:22:55,460 --> 00:22:58,736
Hey, Mike, I did
some more snooping around.

270
00:22:59,740 --> 00:23:02,420
- What you get?
- Something's really weird.

271
00:23:02,420 --> 00:23:03,900
It smells like somebody high up

272
00:23:03,900 --> 00:23:06,700
is taking control on a local
or even state level.

273
00:23:06,700 --> 00:23:08,816
- Are you kidding me?
- No.

274
00:23:10,340 --> 00:23:12,340
That's bullshit.

275
00:23:12,340 --> 00:23:15,700
This prick in here's got my gun
and my badge. Can you go get it?

276
00:23:15,700 --> 00:23:18,060
- I got you, brother.
- Alright. I'll call you, man.

277
00:23:18,060 --> 00:23:19,539
OK.

278
00:23:32,740 --> 00:23:35,700
This is unit 17. I have
a possible 4-2 in progress.

279
00:23:35,700 --> 00:23:37,940
Male suspect is on foot.

280
00:23:37,940 --> 00:23:41,780
3200 Black Oakland Avenue.
In pursuit now.

281
00:23:41,780 --> 00:23:45,540
Unit 17. stand down.
You are outside your jurisdiction.

282
00:23:45,540 --> 00:23:47,974
Unit 17. stand down.

283
00:24:02,820 --> 00:24:05,380
We look at it like
a problem solved, alright?

284
00:24:06,820 --> 00:24:09,892
We don't lose sleep when the bad guys
do the dirty work for us.

285
00:24:14,860 --> 00:24:17,060
Yeah, feathers...
that's gang related too.

286
00:24:17,060 --> 00:24:19,420
He's definitely a stool pigeon.

287
00:24:19,420 --> 00:24:23,811
We don't lose sleep when the bad guys
do the dirty work for us.

288
00:24:35,980 --> 00:24:38,060
He's definitely a stool pigeon.

289
00:25:40,660 --> 00:25:42,180
Can I help ya?

290
00:25:42,180 --> 00:25:45,172
Yeah, I need some work done.

291
00:25:46,700 --> 00:25:48,580
What are you looking for?

292
00:25:48,580 --> 00:25:51,140
Sleeves, front, back, all of it.

293
00:25:52,140 --> 00:25:54,813
Start it off with this.

294
00:25:56,700 --> 00:25:58,179
Right here.

295
00:25:59,780 --> 00:26:01,532
Oi.

296
00:26:06,540 --> 00:26:08,690
I don't know, bro.
Do you know what this is?

297
00:26:10,180 --> 00:26:11,500
Mm-hm.

298
00:26:11,500 --> 00:26:13,377
No.

299
00:26:18,340 --> 00:26:20,979
I suppose I could put two guys on you.

300
00:26:21,980 --> 00:26:23,777
Of course you can.

301
00:26:28,340 --> 00:26:30,500
This goes nowhere.

302
00:26:30,500 --> 00:26:33,900
I think we could work something out.

303
00:26:33,900 --> 00:26:35,618
When do you want to get started?

304
00:26:36,980 --> 00:26:38,459
Right now.

305
00:27:21,180 --> 00:27:22,693
Yeah, I like it.

306
00:27:23,740 --> 00:27:25,740
OK.

307
00:27:25,740 --> 00:27:27,420
I'll take it.

308
00:27:27,420 --> 00:27:31,460
Great. Rent's due on the 1st,
late on the 5th.

309
00:27:31,460 --> 00:27:33,496
But I need first and last month now.

310
00:27:35,660 --> 00:27:37,900
Should cover the first six.
What do you think?

311
00:27:37,900 --> 00:27:41,609
Mm. I like you already.

312
00:27:44,380 --> 00:27:48,300
If you need anything, anything at all,

313
00:27:48,300 --> 00:27:50,020
I'll be right down the hall.

314
00:27:50,020 --> 00:27:51,692
I'll bear that in mind.

315
00:28:26,740 --> 00:28:28,298
Yo, white boy.

316
00:28:39,860 --> 00:28:41,860
What's a fucking Assassin
doing on Indigo's turf?

317
00:28:41,860 --> 00:28:43,820
It's your turf, right?

318
00:28:43,820 --> 00:28:45,180
Fucking right it is.

319
00:28:45,180 --> 00:28:47,660
To me, that street looked like
it belonged to hookers and drunks.

320
00:28:47,660 --> 00:28:49,696
That's a lot of shit
you might wanna clean up.

321
00:28:51,220 --> 00:28:53,540
What do you got? That's it?

322
00:28:53,540 --> 00:28:55,496
That's it. That's all you got?

323
00:29:23,100 --> 00:29:25,820
I'm gonna get you, white boy.
You motherfucker!

324
00:29:25,820 --> 00:29:28,020
You won't get a chance, motherfucker.

325
00:30:12,620 --> 00:30:15,293
- Oh!
- Ooh!

326
00:30:16,300 --> 00:30:18,211
Stand up!

327
00:30:19,940 --> 00:30:21,737
Do you think this is funny?

328
00:30:24,700 --> 00:30:26,611
Where do you want me to hit your sister?

329
00:30:33,540 --> 00:30:35,540
Ohh!

330
00:30:35,540 --> 00:30:37,019
There.

331
00:30:38,020 --> 00:30:39,533
Oh!

332
00:31:02,100 --> 00:31:06,412
Will somebody get the fucking door?

333
00:31:07,420 --> 00:31:08,933
Ohh!

334
00:31:49,500 --> 00:31:52,100
So how about you, Squat?

335
00:31:52,100 --> 00:31:54,136
Do you think you're a match
for Miss Bellona?

336
00:32:00,460 --> 00:32:04,460
There's someone new in town,
an Assassin. Not our set.

337
00:32:04,460 --> 00:32:06,980
Yo, he took out four Indigos by himself.

338
00:32:06,980 --> 00:32:12,054
He took out four Indigos
by himself? Impressive.

339
00:32:13,260 --> 00:32:16,380
No piece, no weapons, no tools, nothing?

340
00:32:16,380 --> 00:32:18,371
He even took their gear
when he was done.

341
00:32:19,900 --> 00:32:21,500
Nice touch.

342
00:32:21,500 --> 00:32:24,697
- You sure it was our ink?
- No doubt.

343
00:32:36,940 --> 00:32:40,171
OK, go find him.

344
00:32:41,180 --> 00:32:45,731
If he wants to tip up,
then see if he'll blast a cop.

345
00:32:47,820 --> 00:32:49,299
Go.

346
00:32:53,700 --> 00:32:57,300
And, Anthony, remember...

347
00:32:57,300 --> 00:33:00,133
we cut off the heads
of those that don't bow.

348
00:33:01,140 --> 00:33:02,700
Yes, boss.

349
00:33:09,420 --> 00:33:11,500
- It's Billy.
- Hey, it's Michael.

350
00:33:11,500 --> 00:33:13,580
Man, where the hell you been, bro?

351
00:33:13,580 --> 00:33:16,780
I, uh, need your help.

352
00:33:16,780 --> 00:33:20,460
Can...can you do a crosscheck on Elias
and the Red Stick Assassins?

353
00:33:20,460 --> 00:33:23,340
You OK? Shit, you sound terrible.

354
00:33:23,340 --> 00:33:26,140
I don't have time
to explain any of that.

355
00:33:26,140 --> 00:33:28,780
I just need...can you do
the crosscheck, Billy?

356
00:33:28,780 --> 00:33:30,260
I got you, brother.

357
00:33:30,260 --> 00:33:33,180
I'll check the system for you,
but how do I get back to you?

358
00:33:33,180 --> 00:33:35,980
Not a good idea. I'll call you
same time tomorrow, OK?

359
00:33:35,980 --> 00:33:37,460
OK, not a problem.

360
00:33:37,460 --> 00:33:40,500
Mike, be careful, man.

361
00:33:40,500 --> 00:33:43,298
OK, yeah. Later, man.

362
00:33:55,020 --> 00:33:58,569
Yo, cuz. You wanna go
take care of some business?

363
00:34:22,380 --> 00:34:26,940
Well, you know what to do.
Make us proud.

364
00:34:26,940 --> 00:34:29,380
Mm-hm, I'll be right back.

365
00:34:36,940 --> 00:34:38,980
This is kind of
fucking dangerous, right?

366
00:34:38,980 --> 00:34:40,857
Hanging out at a fucking cop shop.

367
00:34:52,420 --> 00:34:54,934
What the fuck is he
waiting for, man? Come on!

368
00:34:55,940 --> 00:34:57,498
Hey, you need a hand with that?

369
00:34:59,820 --> 00:35:00,935
Oh, fuck!

370
00:35:02,100 --> 00:35:05,460
Holy shit! Yo, that was Hardwick, bro.

371
00:35:05,460 --> 00:35:08,213
Yeah, it was, or what's left of him.

372
00:35:09,940 --> 00:35:12,660
Fuck you very much, Detective Hardwick.

373
00:35:12,660 --> 00:35:14,940
Fucking asshole.

374
00:35:14,940 --> 00:35:17,408
Oh, shit! Holy shit!

375
00:35:18,940 --> 00:35:20,940
- Let's go. Get back in the car.
- You like that?

376
00:35:20,940 --> 00:35:24,489
- Let's get the fuck out of here.
- He had it coming. You got my drink?

377
00:35:51,460 --> 00:35:53,660
Who was that for?

378
00:35:53,660 --> 00:35:56,380
Homeboy D-Day.

379
00:35:56,380 --> 00:36:00,020
- Fuck that snitch!
- Shut the fuck up, Squat.

380
00:36:00,020 --> 00:36:02,780
You know as well as I do
fucking D-Day was no snitch.

381
00:36:02,780 --> 00:36:07,500
Yeah? Then why the fuck did Zed
make us do what we did then, huh?

382
00:36:07,500 --> 00:36:09,092
'Cause Zed's a fucking animal.
That's why.

383
00:36:10,100 --> 00:36:14,298
David wanted out, man. That was it.
He was getting married and shit.

384
00:36:17,420 --> 00:36:19,500
You said 'Zed', right?

385
00:36:19,500 --> 00:36:24,130
He's Zed, the big cheese, Elias's boss.

386
00:36:25,500 --> 00:36:27,820
You're EC. I thought you would know Zed.

387
00:36:27,820 --> 00:36:29,651
Yeah, I know exactly who he is.

388
00:36:30,740 --> 00:36:33,732
I just didn't know he was down here
taking care of a snitch.

389
00:36:36,780 --> 00:36:38,900
Anyway...

390
00:36:38,900 --> 00:36:41,130
Elias wants to meet you.

391
00:36:42,140 --> 00:36:44,700
So let's go see him.

392
00:38:12,700 --> 00:38:15,772
- You like her?
- Are you kidding me?

393
00:38:18,660 --> 00:38:20,139
Sit.

394
00:38:26,060 --> 00:38:30,980
My boys tell me that you have,
uh, some serious banging skills.

395
00:38:30,980 --> 00:38:32,459
Is that right?

396
00:38:33,940 --> 00:38:35,976
He tore it up at the cop shop, boss.

397
00:38:37,300 --> 00:38:41,498
So tell me...what brings you
to Jigga City?

398
00:38:42,500 --> 00:38:44,860
I wasn't going back in.

399
00:38:44,860 --> 00:38:46,620
The Assassins...I knew they were here.

400
00:38:46,620 --> 00:38:48,300
And what about your boys?

401
00:38:48,300 --> 00:38:50,420
Man, I was on cold storage.

402
00:38:50,420 --> 00:38:53,696
By the time I gated, my EC boys
are either dead or locked up.

403
00:38:58,700 --> 00:39:00,180
Which boys?

404
00:39:00,180 --> 00:39:04,260
G-Ray, Smokes, DC Dog...all dead.

405
00:39:04,260 --> 00:39:08,580
Little Mac, B-Bad...still in prison.

406
00:39:08,580 --> 00:39:10,377
Hoodwink and Lemworth.

407
00:39:12,900 --> 00:39:14,580
How did Hoodwink get his name?

408
00:39:14,580 --> 00:39:16,140
You know that.

409
00:39:16,140 --> 00:39:19,060
Eye socket smashed in
while he was jumping in.

410
00:39:19,060 --> 00:39:21,180
By me.

411
00:39:21,180 --> 00:39:24,570
And you, what's your G name?

412
00:39:25,580 --> 00:39:27,252
Snake.

413
00:39:28,260 --> 00:39:30,455
Snake?

414
00:39:33,940 --> 00:39:37,774
OK, Mr Snake.

415
00:39:40,940 --> 00:39:45,340
Welcome to your new set,
Red Stick Assassins.

416
00:39:45,340 --> 00:39:47,058
Consider yourself blessed in.

417
00:39:48,940 --> 00:39:51,898
But you have to work
a little harder for your set.

418
00:39:52,900 --> 00:39:55,820
Just a tiny little test.

419
00:39:55,820 --> 00:39:57,340
What the fuck is the test?

420
00:39:57,340 --> 00:40:01,700
A test to be a true Essex man.

421
00:40:01,700 --> 00:40:03,660
We have a date with the BRG

422
00:40:03,660 --> 00:40:08,256
and you, Mr Snake,
are gonna be our head-buster.

423
00:40:10,660 --> 00:40:12,140
OK.

424
00:40:12,140 --> 00:40:13,619
Good.

425
00:40:15,180 --> 00:40:17,136
Let's celebrate.

426
00:40:19,420 --> 00:40:20,899
No, I'm good.

427
00:40:21,900 --> 00:40:24,740
He's good.

428
00:40:24,740 --> 00:40:26,332
He's good.

429
00:41:32,180 --> 00:41:35,980
You may be a warrior,

430
00:41:35,980 --> 00:41:40,060
but the throne belongs to him

431
00:41:40,060 --> 00:41:43,973
who has the courage to sit on it.

432
00:41:48,660 --> 00:41:52,175
Ain't that the fucking truth,
hey, right?

433
00:41:54,700 --> 00:41:57,740
You keep doing what you're doing

434
00:41:57,740 --> 00:42:04,020
and me and you're gonna be highrolling
very soon, my brother.

435
00:42:04,020 --> 00:42:06,060
Very soon, very soon.

436
00:42:06,060 --> 00:42:07,700
- That's the fucking plan, right?
- Yeah.

437
00:42:07,700 --> 00:42:10,060
- That's the fucking plan. Hey.
- Here.

438
00:42:10,060 --> 00:42:12,096
- Stay out of trouble.
- Alright.

439
00:42:43,380 --> 00:42:45,416
What's up, ladies?

440
00:42:46,420 --> 00:42:48,100
Man, who the fuck is you?

441
00:42:48,100 --> 00:42:51,020
I'm the reaper, baby,

442
00:42:51,020 --> 00:42:53,500
and Death is with me.

443
00:43:38,660 --> 00:43:41,299
Forgot how fucking fun this was.

444
00:43:58,900 --> 00:44:01,860
Please, sir, could you spare
some change?

445
00:44:01,860 --> 00:44:05,020
No, we got nothing for you, sweetheart.
Keep on moving.

446
00:44:05,020 --> 00:44:07,170
Hey, lady, come here.

447
00:44:08,460 --> 00:44:10,620
Here, take it.

448
00:44:10,620 --> 00:44:12,099
Yours.

449
00:44:17,580 --> 00:44:19,411
God bless you.

450
00:44:22,980 --> 00:44:24,980
What the fuck are you doing?

451
00:44:24,980 --> 00:44:27,660
She needs it more than I do.

452
00:44:27,660 --> 00:44:30,700
Yeah, but...you got nobody else better
to give it to?

453
00:44:30,700 --> 00:44:32,300
Yeah, like who?

454
00:44:32,300 --> 00:44:33,938
I don't know. Your momma?

455
00:44:36,220 --> 00:44:40,133
No, she got killed by a drive-by
when I was a kid, you know.

456
00:44:41,420 --> 00:44:43,092
She have any other babies?

457
00:44:45,580 --> 00:44:47,059
Yeah, kid brother.

458
00:44:49,220 --> 00:44:50,733
Died banging.

459
00:44:54,300 --> 00:44:56,500
What about you?

460
00:44:56,500 --> 00:44:58,060
Sister.

461
00:44:58,060 --> 00:45:00,500
She cool?

462
00:45:00,500 --> 00:45:03,180
No. She's a fucking mess.

463
00:45:03,180 --> 00:45:06,490
Pregnant, strung-out,
pain in my fucking ass.

464
00:45:07,900 --> 00:45:10,020
You gotta love her, though, right?

465
00:45:10,020 --> 00:45:12,420
So they keep telling me.

466
00:45:12,420 --> 00:45:13,899
Way to go.

467
00:45:17,060 --> 00:45:18,209
GUN!

468
00:45:26,300 --> 00:45:27,780
You hit?

469
00:45:27,780 --> 00:45:30,060
You?

470
00:45:30,060 --> 00:45:31,778
No.

471
00:45:34,580 --> 00:45:36,650
Fuck this.

472
00:45:50,500 --> 00:45:53,219
That is unacceptable.

473
00:45:58,220 --> 00:46:03,420
If you get any resistance,
correct it by any means necessary.

474
00:46:03,420 --> 00:46:04,694
Exactly.

475
00:46:06,100 --> 00:46:08,540
Now the summit.

476
00:46:08,540 --> 00:46:10,451
Tell me about the American.

477
00:46:12,380 --> 00:46:17,460
"He's a newcomer"...
that's your...reconnaissance?

478
00:46:17,460 --> 00:46:21,260
Find out everything you can
about this man.

479
00:46:21,260 --> 00:46:25,094
We have very little...time.

480
00:46:26,780 --> 00:46:30,140
Contact our friend at the ministry.

481
00:46:30,140 --> 00:46:32,260
Have him drop the papers
we spoke about.

482
00:46:32,260 --> 00:46:35,536
I don't care what it costs. Do it.

483
00:46:37,140 --> 00:46:38,129
Dance!

484
00:46:39,340 --> 00:46:41,900
Well, aren't you a picture
of prenatal fucking health?

485
00:46:41,900 --> 00:46:43,940
Look, I just need a little, OK?

486
00:46:43,940 --> 00:46:46,940
Probably, if you just give me a little,
I'll be fine, OK?

487
00:46:46,940 --> 00:46:48,820
I don't know
what you're fucking talking about.

488
00:46:48,820 --> 00:46:50,820
- Never gonna happen!
- I know you sell this shit!

489
00:46:50,820 --> 00:46:53,220
I know you sell this shit, alright?!
Just give me some fucking...

490
00:46:53,220 --> 00:46:54,780
Don't you fucking touch me! Just...

491
00:46:54,780 --> 00:46:56,700
Listen to me. Listen to me. Come here.

492
00:46:56,700 --> 00:46:59,380
See this? See this?

493
00:46:59,380 --> 00:47:01,460
- You're fucking pregnant!
- Fuck you!

494
00:47:01,460 --> 00:47:05,780
Listen, if you don't wanna do it
for yourself, do it for the baby.

495
00:47:05,780 --> 00:47:09,740
I am not gonna help you fucking
kill yourself. Do you understand me?

496
00:47:09,740 --> 00:47:11,220
Fuck you, OK?!

497
00:47:11,220 --> 00:47:15,259
I will go suck a dick
if you won't give me none.

498
00:47:16,300 --> 00:47:18,768
Fuck you. Fuck you!

499
00:47:30,100 --> 00:47:32,136
You're gonna give her Mom's ring?

500
00:47:41,860 --> 00:47:43,500
What's up, big dawg?

501
00:47:43,500 --> 00:47:46,094
Let's go bang this, man.
Go blast them fools.

502
00:47:49,660 --> 00:47:51,380
Sister?

503
00:47:51,380 --> 00:47:52,893
Yes, it is.

504
00:47:54,180 --> 00:47:57,100
- You guys always go at it like that?
- These days, yes.

505
00:47:57,100 --> 00:47:58,820
Yo, come on, y'all, man!

506
00:47:58,820 --> 00:48:00,540
I wanna ram
them mother-fuckers up tonight!

507
00:48:00,540 --> 00:48:03,340
Fuck me, Squat.
You got some energy in you.

508
00:48:03,340 --> 00:48:06,100
Yeah, well, Elias says we gotta bounce.

509
00:48:06,100 --> 00:48:08,933
Wants to get his new general
to the game.

510
00:48:33,860 --> 00:48:38,934
Michael, Anthony here tells me
of all your good deeds.

511
00:48:40,140 --> 00:48:43,496
Everyone...bear witness.

512
00:48:44,820 --> 00:48:48,020
You, Michael, are now my general.

513
00:48:48,020 --> 00:48:50,540
What the fuck is a general?

514
00:48:50,540 --> 00:48:53,338
He's been locked up a for a while.

515
00:48:54,780 --> 00:49:00,780
Michael, the world sees us
as nothing but thugs...

516
00:49:00,780 --> 00:49:03,740
street rats, urchins...

517
00:49:03,740 --> 00:49:05,580
as Lucifer does.

518
00:49:05,580 --> 00:49:07,980
We have the world fooled.

519
00:49:07,980 --> 00:49:11,340
Cops are numb,
and our business has expanded.

520
00:49:11,340 --> 00:49:12,940
Sounds like a good thing.

521
00:49:12,940 --> 00:49:18,300
Like the cogs on a wheel,
we build our machine piece by piece.

522
00:49:18,300 --> 00:49:22,260
It's not a problem. We just, uh...
we go recruit more bangers, right?

523
00:49:22,260 --> 00:49:25,060
We get the baddest mother-fuckers
in the world.

524
00:49:25,060 --> 00:49:27,140
It's not like the marines.

525
00:49:27,140 --> 00:49:28,900
It's like the Mayans.

526
00:49:28,900 --> 00:49:31,220
We conquer a tribe, they bang for us.

527
00:49:31,220 --> 00:49:32,740
They're not us.

528
00:49:32,740 --> 00:49:34,260
Doesn't matter.

529
00:49:34,260 --> 00:49:36,660
They're warriors.

530
00:49:36,660 --> 00:49:40,016
How do you think a 13th Street boy
became an Assassin?

531
00:49:41,980 --> 00:49:45,620
And if they won't roll,
Elias jets them to another set.

532
00:49:45,620 --> 00:49:47,220
Fair enough.

533
00:49:47,220 --> 00:49:48,700
They're soldiers.

534
00:49:48,700 --> 00:49:52,978
They know nothing
but thugging, fighting and fucking.

535
00:49:54,180 --> 00:49:56,020
It takes a man like you...

536
00:49:56,020 --> 00:49:58,580
to become a general.

537
00:49:58,580 --> 00:50:00,700
We get paid handsomely...

538
00:50:00,700 --> 00:50:02,540
the world needs us...

539
00:50:02,540 --> 00:50:04,576
and we need the paper.

540
00:50:20,460 --> 00:50:23,020
I'll be watching you tonight.

541
00:50:23,020 --> 00:50:25,739
Just to see how good you really are.

542
00:50:31,900 --> 00:50:35,210
- Kelvin Martin.
- Yeah, I know who he is.

543
00:50:37,620 --> 00:50:39,292
I knew him.

544
00:50:44,340 --> 00:50:46,500
You guys are tied in with the cops?

545
00:50:46,500 --> 00:50:49,492
Wouldn't exactly call Hardwick a cop.

546
00:50:51,180 --> 00:50:53,220
We want Martin.

547
00:50:53,220 --> 00:50:55,260
Anything else, my friend...

548
00:50:55,260 --> 00:50:57,410
is a bonus.

549
00:51:00,900 --> 00:51:03,016
Let's go catch us a tribe.

550
00:51:04,100 --> 00:51:05,579
I'm in.

551
00:51:23,340 --> 00:51:28,300
Look, first thing we gotta do,
make sure they don't have eyes.

552
00:51:28,300 --> 00:51:30,131
You two, go check the corners.
Get back quick.

553
00:51:31,180 --> 00:51:33,140
We get in there, we move fast.

554
00:51:33,140 --> 00:51:36,100
Don't give 'em any chances, OK?
You got it?

555
00:51:36,100 --> 00:51:37,579
Let's do it.

556
00:51:59,420 --> 00:52:01,980
- What's up, mother-fucker?!
- Yeah, don't fucking move!

557
00:52:01,980 --> 00:52:03,860
Yeah, sit your fucking ass right there!

558
00:52:03,860 --> 00:52:05,700
I wish you would, huh? Yeah.

559
00:52:05,700 --> 00:52:08,460
- Get your hands where I can see them!
- RUN!

560
00:52:08,460 --> 00:52:09,580
Arggh!

561
00:52:09,580 --> 00:52:11,220
Don't even fucking think about it.

562
00:52:11,220 --> 00:52:14,257
Keep those fucking hands
where I can see them. Stay there.

563
00:52:15,340 --> 00:52:17,092
Anthony, we got a rabbit.

564
00:52:26,060 --> 00:52:28,140
No!

565
00:52:28,140 --> 00:52:30,176
Come back here!

566
00:52:47,220 --> 00:52:48,900
Fuck you up, man!

567
00:52:48,900 --> 00:52:51,414
Hey, Squat. I got it.

568
00:52:54,700 --> 00:52:56,420
You Kelvin?

569
00:52:56,420 --> 00:52:59,780
You wanna come check my ID, huh?
Come check my ID.

570
00:52:59,780 --> 00:53:01,780
It's in my back pocket.

571
00:53:12,860 --> 00:53:14,498
Ugh!

572
00:53:18,980 --> 00:53:20,698
Ugh!

573
00:53:30,580 --> 00:53:31,729
Oh!

574
00:53:52,900 --> 00:53:57,496
Hey, Kelvin, just so you know, from now
on, you belong to the Assassins, OK?

575
00:54:08,020 --> 00:54:09,817
You made it.

576
00:54:11,260 --> 00:54:13,380
What, you had doubts?

577
00:54:13,380 --> 00:54:15,257
Hmm, maybe.

578
00:54:26,020 --> 00:54:28,454
I'm warrior blood. You risk death.

579
00:54:30,460 --> 00:54:32,815
Shit, then I guess I'm dead, huh?

580
00:54:38,020 --> 00:54:39,900
I'm only slightly dramatic.

581
00:54:39,900 --> 00:54:41,780
No, you're not.

582
00:54:41,780 --> 00:54:43,660
But you are elusive.

583
00:54:43,660 --> 00:54:45,780
Yes, I am.

584
00:54:45,780 --> 00:54:50,140
I am elusive because I do not put
expectations on other people.

585
00:54:50,140 --> 00:54:53,610
That way I do not get let down.

586
00:54:54,620 --> 00:54:56,660
You learn a few things

587
00:54:56,660 --> 00:54:58,740
when you've been screwed over
as much as I have.

588
00:54:58,740 --> 00:55:00,571
Things change, right?

589
00:55:02,380 --> 00:55:05,180
From now on, I'm around.

590
00:55:05,180 --> 00:55:06,820
Oh, really?

591
00:55:06,820 --> 00:55:09,050
And who are you?

592
00:55:10,380 --> 00:55:12,620
And, more importantly, why are you here?

593
00:55:12,620 --> 00:55:14,660
Why?

594
00:55:14,660 --> 00:55:17,300
You waltz in here like you're
king of the fucking world.

595
00:55:17,300 --> 00:55:20,180
I mean, Elias is trying to
figure out a way to adopt you.

596
00:55:20,180 --> 00:55:22,340
- And on top of that, you...
- Hey, hey, hang on.

597
00:55:22,340 --> 00:55:24,058
Maybe, uh...

598
00:55:25,380 --> 00:55:27,700
Maybe it's not that complicated.

599
00:55:27,700 --> 00:55:29,420
Maybe, you know, you and I...

600
00:55:29,420 --> 00:55:31,780
you and I are just here
because we're here.

601
00:55:31,780 --> 00:55:33,850
What do you think?

602
00:55:59,820 --> 00:56:02,493
Oh! Oh.

603
00:56:50,660 --> 00:56:52,060
Hey, Billy.

604
00:56:52,060 --> 00:56:54,660
Mike. Man, how are you?

605
00:56:54,660 --> 00:56:56,940
- Where are you?
- You don't wanna know.

606
00:56:56,940 --> 00:56:58,420
What d'you find?

607
00:56:58,420 --> 00:57:01,060
Well, when I searched
the national database for RSA

608
00:57:01,060 --> 00:57:02,700
and I cross-referenced Elias,

609
00:57:03,010 --> 00:57:05,100
it's pretty obvious
the Feds are all over this gang.

610
00:57:05,100 --> 00:57:08,092
It's on the FBI's national task
force list as well.

611
00:57:09,820 --> 00:57:12,540
Mike? Mike, are you there?

612
00:57:12,540 --> 00:57:14,900
Yeah, yeah, I'm here. Fucking Feds.

613
00:57:14,900 --> 00:57:16,420
Damn.

614
00:57:16,420 --> 00:57:19,940
I guess, you know, sometimes, a man's
gotta do what a man's gotta do, right?

615
00:57:19,940 --> 00:57:22,060
Look, man, this shit is bigger than you.

616
00:57:22,060 --> 00:57:24,980
I know what you're trying to do
and I really understand it.

617
00:57:24,980 --> 00:57:27,140
But if I were you, I'd just let it go.

618
00:57:27,140 --> 00:57:29,500
I mean, look at David.
You knew the life he lived.

619
00:57:29,500 --> 00:57:32,340
And if you're thinking about
doing some vigilante-type shit,

620
00:57:32,340 --> 00:57:33,820
you might not get away with it.

621
00:57:33,820 --> 00:57:36,980
Don't have a choice, Billy.
I gotta take care of this.

622
00:57:36,980 --> 00:57:41,540
Michael, make no mistake about it.
With a badge, it's justice served.

623
00:57:41,540 --> 00:57:45,380
Without a badge, it's murder.
It's like this, man.

624
00:57:45,380 --> 00:57:47,500
Why don't you just tell me
where you are,

625
00:57:47,500 --> 00:57:50,140
so if you need any help,
I can be johnny-on-the-spot?

626
00:57:50,140 --> 00:57:51,900
Thanks for caring, man.

627
00:57:51,900 --> 00:57:54,733
Gotta keep you clean.
You're in deep enough.

628
00:57:56,300 --> 00:57:58,097
Take care, Billy.

629
00:58:00,980 --> 00:58:02,732
Shit.

630
00:58:04,340 --> 00:58:06,340
Fucking Feds. I can't believe it.

631
00:58:06,340 --> 00:58:08,020
Hey, Gloria, wait.

632
00:58:08,020 --> 00:58:10,818
For God's sake, listen to me,
I need to help you!

633
00:58:16,100 --> 00:58:17,897
I wanna help you.

634
00:58:19,340 --> 00:58:21,580
You one of Anthony's homies?

635
00:58:21,580 --> 00:58:24,580
- What you got? Some blow for me?
- No.

636
00:58:24,580 --> 00:58:26,980
Nothing like that.

637
00:58:26,980 --> 00:58:28,940
My name's Michael.

638
00:58:28,940 --> 00:58:30,860
Michael, David's brother.

639
00:58:30,860 --> 00:58:32,612
David who?

640
00:58:33,740 --> 00:58:35,970
David Savion.

641
00:58:37,180 --> 00:58:39,820
What the fuck?! Why am I
supposed to fucking believe you?

642
00:58:39,820 --> 00:58:41,500
Come in here with
these crank-ass whores!

643
00:58:41,500 --> 00:58:43,620
Listen to me.

644
00:58:43,620 --> 00:58:46,453
I'm trying to get you out of here.
This is why I'm here.

645
00:58:47,500 --> 00:58:51,460
Gotta get you out of here, you have
a baby. Your baby, David's baby, OK?

646
00:58:51,460 --> 00:58:53,740
Let me help you.

647
00:58:53,740 --> 00:58:55,260
How am I supposed to believe you?

648
00:58:55,260 --> 00:58:57,900
- That's fucking shit!
- Listen...listen to me. Come here.

649
00:58:57,900 --> 00:59:01,210
Can't fucking tell the whole
neighbourhood. Come here, please.

650
00:59:02,860 --> 00:59:04,851
It's our mother's ring you're wearing.

651
00:59:08,420 --> 00:59:10,540
How am I supposed to believe you?

652
00:59:10,540 --> 00:59:12,780
Listen to me,
I just wanna get you out of here.

653
00:59:12,780 --> 00:59:15,580
Take care of yourself,
take care of the baby, take care...

654
00:59:15,580 --> 00:59:17,780
- Just let me help you, please.
- No, no.

655
00:59:17,780 --> 00:59:20,580
You guys murdered
the only fucking thing I ever loved.

656
00:59:20,580 --> 00:59:22,900
- I loved him.
- How am I supposed to...

657
00:59:22,900 --> 00:59:24,660
I loved him, too, Gloria.

658
00:59:24,660 --> 00:59:28,335
Fuck you!
Get that fucking shit away from me.

659
00:59:36,580 --> 00:59:38,059
Fuck.

660
00:59:42,740 --> 00:59:44,260
Hey, man.

661
00:59:44,260 --> 00:59:46,100
Gonna shoot me through the door?

662
00:59:46,100 --> 00:59:47,897
What, with this?

663
00:59:48,980 --> 00:59:50,500
What's up?

664
00:59:50,500 --> 00:59:52,860
Elias wants to see you.

665
00:59:52,860 --> 00:59:54,860
Yeah, what about?

666
00:59:54,860 --> 00:59:56,620
He wouldn't say.

667
00:59:56,620 --> 00:59:58,292
And I asked.

668
00:59:59,860 --> 01:00:02,820
- What, right now?
- Right fucking now.

669
01:00:02,820 --> 01:00:05,060
OK.

670
01:00:05,060 --> 01:00:07,300
Give me a second.

671
01:00:12,660 --> 01:00:14,740
- Michael.
- What's going on?

672
01:00:14,740 --> 01:00:16,260
- Sit down. Come on.
- OK.

673
01:00:16,260 --> 01:00:18,490
I need to talk to you.

674
01:00:20,180 --> 01:00:21,977
Sit, please.

675
01:00:28,220 --> 01:00:31,580
Do you remember I spoke to you
about the war?

676
01:00:31,580 --> 01:00:35,020
- Yeah. Every...every word.
- Good.

677
01:00:35,020 --> 01:00:40,820
The world you and I travel in
is run by very few powerful men.

678
01:00:40,820 --> 01:00:43,580
Now, these men are not politicians.

679
01:00:43,580 --> 01:00:45,940
Nor are they military experts.

680
01:00:45,940 --> 01:00:50,140
The battles we've fought
over petty turf is now behind us.

681
01:00:50,140 --> 01:00:52,820
We've grown to become leaders.

682
01:00:52,820 --> 01:00:54,617
International leaders.

683
01:00:56,380 --> 01:00:58,940
We no longer divide and conquer.

684
01:00:58,940 --> 01:01:00,900
We conquer and divide.

685
01:01:00,900 --> 01:01:03,380
This weekend is a summit of our network.

686
01:01:03,380 --> 01:01:04,900
I know that.

687
01:01:04,900 --> 01:01:08,940
Arturo is representing South America...

688
01:01:08,940 --> 01:01:11,454
Zed and I North America.

689
01:01:13,260 --> 01:01:15,057
Who's covering Europe?

690
01:01:16,220 --> 01:01:18,420
- I like your thinking.
- Business, right?

691
01:01:18,420 --> 01:01:19,980
Right.

692
01:01:19,980 --> 01:01:22,130
But first things first.

693
01:01:23,140 --> 01:01:27,740
We can unite North and South America.

694
01:01:27,740 --> 01:01:32,340
That puts Zed at the top
and me over North America.

695
01:01:32,340 --> 01:01:34,615
Sounds like a bloodbath to me.

696
01:01:35,820 --> 01:01:40,689
Yes and no. Then again,
perhaps it's down to you.

697
01:01:41,740 --> 01:01:43,540
Me? Why?

698
01:01:43,540 --> 01:01:49,410
We decided to keep it fun...
entertaining...civilized.

699
01:01:50,420 --> 01:01:54,538
Arturo brings his general,
and I bring mine.

700
01:01:55,540 --> 01:01:57,337
You.

701
01:01:58,860 --> 01:02:00,620
How can I help?

702
01:02:00,620 --> 01:02:03,532
A blood match. Winner takes all.

703
01:02:05,340 --> 01:02:07,700
Now...

704
01:02:07,700 --> 01:02:10,380
the question is, Mr General...

705
01:02:10,380 --> 01:02:12,260
are you willing to represent
our organization?

706
01:02:12,260 --> 01:02:13,739
What do you think?

707
01:02:15,380 --> 01:02:17,420
You lose...

708
01:02:17,420 --> 01:02:21,500
we work for Arturo
till the end of our days.

709
01:02:21,500 --> 01:02:23,809
You win...

710
01:02:25,060 --> 01:02:26,539
Look at me.

711
01:02:27,540 --> 01:02:32,340
Riches...beyond your
wildest imagination...

712
01:02:32,340 --> 01:02:34,456
will be ours.

713
01:02:36,860 --> 01:02:38,940
Who would I be fighting?

714
01:02:38,940 --> 01:02:42,091
Hector Gonzales.

715
01:02:43,420 --> 01:02:45,060
Arturo's greatest general.

716
01:02:45,060 --> 01:02:48,420
Really? So how great is he?

717
01:02:48,420 --> 01:02:51,660
You're greater. You're faster.

718
01:02:51,660 --> 01:02:54,060
You're more powerful, more intelligent.

719
01:02:54,060 --> 01:02:55,540
You can win.

720
01:02:55,540 --> 01:02:59,180
No, no, no, no. Not you can win.

721
01:02:59,180 --> 01:03:01,140
You will win.

722
01:03:01,140 --> 01:03:05,380
So I guess, um...your wish...

723
01:03:05,380 --> 01:03:07,740
my honor, right?

724
01:03:07,740 --> 01:03:09,219
I thought you'd say that.

725
01:03:13,460 --> 01:03:15,780
OK, let's celebrate.

726
01:03:18,420 --> 01:03:21,060
Yep?

727
01:03:21,060 --> 01:03:23,820
Yo, it's A-Train. Gloria's here.

728
01:03:23,820 --> 01:03:26,653
- Really?
- She told me about yesterday.

729
01:03:27,860 --> 01:03:31,140
- And?
- She wants your help.

730
01:03:31,140 --> 01:03:34,460
Cool. That's a good thing, right?

731
01:03:34,460 --> 01:03:36,660
Where are you?

732
01:03:36,660 --> 01:03:38,218
Fifth and Broussard.

733
01:03:39,660 --> 01:03:42,652
OK. OK, I'll be right there.

734
01:04:16,900 --> 01:04:18,420
We cool?

735
01:04:18,420 --> 01:04:19,900
We're cool.

736
01:04:19,900 --> 01:04:22,740
You're doing the right thing,
you know that.

737
01:04:22,740 --> 01:04:25,180
I know.

738
01:04:25,180 --> 01:04:27,171
Thank you.

739
01:04:29,940 --> 01:04:31,532
Course.

740
01:04:34,380 --> 01:04:36,820
She wants help?

741
01:04:36,820 --> 01:04:38,460
I hope so.

742
01:04:38,460 --> 01:04:40,337
Why don't you go ask her?

743
01:04:43,380 --> 01:04:45,848
Hey, Gloria, you OK?

744
01:04:47,620 --> 01:04:50,500
I just wanna get out.

745
01:04:50,500 --> 01:04:52,020
That's why I'm here.

746
01:04:52,020 --> 01:04:54,740
Anything you need,
we can arrange that, right?

747
01:04:54,740 --> 01:04:56,332
We'll help you.

748
01:04:58,020 --> 01:04:59,578
Alright.

749
01:05:02,700 --> 01:05:04,497
Let me ask you a question.

750
01:05:06,460 --> 01:05:08,740
Truthfully.

751
01:05:08,740 --> 01:05:12,180
Where do you really stand with Elias?

752
01:05:12,180 --> 01:05:14,180
Elias has a saying.

753
01:05:14,180 --> 01:05:17,660
"We cut off the heads
of those that will not bow."

754
01:05:17,660 --> 01:05:19,580
Yeah, sounds like him.

755
01:05:19,580 --> 01:05:22,460
- How's that working out?
- It's not.

756
01:05:22,460 --> 01:05:26,220
Elias said...

757
01:05:26,220 --> 01:05:29,100
"They've lost their way..."

758
01:05:29,100 --> 01:05:32,012
"..and no man is bigger than the set."

759
01:05:40,300 --> 01:05:41,779
Time for a change, huh?

760
01:05:48,620 --> 01:05:50,099
Just you?

761
01:05:53,340 --> 01:05:54,819
Come in.

762
01:05:58,380 --> 01:06:00,380
I know you're a cop.

763
01:06:00,380 --> 01:06:02,420
What the fuck are you talking about?

764
01:06:02,420 --> 01:06:04,260
I saw the way you cleared
the indigo's house.

765
01:06:04,260 --> 01:06:06,100
If you weren't there,
it would've been bang, bang,

766
01:06:06,100 --> 01:06:07,580
and whoever's left standing
would've won.

767
01:06:07,580 --> 01:06:09,180
Yeah, well, I'm still not a cop.

768
01:06:09,180 --> 01:06:12,060
And I've had similar tactical training
at Quantico.

769
01:06:12,060 --> 01:06:14,779
I ran your DNA, Deputy Michael Savion.

770
01:06:17,220 --> 01:06:19,420
What the fuck? You're a fucking Fed?

771
01:06:19,420 --> 01:06:21,580
Yes, I'm a fucking Fed.

772
01:06:21,580 --> 01:06:23,620
I'm deep undercover.

773
01:06:23,620 --> 01:06:27,580
Look, we've been in the field
on this for a very long time.

774
01:06:27,580 --> 01:06:29,420
I built a DNA database
of the gang members

775
01:06:29,420 --> 01:06:30,900
which we're gonna use to convict them.

776
01:06:30,900 --> 01:06:32,380
We've been hoping to get these guys

777
01:06:32,380 --> 01:06:34,220
all together in one place
at the same time.

778
01:06:34,220 --> 01:06:35,820
The summit is what
we've been waiting for.

779
01:06:35,820 --> 01:06:38,260
You cannot...cannot...
screw this up, Michael.

780
01:06:38,260 --> 01:06:41,700
- It's important to me, too.
- What do you mean?

781
01:06:41,700 --> 01:06:44,380
This guy Zed,
what do you know about him?

782
01:06:44,380 --> 01:06:46,500
Zed...he's one of our main targets.

783
01:06:46,500 --> 01:06:49,139
British sonofabitch. Their "guv'nor".

784
01:06:50,140 --> 01:06:51,780
Why?

785
01:06:51,780 --> 01:06:53,420
He killed my brother.

786
01:06:53,420 --> 01:06:55,340
Yeah, he wanted to go straight,
have a family,

787
01:06:55,340 --> 01:06:57,300
and they shot him in the back for that.

788
01:06:57,300 --> 01:06:59,780
Wait, so this is not an operation?

789
01:06:59,780 --> 01:07:01,300
This is just you?

790
01:07:01,300 --> 01:07:02,940
Yeah.

791
01:07:02,940 --> 01:07:06,980
Jesus Christ, Michael!
You can't just come in like a vigilante.

792
01:07:06,980 --> 01:07:08,460
We're gonna take Zed down.

793
01:07:08,460 --> 01:07:11,180
This is bigger than you
and your brother and Elias.

794
01:07:11,180 --> 01:07:13,171
You can't do something to screw this up.

795
01:07:26,340 --> 01:07:29,500
What have you given up, Zed...

796
01:07:29,500 --> 01:07:34,176
in your...haste for the world?

797
01:07:35,580 --> 01:07:37,140
Given up?

798
01:07:37,140 --> 01:07:39,290
We gain the world.

799
01:07:40,700 --> 01:07:43,660
Oh, it's a little scratch of earth...

800
01:07:43,660 --> 01:07:46,180
maybe...

801
01:07:46,180 --> 01:07:49,660
only until it's swallowed up
by the beast...

802
01:07:49,660 --> 01:07:54,097
with your remnants
and skeletons of bones remaining.

803
01:07:55,220 --> 01:07:59,611
Mother Earth's breath is weighted.

804
01:08:01,820 --> 01:08:04,500
So, what do you know about this guy?

805
01:08:04,500 --> 01:08:06,775
Hector Gonzales?

806
01:08:07,780 --> 01:08:09,500
Well, he's never lost.

807
01:08:09,500 --> 01:08:11,460
The guy's a beast.

808
01:08:11,460 --> 01:08:13,660
Even for you.

809
01:08:13,660 --> 01:08:15,890
We got shit to do, right?

810
01:08:17,660 --> 01:08:19,298
I'm not done yet.

811
01:08:20,340 --> 01:08:22,331
I need a minute alone.

812
01:08:29,620 --> 01:08:31,099
Win tonight.

813
01:08:32,980 --> 01:08:35,699
Don't do anything stupid.
Wait for my signal.

814
01:08:37,340 --> 01:08:38,849
This is bigger than you
and your brother.

815
01:08:39,000 --> 01:08:40,129
I know.

816
01:08:51,940 --> 01:08:54,340
Guess it's worth winning, though.

817
01:08:54,340 --> 01:08:55,980
Huh?

818
01:08:55,980 --> 01:08:58,340
Hey, guys?

819
01:08:58,340 --> 01:08:59,819
They're here.

820
01:09:01,900 --> 01:09:04,660
You see, I heard the whispers.

821
01:09:04,660 --> 01:09:06,900
- Whispers?
- Yes.

822
01:09:06,900 --> 01:09:12,020
Yes, the voices that tell me you seek...

823
01:09:12,020 --> 01:09:14,380
perhaps...

824
01:09:14,380 --> 01:09:19,740
Michael's scratch of earth
for your own, hm?

825
01:09:19,740 --> 01:09:22,100
Perhaps.

826
01:09:22,100 --> 01:09:23,580
Perhaps.

827
01:09:23,580 --> 01:09:28,340
Whispers, my friend, they told me
you were looking for los campeones.

828
01:09:28,340 --> 01:09:31,173
That is why I have come here.

829
01:09:44,260 --> 01:09:46,296
What the fuck is this?

830
01:09:52,580 --> 01:09:54,059
That's for me?

831
01:09:55,740 --> 01:09:58,420
You fucking kidding me?
Come on, I'm old-school, remember?

832
01:09:58,420 --> 01:10:01,660
I guess you should...you know where
you found it? Just take it back.

833
01:10:01,660 --> 01:10:04,500
What exactly do you want, Arturo?

834
01:10:04,500 --> 01:10:05,979
We both want the same thing.

835
01:10:07,940 --> 01:10:09,820
Control.

836
01:10:09,820 --> 01:10:12,573
A little scratch of earth.

837
01:10:14,020 --> 01:10:15,500
At all costs.

838
01:10:15,500 --> 01:10:18,220
This is my sacrifice.

839
01:10:18,220 --> 01:10:22,140
I know you're taking the
best soldiers from all sets.

840
01:10:22,140 --> 01:10:23,620
You've never lost a summit.

841
01:10:23,620 --> 01:10:25,900
That's true.

842
01:10:25,900 --> 01:10:27,620
And neither have you.

843
01:10:27,620 --> 01:10:29,900
That's it, Michael. You stay focused.

844
01:10:29,900 --> 01:10:32,100
I need to go find my sister.
She's missing.

845
01:10:32,100 --> 01:10:37,540
Now, look, brother, at some point, man,
if things go well, I'm gonna go ghost.

846
01:10:37,540 --> 01:10:39,531
You're doing the right thing, man.

847
01:10:41,980 --> 01:10:44,180
Look at them.

848
01:10:44,180 --> 01:10:49,580
I want what you want...spreading
our reach throughout the world.

849
01:10:49,580 --> 01:10:52,300
But unlike you...

850
01:10:52,300 --> 01:10:56,657
I don't forget
who my family really is.

851
01:12:07,460 --> 01:12:12,420
Hail Mars, son of Juno, god of war!

852
01:12:12,420 --> 01:12:14,900
On toward to battle!

853
01:12:14,900 --> 01:12:16,660
Hail Mars...

854
01:12:16,660 --> 01:12:20,335
son of Juno, god of war!

855
01:12:21,540 --> 01:12:26,420
Hail Mars, son of Juno, god of war!

856
01:12:26,420 --> 01:12:28,620
Mine enemies to their knees!

857
01:12:28,620 --> 01:12:31,580
Mars, who will wield the sword of man,
come forth,

858
01:12:31,580 --> 01:12:33,700
for the victory is in their hearts!

859
01:12:33,700 --> 01:12:39,060
For the victory is in their hearts!
For the victory is in their hearts!

860
01:12:39,060 --> 01:12:42,020
For the victory is in their hearts!

861
01:12:59,380 --> 01:13:02,820
Hector! Hector! Hector! Hector!

862
01:13:02,820 --> 01:13:07,940
Hector! Hector! Hector!
Hector! Hector! Hector!

863
01:14:08,500 --> 01:14:11,020
Get up! Get up!

864
01:14:16,620 --> 01:14:17,620
Get up!

865
01:14:30,580 --> 01:14:32,650
- That's it!
- Come on!

866
01:14:34,060 --> 01:14:35,539
Come on!

867
01:14:57,100 --> 01:14:58,260
Come on!

868
01:15:02,300 --> 01:15:04,211
Arggh!

869
01:15:17,820 --> 01:15:19,300
Oh!

870
01:15:24,060 --> 01:15:25,698
Get up! Get up!

871
01:15:28,420 --> 01:15:29,569
Get up!

872
01:15:30,580 --> 01:15:31,780
Yeah!

873
01:15:53,060 --> 01:15:54,540
Yeah!

874
01:15:54,540 --> 01:15:55,768
Yes!

875
01:16:05,420 --> 01:16:08,890
Arrgh! Arrgh!

876
01:16:16,900 --> 01:16:19,740
Yes!

877
01:16:34,500 --> 01:16:37,380
Michael! Michael! Michael!

878
01:16:37,380 --> 01:16:42,060
Michael! Michael! Michael!
Michael! Michael!

879
01:16:42,060 --> 01:16:44,140
Michael! Michael!

880
01:16:44,140 --> 01:16:46,335
To the victor goes the spoils.

881
01:16:48,260 --> 01:16:50,300
He's yours.

882
01:16:50,300 --> 01:16:55,220
Victory goes further than this room.
I'm gonna take your whole empire.

883
01:16:55,220 --> 01:17:00,820
Do you truly think you possess the
virtue to rule all of the Americas?

884
01:17:00,820 --> 01:17:02,820
Do you?!

885
01:17:02,820 --> 01:17:04,740
Don't you worry about me.

886
01:17:04,740 --> 01:17:06,540
Oh, not even for a second.

887
01:17:06,540 --> 01:17:09,940
But perhaps it is you
that should worry about yourself.

888
01:17:09,940 --> 01:17:12,420
The position you seek
is a precarious one.

889
01:17:12,420 --> 01:17:15,260
No, Arturo, I think it's you...

890
01:17:15,260 --> 01:17:17,899
that's in a
fucking precarious position.

891
01:17:20,420 --> 01:17:23,617
Enjoy the elation of your conquest.

892
01:17:25,820 --> 01:17:27,811
Albeit brief.

893
01:17:28,860 --> 01:17:32,060
Michael! Michael! Michael!

894
01:17:32,060 --> 01:17:34,700
Michael! Michael! Michael!

895
01:17:34,700 --> 01:17:37,900
Michael! Michael! Michael!

896
01:17:37,900 --> 01:17:39,380
Let's go.

897
01:17:39,380 --> 01:17:41,660
Michael! Michael! Michael!

898
01:17:41,660 --> 01:17:45,580
Michael! Michael! Michael! Michael!

899
01:17:45,580 --> 01:17:50,608
Michael! Michael! Michael! Michael!

900
01:17:53,300 --> 01:17:54,779
Zed!

901
01:18:00,500 --> 01:18:02,377
What do you think, Michael?

902
01:18:03,420 --> 01:18:05,340
Two for one?

903
01:18:05,340 --> 01:18:07,020
You're fucking monster, you know that?

904
01:18:07,020 --> 01:18:09,020
- What was that?
- Put it down. You don't need it.

905
01:18:09,020 --> 01:18:10,780
Do I need this? Do you need this?

906
01:18:10,780 --> 01:18:12,340
Do it, Zed. Do it.

907
01:18:12,340 --> 01:18:13,820
So, what happens now?

908
01:18:13,820 --> 01:18:16,300
Don't be a fucking coward!
That's what I gotta say to you.

909
01:18:17,780 --> 01:18:19,820
Cops! Get, get, get, get!

910
01:18:30,060 --> 01:18:31,540
Get the girl!

911
01:18:31,540 --> 01:18:33,337
Get over!

912
01:18:50,260 --> 01:18:52,740
Fuck you! Fuck you!

913
01:18:52,740 --> 01:18:54,220
You hear?! Fuck you!

914
01:18:54,220 --> 01:18:56,415
Please just let me go!

915
01:19:12,020 --> 01:19:13,009
Oh.

916
01:19:48,780 --> 01:19:51,214
Ugh. Shut the fuck up!

917
01:19:53,180 --> 01:19:55,535
Oh, my God!

918
01:19:56,860 --> 01:19:58,976
Let me go!

919
01:20:23,300 --> 01:20:25,740
It's OK, Gloria. Come on.

920
01:20:25,740 --> 01:20:28,732
OK. You OK? I got you now. It's OK.

921
01:20:30,580 --> 01:20:32,300
You're OK.

922
01:20:32,300 --> 01:20:34,100
- You OK?
- Yeah.

923
01:20:34,100 --> 01:20:35,580
It's OK now. It's OK.

924
01:20:35,580 --> 01:20:37,500
It's OK.

925
01:20:37,500 --> 01:20:40,020
- Hey, hey. It's OK.
- Michael.

926
01:20:40,020 --> 01:20:43,380
Don't do this. Look, it doesn't
have to be this way, OK?

927
01:20:43,380 --> 01:20:46,338
- Come on.
- You're right, it doesn't.

928
01:20:47,340 --> 01:20:48,898
Michael.

929
01:20:49,940 --> 01:20:51,860
You have a baby, David's baby, OK?

930
01:21:08,380 --> 01:21:10,020
Blood in.

931
01:21:10,020 --> 01:21:11,533
Blood out.

932
01:21:25,380 --> 01:21:27,420
Hey, you alright?

933
01:21:27,420 --> 01:21:29,172
Yeah.

934
01:21:30,980 --> 01:21:33,620
I think we're gonna be alright.

935
01:21:33,620 --> 01:21:36,220
Be OK. You come stay with me, OK?

936
01:21:36,220 --> 01:21:39,212
We'll get you your own place.
We'll get you back on your feet.

937
01:21:43,420 --> 01:21:44,940
OK?

938
01:21:44,940 --> 01:21:46,896
No drugs, no gangs.

939
01:21:48,740 --> 01:21:51,820
I wouldn't want to have to lock you up.

940
01:21:51,820 --> 01:21:54,340
You don't have a job.

941
01:21:54,340 --> 01:21:55,932
I know.

942
01:21:57,340 --> 01:22:00,100
I think we got it from here.

943
01:22:00,100 --> 01:22:02,295
What do you think?