Bucharest, Romania.
The evil exist
in every man,
while some may contain it,
as far it's easier to embrass it.
By the way.
Keep your eyes open.
Stay alert.
Where's your friend Castell?
Where's the fucking warrant?
This is my warrant bitch,
you come with me.
Sorry, can't read.
Drop your weapons!
After 9 / 11 the U.S. realize the narcotics were
responsible for financing majority of the terrorist cell.
That's why they created the international drug task force.
This task forces were fully funded and overseeing by the U.S. government.
They took the top narcotics officers
and created an additional team .... agent.
Six months ago, my partner was killed.
Now, the headquarters has sent me a replacement.
I will find the men responsible,
and bring them to justice.
What a shock.
Sorry aout not pick it up earlier,
It's just
I have been tried to call you since.
Really?
I don't have a missed call Bobby.
Yeah, I have been tried to call you but I mean,
I got tons of stuff this morning, you knows.
As usual the work come before me, right?
It's nothing like that, I've been tied up,
I'll be home soon.
All right?
Shit.
Thanks.
Steve, right?
My name is Ronnie.
I am the team leader officer on Bobby task forces.
The head pick me 1 year ago.
Where's Bobby?
Just received an order for a record.
He asked me to find there.
you can leave your stuff here.
Hey, put his bags in the lock up.
We ride.
This way.
Thank you.
- You want some juice?
- Yes, sure. Thank you.
Did you see this?
- Coffee?
- Oh Yeah, sure.
I have been watching you!
And now I got a treat for you!
Do the right and bend over, bitch!
It's te rigt location,
You lead over the South Building,
and we have to get the north side.
- Let's go.
- Steve, right?
- You got it?
- got it.
Get Down!
You got this stuff?
So let's get out of here.
Appropriate.
Hey let me see your hands.
Hands up. Down!
Man, that hurts!
Put it on.
We clear in.
Cuff him.
No one else lives here?
- I want a lawyer.
- Just answer.
Sit him down.
Check the cabinet.
Why she is not handcuffed?
We got product.
Okay, put that shit down,
go to the car and get the test kit.
Hey, there's somebody under the bed.
Let me see your hands.
- Slowly.
- I'm coming out.
- Hands.
- Nice and slow.
Let me see your hands bitch.
Turn around,
Turn around motherfucker!
Get back!
Listen to me.
Are you listening?
I got this 45 pointing to your brain.
You got lof of guns on you rught now.
- Now, put the fucking gun down and everything will be ok.
- What?
Motherfucker, I'm speaking in English.
It's simple, put the fucking gun down!
- Put the gun down.
- OK
Cuff him.
Hands.
What the fuck is this?
You called this room safe?
You d'ont take the covered, you don't look under the bed.
If you want to be police for living
You go to be on be careful!
You put everyone's life a risk.
What the fuck is wrong with you boy?!
You're late.
I had a little problem in my neighborhood, I needed to address it.
I thought you were interested ...
in making money.
It's a little short.
Midgets are little short.
- Money should never be.
- I get it.
Once I delivered it, you'll get your money.
Damn, look at this.
This will work.
I expect to see you in a few days ...
with the rest of my money.
Yes, nice dealing with you too.
Motherfucker.
- Have you called us?
- No.
Any advance?
You were right, the bullets are from a 9mm Scorpion.
Focus on, has just pulled up.
We'll check this place down to see if anyone saw or heard something.
I think I know the motherfucker.
She runs up too much, keep you shut during the flight to London.
Hey.
Asshole.
Just tell the gentleman your name.
Bruce Sony.
Bruce
Now Bruce, can I ask you a personnal question,
because you seem like a really smart guy.
You wait too long,
but if you have something really good for me I may be only half
or perhaps something much better.
I like your style.
- Will cut through the branches.
- Do you agree?
I've been in the U.S., I know his style.
Really.
Yes, I spent a lot time there, in jail.
I met many Americans, intelligent.
No offense, I just want us to understand.
If I help, it might help me.
Got something good or not?
Buk want to catch this guy forever.
Let sigh office for something.
Christian, I'm taking this guy to my desk I'll be with you in a minute.
Tell me when you want to shut him.
It seems you're excited.
Listen to me boy.
Why you hitting while..?
You're not suppose to hit when I'm holding a man.
Take this guy down.
Put him in a piss tank man.
He has the look of sexual repression. Is it french?
What do you have?
The assault was made by a man named Costel.
He and his men like to make raids on the homes.
Pajero usually the young and rich.
When you see something that catches is eye,
follows the woman, beats her, rapes her and then killed.
The guy is fucking sick.
But this is not all.
The guy also use females
as mules to London.
But when Costel found his man, caught him and killed him.
- Steve?
- Yes?
Do me a favor.
Take off the handcuffs on this man and give him a coffee.
I really need a coffee.
Ronnie you get the coffee, I get the cuffs.
No problem.
I hope you vomit.
How can we get to this guy?
By Russian, a really bad ass.
People say he trained with the military.
Why Russian special forces?
Traffics in drugs and arms, in droves.
Provides all the dust in the market, believe me.
Trust is not one of my most spectacular attributes.
If you catch Dimitri, the Russian
Costel will come up.
Would you bring me one of those too?
What is the problem? Got the seat stuck to butt?
Look it up yourself, I'm working.
There's good news and bad.
The good news is that will take me to that address.
The bad news is that you do not drink coffee.
Come on!
But Dimitri knows that I got pinch.
That's why I'm giving you a little bonus.
Let's move.
Come on, let's go!
There you go.
- Are you sure there is no problem?
- Yeah I'm sure
You can not play with this guy.
You think I like to play?
I just try to cover my ass.
You better get up Costel.
Find the truck and go.
- I'm nervous.
- You should be.
I have not usually this lucky.
Nerves are good, keep you alert.
Psychics make it.
You watch to many American movies.
Don't worry, we'll be watching you at the park.
What?
I need to recharge.
How do you get arrested by the Americans yesterday?
I was released. The police are fools.
Bring a copy of the processing slips, then we'll talk.
It was what you asked me, what more do you need?
I don't need anything,
you're the one who need something.
Look, I'm just trying to do business, trying to stay in the game.
- How much?
- A thousand.
You doubled your business overnight.
Not like that,
it's about making up for my losses.
Work hard, sleep less.
Price is going up.
I'm cool with that, I have no choice.
You're a trusted man.
Yes, I'm in therapy for that.
We'll have to continue this conversation later.
Come see me in two days.
That will close the business.
I need the shit now.
I said, two days.
Yeah, sure. Sorry.
Frank is walking aways.
Let's see if you're lucky.
That was why I brought you,
'cause you're so fucking lucky.
There are about 4 players in this side.
Shit, looks like they coming this way.
Yes, we burned. Do not move.
What she doing?
I lost it. Where is che?
Don't move.
Shit we're burned, you were right.
Come out wherever you are.
We know you're in there.
Motherfurckers man.
Listen guys, I think you know what we're doing
and if you don't get the fuck out of here,
I take you all to the jail.
Fuck American police.
Let me see your hands,
Give it to me!
- We go extra pair to handcuffs.
- Good work.
Ronnie we were burned.
Copy that.
What do you think?"
- Let's do it.
Step out the vehicle.
Can I see your license and registration?
For what?
You're part of an investigation ...
- You're an American?
- Ya
Why is my license and registration in any way concerned?
Well, as I was about to say before I was so rudely interrupted by
your personnal interest
but it is an investigation with the IDTF,
and we need to talk to you.
- Feel free.
- Thank you so much.
Do you mind if I looking at your car?
- No problem.
- Good.
Becare, it's Armani.
He's safe.
Is it yours?
Never seen it.
So I guess that you do not have a licensed to carry firearms.
I told you, I never seen it.
Ok, cuff him and put it back please.
Watch your head.
We're going to look what's the serial number on that.
You're not from this country
Why live this way?
You should be chassing terrorists in Afghanistan, not me.
I already done that, now I moved here to have fun.
The same as that found at the scene.
That what I thought.
Do you want to call the locals?
- You should be careful with your.
- I will.
Holly Shit.
This asshole did us good.
You know I'll be filling a complaint to your American superiors
about you doing this to me.
Go for it.
You Americans, are known for your brutality.
Yeah, but you know, we're proud of it too.
- You want to get rid of the gun charges?
- How?
You know, there's this piece of shit named Castello that you're dealing with,
- Is in this damn shit.
- Like what?
Oh like home invasion, murdering people for fun,
rapping womens before and after there dead
it's a nice guy
The perfect man to join him.
I am a family man.
My wife and my kid are sacred to me.
Sound like you should be chasing this gipsy piece of shit
instead of me.
You have a problem with this guy
you handled it on your own.
I plan to do.
I talked the old man ...
about Costel you know.
He got really cold really quick.
Maybe a night in jail will suffer him up and he'll talk.
I feel in Siberia are lot of worse than here.
That's right
In the U.S. you see on TV,
the Russian that moterfucker is watching you.
Oh Ya? You talking from experience now?
It is self-harm to blame,
- A smart move.
- It's going to sue,
saw the trick in the book, so what?
He does not want a lawsuit, want us to depart.
What We Do We dropped into Russian?
Dimitri going to press, he takes us to Castell.
- There is something I want to say.
- What's that boy?
How much you admire me,
How much you want to be like me.
Yes, that too.
But more importantly.
- I'll be dad in a month.
- Really?
I was not expecting.
Relax, I'm not the first that works in one case
when his wife is about to give birth.
I guess we'll be more careful.
Sorry I'm late, you know how it is.
It's ok, you know I love you.
What's going on honey?
How did hear about your sister?
Well, the man got the job.
You want a drink?
You want something to drink?
The usual.
- Ok, cool.
- Thank you baby, thank you.
Look at that. You still remenber me?
Ya I remenber you.
It's kind of amazing how a piece of shit like you can get on the street so fast.
Come here.
You see why I hate going to dinner?
You get the fuck out!
Don't forget whose house is this, bitch!
Don't forget who pays the rent, you fagot.
Asshole.
Unconsciously, I wanted to fail,
- I call you later.
- Don't bother.
Damn!
Who taught you to drive?!
Looks like it was my bike!
That is, come here!
Leave the car!
He's done.
It is the nature of this business we have some shit.
But we've had enough.
It's not going to happen again.
It should not happen in the first place!
Is this country look like us.
They're feeding police information because there have pression.
Not more shit.
Well, she didn't screw the jog.
Thank you for your health.
His personality has not changed anything.
Just like we planned.
Just what I wanted to hear.
Let's go!
Come over here.
I'm ready to go.
You do not have to worry about.
I hate to admit it, but good work.
We need to find information
on women who are taking the drug to London.
What?
Dead people are my life.
Who died now?
An informant of yours, according to the record.
Can't remenber his name, a biker style.
You signed im, two days ago.
When he died?
About 9, this morning.
It looks like a professional job.
Double shot to the head. There were no witnesses.
Any idea of the suspect?
Yeah I do, the only problem he is in custody.
You may not have anything better than that.
No, they don't.
That's the last, have you tryed?
No, Adrian didn't make his god damn drug this morning.
This son of a bitch is late again.
You wrong your kindness for weakness.
Now, you're going to start preaching?
We are negotiating with Adrian.
Tomorrow we pick up the cash take im out.
And we take care of Dimitri.
Come on baby, let's go.
Let me do that for you.
Listen, when we started I said
you understood when I told you I'm a cop,
and police must work hard outside the home ...
you know, not ideal for a relationship
but you seems to be ok with that.
I understand you're passion for the job, sweetheart
I just wish that were to put the work before me.
And I do not.
I know it's hard, as soon as I finish this case ...
Don't say something we both know is not true.
You know I love you.
You're right, don't worry about anything.
I did not want to make a scene, I just wanted to apologize.
That's why I love you.
- Well, I have something for you.
- You have something for me?
Ok guys,
Listen up.
The target is located by the university.
Caroline Side Boulevard.
Today, people will be work up by the locals,
indicate tat this place maybe a Stashpad,
probably related to our main target,
Costello, who want to catch.
One thing we do know that one of their riders, Adrian, will be there today.
These are the most recent photos we have of some of his known accomplices.
There is more to the table, if you guys look at
But, we don't have one of Adrian yet.
Now, hhe one thing that I want you all to remember,
this is a street level case.
Which means, even know if we have surveillance
depending on the time of the day
this place can be anything from a stashpad to, well a day care center.
Anything else boss?
I want you guys in uniforms two soldiers back.
If we can not break resistance,
abort code word is "Eco" Any questions?
What can of weapons are we runing into?
We know they have Scorpions 9mm
and several assault rifles in the house.
Everybody is good?
Are left behind
if we pursue someone.
Let's go get them.
Don't play with this thing, pack it up.
Do we have enough ammunition?
I have 6 clips for each guys.
- What backup?
- We got a lots.
Listen, I'm going to make you in gard today,
I will put you in the rear.
It's better, you got a baby and everything.
Are you serious?
Do I look like a fucking comedian, boy?
Police!
Come on,
Come on pick up the phone.
What the hell does he want?
Come on man, take the fucking phone!
Ya.
Costel, police are all over!
The guys get me paint down, man!
Back up.
Fuck. A Stashpad, now!
Stay down!
Down,
Damn, Costel
Are you still there?!
Drop the gun.
Don't move, don't fucking breath, drop the gun.
-Please.
- Come here.
- All right.
Come here.
Cuff him and search him.
Shit.
Suave.
They got Adrian.
Turn us around, we going back.
Good job.
Where's Costello?
- Find it yourself.
- I'm going to do that.
You get it?
Yeah, the vest out there, thanks god.
Dimitri is here.
Can I get something else for you, sir?
No, it's fine, thank you.
Mr Costello will be here in a moment.
Look at this place.
Do you think that what the police told you is true?
Not my buisness.
At least until I have my money.
Have aSit.
I feel like our relationship is fading, man.
We used to do buisness at your apartment
then at the park
and now you make me the host.
Where is my money?
Well, there's a little problem.
There was a raid on one of my apartments.
And this is my problem? Why?
It was your agent friend.
He probaly pick up my deal because I do business with you.
I lost a lot of money, so because of you, I lost 50 thousand.
If I don't get all my money back by tomorrow,
you're a dead man.
You want to threaten me, in my own place?!
The IDTF agent ...
specifically asked for you,
and it was not just about selling drugs.
I know you do, who we fight among ourselves.
The shit he told me,
make me sick to my stomach.
If I find out that is true,
I'll come back and I'll kill you myself.
Later.
The hosts suffered three casualties, will you.
Well, I put three rounds.
I think I know who shot Adrian.
Do you think it Costel?
A million percent that he was sure.
Stop.
Ok, back up.
This is the street.
Ok boys, get down.
All right, hide the body and grap the keys.
Expected to return. Let's get this done.
Get back to the house, now.
Wat the fuck you think you can hide from us?!
Where's the old man?!
No one told you to kill her yet!
I had to tell us where the money is!
Go outside and watch for him, both of you!
I'll handle the kid!
Nobody from, close the door behind you!
Surrender.
My family!
Stupid gypsy.
It's ok, It's ok my boy, I'm here.
Your father is here.
Take it.
Will not you die?
Where are you?
Two blocks west, behind the building.
You in the corner.
Shit.
Are you really that fucking stupid?
Where is Costello and the other man?
I don't know.
You smell like fear, bitch.
Fuck, bitch!
They're fucking dead!
Do you want really want to die this way?
And for what?!
Do not stay here, go park outside.
This is the address registered.
Looks like somebody already passed through here.
Drop the gun!
Damn!
8-25 quarters ahead.
I have code red, officer down.
We are in the First Floor club.
I need help and fast.
Make pressure there.
Go after the bastard.
I'll be right back, you ear.
No way!
Hey, come to the front, right now.
God damn it, man.
Hi boss.
I just heard what happened. I'm really sorry.
So just you know, Headquarter sent you an investigator,
who have questions about what you two are doing in the club.
My superiors are looking for the same answers.
I just wish you had asked for backup.
So do I.
You have a major crime task force dedicated to justice.
You got all these guys walking around,
this man is no command.
You know, I don't get it.
I'm here to see Robert Samuels.
Just wait here.
This guy is not a magician, he's not a commander
or a trained soldier, he is not Jesus
he's just a fucking gypsy.
As these two types.
Chief, Dimitri is here to see you.
If you do not solve this find someone else.
Send him in.
What's going on?
I need to talk to you.
Sit down.
About what?
What about him?
He's responsible for killing my wife.
And from what I heard, your partner,
I think we both want revenge.
- I'm listening.
- I veteran, thou Costel.
And I can take revenge on this man for the death of my wife.
Are you serious?
I shall soon know where you are.
When I do,
I will tell you everything
where he hiding up,
where he keep the rest of his cash money and drugs.
All I ask, is you turn blind eyes
on what I do to this "dada".
This is not the place to have this conversation,
but I understand very well,
even better than you think about the futur may bring.
Do me a favor.
Call me soon.
And let's see what happens.
The call you on your cell in the next 24 hours
with the time and the location.
Tell me you found this motherfucker.
We found one of his booker and partner.
Is in a complex.
I want you to stand alone this.
It's just me and the agent, understand?
Until we have finished.
I want you to take my son back home.
This country has taken too much from him.
I have a place.
Come alone tonight, understand?
Are you alone?
I have people close behind,
but they'll not interfere with what we do.
Let me tell you something, you're a gangster,
So technically, we really can't be seen together
hang around togheter or even doing anything
That's all I'm saying ...
- Keep your words.
- I will
My people told me that within the apartment complex.
How many?
4.
If you do not go out in 10 or 15 minutes
happens, it will be all yours.
Just remember our deal.
What are you doing here?
- You're all right?
- I'm fine
Freeze
Hey, remember our deal.
I'm no trying to kill him, just try to slow him down.
Is in there.
Do what you need to do.
Fuck,
Shit!
Direct drive to north on the Dutch street.
Get up there and set a containement.
I hear you breathing.
It wasn't me who killed her, it was Costel.
Where's Costello?
Shit!
Romance in the bar,
Romance Bar, East Side,
is awaiting pickup.
My son told me he shot his mother.
And the one he described to me ... was you.
My guys are close behing, coming fast
you better to leave.
Just go.
Romance is in the bar.
Get out of my way.
Keep your eyes open.
Stay alert.
Where is your friend Costel?
Where is the fucking warrant?
This is my warrant bitch,
you come with me.
I'm sorry, I can't read.
Drop your weapons!
Shit!
Let's see what you got for.
Damn!
That's all you got bitch.
You win, you win.
As a team commander,
the worst thing that can happen is to lose men.
I lost two men,
my partner and now his replacement Steve.
Since I came here,
I hope it's all worth it.
Only a brilliant strategist
could beat me in a move.
Those can only be the hands of one person.
A man of honor
always keeps his word.
That was the deal.
I was thinking ...
men like us
there are things that are hard to say and listen,
but I have to say I'm sorry for your loss.
I thought it would be really nice
if you take your child to their country,
and it would be good for you too.
Funny you should say that.
It's exactly what I was thinking.
- Great minds think alike.
- What is that?
Tickets.
You know you know you are a man of means,
this is just a gesture of respect.
Neither belong here, my friend.
My job is done, now I can go,
find a nice warm place.
Take a break.
You've been one of the good.