Subtitles by YIFY
Turbokit a GT35,
XMotor an intercooler ...
XCS and an exhaust system.
- Nice.
Look, it's the ESX car.
He does everything legally,
sponsors and all the trimmings.
What's next, Krueger?
I want the first gemporteerde
race driver in Topfuel.
I can now better your autograph and
EBay to sell when you become famous.
Come on, you know you're not
here should be that.
Quiet, Mikey. I'm here
but a visit.
If ESX find out that you just
are visiting, you can leave.
Look who show up here.
Will you show respect for your king?
Tony, if I beat you again, you
a complaint against abuse.
Nobody beats my new material
more. You're not a big man anymore.
Do not listen to him, you know
he is challenging you.
I will come back with my slow
car, is it fair.
You know what?
It does not matter what you drive.
Come forward or shut up.
Not tonight.
- Yes, forget it.
What now?
Come show off what you just now?
Go ahead. Stand there like a sissy
and show it next to show car.
Say what you want, Krueger. But if
I went to the ring, I get to boxing.
Okay, come on over.
Let's go.
Walk away from it.
- I let this kid not to embarrass myself.
Who cares what they think?
They just want to see a race.
Attention all units, we have called
of an illegal street race in downtown.
I just heard on the scanner, they come.
- Start the race.
I do not, this is stupid.
Just do it.
It's over within 10 seconds.
Are you okay?
- Yes.
Well, put your hands up.
You're under arrest.
I left you only race for them because I
thought you would stay out of trouble.
You finally do something productive.
I've had enough.
My goodness.
How bad is it this time?
I do not think we should do.
Mr. Ashtar.
I'm so sorry, I can explain ...
- What part do you explain?
The part where you have a car of $ 100,000
bring to an illegal street race?
Or how you managed to get
against a police car to crash?
You are lucky that no one
injured. - I know, I made a mistake ...
What you did was stupid.
This is a disaster.
You're done, Krueger.
I will repay ...
- You're done.
Come on, Danny. We go.
Sorry, Mr.. Ashtar.
I had to listen to you.
- You're like a bull ...
if you see red, go for it.
No matter what anyone says.
Yes.
Keep your head up,
it'll be fine.
What?
We're trying to help
really, it just ...
We will send you to your father to live there.
- What?
You need a clean slate
this all behind you.
When did you talk to him?
- This morning.
He set up for this, right?
No, Joe has nothing to do.
Every time there is a problem,
it is worse than the last.
Fines speed, street racing
and now an accident.
I would not even think about it
what next is going to be.
So you will send me to a guy
I have not seen in five years?
He is a drunkard.
- No, Danny, he's not drunk.
Yes, no more.
I did everything I could think of
and I do not know what else to do.
I'm not.
My whole life is here.
There is no ...
- No, you have no choice.
You go. End of story.
Hi, Lisa.
- Hello, Frank.
You look good.
- You too.
Hello, boy.
- Hello, Frank.
Do you want to load or not?
Nice car you got there. And in 2003?
- 2004.
Converted itself?
- Me and my friend Mikey.
Beautiful, it looks expensive.
What a guy, who stepfather of yours.
I bought it myself.
We can chitchat
keep to a minimum?
That's your plan, ignoring me.
- Until I'm 18, yes.
Why wait, tough guy?
Come on.
Get out.
Go hiking.
You can catch me so much
if you want, but ...
does not change that we
bragged to each other down.
Do you understand?
I'm not a popularity contest
win or your best friend ...
or lost time. I am here because
your mother no more.
Do you understand?
Got it?
Done with it.
- Yes? What about me?
What about you?
So this is home.
Do you have that thing?
- Yes.
I bet it's bad driving.
Well, my humble stulpje.
So, now that you live with me ...
there are a few rules to follow.
There is no girl, well after yourself.
You make your own food, you do your
own dishes, you can do your laundry there.
Your room.
Any questions?
We can now unload my car? - Why
in such a hurry? You should not be driving.
My license has limitations,
I may ride to school and work.
And nowhere else, right?
Ok.
Pack your stuff out.
I take it this is about.
What does it need?
- I work on a turbo upgrade, nothing special.
So you think you know anything about engines?
- Probably better than you.
Fantastic, I always wanted half
mechanic, but I could never pay.
You go to your expertise
show every day after school.
No free rides.
Okay, look after the fuel cards.
If the air-fuel ratio somewhere
comes close to 11.5 / 1, we work it out.
That is not cool, we would
The rich have to test.
Dude, I want a 12.5 / 1.
Ok, if the pistons will give,
is it for you. - Whatever.
Also check the DGT.
- Yes, master.
You'll see, baby.
H Max, how does the schrootbak?
Pretty good, we have
worked there all summer.
Want to see whether all the hard work yields something?
Yes.
- It's much faster with the turbo.
We leave him a poopy smell.
We can not do this, please.
Jake, do not.
Jake, stop.
Ok, we got it.
Keep it up.
- Jake.
You're such an idiot.
Come on.
Shake and bake, baby.
What's wrong with you?
They could get hurt.
All is well with them.
Come on.
Are you still mad?
Quite a price, h?
- Yes.
The best school there is.
All race teams look for their new pilots there.
You need a fast car
have to win it.
I have covered.
- That sounds familiar.
Are you here?
- No.
Another thing to hope for.
- It's cruel that they hang the posters there.
Let them think they have a chance.
- Max H, exciting race this morning.
I am Mr. Briggs, I'm going
now say this ...
No lesson is that you do not
just to succeed.
I give a serious lesson.
Jake.
I'm talking to you.
- Against me?
Yeah, you.
It does not matter who I think you are ...
but in my teaching, you
carefully and do it.
Understood?
- Yes, sir.
Ok.
Now you are in a good mood, you Jake ...
Why do you tell the class is not
what a variable magnetic field?
What did you say?
You.
Explain.
Well, it varies
time of the intake ...
using energy-coupling
the camshaft to rotate.
I am not aware
of the import tuning magazine.
Actually, the variable CTH
Timing is used ...
in domestic vehicles,
like the new Mustang.
Drive a car you not?
Not bad.
What is your name?
Danny.
Do you have a last name, Danny?
- Krueger.
Are you Frank's son?
He said you were coming.
He also said that you have a bad
attendance file.
I'm still no problems
have with you ...
Danny?
- No.
Well.
Frank Krueger's your father? Another reason
not to step on the racetrack to set.
How do I register for the race?
Already 18?
Let your dad drawing and bring it back to me.
At the latest within two weeks.
Danny ...
Ignore them.
Your father was a great race driver.
Ok, for all the new faces,
I want to welcome you into the drama class.
I am Ms.. Parker.
I would like to start each new class
an exercise which I call "first impression" call.
So, how many of you want first?
Ok. You, in the back.
What is your name?
- Danny.
Danny, come stand over here. Who wants
their first impression of Danny?
Jessica.
You seem a lot to say today.
Why not say what you see?
He's definitely a transition student.
- Okay, interesting. Go on.
Probably only in the drama lesson
because that was all that was still free.
Why do you say?
- He does not seem like Shakespeare-type.
Do not you, Ms. Popularity,
with your $ 400 jeans.
Name one character from n
of his plays?
I can not even mention two,
Romeo and Juliet.
Please, everyone knows that.
- You said "any character". Your turn.
This is difficult, there are so many good.
Like Macbeth, Shila, Mr.. Mona,
Affello and Hamlet.
Your turn.
- Are they all characters?
You did well.
Pock.
- Excuse me?
Pock, A Midsummer Night's Dream?
The mischief maker, the night elf.
Someone googled Shakespeare after class.
How did you know I stuck
Sat with drama class?
It happened to me
when I was transferred.
You were also transferred?
When was that?
- Last year, from Tampa.
And you?
- Insino.
A valley-boy, h?
- Yes.
So a huge culture shock Bradford?
It sucks here.
Things are getting better.
I hope so.
I like a "back to school
party "tonight. You should come.
I do not know.
Not a social type?
Here's the address.
In case you could get bored.
You're late. I have 3 cars that have a turn
needed 15 minutes ago.
Faster, you must still
two do next.
I'm not used to
working with antiques.
Antiques.
Do you know the world is?
What I know are programmable
engine management systems ...
no carbs and mechanical inflammation.
Try the fuel valve once,
that will help.
Where do you keep this stupid thing?
- I do not know, I've never needed.
Write it down.
I'm just in the restaurant,
do you want to go?
I already ate.
Or not.
H, Danny.
Now I know where I know you.
- Put that away, that's history.
History is our favorite subject.
I'm Max, this is Harry.
What does a superstar like you in Bradford?
Do you know the girl who gives this party?
Yeah, sure.
- A little.
Do you mind if we go with you?
- No.
There's the pool.
I had to bring a swimsuit.
Let's go get some beer.
Would you also one?
No, thank you.
Nice turnout, Jessica.
Where's Jake?
Come on, Rachel. We have been the worst
dates had, I've had enough.
Yes, but look what he has
done for you ...
social life. This feast
belongs to the top.
My God, that's the boy
the drama class. Danny Krueger.
And?
- Have you invited him?
I thought it would be a good opportunity
for him to get to know new people.
Well, he has been a good start
continue to raise the nerds.
Have you invited them?
- They do no harm?
Hello.
- Hello.
I did not think you were coming.
As the hostess me
VIP invitation gave ...
I thought, I turn over the work
and go there. - And she appreciates that.
That's good, because my boss is hard.
It is good to have you here instead
always in that garage of yours.
It's my turn.
- Frank Krueger, is that you?
I did not recognize you because you are right.
You know that they serve no whiskey.
I have been sober since October, Jimmy.
A new car in your collection?
- What are you talking about?
I've always had this.
Now I recognize it, I just
but still ...
seen in educating
my rearview mirror.
You're a funny man.
Jake, you okay?
How are you?
Can your parents every time
come in and shut down this party?
Are you kidding? I had never
such a celebration ...
My stepfather had to
began to fraternize.
Mine could not wait
to get rid of me.
Have you seen Jessica somewhere?
- That guy is good at Krueger.
Is that how you ended up in Bradford?
- Approximately, yes.
My father lives here.
I do not know why.
Come on, it's not so bad?
- It gets better.
Jake.
- What are you doing with this idiot?
We talk.
- If you leave it at that.
Do not pretend you're my boyfriend, Jake
Because you're not.
I know we had a little fight
But we must get to know each other.
Really? How? The only thing you're talking about,
about yourself and your car.
What's wrong with that?
Bitches. They never know what they want.
- Okay, there's no reason to do common.
Will you do something about it?
- Easy, right? Nobody wants trouble.
Too late.
Are you tired of your life?
Want more?
Is that all you got?
Come on.
Danny, stop.
- He is like a superhero.
Jake, do not.
Damn.
- He is going down.
Come on.
That is,
We have a straight, guys.
Why do we get him in?
- Because you two idiots sitting in the car.
No police.
I'm impressed. You begin at last
your temper under control.
It is not easy with that
uittest child every day.
He is as bad as I was.
- You were worse, and you know it.
He looks like a good boy,
give him some time.
I only hope that I
can keep out of trouble.
You do good work so far.
Out of my way.
Come on Krueger,
We only want to talk.
Go.
Come on.
We got him.
Here we go.
Come on, Krueger.
- Come on.
We got him, boys.
He is going down.
You better leave, you'll be late ...
- My car has problems, give you a ride?
Driving too fast?
I find my own ride back.
H guy, is it true that you
Jake's Mustang have preserved?
What do you have under your hood?
Krueger, you'd better sit down.
Ok, we start with a test
on air-fuel ratios.
Dude, you were faster than Jake.
- That's what everyone at the restaurant said.
He had two people in his car,
So I had ...
advantage. I did it
reasonably well, why?
He is the fastest in the province. Nobody
can beat him in the street races.
His father is the owner of Kendall Performances
He's got a lot to store his disposal.
Yes? - Jake's car is
this school on the map.
Our football team is rotslecht.
- You will participate in the race, right?
Yes, but I must first have
some work on my car.
You do not know what you have started.
Stop it.
There is no fighting in my classroom.
Not if you want
participate in the race.
And if you have a problem with each other,
Will you arrange it on the racetrack.
And stop racing on the street.
See you after school.
See you after school?
- Yeah, okay.
Danny.
Hello.
- Hello.
How's the lip?
- Good.
So, how does it feel to be the most
discussed guy at school?
I liked it better when
No one knew my name.
Thanks.
Well, I liked the way
He did not speak to you ok.
It was very chivalrous.
That's something good, right?
- Yes.
Go out with me.
I shall think about it.
- But my car is broken, so you should drive.
The car everyone is talking about?
- Yes, but do not go.
It's the end of the month.
- You keep kidding, right?
First prize is a full scholarship to
The NHA racing school, that's what everyone ...
Yes, I think you temporarily
The racing should stay away.
I knew you would do about this stupid.
- Watch your language.
Especially if you ask for favors.
- I have not asked for 7 years.
All I want is your signature.
- Do you want my autograph?
Then I best not again
caught in a street race.
I have not done that.
- Who do you think you have it?
You keep kidding.
- You are not the only one with a fast car.
And a gear too.
- What is the use of a Porsche with automatic transmission?
You make me very hard
about you now not to like.
Seat belt.
Where are we?
- To Chuck E 'Cheese.
Chuck E 'Cheese, which is fun.
- Have you ever been?
No.
Who taught you driving?
You're right.
Not like most girls?
- You said, I do not.
That is the car where
I learned to drive.
Mine was an old Honda Civic.
- He's my father.
The day he came home with it,
he was a small child.
He saved it for years to purchase,
My mother was so angry.
She calls it his convertible with my princess.
I remember the feeling of
doctrine when it was new, and that smell.
He always said that the Porsche
learn a unique smell.
And I do not want to leave. So I'm driving
it only on special occasions.
Or if I have a lot to think.
How long is he gone?
- Three years.
I'm sorry.
- For what?
I heard a rumor that you
father once drove for NASCAR.
150km per hour until he against a wall
and drove his foot crushed.
Ouch.
- Yes.
He was never the same afterwards.
It was like living with a ghost.
You knew he was there, but did
just as he wants for it.
But you still closer to him now, right?
- From a geographic standpoint it.
But, I do not know. It's weird.
- What is it weird?
Trying to communicate.
There is too much to say.
- That's not bad, trust me.
Want a ride to make?
- Yes.
Good night.
- Good night.
What is it?
- Can you look at my car?
Maybe this weekend, I must first
the head gasket replaced urgently.
Forget it, I go at it myself.
What is the problem?
He gets fuel, ignition, pipes
are good, there's nothing broken.
I do not understand. Normally I would Mickey's
Laptop at release, but that's not now.
Try it now.
Start him now but.
You forgot the crankshaft sensor
turn, so he was not.
And those links are
definitely loose vibrated.
I have not even thought of as
control.
It's a 2.5, right?
- Yes.
If you link to that little injectors
your turbo, then he is even harder.
He was certainly in the last red.
- I think he can be even harder.
Anyway, now that it works,
you need to get parts for me.
Where to?
Candles.
- Buy items in the rival?
Competitors? I am lucky
that the case was still running.
You're welcome.
Thanks.
If your gas pedal,
make sure that nobody sees.
Are you sure nothing is wrong?
It is built with 1 / 16 racing gas
and lost 3% of it each time.
This baby is ready.
I hope so.
I race against the college boy tonight.
You beat them well.
Better be, or you get a name.
H, you. It is still
by at 7:30, right?
Actually, I do not make it.
I have to work overtime.
I'm sorry, Jess.
Can we do it tomorrow?
Yes.
- Thank you, you're wonderful.
Talk to you later, okay?
- Bye.
Harder, old man.
Are you crazy? When Jake and his boys
You see, they destroy you.
Quiet, I'm just some reconnaissance.
Ok.
Come on, Jake.
You will be defeated, college boy.
It seems that his college boy
handbrake had forgotten to turn off.
Too bad.
Hi, Rachel.
I thought you and the newcomer
going out tonight?
Yes, but he canceled
because he had to work late.
No, he's in street racing.
I'm looking at him.
He finished in the top 4, so
probably about 120 miles / h.
If he can beat him on the
racetrack, he must sit around ten.
Okay, I'll see you later.
What have we here?
Do not be shy, Krueger.
Come say days.
Krueger, I'm glad you stop by.
I think we are wrong foot.
I did not know I was in the presence
was a celebrity.
I did some research and apparently
were you a big man in LA.
Not that that means much if your opponent
China has a rommelbak.
But you did get a good sponsor ...
that surprised me, because I thought ...
This is the son of that loser, Frank Krueger.
Shut up, Jake.
And then I found out that you
You sponsor race car driving piece.
And then I thought, you see,
He is an Krueger.
And now everybody thinks you are quick.
Maybe faster than me.
Let's fix this.
You did not even close last night.
I had three people in my car.
- And I did not drive at full speed.
Let's settle it now.
You still have a few
hours before the cafés close ...
your father to the floor there to pick up.
That's why you moved over here?
Your personal assistant to his father.
That was low, you're right. I had
Your father should not offend.
My gardener says
He delivered a good job.
Would you like racing?
Come on, let's go.
Quiet, Danny.
It appears that Krueger goes down.
Here we go.
Come on.
No.
Damn.
That's it.
That's what happens when you choose Japanese.
I almost had you and you know it.
- Almost does not count.
Now is a good time to leave
for yourself even more ridiculous.
Damn.
I think we lost.
How many did you beat him?
Not enough.
I was almost defeated and you know it.
- Almost does not count.
Krueger, Kendall, follow me.
Be sure the car has a relationship
has 8 / 71. Come on.
What were you thinking?
- I do not know.
I want you to keep track of.
Now I call your father.
Mine almost gave a party
because I've defeated Krueger.
I'll still talk to him,
go back to class.
You put me in a bad position, Danny,
you know?
I thought you were smarter.
What does it need?
- I'm sorry.
Because I think now, maybe
I let him race.
He does his homework, it is timely
I may have less severe.
Give me your keys. You are nothing more than
an irresponsible, spoiled little child.
Give me a lesson about responsibility.
You left your wife and child behind.
You're 17, you remember
nothing about life.
You do not know what it is
if your father left behind.
I was ten.
Come once again talking like 15 years of
hard work explodes in your face by a mistake.
Maybe you better
concentrate on what you had ...
rather than obsess about what you lost.
Enough now, give me your keys.
Gone away.
You know what I think?
I think you're jealous.
Because I have a real chance
to do what you never could.
Give me your keys.
Hello.
Jessica is at home?
What do you, Danny?
I screwed up, but I'm not
went over there to race.
Why were you there?
I wanted to see where I compared
come to stand in the race.
Why did not you just?
- I do not know.
In LA I had a sponsor.
A very big.
And that I lost.
- How?
It does not matter why.
When I heard of the race, I thought,
This is my chance, you know?
My second chance.
So I'm just a little time to spend
until you have the opportunity to get out of here?
No, not at all.
Have you ever thought that there
more important things than racing?
I came here to apologize.
Why are you so difficult?
If that's how you feel,
you'd better go.
Are you serious?
- Now.
Yes.
- Dad?
I need your help.
Where are you?
Are you okay?
- Yes.
Are you sure?
- I'm okay.
What happened?
Someone tampered with my brakes.
You must have driven fast
in order to end up.
I'm telling you,
someone messed with my car.
It's always someone
different from their mistake with you.
You could be dead. You do not think.
What's wrong with you?
Help me with the pull cord.
Hello.
Mommy?
- Danny.
Can I come home?
Danny anyway.
If I did not think this is the best
was for you, I get you right.
He hates me. He wants me here.
He never wanted.
No, that's not true. It was his idea
for you to come there.
Danny, talk to him.
He loves you.
Maybe it's time to forgive him.
I'm sorry, Mom.
I know.
I love you.
Why did you leave?
I could not take it anymore.
I ruined everything by
possible path to follow ...
instead of finishing second and
a family and career to have.
Remember when I
came to collect from school?
Just before I left?
- No.
You had 39 degrees fever.
The school nurse called
for you to collect.
Mum was at work and
I had no job because I ...
When I got there ...
They did not give me.
It was not yet half past nine
Morning and I was already drunk.
I remember no more.
You know what I did remember?
The first time you took me
for a ride in this beast.
I had the whole trip butterflies in my stomach.
That feeling of acceleration was so intense.
I was very scared before.
Then I felt safe.
Because I knew you behind the wheel.
How hard it is to hear, I am happy.
It was better that I have in recent years
was not, it was not a pretty picture.
Then just hated me more.
- I hated you.
I never hated.
An occasional visit would have been nice.
Yes. I should have been there.
Thanks, I ask later
get a ride to Max.
Hello, Krueger, where is your car?
He gets new tires?
- Yes, guys. I do not anymore.
Where's Fernando?
He would normally have to play Ben.
I Am a need.
He sits on the toilet.
- Do you kidding me?
I'll do it.
Nice that you want to do, Danny.
Ok, before you start ...
I want you in your own words say what
Do you think Claire wants to say.
Okay, just keep in mind
he is a compulsive gambler and ...
He just bet all his money on it wrong
horse, now he must answer.
I think he wants to offer his apologies.
Excuses?
He wagered just her wedding ring.
You will have to do better as "I'm sorry".
He would say he was stupid.
Him and that his addiction was just too much.
Well. What else?
He would say he should have listened
to her when she wanted to help him.
And he would say, thank you.
You're welcome.
This is a familiar face. Long ago
I have seen you again driving that thing.
I thought I'd dust it off and apply today
my son with them to school.
I think you've heard that our
boys had a collision last night ...
as we used to.
Kendall only won it once.
It's good for business if he wins.
Other children will then
along and give all their money.
I'm not sure if your son
future in racing.
But you can always name your
case change in Krueger and son.
You know what, Jimmy?
It's one thing to know how the
components of your car can change.
It's another thing to know
how they all work together.
Hello, boy.
- What is it?
Remember that today is the last day to
toestemmingsbewijsjes you to bring.
So give them away if you have them.
I'm glad you're participating.
Will you be part
from my pit crew?
Absolutely.
We have three days, guys, so let
the front strip, stripping everything.
Can you still use a few hands?
Thanks.
Protectors, the front cross member,
radiator support ...
2 arms, intercooler,
the large air intake and total ...
We do not get that, it's too much.
Tomorrow at school, everyone goes home.
We come together again tomorrow.
Hi, Randy.
Same for you.
Do you still interested in my Buick?
I'm Greg, hello.
Long ago.
What can I do for you?
I want you to make a price,
it is for my son.
He participates in the school race.
Have you sold the Buick?
- Yes.
There should be enough to
for the rest of your stuff.
But he needs you
your first trophy worried.
Time to leave the past and
to concentrate on what's coming.
Thanks, Dad.
That's the least I could do.
Help me now to unload this stuff.
The right button makes your car is ready
and the left button makes the nitro finished.
Kendall has a heavier
engine and a supercharger ...
and you have 200 units of nitrogen under your thumb.
If the light turns green, hit it.
Keep it pressed all the time.
Yes, a GT-40 Mansfield. Is that the
best price you can give me?
The rocket fuel.
How does it feel?
Feels good and sounds good.
I have a little surprise.
I do not like surprises.
That's good advertising for the garage.
You would think there is need to
here to change to an import dealer.
Ok, good work everyone.
We go racing tomorrow.
Welcome everyone, to the NHRA racing school.
With over 65 students and 32 schools,
this is the biggest event ever.
Look out for the home favorite and Jake Kendall
the whole team of Kendall Performance Centers.
And newcomer Danny Krueger this year ...
that drives a 2.5 liter, four cylinder,
four-wheel drive Subaru STI.
It is one of the few four-cylinder
and that goes against all these big V8's.
Let's see if this Subaru
There has to cope.
We would like to thank all our sponsors ...
You load it, I'm going to register us.
Next to the warm up lap
Miguel Sanchez ...
with its classical turbo diesel
truck, "Little Red".
11.22 and 11.41. I have these two
see all the faster cars go so ...
I do not think they have given everything.
You go down, Krueger.
It is hereditary.
Like father, like son.
It seems that you
have chosen the wrong team, Jess.
It seems that I
have chosen the wrong girlfriend.
Ignore them,
You need to stay focused.
Here.
We are ready to go.
- Fantastic.
Let's us be at the start,
The formation lap is almost over.
The first round we must provide
we end up under 13 seconds.
That would not be a problem.
This is the last race in the warm up lap
Danny Krueger in STI.
His opponent was Alex Dod ...
with the classic Mustang
Washington secondary.
Look at the burn-out.
Dod make the tires nice and sticky so
he maximum grip on the starting line.
It is not necessary to warm up your tires
if you have a four-wheel-drive Subaru.
Krueger had some problems with the
starting line and the Mustang was gone.
Let's see if he can overtake Krueger.
It failed.
Alex comes in at 12.29 ...
Danny Krueger, there is only
correct with his 12.98.
The race has been won.
I know.
- Come on, man.
The circuit is thicker than the street,
I did not expect that.
And the strength ...
- Each round Now you have time drop.
You would have to have around 11.
If you lose a race,
is done. Concentrate.
To all our racers,
we go to round n.
Now the starting line, Grant Warner
with his 1969 Oldsmobile 442.
Grant is quite the summer practicing ...
and let me say this,
wheeler that bars are not just for luck.
The opponent, Jake Kendall,
with his 2011 Mustang GT.
These are our fastest racers
who compete against each other.
And take a look at Jake, who thumb
down is for Grant.
Jake is confident.
It seems that Grant
fast car has to go ...
who goes on the trailer home.
Jake Kendall won with a time
of 10.98 and went 127 miles per hour.
As next, Danny Krueger
STI against his ...
Kevin Bakar and his 1970 Chevy Nova.
Let's see if Danny
This leaves more time.
A good start for Danny,
He stands for the Nova.
And he did it.
Danny Krueger goes to the next round ...
with a time of 11.40 and 121 miles per hour.
That was a tough ride.
It is difficult to Andrea Faust and her hot,
Dodge rose about to overlook.
This girl racing all her life.
She knows how the boys
to give a firm ride.
They sure like to see her race.
Andrea Faust goes to the next round.
There is some competition between these young
and they're certainly not done.
Let's see what they can do.
H, how are you?
How are you?
- Good to see you.
You too.
Do you too?
No, we belong to Danny Krueger.
- With the Subaru.
He looks good.
As a birthday cake.
In the quarterfinals are still
Kendall Performance a racer ...
Bradford for the secondary,
Clint Johnson with his 1969 Chevy Chevelle ...
which takes on Danny Krueger in his
Corvaille from The Fast And The Furious.
The winner goes to the semifinals.
An easy victory for Krueger
with 11.17 against 11.88 of Johnson.
Yes, successfully.
In the first semifinal
Andrea Faust, we ...
with her beautiful brown hair
From the Patriot secondary ...
by Jake Kendall with
Mustang is from Bradford.
Jake Kendall goes to the final.
This is the fastest ride today.
For the next semi-final ...
We Miguel Sanchez
with his Dodge truck ...
against Krueger in STI.
Hi, Tom.
- Neil, how are you?
Karl, Tom Bricks.
- How are you?
Well.
You have three of your students there.
Impressive.
A guess who will win?
Is that what you are going to give me?
The liquids are ok.
Everything checked? Ready to go?
What an idiot.
That thing has a lot of torque,
He will beat you to the starting line ...
no doubt. Let him not be distracted.
Stay focused on maximum torque.
You get him in the end,
then you have won.
Fun, h?
- Yes.
Danny Krueger gets him on the last.
Ladies and gentlemen, Danny Krueger continues.
He took it just in time.
What?
He did it.
An unexpected victory.
I can not believe this little Subaru
has made it to the final.
But Krueger's work is not over.
Jake Kendall has been faster rounds
Danny Krueger traveled than ever.
Danny must hope for a miracle.
Or at least a few more cylinders.
What do you mean?
- The thrust increase ...
otherwise I think I better not
can do more than my last trip.
Danny, what are you doing?
Your turbo is running at maximum,
you will blow up your engine.
It is only at 23 bar
it is a bit higher.
I do a benefit show.
Do you know how a few
seconds of your time can do?
How?
Powershift with this ride.
Is not that just as dangerous?
- Not unless you screwed up.
Make us proud.
I do not want to embarrass us Krueger.
That would be very bad, you know?
Yes, sir.
Is it almost done?
Yes, the new tires are on it
and the dampers are off.
You would have to go faster now,
but not too fast.
Yeah, okay.
Here we are,
the final of the NHRA racing school.
What is power shifting?
It's off without
accelerator release.
In turbo cars keeps the engine ...
at full speed between two
gears for maximum acceleration.
You need fast
for it to be.
There is no room for
errors or otherwise 'boom'.
RICE DID YOU?
Go.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
It is my honor ...
Danny Krueger for this year to call
as the winner of the NHRA racing school.
Congratulations, you have talent.
See you next summer.
Thank you.
Maybe your idea is not so bad.
Any idea?
In order to transform my garage
to import a race shop.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org