This is Captain Moreti to unit five.
Pick up Brannigan. Use a forklift
if you have to, but get him.
APB on Lieutenant James Brannigan.
Brannigan.
Cream sports. You know the licence.
- Knock, knock.
- Breaking and entering's against the law.
I rang. You didn't answer.
I was working.
Doing your own engraving now?
Hey! Wouldn't know
old Abe without his mole.
Where's Larkin?
No serial number, no prints,
can't be traced...
Nobody'll know who dumped you.
I don't spook, Brannigan.
All right.
The government wants Larkin for taxes.
Chicago police want him for extortion.
Cut out the dedicated-cop act. Everybody
in this town knows you want Larkin.
And the grand jury finally indicts him
and he disappears.
And I'll give you five seconds
to tell me where. You count.
Hey, wait a minute. Wait, OK.
- He left town.
- How?
- I don't know.
- Where?
I don't know. No, wait a minute.
I don't know. You gota believe me.
All right. Cool it.
You must be getin' old, Angell,
tryin' to push second-rate paper like this.
Manny, this is Warehouse 17, Polk Street.
- I got a paperhanger.
- Turn around, big man.
- Angell, you're a real bush-leaguer.
- Yeah?
- Know somethin'? I don't think it's loaded.
- You dirty, lousy Mick!
You got no rules! You got no...
Jim? Jim, are you all right?
Are you all right, Jim?
Moretti's steaming. You got the whole
Chicago PD looking for you.
- Nice to be wanted.
- You're wanted all right.
- There's an APB out on you.
- Listen, Brannigan, you're dead.
There's a contract out on you.
Try explaining that to your parole officer.
Larkin's put up 25 Gs
to get you knocked off.
You're gonna be walking down the street,
or sleeping, or siting on the can,
and the next minute,
Brannigan, you are dead!
You lousy Mick, you!
Brannigan.
He's on the inside, far end of 17.
Not him.
Who?
You. The captain wants to see you. Now.
- You got a warrant?
- I don't need a warrant, Jim.
- You're a public menace.
- All right.
- Get in.
- That's my car.
Joe'll bring your car.
Careful of the paint job.
British Airways flight 570
nonstop 747 to London
will depart from the B concourse.
Ah, you made it.
All right, Captain. You goin' someplace?
No, Lieutenant.
- You are.
- I am?
- What is this, Moreti?
- Passport, airline ticket, 500 expenses.
- I packed a bag for you.
- That is my bag.
I put everything in that was clean.
Here, don't catch cold.
You're gonna make somebody
a nice litle wife.
- I'm doin' you a favour, Jim.
- Yeah.
- Ben Larkin got outa town.
- I know that.
- He's in London. Scotland Yard's got him.
- London?
You got extradition papers.
Miss Allen? I thought you might like
to bring him back and kick him in a cell.
- Miss Allen, Lieutenant Brannigan.
- Hi.
- She'll find a seat for you.
Just follow me, Lieutenant.
Anywhere.
Nice day.
- Want to walk, Mel?
- All right. You're on.
By the right!
Keep up there!
First order of business -
call off the wolves.
Even the elevator man looks
like he's from Scotland Yard.
It may not be as simple as that.
What broke loose?
The word was in the street, Ben.
Somebody talked, somebody listened.
Chicago is sending Jim Brannigan over
with extradition papers and handcuffs.
He'll be at Heathrow any time now.
I told you I wanted
that Irish bastard wasted.
It's being taken care of, Ben.
That won't help your extradition problem.
There'll only be a dozen cops
on the next flight with more papers.
Well, I'm not running. I like this town.
I like the women, the clubs, the action.
- I always did.
- Ben, please. Listen to what I worked out.
Now, in Devon,
at an airport nobody's used for years,
I've got a pilot who'll take you to Ireland
where you'll skip
immigration and customs.
Then you'll head on south
to Ecuador, Venezuela...
Oh, that's just great. I end up eating
bananas, listening to my arteries harden.
Ben... I'm talking to you as your lawyer,
your friend, not a tour guide.
The Cook County grand jury
can't touch you down there.
Look, the boys'll take care of you.
They have to. They've got
more skeletons than most graveyards.
- And you know what closets they hang in.
- Fields,
we didn't build this organisation by
running the grand juries to save our hides.
- We stick together.
- That's what I'm saying.
To the boys, you're still number one.
They'll see that you live like a king.
They'll use me as a conduit.
I'll funnel the cash to Switzerland,
launder it in Panama,
and ship it to you by bank drafts
or leters of credit, whichever you prefer.
That's good. That's good.
You know, Mel, those bananas
will taste a hell of a lot beter
when I know Brannigan's lying
in some guter.
It's done.
- Who you got?
- Gorman. We used him before.
Good. He's a pro.
Enough of the walking. Let's ride.
British Airways flight number BA570
from Chicago is now arriving at gate two.
Is flight 570 in yet?
- It's just arrived.
- Could you make the announcement?
Yes, of course.
- Have a nice stay.
- Thank you.
Would Mr James Brannigan,
British Airways passenger from Chicago,
please report to the British Airways
information desk?
James Brannigan, British Airways
information desk, please.
How long are you expecting
to be with us, Mr Gorman?
- Mr Gorman?
- Oh, sorry. A week.
Business or pleasure, sir?
Strictly pleasure.
- Lieutenant Brannigan?
- Yes? How did you know?
Headquarters told me to look for someone
slightly smaller than the Statue of Liberty.
Detective Sergeant Jennifer Thatcher.
Scotland Yard.
They've made real improvements
since I was last here.
Well, thank you. This way, sir.
Where's my man?
The prisoner, Ben Larkin.
Oh, Commander Swann
is handling the extradition.
- And the return ticket reservations?
- Sir Charles has taken care of that.
- He's expecting you for lunch at his club.
- Sir Charles?
Sir Charles?
I've been assigned as your driver,
and to take care of you while you're here.
- To keep an eye on me, you mean.
- Well, not quite. It's more of a PR job.
Anyway, it'll make a nice change
from the vice squad.
- All clear, sir.
- Right.
Mel...
I'm the one that's gonna take the heat.
Now, nothing can screw up.
Stay cool, Ben.
It's ticking like a Swiss watch.
- Good morning, Mr Larkin.
- Good to see you, Jules.
- Morning, Ben.
- Morning, boys.
Larkin's here.
Get me a box
at the dog races tonight, Gates.
Oh, yeah.
Call Jimmy-the-Bet and tell him
to put L400 on Triple Cross.
Ready when you are, Mr Larkin.
Good.
You've been to England before, sir?
That's right, Miss Thatcher -
during the war.
I expect you'll find London's changed
quite a bit, but it's basically the same.
It's still a very beautiful city.
If there are any places
you'd like to revisit...
Right now what I'd like is eight hours of
sleep, a shower and a change of clothes.
And to get my hands in Larkin's lapels.
Yes, sir.
Oh.
If I sound like a bear cub
with a toothache, it's just...
I understand, sir.
My father flew with the RAF.
Huh?
He said there were three things
wrong with Yanks.
- Yeah?
- Overpaid, oversexed...
and over here.
I really walked into that one.
And deserved it. I'm sorry.
Might we start again, sir?
Why? We're doing fine.
I was just thinking - can I call you Jenny?
Of course.
Boy, I knew a great gal named Jenny.
Whoo!
She used to lend me money
when I was broke.
Did she contribute
any other... philanthropies?
We were friends.
Good friends.
Damn good friends.
- All right, Mr Larkin.
- Hello, hello, hello.
Would you mind lying down,
facing this way?
- All right.
- And relax.
Excuse me, Captain. I've got
a steam cabinet out there for delivery.
Well, the pool's down there, but you'll
have to go outside. I'll show you the way.
Excuse me, Tom. There's a delivery.
What? I don't know
anything about a delivery.
- Neither do I.
- It's a rush order. Where shall we drop it?
You'd beter put it out there
through the open door.
Grand Central Station.
Hey, muscles. It's a bit tight here.
Can you give us a hand?
Excuse me a moment, Mr Larkin.
Now, what's all this?
That's great.
Oh, you like that, do you?
Yeah. Good.
How do you like that?
Morning, sir.
Here we are, sir. The Garrick Club.
- See you later, sir.
- Aren't you joining us?
If I walked in I'd cause
a dozen heart atacks.
It's a men's club - rules strictly enforced.
Too bad.
Sir?
Brannigan. Jim Brannigan.
To see Commander Swann.
Yes, that'll be Sir Charles.
He's in the lounge bar, upstairs.
- Thank you.
- Begging your pardon, sir...
I'm sorry, Mr Brannigan. It's a club rule.
Fine.
Strictly enforced, I presume.
And that was the last I saw of her.
Excuse me.
Lieutenant Brannigan? Charles Swann.
- Pleasant flight?
- Just long.
- Would you like a glass of sherry?
- Actually, I'd like a boilermaker.
That's whisky - neat, you'd say -
and a beer chaser, cold, if you can find it.
- Certainly, sir.
- I think we can manage that.
A good old Polish drink.
Where do we pick up this Larkin?
Well, he's under surveillance.
Surveillance? You come
to the States for a prisoner,
we'd have him standing by
handcuffed at the airport.
Yes, but under our judicial system
Mr Larkin has the right to apply for bail.
Well, unfortunately,
we have the same law.
- That's how we lost him.
- Rather careless, wasn't it?
You can rest assured
that won't happen here.
- Spot of lunch?
- Why not?
Then we'll pick up your friend Larkin.
- Should I call you Sir Charles?
- I think Swann'll do nicely, thank you.
I only use the "sir" for theatre tickets and
table reservations. May I lead the way?
Morning, sir.
Actually, the title is a military courtesy
granted to one of my ancient ancestors,
probably for holding
somebody's horse at a coronation.
- How's this?
- Thank you.
- No castles or booty?
- No, I'm afraid not.
But every Maundy Thursday,
for some reason,
I'm granted the inestimable privilege -
morning, Barker -
of dropping a sprig of myrtle
in the river Thames at Westminster.
- The Dover sole is excellent.
- Thank you. Dover sole?
Commander, it's my breakfast time.
I'd sure like two over easy,
some bacon, crisp, and a short stack.
Right. I think what my guest would like
is two eggs, lightly fried on either side,
a couple of rashers of bacon
and a modest portion of pancakes.
- Not too modest on the pancakes.
- Sir.
- And Dover sole for me, please.
- Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant, you shouldn't be wearing
that particular item.
Well, the fella at the front desk
said I had to put it on.
Not the tie.
The .38 calibre Colt Diamondback.
Commander, I always wear this.
I'm afraid it's placing you in violation of
British law and Scotland Yard regulations.
Well, it isn't in violation
of United States law,
and I work under the Chicago
Police Department regulations
which makes it obligatory.
Then I strongly urge you
to resist any temptation to use it.
Well, I don't think I'll be needing it in here.
Excuse me, Sir Charles.
A gentleman to see you at the door.
Excuse me.
Barker, bring the lieutenant a whisky
and a beer chaser, will you?
You mean a boilermaker, sir.
Make it two.
- What for?
- Mr Larkin has been kidnapped.
It can't happen here, huh?
Well, cheer up.
All we can lose is our jobs.
Oh. Gorman?
Yeah.
A friend said you had a package for me.
Two questions - from where and for what?
From Chicago, to hit something.
Right on, bucko.
Half now and half at ice time.
When he's on ice, you mean.
- A bit light.
- It's just my usual commission.
Off their end, not mine. Don't be difficult.
Why don't you stay awhile
and talk to Luana?
Hm?
Oh.
Nice and gentle, love. I'm not kinky.
You are what you're paid to be.
This is all that Larkin
left behind at the athletic club.
We don't know
he was really snatched.
Of course not. But we do still have
that masseur unconscious in hospital.
It might be just an act.
I don't think that's an assumption
the Yard can afford to make.
If it was up to me I'd get some men
out thumpin' on the streets,
passing out some e pluribus unum.
That's what 90 per cent
of police work is today.
The murder rate in your country, I'm sure,
gives testimony to your superior methods.
Commander, I didn't come
over here to argue methods.
But a certain Ben Larkin is missing, and
I intend to use my best efforts to find him.
Without interfering
with the Yard, of course.
Oh, er, Lieutenant.
I am still a litle concerned
about a certain item you're wearing.
Oh, well, if that bothers you...
wear it in good health.
The old school tie.
Well, guv, what do you think
of our friend Brannigan?
Well...
he's an American.
Sir Charles. Why would
a bona fide lord wanna be a cop?
Because he's good at it.
Why are you a cop?
I don't know. Runs in the family.
But it stops right here. My son is a lawyer.
Uh-huh?
Hello, Central? Central 77 here.
Mollie? Do me a favour, will you?
Call Richard and tell him I'll be late.
I don't know. About seven. Thanks.
Monkey wrench?
You mean a spanner?
Did I throw one in your social life?
Well, not quite.
Not that Richard is exactly
a paragon of patience.
Well, just blame it on your Yankee
slave-driver - who still hasn't eaten.
Would you mind grabbing a bite
before we house-hunt?
I wouldn't mind at all.
Thank you, Mrs Cooper.
- Lieutenant, I'll see you in the morning.
- Around nine?
Fine, sir. Good night.
Mr Lawyer, the next voice
you hear belongs to Ben Larkin.
You'd better listen.
Fields, I've been grabbed
by a couple of hoods.
They're tough, so you do exactly
what I tell you or I'm a dead man.
You got five envelopes with this tape.
First put L50,000 in each envelope -
get old, used bills.
You make the drop in person. Come to the
mailbox in the middle of Piccadilly Circus
at exactly 11.35am tomorrow morning.
You got that? Next, stay away
from those damn limey cops.
They'll just screw things up.
There's a gun at my head, Fields,
so don't blow this one.
My guys'll tear your heart out.
- Why'd you double-cross him, Fields?
- What does that mean?
Larkin told you
to stay away from the cops.
In Chicago, I would have. But, considering
the reputation of Scotland Yard,
I decided it was in the best interests of
my client to put the mater in their hands.
Oh, you're a real eagle scout, Fields.
- We don't even know it's Larkin's voice.
- Inspector.
Mr Larkin called in to complain
about our surveillance.
The call was routed through Central,
where it was in turn redirected
to the switchboard of our department.
In rather sulphurous language,
Mr Larkin demanded...
Yes, thank you, Mike.
The point is, we taped
Larkin's call, voiceprinted it.
They matched.
Do you think you can raise that money
by tomorrow morning?
That's no problem.
Fortunately Mr Larkin has generous
and influential associates in the States.
- Translation, Commander: hoods.
- A bank draft is on its way.
Mob money, squeezed out of hookers
and skimmed off of casinos.
Yes, well, er, I think we perhaps
beter get on with it, Mr Fields.
Commander, what will you be doing?
Well, our interests are mutual -
the safe return of Mr Larkin.
We'll keep you informed.
It's a bit dicey.
Not a copper in sight.
They're down there, all right.
I can smell 'em.
- Morning, sir.
- Morning.
Atention all units.
Rolls-Royce approaching the circus.
Drop completed.
Prepare for pick-up phase.
Well, now we'll see.
The mail van's just passed me.
Approaching the island now.
It's too damn simple.
- Pick-up completed.
- Right, job completed. Let's go.
We'll take him.
It's a messenger on a scooter.
We're on him.
Right. Get going.
- Like I said...
- Too damn simple.
That's right. Too damn simple.
Don't get too far behind.
Hold it!
- Can you swim?
- Yeah.
- Go get it.
- Argh!
I'll sink with these boots on!
Oi, give us a hand!
After a few questions.
What's the idea of throwin'
this money in the river?
Money? I don't know nothing
about no money.
Some bloke mailed me instructions
with a L5 note.
- Newspaper!
- What?!
They pulled a murphy!
Hey, what about me?
A murphy?
OK.
Yeah,
they tunnelled from underneath.
Yes, of course. And then
they switched envelopes by means of a...
A false botom.
As simple as that.
A magnet?
Ruddy sewers.
They'll be miles away by now.
I'll be right back.
Hello, Mrs Cooper.
Good afternoon, Mr Brannigan.
- Would you like a coffee?
- Oh, thank you, no.
- Some people are waiting for me.
- Ah.
Oh, Mrs Cooper?
Yes, Mr Brannigan?
- Did I have any visitors today?
- No, I don't think so.
Thank you.
Oh, there was a man here.
Something about the central heating.
- What happened?
- Your central-heating friend left a present.
- We must call the police.
- He is the police.
- You're insured?
- Oh, yes, I am.
- Jim?
- In here.
- What are you doing?
- Well, I'm afraid that the... I'll show you.
- You mean he's put another one in there?
- I mean...
Yes.
Yeah.
Larkin paid 25 grand to get me that view.
- All the usual checks being made?
- Yes, sir.
Ah-ah. All being fingerprinted, guv.
I want a complete report on all sales
of gelignite in the past two months.
And try and trace that damn thing.
- Where is he?
- Downstairs at Mrs Cooper's, sir.
Oh, don't you look nice!
- Thank you.
- I'm sorry I haven't a room available.
- I can make room in my place.
- That's kind but...
- It'd be a pleasure.
- Lieutenant.
We ought to show our visitor
a bit of British hospitality.
- Why don't you take him out for dinner?
- Yes, sir.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
And leave the police work to the Yard.
- Thank you very much, Mrs Cooper.
- Oh, yes, Mrs Cooper, thank you.
Enjoy yourself, Lieutenant.
I will.
Perhaps you'd care for a cup of coffee.
Come along.
Well...
But it says "for sale".
I can get them to rent it to you,
if you don't mind me as your neighbour.
Why should I?
Puts me closer to my driver.
- It's been a lovely evening, Jim.
- Yeah, pleasant.
And I hate to change the mood.
- Jenny, I want you to do me a favour.
- You shouldn't have that. That's a felony.
- Is that so?
- Yes, that is so.
Commander Swann was not amused.
I had these names run down
by the department.
They all check out except that one.
- Jimmy-the-Bet.
- That's right. You know him?
Yeah. He's a bookie. He's also a grass -
what you call a stoolie.
He's got his eye on every keyhole
in London. Is it important?
Anything that has to do
with Larkin is important.
He's in blackmail, extortion, hard drugs -
you name it, he's in it.
Jenny, I just happen to be working
the other side of the street.
Is that all?
Well, a couple of years ago
I was makin' it tough for him and...
one night he hit back.
Pair of shotguns.
He obviously missed.
But the rookie riding with me
took a blast in his face.
He left a widow and a couple of nice kids.
I'm sorry, Jim.
You must have been close to him.
Well, that'd make a good story.
But that's not the reason.
The truth is, I hated his guts
and he didn't like me.
He had a degree in criminology and...
Well, the hell with that. I...
My job was to keep him alive
until he could get smart enough
or tough enough to take care of himself.
I blew it.
What's that for?
I don't know.
You're just so... damn solid.
Fat, you mean.
- Telephone for you, sir.
- Thank you.
Hello?
Yes, Inspector.
Yes, right away.
He wants us back at the office.
Yes, well, there's no doubt
that fingerprint is Larkin's.
Oh. Forgive me for interrupting
your evening, Lieutenant.
Jenny, the artist has a sketch of our mad
bomber in 194. Pick it up for me, will you?
Your theory that Larkin may have staged
his own kidnapping doesn't quite work.
- Is that so?
- Someone sent a contribution from him.
Did you print it?
Of course.
Third finger of the left hand.
And it was accompanied by a demand
for an additional 350,000 quid.
That brings the ante up
to a million and a half dollars.
The additional payment was a penalty
because Mr Fields consulted the Yard.
- These gentlemen play rough.
- And smart.
They certainly made bloody fools of us
in that Piccadilly caper.
In all my years at the Yard
I've never received a finger in the post.
Lord knows what they'll send us next.
Ah, thank you.
That's it. It's based
on your landlady's description.
We've wired copies to Interpol, the Suret?
and the FBI. Does it ring a bell for you?
No, but if Larkin has a contract
on me, he'd hire top talent.
Well, I want you on
the next flight to Chicago.
You care, Commander! You really care.
I want you in Chicago alive, you big sod.
I don't want you in London as an unsolved
homicide. We're short-staffed as it is.
We have the same trouble in Chicago,
Commander. Good night.
Good night.
Oh! Lieutenant.
- I'll take that particular item.
- You mean, uh...?
- The notepad.
- Oh.
Yes, I-I, uh... I guess
I picked this up by mistake.
Yes, of course. That's what I'd assumed.
- Good night.
- Good night, sir.
Darling, I've got a problem.
I've got to stay on duty till two.
Yeah, well, here comes my problem.
- Jim, this is my fianc? Richard Nelson.
- How are you?
So you're the guy
who's been ruining our love life.
- I'm glad you're not 20 years younger.
- If I were, you'd have to worry.
Well, we're not finished yet.
One more call. I'm sorry.
- Good night, love.
- Good night.
- OK. Where to?
- Jimmy-the-Bet.
Oh. You watch him.
He's a tough customer.
- Evening.
- I've no time for bird cops.
- I've got a thousand pounds on this fight.
- This isn't social, it's official. Open up.
It still isn't social.
- I'm a cop.
- It shows, flatfoot.
And I found your name
on a notepad of Benny Larkin's.
- Is he one of your customers?
- I got nothing to say to you. Out!
Benny Larkin's been kidnapped.
You're gonna give me some information.
I can ask questions easy or
I can ask 'em hard. Which'll it be?
This is what I answer questions with.
It's mighty persuasive. I guess
the questions can wait. But not for long.
Argh!
Now, would you like to try for England's
free dental care or answer my question?
I'll ask it just once.
- Name a name.
- Drexel.
- Did you hear another?
- No, I swear it.
- Where can I find this Drexel?
- A pub.
He goes there. The Lamb Tavern.
He goes there midday.
Well, thanks, Jimmy.
You know something?
That Jackson's a bum.
He won't make it through the eighth.
Jackson's hurt! He's down!
- Any trouble?
- No trouble.
A litle hard to understand his accent.
- That's Scotch rump steak.
- I'll have that one.
I don't mind this turning into a shopping
tour as long as it ends up with Drexel.
I say. Talk of the devil.
That's him in the grey suit,
walking towards the pub now.
Fine. Would you just give me time
to get a litle friendly?
Mind if I but in, partner?
- It's a free country.
- All right, Navy?
- It's a pleasant country.
- I wouldn't argue with that.
Last time I was here, people were
getin' bombed a different way.
- Doris, let's have some service here.
- What do you want?
- Some Guinness. How about you?
- Same again.
- Good. Navy?
- I got enough, thanks.
- How is the second-best navy?
- You should know.
Nice one, Ted.
Well, partner, cheers.
Wait a minute, friend. We're havin' a drink.
Drexel, I'd like a few words.
Let's step outside.
- Scotland Yard. Can't you smell it?
- Is it illegal to have a drink?
May I suggest that you keep out of this?
This is police business.
Oh, tell him to show you his badge.
Drexel, I said outside. Now come on.
That cuts it.
Sorry. Sorry.
It wasn't me! What you trying to...?
- What's the idea?
- Well, who the hell started it?
Awfully sorry.
Henry!
Ah! Guv.
Ah-ah-ah.
Guv.
- Ah, Mike. Have you got it?
- Seems likely, guv.
Gwendolyn Rooke, female,
Caucasian, age 26...
- Well, get on with it, then.
- The subject resides in Balham...
- Sorry, lady. If I were you...
- Look out!
Huh? Oh.
...and has access to blueprints
for telephone and sewage conduits...
under Piccadilly Circus.
This place is getin' kinda unfriendly.
- Where are we goin'?
- Let's go to my place and have a drink.
Are you all right?
Come on, partner.
We beter get outa here.
- The Yank's got our pigeon.
- As far as I can see.
Yes, well. Perhaps we'd beter look her
over, see what Miss Rooke has to say.
Oh, and, er, Mike, while you're at it,
run this lot of rowdies in, will you?
Right, guv.
'Scuse me. How's your wrist?
Ah, Constable. Arrest that lot, will you?
It had nothing to do with me!
I'm only here for the beer!
I think you'll find the evidence
is conclusive, sir, if you examine the map.
Thanks, Mike.
Last month, the, erm...
the 16th, to be exact,
you made copies of maps
detailing the electrical and sewage
conduits beneath Piccadilly Circus.
- That's what I'm paid to do, sir.
- Of course.
- To whom did you give those copies?
- To one of my supervisors, I expect.
Miss Rooke, both you and I know
that that is not true.
Protecting a criminal, Miss Rooke,
is a crime in itself,
and I suggest that in your own
best interests you stop lying to me.
It's OK. It's OK. It's OK.
- Miss Rooke!
- I've always been a good girl, sir.
I'm sure you have, my dear,
but to whom did you give them?
To my boyfriend. Freddy.
Freddy.
- Now, now, come on.
- Whoops! Watch it, partner.
- I'm only just...
- You're a handful.
I like Americans. They think big.
Wait till you see what I got here.
- Take a look at this.
- Look at what?
I've got a deal goin' here
that'll make your hair stand on end.
Uh-uh.
Now, now. You're geting too familiar.
I've only just met you.
We're only acquaintances yet.
What I think you need, fella,
is a cup of coffee.
- I need another drink.
- Get in the kitchen.
Come on, let's have a fight. Marquess
of Queensberry rules. Let's have a drink.
Give me a minute and I'll fix you up,
if I can find the coffee.
- I don't want any coffee.
- Maybe you'll have to setle for tea.
I want a drink.
All right, buster, the friendly hour's over.
Wake up.
Come on. Get up.
Hold it up down there!
Get off, you stupid-lookin' mut.
Whoops! Sorry.
Police, son. Follow that car.
What? Police? What... What car?
- Right-hand drive.
- Of course.
I say, this is actually a new car, you know.
You're not really supposed
to go beyond 4,000 revs...
...till the 1,000-mile inspection.
Please look out. Oh! Agh!
I was rather hoping to keep it
for a year or so.
I wonder if I might get you
a taxi or something.
Oh! Argh!
Hang on.
- I feel sick.
- Not in here!
Oh, nuts.
No!
I waited a year for delivery.
Very good. Thank you.
Well, Lieutenant. How did you, er...
enjoy your sightseeing tour?
The view from the bridge was terrific.
Incidentally, regarding that automobile,
where would you like it shipped?
- Hm?
- You bought it, you know.
- Cor, handsome.
- Freddy.
- Yes, Mike?
- Nothing, guv.
It's not fair. My eyes are murderin' me
looking at all those bloody pictures.
- You smoke when I tell you.
- Listen, I know my rights.
Don't start talking about rights.
I'll tear you limb from limb.
- Oh, aye?
- Now, who did you sell those plans to?
- I don't know what you're talkin' about.
- Poor ignorant wee laddie, isn't he?
They do have libraries inside, Freddy,
and I'll put you away for so long,
you'll come out a bloody PhD!
Swann.
I'd tell that fella what he wants to know.
He likes to hurt people.
Today at a bar there was a fight.
He bit a guy's ear off.
- Him?
- And that's not all.
What, him?
We'll be in touch. No more calls.
Look. I've really had you, you creep.
OK.
OK. He gave me L100
to sell him the plans.
- Who did?
- Charlie.
Charlie Kane!
Put him up.
- That's Charlie!
- Take him away.
And that's our man.
That's the fella that nailed Drexel.
- Are you sure?
- I saw him.
Boy, oh boy, it's really coming together.
That was Fields. They're calling tomorrow
with instructions for the next payment.
- Give us time to trace the call?
- I wish we could.
- They're calling on a marine frequency.
- They ain't amateurs.
- Jim? Where are you going?
- Have you got the keys to your car?
- I forgot my notebook.
- Sure. I'll get it.
No!
You'll get your hair wet!
You wanna bet?
Jenny, look out!
Jenny!
You all right?
- Are you all right?
- No.
What's the mater?
- Well, look at my hat.
- Oh.
Your hat.
Let's get outa this.
Yes, sir.
Dammit, I'm having to take more flak
than an air gunner over Normandy on this.
Forget the commissioner. Now we've got
the Home Secretary blowing his top,
demanding to know what kind
of a lunatic I've turned loose.
- This isn't Chicago, you know.
- That's right.
- You can't buy a decent hamburger.
- You're a bloody magnet for trouble.
First the man hired to kill you
blows up an apartment.
Then you demolish an automobile
in what must be one of the most brazen,
reckless stunts in the annals of this city.
Then you turn a perfectly peaceful street
into a shooting gallery!
If I hadn't done some shooting, Jenny'd be
lying on a marble slab right now!
Exactly! Simply because
she was mistaken for you!
I've asked you politely. Now I'll
ask you impolitely. Give me that gun!
I haven't got it!
Well?
This just arrived
from the FBI in Washington DC.
- Got a name for him?
- Name of John Gorman.
An habitu?of New Orleans, Louisiana.
- Do you know him?
- Well, I know about him.
Word is that he's a stud who won't quit.
We'll pick him up.
Send out a top-priority signal.
Right away, sir.
Yes?
Joseph Brannigan, long distance.
Hello.
Hello, big stuff.
Sure. Fine.
You did? Well, what's the dope?
Uh-huh.
Wait, let me get this straight.
Jupiter equity fund.
He bought 20,000 shares at 49,
sold them at three. Whoo!
That makes Melvin
a living, breathing pauper.
Sure, I will. Be home soon.
Your son? What's his line of work?
- Ballet.
- I should have guessed.
No, he's assistant district atorney
for Cook County.
Anything in that conversation
I should know about?
Commander, I wish it were Christmas.
Have I got some kind of a present for you.
Yes.
Right. Thank you.
- Mr Fields is on his way up, sir.
- You know where he's parked.
Nine, lower level.
I got to the bank at the stroke of ten,
but it took eight clerks until now
to get this package together.
We were worried about you, Melvin.
- Make yourself right at home, Brannigan.
- I have.
We are now ready and willing
to make the payment.
Mr Fields, we have some new information,
and we are now very close to
a breakthrough in this case. Very close.
Oh?
Within four hours, or five at the most, we
expect to have Mr Larkin home and safe.
I strongly suggest, therefore,
that, in the best interests of your client,
you delay payment for those few hours.
No way.
This time I do exactly what they tell me.
You pay that money now and
you'll get Larkin back in chunks.
The lieutenant quotes
chapter and verse, Mr Fields.
This is a gentleman who rejoices
in the name of Charlie-the-Handle,
identified as a member
of the kidnap team.
He will lead us to Mr Larkin.
Kind of unusual, Melvin.
Couple of cops telling you
what's best for your client.
Knock it off. If Larkin's friends
find out I'm in bed with the Yard,
they'll part my hair with a blowtorch.
It's all there. You don't have to count it.
If you lose Larkin and that loot, they'll part
more than your hair with that blowtorch.
Earthy but accurate,
I would have thought.
If you'll accept my apologies, I really
must insist that you give us the time.
Something's coming in, sir.
Put it on the speaker.
Calling Mel Fields on 17.35.
Now you contact us
on marine frequency 15.2.
Repeat: 15.2. We will use
different frequencies to contact you
and you will have only four seconds
to make the change.
Calling Mel Fields.
Calling Mel Fields on 17.35.
Are you there, Fields?
- This is Mel Fields.
- Now, I'm gonna give it to you just once,
so get it good.
This is how you make the drop.
You leave the hotel in exactly ten minutes.
Make sure you come alone.
Have you got that, Fields?
Yes, I've got it.
But I've run into a slight snag.
- What's the problem?
- There's no problem.
But the bank needs four or five hours
more to get the money together.
- What do you think, Geef? Coppers?
- For his sake, I hope not.
- Listen, Fields...
- Come on, Mel. Bring the money here!
Bring it!
All right, you've just bought yourself
four hours. And then you've had it.
Then you've had it.
All right.
You've got four hours to get Larkin back.
But if you don't, I make the payment,
and I won't tell you where or when.
- Fair enough.
- And, Commander Swann,
I want your word that there'll be
no surveillance of any kind.
You have my word, sir.
Oh, and be sure to call room service
if you need anything.
I will.
Find anything?
She's clean, sir, except for this.
A long-range homing device.
Can't trust anybody these days.
Stay back. Not too close.
It's OK. He's alone.
Well, come on. Make the payoff
and let's get the hell outa here.
Not yet, Ben.
- What do you mean, not yet?
- Charlie. Geef.
- You're early, Fields.
- Yeah.
- Has he been a good boy?
- He never raised a finger.
Ooh.
Bad joke, Geef.
Good job, Charlie.
- Well, come on, get 'em off!
- Get back...
on your big, fat rear.
Mel.
What's going on?
You know, I think it's about time.
Yes.
But this is my party, Charlie.
Ben...
The first time we met, you told me
something I've never forgoten.
It's my golden rule, you might say.
Never trust anybody.
Mel, have you gone out of your...?
We pulled it off, Ben. We did it!
I'm sorry about your finger.
I'm really sorry.
I bet you are.
For a million bucks, it was worth it.
And don't forget that first payment
I've got stashed away.
- How do we get this off?
- The key's by the mirror.
It's first class for you all the way
to South America, and on into the sunset.
This makes up for that bath I took
in that Jupiter stock.
Yeah. Sorry about that.
And we got wall-to-wall alibis.
Oh, Scotland Yard'll swear that
I cooperated, made the payments.
And even that big clown Brannigan
backs up our story.
As long as he's alive.
You know, Mel, for a minute,
when you had that gun on me...
I thought you were gonna get greedy.
You know, for a minute,
Ben, I was tempted.
But what the hell kind of world would it be
if you couldn't trust somebody, hm?
We've been had.
- Knock, knock.
- Brannigan!
I wouldn't.
Unless you wanna sing soprano.
Earthy, but I agree with my friend.
They're all yours, Lieutenant.
Don't worry about me, James.
Bye-bye.
And I mean bye-bye.
That fella don't quit easy, does he?
Do you think you can hang onto 'em until
I can get 'em a couple of airplane tickets?
I think we could manage that, yes.
I just hope you don't lose them
back in the Colonies.
- Safe trip.
- Thank you.
How about a lift, Yank?
Gorman. Jim!
- Jim! Jim?
- I'm all right.
Hold it here.
Now!
Get behind that car!
Well...
I'm gonna miss this old town.
It's gonna miss you.
I'm not sure if I agree with what
my old dad said about you Yanks.
You mean that part about being overpaid?
No. Over here.
- Jenny, it's been great.
- It has.
So long.
Subtitle Time Ajusting Program by FZ