Attention please, we are landing
in Naples at Capodichino Airport.
All passengers are kindly requested
to fasten their seatbelts.
May I?
- Everything all right, Father?
- Yes, my child.
Why don't you sit here with me?
It's against regulations.
A good deed is never
against regulations.
Air conditioning? Certainly.
Fasten your seatbelt please.
LOADED GUNS
- Where's Nora?
- I dunno! Get in.
I was sure I'd find you
with a man! Was he nice?
Generous. He gave me 100 dollars
to deliver this letter.
Maybe he gave you his home address.
Well then, 100 dollars isn't enough!
- Beautiful, isn't it?
- Naples is full of warmth.
- It's marvellous.
- The people are full of warmth too.
Can you stop here, please?
I've got to get off.
- Where are you going?
- To run that errand.
- I'll see you at the hotel.
- So, they call it an "errand" now!
It's an amusement park, silly!
What is it, Father?
I started out
as a missionary in Africa.
We're in the same hotel, but I
expect you'll want an early night.
IT'S SPRING
YOU CAN SEE IT, I CAN'T
You're gorgeous!
- May I help you?
- I have a letter for Mr Silvera.
- Give it to me.
- I have to deliver it personally.
Follow me.
Women always follow me.
You're beautiful! This way.
Women always come with me.
Posillipo, Mare Chiaro. You know it?
I'll take you there too.
We're here. I'll wait for you.
He's brought personality
to the team.
Excuse me, I have a letter
for Mr Silvera.
- Mr Silvera?
- That's me.
Well, I'd better be going.
No, we always send a reply.
- It's from the American.
- The American's here?
- Who gave you this letter?
- You'd better answer.
A man at the airport
asked me to do him a favour.
He said he couldn't
deliver it himself
because he was leaving right away.
He said it was important.
- He gave me 100 dollars.
- Describe him.
- I really don't know...
- Not the face!
He was a tall, heavily built man.
He was wearing a Panama hat
and big dark glasses.
I didn't really see his face.
That's all I can tell you,
I don't know anything.
You hardly said a thing.
100 dollars.
Her name's Nora Green.
What was in the letter?
The American says I'm a dead man.
It's his style,
but he's made a mistake
by warning me.
If she brought the letter, she must
work for him. I'm sure of it!
Only one thing's for sure
with the American.
Whoever sees him never lives
to describe him. He works alone.
- But she...
- I think she's telling the truth.
But she must've seen him.
You don't send a death sentence
without making sure it's delivered.
The American is close by
so he can check up on her.
- It's not true that he left.
- Oh yes, the American's here.
But he'll be very sorry
that he stuck around,
because she'll lead me
right to him.
Where are you staying?
The company booked us
into the Holiday Inn.
Think you could recognise him
if you saw him again?
Maybe.
- Maybe yes or maybe no?
- Maybe yes.
Okay, stay in town
until he makes contact with you.
The plane can leave
minus one hostess.
But they'll want to know why.
Because of your health.
Your health's in danger.
- What do you mean?
- Get this through your head:
We don't play games.
And I don't have to remind you
to keep quiet
about what happened
in here.
Not a word to anybody,
understand?
Now get her out of here!
Follow her.
Miss!
How lovely!
She's like a statue.
Miss!
Are you sleeping?
What's she dreaming about?
So smooth!
The tits...
- I really like you!
- Tano, what are you doing?
- Dirty pig!
- What do you want?
- Leave me alone!
- Beat it!
Jealous!
I saw her first!
I know how to handle women!
I've had more than you!
And I satisfied all of them!
I never had any complaints!
I'll come looking for her!
Don't lose them.
He's asking for trouble.
He's taking her home!
Okay, pull up here.
Get out! Everybody out!
Manuel, you said we could
stay here today.
- Some friend!
- Get out!
Beat it!
- Who are you?
- Just get some rest.
This is my place.
You're safe here.
I've got to go out
but I'll be back soon.
Get some sleep
and you'll feel better.
Yes, it's a good idea.
- You're sure it's no trouble?
- Of course not!
I set it for eight.
I'll be back by then.
I'll get your uniform repaired.
You're very kind.
I don't know how to thank you.
Don't worry,
we'll work something out.
213, please.
Carmen, it's Nora.
Where the hell are you?
Chasing after some cute guy?
The captain was looking for you.
- What for?
- We've got engine trouble.
They're sending spare parts
from Turin,
so in the mean time
we're on holiday.
He wanted you to know.
So, what's this man like?
- What man?
- Don't tell me you're not in bed?
- What's he like?
- What's yours like?
Mine's divine! You know him.
I was surprised by his talents.
- Mine's adorable.
- And what's he like in bed?
I don't know yet. Bye, Carmen.
See you tomorrow, at the hotel.
It was a girl I work with.
I thought she might be worried.
- They roughed you up a bit, huh?
- About as much as I could take.
- Want something to drink?
- Oh, yes please!
Fine.
- Just two fingers.
- Okay.
- Here.
- Thanks.
What if Silvera doesn't like the idea
of your helping me?
You work there, right?
It's a risk I'm willing to take.
Anyway, my contract ran out.
I'll go somewhere else.
- What's your name?
- Manuel.
And yours?
My mother always told me
never to trust strangers,
but the man at the airport
seemed nice enough.
And I only delivered a letter
to Mr Silvera for him.
Want some music?
I didn't expect
a welcome like that.
What was in the letter?
I didn't read it,
but from the way they were talking,
it sounds like somebody
called the American
is in Naples and
threatening to kill Silvera.
They think he'll contact me
to ask if I delivered it.
Like to know more about
the American?
Oh God, no!
I don't want roughing up again.
I've never had a beating like that
in my life!
Maybe it's better
that you know everything.
Get dressed now.
- I've got nothing to put on.
- Don't worry.
What are you talking about?
Take anything you want.
My God! Where did you get
all those dresses?
This place is an open house.
Women come and go.
You'd be surprised
at what you can find here.
You should look good in this.
Like it?
It's gorgeous!
- Here!
- Thanks!
It's perfect.
What are all
these photographs?
Are you a boxer?
I used to be.
- But I quit.
- Why?
It was too hard.
Now I work as an acrobat,
it's more fun.
How do I look?
- You're fantastic.
- Thanks.
Come on, let's not waste any time.
We've got to go to the police.
You need protection.
- The police?
- Yes, come on.
- We'd better hurry.
- Shouldn't we just let it drop?
We'll go to Inspector Calogero.
He'll give you a hand.
And what'll I do with Calogero's hand?
Silvera told me not to tell anyone.
But if you really think
the police should know...
l do.
I really do.
Come on. It's near here.
Is the inspector here?
Ammirata, I'm talking to you!
May we come in?
Excuse me! Please...
...sit down.
Hi, Manuel.
You always keep good company.
Are you English?
They're Tuscan,
the finest Italian quality.
Give her a light.
Later. The first drag's bad,
the second one's worse.
I'm at your disposal for
whatever it is you need.
- You're very kind.
- Don't mention it.
Who is the American?
- Who's the American?
- An aperitif.
You want me to tell you
who the American is? Why?
He's in town and wants to kill Silvera.
That's good news.
Did the lady tell you that?
Give me your passport!
Passport.
Nice, eh?
But you're better in the ﬂesh.
She took a letter from the American
to Silvera and now she's bait.
- You've got to do something.
- I'm afraid I can't do much.
Arrest Silvera. The American leaves
and the girl has no more trouble.
There's no evidence.
- Arrest the American then.
- Sure, we'll arrest the American!
It's been five years, dammit,
that we've been trying
to arrest him!
Even the FBI
didn't manage it!
There are no documents,
or proof!
As soon as anyone sees his face,
they're dead!
Then he shows up:
"Why don't you arrest the American?"
As if it was a piece of cake!
His presence has been reported
all over the world!
There's a rumour going round
that he killed Anastasia
at the barbers.
He's always nearby
when drugs are involved.
Hashish, cocaine, LSD,
score settling...
He pits gangs against each other,
screws 'em and vanishes.
He's useful: He screws the gangs
while we try to screw him!
And this one asks
why we don't arrest him!
To make it short. lf l don't have
a case, I can't do a thing.
I've got to make a phonecall.
- What did you say?
- I said good evening.
Are you blind or deaf?
Let's go.
A prisoner governor asks a
condemned man in the electric chair:
"What can do I for you?"
"Hold my hand!"
"Today I'll get some sun!"
"Well, put it back afterwards!"
Government ministers
eat too much.
The cabinet they spend most time in
is the W.C.!
"Yes, who's speaking?"
"I haven't even said hello yet!"
- Are you busy, sir?
- No.
- And you?
Well let's get moving
or we'll be here all night!
Thank you.
- Hi, Rosy.
- My dear Manuel!
Is this your latest conquest?
Good luck, miss.
Few men are as good in bed
as Manuel.
And if I say that...
The American's in town
and he wants to kill Silvera.
Does Don Calf) know?
The only ones who know are
Silvera, Calogero and us.
Us? Who is she?
My name's Nora.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rosy.
The pleasure's all mine!
You're a very pretty lady.
From you, that's a real compliment.
Nora wants to know what'll happen.
She's very interested.
Silvera and Don Calo are the bosses
They've been feuding for years.
If the American is here,
there's going be trouble.
Big trouble for everyone.
I'm telling you this for free,
but if you bring plenty of money...
I'll tell you something else.
- Do me a favour. See those two?
- Yes.
Keep them busy for a while.
The forces of law and order, eh?
- Who's she?
- She was Silvera's mistress.
Then Calo's.
Maybe she's Calogero's mistress now,
but no one knows for sure.
She knows everything about everyone.
Ammirata must still be at the club.
You call this place home?
There's even a john
in the lounge!
I swear by the Blessed Virgin,
I've never seen a house
with a john in the lounge!
Now let's talk about you.
Outings to police headquarters
won't do you any good.
Silvera told you he didn't want
his private business going public.
And Silvera's always sorry when
someone doesn't do what he said.
You'd better go back to the hotel,
someone might come looking for you.
Curtain!
Stop him!
You took a bath, eh?
You still stink though.
Go dry yourself!
Come on, you big lump.
Inspector, we've got
some very rowdy guests here,
can you give us a hand?
I'm at Manuel's place.
Don't worry, I've got men everywhere.
Even outside Manuel's.
Now I'll kill you!
I'll kill you!
I'll send you to hell.
Bastard!
- At last!
- Where are they?
One's in the closet
and there's two on the bed.
They're friends, but they got drunk
and wrecked the place!
You're in trouble
because of me.
Sure, I'm in trouble,
but not because of you!
How disappointing.
I knew something
was going to happen to me.
I happened to you.
- But you're no trouble.
- Who knows?
Would you tie it for me?
Slop it! I'll do it!
Don Calo, it's Manuel.
Yes, she's leaving now.
Don't make a fuss.
Get in the car.
- Where are we going?
- Dancing.
How nice!
You can teach me some new steps.
I'm Cali). I was anxious
to meet you.
I can't say the same.
I heard about the message
you took to Silvera
and what he did to you.
Oh, yes?
Well then, you also heard that
I told your friend everything I know.
Silvera and I are not friends.
Actually, we're rivals.
Would you like to earn some cash?
No. I took a beating while
I was earning some cash this morning.
Take it all the same, you don't have
to deliver it anywhere.
Take it, it's yours.
You can spend it how you want.
Ten thousand dollars.
Nothing I can tell you
is worth ten thousand dollars.
And I don't want to buy anything
from you.
It's a minimum payment
for the pleasure of meeting you.
If the American moves against
Silvera, we won't interfere.
If Silvera moves against
the American, we will.
As you can see,
it's to your advantage.
It's to my advantage to be caught
in the crossfire?
I'm going to dance with my friends.
You know that this
is a very dangerous game.
Are you afraid?
No, I'm not. Are you?
I love dangerous games.
- Father, shall we dance?
- I don't know how.
Come on, it's easy.
We'll teach you how.
But I can't.
- Let yourself go.
- I'm in my work clothes.
Well done!
- Even priests dance too?
- I've got papal dispensation.
Well done!
I'm going back to the hotel, guys.
You boys
don't even know how to kiss!
I'm exhausted!
Later. Listen...
Miss Gren...
Green, not Gren.
- Right away.
- Call her!
Someone to see you,
Miss Green.
- Me?
- I think they're policemen.
Okay, thanks. I'll be right down.
Believe me, she's got a double
helping of legs!
To what do I owe
the pleasure of this visit?
Anything come up?
- What?
- New developments.
None.
Apart from the fact
that I'm always followed.
I don't know if it's because of
my legs or because of the American.
It seems that you received
a large amount of cash.
Ten thousand dollars.
- Did you call me?
- You're wanted on the phone.
- Me?
- You, Miss Green.
Yes, just a moment.
It's Manuel, he wants to make love.
He wants to know if he should come
here, or I should go to him.
I don't know.
Here? His place?
You decide. What do I care?
Come here darling. I'll expect you.
But not till this evening.
I'd like to break her...
- I...
- Let's go!
- Forcella. Quickly!
- Certainly.
- God, it's so hot!
- Yes. Take something off.
- Excuse me, are you married?
- Yes, I was young and foolish.
- Have you got a mistress?
- Yes, I'm middle-aged and stupid!
- Listen.
- Certainly.
A Citroen and a Fiat are behind us.
My husband's in the Citroen
and my lover's wife
is in the Fiat.
What is this? A quiz?
Imagine
that the man in the Citroen
is your mistress' husband
and the women in the Fiat is
your wife. What would you do?
I dunno, but there's a green
Alfa Romeo after us too.
Really? Where?
- Who could it be?
- It'll be the Green Brigade!
If my lover's wife is in one car
and my husband's in the other,
maybe it's the police.
- The police?
- What'll we do?
I don't get it, but if it's
the police I'll put my foot down.
Anyway, it's fun!
Bloody hell!
Where do they think they are?
Monza?
- We've got to lose them!
- Well, we don't want to find them!
I'll drop you at the traffic lights
and you can make a run for it!
You're a darling!
Wait for the green.
Get ready.
Take the second on the right,
it's pedestrians only.
Go!
She loves me, she loves me not...
- What is it?
- I'm down in the dumps.
What happened? You lost?
Everything.
Including a cute guy.
Want to play with me?
I'd prefer Manuel,
if you're hiring him out.
Manuel doesn't belong to me.
Wait a second,
are those pounds or francs?
Ten thousand dollars.
I want to gamble with you.
Dollars? I'm short-sighted,
I need to see them up close.
Well...
Place your bet.
What are we playing?
Who's who.
Don Calo and Silvera
are watching the port, airport
roads and train stations
and they're after the American.
You can't leave either, you know.
Well then, I've won this hand.
- Go on.
- Silvera and Calo hate each other.
They're both waiting for you
to make a move.
Let's Play
- Luck's on your side, eh?
- On mine, yes.
But you're in very hot water.
Not even Calf) can help you.
- One last question.
- What's the use?
- You've not got long left.
- Answer it anyway.
Who controls the drug traffic
here?
Ali. He runs "La Nigra", a nightclub
just outside town.
I'm seeing him tomorrow at ten.
Got a message for him?
Put a good word in for me
with the American.
Tell him I helped you.
- Who do you work for?
- Everyone.
Anyone who has
a Swiss bank account.
- But I'm small fry.
- Try not to get any bigger.
Mr. Manuel
called three times.
Thanks. My key.
I hope you're not trying
to leave town.
Don't worry, if I leave I'll
let you know. You don't scare me.
You still need
to work on that kiss.
- Look who's here. What do you want?
- I've got a delivery for you.
How kind! And what else?
Can't you see?
- What are you doing?
- Taking everything off.
The jacket's no problem. Let's do it.
- Who do you work for?
- I just work for myself.
But if you're nice, I'll work for
you too. I'm yours on special offer.
- Well, I've got better offers.
- But I've got this!
- Let's do it to music.
- Yes!
Music turns me on!
Great!
It's Nora. Yes, everything's fine...
...except for one little thing.
There's a blockage in the bathtub.
Come and remove it.
In there.
Hello, darling.
Yes, everything's fine.
Did he drown?
That's lucky!
What is it?
Okay, this evening.
I can't right now, I'm busy.
Who's Manuel with?
Maybe he works for Silvera, and
maybe he has contacts in the police.
You need to be very clever
to work it out.
I've got it worked out.
Excuse me, but that priest
just talked dirty to me!
We'll take care of him!
These modern priests!
- You're a fine example!
- I'll do the talking!
Father, you've gone too far.
I can assure you that
I had the purest of motives.
- The filthiest of motives.
- No...
Careful with those brooms.
A priest's collar is a uniform!
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
They were swept away!
- We'll win the shield this year.
- I don't think so.
Hi, sweeties!
That bitch!
To Ali's club, quickly.
- It's you!
- Miss!
- Full speed ahead?
- Yes.
Here. Look, this place has
a bad reputation.
I know, I'd never bring
my boyfriend here.
- What are you going to do?
- Don't go. I owe you for two rides.
I don't care, I'll wait.
You'll be quick, right?
- I'm sure I will.
- She's so nice!
She loves me, she loves me not.
What's a girl like you
doing in a place like this?
- Hooking.
- Well!
How much?
Whatever you want to give.
Okay.
What about me?
One at a time!
I work in the traditional way.
You can wait.
- You know the way.
- I come this way often.
Gonna take on my buddy afterwards?
- Is he good in bed?
- How should I know?
Well, these days
you never can tell...
You don't beat around
the bush.
What's that?
Ether.
Lousy thief! What've you taken?
Don't get mad.
Forgive me, please.
Believe me, I...
just wanted some spare change.
Pity. He looked like
he'd be good in bed.
You went in normal
and came out super!
The Holiday Inn.
Slowly, this time.
Maybe we should go fast
to keep ourselves in shape.
Hold tight!
That blind man didn't see me.
The mike's been planted.
It should be on 27 megs.
You've got to tune in.
- Who is it?
- Manuel.
Come in.
- Your uniform.
- Thanks.
This is Silvera.
Let me speak to Ali.
I'll go get him.
Think about me now.
It's me. What is it, Silvera.
- Whers the shipment due?
- It belongs to Don Calo.
I'll triple what he's paying for it.
Forget it. What's going on?
I don't want trouble with Don Cali).
The American's in town.
Just blame it on him.
The Americanls here? You want me
to screw Don Calo and blame him?
You're crazy! Do you know
what I'd be getting myself into?
- I don't want to get killed.
- The American's here to kill me.
I could tell him you came up with
this idea to get him out of the way.
- You can't do that to me.
- I'll do worse, you bastard!
I need that shipment
for the people in Miami.
That's the only way I can watch
my back and get rid of the American.
That's your business.
I can't double cross Don Cali).
I'll give you 25%.
That's a pile of money.
It could be
the cost of my life.
You're life's worthless if you don't
tell me where that shipment docks.
Okay, but don't get me
mixed up with the American.
I don't want
to even hear his name.
I'll tell Don Calf) that
I lost contact with the Tunisian.
The shipment docks
at Cala Bianca at four.
Do what you did last time,
then we'll take over.
It's always three men
who bring it.
Don't mention me to the American.
Don't worry.
Why did you want me to hear that phonecall?
You're not really
a stewardess, are you?
I thought only women
were curious.
You can't get out of it like that.
I want to know everything.
Forget it. You're too young,
too cute and too good in bed.
- Why kill yourself?
- Who do you work for?
Want some advice?
Get as far away as possible.
You'll read about
what happened in the papers.
What else can you do
besides make love?
- Nothing.
- You'll find a job easily.
If you give me a hand.
It's Nora. Get up here right away.
Are you a cop?
Do you work for the guys in Miami?
You're the American's lady friend?
You work for him.
- Tell me who you work for.
- Forget it, darling.
Come here.
Look after him, he's mine.
I want him back in one piece.
The shipment arrived
and has already changed hands.
Silvera's men have got it.
There's three of them.
They're on the way up. Get ready.
The Lord awaits you.
- Me?
- Yes.
Mr. Silvera, how are you?
I've got something here
that's very important to you.
I've got my vices,
but cocaine isn't one of them.
So I thought I'd let you have it.
- There's a price, naturally.
- Any price. Name it!
Send your underdogs out for
a walk and I'll bring it to you.
- Come here right away!
- Don't worry, I'm close by.
I'll come when I'm ready.
You understand that
I can't take any risks.
Be seeing you!
And of course, when I say money,
I mean dollars.
Damn bitch!
Inspector Calogero? Hello.
Did you enjoy the party at Cala Bianca?
Where are you?
I'm out having coffee.
Will I ever catch up with you, goddammit?
Inspector!
It just slipped out!
Where are you exactly?
I'm having coffee.
Work it out.
She's calling from a public phone.
Try and trace it!
Say hi to your deputy for me.
You won't have time to trace me.
Do you want to clean up,
once and for all?
Catch Silvera and Don Calo red-handed?
- No, I want you!
- I know, but you're not my type.
Don Calo is on his way to Silvera's.
They'll probably
tear each other apart.
You'll find the cocaine too.
Goodbye.
What do you mean, goodbye?
Try not to get there
before Don Cali).
- Wait a moment.
- Bye, ugly.
She meant you.
Everyone's after Nora.
She won't get away with it.
No, this time
she's risked too much.
She wanted to invite
the inspector to the party too.
As usual,
Nora loves gambling.
And if we come out of hiding?
It took us 10 years to build
the image of The American.
There's the local police too.
Crooks and cops everywhere will know
that the American's just a bogeyman.
And Nora came here as a stewardess.
That's how she's got to leave.
If she gets out.
She always does what she wants.
Anyway, this character we invented,
The American,
buys us our daily bread.
And he'll keep on buying it.
They just called.
Don Calo's coming with his men.
Get ready, but no shooting.
Okay.
May I?
You outsmarted us all,
you goddamned bitch!
Mr Silvera, what language!
And in front of a lady too.
Here's your dollars.
You won't get far!
What manners!
Don't force me to shoot you!
Watch out, you dirty bitch!
This time the American's
not here to save you!
- Thanks.
- Your welcome.
We came to give you a hand,
the others didn't want to.
- What a waste. Want some?
- Depends on the quality.
Second rate.
- Awful.
- Let's go. See you at the airport.
See you. Bye, my child.
Careful.
Getting out of here won't be easy.
Go look for them.
Get over to the Bumper Cars!
Don Calo's here with his men.
- What use is half a cane?
- It'll come in handy.
Here come two of them.
Here they are...
What is it, my son?
One, two, three, four...
- Now I'll smash...
- Your head.
Now I'll smash...
- Now I'll smash...
- Your head.
- Here!
- My poor head!
I'm ﬂying!
Go, mosquito!
- You big lump!
- How dare you! Shorty!
You big lump!
Wait, I'll be right back.
Fix him!
Wait.
Are you leaving?
Hey, big lump!
Here!
Now I'll unblock your ears!
I'm coming
So, you didn't understand me!
Yes, I understood. Come down.
Forget it.
You're leaving?
- Scared of me? Come here.
- You come here.
I've had a nice rest.
I want to see
what's going on in your head!
I'm fresh as a daisy!
- Come here.
- What are you doing? Get me down!
- Get me down!
- Come with me.
Stay here.
- Putting me a in a cage?
- You're an animal!
- Come here!
- Fly!
Get me down!
I'll show you!
Open the cage!
I'll tear you to pieces!
Get me down!
Big Lump! Poor dear, you're soaked.
You'll catch cold, poor thing!
He said, "Oh".
Call for back up
and go to the amusement park!
The cops! Run!
- Put it in fifth!
- I am!
- Sixth.
- We don't have sixth!
The crooks have six, and we don't?
We're the crappiest cops ever!
Quick!
That's not a mini,
it's a maxi!
We're taking the stairs?
Get off me!
Here we go again!
My head!
Vagliaquiiiiiiiinto!
Vagliaquinto, you stupid dick!
What is this, the way down
from "Wuthering Heights"?
- Why did you stop?
- You said, "Stop, quick!"
I said, "You stupid dick!"
Let's go!
What a beautiful day!
The usual idiot!
Want to overtake, eh?
Get over!
Vagliaquinto!
Can't you go a bit slower?
What is it? Overtake,
if you can!
Let me pass, dammit!
What are you waiting for?
Okay, if that's what you want.
Now some make up,
but I'm keeping an eye on you.
The final touch...
Brake!
You put it in reverse?
Don't go backwards!
How embarrassing!
What are you doing?
You let her get away, as usual!
- Drive, you idiot! Let's go!
- I'll handle it!
You'll handle it?
You're leaving me here?
I'll see all of you in hell!
- Are you gay, by any chance?
- Who, me?
The price of salad, and
we waste it like this!
Engaged!
How dare you!
Instead of crooks, we arrest
people while they defecate!
This is crazy! You can't even
use the crapper in peace!
What a disgrace. They'll report us
for lavatorial abuse!
- I've not finished yet!
- Go home and finish.
The toilet!
- Take it away
- I forgot the most important thing!
Beat it! Vagliaquintol Let's go!
How do the police manage to arrest
everyone in American films?
Put it in fifth!
I was born in Canosa, Puglia and
I emigrated to Naples for work.
Instead of going to America!
- Wait for me here!
- Who's moving?
- Who's she?
- An English girl who likes me.
- What?
- It's true.
- You lucky ass!
- You should see hers!
She hit the wall!
Drive over!
I don't give a damn!
What is this? Where are we?
Stuffed in the tomatoes!
What a disgrace! St. Gennaro!
Why the hell do I bother?!
St. Marzano!
- Full speed ahead?
- Yes, to the airport.
You could have problems
with Inspector Calogero.
What problems?
He's my twin brother!
He graduated but went bald
from the effort.
Quick!
Dammit!
If my kids see me...
I can't find my shoes!
Why give me tomatoes?
Beat it!
Here we are.
Thanks for everything.
I won't forget you!
Last call for ﬂight A 107.
Hurry!
Ladies and gentlemen, the captain
wishes you a good ﬂight.
Good morning, boys.
Here.