Don't take it personally.
Just setting an example.
Ken...
make your peace.
Genji! Fly!
Genji!
Genji...
Damn it!
If I hadn't met you,
my life would have been...
"Suzuran Boys' High School"
"The King of Suzuran"
"Tamao Serizawa"
"Genji Takiya"
Youth is a once in a lifetime gift.
Make it memorable... and meaningful.
Next, a few words from our
freshman class representative.
We look to Suzuran to give us
the knowledge and purity of mind...
to shape us into responsible
members of society.
Yo, listen up!
Here at Suzuran...
a man's worth is proven
by his fists.
But in all it's history,
nobody has ever conquered it.
Who's going to change that?
Me, that's who!
End of speech!
You're full of it, Squid Head!
Who's a "Squid Head"?!
You are.
No fighting, boys.
Please, no fighting.
This is supposed to be
a day of celebration.
Don't spoil your enrollment ceremony.
And disappoint your parents.
This year's freshman class
has some spirit.
Big trouble outside!
Yakuza on campus!
Someone call the cops! Quickly!
Hey, everybody chill out!
Knock it off!
There's something going down outside!
Let's check it out!
I'm looking for a punk
named Tamao Serizawa.
He sent one of our boys into hospital.
Show yourself!
Yo, Big Bro.
What?
Go buy me a soda.
I'll take canned coffee.
Hot chocolate.
And you?
Ice cream for me.
Ice cream.
Are you kidding me?
Please.
Let us handle this for you.
You just relax.
We'll settle this quickly...
by the time you return.
Go ahead.
You sure?
Yeah.
Then here, take this.
You too.
Okay.
It's in your hands.
Of course.
See ya.
Take your time.
Who's Serizawa?
You don't know?
Our own third year monster.
Alright, Serizawa! Get out here!
Make it snappy, punk!
Tamao!
I'm healthy, man!
That's good.
What?
Hurry and get on.
You're walking.
But you can't ride a bike.
Hey, Tamao!
Why are you lying to me?
Watch it, jerk!
Serizawa...
you got a license to drive that thing?
You Tamao Serizawa?
Hey... Hey!
Hey! Hold it!
Don't diss a public servant.
Get a life, Gramps!
Stop tailgating me, fuzz ball!
Move it!
Hey, watch it!
Move!
Serizawa! Let's play chicken!
Serizawa! Chicken!
Don't diss the poor!
Out of the way!
Aren't they my guests?
How should I know?
I haven't seen you before.
I'm new here.
Serizawa!
You're Tamao Serizawa?
Yep.
Looks like we've come to
one crazy school.
What was that
about conquering it, Squid Head?
"A word to my friends"
"Living on the wild side"
"That light which flickers
far off in the distance"
"It just might lead you
out of here someday"
CROWS - Episode 0
"A crumbling afternoon intersection"
"I see a flock of birds without wings"
"Striving to survive,
Still unaware of what they are"
"Wings burned by the sun"
"They can't even fly but..."
"They all have one ambition"
"I wanna fly and keep flying"
"A word to my friends"
"Living on the wild side"
"What does it mean to live as yourself?"
"Breaking free from
the shell that holds you"
"With every season
comes a new self-discovery"
"I wanna change and keep changing"
"I wanna change, I wanna change, change"
THE STREET BEATS in the house!
BEATS in the house!
Feel the buzz, yet?
Rock intoxication!
Must be lonely switching schools...
in your last year.
Right, Takuya?
Ushiyama...
you've got a big mouth.
Don't get mad.
Meet Ruka Aizawa.
So tell me...
Why did you transfer to Suzuran?
The "School of Crows" is considered
the roughest in the nation.
To be king of the hill? Why else?
Sounds like a yakuza.
You should quit.
Let's follow that
hard shot of rock
with a silky smooth chaser.
Our own Goddess of R&B.
OK, here we go!
Am I being a pest?
Yes.
Let's keep on rockin' till the mornin'!
It's getting hot in here!
Keep it hot!
What do you think?
What do you think?!
You're fine the way you are.
I was expecting you the way you are.
Right, Reiko?
Seiko.
Boss...
your son's home.
Excuse us, Reiko.
Excuse us.
This way.
How's Suzuran?
How the hell should I know?
I just started.
That tough guy act won't
fly there, you know.
Advice from a guy who couldn't conquer it.
Young sir...
please watch your tongue.
I'm not you.
I'm going to succeed.
Exactly what a father hopes for his son.
Then I'll take over the business,
like you promised.
That would be something.
First winning Suzuran,
then succeeding me in the organization?
Don't forget those words.
I'm going to do better than you.
Who did that?
Beats me.
Probably one of our fresh-faced
first year students.
Save them for later.
Concentrate on the third years.
Let's crush...
classes B, C, D and E in order.
The Mikami Brothers are in B.
Wow! Hey!
Thirteen Orphans!
In your dreams!
You're cheating again, right?
No, I mean it! Ready!
Genji?
Tokaji!
Chill out, ok?
Who's this jerk?
An old friend from junior high.
So what?
I said, chill!
All right?
How've you been, Tokio?
Okay.
Did you erase that?
Um... well...
Tamao Serizawa...
I hear you're top man around here.
Show me.
Hold it, Genji.
Why do you want to fight Tamao?
Hey!
Tamao, don't!
I had Thirteen Orphans, man!
It was cash in the pocket!
Serizawa!
What?!
The Mikami Brothers.
How convenient.
Sorry, Genji.
We've got no time for you right now.
If you really want a crack at Tamao...
go take down the second year,
Rinda-man, first.
- Rinda-man?
- What are you...
If you beat him, come on back.
Hey, Serizawa!
Let's get this over with!
We're busy men.
Just this once.
Hey, jailbird!
Let's see who rules the roost.
Since when is Rinda-man
one of yours, eh?
You were too chicken to fight him.
Rinda-man... in second year?
Yeah. Is he tough?
Hell, yeah.
Heard he beat the crap out of...
ten guys at once... as a freshman.
I heard it was fifty.
Bull. I heard a hundred.
That's stretching it.
And all hospitalized, too.
Where?
That's not the point.
The main point is that some of
those guys never made it back.
You Rinda-man?
At last I've found you,
you worthless scum.
Let me show you what happens...
when you mess with yakuza.
You're dead, Serizawa.
Me? I'm not.
Don't give me that!
Hey, you all right?
Truth is, I'm a Suzuran grad.
They called me Jarhead Ken.
Came close to ruling it, too.
Ruling Suzuran?
Yeah.
Don't you believe me, huh?
You don't get it, do you?
It takes more than a good punch...
to consolidate a place like Suzuran.
For example, it takes leadership...
and heroic virtues.
Let's see, what else?
Diplomacy... and keen perception.
It takes a bunch of things.
You have all that?
Can't you stop being so disrespectful?
Can't.
I'm new at Suzuran.
I don't know right from left.
So...
What?
Can you help me?
I'm not good with people.
Look...
I'm begging you, Ken.
All right, all right, fine.
Stop that.
You've come to the right man.
Really?
You needn't ask twice.
I can tell you right now
how to win control of your class.
It's all about making an impression.
In the loudest voice possible.
All right, who's in charge here?
The best guy in the class...
who is it?
It's me.
Who are you?
You win.
As of today, this is my class.
If you follow me...
"I'll show you what dreams are made of."
How's that?
You know, when you are at my level,
words like that just fit really well.
Did that really happen to you, sir?
Of course.
I'm speaking from experience here.
But here's the punch line.
It wasn't me doing the talking.
Damn, that's hot!
Morning!
Good morning, Boss!
Looking real sharp, Boss!
Nice jacket.
What?
Nothing, sir.
I was just thinking,
one day I hope to wear
nice suits like you.
Where's the massage parlor money?
Did you collect the dues?
They'd like us to wait
a little longer this month.
You loser.
Sorry.
Ryuseikai poached on our territory.
I'm sorry.
'Cause of you.
Forgive me.
Did they cut into our action?
I'm sorry.
As kids, me and Genji
used to look for
the best spot to watch the sunset.
I figured we'd be friends forever.
But that's all history.
I'm ready to take him on.
I see.
You think
things could change between us someday?
With me, the view never changes.
Anyone who dares to rise above us...
at Suzuran will be crushed.
You can sit back and relax.
This is Tamura of Class E.
Hi. Call me Chuta.
Wait, that would mean...
our strategy worked?
You're good, Genji.
So tell me then, Chuta,
what's the power structure
like at Suzuran?
Okay... I'll start
with the new players.
Have you heard of The Armored Front?
Yeah.
But they have nothing to do with Suzuran.
One of their leaders,
Hideto Bando,
transferred this year as a second year.
I hear you don't want to tick him off.
Then there's the first year...
Ebizuka Junior High Trio.
Kirishima,
Honjo
and Sugihara.
What about Rinda-man?
He's a bystander in the Suzuran war.
He's on another level.
Sounds like a monster.
No.
The real monster is Tamao Serizawa.
He's the closest to
controlling Suzuran High.
In Serizawa's shadow is Yuji Tokaji.
He fought Serizawa for two years.
Some call him the brain of
Serizawa's Army.
Another one of Serizawa's boys,
Shoji Tsutsumoto, was a judo champion.
Then there's Genji's
old junior high buddy.
Tokio Tatsukawa's been through
a lot with Serizawa.
They're like partners.
And the man they all follow,
the "king of beasts", Tamao Serizawa.
Together, they plan to conquer Suzuran.
It's never been done.
Class B, led by the Mikami Brothers,
has joined ranks with Serizawa.
I see.
After "B", comes "C", huh?
My class.
You should avoid a meaningless fight.
We're not going to wave
the white flag without a fight.
Okay. That's what you'll get, then.
We'll be waiting.
Class C is led by Takashi Makise.
He's lost to Serizawa many times,
but he keeps fighting.
That's why he's got followers.
He can't be won by sheer force, eh?
Got anything on him?
He strikes out badly with girls.
That's it then.
Let's get him a girl.
How?
Hi, girls!
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait!
Just tell me your names.
What's that for?
It's on me.
I said I'll pay.
Please let me pay.
Oh, come on!
Just let me have a minute
of your time, please!
Okay.
Really?
That's kidnapping.
Just one or two women...
one or two women...
I'll get them for you somehow.
Wait here.
What are you doing?
Chopping cabbage.
Why?
This is my house.
No way!
That easy?
That reminds me, Tamao...
Yeah?
You owe me 2,000 dollars
in bike repairs.
Eh?
I'll add it to your tab.
Yo, Serizawa! Let's get it on!
- Who's he?
- I don't know.
Go do your homework.
Not so fast, Shorty!
I think he's a second year.
Win control of your grade first.
You've got heart.
What's your name?
Gota Washio.
I'm Manabu. Nice try.
I hear you're asking for me.
You've got some guts.
I called you 'cause...
I know.
But
even if you beat me,
my men aren't going with you.
A group date. Interested?
"Love Love Group Date"?
Maybe it's not for you.
If I don't get a girl out of this,
the deal is off.
You sure about this?
Relax. Group dates are my specialty.
Welcome.
Sorry we're late.
My friends.
I'm Yu.
Kyoko.
I'm Ken.
Small frame, big equipment.
Big guy,
bigger attitude.
This is Genji.
Hi.
And this here is...
I'm... uh...
Makkie.
Your name sound like
a permanent marker.
Wow, pretty voice.
Makise!
Relax.
Yeah.
I might unload without
doing a thing.
Unload what?
Are you really going to force
a boy to explain that?
Why don't we all sit down?
That would be good.
Maki's a little nervous.
Cheers!
Thank you. Excuse me.
What, not drinking?
How about a snack?
Nuts?
I like chocolate, myself.
No? Nothing?
I know! How about a game?
The Yamanote Line Game!
What's that?
What is this?
What do you want?
Ken, this was a flop from the start.
Really? Things are just getting rolling.
Okay, I hear you. Leave it to me.
It's early but...
it's an emergency.
Chuta?
Looks like fun over here.
Can I join you?
Yo, who's the drop dead hottie?
I'm a wizard with my fingers.
Hey, you!
Hands off my girl.
Or what, Grease ball?
Come on!
Chuta!
Oh God, Chuta!
You all right?
Don't say his name!
They'll know it's a setup!
Oh, I get it.
Unbelievable.
Let's go.
You're an ass.
A total ass!
Are you crying?
You sure are weird.
Stop crying!
I sent Chuta home.
Hey, I'm sorry about today.
Forget it.
How about I...
take you to a massage parlor?
A massage parlor?
Yeah.
Really?
Sure.
Genji, what are you, mad?
A massage parlor?
Yup.
Really?
Uh-huh.
You crying?
A massage parlor?
Yes.
First...
you do it on a bed.
Then on an oiled mat.
What's wrong?
You gonna be sick or something?
Sorry to bother you.
Can I buy a pair of pants?
And underwear?
Okay.
You're fashion leader!
No doubt!
Which side's the front?
I'm wearing a women's pants!
I'll see you later, Makise.
Later.
Hey, Genji!
Class C.
It's yours.
Thanks.
Let's take it all.
You, number 7 pin!
You're not lined up right!
You're too close!
Spread out, you idiot!
Number 1!
Okay!
How's that look?
Okay? Let's bowl!
Shut up already!
Let him concentrate!
Anyone who moves, dies!
Cool, let's go!
All clear, man!
Big trouble!
Makise's joined up with Genji!
Stop peeing your pants over everything!
Well, Makise's now recruiting Izaki's gang!
Of Class D?
Yeah!
You sure about it?
Izaki's tough!
And crazy.
Stop whining, you sissies!
Come on!
Ready, aim...
Fire!
Strike!
Congratulations!
Let them join forces.
We can take them all at once.
Yeah.
He looks pale.
Must be the flu.
Rich kids get sick easy
when seasons change.
You're full of it.
Now we own the first years.
Pretty impressive.
As your junior high alum
and upperclassman, you do me proud.
Don't flatter yourself, Izaki.
We're ready to take you on, too.
Hiromi, do you know
who you're talking to?
I'm with Hiromi.
Age makes no difference at Suzuran.
Come see me anytime.
And you get a haircut first.
Even he can't take the third years.
Competition is stiff here.
Is it true you want to join us?
Yeah, but under one condition.
That I get to fight
Serizawa when the time comes.
Not you.
What?
What a naive fool.
There is no clean fight in a war.
Out of respect for Makise,
I figured I'd give you a chance.
But you can't beat Serizawa.
I'm not finished yet stupid.
Okay, who's next?
Genji!
Genji, Genji!
Izaki!
Why'd you get behind this guy?
Don't say it's 'cause
he tried to get you laid.
No reason.
Not one I can explain, anyway.
You tell him this:
Tomorrow, I'll show him
how to throw darts.
You seem happy.
Well, of course I'm happy.
Right now, you're living
my unfulfilled dream.
Thanks in part to me.
Stop trying to act cool.
You let me be cool.
Hey' isn't that?
That's Ruka!
I'll cut that pretty face.
What's going on?
Get back here.
What do you think you are doing?
Who are you?
Know what I hate most?
Guys who...
carry knives and beat upon women.
Sorry about the other day.
Let me make amends.
Get Ruka out of here.
You're way outnumbered.
You have to lead your
men to the top of Suzuran.
Stop stalling and let's go, man!
Kill you!
You shut the hell up.
Just take her and go!
I said, stop acting cool.
From time to time, why not?
Now go!
Want a piece of me?
How old are you?
Old enough to kick your ass!
Let's go.
Hey now wait a second!
Hold it right there!
Wait, wait, wait! Listen up!
I'm Ken Katagiri.
My name can silence a crying baby.
I'm a ranking officer in the
Soshu Family Syndicate.
What's that?
What?
We don't give a damn!
Back off!
No one gets by me!
No one gets by.
There can't go...
We got a call. Figures it's you.
Detective Kuroiwa?
Aren't you getting
a little too old for this?
Leave me alone.
That reminds me.
I ran into Nakai,
the guy who lorded
over Suzuran back in your day.
He was a bad egg then.
Now, he's a company man.
Supporting a wife and kids.
It's time you grew up.
You're the only Suzuran graduate
still being a two bit hood.
Even as yakuza, you're mediocre.
Didn't that "School of Crows"
teach you anything?
I guess not to a dropout.
Right?
You all right?
Hell, yeah!
I scared them all off
with my sheer intensity.
I see. I'm glad.
I figured you dead for sure.
Hey, I'm invincible.
It'd take a lot more than that to kill me.
In that case...
let meet up?
Sorry, but I've got to be someplace.
Catch you later.
About the other day I'm sorry.
Ken's a character.
One of a kind.
Is he your friend?
I guess so.
Your face is a mess.
What happened?
Like here.
Ouch!
Sorry!
Want some candy?
Here.
Thanks.
"Genji's Perfect Succession"
Sapporo Beer!
Come on, Genji!
Tokio...
We can't overlook these guys anymore.
I never asked you to.
I bet the view atop Suzuran
is breathtaking.
Let's go get it.
There is no clean fight in a war.
Right?
Jerk off.
What's that?!
Izaki!
Bring him down easy!
Izaki! Who did this to you?
Serizawa?
No.
I fell.
Don't do it.
We're still outnumbered.
Genji, wait!
Out of my way!
Genji! Izaki's right!
Fight now and we lose.
That's not the point!
Yes it is!
If you lose, it's over for all of us.
That's how far this war's come.
Here.
Drink up.
This really hurts.
It'd hurt much less if it happened to me.
Welcome.
What timing.
Enemy territory. Tamao...
Tokio...
you bastard!
It's me you want.
Did you do Izaki?
Don't play dumb.
Hey! Take it outside!
Wait, Tamao.
Move.
I said, move!
Not here.
Tokio!
Tokio?
Tokio, Tokio!
An operation?
Yes.
I need to talk to our folks.
I'll talk to them.
I'm not a child. Just tell me.
The chance of surgical success
for a cerebral aneurysm this size...
is about 30 percent.
Then forget surgery.
If surgery gets me 30 percent,
I'll take life at 100 percent.
But if you do nothing...
I won't hold you responsible.
I'm not going to die.
Stop whinin' you little wimp!
Hey, Genji!
Genji! What's gotten into you?
Genji!
Stop running!
As of today...
you follow me. Got it?
What are you doing?
I'm getting numbers, like Izaki said.
Not like this!
Listen!
You won't boost our strength this way!
Genji!
They got Chuta!
Move!
Chuta!
What happened?
Sorry.
I was trying to recruit the first years
and got mixed up with Tokaji.
I'll show him.
Hey, Genji!
Hey!
That's enough!
What are you doing wild for?
Sorry but I can't follow you like this.
Wait!
Makise!
So much stuff has gone down so quickly,
I'm lost.
I can't keep the alliance.
What are you saying?
You've come this far.
We're going where no one's been!
To the top of Suzuran. Come on!
You're the only one who can do it!
Trust me!
Okay. So I'm a Suzuran drop out.
A big fat loser, right?
But not you. So let's finish this.
Come on!
You can do it! You said so yourself!
You're living my dream, man!
Fine, forget that, then!
Forget about me! Be a man, okay?
A man.
Don't be a loser.
You made a pledge.
You've got to see this through.
Listen.
I came to Suzuran to outdo my old man.
To outdo your old man?
That's cool.
What does he do?
Same as you.
Yakuza... the Ryuseikai.
Ryuseikai?
Yeah.
Are you...
Hideo's son?
GPS keeps growing.
That's why we've got to make a move.
Without Serizawa, Tokaji?
Not a good idea.
Just listen.
I have plan.
You wanted to see me?
Bando!
I hear you need some soldiers
to bring down our current boss.
If you do something for us,
I'll lend you some muscle.
We got 30 more from the first year
and second year classes.
The rest is up to Genji.
Be ready to go at any moment.
And if Genji doesn't return?
We still go ahead.
There's no turning back now.
Fight me, will you?
If I win...
will you join me again?
You called me, Boss?
You've been hanging out
with a Suzuran punk?
The same guy who beat up some of our boys.
Actually, we mistook him for
a kid named Serizawa.
I want you to kill him.
Thing is
that student
is the son of Ryuseikai's boss.
So?
So I'm saying
if we were to off the heir of...
the Ryuseikai syndicate
We'd start a war.
Is that the intent?
Sorry to cause you so much trouble, Ken.
Izaki leaves the hospital tomorrow.
I've slowly begun to understand
what it means to have comrades.
I've been looking for you.
What for?
I came to tell you something.
I hear you haven't been yourself lately.
It's about Tokio.
What's the story with him?
No story. He'll be back soon.
Illness can't stop him.
We could call a cease
fire until he returns.
No need.
Putting you in the hospital will be
my "get well" gift to him.
That's funny. Mine is to
put you in a bed next to his.
Tokio's my friend.
He doesn't concern you.
I came to tell you that.
See you around, Poor Boy.
Poor people are tough, you know.
Man, I envy you guys.
Driving straight down life's road
at full throttle. No pretensions.
Makes me weep with joy.
If I had spent my time
at Suzuran like you
I'd be better man now.
You woke me up.
What was that for?
My punches don't affect you.
I know about punches.
I've taken my share of them.
Genji.
take the top.
Hey, Izaki.
You're late. Where were you?
You're a nag. And you smell.
Welcome back.
It's been a long time.
You haven't changed.
Back then, I
admired you, sir.
But you didn't let me
join your organization.
So I went to our enemy.
What a fool.
I didn't know a thing.
My boss plans to kill Genji.
What did you say to me?
Why tell me?
I've spent my life running.
I want it to end by
being honest with myself.
I see.
Please give this to Genji.
I hear you'd let him succeed you
if he took Suzuran.
What if he does take Suzuran?
What will you do?
You plan on having him
lead this kind of life?
If he has what it takes
to conquer Suzuran
I'm sure he'll choose not to.
Hey, what's up?
Help.
We've been kidnapped by guys in
leather jackets with skulls on the back.
Skulls?
Yeah.
I heard them saying Bando.
Bando?
They hang out at the Narai Warehouse.
Where's that?
Kijima Docks.
They're dead.
Genji, wait!
Do we take on The Armored Front?
If that's what he wants,
that's what we do.
I hear you.
I'll gather men!
Let's go!
I can borrow this?
They've got spirit.
Let Ruka go!
Who's that?
Don't play dumb!
You don't kidnap chicks!
Okay, that's enough!
No skulls.
You're pretty good.
So it wasn't you?
The third generation
of leadership is rotten.
Until I've cleaned everything up.
I've sealed the skulls.
Look, I don't care.
Who, then?
Who gains the most out of us going to war?
Serizawa.
You've got my boys all fired up.
I probably can't control them.
They'll want some kind of apology.
Especially from him.
Hey, you.
We'll take an ear.
An ear?
Yeah.
An ear.
Only one of them will do.
That's funnier, right?
Then are we even?
If that's what you want.
Would you settle for mine?
I'll give you both.
As you wish.
Hey, Genji!
I don't want our filthy ear.
They came to us with a request
to take the girl.
The basement of Club S.
Go on.
Get her out.
Then, we'll settle things.
Who cares who wins?
Both sides will be depleted.
We'll clean up the stragglers.
I'm in.
Tokio's operation is at 5 tomorrow.
I see.
What is it?
Give me the girl.
Huh?
Don't act stupid.
Get the hell out of here.
What did you do?
You again?
Gig's up. Let her go.
Ruka! You all right?
Where is Kyoko?
She is safe.
Ruka! I'm so scared!
Kyoko!
Tokaji!
Do you know what you've done?
I did it
to assure our victory.
Don't be stupid!
I'd rather be crushed head on
than to pull a punk stunt like this!
We took part in it, too!
Losers.
There's only one thing to do now.
Yeah.
Looks like the time has come.
Tomorrow at 5.
At our very own Suzuran.
Katagiri
left this for you.
Read it.
"Dear Genji, the perch is yours."
"Fly! Fly high!"
What'd you talk about?
He's taking one for you.
What's that mean?
He ignored orders from
his boss to kill you.
Gen!
There is no move for you to make.
I didn't ask.
Don't be stupid.
The man chose this path.
He can wipe his own ass.
You can carry on his wishes.
Genji
take the top.
Let's do it!
Get psyched!
Could you stop?
Stop, please!
Let me walk this.
Is that okay?
You sure you don't want to be with Tokio?
We fight together.
Tokaji!
Let's win and brag to Tokio.
Yeah.
It's starting.
Serizawa's got about 100.
GPS 70.
Serizawa's got the numbers...
and the strength.
GPS hasn't a chance.
Don't be so sure.
I can't do it.
You look pretty sure of yourself.
You probably went
and warned them, anyway.
You're a fool.
It'll cost you.
Get the car.
You'll sleep.
It's begun.
Well, come on!
I'll cover your back
till you reach Serizawa.
Serizawa Army's winning.
What did I tell you?
Wait and see.
Is that the best you can do?
I want Serizawa's head!
Why is Bando siding with GPS?
I guess he just felt like it.
Whoa.
They were only a few but,
suddenly, it's an even fight.
About time.
Hey, ugly!
Baldy!
- Want some plastic surgery?
- Baldy!
Well, come on!
Don't mind if I do.
Izaki!
Plug your hole, pig face!
"I can't contain this feeling"
"Swelling up inside of me"
"You take on the world alone"
"But don't know where to stop"
"Where are you looking for,
flying into the sky?"
"The hero lives in you"
"That is our true destination"
"Taking flight into the future"
"You are the sunlight"
"The hero lives in you"
"Somewhere in this town"'
"you're running breathless again"
"Only to return with scars"
"but so few reasons Why?"
"Maybe we'll find a place one day"
"to share a laugh or two"
"All you gotta do is believe"
You wanted this, right?
Take it. It's yours.
You regret becoming a yakuza?
No way.
Damn you!
You are a pest.
Don't take it personally.
Just setting an example.
Go, Genji!
Kill him!
Come on!
Make your peace.
Genji! Fly!
Genji!
Genji...
Damn it!
If I hadn't met you my life
would've been a complete waste.
Thanks.
Tamao.
It's the hospital.
How's Tokio?
Gotcha.
Tokio...
made it.
What did you say?
He won.
Bulletproof.
Boss.
I'm freezing.
Thank you!
Genji!
I'm alive!
I'm still alive!
Sorry,
but if I don't defeat you,
I don't have Suzura.
You never will.
Just like you beat Serizawa
there's always someone new.
That's Suzuran.
You fight and fight
and then you graduate.
Conquest is just a dream.
Don't be so sure.
I won't hold back.
Let's do it.
"I feel my soul about to explode"
"Into something that will live forever"
"My instincts keep telling me"
"This is my defining moment"
"Eternal rock 'n' roll,
Eternal rock 'n' roll"
"Never ending rock 'n' roll"
"A fate named reality is"
"An onslaught of unforgiving truths"
"The moment I'm cornered in"
"I must face it without regret"
"Eternal rock 'n' roll,
Eternal rock 'n' roll"
"Never ending rock 'n' roll"