You think you're
a big shot.
Don't you?
No.
You've been nine
months here. You
pay nothing.
I'm sorry.
Are you stupid?
That's all I've got.
I should kill you
right now.
And what are
you waiting for?
[Plate clanks]
That's no way to
start a friendship.
Visitor.
You don't look
to good, M r. Riggins.
I'm Clive Connelly.
I'm an attache at the
American Embassy in Gorna.
I'm here to help you.
Well, I've been here
for... almost a year now.
The American government
is a little reluctant to
help an ex Special forces
who gets himself locked up
for smuggling weapons.
You fucked up.
No shit.
Mike. Hope you don't
mlnd me calling
you Mike.
I understand you got
a problem with authority.
You think you're special.
Laws don't apply to you.
Obviously, you're
wrong about that, pal.
So, get to your point.
Well, you're a permanent
resident in the worst fucking
prison in the world.
You owe a lot of money
to a couple of very
dangerous men.
You stay in here
much longer you're
gonna be a dead man.
You're a dead man
on the outside, unless...
Unless what?
I got a
proposition for you.
One that could
get you out of here
with $100 thousand
in your pocket.
We have a complex
situation.
One that's a little
too politically
delicate for us
to be directly
involved in.
An American citizen
has been kidnapped.
She's been held
for the past 18 months
at a compound
near the Black Sea
by this man,
Vlado Karadjov.
He calls himself
a warlord.
So, why didn't you go
get her yourself?
I guess
diplomacy failed.
The fuck wanted money.
The American government
doesn't pay ransoms.
All right.
I get you the girl,
but it's gonna cost
you 200 thousand.
Fine.
When do I get
my money?
Ten thousand now.
The rest when you
deliver the girl.
Twenty now.
I just happen to have
an extra ten grand.
Now, my number
Is on speed dial
on the cell phone.
And this is a list
of people that may
be helpful to you.
There could be
one problem.
The girl might resist.
We think she's
been drugged.
What do you mean?
One negotiator was
allowed to talk to her.
He got the impression
that she was developing
sympathy for her kidnappers.
Which Isn't that
uncommon when you've been
kept for this long a period.
The first guy you should
visit Is here, Zoran Posternoff.
He runs nightclub
In the city center
named...
Club 33.
I know.
Where's Zoran?
Riggins.
What the hell are
you doing here?
Business.
Business?
Sit down.
You owe me
30 thousand.
I got ten
right here.
And?
The rest
if you help me.
How?
I need to see
Vlado Karadjov.
Why?
He's holding an
American girl hostage.
Take my advise.
Karadjov has powerful
allies. Nobody
fucks with him
and lives to tell
about it. Nobody.
So, where can
I find him?
Okay.
Wait here.
I'm gonna see what
I can do for you, okay?
H i, you want
a drink?
You read my mind.
I'll have rakia.
Make it big.
Okay.
You American,
you stay in Gorna?
Well, that depends
on you two.
Here's to having
a good time.
You're coming with us.
Hold him down.
You still owe me
ten. Remember. Ten.
N ice to see
you haven't changed.
Get him out of here.
Move!
What are you doing
in my city?
I'm here
about a woman.
What woman?
Ana Gale.
How much?
What do you mean?
Each time someone comes
with a bigger offer,
only not big enough.
How much this time?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Her family
wants her back.
If you come here again,
I'm not going
to just shoot you.
See, I don't
like guns.
You shoot people,
and hospitals keep
them alive.
We're through.
What else you got?
What else?
You got the Glock G22
that can open a hole
inside of a tank.
Beretta 92
with auto-fire.
Also, AK47
with extended rounds.
Uh, titanium hull points.
What else you can
possibly need?
How about some night
division optics and
stun grenades. C4.
Are you going
to fight the
fucking army?
And some remote
bomb triggers.
Whatever.
I got an appointment
with Vlado Karadjov.
Are you crazy?
Have you picked out
your coffin, yet?
He lives In
a military base.
He's friends with
General Drago.
The Butcher of Sobrewsky,
he made M Milosevic look
like a lump.
I know.
You don't have
a chance. No.
Where is that base?
Mama, Mama!
Hey!
Don't be scared.
J Just try that again.
I'm here to rescue you.
You're going home.
You won't scream?
Are you sure?
Help! Help!
Argh!
Let go!
Get up.
Get in.
Come on.
Let me go!
You gonna stop fighting
and get in the car?
No!
Okay.
Don't you dare!
Come on, get in.
Get in.
Let me go!
Let me out of here!
Let me out of here.
You son of a bitch I
Let me out of here!
I couldve been killed!
Gonna try
to run again?
No.
Who the hell
do you think
you are?
I'm here to get you
away from the kidnappers.
What kidnappers?
Vlado Karadjov.
I wasn't kidnapped!
You weren't?
No!
You weren't
drugged or something?
What? No!
Well, why were you
with Vlado then?
Because I wanted to be.
I work for a help
organization.
I came here two
years ago after
a meningitis outbreak.
Once we got it under control,
he me made an offer to take
care of his hemophiliac son.
Look, something
isn't right here.
What's not right is
that you kidnapped me.
My information says
you were abducted.
You better check
your sources agaln.
I'm going to the Police...
Look, park your tongue
so I can think.
All right. I'm gonna
take you to the American
Embassy in Luka.
Why?
Because they're
paying me to
bring you back.
Paying you? I was at
the embassy five months
ago to extend my visa.
All right. Well,
I can't go back
without you, so
you're coming with me.
Get in the car.
Hey, stay quiet.
Sit.
Good morning. American Embassy.
How may I direct your call?
Mike Riggins for
Mr. Clive Connelly.
Are you sure, sir?
Yeah, I'm sure.
He's an attache
for you guys.
I'll check, sir.
Please, hold.
Hello, sir?
Hello.
There's no one
lasted by that name.
Did you check
all departments?
Yes, sir.
No listing
for Clive Connelly.
No Clive Connelly?
No, sir.
I'm sorry.
Hello.
Mike. Clive Connelly.
I called the Embassy.
You're no attache.
Mike, let me explain.
Explain what?
Mike, Clive Connelly
is not my real name.
What are you
talking about?
It's an alias I use.
I told you this is
a sensitive situation.
It's bullshit.
I spoke to this girl.
She wasn't kidnapped.
Mike, she's been brainwashed.
She lives In an army
camp, for God sakes.
She's become sympathetic
to her kidnappers.
I told you that.
What?
Ask her her name.
Go ahead, ask her
her name.
What's your name?
My name?
Your name.
Ana Gale.
She's lying.
Her real name
Is Ana Robbins.
What does that prove?
It proves that In
her state of mlnd
she can't be trusted.
Neither can you.
How do I know who
the hell you are?
Do you think
I could have got
you out of prison
without pulling
political strings?
What?
Whats he saying?
Lets meet somewhere
and I'll prove to you
everything I said Is true.
Mike, where are you now?
Somewhere close.
Listen, there's
a reservoir just
outside of town.
No. A public place.
The town center
main plaza in
30 minutes.
Okay. Bring
the girl, all right?
J Just bring the money.
Prick.
What'd he say?
He said your real name
is Ana Robbins.
That was my birth name.
So why did you
lie about that?
I took my mother's
maiden name over
a year ago, okay?
I don't care any more.
I'm gonna see that guy.
Find out what the problem is.
And me?
You're gonna stay
right here.
Fine.
What the hell?
Get off me!
No!
Sorry.
M Mike.
You got 20 seconds
to give me my money.
Thats not necessary.
And the snippers?
What are you
talking about?
Call them off, you
lying piece of shit.
They're there for
our protection.
You got 10 seconds.
Seven. Six.
All units stand down.
Where's my money?
Where's my girl?
Somewhere safe.
You shouldve brought
her with you, M Mike.
You must be
fucking joking.
Maybe we got off on the wrong
foot. I shouldve been more
forthcoming. The situation...
Has changed.
I wanna know who the fuck
you are and who sent you.
I work for the U S government.
Its a special division
of the C IA.
Thats why I was able
to work the prison
deal for you.
Why?
We want the girl.
She wasn't kidnapped.
Yes, I know that.
Who is she?
Iùs none of
your business.
I wanna see
my money now.
M ike, I'm prepared to offer you
substantially more money if
you get the girl to me now.
That sounds like
a real good offer.
I think I have a better one.
How about fuck you?
What the fuck is
wrong with you, huh?
Drago wants you dead.
Vlado wants you dead.
You have nowhere to go.
Maybe if I bring her
back, they'll pay me.
Sit down, M ike.
Sit down!
Wanna kill me?
Go ahead. You'll
never find her.
Move! H urry!
Stay on him.
He's on a black bike.
A black bike.
Keep an eye out
for the girl.
Connelly,
we're approaching
the city center.
That jackass.
Where the hell does
he think he's going?
Drago, he's headed
rlght towards you.
Do not lose that
son of a bitch.
Do not lose him.
M r. Robblns?
Cllve Connelly on
the phone for you.
About time.
What do you
have for me?
I'm still
working on it.
What do you mean you're
worklng on lt? I hear Ana
Is not wlth Vlado any more.
Yeah, thaùs rlght.
So, whaùs the problem?
There's no problem.
Don't worry about it.
I've got it under control.
No, Cllve, you don't.
Because If you dld, we
would have Ana rlght now.
What if this guys
goes AWO L and decides to
cross the border with her?
General Drago, who
controls the borders,
is on our payroll.
Riggins won't get across
and it won't happen.
Well, that better be
the fucking case, Clive.
I've got a lot
on the llne here.
See what you can
flnd out about
thls Rlgglns guy.
Right away, sir.
All right. We're...
Damn it!
Drago, we need
to talk.
When I find that fucking
American, I will kill him.
Not likely.
Riggins is very,
very well trained.
General, the guy walked
Into your camp, blew
the place to shlt
and walked out
with the girl.
Excuse me. What
are you saying,
I'm incompetent?
No. I'm saying you don't
understand who the fuck
you're dealing with.
The American
I'll kill for free.
What do you
propose for
the girl?
There's $100
thousand in cash.
You can do whatever
the fuck you want with
Riggins. But I get the girl.
Vlado Karadjov may
have a problem with that.
Fuck Vlado.
Because of him
all this happened.
He brought the girl
to your camp without
considering the consequences.
General, you work for me.
You do what I need
to have done.
And there's another
$400 thousand for you.
Deal.
General.
They are in the train
station. Leùs go.
How do I get
to Plovdlv?
The Ested departs
In 20 mlnutes.
Where do you
think you're going?
Let go off me.
I'm calling for help.
No, you're not.
I don't care
whaùs going on
but I'm not fucking
around any more.
Okay, leùs go.
How did you find me?
The bellboy.
Shit.
J ust get up.
How come everybody's
looking for you?
I've no idea.
I don't.
There's something
you're not telling me.
Why don't you ask
your employer why
he really sent you?
He already told me.
You believe that?
Great.
Get down.
Come on!
Come on.
[Man speaks In
Bulgarlan over PA]
Come on.
Do not shoot the glrl.
The American,
where did he go?
Where is he?
There they go!
This way, leùs go!
Come on.
Get in the back.
Get down.
Hang on.
Helpl
I'm stuckl
You all right?
Okay.
Where are we going?
Sit down.
Two coffees, please.
(newsman)
Were last seen
In a vehlcle
wlth llcense
plate G 1088F H.
Agaln, the Amerlcan
Mlchael Rlgglns
Is consldered armed
and extremely dangerous.
Ana Robblns Is the daughter
of bllllonalre tycoon
Alastalr Robblns
an oll and shlpplng
magnate, who passed
away last week
due to heart
compllcatlons.
Ana has been mlsslng
for more than a year.
Slx months ago
her father offered
a $2 mllllon-reward
for her safe return.
You're Alastair
Robbins' daughter?
Well, that explains a few
things, don't you think?
Look, I'm sorry.
For what?
For your father.
Forget it.
I despised him.
Why?
He had an affair
with my mother and
got her pregnant.
But he never wanted
to marry her.
She loved him
and she drink herself
to death.
I hated hlm
and dlsowned
hlm for that.
It was a lot of
money to give up.
I don't care
about that.
I never saw hlm agaln.
Look, Ana...
Excuse me.
I-I'd like to...
U m, o-okay, I'm gonna
have to call you back.
Mlkel
Get in.
They're everywhere.
Yeah, iùs gonna
get worse.
How much?
How much what?
To take me in?
Not enough.
And if we don't?
You're shot I
I'm fine.
Are you sure?
It looks...
Yeah, I'm okay.
J ust wait here.
No, but others have
tried. We're in trouble.
People are
trying to kill us.
Hold still, okay?
Sorry.
J ust grazed you.
You're lucky.
Lucky M ike.
Good as new.
Who did you call?
Don't lie to me.
A friend.
Someone I can
trust. He'll help us.
Why do you know
you can trust him?
The same way I know
I can trust you.
Sir?
We got a problem.
What do you mean?
This guy's a loose
cannon. Take a look
at this.
M ichael Riggins.
Ex Marine Corps.
Weapons transporter.
Honorable discharge.
Prison time.
Solitary.
The guy's a goddamn
out-of-control mercenary.
This is worse
than we thought.
Get me a flight
to Gorna.
Wait.
Iùll be all right.
Come on.
Vlado!
Ana.
I knew it.
He's here to help us.
Yeah, sure.
Are you all right, Ana?
I'm fine.
You have cost me
much trouble.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Help us, Vlado, please.
They're trylng
to klll us.
Okay. I will take you
to the American Embassy
in Luka.
I'll take care of her
as I always have.
I'm still
coming with you.
I have some
unfinished business.
Vlado.
Why am I not surprised?
Time to show you
the money, M ike.
I assume we stlll
have a deal.
Not that you have much
choice a this point.
Pick it up
and walk away.
What about Ana?
I'll take care of her.
I promise.
Take the car.
Vlado won't need it.
M ike.
What are you dolng?
Everything'll be fine.
So, It really was
all about the money.
You bastard.
Don't worry.
Well, princess.
What do you want?
Your father was either
a sentimental old fool
or he felt guilty about
fucking your mother
and not marrying her.
What are you
talking about?
He left the controlling
interest of Robbins
I ndustries to you.
You must be kidding.
I have no interest
in his dirty business.
Thaùs good.
Then you won't have any
trouble signing this.
Iùs pre-notarized.
Iùs a transfer deed
of your controlling interest
of Robbins I ndustries.
All what it needs
is your signature.
Transfer to who?
Your uncle,
Trent Robbins.
Uncle Trent?
He's behind all this?
Iùs your father's brother.
Somebody has to run
the business, right?
No, this is all wrong.
He can't do this.
What do you care?
J ust sign the
fucking paper.
No! You'll kill
me anyway.
You stupid bitch.
Sign the document.
No.
You are either going
to sing this document
or I'm gonna have
little pieces of
your brain all over it.
Do you understand me?
Where the fuck
did he come from?
Vlado. He saved us.
I'm sorry.
He was a good man.
Drago, he's headlng
out of town In your
dlrectlon. Cut hlm off.
Copy that.
One down.
Watch out!
There they are.
Keep on them.
Hang on.
Get at 'em!
They're getting close!
Stay with them.
[Honks horn]
Shit.
Watch out I
There they are.
Keep on 'em.
Right there.
Shoot now. Now!
How the hell are
they flndlng us?
Connelly.
Where the hell
are they?
Goddammit, we lost them.
We gotta return
to base now.
Oh, shit.
I guess thaùs it.
Well, leùs go.
Come on.
I guess these are the best
accommodations in the area.
At least there is no bed
for you to tie me to.
There you go.
Thaùll have to do.
Thank you for coming
back for me.
Why did you do it?
It beats the hell
out of me.
How did you
end up here
of all places?
The Marine Corps
brought me
to the Balkans.
I was in Kosovo
all the way up
till it ended.
Saw things in that war
no one should have to see.
So I came here.
To do what?
Transport of
high tech stuff.
You mean a
weapon smuggler?
Not exactly.
I was bringing weapons
out of war zones.
Maybe it was
my way of justify
what I was doing.
And you got caught.
Yeah.
And now you're just
a kidnapper, huh?
I was.
Are we gonna make it?
I don't know.
It doesn't
look too good.
Every road from here
to Luka has been sealed.
Isn't there some
other place we can
run to?
You don't run from
a guy like Connelly.
You just make it
easier for him to
put a bullet in your back.
Leùs get some rest.
You get some sleep.
I'll take
the first watch.
At least I'll die rich.
What are you
dolng up?
I couldn't sleep.
How Is your wound?
Where is he?
He's gone under for now,
but he can surface
any minute.
This is the most insane
fucking thing I've seen.
Where's Drago now?
I've got everyone
of his men on it.
Still nothing.
This guy has more
brains and guts than
all of you put together.
If you had paid Drago
the money he wanted
for the girl,
none of this
wouldve happened.
From now on do
not do anything,
I mean anything
without checking
with me first.
Got it?
Hey.
Wow. What
happened last nlght?
The best thing that
happened to me
in a long time.
I don't care
who you are.
I'm just damn
glad I met you.
I need to find
some transportation.
[People shoutlng]
[Honks horn]
Leùs hit the road.
Pollce are telllng me
a truck was stolen
from a farm
twenty kilometers
from here by a
man and a woman.
J ust got a call.
The Board will give me
full control of the shares
within 30 days
if Ana can't be found.
Kill them both.
Three mlles
to the Embassy.
They know we only
have one place to go.
Relax.
Yes, sir.
Here we go.
Buckle up.
[Speaks in Bulgarian]
Oh, shit!
Take the wheel.
Good.
Sir, we got an unidentified
vehicle inbound at a
high rate of speed.
Terrorist attack!
Take your positions!
Fire!
What are they dolng?
They thlnk
we're terrorlsts.
Stay down. Get down.
Leùs go.
Come on.
All right.
Get down over there.
Anna, come on out, kltten.
U ncle Trent?
Stay down.
Fire!
I'm not gonna
ask you again.
Come out, Anal
fuck me.
Ana!
Take the second floor.
Ana?
Ana!
Where are you?
Ana?
U ncle Trent.
You bastard.
Come on, kitten.
Everything's gonna
be all right.
You llar. You've
been trylng to kill me.
Ana.
Ana?
Come on, Ana.
Anna, come on out, kltten.
Shit! God!
Shit. M ike.
Oh, Shlt. Mlke.
Listen, I got a lot
of money. There's
a lot more money.
A lot. I'll give
it all to you.
You'll never live
long enough.
No!
Ana?
Llsten to me llke you've
never llstened before.
I want you
to call Ana now.
You're gonna
talk me to death?
Have it your way.
I can't believe...
Are you okay?
Yeah.
That one
didn't graze me.
Still lucky M ike.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
U. S. Marlnes.
Stop rlght there.
Let me get
those hands.
God bless America.
All rlght, boys,
stand down.
So,
now that you're
a rich woman
what are your plans?
I thought I'd
kidnap you for
a change.
But this time
we'll do it right.