Over here, hon.
- What's wrong, baby?
- Shh, hold on.
Stacey's down.
Target's loose.
West alley. West alley.
On your knees.
On the ground.
Hands behind your head.
Who are you?
Interpol? CIA? Mossad?
None of the above.
Target acquired.
Do you have the package?
Affirmative.
Dispose of the target.
No! Please.
I have information.
We have what we need.
It's not on there.
What I know, no one knows.
It's a thousand times more valuable
than anything on that drive.
Please. Have mercy.
You were supposed to kill this guy.
What part of that wasn't clear?
You were clear.
It's just that...
It's just what?
Your guys went soft?
Or is it just the one guy?
The new guy, what's his name?
Mercy Callo. Is that a name?
It's a crutch.
He's the one who caught the guy.
Yeah. And then
he didn't follow orders.
We're slipping, John.
Stacey's dead, and now we got this.
I know it's your ass in the
world, but it's my ass in D.C.
And in case you haven't noticed,
it's not going well.
He got us information.
Valuable information.
I'll be the judge of that.
Now, in 30 seconds or less,
tell me why I shouldn't kill you.
Colonel, if this intel is right,
and he is who we think he is,
this is a game changer.
If we could get him and flip him,
it would set the terror business
back decades.
Not to go after him, not to try,
not an option.
Colonel?
I agree.
As do I.
Kyle, can your team be ready
in 48 hours?
Yes, sir.
Colonel Harding
will lead this operation.
Kyle, you'll be support.
Excuse me?
Thank you, colonel.
All right.
This is black ops, not military.
Colonel Harding is black ops.
Yeah, a lifetime ago.
It's not the same out there now.
This came from on high, Kyle.
My hands are tied.
These are my people.
We got this intel.
I know you did.
Kid, I'm sorry.
Mercy!
Yes, sir?
What happened out there?
He just started talking, sir.
They're all gonna talk.
You can't question orders.
I know.
Look, you weren't everybody's
first choice, Callo.
You were mine.
You got it?
All right. New assignment came
in. We head out in the morning.
Captain.
This assignment
have something to do
with the guy's information?
Doesn't mean you were right.
Approximately 24 hours ago,
we received information
that a high value target
had been captured
and was being held
inside a Chechen prison.
But the Chechens are denying it.
The target's name
is Rudolph Martin.
Can I help you?
Yes.
Agent Black,
I asked her to be here.
Natalie, grab a chair and join us.
Of course, sir.
So why are the Chechens
denying they have him?
Because they want him
for themselves.
Why?
During the second Chechen War,
Martin was hired by Shamil Baseyev,
the militant separatist leader,
to conduct a series of attacks
on civilian targets inside Moscow.
Martin took their money
but reneged,
never going through with
the attacks. He conned them,
he humiliated them
and stole their money,
and, as a result,
they lost the war.
Many of the old hard-liners
blame Martin for the tide turning.
He is their
public enemy number one.
Our mission is to
infiltrate the prison,
extract Martin, alive,
and bring him back
to the United States.
Any questions?
All right, you're dismissed.
Let me just have a word with her.
You know how to make an entrance.
Too much?
Maybe for some. CIA?
Oh, I'm something like that.
What's Insight?
It's a global intelligence company.
Basically the CIA for businesses.
What's she doing here?
I have no idea.
I could tell by the way those
soldiers were staring at me,
they haven't a clue
as to why I'm here.
They were staring at you because
you're an attractive woman
and they've been running
around the desert for months.
You're here because
I ordered you to be here.
You know Rudolph Martin.
No one knows Rudolph Martin.
Then why did England,
Germany, Israel,
Spain and the United Nations
ask you to advise
their counter-terrorism
division regarding Martin?
How did you know about that?
Well, these medals
aren't just for show.
Yes, I've studied Martin,
but if anyone says
they truly know him,
they're full of shit.
Every sentence regarding Martin
should come with a disclaimer.
In your expert opinion,
what are the Chechens
going to do to Martin?
It's been a long time
since my own country sought
my counsel, Colonel Harding.
Well, the slate is clean here.
Is it?
With me it is.
Well...
I think the Chechens are
going to give him a trial,
something public, and then
they're gonna execute him.
Probably within the same hour.
I agree.
But he's too valuable to kill.
Which is why you're here.
Natalie, your father
was my best friend
and the finest soldier
I ever served beside.
Why is that relevant?
It's relevant to me.
You are in a unique position.
You not only know the enemy,
you have my faith
and trust as well.
What do you need me to do?
Once we get that
son of a bitch back here,
you'll verify his identity
and lead the interrogation.
You'll break him.
Until then, educate the team.
Make sure they know
who they're going to get.
What is this?
It's good to know
who you're talking to.
Martin ascended to
the top of the FBI's
and Interpol's Most Wanted list
a decade ago.
He has no birth certificate,
no passport,
and claims residency
in no particular country.
Rudolph Martin is the man
behind the man.
He puts people together,
he moves money,
and provides intel
on possible targets.
He's not the face of terrorism,
he's the brain.
The prison is located
at the base of
the Caucasus Mountains.
This totally isolated
maximum security facility
is nicknamed Inferno.
The prison is built down, not up,
and there are eight levels.
So you won't find any signs.
No prison yard.
Once you're in, you don't come out.
Your initial point of entry
is a boiler room.
This gives you access
to the northern stairway.
From there, it's a straight shot
to solitary.
We want you in and out of there
in three hours.
The first four are
administrative offices,
lockers and so on.
Then there are three levels
of general population.
There are approximately 60 to 70
prisoners in this area.
And then finally, the eighth level,
is solitary confinement.
Martin is likely here,
although we can't confirm this.
Percy Kendall.
This is the only known photograph
ever taken of Martin.
It was taken in South Africa
five years ago.
It's never been authenticated.
He is hyper intelligent
and extremely paranoid.
He puts out false information
about his whereabouts,
he fakes leads, he employs doubles.
That might not even be him.
You gentlemen will be the first
to know that for certain.
The guards, approximately 40,
live in fear of their warden,
Ivan Rudovsky.
Born and raised in Lebanon,
but of Chechen descent,
he's a former SAS officer
charged with the murder of a POW.
Before sentencing,
he fled Chechnya,
and now oversees
all Inferno's operations.
Once the package is secured,
you're gonna proceed
a half klick east
to the extraction point.
Listen, gentlemen,
you're gonna go in soft,
you're gonna come out heavy.
I expect it's gonna take
a lot of noise to break Martin out.
No one has ever escaped Inferno
and you better believe
they are going to do
everything in their power
to stop you from taking
its most famous guest.
It's just you, gentlemen.
No plan B.
No back-up plan.
No cavalry coming from behind
to save the day.
Success or failure of this mission
lies solely in your hands.
Pretty impressive.
Sorry,
I didn't mean to startle you.
You didn't.
Can I help you?
You know, I don't think
I've ever met anyone
with the name Mercy.
Well, it wasn't the easiest name
to grow up with as a kid,
but I survived.
It's interesting.
Your parents must've been
interesting people.
I didn't know them very well.
I read about how they died.
I'm sorry.
It was a long time ago.
It's a remarkable
coincidence, isn't it?
What was?
Well, the Russian
that you apprehended
had ties to the United
National Defense Front.
But I'm sure you knew that
before the mission
even started, right?
Excuse me?
That's why you didn't kill him.
You needed info from him.
I'm not allowed to discuss
details of my missions with you.
How exactly did it go down?
I mean, did he
offer it up right away
or did you have to lean on him
a little bit?
Conversation's over.
All due respect, colonel,
she's a civilian,
with no authority
to go digging around
into classified information.
This is a decorated sergeant.
Who you just cited in your report
after he failed to follow orders.
Look, according to
Sergeant Callo's file,
when he was 13 years old
both of his parents were killed
along with 300 other people
when a Sierra Air jet
exploded over the Atlantic.
The group that claimed
responsibility
was the United National
Defense Front.
The same group that your
Russian source belongs to
and that has been linked to Martin
several times in the past.
And you think Sergeant Callo
is hunting Rudolph Martin?
I think that Sergeant Callo
may be hunting every single person
that was responsible
for his parents' death.
The mission, gentlemen,
is to get Martin here alive.
You're suggesting that Sergeant
Callo can't follow orders?
I'm not. But he did.
Look, I can only imagine
how one would feel
when coming face-to-face
with the man who killed
someone they loved.
I don't know how I'd react,
but if I had a gun handy
when I was standing next to them,
it might make my decision
more clear.
Okay. Enough. Okay.
Captain Wilkes, Agent Black,
get your team ready.
Thank you, sir.
Sir.
I gave you those files
to familiarize yourself
with the men,
not psychoanalyze them.
Look, this man's past
is his present.
And resolve is within his reach.
I'm sorry,
but if you want my opinion,
he should not be
a part of this team.
Yes?
Is that confirmed?
All right, get the men ready.
Change of plans.
We received intel that
an armored division
departed a military base
outside of Grozny
about 90 minutes ago.
Unless they're about
to invade Georgia,
they're en route
straight to Inferno.
They're planning on moving him?
Or maybe they just realized
there are folks like us
who might just want
to try to come and get him,
and they're taking precautions.
Either way, we can't
have you fight an army.
Obviously,
this moves up our timetable.
The convoy should arrive
in approximately two hours.
Our entire operation can last
no more than 90 minutes.
We need 15 minutes
on either end for travel time,
so that leaves
60 minutes to get in,
get Martin and get out.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Go.
They're through the fence.
What's Sergeant Callo doing?
It's a signal booster for when
the guys go underground.
Helps with the radio,
EKG and video relays.
Bogey guard, 12 o'clock.
He sees them.
They're in.
Something's wrong.
Take it down.
The key is not working.
Gonna blow the door.
Callo, where are you?
I'm in the hallway.
What the hell's going on up there?
I heard something.
Return to your position. Now.
Captain...
Callo, repeat that.
Almost there.
Stand by.
What did Callo just say?
Did not copy, Callo. Repeat.
Perfect.
I'm on to you, you wanker.
I know you're the grass
in this prison.
We're watching.
Now your turn.
Let's see what you've got.
I offer you your freedom,
and this is all you've got?
You're weak!
Now my turn.
Burn that body
and clean this shit up.
And that's how you maintain
order within the inmates.
With all due respect, warden,
that was not order, that was chaos.
Fuck you and your respect.
If you'd sorted this out right
in the first place,
I wouldn't be here
wiping your Chechen ass.
Now, I know you're pissed off
that I got your position.
But I suggest you get over it
very quickly.
I was quite content
never to visit the homeland
of my father ever again.
But what you saw out there,
that was my mother's side.
That was British blood
flowing through my veins.
And I suggest
if you ever see it again,
you should avoid it at all costs.
Now get out.
I've got things to do.
You comfy there?
Almost there.
Standby. Standby.
So where are they now?
Southwest stairwell.
Everything's set.
Just awaiting your orders.
Perfect.
So, what are you waiting for?
Let the show begin.
Go, go, go!
Aah!
Whoa, what just happened?
What's going on?
Sergeant, who's shooting?
I don't know, sir.
Are the cameras on night vision?
- Take us off infrared.
- Yes, sir.
Revolver Actual, this is
Revolver Main, do you hear me?
Revolver Main, do you read?
Shit!
I want him dead now!
We need an image.
Let's go!
Something's wrong.
I'm on it.
Got it.
Colonel?
They're calling in now.
Okay.
Excuse me, sergeant.
Yes, ma'am.
Hi. Would it be possible for me
to look at the video footage again?
We can't tie up those monitors up.
It's important.
Warden Rudovsky?
Five confirmed dead.
I'm not interested in
the five that are dead.
I'm only interested in the one
that's still alive.
I have men checking
every single access door,
but there are literally dozens.
There's barely enough room
to breathe in there,
let alone move. He's most
likely caught inside somewhere.
Warden, look.
So much for most likely, Alexi.
Switch all these monitors
to Level Two feed.
All guards on Level Two,
secure your stations.
I want this rat found now!
Revolver Main,
this is Revolver Actual,
do you read me?
Revolver Main, this is Revolver
Actual. Do you read me?
Everything that's out there
is in here on these back-up
servers.
Should only take me
a second to sync up.
What's this?
That's transmitting
the team's frequency.
Did you hear that?
Ma'am?
I thought I just heard something.
I'm sorry, ma'am,
I didn't hear anything.
Stop calling me ma'am.
Can you roll this back
a few seconds?
We're no longer recording.
Revolver Actual, do you read me?
What the hell's going on out there?
In the hallway, I heard something.
Return to your position, now.
- Almost there.
- Standby!
Standby! Aah!
I'm told we can have a team there
and ready to go
in less than four hours.
With all due respect,
Mr. President,
I'm not so sure
how much good it will do.
Latest satellites confirm
the Chechens have mobilized
an armored division
from the north toward Inferno.
They will be arriving
in approximately 90 minutes.
Any second team
would not simply be fighting
a group of guards,
but an army as well.
Thank you, colonel.
They're not all dead.
Do you have a weapon?
I'm going to take my hand away.
You make a noise or move, you die.
You understand?
I do not wish to die.
You will get no fight
from me. I promise.
Good to know.
I know why you're here.
Yeah? Why is that?
Do not kill me,
and I will take you to his cell.
Whose cell?
Rudolph Martin.
You're basing your theory
that Callo's alive on this?
Primarily, yes.
Also, a few moments ago,
someone tried contacting us
on the team's secure channel.
What did they say?
Well, it was just static,
but I know that something
was there.
That's my man. If he's alive,
we're gonna go get him.
Hold on.
Nobody's going to get anyone, okay?
Even if this could be
authenticated,
there's still not enough
evidence to warrant any action.
I'm sorry.
What are you doing?
You heard the man.
He needs evidence.
I knew he was big shot.
He's terrorist, right?
Heh. Americans,
it's always terrorist.
You people must miss the Cold War.
Why do you say that?
At least we wore uniforms.
You no trust me?
Don't take it personally.
That's why you are lucky
you ran into me
when you did, my friend.
I can show you the way.
How do you say, not normal way,
but back way, the back...
I understand.
And you take me with you
to America?
What?
That is the deal.
We're making deals?
I do for you, you for me.
Is fair?
No. Not fair.
Then you can find him yourself.
Should be easy, all alone,
with the entire prison guard
population looking for you.
And you absolutely know
where he is?
I bring him his medicine every day.
What medicine?
Needles and insulin
for blood sugar. You know.
He's diabetic?
Yes.
If you're not being
straight with me...
I don't understand.
"Being straight"?
If you take me anywhere
besides Martin's cell...
I understand.
So we have a deal?
Let's go.
Lev?
Yes, sir.
Get in here.
What the fuck is that?
That's north stairwell,
between Two and Three.
I will have it fixed immediately.
It's not broken.
He's not trying to get out.
Is okay here.
No video.
How much further?
Not much now. Just here.
At the end, on the right.
That door, then into another.
Hey. I thought solitary
was in the basement?
I don't know what you know.
I only know he's here.
The key?
Never mind.
This opens all doors.
Is better than Black Amex.
Not another step.
The American is in the gym.
Who just said that?
You better hurry.
Alexi! Come in.
Copy, warden.
What are your instructions?
Change of plans.
This way!
Alexi, come in.
Are you there? Report!
Alexi!
I'll give you my car
if you answer him.
Colonel, may I have a word?
What is it?
You said you wanted evidence.
Here, this is moments
before the attack.
Okay, um...
Here, the keycard
that got us inside the prison
and through the first three doors,
suddenly stops working.
And then...
Here.
The lights turn on.
Blinds the team
and the guards enter, blasting.
They knew we were coming.
They let us in.
They knew which route
we were going to take.
They waited for the entire team
to get inside the stairwell
and then they attacked.
Colonel,
there's an informer among us.
Hmm.
Did I ask you to do this?
No. You said you wanted...
Have you shown it to anyone?
No.
Have you told anyone
what you just told me?
No.
Don't.
Your father was a great hero
here in Chechnya, Alexi.
You must be a great
disappointment to him.
We should alert
the perimeter guards
the American is on his way.
He's not going to the perimeter.
Yeah?
Sasha, take two of
your best men to solitary.
Bring the prisoner here,
I want him in my quarters.
Yes, warden.
Are you still here?
Yuri!
Where is that fat son of a bitch?
Stand back.
Which one is he in?
I don't know.
Shit, no signal.
That good, huh?
Oh. Heh. Yeah.
Pentagon will spend
$500 on a hammer
but when it comes to coffee,
that's where they're gonna
ease the tax payers' burden.
Look, we got off on
the wrong foot, all right?
I'm not usually this big a prick.
How big of a prick are you usually?
Right.
Look, you impressed me
in there. All right?
You convinced me.
Thanks.
How well do you know the colonel?
Pretty well, actually.
He and my father served together.
We haven't spoken in years, so...
Did you know his son?
Yeah.
Do you know Robert?
Well, no. I mean, I heard
the stories of his death.
What?
I'm sorry. I figured
you would have known.
How did he, uh...?
Suicide.
Special Agent Black.
The colonel would like to see you.
Sorry.
Natalie Meyers.
This is Sergeant Mercy Callo.
I'm sorry, could you speak up?
Look, I'm sorry,
but you're breaking up.
Could you just repeat yourself?
Mercy Callo.
Is this a joke?
No.
You ask me insulting questions
about my dead parents
and you think
I'm going to ignore orders.
Can we just skip to the part
where you believe me now?
Holy shit.
I knew you were alive.
I'm in solitary,
I'm about to intercept Martin.
Huh?
Warden Rudovsky!
Something's wrong.
What's wrong?
Code Red.
Prisoner's escaped.
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Now you've heard it
All before ♪
♪ Can't take no more ♪
♪ Girl, let me show you
How much I have changed ♪
I never learned to do this.
Lose something?
Yuri!
Where is that fat son of a bitch?
Stand back.
Huh?
Warden Rudovsky!
Something's wrong.
What's wrong?
Mercy, stay on the line, okay?
Code Red.
Prisoner's escaped.
Colonel Harding?
Colonel Harding, I have
Sergeant Callo on the line.
Come again?
I have Sergeant Callo on the line.
Hello, Mercy?
Mercy, are you there?
Sir?
He's gone.
Not so tough.
Tough enough.
Martin!
Hands where I can see them.
What did he say exactly?
He said he was in solitary,
attempting to intercept Martin.
Was that all?
Yes. Uh, no.
He said something was wrong.
No shit. What did he say?
He didn't say what it was.
Sir, we traced the number.
The call definitely came
from Inferno prison.
Thank you, sergeant. Why do
you think he called you?
I gave him my card before he left.
Maybe it was the only number
he had handy.
And you believe it was him?
Yes, sir, I do.
Obviously he's trying
to finish the mission.
We can't let him do this alone.
Well, you got me at a
disadvantage. You know my name.
Now, who exactly are you?
Okay. Guessing by your accent,
I would say you're American.
Marines? CIA?
None of the above?
The cuff's on the ground,
by the guard.
Take 'em and lock your wrists.
That explains why
they were coming for me.
To move me to keep you
from getting me.
What happened out in the world?
Take the cuffs
and lock your wrists.
And what if I don't?
Wow, you shoot the floor,
that's very impressive.
Here's what I think
is gonna happen.
The big boy here
already sounded the alarm.
So right now, there's more
guards coming as we speak.
You want me alive,
so you're not gonna shoot me.
And if they wanted me dead,
they would've already killed me.
So...
I'd say you're screwed, buddy.
That was some really pretty
kicking.
Very nice.
You like that?
Yeah, yeah, it's pretty.
You might like this.
Don't go nowhere.
I told you they would come.
Shut your mouth.
This is bullshit!
Why don't you do some more kicking?
Oh, that'll work.
I need a clear path out of here.
If you think I'm going to help
you get out, you're insane!
How many guards
have I already killed?
How many more do
you want to see me kill?
You can spare them.
There is a passage.
Put it on speaker.
No shit.
Sergeant Callo?
This is Natalie Meyers.
Can you hear us?
Is that you?
Yes, it's me.
Mercy, it's Kyle.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I may have a way out
that should have
minimal resistance.
Sergeant Callo, this
is Colonel Harding.
- Do you have the package?
- Yes, sir.
But he has assured me
he will not go willingly.
Can you subdue him?
I can, but if I have to go up
eight flights,
carrying a 200-pound man,
I don't like my odds, sir.
Hang on the line, sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Martin has to believe
that we're his only
chance for survival.
How is he going to do that?
Natalie, this is a terrorist.
A good one.
He won't believe you
if you're thinking about
some bullshit immunity deal.
I wasn't going to suggest that.
May I?
Sergeant Callo,
does Martin know where he is?
He knows he's in prison.
Does he know he's in Chechnya?
I'm not sure.
He's heard a bunch of folks
speaking Russian.
So he probably thinks
he's in Russia.
He has friends there that remember
how he helped them during the war.
He's probably just waiting
to talk to somebody in charge.
Mercy, you tell him
he's in Chechnya,
he knows it's only a matter
of time before he's killed.
Okay. Is the extraction plan
still in place?
Yes. Look, you have 40 minutes.
Chechen ground forces
will be there in 55 minutes.
- I know it's cutting it close.
- We'll be there, sir.
How can we contact you?
I swiped a cell phone.
Once I can get some reception,
I'll text you the number I have.
Mercy, this is the only shot we
have to get you out of there.
Once the window closes,
you're on your own.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
Good luck, Mercy.
Ms. Meyers?
Yes?
Thanks for answering the phone.
Of course.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
If the warden find out
I helped you escape,
he'll not only kill me,
he kills my entire family.
I understand.
You know, you kicked me,
I punched you.
I think I deserve
a first name at least.
What is this?
When you were brought in,
were you blindfolded?
Maybe unconscious?
Why do you care?
You tell me.
Check the IDs again.
You're in Chechnya.
Seems as though
this prison ain't enough.
The Chechens have
ground forces en route.
We have 40 minutes
to get you out of here.
So you can either cooperate with me
or I'm gonna leave
your ass to them.
It's your choice.
Untie me.
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
Warden, we found him.
Kyle, it's him.
They're moving through
the cell block now.
They? Does that mean
he has Martin?
Well, this is all it says.
All right. May I?
Yeah, sure.
What are you doing?
I'm going to input the cell,
and track it through
the phone's GPS.
How do you do that?
Really?
CIA spy stuff.
I can read his text,
check his email,
even listen to his music
if I want to. Thanks.
I can't get service at my apartment,
but five floors below ground
in Chechnya, no problem.
You know, I'm not a terrorist.
You keep telling yourself that.
You really believe
that the United States
are the good guys, don't you?
Compared to you, we're angels.
Oh, yeah? What about
the Native Americans?
Or, hey, what about
the African slaves?
Or what about the wives
of the guards you just killed?
You really think
they would call you an angel?
Would you just lower your voice?
Sure.
You have absolutely no idea
where we're going, do you?
I know exactly where I'm going.
It doesn't look like it.
Why do think terrorism exists?
You believe al Qaeda
likes sleeping in caves
and living in fear?
They live in fear?
Of course they do.
What about the United
National Defense Front,
they live in fear too?
Yeah, naturally so.
No. They hide like roaches
because they put bombs on children
and send them into restaurants
and soccer stadiums
and airplanes.
They don't live in fear.
You need to be human to be afraid.
They're evil,
just like you.
Now whose voice needs lowering?
Wakey, wakey!
You know why you're here,
now talk to me.
Why are you the only guard
he left alive?
I don't know what their plans were.
Their plans?
So they're a team now, are they?
They've been looking for an exit
with the least
amount of resistance.
There it is.
The exit on Level Seven.
Leads straight out of the prison.
This is it. This is
the fire exit. Come on.
They'd have been home free,
except I had the guards
seal all the exits.
I think I forgot
to mention it to you.
Lev, switch all these monitors
to the Level Seven feed.
It's welded shut.
So don't you guys carry C4
or something to blow shit up with?
Got a grenade.
I could blow up the door
but it's gonna take down
the wall and the ceiling.
Hello, fellas.
We gotta go.
Now how do you think
I knew about that exit?
Detailed information, satellites.
So that's your story.
Shut down all electronic locks
on the main population.
Yes, warden.
Come on.
What's the matter?
Card's not working.
What do you mean
the card is not working?
You're not swiping it right.
I swiped. It's not working.
Then push the numbers,
something. Punch it.
Warden Rudovsky.
We have reinforcements
arriving within the hour.
I fail to see how sending in
what few guards
we have left will do.
With twice as many,
we could not stop them.
Who said anything about
sending in the guards?
Now sit your arse down there
and keep out of my sight!
Attention, all Inferno staff...
report to the main entrance,
Level One, immediately.
This can't be good.
Attention, all prisoners.
This is Warden Rudovsky.
We have two strangers
in our prison.
The man that brings me
these men, dead or alive,
will receive a full pardon.
Shit.
Unlock all the cells.
All of them?
Every single one.
Rudovsky, you've gone insane.
We will never be able to get
control of this prison again!
Never!
Maybe.
But that is no concern of yours.
Guards.
What is the meaning of this?
Get this piece of shit out!
Rudovsky, what are you doing?
Get him out of here.
What you are doing?
Rudovsky!
Look, not to insult
your kung fu or anything,
but I think those AKs might
have really helped us there.
I checked all the AKs,
the AKs are out.
Oh, you checked every single
one of those hundred guns?
They were all out?
Not a single bullet.
We've got 30 minutes
to get out of here...
The key!
Do something!
You ever wish you would have
gone to dental school?
Look, if you want to survive this,
you got to start trusting me.
All right.
Making deals with the devil.
Well, we each our own devil,
and we make this world our hell.
You make that up yourself?
No, that was Oscar Wilde.
All right.
We got four bullets left,
we got 30 minutes until extraction
and the entire Inferno
prison's out to kill us.
You're ready?
Yeah, yeah, I feel pumped.
Let's go.
Let me go!
Get your hands off me!
Open the gate!
There he is.
Have they crossed in yet?
Yes, sir.
And do they have line of sight?
Hey, what's going on?
We're going in to get them.
They're radio silent
right now, right?
- Yes, sir.
- They're in whisper mode?
Come in.
Colonel, I'm so sorry
to disturb you.
How can I help you?
Well, I heard we're going
to pick up Mercy and Martin.
Yes. They got the go-ahead
only a few moments ago.
Still working on the plan.
How does that usually work?
Who decides on the location?
Who gives the order?
Why are you asking?
Sir, I strongly believe
there's an informer among us,
who knew our plans going in.
Natalie...
If that's the case,
then any extraction plan
could also wind up in enemy hands.
I came up with the location
and I alone will relay that
to the extraction team
and Sergeant Callo
only after they've departed.
I will also be ordering
all mobile devices confiscated
10 minutes prior to departure time.
While simultaneously shutting down
Internet access
on the base. Satisfied?
Yes, sir, thank you.
Colonel, I was sorry
to hear about Robbie.
I didn't know.
If you'd please
prep the interrogation room
in anticipation of our guests.
Of course.
Not good.
Really not good.
That one's mine.
Save the bullets.
Are you sure?
No.
All right.
Here we go.
What's going on?
You done?
I'm done.
Oh, shit.
You can use those bullets now.
Come on, come on.
Hold the door.
Hold it.
A little help.
That club won't hold
for long. This way.
Which way now?
Through the main cell block?
Oh, great. Awesome!
Extraction team leader,
you are go for launch.
Power control levers going to fly.
Revolver Actual, Revolver 16.
We have departed for extraction.
Almost out of here.
All right.
Fellas...
Tony, Frank...
All right.
We don't need to do this, do we?
We do? We gotta do it.
Okay, two at a time.
All right, well...
We were given an option
to bring you in
dead or alive.
Choose.
Anyone ever chosen dead?
That's Kong, king of the inmates.
Look, I don't think we...
Hold up.
Are you afraid of me?
What?
You can't hear me up there?
I said, are you afraid of me?
When I was a boy,
a gang broke into my home,
murdered my father,
raped my mother and sisters,
tortured me, left us all for dead.
I was the only survivor.
When police found me,
they said the gang
would most likely come back
to kill me
because I was witness.
I was 10.
I wasn't scared then.
I am not scared now.
That was a very touching speech.
Just give me a second.
You and me.
You keep these others back.
If you win, you get me dead
and him alive.
As you wish.
All right.
Um, can I talk...?
Can I just talk to you
for a second?
I think you got
hit on the head a lot.
Keep an eye on the other one.
This is a terrible idea.
You got four shots left.
Anything happens to me,
you get to the extraction point.
Trust.
Sir, satellites confirm
the Chechen Army
should arrive at Inferno
in approximately 30 minutes.
They've picked up their pace.
Should be over very soon.
Boom! Finish him.
Are you kidding me!
Hold it.
All right.
How about instead of one pardon,
we all get out of here?
What are you talking about?
I got the key to the front door.
Right here.
Robert was sick.
After returning from Afghanistan,
he complained of headaches, nausea,
but mostly nightmares.
I told him it was just stress.
Of being in combat.
That I had gone through what he had
and it would all pass.
But they didn't.
I brought him in for tests,
and the doctors at the VA
pronounced him healthy.
That all he needed was some rest.
I believed them.
Robert didn't.
He would act out, lose his temper.
I told him, you got to stop
acting like this and...
grow up.
Ah. It was two weeks
before we found his body.
I'm so sorry.
Right.
Worse than losing a child, Natalie,
is having someone convince you
to side against him.
Warden, there's been an
explosion by the front entrance.
The prisoners are escaping.
Warden?
Did you hear me?
The guards are outnumbered.
Warden!
All right, the extraction point
is approximately one mile north,
through that forest,
in a burned-out village.
We got about 10 minutes.
Get the fuck up!
Well, I guess your new friend
just took off.
Let me tell you something.
These terrorists,
they're not as loyal
as they used to be.
So you think you defeated
my prison single-handedly.
Well, you forgot about one thing.
Sierra Air Flight 19.
Your tattoo.
That's the flight number.
Yeah?
You also mentioned the United
National Defense Front
and bombs on planes.
It's the only airline
to be hit by that group.
Who did you lose?
My parents.
I'm sorry for your loss.
I think you should hold on to this.
They'll shoot me on sight.
Let's go.
This is an Eagle .50.
Revolver Actual,
Revolver 16 is 10 minutes out
from extraction.
Roger.
This way.
I thought you said we had time.
We did.
Oh. So they're just early.
They're not just early.
They're not even
supposed to be here.
Are you texting?
We need to find another route.
Colonel!
Let's go.
Almost there, Rudolph.
Hang in there.
Get us out of here!
Sir, no bullet exit.
How far out?
Roger. Stop what you can,
push fluids as needed.
Rudolph, you're gonna be
fine, Rudolph.
You're gonna be okay.
What?
Not Martin.
We're still in the process
of gathering
all pertinent information.
At this time, it appears
the man currently in custody
is not Rudolph Martin.
It is someone
employed to be his double.
Did you lose something?
Yes, thank you.
Come in.
It's a Gobrecht. 1836?
It's worth a few thousand dollars.
Yes. You know your coins.
I collected as a kid.
Did you?
No. My father did.
This was his coin.
So, heh, how are you feeling?
Pretty crappy, to be honest.
But I'll be okay.
How's, uh...
I don't know
what you're calling him.
Oh, we're calling him
the Martin Double.
He's not good.
Actually, um,
he's in critical condition.
What does it matter anyway?
Mercy, it matters a great deal.
Listen to me, okay?
This could be
a very high value asset.
If he survives...
I mean, you said yourself,
he knows Martin's work.
He could know his location,
his connections,
possible targets,
I mean, the list goes on.
We won't know for sure
until we talk to him,
but this could be
a very good thing.
I don't want to take up
too much of your time.
But I just, um...
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
I was wrong about you.
And what you did was nothing
short of a miracle.
I couldn't have done it
without you.
You saved my life.
Feel better.
Mercy, what exactly happened
at the extraction site?
Do you have a sec?
Yeah. I was gonna stop by
the infirmary on my way out.
You're leaving?
Already called back to Washington.
But I have a couple of minutes.
What's up?
I don't really know how to begin.
Earlier today, when I was
watching footage of the team,
it was fairly obvious to me
that we had been set up.
Excuse me. What?
The Chechens knew
that we were coming.
You have this on tape?
Well, it's not so cut and dry,
but yeah.
I went to Colonel Harding
with what I had, and...
And?
And he didn't...
And he didn't believe me.
After we found out
that Mercy was alive
and we were planning
the extraction,
I went to him again.
Why?
Because I was worried that
if we did have an informant,
then the extraction
would also be compromised.
Colonel Harding assured me
that was the only one
that knew the exact details,
and that he alone would
relay the information.
I just spoke with Mercy.
He said the Chechens
arrived at the extraction site
at the exact time he did.
Kyle, it wasn't a coincidence.
Look, these are photos
of the troops' movements.
They were making
a bee line for Inferno,
but then all of a sudden,
for some reason,
they changed course,
They went straight to
Martin and Mercy.
And you think Harding told them?
I know that it sounds crazy.
I mean, God, I've known
this man my whole life.
It's just...
I think he blames the military
for misdiagnosing his son.
Enough to commit treason?
I know how it sounds.
It's just, he was the only one
who knew the exact details...
I'm going to input the cell, and
track it through the GPS.
How do you do that?
Really? CIA spy stuff.
I can check his texts,
read his emails...
even listen to his music
if I want to.
Natalie?
You all right?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Sergeant.
Now you have made
one hell of a mess.
You shouldn't have gone and
got yourself captured, Victor.
Can I see him?
Hey, what's going on?
Kyle?
It's not what you think, sergeant.
Your clearance only goes so high.
I'm just following orders.
Come on now, Mercy.
This is not what I wanted.
For you or for the team.
Drop the gun, Agent Black!
You look like shit.
You're one to talk.
I've met him before.
He works for Martin's network.
Why was he trying to kill you?
Because I know
how to get to Martin.
My real name is Victor.
Mercy Callo.
Of course that's your name.
You laugh it up.
Hey.
It suits you quite well.
You're all set, sergeant.
That's it?
Is there anything I need to avoid?
Getting shot.
Sergeant Callo.
Yes, sir.
At ease, sergeant.
Have you given any thought
to what's next?
No, sir.
I've never been given
a choice of assignments
in the past.
And what if that changed?
I've been asked
to put together a new team.
I'd like you to be a part of it.
Doing what, sir?
What you're good at.
This life,
it's not for everyone, Mercy.
It wasn't for Natalie.
It wasn't for my son.
They paid with their lives,
and there's a good chance
you'll pay with yours.
No one would blame you
for getting out now.
I understand the risk, sir.
But there's something worse
than losing my life.
What's that?
Living with the knowledge
that I could've helped,
but chose to get out.
Then what are we waiting for?