You have reached Gold Coast
Savings and Loan.
If you're calling about
a checking account, press one.
Come on, come on.
-You still on hold?
-20 minutes.
lt a felony to shoot a computer?
Only in California.
We show it still
in the computer, sir.
You're telling me some TRW computer
says l bounced a check for $26...
...seven years ago, and now
you won't give me the loan?
This is actually stopping me
from getting my condo.
-It's marked unpaid.
-l paid the check.
l don't believe it.
They put me on hold.
Cheer up.
You have a visitor.
Rita.
This is your mail because
it's got your name on it.
My mail is addressed to "occupant"...
...because, Max, l am the
fucking occupant of my place.
You, on the other hand,
are no longer an occupant.
ls this sinking in?
Get your shit out of my place.
Don't do this to me here.
Excuse me, Max.
Sorry if l am disturbing you guys...
...but do l look like a warehouse?
Because this guy thinks l do.
He won't get his stuff out,
and you should see what he holds onto.
What?
Come here.
Give me a break.
Cut me some slack
on some storage space.
You're out of slacks.
No more slacks for you.
Hey, don't you--
l am not one of your goddamn buddies.
l am sick of this.
Gun.
Don't move.
Put the gun down, or he's dead.
Put the gun down.
Don't be a hero.
Put that gun down.
Get out of the way.
Take it easy.
l am trying to resolve a problem
with my girlfriend...
...and you're interrupting.
Ex-girlfriend.
So why don't you take the .357,
shove it up your ass...
...and blow your brains out.
What you talking about?
Motherfucker.
That was probably stupid.
Somebody had to get the gun out
of the schmuck's ear, didn't they?
Computer is good for something.
-Are you okay?
-Don't touch me.
l don't need this shit
in my life, you know?
You know, Max...
...it's really beautiful the way
you two have stayed so close.
Next time, shoot him.
The next detective who allows
an armed bail bondsman in here...
...does traffic for two months.
l am dead serious.
Way to go, Sly.
Now that you're all warmed up,
how about room four?
She's a jogger.
She caught a stray bullet
on Ocean Drive.
Ocean Drive?
Nobody gets shot there.
Too ritzy.
You caught me.
l am lying.
l like to make shit up.
Come on. Room four.
She's waiting.
Whatever you do, do not
let Hollenbach out of that office.
Order him something to eat.
He'd stay in a burning
building for a free meal.
l will be back in about 30 minutes.
l have to go.
Miss McQuean?
Why don't you take a seat.
l am Detective Kirkpatrick.
l need to ask you a few questions
about the shooting.
l'd like to help, but l can't
even say if there was a shooting.
Kirkpatrick.
Hold on, please.
-lt's for you.
-Thanks.
l need my notes on the Juantorena
settlement typed up for my meeting.
You did it already?
You're a lifesaver.
Can you hold on?
Would you mind not smoking?
Sure.
Thanks.
Can you send them over?
l will proof them here.
So, Miss McQuean,
l am a little confused.
My report indicates
there were several witnesses--
All l know is a window broke
and l got cut by glass.
l saw a car zoom away,
if that's any help.
Who's on this line?
-Who's this?
-Records. Can you get off the line?
lt's the fax machine.
Thanks.
Sorry for the interruptions.
Phones ringing. Faxes coming in.
lt's...
...for you...
...again.
Can l borrow your pen?
What'd you do, move in?
l have been waiting an hour.
l can't stop my life
for your red tape.
My red tape? That's a laugh.
Considering your people
invented red tape.
My people?
You're a lawyer, right?
ls that a problem?
Only if you like seeing
criminals put behind bars.
You're right.
lt'd be much easier if we could
just lock people up without a trial.
Did l say that?
You people all say that.
Because you people
work for the bad guys.
l do civil law, not criminal law.
But if you're looking for bad guys,
you could start right here.
What's that supposed to mean?
Florida law enforcement has set a world
record in bribery and corruption.
A world record?
What's a Florida cop
in a three-piece suit?
What?
The defendant.
What do you call 50 lawyers
at the bottom of the ocean?
A good start.
You know it.
lf you're done, can l go now?
Stay one more minute,
l will charge you rent.
lf you keep me another minute...
...l will bill you for my time.
Wouldn't surprise me.
Hello, is Kate still there?
She's not here.
Do you know where she went?
Try the bottom of the ocean.
Maria, l will be with you soon.
Good morning, Lisa.
How are you?
Made some friends today?
Good.
-Messages?
-Hollenbach's in your office.
Counselor. lt's about time.
l had to cancel lunch
with Donny Trump.
Sorry. l got hung up at
police headquarters for two hours.
Two hours?
Why don't you do what l do?
Plead the Fifth,
you're out in five minutes.
Thanks for the tip.
No charge.
Counselor, why are we confining
ourselves to this stuffy office?
We could be at the beach
in our bikinis.
Or in your case, a thong.
We wrapped up the
Juantorena case weeks ago.
lt just got unwrapped...
...last week...
...when l learned you helped your
client hide community property that...
...l can claim for my client.
What are you referring to?
l am talking about the ski house
you hid with your client's brother...
...the condo you hid
with his sister...
...and the plane you hid
with his mother.
Counselor, there is no ski house...
...there is no condo...
...and his mother borrowed the plane.
His mother's senile.
That's it.
She forgot to come back.
These charges are
scurrilous and baseless.
And may l say between us,
tête-à-tête...
...that this would take,
minimum, two years to prove.
He'd transfer title to new relatives.
As far as this humble counselor is
concerned, the most l would get is...
...a $200 slap on the wrist.
You're right.
l won't waste our time
in family court.
That's ridiculous.
But maritime court...
...federal maritime court...
...that's different.
Maritime court has something
to do with cruise ships, right?
Actually...
...it has to do with all ships.
Like this one.
Never heard of the Tortuga.
l didn't say the name.
Lucky guess?
Listen, Hollenbach, the law of the sea
is simple and federal.
l don't care if you hid the vessel
registry in Panama or Podunk.
l want the title signed over
to my client in 48 hours...
...or you will end up in a federal prison.
By the time you get out, you will need
a walker to chase ambulances.
Are we clear?
You know...
...you're very unattractive
when you're threatening.
Gotcha.
What's our status?
We crossed the underwater cable line.
How long?
Hard to say.
Thirty-six hours, maybe 48.
Now we search for
a junction box down there.
What about our Miami problem?
l will take care of it myself.
Oh, yes, Colonel Kazak...
...the mighty KGB who missed a hit
on a divorce lawyer.
No wonder your country folded.
l will show you how it's done.
Get out of the way.
Go, go, go.
Let someone who doesn't eat borscht
show you how to use a computer.
Give me the grid.
Take it down. Dade County.
Search for target.
There, you see?
She will be dead by dinner.
There's something l really
think you should see.
What's going on?
Make a hole. Let him in.
There you go. Take a peek.
ls that your stuff?
l guess so.
l think you pissed her off.
Definitely pissed her off.
lt amazes me how much shit
a man can accumulate. You fucked up.
Thanks. Rub it in, why don't you?
Not that.
The lawyer didn't sign her statement.
She left her pager too.
Come on, l am off duty.
This job is like a toilet: lt ain't
over till the paperwork's done.
Boss, please. l have dealt
with enough crazy women today.
You have got me confused with
someone who gives a rat's ass.
Signed statement
on my desk by tonight.
want to watch Headline News ?
lt won't kill you.
Oh, my God.
Out of my way. Move.
lt's okay. l got you.
l got you.
l want it straight.
-The girl is still alive.
-She's alive?
You sure?
ldiot.
So, Juantorena,
Miss McQuean is still alive.
l am getting a little bored...
...with your petty incompetence.
Fuck what you think.
You tap phones for a living.
l tap banks.
Without me, you'd still be in Havana
pulling bananas out of your ass.
You think you can do this alone?
What are you going to do, shoot me?
Hey, you.
Do you know how to do
everything he did?
Good.
l want the land team
ready to go in 10 minutes.
Yes, sir.
lt's Nancy. Forensics.
What do you got?
So far, all l got is a blast pattern
and a strong smell of marzipan.
Marzipan? Jesus.
Semtex?
Or C4.
The blast was shaped in a military
configuration to kill all in its path.
These guys are not fooling around.
-Who'd we draw for detail?
-You got B and G.
Good.
Go back to the station
and see what's going on.
-Boys.
-Hi, Max.
You smell like you fell in a sewer.
-You check it out yet?
-No. We just got here.
Top of the stairs, on the right.
Keep her away from the windows.
l will stash the jeep
and check the back door.
Come this way, ma'am.
Be back in a minute.
Have you downloaded the background
information of the target?
l can tell you what size
pantyhose she wears.
We know more about her than she does.
Any food?
Pop-Tarts and beef jerky.
-lt's Max's fault we got night duty.
-That's right.
He springs for Domino's.
-He's springing. l am not.
-l am busted.
-l got $10 to my name--
-Hey, guys?
l will buy the pizza.
Call Caffe Romano.
l have an account there.
Why not?
All right, you two, l need two eyes
on the front. You in back, Bean.
Light's out in the back porch,
so get one from the hallway.
How do you feel?
Like my life just exploded.
What is this place? Motel hell?
lt was a crack house
until the county took it over.
-We use it for witness protection.
-You mean targets.
-l didn't say that.
-Forensics did, on the radio.
What is Semtex?
lt's a plastic explosive...
...used mostly by the military...
...and terrorists.
l will tell you this, Kate:
Whoever's after you...
...they're real pros.
l should take that as a compliment.
lt would be embarrassing
to be killed by an amateur.
l got you some dry clothes.
Shower's right behind you,
if you want to clean up.
You get some rest.
What happens in the morning?
Figure out who's trying to kill you.
Twenty minutes, okay?
To go. Pepperonis with everything.
Extra cheese, four times.
Under Kate McQuean account.
How does she eat so much
and stay so skinny?
Colonel, we have got her.
She just used her credit card.
lt's a delivery going to....
Move your car.
My pizzas are getting cold.
Yeah, and so are you.
Hey, babe, if it were Domino's,
l'd get a discount.
lf l were Domino's,
you'd still be alive.
Door's open. How many in there?
Three more targets.
One on the ground floor at the back.
One on the second.
And one at the end of the hall.
Where's target one?
ln a room by the stairs.
Now would be a good time
to catch him.
That's better.
What did you do?
To the heat sensor? Nothing.
One just disappeared.
Okay, you mook. You better not
be touching my pizza.
Oh, shit.
Wait. Target three is moving.
Bean, G, talk to me.
G, answer me.
What the hell is going on?
Shit.
Where's the target?
Stand by. I am scanning.
Where is he?
Wait.
He's in front of you.
Shit.
Let's go.
Come on, quick.
Come back. The police
will be here any minute.
-They're out of there.
-They?
When did she become a "they"?
She's with a cop. And he's good.
He killed our whole goddamn team.
Stop.
Police cars.
We will be safe with them.
That was supposed to be a safe house
back there. Only cops know of it.
We can't trust the cops?
l only trust the cops that l know.
Right now, l don't know
how many are alive.
Kirkpatrick. Line two.
l got it.
Tell me you have got her.
What's going on?
Bean and G are dead.
-That's what's going on.
-God.
Where are you?
Not on the phone.
Not the way it went down.
What are you saying?
Somebody knows every move we make.
l ain't saying shit
until l know who l can trust.
l have lost two men. l am not
fucking around. Bring her in now.
You should call the suits.
We don't need the goddamn suits.
Got it.
Kirkpatrick.
Nice lrish name for our cop.
Let's see what he's made of.
Here we go.
One life about to end.
lf anybody's dirty,
we need to call the Feds.
Wait. Who said anything
about dirty cops?
Give us an hour.
Where?
Where l used to go on Friday nights.
This is bullshit.
You live through this,
you're fucking fired.
You just make sure
you bring the Feds, understand?
Don't worry.
Watch your six.
How long to police headquarters?
Five minutes. Go south.
-Forensics.
-Jodi, it's Max.
Hey, Don fucking Johnson.
l need a favor.
-I never lend money to family.
-l need a make on a shell.
Yeah, like l need my beauty sleep.
What do you got?
It's a center-fire shell...
...copper wash with a brass primer
and a red surround.
lt looks like a 12-gauge,
but it's marked 33.
Ever heard of a 33?
No such number.
There's no such zone.
You got a phantom cartridge there.
Phantom cartridges blew away
two of my crew.
l am sorry.
The arms world is like the Jersey shore.
lt throws up new shit every day.
I will run it right now.
Can you call me in an hour?
Where are you taking me?
My partner used to moonlight here
as a security guard.
Don't worry,
everything will be all right.
l wish l could believe that.
Lieutenant Meyerson.
Baker. FBl.
Congratulations.
Detective Aragon will take you
to the pickup point.
Come on.
The word for tonight
is "inconspicuous," all right?
Where the hell are you taking us?
l will tell you when we get there.
-You okay?
-This the guy?
Agent Baker.
Where's the woman?
Show me your l.D.
You all don't have to screw with me.
Your partner's done that.
Let me see the badge.
Where is she?
Cruise the perimeter. Make sure
this is the only way in and out.
Howdy, ma'am.
Are you okay?
l am with the FBl.
You're safe now.
lt's okay.
Why don't you ride in the other car?
l will be right behind you.
Why don't you put that out?
Seat belt for safety.
Right.
Hold the wheel, will you?
Come on. Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Stay down.
lf it wasn't for you,
l'd remember where l parked the car.
What happened?
l got my best friend killed.
How?
l was the one who called the FBl.
That wasn't the FBl.
-Who were they?
-l don't know.
l did everything l was supposed to do.
l checked their l.D.
These guys are perfect.
lf you fail again, l will kill you myself.
Now get in.
You got any cash?
l have a credit card.
This is a good place to hole up.
Looks big and busy,
and they won't remember faces.
Stay right here.
ldiots.
They use a credit card again.
Typical Americans.
Got them?
Raleigh Hotel, 1775 Collins Avenue.
Ten minutes from here, colonel.
-Forensic.
-It's me. Listen....
-What if this 33 isn't numbers?
-Go on.
What if it's letters from
a Greek or Hebrew alphabet?
You're not as stupid as you look.
Give me some time.
l will call you back.
Great. Someone gave us
the wrong goddamn key.
lt doesn't need brawn.
Finesse.
Oh, no, you don't.
No time for rest.
l need some answers.
Did you hear me? Get up.
l need your help.
We got to figure this out.
You're a lawyer, right?
That's a perfect place to start.
You got a lot of clients and cases?
This has to be connected
to one of your cases, right?
lt's possible.
You sent someone away,
now they want revenge?
l don't do criminal law,
l do civil law.
Small claims, green cards,
mom-and-pop grocery stores.
Nobody gets killed over that.
Oh, no?
Three of my friends
were just killed over that.
Three families wake up
tomorrow without a father.
l have to live with that.
So do l.
So, genius...
...did you ever piss off the KGB?
KGB?
The Russian letter for "Z"
looks like a three.
So "33" is "ZZ,"
which means Zapadny Zavod...
..."Death to the West." They were
based in Cuba to strike Western targets.
-"They" being KGB away teams.
-Go on.
They were the Navy Seals of the spy
world: wet works, black-bag jobs...
...electronic surveillance.
Very versatile.
lf it was bad, they did it.
Fuck "did." They're doing.
They're on my ass.
Avoid anything that leaves
electronic footprints.
They can enter your home
and pick your nose.
Remember the Russian spy ships
we read about?
Well, these guys worked on them.
They're into
electronic surveillance.
-That's why their l.D.s were perfect.
-What?
-They did it with computers.
-Never mind. You got family here.
lf you need a hand, most of us
are armed and dangerous.
Thanks, cuz.
You're a lifesaver...
...even without the artillery.
KGB...
...computers.
They found the safe house.
How did they find the safe house?
The phone lines.
Quarter of a million...
...cash.
What?
For the girl.
Never fucking happen.
Half a million.
Just walk away.
We got to get moving.
These bastards are on the phone lines.
Phone lines.
Eenie, meenie, miney, moe.
Let's see if you have
your ears on now.
He's using the phone.
l will trace it to the other party.
Stop-n-Shop.
l know you're out there
listening, you motherfucker.
Fuck you calling "motherfucker."
You're never going to get the girl.
l already got your girl, Earl.
l fucked her last night.
And she was good.
Big mistake killing my crew.
Big fucking mistake.
Want to know why?
Because l am going to get
every last one of you.
That's an empty threat,
Mr. Kirkpatrick.
You have no idea who we are.
Why don't you drop
the American accent?
l beg your pardon?
Fuck you, fuck whoever else
on the line. Bring your ass here.
Dasvidaniya, asshole.
Dasvi what?
"Dasvidaniya, asshole"?
Man, fuck you.
Clever bastard.
You in?
l have isolated the floor,
not the room.
Do them all.
Let's go.
What's going on?
Get back. Fuck finesse.
Two more blocks.
-He said, "Dasvidaniya, asshole."
-He knows of the Russian connection.
l wonder what else the scumbag knows.
Locate that woman.
What's that smell?
Pig shit.
Trailer over there is hauling hogs.
Be right back.
They have activated their cell phone.
lmbeciles.
lt's like painting
a bull's-eye on their ass.
l have got their position.
They're heading north.
We will have them by midnight.
Pig shit's sure going to hit the fan.
You have been looking out for me,
and somehow l forgot to say thanks.
So, thank you.
All right, Gomer, wake up.
Open the truck.
Hurry up. Let's go.
All right, okay. Don't push.
Hello, pigs.
Where the hell are they?
-Where the hell are who?
-The cop and the girl.
Good morning.
-How'd you sleep?
-Never better.
Do you have any Russian clients?
Why?
This is a Russian shell.
You got any Russian cases?
Cuban, Hispanic....
Cuban sounds Russian.
l'd have to run a list of names
on my office PC.
Forget it.
We're not going to Miami.
Maybe we don't have to.
We hit the jackpot.
Kirkpatrick's a satisfied customer
of Car-Trac, U.S.A.
Car-Trac?
A vehicle tracking system. The police
use it to locate missing cars.
Can we access it?
Yes, but it's an encrypted system
on a satellite.
lt will take a while.
Then do it.
You got five minutes,
then we're out of here.
You moved the lBMs.
l thought there was....
You're not paid to think.
You're paid to do what l say.
-May l help you?
-Actually, l was in yesterday.
-And Adam was helping me.
-l was?
l will be over in the diner, Adam.
l thought l'd be
in better hands with you.
-So what are you doing?
-Nothing.
Just fiddling with my joystick.
Fiddling with your joystick?
Do any of these have
a communications package?
This unit here has
a Hayes-compatible...
...28-baud fax to something or....
Are you more interested in hardware
or is it more software?
Hardware.
l was hoping to demo your unit.
l'd have to boot up first.
Why don't you?
We have located the junction box.
The divers are in the water.
With luck, by tonight, the targets
will be dead and we will be rich.
She's using a modem
to download files from her office.
lf she stays on,
l can trace it back to her location.
You're not going to buy
anything here, are you?
No, l am sorry.
l am just using you.
That's okay.
-We got to go.
-One more minute.
Got anything?
Do you?
No, no.
Wait a minute.
This could be it.
This guy, Emilio Juantorena.
This thing fax?
You bet.
Jodi can run this name
to see if he's got a rap sheet.
Come on. We're out of here.
Thanks, Adam.
You're the best.
Who's this Cuban guy?
He slammed his wife into a wall
and kept a dentist busy for a year.
-He get charged?
-Yes, but he's bargaining.
With what?
The S & L he owned
ran a major wire fraud.
He and his lawyer took
immunity from prosecution.
What's his beef with you?
He didn't buy immunity from
divorce or property settlement.
lt's in a boat
l am trying to repossess.
What's it worth?
$200,000. Why?
Why, Max?
The guy on the phone at the hotel
offered me $500,000 to give you up.
lt was him.
Speak.
-What the hell is that?
-Shit, the radiator. Great.
l believe we have found the bastard...
...who's been helping those idiots
put two and two together.
lt's the radiator.
lt must have overheated.
Could you come right now and check it?
You will get an extra $50
if you get here sooner.
l am into the Car-Trac system.
Got him.
They're on the inland waterway.
Thank you, Car-Trac.
We will split up. Get after them.
Take them out.
l have my own little subtraction to do.
Pull over.
We're splitting up.
Tow truck's coming.
ls this you?
Yes, that's me.
The one with the funny haircut.
lf you need a clean T-shirt,
you'd better do it now.
You look like juvenile delinquents.
We were 17.
Kids. New Jersey.
You got that much testosterone...
...and no idea what to do with it...
...looking like a hood works.
How'd you get from there
to being a cop?
My father was a cop,
brother-in-law's a cop...
...my cousin Jodi's a cop.
Family business.
-Forensic.
-Internal Affairs. Open the door.
What's the problem?
Open the door, detective.
Something punctured your radiator.
What the--?
Oh, shit.
They could have been
using Car-Trac to catch us.
We got to go. Come on.
Let's go.
-$100. Pay up front.
-Just fucking drive.
l am serious.
$100. Pay up front.
$50. Pay later.
Drive.
l always hated stick shift.
Faster.
Keep your head down.
Let him get even, we're dead.
Faster.
Shoot him.
What are you doing?
l am losing the Jeep.
lt's slowing us down.
Shoot him.
They zig, you zag.
Don't let them get ahead of us.
Look out.
lt's just a woman driving.
Shoot her.
They're behind you.
Floor it.
lt's going to blow.
Get ahead of them.
Cut them off.
Nail the brakes on three.
Hit it.
Jesus Christ.
lt worked.
-Where are you going?
-Away. Out.
Gone. l am gone.
-l am going to get away from this.
-No, we stay together.
Remember, we stay calm.
There's no "we" here, okay?
lt's me they want.
See this car? Get in.
-You can't make me.
-Watch me.
You happy? Get in the car.
You're stealing a car.
Would you shut up?
Take these things off.
l am calm now.
l'd love to, but the key
is on the key ring.
l left the key in the ignition.
Of the Wagoneer?
Shit.
What are you doing?
Don't be so stubborn.
Let me go.
What are you doing?
You will hit the pole.
You will be killed.
That was dumb.
No, you running off alone was dumber.
Who elected you
my knight in shining armor?
The same person who made you
a royal pain in the ass.
-Back up.
-Or what?
-l will take your head off.
-Bullshit.
Good right.
Had enough?
Give me your best shot.
l am waiting.
They're not on the interstate.
They took the coast road or
ditched the car and jumped the train.
What train?
l have got a thermal reading.
Rosa and l will work
toward the center.
You go back there.
Stay down.
l see them.
-Move, move, move.
-Let me go.
Let's go, let's go.
Kazak to away team.
Report in now.
We got the girl.
What about the cop?
He fell off. He's probably dead.
Whatever you do,
don't harm her for now.
I need to interrogate her...
...to find out if anyone else knows.
Bring her to me.
Where are you relative to Tortuga ?
About 40 minutes due east of Downs Bay.
Good, you will be back shortly.
You're coming with me.
You have reached Detective
Kirkpatrick's meddling relative.
Cousin Jodi can't come
to the phone right now...
...but if you'd like to leave
a message, contact a psychic.
Dasvidaniya to you, asshole.
We haven't been formally introduced.
Welcome to the Tortuga.
When l ran the KGB out of Cuba...
...l helped some very politically
incorrect characters...
...hide billions of dollars...
...in various free-world banks.
But l kept the account numbers.
Magic numbers.
All l had to do...
...was break the bank codes
used for wire transfers...
...and help myself.
Downs Bay.
Numbers are so beautiful.
Don't you think so, Miss McQuean?
Your client's husband, may he
rest in peace, knew about banks.
l know about tapping into
the secrets of phone lines.
A match made in heaven.
Unfortunately, you came along
and fucked it up.
l don't give a shit
about you or the money.
l only wanted the boat.
But you'd have brought a marshall
with repossession orders.
l couldn't afford the intrusion.
But don't worry...
...you can have the boat,
only it will be in little pieces...
...with yourself in it.
We're in.
Final decryption in process.
Good.
Start transferring the money.
This is the Cayman Islands
International Bank.
To deposit funds, press one.
Enter your international
secured PIN number now.
This is like taking candy
from a baby...
...only less screaming.
Hey, Kazak, you listening?
lt's the cop.
I know what you're doing.
l doubt it.
How tough could it be to figure out?
The Tortuga...
...Emilio Juantorena, the Cubans....
I know it all.
-Who have you told?
-Nobody yet.
I just want the girl.
-Why not trade her for me.
-But I don't want you.
Stay out of my business
for the next four hours...
...and l will leave her where she is.
l don't believe that.
l am a businessman.
My word is my bond.
How do we find him?
These radios have a 10-mile range.
The only land mass
within that radius...
...is Downs Bay.
Take the Zodiac and get rid of him.
That hurt?
Poor little baby.
Let Mommy kick it
and make it better.
This is the Cayman Islands
International Bank.
We are now processing your transaction.
You are withdrawing...
...957 million...
...831 thousand...
...150 dollars...
...and 0 cents.
Help them with the boat.
l will call and tell Kazak
he can kill the woman.
Get the fucker?
-lt's him.
-Obviously.
Go get him.
You killed my crew, my partner?
Sorry.
You have no fucking conscience.
l can't afford
the luxury of a conscience.
Kill him.
Your withdrawal will be complete...
...when you enter
the appropriate currency.
For British pounds, press one.
For French francs--
For American dollars--
Please wait for the
first available operator.
lt's all right.
lt's over.
Not quite, officer.
You just sank my client's boat.
There's going to be
one hell of a lawsuit.
Sounds terrible.
What do l have to do
to get out of it?