♫Bleak winds roar in the wilderness♫
♫Coldness numbs the senses♫
♫The haze of obscurity haunts our path♫
♫Darkness falls upon us♫
♫Let pain pervade our flesh♫
♫Let cold congeal our blood♫
♫Let havoc crush us down to the ground♫
♫But we will still be one♫
Over hundreds of years, the story of demons never ceased.
But no one has ever met one, nevertheless knew what they looked like.
They have always been described as being ridiculously beautiful and evil.
They chased them while simultaneously tried to destroy them.
They appeared in many dramas, movies, and dances yet also disappeared.
People always wondered if they really did appear, what will they do?
two two three four. Do it properly.
Come. Let's do the next steps. 3, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6...
Wait a moment. Where are you guys from. We live beneath the bridge.
What about your parents? My dad is pulling a rickshaw.
My dad is helping someone fix his house. I don't have parents, I live with my uncle and aunt.
Do you guys all like dancing? Yes.
But learning dancing is very expensive, we barely have enough to eat. How would we have an opportunity.
I'm the teacher. I can tell that you all really like dancing, right?
Right! If you guys promise me to learn sincerely then I will let you guys learn okay?
Okay! Then hurry and come in.
Okay, everyone get ready. five, six, seven , eight.
five six seven eight.
Dr. Jiang especially invited me for some tea. What is concerning you?
President Li is the older brother of Shang Hai's newspaper's Long Tou. I invited you over for some tea so that we can talk about our feelings.
You're the one who's a Shanghai celebrity. If not because you were straightforward first,
I dare not drink this tea.
A few days ago, I performed a surgery. Many reporters came to cover it.
I heard that it will be the weekend's front page.
I especially came here to thank you.
Dr. Jian's medical skills are exquisite.
But about this weekend's front page, I think you have misunderstood.
Is it possible that there can be some bigger news in Shang Hai?
Timing & subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
Nie Qing Cheng. You know her too?
I have met her a few times. Do you know her well?
I don't even recognize her. I've only seen that picture of her.
You also know that the situation outside is very chaotic. Either there's war or there's gang fighting for territories.
I think it's probably best to write about something more mellow.
That's why I decided to use this photograph as the headline for the weekend edition.
This time, I can only apologize to you.
It's nothing. I have to leave it to President Li for being so considerate.
There will be plenty of time for us. Yes.
So in conclusion, our profits for this month is good enough.
Along with the president's unbiased-
What I what isn't an unbiased view.
I want exaggeration.
- The more you are hasty, the more you won't get there.- The matter depends on the individual.
Or perhaps, there's one more option we can try.
What method?
Hello? Hello is this Mr. Luo?
Yes and this is? I am Dr. Jiang.
Dr. Jiang, is there anything you need? I want to order your medicine.
Of course. Okay, then I'll order some.
Doctor, this hasn't gone through inspection yet.
So what if it hasn't. All the medicine that have been inspected have risks too.
But you can't say that they didn't have an effect. This Luo Wen was advertising it so well.
If there's really something bad that will happen, he also can't escape.
- Okay already. Don't say anything anymore. Just do as I said.- Okay.
Hospital Director Jiang! Hospital Director Jiang! Your special drug was really so effective.
My mother was sic for so many months already but after taking your medicine, she got well immediately.
- Really so thank you.- Thank you Hospital Director Jiang for curing my long time illness. Thank you. Thank you.
That's right. I kept on coughing. I've been coughing for so many years. I've seen so many doctors but none worked.
But after taking this special medicine, I'm fine already.
- Thank you. Thank you. Your medicinal skills are really great.- Thank you, Hospital Director Jiang.
- Hurry and stand up.- Thank you Hospital Director Jiang.
Hospital Director, something bad has happened.
Those who took the special medicine had adverse reactions.
- Vomiting froth and having nonstop seizures. Someone has already reported it to the police.- What?!
What's going on?
Hello. I'm looking for Luo Wen. Is he there?
What?!
- What happened?- That guy has ran off already.
- Looks like these people knew from the start that these drugs are problematic.- Then what should we do now?
We have been in very high profile these past days. Our industry colleagues have been watching our every move.
I'm afraid that it would not be easy to bluff our way out of this.
I think that you should leave now while the police are not here yet.
Then I'll go in hiding first.
Are you Jiang Xue Wu?
- Take her away.- Go.
- Go and find Commander Ming. See if he can think of a way to save me.- Yes.
Hurry and go. Hurry.
Ming Xia, wait for a moment. I have something to tell you.
I've finished with my official duties. If it's a personal matter, let's just talk about it tomorrow.
Today is Qing Cheng's birthday. Let me off already. Allow us two have our romantic couple's world.
- Jiang Xue Wu was arrested.- What's going on?
- Reportedly, she was tricked and brought in fake medicines.- How can she be so muddle-headed? How can she buy fake medicines?
Now is not the time to say those. You also know that other than our district's police station,
what methods does other police station use? Once a person enters, he most likely will be tortured.
Then what should we do now? Do we get her a lawyer or what?
That won't work too. I'm thinking that maybe we can gather some money
- and see how many comlainants were there and ask them to withdraw their complaints.- No.
- Why?- First, we don't know if these complainants will be willing.
What if they are not willing? Wouldn't we have just wasted time?
Second, they are victims to begin with. If we use money to buy them,
isn't that intentionally breaking the law? I think that the best way now
is to find those people who sold the fake drugs and see if they can be the one to bear a part of the crime.
But those people have already ran off. In this vast world, where are we going to look?
These people usually are under an organization. I know some people who had already turned over a new leaf. I'll see if I can find some clues.
Time is pressing. Let's move.
How come he isn't here yet?