Josh: Hey, John.
How you doing, man?
It's Josh.
Hey, listen, I know we were supposed
to close our deal tomorrow,
but you've been a loyal client
for a long time,
and I wanted to reach out
and kinda offer you a deal.
I'll take 20% off the top.
I'll even take my commission off
if you wanna close today
and sell it tomorrow.
I know we have our meeting
set for tomorrow,
but I thought I'd offer
you this because,
you know, you've been such
a loyal client of ours.
Listen, we're set for tomorrow
if that's what you want.
I just wanted to
kind of give you
a heads up and see
if you were interested
in saving a few bucks.
It's not, it's not.
It's really, it's just one
of those transactions
that will, you know,
kinda help you out,
and help us out at
the same time, you know.
You know, we've been friends
a long time,
so I thought maybe you'd be interested
in something like this. But...
Yeah, I know.
But I mean, I just...
I thought maybe it would
be easier for you,
for tax purposes or whatever.
We could just, like, bang it out
and take care of it right now.
All right.
If that's what you want,
that's what we'll do.
All right.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Take care.
Fuck!
Man: All right, I call.
I'm in.
For two.
Man: Two hundred.
Come on, Jerry, let's go.
Man:
Man! Shit.
I don't wanna rush you, Jerry.
Give me a fucking break already.
If you're looking
for a slower game,
there's a rest home
down the block.
Mel, when you brought
this guy to my game,
you said he was a strong player.
I didn't realize
you meant strong
like a rock that just
sits there.
His name is Joshua,
not Jerry.
Who gives a fuck?
Make your fucking
decision already.
No.
I'm out.
Surprise, surprise. I'm
glad I waited for that one.
You all right?
I can't do this.
I'm not doing this, Mel.
Come on, you guys.
Let's just go.
One more round.
You're the boss.
Nick: You're pieces of work,
you know?
You take a deep breath
and you do what you gotta do.
Or you will never see
your family again.
All right, gentlemen.
I gotta go.
Punch me out, will you, kid?
Nick: Where you
going, Melly?
It's time. It's time.
All right.
What's going on, Mel?
Oh, I'll see you next time,
all right?
Always a pleasure, my friend.
Oh, you know you're my favorite.
You straighten this guy out?
All taken care of.
All right.
I want you to know something.
I'm making this a regular game.
I want you to hear that from me.
That's not gonna be a problem
with you and your boss, is it?
No.
There's plenty
for everybody, right?
That's exactly right.
Love you, Melly.
Me, too.
What the fuck?
Mmm.
You ready for a few more hands?
Yeah, sure.
Where do I gotta be?
Ah, see, that's the problem
with the old guys.
They're always
crapped out early.
Want some blow?
Yeah. I do.
Mmm. Get in there.
Good man.
Look at you.
Five card draw, no bullshit.
Wow. Who is this guy?
So, uh, how do you know Mel?
She's my bookie.
Hey, how's that
working out for you?
Not very well.
Mmm. You don't want to get
in too deep with
with that ball buster
and her boss.
Trust me.
Tell me about it.
You want a drink?
I'm good.
Yeah?
I'm all in.
What's going on, Jerry?
It's Joshua.
Who gives a fuck?
You have something?
Raise your bet.
You know, I'm starting
up my own book.
The terms are gonna be
a little more favorable.
At least as first.
Yeah?
How does that work?
You kick off money
to the old guy?
Fuck the old guys.
They can suck
my big, fat Greek cock.
What are they gonna do?
Come after me?
Let 'em try.
My uncle's gonna fucking
skin them alive.
I'm gonna take one.
Let's go again.
How much?
All right. Go ahead.
Get out of here.
Are you gonna be all right?
Well...
Let's go again.
Where do I have to be?
When did you get home?
What's going on? It's
7:00 in the morning.
I know.
Good morning.
Let me buy you a cup of coffee.
Why don't we go somewhere
we can talk?
I'll be right back.
What do you mean
you'll be right back?
You're supposed to help me
with Lucy's play date.
I know. I'm just gonna grab
a cup of coffee with him,
and I'll be back
in a few minutes.
No. Why?
What do you...
Why? Who is this?
Who are you?
His name is Alexander.
He's a business associate.
And we'll be back
in a few minutes.
Everything is fine.
I promise.
What's going on?
What did you get into? What
are you not telling me?
Nothing.
I did everything right.
I will tell you everything
as soon as I get back, okay?
I love you.
So, what the fuck happened?
You have no idea
what happened last night.
I got all your money back.
But I got all your money back.
You know what I'm saying?
I couldn't lose.
You should have seen him, man.
I cleaned this guy out.
I was pulling flushes and
straights out of my ass.
You know? And then, as soon
as I got enough money,
for the first time in my
miserable life, I stood up.
I stood up and walked
the fuck out of there.
And you know how much
force of will that took?
Did you get the gun?
Yeah. It's right here.
This gun hasn't been fired.
You're not listening to me, man.
I got the money. I didn't
need to use the gun.
You know?
The time to get my money
was last week.
We had a different deal.
I thought you understood that.
I thought you understood that
wasn't a fucking option anymore.
What are you, fucking
playing games with me now?
I'm not a... I'm not a killer.
You know what I mean?
I'm an accountant.
I got the money.
What else do you want from me?
I want you to do what you
said you would fucking do.
But I guess for a...
Fucking spineless
degenerate fuck like you,
that's kinda hard
to comprehend, right?
Like you did to
your fucking wife.
"Right. Oh, yeah. I'm gonna
help you with the kids honey.
"Oh, yeah." Bullshit, right?
You never had any fucking intention
to help her out, did you?
Come on. Between you and I.
Did you? You didn't fucking...
I got you...
Did you?
Were you gonna
help your wife today?
Were you gonna help her?
No. See?
What else do you want?
I want you to fucking do
what you said you would do.
Do you know the coordination,
the favors to get this
fucking gun there for you,
so you can do what you
said you wold do?
Do you know what all that took?
I tried. I tried to do it.
I couldn't.
I'm sorry. You tried?
Okay, you tried.
Well, you know what?
Fuck your trying.
I tried, all right. I tried.
I just couldn't do it.
You couldn't do it?
No, I couldn't.
That's where you and I
are different, scumbag.
'Cause I say I'm gonna
fucking do something,
and I do it.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Mom, where's dad?
I don't know, honey.
When is he coming back?
Uh...
I'm not sure.
Can we facetime him?
No, sweetie, we can't
facetime him.
Why not?
Because he's not in a place where
we can do that right now, okay?
Can I have some more OJ?
Sure.
Lucy: Yeah, but I don't
know anyone.
I wanna get some more blocks.
I don't know, sweetheart.
No, I want it now.
I'm not sure.
I love you, mom.
Joshua?
Hello?
No. No, thank you.
Sorry, I couldn't help you.
Look. I know he hangs out
here sometimes.
Are you sure he's not inside?
I'm sure, honey.
I don't know what to tell you.
We haven't seen him.
Mel: We haven't seen him.
What did you tell her?
I told her I didn't know
where her husband was.
Ready?
Yeah.
Thanks, bud.
Can you close the door
on your way out, please?
Let's be civilized.
You know, I don't need this
petty bullshit right now.
We're in the middle of
a fucking shitstorm.
And you both know it,
and then you come to me
with this kind of shit?
I just want what's right.
He can set up a game in any
other fucking neighborhood.
You want what's right?
I'll tell you what the fuck
is right.
What's right is that you go out
and you get the guy
who did Frankie.
That's what's right.
This whole town
is ready to go to war
because of it.
And excuse me, pardon me
if I don't give a shit
about your petty bullshit,
but I don't.
Now you listen to me.
You get your heads together.
You work this out.
You go out and get me the guy
who did Frankie.
And then you
bring his head to me.
You got that?
You understand that?
Do you understand?
Yes.
Good.
This is fucking bullshit
and you know it.
No. I'm doing what's right.
Small steps.
Perfect timing.
This is the only move you had,
and I thought of it before
I even started.
That's strategy.
Not like that ridiculous power
grab you pulled with Frankie
that's blowing up
in your face right now.
I know what you did.
And I know you know it.
I don't wanna hurt you.
You wanna take all of this on?
Go for it.
I just want to start to spread
my wings a little bit.
This is my neighborhood, too.
So, don't worry.
Your secret's safe with me.
So what, I'm just
supposed to trust you?
I don't give a fuck what you do.
It's just time you finally
learn how to share.
Get the fuck out of my club.
Gladly.
He's gonna fucking
hold this over me
for the rest of my life.
Then I suggest you stop
fucking around
and end this.
Hey, val.
What's going on?
Hey. Joshua isn't
inside, is he?
No.
Where is he?
And please tell me he's coming,
because we really need this.
I don't know. I feel
like something's wrong.
He never would have missed
this meeting.
I feel like something happened.
Or he just panicked and went to the
fucking casino to lose his shirt again.
No, this feels different.
It feels bad.
This guy, Alexander, came
to our house this morning.
You don't know anything? There's
no meeting set up or anything?
No. We cleared the deck so we
could spend the morning prepping.
Fucking dick.
Look, you know, I'm sorry.
I'm just gonna...
I wanted to marry a man
and I married a fucking child.
If he calls, if he
comes to this meeting,
just tell him to fucking
not come home.
Look, I don't know
what the fuck you did,
or what the fuck is going on,
but you better call me back
pretty fucking quick, mister,
and tell me what is going on.
Stop being a child and be a man.
Hello, Valerie.
I want you to come and sit down.
We need to talk.
I don't wanna wake Lucy.
I just wanna talk.
Where's my husband?
Have a seat.
I'm not gonna
bullshit you, Valerie.
I want you to know that,
right off the bat.
I'm not gonna bullshit you.
I believe we
teach people how to treat us.
Joshua's dead.
Do you want a drink?
Yes, please.
Brian, you make her a
Tequila, I'll take one, too.
We both know Joshua was
a degenerate gambler.
And he was...
Joshua was heavily
indebted to me.
Now, usually when somebody
dies, the debt is forgiven.
I mean, what more do you have
to give than your life, right?
But what Joshua taught me,
is that it's your word.
Your word is worth more
than your life.
I don't understand.
The debt your husband had
with me,
I can't forgive.
So I'm forced to come
to you to collect.
"Collect"?
Collect what? You just
said you took his life.
What more is there to collect?
This isn't about money, Valerie.
This is about honor.
What the fuck are you
talking about?
Joshua and I made a deal.
Joshua was gonna kill
somebody for me,
and I would forgive his debt.
Your debt.
Joshua couldn't do that.
Even though he knew
that I would wind up here,
sitting across from you.
He couldn't fucking do it.
So now I'm forced to
come to you.
You have to do this.
And I will make you
the same deal I made him.
One life for yours
and your daughter's.
You leave my daughter
out of this.
She has nothing
to do with this. You...
You need to do this...
Or I will slit your throat
and sell Lucy to
the highest bidder.
Give me a glass of water
for her.
And if you're thinking about
going to any of the authorities,
just know that they may
catch me,
but you will never see
your daughter again.
Wait. Wait.
Wait a minute.
Alexander:
Go wait in the car.
Morning, beautiful.
Sausages in the microwave.
Coffee is brewed.
Ready to rock and roll.
I tried, you know.
I tried.
You gotta go.
You have a little...
Go!
Lucy?
Lucy? Come on.
Lucy!
911. What's your emergency?
911. Hello?
Yes, I'm here.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right, ma'am?
No... I'm fine.
I'm sorry.
Do you have a child, ma'am?
Yes.
Please explain to them
that 911 is not a joke.
I will.
Get in.
She's here.
Where's my daughter?
Relax.
Hello?
Lucy: Mom?
Lucy?
Lucy, sweetheart. It's mommy.
Are you okay?
Yeah, but where am I?
I don't know anyone.
That's mommy's friend. I'm
gonna come get you soon, okay?
I just have to do something.
Can you come now?
I can't come now.
But I promise I'll come soon.
So just be a really good girl
for mommy, okay?
Hey, come on, come on.
I promise.
Pinky promise?
I pinky promise.
Alexander: All right,
wrap it up, come on.
I love you, okay, baby.
I'll see you soon.
Just be a good girl for mommy.
I love you.
Bye, baby.
You know...
I always thought women were
stronger than men.
I swear to god,
if you hurt my daughter,
I will fucking kill you.
So you better kill me first.
You see?
I totally believe you.
I told you from the beginning.
I am not gonna bullshit you.
You do this for me,
get your daughter back,
you get your life back.
Here's your target.
That's what he looks like.
This is what he drives.
This is his schedule
for the next three days.
Lucky for you,
he's very predictable.
And how am I supposed
to kill him?
I won't know what
to do with that.
This gun is loaded.
You just point it at him,
like you would your finger,
and squeeze the trigger.
The gun will do the rest.
And what happens
after I do that?
How am I supposed to know
that I'm not gonna end up
behind bars for
the rest of my life?
This gun is clean.
Do the deed,
leave it at the scene.
And make sure your prints
aren't on it.
Walk away.
I'll give you
your daughter back,
I'll give you another
envelope full of cash,
like the first one,
and you disappear into the wind.
I don't wanna know where you go,
I don't give a fuck
where you go.
And I'm supposed to
just believe you?
You don't have a choice, girl.
Have you checked your
financial situation lately?
Have you any idea
the fucking whole
your asshole of a husband
has put you in?
Wake the fuck up.
You're underwater, girl.
You're drowning and you
don't even fucking know it.
This is the best offer
you'll get.
Do this, you'll walk away
rebuild your life.
Why don't you just
do it yourself?
I mean, you seem pretty capable.
None of your fucking business.
Go.
Wait. When do I get to
see my daughter again?
You'll see her
when you get it done.
You have three days.
Get it done, Valerie.
Hi, I'm calling to check
on my mortgage.
Valerie Webber.
Excuse me.
Did you just say there hasn't
been a payment in three months?
What are you talking about
"refile the house"?
Can you please
double check this?
I don't... that can't be
what's going on.
My signature? No, you
don't have my signature.
No, I think you're mistaken.
We did not refile the house.
This is Webber.
No. I'll have to
call you back.
Thank you.
What the fuck!
Having fun?
Yeah.
What's the matter?
I miss my mom.
She coming to pick me up soon?
Yeah, she is. But...
You know, you get to hang out
here for a couple of days.
She just has some work to do.
Will you play with me?
Okay.
Where do you wanna play?
Here.
You can be him.
Okay.
You see that lady over there?
That's my mom.
She looks kinda mad,
doesn't she?
Why?
I don't know. I'm gonna go
ask her and find out, okay?
Okay.
I'll be right back.
Got it.
- Who is this little girl?
- I told you.
- It's my friend's daughter.
- How long is she staying?
Maybe I'll keep her.
What's going on with Nico?
Mom, why don't you call
and ask him?
Hey, wait, wait.
You all right?
I'm fine. Yeah, I'm fine.
Thank you.
Hold on.
Hold on a sec.
Come to this quiet spot with me,
have one drink and I'll
tell you if you're all right.
Okay.
Okay?
Come on, this way.
So, do you have a habit
of saving girls?
Only ones that I know
I have no shot with.
Smooth.
Does that ever work for you?
No, not really.
But I don't usually have to say much
after I've saved a girl's life.
My brothers used to fight
like that all the time.
Where are you from?
I'm from Florida.
I've been our here
a few years, though.
What about you?
L.A.
Born and raised.
What do you do?
I run a sports book.
What is that, like a magazine?
No.
People bet on sports through me.
Is that legal?
Are you a cop?
No.
Then what difference
does it make?
Does it ever bother you that
people betting through you
might have a gambling problem?
No.
How about you?
My father had
a gambling problem.
And so I was in and out of private
school and public school.
And I married a guy
with a gambling problem.
It's my story.
Not very original.
Where's your husband now?
Why did you do that?
'Cause I wanted to.
You always do
everything you want?
Yes.
Sounds dangerous.
It can be.
It also makes life
a lot more interesting.
Let me take you home.
I was told to never
get in cars with strangers.
Or pick up hitchhikers.
The same speech.
You can follow me
in your own car.
Lead the way.
Welcome, my lady...
To my humble abode.
This way.
You okay?
Yeah.
Drink?
Yes, please.
So polite.
My mom raised me to be
a good girl.
That's too bad.
Obviously it didn't take, otherwise
I wouldn't be here right now.
Ha! Is this a bad girl
thing to do?
I haven't done anything yet.
I don't know about that.
What would your mother say about coming
into some stranger man's apartment?
In the middle of the night...
Where no one could hear you
if you called out?
What would your mom say
if she knew
that you were inviting some
strange woman over?
Someone you know nothing about.
I'm sure in your line of work
you have lots of enemies.
Lots of 'em.
Is that why you're here?
To exact some sort of
revenge?
It's a hell of a thing
to kill somebody.
Especially when they
saved your life.
And you don't look
like a killer.
Not yet.
God, you're beautiful.
I'm not who you think I am.
Okay
where's this from?
Past life.
Did you always wanna run a
sports book when you grew up?
No.
I wanted to be my brother.
He was a bad ass.
It's true.
And he took care of me.
What about you?
What did you want to be
when you grew up?
Well off.
So nobody could tell me
what to do.
And I'd be safe.
You're safe now.
Mind if I indulge?
No, I don't mind.
You have a light?
No, I don't.
Not on you.
No, I don't smoke.
It may be in your purse though.
You never know.
You go to a restaurant...
Throw some matches in the purse.
For nothing else,
you didn't take a shit.
Get back in bed.
I'm not through with you yet.
You fucking scared me.
I should shoot you.
You'd never see
your daughter again.
Is it done?
No. You said
I had three days.
Now you got two.
I wanna talk to
my daughter again.
Then you better
get this done soon.
I would hate to think
what would happen to her
if she lost her mother.
Hi, mom.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
You sound weird.
I said hello.
Why haven't I heard from you?
Things have been a little crazy.
What do you mean "crazy"?
Like what?
Like... like whatever, mom.
I don't know.
It's just been a little crazy,
okay?
I'm fine.
How's Lucy?
I tried facetiming
you guys yesterday.
I know. She's good.
She's playing at a friend's.
What's wrong though?
Nothing. Can you please just
stop asking me that. Okay, mom?
I have to go.
Where are you going so fast?
I just have to go.
Call me later.
I wanna see my girls.
Okay.
Okay, bye.
So...
What about this accountant
that the police found?
He was a...
He was a customer.
Was he dirty?
Wait. You think he had something
to do with the Frankie thing?
Well, somebody made him die...
Very dramatically.
I'll look into it.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah...
No, no, no, no.
For the past few days your
head has been out of it.
What happened? What?
I just got all this shit
going on, man.
I'm just trying
to make a living.
And then I got Nicky...
No, no, no. You get your head
back in the game,
you dig this other shit and you
put it to bed and get rid of it.
Because you got to get back
to making a living.
You got it?
Do you got it?
Yeah.
Do it.
Fuck!
Hello?
Nick: Hello?
You know who this is?
Yes.
So polite.
So you got my note?
Of course I got your note.
I was sad that I didn't get
to say goodbye.
Well, I'm not really used to
these kinds of things.
So, I don't really know
the protocol.
Nick: I had fun.
I did, too.
Nick: Let's do it again.
Okay.
Let me take you away
this weekend.
Valerie: Where?
Uh, I have a little cabin
up in the woods.
Nothing special, but you know,
maybe we can go for a hike.
Make a fire,
drink a little wine.
What do you say?
I say that sounds perfect.
Okay. Do you mind
if I drive?
I mean, I'd hate to take
two cars, you know.
Okay, yeah.
You can drive.
I think we're at this point
in our relationship now
where we can take one car.
Good. I do, too.
All right.
Text me your address.
I'll pick you up in the morning.
Okay.
I'll see you then.
Hello?
Hello. Mrs. Webber?
Yes.
I'm detective Jackson.
This is a warrant to
search your premises,
which we're conducting
right now.
Uh, okay.
Why?
Why don't we just go inside,
sit and talk.
I'm sorry.
What is this about?
Mrs. Webber, when was
the last time you spoke
or heard anything
from your husband?
Um, the day...
The morning before last...
Why? What happened?
I'm sorry to tell you this,
but we found your husband's
body this morning, downtown.
We believe that this was
an intentional killing.
What does that mean?
The coroner is conducting
an autopsy right now.
We'll know more in a few days.
Mrs. Webber?
Do you know any reason why anybody
would want to murder your husband?
No.
Was he having an affair?
No. No, no.
You said that you hadn't spoken
to him in three or four days.
Why didn't you report
him missing?
My husband is
a compulsive gambler.
This is not the first time he's
disappeared for a few days.
Lieutenant.
Have you ever seen
this gun before?
No, no. Joshua hated guns.
He would never have
anything like that.
Not around Lucy.
Who's Lucy?
Our daughter.
Where is she right now?
She's at a play date
at a friend's house.
Lieutenant, I also found this.
That's my emergency fund.
There's a lot of money in there.
When your husband is
a compulsive gambler,
you can't just
keep money in the bank.
I have a lot of things
to consider now.
I have my little girl.
Are you all right,
Mrs. Webber?
Are you okay?
No, I'm not okay.
Do you have somebody?
You family who could
stay with you?
I do.
This is my card.
I want you to call me
if you think of anything.
Day or night.
I'm sorry for your loss.
We will find who's
responsible for this.
You take care of your daughter.
Okay?
Thank you.
It's nice.
Yeah?
Nick: You ain't
seen nothing yet.
Mmm-hmm.
We're gonna wander all
up till that Ridge up there.
You see it?
Yeah.
It's gonna be us.
Just you and me.
Looks like you don't have any
neighbors around here.
Not as far as the eye can see.
Lot of cool hammocks though.
Not bad, huh?
No. Not at all.
I only come here, like,
once a year.
So I blame you.
Not that it's a bad thing.
You know, my grandpa was
kind of a hippie.
Greek hippie. You never
would have thought it, huh?
Yeah, I can see that.
Let's go for a hike.
Yeah. Yeah, let's go.
Nick: Yeah.
We got a bunch of woodpeckers.
Valerie: Woodpeckers?
Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't really remember
the name of this path, but...
What would you name it
if you could?
Oh, anti stone.
"Anti stone"?
Yeah.
What does that mean?
Nick: The one over there is
full of stones.
Valerie: And this is not at all?
Oh!
It's okay.
I gotcha.
The leaves are
a little slippery.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm good.
Come on, let's...
Let's hang out for a second
right there.
I'll just go right here.
Water?
Yeah, thank you.
You're always rescuing me.
It just feels that way.
So nice out here, huh?
Yeah.
You wanna get back to the cabin?
Let's just stay here
for a second.
Take it in.
Okay.
No, really. I don't
mind experimenting.
I like, you know...
To try new things.
So I feel like, "you get
the fuck out of here."
I'm serious.
My husband used...
Don't worry about it. It's
none of my fucking business.
Mmm.
Matches...
Babe, I'm checking for a match.
Wait, wait, wait, wait...
Who the fuck are you?
How the fuck did you get
that envelope in there?
Where the fuck did that
envelope come from?
Start fucking talking!
Let's start with your
real fucking name.
Valerie Webber.
"Webber"?
Like that fucking accountant
Webber that they found?
He was my husband.
Then what the fuck do you
want from me?
You got my money.
What are you talking about,
your money?
I didn't fucking kill him.
He fucking cleaned me out
and then he left.
So what the fuck do you
want with me?
Talk.
He was sent to kill you.
What did you just say to me?
Joshua was supposed to kill you,
and he couldn't do it,
so they came after me.
They came after my daughter,
and that is what
the envelope is for.
Who sent you to kill me?
I don't know.
I don't know his name.
Alexander...
That's all I...
You're lying!
He came to the house and
that's what Joshua called him.
He told me he killed him and
then he came after my daughter.
Is that him?
Yeah...
Is that you?
Why are you together
in that picture?
That's my brother Alex.
That's your brother?
That's your fucking brother?
He has my daughter!
He was at the house
when you came to pick me up.
Please, you have to help
me, he has my daughter.
You want my help?
Do it.
Shoot me.
No, I can't.
Do it.
Because I'm the fucking asshole
who actually thought that
this was something special.
So if that's all that
this was to you,
then just go ahead
and shoot me now.
Go ahead and shoot me.
I can't.
Please take care of my daughter.
Motherfucker!
Why won't you die?
You fucking piece of shit.
I told you I would
never hurt you.
No. You're just gonna
fucking blackmail me
for the rest of my life.
I would never say anything!
That's not what people think.
This one affects
a lot of people.
You fucked this up, not me.
You fucked this up by
bringing Cudi in.
It made a lot of
fucking people nervous.
So what, people are just
gonna keep fucking dying
for this fuck up of yours?
Better them than me.
You fucking destroyed
this poor family.
This poor girl.
What did you do to her kid?
I'm not a fucking monster.
She's fine.
She's at mom's house.
You're not a fucking monster,
but you'll kill
your own brother?
You fucked this up.
You did this.
You saw me drowning,
and you chose then
to get in my face,
to fucking get greedy.
You couldn't stand
by you own brother,
even though
you knew I was wrong,
you couldn't stand by me.
I'm your brother, man!
You couldn't stand fucking
by your own brother.
Think about that.
Fuck!
You're gonna really kill
your own brother?
You left me no choice,
little brother.
It's not personal.
It's just business.
I just wanna see
my daughter, please.
I don't wanna
go to jail, please.
I just wanna see my daughter.
Can we go see my daughter?
Yeah, we're gonna go
see your daughter.
We're gonna see your daughter.
Okay?
I'm just gonna make
a phone call real quick.
Listen to me.
This never happened.
Okay?
Come here.
Uncle Cudi?
It's me, Nicky.
I need your help.
Okay.
Mommy!
I told you I'd come
back for you.
I'm so happy to see you, mom!
I'm so happy to see you, too.
I'm sorry you got
brought into this.
Yeah.
So, is this the part
where you tell me
I have to leave town?
Might be a good idea
for a while.
Till I see how this plays out.
Can you still protect me?
I'm pretty sure you can
protect yourself.
Am I ever gonna see you again?
Do you wanna see me again?
Lucy: Come on, mom.
You think about it.
You know how to find me.
Yes, I do.
Let's go, baby.