Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
FORMER CIA AGENT WANTED
DEPRIVATION AND FOR MURDER
Driving.
Well done.
Come on. Continue.
Good game.
Stay on the right path.
Another pot.
Until Sunday, guys.
Good morning.
What can I do for you?
The question is
what I can do for you.
I do not understand.
Is something wrong?
I saw you play basketball with youths.
There is much poverty here, huh?
- Many poverty.
Want to confess?
- Confession?
I have not done a long time.
No Father,
I can not be saved.
Just you, me and God are there.
And I have a duty of confidentiality.
What have you got to lose?
Come on. Sit down.
Take your time.
Forgive me Father,
for I have sinned.
for I have indeed sinned.
Go on.
Air your heart.
All they in the newspaper
writing about me is true.
I'm undercover for the CIA.
Continue.
I am ... a murderer.
Previously I believed that something was.
Not anymore.
Good work you're in New York, Mark.
Now Zarahoui dead,
walk the Iranians miss their mission.
Okay?
- Yes, sir.
And with your team?
- No problem.
I swore my country
against all its enemies to defend ...
... But the world is complex
to be.
We are at war with an enemy
faceless.
He is often among us.
The Redvale Corporation
Detroit is a large hedge fund.
They have over 10 billion U.S. dollars
invested in oil production in Africa.
Because they are unsatisfied
the local government ...
... They dealer
Frank Smith hired.
He must arm the rebels.
That Smith is a huge asshole.
You will make contact with him,
work for him and infiltrate.
And when the time comes,
Smith and disable Redvale out.
Agreed.
Marcus?
This may not be returned
to the CIA.
I understand completely.
- Maybe you'll get a medal ...
... Maybe you'll be sued.
This is for you.
Success.
SIX MONTHS LATER
I do not care. We have
2 million invested in this deal.
I can not help it if it's too late.
Tell him I cut off their balls
if they do not pay.
You're my lawyer,
I pay you $ 800 per hour.
No longer wasting my time.
Put batter in the belongings of that jerk.
Jane, how are things?
The money for Mr. Smith
African transaction is completed.
Fucking Wall Street.
Acorns that create the greatest
economic disaster in 80 years.
Millions of people lose their homes,
their jobs. The country is almost bankrupt.
And what happens?
They are rewarded with
a financial injection from the government.
Here we go.
The suspect left the airport.
Not too close. We do nothing
before he grabbed the money.
Mark gives us the sign.
With the bakery?
Is the oven preheated?
We are on schedule.
- At the minute?
On the second.
Everything is ready, sir.
"Punctuality is the politeness
of rulers. " You know who said that?
No, sir.
- King Louis XVIII.
He was a slimy bastard.
Obsequious klutz.
Mr. Smith and his team are on their way.
Everything is ready.
Would you even turn on the aircon?
It's hot.
That is all, sir.
- What louder, please.
Zander here.
Dietrich does not anymore.
I'm now in charge.
Christ.
Jesus.
What is this?
Is everything ok there?
- Jesus ... my chest.
Hold on.
To the hospital.
What happens?
It leaves its target rate.
How far yet?
- Five minutes. We're being followed.
Have you swallowed something?
Have you swallowed something, boss?
They do not lose touch.
I ask permission to shoot.
Smith should at all costs
live.
We get rid of him.
He goes to the hospital.
Backward.
- I'm his head of security.
Let the doctors do their work.
- I Can not count?
No, it's best all data
the patient register at the desk.
It only takes a few minutes.
Thank you.
Would you fill this out?
I'm Dr. Brown.
What happened?
My boss has a heart attack.
What's his name?
- Frank Smith.
Has he had previous heart problems?
- Not that I know.
Stay here.
- He's my client.
We will take good care of him.
SECURITY
Agent 1 covers the stairwells,
Agent 3 emergency exits.
Agents 4 and 5 take the elevators.
Make sure everything is searched.
We see something suspicious.
Will you make an emergency call?
We got him.
- I know. The emergency number is called.
We have to plan accordingly.
Here station. Ignore the call
the Detroit Medical Center.
It is an operation
of security.
There are undercover agents on the spot.
Do not touch. I repeat: Do not touch.
Do you wear a gun?
Yes. I'm bodyguard.
Want to give your gun to the agent?
Hospital Policy.
He will be safely stored.
How is it, doctor?
He is stable, he goes to the ICU.
Smith is in ICU.
Are you okay?
No. Do you have some orange juice
or a bar or something?
I have diabetes.
- I'll get a nurse.
Sit down, then a nurse
you test.
I will direct someone to fetch you.
But as you walk with me.
Thank you.
Why the fuss in the hospital?
We have a new wing. Today
patients are transferred.
Your timing is not so good.
Pardon?
You may not come here.
Has anything ever happened to you,
Mr. Smith?
We'll go testing.
Nice.
May I have the results of
enzyme analysis have directly?
We are inside.
Marcus is alone with the nurse.
What do you do for a living?
I protect important people.
- That sounds exciting.
Are you from Detroit?
- No.
Is it dangerous?
- Sometimes.
Then you will not feel the needle down.
I've always wanted to go out
with a bodyguard.
Thank you.
I worry about the man
I brought in here.
He had a heart attack.
Where are they taking such a person?
To ICU. That has not moved.
ICU is on the fourth floor.
Can you bring me there?
- Sure.
Marcus did you disabled?
What is your status?
Mark is in the stairwell
on the third floor.
Understood.
Kill him. Now.
I've dreamed about you.
I've dreamed about you
and now you're real.
Get me outta here.
From me, from me.
Take me with you.
Can I touch you?
One time only.
I will be careful.
I can show you how to get out of here.
I have never gedatet.
Dr. Green?
- Buy ice cream for me?
You know that red? And that pink?
- He looks.
The blue I find delicious. Dr. Green?
- I know how to get out of here.
Dr. Green, I need those pills.
- He pushes.
Above.
He pushes.
He points.
- To the wall. Against the door.
Are we the door game?
- You, there.
Where are the doctors?
They said they would come back.
Take me with you.
Agent 3?
Agent 3, answer.
Go to the third floor
and see what's going on.
You may not come here.
Want to go?
This patient is a threat to
national security. He calls.
Really.
He just had a heart attack.
We probably need a stent
artery in his place.
He may not be carried.
Marie, would you call the security guards?
I would not do.
You have no choice.
Your opinion is not sought.
We are now security.
Good morning, Mr. Smith.
We go to your buddies.
- Easy, Mr. Smith.
Give him something that gives him strength,
it makes me no matter what.
Do I need a man like a heart attack
epinephrine had it?
This is his death that I do not allow.
That you are.
As said you have no choice.
How long will this take?
He will almost definitely be a heart attack
get.
You ask me life
of my patient's risk.
I ask nothing. You give him a shot
or you get one yourself.
Floria.
Are you?
What's going on?
- The plans have changed.
Oh yeah?
Where's Dietrich?
Dietrich is dead.
What happened?
It's complicated.
Can we talk?
No, you want me dead.
I will deal with you.
Mr. Smith that we both want to live.
I will go through the procedure
he needs.
If he is not alert after stent
was successful, I give him epinephrine.
Calm down, Mr. Smith.
Quiet.
Demerol.
If he gets epinephrine,
he did not survive.
Why not just tell me
what's going on?
Where is Zander?
Zander has the lead.
- What?
This was my mission.
- Like I said: Everything has changed.
How long will this take?
- At least one hour.
You get 30 minutes.
Why do not you tell me
what the new mission?
We take the money and we lubricate 'm.
You can join or die.
Do not be a fool,
We know all your tricks.
There we are each other's opponent.
Would you no longer focus on me so
I care for my patient?
100 million U.S. dollars.
Come on.
You can lead a good life.
We have this whole place in our pocket.
You are in the minority.
The police will not save you.
You have no support.
That's us.
This is not about Smith.
That bastard should be killed anyway.
What is this about?
The system is corrupt. We risk
our lives every day and why?
We protect traitors and monsters.
We do have long
and that does not change.
This time they can get the fuck.
We grab the money.
Go see what's going on.
Ensure that patient survives.
If you're smart,
You can still come out the winner.
I'm going to a great new life.
I've always liked. I thought
you probably ever would hit me.
Say something.
I would like to talk to you.
I am the only one who is speaking.
Not very polite.
Got nothing to say?
I 'm
- I want him alive.
Hi, Mark.
You will soon feel better, Mr. Smith.
- Marcus.
My good friend.
My teammate.
Did you think your bodyguard
you would save, Frank?
He's with us.
I will briefly introduce you to him.
Agent Mark Jones.
CIA.
You are the mission.
We go off you and Redvale.
Look at him.
The perfect scout.
You've made the wrong choice.
But you know what?
I had expected.
You have killed Dietrich.
- Yes. Your beloved mentor.
He was like a father to you, right?
He would not support our plan anyway,
so we have him eliminated.
When this is over ...
... I will kill you.
For now you kill anyone.
We should go.
Time's up.
Put him in a wheelchair.
If I go too fast,
that is fatal.
Hurry up, we have no time.
Put medication in his pocket.
Hurry the fuck up.
Get that thing away please,
that's not faster.
When he was in the wheelchair.
Pick a wheelchair.
Come on Frank, we go to your friends.
He's behind you
Come on, Frankie.
And sweetheart ...
You go along.
Belongings, so.
Grab what you need.
We go.
Smith and have Redvale
revolutions unleashed more than Karl Marx.
And more blood on their hands
than many a dictator.
Yet the law protects them.
This is my life, Zander.
I've wasted a country
that do not give a care about me.
So yes, I am disappointed.
- Listen to me, Flor.
I'm busy with something.
Something would be good
for you and me.
Betrayed by my team
by the people I trusted.
We were like a family.
Do you regret your life?
Do you think God forgives you?
- No, Father.
I would not be forgiven
for what I did.
I sat all night in the car.
Then I realized ...
... I had nothing left.
My enemies had won.
When I was this morning with that young
saw play, I thought: Wow.
Life would be so simple.
I just wanted ...
... To follow you here.
But ...
... I realized that the world
would be better off without men like me.
I had to get going.
I would not waste your time.
Tell me what happened with your team.
That's exactly what I say.
Got it?
All agents: There is a murder
the Detroit Medical Center.
The suspect is a former
CIA agent. He is armed and dangerous.
What's so funny?
You're a jerk.
- What did he say?
That you're a jerk.
I'm not the one who dies.
- Yes, you do.
True.
Once he Redvales building canopy and
he is dead.
Once you walk into Redvales building,
you're dead.
He must still live?
It's just about your money.
It's about power Redvale do.
He is like the mobsters in Sicily.
They have billions of dollars,
but live in a ruin.
Rather, the power also.
It's about power.
What's he saying?
- Nothing.
Babblings of a dying man.
He will never give a penny.
We'll see.
Welcome to the Redvale Corporation.
What can I do for you?
This is Mr. Frank Smith.
We're here for John Redvale.
Do you have an appointment?
- We're a little late. He expects us.
I call his office some time.
One moment.
Thank you.
Would you like Mr. Smith and his guests to
the office of Mr. Redvale bring?
Follow me.
Hello, Mr Smith.
Are you okay with you?
- Hi, Jane.
I am Mr. Smith's bodyguard. He has
burden of his heart and not feeling well.
We had an appointment
with Mr. Redvale.
Of course.
He is on the phone ...
... But requires you to sit
in the conference room. This way.
Mr. Smith is there, but he does not
good and has many people with him.
I'll go look.
How are you?
What do you look like.
What's going on?
Mr. Smith suffers from his heart ...
... But wanted to
complete the proposed transaction.
Heart problems? You look like shit.
You would lie in the hospital.
John ...
... Let's close this deal.
It is now not so good.
I did not do it here.
I wanted to celebrate with a dinner party.
Mr. Smith wants to make
Handling today. Now.
Right, Mr. Smith?
Excuse me,
but who were you again?
Do you work for Frank?
You are much to speak
and I do not know you.
Where is Marcus, Frank?
Which was removed from his position.
- Is that so?
Well, gentlemen ...
... I do not like this.
I do not know you and I do not like
strangers walking into my office.
Spend some time relaxing.
Come back in a few days,
we talk about it. Okay?
There are no injuries to fall.
- What do you want?
The money.
Very simple.
Only Frank's share.
- Do you think right, Frank?
Unfortunately I can not grant your request.
- Unfortunately, you have no choice.
No choice?
Any idea who you are facing you?
I'll tell you what will happen.
Suppose you come alive here
with the money.
Over ten years, if you completely trust
your new identity ...
... And you think back with pride
what you have accomplished here ...
... You go jogging. When you return,
are your wife and children dead.
Then I wait another ten years.
If you still have not hung
of remorse ...
... I'll kill you.
That will not happen.
- Get it fast to the idea.
Imagine a room.
A room like this ...
Full paper trail ...
all your illegal transactions.
Now imagine me,
with the key to that room.
Who are you?
- CIA.
Is that so?
We love you and Mr. Frank Smith
long been in the holes.
In advance again.
I count to three and then we slowly
our weapons down.
One ...
... Two ...
... Three.
That was not necessary.
I do not like witnesses.
We go.
Run.
Call the safe and say that I am coming.
- Now, Jane.
It is good Jane, go ahead.
- I will do immediately.
Sam, Jane. Mr. Redvale is underway
to the vault with some guests.
He asked if you wanted it open
if he's there. Well, yes. Thank you.
Very good, Jane.
What is wrong with you?
- Walk.
Get out.
Stupid bastard.
Wrong CIA agents, so.
- Good CIA agents do not exist.
I totally agree.
This is your pension?
- Exactly.
Come work for me.
You would not trust me.
Hi, Sam.
- Is everything all right, Mr. Redvale?
Everything is in order.
Jesus Christ.
Open it.
Ment.
True enough.
Please.
100 million in $ 100 bills.
As we agreed, Frank.
This is your money.
Let your really happen?
Got a better idea?
They never come away with that money.
You think so, Frank?
Shall we bet?
What do you say?
I put $ 10,000 on.
Oh, that's your money, eh?
It does not look good for you.
I'm in favor.
I'm looking for Frank Smith.
Who has just gone to the vault.
Sir?
Damn.
I need your help.
Tell them that I feel weaker.
Fredo, bring that bag to the roof.
Make sure the helicopter is ready.
Tell us about ten minutes.
Is that you, Marcus?
You're trapped, Zander.
Surrender.
Have you not slain him?
Over there.
Run.
I had to listen to Floria
and you have to kill.
There is a lot of money.
Do not do stupid things.
Grab that bag and fuck off.
Is not that easy. There is
only one way and he goes past me.
You are in the minority.
You are alone.
Think you're in favor
with Smith and Redvale?
Now.
That interest me shit.
You can divert them from me.
I can not breathe.
- He has another heart attack.
Hold on, Mr. Smith.
Can anyone help me?
What is wrong with you?
Shut up.
He's dying.
- There goes another one, Zander.
I have something else.
Shut up.
Hear this, Marcus? Our doctor
try here the hero.
Surrender
I hunt or a bullet in her head.
I'll send you a packet to get you another
mind.
Last chance.
Take the money and fuck off.
That was it for you?
Throw away your weapon.
Throw down your weapon, I said.
On three counts
I shoot her head from her torso.
Let her out.
- Go on, honey.
One ...
... Two ...
Well done, Marcus.
Kick the gun this way, Rachel.
Come on, you can.
Now.
Come on, Doctor.
What do you disappoint me, girl.
Three.
When this is over, I will kill you.
Help her.
Call the police.
Thank you.
Gardian emergency in the building.
We need assistance.
Lock the elevator.
Come on.
Damn.
Zander?
Come on. Get the key.
Pick up the bags.
We go.
Come on.
Give me the key to the elevator.
Damn.
We're there, be advised.
Run.
Disabling Marcus Jones
has priority.
He is armed and dangerous.
Block the stairwells and elevators.
Inside.
I have spared your life.
You can half the money.
What more do you want?
I trusted you.
- I got the world to purify you.
That is always our mission.
No one still believes in.
Only you and Dietrich.
I was like you.
I believed in the mission.
I was blind, and now you.
I'm just a man who entered.
- Stop it.
I've saved your life once.
I will not again.
No sign of the suspect
on the upper five floors.
Continue to search.
There is here a corpse,
but it is not the suspect.
Where is he?
- We could not find him.
Why?
- We have searched every floor.
Is this the man you saw in the vault?
Yes, that's the man
who saved my life.
Take her to my office.
What a story.
Have faith in Jesus Christ
and He will lead you out of darkness.
Pray with me.
Our Father which art in heaven,
Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done,
as it is in heaven on earth.
Give us this day our daily bread ...
... And forgive us our debts,
as we forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom
and the power and glory ...
... For ever.
Amen.
Go with God.
You're forgiven.
Here.
Translation: The
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org