The Vietnam peace talks
are continuing here in Paris today...
... against the background of what to do
about the release of American POWs.
In the United States,
sentiment is running high...
... for a complete accounting
for all of the POWs and MIAs...
... those listed as Missing in Action,
before any treaty is signed.
The prisoners, men such as these...
... are Americans who have been captured
during the 10 years of fighting in Vietnam.
The Undersecretary of State,
Conrad Morgan...
... is the chief American delegate
to the talks.
This morning, outside the mansion
in which the talks are being held...
... Morgan told reporters
that he is optimistic.
I now sincerely believe...
... the North Vietnamese delegates
are dealing in good faith...
... and that significant progress
can now be made.
As chief delegate to these talks...
... are you saying a final agreement
has been reached?
What I'm saying is what I said.
The situation is extremely delicate,
but significant progress can now be made.
Is that clear? I certainly hope it is...
... because I would appreciate
those of the press getting that straight.
What if Kuong Yen decides to throw
new roadblocks into these negotiations?
I suppose we'll have to
take things one step at a time.
There is one more question the American
public deserves to have answered.
What about the Missing in Action?
Have you and Kuong Yen
discussed that at all?
Of course we have discussed that...
... and we will continue
to discuss that question.
But I'm sure you can all realize,
that is of such a sensitive nature...
... I'm not at liberty to go into that now.
I can only say this: I'm very hopeful
that we will arrive at a solution.
- What the hell are you doing in my room?
- You told me to meet you here.
Could have waited in the lobby.
Turn that goddamn thing off, please.
I'm enjoying it.
Mr. Morgan, please,
can we have a statement before you...
Harolds?
- Come on, bring that shit in here!
- Coming.
I'm not as nimble as I used to be.
Nor as coordinated.
Actually, Conrad,
I have always been rather clumsy.
When you get that stuff cleaned up,
make me a scotch, will you please?
So, the war is over, Mr. Undersecretary?
You're practically a national treasure.
Son of a bitch.
Which son of a bitch is that?
Hope they cut his balls off.
- Give Harolds a pair of scissors.
- When the time's right, I'll do that myself.
Sounds like your private meeting
with Kuong Yen...
...was what you guys in State
called "a frank discussion of the issues."
What the hell is this,
some kind of a joke to you?
- You could say so.
- It's not to me.
Somebody's gotta take it seriously.
I told 'em I didn't need
any goddamn CIA help on this thing...
And they shove me down your throat!
We've been through this before, Morgan.
Now, what the hell is it this time?
How many of your CIA people
are the VC holding?
What are you talking about?
Save that bullshit for Congress.
How many?
150, maybe. Why?
They're dead.
The fact that we have positive information
to the contrary is irrelevant.
He wants a sacrifice.
Speak intelligently, Morgan.
As an addendum to the peace terms,
Kuong Yen wants a sacrifice.
Call Omaha and get a flock of sheep.
He claims he's lost a lot of family
to you people.
This isn't important, of course,
but I also think he's a psychopath.
That makes him unique in this business,
doesn't it?
In any case, we agree to write off
those people as Missing in Action...
...and they agree to call off the war
and give us a lot of other people back.
And you agreed?
I didn't agree to anything.
You practical son of a bitch!
You're gonna cash in those people's lives
just for a shot at the Nobel Peace Prize!
Saunders, don't get sanctimonious
with me.
Nobody's gonna win anything
when this war's over.
If the VC want 'em dead so bad,
why don't they just kill 'em?
They won't because they're worth
too much as a bargaining point.
Wrong. They'll kill 'em...
...as soon as they sign the treaty...
...or they'll hold them as MIA
till they're through interrogating them.
In any case, what I'm trying to say is
we have to at least try...
...to get some of those people out of there.
I hate to think I've been misjudging you.
That would be unfortunate.
What do you call the commandoes...
...you're holding
under the Phoenix umbrella?
Black Tigers.
Who the hell thinks up names like that?
Black Tigers!
Actually, a group of us did,
some years ago.
Don't let anybody kid you, Harolds.
It's a great name.
- Can they get your people out?
- I don't know, it's very risky business.
Take at least a couple of weeks
for an operation like that.
Forty-eight hours.
Forty-eight hours? Right.
What about staging a major operation
in the middle of your peace talks?
I'll worry about the diplomacy.
I get the feeling I'm offending
some sensibility in you.
The American public is crying for peace.
I intend to achieve it for them.
Like I said,
you're practically a national treasure.
Saunders, when this war is over...
...you should get a job
as an advance man for cancer.
In support of the disease or the cure?
I sometimes find it difficult to understand...
...the American custom of joking
during a time of crisis.
How certain are you of your intelligence?
To be perfectly honest with you,
Maj. Mhin...
...the only thing certain about intelligence
is uncertainty.
As usual, you're a big help.
This better be as important
as your boys at headquarters said it was.
Let's go, Mhin.
What do you think Prince will say when
we come walking in there after him?
"You came a long way, Fred,
to collect your bread."
- That's what he's going to say.
- You'd better believe that, baby.
What makes them think Hanoi
will sit still for this kind of stunt?
It must make sense
or they wouldn't be sending us.
One camp. What good could it do?
The POWs are in dozens of camps.
It's the camp with the most guys in it.
I do not see how a raid at this time
can do anything but harm the negotiations.
Major, I thought
the goddamn war was over.
So did I, but it's not. What's your point?
The point is we don't want to be
the last guys killed in this war...
...if there's someone else available.
I think they've got us down
for second to last.
Whatever happened to the good old days
when Randolph Scott and John Wayne...
...were happy to get their asses blown off
for the good ol' US of A?
Who the hell is Randolph Scott?
Randolph Scott Key:
dude who wrote the national anthem!
Oh, that Randolph Scott!
You can joke if you want,
but I've got a score to settle.
That's the spirit, Gordie, an ear for an ear!
I said not to joke around
about my ears, didn't I?
You're gonna have a hard time
finding an ear that size.
Just give me a couple whole heads.
I'll use what I need.
What do you know? We can go first class!
- You gonna serve coffee, Randolph?
- Sure!
I want Lola Falana to serve my coffee!
- Gonna be a movie on this flight?
- Yeah.
Mhin?
- Major, over here!
- Get in!
Gordie, he's hit!
Get him.
- Come on!
- All right, let's get out!
- Get him!
- Come on!
- What's the matter?
- Goddamn thing won't start!
Come on!
Get out! Move out! Let's go!
Come on, Gordie. We gotta run!
Where we running, Mike?
Are we late for the train or something?
Where the hell are the choppers?
The choppers aren't here.
Why don't we take the train?
Radio.
Nighthawk, this is Tiger 1. Over.
Somebody's going to pay for this screwup.
I think I know who.
Yeah, us.
Nighthawk, this is Tiger 1.
We're at LZ and waiting for pickup. Over.
I don't get it.
Everything went wrong by the numbers
and that takes planning.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying we've been set up.
Where are the choppers?
I just told you, Gordie, it was a screwup.
I like choppers. They're like birds.
- You like birds, don't you?
- Sure I do, Gordie.
Jesus.
Where are the choppers?
I like choppers. They're like birds.
I shot a bird once.
My daddy took my rifle away...
- Take care of him, Mike.
- Yeah.
- What do we do now?
- Survive.
Lou, the point. Walker, the rear.
- Where are you going, Mike?
- Going home.
- What do I do, walk out?
- lf you spot a taxi, flag it down.
- How'd it feel?
- A hell of a lot better!
Let's clean her out
and I'll give her another try.
I think our troubles with this baby
are just about history.
You spend one more minute with this car,
I think that baby there will be history.
Damn, can you believe
I forgot all about her?
Any man who forgets her
needs a lube job and oil change real bad.
I can't wait to get her on the rack.
Goddamn it, Booker, what's a girl
have to do to get your attention?
I'm sorry, Kelly.
You're really going to be mad.
I've got a class to teach in one hour.
Shit.
Come on, Booker, get in.
And so, as history slowly places it
into some kind of perspective...
...a few things about the Vietnam War
have become clear.
It was a war
that never should have begun...
...in a country
we never should have entered.
And its thousands of victims died
without really understanding why...
...mainly because the reasons for the war
were beyond any rules of logic.
On Wednesday, we'll sing patriotic songs
and pretend I said none of the above.
- Good lecture, man.
- Thank you.
- See you, Booker.
- Okay.
I hope you didn't mind my sitting in.
It seems a long way from the '60s,
doesn't it?
Yes, it does.
Can I take you to lunch?
I don't eat lunch. Who are you?
Let me take you to dinner and find out.
- You do eat dinner?
- I've been known to.
I'm on an expense account.
You're a reporter.
Why else would I fly all the way out
from Washington to see you?
I don't know.
Pick me up at 7:00?
7:00 is too late.
For us?
For dinner. How about 5:30?
At 5:30 in Washington,
they're still out to lunch.
In Washington, they're always out to lunch.
Besides, I have a feeling
this might be a very interesting evening.
You're the professor, Professor.
- That's it, mister.
- That's a good job.
Too bad you weren't born black.
There might have been a future
in this for you.
Hey, mister, you forgot your newspaper.
- 19 and 25.
- Thank you, my man.
Quite a car.
Not exactly ideal for going
from stoplight to stoplight, is it?
- Only if they're 200 miles apart.
- Pretty much for a grad student.
I do test driving, and like a damn fool,
I took the car instead of the salary.
What the hell is he trying to do?
Hang on!
You son of a bitch,
what the hell's going on?
Relax! The accelerator pedal stuck!
- What?
- I said, "The accelerator pedal stuck!"
Why didn't you kill the engine?
Because I thought
I could kick the pedal loose.
What the hell was that all about?
- I wish I knew.
- I think I need a drink.
- Any place in particular?
- Your place. As long as you drive carefully.
Are most of your days usually
as exciting as this one?
Not quite, but I've got a feeling
things are about to change.
If you've got something to say, say it.
You were on a top-secret mission to rescue
some POWs at the end of the war.
No response?
I get it.
You're writing a book about the war.
Something like that.
When you arrived at the camp,
there were no POWs, only Vietcong.
You lost most of your men.
I wonder who told you about that.
It was all top secret.
Shall I go on?
Are you married?
After the raid, you were to be met
and flown to safety with the POWs.
The helicopters didn't show...
...so you marched out of the jungle
with five of your men.
Do you fool around?
It took you three weeks
to get out of the jungle.
Then you were, as they say,
"debriefed" in the hospital for two months.
Nothing was ever printed
about that strange sortie.
Why not?
How about something to eat?
What ever happened to those POWs
who weren't there to be rescued?
Have they been returned? Are they MIA?
Are they dead?
Will anybody admit that they ever existed?
- Will you answer any of those questions?
- Now, what can you do with one egg?
Watch out.
Nice selection. We can sauté these.
I tried it once. I didn't like it.
How about some frozen halibut?
Your unit was a part of Operation Phoenix.
Its job was to neutralize,
I believe they called it...
...the Vietcong undercover agents.
You were also assigned
to rescue our own POWs.
You're very intense for a girl with such...
How about one egg
with oysters and sauerkraut?
Are you going to tell me anything?
There's really not much to tell.
In the hospital, they told us the VC
intelligence had cracked our security.
Reasonable possibility.
They said our choppers
had been shot down.
Reasonable possibility there.
Then by the time they got replacements
to us, there was nothing but bodies.
That's what they said.
And like an obedient soldier,
you believed them.
In the hospital,
I told myself the war was over.
I lived through it, now put it behind you.
I could spend years trying to find out
if somebody set us up.
And if I found him, well...
...he most likely would be someone
I couldn't get to anyway.
What if he were someone you could get to?
I decided no to waste my life
to avenge something I'd survived.
It's over and I want to keep it that way.
I don't believe you really feel that way.
- Why are you asking all these questions?
- I can't tell you.
Then stop asking them.
I met a man at a cocktail party
in Washington.
He was what the newspapers refer to as
"a high-ranking government official."
He was also very drunk.
The scotch seemed to break
some barrier in his mind.
- He mentioned the Black Tigers.
- How's the sauerkraut coming?
Coming nicely, thank you.
John T. Booker:
A man taking his Ph.D.
in Political Science...
...who used to be a member of the CIA.
- Sounds schizophrenic.
- I was never a member of the CIA.
The Black Tigers were CIA.
I didn't know the Freedom of Information
Act was that effective.
It isn't, but I am.
What do you think of Conrad Morgan
being named Secretary of State-Designate?
- Nothing.
- Doesn't interest you?
I'm only interested in finding out
what you're not telling me.
Who's going to tell who first
what he or she isn't telling?
Maybe I'll tell you after dinner.
Or maybe in the morning.
How about the morning?
- Bad dream?
- Yeah.
What?
- You don't sleep well, do you?
- No.
I don't either.
Did I keep you awake?
I didn't mind.
- I'll make it up to you.
- You already have.
How do you turn this thing off?
Why does anyone who doesn't sleep well...
...have an alarm that sounds like Big Ben
that can't be turned off?
- Where are you going?
- To run.
I run, too.
Well, come along.
I think I had sufficient exercise last night.
- Breakfast?
- lf you can find anything.
Of course, you don't eat breakfast.
I'll see you in exactly 27 minutes.
When I get back,
we can talk about breakfast, maybe.
Hey, Murray.
Why don't you get an honest job?
What, and give up my cloak and dagger?
John, I have to talk to you.
Pull over. Gas is expensive.
I know better than to ask
where you've been...
...but that cigar smells like pure Havana.
Fringe benefits.
John, what did you and Marilyn talk about?
Do I know her?
The reporter who seems to have
more answers than questions.
You wouldn't be talking about a writer
named Margaret?
She told me "Marilyn."
Next guy'll get "Myrna" or "Marilee."
She's obviously in the "M's."
What did you tell her?
I told her about a long walk I took
a couple of years ago.
What did you tell her?
Somebody told her more about
that mission than even you and I know.
That scar is ugly, but it's healed.
It's about to be reopened.
"Operation Sandstone."
I don't recall that one.
There was no Operation Sandstone.
You see that line with "D.A." on it?
It means that sometime during
an operation which never happened...
...it was confirmed
that you were a double agent.
See that "Sanction Authorization 1"?
There's a contract out on me.
- Correct.
- Why?
I think the reporter found out something
she shouldn't. What'd she say?
Someone talked to her about the mission.
I didn't want to hear about it.
That's why ostriches die young.
Whoever talked to her
has evidently decided to rectify his error.
Who the hell can get into
this machine and put out a hit on me?
Only the President, the Secretaries...
...and a few
Undersecretaries of Defense and State.
The directors of the FBI, the CIA...
...the Chairman
of the National Security Council...
...and the Chairman
of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
Thank God it's nobody important.
Jesus, this is crazy.
It's not just you, John.
I had reason to check out all five of those
guys who came out of that jungle with you.
Holly Washington is dead.
I think Lou Goldberg is, too.
- Was it your people?
- I don't know.
Well, find out.
Look, first I get a tip on Holly and Lou.
Then I meet a girl who knows more about
that goddamn raid than anyone should.
Then there's the fact that
I'm the one that sent you on it.
It isn't on that computer,
but it's a good bet...
...that my name is there
with the rest of the Tigers.
- Can't you warn them? Protect them?
- You can.
Last known names and addresses.
Mhin Van Thieu?
What is his name doing on here?
He was killed on that last raid.
Evidently not.
First listed as MIA, then POW...
...released at the end of the war.
We obviously paid him off
by bringing him into this country.
He's cooking for some Peking-style
restaurant in San Francisco...
...specializing in fried dumplings.
That's great. What else do you know
that you may have forgotten to tell me?
There is something,
but I just can't remember what it is.
That helps a hell of a lot.
Look, John,
there's a lot I can't help you with.
The company has too many eyes.
So you're going to have to
warn those guys yourself.
This is my life
you're screwing with, Murray.
It's mine too, friend.
Hello?
- Gordie Jones, please.
- He's not home.
- Where is he?
- At his Uncle Sheffield's Travel Town.
Can I call him there?
He ain't got no phone there.
God, we don't owe you any money,
do we, mister?
Look, you can find him at his uncle's.
In Washington, Secretary
of State-Designate, Conrad Morgan...
... goes before his final Senate
subcommittee hearing this morning.
Morgan's approval by the committee
is virtually certain. At 41...
- Good morning.
- Is Gordie Jones here?
All aboard!
Hey, Gordie!
Hey, Sammy! How ya doin'?
Not much business today.
- You doin' any?
- No, business isn't too good.
It's Maj. Booker, Gordie. John T. Booker.
I thought you were Sammy.
You look just like Sammy.
Has anyone been to see you recently?
Has anyone asked you about
that last mission?
What I wish we had is pelicans
instead of seagulls.
Who asked you about the last mission?
Just yesterday. A lady. Maybe today.
I told her about the pelicans.
How was the halibut?
Who the hell are you?
That's the lady, Major.
Where are we going?
Skiing. Maybe we can get to Mike Potter
before they do.
But I've got a rental car.
You're on an expense account.
Don't worry.
- I don't have any ski clothes.
- We'll get something.
- Want some?
- No, thanks. Is it occupied?
Go find out.
Go to the bathroom.
No. 1 or No. 2?
The window seat, last row,
left side as you go down the aisle.
An Oriental. See if you recognize him.
Looks like a waiter in a Chinese restaurant
I used to frequent in Des Moines.
I'll bet Chinese food in Des Moines
is something to remember.
- Is he following us?
- I'm not sure yet.
Maybe it's that waiter.
I don't think I tipped him
last time I was there.
Who did you talk to
at that cocktail party in Washington?
Please don't ask. I'm almost certain I'll lie.
Make a call.
There's another one.
So much for that.
When you're silent, you're silent.
What are you thinking about?
Old friends.
Mhin.
That guy on the plane was Mhin.
Maj. Mhin Van Thieu?
Another Black Tiger.
What don't you know?
What did you talk to him about?
I never said a word to him in my life.
- What about Murray Saunders?
- I don't know any Murray Saunders.
You were someone named Marilyn.
That Murray Saunders.
- What did he tell you?
- Nothing.
Good evening. You got here just in time.
- For what?
- The snow is melting fast.
Is Mike Potter in? He's on the ski patrol.
Mike? No, try his house. I'll dial it for you.
Do you want to take it over there?
- He's not in.
- Tomorrow's his day off. He's jump-crazy.
He'll be on the jump
first thing in the morning.
We better spend the night.
- Do you have a room?
- I think so.
Do you want to fill this out?
To what extent
are we speaking to each other?
What do you want to talk about?
I was wondering, for instance...
...if we're speaking enough
to share the only bed in the room.
Sure, we can share the bed.
Any enemies out there?
I'm just as worried
about the enemy within.
- Are you an enemy, Margaret?
- No.
You just happened to be there
when Gordie was killed today.
- Were you there when Lou and Holly died?
- No.
Are you some kind of finger-man
for whoever's doing this?
Finger-person.
John, I haven't lied to you.
Including last night?
Especially last night.
You fit in somewhere.
So do you.
Mr. Morgan, I want to thank you
for the cooperation...
... you're affording this committee
by your appearance here.
Thank you, Senator.
And I want to assure you
and the other members of the committee...
... that I fully understand the necessity
for hearings such as these.
And I want you all to feel free
to probe into any areas at all...
... that might be of interest to you.
I'm sure I can speak
for the entire committee...
... when I say, sir, that such an attitude
is deeply appreciated.
Because we've had to deal...
- Think he'll make it?
- Morgan?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
He's the new darling of Washington.
The attitude of the nation today is
far different from what it was...
... in those early days before Vietnam.
I think the American public today
is far less eager...
We'd better get going.
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to Squaw Valley, USA.
After being selected as the site
of the 1960 Winter Olympic Games...
... the Squaw Valley Complex
was developed...
... into one of the world's greatest ski areas
at a cost of over $25 million.
You are now standing
in the lower terminal...
... of one of the world's most spectacular
aerial tramways.
The terminal alone cost
over $3.5 million in 1960 dollars.
What snow we had this year
is now melting rapidly.
So as we approach the top station,
we advise you to hurry out to the slopes...
... and make the most of what's left.
On behalf of Squaw Valley, USA...
... I'd like to thank you for joining us,
and have a happy day.
- I'm looking for Mike Potter.
- You got him.
Major?
- What are you doing up here?
- Didn't you get my message?
You mean the Code Red?
I thought that was a gag.
Mike, you're up.
Let's go in the shack. We've gotta talk.
Meet me at the bottom.
Bring these with you.
Mike, wait.
Oh, Jesus!
Jesus Christ, I thought I'd never find you.
There were cops
all over the place up there.
I've got your clothes.
You can change in the car.
Are you all right?
- It was Mhin, wasn't it?
- The woman he met at the airport.
I'm sorry about Mike.
But you were right on the scene again.
I'm not the enemy, John.
I told you that last night.
- I think we better talk.
- Tell me!
Edgar Harolds.
- Childhood sweetheart?
- A drunk at a cocktail party.
- Who is he?
- Undersecretary of State.
A career man at the end of his career,
maybe the end of his rope.
Goddamn it, who are you?
Edgar Harolds worked for Conrad Morgan
during the Vietnam War and he hates him.
Morgan on the TV?
The Senate does more than question a man
who's nominated for Secretary of State.
Before Watergate,
it was generally a formality.
Now, they do a pretty thorough job of it.
They even hire attorneys to investigate.
- What does that have to do with you?
- It's actually pretty funny.
I was invited to a cocktail party
by the head of the committee.
Just a social event.
I had barely started to work for him.
You're a lawyer? An investigator?
I'd been standing for hours...
...when I noticed this man
sitting all alone at a table.
He looked pleasantly drunk and harmless.
I went over and sat with him.
- Is Morgan mixed up in this?
- I don't know.
Harolds never mentioned him,
but it seems there's a connection.
The papers keep saying
his approval is assured.
- How, if you told the committee...
- I never told the committee anything!
You don't survive in Washington...
...by attacking men like Morgan
without substantial facts.
I just said I wanted to follow up
on some leads and they said, "Go."
- They know nothing about this?
- Not yet.
That's why we'll take the first plane east.
That may take days.
I have to get to Joe Walker in Mexico.
- He's the only man left.
- You're left.
And I want you to stay alive...
...for personal reasons.
Do you believe me now?
Your attention, please:
Will all passengers holding tickets for
Intermountain Flight 184...
... please contact the agent
at the Intermountain ticket counter.
Is there any space on 322
to San Francisco and Washington?
Yes, ma'am. Round trip or one-way?
- One way.
- Round trip.
You'll need it, back to LA.
You heard the man.
Make mine one-way to LA. Next flight out.
Final call:
Flight 2, now boarding at Gate No. 21.
- How about a farewell cup of coffee?
- Why not?
You better hurry.
They're beginning to board.
Have a good flight.
I'll do my damnedest
to get them to delay the confirmation...
...but I'm gonna need you there to stop it,
if Harolds'll talk.
I'll be there day after tomorrow.
Flight 62, now boarding at Gate 21.
That's me.
- You gonna wave goodbye?
- I have to turn in the rental car.
Oh, God, I left one
with the meter running in San Diego!
The committee will love you.
They can ask for a bigger car rental budget.
Don't worry about us taxpayers.
Bye.
Collect call, please.
John T. Booker calling Murray Saunders.
The emergency over the runway
is causing no danger to the terminal area.
Please remain calm.
All persons in the terminal area
are asked to clear all gates...
... and entrances to the field
so emergency workers...
...and equipment can get through.
- Hold it!
Obey the commands of the airport guards
and police officers...
... so that rescue workers may perform
their duties as efficiently as possible.
I repeat,
there is no danger to the terminal area.
Thank you for your cooperation.
What are you doing with that gun?
Harolds!
Jesus Christ, I should have figured it out.
In Paris.
It was a setup all the way.
That's what Harolds
was trying to tell Margaret.
John, are you okay?
Yeah, thanks.
She wanted me to talk to him
and get the proof we need.
I think our next stop is Washington.
Are you sure you've got Walker covered?
I still can't figure out
why they suddenly decide to kill us all off.
Maybe Morgan found out
that Harolds was about to crack.
Why didn't he arrange an accident
for Harolds?
Five'll get you ten
there's a damn good reason he didn't.
Let's go ask him.
Morning.
- May I help you gentlemen?
- Yes, Mr. Harolds' apartment, please.
- May I have your name?
- We want to surprise him.
I'm afraid we're not allowed
to surprise our tenants.
Even if you were J. Edgar Hoover himself,
I couldn't allow you upstairs.
It's not likely he could be Mr. Hoover
if he wanted to.
Not only is he the wrong color,
but Mr. Hoover is dead.
I'm sure you get my meaning.
Yes, we do.
We want to make sure
you get what we mean.
You see, my friend here is very cranky.
In fact,
I'd say he's on the very edge of anger.
And in about five seconds,
I'm going to ask him to kick your teeth in...
...if you don't show us the way
to Mr. Harolds' apartment.
Very well. Follow me.
He must have good teeth.
Remember what happened...
...the last time a Washington apartment
was broken into for political reasons.
Think about it.
It altered the course of history.
He will alter the course of your nose...
...if you don't show us
where the apartment is.
- lf you put it in that perspective...
- Now!
There it is.
- Should we ring the buzzer or kick it in?
- No, I'll ring the bell.
Yes?
- Tell him it's you.
- It's me, Mr. Harolds.
Who?
Louder. Be more specific.
Albert, the doorman.
What do you want?
- Package.
- I've got a package.
- It's all right, Albert.
- Thank you. You've been quite civilized.
Good morning, Mr. Harolds.
"My vengeance is swift, saith the Lord."
I expected it to be swift and very violent.
I haven't been disappointed.
Since the day you walked out of
that hotel room in Paris...
...l've been wondering
if I might not see you again.
The fact that you are here now
is testimony to your powers of survival.
The test is not over yet.
I'd like you to meet John Booker.
Maj. Booker,
the shepherd of the betrayed flock.
That's what we're here to talk about.
Normally, I'd do what I've done
all the years I've served my country...
...and feed you a line of shit.
But I don't think I'll bother.
Perhaps you're doing me a favor.
No, Major, there's no one else here.
My wife and children had the good sense
to go on about their own lives years ago.
- Do you have a family, Major?
- I had plans, but they didn't work out.
Then perhaps you're fortunate.
So this is what I get...
...for having too much to drink
and finding a receptive ear.
Can you imagine a career diplomat
getting drunk and babbling...
...at a Washington cocktail party?
You don't get to be an old-timer here
without learning not to do that...
...unless you're over the hill.
An interesting phrase, "over the hill."
Conrad has been telling me for years,
that's where I am.
He's a brilliant man, Conrad.
Most of us think we know
what we want out of life.
But Conrad is one of those few
who knows how to get it.
Of course, he learned immediately
of my drunken indiscretion.
The captured indiscreet remark
is a source of power in Washington...
...a lesson Conrad learned well.
I may have been the one
who first taught him that.
Perhaps I am over the hill.
And she is a brilliant young woman,
quite lovely.
There was something about her.
I just wanted to talk to her.
But, of course,
you must know that by now, Major.
Your being the leader of the Black Tigers...
...I assume she must have gone
directly to you.
Of course,
Morgan assumed the same thing.
His efforts to find out
just how much you knew...
...and whom you might have told
have probably kept you alive.
Four of the men who came back with me
weren't as lucky.
My condolences, of course,
will seem meaningless.
I was there in the beginning...
...when they invented
the Phoenix Operation.
Do you know what everyone
was most upset about?
Not the idea that we were
consciously structuring a group of men...
...whose purpose was
the clandestine murder of other men.
Not the moral ramifications
that might befall us in another life...
...for the decision
based on political expediency.
What we got most embroiled in
was an argument over what...
...a particular group of assassins...
...we decided to call the Black Tigers...
...what that group of assassins
would wear...
...when they went out to relieve
selected individuals of their very lives.
Finally, after a great deal
of bitter argument...
...we determined
to dress the Black Tigers in all black.
The commission was then paid to
a noted designer who shall be nameless...
...who designed the black clothing
the Black Tigers wore as they rolled out...
... on their holy crusades.
You made quite a reputation
for yourselves.
Mr. Morgan?
Mr. Harolds has some visitors.
No, sir, I'm not sure.
I think one of them is Murray Saunders
from the Los Angeles office.
You want them stopped?
Right, and a man on Harolds.
You've got it.
We were set up.
Yes.
What was the deal?
When I was a younger man, I knew
I was going to be Secretary of State...
...or perhaps even President.
If I tell you the answer to that question...
...I may not even be afforded
the opportunity to retire next year...
...with the modicum of dignity left to me.
But then, I suppose your life...
...is not nearly so inconsequential to you...
...as it is to Mr. Morgan...
...or even to me.
- I hope this letter's the answer.
- It's the best shot we've got.
Okay, Saunders, I want that letter.
Listen, Al.
Somebody got into that computer
and this letter proves it.
The letter, Murray.
Come on.
- Get the letter. I'll cover you.
- Watch out!
- Enjoy the fight?
- Terrific.
Here it is.
Why would this guy live
halfway to Baltimore?
Who knows? Maybe it has
something to do with Spiro Agnew.
It wasn't very hard
to get an appointment with the big man.
Morgan's very interested
in what he thinks we might have to sell.
- Good morning, Saunders.
- Good morning, Morgan.
I don't believe I've had the pleasure.
A gentleman whom I'm sure
will add to our discussion.
I see.
John T. Booker.
Saunders, I trust this rather unusual
meeting is as important as you indicated.
Something you said had to do with
our last rather unusual meeting...
...in that Paris hotel room.
Something, yes.
But with one notable addition.
- Coffee?
- No, thanks.
Can we get on with it?
I have a rather busy day ahead of me.
You made a deal in Paris with Kuong Yen,
the North Vietnamese negotiator.
Secret deals are the heart of diplomacy.
This deal called for
the murder of the Black Tigers.
Murder, Mr. Booker?
One other American knows about it
and he talked.
Indeed?
At first, I couldn't figure out...
...why you didn't try to kill Harolds
along with the rest of us.
He told me.
He sent a registered letter to four lawyers,
none of whom you know.
The letters were to be opened
in the event of his untimely death.
Early Agatha Christie.
And just as effective.
The letters explain what was known by you
and Kuong Yen as the Phoenix Solution.
I couldn't figure out what Maj. Mhin
was doing popping in and out of my life.
At first, I assumed he worked for them,
whoever "they" were.
But of course, "they" are you,
and you are all one.
I see. "We have met the enemy
and they is us."
Comic strip philosophy, Mr. Booker.
Agreed, and now Kuong Yen
is manipulating you...
...like the comic strip diplomat you are.
He waited patiently until the moment
of your greatest vulnerability...
...the eve of your confirmation
as Secretary of State.
Now he's blackmailing you...
...into completing the deal
you never finished...
...the extermination of the Black Tigers.
They are very unforgiving people.
Toward you or the Black Tigers?
- Toward us, Mr. Booker. "We" is us.
- Perhaps.
Interesting document.
Morgan, you're gonna pick up that phone
and call the White House.
Sudden personal problems
are going to prevent you...
...from accepting the nomination
as Secretary of State.
If you don't,
the news media is going to have...
...one hell of a time with that letter.
I understand, Maj. Booker,
that you were quite a jungle fighter.
This is my kind of jungle, Major.
No, I just don't think it would be...
...expedient for me to resign at this time.
Expedient?
Just like it was expedient
to send us on that POW raid?
Expedience built this country, Maj. Booker.
It was expedient for this great democracy
to have legal slavery for half its existence.
And it was expedient to keep the vote
from women for 150 years.
Expedient to declare war on Spain
and Mexico and to invade Cambodia.
From the halls of Montezuma,
Maj. Booker, to the shores of Tripoli...
And it was expedient, goddamn it,
to get rid of the Black Tigers.
The end still justifies the means.
I don't buy that.
It occurs to me that most of those
who follow your logic end up in places...
...like Elba and San Clemente.
Come now...
Check your history.
Most of our expedient wars
ended up in failure.
Our successes didn't just happen
because they were expedient.
Those Americans you spoke of
gave up their lives willingly.
Does that really make such a difference?
It makes all the goddamn difference.
People like you never could see that
and maybe they never will.
It's not that you don't deserve
to be Secretary of State.
You don't deserve to live.
That's an interesting philosophy, but...
But philosophy is bullshit, right, Morgan?
That letter isn't.
I tell you what.
You take this letter over to
the Washington Post with my best regards.
But tell them they're gonna have
a hard time verifying that with Harolds...
...because visitors are not allowed
in the Bethesda Hospital psychiatric ward.
Yes, it was a shame.
They found him crawling on the floor...
...and howling like a banshee.
Took four men just to put him
into the straitjacket.
Nervous disorder, they called it,
but actually, he's quite mad.
Hello? I'd like to check on
the condition of a...
...Mr. Harolds, Edgar J.
Thank you.
A letter written by a madman is...
...hardly what they call prime evidence.
Is it, Mr. Booker?
As I told you,
I have a rather busy day ahead of me.
So if you'll excuse me,
I'm sure you can find your own way out.
By the way, Mr. Booker.
Tragic news about your lady friend.
Margaret, was it?
All that information she had
must have been irreplaceable.
Tragic.
You bastard!
Wait a minute.
Accelerator pedal working all right today?
Work for Morgan?
Do you?
We're running a little late, Franklin.
Secretary of State Morgan will become
one of the youngest men ever...
... to achieve this high office.
He's described as one of the new breed
of diplomats for the '70s.
Although still in his early 40s...
... Morgan has had
a long and distinguished career...
... as one of America's leading diplomats.
His skill at top-level negotiations
has made him...
... one of the few
State Department leaders to...
Franklin, where are we going?
I said, "Where are we going?"
What the hell is this?
Good morning, Mr. Secretary.
Booker.
Just what in the hell
do you think you're doing?
You said I was a good jungle fighter.
I'm also a fast learner.
All right, now, you stop this car, you fool.
Relax, Morgan, we're just going to talk.
All right, go ahead. Talk!
What you said about expedience
made a hell of a lot of sense.
I see there's only one way to deal with
people like you: expediently.
You won all the battles, Morgan,
but you're gonna lose this war.
How would you like to be an MIA?
What're you talking about?
When it comes time for your swearing in
today, you're not gonna be there.
I'll be there.
You're dreaming.
Am I?
Booker, they're going to come
looking for me.
You can't just disappear a Secretary
of State without arousing someone's ire.
Let 'em look.
All right. Tell me, what's your plan?
If you get away with this...
...it'll betray every guy that ever died
in any war we ever had.
And God knows how many more people
you'll kill in the future.
I'm not gonna let it happen.
You're insane. It won't work.
You can bet your ass it will.
Crazy, goddamn idiot!
You stop this car! You hear me?
Stop this car or I'll kill you!
You're panicking.
Stop the goddamn car!
The Greenpeace Foundation
in San Francisco...
... says the Russians
are using 250-pound explosive...
Are you okay?
... which are against international treaties.
In Washington, meantime...
... the State Department
has an even bigger headache.
Who will be its new boss?
Morgan, due to be sworn in
this morning, suddenly...
...withdrew his name.
- I'll give you a lift.
Morgan himself has been
unavailable for comment.
He is said to be keeping a low profile
in a secret hideaway on Chesapeake Bay.
- In we go.
- Also unavailable...
... is Morgan's long-time deputy,
Edgar Harolds.
It is speculated that Harolds
might now be nominated for the job...
... but he is reportedly
in the Bethesda Naval Hospital...
... undergoing his
annual physical examination.
Morgan's withdrawal
came as a shock to most...
I see you've had a busy morning, too.
Yeah, it was nothing like yours.