You're born,
you live, and you die.
There are no do-overs.
No second chances
to make things right
if you frak them up
the first time.
Not in this life, anyway.
This is the Battlestar Pegasus
to the ship claiming
to be the Galactica.
Please respond.
Pegasus. How could that be?
The entire fleet
was destroyed.
Admiral Cain, we had
no idea there were
other survivors.
On behalf of the
officers and the crew
of the Pegasus,
welcome back
to the Colonial Fleet.
What they did
to you was wrong, evil.
What you need is justice.
Frak you.
And she died knowing
that her ship and
her crew were safe,
and that her mission
had been accomplished.
Nothing was more important
to her than her ship,
her crew and her mission.
And as I take
command of Pegasus,
I pledge to
uphold those values
that made her such an
effective and heroic leader.
Word of Fisk's murder
has spread out
through the entire fleet.
Crew can fall apart
when their
commander is killed.
Pegasus lost two
in a matter of weeks.
I'm putting
Garner in command.
Commander Garner,
two Base Ships
just jumped in.
Nukes inbound.
We're under attack.
We need those FTLs
fixed soon, or we're dead.
I need you to go down here.
Sir, we've lost Garner.
He sacrificed himself
to save the Pegasus.
Garner was my decision.
His failures,
my responsibility.
Congratulations, Commander.
The Pegasus is your command.
Like I said,
you make your choices
and you live with them.
And in the end,
you are those choices.
I swear,
you're like a kid
on his first day of school.
You're gonna make me
regret having you along,
aren't you?
And so I am very proud...
Every chance I get.
to officially
welcome the new
commander of the Pegasus,
Commander Lee Adama.
Thank you,
Madam President,
Admiral Adama.
Eight months ago,
the world changed.
Our lives changed forever.
We found ourselves
shouldering responsibilities
we never thought we'd have.
Duty.
Honor.
Service.
They're more than words.
Those are the
guiding principles for those
who serve in the military.
And recently,
all have been in
short supply on this ship.
That's gonna change
beginning today.
We can't always choose
our circumstances, but we can
choose how we handle them.
I intend to give you my all.
I expect nothing
less in return.
I've already
appointed Kara Thrace
as my acting CAG.
I'll be making other
officer and duty assignments
in the coming days,
as I review your...
The more things
change, the more they stay
the same, huh, Gus?
Yeah.
Come in.
Lieutenant Kendra Shaw,
reporting as ordered, sir.
At ease, Lieutenant.
Have a seat.
No, thank you.
Frankly, I'm used to
standing in this room.
Yeah, Admiral Cain
apparently wasn't
big on chairs.
Even dead,
that woman
casts a shadow.
But I'm sure
I don't have to
tell you that.
Sir?
I've been reviewing
the fitreps for
the ship's officers,
and frankly
you're a puzzle.
Top ratings from Cain,
who clearly thought
the world of you,
but then a whole series
of increasingly
negative reports
from Fisk, then Garner,
who demoted you
to kitchen duty
for "persistent
insubordinate behavior."
So the question is,
who are you?
Come in.
That's your idea of
vacation reading?
What is that?
Your idea of a hobby?
Yeah, it is.
So have you figured out
how you're going to spend
your shore leave?
I was thinking about maybe
going home to Tauron
to visit some friends,
but I haven't made
any definite plans yet, no.
Well, in that case,
how about spending some time
with us on Gemenon?
I know Rika
and the girls would
love to see you.
Come on, Helena,
you deserve a break.
You've been going
full tilt for over
a year now.
Look, I've got
a repair list
as long as my arm.
Plus, our network's
gonna be down
for the retrofit,
and you know
I don't like leaving
Pegasus at the mercy
of a bunch of
civilian contractors. So...
All right,
listen to your XO.
Once in a while,
it's okay
to get off
the treadmill.
I will think
about it.
Think about it.
Okay.
Excuse me,
could you please
point me towards...
Excuse me,
could you please show me...
Looking for the CIC?
Yes, how did you know?
You've got that
"new officer needing to report
to her CO" look down cold.
One of the benefits
of being a
network administrator.
This is us.
This is where you
need to be.
You're a lifesaver.
Kendra Shaw.
Gina Inviere.
Inviere.
That's Old Germanese for
"resurrection," isn't it?
One of the benefits
of being a lapsed
Classics major.
Guess you never know
when something like that
might come in handy.
Welcome to Pegasus,
Lieutenant.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Kendra Shaw
reporting for duty, sir.
Did you enjoy
your coffee, Lieutenant.
My coffee?
Just say yes
so we don't get off
on the wrong foot.
Yes, sir.
Good.
You see, because
I figured that you either
got lost on your way to CIC,
or you stopped
for a cup of coffee.
And frankly,
I'd rather think it was
that cup of coffee
than realize my new aide
can't find her way
around a Battlestar.
Sir, I've just arrived...
I'm not finished speaking.
I know why you're here.
You're here because
you think this job
is a stepping stone
to a still better one.
So let me guess,
you had your mother
pull some strings, and she...
My mother's dead, sir.
She died of cancer.
Yes, I know.
I read the papers.
And while
I'm very sorry
for your loss,
you'd be well advised
to make that the last
time you attempt
to play on
my sympathies.
Between you and me,
I'm feeling a hell of a lot
sorrier for myself.
Mr. Hoshi.
Sir?
Can you please direct
this lieutenant
to her quarters?
HOSHl: Yes, sir.
You're dismissed.
Lieutenant.
A little
midmorning snack.
Yeah.
I'm gonna be
in my quarters.
Yes, sir.
The beauty of
a network system is that
with the right pass codes,
you can control
just about any part
of the ship from any other.
Of course,
the system's down right now
for the retrofit,
but in an emergency,
it's like having
unlimited backups.
Assuming no one hits
the wrong button.
Yeah, not on Cain's ship.
Puts the fear of the Gods
into everyone,
does she?
Are you okay?
Come on, soldier, get up.
On your feet.
Hoshi! Hoshi!
Okay. Follow me to CIC.
Come on.
As soon as your men are out,
seal the hatches and
vent the compartments!
What in the hell
hit us?
From the
radiological readings,
looks like a
nuclear detonation,
multiple hits.
It's the Cylons.
It has to be.
They've broken the armistice,
and this is part
of an all-out attack.
But at least we
still have our power.
Yeah, but that's about it.
Dradis is erratic,
weapons are offline,
same with all our computers.
We'll have to do
everything manually.
I want all hatches sealed.
Docking connections severed.
Lieutenant,
spin up our
FTL drive.
Yes, sir.
We're preparing
for an emergency jump,
everyone.
Insert jump key.
Sir, two more nukes
heading straight for us.
Estimate 20 seconds to impact.
FTL's spooling, sir,
but without the computer,
we can't calculate
a safe jump.
Don't bother calculating.
Just do it.
You want to do a blind jump,
sir? We might end up
inside a sun.
Missiles closing.
It doesn't matter
where we jump,
just frakking do it,
Lieutenant.
FTL's online.
Five seconds.
Lieutenant, now!
Who am I?
I'm a soldier,
as were Fisk and Garner.
Neither of those men
deserved my respect,
so they didn't get it.
Can you be more specific?
Fisk was a black-market
sellout, a piece of garbage
unworthy of the uniform.
Garner was a
martinet who tried to
micro-manage this ship
like it was some
balky piece of machinery.
Hard to dispute
either assessment.
And what about me?
Don't hold back
just because
I've got a pulse.
You're a step up,
but that doesn't change
the fact that you're
an outsider
who was brought in
to clean up our mess.
Or the impression
that your daddy
just gave you a Battlestar
like he was tossing
you the keys
to a new car.
You certainly don't
disappoint, Lieutenant.
So how would you
like to be my new XO?
Sir?
One thing I learned
from my father, before
he "tossed me the keys,"
is that a commander needs
a strong right arm.
I also need to
send a message to this crew
that I respect Cain's legacy,
even if the truth is
that I don't.
I'm no Cain,
but I intend to give
this crew their pride back,
so I'll let you
carry her torch.
Deal?
In that case, Major,
you're out of uniform.
Dismissed.
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four,
three, two, one,
you're done.
Do you think
that weapon's ready
to fire, soldier?
Yes, sir!
You're ready
to bet your life
on that, soldier?
The lives of
all your buddies?
Sir... Yes, sir.
Then fire your weapon.
Are you deaf, soldier?
I said fire your
frakking weapon.
Again.
Didn't think it
possible that you could find
an XO meaner than Saul Tigh.
Yeah, she's tough,
but I think
we need it tough.
Any ruffled feathers?
Well, she and Kara
don't exactly get along.
Like to sell tickets
to that dance.
Just remember
that an XO's
not a blunt instrument.
The two of you have to
make up a team.
That takes trust.
Oh, we trust
each other to do
our jobs.
Guess that's a start.
Now that your house
is in order,
I have a mission for you.
Against my better judgment,
I let a science team take
a Raptor from us
to go out to study
a supernova remnant.
They're overdue.
I want you to
track their course,
see what you turn up.
There are three civilians,
two pilots.
And if we
run into the Cylons?
It's a search
and rescue mission.
Don't get into a battle
that you don't want to fight.
That being said,
use your own judgment.
This is your command.
Nothing to the right of me,
nothing to the left of me.
Feel like I'm drowning
in nothing out here.
Come on, Showboat, sing out.
Let me know I got company.
Sing out, Cap? What?
You mean like a song?
How about 99
Bottles of Ambrosia?
Damn, Showboat,
you're taking me back.
Road trips.
Thank you.
Pass me
the circuit board.
Here you go.
The sickbay just
lost another two.
That brings
our casualty to what?
Seven hundred
and twenty-three.
That's more than
a quarter of our crew.
What's our fighter status?
Twelve Vipers destroyed,
along with two Raptors.
Another 17 ships
too badly damaged
to be repaired.
What else?
Sir, we've tried to keep a lid
on what we learned
from com traffic
before it stopped,
but rumors
keep leaking out.
We need facts,
not supposition.
I agree.
We're four,
maybe five
plotted jumps
back to the colonies.
Don't imagine you want
to risk the whole ship
for a recon run.
Send two Raptors.
Tell them not to
engage the enemy.
I want information only.
Yes, sir.
Ready to reboot nav and
defense computer systems.
Stand by.
Lieutenant.
Admiral.
The helms, weapons
and FTL computers
are all back online.
And I think I know how
the Cylons took down
our defense grid.
These lines of code in
the new navigation program
we're about to upload,
they've been designed
to create a back door
that could enable an enemy
to wirelessly
access the program.
And that could introduce
a virus that could infect
the entire network.
Is that what
you're saying?
Yeah.
Luckily, ours
was already down,
but I suggest that
we keep it that way,
even after we've
purged the program.
All right, Lieutenant.
It's your ball, run with it.
Maybe you're not
quite as useless
as I thought.
How long have you
been at your station?
I don't know, sir.
I guess I just never left.
Well, you might want to
consider getting
some rack time.
It's been two days
since the attack.
Sir...
Sir, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about the way
I behaved when
the nukes hit.
I was scared.
Actually,
I was terrified
and I froze.
You're not afraid anymore,
are you, Lieutenant?
No, sir.
Good.
You hold onto that anger
and you keep that close.
It'll stop you being afraid
the next time, and it'll
tell you what you have to do.
Lieutenant, button up.
This is your admiral.
I know there have been
a lot of rumors going around
about the destruction
that's been visited on
our home worlds by the Cylons.
I would like to tell you
that they're exaggerations,
but, in fact,
they don't even come close
to conveying the horror
that has just been
unleashed upon us.
The facts are
that our colonies
have been destroyed,
our cities have been nuked,
and our fleet's gone, too.
So far, there are
no indications of
any other survivors.
I imagine
you're all asking yourselves
the same question I am.
What do we do now?
Do we run?
Do we hide?
I think those are
the easy choices.
You know,
a philosopher once said,
"When faced with
untenable alternatives,
"you should consider
your imperative."
Look around you.
Our imperative
is right here,
in our bulkheads,
in our planes,
in our guns,
and in ourselves.
War is our imperative,
and if right now
victory seems like
an impossibility,
then there is something else
to reach for.
Revenge.
Payback.
So we will fight,
because in the end
it's the only alternative
our enemies have left us.
I say let's make
these murdering things
understand that
as long as this crew
and this ship survive,
that this war that they
started will not be over.
Thank you.
So say we all.
So say we all!
A com relay? That looks
more like some kind of
frakked-up can opener.
From what we can tell,
it's guarded by about
a half dozen Raiders.
That's all? Well, they're not
expecting anyone
to attack it.
Gentlemen, you're looking
at our first target.
Nice work finding it,
Lieutenant.
Thanks. I had help.
Speak of the devil.
Hello, Gina. Welcome.
Hello.
Gentlemen,
I'd like you to meet
Miss Gina Inviere.
Miss Inviere and
Lieutenant Shaw have been
working very closely
upgrading our systems.
And before that, she was
supervising our retrofit.
And I must say,
she's proven herself
invaluable in both capacities.
Thank you.
Well, you certainly
set a beautiful table.
Thank you.
Everyone, please have
a seat. Please.
I actually think
it's quite important
for our ship's officers
to get together
every once in a while.
Share some food, some wine,
some good conversation.
Helps morale.
And not to mention,
it's the only time
we get to park our butts
in a chair around here.
Now that you're all here,
I would like to take a
moment to say a few words.
In all seriousness,
I said some things before
in the heat of emotion,
things that I felt
this crew needed to hear.
But I don't want
any of you,
for one moment,
to think that
I would ever risk
lives or resources
in some mad quest for revenge.
My plan is to wage an all-out
classic guerilla war campaign.
I want to find
their weak links and
I want to hit them hard.
As they say,
the best defense
is a good offense.
Well, then,
here's to a good offense.
And to kicking some
Cylon ass.
Hear, hear.
Almost done here.
I don't know how
we're going to firewall
all these systems
by tomorrow unless
we split up.
And you're the only one
with the access codes.
Well, we could speak
to the Admiral about raising
your security clearance.
Here I thought
we were being so discreet.
Guess that's hard when
you truly care for someone.
Program's uploaded.
You need to input your code.
Alpha-one-niner-six-Gamma-one.
To satisfy your curiosity,
we met a few months ago
when I presented the plans
for the retrofit.
We spent
a lot of time together
working out the details,
and I guess
one thing led to the other.
You seem so surprised.
It's just that Cain
seems so self-sufficient.
She has needs,
just like the rest of us.
No one can survive
entirely on their own.
Trust me, Lieutenant.
In the end,
we're all just human.
How about
99 bottles of Ambrosia?
Damn, Showboat,
you're taking me back.
Does she ever shut up?
Road trips.
Chatter like that
breeds sloppiness.
She's gonna set
a bad example
for the other pilots.
Well, as long as
she sets a good example
with her flying,
we'll come out ahead.
HOSHl: Sir, multiple
dradis contacts.
Bearing 399, carom 620.
Fighter size,
unknown configuration, sir.
Raiders.
Has to be.
We got company.
Pegasus, Starbuck,
where the hell did
these guys come from?
Starbuck, Actual.
You and Showboat
double-time back to the nest.
On our way, Pegasus.
I don't like these odds.
Showboat, stay with me.
All right,
defensive batteries,
selective fire only.
Watch out for our people.
Prep for jump
as soon as we recover
our birds.
HOSHl: Aye, sir.
These ships. I...
I can almost see them.
There's something
weird about them.
Sir, shouldn't we launch
alert Vipers and engage?
That's not
why we're here, Major.
Sir, we...
If we spot our
missing ship,
we'll go after her.
Otherwise,
we jump out of here,
we report back to Galactica.
Pegasus, Starbuck,
we got ourselves
a problem out here.
Our new friends
don't wanna say goodbye.
Sir, FTL crew reports
power failure in the
main navigational computer.
No, you got to be kidding.
Let's go to emergency backup.
We need those
jump coordinates.
They're all over us.
We can't break free.
Ensign, direct all batteries
to commence full auto-fire,
close range.
Now, Ensign.
What the frak?
We're inside
their firing solution!
No frakking kidding.
All right, open up
with all you've got.
We're gonna
shoot ourselves a hole.
Is that gonna work?
No, but it will
make you feel better.
Frak.
Son of a bitch.
For frak's sakes,
it's like she was trying
to get us killed.
Look, Major Shaw
has the authority
to take any actions
she feels necessary
to protect this ship.
She's a loose cannon.
And she's also the XO.
And frankly,
ordering that barrage
probably saved your skin.
Forgive me
if I don't say thanks.
Oh, come on, Kara. Just...
Don't.
You wanna tell me
what the hell
you were thinking?
That was a nice bit
of flying up there,
Captain,
but I'd think twice
about questioning
my tactical orders.
"Tactical orders"?
That's what you call
blowing the crap
out of your own pilots?
Questioning orders
is a bad idea
on this ship, Captain.
How many Raiders, Lieutenant?
I'm reading 12
signatures, sir.
It's more than we anticipated,
but one squadron should be
able to handle them
and destroy the target.
Launch Blue Squadron.
Sir, new contacts.
What the hell?
There's a lot of jamming
going on out there,
but I'm reading
15 full squadrons
of Raiders, sir.
They must have
jumped in right after
we launched our fighters.
This isn't a com relay.
This is a staging ground.
Recall the Vipers,
sir? Sir?
Two minutes to contact.
Admiral, the Cylons
knew we were coming.
We have to recover the Vipers
and jump out of here
while we still can.
No.
Scramble the reserves.
Order them to provide cover
while Blue attacks the target.
They'll be outnumbered
four to one!
Sir, a squadron of Raiders
is breaking off
and are now inbound.
Activate defensive batteries.
They aren't responding, sir.
The network's locked us out
of our weapons grid.
Then have gun crews
assume manual control.
Admiral,
we're hugely outnumbered,
and now our own weapons
grid won't respond.
What more proof do we need
that this is a trap?
All the more reason
to launch everything
we've got.
Helena, this is exactly
what you said we wouldn't do.
Even if we succeed,
is this relay
really worth the lives
and planes it will cost?
Mr. Belzen, are you refusing
to carry out my orders?
Sir, I cannot
in good conscience obey them.
Mr. Belzen,
give me your sidearm.
Sir?
I said give me
your sidearm. Now!
Gods.
Colonel Fisk. Colonel Fisk!
You are now my XO.
My order still stands.
Will you execute it?
This is the XO.
Launch all
remaining squadrons.
Clear the tube.
Stand by for launch.
Sir, the controls on
portside airlocks four, 10
and 12 have gone active.
We're being boarded
by the Cylons.
Colonel, fire up
the fast response teams.
All hands, repel boarders...
Lieutenant,
get to secondary
damage control.
They're gonna try
and vent our air and kill us
before we have
a chance to fight back.
Yes, sir.
Go.
They were coming this way,
killing everyone. It's...
Go to CIC.
You'll be safe.
What the frak?
You! Step away
from the Admiral.
Lieutenant.
I said step away
from the Admiral. Now.
You two take her
into custody.
Belay that.
Lieutenant, what
the hell is going on?
She was just
helping us get control
of our weapons grid.
No, she wasn't, sir.
She's a Cylon spy.
They look like us.
Oh, for Gods' sake.
Mr. Hoshi, can you
please show us the security
feed from airlock four?
This is crazy.
I don't know what
she thought she saw...
My Gods.
Get that thing
off my bridge.
Yes, sir.
Hey! Hey!
Act like officers,
Gods damn it.
You got everybody
watching you
on this deck.
Where the hell
did they come from?
Been a long time
since I've seen
one of these outside a museum.
And you say
the entire fleet
jumped you?
They came out of nowhere.
Why would the Cylons
resurrect a machine
that, by their standards,
is hopelessly obsolete?
Maybe they
didn't resurrect it.
Maybe they were
out here all along.
You have something
you want to tell us?
There are references in our
databases to a force of
Centurions called Guardians.
Early models like this
that somehow escaped
being scrapped.
What did these
Guardians guard?
A hybrid.
An entity that represents
the first step
in our evolution
from pure machines
to organic beings.
From them to us.
A Cylon missing link?
No, more like an
evolutionary dead end.
There were other
hybrids created
to control our base ships
before the experiment
was abandoned,
but this one was the first.
And some think
it's still alive,
protected by these Guardians.
And that it's still
somehow seeking
its own way to evolve.
The last operation
of the war,
Galactica was part
of a task force that
destroyed a Cylon base.
I was on that mission.
The Cylons were supposedly
building a super weapon.
All this has happened
before and it will
happen again.
Someone in there?
Help. Help us.
They left us here.
Don't leave us here, please.
I'm gonna get you
out of there.
We're civilians.
The traders from...
From Gemenon, who...
They jumped our convoy,
they destroyed our escort,
they took us all prisoner.
There were 50 of us,
but they've been taking us
away, one by one.
We'd hear
the others screaming.
We didn't know what
was happening to them.
Please, you've got to
get us out of here.
I'm trying.
The door must be welded shut.
Feels like a quake.
The place is starting
to come apart.
I can't.
I got it.
It's still stuck.
I can't open it any wider.
You got to go. You got to go.
You got to go get help.
I'll stay here.
I'll stay here with you.
No, you can't do it
by yourself. Just go!
Tell them what happened to us.
Our ship was
the Diana from Gemenon.
All right, just tell them.
If you stay here,
you'll be trapped like us. Go!
Don't...
Go, go! Save yourself. Go!
Galactica, Husker.
Galactica,
this is Husker.
Do you copy?
Husker, roger that.
Report status.
I crashed on the surface.
They were making
something down here.
Experimenting
on people to do it.
And now they're getting away
with whatever they built.
Husker. Husker,
the war is over.
What?
Galactica, repeat.
The war is over.
An armistice was just signed.
Activate your beacon
and we'll send you
the SAR bird.
Husker, respond.
They escaped with it,
right before
they signed the Armistice.
If this hybrid still exists,
and it's captured
some of our people...
I don't want to
think about it.
Baltar and Tyrol
were able to pull
the Raiders' computer
Baltar and Tyrol
were able to pull
the Raiders' computer
and download
the ship's navigational data
and extrapolate
a possible location
for a base,
but it's more likely
a base ship.
That's where we'll find
our Raptor crew.
It's two, maybe three jumps
from where you were attacked.
I was just telling
the Commander
that we can't afford
to commit both Battlestars.
Which is why I'm temporarily
transferring my flag
to Pegasus.
You're going along?
You're still in command.
Let's just say
I have a personal stake
in this mission.
A mission based
on a Cylon legend.
It's not a legend, Son.
I was in the place
where they made that thing.
I saw what
they did to make it.
We're not going to
let this happen again,
not to our own people.
Well, I'll... I'll have my XO
start preparing
an attack plan.
I'm afraid that brings up
another matter, Commander.
Misdirection is the key.
Pegasus jumps right into
the hornet's nest.
They swarm us with their
Raiders, we let them think
they've taken out our FTL,
before moving off
at sub-light speed,
drawing them away.
That's when my
strike team jumps in.
It's a hell of a risky plan,
but I guess you know that.
Just remember
it's search and rescue.
Get aboard, find our people,
set your nuke, then get back
in one piece.
Who's piloting the Raptor?
Captain Thrace.
No other pilot
I can trust
to pull this off.
Well, then I guess
the question is
whether I can trust you.
The President believes
that under Admiral Cain
you were involved
In an incident
aboard a civilian transport
called Scylla.
An incident in which 10 people
were executed. Is it true?
I said is it true?
I was there.
I'm guessing
that's enough to indict me.
Why didn't you tell me?
You said you wanted
to send a message
to this ship's crew
about respecting
Cain's legacy. I am
Cain's legacy.
I'm alive because
of the choices she made,
and so is everyone else
on this ship.
I'll tell you something else,
Cain wouldn't have
blinked twice at this plan.
'Cause she knew
that you don't win battles,
never mind wars,
without risking lives.
Are you finished?
Yes, sir.
If you'd like my resignation,
you can have it.
It'd be easier,
wouldn't it?
Then you could go back
to peeling potatoes
and wallowing in self-pity
'cause poor Kendra Shaw's
the only officer in the Fleet
who ever had to
make a hard call.
Well, it's not gonna fly,
Major. Not while
I'm in command.
Plan's risky, but right now
you're the only game in town.
So complete
your mission, Major.
Your plan's approved.
got
another load of solid waste
stinking up our cargo hold.
got
another load of solid waste
stinking up our cargo hold.
Demetrius, this is Adriatic...
... and we're back with
Gaius Baltar.
Doctor, a lot of people
once thought of Pegasus
as the answer to prayer.
Were they wrong?
Final casualty
report lists 816 dead,
121 injured.
Thirty-two Vipers destroyed,
61 badly damaged.
The acting chief says
we don't have enough parts
to repair them all.
It's a rather high price
for a tactically
insignificant victory.
I wouldn't say it's
insignificant, sir. I'd say
we put the enemy on notice.
The price
we paid is my fault.
How do you figure that,
Lieutenant?
Well, I gave her...
It my access codes.
It must've used them
to override our
security lockouts.
You gave it something
far more important than that.
You gave it your trust,
as did I.
But this thing
really knows how to
manipulate human emotion.
Preys on them.
Lieutenant Thorne.
I want you to interrogate
our Cylon prisoner. Find out
everything it knows.
And since it's so adept
at mimicking human feeling,
I'm assuming that
its software is vulnerable
to them as well.
So, pain. Yes, of course.
Degradation,
fear, shame.
I want you to really
test its limits.
Be as creative
as you feel you need to be.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant Thorne.
Access granted.
Admiral Cain to CIC.
Lieutenant, come with me.
Colonel, sitrep.
We just detected a fleet
of ships broadcasting
Colonial IFF signatures.
Sir, they're civilians.
A civilian fleet?
Fifteen ships, sir.
The Cap has
gone ahead to intercept.
Lieutenant,
I want you to contact
those ships' captains.
Ask them to
forward their crew
and passenger manifests,
along with the
ships' schematics
and inventories
of any weapons
and spare parts.
Yes, sir.
Colonel, I want you
to assemble teams
of engineers and Marines,
and have them board
each of those ships.
Sir, are we...
We're gonna take
everything we need
from those ships.
Once they realize our intent,
there's bound
to be resistance.
So we need to act
quickly and decisively.
Colonel, if you have a problem
with any of this,
I need to hear it now.
No.
Get to work.
Permission to come aboard.
Permission granted.
Welcome.
We've prayed for
this miracle.
The last time
the Cylons found us,
we lost four ships.
But now,
thank the Gods,
you've found us.
Mr. Laird,
Admiral Cain ordered me
to give you this.
What is it?
It's a list of materials
and passengers
that we need
transferred to the Pegasus,
effective immediately.
Your name
is on the list.
My name?
Wait, you want to take
our FTL drives?
We'll be helpless.
As I said, we're adding
some of your people
to our crew.
So you're going to
decide just like that
who lives and who dies?
We'll make whatever
accommodations we can,
but you have to understand.
We are at war.
Military needs
must take priority.
No. I don't
understand. They're...
They're going to take
what they want and leave us
to fend for ourselves.
You can't do that.
Can't do it.
No!
Listen, all of you!
We have orders to transfer
the crewmen and the equipment
on that list to Pegasus.
We have no wish
to harm anyone,
but we will use
force if necessary.
No.
Leave us here.
Go back
where you came from.
No.
Keep them back.
You're here to help us.
You can't do that.
Ship-to-ship call
from Colonel Fisk.
What's going on,
Colonel? You're already
behind schedule.
Sir, they're denying us access
to the rest of the ship.
We're not dealing with
just individuals, sir.
We have whole families here.
Then tell them you will shoot
the families of any selectee
who doesn't comply.
Sir, did I hear you correctly?
You don't seriously mean...
Just get it done, Colonel.
Corporal.
Sir.
Get these people on the deck
and get them lined up.
Yes, sir.
My boy! No, not my boy!
We have orders
to shoot the families
of any selectee who refuses
to return with us.
We will carry out this order
unless those individuals
are brought forward now!
You're supposed to protect us!
I repeat. We will
carry out this order.
We will shoot these people.
What are we doing, sir? Sir?
Colonel Fisk to Pegasus.
My son!
It's over.
The whole fleet has word
of what happened here.
There won't be
any more resistance.
Ruin innocent people...
Rodeo 1
to Raptor three-five-niner.
Clear for docking approach.
Rodeo 1 to
Raptor three-five-niner.
Clear for docking approach.
Galactica
to Green Leaf shuttle,
you are cleared for landing.
Checkers red...
So the XO's
human after all.
I used to do that myself.
Scrub through
the wireless bands.
Reminds you
you're not alone
out here.
Got any more?
More of what?
Whatever you're about to
stick in your neck.
You don't miss much,
do you?
Whatever floats
your boat, right?
I came down here looking
for a loose bottle,
you came down here for...
Guess we're both
just trying to take
the edge off, right?
Guess so.
That's good,
'cause I'd hate to think
that Lee's new XO
can't handle the pressure.
Maybe wants
to get busted back
to peeling potatoes.
I'd hate to think that Lee's
favorite pilot wants to find
herself scrubbing floors
for pilfering
ship stores.
You keep my secret,
sir, I'll keep yours.
A confirmed report
continued
to attribute
President Roslin's recent
miraculous recovery from...
to attribute
President Roslin's recent
miraculous recovery from...
I've seen
officers happier
about a promotion.
I am happy,
sir. I am.
I guess I just don't know
what I've done
to deserve it.
Don't, Captain.
Don't do it.
Don't look back.
Sometimes we have to
leave people behind
so that we can go on,
so that we can
continue to fight.
Sometimes we
have to do things
that we never thought
we were capable of,
if only to show
the enemy our will.
Yesterday, you showed me
that you were capable
of setting aside
your fears,
setting aside
your hesitation,
and even your revulsion.
Every natural inhibition
that, during battle,
can mean the difference
between life and death.
When you can be this
for as long as you have to be,
then you're a razor.
This war
is forcing us all
to become razors,
because if we don't,
we don't survive.
And then we don't
have the luxury of
becoming simply human again.
Do you understand me?
Good.
Well done.
Congratulations,
Captain.
President Roslin's
recent executive order
outlawing abortion
led to a demonstration...
Portside hull breaches.
Deck 4, frames 12 through 14.
Damage control crews
are sealing them off now.
I'd say that's enough of that.
Get the FTL offline.
Bring her around, heading
one-six-one-carom-zero.
Sir.
They're pursuing, sir.
Let's hope they keep it up.
Looks like
they bought it. Now let's go
get our Raptor crew.
Maybe this will be easier
than we thought.
Guess again.
Two bandits inbound.
Showtime, people.
Ready?
Go, go, go!
Enemy target destroyed.
All wings regroup and
continue pursuit of
Battlestar Pegasus.
By your command.
Gunny, report.
Red Squad all accounted for.
Speak for yourself, Sarge.
I'm still counting fingers
and toes.
Knock it off, Hudson.
Red Squad, form up on me.
Ain't it grand when
a plan comes together?
Red Squad, on my mark.
Fire thrusters.
Red One, Pegasus.
Red One, this is
Pegasus Actual. Report
mission and team status.
We're in. We were able
to access an airlock on
one of the radial arms.
Proceeding towards the core.
No contact, no casualties.
Stay frosty, kiddies.
No telling how many
of those old toasters
they left watching the house.
Shut your yap, Hudson,
maybe we won't
have to find out.
DaSilva,
what're you reading
on thermals?
One heat source,
could be biological,
near the core, but that's all.
Wait. I'm picking up
three more signatures.
Two of them are pretty weak,
but they're coming from
about 30 meters ahead.
Could be our people.
Gunny, take point.
Holy frak!
Get'em out of there!
Go, go, go!
Help us.
Get him out of there! Come on!
Cylons!
Everybody out! Get out!
This way. Let's go.
Come on. Go!
Come on.
Come on!
Man down!
They got DaSilva!
No!
Pegasus, Red Two.
Come in Pegasus.
Copy, Red Two,
but your signal is weak.
We've recovered two civilians.
One dead, two wounded,
including the XO.
We're pinned down,
taking heavy fire.
Mission outcome doubtful.
Pegasus, Red Two.
Report, Pegasus.
Pegasus.
Frak!
Captain, sitrep!
We just lost communications.
The Cylons must be jamming.
What about the nuke?
How's that detonator
coming, Mathias?
The detonator's fried.
Get it working.
You want to tell me
what the hell
that was with DaSilva?
Can't let them take
any more prisoners,
Captain.
You saw what they
were doing in there.
Yeah, I saw.
Keep trying to
resume communications
with Red Two.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Hoshi,
order nuclear
ship-to-ship missile
into launch tube 3.
Aye, sir.
This is a
nuclear mission order.
Load ship-to-ship missile
into launch tube 3.
What're you doing?
They've been
compromised. We can't
regain communications.
We have to assume
that the team's been lost.
We have to
give them a chance.
HOSHl: Commander Adama.
Open launch tube doors.
Major? Major?
Watch those corridors, Hudson.
Pegasus, Red Two, come in.
Destroying that ship
with people on board
is the last resort.
Like it or not, Admiral,
this is no longer
a rescue mission.
Gods only know what will
happen to our people
if they're captured.
I know what
will happen.
I was there.
HOSHl: Missile loaded,
Commander.
Release of nuclear weapons
is authorized.
Disable launch and
warhead safeties.
Mr. Hoshi,
take your launch key,
put it in the firing lock.
Aye, sir.
Belay that order.
I'm not prepared
to sacrifice any lives.
Not yet.
If you're wrong?
Then I'll have to
live with it.
You said it yourself,
Admiral. That thing
may be headed toward Earth.
If it jumps away,
then we lose our only hope
of taking it out.
HOSHl: Sir, jamming's
clearing. I'm receiving a
transmission from Red Two.
Put it through on speakers.
Aye, sir.
Launch evac Raptor.
Pegasus,
this is Red Two. Come in.
Pegasus, this is Red Two.
Come in.
Yes. Red Two,
this is Pegasus Actual.
Starbuck, report.
Still pinned down,
but holding on. Tell me
there's a ride waiting for us.
On their way, Red Two.
And the Raiders have
broken off their attack.
They'll be headed towards
your coordinates
any second now.
Roger that.
Means we're
running out of time.
Evac Raptor's on its way.
They want us to set the nuke
and get the hell out.
That's gonna be a problem.
Remote detonator's
definitely shot.
Can you rig a manual trigger?
Probably.
Then do it.
Do it? What the hell
are you talking about?
We are completing
this mission.
Am I clear, soldier?
Yes, sir.
Red Team, Pegasus.
Evac ETA two minutes.
This is Red Two.
Give me Actual.
Red Two, this is Actual.
What's taking you so long?
Starbuck,
they're gonna be
on you any second now.
Our nuke's
remote detonator
is still fried.
We're gonna have to
cook it off by hand.
Red One is still down
for the count, which
doesn't give us many options.
What are your orders, sir?
We still got a missile
in the tube.
That evac bird gets them off
that ship, we can still fire
this thing off. Mr. Hoshi...
The Raiders are
in their air
defense position.
We launch anything,
they're gonna intercept it.
Then we have to leave
someone behind,
arm the warhead manually.
That's right.
This is your team, Son.
You make the call.
Red Two,
this is Pegasus Actual.
Get the XO,
get your men and get
to the evac coordinates.
Secure your men,
then detonate the warhead
using the manual trigger.
Complete your
mission, Captain.
Understood.
Sergeant, get ready
to move out.
Sir.
Toasters are bugged out.
I'm gonna get you
on your feet. I'm gonna
get you out of here.
Come on, everybody,
move inside! Let's go!
Get your suits on.
Come on! Go, go, go!
You, too, Major.
Let's get...
You, too, Captain.
Leave the nuke
if you don't mind.
What the frak are you doing?
Completing the mission.
Take it. I don't
need it anymore.
Major...
I just gave you
an order, soldier.
Unless you wanna die,
I suggest you obey. Go.
Why?
You know damn well why.
Put on your suit,
you're about to
run out of air.
It's been an honor,
Captain.
All this has happened before,
and will happen again.
Come in, Major.
I've been waiting for you
for a long time.
You're what all this is about,
aren't you? What are you?
What am I? A man?
Or am I a machine?
My children believe
I am a God.
Are you a God?
I have seen things.
Your life, Kendra Shaw.
The things you have done.
Things you felt you had to do.
All leading to this moment.
Do you wish
to be forgiven,
my child?
I repeat. We will
carry out this order.
We will shoot these people.
What are we doing, sir? Sir?
Do you wish to be forgiven?
Yes.
Then come closer.
There's something
I have to tell you.
Come.
Kara Thrace will lead
the human race to its end.
What?
She is the
herald of the Apocalypse,
the harbinger of death.
They must not follow her.
Pegasus, evac Raptor
inbound. Extraction complete.
Clear base ship.
Raptor's on its way back, sir.
They have Starbuck aboard.
Major Shaw stayed behind.
Starbuck?
Actual, this is Red One.
Come in.
Red One,
this is Pegasus Actual.
Report.
Commander, I gotta warn you.
It's Captain Thrace.
Red One, report!
HOSHl:
They're jamming us
again, sir.
Red One, this is Actual.
Come in.
HOSHl: We lost her.
Actual, come in.
Actual.
As my own existence
comes to a close,
only to begin anew
in ways uncertain.
You're scared,
aren't you, motherfrakker?
You should be.
All this has happened before
and will happen again.
Again. Again.
Again. Again. Again.
You wanted to see me, Admiral?
Thank you for coming in.
Starbuck was here
a little earlier.
She's recommended
Major Shaw for
a posthumous commendation.
She wasn't looking for medals.
No, she wasn't.
But I've been
going through Cain's logs,
and from a
tactical perspective,
it's hard to find fault
in anything that she did
or that Kendra did.
They butchered
innocent civilians, Dad.
Come on. How can you
ignore that?
I know that I didn't
have to face any of the
situations that she did.
I had the President in my face
arguing for the survival
of the civilian fleet.
I have Colonel Tigh
keeping me honest
and balancing my morality
and my tactics,
and I had you.
Now, you don't have
any children, so you might
not understand this,
but you see yourself
reflected in their eyes.
And there are some things
that I thought of doing
with this fleet,
but I stopped myself because
I knew that I'd have to face
you the following day.
If you hadn't been in CIC,
I would've
ordered that strike.
Kara would be dead,
so would the rest of the team.
You did nothing wrong,
neither did I.
We both made decisions
that we had to,
to accomplish our missions.
Yeah.
Cain, Kendra.
Were they wrong?
Well, if I believed
in the Gods, I'd say they'd be
judged by a higher power.
But since you don't believe?
Then history will have to
make its judgments.
And since history's
first draft will be written
in our logs...
Well, then I guess
I've got some writing to do.
Think about that commendation.
Yeah, I will.
Not a lot to show
for a life, huh?
I guess not.
You have any idea
why she did it?
Maybe she thought
she had a lot to answer for.
Maybe she had it coming.
We've all got it coming.
You might as well
hear this from me.
I've asked to be
reassigned to Galactica.
Any reason?
You might say
that I have a beef with
my commanding officer.
And what's that?
The motherfrakker
keeps trying to
get me killed.
Well, you ever think
you might deserve it?
Speak for yourself, Lee.
I have a destiny.
I had my palm read
by a Cylon, remember?
A destiny. Right.
You better believe it.
So I guess you are stuck
with me till the end.
I gotta go break in
your new CAG, sir.