Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Tripoli,
where the time is 8:15pm
and the temperature
is a mild 82 degrees.
We ask you to please be patient with
our security procedures on the ground
and wish you a pleasant evening.
Oh, please, Chuck, none of that.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm praying you've got good news for me.
How did it all go?
The mission to assassinate
the Libyan dictator has failed, ma'am.
I'm sorry.
Well, that's it, then.
The last roll of the dice
and it comes up snake eyes.
Thank you for your efforts.
It was always gonna be a long shot,
ma'am.
Now that we have exhausted
your final option, Madam President,
have you made a decision on mine?
I have.
Reluctantly,
and with a most heavy heart,
I am faced with no other option but to
support your position, General Thatcher.
We are going to war.
Fuck it! Fuckin', fuckin' outrageous!
I guess that means no needle.
If only, asshole.
We'd love to see you good and dead
like the innocents you slaughtered.
But your friend has pulled some strings.
I don't have any friends.
Oh, no?
It says here old Ironguts himself
has signed off on your release.
I thought Thatcher was dead.
Well, you thought wrong.
It'll take more than a stroke
to kill that old warrior.
Sign there.
There and there.
He's all yours.
So, Mr Tyler -
Rick -
let's make a deal.
I'm Meredith Baxter,
Senior VP with the network.
Given the circumstances, I won't shake
your hand but consider us well-met.
What is this?
I'm the Executive Producer
of the most successful show on earth
and... you're our new star.
So now, just a quick briefing
and we're ready to play.
Mr Tyler.
Rick.
I'm fucking this puppy -
he's just lifting its tail,
so, stay with me, please.
Turkey Shoot's the game,
and you're the Turkey.
The game has three levels
and hidden in each level is this box.
You have a GPS with its coordinates
and the lock is activated
by your thumbprint.
So, here's the deal.
Locate and open the box within the time
limit, and proceed to the next level.
Run out of time, and you're eliminated.
Open all three boxes...
you win your freedom.
Eliminated?
It sounds a lot nicer than dead,
but that's what we're talking about.
Life and death.
- What the fuck is that?
Just a mild sedative
to introduce a tracking device
so the cameras can always find you.
Level 1 has four shooters,
with double that amount
introduced each level.
Their job is to hunt and kill you -
no prisoners, no mercy.
Of course, you can return the favor.
Any questions?
What if I don't play'?
Then you'll be a sitting duck.
I studied your file, Rick.
You survived combat, suicide missions,
attempts on your life in prison,
even a bullet in the head.
A guy like you...
just isn't wired to give up.
You might even be our first winner.
So... do we have a deal?
What's in the box'?
That's for me to know
and you to find out.
Sleep now.
When you wake... it's game on.
Real criminals, real life, real time!
You're watching smash hit event TV,
coming at you right here, right now,
wherever you are!
- Turkey Shoot!
It's live... with death.
Now let's give it up
for your hosts... Tom and Teena!
I'm Teena Fine.
And I'm Tom Faye.
Welcome to Turkey Shoot.
Teena, last week's Turkey
just not up to the challenge.
That's right, Tom.
Convicted multiple murderess,
Olga Rashenko...
- ..dubbed 'Satan's Babysitter'...
Straight from death row
in Russia's notorious Vladimir Prison,
Teena, and playing for a pardon.
Stumbled on the first level,
and didn't that make you happy?
This time,
she met something a lot tougher
than 14 defenceless children, Tom.
That's right. She forgot one of
the golden rules of Turkey Shoot...
And what is that rule'?
Remember Ramrod!
You got it.
You should never forget
our most successful shooter ever.
With 85 kills...
86 now, Teena.
Deadly from a mile, with a lethal smile.
When he's in the game,
get ready for pain.
The world's greatest marksman...
Ramrod!
Ramrod! Ramrod! Ramrod! Ramrod!
Afghanistan, Korea ll, World War Africa.
The stats are unanimous, people.
50,000 rounds expended
for every military kill.
Now, the elite sniper...
one round, one kill.
The deadliest weapon in warfare...
You're looking at him.
Congratulations, Ramrod!
You just keep extending your record.
Just doing my job, sir.
86 in the trash.
Don't be so modest, Ramrod.
As the successful shooter, you're
now in Game 177, to do it all again.
Looking forward, ma'am.
Where you'll be joined
by three new shooters,
as voted by our viewers worldwide.
That's right, Tom.
The count is done and the results
are tallied, as smartphone voted by you!
Individual territory charges applicable.
Meet the shooters
for Turkey Shoot, Game 177.
The USA has voted Alpha!
He's deadly with
primo weaponry.
Alpha!
Ooh... I love that guy.
Japan has elected Kintay -
martial arts and ninja
smarts are her thing.
Kintay!
Awesome!
And the Middle East
is unanimous for Golgotha!
He loves it up close and
personal with a blade.
Golgotha!
What a beast! Ramrod'?
Good men all, sir - including her.
OK, Tom, the suspense is killing me.
Just who is our new Turkey?
Teena,
we've got someone very special for 177.
He's a decorated soldier,
court-martialled three years ago
for massacring women and children.
He's Rick Tyler!
- Disgraced former Navy SEAL...
currently incarcerated
at Nee-Alcatraz Military Prison,
where he's serving life,
plus a thousand years, for war crimes.
My God! How can he live with himself?
He maintains
he has no memory of the killings, Teena,
after being shot in the head.
Uh-huh.
So, Ramrod, a fellow soldier.
What do you say to that?
Navy SEAL is Marine for 'pussy'.
- Oh... Ramrod!
I'm a jarhead, Torn.
I say hoorah! Bring it.
You heard it from the man.
It's game on!
With nothing but the clothes
on his back and a GPS,
Turkey 177 will be dropped
into the
Appalachian Mountains rainforest,
approximately four miles
from the target.
While avoiding four shooters
with a license to kill.
Now...
- Are you...
- Ready to play'?
It's time to go live on Level 1,
for a rumble in the jungle,
where an ex-Navy SEAL takes on...
Ramrod,
Alpha.
Golgotha and Kintay
in Game 177 of Turkey Shoot!
It's live... with death.
Agh!
Aghhh!
Fuck!
Agh!
Tricked that asshole.
You ain't gonna make it, SEAL.
Fuckin' numbnuts.
I'd like some water, please.
Got yourself a nice little hide-out.
You've gone soft, Llewyn. And stupid.
It's 'Ramrod' now.
What kind of fuckin' name is that'?
That's cheating.
That's the perks for being number one.
Plus they really want you dead.
They'?
The powers that be.
Thatcher?
Even if I knew...
Like shooting fish in a barrel.
That's not very righteous.
What happened to you'?
Money, fame.
See, I'm a celebrity now.
What are you'?
The killer of women and children.
Isn't that what you said at my trial?
At least you remember that.
They shoulda offed you in the brig.
They tried - they died.
Don't do it.
I can tell you things
you don't remember.
You didn't kill those kids.
The massacre - you were framed.
One minute remaining.
59, 58...
You're not going to make it, SEAL.
57, 56...
- I'll see you on the next level.
- ..55...
Not if I see you first.
53...
34, 33, 32, 31...
30 seconds remaining.
18,17,16,
15,14,13,12,11...
10 seconds remaining.
9, 8, 7, 6...
At ease, Commander.
Did you bring it?
Bunch of Nazis in this place.
It is a hospital, sir.
It's a filthy habit,
but when your days are numbered,
you have to do what you want,
whatever the consequences.
Did you watch it'?
Yes, sir.
I thought he looked good, considering.
I didn't recognise Sergeant Llewyn.
Ramrod?
He's different since the trial.
Profiting from death changes a person.
So, you know we're sending in
a team to finish the job'?
Yes, sir.
I want you to pilot the chopper.
Now, we both know that
Commander Tyler is a good soldier
who would never divulge
classified intelligence,
but my colleagues consider him a
loose end - and loose ends come undone.
Commander... it is imperative
to the security of this nation
that Rick Tyler be silenced.
I can't tell you any more
but know this position
is unanimous across command
and goes right to the very top.
Do you read me?
In triplicate, sir.
He should have died in that massacre.
But if you want a clusterfuck,
send in the Marines.
I don't understand, sir.
What's not to understand, Commander?
We framed Rick Tyler.
They say only
the pure of heart sleep well.
- Relax.
It's a cocktail
of vitamins and antibiotics.
It's cheating, I know, but I want you
to give Level 2 your best shot.
How do you feel?
Water.
Decapitation, self-surgery,
that thing with the arrow -
Game 177, so far, so amazing.
The audience like you.
No-one's retired
this many shooters before.
You've even been voted a classic-kill
and you're not even halfway through.
You haven't seen anything yet.
Really?
When I get Llewyn on the next level,
make sure all cameras are pointed at us.
Ramrod.
What is it with you two'?
Wait and see.
Tonight,
following the News At Ten,
a special report.
World War Africa -
a continent in meltdown...
"with the President..."
The Libyan dictator
must be removed.
..her allies...
I fully support my American counterpart
in our joint endeavors in Africa.
“the Libyan dictator...
and the consequences.
That's tonight,
after the News At Ten.
But now,
what you've all been waiting for...
Real criminals, real life, real time!
You're watching smash hit event TV,
coming at you right here, right now,
wherever you are!
Turkey Shoot!
It's live... with death.
Now let's give it up
for your hosts... Tom and Teena!
- I'm Teena Fine.
- And I'm Tom Faye.
Welcome to Turkey Shoot.
Teena, Turkey 177 - an army of one.
You're not kidding, Tom.
Ex-Navy SEAL Rick Tyler...
Currently serving life
plus a thousand for war crimes
and playing for his freedom...
"has embarrassed the best shooter
in the game to progress to Level 2!"
I'm betting our Marine
will have a new respect for SEAL skills
after Level 1, folks.
And the bearded beast,
also no match for Turkey Tyler.
Ditto Alpha.
He sure got an unexpected headjob.
And the deadly and beautiful Kintay,
a victim of friendly fire.
Ohh...
- So, now only Ramrod to the next level.
Where he'll be joined by more shooters,
as voted by our viewers worldwide.
Yes, Teena,
the count's done, the results tallied,
as smartphone voted by you!
Individual territory charges applicable.
Meet the shooters for Level 2.
Greater Europe's gone Viking
with Haakon.
- My, my, that's a big one.
-  Haakon! Haakon!
Haakon!
This guy is a lethal weapon.
Australasia ﬂips for Killshot.
She puts the 'hun' into machinegun.
Killshot! Killshot!
- Killshot!
- What do you think, folks'?
Neo Korea
explodes for Armageddon!
He's dyno-mite!
Armageddon!
Armageddon excited!
Well, get ready
for maximum excitement, Teena,
because we've also got some
very extra special guest shooters
for Level 2.
Four crack Navy SEALs
from the disgraced Turkey's own platoon.
- Wow!
They want some payback?
You got it, Tom.
They've got an axe to grind...
in the Turkey's skull. Lieutenant?
We've got a big chit to cash
with that mass-murdering son of a bitch.
He brought disgrace on the SEALs.
I can promise you now, we won't
stand down until honor's restored
and the chit's paid... in blood.
You heard it from the man.
These guys want vengeance!
It's gonna be all-out war!
With the added advantage
of a pair of boots,
Turkey 177 will wake
in the San Diego Docklands,
approximately one mile from the target.
He has exactly 90 minutes
to reach his goal,
while avoiding eight killers, armed to
the teeth and out for his blood.
Now...
- Are you...
- Ready to play'?
It's time to go live
in an eight-to-one showdown
when Rick Tyler takes on...
Ramrod, Haakon,
Killshot, Armageddon
and four SEALs on Level 2 of...
Turkey Shoot!
It's live... with death.
Say hello to my little friends.
Ha!
Keep tight, keep tight.
OK, keep... keep tight, come on.
Two exits here.
Two exits, I got two.
Clear!
Open season!
Yahh!
Aghh.
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Clear!
Keep tight.
- Clear.
- Agh!
Contact!
Pursue! Pursue!
- Go, go, go, go, go, go!
- Forward! Forward!
Target! Target!
Left and right, left and right.
Fall back! Fall back!
Get down!
Target!
Keep tight, keep tight.
- Keep tight, keep tight, come on.
- Go through. Go through.
- Keep moving, just keep moving.
- Clear.
- Agh!
- Are you alright?
Get back, get back. Get outta there.
Keep tight, keep tight, come on.
Guys, keep together. Keep working
the sides, keep working the sides.
Keep moving, keep moving.
Clear.
Come on, keep together.
We're splitting up here.
Man down!
Go, go, 90, 90, go!
Go, go, go!
Man down! Man down!
Get him out of here,
get him out.
You fuckin' piece of shit.
Go, go, 90, 90, go!
Fucker.
Now, you fucker...
Fuck it!
Commander Wilson?
What the fuck is going on here?
What's it look like?
I just saved your ass.
Shit!
Putting her down.
Excuse me, sir,
we have a military emergency.
I need to commandeer your vehicle.
Yes, ma'am. Is that a Black Hawk?
I need you to stay here
with the Black Hawk, sir,
while we take your vehicle.
- Terrorists?
- I'm not at liberty to say, sir.
- I just filled her up.
- Your country thanks you, sir.
That was easy.
Hard word gets them every time.
One minute remaining.
- Piece of fuckin' shit!
- ..59...
Christ, you stink.
And you look like shit.
So is this part of the Turkey Shoot
as well?
Fuck Turkey Shoot. 24 hours ago, I was
happy for you to rot in jail forever.
Then I found out
you didn't kill those children.
Found out?
Thatcher told me
you were framed for the massacre.
He told you'?
The question is, why'?
Why were you framed'?
Hey, I just ruined
a brilliant career for you, asshole.
You owe me an answer.
Tell me.
Hick?
I assassinated the Libyan dictator
two weeks before the invasion.
A black op, on the President's orders.
Her last-ditch effort to avoid war.
He's dead'?
I watched his head explode.
But the Libyans put in a double,
like we knew they would.
But the Generals told the President
that my mission was a failure.
Thatcher wanted war.
And you're the loose end.
The only one besides them
who knows the truth.
I can't believe it.
This whole shitty war is about
killing someone who's already dead.
- Why didn't you try and say something?
- I didn't have any proof.
- But at your trial you could've...
- Who would you believe?
A psychopathic killer
of women and children,
or four-star generals?
We've got to deal with
that tracking device
or we'll never even
make it out of the county.
Wrap this around you.
Will this work'?
If it doesn't, it's been nice
seeing you again, Commander.
Likewise, Commander.
Sorry I got angry before.
It's a lot to take in.
Somethings still bothering me.
Why did Thatcher tell you
I was innocent?
He never does anything without a reason.
I'll be sure to ask him,
right before I kill him.
Go back to sleep
while I find us a motel.
Whatever happens, thank you.
You're welcome, Rick.
I don't care if his tumor
is having a triple fucking bypass,
you tell his people
if I don't speak with General Thatcher
in the next 15 minutes,
he's gonna wish he was dead.
Good morning, Meredith.
Where is he, General?
I'm not too bad, thank you for asking.
Don't fuck with me, Thatcher.
Where's my Turkey?
Calm down, Meredith,
I've got my best people on it.
Don't patronise me, you asshole.
I know you're behind this.
I thought we had a deal.
I had nothing to do with it.
One of my people went rogue.
These things happen.
This is television, Chuck,
nothing happens on television -
not on my network.
We'll find him, Meredith.
You have my word on that.
If I don't get him back
within the next 12 hours, General,
that cancer of yours
is going to have to get in line,
because I will fucking bury you.
Knee reconstruction - metal pins.
Nothing there?
Keep moving, soldier.
Bullet.
- Metal plate.
Roll over.
Anything there?
Not that I know of.
Found it.
- You ready?
- Uh-huh.
This is gonna hurt you
a lot more than me.
Oh, fuck!
Gotcha.
Now...
hold still.
32 seconds - you manipulate it
well, my dear, like part of your body.
It is my own design.
Yes, a very nice piece. Mm.
And what did you bring
for the hunt, Tito?
Something excessive, I imagine.
Of course, my dear.
After all, excess is what makes
life worth living for people like us.
If I had more men like you
in the department,
I wouldn't have all these problems
with these blasted deviants.
Yes, sir. Kill 'em.
No fancy stuff - just kill 'em all.
- What took you so long?
- The ultimate solution.
Food, clothes.
- You're a sharp man.
And I got us a car.
Anything you want, sir,
just let me know.
Hitler...
Are you having any?
I'm gonna take a shower.
It's an amazing twist
in an amazing game, Tom.
You said it, Teena.
The Turkey's gone and the hunt is on!
And just who is this mysterious
blonde bombshell helping him?
She's been identified
as Commander Jillian Wilson,
a fellow Navy SEAL and an ace
chopper pilot - as if we didn't know!
And check the live stats, people.
Rick Tyler's approval rating
is off the charts.
Wow!
You guys are really liking this Turkey.
We all love a man
who can take charge, Tom.
But let's not forget
what Rick Tyler is, Teena -
a cold-blooded killer
of innocent women and children.
Even battle-hardened veterans
were shocked by the insane bloodlust
exhibited in one of the worst rogue
killing sprees ever seen in combat.
That single act of merciless carnage,
perpetrated against unarmed...
For three years,
I thought that fuck was me.
I remember the kids, the village
and waking up in a hospital in Germany.
I can't remember the massacre.
But I knew I was guilty.
Now you know the truth.
Being innocent doesn't matter.
Knowing you can do it...
I've killed a lot of people, Jill,
and felt nothing.
Maybe I don't have a heart.
Which hospital is he in'?
There is no way
I'm taking you there.
The place will be crawling
with security.
That's never stopped me before.
Don't be crazy.
Thatcher's not worth it.
I wanna see him.
I mean it, Rick, it's too dangerous.
Just forget the General.
Let's disappear.
You realise he's planned
this whole thing.
- He wants me to get to him.
- Bullshit.
He knows you, Jill, and he knows me.
He knew you'd do something.
He's crippled and helpless.
You know what that means for
a guy like him? He's already in hell.
Killing him is just doing him a favor.
I'm not gonna kill him -
it's not about revenge anymore.
Then what's it about?
I don't know.
Shit!
Fuck!
Hold On!
Breaking news this hour.
I'm Pete Sanchez.
Chaos in the downtown tunnels
as authorities pursue a high-speed chase
causing a score of pile-ups
and creating gridlock across the city.
Police say the vehicle,
believed to contain the mass murderer
whose dramatic escape from Turkey Shoot
has amazed the world,
has been lost
in the serpentine transit system.
Crossing now to the network's
eye in the sky for live developments.
Here's Gina Jones.
Thanks, Pete.
The network can report
that the chase is back on,
after the
pale-or white-colored vehicle,
believed to contain escaped Turkey
Rick Tyler and his beautiful accomplice,
dramatically reappeared at the L21 exit.
Dr Schwartz,
please report to Oncology.
SEAL Commander
Jillian Wilson surrendered to police
after a crash ended the chase.
But the convicted mass murderer
remains at large this hour,
as a manhunt continues downtown.
It is believed
Turkey Shoot escapee Rick Tyler
exited somewhere
in the cover of the tunnel system
when the vehicle was lost
for over 20 minutes.
Authorities...
I've been expecting you, son.
I know. Why'?
Can't a dying old man say he's sorry?
Fuck you.
The President's mission was impossible.
You were meant to fail.
I cannot let World War Africa
be my legacy.
It has got to end.
And here you are.
We buried your mission, Commander,
but we couldn't bury you.
You're too good a soldier.
I have got the blood of millions
on my hands.
I'd like the chance
to wash a little of it off.
I'm sending you
on one last mission, soldier.
What the fuck makes you think
I'd do anything for you?
Because you can end this war
and you can clear your name.
Unit 226, rails bag storage downtown.
Three years ago,
I stashed a little insurance policy
and now it's time to cash it in.
I'd do it myself,
but you know as well as I do
I'm not gonna leave this room alive.
Hubris, Commander.
I went to bed
the most powerful man in the country
and woke up wearing a fuckin' diaper.
Don't worry - I can't feel it.
I'm not worried.
The lock is thumbprint activated.
And inside that unit is the truth to
bring down the whole stinking mess.
But you have got to get it to the
right people - people who won't bury it.
Would you do me the honor, son'?
It'd be righteous coming from you.
I started a war
that has become a monster.
You have to end it.
That's an order.
I told you, no calls.
I have the President
of the network, ma'am.
Put him through.
Jeremy! How are you'?
I don't know, Meredith. You tell me.
Well, the Chinese were very receptive,
like we knew they would be.
I'm talking about Turkey Shoot.
You've seen the numbers?
Through the roof. Congratulations.
I must say, it really was a masterstroke
on your part staging that escape.
That blonde chopper pilot - genius.
Thank you, sir. It's all going to plan.
Really?
Because I just got off the line
to the Joint Chiefs.
It appears our friend
is no longer with us.
Thatcher committed suicide an hour ago.
I hope the rats
aren't deserting the ship, Meredith.
His illness was weighing heavy
upon him, sir.
He knew there was no hope.
Warriors make bad invalids.
But they make good Turkeys, sir.
And Rick Tyler is about to take
this network to a whole new level.
Well, I can't argue
with the stats, Meredith.
Hell, even the afternoon news
is getting a bump from this guy.
When the numbers plateau,
we'll stage his recapture
and then we'll go to Level 3.
It's going to be
history in the making, sir.
So, everything's under control?
Absolutely. No question.
Then keep up the good work, Meredith.
I'll have my girl set up a dinner.
Thank you, sir.
I have your PA, ma'am.
Speak.
The police
cornered him downtown, ma'am.
Yes?
They got him.
And?
He's been shot.
Breaking news this hour.
I'm Pete Sanchez.
The past Chairman of the Joint Chiefs,
General Charles Thatcher,
has died at Madigan Memorial Hospital.
The network can reveal the cause
of death is a single gunshot wound.
No further details
are available at this time,
but the President scheduled
a hasty press conference.
For those of you who say
World War Africa has gone on too long,
I say to you, liberation day is near!
Victory is within our grasp!
Bravo, Rick.
Exceptional.
That buzzing in your head's the taser,
but it'll fade.
What's going on?
You mean what's going up?
The ratings, mister.
The last 24 hours have made Turkey Shoot
the fastest trending show in TV history.
You're a bona fide superstar.
And that's why
we're going to give you Level 2.
Wilson?
She's in jail.
But she's OK... for now.
So... Mr Tyler,
Rick...
let's make a deal.
No-one's ever gotten this far.
Our tracking estimates
Turkey Shoot 177 Final Level
will be bigger than a Super Bowl
and a Royal wedding combined.
You're a game changer, Rick.
The audience love you in the real world.
So we want you to finish the game
in the real world.
Excited?
No.
Your girlfriend's facing a court martial
and, I promise you,
I will make them throw away the key.
Or... I can make it all
go away just like that.
All you gotta do is play.
She helped you, Rick, have a heart.
Save your girlfriend, finish the game.
Win or lose?
You got yourself a deal.
Real life, real time, real world!
You're watching smash hit event TV,
coming at you right here, right now,
wherever you are!
Turkey Shoot!
It's live... with death.
Tyler! Tyler!
Tyler! Tyler! Tyler! Tyler! Tyler!
Tyler! Tyler! Tyler!
Now let's give it up
for your hosts, Tom and Teena!
- I'm Teena Fine.
- And I'm Tom Faye.
Teena, Game 177!
It's mighty real.
Sure is, Tom.
Turkey Tyler flew the coop
and took us to a whole new level.
That's right, Teena.
We had an amazing chopper extraction,
the high-octane chase and arrest
of his blonde bombshell
Navy SEAL accomplice,
Commander Jillian Wilson,
and the Turkey's own dramatic
taser arrest by authorities downtown.
But now, he's back where he belongs.
And, for the very first time,
Turkey Shoot goes to Level 3!
- But there's more!
- That's right, Teena.
Turkey Shoot Final Level
will be played in the real world!
Wow!
With the added advantage
of a hoodie for disguise,
Turkey 177 will find himself
in the middle of an unknown city
approximately five miles
from the target.
He has exactly 90 minutes
to reach his goal,
in a world where anyone could be
a shooter and anything can happen.
- Now...
- Are you ready to play'?
It's Rick Tyler versus
the world on Turkey Shoot Final Level!
- Holy crap!
- Awesome!
Kill! Kill!
Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
Stop the war! End it now!
- You really want to stop the war?
- Don't you?
Get this to someone. Take it.
Hey, you're that guy
from that disgusting show.
Yeah. Get down. Down!
Useless piece of shit.
Where are you, SEAL?
No way.
You ready for your close-up'?
Oh, you're a real funny...
..funny man.
So, you finished Turkey Shoot?
So what?
There'll be a new Turkey next week.
You'll always be remembered
as a chickenshit coward killer
of women and children.
And I'll always be Ramrod -
bona fide celebrity hero.
The victors write history, SEAL.
I want to you look into that camera
and tell them the truth.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please.
The great Ramrod has something to say.
Tell 'em what you told me.
Tell them.
Navy SEAL Commander Rick Tyler
was framed.
He didn't massacre
those women and children.
In fact, he tried to save them.
He shouldn't be in prison.
He's innocent.
How do I know this?
Because I was there.
I saw everything.
You think they're going to put that
to air, you're stupider than you look.
There's live and there's live, SEAL.
Who's laughing now?
Not you.
Ten seconds remaining.
Nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two,
one, zero.
Game over. Game over. Game over.
Game over. Game over.
It's official - the highest-rating
two hours in television history.
These seem to be in order.
Ramrod will be buried
with full military honors'?
The whole nine yards, ma'am.
As befitting a true hero.
And we'll be there
to cover it exclusive.
Correct, ma'am.
OK, then. Do your duty.
Commander Rick Tyler,
I'm arresting you
for the murder of
General Charles Donald Thatcher ll.
Hand over your weapon
and stand down, Lieutenant.
Stay out of this, Jill.
It's a civilian risk, soldier,
stand down.
That's an order.
Breaking the stories that matter.
Here's Katy Kelly - Global Cable News.
Bringing you this GCN exclusive.
The architect of World War Africa
confesses from beyond the grave.
Will it bring down the administration?
And could it stop the war?
You're listening to a dead man.
Ironguts!
And whatever you may have been
led to believe, I took my own life,
with a gun that has served me well
in Afghanistan, Korea ll
and numerous other theaters of war.
Simply put, I did it because I couldn't
stomach the secrets and lies any longer.
Three years ago, our best marksman
killed the Libyan dictator
on a mission ordered by the President.
Holy shit!
We told the President
the mission had failed
in order to perpetuate a conflict
that has now become
the terrible humanitarian catastrophe
known as World War Africa.
And we framed the brave, honorable
soldier who pulled the trigger -
Navy SEAL Commander Rick Tyler.
We imprisoned him
for a crime he did not commit.
Here's the truth.
Back up, SEAL!
Back up, SEAL! Back up!
Take them out!
Jesus Christ!
Isn't that our hero'?
You're listening to a dead man.
Not anymore.
We told the President
the mission had failed
in order to perpetuate a conflict...
So, Commander Tyler...
"Hick."
Let's make a deal.
..soldier who pulled the trigger...
Here's the truth...
Navy SEAL Commander Rick Tyler...
We imprisoned him
for a crime he did not commit...
the truth... Here's the truth...
Here's the truth...