Subtitle Presents by Lynn Studio
- First time to France?
- Yes.
Purpose of your visit?
- Business or pleasure?
- Pleasure.
Do you like this music? No?
Yeah, yeah.
You can put your things over there.
How long are you
planning on staying?
Not very long.
Message for Mr. Smith.
- Smith?
- Yes.
Smith.
He's here.
Monsieur, good evening.
Anything to drink?
- Water.
- Sparkling or flat?
Flat.
- Last one for the road.
- A beer?
Oh, yes.
So, how are you, pal?
Just a little
pre-takeoff takeoff.
Gives new meaning to
"flying the friendly skies."
- Can I buy you a drink? A serious drink?
- No, thank you.
- Where are you from? Ah, China.
- Beijing.
My favorite. I love China.
I love the food-- Chinese food.
It's the best.
Yeah, the way they cut things
in little pieces...
so that you don't have to
use all that heavy silverware.
Brilliant invention, the chopstick.
Not like us barbarians.
I mean, there we are,
sticking our forks into the food...
and hacking it up
with our knives.
- First time in Paris?
- Yes.
Mmm. Great.
Men's toilet, now.
You're gonna have
the time of your life.
Hands up, please.
My boss is dying to meet you.
Gun, please.
You won't need it.
You're safe with us.
So, you came all the way from China
to keep an eye on us.
- To help you.
- Yes, of course.
To help us,
since we are so incompetent.
'Cause after all,
what is our miserable history...
compared to yours?
Since we have to work together,
I don't want to spend half the day
killing your name.
- You got a nickname?
- No.
Why don't we give you one.
How about John?
I like that.
Richard.
Inspector Richard.
Welcome to Paris, Johnny.
So, what's on the menu tonight?
They're talking about
the stock market.
What fuckin' time do you call this?
Don't ever keep me waiting.
You got me?
Come on. Let's go.
Ah, there you are.
Smile, girls. Smile.
Welcome to gay Paris.
This is a few friends of mine.
This is Veronica, Susan.
Say hello.
Yeah, sit, sit.
Hey, cool it.
Hey, fuckin' cool it, all right?
I think we have a situation.
One man, two girls.
- You see them?
- Yes, I do.
Want to go to Heaven?
Let's go.
- I'm going up.
- But, boss, the meeting.
I flew 12,000 miles for a cocksucker
of a contact. He can wait for me!
I don't know if I can do this.
Don't worry.
Let Mama run the show.
- Hmm?
- Okay, let's go to Heaven.
He's leaving with the two hookers.
What should I do?
Come up... and enjoy the show.
- Boss, we didn't check the room.
- One minute.
Let's party, big boy.
Come on, baby. Let's have some fun.
- I don't feel so good.
- Want a fix?
- No! I told you, I quit.
- More for me.
Your meeting's up, guys!
Everybody, out!
But, boss, we didn't
finish searching.
- Get out!
- Okay, guys, let's get out of here.
I have to go to the bathroom, okay?
- Okay. Come back soon.
- Sure.
Oh, hey, Johnny. Just in time.
- This wasn't part of the plan.
- It is now. Don't worry.
It's all under control.
He'll do his thing, then we'll do ours.
- Where's the other girl?
- Prettying up in the bathroom.
- You want to go to Heaven?
- Take me to Heaven!
I'm going! Yes! Yes!
I'm going!
No!
You mother fucker! Let me up!
She stabbed me!
The dumb bitch stabbed me!
Stay calm.
Stay calm. Stay calm.
I'm dying.
Stop recording.
- Fuck!
- We need to get him to the hospital.
He doesn't wanna go to a hospital.
He wants to go to Heaven.
- Why did you kill him?
- The question is, why did you kill him?
Richard, look what he did to me!
Help me!
Thanks for the help,Johnny.
I was just in here.
I felt a little sick, and then there was
all this screaming and shooting and--
Shut up!
There!
He's on the fifth floor.
Everyone, down.
He's on the eighth floor.
Everybody, back up!
I want him dead!
He's in the laundry room!
Everyone, down!
- He's down in the laundry room!
Everybody, down!
- You, down!
But I think--
You! And don't think!
You and you, go to the next level!
You know, the Chinese have the best
roasting methods in the world.
I prefer the French one.
Give me your lighter.
What do they say, Johnny?
Out of the frying pan, into the fire.
- Get 'em out of here!
- Go!
Down, you piece of shit!
- You're still with us,Johnny?
- Yes.
All right,Johnny. You wanna play?
Give me a green one.
No!
Oh, shit!
Go!
You're dead.
Shit!
- He's gone.
- I can see that.
He-- He got the cassette.
So what?
They show nothing but a fat degenerate
with some hooker killing him.
- Except that--
- What?
One-One machine was still running.
Fuck!
Turn the city inside out.
I don't care! Find it!
- Get the cassette!
- And kill him?
No, bring him to me. I want him alive.
I'll kill him myself. Go!
Nothing's on one.
We're still looking. Shit.
Gare de l'Est.
It's a train station.
Take the direction Bibliotheque
until Chatelet. You change.
And you take line number four and--
Yes, yes.
Direction Porte de Clignancourt,
and you're right there.
Okay? Yes.
Excuse me.
Thank you for coming.
In the name of the president, I want
to personally apologize for this mess.
I want to stress that we would
not want anything like this...
to jeopardize the warm relation
and successful economic ties...
shared by our two countries.
So...
we have assigned our best man
to supervise this case.
He handled the Tehran incident
for us masterfully.
There is no one more qualified
to bring this...
to a mutually
beneficial conclusion.
- Inspector Richard. Bonjour.
- Sir Minister.
This is Minister Tang, our liaison
from the People's Republic of China.
- It's an honor to meet you, sir.
- The honor is ours.
The minister tells us
you are the best of the best.
Well, the minister is too kind.
If that were true,
I might have been able
to avoid this tragedy.
I'm hoping that you might help us
understand what went wrong...
so that we can avoid
further bloodshed.
And hopefully, bring this matter to
a quick and satisfactory conclusion.
If we could be showed the facts.
Yes, of course. Please.
Uh, as you know,
as soon as you informed us...
of the criminal activities of the gangster
Sung, we set our operation in motion.
We identified his heroin
smuggling routes into France.
And in the spirit of cooperation,
we graciously accepted your offer...
to have one of your people,
Liu Jian, come over...
to assist us in Sung's arrest as he
was meeting with his French contact,
who unfortunately
we haven't yet identified.
Here...
he is surveilling Sung as we were
waiting for the contact to arrive.
And here, he's observing
along with us.
And then, for some reason we still can't
understand, he went completely insane.
Left the room to pee,
and next thing we know...
he's knocked out the bodyguards,
killed Sung and the prostitute.
This is the gun
he used to murder Sung.
Chinese police issue.
Do you recognize it?
- Yes.
- Good.
Oh, we have also verified
his fingerprints on the weapon.
Well, please, feel free to verify
our findings with your own people.
We assume that your man was
part of the conspiracy--
that he murdered Sung to
keep him from being captured...
and testifying in your courts,
as you had requested.
But that is only an assumption.
We are hoping you could give us
some background on him...
which would help us in his capture.
Inspector Liu Jian was top in
all his classes at the academy.
He received the highest training
in martial arts,
weapons and police tactics.
He's been decorated for bravery
in the line of duty six times,
been promoted five times,
and has never lost a case.
He has no wife, no children.
His only dedication is to his work.
He's our best,
which is why this is all so confusing.
Well, you know, sometimes
the best are also the worst.
It's really sad.
Any surveillance cassettes?
Destroyed as he made his escape.
Do you know if he has any relatives
in Paris? Any friends or--
He has no one.
Well, then we should be able
to wrap this up very soon.
Excuse me.
I found the emergency phone.
Oh, that's good news.
Stay by the phone.
I'll call you back later.
Inspector Richard, we are very sorry...
that the operation was sabotaged.
I will report back to my superiors
and get you any help I can.
- Thank you.
- Let me show you out.
I want them followed.
I want their phones tapped.
I want to know every move they make,
every word they speak.
There must be a sleeper he's
staying with in Paris. Find him.
So, I guess you will be staying...
longer than you expected.
A little longer.
Paris is a nice city once you get used to it.
And the French are nice people
once you get used to them.
- Are you hungry?
- No.
Family recipe. Very tasty.
Fifty men on the street,
and you can't find this son of a bitch?
- Did you try his hotel?
- The fuck never checked in.
"The fuck never checked in."
That means he has a friend in Paris,
or family. Even better.
- Who tried Chinatown?
- Here. But it's hard to be discreet.
So put on a wig and a kimono.
I don't care how you do it.
Now, get out. Get out!
Get out! I want that little prick
in my office by tonight!
Oh,Jessica, my love.
Come to Papa. Come.
Richard, I tried.
I really tried.
I was only in the bathroom for a minute.
You know, I was getting
ready to do my part--
Getting ready to do what it was
that I said that I would--
What you wanted-- I really-- I really--
I really was ready to do what it was--
what you wanted--
Jessica.Jessica.
I know you were. I know, I know.
Coming from such a quiet place
as North Dakota,
you must have been so scared.
- Richard, I tried. I- I--
- I know.
- I tried. I really did.
- I know you did.
All that noise.
My poor little farmer's daughter.
Don't be scared.
You're the best girl I have.
And you know how I treat my best girl.
I know.
So you'll keep your promise?
Promise?
Did I make a promise?
Yes-- Yes. You said that
if I did it one more time,
that you would let me--
let me have my daughter back.
- You said that you'd help me
get the papers to get her out.
- Did I say that?
- Yes.
- Did I say that, Max?
Oh, yes, you did.
Well, there you go. Two to one.
I guess you're right. So I'll have
to let you go,you and your precious.
Do you realize how much I must trust you
to let you go just like that?
With everything you know?
Everything you've seen?
One phone call from you,
one word, and I'd be locked up
for the rest of my life!
I'd never do that!
I'd never give you up, ever!
I know that. If I didn't
trust you, would I let you go?
- What is he doing?
- I don't know. What are you doing, Max?
- I'm preparing a fix.
- He's preparing a fix. Do you want a taste?
Richard, I told you I quit. You know I quit.
I don't want it anymore! I quit!
You don't tell me when
you're gonna quit! I tell you!
You don't tell me what you want! I tell you!
How long will it take for a fucking junkie
like you to betray me for a lousy fix?
I won't betray you! Please, don't!
"I won't betray you! Please, don't!"
Put her back to work.
Come on. Come on.
Get the fuck out. Come on.
Move your fuckin' ass.
Get to work, you fuckin' animals!
You cock sucking pigs.
Youplaymah-jongg?
A little.
I love mah-jongg.
Keeps the mind sharp.
It's hard to find good players around here.
That's why I play by myself.
This way, I always win.
Bitch!
I'm gone for five minutes,
and you think you can park
your skinny ass in my spot?
Fuck off! You want some more?
She--
She broke my nose!
Come on! Look at you!
I haven't been home for 15 years.
That's a long time.
- You stupid piece of shit.
- I have seven grandchildren.
You are a fucking dog.
All right?
Get back to work.
And one big girl 14 years of age.
Almost a woman now.
She wants to come to Paris.
She goes to university.
Hey! Go away! Go away!
- Please.
- You don't know these women.
They say they want to use the bathroom
to pee, and next thing they're shooting up.
She only hurts herself.
Please, don't draw attention.
Excuse me.
- Can I use your toilet?
- No.
Oh, please. I just--
I only have to pee. I won't be long.
No!
Okay.
Wait!
What are you doing?
Well, if you're gonna treat me
like a dog, I'm gonna act like a dog.
- I'm gonna pee right here.
- Stop!
Okay.
There.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
- But nothing else.
- I'm not gonna do anything else, I promise.
- Do you wanna check?
- No.
- Just hurry.
- I'm sorry to have to force you to.
It's just I have got to go so bad. I really--
- I'm only-- I'm only gonna be a minute.
- Okay.
I'm Lo, the chef. I came for my order.
Oh! That feels so good.
- How many?
- Uh, one, two,
uh, three, four--
- I owe--
- Don't worry about paying.
Come back later, okay?
Come back later. Okay.
Thank you. Thank you.
Miss, you have to finish now.
Minute's up.
You have to leave!
Miss?
Miss? Please.
- I slept long?
- Only a minute.
Oh, that's good.
I've gotta get back to work.
Every 15 minutes they come by in a
fuckin' car, and if I'm not out there--
It's just that I'm so tired.
They gave me this shot and--
Oh, my God.
Are you gonna finish this?
- This is pretty good.
Did you make this yourself?
- Yes.
- Is that what you do, then? You cook, huh?
- No.
- But you make these chips, right?
- My uncle does.
I love those chips. Do you mind?
I love the pink ones.
My daughter loves the blue ones.
That's her favorite color.
Miss, you really have to go now.
Delicious. I'm sorry.
- It's not every day I get to eat
in a Chinese restaurant.
- Here.
One for you
and one for your daughter.
Oh, my God. This is so nice.
You're the first person that's been
kind to me since I've been in Paris.
Look, I- I-- I don't like
to take things from people.
Usually I like to pay my own way, so...
maybe later on, if you wanna, you know--
- No charge?
- No. Thank you.
I don't have any other way to repay you.
- Don't worry.
- I'm not your type. Is that it?
I don't have type.
Miss?
I'm sorry for hitting you.
That's okay. I'm used to it.
Kittana in one hour.
Follow me.
He's on board.
Let's go.
Tell me everything.
Richard, the cop in charge,
set up the whole thing.
- He is the connection.
- Do you have proof?
They recorded everything.
They said that, uh,
you destroyed all the cassettes.
Except one.
Hand it to me, carefully.
The main thing now is to get you
out of the country. I have a car.
We can go to the airport,
and from there we can--
Shit! He's under the bridge!
Get out!
Block the north side!
I'll cover the south!
Go! Go!
Will this be a problem?
With a billion of them,
do you think they'll miss one or two?
The embassy's asking for the release
of his personal effects.
Send them a big wreath of flowers...
with my condolences.
How much should I spend?
This much.
Here are your assistant's
personal effects, and here...
are some photos of your hero
killing another Chinese citizen...
on the French soil.
There's a time for diplomacy
and a time for action.
Diplomacy is dead.
- You should go to the hospital.
- Do you have a needle and thread?
You know, since I began my work...
I have received five of you young men.
Fast, proud-- like you.
Four have died--
the last one right in my arms.
Before my time is up here,
I would like to send one home alive.
I'll go for some bandages
and disinfectant for you.
Hi.
- Need any help?
- No.
I have some experience.
You know, the longer that
that thing stays open,
the more risk there is of infection
setting in, and then you are in for it.
I once had a scrape I ignored.
I let it go for a couple days.
- It turned into staph infection.
- All right!
But only to sew it.
- Then you must leave. Okay?
- Yeah.
Doesn't like me standing outside, huh?
Your uncle.
Well, I don't blame him.
If I were him,
I wouldn't like me
standing out there either.
Now, this is gonna sting.
Believe me, if I had any other
place to stand, I would.
It's just all the good spots
get taken by the others and--
You would not believe how much business
some of these girls do.
- Guess how much some of them do in a day.
- I don't know.
- Well, guess.
- I can't.
- Sure you can. Pick a number.
- Five.
Five? How about 25?
- Twenty-five?
- Mm-hmm.
That's the record.
But at least 15.
- Can you believe that?
- No.
Yeah. Me? I'm lucky
if I can do five in a week.
- You ever been with a hooker?
- No.
- Not even once?
- Are you gay?
- No.
That'd be okay if you are. I think
everyone should be who they want to be...
- and do it with who they want to do it with.
- I'm not gay!
All I'm saying is, I don't hold
nothin' against nobody that way.
- Are you finished?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
There.
Mmm. Here you go.
Good as new.
Oh, my God. Look at that scar.
Let me see.
I'm fine. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
You did a very good job.
I used to sew up pigs.
That was my specialty.
Used to have this big, fat mama sow, and
she tore herself along the barb wire when...
she was trying to get to the other side
of the fence to get at these apples.
- You gonna be around long?
- No. I go home as soon
as my business is over.
Hmm. And so,
what is your business,
- if you don't mind me asking?
- Shrimp.
Oh, yeah.
Pretty aggressive shrimp.
You should probably be
more careful.
- No wife?
- No.
Haven't met the right girl, I bet.
- Right?
- My work-- It's hard to meet any girls.
Any interest in an ex-junkie hooker...
who can cook, clean, sew
and who likes Chinese food?
No, thank you.
I'm just kidding.
Hey, look.
See? My daughter.
- My angel. Sweet, huh?
- Yes.
Why do you do this kind of...job?
Well--
There was this guy, and, uh,
I met him after I had my baby.
And where I come from, girls without
husbands just do not have babies.
And if they do, well,
it's kinda hard on 'em.
So, anyway, this guy I met--
He's this French guy.
He's really cool
with this great accent...
and always talking about art and books
and movies and everything.
And, boy, when you're, you know--
When you're young and really desperate,
you know, this--
And this guy could really--
I mean, he could talk. You know?
And so-- I don't know.
The next thing you know,
you're on the street.
Why don't you just... quit?
It's a little more complicated than that.
What do you mean?
I should probably get back. See you later.
Nice talking to you.
- Lupo!
- Practicing embroidery on the clients?
No, no, he's not--
Lupo, he was just--
He had a cut on his arm.
I thought he was gonna call the medics,
and they'd be blocking off the street,
and then the clients couldn't come,
and I couldn't be standing on my spot,
and I couldn't make any money for you,
so I thought if I just took five minutes, then--
Shh. Get back to work.
Lupo, he had nothing to do with--
I said, get back to work!
Excuse me.
I'm really sorry to interfere in your business.
But I would really appreciate it...
if you...
don't do that again.
The little statue speaks.
You know, I don't care
if you fuck her, bleed on her.
You're still using her time,
and her time is my money.
You've kept her busy for 20 minutes.
- Do you know the going rate for 20 minutes?
- No.
Five hundred francs.
Ah! Five for her time, now five for mine.
My kind of client.
Lupo, we should get back--
Hello, Max?
Fuck!
What happened?
Down!
Fuck!
Ah! Damn-- F-- Oh!
Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, my God!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
What're we gonna do?
Respect his wishes.
Listen.
The longer you keep information from me
about this psychopath you sent over,
the longer my city will bleed
innocent blood.
I assure you, Inspector,
we have kept no information from you.
Good.
- What're we gonna do now?
- I don't know.
- I can't walk the streets all night.
- Walking helps me think.
- Walking hurts my feet.
- Then go home.
Oh,just like that.
First you put me in this mess,
and then you think
you can just get rid of me.
I put you in this mess?
You were the one
who came to the shop to pee.
who offered to sew me up.
I didn't ask you for anything!
I only asked to be left alone.
Oh, yeah, that's you--
don't need anything, don't need anybody.
Just have yourself and your stupid job
selling shrimp chips.
I don't sell shrimp chips.
Yeah, I figured that out. I mean,
I'm stupid, but I'm not that stupid.
- I'm a cop.
- I'm Santa Claus.
Who is Santa Claus?
A big fat guy, red suit, flying reindeer?
Jesus, God, don't you know anything?
Take me here.
Why do you want to go there?
The best thing to do. When you lose
your way, you go back to the beginning.
Beginning? Beginning of what?
My work. Last night.
You-- You were there last night?
Working with the French cop.
- Richard?
- You know him?
Yeah. I was there too.
The redhead.
Yeah. No, it was a wig. It was--
- Come on.
- Wait a minute!
- A second ago you couldn't wait to get rid of me.
- You're my proof.
I will take you to the embassy,
and you will tell them everything.
No, no. I'm in deep enough.
I'm not gonna be your witness.
You're the only one who can save me.
Don't you listen?
Richard has my daughter.
But you don't think about that,
do you? No!
You don't think about what's gonna
happen to her, what's gonna happen to me.
Of course not! You only think of your job.
That's all that matters to you, because that's
all you've got in your crummy cop's life.
You take Richard down, and it's just
gonna leave a space for another bastard,
one who we pray will be less of
a bastard than the one before him.
And that's reality!
Maybe it's not your reality,
but it's my reality every day, 24-7.
And there's nothing you or anybody else
can do to change that.
Wait.
If I get your daughter back,
will you help me?
I'm-- I'm-- I'm really screwed this time.
My government will protect you.
They will give you safely away.
Away where? To China?
I mean, I like the chips, but no, thank you.
Listen to me.
I know you've had some bad experiences
trusting people.
But if I gave you my word,
you will be safe.
Yes, Minister.
We're doing all we can, Minister.
But we are not magicians who can pull
killers out of hats like they're rabbits,
especially one who is trained like this.
I'm just a cop trying to do his job. Yes.
I'll call you back.
Richard! My God, Richard!
You're not gonna believe this.
Try me.
I-- This crazy little Chinese--
Lupo picked the perfects pot,
except its melled like shrimps.
And how can I get any clients
when I smell like a shrimp?
So anyway, I was trying to work,
and Max and Lupo come along.
They went into the shop,
and the next thing I know,
the little fucker goes nuts,
you know, and-and-- I mean--
Max tried to protect me,
and the Chinese guy killed both of them.
I believe you.
And then?
And then he takes me as a hostage.
He made me carry this stuff, and he
dragged me all the way up to that church--
You know, the big church
on the top of the hill?
And then-- You know-- And he made me...
help him do these things-- these weird
things with incense and pajamas.
- And everytime I tried to run--
- He stopped you?
Yeah.
You know-- You know those movies...
with that Chinese guy who's always
kicking and screaming all the time and--
- He used kung fu on you?
- Yeah. Yeah.
He did. Look.
Wow.
And then he made me go to this
restaurant while he ate this goop...
with weird things in it, you know,
like snails and frogs' legs and--
That is when you escaped
out of the bathroom window?
- When he fell asleep.
- In the restaurant?
He-- Yeah.
Richard.
Please, don't-- don't do that.
Do you think he is still there
in the restaurant?
Well, he drank a whole lot ofbeers.
That's why I came here.
- 'Cause I thought if I helped you--
- What?
I could show you where he is.
- You're not too tired?
- Oh, yeah, for sure.
I could probably sleep for a week.
But, I don't know. I--
You want me to come?
I don't know. What do you think?
I think... I should come.
I think you should stay.
Okay. He's-- He's at
the Mandarin in Belville.
But-- But I'll do whatever you want,
though. I mean, I just--
I want you to trust me.
I trust you.
Ow! Wait. Wait.
And if I discover I can't,
I know where to find you.
What about my daughter?
She's safe,just like her mother.
Watch her.
So, what's a girl gotta do
to get fed around here?
Okay. Okay.
Wait a minute. What do you think I am,
the village idiot?
No. First you go get mysandwich,
and then I give you your dessert.
Hello?
- Don't do that!
- You get it?
No, I always walk around handcuffed to
a steam pipe with a turtle for company.
So you didn't get it.
Is it just you, or do all cops
lack a basic sense of humor?
Now will you help?
Relax your arm.
I can't relax it anymore.
Come on, you know about handcuffs.
- You sure you got all of them?
- The deal was I get you all the tapes in his office.
Are you gonna live up to your end
of the bargain or what?
Are you listening? Hello!
- No, no. No needles.
- No needles. No.
- How did you do that?
- Chinese magic.
- Let's go to the embassy.
- No.
- First we get my daughter.
- No, first the embassy, then I get your daughter.
Bullshit. I'm not gonna sit someplace
safe while my kid's life's in danger,
so forget it!
Which way?
She escaped?
What do you mean she escaped?
How could she escape?
It's here.
See you around.
What is this place?
It's an orphanage.
- Do you mind?
Oh, no.
Shit.
Oh, come on.
There it is.
Section "B," bed 13.
Okay.
What's wrong?
I don't know. I guess I'm kinda nervous.
I mean, I haven't seen her in almost a year.
Then don't make her wait.
Go.
- Are you okay?
- I don't think so.
Somebody help me!
Here, sweetie.
That's for boys.
Don't you have any Barbies?
All my Barbies are working.
I had a turtle,
but your mother took it.
When am I going to see my mommy?
Soon, darling.
Very soon.
My daughter?
Calm down. Everything's gonna be okay.
But he has my daughter.
And we have them.
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be fine.
No. You don't understand.
My life is not some fairy tale.
My life is hell.
Richard is the devil,
and he has my daughter,
and he's gonna kill her,
and then he's gonna kill me.
And then he's gonna find a way
to get out ofit clean.
You're wrong. They will arrest him,
and they'll take care of you and your daughter.
"They"? "They"?
I don't give a shit about them.
I don't trust them.
I trusted you.
For the first time in--
God, I don't know, forever--
I don't know why I trust someone.
You promised you'd take care of her.
Yes.
You're tired. I think you should sleep.
- Hello?
- I want the child.
- I want the cassette.
- I gave the cassette to my government.
- They will know what to do with it.
- Bad move,Johnny Boy.
Now that the kid has no value,
what am I going to do with her?
She's too young to work.
Maybe not.
- What do you think?
- I think you should come to the window.
Now I know where you are. I'm coming up.
He's coming up.
Hey, monsieur--
Sound the alert!
Fight!
Come on! Come on! Get those out!
Move it!Move it! This is not a drill!
Go now!
Ah,Johnny,Johnny,
I'm disappointed in you.
Coming to Paris for the first time,
and instead of enjoying yourself,
you're doing all this useless running around.
- I don't like to get bored.
- Me either.
And right now I'm finding you very boring!
Wait!
You're making a big mistake.
- Ah, really?
- In the second...
it takes for you to kill her,
I will have all the time I need to kill you.
I got you.
Yes, you did,
but I also got you.
Isabel?
I'm a friend of your mom.
Can you wait outside?
Okay.
Good-bye, mister.
What did you do to me?
I put a needle in your neck.
- That's it?
- In a certain point, very forbidden.
It's called "The Kiss of the Dragon."
Kiss my ass!
The blood from your whole body
goes to your head.
It stops there, never comes down.
But soon it will come out from your nose,
your ears,
even from your eyes.
And then... you will die, painfully.
You're really a smart guy, Johnny Boy.
My name is notJohnny.
- I slept long?
- Only a minute.
My daughter?
THE END
Subtitles by: