Glory be to Allah.
l testify that there is
none worth worshipping..
..except the Almighty Allah.
'Questions were many.
One of them was..'
'..did Noor win or lose?'
'But the bigger question was..'
'..how can there be a relationship
or brotherhood with the country..'
'..we'd fought three wars with?'
The Quaid-e-Azam
kickboxing goodwill tournament..
..which has been
organised in Lahore..
l'm certain that
we'll win this tournament.
Our players are fit,
trained and experienced.
Thank you very much.
And now, the lndian coach
Mr. S.K. Rao will address the press.
What do you speculate
about today's match, Mr. Rao?
What do you wish to hear?
Even today, we're going to win.
Every individual
has his own opinion.
And if l were to share mine..
..you didn't win in
Kuala Lumpur either.
lt's the question of Lahore today.
l won't accept defeat here,
at any cost.
Sorry, sir.
We'll decide the codes today.
The prime issue today is
the competition at Lahore.
And the confidence..
..with which he has assured
the victory for his team..
..l think even l can say
this with full confidence..
..that we've come fully
prepared to return as winners.
Thank you so much.
ln the last 62 years,
lots of things have been played..
..between the two nations.
Lots of things.
lf there's something that
hasn't been played, it's sports.
Well said, sir.
Sir, what's your
opinion regarding the fact..
..that the sport which
will be played now..
..will further
strengthen the relations?
When l was a child, my
granny would tell me..
''Go out and play with friends.''
Now, after all these years..
..l've again stepped out
in search for friends.
So that l can play with them.
After all, sports are only
played with friends. Right?
But sir, the nations where
cricket is seen as a religion..
..does the success of a kickboxing
tournament in those places..
..seem to be a far cry?.
No, no. Look, this is not
a platform..
..to criticise cricket or hockey.
lt's about time we paid attention
to other sports as well.
Kickboxing is just the beginning.
Just wait and see. What did you say?
This is the result of
Mr. Mohammad Akhtar's efforts.
This Quaid-e-Azam
goodwill kickboxing tournament..
..which shall be played out in Lahore.
The 16th national kickboxing
championship's final bout..
..in the featherweight
category is being fought between..
..Rajasthan's Dheerender
Singh and Gajanan Oinam of Delhi.
Delhi's Gajanan Oinam..
..has been a national
champion for the last five years.
Whereas, this is not just
Dheerender Singh's first time..
..at the national championship..
..but he's also made it
to the final.
And he seems to be
in tremendous form.
Yes. Take him. Look out.
To the left. Left.
Move. Corner.
Come on. Yes. Come on.
Yes. Comeon. Come on, come on.
Very good. Well done.
Stop. Stop.
Start.
Running up from the
pavilion end to bowl..
..is Haryana's medium-pace bowler.
And the ball..
And the batsman has been beaten.
He has been beaten completely.
He wanted to play it..
Yes.
- What happened?
lt's still on.
What are brother's chances?
Can't say anything right now.
This is the second
success for Haryana.
Delhi has lost its second wicket.
Oh, no. Every call of
yours costs a wicket.
lt's you who called up, not me.
- Veeru, you're on.
The crowd is eagerly
waiting for the next batsman.
Delhi's run machine.
That means, Veerender
Singh is on the ground.
This majeesic batsman
hailing from Delhi..
..is well known for
his powerhouse batting.
Right-handed Veerender Singh.
He has scored seven half centuries.
That means seven 50s.
And his average is 80.88%.
And the first ball..
Veerender Singh used his wrist
beautifully to play this ball.
And the ball has crossed the
boundary line for four runs.
Dig it in.
- Yes.
Go in.
- There's.. There's a hit.
Yes. Yes..
Tough competition.
Gajanan Oinam wouldn't
like to lose..
..the national title at any cost.
And this is one opportunity
for Dheerender Singh..
..to secure a place
in the national team.
Both the players are trying
every possible way to win.
Corner.
Good. Good.
Hey, Rao. What are you
looking at so intently?.
Gajanan is going to win.
He's been the national champion
five times. He'll win for sure.
This boy from Rajaeshan will win.
What are you saying?
He's playing rough.
Jues get up close to him.
Remember that. Keep up your defence.
And you have to get up close.
Make sure you have to get close.
- Yes, sir.
Very good, very good.
Concentrate on foot work.
Be on your guard.
- Careful.
What's the score?
Listen to me carefully, Dheeru.
Phone? - Nothing else.
Look at me. Pay attention to me.
Listen to me carefully, Dheeru.
- Yes, sir.
Look, Dheeru, this game is
in the bag. No need to worry.
Don't worry, don'tworry.
Oh, yes? Are you sure?
Absolutely sure.
All right. Want to bet?
- Round two.
You'll pay for the coffee?
- Done.
And VeerenderSingh has
taken the aerial route..
..and has hit the ball
beyond the boundary line.
The ball has landed in
the stands for six runs.
Foul, foul.
- lt's a foul.  A clear foul.
Move. Stop.
This is your last warning.
Go to your corner.
Hey, foul. Foul.
Gajanan wants to
prove Dheerender Singh..
..that he has lot of potential
left in him. - Are you okay?.
Yes, Veeru.
And it's difficult for a new
fighter to last before him.
But Ronnie, Dheerender's
will power is quite strong.
Yes.
- Yes.
Very Good.
What?.
Do you want to continue?
So, Ronnie,what do you have
to say about this final kick?
Over.
And with this, the
new national champion..
..is Dheerender Singh
from Rajaeshan.
Yes. He's the hero.
You're right.
You..
- You. Coffee is on you.
Yes.
This is the 11th four by
Veerender Singh today.
Veerender Singh is in great form.
This takes his individual
score to 95.
l would like to remind you here..
..that Veerender Singh has
fallen prey to nervous 90s..
..seven times before this.
And there's no century
to his credit to date.
And thecrowd is at their seat.
Will he be able to
make a century today?
He was trying to attack
from the back.
lt's good that he got trumped.
But you shouldn't
have turned your back.
This is a bad habit.
This boy fought well.
What are you doing?
You fought very well.
- Thank you, sir.
My name is S.K. Rao.
l'm the coach for the
kickboxing federation team.
l know, sir. l know.
This is Mr. Suri, technical
director ofthe federation.
Hi.
- Nice to meet you, sir.
Very well played.
- Thank you, sir.
l'll wait for you in the canteen.
Meet me before you leave.
Okay, sir. Thanks.
- Okay?
l'll be waiting.
- Okay.
All the bees.
-All the best.
Have you filled in the names?
- Yes, sir.
Has the winner's been included?
Good. Thank you very much.
Shall we?
- Let's go.
Clean bowled.
With this, Veerender
Singh's beautiful knock..
..comes to an end.
Yes, tell me.
lfl fail to put an end
to your love story today..
..then you can call me any names.
Veeru.
The match was at its peak.
How could l've replied?
What happened?
Knockout in the second round.
Long live Prince Dheerender Singh.
What? Knockout?
- Of course.
Are we going to settle for any less?
Here, you talk to him.
Yes, junior.
Hey, Brother, great going.
At least today we deserve a drink.
Stupid. Should l call up mom?
Brother, it's not
like l drink every day.
And, neither do l
make a century every day.
You scored a century?
Yes. That too in 65 balls.
Hey, he made a century in 65 balls.
Hey, give me the phone.
- Couldn't you do it in 63?
You could've broken Sehwag's record.
Hey..
Couldn't you tell me earlier?
- Tell him to come here.
But l told you now, dear.
Okay, tell me. Where are we going?
Nowhere. l'll be late.
Got it? Let's keep it till tomorrow,
okay?
Stay back at our place today.
l swear l won't even
peep in your room.
Shameless. Okay, listen.
Come soon and pick us up.
Stupid, come here directly.
Don't go on a drinking binge
with your friends. - Excuse me.
Autograph please.
Yes, sure.
We're from Pakistan.
Lahore Medical College.
Welcome to lndia.
- You play really well.
Thank you.
But l'd definitely like
to add one more thing.
You also get out very well.
- What do you mean?
l mean, this is my first time..
.. l've seen someone reverse
sweep on a full toss ball.
You finally saw it today, right?
This is called anxiety syndrome.
Nervousness in common language.
Are you the
psychiatrist of the Pakistan team?
What if l am?
Then do one thing.
Cut Shoaib Akhtar's hair short .
His line and length will
improve by itself. Right?
Left an impression.
Yes, he did.
Pakistan High Commission,
New Delhi.
Hello?
Could l talk to
Mr. Sikander Hayaat?
Hello?
Why didn't you come
for the tournament?
Flight was delayed.
How is the new fellow?
Very good. He's from Rajasthan.
He won't be less than
Noor in an Asian championship.
l wish you'd seen him.
lf l get selected for the
Asian Championships..
Not ' if '.... You will be.
He's here. Hey.
- Veeru.
Oh, Brother.
You centurion..
Congratulations, Brother.
You, too, fool.
- Thank you, Brother.
How are you, Sister-in-law?
Hey, shameless.
- Hey, she's your sister-in-law.
When did l say she wasn't?
Come, l'll introduce you to someone.
Who is it, Brother?
- Our coach.
Sir,this is my younger
brother Veerender.
Yes, yes. Who doesn't know him?
He's a renowned
player ofthe Delhi team.
By the way, how's this?
Elder brother is into kickboxing.
And the younger brother is
playing cricket. How's that?
Sir, even l was a kick-
boxer till college. - Then?
Then l changed my mind.
- Why?.
Because l have a problem
with fighting as a sport.
lt's correct in a way.
As a cricketer, you'd be
staying in five-star hotels.
lf he'd been a kick boxer..
..he would've been lying
somewhere in the  stadium.
Mr. Rao always cribs on this issue.
Dheeru.
- Hey, Gajanan.
Good show.
- Thanks.
You played very well.
l guess my wish to be
coached by you..
..remained a wish.
The committee is yet to be formed.
Who knows what their
decision will be.
Then we'll see what's
done and what's not.
Now, what more is
left in this, sir?
By the way, people from
Rajasthan know how to fight.
l really feel sorry for him.
Never feel sorry for your opponent.
Got it? You played well,
that's why you won.
l agree with you 100%, sir.
Are you getting it?
- Yes.
Now, he'll go and fight in Delhi.
And, you can never win there.
l didn't get it, sir.
Actually, he's very close
to the cabinet minister.
He's right.
These days, sports are
played less in the ring..
..and more in the offices of the
ministers. Understand, mister?
Gajanan.
- Yes, sir?
How long do you intend to play?
You've held the national
title so many years.
lt's not about being
national champion, sir.
But the Asian
championship means alot to me.
Don't worry, don' tworry.
lt's not difficult.
Your selection is not an issue.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
- Welcome.
Yes, Gajanan.
- Yes?
Now, l want my
people in the federation.
Be prepared.
- Okay. Sure.
''Birds have flocked in
from beyond borders.''
''Birds have flocked to
the walls of the country.''
''lmbue me before
l fly away, my friend.''
''lmbue yourself in
my hues, my friend.''
''lmbue me in your hues.''
''lmbue me.''
''lmbue my every pore.''
''lmbu emy core.''
''Win over this heart, my friend.
Win over this heart.''
So, when the questions
rose in the senate..
..l asked who'll take these steps.
And even you have
a good government.
lf they don't take
the initiative..
Oh, lda. Sir ,this is
my daughter lda.
Hello.
- Hello.
Mr. Rao, the coach of
lndian kickboxing team.
Oh. So, him too?
He's not that kind of a coach.
Please come.
- Come.
Well, l'm a psychiatrist.
Maybe, l'll join father's team.
Psychiatrist? ln kickboxing?
Mr. Rao, you have
misunderstandings about Pakistan.
Pakistan is an independent
and an advanced country.
Why not, sir? The coach of the
team that downs eight pegs..
..in just half an hour..
.. must surely be very advanced.
Mr. Rao, you should see Mr. Sikander
with his team some time.
His preparations are no less
than a war. Right, Mr. Sikander?
Look, kickboxing is not possible
without aggression, Mr. Rao.
Anyway, this sport is not
much different from war.
But as usual,
l don't agree with uncle Sikander.
ls there any professor in the
Lahore Government College..
..whom you've agreed with ever?
Absolutely right.
Uncle, everyone has a right
to have an opinion.- Right.
By the way, even l have objections.
How can sports be war?
Because, victory comes
only with this spirit.
Absolutely. Victory is important.
But life doesn't end if at
all you face defeat, right?
lt can. And maybe,
this is the very reason..
..why such a big country of yours..
..could never bag even a
single gold medal yet.
Mr. Rao, sports has
been the dominant factor..
..in yesterday's treaty?.
Because only sports bring
our nations closer, doesn't it?
You're absolutely right, sir.
By the way, there's a poem
by one of our Urdu poets.
A phrase apt fo rthe coach.
- Go ahead.
''Both of our houses
are made of glass.''
''Worth pondering for both of us.''
''And still, we both
have a rock in our hand.''
''Worth pondering for both of us.''
- Wow.
Wow. Wow. Well said, Mr. Rao.
Even Gajanan is a capable player.
Maybe, sir. But not
fort his tournament.
l mean, can't it be possible
for someone out of the others..
..to report sick
at the last moment?
Even if that does happen, sir..
..there are many people
above Gajanan on the merit list.
Who are more capable than him.
We're spending so much money.
Then Delhi should get a
chance at representation.
Sir, this is sport.
People rise only on the
basis of their capabilities.
Capability is not the only
thing required to run sports.
You need money,too, Mr. Rao.
Now, all the hurdles..
..against the good will match
with Pakistan have been resolved.
l'll be meeting with
their high commission today..
..and decide on the dates.
lt'd be better if this
tournament of yours..
..happens after the
Asian tournament, sir.
Players are usually very tired.
Two-nil.
Less beer, more exercise, Suri.
What are you doing?
Look, Rao, the game
l play with the management..
..is tougher than this.
Really?
- Absolutely.
Look at yourself.
Oh, God. Why in
heaven's name is he calling?
Hello? Who's speaking?
Bhaskar Reddy.
Yes, sir.
- What's this, Mr. Rao?
How did this news reach the press..
..without my permission?
Sir, l thought since
l selected the team..
..l should be the one to inform.
Do you know it requires
the president's signature?
Yes, sir. That's why
l'm sending you the file.
Sign it.
Look, Mr. Rao.
l challenge you openly.
lf not today, then tomorrow..
..Gajanan will definitely
play for the national team.
Really? Let's see what happens, sir.
l'm a little busy
right now, sir. Yes, bye.
As if the team's your
lineage for you to select it.
So,was it the devil's call?
Yes.
Was he giving you threats?
He tried to, but l didn't take it.
ln such a coalition
government, Suri..
..a minister's threat
doesn't last for along time.
Everyone is out to
double cross the other.
Rao, tell me something.
Why do you lock horns with them?
These people run the nation.
Don't lock horns with them.
These people run the
nation and the media runs them.
That's why l always have
media on my right side..
..to make the
minister work dead straight.
So, what's the score?
2-0.
- l'll makeit 5-0. Come on.
Oh, really?
- Yes.
Challenge?
Wow.
- Mother, do you know?
What?.
- This Delhi player.
Gajanan?
- Yes?
He was the champion
for the last five years.
Really?
l knocked him out.
- Very good.
Leavemybag.
- What's this?
Tamarind.
Mom, tamarind.
- So?
Mom, why does she eat tamarind?
Hey, even normal people
eat tamarind. Understand?
Shut up, naughty.
Don't talk rubbish.
Mom, l doubt something is wrong.
You..
- Hey.
Shut your mouth.
Otherwise, l'll smack you.
God knows when you'll
stop babbling.
By the way,
what are your plans, dear?
Tiill when are you
planning to live like this?
You know people outside
have big mouths.- Mom.
Get them married, Mom.
They're so restless.
Dheerender. You tell me, Son.
Mom. Let this Asian
Championship get over.
Pick any date after
l return from Kuala Lumpur.
l just want everything to
be done in time. That's all.
Bytheway, l'm getting very late.
Veeru, get up quickly.
Change your clothes and drop me.
Stayback here tonight?
Naughty. What nonsense
are you talking about?
Mom, it's not like
this is the first time.
Right, Brother?
What is he talking about, Dheeru?
Mom, who are you listening to?
He's talking nonsense.
lt's a complete lie, Mom.
She's listening to me today.
- So, Brother?
Quick, she's getting late.
Mom, l'll leave. See you tomorrow.
Come on.
l'm very happy.
Just let your wife come.
l'll settle all the scores.
l won't let anyone touch my wife.
l'll hide her from the whole world.
Yes, yes, sure.
We'll buy a cage for her.
We'll lock her in. Okay?
That'll be better for her.
Hey, mister. Can you please
ask them to sit at the side?
They're tired. Why don't
you go from some other route?
My friend, that's
not where l'm headed.
And it's they who are
sitting in the middle.
Hey, don't you understand?
They're tired.
Go from some other lane.
Just because you're tired doesn't
mean you can occupy any lane.
Why are you racking our brains?
Just get lost.
Veeru, leave it.
We'll wait and then leave.
Why wait? We'll go right now.
What's your opinion regarding
national coach Mr. S.K. Rao?
He's a capable and
intelligent coach.
Our team will definitely
win under his guidance.
But your differences
with him are world famous?
Differences? These
differences are media creation.
lt's not the truth.
Did you send this reporter?
We all work together
for our country's honour.
You have to do these
things sometimes. You have to.
But questions have
always been raised..
..regarding a team's fair selection.
Any comments on that.
Fiive times national
champion Gajanan..
..didn't get a place
in the team this time.
What can be a better example
off air selection than this?
This was the cabinet
minister Mr. Kunjal Bhaskar Reddy.
Who's also the president of the
Kickboxing Federation of lndia.
You're always ready
with your tactics.
He's a shameless fellow.
How else can we manage him?
Yes, you're right in a way.
Today's second big sporting
news is related to cricket.
'Last evening, there
was a huge fight..'
'..between the famous Delhi
cricketer Veerender Singh..'
'..and those on a pilgrimage
near Chhatarpurtemple.'
'Veerender Singh is a
renowned cricketer.'
'And the rumour has it
that he'll soon be selected..'
'..for the national team.'
'This is Sumeet Vidrohi from
Chhatarpur temple for lndia TV.'
Veeru, let's go. Veeru.
lsn't he Dheeru's brother?
What?.
Yes. Looks like him.
Well, then why is
he playing cricket?
He should be
in the kickboxing team.
That's what he's doing
on the road.
Hurry up. Faster. Faster.
Jump.
Further. Come on.
No or, your ribs
could've easily been broken.
But they weren't, right?.
What if they had broken?
We'll worry about it
when it happens.
Look, your ribs have become swollen.
Your blood pressure
is running high.
lt happens to everyone
while fighting.
lt's been six hours since
the practice got over, Noor.
What are you getting at?
l'm just saying you don't
need to bring your arena home.
lt ends right there
in the ring, Noor.
Coach knows better.
lt's your life, not the coach's.
Look, ma'am. l came here
for my routine session..
..not to waste time.
l'll take your leave now.
71..
72..
73..
74.. 75..
76..
Don't stop!
That's it.
Now, hit on the chest.
Yes. Ready.
You can't talk like that about him.
Father, l'm just
giving you advice.
Are you listening to
what l'm saying? - Yes.
l think Noor needs
more counselling.
He was counselled by a
Dr. Hidayat.
But it was six months ago, Father.
Do you know that a person's
psyche undergoes changes every day?
l know that.
But Sikander won't agree to it.
And he's the team coach.
l'm concerned only
about Noor right now.
He's not playing
this game like a sport.
lda, this is
Sikander's responsibility.
And l'm sure he knows his
responsibilities as a coach.
lf only that were true.
What do you mean?
Sir, your call.
- But..
Hello? Yes, speaking. Go ahead.
All of you stay there.
l'm on my way.
lda, how was Noor's
health when you met him today?.
ls there anything serious?
There's swelling in the ribs.
lt'll be all right till tomorrow.
But Mr. Sikander
should be a little lenient.
The Championship is around the corner.
Saying that to him at this
time is like belling the cat.
His work is an obsession with him.
l don't have any
objection to his obsession.
But Noor is our best bet
for this championship.
Pakistan can't afford him failing.
lda. Did you speak
to Noor yesterday?
Yes. l just said..
Do you know you're just an intern?
Yes.
Then behave like an intern.
Don't try to
demoralise my player next time.
Please come, Mr. Mohammed.
Yes. Yes, sure.
You people please go ahead.
Yes? - What if Noor
gets sometime to relax?
He's the pillar of our team.
No. Nothing will happen to
his health. He's a tiger.
Please see this.
- Yes. Sure.
These are all the
players Noor will be facing.
But l'm eyeing this lndian player..
..who's much better than theirs.
But everyone will be there to win.
This is life for me, Mr. Mohammad.
l have to win this championship.
God willing.
l won't return from
Kuala Lumpur defeated.
l'll get few Malaysian girls
for you from Kuala Lumpur.
l'd rather prefer
someone from Pakistan.
You're still not over her?
There was definitely
something about her.
So,what else can l get?
Besides girls.
Veerender Singh will get
''what else'' for you. - Oh, really?
Just wait for three-four years.
And what are you going
to do in three-four years?
ln the next two-three years, the lndian
cricket team will be touring..
..England, Australia.
And now, even Pakistan.
And at these tournaments, girls will fall flat..
..on every six
prince Veerender Singh hits.
How many?.
- Look,who's talking. Understood?
Just wait and watch.
Yes, l am. And, l understand, too.
- Wait.
Mother's right here.
Should l tell her?
You'll put me in a fix.
And this, to protect
you from a bad omen.
What are you doing, Mom?
l'm not a child.
You'll always be for me.
Let's go, Neela.
Bye, Mom.
- Bless you.
Junior.
- See you, Brother.
No gallivanting. And
do take care of mom.
Now, why..
- lfy ou return after 7 o'clock..
..l'll come back and bash you up.
Look, Mother.
- Don't.
He's scolding me
even while leaving.
Let's go.
Bye.
- Hey, bye.
Take care of yourself. Bye, Mom.
Bye.
Bye, Mom.
- Bye.
Bye, Veeru.
Bye.
Behave respectfully with Sikander.
He's a very experienced person.
Father, did l complain till now?
But still. Do remember
what l've said.
''So, the skies can be embraced.''
''Fly, seeking new directions.''
''Yes, this group will reach
for the skies and beyond.''
''When they accomplish the task..''
''..their victory will be
etched in golden letters.''
''Listen carefully, move your feet.''
- By God's grace..
..this is not the first
time l'm playing in Malaysia.
l've played many tournaments here..
..and hope this tournament
also turns out well for us.
''Listen carefully,
move your feet.''
''Now, the blood flows
redder than ever before..''
''..pounding through the veins.''
''May every drop of
blood serve the country.''
''lt will be
immortalised for eons to come.''
So, Neela, when is the
wedding planned for?
Well, mom was saying as soon
as we return from Malaysia..
Oh, then we must
apologise to your mom..
..as it will take some
days at least in Malaysia!
Rao is a tyrant, but don't worry.
l'll try to get him to
call it for the day.
How was your practice?
- Verynice.
Don't watch TV too much.
You have to wake up early
in the morning.. - Okay.
Hey, Rao, tomorrow
is the tournament.
Call it a day today at least.
''Listen carefully, move your feet'.''
''We have let our kites fly..''
''..loosening these
rings from our hands..''
''..letting them fly free, sky high.''
''lf you wish, you can see..''
''..the kites gliding
and cutting through..''
''..the clouds.''
''Uninterrupted, this roadwill
go forth to the destination.''
''Yes, all those who
continue this journey..''
''..will have their names
etched in golden letters.''
''Listen carefully,
move your feet'.''
''When they accomplish the task..''
''..their victory will be
etched in golden letters.''
''Listen carefully,
move your feet.''
Ladies and gentlemen,
a very warm welcome to..
..the inaugural day ofthe 14th
Asian kick Boxing championships.
Welcome one and all.. the players,
the delegates and the spectators.
''Listen carefully,
move your feet'.''
l declare the 14th Asian
Kickboxing Championship open.
Here is the first fight round of
the bout between Nusrat Khurram..
..of lndonesia and
Kim Sui of South Korea.
Yes, Kim Sui the pint-sized boxer
hasn't given any chances to Khurram.
Khurram, though an experienced
player, is lagging behind.
That was a round kick,
and Khurram is down!
1. 2. 3.
4. 5. 6. 7.
8. 9. 10!
The winner is South Korea.
The next fight is between Chang Li
of China and Ozu Hokarito of Japan.
And now the bout is between China..
..and Japan. Chang Li of China
and Ozu Hokarito of Japan.
Both the players have an
exemplary pedigree in martial arts.
Welcome to the grand finale of the
14th Asian Kickboxing Championship..
..and the
contestants are two arch rivals.
Dheerender Singh from lndia
and Noor Mohammad from Pakistan.
Welcometo the grand finale of the
14th Asian Kickboxing Championship.
Two arch rivals contestants
Dheerender Singh from lndia..
..and Noor Mohammad from Pakistan.
l've seen Noor earlier. He has
put on a bit of weight since then.
Look, Pakistan's
honour is in your hands now.
ln the beginning, he
showed a lot of aggression..
..out of over-confidence. Got it?
This is the fight that you can get.
Players, come inside the ring.
Be careful.
Don't loose Concentration.
Don't get excited.
All the best!
Come on, players.
No elbow attack, no knee attack
and don't hit below the belt.
Okay.
Round one. Start.
Okay, get ready and fight.
Very good. Just like that.
Stop! Go! Go!
Dheeru, getup!
- Get up!
Come on! Come on!
You can do it. Come on.
1. 2. 3.
You want to fight?
Okay. Start!
Hey, what is he doing? He's playing
a foul! - What's he doing?
Go to the corner.
- That's the way.
Corner.
You're doing good. Very good,
very good, very good. Keep it up.
Let me see what happened.
lt's nothing. Perfectly fine.
Sir, he's playing foul.
lt doesn't matter. Just take care.
Take care oft he blocking. lf he
blocks the punch, then kick him.
lf he blocks the kick,
then punch. Got it?
Just play your natural game.
Don't worry. Play close. Close!
Use your body weight, okay?
Round two. Start.
Start.
Come on!
Good! Now, go!
Move, move, move.
Hit him!
- Hit him hard, hit him hard.
Steady. Steady!
Punch him! Punch him!
Leave.
- Yes!
Yes, very good.
- 1. 2. 3.
Get up! Get up!
6. 7.
You want to fight?
Come on, Noor! Getup!
Get up! Comeon.
You want to fight?
Start!
Stop!
Very good, very good.
Go to the corner.
How are you playing?
What are you doing?
You're doing well!
Come on, come on!
Give him the towel!
What are you doing?
Why can't you hit him?
He's very solid, sir.
His kick has tremendous power.
Look, don't worry about his kick.
The game is in our hands.
He has more points,
so he will waste time.
Don't give him a chance to do that.
lf he tries to block,
hit him below the waist.
Jues a defence and a right kick!
Yes, sir.
-And a strong right hook.
l'll knock him out sir.
- Absolutely.
Front kick, right hook.
Absolutely, absolutely.
- l'll finish this off, sir.
Round three. Start
Our prestige is at stake.
We have to win. Getup!
Players, ready?
Start!
Come on, come on! Come on! Faster!
Yes!
He's blocking! He's blocking!
Keep going!
Well done! Well done!
A hit for thatwretch!
Look back! Look back.
Turn around!
Are you okay?
Are you fine?
Dheeru? Dheeru.. look at me.
Look at me!
Move aside! Move aside!
Dheeru, what happened? Dheeru?
lndian kickboxer Dheerender
Singh passed away at the..
..14th Asian Kickboxing
Championship at Kuala Lumpur.
The government of lndia has
declared it a state funeral.
Down with them! Down with Pakistan!
What is this? What is this?
lt's a public outcry, sir.
When there's such a huge injustice..
..people are bound
to be outraged, sir.
People like you don't understand..
..how this will affect our
relations with Pakistan.
Sir, you're the
chairman of this federation.
Haven't you considered..
..how Dheerender Singh's
death has affected his family?
We have to answer to lslamabad..
..whether the goodwill
match will be taking place or not.
Do we need to answer them
or get an answer from them?
We can't blame anyone..
..until the Malaysian
committee's report is released.
Sir, our boy is no more.
Now what is the use of the report?
Sir, l agree it's good to
improve relations with any country.
But that doesn't mean we
succumb to absolute injustice.
Don't worry about
government policies, Mr. Rao.
Actually, even you
should be held answerable.
Definitely, sir. But
when you get time from..
..all the formalities of sending
reports, questioning and answering..
..then do realise the man who
died was representing lndia.
The meeting is over.
Thank you very much.
Yes, Father.
lda, how is the situation there?
What would you expect, Father?
l have no words to say.
Just take care of yourself.
How long do you intend to stay?
For a few more days.
Dear, keep your emotions
under control. No interviews.
lt might create trouble here.
l know, Father. Our
relations are improving.
Both the countries
want the same thing.
''Dear one.. dear one..''
''Happiness has left with you.''
''The paths seem deserted.''
''The courtyard lies
empty before me.''
''And my heart is desolate.''
''Dear one.. dear one..''
''Happiness has left with you.''
''The pleasant breeze
passed me by.''
''The monsoon showers went by..''
''..and the kites and
boats of the season..''
''..no longer matter without you.''
''The stars serve as a blanket,
but even thes ky can't sleep.''
''And dreams take flight.''
''Dear one.. dear one..''
''Happiness has left with you.''
We welcome the spectators
in this lrani Trophy match..
..being played between Ranji
Trophy Champion Uttar Pradesh..
..and Rees of lndia at
Fiirozshah Kotla stadium.
We welcome the spectators
to this match.
After this series of matches..
..the winning team will tour
Australia and New Zealand.
Winning today's match is
crucial for every player. - Out!
Appeal.. And he is out..
The first
breakthrough for Uttar Pradesh.
The next batsman for Rees
of lndia is Veerender Singh.
Veerender Singh has been
exceptional in this season.
Veerender Singh is
playing on his homeground..
..in front of his home crowd..
..and that is certain to help him.
This is a huge chance
for Veerender Singh.
And he is a very aggressive player.
His striking rate is 90.68.
Little brother!
Clean bowled! Veerender Singh..
..is clean bowled off
the very first ball!
Very good bowling from Uttar Pradesh,
and it's a big achievement..
And the next batsman from the
rest of lndia is Nitin Ojha.
Long live Kunjal Bhaskar Reddy!
Pleased to hear that.
Our youth should unite and
become an inspiration to others.
Long live Kunjal Bhaskar Reddy!
What do you mean,
''it's 'their' country''?
Don't they abide by
international law?
Don't they respect
a sportsman's spirit?
lt's their decision, Mr. Rao.
They say the referee
failed to raise his finger.
My player has died.
Do you get that?
And he hasn't died due to some
referee's not raising the finger.
The person who is responsible..
..for his death is moving
around free and proud.
What should l do? l was helpless.
Lousy rogues!
You're more talked about
in Pakistan these days..
..than even the prime minister,
Mr. Sikander.
This accomplishment's credit
goes wholly to my boy Noor.
You're right.
You're my tiger.Always
fight fearlessly like this.
This time too, l will accept
nothing less than in Kuala Lumpur.
And the world will
watch how Pakistan's hero..
..gets his deserved
place in the latest match.
Godwilling!
So they declared it an accident.
Yes.
And what about your Pakistan?
Our report corroborates theirs.
Noor may get a clean chit.
So, my brother's
death has become a joke.
The media got spicy content and..
..politicians got a
chance to blame each other.
And amidst all this..
..a happy family..
When are you leaving?
l haven't yet decided.
You've been a great support.
l won't be able to forget you.
lt's so difficult to
predict what form death..
..and humanity might take
and come in front of you.
l ask you for forgiveness on
behalf of all ofPakistan.
On behalf of the government
of lndia..
..l am honoured to announce
the resumption of the..
..Kickboxing Goodwill Championship
between lndia and Pakistan..
..to be held in Lahore
in a few days.
We have taken the decision
in order to promote peace..
..love and harmony
between the two nations.
Dheerender Singh's sudden death..
..at the Asian Championship
was given a clean chit.
What does the government
have to say about that?
lt's still very soon to
pass a comment on that..
..but justice will not be denied.
lf that is so,
then why did you decide..
..that the Goodwill
Championship be held so soon?
Well, there's a famous saying.
lt's never too late..
l can't sum up courageto ask you..
..to come to Pakistan some day.
Neela, my country and
my people are not bad.
Do you even know what
you're talking about?
This is kickboxing.
lt's a specialised sport.
What's with you?
No, sir. You will
make me a kick boxer.
l've had the skills since childhood.
My friend, there are
more people above me..
..in the federation authority.
l'm answerable to them.
lt's not a walk in the park.
l've read the federation
rules, sir.
National coach and
technical director..
..can give a chance to a fresh
candidate at their discretion.
Provided, there's more than a
month's time for the tournament.
There is such a rule
in the rule book.
But it's never been implemented.
Understand?
Many things happen for
the first time, sir.
My brother's death is
one such thing.
Look, you have such a good and
a well-set career in cricket.
Why do you want to
forsake that for the ring?
l just want to
fulfil my brother's dream.
l want to fight. Just like him.
lt's not that simple.
lt's not easy either.
Hey, Bhagyaram,what
are you all doing?
Am l supposed to check this
ball and the rubber density?.
Then, what are all of you here for?
Nothing is easy, sir.
lt has to be made easy.
Give me some time. Let me think.
You sure can think about it, sir.
l juts want to say
that you won't regret it.
Look, Rao, don't
even think about it
l'm telling you.
Kunjal will kill you.
l'm the coach of
lndia's kick boxing team..
..not your Kunjal's slave. Got it?
But what's the need? This
is just a good will match.
Good will match? Do you
know what goodwill means?
To walk with pride with
humiliation written on our face?
ls that what goodwill means?
l mean, he's a cricketer, right?
Not a kick boxer.
Gajanan is far better.
And even you know that.
Oh, okay, okay.
Now, you'll teach me who's
a better kick boxer, right?.
Look, Rao.. - Suri, even you
were a sportsman once, right?
What happened to you?
Look.. - Why are you so
paranoid about Kunjal?
Don't tell me all this, get it?
l don't know
why are you so difficult?
Why are you putting your
career at stake, along with mine?
Nothing will happen to your career.
l'll be responsible
for whatever l'm doing.
Fine.
- All alone.
So, it's your responsibility.
This is your
decision and responsibility?.
Yes. My responsibility.
You'll be accountable for
whatever happens. - Yes, l will.
Same lousy story.
All right. Treat me to a coffee.
Do you people think this is a joke?
Gajanan has been finalised.
Sir, he's still a candidate.
Just like Veerender is.
What? A cricketer
will fight in kickboxing?
And in the national team?
That'll be proven
in this match, sir.
What do you say, Suri?
Look, sir, what l'm saying is..
..that if Gajanan wins,
he'd be in thet eam anyway, right?
Okay. Bye.
Bye, sir
Happy?
Veeru.
Why are you doing all this?
Withdraw your name.
l don't hav eany courage left.
Nobody did anything, Mom.
l met everyone.
Everyone wants to brush
it off as an accident..
..and forget my brother.
lt's all over. For them,
as well as for us.
Can you believe that
he's not alive anymore?
He has been killed in
the name of victory.
lf this is the truth,
then we have to believe it.
l won't be able to accept it, Mom.
Because l see a burning
pyre in these eyes every day.
But my Dheeru won't come back.
Look, l've tried my best.
But l doubt if Kunjal
will give in so easily.
He's a minister after all.
Gajanan? You should've
been in the selection hall.
What are you doing here?
Sir, after proving
myself for so many years..
..l don't see the need to
compete with a cricketer.
That too, just
for selection's sake?
What do you mean?
- l've changed my mind, sir.
What are you doing?
You're a sportsman.
This is an opportunity for
you as well as for Veerender.
lf Veerender has the guts and
talent, he'll prove himself.
But you're losing out
on a good opportunity.
Are you getting what l'm saying?
Yes. Okay, sir.
'Hey, Veeru.'
''No one has been able to outdo me.''
''The horse Chetak
belonged to Rana Pratap.''
''Who never backed off
from a battlefield.''
''That horse Chetak
belonged to Rana Pratap.''
''When Chetak was spurred..''
''..every foe was
left biting thedust.''
''He shared an
unbreakable bond with Rana.''
''He was a warrior,
a Rajput caste.''
''He was a warrior, a Rajput.''
So, what is to be done, sir?
Let's see.
Bye, sir.
What does the minister say now?
Shall l order coffee, Mr. Rao?
Mr. Singhania, this should be
the most explosive news tomorrow.
You have no idea how
big this story is.
Juts read it tomorrow.
You got it on the
internet as well, Mr. Rao.
This is front-page news.
Even Kunjal's
messiahs can't do anything.
You have to do these things,
dear. You have to.
You might be fighting
againts Noor Mohammed.
The Noor Mohammad your
brother died while fighting with.
l know.
Any comment on that?
Look, it was an accident.
Accidents have been a part of sport.
And they'll continue to be.
'Veerender Singh has been
included in the lndian team..'
'..that's arriving here
for the goodwill tournament.'
'Veerender Singh is the
brother of theperson..'
'..who died whilefighting
Pakistan's Noor Mohammad.'
'Only Veerender
Singh knows the motive..'
'..with which he's come to Lahore.'
'The motive can be victory,
or to avenge..'
'..a brother's defeat, or
you can say, his death.'
Yes, l understand you.
But l'm sorry..
..l completely disagree with you.
l believe..
..that this is not an appropriate
time for the tournament.
Look, if anything happens..
..Pakistan will be answerable
to the whole world.
Sir, everyone knows why
Veerender is coming to Pakistan..
..except for politicians like us.
So, l'm repeating myself again.
We've been given one
opportunity to prove..
..how seriously committed we are..
..regarding the
restoration of peace with lndia.
Don't let it go to waste.
We should leave something
good for our next generation.
Please. Think it over.
Before it's too late. Thank you.
This tournament was my dream.
l had to give everything l had..
..to get my own
government consent to this.
And today, l'm being
explained its significance.
Father.
- Yes?
Can't anything be done now?
There is.
lf any one of them withdraws.
Yes.
Oh. Ms. lda.
- Hello.
How come you're here?
Anyway, you've been
recommended in abundance.
lf God wills, you'll be
permanent by the end of this year.
What's this?
Resignation letter.
This is not the place to resign.
Even great people
have resigned here..
..Mr. Sikander Hayaat.
What's the meaning of this?
That's the problem.
One who should know the meaning..
..is standing here
like a spectator.
Noor, if you think by
playing this match..
..you're adding another
feather to Pakistan's cap..
..then it's your
huge misunderstanding.
Don't you dare talk to him
like this. He's my player.
And don't you dare talk
to me in this way, Uncle.
l'm no more your employee.
Look, Noor..
..if you still want
to save your own..
..and this country's
conscience from this blot..
..then you should
withdraw from this match.
Report yourself sick.
Get your hands broken,
or your legs. Do anything.
l said stop it and get away
from here. Let's go, Noor.
You've ruined a family.
Remember, you'll be cursed
in the name of humanity.
Jues get away from here.
You're a very petty player, Noor.
Just fear Him. No one's a
superior coach than Him.
What are you brooding over?
Don't?
Stop thinking.
You shouldn't think at all.
You just have to fight.
Sir.. Sir, please. Please.
Minieser is coming.
Ask the minister.
Sir, one question.
- Ask the minister.
Would you please, sir..
- Sir.. Sir..- Ask the minister.
Sir, please.
- Ask the minister.
Sir. Sir. Just a short question.
- Come on.
Best of luck,
Mr. Rao. Return as winners.
You've already put a noose
of defeat around my neck.
He's not incapable.And it was
his dream to play in your team.
Then you should also think
about the person you dropped.
No, no. He wasn't dropped.
He's injured. lnjured.
That means you've already decided.
Mr. Rao, your heart knows
that Gajanan is better than him.
l'm not commenting
about Veerender Singh.
Gajanan, comehere.
Please take care of him, Mr. Rao.
You're always there for that,
right, sir.- Yes, yes.
Thank you.
Best ofluck, dear.
- Thank you, sir. Thank you.
l'll leave kickboxing forever..
..if l don't play up
to your expectations.
l won't let you down.
Just allow me to be
a part of the team.
Let's do our best. Come on.
The lndian kick boxing team,
along with the group of delegates..
..arrived today at Lahore airport..
..for the goodwill
kickboxing match..
..to be held at Lahore
in the next few days.
Special correspondent Mr. Jade..
..reporting live
from Lahore airport.
With the arrival of the
lndian kick boxing team..
..the excitement among the
Pakistan people is already rising.
So,what do the officials
have to say about this issue?
Well, the things are still not
very clear regarding the issue.
Also, there had been
a little furore..
..when the brother ofthe
deceased player Veerender Singh..
..joined the team.
Move, mister. Move, move.
Let us through.
Mr. Veerender Singh, you'll
be fighting Noor Mohammed.
ls it a mere coincidence?
Do you think you didn't get
justice in the Kuala Lumpur case?
Are you in Pakistan to
avenge your brother's death?
Look, this is a goodwill
match and they're our guests.
At least think about the
dignity of our country.
Mr. Rao, the rumours
are doing the rounds..
..that you can even bring
hockey and Kabaddi players..
..in kickboxing.
Make way. Make way.
No comments.
- Let them through.
lt is now a matter of a few days..
..that will determine the
fate of the two countries..
..and the noble
endeavours towards the peace process.
l called you many times.
l even spokewith Neela. But..
you never replied.
l was about to come here myself.
So, did you come and meet me?
l was practicing.
Practice doesn't go on
for 24hours, Veeru?
You'll feel better if you tell me.
l don't have anything to tell.
You do. What's going to
happen in tomorrow's match?
What happens in a match, lda?
You won't be doing what
usually happens, right?
Only l know what l'm going to do.
Then, why can't l know about it?
Can we talk after tomorrow?
Why shouldn't we talk
about tomorrow?
Just leave me alone.
You've changed, Veeru.
lt's better this way, isn't it?
You take care of your own life.
But my life is not
separate from yours.
Just get out of my life.
You can't bring
Dheerender back by killing Noor.
He was my brother.
- He meant a lot to many.
Fire of revenge burns not just
in one house but the whole city.
l don't care about
the house or thecity.
You have to, Veeru. You have to.
These issues don't ever end.
Tomorrow, someone
will come to kill you.
More sobs will be heard.
Then, l'll cry. Like Neela.
And now let us take you to Pakistan
where, a little while from now..
..the Quaid-e-Azam Goodwill
Kickboxing Tournament..
..will be commencing in
Lahore's Gaddafi stadium.
This tournament was
started at the instance..
..of the Pakistani representatives..
..who had very recently
come to lndia on a tour.
This tournament has been a topic
of discussion for many reasons.
Pakistan will win!
From Gaddafi Stadium,
l, Deepak Sharma..
..with my fellow
commentator Asiflqbal..
..welcome all the officials,
guests and competitors..
..to theQuaid-e-Azam
Kickboxing Goodwill Tournament.
Today is a historic day as this
match is part of the ongoing effort..
..to improve the relationship
between the two countries.
Hello.
- Hello.
Do you think that you'll be
victorious here in Lahore?
Are you still thinking
about winning and losing?
Let me explain the
rules and regulations..
..to be followed in the tournament.
The two teams will be
playing five matches.
Whichever team gets more
wins and more points..
..will be entitled to lift..
..the trophy of this
Quaid-e-Azam tournament.
Let him get tired.
Come on. Let's go.
All the best, Jasbir.
Best of luck, Qasim.
The treatment of tuberculosis
is not tomorrow but today.
And with this,
the tournament is about to start.
The first match is between..
..Pakistan's Qasim Ali
and lndia's Jasbir Singh.
Qasim Ali takes on Jasbir
Singh in an aggressive manner.
1. 2. 3.
- Yes!
And Pakistan gets its first win.
Very good. Very good, my boy.
You're next.
- Yes, sir. Okay, sir.
The second match is
between lndia's C. Subramanium..
..and Pakistan's lqbal Khan.
lqbal Khan leads with his
strong defence.A tough fight..
Stop.
- Well done.
C. Subramanium has been hit
below the belt by lqbal Khan.
lt's foul, sir!
This is Pakistan's
second consecutive win.
This is the second
successive loss for lndia..
..and Pakistan is
leading by two matches.
lqbal, very good! Very well done.
And here begins the third match..
..and if Pakistan manages
to win this bout as well..
..team lndia will have to go back
empty-handed with a crushing defeat.
No!
No! Darn it!
Well done!
Stop! Stop! Go to your corners.
lt should be 6/7..
What are the judges doing?
Both sides are tense. Everyone
seems to be holding their breath.
Winner!
Yes!
- Yes!
And Almino Pereira
has won the match.
And now with this, lndia gets its
first victory in this Championship.
With Almino Pereira's win,
lndia is back into the tournament.
Rejoicing among the lndians..
And now the points are
lndia 9 and Pakistan 15.
But lndia is still in the
more difficult position.
The fourth round will be
between Gajanan Oinam of lndia..
..and Sohail Raza of Pakiesan.
Raza, what..
Go to your corner.
- Get up!
So far,this fight between
Gajanan Oinam and Sohail Raza..
..has proved to be the..
..most interesting
match of this tournament..
..and both the teams are expecting
their players to win this match.
Are you okay? Start!
Raza, don't lose this opportunity.
That's the way, Gajanan. Good.
Good, very good.
Sponge him. We've
already won two fights.
lf you win the third one,
we'll win the tournament.
Keep the same pace.
You can knock him out.
His left hand is weak.
Keep your focus on that.
l know you can do it. Got it?
Only your victory can bring
us back in this tournament.
You got that? Come on, do it.
Come on, get ready. Move.
Keep it up. Come on, come on!
Gajanan is trying his level
bees to win this match for lndia.
lf lndia wants to
win this tournament..
..then they have to win
both the matches for sure.
Push him away.
Stop! Stop!
Come on!
Yes!
Go back.
Come on, he's hurt!
Gajanan Oinam has
been seriously injured..
..and is being
taken out of the ring.
The fight was still ongoing
and Gajanan was leading so far.
lt's okay, Gajanan.
Only 30 seconds remain
for the match to get over..
..and if Gajanan
doesn't enter the ring soon..
..he'll be considered knocked-out..
..and Pakistan will
win this tournament.
You have two minutes to
decide whether to continue or not.
All right, all right.
His shoulder has been
dislocated and is very serious.
Sir, no.
- He must be taken to the hospital.
Sir, please don't withdraw
from the match! Sir.. no, sir!
Look at your shoulder.
- Sir.. no, sir!
Now if l withdraw..
..winning on Pakistan's
soil will remain a dream.
Please, sir. l won't
let you down, l'll do it.
lt's over, Gajanan.
- No! No, sir!
He can't come back now.
Now what should this be called?
lnnocence or passion?
To play for your country
is the greatest of emotions.
Gajanan is back in the ring
despite being injured.- Start!
Yes! Yes!
- No! - Yes! Yes!
Wait! 1. 2. 3. 4.
Yes! You've done it!
- 6. 7. 8.
9. 10. Over!
Gajanan has won.
lt's a very big victory for lndia.
After winning two matches each..
..both Pakistan and
lndia are in equal position.
l'm proud of you, my boy!
You're a young tiger! A tiger!
You should have hit
him on the shoulder.
Why didn't you just
hit him on theshoulder?
You were playing slow.
What else do you expect?
And now, all eyes are
set on the fifth match.
Veeru, remember he
isn't just Noor Mohammed.
He's just your opponent.
But how can l forget
that he's not just..
..an opponent, sir?
He's also Noor Mohammed.
Noor, you know the
reason why he has come here.
But only you must win.
Red corner, blue corner.. start!
That.. This is foul!
Don't do that!
Stop! Stop! Go back.
Come on, Veeru! Come on!
Are you okay?
Ready?. Start!
Stop! Stop! Leave him!
Go back! Go back.
Are you all right?
Get up, get up. Noor.
Despite several
warnings from the referee..
..Veerender Singh is
unable to control his anger.
lf he persists, then
points may be deducted.
Stop! Stop!
That fool will cos tus points!
Leave him! Leave him! Stop!
You're playing perfectly.
Take advantage of his anger.
What are you doing? He doesn't
need to even try for a win.
You're making your team lose.
Make him play foul.
He has already received a warning.
Next time, his
points will be deducted.
lf you keep making fouls,
you'll soon be disqualified.
Come on now.
He's doing well. He's doing well.
Get up! Get up!
Yes! Come on!
No! No!
Stop! Stop! Go to your corners! Go!
You wretch!
Leave him. Listen to me. Leave him..
Both of you will be disqualified!
Leave him!
Please stop them. Somebody..
You wretch!
You rogue!
What are you doing?
He was punching under the belt.
l also gave him a
Lahore punch. That wretch!
You're not going to do anything.
Let him do it.
Wipe the blood.. and cover
the eyes. Apply some Vaseline.
Our goal is just winning.
Let him make a mistake.
We'll win just like that.
Go. Come on.
l had assumed that
there is a difference..
..between my player
and a player like Noor.
But if you have
a different opinion..
..then l have
nothing else to tell you.
This is the last and the
final warning for you.
Next time, you will be disqualified.
Start!
Yes!
1. 2. 3. 4. 5..
Come on!
Are you okay?
Start!
That's it. Keep it up, Noor.
Yes! Very good!
1. 2. 3. 4. 5.
You want to continue? Okay. Start!
'Hey, little brother..'
'..it's sport.'
'Not war.'
Sir,we've won!
Veeru, what you've won
today is far greater..
..than any fight,
medal or tournament.
Today, you've
conquered everyone's hearts.
l'm proud of you.
l'm very proud of you.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the grand finale of the
Quaid-e-Azam Kickboxing Tournament..
..which has been a high-voltage
spectacular show of..
..grit and conviction.
And now, l call upon
His Excellency..
.. the Honourable
Minister of Interior..
..Mr. Shahnawaz Qureshi is
to award the medals.
And the medal goes to Qasim Ali..
Thank you very much.
lqbal Khan.
Thank you, sir.
Masoom Malik.
Sohail Raza.
And Noor Mohammad.
Thank you, sir.
Until now, l've been
fighting for victory..
..because l have been trained
to think that my victory..
..was entwined with
my country's victory.
But today, l've realised
that a nation's victory..
..is the victory
that you've won today.
No victory or loss can
be more important than..
..the life of a human being.
Your brother was not
only a great sportsman..
..but also a fine human being.
Today, l truly regret his demise.
l'm sorry.
Mr. Rao, you've truly won  over Lahore.
Mr. Sinha..
..we've always created barriers
between Lahore and Amritsar.
But today, l can see those
barriers tumbling down.
This is a historic moment.
What else can we say of it?