Don't worry.
What, you don't trust me?
I've got the money.
Let's see the stuff.
Let's see
the money.
Money.
This is sugar.
No shit.
Yeah, no shit.
And this is gasoline.
That's right, man.
It's gasoline.
Yeah, come on.
Torch him, man.
No.
Mrs. Gaultier, I'm sorry this
had to happen to your family.
We've done everything
that can be done.
In cases like this it is very difficult
to make any kind of prediction,
so for the next couple of months
it's going to be touch and go.
Mrs. Gaultier...
The insurance has expired,
I know.
Does he have any
other relatives,
anyone else that
could possibly help?
No. Come on, Nicole.
Let's go.
Lyon. Lyon.
Lyon? Lyon!
Lyon!
Hi, Lyon.
I bet you're wondering what's in the
old goodie sack for you today, huh?
Let's have a look.
There we go.
Legionnaire Lyon Gaultier.
Yes.
It's very nice.
No interest, eh?
Okay, back she goes.
Yeah, Gaultier,
that's me.
This one's been out
in the sun too long.
She said she tried to call me
two weeks ago. Nobody told me.
Why?
This is the Foreign Legion,
Gaultier, not Club Med.
We're talking
about my brother.
He could be dead by now.
And we could be at war with
the bloody wogs tomorrow.
I need your ass here. Your
brother is not my problem.
Or yours anymore.
You gave up your family
when you joined the Legion.
I never gave up my family.
Never.
Legionnaire, I don't have
time for this Scheiße.
I need to see my brother.
You need what
I tell you you need.
And right now, I think you
need two weeks' hard labor.
Starting tomorrow.
You want something else
to cry about legionnaire?
We can arrange it.
You only have six months left
in the Legion, Gaultier.
Don't make it six years.
You're a real asshole.
Is there
a problem, sir?
No, no, no, no, no.
No problem.
Desert fever, this is your real problem.
Too many weeks
in the hot sun.
Shall we try
sweatbox, sir?
Yes, this might help.
Just until his
fever breaks.
Cover your head,
Legionnaire.
Move.
Your belt.
Come on.
Move!
Your hotel room
is ready. Let's go.
Come on.
Okay.
Get me a fucking jeep!
There is no sign
of him, sir.
He'll never make it.
If the wogs don't
kill him, then the desert will.
Just in case, head down to the
docks first thing in the morning.
The ocean's his only
way out of the country.
Moustafa,
go this way.
Hey!
Get your ass back down below!
Get down to those
boiler rooms now!
Okay, okay.
This ain't no pleasure
cruise. Move your ass!
The letter was
from his sister-in-law.
We are fortunate.
Our intelligence section makes a habit
of recording the return addresses.
We'll contact the Americans and ask
them to keep her under surveillance.
Inspector,
this man is a deserter,
a traitor to France
and a goddamn terrorist.
Adjutant, all I can do
is transmit the word.
If the Los Angeles cops
aren't too busy busting dope dealers,
gang rapists and serial killers
maybe they will have time
to bring the asshole in.
And if they don't,
tough shit.
If they do not,
maybe I can help.
You stay off the top deck,
First Mate's orders.
You were told not to come up.
Am I right?
Yeah.
And you told me that ship's
gonna go to Los Angeles.
What difference
does it make?
You ain't got no green card,
you ain't got no visa.
You ain't getting off this
boat anywhere, Frenchie.
So get your ass below
before somebody reports you, a
deserter, stowed away on their ship.
I pay for the trip.
I'm being generous Frenchie.
You keep stocking my boilers or you'll
be breaking rocks in the hot sun.
Now, what's it gonna be?
It's going to be simple.
Hey, maybe we make a deal.
You've been so generous to me.
Huh?
America.
Los Angeles Information.
Please deposit $2.40.
No, no.
It's my sister-in-law.
She's waiting for me,
Helene Gaultier.
Honey, I don't care if she's
the mayor's sister-in-law.
If I don't hear the coins,
this is the end of the
conversation, you got it?
Hey! Come on,
come on!
Come on,
get in there.
Come on.
Come on, get up.
What are
you doing?
Come on.
Yeah. Come on, man.
Come on,
God damn it.
I want my money, man!
Hey, hey, all right.
The man won.
You want another fight? You sure
you don't want another fight, mother?
Look at that, man,
you can win.
Come on, get your money. Now
I ain't got all goddamn day.
I want my money.
Shut up. Shut up. Now who's
gonna fight the next fight?
Look here. Who's gonna
fight the next goddamn fight?
Do we even have a next fight? God
damn it, do we have a next fight?
Come on, man,
do we have a next fight?
All right, all right. Hey, hey. Look
here. We got a visitor, all right.
Who might you be,
my man?
Lyon. Lyon.
What?
Lyon.
What the fuck is Lyon?
Lion. You're the Lion. The
Lion. MAN: All right. Hey!
All right.
All right, all right. Who
wants to take on the Lion?
Who wants to
take on the Lion?
Somebody's got
to take on the damn Lion.
Hey, that's my man now.
Yeah, we got us
a fight now, baby.
Wrestle him.
Yeah! Let's get ready
for this one.
Bets down.
Put your bets down.
Put my money down.
Who are you taking?
Come on, come on.
Ain't nobody gonna
bet on the Lion?
Bets. That's it. Bets over, bets
over, bets over. All right. Bets over.
All right.
Look here.
You sure you want
to do this, my man?
I'm the only one betting on
you. Don't let me down, now.
This is ours, my man,
if you can beat this dude.
It's going right here.
Trust me, man.
Can you beat him?
Kick his lion ass.
All right.
It's on. It's on.
Take him.
It's on. Yeah!
Come on. Come on.
Yeah! Let's go!
Yeah, that's good, man. Good.
That's right. That's it,
that's it. Right there.
No, man.
Come on.
I don't believe this.
I got me a man here.
Yeah, look at this.
Do you see this?
Yeah, brother.
Come on, come on.
That's it, my man.
Mother, cut him.
Oh, my God.
Hell, boy.
Hey, hey, you see that shit?
Look at this here.
Shit, boy,
you're a bad motherfucker
with that foreign shit, boy.
Put it right there.
Shit. Goddamn,
you're bad, boy.
What the fuck
are you doing, man?
Get the fuck out of
my pocket. You break...
All right, fuck, then go
ahead and take it, man.
It's your money
any goddamn way.
Wait a minute. Let me count. Thanks.
Wait. Hold on. Let me count
this shit. Wait a minute.
Wait, wait,
wait a minute, man.
You didn't give me enough
goddamn money, man.
Hey, look here, boy.
You're a good fighter, boy.
But you can't count
worth a shit.
God damn it, give me
my goddamn money. Hey!
The number you
have dialled is no longer in service
and there's no new number.
If you feel you have reached
this recording in error,
please hang up
and dial again.
There's nowhere to go.
Nobody home?
No.
Hey, man, don't be looking
at the damn sandwich, man.
Pick it up and eat it.
It ain't gonna hurt you.
'Cause you're Lion,
king of the jungle.
So you want to
get to LA, huh?
Yeah.
Hey, man. Thank you
very much for that, man.
Look here, I'll get you
back in LA, all right?
Thank you for paying
for the sandwich.
Yeah, sure.
It is where you
want to go, LA, right?
Yeah, can you take
me there?
Damn straight, baby.
When?
That totally depends
upon you, my man.
We just got to go see some
people, you know what I'm saying?
Hey, now.
What's happening, huh?
May I help you,
gentlemen?
Here to see
the lady, man.
Uh...
You'll have to be a little
bit more specific than that.
Oh, man,
cut the shit.
Just tell her Joshua's here with
someone I think she'd like to meet.
Well, if it ain't
old Joshua.
My main man.
Yeah.
How'd you find us?
Here, look here, man. Word gets
out. You know what I'm saying?
I want you
to meet somebody.
You chose
a bad time.
Call me middle
of next week.
No, no. Now.
You don't know
when to quit, do you?
Hey, the man just
kicked five asses.
You want to make
yours number six?
Okay. Fuck it.
Follow me.
Hey, I love New York.
Hey, cool down, man.
Just look at him.
Fire someplace?
Hey, look here.
Wait here.
Yeah, all right.
Formal, ain't it?
Hey, this is
your ticket, man.
Ticket to LA, any place
else you want to go.
Check it out.
That, my man,
is the lady.
And this is her show.
Been a long time, Joshua.
I see your taste
is improving. Who's this?
This is the Lion,
king of the jungle.
Joshua, please.
What's your name?
Lyon.
Lyon? You're French?
What's the difference?
It's all right. My man
don't like talking about himself,
you know, where he comes from, any of
that mess, you know what I'm saying?
Is it cool?
Cool.
I can appreciate
a little attitude
as long as he can give them
what they want to see.
Come on!
Come on. Kick him.
Yes, kick him. Come on.
Kick him. Yeah.
You can do it. Come on.
Come on. Get him.
Get him. Come on. Let's go.
Kick his ass.
Come on.
Come on. Get him.
Get him!
Come on. Yeah.
Come on, get him.
That's right. Yes.
Come on. Get up.
Get up. Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Get up!
Get back. Come on.
Come on.
Come on! You can't
just scuffle. Come on.
Finish him!
Bring it in. What
is this? I paid for a fight!
Come on. Come on.
Let's do lunch sometime.
What is this?
Know what? Get the mop!
Busted. Busted.
Bring in the mop.
Sonny,
Sonny, Sonny, Sonny!
Sonny, Sonny, Sonny, Sonny!
Hey, now it's time to find out how
bad you want to get to LA, my man.
Ain't no nickel-and-dime
shit here.
I didn't agree when they said
you were a bum, but that's right!
Hey, there you are.
Sure you want to mess up
that face, handsome?
You're up, stud.
Hey, wake up.
Fight's this way.
Things are gonna be
just fine, my man.
Hey, hey.
Hey, how you doing, Joshua?
You all right, man?
Hey, yeah.
Lenny,
what are you calling it?
I make Sonny a three-to-one
favorite. What's the other kid's name?
Lyonheart.
Hey, I got three-to-one
against Lyonheart.
Three-to-one
Dig it, Lyonheart, 15% off the
top if we win, 5% if we lose.
We?
Hey, man. Who brought you here, sucker?
I got it. I got it.
I got it. Okay.
I'm gonna bet this whole
damn wad on your ass.
You whip this sucker's ass and
we split 50-50. All right? Huh?
Oh, shit. Look here.
Hey, we partners, man.
Huh?
Yeah. Don't either one
of us ever forget that.
Come on. Talk to me, talk
to me. Haven't got all night.
On Lyonheart, all of it.
And keep this between us.
It's over. It's over.
Come on, guys.
Come on, come on.
You know the rules, huh?
There's no rules.
You're kind of pretty.
I don't know if I want
to fight you or fuck you.
Sonny.
Come on, boy.
Come on, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Sonny.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on, Lion.
That's it, that's it.
Get up, Sonny!
Get up, Sonny, get up.
Get up, Sonny.
That's my man right there.
I brought him here.
Get up, pussy.
It's over, man.
He's had it.
Shit.
Hey!
I could fucking kick
this guy's ass.
You see this shit, man?
I know, baby, I know.
Not bad.
Hey, come on.
Who is this guy?
Right now, you and me.
Hey. No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no. Hey, no,
no. Don't do that, man.
Hey, come on,
come on, come on.
Hey, now come on, man,
you ain't gonna go do shit.
Hey, the winner.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Lyonheart,
king of the jungle.
Don't ever insult one
of my patrons again.
If there's something that
Russell or I can't handle,
we have paid
security personnel who can.
You clear on that?
Yeah.
Good.
Now, what's this shit
about a trip to LA?
Because I think I can have another fight
lined up for you in less than a week.
Better money for
everybody this time.
But it's up to you, Lyon.
I'm going to Los Angeles.
What the fuck
is in Los Angeles?
All right.
Can you at least make it
back by Tuesday?
No.
Do us a favor. Talk it
over with your manager.
My manager?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Look here.
My man wants to go to LA. What he's
got going there is his business.
And we'll be back here when we're
good and ready to come back here.
You understand what I'm
saying? Right, my man?
Let me tell you
all something.
What I did tonight I did for my
family, not for you, not for me.
You made a total of $5,000.
That's a pretty substantial
amount for a one-night stand.
Where else are you gonna
make that kind of money?
That's my business,
not yours. Stop the car.
What if we can arrange
a fight for you in California?
We do have a circuit
out there, too.
Arrange it
for somebody else.
And stop the car.
That $5,000 won't go
as far as he thinks.
My private number,
in case he changes his mind.
Hey, hey, man. Get up off
the celebration, will you?
Come on, man, you know how far
the damn airport is from here?
Hey, come on, man.
It's just me and you now.
I left them other
jive turkeys way behind.
All right. Hey, look here.
I can dig it.
Hey, my brother done
made me some money,
so I'm gonna leave his ass
in the damn street.
Well, that's all right. That's all
right. Go ahead with your bad self.
We'll see how far your ass gets
without my help, God damn it.
Go ahead.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Jive motherfucker.
Tonight, I fought
for you.
Didn't make
enough money, huh?
Wait a minute.
You want some more?
Don't be talking about no
damn money around here, man.
Shit, man, if people find out
we've got $10,000 in our pocket,
we won't even make it
to that damn corner.
Man, just put your money
back in the pocket, there.
That's... Yeah, there.
That is just... Yeah, yeah.
Look here, man.
Hey, look here.
Why don't we get a cab
out of here, man,
right now, all right?
Yeah. Come on.
Hey, hey, look here.
There it is. There's a telephone.
That's what we need, man.
Hey. Listen to me.
Yeah.
Listen to me. I'll get
you out of this, all right?
Yeah. We'll survive.
Now come on, man.
God is merciful, you
know it. Come on, man.
Hey, yeah, yeah, hey. Looking
for an honest man? I'm him.
Never steer you wrong.
There it is. See?
Hey, man.
What is this, man?
Shut up, man.
Hey, cuz,
you want to use our phone?
Look, that's all right, blood, we'll
go someplace else. Don't worry about it.
What, you don't
like my phone, cuz?
How much you want
for your phone?
Let me do
the talking, man.
Hey, shut up,
nigger.
I want to hear what
the white boy got to say.
This is my hood, motherfucker,
and I ask the questions.
How much you want to pay?
He ain't got no money,
motherfucker.
I got the goddamn money.
And I'll kick your ass.
You ain't getting shit.
Motherfucker's gonna pay now.
Come on, man.
Get in there, man.
Today's your
lucky day, punk.
Yeah, that's right.
I want a cab.
What, you expect me
to walk to the airport?
What do you mean, you don't send
no cabs to this neighborhood?
Wait, are you...
Hey, man,
you want to use the phone?
Come on. Let's go.
Hey.
You're gonna listen
to Joshua now, huh?
Yeah.
I've been all over the
world, man. I've been around.
From the Big Apple to the
Big Orange, I know the score.
How you gonna get around
in all that smog?
Huh?
Them freeways?
Now, people in LA, man,
lot of shit going on.
Lot of weird-ass
motherfuckers running around.
Besides,
I owe you lunch.
Yeah, yeah.
You owe me lunch.
Good.
But you're wasting your time
if you think I'll fight again.
Hey, I can dig it.
It's cool.
Okay. Okay.
$5,000 will go a long ways
in the land of sunshine.
He is my brother.
I want to see Francois now.
I understand but we still
need to see some identification.
I want to see my brother.
- What's going on?
- Please come with me. Please.
It finally happened
late last week.
With the extent
of his injuries,
honestly, I don't know how
he held on as long as he did.
It's because I told him
I'd always be there for him.
I'm truly sorry.
The guys who did this to him,
did they catch them?
Mr. Gaultier, he's gone, and nothing
we can do will bring him back.
Doc, my question is,
did they catch them?
Yes, Mr. Gaultier. I believe
the police have them in custody.
The guys who set him on fire...
might have been...
rival drug dealers...
they might have been customers
that he sold some bad stuff to.
It might have been kids
playing a sick prank.
We may never know.
He was too delirious to tell
the police much of anything.
Now if I were you,
I'd be a little more concerned
about his wife and his child.
He left them with a stack
of unpaid medical bills
and not too much
of anything else.
Now I can give you
their address, if you'd like.
I have it.
Thank you.
Hey, you don't look
sick to me, baby.
Hey, Lion. Hey, Lion!
Hey. Hey, Lyonheart.
Hey, man, what's happening?
You acting like they said you
were pregnant or something.
I don't need you.
Just go, okay?
Go.
Hey. Look there. There he is.
Hey, my treat, remember?
Damn inflation, man.
Look here. Here's $2, man.
Keep the change. For your kids.
I heard Russell say you
don't know when to quit, huh?
Hey, that's me, man.
That's you.
Can't argue with
the facts, right?
You have nothing
better to do?
Okay.
Maybe you can
help me then.
Find this place.
That's the address.
No problem, man. Who lives
there? You got a sister?
Just find me this place and
don't ask too much question.
Hey, hold it, man.
Hold that goddamn car. Yeah.
Motherfucker.
Hey. Oh, hey, hey. There it
is. There it is. Right there.
It's yours?
Do you know where a lady
named Helene lives?
Can you show me?
My mommy told me not
to talk to strangers.
Your mommy, huh?
She's right.
My name is Nicole,
and I'm five.
Nicole, c'est très joli.
My name is Lyon.
Now you're not
a stranger anymore.
I'm not a stranger when your
mommy says I'm not a stranger.
Just give me
some time, okay?
Just a few more days
and I will have it.
You will have it, I promise.
Friday.
Not a partial payment, cash.
450 bucks, cash.
Absolutely.
Okay. If you don't, you
and your family are on the street.
I don't think this would be
a good time to ask my mommy.
Deadbeats like you are why I can't
get the goddamn elevator fixed.
You live here?
I came to visit.
Well excuse me.
Let's go.
Mommy, is he a stranger?
Nicole, go inside and draw
with your crayons.
Just for a minute, honey.
So you finally decided to
grace us with your presence.
Helene, it was impossible
for me to go.
I put myself in lots
of trouble to get here.
Well, I've got news for you. It wasn't
worth it, because you're too late.
Helene, I tried.
I'm sorry. I tried.
You know, the only thing that he
wanted was just to see your face again.
Maybe we should
go inside.
No, I don't want you inside.
I don't want you anywhere
near me or my daughter again.
You're the one who started
her father on that shit.
That's not true.
Oh, yeah?
He took that shipment
to Amsterdam for you.
That's what
I say to the cop.
He was a smart kid. I didn't
want him to go in jail.
He had a future.
You were pregnant.
Oh, spare me the details.
You're family.
He might have been better off if
you had just kept your mouth shut
and let him go to jail.
He was not enough
strong to be in jail.
It would have killed him.
The streets that you left
him on are what killed him.
No, Helene.
Come on.
I don't have anything
more to say to you.
Helene, come on.
Helene, you and Nicole,
we're family.
You're my only family.
Let me try to help you.
Helene.
This is to help you
with your bill.
I don't want your money.
Don't you get it? I don't want
anything from you ever again.
Now, get out of here
before I call the cops.
You look like you're about
ready to jump off a bridge.
Here, have some chicken.
No. Thanks.
I need something else.
You don't even have to
say it, man. I'm psychic.
Foreign Legion, huh? That's them
guys with those white hats on, right?
I thought the Foreign Legion was something
that you see in old movies, or something.
I wish it was just
an old movie.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, where you want
to go now, man?
You want to get some girls,
you want to go dancing?
You know what I'm saying?
Where you want to go?
I've got some
business to finish.
Personal business.
Is it something I can
help you with, man?
Yeah. Maybe.
Hey, look here.
Let's drink to that, man.
Hey, put them up there.
Here, all right.
Jump the devil with
his blind children.
Look here, man,
I gotta make phone call.
I'll be right back, all right?
Yeah?
Yeah.
Where you going?
Hey, we got to find us a place
to stay for the night, right?
I'm looking out for you.
I'll be right back.
Hey, hey, there's a phone.
Look out, look out.
All right. All right.
Just stand up.
Hey.
Check it out, Dorothy.
We ain't in Kansas no more.
Where are we going?
Visit an old friend of mine. There.
Yeah, that's the place, right there.
Sure you all right?
Yeah.
Yeah. She only uses this place
when she's in LA on business.
Go, go, go ahead. Look around.
It's yours for the night.
How about you?
Yeah, I'll be
right next door.
That's hers, too.
Okay.
It's nice to have friends,
ain't it?
Hey, go look. You relax, man.
Enjoy yourself.
Good morning.
Joshua told me you needed a
place to stay for the night.
I hope this was adequate.
Yes. Thank you.
I need to go. Excuse me.
So go.
When I came in this morning,
you were spread across the
bed like an old throw rug.
What happened
to my clothes?
I gave them to the valet with
instructions to burn them.
You told them to
burn my clothes?
Give me a break.
There are a few shops
right down the street.
I'm sure we'll be able to find a way
to replace your fabulous wardrobe.
I just want my clothes back.
Not on your life.
I'm taking you
shopping today
if I have to drag you
kicking and screaming.
Why are you so nice to me?
Just try one more.
S'il vous plaît.
It's nice.
It's not for me.
No?
How about this?
Any better?
Everything okay in there?
Everything is fine.
You know, people in New York are
still talking about your fight.
Let them talk.
You planning on sleeping
in the hallway?
No. I'll stay next
door with Joshua.
Is that it?
You two got
something going?
Cynthia,
I'm not your toy.
If you want a toy to play with,
talk to Russell, not to me.
You want to carry this?
There. Come on.
Is this your ball?
Take some money.
Oh, Christ.
I'll do it.
Well, finally.
I mean, I'll fight.
Oh.
But first you have to help me
to take care of some business.
All right, talk to me.
I need to open
a bank account.
I like that kind of talk.
Not in my name, we'll make up a
name. Don't ask me why, just do it.
That's my condition.
I'll call my accountant
first thing in the morning.
Anything else?
Yes. I have
to move out of here.
Do I have the right to ask what
brought these sudden changes on?
Look, I'm gonna fight for you.
I have to live like a fighter.
This place is too nice
to me, too soft, too easy.
I see.
Are you sure it isn't because you've
found something a little softer,
a little easier out on the street today?
Don't answer that.
That's "My business. My business!".
I'm sick of this shit!
Get out!
Get the fuck out!
And take that goddam cripple with you.
In the morning you call Russell
and you tell him where you're staying.
From now on, you deal with Russell,
and only with Russell.
Our relationship is strictly business.
The way it should have been
from the beginning. You got that?
And you owe me for these.
I'll call Russell in the morning.
You don't forget to call your accountant.
I'll think about it.
Yeah. Think about it.
Don't fall
in them damn skates, boy!
Excuse me. No, no. Please,
sir, go right ahead.
What is this, a dance, man?
He's got on a damn skirt.
Scotland.
Scotland? Scotland's shit. Kick
his Scotland ass. It's not that bad.
Go up his dress. I'd like to
see if he got any drawers on.
Take your time,
take your time now.
Don't be shaking
hands with him.
Come on, man,
come on. Now...
Damn.
Look at all this.
Get off my car.
Move, move, move.
Get off my car, man.
Get off the damn car.
Yeah, that's it,
that's it, that's it.
That's it. One more round,
one more round. Almost there.
That's it. Yeah,
that's all right. That's it.
Lay it on him, that's it.
You got it, man.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Let go of
him, Lyon. He's gone. Let go of him.
Hey, let him go, let him go,
let him go. Let him go.
He's gone. Let him go, Lyon,
come on. Yeah, that's right.
Be ready with the cash, Flash. Okay.
All right. All right.
Yeah.
I'm back. Who's back?
We're back in town.
That's right, baby.
After you, ladies.
Moustafa, it's your turn.
Mommy, does this mean
I can have a bike?
Honey, why don't you
go in the other room
so I can talk to
Mr. Eldridge, okay?
You could draw me
a pretty picture.
I'm gonna go
draw myself a bike.
Well, that would be
very nice, sweetie.
Cute.
I just don't know how I
couldn't have known about it.
Well, husbands do
this all the time.
Yeah. Secret little
insurance policy,
want to make sure the wife and kids
will be taken care of, you know?
Without freaking them out.
You know what I mean?
Well, you'll get one
of those every month.
You know how the post office is around
here, so I'll be bringing them by myself,
if you don't mind.
Oh, no, that's fine. Yes.
Thank you, Mr. Eldridge.
Don't thank me. Thank the
man who set up the policy.
May he rest in peace.
Oh, just do me
one little favor.
I know it's something
that he would have wanted.
Well, what is that?
Get the little girl a bike.
All right,
you have a nice day now.
Yes! That's it, that's it.
I like that. Yeah.
Hey, hey. That's bad for you.
Destroys your concentration.
Well, it looked
good to me.
It looked good to me,
but get on out there, boy.
Hey, you guys.
What are you doing?
What is that?
Like my new bike?
Yeah.
Bye, you guys.
Bye.
See you tomorrow.
Moustafa, wake up.
He's here, downstairs!
Come on, let's go.
Nicole!
Come on inside, honey.
Think he see us?
He'll be back.
All right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Okay, I'm taking some bets.
Lyonheart five to fight in the pool.
No wading.
Yeah!
Get up!
That's it.
Better luck next time, man.
We don't need
to go Rambo, huh? That's it.
Yeah! Hey.
We did it. My boy did it.
Who is Helene Gaultier?
According to the bank,
she's the one they said cashed
that phony insurance check.
She used to be married
to his brother.
He's just trying to help
the woman out, that's all.
Is he fucking her?
Cynthia, you're one hard,
cold, sick bitch, you know that?
I asked you a question.
Bitch, the man don't even
step inside her apartment.
She don't know where the
damn money's coming from.
Well, as his
self-appointed manager,
I'm counting on you
to keep him out of trouble.
You mean keep
him making money.
That's right.
For me. And for you.
Start keeping
an eye on those two.
Hi. See my new bike?
I said that's a nice bike.
Is that French? My daddy
used to talk French.
I've got to go now.
Who's that?
Nicole.
Okay, you go home right now.
You go home right now.
You know why we're here.
Don't force us to get rough
in front of little girl.
Without me they'll
be on the street.
Tell your sad stories
to the court-martial.
We're just supposed to take
you back, any way we can.
Just give me one week to get
the money for them. One week.
Your time was up
in the desert,
and we still owe you
for that one, fucker.
Go to hell.
I show you hell.
Grab him!
Come on.
This is the end.
Let's go. Let's go!
Lion.
If you're in some kind of trouble,
maybe we ought to know about it.
And you spying on me,
I should know about it, too.
Okay, now you know. Maybe we should
lay all our cards on the table.
Do you hear that?
Either you take a ride with the
cops or you take a ride with me.
Now what's it gonna be stud?
What about them?
If I was you I wouldn't be
so concerned about their health
It doesn't look like they were
doing you any big favours today.
Come on.
Here.
Oh, man!
These dudes did a number
on you, huh, homes?
Do you know
what you need, man?
You need karate lessons, man.
That way nobody
will mess with you.
I mean, look at you.
You got a broken rib.
You're gonna have to stay
in bed for a month, homes.
Do me a favor.
Yo.
Don't talk to nobody
about my rib.
Don't worry about that, man.
Shit, $100, man.
Have a nice day.
Business all the time.
His name is Lyon.
I know he's here.
I have to go find him.
Now is he in here?
Can you tell me if he's in here?
Well who knows?
Who knows where he...
...Excuse me, I have to go.
I rushed over here as soon
as I heard what happened.
My God.
You're staying here tonight, aren't you?
When did you start to care?
Get off it Lyon.
I know I said some things
that I probably shouldn't have
But if I had known the
truth about your situation
Why didn't you tell me?
I could have helped you with your family.
- You want to help?
- Yeah.
I need your help.
Whatever you want.
Who's there?
Mr. Eldridge.
I wasn't expecting
you back so soon.
Yeah, I know. Look, something's
come up. We've got to talk.
About what?
Look, I heard about the shit
that went down today. Look...
Please, Mrs. Gaultier,
this is real important.
Look, you've got to get out
of this place tonight.
You and the little girl.
How do you know
what happened today?
Hey, my man?
So there never was an
insurance plan, was there?
Okay. Now you see that?
Yeah, that's where your money's
been coming from. No, no, no, no.
Look, now I think you owe him a minute
of your time to say what he's got to say.
So, say what you got to say.
Okay. Those men today, they
followed me from North Africa.
They knew I'd be
coming to see you.
Does this have anything
to do with drugs?
Because if it does, I don't want
to have anything to do with it.
I've been through this
shit with Francois...
Helene, I swear,
it's not drugs.
Now I don't have too much
time, but I'm here to help you.
Don't do this to me.
My life is hard enough
as it is, I...
I'm not trying to give you
problems. I'm here to help you.
Please,
you've got to trust me.
Hi, Mr. Eldridge.
Hey. Yeah, yeah.
See my new bike?
He's already seen it.
Mommy,
is he still a stranger?
No, honey.
This is your uncle Lyon,
your daddy's brother.
I knew you weren't
really a stranger.
That's him. Atilla.
A born killer. Real pro, not
some bum we picked off the street.
He likes to toy
with his opponents,
give them hope.
Then he tears them apart.
Never seen anything like that
on our circuit, huh?
And that's why I can't
let you have Lyon just yet.
The fight's already scheduled.
But if I get hassled by the French
Consulate or the immigration people,
it'll screw up everything.
So I need your cooperation.
And I promise you,
as soon as Atilla's
finished ripping him apart,
I will hand him over to you
as is. What do you say, guys?
I say...
Can we watch?
Yes.
I hope this is the right
stuff. Joshua picked them.
Well, there's enough to feed
her entire kindergarten class.
And there's something else
Santa Claus brought. Oh, no.
Merry Christmas.
You guys are gonna spoil her.
It's my only niece, I've got
the right to spoil her, right?
Yeah,
I guess so.
Well, if there
is no real food here,
I guess I'll pick some things up
from work tomorrow, bring them home.
That's something else
I want to talk about.
I don't think you should go
back to that place anymore.
Are you serious? How long do
you expect us to stay here?
I don't know, just until
you have a new job
or another husband.
I mean, it's no problem, you
can stay here. It's home now.
This is beautiful.
Yeah, your niece,
she made it for you.
And insisted I put it
right where you'd see it.
Nice.
Oui.
Hey, man,
guess who's outside?
Let's get crazy.
Where are we going?
Loosen up, we're going
to see some friends.
How are your relatives doing,
by the way?
They'll be much better
if I was there.
Well, this little party
we're attending tonight,
it's for their benefit
as much as ours.
These friends of mine are thinking
of betting some serious money
on your next fight, Lyon. Just
how serious depends on you.
We can all retire on this one.
Don't fuck it up.
Mr. Lyonheart, welcome.
We've just been watching your
videotape. Most impressive.
Would you like a drink?
Can I get you a drink, sir?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll have a gin and tonic
with a twist of lime,
my good man.
By all means.
Come this way, please.
Did you have a pleasant
journey over here?
No, man.
I'm sorry
to hear that.
So, did you get
the tape?
If you knew what I went
through to smuggle this out...
What do you think?
Not too good.
Full of shit.
Enough of this.
Well, I have to tell you,
I'm not too impressed.
What about you,
Mr. Lyonheart?
We have friends in Hong Kong who say
that he will wipe the floor with you.
What do you think
about that?
Anything is possible.
Humble devil isn't he?
Talk is cheap. You've
all seen him in action.
Draw your own
conclusions, gentlemen.
As far as I'm concerned,
Lyonheart is gonna eat
this bozo for breakfast.
And I've got a quarter mil
ready to back it up.
We'll let you know which
way we're going on the day of the fight.
Faster?
Yeah, faster.
Okay.
Okay, that's it
for today, guys.
She's so beautiful.
Tonight, I'll have a fight,
a big fight, lots of money,
and if I win, I would like to take
you and Nicole away from this place,
away from this city, and leave
all the bad stuff behind us.
No problems. No problems,
it'll be clear.
This is going great.
Picked up your
highest script.
You understand
what I'm saying?
You don't understand
at all, right? Okay.
Madhouse out there, man.
Hey, hey, hey! My man.
Hey, look at you.
Yeah. Ready to get rich?
Come on, throw a few,
throw a few.
I took all my money out of the
bank and I put a bet on myself.
We're going to
win that fight.
Confidence, that's what I like to
hear, man. You know what I'm saying?
All right, all right,
what is it, man?
You've been hiding something all
week long. What's going down, man?
Nothing.
Nothing, huh? Nothing?
Easy.
You know what's circulating
out there, man?
12 million motherfucking
dollars, man.
Cynthia's friends have come
through like a motherfucker, man,
and then I hear
that shit about Atilla.
Man, this dude's already
bagged eight bodies.
I'll beat him.
Beat him?
You ain't gonna beat him,
not if you're all fucked up.
How're you gonna beat him
if you're all fucked up?
I'll beat the guy. I have to.
You don't have to do shit,
motherfucker,
but get yourself all
fucked up like I did.
Is that what you want?
Be out there on the street,
motherfucker,
running $5 fights
for winos and junkies?
I'm gonna take you away
from this shitty business.
You and my family, even
Cynthia, if she wants to.
Cynthia, man?
You think Cynthia gives
a flying fuck about you?
You know what
your problem is, man?
You got a big heart,
Lyonheart.
I mean, you're strong
as a lion, man,
but this right here, this?
This is what fucks you up
and leaves you bleeding
on the motherfucking ground with nobody
to give a two-bit shit about your ass.
Look, Lyonheart,
nobody gives a shit
about you but you, man.
Nobody.
You care about me.
I'm gonna win that fight.
You've got to trust me.
Hey, Josh.
What it is.
Who you betting on?
Look at the board.
I'd say the wind's definitely
blowing in our direction.
I didn't ask you that. I asked
you who you were betting on.
Why? Having any last-minutes
doubts about your boy?
No, I... I was just
remembering the way you did me.
Is there something
I should know about Atilla?
I should know about Lyon?
No, no, no, no. No. He's gonna
stomp that dude in the ground.
Send him home
in a little box.
Well then,
there's the desk.
You've got about five minutes
left to place your bet.
You near an hour
too late, man.
Hookie-bookie,
what's up, man?
Hey, talk to me, man. You
gonna make a bet, or what?
All of the stuff.
Yeah? Very good.
Which way are you
going, man, Lyonheart or Atilla?
One minute till post,
my friend.
Did you see the look on his
face? He's totally psyched out.
He's toying with him.
That's right. That's
it. All right. Got him.
Another one.
Keep going.
Yeah. Kick him again.
There we go.
Yeah!
What's wrong?
Man.
Lyonheart, stay down, damn
it. Stay the fuck down!
Stay down, man.
Just stay down.
We bet all the money.
Don't worry about that,
just stay down.
Cynthia, she bet against me.
I know it.
You were right, you were
right. She bet against me.
Damn it! This dude's gonna kill
your ass. Don't you know that?
This dude's gonna kill your
ass, man. Don't you know that?
Look, he's hurt.
Come on, Lyonheart. Come on.
That dude's gonna kill your
ass. Don't you know that?
Lyonheart, I told you
the way this shit did me.
Don't let it do you, man.
Stay the fuck down.
Come on, man.
Come on, Lyon.
We don't need the money, man.
I got us a deal.
I told you, 50-50 all
the way down the line.
Well, I'm gonna split it with
you, man. 50-50, all the way, man.
Just like I said I would.
Look, it's on him, man.
The whole bet's on Atilla.
Wrong bet.
Yes!
This dude's gonna
kill your ass, man.
Come on,
kick the snot out of him!
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on, Lyonheart.
Hey. Let's go. Let's go.
Lyonheart!
Yeah!
Come on! Come on!
You...
All right!
Get out there.
You bury that motherfucker.
Kick the shit out of him!
We got him! We got him!
Finish him, man.
Right.
Great fight, Lyon. Your
family's going to be okay now.
It's time to go home.
Let's go.
Oh, Cynthia, darling, I just wanted
to thank you for such wonderful advice.
Open the door.
You definitely got heart,
Lyonheart.
Don't ever lose it,
because you never get it back.
Take it from me.
I've been there, man.
Miss Caldera,
the house would like to have a word
with you regarding your unsecured marker.
This way, please.
If you find that
bitch, don't let her off the premises.
She's headed toward
the front door now, sir.
With the cash?
Tell him it's
in New York. I swear it is.
I'll have it tomorrow.
You better.
Oh, my God.
Look. We're all ready to go.
What happened?
Come on. I love you.
Nicole, you and your mommy will
have to go without me, okay?
Here, this will help you.
No. Why? You have
to go with us. You have to.
It's not fair! Why can't
you go? It's not fair!
It's not fair!
I know, life is not too fair.
And sometimes it's ugly
and it's stupid and mean.
But sometimes,
life is beautiful, too.
Now I've got to go back
to an ugly place,
and if I don't, I'll be
running for the rest of my life,
and you and your mommy
will be running with me.
I don't care.
Nicole, chérie, you've
seen too much ugly already.
What about you?
I'll always have something
beautiful to remember.
You take care
of them, okay?
You got it, man.
You got it.
I love you.
Me, too. I'll miss you.
Come on,
let's go.
I love you.
Get out.
Good luck.
Lyon!
Hey, man. What the hell?
Hey, man.
Hey, why...
English - US