Apúrense, cabrones! Rápido!
Pásale! Pásale! Échale!
Órale! Échale! Échale!
Órale, muchachos!
Apúrense, muchachos.
This is Deputy Sheriff Oscar Garcia.
You are all under arrest
for horse stealing. Drop your guns.
Échale con tu chingada madre, cabrón!
(shouting in Spanish)
You gonna steal these horses
back from me? Huh? Policeman?
These are my horses!
Garcia, Ramos, policemen...
Órale!
You'll never get away with this. You can't
kill a policeman. They'll hunt you down.
Hijo de perra!
I'm gonna teach you a lesson.
I'm gonna teach him a lesson.
Some of these guys
are a lot taller than me.
A whole head taller.
Pues de la chingada!
Qué está pasando?
Hey, you, cabrón! You're hurting my cars,
pendejo! Why you do that?
This is JJ McQuade, Texas Ranger.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Put 'em down.
- Do not move.
- "Do not move." (cackles)
Hey, you. Stand up like a man
so I can see you.
Puta!
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
There! You think I care
about your pinche friend now?
Put down your weapon
or I'll shoot this man!
I say I'll shoot this man, motherfucker!
Better listen to me, cabrón!
Right now! Come down!
Ranger! I'm gonna kill this man!
Drop your weapon! Qué quieres?
Ain't no one ever killed no Texas Ranger
and lived to tell it.
He ain't that big. Muchachos, come down.
Show our honoured guest some respect.
(laughs)
Echa, hijo puta!
I've never seen
a Texas Ranger up close before.
You know,
once a Texas Ranger
kicked my father's teeth out.
Would you do that to me, Texas Ranger?
Don't shoot me.
Don't shoot me! You already kicked
my teeth out! What else do you want?
Like father, like son.
Come on.
(shouts in Spanish)
Get back, kid.
Stay there and I'll cut you loose.
I just wanna say thank you.
Thank you. You were great.
OK, OK, kid. OK.
Go cut your buddies loose. Go on.
Chinga a tu madre, puto.
Come on. I'm gonna fix your teeth.
(continues shouting in Spanish)
(siren)
- (PA) We present to you, Dakota Brown...
- (cheering and applause)
For 38 years of unrivalled performance
as a Texas Ranger...
for over 2,000 felony arrests...
(cheering and applause)
For serving the great state of Texas
with fearless devotion...
this gold watch...
and honorary plaque.
(Dakota) Hey, how about that?
How about that? Ain't that somethin'?
Dakota.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
(snores)
It's a real honour.
Adios, amigos. Hasta la vista.
Thank you, folks. Drive careful
goin' home now, you hear me?
- Good speech, Dakota.
- The hell with it. Did you get 'em?
- You bet.
- Sorry I was at this hand-job session.
- I'd love to have helped.
- I could have used you.
- Dakota?
- Yeah, Captain?
Can't say as I'm gonna miss you.
Thank you very much, Captain.
And thank you for the watch.
- And you, McQuade...
- Drink, Captain?
My office in ten minutes.
"And you, McQuade..." (laughs)
Hey, McQuade.
Hi, there.
- Captain?
- Sit down, McQuade.
You think you're pretty damn good,
don't you, McQuade?
In case you didn't know it there's more to
being a Texas Ranger than making busts.
- You gotta look good doing it.
- (toilet flushes)
Style.
The best always have style.
- I said, sit down.
- I'll stand, Captain.
Now, in terms of
unassisted felony arrests,
I admit your record is unrivalled.
But my kind of Ranger is a model citizen.
A pillar in the community. Goes to church.
He lives clean
and he's got a lovin' wife and kids.
Read it.
It's an editorial by the senator who
happens to approve our annual budget.
I quote: "Ranger JJ McQuade
is a walking symbol
of the brutal, uncooperative, obsolete and
discriminatory nature of Rangers today."
Unquote.
Well, your "lone wolf" attitude
is gonna change.
You're going to start cooperating with the
state and federal agencies. Understand?
(knocking at door)
Come in.
- You wanted to see me, Captain?
- Yes.
Ranger, meet your new partner.
Deputy Arcadio Ramos.
Arcadio. You can just call me Kayo.
You gotta be kidding.
(clears throat)
- It'll be an honour workin' with you.
- Forget it, kid. I work alone.
Where'd you get that piece?
- That's what I'm gonna find out.
- Ranger?
Stay with it, son.
Our Russian friends have failed us. We
will have to finance the coup ourselves.
(speaks Spanish)
The shipment has to be in Havana
before Wednesday.
Splendid.
Would you like to count it, Senor Wilkes?
Trust is the most important thing
in our business.
Of course it is.
Now, have the plane loaded at once.
I am in a hurry
to get back to Havana, Senor Wilkes.
Quickly, now.
That quick enough?
Bury them.
Ranger?
Good dog. Good wolf.
Good boy. Good wolf.
(whistles)
Chingao.
What a pisshouse.
Ranger?
What are you doing here?
I came to wake you up.
I'm your new partner, remember?
Kid, get out of here.
And forget that partner crap.
But Captain Tyler...
Tell Tyler to shove it!
Chinga a su madre!
Holy shit.
Hey, Ranger, I'd like to apologise.
I didn't mean to barge in on you
this morning.
You can't outrun me. I got superchargers.
Oh, yeah?
Supercharge this.
(Kayo) Damn!
Oh, piss.
Dammit, Ranger!
Aaah! Oh, sh... Aaargh!
La pura pinche madre!
Pinche cabrón, Ranger.
Daddy!
- Daddy, hey!
- Hey, sugar.
Hey, what's this, huh?
- About time you stopped by.
- I thought you might like to go riding.
- You mean it?
- I'm takin' the day off.
All right!
- I didn't know you took days off.
- Hi, Molly.
- Where have you been, stranger?
- I've been real busy.
- Oh, boy. Same old trouble?
- My kinda trouble doesn't take vacations.
- Aren't you gonna tell Dad the big news?
- Oh, honey.
Mom, I...
What news?
- Jim, I got a real good job in Las Cruces.
- Las Cruces?
We're gonna move there in two weeks.
- What do you mean "move"?
- Don't get all worked up.
I'm an independent woman now
and I got my own life to live.
I know, but you can
make your life right here.
- Oh, Jim.
- (car pulls up)
One day you're gonna meet some real
nice gal who won't mind sitting up nights,
waitin' to see if you're
gonna come home in one piece.
Oh, come on, Jim.
It's a nice town, it'll be good for Sally.
- Honey?
- Oh, hell.
Daddy, this is my boyfriend, Bobby Drew.
Boyfriend?
I heard a lot about you. You were in the
Marines, won a Silver Star and everything.
- Nice to meet you, Bobby.
- Nice to meet you, Ranger.
Bobby, Daddy's takin' me riding. I hope
you don't mind. I'll see you tonight, OK?
Uh, yeah, sure.
- See you later.
- Have a good old time.
Bye. See you later.
Bye, Mom! See ya!
(Sally) I'm ready to take Foxy out now.
- (Dakota) Just be patient.
- OK.
All right. I'm ready to go.
Pay attention, dummy.
She's got some mustang in her.
- I can handle her, OK? Let's go.
- OK.
- Be careful, honey.
- OK. Easy, Foxy.
Hey. How'd you like to
bite that in the butt,
develop lockjaw and be dragged to death?
- Who is she?
- Clark Richardson's widow.
- That's her, huh?
- That's her.
From a poor family.
Married Clark with all that money
just before he got himself squashed
in that Italian racing job. Quite a crash.
Clark ran with a pretty tough crowd
and talk is it wasn't an accident.
But nobody can prove it.
Shame, though.
All that fruit just rotting on the vine.
Doesn't look too rotten to me.
- Sally!
- Foxy!
- Help me!
Help!
It's all right. It's OK.
- You all right, honey?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
- What's your name?
- Sally.
- Next time, Sally, be more careful.
- I will.
I wanna thank you for what you did.
The name's Jim McQuade.
The infamous Texas Ranger.
Pleased to meet you.
(car horn)
This is Rawley Wilkes, my late husband's
partner. Ranger McQuade.
And now you're my partner.
I understand you're very good
with your hands and feet.
Pretty good.
Rawley was all-European
karate champion.
Is that right?
Ranger Brown. Sally.
Ranger McQuade, it was especially nice.
Oh, by the way, Rawley's giving a little
martial arts display by the racetrack.
- Just a little exhibition.
- Why don't you gentlemen drop on by?
- I don't think we...
- Oh, it'd be our pleasure, ma'am.
Good.
Hey, Foxy.
- Wait. What are you doin'?
- I wanna ride.
- Are you sure?
- Sure I'm sure. Excuse me, please.
Gallop. Let's go.
Never backs down, does she? Reminds
you of somebody else in her family.
But choosin's never easy and
I can't decide which one I'd rather see
There's a woman from El Paso and I
know she will be comin' here this evening
She'll be wearing a red dress and
I know the one with whom she'll be leavin'
There's another girl from Dallas...
- You got Pearl beer?
- No. Heineken, Michelob or Dos Equis.
Forget it.
- Bottom shelf, Sam.
- Yes, ma'am.
(woman) It's Rawley showing off.
This should be very interesting.
I see we are graced with the presence
of a media favourite, Ranger JJ McQuade.
Care to go for one, Ranger?
A little wager, perhaps?
No, thanks. I don't fight for money.
I don't want you dancin' with no greaser.
You are a greaser, aren't you?
Excuse me a minute.
- Quit while you're ahead, partner.
- Who the hell asked you?
Let me show you.
Come on, tough guy.
Boys are just havin' a little fun.
Do you wanna join the fun?
This is not my idea of fun!
Please let me apologise. Some of my
friends could learn a little manners.
Maybe you need some new friends.
Music! Play!
(cackles)
This was my party.
We should have booked those bastards.
If I locked up every guy who took a swing
at me, half the county'd be behind bars.
Well, you're makin' a real habit
of saving my ass. I appreciate it.
- You take a good punch, kid.
- I'll take old hamburger-face home.
- Good idea.
- Come on, boy.
You look like you could use
a change of scenery. Come on.
I'll drive.
Cuidado, mis cuates, la chota.
Not too popular, are you?
They understand me.
Por favor.
Una botella de mezcal, dos limones
y si me puede limpiar la mesa. Gracias.
- Mezcal?
- Yes.
How about a kiss, baby?
Excuse me.
Time to leave.
Watch out!
- Sally, get back here.
- Nope.
Hey, come on. Open up.
Let me in. Come on, Sally.
- Nope.
- Come on, open the door. Let me in.
- You promise you won't try anything?
- I promise. Let me in.
OK.
- Aaargh!
- Bobby!
- You promised. Cut it out.
- I lied.
(trucks starting up)
- What is it?
- It's coming from down on the highway.
Stay here.
Bobby?
(gunfire)
Holy shit.
Let's get out of here.
Get down.
What do you guys want?
No!
Bobby! No!
(screaming and sobbing)
See you around.
(woman on radio) Come in, 6R1.
Can you read me?
- 6R1 here. Over.
- Roger, 6R1.
We've got a multiple fatality and injury
on I-10 south of Estelline.
I'm going home. Is there anyone closer?
Negative. You'd better go. We've been
notified that your daughter's involved.
- My daughter?
- (siren)
- Sally McQuade.
- Room 418.
Ranger! Wait!
Please. She needs rest.
She was very lucky.
Bobby...
Bueno.
(siren)
Howdy, Ranger.
The feds. They've taken over.
Marcus Jackson, FBI, Houston.
- McQuade, Texas Ranger.
- I know.
I'm sorry about your daughter,
but this is a federal case.
From now on, it's out of your jurisdiction.
There's brass everywhere. 9mm.
Excuse me. Get it to the lab. I want a
ballistics report. Let's see what we got.
I guess this is his show.
There were pages blowin'
all over the place when I got here.
I kept this one.
It's a logbook page from an army convoy.
Fort Nelson.
Ranger?
- Hello. Lieutenant Dade, Shipping.
- McQuade, Texas Ranger, El Paso.
I'm calling to verify that shipment
number... 5501 left Fort Nelson yesterday.
Yes, sir, it certainly did.
- What were the contents of those trucks?
- Sir, I'm not at liberty to say.
- Who is?
- Colonel McNeil, sir.
- Would you connect me, please?
- Yes, sir.
(knock at door)
- Colonel McNeil's office.
- Could I speak to the colonel?
- He isn't in today.
- When do you expect him?
- I haven't the faintest idea.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
- Lady, what the hell do you know?
I only work for the colonel.
I don't sleep with him.
You won't get anywhere that way, Ranger.
Follow me.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Accessing into Aristotle.
- Who?
- The military central computer.
You see, I borrowed the codes
from the Texas Criminal Info Center.
- Shit. - If you get it figured
out, kid, let me know.
Wait, Ranger, I'm in. I got it.
I got it.
They got a shitload of guns. Oh, man.
- Look at that.
- Holy shit.
- Good job, kid. Really a good job.
- Thanks, Ranger.
(McQuade) Here's our little Judas goat.
- What's his connection?
- His name's Snow.
Hustler, dealer, pimp, you name it.
There isn't any dirt
he doesn't have his hands in.
What do you say
we pay him a visit, Ranger?
Let's go.
- You gonna park?
- Hang on.
What?
You're learning, kid.
I see I got a lot more to learn.
Come on, kid.
Son of a bitch.
Whoops.
Senora?
Dondé fue el hombre que pasó ahorita?
Gracias.
- Remember me, Snow?
- J-Jesus!
Watch it!
Round the front.
Muchas gracias.
Goddammit! Shit!
Don't!
- No! No!
- Come on!
(Snow moans and whimpers)
Come on.
- Take him.
- I'll call the fire department.
Later. I need to talk to him
before I let the feds have him.
You're gettin' more slippery all the time,
ain't you?
Come on. How many times
have I busted you, you son of a bitch?
- Argh! It hurts my hand!
- Yeah, it does, don't it?
(Snow) You son of a bitch!
Can I borrow that contraption?
Sure.
What are you gonna do?
Stop! Wait!
(Dakota) Got something to say, pissant?
I know who you want.
It's the Mexican Mafia man, Falcon.
Emilio Falcon?
They're heistin' guns everywhere.
All they can get.
What are they gonna do
with all that hardware?
I said, what are they gonna do
Shit! They fly 'em off to Mexico, to
Central America, to terrorists and stuff!
All over the place.
I don't know.
They're gonna kill my son, man!
Goddammit!
Please? Please?
Please, man. Let me go, goddammit.
You stay right there, boy.
Don't you even breathe fast.
Thanks. I figured you'd bring him around.
It has been my pleasure, JJ.
Hang onto him till I get back.
I'm gonna clean up
and pay a little visit to Senor Falcon.
- What about me, Ranger?
- Hold down the fort... partner.
Bueno.
Let's go have
another little talk with our guest.
(Snow) What you gonna do? What you
gonna do, man? I'm not scared of you.
(singing)
What the hell...?
Damn!
(singing and sound of vacuum cleaner)
(she sings loudly)
- What the hell are you doing?
- Oh, hi.
- I just thought I'd clean up a bit.
- Lady, if I want a maid, I'll hire one.
Jim, you're a hopeless slob.
Let me have my cord.
What's this?
Vitamins.
Where's my beer?
In the garbage.
Can't you see you're killing yourself?
Lady...
if I want to kill myself,
it's my own business.
Fine. That's just fine.
Adios.
(door slams)
Shit.
Hey, wait a minute,
wait a minute, wait a minute.
Look, uh...
I, uh... I didn't mean to be such a...
What I mean is...
Lola, I...
I'm sorry.
You know, you could use some
improvement. You really could.
Yeah, I know.
(she sobs)
Hey! I'm not the trash.
OK, you're asking for it.
OK. Here.
- Sorry. This is by invitation only.
- This is my invitation.
Hey.
So, the lone wolf pays us a visit.
As you can see, mine's bigger.
Mine's loaded.
(laughs)
- Tell me, Ranger, do you like games?
- I'm not here to discuss games, Falcon.
- (buzzer)
- Damn!
- Then what brings you?
- Guns.
Guns? You know, at one time
I had a great interest in guns.
- Somebody tells me you still do.
- And you would like to believe him.
Two nights ago,
several men died in a convoy heist.
Yes. Of course I'm aware of these things.
However the certain party who is stealing
the guns was once a close friend of mine.
He might take it personally
if I were to divulge details.
He is a businessman, just like I am, and...
Why am I telling you this? You will find
these things out for yourself in good time.
- Meanwhile I'll enjoy watching the game.
- It may be a game to you, Falcon.
But if I find out you're playing,
I'm gonna have your little ass.
Well, Ranger, it's been a pleasure having
a chat with you. But I'm afraid I must go.
(Falcon) Oh, and Ranger?
The man you caught - Snow.
I understand he won't live
through the night. Adios now. (cackles)
- You can't get through?
- I'm sorry, 6R1. I can't help you.
That line's been reported out of order.
Mm-hm.
Tell you what I'm gonna do.
Snow calls it. There's his 30 cents.
I call it. There's my 30 cents.
What have you got, baby?
- Best hand all day.
- Look at that. Pair of kings.
Look at that, folks.
Three eights. Isn't that delicious?
You didn't win here. I'm gonna
take a little bit of your money.
How much this time?
- A quarter.
- One quarter, you wish to try. 25 cents.
Sit still, boy!
Now, you are going to love this game.
You're gonna get a marvellous hand.
Unfortunately it is going to be slightly
inferior to mine, but
you're going to like it.
What do you got, boy? What do I hear
from you? What do I hear from you?
- I need another beer.
- Oh, you need another beer.
- No cards up the sleeve, huh?
- No need to, with a patsy like you.
You learn when you play this game
that you really play people, not...
You don't play cards, you play people.
Loose lips sink ships.
You understand?
I thought you would.
I just play the cards good and tight.
Oh, fuck!
(siren)
(cracking)
(Snow screams) No! Don't kill me!
(Kayo) Dakota! You all right?
Dakota! Answer me!
Kayo.
Kayo?
It's OK, kid.
Captain.
Ranger, I think you know Agent Jackson.
This is Colonel Remsing
and ATF Special Agent Burnside.
- Feds.
- You better read this.
- Federal indictment?
- With your name on it.
You're dealing with
international gun smugglers. Butchers.
They provide every damn terrorist
organisation in the world with our guns.
I can't stand by you on this one, Ranger.
You withheld evidence, harboured
a key witness in a federal investigation,
caused a good man's death and violated
every jurisdictional clause in the book.
I've no choice but to put you on probation.
You'll take a mandatory vacation without
pay until this matter can be cleared up.
You want my star, Captain?
That won't be necessary. Not yet.
Hey, Wolf. How's my boy?
Jim...
What's wrong?
Nothing worth talking about.
Hey.
Are you OK?
Yeah, I'm OK.
(wolf growls)
Lola!
- You think they got the message?
- Just like you planned.
Damn.
(he yells)
Jim?
Come on. Let's go home.
I'll see you soon, honey.
- Daddy, aren't you coming in?
- No, I'd better get going.
I don't wanna leave you.
You're becoming quite a lady, you know.
I'm gonna miss you, honey.
- I love you, Daddy.
- Oh, I love you too.
Pretty jittery for a Ranger.
- Pretty quiet for a fed.
- Oh, I make it my business.
Looks like somebody
doesn't like you, McQuade.
- I make a few enemies here and there.
- Yeah? So do I.
- What do you want?
- I came to enlist your help.
See, I'm not the token nigger
when it comes to following the rules.
Get to the point.
(Jackson) I know they got a drop-off point
somewhere between here and Big Bend.
- That's 500 square miles.
- Who knows? We might just get lucky.
Pretty desolate terrain, McQuade.
(McQuade) There are no roads up here.
- This could take weeks.
- Yeah, it's gettin' late.
We'd better turn back.
See somethin'?
Take us down over there.
There's been some activity here. Pretty
well-organised for the middle of nowhere.
There's nothing
indicated here on the map.
What's goin' on?
I've got a bad feeling about this place.
(Kayo) Well, Ranger, how does it feel
to be baby-sitting Burnside?
(McQuade) Candy-ass feds.
McQuade! What is this?
A damn goat trail?
- If you wanna turn back, that's fine
by me. - Who the hell does he think he is?
He knows this country better than you
know the warts on your wife's backside.
Why don't we all line up and kiss his ass?
- I'll be damned.
- You need some help?
Let's show 'em what this baby can do.
What the hell does he think he's doin'?
What the hell...?
Hang on.
- What's he got there? A damn tank?
- Why don't you just shut the hell up?
Let's go.
A real pretty setup, huh?
It's been too easy.
Let's check around
before we make a move.
Burnside, hold it.
- This is the FBI.
- Burnside!
Drop your weapons
or we'll commence firing.
Get down!
- Run for it. I'll cover you.
- I'm staying here.
Get your ass out of here!
That's an order, Trooper!
You son of a bitch!
Now this is my idea of fun.
Rawley, that's enough!
Look, darling. I have a surprise for you.
One of your new friends.
Rawley, please! Rawley!
I waited a long time for this.
Please don't do it this way, Rawley!
Very well, my dear.
Get his truck. I have a better idea.
Get her out of here.
You murderer! You murderer!
Let go of me!
Pick him up.
Put him in it.
Something to remember you by.
Adios.
Freeze, assholes!
Ranger!
You son of a bitch!
Ranger?
Don't die on me now, dammit.
Dammit, don't die on me now!
Get me a beer, kid.
Yes, sir!
Aren't we a sorry bunch of bastards?
Whose idea was this, anyway?
(groans)
- Oh, Jim, thank God you're here.
- What's wrong? What's wrong?
It's Sally. She's missing.
I called all of her friends.
OK, calm down, calm down, calm down.
Are you sure you checked everywhere?
Oh, Jim.
I'll take care of this.
Is it "Ranger" or "Mr" McQuade?
May I come in, please?
- Say what you came to say.
- I came to offer my assistance.
A business acquaintance of mine, Rawley
Wilkes, has disappointed me greatly.
I'm not interested in your problems.
I'll get him my own way, in my own time.
- Wilkes has your daughter, McQuade.
- Oh, Jim! Jim!
It's his way of saying
he would enjoy your company again.
I want my daughter back, Falcon.
Please, please. I'm more than willing
to help you retrieve your loved one,
providing, of course,
that you return the favour.
What's your deal?
I will tell you precisely where
you can find Mr Wilkes and your daughter.
However, in return I would like
certain assets of mine protected.
I wish to claim what is mine.
Jim...
Anything. Please.
- Hey, partner. Where you headed?
- Mexico.
- Mexico? What the hell for?
- They got my daughter.
- Hold on. I'm comin'.
- It's not your fight.
Hey, Ranger!
You're in no shape to do this alone!
Dinero, por favor. Dinero, por favor.
Gracias. Muchas gracias.
- Se lo lleno, senor?
- Sí.
Vaya con Dios. God protect you.
(all murmuring)
Senor?
They are wishing you well.
You didn't think
I'd miss all the fun, did you?
- A new toy, huh?
- Just a little surprise.
(car approaches)
You gotta be kidding.
Hey. You guys remember me?
How we gonna
smuggle him back to Texas?
That's your problem.
Can you make it?
I didn't come this far
just to drop dead on the trail, did I?
It's all downhill from here on.
OK!
We split up from here. Stick to the plan.
- Right.
- Good luck.
Hello, Sally. How you doing?
What does he want from me?
Why is he keeping me here?
Rawley...
Daddy! Daddy!
Jim...
I'm so happy you're alive.
Where do you think you're going, dude?
- Let's go. It's gonna get rough
round here. - McQuade.
Get that crap off.
Let's get out of here.
- (Sally screams)
- Sally! Sally!
Remember me, greaser?
Yeah. I never forget an asshole.
Stay here.
Oh, shit.
Dammit.
Agh!
Come on. Come on.
Damn! I knew I forgot something.
(clang)
Welcome to my hacienda, Mr McQuade.
How nice of you to pay a social visit.
Daddy!
Come on.
- Daddy!
- No! Sally! Sally!
No! Stop it!
(yells)
Sally! Sally...
Are you all right, honey?
Gimme that gun.
- McQuade!
- Rawley! No!
Come on.
Jim...
I didn't betray you.
Rawley killed my husband
and forced me to be his partner.
I had no choice. He would have killed me.
I love you.
Hey, McQuade!
Daddy...
My arsenal! My investments!
What have you done?
Don't move, don't talk,
and everything will be just fine.
We made a deal, McQuade.
You made the deal, shorty. Not me.
You wanna try for three?
McQuade, wait. Wait!
You can't leave me here.
What about the Federales?
- You know how to fly this thing?
- I sure as hell don't. But he does.
You can't leave me! McQuade!
McQuade!
Wait! McQuade!
That's my chopper!
McQuade, come back here!
McQuade! That's my chopper! McQuade!
Can we print the comment that you made
about your daring rescue?
And the FBI credits
the Texas Rangers with the rescue?
- Absolutely correct.
- Can I have another picture?
Why not?
Ranger, you feel up to a picture?
Ladies and gentlemen, I wanna say it's
a pleasure having this man on my team.
I feel responsible for every move he's
made. After all, I taught him all he knows.
- He has style. The best always have style.
- Bullshit.
Daddy!
- Dad!
- That's my girl.
I can't wait to show you our new house.
Come on, let's go.
- Hi, Jim.
- Hi, Molly.
Gimme a hug. I really
appreciate your helping us move.
- My pleasure.
- Come on, let's go.
Oh, boy. Here we go.
(siren)
Ranger, we got a 10-31 in progress
at the Texas National Bank.
- I'm on vacation.
- They've got hostages.
- We really need you, Ranger.
- Comin', Jim?
Daddy?
Hostages?
Are you comin'?
See you later. Let's go.
JJ McQuade, you'll never change!
Oh, hell.
ÊãäíÇÊäÇ ÈãÔÇåÏÉ ããÊÚÉ