How is it? Are you convinced?
Yes, we're convinced.
OK, I'll go with you.
Sir, where are we going?
To see your boss.
You're magnificent.
My boss will definitely hire you.
This way, please.
OK, let's go.
Here. What are you afraid of?
Hand it to me now.
Sir, what do you want?
Black cloth.
You said you have to blindfold me.
That's right.
- Here it is, Ting.
- Go on, then.
Oh, of course... of course...
Please hop on, sir.
- Go.
- All right.
Lau Ming, Wong Gwan,
Wong Chi-Ping, Lee Man-Tai
Guest Starring Luk Chuen, Fang Fang,
Ko Keung, Wong Ching
Music composed by Yeung To-Fuo
Lyrics by Mak Ching
Art Direction by Kam Pui-Ling
Assistant Directors:
Xu Shiao-Liang, Chiu Liu-Kong
Production Manager: Lee Siu-Cheung
Props: Lee Ching-Fu
Edited by Leung Wing-Chan
Sound by Cheung Wah
Stunt Directors:
Jackie Chan, Luk Chuen
Photography Director: Chan Wing-Shu
Lighting: Hui Muk-Wong
Master Ting, this is the place.
I can't find my way blindfolded.
Get me a stick.
What? A stick?
I promise not to hit anyone with it.
Master Ting,
I have nothing to do with this.
I know your boss is testing
my Kung Fu. Let's go.
This way...
It's here.
Master Ting, please wait a moment.
Hey, if you don't remove my blindfold
now, I might really become blind.
This place is quite impressive.
Such good wine and food,
but no one's touching it.
You're overly cautious. You're my
invited guest, I won't poison you.
I'm used to my own chopsticks.
I'm Lam Nan.
Lady Nan...
I'm very different from the big
bosses you've met, aren't I?
You didn't invite me here
just to wine and dine me, right?
I've been hearing the name
Ting Chung for a long time.
You're brave and good at Kung Fu,
you're a busybody but a fair judge,
you fight a lot and hardly ever lose,
not many people can beat you,
even if you're blindfolded...
That's why you're the one.
- The one for what?
- The one to die for us.
I won't die. If a cat has nine lives,
I've got eighteen.
How many lives do you have left now?
I don't keep track.
I've got more than one.
You certainly do... One is
my brother's and one is mine.
Where do you want me
to deliver your lives?
- The Stormy Mountains.
- Are you crazy?
I'm not crazy.
My younger brother is very ill.
If I can't get him to the capital
to Yip the physician in three days,
I'll have to watch him die.
The only way to get there in time
is through the Stormy Mountains.
Do you know how many bandits
there are in the Stormy Mountains?
They'll want your body,
your money and your lives.
That's why I'm hiring you
to be our bodyguard.
Money is no object.
Just name your price.
How much do you think
my life is worth?
I'll pay whatever you ask.
I have no price.
I might be worthless.
I'm curious. Why pick me?
As you have so many lives, only you
would agree to be our bodyguard.
You're right. You've found
a lunatic to die for you.
This lunatic doesn't work
for money or lives.
- What do you work for?
- Nothing.
- Why are you agreeing to go?
- You'll never guess.
I've also employed
a few highly skilled assistants.
- You'll lead them.
- Can I meet them?
Certainly.
Lady Nan.
Here they are.
They're all very well trained.
I'll pick just a few.
You... you...
You and you...
Those I've picked stand over here,
the rest stand there.
Those I picked can work as porters.
The rest can go now.
What? Work as porters?
That's what you're fit for.
Ting, are you doing this to deny us
the chance to make some money?
What's the use of money
if you'll die while making it?
You can't get rid of us this way.
What can you do?
Any more challengers?
With their kind of Kung Fu, they'll
surely die on the Stormy Mountains.
They're really useless.
Would you be OK alone?
I have to bring two guys with me.
- Who are they?
- I don't know.
- I have three holes to show you.
- Three holes?
Look at the first hole.
I made this secretly.
I was blindfolded but not blind.
Look at these two holes.
If I was really blind,
these two holes would be on my body.
I'd like to have these two fighters with me.
- Do you think they're of use to you?
- Definitely.
You've got taste.
You picked the two beautiful ones.
Beautiful ones?
Sisters, come and meet
the famous Ting.
On our way!
The formidable Twin Swords.
I'm impressed.
It's our honour, Master Ting.
Well done.
How do you know of them?
I've known of the Twin Swords
for a long time.
We can't go to the Stormy Mountains
without them.
Can we set off now?
- Not yet. I need one more helper.
- Who is he?
Chang, the deaf guy at the city gate
who repairs leather.
- The deaf guy? What use is he to us?
- He's very useful.
This way.
- Here?
- Yes.
Here. Here.
Hit it!
You're the leather repairman?
Is there another reason
you sent for me?
What kind of skin
do you specialise in?
I do them all, except for human skin.
How could he hear me
with all the drumming?
He was reading your lips.
He knows how to lip-read.
Long time no see, Brother Chang.
Brother Chang!
Brother Chang,
why do you always run from me?
You always bring bad news.
- You're quite right.
- There you go.
You can't run.
We've got a business deal.
- Like what?
- We're trading... our lives.
Where?
- The Stormy Mountains?
- Yes.
We really need your help, Chang.
- Are you going?
- How could I refuse such an offer?
It's late now.
What are we waiting for?
For the women. They're usually late.
We can set off now.
Come and get the sedan chair.
I thank you in advance
for this journey.
Why is the sedan chair so wrapped up?
He might suffocate.
- He can't be exposed to the wind.
- Or he can't face anyone.
If he gets worse,
who will be responsible?
Don't forget that she's our boss.
The boss is always right.
Let's go.
- I entrust our affairs to you.
- Rest assured, Lady Nan.
Let's go.
Stop.
The Town of Flags is straight ahead.
Beyond are the Stormy Mountains.
Brother, you go
and check the place out.
There's nothing to check out.
No one's been brave enough to go to
the Stormy Mountains in ten years.
So there's no reason to go to the town.
It's a ghost town.
I know of someone
living in this ghost town.
- Who is it?
- The Old Lady of Mar Po Inn.
That monster who can hardly walk?
I also know that some people
visited this town recently.
Hey, Old Lady!
Finally, I've got customers.
Sir, what would you like to eat?
A spring chicken, pork liver,
steamed prawns and a bottle of wine.
- I don't have...
- What don't you have?
Spring chicken, pork liver,
prawns and wine...
I don't have any of it.
Why did you have them on the menu?
We had them earlier. You're too late.
How late are we?
Ten years too late.
For the past ten years,
I haven't had a single customer.
Where could I get the money
to buy meat and wine?
- What do you have now?
- Egg fried rice.
- And?
- Rice fried egg.
Which one do you want?
Both.
Sir, you're such a kind man.
Two taels of silver. Pay up now.
What? Two taels of silver?
Customers are rare here. We have
to make up for the previous years.
Thank you, sir.
And you two?
- Here you go.
- Take this, too.
Thank you.
Welcome, everyone. Welcome.
No wonder the birds are singing. The
god of fortune is sending customers.
It's more like the work
of the gods of misfortune.
Strange. They paid for the rice,
but no one is eating.
That's all right, I can keep it
for the rest of the week.
Cowards! Shame on you.
I presume you all know of me?
You must be the God of Darts,
Wu of a Thousand Hands.
Right. You robbers are afraid
of just one man. Tsang.
Did he invite you here?
He demanded half of your spoils.
Any opposition will be
skinned alive. Am I right?
- Am I right?
- Yes, yes, yes...
Don't worry. With me around,
he won't dare to even touch you.
But...
I need to collect a protection fee.
How much do you want?
A 3-7 split.
- You take 30%?
- I want 70%.
What?
You want more than Master Tsang?
I'm the God of Darts. Who is he?
What about you?
Wu, these things can't touch me.
Come out here.
I'll only take half your spoils.
First come, first served.
He's back.
- Did you see anything?
- Yes, I did.
What did you see?
- Wu of a Thousand Hands.
- The God of Darts?
He not only lost his hands,
he lost his life and skin as well.
The God of Darts is highly skilled.
Who is more skilful than him?
He also deals with skin,
but not the type I deal with.
What's the difference?
I repair all kinds of skin
except human skin.
- And him?
- He doesn't repair, he only skins...
and he only skins humans.
But he doesn't skin good people.
I know. He must be the famous Tsang.
Thank you, Master Tsang.
Neither of us have enough.
What shall we do?
I'm very old now, but you're still young.
If you take mine, you'll have enough.
Uncle, I can't do that.
You've got a wife and kids.
I'm single
and no one will miss me if I die.
Take mine and you'll have enough.
- That's no good.
- It doesn't matter. Take it.
Stop the hypocrisy!
I've never seen a considerate robber.
I hate the likes of you. If you don't
come in now, I'll skin you two.
Uncle, you go.
- I can't.
- I'm serious, Uncle. You go.
What about you?
Congratulations, you two can go now.
- Go?
- That's what he said.
He's letting us go?
Why are you so dense? Can't you tell?
I know him well.
He's normally a man of few words.
If he scolds you, you're in luck.
Ting, when did you become
such a busybody?
Ask them to go now.
What did he say?
- You two can go now.
- Go, go, go...
Thank you, thank you.
Does he always scold people?
No, it's easier for him to kill
than to scold people.
Hey! Are you coming out, or do we
have to come in and carry you out?
What now?
He's smarter than me.
What? He's left?
Don't worry, we'll find him.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- I need a ride.
- There's someone inside.
- Dead or alive?
If he's alive, tell him to get out.
- He's very amusing.
- Hilarious.
Stop!
Brother Tsang, please be kind.
How are you, Big Brother?
He's bad news,
but you can't ignore me, right?
It's been two years since we
last met. How are you doing?
So-so.
I know you won't go.
You know I'll drag you in.
Do you want to see
who we're protecting?
- Who?
- My brother. He's seriously ill.
Come with us to the mountains.
It'll be fun.
Do you think he'll go?
He killed the God of Darts,
so he will.
Why?
Wu was the lover of Lady Liu
of the Stormy Mountains.
He'd rather go look for Lady Liu than
wait for her to come seeking revenge.
Ten thousand taels of silver
and two jars of good wine.
Is that all you want?
Ten thousand taels of silver?
I'll pay.
A bond
of ten thousand taels of silver
and the finest Nu Er Hong wine
as my gifts to you.
I'm Tsang Mo-Yi, third in the family.
- Your father is Tsang Man-Tien.
- Yes.
Good wine must be shared.
Drink with me?
Certainly.
Go on.
Wonderful wine.
More.
Are you going
to the Stormy Mountains?
Your whole family died doing that.
Do you want to die like them?
No.
The bandits of the Stormy Mountains
are managed by four deputies.
One is called the Scholar,
the second is called Fake Monk,
the third is called Old Wolf
and the last is Lady Liu.
I'll keep that in mind.
The four of them may be powerful,
but I think you can deal with them.
But if you met the Lord, I'm not sure
you'd survive three of his moves.
Who is he?
Did you know that I had a lover?
Look at this portrait of me
when I was young.
Though I wasn't exquisite,
I was considered beautiful.
So he loved me.
He loved my cooking
and visited me often.
He hasn't been visiting lately,
but I believe he'll come soon.
I'll wait for him
until the end of time.
Do you know who he is?
The ruler of the Stormy Mountains,
Lord Chu.
Lord Chu?
You're drunk.
Good wine is hard to come by.
You're a good kid.
I don't want you to die there.
This is for you.
- What can it do?
- It can save lives.
In the mountains, give this to a man
with six fingers on his left hand.
He can save your lives.
Thank you.
There's no need for that.
Be off with you.
# When the spring comes
# Hundreds of flowers start to bloom
# In a garden
of hundreds of flowers
# I wait alone... #
The Stormy Mountains
are a menacing place.
If you don't want to die there,
you have to follow the rules.
Follow the rules?
From now on,
I'm leading the expedition.
Do not leave the group without my
permission and be quiet at all times.
- No drinking, either.
- Can we be flexible on the drinking?
If you break any rules,
I'll skin you alive.
Big Brother, I'll follow all your rules.
Let's go.
Move out!
# The lofty, undulating
Stormy Mountains
# As hard to conquer as the sky
# Dangers and obstacles along the way
# Like the path
leading to the gate of hell
# The four deputies guard the corners
# Lord Chu's skills
are hard to counter
# The Stormy Mountains
may be our graves
# Fast and furious, the Iron Fist
# Spreading virtue and stifling vice
# Friends to share
our woes and worries
# We'll sacrifice to do our duty
# Tsang is a fighter
whom few can match
# Chang is deaf
but his eyes are sharp
# Together, as one,
we'll conquer the Stormy Mountains
# The lofty, undulating
Stormy Mountains
# As hard to conquer as the sky
# Friends to share
our woes and worries
# We'll sacrifice to do our duty
# Tsang is a fighter
whom few can match
# Chang is deaf
but his eyes are sharp
# Together, as one,
we'll conquer the Stormy Mountains #
Pretend you didn't see them.
Go on.
Read their lips
and see what they're talking about.
They said that we'll never
get out of this place alive.
There could be another ambush ahead.
Be careful.
This is only the beginning.
Anyone want to quit?
Tsang, we don't need cynicism.
None of us here are quitters.
Sister, that's rude.
He has no faith in us.
You're not afraid to die?
Good on you.
Let's run across!
Listen.
- What's up?
- Someone's shouting for help.
I can't hear it.
I heard it too.
It's coming from over there.
They'll be victims of the robbers
in these parts.
Nonsense, I don't see anything.
Are you blind?
There are so many wounded there.
I can't see them.
Don't forget
we still have a long way to go.
How can we leave them here to die?
Sister, let's go and see.
- They've fallen for it.
- Right.
- They're faking it.
- Faking?
They said we've fallen for it.
Guard the sedan.
Drop your weapon, or I'll kill her!
Let's help them.
No need, Tsang can deal with it.
Come here.
I know you're the skinner.
Do you dare to skin me?
Maybe... not.
Come any closer and I'll kill her.
If she dies, you'll die as well.
Let her go.
I said let her go.
Let her go!
- Now get lost!
- OK.
He was so fierce a moment ago, Sister.
Look how obedient he is now.
- Go thank that gentleman.
- OK.
Thank you for saving my life.
Serves you right.
Didn't I tell you to get lost?
What are you waiting for?
Go!
Mister, thank you for saving my sister.
It's my pleasure, ladies.
Courtesy is a way of life. Take this!
I'm Wan Leung Yoke.
I'm familiar with your reputations.
Your visit has livened up
this uneventful place.
Mr Wan,
what is it you really want to say?
The Stormy Mountains
are full of danger.
If you don't want to die, be careful.
Mr Wan,
why are you being so kind to us?
I'm concerned about my assets.
What you're guarding
will soon be mine.
Come and get it, then.
Robbers also have standards.
Courtesy before aggression.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Hope you survive the night.
Bye for now. See you tomorrow.
Chasing your enemy is foolish. As
you're still young, I'll forgive you.
If you leave the group again,
I'll skin you alive.
You lot stay here to guard the sedan.
Let's check the place out.
It's strangely quiet here.
Big Brother,
this must be the Luo Han Temple.
The candles are lit.
There must be monks here.
I'll go get them.
Did you say we're in
the Luo Han Temple?
Haven't you seen those eighteen
Luo Han Buddhas there?
Eighteen Luo Han Buddhas?
The weapons in their hands are
different from the Luo Han Buddha's.
Could be another ambush.
Let's get out of here.
Get out.
- I can't take it any more!
- Me either!
- How do we get out?
- We'll be carried out as corpses!
Hey, what are you two doing?
- We'll be dead soon!
- You'll die with us!
Me, die with you?
Fine.
BUDDHA
No one escapes from
the Chamber of Monster Bells.
Sifu, the three of them
will stop breathing soon.
This is Ting Chung.
He's got the world's fastest punch.
What a pity
that I won't get to witness it.
Now you'll get to witness
my stinking feet.
Now you'll know how fast I can punch.
Let's get out of here!
They won't give up that easily.
We'll be in more danger
if we don't escape.
I'm worried about the ones outside.
- Let us out.
- OK.
That way!
I waited here just like you said to,
so am I a good girl?
Cut that crap out.
What took you so long?
I was worried for you guys.
This place isn't safe. Let's go.
Please don't worry.
I'm a businessman, not a robber.
Don't be afraid.
There's nothing to worry about.
You're safe here.
I really am a businessman
and not a robber. Don't worry.
Doing business
in the Stormy Mountains?
I'm the only one doing it.
With so many robbers,
what business can you have?
Even robbers need to eat and drink.
I make their lives here bearable.
So they let me run
a small business here.
It's getting dark soon.
It's lucky you met me, or you
wouldn't get any peace tonight.
Is there a peaceful place
in the Stormy Mountains?
- There's only one.
- Where is it?
Peace Hotel. That's my place.
Shameless self-promotion.
You only care about our money.
I can guarantee your safety, but I
only welcome certain kinds of people.
- What kind of people?
- Rich people.
Only the very rich, because I do
charge more than your average hotel.
How much more?
20 to 30 times more.
That's daylight robbery!
I can't help it.
I don't have many customers.
What kind of people are you,
may I ask?
- Rich people.
- That's right.
We're filthy rich.
That's wonderful. This way, please.
I assure you, you'll feel safe and
peaceful as soon as you're inside.
I have an agreement with the robbers.
- Boss, you're back.
- Yes.
Ask them to keep quiet.
Stop!
Sir, I thought we'd agreed that you'd
let me run my business in peace.
But they're not
inside your hotel yet.
Who killed my brother, Iron Wolf?
I did.
So you're the skinning swordsman. Did
you kill my brother with that sword?
I don't have to draw this sword
to defeat scum like you.
You sure talk big. Come over,
I'll avenge my brother today.
Big Brother, let me deal with him.
I'm second, I'll be next in line.
Stand aside.
Let's play.
Who are you?
A leather repairman.
What weapon do you use?
Legs.
Legs? It's not fair.
That's to your advantage.
Move back!
Impressive kicks.
I've been walking the whole day,
so my feet might smell.
Time to vomit?
Enter, please.
Your Kung Fu isn't quite there yet.
Get lost.
Let's go.
Everything is fine now.
Please go in.
Look how spacious and peaceful
my place is. You'll like it.
- Which is the biggest room?
- That one.
Can I carry the sedan to the room?
What? You want to carry
the sedan into the room?
That's what I just asked you.
Of course you can. Rich people
can do whatever they like.
- Bring the sedan in.
- OK, come in, please.
- This way.
- Come in, please.
- Be careful.
- Slowly...
- That's the way.
- Straight through...
Staff, brew some nice tea
and prepare some food.
They're filthy rich,
give them the best service.
Please knock before entering my room.
I'm here to ask you something.
- Is it about the sedan?
- Something's fishy about it.
What's so fishy about it?
Have you ever seen anyone carrying
a sedan into a room before?
I thought the patient
couldn't be exposed to the wind.
I wonder if it's the wind, or if
it's that he can't expose his face.
- Are you curious?
- Aren't you?
Let's go, then.
Can you sleep comfortably
in the sedan?
There's no wind here.
Come out for a chat.
What are you doing here?
No one's around. I stayed
to find out what's happening.
Big Brother, what's going on?
- Let's discuss this outside.
- OK.
Big Brother, do you know
what they're up to?
I'm risking my life
guarding an empty sedan.
How do you know it's empty?
You saw it before.
I didn't see anything.
I was sleeping in my room.
I was sleeping in my room, too.
They're definitely smarter than me.
Dinner for 14 costs
135 taels of silver...
Water costs five taels, candles
five taels, and toilet paper...
Boss, hurry up, please.
We've got a long way to go.
I'm a fair businessman.
I need to charge you accurately...
- Pearl...
- What do you need?
Get me some medicine.
Quickly.
It's 245 taels of silver in total.
Your place is really pricey.
I've been very fair, I told you
in advance that we're expensive.
You're our best guests.
Please come again.
Fat chance.
- Let's go.
- What's the rush?
Have some hot tea before you go.
It's half-price.
- Let's go.
- Have a safe journey.
- Quick.
- All right.
- Big Brother.
- What?
- Did you see?
- See what?
- There's someone in the sedan.
- Did I say it was empty?
- Why didn't he meet us?
- Why must he meet you?
Big Brother, this way is very dangerous.
What choice do we have?
This is the only way through
the Stormy Mountains.
Wan. He's really waiting for us.
Glad to see you again.
You look fresh and well rested.
You must have slept comfortably.
You seem to care a lot about us.
I don't care about you. I care about
the assets of mine you're guarding.
On what condition
will you let us through?
- My conditions are simple.
- Spit it out.
I'll keep the treasure,
he'll keep the ladies...
He? Who's he?
Amitabha...
He's me... I'm him.
That's how it works in the Stormy
Mountains. We split equally.
So you'll split it equally?
What about the other men here?
Each of the men must leave a hand here.
It's up to you which hand.
You're a scholar.
We're simply passing through.
Is there room for negotiation?
I always mean what I say.
End of discussion.
What if we disagree?
It's up to you.
You have till the afternoon
to consider your options.
Don't be foolish. If you don't
believe me, just take a look...
This is our territory.
Unless you meet our demands,
you must suffer the consequences.
Retreat!
Big Brother, we can make a run for it.
You might be able to.
What about the rest?
At least we could try.
We can't take that chance,
unless it's our last resort.
What can we do now?
There's one person who can help us.
Who is he?
I don't know. All I know is that he's
got six fingers on his left hand.
Six fingers?
Oh... six fingers?
- Where can we find him?
- He might know.
- The hotel owner?
- Yes, I'll go look for him.
If you see the six-fingered man,
give him this. He'll save us.
How will you get out of here?
You guys have to cover me.
Why did you grope me? I'd rather
be with that monk than you!
When did I touch you?
- I'll teach you to harass my sister!
- Stop being unreasonable!
- How dare you?
- Stop, please!
- Mister.
- My beloved guest.
You're here again.
What business
are you bringing me this time?
I've got some
unusually big business for you.
I thank you in advance.
How many guests?
It's not accommodation...
I want to sell you something.
Something to sell me? What is it?
Someone's life.
- Whose life?
- Yours.
My life belongs to me.
It's mine now.
Do you want it back?
It's no use threatening me.
I grew up with robbers.
Is it because I overcharged you
and you want your money back?
- I don't want money.
- What do you want, then?
- Help us cross the mountains.
- Cross the mountains?
I don't know of anyone who's made it
across the Stormy Mountains alive.
You'd have to cross
with Lord Chu's blessing.
- Take me to see Lord Chu.
- Me? I'm not that influential.
I'm just a businessman.
Why are you doing this?
Help me look for someone.
- Who is he?
- A six-fingered man.
- Why are you looking for him?
- I have something for him.
Bring me to Lord Chu.
He can't help you,
even if you threaten to kill him.
I'm the only person who can do that.
You must be the notorious Lady Liu?
That's right.
Are you the one
who killed the God of Darts?
I'm Ting Chung.
So you're the Ting with many lives.
The world's fastest boxer.
I'm familiar with your reputation.
Can you take me to see Lord Chu?
Yes, but...
you killed my lover, the God
of Darts. Find me a replacement.
This guy's eloquent
and has good business acumen.
He'll be a fantastic lover for you.
No, I don't like him.
Who do you like?
I like you.
May I have a cuddle?
Your punches really live up
to my expectations.
What else can you do, you bastard?
First I'll blind you in both your eyes,
then I'll take you home
and torture you slowly.
You've inhaled poisonous gas.
You'll die in a few hours.
Luckily I found the antidote on her.
You...
So it's you.
They've been surrounded
and their lives are in danger.
They must be in Death Valley. Take
the antidote, I'll see what I can do.
Can you save them?
I'm wearing a good-luck charm.
I hope it helps.
I'll be back soon.
Tsang, it's past noon now.
Why haven't we had any news?
Don't worry.
There'll be a way out.
Look.
- How did you get here?
- Don't worry, I'll get you out.
Why should I trust you?
Look.
It's you. Thank you.
Let's go with him.
Fellows, listen up!
They carry Lord Chu's insignia!
Let them through.
Let's go.
Fellows, listen up!
They carry Lord Chu's insignia!
You have to let them through.
Fellows, listen up!
They carry Lord Chu's insignia!
Please let them through.
- How is it?
- I've taken them to a safer place.
- They can't cross the mountain yet.
- Why?
No one crosses the mountain
without Lord Chu's permission.
Take me to Lord Chu. If he doesn't
let us through, I'll fight him.
- It's no use, unless...
- Unless what?
Trade in your fists.
Is he interested in my fists?
Yes, I know that he lacks
a pair of fast, strong fists.
Sounds like a business deal.
Yes, I'm a businessman.
I'll make sure you get a good deal.
Where are my friends?
Only I know where they are.
I want to see them first.
OK, follow me.
Where are they?
Are you trying to trick me?
Nonsense.
Why would I to lie to you?
You're too mysterious
for me to trust you completely.
- This is...
- They've definitely been here.
- Lady Nan!
- Tsang!
NAMO AMITABHA
Long live Lord Chu.
Rise.
Are you Ting Chung?
We're helping an ill man across the
mountains. Please give us permission.
I can't break the rules of
the Stormy Mountains just for you.
Isn't Lord Chu interested in my fists?
If you let us through,
you'll have free use of these fists.
You may be willing to offer them,
but I need to try them out first.
I'm not sure if your fists
are worth that much.
- Iron Man.
- Here!
He's learnt the Thirteenth Prince
fighting technique.
His left punch is 300 pounds,
his right is 500 pounds.
Impressive.
See if you can handle my Iron Fist.
You call these Iron Fists?
Lord Chu, I deserve to die...
- Begone!
- Yes...
Thank you, Lord, for sparing my life.
Is Lord Chu satisfied with my fists?
Yes, if you stay here with us,
you'll be handsomely rewarded.
What about my friends?
Your friends are safe with us.
They've just eaten and showered.
They're resting now.
- Where are they?
- There.
Sister, look at him.
We've been tricked.
You lied to me?
I haven't lied to you. I was helping
the Old Lady of Mar Po Inn
to get you out of Death Valley.
I'm Lord Chu's man.
How could I betray him?
I had to bring you here.
Don't forget that I hate liars.
Tsang, don't threaten me.
Have you forgotten where you are?
No matter where I am,
I'll skin you alive.
Big Brother, watch out!
How dare you kill my man
right in front of me?
I haven't killed a man, I killed a mongrel.
You don't have much respect for me.
I have no wish to offend you.
We have no conflict of interest.
If you let us through,
I'll repay your kindness one day.
What if I refuse?
We'll have to do it by force.
You two are very naive.
Luckily for you, I've just struck
a deal with your friend,
or I'd let you learn
from your mistake.
- We just need your blessing.
- We're not afraid to die.
I will settle this peacefully
for Ting's sake,
but I'll need to know
what's in the sedan.
It's my brother. He's very ill.
Is he really ill?
Of course. Why would I lie to you?
All right, can I meet him?
He can't be exposed to the wind.
It'll kill him.
Death from wind exposure?
I don't believe it.
Can't you hear how sick he is?
- I must look at him!
- I urge you not to disturb him.
- Force him out!
- Yes!
Didn't I warn you not to disturb him?
As I expected, the best fighter
among you is inside the sedan.
Please show yourself.
A trivial trick. Get out!
- What's happening?
- Just watch.
It's been five years.
We will settle our old scores today.
The Old Lady of Mar Po Inn!
- It's unbelievable!
- How strange...
I was forced into hiding
for five years, all because of her.
Lord Chu, it's our fault
that we mistook her for you.
Lord Chu, how did it happen?
She came to me for help ten years ago.
For old times' sake, I let her
run the inn in the Town of Flags.
I never thought she'd set me up.
She used my name for material gains.
Lord Chu, how could she sound
so similar to you?
She'd planned it right from the start
and had made a mask of my face.
Imitating my voice
wasn't a problem for her.
She drugged me
and tried to bury me alive.
I managed to escape and came back
to the Stormy Mountains.
That's when I realised
that there was another Lord Chu.
When I went to the inn,
the Old Lady was there, too.
I was puzzled. To get to the bottom
of this, I went underground.
What has this got to do with Lady Nan?
She's my daughter
and had never lived in the mountains.
We'd planned this for five years
before we got to see the Old Lady.
Now the truth is out.
I'm here and I'm the rightful Lord.
Long live Lord Chu!
Health and power to Lord Chu!
Father...
Uncle Chu.
- You may rise.
- Thank you, Lord Chu.
I thank you for your effort
in making this possible.
Stay here with me
and you'll live in luxury.
A life of luxury is not what we seek.
Rejecting my offer
is not very respectful.
I'm sorry, we've not
completed our mission yet.
What mission?
To help you cross the mountains
to get to the capital.
The Stormy Mountains are home.
I'm not going to the capital.
- You have to.
- Why?
You've occupied the Stormy Mountains
for nearly 20 years.
I must take you to the capital
to face justice.
Can you?
Lord Chu, do you remember
that the imperial army
tried to retake this place 15 years ago?
You killed over a thousand soldiers
and General Ting Kwok-Chung.
How are you related?
He was my father.
No wonder you joined this mission
with no care for money or your life.
There's no way any of you will get
out of the Stormy Mountains alive.
I must avenge my father's death
and rid the world of crooks like you.
Father!
Run!
We'll take it in turn to exhaust him.
Big Brother, I got him!