Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Masked Love Team @ Viki.com
♫ The martial arts world in my mind ♫
♫ The wonderful scenes are ever changing ♫
♫ Looking back at my ordinary face again ♫
♫ I don’t wish to owe anything ♫
♫ I am deeply immersed in you ♫
♫ In such a dilemma that I wish to back out ♫
♫ The shyness is slowly replaced by carefreeness ♫
♫ The corners of my mouth lifted up with sweetness ♫
♫ I want to think of you more each day ♫
♫ I just want to be side by side with you Starring as a hero couple ♫
♫ The corners of my mouth lifted up with sweetness ♫
♫ Inexplicable joy so obvious ♫
♫ Even if there’s ups and downs and life pulls a heavy punch ♫
♫That’s  also a happy minor test of life ♫
[Face Off]
[Episode 10]
Let me tell you, use whatever way to persuade Yunyun to come back.
This concerns the cooperation between Darwin and ZM Group.
Nothing else matters. You women
never know what's more important.
Dad, how many times have I told you?
Yunyun and my wedding has nothing to do with the co-operation. If you want to use our wedding
to gain any benefits from Darwin, then you should forget it.
This isn't the reason why I want to marry Yunyun.
What is wrong with you lately? Why do you talk back to me?
Who did you learn it from? Did you know if someone else heard what you said,
everyone would think of it as a joke.
You better remember your role as the general manager.
The collaboration between two major corporations won't last long if there isn't any marriage union to fall back on.
Also, the projects for cooperation with Darwin,
you better not mess it up. If you do,
you might as well not get married.
Don't worry. I will do as you wish.
To complete the wedding perfectly.
But it isn't because of any advantage, nor it is for ZM Group.
I did it for myself.
Can't you just go with our son for once?
Just now, those were the  stirrings of love on your face.
How do you change so much when we talk about work?
I'm depressed.
I still can't get Ian's recognition in Bertone.
He doesn't even regard me as his student.
I've worked so hard, it's not for my idol to hate me.
Stop drinking! You're drinking wine as if it were water. It's bad for you skin.
Who cares. Only alcohol can comfort me now.
Look, Tian!
Now that Qianjin said that he likes me,
I don't know what has gotten over him. I think I should go look for a Daoist priest to change my fortune.
Why is it bad luck if Qianjin likes you?
This is a fate that Heaven has destined.
No, no. I don't want it.
Right now, I'm worried about this situation. So awkward.
What happened to the fearless Chen Zhen that I knew? Has she gone missing?
The fearless Chen Zhen has been defeated by reality.
I've been despised by my idol. I've been overwhelmed by my inferiority–
Then just be re-born it again.
What do you mean?
For example, accept Qianjin's confession.
Maybe Qianjin is the right man for you in this life.
With him as the man behind you, all things will go smoothly for you
and lead straight to success.
I'm going to the toilet.
Zhen!
Enough.
Why can't you love me?
I loved you for more than ten years.
Can you bear to push me away?
Do you have someone that you like?
If you don't, then can you
see the fact that I have waited for you for over ten years–
Don't talk about this. I ignored your feelings.
It was my problem, sorry. If I found out earlier, then this may not have happened.
You can't stop it. There's nothing you can do.
Just like me, I thought I could not love you.
But I can't do it.
Stop saying such things.
Which part of me isn't good?
Why are you always cold towards me?
- I treat everyone the same.
- No.
You don't treat Wang Xiao like that. You are warm towards him and bear with him.
Because Wang Xiao loves me,
so... you controlled yourself to not love me. Am I right?
Yunyun, I've already clearly told you about my rejection.
I don't understand. I really don't understand.
What is the barrier that's stopping us?
Some people don't have love from birth. You can't tell me to use something I don't have.
Don't use this lousy reason to reject me.
That means that you really don't understand me.
Why are they here?
Two love rivals appearing at the same time. This can only mean one thing.
You mean that...
Shen Yun knows about Ian and Wang Xiao's relationship and told him to come here?
To negotiate.
The plot is reaching closer to the climax.
What do we do? I'm so nervous. So exciting.
Hey, Zhenzhen. Who are you rooting for?
Of course, Shen Yun. A woman should support other women.
And those two men have deceived her from the beginning. We can't tolerate it.
But these two men, one is prince charming and the other is your master.
I don't care anymore. In the face of morality and justice, I choose
righteousness!
After you left, I tried my best to be worthy of you.
I've studied my way up to the research institute.
I entered the company and worked hard to make the company
increase in sales. I just wanted
every part of me to be perfect and outstanding.
I also hope that one day
that  you will realize that I'm the brightest star. I want you to notice me.
Maybe love is what motivated you to go forward, but that's not my case and it will never be.
So much that it doesn't even cross my sight.
Do you not need love?
I indeed do not need it.
So if you want it, I can't give you any.
Please don't leave!
Why do you like me? Because you're the princess.
You're looking forward to some day that a prince will come and save you. But I'm not that prince.
Wang Xiao is your prince.
No, he's not. If one day you can love someone,
then you'll understand how "she" is
more important than your life.
You place too much importance on love, it's too unhealthy.
You're the one that's unhealthy.
You've worked so hard within the 10 years because you were looking for that one person.
Rejecting love, rejecting all women around you.
Now your mother isn't here anymore. You should think for yourself.
A person can't live without love.
You drank too much. I will get some water for you.
You can't leave!
Can't you just look at me? I'm Shen Yun.
The Shen Yun whom everyone cherishes and regards as their darling.
Why can't you see me? Why can't you care?
Ten years ago, you left without a note. Now you're leaving  again?
You can't leave without taking responsibility.
Today, we must be clear on everything.
I'm sorry.
Stop! Don't go!
That person there, what's his situation?
How should I know? Let's wait and see.
Uh, she had a bit too much today. She didn't mean to splash on you.
What do you mean not on purpose? Then do you mean she poured it on me and it's fine?
- No.. I don't mean that
- What does it have to do with you?
- Okay, enough.
Go away!
- Then what do you want?
- Pay up.
We are men. Just let go of it, all right? Bye.
What are you looking at? You should hurry home!
Why are you so fierce?
You have to feel sorry toward Shen Yun. Aren't you responsible for hurting her and losing her happiness?
Hey, stop! Don't go!
You made my clothes wet and you want to leave? Pay for it!
Pay what for? Are you trying to extort money?
- I'm extorting you, so?
- I detest people like you. Go in and we will discuss. Come, come.
- Hey!
- Go in.
Don't start a fight! Stop it!
They are starting a fight.
- Don't fight!
- Don't fight! Don't fight!
- Stop!
- Stop fighting.
Did I cause this? What do we do? Should we call the police?
Call the police. Hurry!
Or should we call the ambulance?
- Which one should we call?
- The police!
Stop it! Don't fight anymore!
- Save me!
- What are you screaming for?
You don't even admit that I'm your disciple. I don't know any martial arts, how do I save you?
You did this to yourself. Let's go.
You traitor!
Warrior, I never knew you were so good at fighting. You made me worry for nothing.
I will find time to settle this score with you.
Did I say something wrong?
Did you get hurt?
Can you stop being so impulsive!
Don't think you're on your own and nothing matters.
If something bad happen to you, what should I do?
Let me go!
Let go.
Wang Xiao...
Hey, look out!
Yunyun, are you all right?
- Are you hurt?
- I'm okay.
Why are you so good to me?
It's okay.
Who did this?
Who started the fight? What happened?
Hey, he started first! My hands are bleeding already.
How can you say that! It was them who started it.
Yes! I can be the witness!
Why did you start the fight?
- His hand is hurt. Can he go to the hospital first?
- I'm all right.
The bottle was smashed. How could you say it's fine?
If they go to the hospital, we are going too. See, I'm also bleeding.
- That's right.
- Quiet down. Back to my original question.
Why did you start the fight?
We couldn't stand him cheating that lady's feelings.
We were lending a helping hand. Is that wrong?
Sir, you've misunderstood!
I think you've misunderstood my relationship with my older brother.
Older brother?!
My name is Wang Xiao.
- He is called Wang Yi.
- Really an idiot!
Miss Chen, do you admit you are guilty?
Sir, please let me live. I'm innocent.
Outrageous shrew! It's clear you who can't distinguish right and wrong.
This is deliberate misrepresentation, spreading false rumors everywhere, tarnishing others' reputation.
How are you innocent?
Sir, I didn't do it on purpose. I admit my mistake.
Even though you admit, but the mistake has already been made.
This crime cannot be revoked.
Sir!
How should I punish you?
She loves to gossip. How about slicing her tongue off?
Blinded from the truth. How about taking her eyes out?
If there is a problem with someone's intelligence, even if you slice her tongue and pull her eyes out
that still doesn't solve the problem.
Let her learn how to become how a good person again; learn the right ethics.
But a person's intelligence is already set from birth, you can't change it.
That's true. No matter how hard a pig washes itself, it is still a pig.
You guys are right. I'm not even worth a pig.
How about I die instead?
-This is a big misunderstanding.
-So I was right.
- It was him. He toyed with the lady's feelings.
- Right.
You are trying to give me a love story, right?
Who can say it clearly?
Miss Shen, can you confirm your relationship between you three?
One is my fiance...
- I am their brother--
- ...and the person I love.
Wang Xiao, Shen Yun has drunk too much.
Wang Xiao, I...
You don't have to explain anymore.
Sorry. If there isn't anything else, can I leave?
You have to resolve your love problems in private.
After you sign here, you can go.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Masked Love Team @ Viki.com
When we were little, I knew you were the person she liked.
You have always been my big hero. I could only follow behind you.
During the time while you were away, I thought I could replace you in her heart.
But I never thought...
I'm very sorry. I put you in this situation.
It's not your fault. I know you didn't do anything.
If I had resolved this well, then the result may not be this bad.
Hearing what you say,
you already knew! Why didn't you tell me?
I was worried you'd think too much. I thought Yunyun was just temporarily out of her mind.
Temporarily?
Ten years isn't short, right?
- Sorry
- You don't have to apologize.
The more you do this, the more you make me feel like a failure.
Miss Shen.
Miss Shen, don't blame me for minding so much. I just want to ask.
General Manager treats you so well. Why don't you love him?
Him being nice and me loving him or not are two different matters.
- But we can see that General Manager really loves you!
- Enough!
This has nothing to do with you two.
How pitiful.
General Manager must be really hurt right now.
I never thought prince charming would be abandoned by the princess.
Please don't overthink it. Your wound hasn't healed yet, let me take you to the hospital.
I'm okay.
Comparing to what happen today, this injury is a small matter. I won't die from it.
I want to be by myself.
Brother Wang Yi,
I... I know whatever I say is wrong.
But the person who I don't want to hurt the most is Wang Xiao.
You've already hurt him.
♫   I sigh every time you pass me  ♫
♫  It's the expression of suffering, gain and loss ♫
Why are you here? Don't you hate these types of events?
I am here to stick a tag.
What tag?
Shen Yun is the property of Wang Xiao. Whoever dares to touch her,
you will die.
Marry me.
If you aren't prepared to be my wife, then I can delay the wedding.
I want to be your wife. I want to marry you as soon as possible.
- Brother, are you okay?
- Are you all right?
Why are you still getting into fights with others? Don't you know how important your hands are?
If they are hurt, how can you continue in the special effects makeup field?
[Sorry, I don't love you.]
Tell me why!
She might've just temporarily lost her mind.
Look at her.
I'm their brother--
...and the person I love.
♫ For you to understand yourself ♫
♫ You were also willing ♫
♫ To send the message of love ♫
What type of homework is this?
This is just making things difficult for me.
Later, I will demonstrate to everyone.
Every step of the skill and the materials needed, you must write down.
Because we have a test in one week.
What are you doing?
Today, Teacher Wu Qing is teaching us alien special effects makeup.
Alien?
- I want to look, too!
- You're not allowed.
Quickly go back. Don't you know she kills people? If she finds out, you are done for. If you're done for, I am, too.
She won't find out, I'll hide behind you.
I'll hide.
Today, we're doing a simple model of an alien.
Let's see what we need to use during this process.
Liquid glue.
Face mask.
Bald head cover.
Black and white paint.
The clay you use to make the teeth.
You can change the shape of this clay by adding water.
Today we will be molding it into a longish shape.
and make an alien's horns.
Are you trying to get me in trouble?
This is the button from home which I wanted to throw away.
I thought it looked like alien's eyes, so I used it.
You guys must always observe the items around you.
You must keep all usable things that are unique, creative.
You must be ready to use them on your special effects art.
Teacher Wu Qing really puts materials to good use.
She can even think of using buttons to use as alien's eyes.
Or else she wouldn't be a teacher.
- You shouldn't talk.
- I won't talk.
When it dries, we will do a few copies.
For example, like this sharp style.
When it dries, within the special effects work, you can use it to kill people.
So amazing, you can make this out of clay?
Stop talking! I beg you. Just stay right there.
- But I can't see it.
- Even if you can't see it, you still shouldn't talk.
I won't speak. I'll just look.
What are you two talking about?
- Oh. Nothing.
- Who's behind you?
- There's no one behind me.
- No one's behind me.
- Who is it?
No...
Chen Zhen?
Hi, Teacher Wu Qing, what a coincidence.
You're Ian's student, why are you in my class? Do you have any intentions?
I don't have any intention, I just want to learn.
You're not learning with Ian but instead you're here?
Do you think that you can't learn anything from Ian?
It's not that I can't learn anything. It's because I don't understand everything Ian teaches me.
Let's go. Go!
Come with me.
What is she up to?
These are all the documents.
Ian is here, too? That's great.
What's wrong? Why are you two together?
Boss, don't be anxious. I just want to tell you something quite interesting.
Oh? What interesting thing?
This student Chen Zhen came to my class to listen in secretly.
I really do want to ask Ian, how do you teach your students?
Letting your students go to other teacher's class to learn secretly. Is that your way of teaching?
- You ingrate! Where are you off to?
- Master!
You betrayed our sect. Today, I am going to disable your martial arts, and purge you out of the sect.
Master! I had no choice.
Stop talking nonsense, take my hit!
Master!
My way of teaching is my business. No one else can have a say on it.
That's right. How ever you teach your student indeed isn't my business.
And I don't care about it either. So I plan on asking her.
Chen Zhen, you came to class today to listen in secretly.
Is it  because you want to learn from me?
Then do you think that you can't learn anything from Ian, and want to learn from me?
Of course not. I went today because I was curious.
Wu Qing, students want to improve themselves is a good thing.
You should all be their teacher.
Boss, I don't have any other intention.
I'm just thinking if Ian is too busy  and doesn't have time to take her,
and I see Chen Zhen is so willing to learn, I am quite happy to take her in.
Then let her go with you. I really don't have enough time to take her.
If there are even better chances to learn, then that's good for her, too.
You get busy. I have something on so I'm leaving.
Ian really does have special perks.
He doesn't even need to teach students. So easy for him.
Wait! How can you just push me to another teacher?
Teacher Wu Qing is one of the professional special effects artist within the country. Learning  under her is your good fortune.
I know my actions today weren't good, but...
But I just wanted to learn more things.
Are the things I get you to do not considered learning?
You're just making me draw. I know that drawing is the basic of special effects art,
but... I don't understand;  I don't even know what I'm doing.
After many days, I haven't learned one technique on special effects art.
If you really think this way, I really don't know what you can do in the future?
Compared to others, my progress rate is slower.
You think it's nothing because you're busy and have projects to accept.
But you don't understand the anxiety and fear I have of not being able to do anything.
Aren't you just that impatient to successfully become a master within a short time?
You aren't a genius. If you don't go the normal way, you will fall.
Your skills and attitude don't fulfill the requisites of being a special effects artist, so I don't want to teach you.
You've finally said the words in your heart!
Do I have to say them again? Go report to Wu Qing this afternoon.
No! Don't give me to Teacher Wu Qing. Don't be like this to me.
Can you not be this loud? People will think I did something bad to you.
You really are bad to me.
I originally drew you out as my teacher. I was originally your student.
But you've been very cold to me, and you don't treat me like a student.
You even said that I'm not your student. You make me very sad.
If you're like this, then I will never let you follow me anymore.
Wait... Please don't let me go to Teacher Wu Qing there.
I beg you. If I learn under her, I will be done for.
Luo Wen is almost dead learning under her.
I don't want my graduation day to be my funeral day.
Have you thought of your own problem? All day you just want to become successful.
Let me ask,. Have you ever been mature enough to ask me to bring you to the production crew?
-No, but–
- Teacher Wang Yi,
This is the production company's contract. If you think it's fine, then you can sign it.
You've never told me your thoughts before. How would I know what you're thinking about?
Shut up!
Didn't you go to Wu Qing to learn? So you shouldn't be following me.
Don't go around being jealous.
So boring. Who's the one jealous?
Wait!
I want to have a conversation with you today.
Okay. I give you 2 minutes. Get on with the main points.
I wish you'd see me as your student and teach me well.
Even though Sha Tian, Meili, Luo Wen all work very hard and are exhausted,
you can tell they are learning a lot.
And my special effects notebook is still blank.
The things in the notebook, you study them enough at school and cram school. No need to come here.
Do you know what I'm going to say?
Am I not giving you a chance to express yourself?
Let me ask you. Why are you so anxious?
Of course, I'm anxious. I'm anxious to become a special effects artist!
I'm anxious to be successful and earn money. I'm rushing to renovate my house.
I'm anxious to buy my dad a big shop. I want to give my dad a better life.
To you, it's nothing if you don't teach me well; but to me,
it just means that my future is without hope.
I've told you. If you follow me, then you have to do as I say.
If you're not happy or don't have the brains to understand, then you can leave anytime.
Two minutes are up. Don't take your emotions on me.
What has he done to Chen Zhen?
I'm very curious.
Teacher Zifan, no matter what you do to me, I still won't get angry.
- Dig your nostrils.
- Okay.
Zhenzhen, why did you come home so early?
When I left Bertone, Meili and Luo Wen were still there.
That's right. I'm the only student who's the most free.
Being free is good. If you're so busy to a point that you don't have time to eat, then it'll only make you feel bad.
If you don't understand then don't speak. I'm pissed off right now.
Okay. Then I won't say anything.
I'll cook for you. You're probably hungry so you're angry.
You'll feel better after you eat.
Zhenzhen, are you angry because I let him in?
I was venting my anger of Ian on him.
Then are you still willing to be his friend?
I think you need to have a good conversation with him.
Enough, talk to each other.
- Qianjin.
- Go sit in the living room. I'll be done soon.
I have something to say to you.
What?
I don't understand. I thought the person who you liked was Sha Tian.
A girl like Sha Tian,
she's pretty, has a sweet voice, very gentle and knows how to dress prettily. Out of ten men, eleven would like her.
I don't even look good, my voice isn't sweet either.
My body isn't great, I'm not gentle and could possibly beat you in a fight. Are you blind?
What do you like about me?
I don't know either.
I just know that I want to see you everyday.
I want to see you smile. I want to see that you are happy after eating the food I cook.
Stop talking!
Then you should know when you started to like me.
It's... that time.
The first time you went to the restaurant to eat.
Hey, Zhenzhen. Put your foot down.
- What's wrong?
- You're not like a girl. That way you can't find a boyfriend.
My man would love every part of me.
What kind of theory is that?
Hello. All your dishes have arrived.
- Your food is very good.
- Really? Thank you.
Please get me another two of chef's special.
You... are you not full?
Are you still eating?
I can still have quite a bit.
Look at the girl. She can eat so much.
- Hey, the bill please.
- Yes.
A total of ¥52, just give me ¥50.
- Do you need me to takeaway these dishes?
- No need.
- Thanks.
Do you not want your dishes anymore?
- That's right.
That's so wasteful. Then can you order as to how much you can eat in the future?
It's none of your business.
Zhenzhen!
Look, these vegetables and meat,
all these are the hard work of the farmers.
They took these to the market. The master then carefully selects them .
Then the chef makes these delicious foods before they arrive at your table.
You ordered these but you're not eating it. How wasteful is that?
You're crazy.
Give me some rice!
All right.
What is your name?
Qianjin. Song Qianjin.
I don't care if you're Qianjin (forward) or Houtui (backwards), you have to keep our promise.
- What promise?
- When customers come, only let them order the amount they can eat. Don't let them waste food.
When did I agree?
- Yes, I promise you.
- Do I still have two more dishes?
- What?
- Didn't I order two chef's special?
Oh. Yes.
My god. Song Qianjin, do you like being abused?
You're very kind, and truthful.
I've always seen customers waste food.
Food can't speak and can't get angry. They think wasting it doesn't matter.
But you'd come out and speak up for them.
You're very brave. Very good. Plus, you can understand that every dish comes with a process of hard work.
I really think you're special.
Stop looking at me like that.
I'm not comfortable.
Qianjin, right now, I don't have any plans in be in a relationship.
Can't we keep our good friendship?
Because I don't want it to be awkward to see you in the future.
All right, I will do as you say.
As long you don't avoid me. I am willing to sincerely see you as my good friend.
- Really?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Zhenzhen, then what kind of man do you like?
Tell me. Maybe I can still work towards it.
It'd be faster for you to reincarnate.
It was your old company's general manager, right?
Shut up!
Whatever he is capable of, what he has... I'm able, too.
I will definitely prove it to you.
Wait till the day Sunshine Boy can defeat Mr. Tall, Rich and Handsome.
Wang Xiao.
Dad.
How did your talk go with Yunyun yesterday?
You returned home without saying anything.
Also, when are you going to re-schedule your wedding?
About that... Dad, yesterday evening I didn't have the opportunity to talk about that with Yunyun.
Then why did you go there? Do you know you are wasting time right now?
Besides, I'm telling you again. The tender bidding was halted because of the wedding.
The company can't wait anymore. If we keep on delaying, our company will make a big loss.
I hope you will hurry and resolve this problem.
I don't want to force Yunyun! I want to give her a little more time.
She is so stubborn now because you always go with her wishes.
Why are you so useless?
You can't even deal with a woman, how are you going to do great things in the future?
Dad! You don't understand a lot of things!
All right. Tell me what the problem is between you two?
Dad, you can be assured.
I won't let you wait too long for my marriage with Yunyun.
Okay. I hope you won't disappoint me.
I'm so full!
Qianjin is very pitiful. After cooking so hard,
he still had to wash the dishes before leaving.
If you're not a queen, then what is a queen?
Stop talking nonsense. He's a real brother and a good friend.
Doesn't it feel good clearing things up?
Not just good. My appetite is so good, I ate an extra bowl.
- Are you satisfied?
- No. How could there not be dessert after dinner?
- What kind of stomach do you have?
-There is another stomach for dessert.
Tian, should we go have dessert?
No! I don't want to eat.
Dessert is the main source of being fat, the evil of all evils.
If you want to go, then go on your own. I cannot go with you.
What you said is right.
But what does it have to do with me? Eat.
Eating alone is very lonely.
But the good point is that no one snatches food from you.
I don't care if you snatch my food; instead, I'm very happy for you to share with me.
Sit down.
Then I'm not going to be polite.
Waitress! Another set of tableware please!
You are lucky! I just ate so I won't snatch so much from you.
Lucky?
That is just what I need right now.
I always thought that people like you who had meals outside,
you'd go to Michelin starred or five-star restaurants.
Never thought I would meet you here.
Because of my situation right now, I can only come to this kind of place and be at ease.
One person eating alone is good, but drinking alone isn't good.
Come, I will accompany you! Let's forget every problem!
- Cheers.
You shouldn't care how people will look at you.
You just have to live happily.
I also want to live the way you just said.
But sometimes, we can't live according to what we want.
Seems like your prince's and princess' lives do have their share of heavy burden.
Prince? So that's what you guys call me.
It sounds really sad.
What is so sad about it?
What's wrong with being a prince? Princes still need to pee and poo right?
That is true, but do you have to be so direct?
What direct? Still caring about your image? Your woman already ran away!
If I were you, even if I broke my arms and legs
I'd still try my best and snatch her back.
The end!
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Masked Love Team @ Viki.com
♫ Hey baby, I got something to tell you. Come on. ♫
♫  Distorted faces can easily create false impressions   ♫
♫  So as to deter your heart  ♫
♫  It's alright to have shortcomings.   ♫
♫ The ideal appearance will shine forth brightly from the mirror in the next second ♫
♫  Heightened dreamlike atmosphere.  ♫​
♫  Love your stubbornness with your dream as companion  ♫
♫  With so many challenges in this world  ♫​
♫ Be with me to fill in the future answers  ♫
♫  What you see is not the truth  ♫​
♫ But your innocent kindness I never forget ♫
♫  The appearance is a wall of time  ♫
♫ Specialized disguise is framed in time ♫
♫ Baby Don’t put up your defense.  ♫
♫ Be at ease and light up others’ life. ♫
♫ Don’t yearn for it  ♫
♫  Distorted faces can easily create false impressions   ♫
♫  So as to deter your heart  ♫
♫  It's alright to have shortcomings.   ♫
♫ The ideal appearance will shine forth brightly from the mirror in the next second ♫
♫  Heightened dreamlike atmosphere.  ♫​
♫  Love your stubbornness with your dream as companion  ♫
♫  With so many challenges in this world  ♫​
♫ Be with me to fill in the future answers  ♫
♫  What you see is not the truth  ♫​
♫ But your innocent kindness I never forget ♫
♫  The appearance is a wall of time  ♫​
♫ Specialized disguise is framed in time ♫
♫ Baby Don’t put up your defense. ♫
♫ Be at ease and light up others’ life. ♫
♫ Don’t yearn for it  ♫​