Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
Math is the core of all the sciences.
The rest are just embellishments.
Hey, handsome! Can you lend a hand?
Please help us get our balloons back.
It's dangerous under a flight path.
(What's with him?)
♫ Distance times pi, puts us poles apart ♫
♫ I can't forget the angle of your face, the arc of your smile ♫
♫ Who's fallen into the advancing scarlet flames? ♫
♫ You know, you know, you know ♫
♫ I thought that loneliness was my everlasting prophecy ♫
♫ When I look at you, my reason seems to crumble ♫
♫ I want to change, to take on a huge risk ♫
♫ You know, you know, you know ♫
♫ I embrace this thorn-covered rose, and the thorns pierce into my heart ♫
♫ It fills in all the empty spaces ♫
♫ The wild lion inside me awakes with my love for you ♫
♫ Now I fight for my throne ♫
♫ Baby, I want you to be my only lady ♫
♫ Who can love more crazily than us? ♫
♫ Love makes us braver, stronger ♫
♫ If I don't love you, who would I love? ♫
♫ What do I mean to you? ♫
♫ Give your beauty to me ♫
- Episode 1 -
Criminal caught red-handed. Ah Fei, turn on the siren. After him!
Guy on the bike, stop!
Police!
Get closer to him!
Wang Qiangda, stop!
I know you can hear me!
Police! You're still biking?
Stop! Wait!
He's terrible.
Why are you looking at me? Keep driving!
Where's that weird guy?
Over there! In front! After him!
Stop!
Police!
Hurry!
This is the worst!
Everyone, freeze! Police! Men to the left, women to the right!
The one writing on the board, get against the wall!
What are you doing?
I've been practicing that for a long time. Can't you just let me say it?
You can go inspect around the clubs. It'll be faster.
What's so urgent?
Turning on the siren... Using a public utility for personal reasons.
It wasn't for personal reasons. There's an urgent matter this time.
We picked up a conversation by the drug trafficking syndicate, but they spoke in code.
All we know is the deal's going down today. The time and location is unconfirmed.
Did you track their cellphones?
They're too cunning to use cellphones!
Right, so why are you asking me about it?
I want you to listen to part of the recording.
Maybe we can figure out the relative position.
And I heard that the seller is someone named Black Ghost.
From my investigation, he's related to the case from that year.
Daddy, what's wrong? Hurry, wake up!
Daddy!
It's the sound of a car accelerating.
There's a traffic signal nearby.
7-Eleven's door chime. And FamilyMart's as well.
A siren sounds suddenly.
There's a fire station nearby. When the vehicles leave, their siren turns on.
The codes that comes up most frequently are "hen" and "eggs."
They must be the money and the drugs.
Finish before the brats arrives.
The signal is an upside-down cup.
There's a high school nearby.
Time is between 4:30 and 5. Location, a coffee shop.
Awesome. Thank you, Master Qiang.
Thank you so much.
Hey, Ah Fei, you need to find
a coffee shop by a street that has both a 7-Eleven and a FamilyMart,
and check if there's a fire station and high school nearby.
Hurry.
So, how do you know this Black Ghost is involved with that year's case?
I can't reveal the details.
But I can tell you that Black Ghost was involved with Zhan Dingxuan before.
You're resigning?
Because of that joke I played online?
It's not that serious.
Listen, I can help you clear your name.
- I'll say that I posted it.
- I've already decided.
Hello? Yes.
Yeah. Okay, I got it.
We've narrowed it down to three possible locations. We'll split up to check.
- Hey...
- I'm going, too.
Let's leave catching the criminals to the professionals, okay?
Just wait here for my news.
Don't act impulsively. Just wait. Be good.
Yes. Okay, pick me up first.
I won't wait.
Did you get the shot yet?
Which one is Black Ghost?
You're sure this is the place? You verified the other two spots?
One has a restaurant without a business, and the coffee shop at the other...
Okay, okay. Photograph all the customers here and then send them to my tablet.
Okay.
Qiangda, what are you doing here?
How's the situation?
I told you to leave this to the professionals--
The prosecutor and I are determining who Black Ghost is.
A man, around 40 years old.
He should be by himself, and he'll only order one cup of coffee.
Miss Sun.
Miss Sun, this jade cicada is authentic.
It feels gentle in your hand, and the color looks natural.
If you meet a true collector, I'm sure you'll get at least 10,000 USD for it.
You're truly an exceptional antiques appraiser.
Let me show you something even more amazing.
This...
The old devil said he spent 1,35 million TWD (45,000 USD) to buy it.
Here, take a look at it.
Wow... Okay.
What is it? Is there a problem?
Miss Sun, I have to be honest.
There's a problem with the quality of this jade bracelet.
It's not very high grade.
That can't be.
Take another look. You must be mistaken.
Take another look.
Okay, then let me look at it again more carefully.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
Ah Fei, it's him.
- He's Black Ghost.
- Okay.
Okay? Hurry and get a move on it!
All teams, get ready to move.
Hey, watch where you're walking! Are you blind?
What happens if the coffee spills?
Mister, don't you look while you walk? Aren't you going to apologize?
The situation doesn't seem right.
Hey! Hey!
Your manners are too lacking.
You won't be able to pay if you break anything on this table.
He looks so suspicious.
Danger.
The jade bracelet!
Ah B, take all the suspects.
Xiao Tie, where's Black Ghost?
Um, he got away. But Ah Fei's chasing after him. Don't worry.
- What are you guys doing...
- Wait!
You broke this jade bracelet. You have to pay for it.
Can I get a cup of coffee? Thanks.
I broke your jade bracelet?
That's right!
Miss, if I hadn't saved you, you'd be on your way to the hospital right now.
You should be thanking me, not making me a scapegoat.
Hey! If you hadn't saved me, I would have caught the bracelet, and it wouldn't have broken.
So you have to take on half of the responsibility!
Are you part of some kind of fraud group?
Miss, I grabbed onto you. I never touched the bracelet.
There's nothing to discuss here. I need to leave now.
- You—
- You can't leave! How are you going to repay me?!
How are you going to repay me?
All right, let's not tug at each other. It doesn't look good.
- Let's talk at the police station.
- Who are you?
Public Prosecutor Tie Bufan.
- I want to sue her for damages!
- I want to sue him for damages!
Let's deal with it at the station. Let's go.
Are you going to talk or not?
Officer, I've already told you everything I know.
I really don't know anyone named Black Ghost or White Ghost.
I lost a lot in this, too. Can I apply for state reimbursement?
Forget reimbursement!
Miss Sun, I didn't say I wouldn't pay.
But shouldn't this man also take part of the responsibility?
Moreover, though your bracelet may be A-grade,
considering its quality, it isn't worth 1,35 million TWD.
What are you saying?
Prosecutor, help us resolve this.
She broke my bracelet, and now she's mocking me like this.
Do you think that makes sense?
Miss Sun, I'm not mocking you. I'm telling you the truth.
The quality of this bracelet is very problematic.
Quit pretending to be handsome.
Okay, we can take care of this matter. This bracelet...
I think what you said makes sense.
This man should take some responsibility. Let's talk.
Mister...
Miss Sun, you can have the bracelet appraised by a third party.
There's no reason to turn this into a big issue.
You two are a pair of thieves, aren't you? I won't be scared off.
I want to turn this into a big issue!
Okay, then I'll say it directly.
With the exception of your thumbs, your remaining eight fingers have different ring marks.
This shows that you often change your rings, because you wear different rings with different companions.
Today, you're carrying a name-brand purse, which costs upwards of a few hundred thousand,
but you're wearing a pair of very ordinary shoes, and they look pretty old.
That's because your only appointment today was with Miss Wang,
so you only picked out an expensive-looking bag, without much care to the rest.
What's your point?
In your house, you have a lot of expensive brands, but you also have a lot of inexpensive items.
That's because you need to adjust your outfits when you ask men for money.
And the fact that you're having this 1,35 million dollar gift appraised
means that you receive money, not feelings.
- Prosecutor!
- Yes?
How long do I have to listen to his crap?
Miss Sun, I suggest that you not make this a bigger ordeal.
There are actually a lot of reporters in the police station.
If this news gets out, it won't be good for you.
I...
- I just want justice.
- Great.
The appraiser you invited is here with us.
Please evaluate how much this bracelet is worth.
It's true that this is natural Myanmar jade, but it has defects.
It's only worth 200,000 TWD (66,000 USD).
- What?
- And that's before it was broken.
200,000 it is then. Miss Sun, do you have any problems with that?
What kind of joke are you playing?
If we can't come to a consensus on the compensation, I suggest we send the bracelet to a third part for appraisal.
But with all the news online recently, I don't think it's a good idea.
You're really bullying someone here.
Fine. Then 500,000.
- 200,000.
- 400,000.
- 190,000.
- 200,000.
- 180,000.
If it's not 200,000, I'm going to die right here!
- 200,000 it is then.
- Great!
Everyone's satisfied! Let's write down a contract.
Amiability brings fortune. No need to get angry.
All right, sign here.
Ah Fei, make some tea!
Okay, you're Party A, and you're Party B.
Here. Sign your names.
Consider it my bad luck!
You're leaving? You don't want your tea?
Ah Fei, forget the tea!
What rotten luck.
Prosecutor, you need to uphold justice for me! This man needs to take on half the responsibility!
The bracelet breaking was a matter of probability. Why do I need to be responsible?
- You!
- Enough!
Miss Wang, leave this to me.
Mr. Wang, I think that...
What is it, Xiao Tie?
(Xiao is an affectionate prefix, usually for someone younger)
Call me "Prosecutor."
By saving Miss Wang, the bracelet ended up breaking.
So Miss Wang has every right to request that you take some responsibility.
The right to request I take responsibility?
From my calculations, even if I hadn't saved you, the chance of you catching the bracelet was less than 10%.
If you're so good at calculating, why don't you go calculate fate (fortune telling)?
You should at least take responsibility for 10%.
She's a young lady. You should have some compassion for women.
I just brought the compensation of the bracelet down from 1,35 million to 200,000.
That's an 86% savings, much greater than this 10%.
Really? Let me calculate it.
You need to calculate that?
You know that I haven't even calculated about that nonsense you posted online.
Qiangda! Where is he?
Professor Wang, this question's really hard. Please help!
Even my cram school teacher didn't know how to solve it. Isn't this too extreme?
If a cram school can solve this,
then I'll go to class there.
When you have news about Black Ghost, find me.
Hey! We're not done here yet! Where are you going?!
Prosecutor, how can this person not take responsibility?
Since Mr. Wang isn't directly involved in this case, we can't keep him here.
But you can't just let him go either! This is about 200,000 dollars!
Actually, the two of us are old classmates, good friends, and roommates.
I'll convince him.
Okay. Then I'll ask for your help, Prosecutor.
Call me Tie Bufan, or brother Xiao Tie if you'd like.
After midnight, just call me Tie.
Niuniu, come here.
- How did you injure your foot?
- Ah, just a small car accident. It's fine.
Take a look.
Professor Wang, this video proves
that one of our students at Changtai solved this.
Once we posted the video, the entire cram school industry shared it like crazy.
Everyone was congratulating me for finding such a famous teacher. I mean, a master.
The phone was off the hook all day.
Who is this student?
The student? I don't know who he is.
He purposefully kept his face from showing.
But if you come to class, Professor Wang, you should be able to find him.
- I'm very interested in this student.
- Is that so?
Don't worry. I'll fulfill the promise I made online.
This is great! You can teach the specialized advanced class.
But I'll only teach for one semester.
Professor Wang, don't worry.
I won't be stingy with the pay. Don't kill the words off so soon (to be firm).
The words we speak are neither dead nor alive.
Words simply express things we can and cannot do.
Yes, yes, Professor Wang, you're right.
Things are either "yes" or "no."
This isn't a university, and I'm not here for a lecture, so please don't address me as "Professor."
Teacher Wang.
- Niuniu, bring that over. You know what I mean?
- Of course.
Teacher Wang, printing it like this is amazing.  Isn't that so?
Yes.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
Let's lower the expected salary then.
Isn't this that guy?
Open enrollment for the top math teacher.
Wang Qiangda?
What kind of weird name is that?
"Taiwan Fields Medal recipient."
"University math professor."
"Declined position as research fellow at Academia Sinica Institute of Mathematics."
"In an unprecedented move, he's joining Changtai."
So he's a teacher at a cram school.
He brought himself to this point.
And he's an irresponsible miser.
You're done for.
Master Qiang, come out for a late-night snack.
I brought you a late-night snack, Master Qiang.
Hey!
The food goblin's come out, huh?
You're really amazing. You can eat from the same place every day.
Can you be more accurate with your words? Liking it and having to eat it every day are different.
If you have to be accurate and precise with everything, it gets tiring!
Accuracy decreases the rate of failure.
And it saves you time and energy.
Speaking of. Do you have any news about Black Ghost?
Unfortunately, no.
The person we arrested really doesn't know Black Ghost.
It was just a simple transaction.
This trail was a dead end.
All right, enough with that face.
Know when to let things go. Don't get tied up in that case.
I'll get you something to drink.
The only thing I pick up and won't let go of are chopsticks.
Hey, food goblin, drink some juice to quench the fire.
Oh, the food goblin's already finished his late-night snack.
Prosecutor, I'll leave the investigating to you.
He doesn't even wait to eat with you.
I don't wait.
Find some clues.
"Find some clues."
[Top-Quality Teachers: Changtai Tutorial Classes]
[Strongest lineup in all subjects]
Excuse me, I'm looking for Wang Qiangda.
The line is downstairs for a sit-in.
I'm not a high school student.
Of course, I know that, but it's the same for parents.
Line up to register. The sit-in lecture is this evening.
The sit-in lecture isn't until this evening?!
But the line downstairs already goes out the door.
Of course. Wang Qiangda is the highest-salaried math teacher here.
Ordinary people might not know, but he's very famous in math circles.
Oh, I see.
Now what? I have to wait until this evening.
Should I just ask the prosecutor?
But that prosecutor was kind of weird.
I should just go find Wang Qiangda later.
Niuniu, prepare more registration forms. There will be a lot of people later.
Okay. Boss, be careful with your foot like that.
What? I just injured my foot. Everything else is in perfect working order!
Doesn't this painting have such character?
Yes.
When I first saw this painting,
I just felt so touched by it, like you feel now.
I decided right then, that no matter the cost, I would buy it!
And look. This is an authentic piece.
It was worth the price, worth the investment.
This is copy.
A copy?
But it's not a forgery.
The copy artist kept their own charm and grace.
You can see this in various brush strokes.
B-But...
Are you sure it's a copy?
Daddy, what are you painting?
Xiao Wei, I'm trying to analyze the original painter's emotions.
Then I paint those out with my brush.
This way, our souls can communicate with people from long ago.
Understand?
That's why, at first glance, it looks authentic.
But the copy artist maintained their own style in the details.
If you have someone appraise it, they'll be able to tell you.
I...
I bought a fake?
A-And I even hung it at the entrance?
It's not a fake!
It can speak to you.
You can communicate with it and feel touched.
All of that is real.
That's what's important!
The way this crazy girl talks about it, she seems to really like the painting.
Maybe I can re-sell it to her for a high price.
Boss, the history teacher who was supposed to report in today isn't coming.
Not coming? Why?!
She was poached by World Tutorial Classes.
What?!
Wang Qiangda is joining today!
Mandarin, English, math, natural sciences, and social sciences!
All the subjects are set! How can we be missing one now?!
Everything's ruined now!
That vile, wicked, shameless Li Dashi!
No need.
Is someone badmouthing me?
What should we do?
L-Let me think. L-Let me think, won't you?
Goodness, is this the job God arranged for me?
My boss is soulmates with my dad,
and I'll be near Wang Qiangda to settle our account.
If he doesn't cooperate, I'll just ask the boss to deduct it from his salary.
Boss, sorry to interrupt, but I haven't introduced myself yet.
My name is Wang Qiangwei,
and as chance has it, I'm originally a high school history teacher.
Of course, I can also teach geography.
When I taught, I was earnest and enthusiastic.
Teachers and students alike, all had praises.
The students especially. They were just too adorable.
During class, they were very eager.
When I marked their homework, I was very happy.
After class, they would surround me to ask questions.
Their exam scores were, of course, very ideal.
That environment was just too comfortable.
I hoped to prove myself in the competitive arena of cram courses.
It's such a coincidence that you're looking for a geography teacher.
If you find me suitable, I'd very much like to take this chance.
Goodness, is this my chance to recover my losses?
She can fill in the position, and I can sell her that fake painting.
If she doesn't have the money, I can just deduct it from her salary.
You! You're in!
- Really?!
- Yes!
Welcome! Get ready for tonight's sit-in lecture.
Niuniu, get her picture on the poster!
Understood! Teacher Wang, please provide a photo.
Thank you, Boss!
Good luck!
Are you sure Wang Qiangda will pass by this way?
My source is very reliable.
He's coming.
This side!
Would you like to join World Tutorial Classes?
Do you know what you're doing?
Let me show you!
Hello! I'm from World Tutorial Classes!
Get in front, block his way. Okay?
Great. I have to do my best with this chance.
- Sorry, I'm in a rush.
- No problem.
Looks like the guy who had a deal with Black Ghost really doesn't know about his whereabouts.
I figured as much.
Someone as careful and cunning as Black Ghost won't be easy to catch.
But there is someone who's rather suspicious.
Should I surveil them?
Hey, don't you only know how to act cool?
You finally want to set yourself straight?
You're even taking the initiative to catch a suspect?
Looks like I didn't waste my time teaching you after all.
Who is it?
The clues are in there.
These...
After looking through the photos, I thought about it.
Miss Qiangwei and Black Ghost sat at adjacent tables.
And of all the tables, Black Ghost knocked into hers.
I think that Miss Qiangwei surely knows something.
Hearing Miss Qiangwei's name coming out of your face makes me uncomfortable.
Are you going to monitor someone or pick up a girl?
- What's that mean?
And you're missing a photo.
A close-up. She's pouting and super cute.
What's that mean?
You took it. Hand it over.
- Boss, I don't have it.
- Don't have it?
If I find it, you're dead.
Boss, I'm going.
- Do you have it or not?
- Remember that I developed the photos.
If you want one...
- If I find it, you're dead!
- ...you should develop your own copy.
You could have just developed an extra copy for me!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
What would you like?
I want an egg and ham croque madame and a cup of green tea.
Isn't that Teacher Wang Qiangda?
You have his class?
Yeah, and he's super handsome.
Your egg and ham croque madame is ready. Thank you and enjoy.
Professor Wang, bye.
- He's a total catch.
- Professor Wang's so handsome.
Both Professor Wang and Teacher Wang teach math all the same.
No matter where I teach, my power comes from being well-fed.
Maybe having courage is trying things you've never done before.
Is your kid going to Teacher Wang's sit-in lecture tonight?
Yes, my kid's really excited for Teacher Wang's class.
He's really amazing.
Yeah, I heard the lines were really long.
Teacher Wang, this way.
Wow, the classroom's really big.
Wang Qiangwei!
Boss Yan really helped me.
I have to work hard!
This is too excessive.
Look at this.
Is there a need to treat the new guy this well?
Is he treating us like we're air?
We're air, nothing. Is that it?
Teacher Side, what do you think?
Teacher Side?
What are you scared of? If you're capable, just be competitors.
Finally, you're making sense.
Sometimes, I feel that Old Yan—
Hurry, hurry. Teacher Wang Qiangda will arrive soon.
Let's all welcome our new colleague, okay? Teacher Side--
Old Yan, considering our friendship—
We can only create the right atmosphere if we have a lot of people.
Hey, where's Old Gu? Go find him.
Old Yan, I actually think the new guy—
Hello? Yes.
Yes.
A hundred. A hundred apple pies. Right.
The students and parents are all here. Hurry.
And don't forget to bring the drinks.
Hello, everyone. Welcome to this sit-in lecture.
Let me introduce myself.
My name is Wang Qiangwei.
Wang, like a dog goes "wang wang" ("woof woof").
Qiangwei, like the very beautiful rose.
Goodness, what's going on?
Hurry, get down.
♫ If I don't love you, who would I love? ♫
♫ What do I mean to you? ♫
♫ I'm not retreating, I won't retreat ♫
Goodness, what's going on?
Hurry, get down.
Get down?
Be careful! Don't get that dirty! The red carpet!
The carpet.
What's on the board? Southern Song? Northern Song? Niuniu!
Hurry and clean the board! You got it wrong!
Teacher Wang isn't in this room. How could you mess it up?
Boss, what's going on?
Sorry, but the history lecture doesn't have that many people.
So you won't be using this classroom.
- But, I—
- It's fine. Niuniu!
I'll clean the board. Take Teacher Wang to the room next door.
Got it! Teacher Wang, this way.
Just wait a moment. I'll clean the board.
Teacher, can you do this quickly?
I want to check out if the math class still has any spots left.
Math?
Me too. Because the math class is pretty full.
Okay!
This classroom is small, so I'll just speak without the microphone.
Things are a little awkward, aren't they?
That's okay. I'll tell a joke for all of you.
Taiwan has black bears, Sichuan has pandas.
Then, what kind of bears does a hospital have?
I'll tell you then.
The answer is psychiatric patients.
(The words all end with "xiong")
Don't you guys think it's funny?
Wang Qiangwei, this is just the first day.
It will get better after this!
Or you can just use a different joke.
I can do this!
The teacher's here!
Everyone, Teacher Wang Qiangda!
[Wang Qiangda]
I'm Wang Qiangda. Are you all ready?
Wow, is this Wang Qiangda really that amazing?
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Teacher Wang Qiangwei.
Teacher Wang, take a look around.
All the students are taking notes.
Why? Because they know
how rare it is for someone of Wang Qiangda—no, Professor Wang's caliber
to come to our cram school to give a lesson.
The rarer something is, the greater its value.
Look at them all. They're so devoted to their studies.
This is what separates the elite from the ordinary.
Of course.
Of course, students who seek to learn and those who are force-fed learning materials are different.
I'm going to open an elite's class
with increased prices!
Quiet. Focus, focus.
What would this be?
We set an end point here.
Now what is this?
From birth until death,
all the points in time and all the things that happened
accumulate together...
and they form your life.
Everyone has different outlooks on life and different values.
At this point in time, what is the most important thing to you?
Some believe it's money.
Some believe it's accomplishments.
What do you think?
I personally believe that the outcomes that I reach
at each point in time
are added together to form my life.
All right, let's start the class.
Does anyone have a question?
- I have a question.
- Go ahead.
But it's not the problem on the board.
Can I go up to write it?
Come up.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
This student's here to stir up trouble.
I've solved the problem he wrote before. It's very tricky.
Even if I were to solve it, it would take some time.
He probably didn't come with pure intentions.
It's okay. What kind of person is Wang Qiangda?
He's Academia Sinica level!
I can't solve this.
Brilliant.
Ah Xin,
you did a good job this time.
Of course. I was meticulous with hiring this guy.
Yan Changtai, you think you can dominate the market just because you got Wang Qiangda?
With me, Li Dashi, around, don't even think about it.
Teacher Wang, you really can't solve it?
The pamphlet said that you're the best on Earth.
I really can't.
Stop streaming!
Because the question is wrong.
You folded the paper a few times.
And you happened to fold it on the subtraction sign, so it wasn't clear.
I knew it!
I trusted Teacher Wang.
Keep streaming!
So? You should teach irrespective of a student's background.
You could have just pointed out where I was wrong.
But you're not a student.
Ordinarily, bakeries wouldn't have their student workers operate the ovens.
But you have burn marks on your arm from the baking trays, old and new.
And your hand is very tender
because you knead bread and your hands are often in contact with yeast.
To put it simply, you've already graduated, and you're working as an apprentice at a bakery, right?
No.
I'm still studying. I want to go to college.
First work, and then go back to school? That's not impossible.
If you take your phone out,
and there's a record of your contacting a nearby cram school,
then your words will be more convincing.
For geographic reasons, a faraway cram school wouldn't need to go to such means.
That means this was set up by a nearby rival.
Huh?
Li Dashi!
You're playing this game again?
Whenever you say you can't solve a problem, I know you're up to no good.
Talk!
Did World Tutorial Classes send you here?!
Take your phone out!
Just let him go.
It's hard work being an apprentice at a bakery.
If he's taking on other jobs, I suspect he has other troubles he can't share.
I'm sorry.
Settle down. Let's continue with the class.
That was amazing!
He's been laughing for five minutes. Is he okay?
It's fine. His record for losing his senses is eight and a half minutes.
What a success!
Teacher Wang, that was so great! I'm so happy!
Oh, let me introduce you.
Our teachers are also your future colleagues.
First, I'll introduce our physics and chemistry teacher, Teacher Guo!
He's cleaning.
His name's actually Old Honest Guo, but Teacher Guo sounds better.
Next is our top math—
Former top math teacher,
Teacher Zeng Renyi.
If you have any problems at the school, feel free to ask me.
Next is our beautiful and refined English teacher,
Lian Side.
Hello.
If a woman extends her arm, a gentleman should shake her hand.
Manners make the man. Haven't you watched Kingsmen?
Sorry, I don't have this custom.
Okay.
You'll have to get accustomed, because we'll be colleagues.
How conceited.
And finally, our history teacher, Teacher Wang Qiangwei.
No need for introductions. We've already met.
♫ If I don't love you, who would I love? ♫
♫ What do I mean to you? ♫
♫ I'm not retreating, I won't retreat ♫
And finally, our history teacher, Teacher Wang Qiangwei.
No need for introductions. We've already met.
Yes. I didn't expect you to also be a teacher.
Yeah. I hadn't expected
that the world's best teacher and a math professor
would cause an accident and then run away without taking any responsibility.
You don't live up to your fame.
Teacher Wang, I'll tell you for the sixth time.
The chance was only 10%.
The two of you...
A one-night stand?
No, no! You've misunderstood!
Teacher Wang, I know your math is very good,
but calculating "safe days" isn't really safe.
If you really want to be safe, you have to use a con—
Guarantees have nothing to do with this situation.
Wang Qiangda, aren't you going to say anything?
Take care of your own problems.
You...
Let the past stay in the past. Take hold of the present.
Today's sit-in lecture was very successful.
A bunch of students have already enrolled and paid.
To celebrate this great success, I'll treat everyone to a late meal!
Boss, I haven't cleared things up yet. The two of us really aren't—
Excuse me, I have other matters, so I'll take my leave.
Teacher Wang!
The new guy seems to have a great personality, huh?
He seems skilled.
People with true skills have this kind of temper.
It's called pride.
Right. He has this lofty aura, like a hero looking down at you.
Proud and aloof, standing above the crowd.
Just like a...
A lion?
A lion. Yes.
The lion, Wang Qiangda.
No, no. The lion king, Qiangda.
Not bad! We can use that on the advertisements.
I'm just a small, little plant here. I'll take my leave.
Teacher Wang, we haven't discussed your salary yet.
And we haven't discussed your sit-in lecture yet.
But I really have another appointment. I only have an hour.
One hour is enough.
I don't treat often. Let's go eat.
True, you never treat.
- Yeah.
- It'll be a long time before it happens again.
Teacher Guo, you clean up.
We won't disturb you. Bye.
Let's go.
Here, here. Cheers!
Xiao Wei.
Cheers, boss.
I'd like to ask if I've been accepted or not.
Yes.
Yes, there's a plan.
The plan is, if you enroll in Wang Qiangda's Math Essentials course,
you also get to take Wang Qiangwei's Comprehensive History course.
It's a package?!
Or you can have a Yo-kai watch.
(manga character)
Yo-kai watch?
Most of the students picked the watch.
But don't be discouraged. Some students still picked your class.
Right, right. So, what about my salary?
Come on, don't ask that kind of question here.
It's so awkward.
Old Yan, she just got into the cram school business, so you should be more generous.
Since when were you so considerate?
You pay her salary then.
All right, the rest of you, don't look.
This much.
[2,600 TWD (86 USD)/Hour]
[3,000 TWD (100 USD)/Hour]
This much.
[2,700 TWD (90 USD)/Hour]
That's my final offer. No more negotiating.
But I can give you a proposal.
For each additional student who enlists in your class, I'll add 500 TWD (16 USD) to your monthly salary.
But first, you have to subtract the students who first enrolled in Wang Qiangda's math class.
You can do the calculation, right?
So, M is the total number of students.
And N is that lion's students?!
Hey, your math's not bad.
I'm the one whose math isn't bad.
Of course, your math's not bad.
It's just not strong (qiangda) enough.
Qiangwei, he's always like that in the beginning.
As long as you're capable though, you don't have to worry about increasing your pay later.
I'll work hard.
Let me toast everyone.
Please take care of me in the future.
Good luck to you all.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
I heard from Xiao Qing that you had a lecture at the cram school today.
How was it?
It was fine. I'm still teaching, like before.
Is that so?
There's quite a big difference between a university and a cram school, isn't there?
He's pretty much still just as cool.
He also caught someone trying to stir up trouble.
Why are you coming back so late?
The kids found out that I know Qiangda and kept asking me questions.
We got something to drink before I came back.
Finish eating and head upstairs.
Okay.
Qiangda, please take care of Xiao Qing.
I can only cook. I don't know about anything else.
As long as she wants to learn, of course, I'm willing to teach her.
But what's important is what she finds interesting.
What do kids know about their interests? They just need to study.
Eat slowly. If a girl saw you eating like that, she'd be scared off.
He's a food goblin! And he met...
- Uncle Xun!
- Hello.
- I want the same. Chef's Special.
- Have a seat.
Brother Xiao Tie!
- Hey, there.
- What were you about to say?
I was just about to say that this food goblin met the queen of darkness.
- You've said too much.
- Queen of darkness?
Is she part of a crime syndicate?
Or Qiangda's girlfriend?
Or a video game? Hurry and spill!
Well...
I'll cook you something delicious.
Okay, then I'll tell you!
My old classmate and current roommate is a bit eccentric, and he doesn't like crowds.
But he does enjoy eating delicious food.
There's a restaurant where you dine in the dark, and some of their food's pretty good.
This food goblin went to try it out.
But who knew that, while he was trying it out, he would meet this so-called queen of darkness.
That place is pitch black.
You can't even see your fingers on an outstretched hand. Like you're blind.
You have to leave any device that can emit light in the restaurant's care.
The server will guide you to your table with a night-vision device.
If you go to eat alone, there's a chance you'll end up sharing a table.
You might not even know who's sitting right across from you.
But maybe because you can't see each other, there's no pressure.
You loosen up.
And so, this food goblin very naturally ended up eating with a woman.
In the end, he even got a bit drunk.
In a woman's world, "If you love me, you should come find me."
So then what happened?
All I know is that that night, this food goblin was both rational
and yet sensitive and romantic.
He had a very pleasant chat with his queen of darkness.
They spoke from the bottom of their hearts and felt like they were floating in the air.
In the end...
What happened?
♫ If I don't love you, who would I love? ♫
♫ What do I mean to you? ♫
♫ I'm not retreating, I won't retreat ♫
He had a very pleasant chat with his queen of darkness.
They spoke from the bottom of their hearts and felt like they were floating in the air.
In the end...
What happened?
I don't know either.
Meeting the right person at the wrong time truly is just a fairytale.
I rarely have the chance to talk this much with a stranger.
You seem to have filled in the missing piece in my life.
Really?
Are you shy...?
Or afraid?
Strangers are too variable. They're not good for calculations.
What does that mean?
Life's very short, and it can't sustain that much unpredictability.
But there's a certain beauty to accidents.
Many beautiful things happen by chance.
In a woman's world, "If you love me, you should come find me."
In a man's world, "If you love me, you won't leave."
So I won't turn back.
So I won't try to make someone stay.
Thank you, Uncle Xun.
So basically, you don't know anything.
No matter how much I asked him, he wouldn't talk.
But from all my years of experience, any time he says there's nothing, he's hiding something.
You're crazy. What could happen between two strangers who didn't even see each other?
Really? If that's true, why do you stop by that restaurant every now and then?
Because the food is good.
Is it as good as Uncle Xun's food?
I'm heading up. Goodnight, everyone.
Goodnight.
The time is 11:00 p.m. on the dot.
You're listening to Sophie's Night Sky.
None of us are perfect, but we're all working hard. I'm Sophie.
Hey, don't you think RDR's are the worst?
(Read, Didn't Reply)
Which woman is it this time?
"Which woman?" This is a goddess.
By the way, on the topic of the broken jade bracelet...
In the end, "You didn't kill Boren, but Boren died because of you." Shouldn't you do something?
The woman who didn't reply to you isn't possibly Wang Qiaowei, is she?
You think she's a goddess, too.  Don't you?
I approve of her not replying to you.
It's better to not get involved with a strange woman like her.
On that subject, it's true the police are partly responsible for the bracelet breaking.
If I were her, I would request for state reimbursement.
Yeah.
This all happened because the police charged into the coffee shop.
She was just an innocent casualty.
Qiangda, why are you getting involved in police cases again?
What happens if you get hurt?
Actually, Uncle Xun, I was the one who asked for his help.
Qiangda, I still have to tell you that you shouldn't keep getting stuck inside it.
Uncle Xun, this involves my dad's reputation and my mom's final wish before she died.
I can't just ignore it, so I have to keep chasing after it.
Hello, everyone! Sorry, I'm late! There was a traffic jam.
As if there would be a traffic jam this late at night.
What are you laughing about?
She's making a joke.
She's mocking the fact that traffic jams are always the excuse for being late.
Oh... Is that so?
Get off.
I just want to know where your low-level humor lies.
- Stop touching me.
- Ah, is it on your lower half?
Good evening, listeners. I'm Dorothy.
Dorothy, you know, everyone was really worried about you.
One after another, they asked "Dorothy, where have you gone?!"
Of course, I was still in Taipei.
Did you think I was Dorothy from the Wizard of Oz, stuck and lost in the Land of Oz?
Yeah.
I want to ask our listeners a question.
Do you know who likes going to the Land of Oz the most?
Who?
The answer is baseball players!
Why?
Because they always slide into the base.
And then the umpire calls "Out!"
♫ If I don't love you, who would I love? ♫
♫ What do I mean to you? ♫
♫ I'm not retreating, I won't retreat ♫
Baseball players! Because they always slide into the base.
And then the umpire calls "Out!"
I hope everyone's not put off by this joke,
and please don't tune out from our station!
All right, let's listen to a good song.
He can laugh like that from such a rotten joke?
He really likes Dorothy, for whatever reason.
He's some kind of weirdo.
I really don't get it.
Why is this Dorothy person always guesting on the show?
Because her sincerity is so interesting.
Uncle Xun, turn that off or I'm going to break it.
Forget it.
What?
You got a new job?
I did.
But I also have a big debt now.
This Dorothy isn't a simple person.
She's a cheerful and optimistic girl.
I see.
She said she was caught in a fire when she was young.
Her back and chest are covered in burn scars.
When the Furmosa Fun Coast explosion happened, she shared a lot of her rehabilitation experiences.
It touched a lot of people.
Who would have thought that our cold Master Qiang had such a sentimental side?
You sure talk a lot of crap. If you're done, go home.
Be happy!
Being happy's the most important; otherwise, you start spewing crap.
Thank you for the delicious meal, Uncle Xun.
I'll take my leave.
Let's go home.
- Let's go.
- You go first.
Bye, Uncle Xun.
When I'm in a bad mood, or I feel upset about something,
I find a place where I can see the nightscape but there aren't too many people.
There are a lot of options around Taipei.
Jiannan Mountain and Elephant Mountain are both pretty nice.
Then shout into the distance, releasing everything you're holding inside.
You'll feel a lot better.
Maybe some people will find this a bit silly,
but that's because you're really concerned about what others think of you.
These are all invisible forces of stress.
There's a certain beauty to accidents.
Many beautiful things happen by chance.
Let me ask you this. Did you choose your parents?
You didn't, right?
So your birth and life up to this day is the most beautiful chance happening.
Why are you pulling it?
Daddy!
But the chance happenings that belong to me aren't beautiful.
They're cruel and repulsive.
Wang Qiangda, as a man, you should take responsibility for your actions!
Don't think that you're so high and mighty!
Timing and subtitles brought to you by
Proud Lions Team @Viki.com
- Preview -
Go to Wang Qiangda's math class to observe and learn.
Please make copies of the other teaching materials. We'll need them shortly.
I'm willing to sacrifice my time to let you finish speaking.
Leave your contact info.
There's a thief in my cram school.
All of you are suspects!
I told you. Someone's been following me. Should I report it?
♫ Meddlesome people whisper in each others' ears ♫
♫ It's an inescapable net, with nowhere left to hide ♫
♫ You can't deal, but there's no choice—Get over it ♫
♫ Come on, no one knows better than me ♫
♫ Cover your ears, and let the sounds fade away ♫
♫ Who says you need to fear loneliness when you're alone? ♫
♫ I know that I can do it, no problem ♫
♫ I was born with the resolve ♫
♫ I'm not retreating, I won't retreat ♫
♫ I'm an unbending wild rose ♫
♫ I said I won't retreat, so I won't ♫
♫ Let the storm keep blowing ♫
♫ Condense the beautiful moments, leave out the worries ♫
♫ In the end, the rain water will slide off my face ♫
♫ The pain and bitterness will fade ♫
♫ From the bottom of my heart, I'll be happy ♫
♫ I'm happy, for myself ♫
♫ I'm happy ♫
♫ I've already forgotten who I am ♫
♫ My heart and my face, they've turned to dust ♫
♫ I no longer feel ♫
♫ Without warning, the tide crashes in ♫
♫ Humans struggle to survive ♫
♫ All of our souls are no longer whole ♫
♫ I have to leave now ♫
♫ I'm headed to the survival zone ♫
♫ With the rest of my life... ♫
Sir, these were left behind at your seat.
♫ The seller of souls wears a disguise ♫
♫ Can he satisfy all those bodies? ♫
Thank you.
♫ The seller of souls has captivating eyes ♫
♫ If he's locked you in, baby... ♫
- Excuse me.
- Hello.
I forgot to pay. How much was the total?
Miss, your bill was paid for by the gentleman you ate with.
The one who ate with me?
Okay, I'll figure it out.
By the way, did you find a long, rectangular box? There was a bracelet inside.
Yes, but we thought it belonged to the gentleman, so we gave it to him.
Sorry.
Oh...
That's okay. Thank you.
♫ I need to leave now ♫
♫ I'm headed for the survival zone ♫
♫ With the rest of my life, I need to seek the truth of existence ♫
♫ You were once my most beloved ♫
♫ But now, we're both alone ♫
♫ After moving through all the bodies, will we be able to meet again? ♫
♫ The seller of souls wears a disguise... ♫