Why does the wind blow?
It wipes the tracks
where we have passed..
so that no one can tell
whether we still exist.
Long ago when warriors
of Light and Darkness..
clashed on the Bridge of Justice..
and blood was spilled..
the great Gesser's heart
could not bear it..
and he stopped the battle.
But in due time, when the night
is longer than the day..
a new Great One will come.
The world will be
plunged into darkness..
and nothing can save it..
except the Chalk of Fate..
which is kept
in an impenetrable fortress.
And all who come for it
and pass through the gates..
perish in its endless maze.
So had it always been..
until Tamerlane came.
Mercy!
Mercy! Mercy!
Please! I have done you no wrong.
Don't kill me!
The temple holds the Chalk.
It's in there.
Long and hard have you
fought to be here, Tamerlane.
I will control
the fate of the world-
You can't even
control your own fate.
What should I write?
- What is it you want?
- To live.
Then write that.
The temple holds the Chalk.
You said that before.
Don't kill me.
Don't kill..
"From that time on, Tamerlane made no
more mistakes that he could not correct."
You knew that?
Trainee Nazarova, just do me
a favor and put the book away.
Could it be?
The Chalk exists?
Anything you want to change?
Would you move the knee away?
Why do you always talk to me
like I did something wrong, huh?
That's enough. Just move your knee.
I'm starving.
Well, then.. can I
take you out to dinner?
Yeah? Like where?
Here. Chinese.
Chinese? Sounds good.
Tomorrow at 6:00-no, 7:00.
- Yes?
- Yeah.
Um, all right.
We will then.
- If nothing happens.
- That goes without saying.
Is anyone out there near the Expo Center?
Gorodetsky. I'm about five
minutes away from there.
Report of a human being attacked.
Another old woman.
Same pattern as before.
Stabbed with a large needle.
Attacked from behind.
The needle was placed so it entered
under the victim's shoulder.
What's happening?
The attacker is sucking
the victim's energy.
No I.D. on this one.
Be careful. He's very dangerous.
Sorry. Can't go there.
I'm with a trainee.
Read you.
14-85, on our way.
Thanks, Anton. I knew you
wouldn't let me down.
Someone really needs
to deal with those Dark Ones.
Do not go into the Gloom without me.
- Hmm?
- Move slowly in there and breathe deeply.
And the second level
is out of bounds.
- What's in there?
- Don't know. Never been there.
They say mosquitoes.
- Even mosquitoes don't live there.
- Boris Ivanovich said they did.
Well, of course, if he said so.
Only use the flashlight
for lighting, okay?
- What's it do?
- Don't touch this.
Right there!
Sveta. Sveta!
Sveta!
What the hell do you
think you're doing, huh?
Hey, Sveta! Who said you could
get out of the truck?
- And then, uh..
- Stop yelling at me.
He hurt me.
My shoulder hurts me.
He stuck me under the shoulder.
And then..
then I fell over and..
You there! Hold it!
Freeze!
- Hold it! Freeze!
- Sveta!
- Stop!
Easy, grandma.
Just hold on one second.
Okay? Easy. Hold on.
The bastards.
They all got away.
- Come on! Out of the way!
- Come back!
Move it! Make way!
Sveta!
Stop!
Freeze! Don't move!
Hey!
Don't!
Stop! No!
Come back here!
Svetlana!
Come back!
Behind you!
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Behind you!
Behind-
Hold it! Hey!
- Stop!
- No!
- Don't shoot!
- Wait!
Oh, God.
What's with this
insubordination, huh?
Why did you have to stop me?
I almost had him.
I'll deal with him, understand?
How do you know that one?
I just do.
But he's a Dark One.
Dark, Light?
Who cares?
How did this happen to you, eh?
Just a lot of nice people
in the world.
As long as this ring is
on you, you will do as I say.
It hurts.
And is that bad?
Till death do us part.
- Sign here, please.
- What is this?
A contract.
- Another one?
- Well, obviously, you haven't
been able to sign one yet.
- Excuse me?
- It's for the hall.
- The cost?
- A thousand.. per hour.
For this?
You must have no shame at all.
- These are the times we live in.
- Uh-huh. Not for long.
Zavulon!
Yegor?
What happened to you?
You said to me that only Great Ones
can go into the second level of Gloom!
Give me a weapon!
Give it to me!
A few minutes ago..
near the Expo subway,
a murder was prevented.
A Dark One attacked a human
in full public view.
- Did you make an arrest?
- No, we didn't.
- No case, no trial.
- We've recovered some physical evidence.
What kind?
Now you've done it.
Who the hell was she?
Rogova, do you not tell
your students that
committing murder happens
to be a crime now?
No! No! No way!
Where's your hat?
This is it? The best evidence you've got?
Yeah.
- What'd he look like?
- Don't remember.
- You don't remember, huh?
- No.
Okay, let's give it to the
lab and let them worry.
Come on.
Anton, let me have
your car keys, will ya?
Forty-nine years
since I rode the subway.
- Yeah, happy to give'em to you, man.
- I got all day.
Here.
And how are you doing, Sveta?
You feeling okay?
Uh-huh.
You need to get something to eat.
Let's find a restaurant.
Why didn't you tell Semyon
you knew the kid?
So now what do we do?
Where are you going?
If this damn hat's a problem,
why don't we just steal it, huh?
Oh, what's that? Hobo steaks again?
Of course not.
Willing donors.
I have a small request.
- My son, he just got his first
blood license in the mail.
- Congratulations.
- But he doesn't drink.
- By now they've already closed
the Night Watch lab, Zavulon.
Where do they store the
evidence over there?
In the archive.
You can have until the morning.
All right. How do you
want me to get there?
Quickly.
Kostya was out,
so I signed for it..
but.. but I didn't know.
Is there a way we can
take care of this problem?
- Your son is not a natural Other?
- Um, but, uh..
No. He bit the kid himself.
Because he had pneumonia,
sir, in both lungs!
Guess Mom had pneumonia too.
You bitch!
- I'm sorry.
- It happens.
He needs to wait a bit.
You can do that.
Yeah? I'll do anything.
Anything you need.
Anything, hmm?
That would be illegal.
You get that?
Get what? The Night Watch archive,
how am I getting the hat?
How? How?
Well, let's try asking the dad.
All right, food folks,
we need something for a growing boy.
All right! On the double!
On the double! Hustle it up now!
Here. Bottoms up.
Drink it.
- Yeah?
- Mr. Gorodetsky, I'm Yegor's teacher,
Galina Rogova.
- Your son lost his hat..
- Sorry. Wrong number.
You see hats like that
all over Moscow.
Well done.
You'll go far.
- Diving into the second-level Gloom.
- That's not much.
I couldn't push in there.
Barely got my hand in.
Can we get a menu
so we can get some food?
You ordered already.
Hmm. Don't remember.
Good.
Why are you so.. dirty?
You're worse than me.
It's Boris Ivanovich.
Well, Boris Ivanovich.
So, what are you doing?
Oh, we're just sitting here
waiting for our dumplings.
- Don't you have a lecture?
- Do I?
I forgot.
Uh, not tonight then.
- Tomorrow. 7:00.
- Mm-hmm.
Anton, you understand
that engaging in..
informal relations with
trainees is forbidden.
Well, it's a little late
for that. Isn't it?
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
As-salaam alaikum, Zoar.
Haven't seen you for a while.
Everything going well for you?
It all goes just as it should.
See you later, Zoar.
Anton, she'll soon be a Great One.
There is no room for two
Great Ones in this city.
You're talkin' about me.
No, Anton.
I mean your son.
If Yegor and Sveta cross paths..
the world will be lost to darkness.
Look at you.
You are a Light One..
drinking dark beer.
Real nice talk, you know?
Go ahead.
Eat, Yegor. Eat.
Tomorrow's going to be a big day.
You're going to need your strength.
- What's going on tomorrow?
- Mmm.
We'll be seeing a lot of guests.
Granny Darya is being released..
so she'll be there with Mashenka.
There will be presents.
So, anything you might like?
- It's early for this.
- I won't go.
We won't force you.
Don't want that to happen.
"On his deathbed,
Tamerlane told his servants..
"to bury him with his fist clenched.
His order was carried out."
I need these dumplings
to take away, Zoar.
I'm going home.
- These are manti.
- Yeah, whatever.
Ah, "The Lives
of Remarkable People."
Mm-hmm.
A remarkable life I've got, boy.
A son who is dark and unhappy..
and a girlfriend
with more talent than me.
Tamerlane had trouble with his son.
In those days, just how bad could
his problems have really been, huh?
He was killed.
You shouldn't
drink any more, Anton..
or you'll really run into trouble.
You have a heart of gold, Zoar.
- What do I owe you?
- A hundred.
Here.
You were warned.
"The location of
Tamerlane's burial site..
"long remained a mystery.
"In 1941,
under Professor Gerasimov..
"an expedition was organized
and went to Samarkand.
"But the war interfered, and all the
records of the expedition were scattered..
to various archives and research centers
dedicated to Central Asia."
"Your house is connected."
What is this nonsense?
Listen, Gorodetsky.
Seems your boy is in trouble.
They'll disintegrate him.
I told you, wrong number.
What a sad excuse for a father.
It's Yegor's birthday tomorrow.
Did you remember that?
Huh?
- Get a present.
- Oh, a present?
- A hat.
- A head warmer?
Like this one.
You know how many there are
in Moscow like this?
I absolutely can't help you.
- Can't or won't?
- Yeah.
- I'll write to the Inquisition.
- Oh, please. Write who you like.
Drop dead, will you?
Today we face an extremely strong rival.
The entire nation
is watching this match.
Dangerous.
There's the strike!
- Oh!
- And Ovchinnikov makes an amazing save!
Our team makes an immediate
counter-offense.
Long pass.
Hey! Hey, come on!
Hey!
The kick is good. Goal!
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
Two time-outs.
That's 15 minutes.
And then they take the penalty kicks.
- So we've changed the score.
- Goal! Goal! Goal!
- The balance has shifted..
- On the attack.
And the difference
is a dramatic one.
- Yes! Strike!
- Goal! Yeah!
This is the turning point.
The main thing now is not
to go back to defense but attack!
And attack with great care.
Both these teams are strong.
Around back! There's the strike!
It's in! Goal!
"Central Asia, Special Vault."
"CHALK OF FATE"
"Request permission for a
Samarkand expedition..
"to open the tomb
in the Gur-Emir mausoleum..
"where, according to our research,
Tamerlane is buried..
"with the Chalk of Fate
in his right hand.
Gesser. June 19, 1941.
Denied."
Once again our team attacks. The strike!
It's in! It's in!
A 4-2 victory!
But the price it cost was the nerves..
of not only the players
but you and me as well.
It's a great moment for us!
Oh, you're good.
He gave me such a look, Alicia.
It scared the hell out of me.
- You mean no one's covering you?
- I'm alone.
- Want me to come over?
- Thank you, but I'll be all right.
You be careful, okay?
Hello? Galya?
What is it?
Oh, sorry.
I'm just so exhausted.
- Call me later?
- You call me.
Yeah.
I need to get home.
Galina!
Who's there?
Enough with the jokes.
Who is this?
A judge.
Yes? And who would be on trial?
You are.
This is 741.
Forensic team is on the scene.
Paramedics are gone.
They left a report.
Galya! Galya! Galya!
- Let me through!
- Let's set up as close as we can.
- She's my daughter!
- I'm sorry, but this area is closed.
The team is working.
There are no wounds in evidence.
Why would you think it's a homicide?
We know who killed the woman.
Let me tell you where you're going to go!
Do you understand what I'm saying?
- Quit arguing! Go get me Zavulon!
- He's unavailable.
- Did you tell him it was me?
- I did.
- Who's with him?
- He can't be disturbed.
You can't go in there! No!
I did what you asked. You
said you would help.
Go on to work. I'll tell you
what to do next tonight.
- Hello.
- Don't you worry about a thing.
Ever heard of knocking?
You might try it.
Oh, well, look who's here!
You know, for some reason,
I can't seem to get hold..
- of your girlfriend, what's her name.
- Rogova is dead.
Bastard!
You know who did it?
The man's gone totally insane.
Galina met with Gorodetsky.
Evidence is what we need
to prove it.
- You think..
- Now get some!
- All right, I..
- Go now!
Can I take the wheels?
Chalk of Fate.
Samarkand.
Tamerlane's tomb.
Samarkand. Select.
Username: Anton.
Enter.
"YOU'VE GOT NEW MAIL
FROM USER ZAVULON"
"Thanks. You've helped your
son and the rest of us.
"Destroy the evidence right away.
And don't forget
it's Yegor's birthday."
Ah.
Ready?
Enough. What's the deal?
Have a bad night?
Are my eyes red?
Mm-hmm. Come on. We are
going to see Gesser.
- Why?
- Come on. Come on. Move. Move.
There is a major influx
of Dark Ones in the city.
Checking by districts, we're done
in Dimitrovka, Yaroslavka and Fili.
But, uh, in Bibirevo, uh,
we haven't, uh..
- we haven't gotten..
- Start.
A start yet.
No start yet. We simply don't have
enough men to cover it.
- How's it going?
- Shh.
There are just too many
of these Dark Ones gathering.
It's getting dark during the day.
They are getting ready
for something big.
Ilya, do you remember Galina Rogova?
- Rogova?
- Yes, Rogova.
My opinion is, um, she's dangerous.
- She could, uh, shatter the Truce.
- No, not anymore.
This morning Galina Rogova
was found dead.
She was discovered
in the hallway of her apartment.
There were no wounds anywhere.
Apparent cause of death:
total removal of life force.
Uh, all right, young lady,
use care now.
What's she called?
Mashenka.
Masha Rogova.
This man familiar?
Uh, no.
If you will allow it,
I am going to talk with Masha.
- Hello, Mashenka.
- Hi.
Oh, that's a nice turtle.
He's almost like a real one.
Do you know who this is?
N-No.
Your mama is gone.
My mama is gone.
She went on a long trip.
Your mama didn't go anywhere, honey.
Your mama is dead.
What do you mean, dead?
She's dead and gone.
Grandma! Grandma!
Ah, now what's the matter?
What is it, dear?
Grandma, Mama is dead.
Mama is dead and gone forever.
Oh, my poor darling angel.
Where did you hear that, huh?
The lady told me it was true.
What lady?
There's no one here.
Oh, my dear.
It was your mama, wasn't it?
She came to say good-bye.
The bottom line is that
we're being accused..
of a situation
which is.. unfortunate.
A Light Other who either
doesn't know that there is a truce..
or worse, is ignoring it.
This is the state we find ourselves in.
Have a question?
No?
Thank you. You're all free to go,
except for Semyon, Olga..
Ilya.. and Anton.
Thank you for the compliment,
Boris Ivanovich.
I have to conduct
an inside investigation.
Write your reports.
Where you were that night and..
whether your alibis
can be confirmed or not.
Ha!
Can I have the ball?
Come on.
- What is your major?
- Biology.
Mm-hmm.
Not drinking human blood,
is that what you study?
You're really kind of cute.
Shame you're a vampire.
We might have been friends.
So you think we won't?
Okay, maybe.
Easy there.
Tell me a story.
Your friend next door,
he around lately?
Why do you say he's my friend?
- Come on back!
- Hey, I really can't judge you.
- You can do whatever you want to do.
- Let's go!
You're a Dark Other.
You could even make friends
with Light Ones.
Thank you, miss.
Your humor's interesting.
You got the ball. Come on.
Last night, Galina Rogova
was killed at her home.
What's that got to do with me?
Her daughter is five years old.
Kostya, we're waiting!
Come on!
I saw her last night
talking to Gorodetsky.
Give us the ball at least!
Thank you.
Kostya!
- What have you got?
- Last night she met Gorodetsky.
- How did you find that out?
- A witness.
Hmm. Vampire Junior.
How did you know that?
Why don't you come on over?
I miss you.
Send Gorodetsky in.
When they killed Rogova,
Gorodetsky was in the archive.
- Hmm.
- Yes?
So he has an alibi.
But he won't confess to
it, and quite right.
And so we'll have no choice
but to turn him over to the Dark Ones.
What will they do with him?
I don't know,
but they won't get him alive.
You've thought of something?
Yes!
- Olga, have you seen the boss?
- Sit down.
I'm sorry, Olga.
I have to do this.
- What?
- I know you do.
Well, I don't.
But the problem..
Are you completely out of your mind?
I'm sorry.
Anton, you never
would've agreed to it.
Anton.
It'll be all right.
I need Gesser for a minute.
Get lost, you and Gesser.
Anton, no one gave you
permission to leave.
- What do we do with the voice?
- Not a problem.
Should be working. Give it a try.
Yes? Yes?
Yes. Hmm. Great. Now I'm a tranny.
You don't like it?
How do you walk?
These are important details.
Anton, remember, I don't smoke.
Look, you've smudged
your makeup already.
I'll manage.
Pay attention.
Nothing in your pockets.
That's why you carry a bag.
Another thing..
You're a woman now.
You need to keep your back straight.
Then why is my ass wiggling?
- Reflex reactions.
- You!
Easy, easy, easy, easy, easy.
- Boris Ivanovich.
- Ilya, hello.
- See you later.
- I was trying to, uh..
- Nothing to worry about.
- Nothing.
How long do I do this?
Two or three days. Until
we find the killer.
So where do I stay?
Work something out.
Call one of the guys.
Hey, look, Semyon.
Semyon, hey, can I crash with you?
- Okay. Starting..
- Today.
- Oh.
- No, no, no. Forget it.
- Boris.
- Sorry.
- We could try Svetlana, eh?
- Good idea.
What do I say?
Say that Boris Ivanovich
has a snoring problem.
Hold on!
Do I snore?
To sum up..
you have all now
learned the technique..
of detecting objects
hidden from us behind a barrier.
Svetlana..
show us the miracle of introscopy.
Tell us who is at the door.
It's Anton Gorodetsky.
Hello.
Excuse the interruption.
Please, Olga, not at all.
We're privileged that you join us.
- Thank you.
- We're studying the basics of introscopy.
- Since you're here, maybe you'll
show us a demonstration?
- Um..
- Just a small one.
- Well, timing's not good now.
Just something. Anything.
It would mean a great deal to us.
Really. Sorry. Now's not good
for me. I'm here for Sveta.
You smoke now?
Excuse me.
Poor Svetlana.
What's she going to do with him now?
Thank you. Let's go.
- Pretty soon Anton should be here.
- He's not coming.
- How do you know?
- He got stuck somewhere.
We were supposed to meet here
and go to a restaurant.
No time for that now.
I'll tell you why later.
Uh, I have a question for you.
Mm-hmm?
Yeah, ask me.
How much do you like Anton?
You like him?
He's a little
strange sometimes..
as if he were afraid of me.
Not as a woman, you know.
And not so much, uh, afraid.
- He just..
- Maintains his distance?
Uh, yeah.
Something like that.
No surprise there.
You're destined
to become a great witch..
and he's category three,
at a stretch.
I don't care what his category is.
It's all the same to me
as a woman. I love him.
Olga!
Careful there.
You be careful!
You're insane!
Look, I really know it's
none of my business,
but when you take a look
at it, it's obvious.
I think he loves you
very, very much.
A lot! He's just afraid.. afraid
that one day there'll come a time..
when you'll be too far away
for anything to happen.
Okay, yes, it's possible.
Someday something could happen..
but right now,
in the present, I'm here!
Come on, Sveta.
Can't you see that time is now?
It's now.
Ladies, you all right?
We'll be there in a minute.
Stay right where
you are. We're on our way.
Come on.
Let's go.
Then at night I called him.
Come in.
He wasn't home.
I called his mobile,
and he hung up on me.
- Not important.
- So maybe he was busy.
- Or maybe he has someone.
He hasn't had anyone for 12 years.
Really? Then he's got
some kind of complex.
"Biocomplex.
"Amazing natural way to enhance
all of your health characteristics..
and sex drive."
- Here.
- Thanks.
Why are you looking at me?
I'm going to have a shower.
Would you put on the kettle?
Why hasn't he had
a girlfriend for 12 years?
Bad time.
Strange.
Really. Why?
Sveta, listen.
Oh, God, how can I
possibly explain it?
Olga.
- Sometimes life throws a curve..
- Olga.
- And then everything is changed forever.
- Olga!
- Why forever?
Huh?
Bring me a towel, please.
They're in the cupboard.
- Not Olga.
- What?
What did you say?
I can't hear you.
What are you doing?
Not Olga. Anton.
I love you.
What is it?
What are you doing?
Not Olga. Anton.
They switched our bodies.
How dare you do this to me,
you bastard!
What made you think you could do a thing
like this to me now? I want you out!
You hear me? Out of my house! How could
you take advantage of me like this?
You.. I don't ever want
to see your face again!
You're a real bastard!
Are you crazy? Get out!
Just get out of here now!
- Whoa!
- ..nowhere near his best today.
- Oh!
Sergei Federov is not at his best.
He's got possession of the puck,
goes for the pass.
No, no, no!
Come on! Come on!
Pass back.
Markov grabs it.
Clear ice.
Body check.
- Oh!
- No flag on that play.
Our team is taking
some big risks out there.
- Come on! Come on! Go, go!
- No!
You morons.
What are they doing? They're not thinking.
You should show this body
a little care.
What am I doing that's bad?
I'm making sure it gets food.
Lines up and shoots.
No goal. Puck's back in play.
Each ounce of extra weight on her..
she'll remove a full pound
of flesh from you.
That lock doesn't work.
Gonna say hi?
Hi there, vampy.
Yes, yes, yes!
Look at that shot! It's amazing!
Look at this!
That was a game! Ah!
Amazing how men will think of
anything not to keep a promise.
What do you mean?
We made serious plans to go
to a restaurant.
Slapshot. Almost another goal.
- I'm not allowed.
- That was close.
Not a very pleasing moment..
I need your son.
Uh, Kostya.
- Hi there, Kostya.
- Yeah, hi.
Come.
Uh, who's this?
Papa, no.
Have you seen Gorodetsky?
Because we can't find him.
Too bad.
We think he switched bodies
with a young lady.
It's really amazing
what people get up to.
To you. May you get out of
this mess as soon as possible.
Look, a Dark One.
What kind of Dark is he?
That boy at the Expo Center,
he means a lot to you, doesn't he?
You help him so much.
Are you trying to break me down?
Once again
I see what you are..
an idiot.
Off to suck someone's blood..
and say a few incantations.
What do you want?
Would you know him
in a different body?
Hmm. Don't know.
Haven't tried it.
Mine, for example.
Mean something?
Yeah. And this car is unreal.
I'm going.
- I need a minute.
- Don't mix up the doors.
The one with the boy's
picture on it - not for you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh! Damn it.
They set me up.
Good work, Anton. Now they
have the proof they want.
I didn't do it.
It's a coincidence.
It's not a coincidence.
It's a frame-up.
But Anton wasn't there.
You shouldn't have left the house.
You shouldn't have been there.
Now they have the opportunity..
to do whatever they want with you.
Why aren't we moving?
- Next time say "please."
- Zavulon!
I'm listening, Zavulon.
I am bringing a formal
charge of murder..
against the Night Watch agents..
Anton Gorodetsky.
Are you?
- Well, maybe we can find him.
- Oh, we'll take him right now.
He's not here.
The one we accuse
of committing murder..
is in the body of that young woman.
What are you doing?
You don't have
the right to interfere.
Stop this! Why aren't you
doing anything?
Why? Why aren't you doing anything?
- No!
- That's enough!
Listen to me.
We cannot interfere.
If you break the Truce,
they'll kill you.
It will achieve nothing.
Line 22.
Why is the trolley here?
You have to stop this!
Step on it. Step on it. Come on.
Let's go.
You're an actor, right?
If you can't prove
before dawn..
that Gorodetsky is innocent in regard
to the deaths of the Dark Ones..
providing suitable evidence..
we will issue a warrant..
for his elimination.
Day Watch has already filed
the procedural request.
Here is a copy.
We won't turn him over to you.
I'm writing an official
note of protest.
If you refuse to comply
with this order..
the result will be war.
This is a provocation
by the Day Watch.
The Supreme Powers will not
be on your side in this.
The charges brought by
the Day Watch are quite real.
Your protest will be turned down.
- Hello.
- Alisher. It's Gorodetsky in Moscow.
- Ah! Anton, friend. How are you?
- Hey.
Okay. I'm going to be
flying in soon..
and I need a way to
get to Tamerlane's tomb..
- without anyone knowing.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Yes. You're welcome.
- Hello? What was that?
- I wasn't talking to you.
- Can you help me with this?
- Of course.
For Gorodetsky, it's do or die.
Just come in, we'll fix it all for you.
Yeah. Say hi to Semyon.
- Salaam alaikum, Zavuloroka.
- Salaam.
Zavulon, there is a Gorodetsky
coming here.
Gorodetsky going to Samarkand?
Thank you, Mahmud.
So I'm flying to Samarkand?
Hold on.
His plane..
what if it fell out of the sky?
What do you mean?
Hmm. We should let the parrot fly.
Okay.
Yep.
- There.
- And this is..
His ride, of course.
To the airport.
Yes?
- Olga?
- How are you?
Bad. We gotta switch back.
I'll meet you at the airport
in a half an hour.
Late passengers,
please proceed directly to the gate.
Let's walk.
Let's take the lift.
- My body.
- Going someplace?
- Mm-hmm. I need it.
- My body's not good enough for you?
Don't want it to get messed up.
In what way?
Excuse us.
You can stop staring now.
Uh, we should walk.
- What's this?
- It's a belt.
No, it's not.
It's a weapon.
Purpose of visit?
To study monuments in the ancient
Uzbek capital. And listen.
Right now I'm really
running late for my flight.
Why Samarkand?
- Return flight's in the morning.
- Right. Yeah, yeah.
How many monuments
can you see in only one night?
One.
Hold on.
No daydreaming on duty.
- Flight to Samarkand?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Anton, where are you off to?
- Seats, please. We're leaving.
- Yeah, sure. One minute.
- Please take your seat now.
- Okay. Okay. I'm sitting.
- You have any of those candy mints?
- Yes, I've got them. Sit down.
Great. Thanks a lot.
- I'm sticking with you on this.
- Just buckle in. Okay?
Tower, come in. This is 593.
We are ready for takeoff.
593, copy. Use Runway 2. Conditions are..
Take off.
If you open the tomb, it'll be war.
And you will not make it out.
I'll be careful then.
Okay?
Just stick my pinky in.
No, that won't fly.
- What was that?
- Under control.
Go, please, now.
Proceeding.
No. No can do.
593, what is it?
Conditions seem normal, but no can do.
Listen here.
Listen. You all want to
fly to Samarkand, right?
Yes! Yes!
They all want to go.
Understand?
Off we go.
- Losing runway. Yes or no?
- Wheels up.
We're not gonna make it.
We need more thrust!
Get her nose up!
Pull her up!
Get the damn landing gear up!
Oh, my God.
593, we need a status report.
I didn't send for you.
Why aren't we doing anything?
Want some?
No.
Once a man of ours
found himself in danger.
And he broke the Truce.
And..
when he found himself
facing the inevitable punishment..
there was a girl who tried to help him
in this, much as she could.
Oh. It was Olga.
Later he was acquitted, and..
the Inquisition let him go.
- But the witch..
- Hasn't changed at all.
The one we Light Others needed
very greatly just then..
she was sentenced.
That's a sad story..
Boris Ivanovich.
She was the real target..
and I was only the bait.
She was the Great One.
The Chalk isn't in Tamerlane's tomb.
How do you know?
Have you been there?
In '41, Boris had problems,
and I needed the Chalk.
I arranged with archaeologists to organize
an expedition and went with them.
In Samarkand, an old man
came to me called Zoar.
He said if we opened the tomb,
it would start a war.
But I knew that I would have the Chalk
and I could change everything.
When we opened the tomb,
there was an inscription.
"I held the whole world
in my hand..
but I can't take it
where I'm going."
The Chalk was not in his right hand.
- What was Zoar doing?
- He worked in the government.
Ideology section.
And with Tamerlane?
Pretty much the same thing.
Zoar as right-hand man.
Right-hand man?
Oh, Zoar.
You sly dog.
- Olga.
- Hmm?
Let's turn the plane around.
I know where the Chalk is.
Zoar's got it.
Zoar, give me the Chalk.
Here it is.
You don't get it.
I mean the magic Chalk.
It's the magic Chalk.
- And where do the markings go?
- Well, here.
- On the blackboard.
- And does it work?
Every day.
What do I write?
Whatever you want.
How is it? How is it
that you're here now?
I was just passing by
and happened to look in.
You were just passing by?
You think you were just passing by?
No, no. Yegor, it worked!
Don't you understand?
- It really worked!
- What did? What worked, Papa?
The Chalk. The Chalk.
It worked!
What a blessing
that you've come back.
Wait. Why are you so cold?
You're frozen.
Now wait. Wait a second. Come on.
We'll get you something to eat.
That'll warm you up.
Zoar, get me something good and hot,
because I have a son today!
Oh, sit. Sit. Sit down.
Please sit down. It really worked.
Maybe we should
wash your trousers too.
Then what am I going to wear?
- Hmm?
- And where are you going to
this time of night, huh?
No. Go away. Go away.
- Go away. I'm busy.
- What, are you ticklish?
Oh.
Excuse me. I'm sorry to bother you,
but I'm looking for your neighbor.
You're not alone.
Thank you.
You have to be careful, Svetlana.
A vampire?
Yes, I'm a vampire!
That's me!
Excuse him. Please.
Really. No laws are being broken.
- I'm not accusing you of anything.
- Look.
- I.. I'm not.
- We have the registration.
- I'm not accusing you.
- Here is a permit, see?
And everything in
the fridge is good.
- There's some cheese, milk.
- I'm sorry.
- Potatoes.
- Papa, go inside.
- Don't do this to yourself!
- Kostya! Kostya!
- Hello?
- Hello. Anton?
- Who is it?
- It's me, Svetlana.
Svetlana. You know he has a family.
A son.
Please don't call him anymore.
Riceplov.
You eat it with your hands.
You like it?
Uh, Papa, will you
come and eat with us?
- And who would that be?
- With me.. and Mom.
Yegor, I can't come with you.
I have another.. Life.
Yegor, understand..
You'll come anyway!
Zoar, why didn't it work for me?
I put it where you told me to.
This is the place
where my fate happens.
Plov - that's 150 rubles.
And your fate is somewhere else.
You can't change
the fate of another.
Every living person
must answer for his own.
Do you remember where it was..
you broke your own destiny?
You waited.. till now to say this?
You didn't ask.
And so it's my fault?
I am sorry, Anton.
What's the matter?
He took the Chalk.
- Hello.
- Sorry. Uh, I know it's late..
- but could I speak with Yegor?
- Are you crazy?
It's 1:00 in the morning.
Yegor's asleep.
Listen. Can you take me
to the Expo Center?
Zavulon! We found him!
Go on! Finish him off!
You idiots! I need him alive.
Just run him around
for a while, okay?
- Anton.
- Boris, I'll look over this way.
Is anyone here? Anton.
Zoar?
There isn't anyone here.
- What's that?
- I think it's his phone.
But why is it broken?
The Dark Ones want the Chalk too.
The big game begins.
What do you think you're doing?
What station is this?
I'm gone.
Okay. What's going on?
Stay there!
I mean it!
Freeze!
Don't move!
Stop!
Who was it you spoke to?
I don't know. They told me
not to call there again.
Yegor.
- Why was he here?
- The Chalk's with him.
- What is it?
- What?
Just a sec.
- Remember Yegor's address?
- Got it.
- Then let's go.
- Right.
- Please get her.
- Sveta.
Sveta?
Flushed out.
Wanted to get out of the cold, huh?
Take me anywhere.
Sure thing.
Uncle Zavulon,
why are we the Dark Ones?
Imperfections are hidden
in darkness, Yegor.
And people..
always have their imperfections.
It allows us the luxury
of doing what we want.
Of being exactly who we truly are.
Gives us the gift of love.
Look what I found, Uncle Zavulon.
The Chalk of Fate.
- Hello.
- Zavulon.
- What now?
- Have you got the Chalk?
No.
- You do not have the right to touch it.
- I know that.
So, what's up with your shindig?
- You are inviting me?
- No, but I'll take some pictures.
Slow down, Semyon.
I want you to get everyone
over to the Hotel Cosmos.
- Where are you going?
- Ah, I need to change.
Alicia.
You could correct your mistakes with it.
- No. Why don't you keep it?
- What about you?
I don't need it.
I n your whole life,
no errors were made?
- I just don't regret them.
- Then what should I do with it?
You could give it to Alicia.
What does she regret?
What do women normally regret?
Loving wrong.
Sure you're making
the right decision?
I just can't live like
this, scared to death
of shadows, fearing
every phone call.
Not me.
I'm not afraid of anybody.
Even if you're like us,
you're still a human being.
Human, Papa?
Can you turn me back into a human?
No. No.
But listen.
Son. Son!
Listen here.
Wait a minute.
- Alicia, are you coming?
- Yes.
- We're starting.
- On my way.
And don't fiddle with the ring.
It hurts.
Kostya.
Why did you come here?
Not welcome?
You are.
Close the door.
- Hello.
I'm going to take you from here.
Zavulon.
Coming.
- I said..
- Good evening. I..
Come back later.
- I'll go.
- Kostya, wait.
No.
There's something I
have to explain to you.
No need.
I can't do this. He
feels everything I feel.
Do you understand?
- I can't take it off.
- I'll help you.
Don't. He'll kill you.
- I'm not afraid.
- I am.
I believe I told you to come back later!
- Listen. I said..
- Come on. Time to go.
- And who's this?
- Neighbor of Gorodetsky.
- Knows him in any disguise.
- Hmm.
- So, where's your dad?
- Uh..
The person you're calling
is not in range now.
Does that hurt?
Come on.
Come on. Stay. Stay.
Okay. Okay.
You have no right to do this.
This is against the law.
Stop it! You can't do this!
There we go.
Okay. Let's see now.
What have we got?
- I'm just following orders.
- Oh, yes. I understand. Absolutely.
I do just what I'm told.
Good bird. That's Gosha.
- Gosha's going to the hotel
for some kid's birthday.
- That's it.
What idea do you have?
No. You won't get away with it.
Everybody knows exactly
what your ugly face looks like.
But.. But..
Not my style, of course.
- Sorry. Running a little late.
Where's the party going on?
- Top floor.
- Parrot's on his way to you.
- Right.
- How's the food?
- Not bad.
Hurry or you'll miss out.
Uh, Victor, give me your coat.
Hey, Victor.
How's it going?
Don't "Victor" me.
Oh.
That's not you.
Where is he then?
You know?
Yegor!
Who's there?
Yegor.
Quiet. Quiet.
Let his dad say a few words.
Did you forget
it was his birthday? Shame.
Let's punish the man.
Come on, Anton.
Say something.
He waited for you.
You're a Light One.
You guys are good at this stuff.
Come on.
I, uh..
want to wish you..
happiness and good health.
Is that it?
And that everything..
in your life is.. good.
I'll tell you the rest later.
- Let's leave here.
- No.
Say it now.
Later will be too late.
Yeah. Sure.
For you, I wish only one thing:
that you learn how to forgive..
and that no one
you know ever tells you..
Bravo!
You need to forgive him.
Your dad's tired.
He's been poisoned.
- I'm trying to exit. Do you mind?
- Intercept that vehicle immediately!
Got it.
You're cutting me off!
So that's how the salad
came together, sonny.
- Now try a bite.
- What is it?
Which is more essential?
The ingredients or the effect?
Grandma, you ruined my
life, so just back away.
- You did the same to me.
- Yeah?
Yeah. Thanks to you,
I got 12 years in the zoo as a toad.
Fancy that.
So what are we supposed
to be doing for you now?
Forgotten why you came here?
Maybe.. Chalk?
Chalk, you say?
But there's nothing to write on since
they tore down your apartment house.
You're right.
The wall's still there though.
Come here, you.
How about a grape?
Want a grape, huh?
No? Yeah. Just get me the Chalk,
and I'll give it to you.
- She won't take it.
- Well-trained, huh?
- Very well-trained.
- Not eating.
- Yeah. Not eating.
- Well, I am.
Well done.
- Eating it all.
- Excellent.
Right now. Everything!
I think we're
really close to him now.
Oh. Oh.
He got a license?
Look out!
Are you a complete idiot?
Fine!
Stop it, Semyon. Pull yourself together.
What are you doing?
Don't. Step on it!
We're late.
Shall I call the Inquisition?
No hurry.
We are missing a guest.
Zavulon, my friend!
Let's have a beer.
Come on now. No joking.
One beverage.
Watch it now, Gorodetsky.
The Inquisition's taking you.
Me? I don't think so.
Not at all.
I didn't kill anyone.
And you know it.
Then who's the right one?
Like in a detective story..
it could be the man
who does the floors.
Or a butcher.
Valery Sergeevich!
What brings you here tonight?
I've come to get my son.
He came here for his boy too.
Kostya got a license.
First one.
Good for him.
You know, that's not him.
Okay. Then what?
He's harmless.
The son of his mother.
She was special, you know.
More like his dad, I'd say.
Dark Ones.
Pay attention!
Would you like to know
who murdered Galina Rogova?
She was murdered..
and the one who did it..
Uh, that man is you.
Why me murder those folks?
Huh.
Those?
A very good thing to ask about.
Now, why were they killed?
Huh? Oh, wait, wait, wait.
You know who put him up to it?
That's the good part.
Now you die!
Papa, no. No, Papa.
With this very knife.
I wanted.. so much..
for you to be human.
No circumstances..
can ever justify the crime
of breaking the Great Truce.
So, do you confess your guilt now?
Yes. I do.
Last words?
What is, is.
The Inquisition declares the innocence
of Anton Gorodetsky.
You are free to go now.
Thanks, but I'm good here, you know.
- Papa.
- Kostya, I'll explain it all.
Alicia, did you call them?
No.
Zavulon! Keep your word!
Hey, granddad.
Don't spoil the mood.
- Just go away.
- They set him up. It's not right.
Only one man set him up.
Tango!
- Oh. Quiet. Quiet.
- Kostya.
Just give me the Chalk.
Quiet. Quiet.
Leave me alone!
Ooh!
One is lost.
One is found.
One goes.
Another arrives.
She's here.
Now the guest list is full.
You've got to stop her,
Uncle Zavulon.
There's no stopping her now.
And death would be..
Melodrama, Yegor, is not my style.
I'll do it.
Hmm. She's stronger, so be prepared.
Don't do it.
- Svetlana.
- Anton!
Go. Just go home. Okay?
Look. I'll explain all of it.
Everything. Later.
It'll be better if you go.
You know? Hey,
don't be offended, huh?
Oh.
It's all just great here now.
Go home, please.
Uncle Zavulon, he doesn't love her.
- He's a Dark One now.
- No, Yegor.
Just casting shadows.
- Then what do we do?
- Hmm. Think, Yegor. What is there?
I stuck a needle in her.
In the Gloom the other day.
I could drink her now.
125. Three minutes to target.
- 320. Seven minutes.
- Thirty-four. Six minutes.
540. Two minutes.
518? 518?
518. One minute away from target.
On no account should anyone
start any heavy action without us.
Hold your position, all units.
Repeat. Hold your position.
They've got us surrounded.
There's no answer.
Sveta.
It's me. Look at me.
Don't close your eyes, Sveta.
I'm losing you.
- Do not close your eyes.
- Hello?
Easy. Just help me out a little.
- If you can give me a little help..
- Hey, stupid!
- Come on, man! Open the door!
- I want you to stay on the line.
Open the damn door!
It's been nice!
Don't stop breathing.
Up you get, Sveta.
You're doing well.
- Get that ramp in place!
- In front?
Yeah!
Talk to me. Come on, Sveta. Talk to me.
Tell me what's happening.
Stay with me now.
They're crazy. Nuts.
Well done, Sveta.
Great. Breathe. Breathe.
That's good. Now, let's get up.
You're a beauty.
Now come on, Sveta.
We're standing up.
Come on. Come on.
Up. Let's go. Let's go.
Sveta.
- Yes? Hello?
Hello?
Olga?
- We're almost there. Wait.
- I found Anton.
Only he's drunk.
H-He doesn't want to go anywhere.
Go practice now.
He was drugged?
You have to get out of there.
It's a trap. And
you stay away from Yegor.
Do you hear me?
I understand.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes, I hear you.
What do you want?
- I need Anton Gorodetsky.
- I need him too.
- We need to talk.
- No.
You're a liar.
You really came to
take him away from me.
No.
He loves you too much.
And you.
Ladies and gentlemen..
it's finally time for the main event
of our celebration..
which we've been patiently
waiting for a thousand years.
Today, a Great Other
appeared before us!
I'm not going to fight with you.
You don't have a choice.
You strapped in?
We've chosen to start the battle.
And this time, we'll be victorious!
Damn, he's big.
Because if a single drop
of Dark blood..
is spilled anywhere,
I will tear the Truce apart!
And it is time to create
a brand-new world where we're on top!
We made it.
How long are we supposed to
keep hiding in corners?
Who's breaking a law here?
Is it us or them?
That's the point, men.
- We know the faces of every one of them.
- That's right!
Every single Dark, horrible one!
The people believe in our cause! If we
don't give them protection, who will?
Because there is no longer
anyone left anywhere
who is able to change
the shape of fate!
Because that fate is now
here in our hands!
- And that's the point!
- Listen!
Listen to me!
They want to start a war!
And over the world..
there will be darkness,
like eternal night!
Hey.
And nothing can..
The two of them
in there, fighting..
- Now I'll leave.
- Not happening.
What is this?
Blood! Blood!
Blood!
- So.
- So what?
- It's started.
- Oh, no.
Blood! Blood!
- It's begun.
- Gesser.
Let's go!
- Everybody out. Evacuate!
- Out!
- We have to evacuate the top floor now!
- Everyone out! Fire!
- Everyone! Evacuate!
- Fire. What the hell?
Fire! Fire!
Everyone leave now!
- Come on!
- Fire.
- Get out. Hurry up.
- What's going on out here?
Someone tell me.
What's going on?
Everybody out!
Anton.
Anton, where are you?
Panic in the streets as the people of
Moscow try to find some kind of safety..
for themselves and their families
in the midst of this devastation.
They're on the way back.
There's a fire on this floor.
Everyone stay ca..
- What is happening?
- There's a fire. Run!
Right, right, right!
I'm running! I'm running! I'm running!
The destruction
is tremend..
Getting good shots?
- A little dark.
- Hmm. The end of the world.
There's always hope.
Stepan.
Find Alicia.
Get the Chalk from her.
- Alicia! Where is she? Do you know?
- Alicia? That way, I think.
Alicia.
Alicia, stop.
I'm too old to run around after you.
What are you doing?
Hold it. Stop.
Run. Anton, run!
Now you.
Stay there.
You die!
Come back here, you.
You little freak.
Stop.
Stop, you little bastard!
Shh. Shh. Shh.
Quiet. Quiet. Quiet.
Hey!
Are you going to show me
where Alicia is?
Okay?
Okay.
Take me to her.
Kostya.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
Kostya.
Give it to me. Give me the Chalk.
No.
- Bastard! Go away!
- You can't do it, Alicia.
- Believe me. There is no way
you can bring him back.
- I can change it!
You can't fix it,
no matter how you try.
- Why not?
- Because it's not your fault.
Now hand the Chalk over to me!
- Then whose fault is it?
- What difference does it make now?
I'll tell you!
None at all!
I am to blame.
Anton. Anton.
- Is that you? Are you there?
- Okay. Okay.
- Moment here. Moment.
- Anton, please help.
- I got you, Sveta.
- I can't see.
Shh, shh. It's.. it's okay.
Let go! Let him go!
- I'm not giving him to you! You hear?
- Don't let go of me!
Anton, don't let go!
Anton, hold on to me!
Hold on!
Anton! Don't leave me!
- Anton! Don't leave me!
- Yegor!
- You let go of him!
No!
Let go, Yegor!
What a mess you've made, Anton.
I, uh.. I found..
the Chalk, Boris Ivanovich.
- That building's gone.
- Yeah.
There's still a wall there.
Farewell, Anton.
You need to run.
The camera's only good
for a short exposure.
I'm grateful, Boris Ivanovich.
All right.
So, do you agree?
Well..
No.
I think I can handle this.
On my own.
No case, no trial.
I'm sorry.
Got a smoke?
You sure?
I don't smoke.
- Nothing?
- You sure?
I'm sure.
He's human again.
He won't know her.
Yes, he will.
- No pushing them now.
- And no blocking, eh?
Guess who's wrong.
Hey. Wait.
Who's your daddy?
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Have we possibly met?
Somewhere else?
- Maybe we did.
- Yeah?
Oh!
They're all over.
Trendy too. Incredible.
Good job.
Hey!
SubText: NoRMITA.326