The police are searching for Robert
Zeuthen's nine-year-old daughter, Emilie
who disappeared earlier this evening
from her home.
What are you doing to find her?
- Sarah Lund. Who is this?
- The girl's all right.
I'm collecting on a debt.
We're looking into a connection between
this case and the Zeuthen kidnapping.
Those killed have been
instrumental in closing the case.
- They're willing to pay 100 million.
- I can get more out of it than that.
Why didn't you
let me take her home?
- What case?
- I don't know anything about it.
It's important to the perpetrator.
Get a hold of the directors.
- Make sure we're not hiding anything.
- Hiding what?
Maja is looking for the smallest thing.
Perhaps one ought to look elsewhere.
PM Kamper broke off his electoral tour
in Jutland to return to Christiansburg.
- A 13-year old girl was found dead.
- Did you intervene?
No. There was nothing to suggest,
the case wasn't solved.
No, but there bloody well is now!
Emilie's life depends on this case.
- You can't get personally involved.
- I know what I'm doing, thanks.
He's asked me to tell you,
that he'll pay anything.
I have a suggestion.
A life for a life.
I'll get Zeuthen,
and you'll get the girl.
If he loves his daughter enough,
then he will save her.
Prepare Zeuthen.
And, Lund...
remember, this is your last chance.
THE KILLING III
The situation is very tense tonight,
and sources have revealed,
that the kidnapping of Emilie Zeuthen
may be entering its final phase.
The Prime Minister has rushed back
to Christiansburg,
after once again denying all criticism
of the government's handling of the case.
Zeuthen is in the car,
the perp hasn't called,
and no one knows where they are.
- Do we know why Zeuthen is with them?
- He wanted to cooperate.
About the call from Jens Lebech.
I have informed Special Branch.
They're taking it seriously,
but it's not illegal to call the PM.
Hello?
He's just provoking you.
In his eyes, you've taken his wife.
- He must have leaked...
- I don't give a damn about his motive.
I've defended the Justice Minister.
If his story checks out, I want to know.
- The Treasurer wants a meeting.
- Not now. Focus on the kidnapping.
- She's in the department - talk to her.
- You just fired the Justice Minister.
- If you like Mogens so much, join him.
- Come on, we're on your side!
- Everyone's trying to save your arse.
- It's a risky move, please reconsider.
The perpetrator was last seen
driving a black truck.
Emilie is probably on board, but so far
there's no contact with the vehicle.
Lund and Zeuthen
are on the E20 South.
We're using
encrypted radio channels.
All escort cars
will keep a low profile.
No lights, no helicopters -
understood?
- Have you found the truck?
- No, but we have people on the address.
I was just there.
Emilie's been there,
but nothing points to where they went.
- Can we trace him?
- No, he's changed internet providers.
Excuse me, Brix,
but you must be able to find a truck.
What do you think we're trying to do?
Lund and Zeuthen are well covered.
- SWAT can be deployed in 20 seconds.
- I'm sure the perp's aware of that.
Borch.
- Why doesn't he call?
- He will call.
What do you intend to do?
When we know the exchange location,
we'll pull you out and free her.
What if he finds out
that you're cheating?
As soon as we've tracked him down,
we won't be waiting for him.
- Don't worry about that.
- What if that's what he expects?
- We have the necessary manpower.
- And you've tried this before?
Yeah, yeah.
- Is Robert Zeuthen there?
- Yes. Do you want to talk to him?
I'll get my chance.
- Where are you?
- By exit 37.
- Where are we going?
- The invitation is only for two.
- There's only two of us.
- I don't believe you.
Don't do anything stupid,
if you want to see the girl again.
- Just tell us what to do.
- Take exit 38.
If I sense that you're not alone,
this is the last you'll hear from me.
- Do you understand?
- I understand.
- Next exit. She's there in one minute.
- What's in that area?
It's a deserted country road.
There's nothing there.
Shit, the perp's been able to spot
the escort cars from miles away!
- Then we'll increase the distance.
- We've no idea where he is, Brix.
- What will Lund do if anything happens?
- We're following her via the car's GPS.
And I refuse to ask the perpetrator
for permission to stay on the motorway.
There's news on the truck.
I think we've found him. A Volvo FH16.
The same model we saw at the building.
- But is it that one?
- It's carrying a shipping container.
- One tail light's smashed. It's him.
- What's he doing with a container?
- No idea, but it's him. Do we stop him?
- No, don't do anything.
- We could stop him for a faulty tyre.
- Just keep your distance and wait.
Where are you exactly?
I can still see the cars. Get them
out of here. I'm about to exit. Over.
Roger that. Asbjørn has a visual on
the perpetrator, a few miles behind you.
We'll send two cars forward.
The rest will follow Lund with GPS.
No escort cars within viewing distance.
Birgit, it'll have to wait.
I don't want Mogens around right now.
You defended him in the press and on TV,
and then you go and sack him.
Because he's not in control.
His own officials say so.
- Jens Lebech has his own reasons.
- I need to go back in.
There's no evidence Mogens put pressure
on the assistant public prosecutor.
Not even Special Branch believe
there's anything to it.
If the kidnapping ends badly,
they will pin it on you.
They've traced the perpetrator's car
and are planning to free Emilie Zeuthen.
Keep me informed. Tell Stoffer
that we're meeting with Birgit.
He went downstairs to pick up
a report from the Ministry of Justice.
You don't need to go to reception.
I'm the one who called you.
I've asked your brother to call, but his
arrogance is clouding his judgment.
- What do you want?
- Your brother has ruined my life.
It doesn't take up much space
in his calendar,
but I want to give him a chance
to make up for it.
You want him
to keep his hands off Rosa?
Yes. I have information that could ruin
everything you've fought for.
So, is that too much to ask?
If you want to help your brother,
then scamper off to get him.
The Prime Minister won't be blackmailed
by some disloyal official,
who can't hang onto his wife.
Does that answer your question?
Yes. Then you're asking for it.
You've just received an email.
- Yes, but what did he say?
- He didn't say any more.
I told him to get stuffed,
because he doesn't have anything.
We'll get Special Branch
to check the idiot out.
I'm going back to see what's happening.
Kristian, wait. We received some images
from an anonymous source.
It looks like something from a
surveillance camera at Christiansburg.
Isn't that the Justice Minister?
- And who is that?
- We didn't finish.
Get hold of Mogens right away.
- Lund speaking.
- I'm on my way. Everything OK?
Yes, I'm still on the main road.
The truck is approaching the exit.
They'll stage an accident and stop him.
SWAT are joined
by army sharpshooters...
I understand. I'll just continue
until further notice.
One more thing.
Maybe it wasn't Zeuthen or Zeeland
who were covering things up.
What are you talking about?
I've discovered that the prosecutor and
the investigator fiddled with the time.
In the report, she disappeared on Friday.
The foster family says it was Thursday.
Why is that important?
The Zeeland sailors weren't
in Danish waters on the Thursday.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Yes. You'd better stop that car.
- They'll shoot him with Emilie there?
- They know what they're doing.
- Yes?
- Have you reached the woods?
No, there are only fields.
Then it's coming up. You'll find
a disused workshop. Wait there.
04-36, the workshop is disused.
The perpetrator is nowhere near it.
Pull over and wait.
Carl is at your mum's.
She's trying to get him to sleep.
We have visual contact with the truck
that Emilie is likely to be in.
- We're about to stop it.
- What if...?
I can't go into detail, but we're not
taking any chances. We're very careful.
- I'd like to be there.
- Yes, I'll provide a car for you.
But you'll have to wait
until the operation is over.
- He's speeding up. Will you make it?
- SWAT are in position.
Keep your distance. The accident site
is coming up in 1,200 metres.
Roger that.
He's slowing down now.
010-04, Brix, we have a problem.
The truck is indicating.
He's taking exit 35. I'm positive.
He's taking the exit now.
- It makes no sense. Lund exited later.
- 010-04, we'll follow him. Over.
What's happening?
Asbjørn has a visual.
We'll try again.
- What do we do?
- Stay where you are. He's far away.
- What?
- They'll try again in a while.
What happened?
Did he spot them?
- Hello?
- You took your time finding the phone.
What do you have in mind now?
This is more private.
Get in the car.
No, stop.
Not that car, Lund.
Look up.
Leave your phones
where I can see them.
You don't have a choice.
Just do as I say.
Do you see the van?
It's for you.
We need to increase our distance.
There's no traffic. He'll spot us. Over.
SWAT are 300 metres behind you.
When the road splits, they'll overtake him,
and then cut him off. Over.
Yes, but they need to hurry.
022-12, what's happening?
The truck has stopped
in a viaduct. Over.
Is he stuck?
- 022-12, report back.
- Shit!
Brix, he's gone.
He left behind the container.
04-36, Lund, come in.
Brix here, we have a problem.
Lund, come in.
Lund?
The car's abandoned. Their phones
have been thrown on the ground.
- They've continued in another vehicle.
- We have the area surrounded.
- They can't just up and disappear.
- Just find that bloody truck, now!
No, wait.
Yes?
Send Zeuthen over,
then the girl walks.
We've traced you.
You have no chance of escape.
If anyone knew where I was,
don't you think they'd step in?
What's he saying?
Send Zeuthen over now.
Last chance.
- I'll go.
- No, you'll stay here.
He'd have no reason to let her go
once he's killed you.
They'll be here soon.
I'll go.
Stay here.
- Lund, what are you waiting for?
- I'm coming for Emilie now.
I want you
to send Zeuthen over first.
Zeuthen will come
when I have Emilie.
Why are you doing this? Why do you
risk your life for these people?
I know that Louise Hjelby
meant a great deal to you.
What happened back then was horrible,
but Robert Zeuthen is not to blame.
Zeeland had the case closed.
Zeuthen is responsible, and you know it.
Why risk it all
to protect the sailors?
You can ask Zeuthen that.
I don't have to, because I know
that they couldn't have done it.
The local investigator or the assistant
public prosecutor fiddled the case.
The date of the girl's disappearance
was changed to the following day.
That means, the sailors weren't even
in the country the day she went missing.
Just shut up and send Zeuthen
out onto the bridge.
All they did was to find the girl.
Someone must have stopped them from
saying that it didn't appear to be a suicide.
They never admitted
anything else to you, did they?
And what about
the assistant public prosecutor?
Did he say anything about Zeeland
or Zeuthen getting the case closed?
Did he?
I'll put down my gun
and come in unarmed.
We can talk more about that
when Emilie is safe.
OK?
You speak well for her, but it's too late.
Zeuthen deserves to suffer as I have.
Zeuthen has nothing to do with this.
Where is she?
- Dad!
- Emilie!
Emilie!
Dad!
- Dad!
- Emilie!
Dad!
Emilie!
You'll get whatever you want,
but you have to give us Emilie.
Emilie!
No!
Zeuthen!
Emilie!
No!
Did you or did you not have a meeting
with that public prosecutor?
As I've always said,
the answer is no.
So, it isn't you with him here?
- What did you talk about?
- I don't know...
Will you recall if I tell you the photos
have been sent to several news editors?
I just wanted to make sure
that everything was done properly.
Zeeland were mentioned in the case.
You got him to put a lid on the case,
and Zeuthen's daughter is paying for it.
- I didn't. I would never break the law.
- You've shelved this case.
You've withheld information that could
have helped the police solve the case.
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
What the hell were you thinking?
They say that he shot her.
They say that she's been killed.
The helicopter won't be an eye in the sky
in the dark, but he can't have gone far.
- What about the girl?
- The tidal current is strong,
but we'll find her within a few hours.
Emilie!
Where is she?
Emilie?
It can't be.
No.
No! No!
Good morning.
I hope it's OK, I stayed another night.
I haven't slept that well for ages.
I've had a lot of problems
with my lower back.
When the baby turns and kicks.
Did you have that?
I took some sofa cushions,
and now it's all gone.
Did you get a chance to talk to him?
- Who?
- Mark.
- Oh, yes.
- What did he say?
We didn't quite finish.
I'll try to get hold of him again.
That's all right.
I'll figure it out myself.
He knows we're going for a scan today,
so, I'm expecting him to show up.
It's just a routine check.
But I'm a little nervous.
You hear so many stories, right?
There was a call for you from Bopa...
- OPA. Yes.
- There's no point.
That one, it's completely dead.
You can't bring it back to life.
If you lift it up
and have a look at the roots...
Look, they're all dried up.
It's a pity. It could be a really nice
garden, if you did a bit of planting.
Not right now but...
I used to work at a plant nursery.
That's how I know.
I'm going in to have my bath.
Don't forget to drink your tea
while it's hot.
We found the boat a few hours ago.
It was abandoned in Copenhagen harbour.
No one's seen the perpetrator,
but there were muster rolls,
departure times and a list of ships
that passed through Øresund last night.
He seems to have escaped on one,
so, we're checking
with the shipping companies.
- Great. Has Brix been informed?
- Yes. He's in a meeting with management.
The assistant commissioner called.
They want a word,
when you've seen the boat.
If the perpetrator has sailed on,
it doesn't make much difference.
- Are we just giving up?
- We did what we could.
It's out of our hands. Interpol
and Europol will take it from here.
- Why didn't you wait for us?
- I didn't have that option.
You did everything he asked of you.
You could have shot him.
You let her die in front of her father.
- Has the body been recovered?
- They're trying to get it free.
The concrete block pulled it in between
some old bridge elements on the bottom.
Great. Let the parents know that
we'll brief them when they're ready.
And inform Borch that Special Branch
will have to deal with Interpol.
Borch is here. He came back
when he'd been to see the boat.
He hasn't been home to sleep.
- They say he's gone abroad.
- Why don't you just go home?
The head of Special Branch
has called to ask...
I know, Kasper.
Why did he sail the boat all the way
to Copenhagen harbour? It's odd.
I've passed the case on to Interpol.
They're now collecting the material.
The perpetrator prepared this well.
He kidnaps Emilie Zeuthen,
kills people left and right,
and rejects a shitload of millions,
because apparently he's only out
to avenge a forgotten crime out west.
But when you tell him on the bridge,
there's a chance
he may be wrong about Zeuthen,
then he shoots the girl anyway.
- Yes.
- It doesn't make sense.
If he understood you, he can't just kill
the girl as if it doesn't matter.
- Just go home. Interpol will...
- I have been at home.
Well, I was sitting in the car watching
Marie making breakfast for the girls.
It looked nice. They were probably
chatting about oatmeal and swimming,
and the squirrels in the garden.
I just couldn't get things to add up.
We have to find this guy.
We must have overlooked something.
I feel as if I've forgotten
my phone or my keys.
The head of Special Branch
has just called again.
I've told you already!
I'll be right there, for fuck's sake!
You don't let up!
There you are.
DI Sarah Lund, this is Tage Steiner
from the Public Prosecutor's office.
The Commissioner has requested
an inquiry into the handling
of the Zeuthen kidnapping.
It's a bad situation, so we need
to account for what happened,
and place responsibility
for possible errors.
I'd really like to speak to you,
so, if you stay in the building,
I'll let you know when I'm ready.
Get this mess cleaned up.
Robert, I don't know how to express...
Please tell me if there's anything,
you want me to...
Everyone's... deeply touched,
and we've received many...
They've found her, and they're
expecting to bring her up soon.
Then she will be driven
to Forensics where...
The police have offered to give you
an update whenever you want,
but not until it suits you, of course.
- Would you handle the practicalities?
- Certainly.
Prepare the priest and tell him,
that it will be as Maja wants.
Yes, I will.
Carl is at his grandmother's.
He hasn't been told anything,
so, it's up to you and Maja
when you want to...
The new material raises doubts about
the Prime Minister's role in the case.
The government have apparently kept
vital information out of the investigation.
So far, Kristian Kamper hasn't reacted
to the tragic outcome of the kidnapping.
I told you to keep an eye on him.
It's essential we're there for him.
- He just wants a little time to himself.
- We help him make the right decisions.
He shouldn't be sitting in this old house,
when half of Denmark is asking about him.
We're here, so let's be constructive.
And nothing's happened.
Karen...
- Hi.
Would you please
bring in a couple of these?
I've decided to keep the house.
I came to see if they had
sorted out the water damage.
It dawned on me that the fireplace
hasn't been used for a long time.
But we have plenty of things to do,
so maybe we should get going.
Let's focus. Special Branch will take care
of the crazy ex-husband...
I have decided to resign
as Prime Minister,
and as party leader.
I should have listened to you.
I shouldn't have gotten involved.
- But I couldn't help it.
- What the hell are you on about?
- Is this a joke, or a piss-take?
- The Justice Minister is to blame.
- He'll have to swallow it.
- No, it was my responsibility.
Listen, he had a two-hour-long meeting
with the assistant public prosecutor.
Maybe so, but my role
will always be questioned.
And I won't discuss responsibility
over Emilie Zeuthen’s grave.
- You won't have to. It's down to Mogens.
- Set up a meeting with Birgit.
- I want to tell her before the group.
- No, I won't.
This is about personal involvement.
You've done what you could.
You've had your own personal misfortune.
People will understand.
It was no misfortune,
so, we're not going there at all.
Benjamin had been depressed
for quite a long time.
One morning he suddenly
disappeared from his room.
We thought he'd come back,
but he didn't.
And he didn't come the next day
or the one after that.
When the police finally found him,
I threw myself into my work,
and kept telling myself
that I'd done what I could.
But the truth is
that I should've been there for him.
I've known all along,
but it doesn't change a thing.
And it doesn't give you
the right to give up.
Karen, let's just get it
over and done with.
A minute's silence
will be held at noon.
Then I'd like to pay my condolences
to Zeuthen in person... when he's ready.
I'll get him to reconsider
for the meeting with Birgit.
Everything possible is of course
being done to find the perpetrator.
We have a suspicion
that he may have escaped abroad.
And we're not sure of his identity yet,
but we're working on the assumption
that he could be
a former Zeeland employee.
We can offer you
psychological counseling.
Where is she now?
She'll be brought up soon. It's something
technical to do with salvage operations.
I don't know the details,
but it shouldn't be long.
What was she wearing?
You saw her.
- It was very dark.
- She was wearing black rain clothes.
Was she afraid?
She didn't see anything.
I don't think she understood
what was happening.
She didn't feel the water.
I would like to see her.
Yes. I'll pass that on.
- If there's anything else...
- Maja?
I'm really sorry.
The public prosecutor
will see you now.
Carl will stay at his mum's.
We'll come for a few things later.
You've been involved since they found
the first dead sailor at the scrap yard.
There have been three exchange attempts,
all with a fatal outcome.
It was never the perpetrator's plan
for those exchanges to succeed.
You refrained from passing on an amount
equivalent to 100 million kroner.
- Who gave that order?
- It was my decision. It didn't matter.
- The perpetrator accepted the amount.
- Yes, but it was all about the old case.
Which allegedly is the reason why
a colleague committed suicide in custody.
It was partly his responsibility that
the killing of Louise was never solved.
If it was a killing.
The coroner changed the autopsy report
under pressure from the public prosecutor.
Someone must have
put pressure on him.
There's never been any evidence,
and all the witnesses were killed.
There's the original autopsy report.
Regarding Emilie Zeuthen's death
and what happened last night,
did you feel properly covered?
Managerially - the decision
to bring Zeuthen along in the car.
I helped make that decision.
You didn't have managerial
responsibility for that operation.
We need to place responsibility.
- Don't we owe that to the girl?
- You want rid of Brix.
I didn't say anything about that.
But I understand that you're transferring
to OPA, so you can speak freely.
- Is there anything else?
- Only what's on your mind.
- Hi, it's Mark, leave a message.
- Borch called, give him a call.
Thanks. I'm afraid I'll have to go
to the hospital with my son's girlfriend.
Numerous sailors were signed onto ships
from Copenhagen harbour last night.
If the perpetrator boarded one
that passed through Øresund...
Anyway, the clues lead abroad,
so he's gone.
I'm sorry that it had to end like this.
I hope that you...
- Time to place the blame.
- That's not what this is about.
- The public prosecutor is ready for you.
- What's it about then?
Isn't it obvious? Robert Zeuthen
and Zeeland aren't just anybody,
and the government stands to fall
on this, so it must be investigated.
Ruth, I took the responsibility that none
of the other jerks in management wanted.
And I'm being punished for that?
- I just do as I'm told.
- Yes, but what's your opinion?
- Back me up, damn it.
- This is the last thing I want.
But because you and I...
...share a past together, I can't risk
anyone getting the wrong idea.
Let's go all the way. We'll put a new
candidate forward before the election.
We'll show initiative and perhaps
limit the extent of the defeat.
No prime minister has ever stepped down
in the middle of an election campaign.
If Kristian doesn't step down, we risk
this case haunting us for a long time.
This is utter madness.
- The group will never support it.
- I've made enquiries.
Everyone's in agreement.
Kristian's hurting the party.
He will always be the prime minister
who lost Emilie Zeuthen,
and it has damaged the government's
relationship with Zeeland.
- But he's not to blame for that.
- I didn't want all this to happen.
- If you disagree, then let us know.
- I don't disagree.
Get hold of Karen and ask her
to set up a press conference.
I'm sorry the case is hurting Kamper,
but don't forget about me.
It's also my future. I haven't slept.
Journalists are hounding me with calls.
Come on. Admit that you put pressure
on the assistant public prosecutor.
- But I didn't put pressure on him.
- Then you account for the whole affair.
It has to be clear that at no point
was the prime minister aware,
that you had withheld information.
My meeting with the public prosecutor
was merely an enquiry.
I need to go upstairs and lie down.
I feel bloody awful.
Were there any others present?
Can anyone confirm what you're saying?
No, it was unofficial.
We were the only two at Snapstinget
for the half hour the meeting lasted.
- What?
- I should have told you about it.
- I just wanted to keep things quiet.
- You said half an hour.
Yes. 20 minutes. I don't know.
I was running late.
The assistant public prosecutor
was in a meeting for two hours.
I got the times from the guard.
He arrived at 13.54 and left at 16.10.
That's more than two hours later.
I'm not remembering wrong.
Not this time anyway.
Let's find some good images
of the little one.
It's not really with it today.
It's OK to sit down.
I'm really happy that you're here.
Maybe it's more for Mark's sake,
but I'm really happy that you're here.
It's turned around nicely,
so it won't be long now.
Here you can see
the two ventricles and atriums.
And nice little fingers.
Mark should have seen this.
Look the other way,
if you don't want to know the sex.
- Now it's started moving about.
- Yes, I can feel it.
How does it look, Sarah?
Can you see what sex it is?
Yes, you can.
It looks great.
There are no problems.
Everything's in order.
It looks like it's going
to be a lively little one.
I'll wait outside.
- Excuse me, Brix said you were here.
- I can't talk.
On the bridge last night you tried to
explain to the perp that he was wrong.
Later we find his boat. He's eager
to show us that he's going abroad.
I don't have the time now, Borch.
Then this morning there's a break-in
at the Maritime Authority's archives.
These are copies
of the stolen papers.
Routes, port calls
for the Zeeland ship.
- Sarah, listen!
- I don't care.
What's your problem?
Don't you understand that it's over -
that she's dead?
The perpetrator listened to you.
You made him think twice.
He probably planned to go abroad,
but he changed his mind.
You made him stop and think
about what he was doing.
I saw him shoot her.
Did you?
I didn't find Karen, but we're ready
and I have to let the journalists in.
I've put in a good word to Birgit.
You and Karen will continue in the party.
Am I supposed to be grateful or what?
- Kamper, I just wanted to dip the flag.
- That's nice of you.
I'm genuinely sorry after all
that it had to end this way.
- But you've made the right decision.
- Thanks. I have a press conference so...
I'm sure that you've done your best.
You've tried to make a difference. You've
been at the head of the table so long,
that the skeletons come crashing out
of the cupboard, which is rarely pretty.
- Let's hope you can do better then.
- We have to win the election first.
Rosa and the Centre Party have said yes
to a meeting, so we may put things right.
- Well, congratulations.
- Thank you.
Good luck in the future.
Rosa is a bit of a turncoat, huh?
Shall we get started?
There you are, Karen.
I was beginning to worry.
There's something you need to see.
- I have a press conference.
- You need to see this first. You too.
I borrowed this footage
from one of the guards.
Mogens' meeting with the prosecutor
lasts 17 minutes.
Mogens rushes off to another meeting.
The prosecutor goes to the toilets.
- I don't have time.
- Just look at this.
- He comes back out but doesn't leave.
- It doesn't matter, let's go.
If Karen thinks this is important...
It's pathetic
that you continue with this.
I've made sure
that you both have jobs, so drop this.
Do you think we're helping you
for our own sakes?
- It's not for my sake or the nation's.
- All right.
- You can bury yourself in peace.
- Stoffer, wait a minute.
- It doesn't matter. Let's go in.
- No, don't be so damn self-righteous.
You're watching this to the bloody end.
You can go home and give up afterwards.
This is the entrance by the show grounds.
The prosecutor met with someone else.
It's Reinhardt.
I'm afraid it's still dragging on.
The police are hoping
to salvage her soon.
I'll call when there's more news.
I can't find Carl's bedtime book.
The one about...
I can't find it.
I don't know where it is.
Perhaps it's upstairs in his room.
I've already looked there.
The rain clothes weren't black.
They were dark blue.
Her hair was loose,
and it was ruffled.
Maybe she'd been wearing a woolly hat.
She looked lovely.
She called out to me,
and I replied but...
At first I couldn't see her,
but she was looking up at me...
...and I could see that she was afraid.
But she was too far away for me to...
There wasn't enough time.
If you think it's my fault,
then say it.
Just say that it's my fault.
You think I should have done something.
You think I should have...
They're pulling her up now.
The sack has come loose.
It probably drifted off with the current.
We'll start dragging the spot
in a few minutes.
What's their progress?
The boat has just arrived.
The technicians were about to begin,
but then Borch came to do something.
- Why?
- Come.
You took your time.
So we're assuming it was the perpetrator
who stole the papers this morning.
Do you remember,
if this one was open?
- It wasn't. He didn't stand there.
- What are you talking about?
Doubt sets in. He finds out that
he isn't done, and he's in a hurry.
What about this one, Sarah?
It happened so fast.
The boat was only out of sight
for a few seconds.
You saw her die.
He threw her overboard.
Let's try to rewind here.
Where was she standing in the end,
and where was he?
What the hell are we looking for?
Move away from there.