Narrator:
In 1431 A.D.,
in the reign
of King Borommaracha Thirat II,
the Kingdom of Ayothaya
has seized the territory
of Sukhothai
and has expanded its power
across the highland
to the East.
After a seven-month siege,
Ayothaya captured the divine city.
One year
and three months later...
(thunder rumbling )
(whinnies)
( shouting )
Take care of yourself,
young master.
Shoot!
( labored breathing )
( thunder crashing )
Get the boy.
( Birds chirping )
Hey! Stop!
( Shouting )
(growling )
Hey!
Come down quickly!
Hurry UP-
Hey, come down!
Not going, are you?
Let me go! Let go!
Let go of me!
Get up here.
- Little troublemaker, huh?
- I said, let go of me!
( Screams )
Make sure he's the next one.
- Let me go.
- Get up. Go.
Go.
( Chanting )
( breathing heavily )
( laughs )
He's the next fighter.
( laughing )
I will give you a chance, kid.
Let's see if you can
make it out alive.
(yelling)
( screaming )
- ( gasping )
- ( chanting )
Begin.
( Gasps )
( roaring )
( screams )
(grunts)
- ( roars )
- ( screams )
( groans )
( panting )
Your life is
in your own hands, kid.
( Panting )
Tien.
Young master.
Get away.
It's because of you.
Traitor.
I want to be a great warrior
like my father.
How long will you be away?
- I hate you.
- Give him to me.
Father...
(thunder rumbling )
(groaning )
Is this the boy?
That's right, Father Sengpa.
The way he looked
when he was fighting,
reminded me of someone.
Even the spirits
don't dare touch him.
He has a powerful destiny.
Whenever he holds a weapon
in his hands,
he can conquer the world.
I'm Chernang,
the king of the outlaws
here at Garuda Wing Cliff.
I was impressed
by your courageous fight
with the crocodile.
If you want to train in the way
of weapons and martial arts,
you can stay here.
But if you don't,
I will not stand in your way.
( Explosion )
( laughs )
Chernang:
Unite your body and soul.
Fuse the rules of fighting.
Set your mind
on the path of power.
That is what you have
to accomplish.
Each weapon has its own strengths
and weaknesses.
Short or long.
Sharp or blunt.
Soft or hard.
Heavy or light.
Weapons are the tangible form
of power.
Anyone who can fuse
his body and soul with them
shall possess the greatest
power in the land.
The world will bow down
to your strength.
I am Chernang,
the outlaw king
at Garuda Wing Cliff.
I've given you a new life.
From now on,
always remember...
you are one of us,
the outlaws of Garuda Wing Cliff.
(grunts)
( trumpets )
( trumpeting )
( bellows )
( shouts )
( trumpeting )
The test of agility and wit.
Tien has passed.
Next, is the test of martial arts.
(grunts)
( rings )
( shouts )
(grunting )
( shouting )
( screams )
( laughs )
That's what I'm talking about,
my son!
Chernang: This place will test
the power of your mind.
Woman:
Help me.
Let me go.
Help
Help me.
Don't be afraid.
I'm here to help you.
I'll get you out of here.
Come with me.
I'll help you.
Don't be afraid.
( Hisses )
(growling )
( hisses )
( growls )
(growling )
Your life depends on yourself.
To kill someone,
to be merciless,
is the last thing
a leader must learn.
Father Sengpa:
My people, my children!
The spirits in the sky
have written
that the great black-tusk
shall become the king
of all elephants.
This sacred animal
will bring prosperity
to this community.
( Cheering )
Hooray!
Now...
I, Chernang,
hereby proclaim that
from now on,
in all the raids,
Tien
will replace me as the leader.
( Cheering )
Hooray!
( horses whinny )
( shouting )
( roaring )
Why haven't you taught me
the art of weaponry?
Young Tien:
I don't want to study the dancing arts.
I don't want to go.
I want to stay with you.
You have to study so you'll
grow up to be a great man.
Believe me.
(thunder rumbling )
Pay respect to Master Bua.
You've traveled so far.
Let's go inside.
It's been more than three months
since Ayothaya took control
of the vessel states.
The situation in the capital
is still in disorder.
But the Crown Prince
is behaving impetuously.
He has ordered me
to suppress resistances
in the protectorate territories.
Why is Ayothaya in such a rush
to expand its power?
Why didn't Lord Rajasena,
chief of the royal army,
oppose the Crown Prince?
Everything
was Lord Rajasena's idea.
Power is terrifying.
But those who abuse power
are even more terrifying.
This land will burn.
People in every corner will suffer.
In this time of uncertainty,
there is only you
in this distant land
to whom I can entrust
my son's life.
Master Bua,
I feel like my heart
has been pulled out.
May you take pity on me
and take care of him.
Master Bua:
I will try my best.
You take care
of yourselves as well.
Muen Sri. Luang Krai.
Take us back.
Yes, sir.
My name is Pim.
I'm an orphan.
Master Bua has raised me
since I was a baby.
How about you?
My father is Lord Sihadecho,
one of the four commanders
of the East.
I told my father I want to study
weapons and martial arts.
I want to be a great warrior
like my father.
I don't understand
why he sent me here
to study dancing.
How can I fight anyone then?
( Imitating flute )
Hoarse flute.
( Rattling )
Hey!
Ooh, itchy.
Scratching your balls too?
No, I'm not itchy.
Why are you scratching?
I have it too. The same.
Throw it up.
Oh, throwing it up too.
Turn around,
around, around.
He's gone.
Oh, he's really gone.
Gone.
( Sizzling )
Tien,
do you think being
a master of weapons
can bring peace to the land?
I think
that weapons can help me
protect myself,
assist righteous people,
and fight treacherous people.
That should contribute
to bringing about peace.
Well said.
Tien,
there are various kinds of weapons
in the world.
Which ones
do you wish to study
so you can help your homeland?
( Chuckles )
You don't have to answer me
right now.
Hey, take it.
( laughs )
(gongs)
Let the slave trade begin.
(wailing )
Hey, come here.
Let me go.
Mother!
- Hey, come here.
- Let me go.
My son! My son!
Go!
Mother! Mother!
Mother!
( Groans )
(whimpering )
( screaming )
Who the hell?
Was it you?
You want to drink?
Drink it!
( laughing )
(grunts)
( screaming )
( groans )
( laughs )
( shouts )
( snapping )
(whimpering )
( screaming )
Please spare my life.
I don't want to die.
I have money. I have slaves.
Whatever you want,
you can have it.
Good.
I'll give you a chance.
The same one you gave me...
Throw him to the crocodiles!
Huh? No!
I don't want to die.
(wailing )
Release all the slaves.
( Sobbing )
You saved my life.
Thank you so much.
( Cheering )
( drums playing )
Pim: Tien, how long
will you be away?
Are you really leaving, Tien?
Who will play with me
if you're gone?
I won't let you go, Tien!
Tien, don't go!
Don't you worry.
I'll be back soon.
Hurry, young master.
We don't have much time.
I have to go.
Tien.
( Rattles )
Why are we in such a hurry?
Luang Krai! Where are you taking
the young master?
How dare you betray
the commander?
Traitor!
( Shouts )
Run, young master.
( Shouting )
(woman sobbing )
You!
Let me go!
Let me go now.
I need to see my husband!
Don't do this to me!
Let us go!
My husband!
(woman wailing )
( laughs )
Let me go.
( Muffled screams )
I'll send you
to serve your master in hell.
Rajasena.
You bastard traitor!
Kill him.
( Shouting )
( laughs )
Father...
Get him.
Take care of yourself,
young master.
Shoot!
( labored breathing )
Get the boy.
So, you have made up
your mind.
The day I met you
at the crocodile pit,
you reminded me
of someone.
That someone was me,
when I was young.
That day...
your eyes were sun-parched.
But they were shining brightly
with flames of anger.
Even today,
those flames are still shining
in your eyes.
Actually,
I was going to make you
the Outlaw King today.
But since you have
something on your mind,
you shall go and finish it first.
Inn:
and everyone
at Garuda Wing Cliff...
will be waiting for your return.
( Horse whinnies )
( drums beating )
Honorable governors,
ministers, royal advisors,
and commanders...
now is an auspicious time
destined by heaven.
As the first monarch
of the Garuda Deva dynasty,
I shall commence the holy ritual
to pay homage
to the divine monument.
It shall eternally stand
as the symbol of power
of the Garuda Deva dynasty.
( Drums beating faster)
( screaming )
( groans )
This is for my mother.
Guards!
This sword is for my father,
Lord Sihadecho.
( Groans )
Guards!
( Screaming )
( shouting )
Father Chernang!
I have returned.
( Shouting )
( gasps )
( panting )
( screams )
( groans )
(coughs)
( men shouting )
(yelling)
( shouting )
( panting )
( bellows )
( rumbling )
( Caws )
( screams )
( bellows )
( panting )
My blood is not
for your sword to drink.
You don't have to waste
your energy, my guards.
I have someone
who has been waiting
to kill you.
( laughs )
Now, the clan of Sihadecho
has been wiped out.
The only one left is his son.
He is standing right there.
Now, you shall hurry to finish
what you still owe me.
Father.
A king shall never go back
on his word.
Your Majesty
must keep your promise
and spare the lives of my people
whether I live or die.
The man in black in front of you
is the one who killed your father.
Kill him.
Kill him...
...if you can.
( laughing )
Rebel!
Your clan deserves to be
exterminated.
Had I known
you were one of them,
I would have finished you off
long ago.
( Shouting )
I was the one who slashed
your father's throat.
( Shouts )
Let me repay your father's life
with mine,
my dear son.
Chernang.
Take him away.
But don't let him die too easily.
Torture him.
Put him through
the kind of pain he deserves.
Make sure he suffers
until his last breath.
Narrator:
Tien's life has come to an end
because of his cursed karma.
But if we could unite
the power of our minds,
our strength of faith
might be able to prolong his life
and guide his tormented soul
back to his body.
SubRip: HighCode