In an unprecedented meteor shower,
falling off the coast of Tokyo.
The entire city is mesmerized
by this incredible sight...
An unidentified enemy have
breached our coastline.
Right now one thing clear.
The world is at war.
At 14:46 Pacific Standard Time,
12 different locations across
the globe was breached.
In what appears to be a coordinated
attack by an unknown enemy.
All breaches were along the coastline.
In what is a campaign
of rapid dominance.
This is a textbook military invasion.
With massive casualties in New York.
Defensive lines are been setup in Boston.
and at 13:15 ZULU time,
we lost communication with
San Francisco and San Diego.
Their status is unknown.
What we do know is that
we're the last offensive force on the West Coast.
We cannot lose Los Angeles.
All ... abort!
- Unable to dismount...
Enemies at positions of fire, Over.
Good Wednesday morning.
Natural 25 with these surfers'
foundations surfers news report.
Surfers!
Hard northeast conditions blowing out there
with the ocean slopping and chopping things up.
There is some size starting to earthquake...
Good morning, Staff Sergeant!
Morning Staff Sergeant!...
You know what they say,
You're only as old as you feel. Staff Sergeant.
That's what I'm worried about.
I can't feel a damn thing.
Now down pacific for out next report:
Where what appears to be a small cluster of meteors,
is predicted to enter our atmosphere sometime
the early hours of tomorrow morning.
They're expected to strike miles from land.
Far into the Pacific Ocean and with the rock...
John.
- God.
What's up, Mike?
Hey!
What happened to that picture of us in
Iraq with that camel? I mean your girlfriend.
Hey, is that for real?
It's got your signature on it. I
said that's got to be a mistake.
He can't write.
No mistake, John! I did my 20.
I know when to get out.
C'mon you've got a box full of medals
And file full of commendations.
- Well, you can have them.
Seems you like interior decorating.
Marines got a shelf life you know.
After that!
- What?
It spolits...
- Something like that.
I'll finish my training assignment with these Marines,
Get them combat ready.
Then I'll be on my merry way.
You know we could always use
another lean mean typing machine.
Shit, I ain't built like you, John.
Ugly, slow, soft.
Have to make some tough
calls... That right?
Especially that last one.
We all wish your men made it home.
Here we go.
You're expired.
Clear the shelf.
Staff Sergeant.
Everything I know is in here, John.
What typically would have been
detected months if not years before,
surfaced in less than four hours.
These images giving you some idea of the rate,
at which these meteors are traveling.
Scientists are advised scrambling
to try to understand it.
You know what? There's something just extremely
uncomfortable well about a man your size sniffing a flower.
What you want is some
hydrangers.
Popular wedding flower
come in green and blue.
What color are bridesmaids'
dresses?
Good question.
You're amazing...
Just take a whiff.
Yes, pretty girl?
For 300 more, she said we
can have a sprays of lilies.
And I know it's a lot,
but it'll be so beautiful.
What do you think baby?
$300 dollars... Goodness gracious...
Well I think it's a no brainer.
You're only gonna get
marry once.
Why you gonna worry about 300 bucks.
- Thank you, Stavrou.
Thank you.
- Yeah, no worries.
You know what? It's your day.
Do whatever you want.
I'm gonna hit you with something
really heavy. What are you doing?
Busting your balls.
- Tomorrow, we shop for cakes.
And I can't wait
- I love cake.
Yo Doc! What you doing?
Skyping back home.
- Is that your girlfriend?
Damn! She fine.
Doc, my boy.
That's my sister.
God damn...
Aw, shit I'm just speaking objectively here.
You know what I'm saying?
I think a 20...
Alright! Alright! Stop playing! Stop playing!
Doc? Is it alright if I have one of those roasters?
Eat it at your own risk.
They're very old.
So do you feel that you're making progress?
- Yeah, yeah, yup.
I'm sleeping a lot better.
And then also around the firing range and everything...
when I first came back...
I get very jumpy and it would,
it would mess with me a little bit...
A little bit of setback.
But now you know...
It didn't bother me.
So I think that's progress.
So what's the story with my status, Doc?
Are you going to clear me for combat?
Ya, I feel good.
Let's meet again next week and the...
we'll discuss it. Okay?
Alright, Thank you. Thank
you very much, Doc.
Here's a girl is making a dude organizes his
entire wedding two weeks before we deploy.
I'd say this chick is busting his
balls like nobody's business.
Well, he's got two weeks to get
it done cause we're outta here.
So I just came by to visit you one
last time before we leave.
And I have brought dad's 5 iron with me.
You know what that means.
Me and the boys are going to go out
tonight and continue the tradition.
Have a good time, you know.
I'll see you soon, bro,
See you soon.
Motown! Give me my boots, I'm going skiing.
Oh, that's how you do it baby.
Here they come.
Don't mess this up. They cannot
know that you're a virgin. Alright!
How do you I...
Who say's I'm a virgin?
We know you're a virgin.
- What are you telling her?
Telling her what!?
C'mon you guys!
You're killing me!
That dawg got hunt!
Damn Doc, you can play man!
We've have courses
in Nigeria. Imlay.
Sham! How am I suppose to know that.
This is an American game man!
This dude is our naval
corpman. It's like a medic.
No! Not like a medic.
Medic is the army.
And I'm a navy corpman. It's different.
Well, save it and give us the bullshit.
I came here to become a doctor.
Hey! Slow down.
It's like number five!
How many had you've had?
- No, I'm good.
Now this guy over here, Mr. Lenihan!
- Hey!
His mom signed, so he
can join up at 17. And a...
I look after him because this boy
don't know his ass from the hot rock.
Not on my trunk! Dude!
A toast to Lenihan.
- To Lenihan!
Good luck, rookie.
Retreat Hell!
An emergency developing throughout NASA
and the space community.
We now know that the meteors will land
off the coast of eight different cities.
And that number could keep rising.
Evacuations now underway
in Southern California.
Moving the population
back from the coastline.
But a lot of curious people are
clamouring for views as...
Why are you doing up so early?
Lieutenant, still gonna get used to that.
This thing right?
Here...
- It's shaking.
It's gonna be parallel to the deck.
That's the whole thing with these bars.
- Okay...
I'm gone. Don't forget to call Mr. Gilliam. Okay?
- Okay.
I'll call you later.
- Call you later.
That's my baby. Alright...
Let's go! Move!
Quick charge! March!
Marines! Into the trucks and
report to your company. Let's go!
Move it!
- Let's move!
Load ém up!
Move it!
What's going on, First sergeant?
Meteor's hitting off California now but...
They've got the whole god damn base being mobilized.
I'm bringing you back to the company. Mike.
I need you.
First Sergeant.
- All hands on deck, Staff Sergeant.
Take it you heard we maybe mobilizing?
- Yes, sir.
Moving you up to squad leader.
It's a big responsibility.
You can handle it.
Thank you, sir.
Staff Sergeant Beck is replaced
by Staff Sergeant Nantz.
What do you know him?
- He's a very dedicated Marine.
Don't bullshit me, Corporal.
What'd did you hear
about his last tour?
Just the grimy details that
everybody else knows.
But at the end of the day you're our lieutenant
and we take our orders from you. Sir.
So you're gonna be assigned to 1st. platoon
under the second Lieutenant Martinez.
His platoon sergeant's on leave,
So you're gonna have to suck it up.
So here's the lieutenant,
right up here at 1 o'clock.
He's a kid, Mike.
Right out of Officer training school,
he's only with us a month.
But I think he's sharp.
It's just an evacuation, buddy.
He's in charge.
Just keep an eye on him. huh?
Just don't lose my paperwork.
Afternoon Lieutenant.
- Good afternoon, Staff Sergeant.
Happy to finally meet you.
- Thank you, sir.
We've been called in, to help
with evacuation, Lieutenant.
Because of these meteors?
- I assume so.
Whatever it is, I'm just happy to finally
get out in the field with the men.
At approximately at 4:42 am pacific
standard time. The meteors impacted...
Who the hell took my tortelini?
You got tortelini?
Think, this is some kinda drill or what?
- Get ready, man!
Get ready. This is serious. Okay?
Meteorites continued to fall off
the coast of California ...
Ireland and the Bay of Bengal.
Corporal.
- Yes.
Probably just a training exercise, right?
No, man... they shifted Nantz into our unit.
Something must be going on...
That's great, the guy wants out of the
Marine Corp. And now we're stuck with him.
Stav! You'd got tortelini's?
Well, I heard Nantz kicked asses his last tour.
I mean he went into that compound alone
and killed like about 10 insurgents... Didn't he?
That's what you heard Lenihan, huh?
That's what you heard!?
Yeah!
- Chill out...
Johnson and Foxtrot told me,
- Hey...
he was going on like some...
- Don't worry about it...
The hell did I do?
Nantz got a couple of guys
killed on his last tour.
What are you talking about?
- Well, that's the story.
Lockett's brother was one of them.
So! Now, I know you didn't know about this...
Lockett, man! I'm sorry!
- Man, don't worry about it...
Looks like we're getting
into some heavy shit.
It's been my experience Lieutenant...
heavy shit is highly overrated.
Look, Staff Sergeant.
Let's just be clear.
I know your rep, I know
what'd you've done.
This is my platoon, these are my men.
Not gonna have a problem, are we?
No problem, Sir. She's all yours.
It appears our inital assumptions were wrong.
Alright! Listen up!
I want you to get your weapon!
Get your gear! Get your
muntions! Move outside!
White chocolate wrap for my men and
that should finish the new mix, right?
Good
No...!
- National Guard troops have flown into...
evacuate surrounding meteor areas.
And we have word the military is now deploying.
Aw, that's us...!
Armed military for a meteor shower?
- I don't know why they're so happy?
Just a minute. A meteorite
just hit the ocean,
Large plumes of smoke
are coming up...
Visibility is getting worse.
These objects were completely undetectable
until they entered our atmosphere.
NASA estimates that they are not
hitting the water at terminal velocity.
They're slowing down before impact.
These objects in question...
are falling into the ocean in tightly packed clusters.
10 miles outside a major population centre.
Thermal imaging from the
Hubble telescope shows us that ...
within each cluster is a central
object much larger than the others.
And these central objects are
all the same geometrical shape.
They appear mechanical in nature.
This is not a meteor shower, Marines.
We are in threat con Delta.
That's right!
C'mon! All units!
Gear up!
Be ready to move!
Combat situation.
- That's what I've been training for.
And just now being told that one of the Coast
Guard cutters have issued a mayday.
It is difficut to see.
Oh my gosh!
There's just another meteor
that just hit the ocean.
And it's the closest one yet.
Right behind those cutters...
There are two or three
meteor's just impacted...
Do we have that information from the studio?
Oh my god.
Hey, hey! Are you hearing us?
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Hey! Are you still hearing us?
Yeah. Jean, I can... I can hear you.
What is that...?
I can't really get a good look.
But It appears like there's something ...
I... I am looking for the people trying
to determine exactly what this is.
Maybe... I don't even know... like shadowy figures...
Maybe 5, 6, 7.
I can make out... maybe...
What the hell is that!?
- holy shit!
Look at that!?
I think I'm gonna head back now!
Everyone needs to get
outta here, right now!
I think I'm gonna leave, Jean.
I'm gonna head back.
Oh my god.
Corporal Grayston and Corporal Imlay
are both expert marksmen.
As well as strong Fire team leaders.
We also have PFC Lenihan
who is our second best marksmen.
Just behind Lance Corporal Guerrero.
Yo! What's your take on this, Specks?
I don't know. Extraterrestial?
You mean like from space?
- No, Imlay! From Canada.
Oh! You've always got jokes. Don't you...
Alright! First squad! Line it
up! Bring it in! Let's go!
As you may have heard already!
Staff Sergeant Nantz will be
taking over for Staff Sergeant Beck!
We're lucky to have him aboard!
Alright! Here's the situation, Marines!
We're facing an unknown enemy!
We don't know how strong they're
force is, or what they're capable of!
But one thing we do know!
Is that we're fighting for our land!
Our families! Our home!
And our Country! God dammit!
So whatever those things are!?
Let's go show them how Marines fight!
Retreat!
- Hell!
25!
- Shake Hell!
Let's go!
First it. Last out! Marines!
Breathe Lenihan!
Breathe! Your training will kick in!
- Thank you! Staff Sergeant!
Got something to get off
your chest, Corporal?
No... it's cool Staff Sergeant.
You got a Silver Star, my brother
came home in a box. I get it.
All stations, stand by for sitrep.
Enemy elements have
advanced beyond the beach.
Aliens!?
That's not possible? Right!?
We'll know soon enough! Brother!
It's in case his head gets blown off,
so that they can identify his body...
Yo! Staff Sergeant!?
Promise me you won't let
me be taken alive
by some godless predator from
another world. Staff Sergeant!
No promises in combat!
Stop screwing around and
keep your head in it!
My dearest wife.
We're not evacuating civilians fast enough.
I say again: We're not evacuating
fast enough. All units be advised...
There are friends behind enemy lines.
You gonna take me to dinner first lady.
- Boys, better hold on to something.
Things are about to get rough.
Let's go...!
Form it up!
What have we got , sir?
- Right. The situation is as follows ...
Most of Santa Monica's been cleared of civilians.
We've got a defense line at Lincoln
Boulevard a mile from the ocean.
Air Force has got Warhogs and B52's on deck.
At 19:30 hours, they will pound the
entire area at Lincoln to the ocean.
We're leveling Santa Monica, sir?
- We've got a infestation and God knows what!
But they are not of this earth! And we
gotta hit them with everything we got!
We got to hit ém hard!
They are ground force enemy only.
They have no aircraft...
so the airforce will tear them a new asshole.
And we WILL rule the air.
You said, MOST citizens, sir?
- That's a firm.
Get a distress call,
sending squads out.
Golf: you take Santa Monica to Olympic.
Foxtrot: Olympic to Peaco,
Echo: Peaco to Ocean Park.
Lieutenant Martinez,
I want you to break off a squad
and a machine guns team.
Proceed west from Lincoln to
a police station located here.
Venice and Amarosa.
Police were overrun. Got a distress
call that civilians are still there.
We don't know how many?
Just gather survivors and you radio in.
We'll have helicopters in the
area to evacuate you out.
But be advised! You've got exactly
3 hours before our bombs drop.
Make no mistake they will DROP.
With or without you.
So you get those civilians and
you get the hell out of there.
And you kill anything
that is not human.
Let's go! Let's get it done!
Captain, this is not a drill.
You hold that line. You understand me?
- Yes, sir.
10,000 moving inland,
they are advancing east from
the coastland into the suburbs.
Golf company is overrun,
Lema company is requesting immediate air support.
Civilians are been stranded
behind enemy lines.
Take on 1!
- Fire in the hole!
Troops are amassing on every coast,
along every major coastline.
The U.N. has called an emergency sitting in an
attempt
to establish a means of sharing resources...
Watch out! Go!
Which is? This way?
Where we supposed to go?
Jesus Christ.
Marines.
Anything beyond this point.
Considered to be hostile.
Nice and easy.
Okay.
Hell of a way to earn your citizenship, right?
Shit!
I'd rather be in Afghanistan.
How many civilians you'd think we
gotta get out of that police station?
I have no idea, Guerrero.
Just stay focused.
Hey, what the hell is that?
What is that?
- This is insane.
Ya, it's open.
- Unidentified enemies has reached our coastline.
In a swift and military sneak attack.
At this point, there are many
more questions unanswered.
Right now one thing is clear,
the world is at war.
See something, Simmons?
Can't see shit.
Kerns! You see across the street?
Lieutenant, I don't see nothing.
Police station's about 1
click northwest of here.
12 o'clock!
- 100 meters front!
Turn the radios down...
It's just a dog.
Just a little doggy!
Come here, come here.
It's just a dog.
- Dog! Dog! Dog!
What's his name?
Glenn. You're kidding me.
Who's the idiot names his
dog these days, Lieutenant?
What'd you want to call him? Friday?
Where's it coming from!?
- I don't know!
On the roof!
- Watch your head!
Enemy fire!
Out on the roof! On the roof!
- Cover me!
25 meters...!
Left flank on the roof!
Cover me, Cover me!
We got to move now!
- Lockett!?
Yes!
Get me an exit down that alley!
- Roger!
Kerns! Motown! Let's go!
Get up! Falling back...!
C'mon!
Watch your head!
Keep your head down!
Where did they come!?
- Move it!
Enemy fire!
Keep your head down!
They're all over the damn place!
What do you see?
- I dont know man! I don't see shit!
How do we get outta here!?
- Lieutenant! Where's the exit at!?
We're working on it!
- Shit! We're boxed in!
Go take positions by
the wall! Go! Go!
Ambush!
Cover me, Lockett!
Man down! Man down!
Shit!
Medic!
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant...!
We have an exit!
Everyone move out!
Move out! Move...!
Staff Sergeant, we got an exit!
C'mon! Go! C'mon! Go!
Move back Move back!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go! Keep moving! Keep moving!
- Get outta here!
Move it!
Lorenzo!
- Move! move! move!
Keep moving...!
I can't see shit!
Shit! shit! shit!
Imlay!
Oh god! oh god! oh god!
Coming in!
- U.S. Marines! Anybody here!
Kitchen's clear!
Kitchen's clear! Lieutenant!
Get on that window! Are we clear!?
- Put the wounded in the kitchen!
Kerns, Lockett! Secure the back of this house.
Yes! Staff Sergeant! We're on it!
Doc? How long do they're able to move?
- 10 minutes!
10 minutes! Staff Sergeant. 10 minutes!
- You want me, man!?
You want me? Try and get some!
I'm right here!
What have we got? Imlay?
I got nothing, Staff Sergeant.
I can't see a god damn thing!
This smoke is zero visibility.
- You're dead!
Stow that shit, Simmons!
You're gonna get shot before
you're able to kill any of them!
Your orders, sir?
I led us right into that ambush.
Mottola, any word on command?
- No, sir.
Well, we need to find answers
on how to get out of here!
You're in charge, sir.
Your orders?
Let's radio that evac.
Civilians or no we need to get these wounded out.
- Roger that.
Hey! Hey! You guys.
Where's Lenihan?
I didn't see him come in with us.
Where the hell is he?
Lenihan!?
- Lenihan!?
Anyone got eyes on Lenihan?
I'll go for Lenihan, sir.
- Imlay, Harris on me.
Let's get this shit out of here.
I'll package the wounded,
we're rendezvous on 10th Street.
Roger that.
- Be prepared to move. We're moving out soon.
Mottola? Mottola?
Oh! C'mon!
Mottola, you copy?
Lenihan, where are you?
- Staff Sergeant?
Jesus Christ!
I had to take off my radio,
these things are everywhere.
We'll coming for you,
what's your location?
I'm in the laundry room of
some apartment complex. It's...
It's like three stories...
Lenihan? Lenihan?
Lenihan... Lenihan...
Shit...
Lenihan! Lenihan!
- Lenihan! Lower that weapon!
The hell you...
Keep firing!
Jesus Christ!
- Shit!
What the hell is that thing!?
They're not dead, they don't die.
Hit it a 100 times and they don't die.
You get separated from the unit again.
I'll find you and
shoot you myself.
Imlay, drop a grenade in that pool.
Let's move!
Frag out!
Street's clear.
Get down, get down, get down...
- What's happening?
Doc, what's going on?
- Come on...
It's Lenihan.
Lockett!
- Huh?
You owe me five dollars boy. I told you the
virgin ain't gonna die til he get em some.
Move to the police station?
Alright! Let's move, let's move!
Where did they come from!?
- I can't see!
Take care of him.
- Where that shot come from?
Kerns! Go! Before they
detect us move!
C'mon let's go!
Move! Move! Move!
Stavrou, you got front!
Stavrou cover front!
Harris, cover front!
Room's clear! Room's clear!
I got... I got it covered.
Harris! Find me where
that shot came from, guys!
Imlay! Get eyes on that roof! Alright!
- The rooftop. Cover the roof.
Roof's clear...!
Lockett! On me!
Anyone even see where
that came from!?
Doc! How serious?
Third degree thermal burns
on his neck and face, Staff.
You'll be surfing soon, Simmons.
Hostiles, 11 o'clock!
- Hostiles at 12 o'clock!
Staff Sergeant!  Hostiles at 12 o'clock!
Prepare to fire!
Hold it! Hold it!
Friendlies, sir!
Shit...
Friendlies...
Let's get them in!
Get over here...
Move! Move to the back! Let's go!
Get in here, get in here.
What's your unit?
- 40th I.D.
Where's the rest of your unit?
Everyone else is either
dead or missing.
I picked up the Air Force here.
Tech Sergeant Alena
Santos, Air Force. 61st. Wing.
Intel surveillance, recon division.
Tech Sergeant, what the
hell you doing here?
We were tracking enemy transmissions,
about 12 clicks south of here.
They ambushed us. Like they
knew our freaking address.
I'm the only one left,
I found these guys on the way to
the safe zone at the Santa Monica Airport.
You ready to use that
weapon? Tech sergeant?
With all due respect, Staff Sergeant.
I didn't get this far off
on my good looks.
I'm ready for payback.
- Outstanding...
Lieutenant, we're burning about 25 minutes, sir!
- Roger that.
Let's get to that police station.
Alright! Let's get Simmons to move!
Let's go!
Here we go!
Into the right! In that building!
- Watch your feet!
There's the Police Station!
Let's get those civilians and
get back to the F.O.B.!
Go ahead!
C'mon! C'mon! C'mon!
Alright. I'll stay with our wounded and wait for Medic vac.
- I'll go for the civilians.
Roger that.
Kerns, Deaver! On me!
- Mags! Mags! Mags!
Alright, Santos! When that bird arrives.
I'm gonna need your help on this stretcher.
U.S. Marines! U.S. Marines!
Open the door...
Elevator right...
- Clear!
Elevator right!
Second elevator clear!
No pulse!
Door left.
It's lock?
- Door lock.
Hey! What's your name?
Harper.
Harper, I'm gonna need you on this stretcher...
- Roger that.
Bird incoming, sir!
- Roger that!
Imlay, pop the smoke!
Door lock...
- Door left...
Radio's on.
U.S. Marines! U.S. Marines!
How many people?
- Five of us. Three kids.
Kerns, kids!
Let's move!
- Let's go! Let's go!
Here we go!
- Aye, sir!
I've got room for four!
And that is it!
Get your wounded on!
Hey! Guerrero!
- Ya!
Yo!
I'll work on that mix for you!
I'm gonna need it, dude! You're
gonna be fine! You're gonna be fine!
Get ém out!
- Go!
Shit!
- C'mon, man...
- You just had to get out of this shit.
You take care of yourself!
- I will.
I'll see you soon, buddy.
Alright, that's it!
- We have civilians coming out!
Can't take ém! We've got no room!
Make some god damn room!
- I can't!
Now get back, sir!
Fall back...!
Wait! Kids...!
Backup! Everybody! C'mon! Back!
I say again: Enemy has air support.
We have a burned down...
- Dammit! Dammit!
We've disengaged and pulled on
back to the old police station.
We have civilians!
I say again: We have civilians.
Lockett, Kerns! Secure this door.
Nothing gets in!
You understand!?
We've got a body.
Do you think you can get rid
of it so the children don't see it?
What you want? What you want us...
Where should we go?
- Just back up.
Deacon!
- Setup back there, okay.
Come on, you guys.
Take the back.
Stay away from the
window, alright!
Are there gonna be more copters?
Did you guys call any in?
I'm sure they're gonna come for us.
They know where we are.
Shit...
You okay? You alright?
- Ya, I'm good. Sure!?
Yeah!
- You didn't... didn't get hit?
I'm good, man!
I'm good...
They're gone! They're gone!
Everybody's gone!
Lenihan, Guerrero, Grayson!
Grayson... the kids...
he didn't deserve that.
He didn't deserve that shit!
He didn't deserve that...!
You hear me!
You're gonna make it thru this!
Alright! You're gonna get out of here...
You're gonna marry Cherise!
And you're gonna be her
problem from now now.
Cause... cause. I'm done taking care
of your sorry ass! You got that!?
Enemy aircraft No:4 ... at this time.
Be advised...
... bearing 29750.
- They got air support too.
Knocked our bird right outta the sky.
So much for ruling the air.
There's no time for
that Lieutenant.
Those bombs are gonna drop.
We're in the blast radius.
Top of my god damn class...
And I get out of combat
in the middle of that shit...
God dammit!
I already lost four
god damn men!
Four good men.
- I'd go to hell and back for you, sir...
Have you?
- Yes...
You're not the first to lose
men and you won't be the last...
Now, put that away.
You understand me?
Right now, your men
are awaiting orders.
You go left, you can go right,
I don't give a damn.
Just make a decision.
Lieutenant.
There's no go on the helo, sir.
Enemy aircraft's slicing it up.
Command says it's nothing
they ever seen before.
We got to find a way out.
We got to get to that F.O.B.
You're right. We gotta move.
Let's get these people safe.
Lockett, Kerns!
I need you to setup an observation
post on the roof!
We gonna move by foot
so we got to move fast!
I want you guys to scan for hostiles.
And find the best ride outta here!
Lieutenant.
Officias are now saying: any civilians
within 10 miles of the coast,
should try to make their way to a
military Forward Operating Base (F.O.B.).
It's the safest place you're
gonna be right now.
Now the military has set up a line of
defense to try to protect civilians.
Authorities...
- Just look at you and make sure you're alright. Alright?
Just look at this... Here you go.
Our Staff's just there, Mr. Rincon.
- Okay, thank you.
No problem.
- Thank you...
Joe Rincon.
- Staff Sergeant Nantz.
This is my son Hector.
We... we all wanted to thank
you for coming to get us.
Yeah?
Hey, Hector.
We leave no man behind.
So you're here when
the police got overrun?
Right, well as long as
you're both okay.
Are you alright, man?
- Ya, ya. I'm good.
Okay. If...
If you need him to
do anything.
You know?
- I'll let you know.
Aye aye, sir.
Alright.
Thank you.
We've got 2 dozens hostiles.
About 300 meters out.
Lieutenant, we've got 2 dozen
hostiles. 300 meters north only.
Those things are on
overwatch. Just like us.
That one out front looks like a leader.
So now they've got leadership.
Yeah, so do ants, Kerns.
You think those things
get scared too?
They're probably just like us.
Grunts just told to go fighting.
C'mon...
Just find us a way
out of here, marine.
Cause we're sitting ducks.
They dragged him outta the house.
And they brought him outta the street
And they put him in perfect
order before they shot him.
They shot him right in the head.
Do you have any idea? Why this is happening?
Well, it's clear that there's been
no attempt at any kind of communication.
No demands, nothing like that.
So! Obviously, they are
here for our resources.
When you invade a place
for it's resources.
You wipe out the indigeous population.
Those are the rules of any colonization.
And right now.
We are being colonized.
Brave kids.
- They're my nieces.
My sister and her husband
are on vacation.
The thing is... they live in Arizona.
I see them once or twice a year and...
Now maybe I'm the only
one they have left.
You have children?
- No.
Neither do I.
Used to regret that.
Maybe... it's for the best.
And of course our planet's is 70% water
and so again I have to stress this
without certainty, the leading hypothesis remains.
Their objective, their target is our water.
There ain't gonna be nothing left.
I think I got a way outta here.
What'd you say?
- Right here. Look.
200 meters out,
What's that. Right behind
that backside there?
Bus.
- Lieutenant, we've got a bus.
Roger that.
- So the men on the roof saw bus.
I think it could be operational.
Maybe we're be better off on foot.
It's miles to the
Forward Operationing Base.
Those bombs are gonna
drop in a little more than an hour.
We gotta move fast.
A bus is a big target.
I'd made the call.
It's my responability.
Stavrou, Harris!
Lieutenant, needs recon on a bus.
If it runs. Get it back here.
Either of you know how to hotwire a bus?
Stavrou can. He's from Jersey, sir!
Ladies first.
200 meters.
You go down. There's cars parked out.
There's a pickup truck, right...
right back behind that.
We have a situation.
Ya'll need to follow me.
Harris found it out here.
Ya'll got to see this thing!
Weapon looks like it's
been surgically attached.
Talk about commitment to cause.
Shit...
You got to be kidding me.
- Corporal. Hold it.
Let me shoot this damn
thing Staff Sergeant.
That weapon's still hot.
Let me just shoot it.
Doc?
- Yes, Staff Sergeant!
God have mercy.
We need to know exactly
where to hit this thing?
So we don't waste
our own ammo.
Maybe I can help.
I'm a veterinarian.
Sure you want to do this?
I was more sure when I
was standing over there.
We got to figure out how
to kill these things
Otherwise we won't last another
five minutes out there. Okay.
Peel this back.
Staff Sergeant, look at this.
We've got our organ. Right here.
Look at that.
I got another one right here.
- Yup.
It has some sort of cognitive
mechanism, anything?
There's no frontal lobe.
No temporal lobe.
No parietal lobe.
The cranial vault is unlike
anything I've ever seen.
Oh, Shit... Shit!
- What'd  you see?
You see what I'm seeing?
- what?
The ones just on the roof weren't
on the roof right now anymore.
And there's a dozen more coming
out the door down there.
Shit.
Gosh! Dammit! They're on the street
and they're heading this way.
They're headin'this way? Lieutenant,
we've got movement out here.
Roger that.
We have contacts 300 meters out.
We got to cut quick.
Lieutenant, we got to move!
What do we do!?
Shit's hitting the fan.
We've got to move.
Staff Sergeant?
C'mon, how do you
kill this thing?
God dammit... Stavs.
We lost them.
- We lost them.
Lieutenant, they've gone out.
Lieutenant, I don't see anything.
What's the hell's that!?
We've got a breach.
Lieutenant! We got a breach
down at north entrance!
They're inside the building.
I'm gonna gather everyone by the door
at south side of the building. Okay?
We're right behind you.
Adukwu! You go with her.
- Yes, Staff Sergeant.
Imlay, you've got a HE
grenade round?
Never leave home without it, Staff Sergeant.
- You cover that hall to the rear!
Buy me some time.
They start coming. You
blast the hell outta them.
Hey, Harris? Where's
that god damn bus?
Stav? Stav? We've got enemy
scouts. C'mon let's go!
Yes! Yes! Yeah, baby!
New York represent!
Lieutenant? Got the
bus. Heading back.
Okay, guys! The bus is enroute!
Bus is enroute! Guys!
30 seconds til we move out!
Imlay, give me a sitrep.
I need an update on the breach.
Report back over.
We're running out of time.
Move!
Contact!
They've breached.
This is our last shot.
Got it.
Right here...
That's got to be it.
It's dying.
That's how we kill this thing.
To the right, where the heart would be.
Got it.
- I got three more!
Let's get outta here.
Get onboard that bus!
Get up on that bus!
Let's go...!
Get underneath fellas!
Cover your sector's of fire!
Head's up!
Marines!
Concentrate all your firepower
to the right where the heart would be.
Yes, Staff Sergeant.
That's how we kill these things.
Alright! Remember your training.
- Hostile warbird, a 1000 meters out.
Everybody keep your eyes up.
All buckled back there, Lieutenant.
Roger that.
It should be about
6 miles to the F.O.B.
I don't know...  25 to 30 minutes.
Cruising down these side streets.
Air Force is gonna level
this area in 40 minutes.
Gonna setup a Forward Operating Base. Fast.
What the hell's that?
Stavrou, stop the bus.
Everyone, get down.
Foxtrot to November.
Sitrep is as follows.
Go ahead Foxtrot to November.
Enemy impact, all over the sky.
They're lighting up the sky.
Heading... heading east towards
downtown Los Angeles.
Copy that.
They're tracking our signals.
Turn off that radio!
Turn it off! All radio's off!
Cell phones! Everything!
Radio.
100 meters!
- Give me your radio.
Where's he going?
- Staff Sergeant.
Where the hell's he going!?
Be prepared to get off this bus, alright!
10 o'clock, Lieutenant! 10 o'clock!
Yeah! I see it! 8 o'clock!
It's getting close.
There's some my 6!
A 100 meters!
Oh my god...
Shit...
Woah!
- What the hell's that!?
Staff, is he alright?
- Make it out?
Staff Sergeant.
There he is.
- Staff Sergeant's alive!
He's alive!
- There he is.
Their craft was unmanned, Lieutenant.
Drone.
That was real John Wayne shit, Staff Sergeant.
Hey...
I can't afford to lose you.
And neither can these men, alright?
They're your men.
Alright, Staff Sergeant!
That's how you do it.
That's retreat hell!
- That's right.
Who the hell's John Wayne?
Everybody, eyes open.
Stay alert!
Thank you for that.
It's nothing...
What's that mean,
Retreat Hell?
During World War I,
an officer from our regiment
was ordered to retreat.
He said,
Retreat Hell.
We just got here.
Should have the doctor
take a look at that.
I thought you were a doctor?
Animals and Aliens only.
I'll put it on my to do list.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Staff Sergeant?
Did you say that was an unmanned drone?
- Correct.
They must have a helluva
commanding control system.
If Northcom didn't agree with
you, I wouldn't be here.
Why?
My mission was to provide A.I.S.
with a strike package.
A strike package?
Yeah, the coordinates for a missile strike
on a Command and Control Center.
But the acid fell
off the grid.
And we lost them.
All side streets are blocked.
Why don't we stick to the freeway.
Alright. Well, it's your call.
Stavrou, get us on
the freeway.
Don't wanna be in this area.
When these bombs start to fall.
Try to miss at least
one of the car, Stavrou.
Just keep driving.
All friends, a mile ahead.
Jesus.
Eh, the ramp.
It's gone, Lieutenant.
Alright! Robertson Exit.
Half a click away.
Look out!
Incoming! 12 o'clock!
Corporal!
Tank's drawing enemy fire!
It's a good time to move!
I'll suppress firing front! You should
take the civilians out the back!
Secure this exit, Imlay!
Imlay! Give me a defense
line on that vehicle!
Keep firing on that bridge!
Move...!
Cover your eyes!
- Let's go! C'mon! Let's go!
C'mon! Settle down!
Just keep everyone calm.
Be right back, alright?
Alright! Safety first, buddy!
Lieutenant Martinez!
If we could get those
civilians, into that Helo.
They'll take cover
and repel down.
I got a dozen up on the
bridge! They're moving down!
Lieutenant!
Tank's out! Nothing's
stopping them now!
Staff Sergeant! Civilians won't make
it to that Helo without cover fire!
Lockett, Kerns! On me, let's go!
Let's move...!
Get the civilians down! Alright!
- Yes, sir!
Move!
30 foot down. C'mon,
c'mon. let's go!
Get behind the bus! Now...!
Get back!
Kids first! Around the body!
Bring ém down, one
at a time. Got me?
Roger that!
Imlay!
Get your first team up
on that gabbage truck!
Move!
- Yes, Sergeant!
Cover us out front!
Stavs! On me! On me, now!
We're gonna run behind the helicopter
and we're gonna rope down, alright?
Do you understand!?
- Yeah! Yeah.
Again! The girls will go first! I promise
you, nothing's gonna happens. Okay!
Stay down!
Lieutenant! A dozen
hostiles maybe more!
400 meters and closing! Fast!
Cover! Cover!
The hell are you doing?
You guys need another gun.
3 o'clock, c'mon.
Top one on the bridge!
There's something on the bridge!
Incoming!
1 o'clock!
Reloading!
- Aim for the leader!
Hell!
You can take all
the room you want.
Move...!
Yes! Staff Sergeant!
C'mon! Let's go...!
Right now, run! Keep running!
Get in there!
- Cover me!
I'm going for the 50 cal!
Hurry up!
Get some! Lockett!
Shit.
What the hell is that thing?
- I'm engaging!
Alright!? It's okay. Listen.
You're going to be okay.
I got you. I will not let anything
happen to you. Alright.
Shit!
Man down!
You'll be okay.
Hold on! Kirsten, hold on!
Keep looking up.
Kirsten!
I got you. It's okay. It's okay.
Get the ass that's
controlling that thing!
Imlay! Get off you ass!
It's turning this way!
About to hit the fans, guys!
Get out now!
Come on!
- I'm stuck!
I'm going!
Incoming!
Where is Stavrou?
Mottola! How many down?
Two down, Staff Sarge!
One to go!
Look...
Be good, okay. It's
gonna be fine, okay.
Get ready to go down.
- You ready?
Lieutenant, C4!
Let's blow this sucker to hell!
Hoo-rah.
Alright?
- Let's do it.
Covering!
Alright! It's good to go!
Dammit! I've lost the detonator.
Alright?
- Yeah, got the wind knocked outta me.
Mottola!
- Dad!? Dad!
I need the bandages from
the first aid kit.
Sir! Sir!
Oh my god!
Shit.
We got to get you
to a medic vac.
Doc!
Shit, man.
We need some cover!
- Dammit! I'm out!
Get another mag lucky!
- Hey! Take an eye out!
They get them pin
down, Staff Sergeant!
Our Marines! They
get 'em pin down.
I'm not leaving you, Lieutenant.
Staff Sergeant! You need to
get them outta here.
Lieutenant, I am not leaving!
You gotta get them outta there!
- No, I'm not gonna leaving you...
You gotta get them outta here!
- No!
Not again!
I've a bag of C4 on the bus.
Give this to my wife.
And get them off this
god damn freeway.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Right behind you.
Cover the Lieutenant!
They're closing in!
Here we go.
This is Lieutenant William Martinez.
Echo Company, 2nd Battalion, 5th Marines.
Hoo-rah!
We're still half a click
inside the bombing zone.
Move to live, Marines.
Did he just leave the lieutenant
back there to die?
Sure looks that way.
And this is the guy in
charge of us now?
Let's move.
Hey! Those are our jets.
We're still in the fight.
Alright, clear the bomb zone.
Let's tighten this place down.
Bombs drop in 6 minutes.
Santos, Kerns. On me.
See if there's any comms. Alright?
Hard wired only.
We're clear?
- Yeah! We're clear!
Do you have a hardline in here?
- Over there.
Now my son's a optimist.
When... when this first happened. He said
Why don't we try to
go talk to them.
Maybe they wanna be friends.
Hector?
Hey, we're gonna get some
food and water for your dad okay?
It's okay.
What'd you tell him?
I said the...
you know. If they're
chasing and shooting us.
They're probably not
good friends.
Should've followed directions
and gone to the F.O.B.
I should've never stayed at the
police station. But I was scared, man.
I... I made all the wrong decisions.
You trusted your gut, Mr. Rincon.
You made a call.
I'd do the same thing
to protect my Marines.
I had a situation on my last tour.
There was no angle.You want left,
you go right. It didn't matter.
But you're alive.
- Yeah, I survived.
I wasn't suppose to.
Staff Sergeant Nantz?
You promise to save my son?
Staff Sergeant!
We have a hardwire connection!
Doc, keep him warm.
The sun's going down.
This will keep you warm.
We estimating that 20 cities in
17 countries are now into full attack.
It's obvious the enemy is
attempting to cut us off from one another.
Is there anymore information
at this time, Professor Stavert?
New data shows that their
using our water as their fuel...
and our ocean levels are
already decreasing.
They're using it to power their ships,
their machinery. Possibly
even their own bodies.
It's the composition of our
water that's unique.
It's in a liquid state.
No other locations in our
known universe have liquid H20.
Anywhere near their surface.
I just saw a field report that said...
they would use our sewer
system to follow...
our water back to their ships.
- How the hell did you get that to work?
These things are everywhere.
There's one off the
coast in 20 countries.
They're calling it the
Command and Control Center.
It is who you were tracking?
- Yeah.
So you're saying. That's the
thing controlling the drones.
Yeah. And if we wipe it out.
We take out their air power.
These bombs better work.
Move it! C'mon!
_ Put him into a safe spot.
Set him down.
How much time we got?
1 minute.
Air Force better lay some pain on
those extraterritorial bastards.
Alright! 25! Retreat!
Hell!
Retreat!
- Hell!
Here we go.
- C'mon.
Let's fry these son of a bitches.
We're get to the F.O.B. after these
bomb drop. Get some ammo.
And some god damn reinforcements.
God damn tanks!
10.
- You gotta be strong, okay.
Bloody brace!
Hey! They should've dropped!
- Shit! What the hell?
We've felt them from here
if they'd had dropped?
If they'd had dropped by now.
We would've felt from here, wouldn't we?
Should've felt them from god damn
Nevada with that much joyness!
That clock right?
- That's what I got.
Maybe it's a good thing, right? Maybe
we've turned the tide. I mean...
I mean that's a good thing, right?
You're damn straight, Imlay!
We were kicking some ass out there.
Could they have taken out
the whole air force?
This isn't happening.
Let's move... Everybody up, up.
Let's move. C'mon.
Home stretch... home stretch.
Now we know why
those bombs didn't drop.
They wiped the Forward
Operating Base right off the map.
All clear, Staff Sergeant!
Alright, Let's bring ém
back here.
I feel like it's a million to one odds,
we'd get here in the first place.
We'd get here and
ain't nothing!
I knew Nantz would
never get us out.
There were thousands of Marines here.
- Now there's just seven of us, Imlay.
You remind me of my older brother.
How's that?
He never smiles either.
Secure the front with Harris.
Imlay, anything?
- Nothing, Staff Sergeant.
We'd only got maps of Santa Monica.
We need something further
east. They're all burnt.
Follow me, Imlay.
Alright.
This is the battalions
command for hooch.
We're looking for maps, Anything with an extraction point.
- Yes, Staff Sergeant.
I'll be right back.
Find a tactical map, Staff Sergeant.
Shows where all the units
were deployed.
What the hell's all these red marks here?
-  It means they're gone.
Well, you mean units that got moved?
- Wiped out.
All of them?
- All of them.
Shit...
Alright.
One alternate extraction
site is still operational.
Eight clicks.
Staff Sergeant?
Staff Sergeant!
Adukwu, plenty of weapons around.
Find yourself an M16.
Mr. Rincon is dead.
Please get up, dad?
Please, don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
I'm so sorry, Hector.
I'm sorry.
Your father tried so
hard to stay with you.
I don't want to be here.
It's okay, bud.
Your father was a
brave man, Hector.
Hector, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, buddy.
It's okay to cry.
He loved you very much.
Listen to me, Hector.
I need you to be brave for me,
I need you to be my little marine.
Okay?
We gotta be brave for
the others.
You know why?
Why?
Because Marines don't quit.
Do you believe that?
Say it for me.
Marines don't quit.
Good. I want to get you
out of here.
I promise.
Let's go see the priest, okay.
Come on.
We're not losing one more of
those civilians, understand?
You getting us out
too, Staff Sergeant?
Or are we expenable?
Hm?
Alright, Lockett.
You want to go
there. Let's go there.
I commanded men.
And men died.
Kids.
18 years old.
Best men I ever led.
Do you think that 1 second.
That I'd rather trade
places with them?
I know you think I
got my men killed.
They're dead.
I'm here.
Like the punchline of
some bad joke.
You think I like that?
You'd think a minute goes by
that the faces are right here.
Seared into my brain.
Dante, Thomas D. Corporal.
156509386.
M Brewster, William R. Private - 876662354.
Warden, Geoffrey H.
Lance Corporal.
874273993.
Lockett,
Dwayne
Dwayne G.
Corporal.
1568709
55.
Your brother was an
outstanding Marine.
He was my friend.
And I miss him.
Everyday.
And you remind me of him.
None of that matters right now.
Because our duty is keep
moving forward. Keep fighting.
That's how we honor your brother
and Lieutenant Martinez.
Corporal Stavro,
Lance Corporal Mottola.
Hector's father.
Who picked up a weapon and
did what needed to be done.
Civilian did that.
So we better damn
well step it up!
Discard any lingering doubt!
Work fast!
Work as a unit!
and we will prevail!
Let's figure out how to
get out of this mess.
Imlay, you come with me
and get to higher ground.
Rest of you! Find some
ammo. Some vehicles.
Gotta be a few LAVs or armoured
humvees still operational.
Sorry, bro. You didn't deserve this.
You went down fighting.
Holy shit.
No one expects to see all this.
Now that don't look good.
Reinforcements.
Holy shit.
They already set up a B10.
Alright.
If that evac site is still operational.
I think we can get behind the line.
That's gonna be a hell of a ride, Staff Sergeant.
- Yeah, that's what we get paid for.
Everybody move to the LAV. Now!
Follow me!
- Go...!
Any station, this net.
This is Foxtrot 2 November.
We have 11 passengers.
Requesting evacuation at alternative
extraction point, Charlie.
Are there any birds
in the air? Over.
Foxtrot 2 November, this is Sierra 25.
Orders are to pull back.
Get to evacuation point: Charlie.
By 0300.
Or we'd be gone. Over.
Roger that. At 0300 and not
a minute more. Out.
Imlay? You ever seen what
a Bushmaster Chain gun can do?
Aw shit, Staff Sergeant.
- Get on it, son.
Let's do this!
No lights, Kerns.
- Roger that.
Let's move.
Bushmaster's locked and loaded.
Give ém hell.
Damn right.
Two minutes til the Helo drops.
Everybody okay?
Alright, Kerns!
Take a left.
So you go over 3 blocks,
Then you go about five blocks.
Hang a right. And straight.
That should get us to the evac site.
Yes, Sergeant.
Better hold on if I were you, Lockett!
- Copy that!
We've got hostiles, Staff Sergeant?
- What's going on?
Let's not wait around and find out.
It's gonna be okay.
Got about 250 rounds, Staff Sergeant.
You know what they say
if you're gonna hit a deer!
Speed up!
Damn straight!
C'mon!
You all hold on. We have to
gonna go right through ém!
Saw that!
They're going down like bowling pins.
Take it out!
Run that fucker over, man!
Santos! You okay!?
I'd got that nasty stuff all
over my mouth, man!
Not funny.
You let him do you
on your first date.
Everyone, okay!?
- Yes!
Let's get us home.
Cease fire!
Stay close...!
We do it!
Load ém up!
Their flight path won't
be clear much longer!
You're in the middle of
that shit, Staff Sergeant!
What happened to all our air!?
Fall back to save our asses!
They were blowing us out!
We're abandoning Los Angeles!
Let's go, Imlay!
Sir, you okay?
Alright, sir.
Let's move! Move...!
C'mon, let's go!
Come on.
You alright? Everybody all good?
Everyone Okay!?
- Hold on tight!
What happened!?
Pilot says something was
playing hell with our power!
Staff Sergeant!
9 o'clock!
Santos, you said you were
tracking massive RF signals!?
Could a concentration of
them knock out power!?
Yes, definitely! Why!?
Could be their Command and Control Center!
Get me down there!
- What?
I got to recon that area!
No way! It's suicide!
Dammit! We're the only ones left!
All the other forces have fallen back!
We can't land! We may not
have power to takeoff again!
This is a letter for Martinez's wife!
Would you give it to her?
Yeah!
Hover at 40 feet!
20 seconds!
- Roger that!
Come on Adukwu!
Let's get these off!
Staff Sergeant!? what
the hell are you doing!?
We're in the clear!
We're almost home, Imlay!
You 're in charge now!
You get these civilians home safe!
You're the bravest Marine,
I've ever seen, Hector!
No!
Everyone take cover...
Thought I told you to stay in that helo?
- Civilians are free and clear.
We were worried about your ass.
I think the Command and
Control asset is nearby.
Harris? How many clicks
is that blackout?
It's about 5 clicks, Staff Sergeant.
5 clicks. Alright.
We'll use this overpass
for cover.
If we can take out those drones.
Our military might have chance
to get back into this fight.
Santos?
Where would you put a Command and
Control asset, if you want to protect it?
Underground!
- Let's go.
Move...
Move.
They must've gone back up.
It just leads back to the street.
I thought they were leading us to
the Command and Control Center.
Dammit!
Let's go.
They know we're here now.
That's the Command and Control.
Everybody out now! Move...!
Follow me!
Up here!
Up that ladder! Move...!
Up that ladder!
Let's go! Move it up!
Blow that tray! Imlay!
Move...!
We're right over their Command asset.
- That it, alright. Okay.
Let's move to that concrete slab, 1 o'clock!
Let's move!
Fire in the hole!
That should give us a couple of minutes.
Laser target, Staff Sergeant?
We don't have any more planes, alright.
Hopefully, they can still fire ground to
ground missiles from Edwards Air Force Base.
So we'll radio in a strike.
Paint the target with the
laser, guide them in.
Aye, Staff Sergeant.
- Hoo-rah.
Our best chance of radio
reception is on top of that building.
But it's the most exposed.
I'll do it, Staff Sergeant.
I'll make the call.
Santos, you got those codes?
Air Force straight package coming up.
Get to high ground.
Alright, once you radio in,
they'll track that signal.
They'll be coming in real hot, real fast.
So once you make that call.
You get the hell out of there. Alright?
You know what that means.
Means, we gonna have to hold
those things off till the strike gets here.
Bingo.
Marines?
We make our stand here.
Let those bastards know
who they're fucking with.
Retreat
- Hell!
25.
Right to the heart, right?
- Right to the heart.
They'll be coming up from there.
I need you to take two of these.
Plant one right there!
And another one on the other
side of that rubble, alright.
Keep your head down, get down fast.
- Doc!? Watch your back! Doc!
Watch your head...!
Any stations! This is Foxtrot
2 November. Do you copy!?
2 November.
Do you copy!?
Foxtrot 2 November.
This Yankee Tango! Over.
We've a priority fire mission!
We located a major Command and Control center.
At the grid 8885342.
We will be lasering. Code: 120.
I say again, we will be lasering Code: 120.
Copy that. Time to target. 3 minutes.
Staff Sergeant! We got 3 minutes!
It's coming in 3 minutes!
Alright. Let's paint this target.
Helluva shot, Kerns!
Get your ass outta there!
Get outta there, Kerns!
Shit.
- Kerns!
Shit...!
Doc!? Doc!?
Get to cover now!
Move...!
Contact!
- 12 o'clock!
Get in there!
Fire left! C'mon!
Right there...!
Got it!
60 seconds left!
Got cha!
Shit!
Who's got...
Back in the fight! Santos!
Stay down!
- Covering!
Imlay, use your grenade launcher!
- Got it! Doc!
Where's that god damn artillery!?
Should've hit by now.
Doc! Let's go.
Imlay!?
Incoming!
Yes!
Missiles! We got ém!
We got ém!
Direct hit. Direct hit!!
Staff Sergeant! You did it!
You did it!
Yeah! We got it!
We strike back. It went through?
You did alright, Kerns!
It's coming up...
It's trying to get around.
The god damn thing could fly!
Staff Sergeant! It's flying now!
Get you out!
We got to protect the laser. C'mon!
C'mon!
Santos!
Son of a bitch!
That hurt!
- Cover me, Lockett!
The drones are pulling it away!
We got to take it out, now!
Incoming, Copperhead!
They're using the drones
to protect the ship.
I'm running low on ammo!
- Santos!
How is he?
- He's hanging in there, Staff Sergeant!
Crazy bastard, you should
have leave me there.
Covering!
Grenade!
Staff Sergeant!
We are not dying here, Lockett!
- You damn right, we're not dying!
It's getting outta range!
I'm gonna take it down!
Doesn't have enough
punch! Save that shot!
Staff Sergeant!
Lockett! You okay?
- Harris, You're gonna to be okay.
That's the last Copperhead!
Santos! Take out that drone!
Firing!
Yeah!
- We did it!
We did it...!
I can't believe we did it!
I can't believe it worked!
Yeah...!
Staff Sergeant, you did it!
There's nothing controlling
the drones anymore.
Marines, on me!
They're retreating! Advance!
You guys saved our lives out there!
Semper Fi! 25!
Alright! 25!
Retreat Hell!
You kicked ass, Staff
Sarge! Welcome home!
Good work, Marines!
Outstanding.
The civilians are safe!
Why and how you brought
their ship down,
it's going out to every
army and every city.
We're mustering up whatever
troops we can get.
Going back in.
So get outta that gear!
Get some chow in ya.
There's breakfast in the tent.
You earned it!
Hoo-rah, 25.
For smoking light.
- Got'd you.
Got grenades over here, anybody need?
Yeah, flat rounds coming down.
Imlay, I think you could use this.
- Got it.
HE rounds.
- Hey! I need a couple of magazines.
Very nice. Very nice.
- Everybody got ammo?
Yes.
- Yes, Staff Sergeant.
What'd think you're
doing, Staff Sergeant?
We've already had breakfast, sir.
I'll be borrowing this, sir.
Carry on.
This is Knoll Pet 23. Who's with me?
Morning, Knoll Pet.
Dog Pad 21, on your left.
Hear a friendly voice. Dog Pad 21.
This is Snake Eyes joining the fight.
Hiya, Foxtrot 2. We're on your 6.
- Morning, Dog Pad 21.
People on your right.
This is Foxtrot 2 November.
Let's take back Los Angeles.