Put your clothes on, Tarzan. Time to
head back to the land of the big P.X.
You got 30 minutes
to pack your gear.
Now, get a move on, son.
let’s get out of here.
Obrigado.
Over here!
See what I'm sayin'?
For real! Yeah, yeah.
Check it out.
Hey. My man.
Hey, you sellin'?
'Cause I got 20.
What do I get... for 20?
Hey, man. What do you think,
you're the only pharmacy in town, man?
This information is basic...
to the understanding of
20th-century thought and civilization.
Charles Darwin’s theory,
"Natural Selection,"...
A general description?
Anybody?
- We went over all of this material yesterday.
- Yo, Kerrigan.
I got your natural selection,
my man.
How 'bout I naturally select to walk
out of this boring-ass classroom.
God help us all.
Whoo! Outta here!
Oh.
Mr. Kerrigan?
Louis?
Maybe it's not such a good time.
I- I-I can come back.
Nah. No better or worse
than any other time.
No, no.
Come on in, Louis.
Excuse me. It's been
a rough morning.
So, the last I heard...
you were off on the great
South American crusades...
training our stalwart
indigenous troops...
how to fight
the malignant cartels.
I spent four years fighting a lot of
bureaucracy is what it comes down to.
Now I'm back, and, uh...
I'm just trying to find
square one all over again.
And you think maybe
I can possibly help?
Kid, you're in
serious trouble.
Come on. let's go down
to the feeding grounds.
What do you think of these?
They installed them
a couple of years ago.
Too many kids were getting high,
thinking they were Superman.
Either that or they were just throwing
each other off the third story.
- Hello.
- Hiya. How ya doin'?
Janitors got tired
of scrapping 'em off the floor.
I signed on to be a schoolteacher,
Louis, not a zookeeper.
I'm tired. I'm tired of trying
to lead the horses to water...
and I and everyone else
knows they're not gonna drink.
Mr. Kerrigan, people like you
do not just up and quit.
They stick around and keep people
like me from quitting.
There was a time,
young Mr. Stevens...
when there were some students,
like yourself, who were worth saving...
but... that's in
the past tense.
Take a look around you
at our current student body.
Seventy-five percent of them
are packing weapons.
Forty-five percent are high. Eighty-one
percent are living in one-parent families.
Is it any mystery
that 12% of the students...
who come to Lincoln High School
go full term and graduate?
Well, what about those 12%?
What about the peasants?
The ones who wanted to plant
sweet potatoes and not coca leaves.
I don't see you re-upping
for another four years.
No, I guess you don't.
Sorry.
I'm sorry I came here
in the first place.
You'll be selling the product,
or you'll be sorry.
- Now, pick it up!
- Aw, man!
You better pray.
- Shay should just go ahead and...
- Shay, get up, man.
Just having a little
family problem here, Teach.
little brother here forgot to finish
his homework last night, eh?
Why don't you let the kid go?
I just told you.
This is family matters. None of
your damn business. Who is this?
First of all,
I ain't a teacher.
- Oh.
- Second...
I'm in a real shitty mood.
Ooh!
And third, no law says
I can't make it my business.
So let the kid go!
Well, me man...
you just made it
your damn business.
Get him.
Come to me.
Yes.
Boss, look at me.
Back! Get back!
Aaah!
- Yeah, mon!
- Come on!
Do it again! Get him!
Good, good, good!
Yeah, yeah! Get him!
Come on! Get up!
Yeah. Yeah!
Come on!
- Oh!
- Unreal!
He got kicked
right back to Jamaica!
Louis, do you know
what you just did?
You did something none of us professionals
have been able to do for the last five years.
You got their attention!
Hey, hey! All right! Hey!
These kids are no strangers
to violence.
It's been a part of their lives
since the day they were born.
look how they responded
to Louis...
when he threw
those dealers off campus.
And so by teaching them this,
uh, this Brazilian kung fu...
Capoeira. Capoeira.
Yes, thank you... we will be
channeling their hyperactive...
hormone-driven energies
into something constructive.
- That's the idea.
- let me get this straight.
You propose we scrape the bottom
of the barrel for 12 of our worst kids.
Students who are without redemption,
who are prime dropout material.
And in lieu of their gym classes,
young Lawrence here...
- Louis. My name is Louis.
- Teaches them this stuff...
and hopefully...
It'll show them
some respect.
- Give 'em something to strive for, to work for.
- Gentlemen. Gentlemen!
listen to what
we're being sold here, people.
Teach violence
to violent kids.
We, ve been told
that this young man...
has just returned
from military service in Latin America.
Doing what, pray tell?
Training death squads?
Now, there's a fine role model
for our disaffected youth!
Mr. Kerrigan, we tried.
- It's not gonna work. -
Louis! - Wait, wait, wait.
- Hang on a second.
- I know Louis.
We were both students
at Lincoln together.
When he was
a freshman and a sophomore...
he was a troublemaker, going nowhere
like most of the kids in this school.
But someone turned him around.
His 11 th-grade
social studies teacher.
Now I think he's back
to try and return the favor...
and if this is a last desperate attempt
to help these kids...
because what we're doing
is not working...
I think it might
be worth a shot.
What have we
got to lose?
Hey, Dianna.
Dianna, whoa.
I just wanted
to say thanks.
- Thanks for talking me into it.
- You're welcome, Louis.
Can I help you carry something?
Your books?
Thanks. We're not
in high school anymore.
No, we're not,
and we shouldn't act like it.
So I can take you
someplace nice now.
look. You're not
getting it, are you?
I liked your proposal.
I thought it was fresh and offbeat.
- Thanks.
- I doubt it's gonna work, but at this point, I don't care.
I'm willing to try anything.
But just don't think that my support was
based on anything other than those kids.
That's all you should expect.
- Hector.
- SI’mi amor.
Will you help me
with these?
Thanks.
There's the front door.
Or maybe that...
Yeah, that's
the front door.
- What's with the windows?
- Well, we can take those out.
Yeah, that'll help.
Well, at least
we got ourselves a dojo.
We got ourselves a disaster, that's what
we got ourselves. look at this floor.
Somebody's been using it for a toilet,
and I'm supposed to do handstands on this?
Oh, Louis,
we're in a firehouse.
There's got to be hoses
around in here.
A hosing ain, t gonna do it.
This place needs to be nuked.
Fellas, your lease is up.
look out! look out!
Well, let's see what they sent us.
let's go, guys. Come on.
You must be kilng.
Eie. Will you just
line up down here, please?
Yeah, yeah. Whatever you say, Kerrigan.
Whatever you say.
Danny, stay in the city limits,
would you?
Come on, guys. line up.
Down to your left.
That’s it, gentlemen.
Down to your left. Your left.
The other left.
Shay, move on in here.
Right in here.
Just follow him down.
That's it. Hold it.
This line down here, please.
All right. let me have
your attention, please, guys.
As you all know, were it not
for this opportunity...
you, d probably be spending your time in
detention or Mr. Casper’s gym class...
and if you, d like,
those options are still available.
- looks like Shay’s place.
- You get my drift?
Oh, no.
Now what?
Ooh! Mrs. Esposito!
look at that sexy mama!
Boy, did we ever scrape
the bottom of that barrel.
Mrs. Esposito.
- School and juvenile records.
- Ah, thanks.
Well, the Vienna Boys' Choir
it ain't.
But I'm sure in a month's time they'll
be saluting and calling you "sir. "
Make us proud, soldier. Ed.
I'm sticking my neck out for you.
Do not make me look like a fool.
That's gonna be
pretty near impossible.
All right, fellas. let’s go.
Into the firehouse.
let’s line up for roll call.
Everybody.
Everybody. Come on.
Hey, Shay, looks like your house.
What a shit-hole.
- Place is fallin' apart.
- Those are rat holes.
look at this, man.
Hey, Kerrigan, you oughta
condemn this place, man.
We could hurt ourselves here.
Okay, guy...
Donovan, would you turn that off.
- What?
- Turn it off!
- This is a class.
- Oh.
All right.
Your instructor today...
or mestre...
is Mr. Louis Stevens.
- Ooh.
- Oh. The tough guy!
- He's a former graduate of Lincoln High.
- He must be a loser then.
He’s also a former Green Beret.
- Ooh.
- And he’s not predisposed to tolerating...
any disorder the way
some of your teachers are.
He has kindly agreed
to show us...
He's that punk that kicked your brother's
ragged ass out on the lunch yard, man.
I'll do the same to you, faggot.
Any day!
- Hey, listen up.
- I think so, man.
- listen up!
- Take your best shot.
Aw, I'll kick
his ass later, man.
You!
I want you
to turn that music up.
I said turn it up!
- Okay. Happy?
- All right.
Yeah. I like that.
In capoeira,
everything starts out with the ginga.
This is a ginga.
That's a ginga.
- I know that!
- Yeah, that's it!
Think you got it, Eie.
- looks pretty funny, doesn't it?
- Very funny.
It's the basis
for moves like this.
Hey, man!
This doesn't seem
to be working now, does it?
You mind?
No.
Mr. Kerrigan, you have that tape?
Now, this is
the real capoeira music.
I recorded it in Brazil. It's a little
different, so keep your mind open.
Hey, man, turn that
voodoo music off!
Give it a chance, guys.
Keep an open mind, huh?
I said turn
that shit off, man.
- It's giving me a headache.
- Go back to the jungle.
Ooh!
You must think
I'm playing, punk.
- Ooh.
- Cut him up, Orlando.
Do it, Orlando!
Hey, give me that!
Where you going?
let's dance.
He's only human.
Get up!
Will you turn that off, please?
Okay, that's class for today.
Tomorrow I want everybody to show up in
baggy clothes, no shoes and ready to ginga.
That’s it, guys.
You, re dismissed.
- What's your name?
- Eat shit.
You want your blade back,
eat shit?
His name's Orlando Oliveiras, and he has no
business carrying that knife in the first place.
We're not technically
on campus, are we?
- No.
- Heads up, tough guy.
- Louis, what are you doing?
- Tomorrow baggy clothes, huh?
Louis, that kid has got
a disciplinary file as long as my arm.
He's got a cousin
named Silverio...
who runs one of
the toughest gangs in the city.
Mr. Kerrigan, if we don't start trusting
them, why should they start trusting us?
Um, could I borrow this?
I mean, just for tonight.
Just don't forget
where it came from, huh?
Promise.
- You have a name?
- Yeah. Uh, Donovan.
Donovan.
See you tomorrow, Donovan.
- Okay.
I hope you have
another copy of that.
Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
Trust them.
Thanks, Mr. Stevens.
What? Oh, this?
Well, you see, I ran your tape
through a MI DI setup.
Your percussion and vocals are panned
from left to right on eight...
and then I filled in the other 16 tracks
with some prefab Brahms samples.
And then I aed
some reverb and some delays...
and some custom-made sounds.
It's kind of like a blend
of the old and the new.
I hope it's cool with you,
'cause I would not want to offend...
any of the ancient mestres
or anything like that, you know.
I think they're gonna like it.
Danny.
Come on, guys.
- Hurry up.
- What, are we going on a picnic here?
What, are you nuts?
Come on, you big dope! Come on!
Hey, guys.
- Music any better? It's Donovan's mix.
- All right.
- Huh?
- Aww.
Yea!
Oh...
Okay, let's get started.
Um, spread it out.
Drop your bags.
Danny, drop your skateboard.
Drop your pants.
Come on, guys.
let's start up with the ginga.
Shay, why don't you
help me out, man.
Everybody, watch, please.
Right leg out.
Then left.
Mr. Stevens.
I thought we was gonna learn
how to kick ass.
- Shut up, Shay.
- All right, listen up.
You can't ginga, you can't fight.
- That's the basic of it.
- But, uh, Mr. Stevens...
I thought we was gonna
learn how to kick ass!
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
Break it up!
Break it up, guys!
All right, class dismissed.
Everyone, out.
Yeah! Whoo!
let's go.
Except you, Shay. You stay.
- He started it!
- I said you stay!
Forget you, man!
I'll take detention over this shit!
Whoa, whoa. What? You wanna let your brother
keep slapping you around for not selling drugs?
Or do you wanna learn
how to kick ass?
Today's your big chance, man,
because tomorrow...
tomorrow it's you and Eie
in front of the entire class.
Now, we got the rest
of the afternoon.
If you want it.
And mark.
Good. Go, Shay.
One more.
That’s it. That’s it.
Come to me.
Hey, Mr. Kerrigan.
Check this out. All right.
Queixada, queixada, bencao.
Now, do it slow one time.
Queixada. And light
and slow first one. And bam!
Good. All right.
Now this time hard.
let’s do it.
Don’t wuss out on me now.
All right.
let's do it hard.
Queixada, queixada,
and wham!
That was pretty good, man.
I knew you had it in you.
- Huh? Huh?
- Yeah.
All right.
let's do it again.
Queixada, queixada.
let’s go, Shay!
Get up, man!
- You can take him!
- Get up!
Teach him a lesson, man!
Come on.
What's up? Get up!
Get up, man!
You, re weak, man! Get up!
Get him!
Come on! let's go!
Come on. Get up!
What’s wrong with you, bro? Get up!
let’s go, Eie. Come on, man.
Come on, Eie.
Oh, man! I felt that one!
He’s messed up.
Oh, Eie, man.
You ready to try this yet?
Mr. Kerrigan, please.
Danny, man.
Come on. let's go.
That's it. That's it.
loosen up.
Come on in, Donovan.
Yeah.
It's easy, man.
You got it.
See? There you go.
You got it, guys.
Ooh. Whoa.
Come on, Eie.
Do it, man.
Come on.
Break it down, Danny.
- Go, Shay.
- Whoa.
Yeah! All right, guys. Not bad.
This instrument
is the berimbau.
It sets the pace
for the jogo, the game.
All right, Donovan.
You try to stay with my beat, huh?
Okay. Here we go.
- What do you think?
- Nah, man.
- Come on, man. Just give it a try.
- No, man.
I know you got this
in your blood. Just try it.
You know I've got this
in my blood?
Boy, you don't know
caralho about me, man.
Just 'cause you read some files,
you think you know about me?
Man, you don't know nothing
about anybody here!
You're right. I don't. But I'm trying
to learn. That's why we're here.
What are we gonna learn, huh?
What are you gonna teach us?
How to play your poja bongo drums
and dance around like little viados?
You're a loser, man.
A loser!
lando!
Orlando!
What you lookin' at?
Why'd you walk out
on the class?
- You gonna hide behind
these guys all night, Orlando...
- or you gonna speak up for yourself?
- I already told you.
I don't got time to be playing
your poja games, man.
What do you got time for?
Running little errands for your cousin?
Stealing cars
and chopping them up?
Yeah, teacher, I do shit for my cousin.
Everybody knows that.
Cops know that,
school knows that.
I'm sure you saw it
on my files.
Oh, so now what?
You got something better for me?
You gonna pay my mama's rent? Are you
gonna feed me with that jungle music, man?
Teacher, let me tell you
something about my cousin.
He don't play no jungle music,
but he takes care of business.
He takes care of his family,
and he takes care of his neighborhood.
You better go, man.
We gonna see you
in class tomorrow?
Hey, sacana. Now, maybe you
Don’t hear so good. He said go.
Now!
look at this.
Oh, man.
So, you must be the guy.
Eh, primo?
The one who teaches
capoeira, eh?
You must be the cousin.
Silverio.
So, tell me, teacher.
How much are they paying you
on the high school?
- Enough.
- Don't play with me, cu.
How much?
I got a roof over my head.
That's all I need right now.
"A roof over my head. " Ha!
You know, my friend...
it's been a long time
since I met a real-life santo.
A saint. Right before my eyes.
In the flesh and blood.
Tell you what, santo.
- You see
all this useless garbage?
I need someone...
who can take these pieces of shit
and make men out of them.
If you can teach them
how to fight...
I'll give you a roof over your head
like you ain't gonna believe.
And probably all
the coke I can snort.
Whatever.
I'm a reasonable man.
Just tell me
what you need.
You know what I need?
I need to get out of here
before I puke all over your fancy shoes.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, santo.
Your interview
is not over yet.
I still gotta check
your qualifications.
See, you Don’t
fool a man...
who was born and raised
in the worst barrio of Rio deJaneiro.
We, re gonna find out
real quick...
who's the real capoeira mestre
in this neighborhood.
You know what?
You're okay, santo.
Get up.
I say, "Okay. "
Which means not good enough
to train my boys here...
but good enough
to train my primo.
Santo’s gonna teach you the simple shit,
and when you're ready to graduate...
I'm gonna be
your college...
to teach you what they don't
teach you in the playgrounds.
He's my blood, santo.
I got big plans for him.
Don't be putting
no crazy ideas in his head.
I, d say going there
by yourself...
was not the smartest move
you ever made.
look who's talkin'...
you waitin' outside the fire station
alone on a night like this.
Yeah, I'd say that's
pretty levelheaded, huh?
- Aaah.
- Sorry.
- So why did you wait for me?
- 'Cause I know that neighborhood.
And I know about
Orlando's family.
- I tried to warn you.
- Hey, you know me.
If someone says it's a lost cause,
I'm the first sucker in line.
Uh-huh. Is that
what these kids are?
They just another
lost cause to you?
This time it's my backyard.
What does that mean?
It means that if I don't do something
about it, I've got to live with it.
We've got to live with it.
Is this that same
self-absorbed guy I used to date?
What happened to you
down there?
It's okay.
- How's your hand?
- I don't know.
let's find out, huh?
Oh... God!
Louis, you're crazy!
- Guess the hand's better, Doc.
- Take two aspirin, and Don’t call me in the morning.
Wait. It's your turn. I bet you can't
even do a handstand anymore.
- You're right.
- This is a challenge.
You gonna wimp out
on a challenge?
Swim, or do a handstand.
- This is my choice?
- This is your choice.
- All right, Mr. Show-off.
- All right.
Does teacher need
a spot or some help?
No, no. Just don't look
when I try one.
- So you do need a spot.
- All right.
- Just get back.
- Drumroll, please.
Oh, my God.
Oh... Grab me!
God...
Well, your handstand needs some help,
but your back bend's pretty good.
- Are you happy now?
- Could be happier.
How?
Oh, my God.
Louis, what are you doing?
- You're crazy.
- I know.
Dianna!
Dianna, there's a rumor
being circulated...
by my own students,
no less...
about you
and Mr. Death Squad...
who, guess what, turns out to be
a former boyfriend of yours.
Since when did you start teaching
current affairs, Hector?
Since you started
piling on the fiction, Dianna.
look. What is going on
down at that firehouse?
I don't think that's
any of your business.
Although it probably wouldn't hurt for
you to come down and see for yourself.
I wasn't expecting this.
This is very... impressive.
So the techniques are
mixed in with the dance?
And the rhythm. Yes.
Great. They've learned a more efficient
way to give each other bloody noses.
Apparently, that's not all
they've learned, Senor Cervantes! look!
Ordinarily that would have led to a
shooting, especially with those two kids.
look at what he's done with them.
And these are...
These were the 12 worst kids at Lincoln,
the absolute bottom of the heap!
Hell, I'm ready to give him
Casper's entire gym class!
- let's do it.
- All right.
Granted, he's instilled
a small degree of discipline...
but let's not blow this
out of proportion.
"Out of proportion"? like taking this proposal
directly to the head of the school board?
- Would that be out of proportion for you?
- What proposal?
The capoeira program, Kerrigan. Citywide,
at every high school in the district.
God knows, if it works at Lincoln, it'll
work damn near anywhere. You shut up!
Come on, Kerrigan.
Get with the program.
It's all right here, and they're
gonna love it when they see it.
What they'll want to know
from you, Louis...
is how you're going
to teach this to 1,200 kids.
Meanwhile, if there's anything more I can
do for you and the class, just name it.
Uh, well, sir,
now that you mention it...
I was kind of thinking
about a field trip.
We got a flat tire, or what?
- Mr. Stevens?
Where you going, man?
- This is it!
- Hey, Mr. Stevens.
How are you so sure
that this is the place?
- Maybe it's me, but you can't see shit out here.
- Trust me.
- Oh, yeah, trust you.
- Now, come on. Everybody, out. let's go.
Out? What for? I thought
we were sleeping on the bus.
Eie, you ever try
to set up a tent inside a bus?
- He never tried to set up a tent, period.
- Yeah, what are we, injuns?
Here I thought you're supposed to be
the 12 baest kids in Miami, huh?
This don't look like
no Miami I ever seen.
This looks
like snakes and alligators, man.
- like Frey Krueger be livin, here.
- Dianna.
Louis, it's so late.
Wouldn't a hotel be a better idea?
Whoo, Mr. Stevens.
You and the prettiest teacher in school!
- Hotel room?
- Eie!
All right.
You wanna stay on the bus?
Sleep on the bus. I like the beach.
I will sleep on the beach!
Screw it, guys.
I’m goin, with him.
Forget it.
Shut the door!
- Shut the door.
- Shut the door. Shut the door!
Wow. look at this place.
All right! All right, Donovan!
Yeah!
Yeah, Orlando!
look out!
- Oh!
- Ouch!
One more time. Please. Okay.
Come on, guys.
Hey, Mr. Stevens.
When do we eat, 'cause I'm starvin'?
Eie, put up the tent.
So where's your partner?
If you're looking for
Mr. last of the Mohicans...
he's over there.
I was supposed to be
working this weekend.
- For your cousin?
- Yeah.
Stripping cars.
It's good money, bro.
They'll find somebody else.
One thing for sure,
in my neighborhood...
there's always somebody else.
I'd like to think you're
better than that now, Orlando.
Yeah, right.
Better for what?
Stripping cars is all I know.
Oh, and capoeira.
That's all your life
is supposed to amount to, huh?
Who sold you on that
load of crap, or should I guess?
I've got some major news
for you, man.
This world can be about as big
as you ever want it to be.
Or as small
as your own tiny, little hood.
I'm showing you
some choices.
You decide.
I'm here.
- Hi, Tanya. How you doing?
- Good.
Back to school, gentlemen!
let's go! Hustle up!
- You got about 10 minutes before class starts.
- Party's over.
Hey, look at this.
The children’s are back
from the playground.
You had a job you were supposed to do
last night, you little piece of shit.
Silverio...
you're family...
and I respect you, man...
but... I'm not your slave.
Hey! Back off, man.
Hey, we got a little rebellion
going on here, huh?
You starting to talk that kind of shit
to your brother too, eh?
He ain't no brother of mine no more,
and he sure don't own me.
That's why you Jamaicans
are so weak.
No loyalty for the family.
I'm gonna show you something.
Hey, primo!
You got me in a bad mood already!
You, re getting in that car!
He's not going anywhere
except to his first class...
which starts
in about five minutes.
Hey, santo. I should've known you
were the one who started this shit.
- Well, hello.
- Stay on the bus, Dianna.
Tell you what, santo.
You take my cousin...
and I'll take her.
Mr. Oliveiras,
you'd better leave now...
without your cousin.
My cousin, in case you didn't know,
is not a student of this school anymore.
He's now working
for me full-time.
Was this his decision,
or was it yours?
You know what, santo?
I'm trying to be a nice guy...
but now you're really
starting to piss me off.
A lot of people in this town
will tell you...
pissing me off is not
a smart thing to do.
Vamonos.
Hey, hey!
You want to play, santo?
Come on. Come on.
You wanna play with me? Huh?
Come on. This time I play for keeps.
And this time I don't play.
Come on. Come on. Huh?
Ha, the cops!
Well, well, well.
What do we have here? Mr. Oliveiras.
Why don't you explain why we
shouldn't run your ass in right now?
Something about violating
a restraining order...
not being within a hundred yards
of a school zone?
Little family emergency. I just gotta
pick up my cousin and I'm outta here.
It's your choice, lando.
It's your life.
He's my family, mestre.
Can't go against my blood.
We'll work it out.
I promise.
Excuse me, Officer.
Just gotta say one more little thing
to my homey and I'm outta here.
You want a war
with me, mestre?
You're gonna get one.
Have a nice day, Officer.
I still say we shoot
the little bastard.
Not good enough.
These kids are starting to look up to
this guy like he's some kind of a hero.
We need to make
an example out of him.
Hey, Teach, what's up?
Excuse me.
Can I help you gentlemen?
Hi.
How are you?
Ooh!
So, where's your
capoeira mestre?
You give him a message.
If he wants to take over
my territory...
he's got to give me something...
something I want.
- You think he's gonna give it to me?
- No.
Then he better leave...
and never come back.
- Ooh!
- Go with your mestre. Bye!
- Bye! Bye!
- Ciao!
Hey!
Wonder who this
belongs to, huh?
He's gonna kill you for that.
One thing is for sure, old man.
Somebody's gonna die.
He saw our faces.
let him turn into toast.
Adeus.
Donovan, man, look.
Mr. Kerrigan's class.
Fire!
Get out, get out, get out!
Mr. Kerrigan!
Come on, man!
You all right?
- I'll be right back!
- Where you going?
- Just stay with him!
- You crazy?
No!
Donovan! Get your ass
back here, man!
The whole place
is going up!
- Stop that guy!
- Louis!
Mr. Stevens,
I tried to stop him.
Forget it, buy. He’s gone.
Lincoln High finds itself being consumed
by a bloody reign of terror...
that was unleashed
when the instructor...
of an experimental martial arts program
crossed swords with local gang members.
Today, both students and faculty members
alike are asking themselves why.
Was the death of a 17-year-old student
and the hospitalization...
of two teachers a fair price to pay
for a dubious program...
which we now learn had no official
authorization from the city school board?
These are just a few
of the tough questions...
that Lincoln High principal
Donald Cochran...
will be facing when he goes
before the board this afternoon.
You, out of my office,
off of my campus!
If I see your face again,
so help me, I'll have you arrested!
Escort him to the sidewalk.
Avoid the cameras.
Mr. Cochran, the program worked.
He turned them around. You saw it...
Miss Walker! In case
you haven't figured it out yet...
this kung fu business is over...
terminated, banished
from our campus...
along with this scum bucket
who brought it here in the first place!
What are you waiting for?
Get him out of my sight!
One, two, three.
One, one, two, three.
Two, one, two, three, four.
One... What’s the matter? You got a problem
keeping up with the rest of the class?
- Mr. Stevens.
- You got a hearing problem too?
Just a second, okay?
lando didn't show up today.
I don't think
he's showing up no more.
Hey, wimp. If anybody needs
this exercise, you do.
Well, Mr. Capo-whatsis.
Correct me if I’m wrong,
but I Don’t think...
that you are supposed to be messing
with my students anymore.
Okay, hotshot, let's go.
I gotta go now.
You watch out for yourself. I hear they,
re looking for you. You know who I mean.
Come on, come on, come on.
I ain't supposed to be here.
Guess you know that.
Yeah. I guess you ain't supposed to be
in school anymore either, huh?
Hey, I didn't have
too much of a choice, all right?
- Yeah. I can see that.
- look. You gotta leave, man.
I mean, get out of Miami,
out of Florida, far away as you can go.
"Yankee, go home. "
Where have I heard that before?
This time it's no bullshit.
They're gonna kill you.
This time it's my home.
This time I don't leave until it's over.
So how'd you find out
where the car shop was?
- Your cousin's quite famous around here.
- So what you gonna do?
He's got an alibi for all that shit
that went down at the school.
Ain't one person in that neighborhood
gonna speak out against him.
They're either scared,
or else they think he's Robin Hood.
Cops can't touch him, and you're just gonna
be one more dead body if you go after him.
Yeah, like Donovan?
He was your friend, Orlando.
He was my friend.
Gonna forget about him
just like that?
Man, I just don't want
to see you ending up like him.
You know what Mr. Kerrigan
says in his classes?
All that crap about
only the strong survive?
Well, let me tell you
something, mestre.
No amount of capoeira,
no amount of Green Beret bullshit...
none of that gonna make you
strong enough...
to take on
an entire neighborhood by yourself.
Then he'll just keep on being
the master of the plantation.
- Is that what you want?
- Doesn't matter what I want. That's just the way it is!
Unless we do
something about it.
Anybody know where
I can buy a hot Mercedes?
Hey! I got a message
for your boss.
He's got no car. That means
he's still in this neighborhood.
You find me this cockroach,
and you bring it to me alive, tonight!
We finish this war!
Hey, where the hell have you been?
Take a look at our shop!
See what your mestre did? He's
a sworn enemy, primo, but I'm stronger.
In an hour you meet us
at Macumba Grove.
We'll find out once and for all
who really owns this neighborhood.
Yeah.
Talk to me.
He's near the corner of Biscayne
and 28th. Get your men there pronto!
And remember,
I want him alive.
We're on the way.
Make a U-turn now!
Alive!
We want him alive!
Hey, little cockroach.
- We have a very special treat
for you tonight.
Bring him!
What is this?
Some kind of joke?
We're here to take our teacher back,
and that ain't no joke!
Stop! Back off!
Back off!
I would seriously suggest...
that you boys get out of the way
before somebody gets hurt.
And you... I will deal
with you later.
Deal with me now, primo, 'cause you ain't
getting past us unless you hand him over.
You bad shit now, huh?
I think you're right, primo.
We're gonna deal with this shit
right now, right here.
- Should we get rid of these ladies, or what?
- Yeah!
Silverio!
Just you and me.
This time we finish it.
let's finish it.
let him go.
If I win, these kids
are mine again.
If you win.
All right.
Is somebody gonna start talking, or are
we all gonna take a ride downtown?
Hey, you're that guy
from Lincoln High School, aren't you?
Yes, sir.
- Who that?
- His name's Silverio Oliveiras.
He’s my cousin. He’s the guy
who started the fire at the school.
He killed my friend Donovan.
Are you willing to swear
to that in a court of law?
- That's right, sir.
- And you, re fully aware...
of this man's reputation
for intimidating witnesses?
That shit's over, man.
He don't own
this neighborhood no more.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Hey, thanks.
- Oh, yeah!
- Way to go, man. All right!
- Yea!
- Whoo!
Oh, yeah!
My heartiest congratulations
to this year's graduates.
- May your futures be filled with purpose and success.
- let's go do it. Come on.
Whoo!
This year, I am proud...
to announce that we have
a special aition to our ceremonies...
courtesy of Mr. Louis Stevens.
I...
And so, without further ado.
Whoa!