You did it, John.
All fighting has stopped.
There's no more dying.
And all of a sudden,
three is not such
a scary number.
But no matter
how wonderful this is,
I will not accept it
as a trade-off
for losing you.
I've got you.
Thank you ever so
for your kind assistance.
Always anxious to lend a hand
to a Dominar.
So often I've proclaimed having
a belly full of Crichton and Aeryn.
Never thought
it would be so literal.
What did you call
their species again?
This is Crichton.
He is called a Human.
And Aeryn, Sebacean.
Definitely Sebacean.
Rygel, do you have
all the pieces?
From under every rock,
every crevice,
I sifted the bottom sand
with my bare hands!
Look at my nails!
Caa'ta, the Leviathan ship
has returned.
Their transport pod
is approaching.
Order the concealment
canopy lowered.
Sir, another deep-space contact
from Peacekeeper Strategic Command.
It's Grand Chancellor Maryk again.
Grand Chancellor.
Where the Hedsmana
in my orders did you find the phrase
"preemptive attack"?
The Scarrans are massing
for an impending onslaught
we all know is coming!
A conflict we are
ill situated to win.
By challenging them before they are
prepared, we have a fighting chance.
- You were sent to gather surveillance
and... - With all due respect, sir,
I was sent here to perish
at the vanguard
of this inevitable conflict.
I simply refuse to participate
on their terms or yours!
Because of your actions,
the Scarran Empire
has declared war against us.
Do you know what that means,
Scorpius?
We are now officially engaged
in the last war of our era!
Congratulations.
- D'Argo!
- Chiana!
- Your eyes.
- I can see again.
- What happened? How?
- He, He gave me n-new eyes.
- We found one, yes.
- Stark and I found a Diagnosan.
What's wrong with him?
Nothing's wrong with him!
He's fine.
Grunschlk, I thought
you were dead.
Me? Hardly at all.
Those crystals
are people's lives.
Stop waving that thing around.
This had better work.
You're lucky
to have him, mate.
Diagnosans,
they're at a premium.
Especially now
that there's a war on.
What war?
The Peacekeepers and the Scarrans
have declared war against each other.
Do the Peacekeepers know
what they're getting into?
The Scarrans didn't
give 'em much choice.
They were already taking
the galaxy by force. System by system.
A galaxy-wide war.
The Scarran vanguard has breached our
defense perimeter.
We've drawn them in
sufficiently. The trap is set.
Captain, initiate the plan
exactly as I instructed.
All pilots, deactivate
targeting in-flight systems.
We fly manual from here.
Fly straight in.
Their targeting telemetrics
will be corrupted
at least two degrees off center
by the ambient magnetics.
You dared them to hit you.
Red Team, move close to my
left flank. Blue Team, likewise.
Upon signal,
execute tier attack
on lead Scarran Dreadnought.
Confirm.
All armada ships
now taking heavy fire, sir.
Only for the moment.
Stay positioned.
And... fire!
Lower your weapons.
How long?
About 60 solar days.
Where?
Still on the water planet.
Put your weapons down now!
Bad guys?
Yes and no. They did help us
put you back together.
Put us back together?
They said it was an accident.
You were crystallized.
Crystallized?
Last warning.
- You said yes.
- I did?
- Sixty days. Any regrets?
- No. It's going really well.
Hey, we're gonna get married!
Congratulations.
Sir, you were
absolutely correct.
Their pilots and gunners
were no match for ours.
- Scorpius?
- Prepare to withdraw.
What?
The rest of the armada is to continue
to engage the enemy, covering our escape.
But, sir, we're winning.
- Without this carrier, all remaining units...
- My orders are clear.
Sir, you're asking us
to withdraw our troops,
our ships, our...
Close hangars!
Wait for maximum speed.
He is alive, Sikozu.
John Crichton is alive.
One more time.
Begin again.
Fine.
For the 89th time.
Once upon a time,
there was a boy named John.
And John was an astronaut.
He lived in a faraway place
called Earth.
Which is so far away,
you've never heard of it.
One day when John was out
doing astronaut things,
a big blue wormhole
gobbled him up and spat him out
at the far end of the universe.
- Things were looking grim in Mudville
- Canaveral?
Till our hero met
an amazing living ship,
made some nice new friends
and he hooked up
with his dream girl.
We could've lived happily ever
after, but the Peacekeepers
raped, chased and tortured us
for years on end.
Fire!
Then two months ago, we got
our asses shot off again.
This time it was the Scarrans,
big reptiles. Oooh!
And Moya, our living ship,
limped her way to your
happy planet for a little R&R.
Because we figure, it's empty!
Hey, no one is gonna bother us.
We're gonna have a baby!
- Will you marry me?
- Yes.
Next thing, me
and the future Mrs. Crichton
are having a private moment
when you guys fly by.
Boom bada-bing,
squiggly line, squiggly line.
Crystallized.
And it's two months later.
What?
Retreating.
Scorpius has powered off
his onboard beacon.
We have no way
of tracking him.
Broadcast this order.
Highest priority.
The instant his command carrier
is spotted, it is to be fired upon.
No hailing,
no offer to surrender.
I want this coward Scorpius
and all who fly with him
erased from existence!
Aye, Chancellor.
Scorpius is many things, Maryk.
None of them good.
But a coward? Never.
He has initiated this war,
and then turned and run!
How do you define
cowardice, Grayza?
Grand Chancellor,
please consider my counsel
on this carefully.
Hatred of the Scarrans
is Scorpius'
sole consistent trait.
There is something else.
Perhaps.
But my orders stand.
- Funny how?
- Different.
Different how? Like ice cream
cucumber different?
I don't know.
That's why I'm here.
All right. Everything
is gonna be okay.
Do you know why?
Because we're done.
We're checking out.
Next Ferengi we see, we run.
No questions later.
From this moment on,
my one concern, my life
is you
and our baby.
Are you sure?
- What?
- Is she all right? The baby all right?
Doc says he doesn't know what you're
talking about. There is no baby.
What? Whoa, whoa!
What do you mean, no baby?
Ah, if there was
a little passenger before,
it ain't aboard the train
no more.
Doc says you
never were pregnant.
- I was.
- She was!
She was preg...
You were pregnant?
I was pregnant!
There is no baby.
No. Nothing.
Whoa!
We were in pieces,
thousands of pieces.
Rygel said he got every single
piece off of the ocean floor.
- Rygel.
- He was very thorough.
We made sure of it.
Even carried the pieces
up in his stomach
to make sure
he didn't drop them.
Congratulations, mate.
You are a mother!
- Oh, no!
- It's all right.
The wee babe
is doing just fine.
Yes, but it's doing
just fine inside me!
This is not happening.
- Do something.
- Hands off, missy.
The fee.
The fee is going up.
You take it out of him,
and you put it back in her.
Whatever it takes.
Won't do it.
Won't? I want this thing
removed immediately.
It's not a thing!
Fine. I want this miracle
of life out of me!
All right.
At the end of
the first quadmester.
The baby's too small now.
Fragile.
First quadmester?
Give me a drink!
Hey, princess, the nar's
in your stomach? Drad.
- What does it feel like?
- You tell me.
Hey!
Weeber eggs? I hate them.
Well, apparently babies
love them.
Actually, Rygel, what does
it really feel like?
Like having a parasite,
a large parasite
that's growing!
Okay, what did we do
to piss off the locals?
- They're paranoid.
- No, wrong, not paranoid.
I've been talking to many
of them.
Stark our ambassador?
No wonder they're avoiding us.
What's their problem then?
- Fear. Abject fear.
- Of what?
Their fear extends to the point
of not talking about their fear.
Perfect. Let's not exacerbated
it by staying any longer.
D'Argo, beyond that concealment
canopy is Armageddon.
Do we really wanna
fly into that right now?
I'll ask 'em if we can stay.
They're not gonna like it.
So what should we do
in the meantime?
We get married.
What?
Now.
You will make a beautiful bride.
I will see to it.
- Emperor Staleek.
- What is it?
We have received
a deep-space comm cipher.
- We receive tens of thousands...
- This is from a most unexpected source.
With a most
unexpected message.
It is about John Crichton.
The sender knows the Human's
current location.
An out-of-the-way water planet.
No defenses to speak of.
- Do the Peacekeepers have him?
- Not yet.
Your source, is it reliable?
At the moment,
impeccable.
Have a course plotted.
We will send
a full battle contingent.
A full contingent
for one man?
Not for the man.
For the knowledge
he possesses.
It's very generous
of you to do this for us.
It is the first time I have presided
over the union of soldiers.
We're not soldiers.
In fact, he's the only one
carrying a gun.
Either way, your petition to remain
among us is being denied.
On conclusion of your sermon,
you will all leave.
Right.
If you don't mind my asking,
who are you hiding from?
Everyone.
Aeryn's coming!
The bride! The bride!
Come on!
- Okay, are you relaxed?
- I am relaxed.
- I've heard the key is being relaxed.
- Stand here. Stand.
- What about me?
You're right here.
- Good.
- Okay, perfect.
What are you doing?
No, no!
Stark!
Oh, she looks so...
Beautiful.
You look great.
- You owe me.
- I know.
Is there a particular invocation
you would like me to use?
Yeah, um...
Dearly beloved.
"Dearly beloved. "
We are gathered here.
"We are gathered here. "
Beneath
this magnificent...
Command Carrier.
Peacekeepers.
Lies. All lies!
They seem to know
exactly where we are.
How, if the concealment
canopy is still in place?
They know because
we have been betrayed.
Stark, go with them.
Witchiepoo, you go as well.
- What should we do?
- Convince them it's not our fault!
Hide Rygel.
Guard it with your life.
It's not our fault.
We knew nothing about this.
Crichton will fix it.
- He'll fix it. I assure you.
- Come on, old woman.
Now, that's familiar.
Why do I know that?
Now!
Oh.
Eidelons.
Of course!
Eidelons!
Eidelons.
You're Eidelons.
Yes, we are.
You know who
it's gonna be, don't you?
I know who it is.
Come on, "D," bet me.
How much?
You're on your own,
my friend.
Hello, John.
Easy money.
Apologies if this is
a bad time,
but I believe
we need to talk.
How did you find me?
Harvey?
- I would prefer to be called Albert.
- No.
Invisible sidekicks that only
I talk to get called Harvey.
How the hell
did Scorpius find me?
Scorpius is like God.
He does not play dice
with the universe.
He has a great plan, John.
But his mysteries
unfold slowly.
Perhaps they
will be answered
when the proper tribute
is provided to him.
The wormhole!
Or in your case,
the wormhole weapon!
Listen up, Strangelove,
I can find wormholes,
sense when they will open.
Push comes to shove,
I can even navigate one.
But I cannot make
a wormhole weapon!
That is true, John. But you do know
where to obtain the knowledge.
It does not take an Einstein
to figure that out, huh?
Make sure he gets
that message.
So how have you been,
Crichton?
- I'm good, Bob. You? The wife? The kids?
- Busy.
Yeah. I hear
business is booming.
You're right. The Scarrans
and Peacekeepers are at war.
And the Scarrans will prevail
unless you help us build
a wormhole weapon.
Gee, that all sounds
reasonable, Bob.
Only two problems. No matter
what you may believe, I can't do it.
Just as important, I don't think Peacekeepers
are any better than the Scarrans.
So make sure you validate
your parking... on the way out.
You will find no serenity
during this conflict, Crichton.
Examine your choices.
You are not listening.
Wormholes, no! Weapons, no!
Killing, no.
Crichton, no.
You want to see it?
The thing you've been chasing
my ass all over the universe for.
Torturing me, my wife,
my friends for.
- You wanna see it?
- Yes.
- Say please.
- Please.
- Pretty please.
- With a cherry on top.
Happy birthday.
Now get out of my sight.
D'Argo, D'Argo, a miracle!
Eidelons, Jool, Arnessk, peace!
Okay, what's
he talking about?
Eidelons, Jool, Arnessk,
peace!
Thank you.
Please.
We are the last Eidelons.
- All others hunted to extinction.
- Hunted?
Our ancestors possessed
the means to influence peace.
A gift that sadly has
not survived to our generation.
I'm familiar
with the history.
Then you would also know
that 12,000 cycles ago
their great temple
was destroyed,
the conciliators
were murdered,
and all outposts
of our species, slaughtered.
Arnessk was the center
of our spiritual power.
The sight of the long-lost
great temple,
upon which this very edifice
is modeled.
However, today, Arnessk
is a barren and lifeless world.
Perhaps not.
We've been there.
These images are part of a data
upload transmitted by Jool
before we left her on Arnessk.
I have more in the archives
if you require.
Undoubtedly you will recall...
Except not you
because you weren't there.
It was right after Crichton realized
that he loved you more than anything.
- And you were as frizbot as a...
- Shh.
Hmm? Oh! Arnessk.
These ancient Eidelons were not
long dead as everyone assumed.
Just suspended in time
for 12,000 cycles.
When we reversed the device
that was holding them,
back they came into existence.
Right after I went swimming
with the creature from the black lagoon.
That sounds exciting.
There is no doubt that today's
Eidelons are a direct descendent
of the ancient peacemaking
Eidelons of Arnessk.
And?
They have a unique ability
tied to their physiology.
Which is latent
in our host Eidelons.
Why can't their ancestors
reignite that ability?
Thus recreating the greatest
peacemaking race in history!
Am I going insane or is the crazy lady
starting to make sense?
- Yes. But I thought we were finished.
- So did I.
What happened to
"run first, no questions later"?
Scorpius. We wake up and he finds us
before we have our first cup of coffee.
- This is not our fight.
- I agree.
But as long as there's a war on,
everyone's after me
'cause I'm the
winner-take-all weapon guy.
- Every time we get involved...
I know. People die.
We out of options?
This Eidelon
education program.
- What are the odds it'll work?
- Not good.
Not good is the best odds
we ever get.
The most exciting aspect
is the possibility
of learning how to influence
peace in others.
Noble aspiration,
High Priestess.
We have discussed it
amongst ourselves,
and would be most appreciative
if you would transport
Pikal and Caa'ta to Arnessk
for an introductory delegation.
- But we can take many more.
- As I have repeatedly said...
Centuries of hiding do not
melt away suddenly, Pikal.
We remain skeptical
about your motives.
And that's just on our side.
I know a little something
of the Leviathans
and their symbiotic Pilots.
Peaceful to a fault,
if I recall.
To Moya or myself,
violence is less than an option.
Then I have a simple query.
These beings that you ferry,
do you trust them?
Implicitly.
Then I entrust Caa'ta
and Pikal to your care.
Tissue transferal conductor.
The doc hasn't got
all the bits,
but you'll probably find everything
you need up on your ship.
And the doctor will give you
detailed instructions.
That's unacceptable.
He's coming with us.
No, I'm sorry. The doctor and I do not
travel into Peacekeeper territory.
We have some previous issues
with them.
Aeryn, this is a relatively
simple procedure.
My baby is in a Hynerian.
It's nowhere near simple.
Of course it is.
This part attaches to Rygel,
the other part to you.
Before you know it,
the baby's transferred.
So elegantly designed.
Anyone can use it. Good luck.
- What? Where are you going?
- Not with you.
Why not?
These Eidelons have just
absorbed a thunderbolt revelation.
I know more about their
ancient culture than they do.
They can benefit from my
instructions until you return.
Can I do it myself?
No.
Right.
What the hell
is he doing here?
- We were invited.
- Just stay there.
I've thought this through.
We need him.
I don't like it.
Well, blame me.
I do blame you.
I don't like it!
I don't like it either.
But we are currently flying
through Peacekeeper
controlled space during a war
and he is a
Command Carrier officer.
Actually my most recent commission
was commander of
a full Peacekeeper armada.
Uh-huh. Among other things!
He knows all the current
pass codes.
I'll keep him away.
I hope so.
Oh, Aeryn, Rygel,
off-limits.
- Good morning, Commander.
- Morning, Pilot.
Moya looks beautiful.
How much did you miss us?
We have received a message that appears
to have been hailing for some time.
First Arnessk.
I have enough of a fix
that we can begin our journey.
I will find the exact location from
Moya's data banks as we grow closer.
Excellent, Pilot.
Proceed.
- Their message?
- Sure, Pilot. Who is it?
Apparently the
Royal Palace of Hyneria
coming from someone
named Bishaan.
What is really
happening there, Bishaan?
It is this damned war.
The Scarrans have already taken our
outer territories. Millions are dead.
You are a direct descendent
of the royal lineage.
If our people will unite under
anyone, it will be under you.
Cousin Rygel, you are welcome
to return to Hyneria.
You must return
If Bishaan thinks
I'll return to a shared throne,
he is beyond diluted.
Ow!
You're not going anywhere.
You rest.
Some mother
you're going to make.
Ship-wide announcement
for our new guests.
Prepare for starburst,
people.
- Chiana, Chiana!
- In here.
Blessed Eidelon, may
I enter the room and...
Enough!
What is it exactly
about these guys
that makes you
so faasbotten?
Are you serious? The Eidelons
are remarkable negotiators.
The Scarrans aren't
gonna be reasoned with.
But they will if...
If what?
Frell...
- Is he propositioning me?
- No.
That's a very special gland.
Smart.
- In a weird place.
- It's an antenna to feelings.
An inner eye.
Am I right, Pikal?
Yes. And our history
leads us to believe
substantially more.
It gets bigger?
Not that we know.
However, it vibrates.
We used to be able
to create an energy field
that had a calming effect
on individuals,
allowing them to see reason.
Yeah, but your
little, limp thing.
It can't do
the trick anymore.
Unfortunately not.
We've really
gotta get married.
Now.
She has a good strong kick.
Perhaps to remind you that you're
needed on the command deck.
There is nothing to be done
at the moment.
You know the situation.
Situations change.
We are outnumbered,
out-gunned,
and our populace has grown
averse to hardship.
What are you trying
to say?
More to the point,
what are you not saying?
We have now lost every single battle
since the start of the war.
I seek your opinion
on a truce.
The Scarrans will accept
no truce.
Only surrender.
A surrender then.
When all is lost... only.
What are the signs,
my dear Grayza,
that all is lost?
A military leader
who broaches surrender.
Crichton has departed
the water planet.
My contact has provided
approximate coordinates to his destination.
Fearful flight
or purposeful journey?
He seeks the means
to end this conflict.
- Wormhole weapon.
- Unknown.
Though he does now have
a traveling companion.
- Scorpius.
- How well do they guard Crichton?
The Leviathan travels
unescorted.
Though Peacekeepers now
protect the water planet,
they have left.
Order the remainder
of our battle contingent
to engage the enemy there.
Defeat them.
Then subdue the inhabitants.
And this Decimator?
To follow Crichton,
and settle old scores.
Any good vibes
from the Eidelons yet?
Caa'ta is suspicious.
Imagine finding out your 12,000-cycle
old relatives are still alive.
I once thought
my Aunt Ruth was dead.
You can't believe the stuff
we found in her closet.
- Do you think they can do it?
- I don't know.
Think the Eidelons
can stop this war?
If they can't,
we get to find another galaxy
to live in.
John, between you and me.
- If this doesn't work, can you...
- No, I can't.
Ohhh, by Hedsmana's sight,
why me?
You're a Dominar.
It has to count for something.
Carry their baby.
Marry them off.
What next?
Let them move in?
What?
Forget about it.
This is all wrong.
Stop! You are ruining
my wedding.
Honey?
- What?
- You're pointing a gun at the baby.
I've traveled with the two
of you for quite a while now.
Known you
since you first met.
Over the cycles,
there were times
when it looked like you were
gonna kill each other.
Other times we couldn't
have got you off each other
with a fire hose!
Sounds like a marriage
to me.
So,
upon my pronouncement,
may these two
be joined as one
and evermore
let nothing come be...
No!
Pilot!
What the hell is that?
We're under attack
by Tregans!
You, hide.
Reporting multiple
harpoon strikes.
Each with
a hauling line attached.
- Can Moya free herself?
- There are too many!
The Tregan ship
is already pulling us in.
We're still in Peacekeeper territory.
Most likely they're mercenaries.
- What does that mean for us?
- They're probably less likely to take prisoners.
I've counted at least seven
two-man craft coming towards us.
They'll attempt
to incapacitate Pilot
and cripple Moya's
vital systems.
One way or another, this will
all be over in half an hour.
- These guys work for the Peacekeepers?
- Quite likely.
Right. You're with me.
I wanna hear those pass codes.
If the Dark Lord here can't convince
them we're a Peacekeeper vessel,
make sure you have
an outstanding plan "B."
We'll protect
neurocluster.
Chiana, Sikozu, go
find Caa'ta and Pikal
and keep them safe.
- What about me?
- How best can you help?
- I can stay out of your way.
- Excellent.
This may not go
as smoothly as you'd hoped.
What? You don't do improv?
When I received the signal
you were still alive,
my departure from Peacekeeper
service was less than sanctioned.
Meaning what?
You there, hold position.
We're about to find out.
Do you know who I am?
Scorpius.
I take it, you are sentries
for this sector, yes?
I wasn't informed
you were out here, sir.
Nor do you know it now,
lest it cost you your life.
In special service
to the Grand Chancellor,
I order you to release
and vacate this ship.
That won't happen.
And you are?
Chief of my vessel.
Our orders are
to commandeer any ship
not broadcasting
a Peacekeeper ident.
My mission would be jeopardized
by advertising such a beacon.
Your mission is more
than jeopardized.
It is over!
Who is in charge here?
Whom should I be addressing?
And who is going to take
the blame?
Chief, release the harpoons.
On Scorpius' authority.
Your command code, sir.
767 decahelot.
Scorpius, it is an honor
to meet you face-to-face.
That's a damn nice set
of body armor.
Does that come in blue?
What the hell did you do
when you left the fatherland?
- Kill the goose that lays the golden egg?
- Deserted my post.
What? For little ol' me?
It's amazing what a man will do
when he's in love.
Pilot, anything
you can do to help?
- Not without killing you also.
- Hold that thought and be ready to duck.
- Who's taking fire?
- Who isn't?
You all right?
Other than being shot at by the
Electric Mayhem, I'm fantastic!
You must stay hidden.
And you?
Your sensitivity is
of much more value
when we are meeting
our ancestors.
It is my function
to assure your safe arrival.
- But...
- There is no time to argue.
Three of them
heading parallel to us.
You can see that?
I can with my new eyes.
Two.
Son of a bitch!
- Pilot, stay down!
- I can't!
We have to get outta here
before Pilot gets shot.
What we need is
the release transmitter.
- Where is that?
- Over there with the head Treg.
Fine. Surrender or die!
You enjoy this,
don't you, Crichton?
You know this species?
Then dead is okay.
You never struck me as the type
who would want children.
You either, huh?
He wants it so badly.
So I do.
You'll come around when you see the little guy
in person.
I hope so.
All right, lover boy,
get ready to cover me.
Are you having fun yet, John?
You call that covering fire?
No more Tregans aboard.
That's good news, Pilot.
However, they're
still reeling us in.
- Because we can't release the harpoons.
- Why not?
'Cause somebody sent
the transmitter down the abyss.
This transmitter,
what does it look like?
A star-shaped medallion.
- Pilot?
- All lines disengaged.
We're free!
Ooh! Guess they figured out
their captain's dead.
Rygel?
Pilot, can Moya starburst?
She will try.
That's our girl.
This is not good.
Rygel? Rygel?
Don't get your knickers
in a twist.
The baby is all right.
I'm terribly upset
I failed to detect the Tregans.
1812, pipe down.
I was so preoccupied with other
duties, they snuck up on us.
That's all right, Pilot. You're a few
thousand mistakes behind the rest of us.
Hey, Pilot, how much is this gonna
slow us down getting to Arnessk?
The answer, Commander,
is not at all.
Excellent.
Okay, I'm lost.
Not lost.
- Your business?
- Hiya, Jool.
- You.
- Me.
- Crichton. You?
- Crichton.
- You are crazy.
- I knew you wouldn't forget me.
The more we were apart,
the more I knew you'd realize
that you are meant
to be with...
Aeryn.
- Jool.
- Get your own fantasy, they're having my baby.
Baby?
And it goes without saying
you show deference and respect.
- Absolutely.
- Please, don't embarrass me.
Excellent acoustics,
are they not?
Perhaps you'd care
to lead us in prayer.
Apologies, Hierarch Yondalao.
I was explaining to them...
So you are the pilgrims
who purport to be our heirs?
Not us. Just him. Go.
We understood all
of our descendants to be gone.
Though we trace ourselves
to your lineage, my people
have lost the ability, but not
the desire to influence peace.
Troubling.
And exhilarating.
I shall confer
with the other conciliators
and notify you
when the matter can be assessed.
I told you this was
a waste of time.
Myths are rarely satisfying
upon examination.
Hierarch, please.
You know me.
I know these travelers.
They are honorable.
Why do you send them away?
I do not. I simply require time
to examine the issue.
But, but with great respect.
What is there to examine?
Pikal is an Eidelon
like you.
We have awakened
from 12,000 cycles of sleep.
What pertinence can we have
to your galaxy now?
But the war.
The deaths, the slaughters!
Peacekeepers, do your duty!
The horror!
Sit.
May I speak?
The Peacekeeper
shall be heard.
We apologize for invading
your sanctuary.
And we understand
you have reason for caution.
But what could be
more pertinent in this time,
or any, than the ability
to inspire peace?
Even if he's Eidelon,
how can this one supplicant
help that cause?
You are few here,
and Pikal's people are many.
With your instruction,
they could become
a great force for peace.
Though the Peacekeeper
provides sound counsel,
I still sustain reservations
that must be meditated upon.
Peacekeepers, clear the temple.
Can you believe this?
Somebody wants us
to be Peacekeepers.
Are you assassin?
No! I'm just the guy
without a brain.
The Lion here would like
some courage.
Tin Man, he needs a heart.
Toto here just wants an easy birth.
And Dorothy here, she is
just looking for a way home.
Now we're not gonna be here
tomorrow so I suggest
you take a long hard look
at our broomstick.
He is your heir!
An Eidelon.
As youths, we open our faces
to the universe,
absorbing the joy and anguish
all creatures feel.
Then upon maturation,
we step to the altar
to receive Hora Dalay:
The ability to encourage
rationality
and tranquility
in others.
The capacity to influence
others toward peace
carries great
responsibility.
Do you accept this burden
for the rest of your days?
It's going to work.
With training,
Pikal and his kind,
should be able to stop the war.
- No wormholes.
- Exactly what I was thinking, John Crichton.
Can we go back to Moya now?
I'm starving.
In a microt. Go and get Stark.
- Is it just me or is he getting bigger?
- It's a geometric pregnancy.
Please tell me that means we're
gonna have a mathematician.
A soldier more likely.
But we will be having it
sooner than you think.
How sooner?
With genetic modifications
put into someone born into
a battle unit like myself,
essentially we're going
to be parents
in a matter of solar days.
Days?
- We don't have a name.
- Already picked one.
Well, what?
- Excuse me?
- Do you not like it?
Uh, boy or girl?
Either.
It works for both.
You just made a joke.
Soldiers don't have
a sense of humor, John.
You better have my dinner ready
when I get back on that ship now.
Is there nothing
they can do?
Then order retreat
from Alentro Quadrant.
Have Commander Spreddic
regroup
in defense of our nearest outposts.
Sir, how have the Scarrans
moved so quickly
through our
forward positions?
Because they have been planning this for
many cycles,
Lieutenant.
And you have a design
to turn it around?
Of course.
In due time.
Thank you for
your assistance, Aeryn.
Independent verification
of hull integrity is
invaluable to Moya and me.
- It's the least I could do.
- If you'll close the thermal-imaging ports,
I'll begin cycling
to numistatic distance
calibration, completing
our harpoon repairs.
Back so soon?
Why don't you tell Scorpius
that continuously asking me
will not change my opinion?
Peace is still a better option
than trying to build
a wormhole weapon.
Not spoken like
a true soldier.
Depends on your definition.
With all due respect,
Crichton is your inferior.
So why would you bear
his child?
You should leave, Sikozu.
And I mean off this ship.
I did not mean to offend.
When I first met Scorpius,
I naturally assumed
I was his superior.
I have since learned there is
a reservoir to his abilities
that continually
overshadows my own.
Same with Crichton.
You view Crichton
as your superior?
No, as my equal.
Sikozu, perhaps your under
and over estimations
of yourself are meaningless.
Perhaps you're just meant
to be together.
Interesting these Eidelons.
Yep. Tell me
about it, Bob.
Despite the fable
around them,
these Eidelons
can only affect peace
when the combatants are willing
to let them get near them.
Am I detecting a little
professional jealousy?
The Scarrans for certain
will destroy these Peacemakers
long before they can get
close enough to have any impact.
Great! Then you won't mind
them doing their thing.
Fine! But do yours
at the same time.
Me making weapons
is just a means
to your ends.
God! What is it
you really want, Scorpius?
Privacy achieved during peace
will always be challenged.
However, if ascended
during conflict,
it can last a lifetime.
You wanna say that
in English?
We've been hit.
I have a highly-developed
survival sense.
It's telling me to leave.
John, it's a Scarran warship
closing in on the planet
at maximum speed.
Stryker or Dreadnaught?
Neither. Something new
and much faster.
How much time we got?
More like how little.
D'Argo!
I'm on my way
to get you now.
Hey, where the hell
do you think you're going?
To remove as much of
our presence as possible.
The Scarrans will be hard enough
on these Eidelons as it is.
Don't worry about it.
We're taking them with us.
- Everyone has to go.
- That is impossible.
Jool, will you explain
to him what is going on?
- He knows.
- Hierarch, listen.
These are not chirpy Saturday
morning Sleestaks coming.
The decision has been made.
The big hand says
I don't have time to argue.
And the little hand says,
Pikal, it is time to go.
He is not yet prepared
to instruct others.
His education must continue.
We came here because
we need conciliators.
There is an entire planet
of his people waiting.
How the hell are we supposed
to bring them up to speed?
I will instruct them.
Fine. Fine.
Jool, you should come
as well.
I can't.
I belong here.
Go.
You always made
the best mistakes.
This is not good.
No dren!
This frelling thing is supposed
to get the baby out of me.
I don't think so.
- Not you, them!
- Who them? What?
You wanna worry about someone?
Worry about me.
The Eidelons.
What about them?
Their good give in peace.
Their good sleep in peace.
Their good die in peace!
- Why aren't we moving?
- Ask Pilot.
The Scarrans are close enough
to have targeted us.
Initiate starburst.
Moya refuses. Before she has time
to fully power up, we will be hit.
Any ideas for a diversion?
Scarran vessel.
The inhabitants of Arnessk are peaceful.
We have no weapons and pose no threat.
Do you wish to land?
- What are they doing?
- Deciding how savage they want to be.
- Okay, come on.
- You'll be safe in here.
- Pilot, we can't just sit here.
- Moya's got to take the risk. Pilot?
At this range?
It's suicide!
Scarran vessel, please respond.
Bad feeling.
Jool, can you hear us?
Get away from the temple.
Now, Jool!
The Scarrans have fired.
- Evasive!
- No time!
Son of a bitch. Not us.
Jool!
Crew of Leviathan, you must
immediately abandon ship
and surrender to
the Scarran Imperial Forces.
Noncompliance with this command
will result
in the immediate
annihilation of your ship.
- Repeat, noncompliance with this command
- We're cursed.
Will result in the immediate
annihilation of your ship.
Everything we touch.
Prepare for
emergency starburst!
- Crew of Leviathan...
- Shouldn't I stay here?
If anyone stays behind the
Scarrans will destroy Moya. Come on!
But I'm pregnant!
Let's do it.
I cross-connected the power drive and the
fuel system so we can detonate ourselves
should we choose.
Comforting.
"D," last chance to bail.
I'm fairly certain they can't
pierce Moya's invisibility shield.
But you give us the signal,
we'll be there.
We hope.
Good fortune.
Now, get out of the way.
Well, when this idiot plan dies,
I would say
I am the first one
you rescue.
Ask Aeryn.
Rescue Yondalao first.
Isn't he supposed
to be rescuing us?
Yeah, how about that?
We stride onto the ship
and you convince the Scarrans
to smoke the peace pipe.
They are a species
unfamiliar to me.
I must first sense their fears
and desires through proximity.
You're about to get all the proximity you
can handle. Scarran vessels straight ahead.
Probe the Leviathan.
If you discover any life
other than its pilot,
annihilate the vessel.
Oh, I must've
overlooked this.
Sorry.
- You lived among the Scarrans.
- Most of my life.
Assisted their dying rituals.
Passage to the other side.
- Then you know their psyche.
- As much as possible.
Assist me
with that knowledge.
Welcome to my flagship.
That was a temple
you nuked down there.
An act of precaution.
Requisite in times of war.
As is truth-seeking.
The Luxan and Nebari
who are traveling with you?
Gone... a short while
before we came.
Strange. I always assumed
His Highness was male.
A tumor. Not long to live.
I would agree.
Take the Hynerian
to separate barracks.
Stop it. Let go of me!
I find it troubling that Humans
and Sebaceans can propagate together,
and intriguing.
How could you know that he
was pregnant with their child?
The same way I knew
to find you here.
- A traitor.
- But who?
Grunschlk.
Ah, they say one traitor
can always
recognize another.
If you hadn't facilitated
Crichton's earlier escape,
there would be peace now.
With you the Supreme Ruler?
A position I know
you dream of, Scorpius.
You, John Crichton, are alive
for one reason only.
I will have the
wormhole technology you possess.
If not, War Minister Ahkna
will pleasure herself
torturing the Hynerian
and the abomination
in his belly.
You have one arn to decide.
Here, here.
Options?
It's not ready.
They have Rygel and the sand is
trickling though the hourglass.
- We can't give them wormhole weapons.
- They don't know that.
And I can give them
the middle finger.
You don't know
what you're doing.
I never do.
You, give them nothing!
Let's make a deal.
One power source.
Two compartments,
forward and last.
More intense,
and smaller.
And here.
That's it.
Excellent.
I'll be able to stop 'em cold
with three perfect shots.
Why three? You usually
slay me with just one.
Rygel's invited us
to Hyneria.
Thought I could do
some work with my hands.
Plant some food,
make some wine.
Oh.
Hey, Godzilla,
let's get this over with.
- You have something to give me?
- Yeah.
I got something you don't
get very often. The truth.
- I can't give you wormhole weapons.
- Then you will die.
You're asking for a kilo of pure
wormhole technology which I don't have!
But I can take you
to a guy that does.
In exchange,
you give me Rygel.
Undamaged, free and clear.
Give me the coordinates!
It doesn't work like that.
You are immune to the probing.
'Cause I always speak the truth.
Okay, here's how it works.
We go in my module
down a wormhole to the
source of ultimate power.
It's a two-seater.
Me and one other.
It's the only safe way
to get there.
The emperor will never go alone
with you in your craft!
I will accompany him.
Yes, always good to see who wears
the britches in a relationship.
No!
Set a course to rejoin the battle group
at the water planet.
We shall leave
as soon as I return.
It's a question of balls.
The ball's in his court.
How would they react?
I see. If faced
with such a moral choice,
the Scarrans would still choose
to slaughter innocents.
A conundrum: How to tap into
their morality. I must think.
- Is there progress?
- A great deal.
- I will soon be able to influence their passions.
- Excellent.
In the temple, you said,
"Peacekeepers, do your duty. "
What did you mean?
I had forgotten
that you had forgotten.
At the dawn of our period of usefulness,
27,000 cycles ago,
we developed need of a guard,
a race no one had quarrel with.
A force to insure
harmony prevailed
once negotiations
had finished.
Peacekeepers.
Apparently your forebears
attempted to carry on
once we vanished.
However, lacking
our mediation abilities,
they kept peace
the only way they could:
At the muzzle of a weapon.
And that's why
they're hated.
It wasn't such
at the beginning.
We took great care to choose
a species no one had met before.
We found your kind primitive,
barely clothed.
Far removed on
the galaxy's outer spiral.
Having brought some
of you back,
your evolution was accelerated
with generous alterations
until you became
our trusted acolytes.
The emperor wants
this one maintained.
However, I would consider it
a personal favor
should he die
of explainable causes.
I grow weary.
We'll stop for coffee
on the way back.
There is a problem?
Take your hand off me.
You know what
you have to do, John.
Yeah, I know exactly
what I have to do.
Just crash the module.
No more Staleek.
No more Crichton.
No more Aeryn.
No more anyone.
Do you think War Minister Psycho-Drama's
gonna be a kindler, gentler soul?
Somebody else's problem.
But you would've done your duty.
Get your hand off me.
Please take your hand off me.
We shall return to my ship.
There is no wormhole here.
We're catching the 7:15 to Enlightenment.
It's just a little late.
I have been informed
you plot escape.
- We are prisoners with no weapons.
- None here.
But perhaps out there.
I promise you. You will never
be reunited with your baby.
I'm sure your mother wished
the same thing.
How brave you are.
Ordinance Officer, fire!
Fire!
- D'Argo!
- They know where we are!
Fire!
You can stop now.
You've proved your point.
The Luxans are
like Peacekeepers.
Soon to be enslaved or dead.
Fire.
You...
Enshrine their souls,
end their suffering
and guide the passage
of D'Argo and Chiana
to their place of rest.
Cannot a Luxan survive
in space?
Quarter arn.
Maybe a little longer.
Scarran brutality
surprises me.
They will be difficult
to influence.
The Scarran blood
that runs through my veins
knows more than
you'll ever know.
The first scent of interference,
you'll be as dead as D'Argo.
And then the...
There is only one path
out of this prison.
We must fight our way out!
Bingo.
This is the source
of your knowledge?
That and the back
of cereal boxes.
Cinch up your diaper, big boy.
The first time is
always the worst.
This is normal?
No. The module's overweighted.
We got a big bubba in 2-B.
Last chance, John. Veer into
the wall of the wormhole.
It'll be over fast.
Nope. Child's gonna have
a father.
I hope it's a boy.
Boy, girl, either is fine.
Buckle up.
Check it out. I'm Rudolph
the Red-nosed Reindeer.
You have violated
our trust.
He has my family.
Unimportant
to the greater agenda.
They are my greater agenda.
- Why have you brought him here?
- Who is this creature?
You can call him Einstein.
I suggest you do it nicely.
Staleek!
Staleek, he can wrap time
round his little finger.
The whoo-doo voodoo
is not gonna work.
Einstein, do you possess
the knowledge of wormholes?
Yes.
Can these wormholes
be made into weapons?
Yes.
- Then you will give me that power!
- No.
Hang on. I can find a wormhole,
and fly down one.
Right?
With the rudimentary knowledge
we have given you.
Can I make a weapon?
You cannot.
Why not?
Because no one
should have that power.
Exactly!
Listen up.
This is your universe.
This is your universe
on wormholes.
You mess with the natural order,
you destroy multiple time lines.
I will have that power!
Humbling, ain't it?
Returning here was wrong.
I have to protect
the people I love.
And you owe me for putting
that crap in my head.
It may soon be prudent
to remove it.
Amen. I wanna be
blond again.
You truly cannot create
wormhole weapons.
We should get back
before Rygel damages your wife.
Absolutely not.
Our best opportunity
is when or if
Crichton walks through those doors,
we must try to escape!
Not without my child.
A disagreement past
its time.
- You should be dead.
- And how was your day?
I saw a wreckage
on the way in.
They killed Chiana
and D'Argo.
Is Yondalao good to go?
Apparently not.
Well, Staleek's
gonna give us Rygel.
You've traded ultimate power
for an unborn offspring.
No. I gave it to him.
You know why?
Because he's such a nice guy!
But the funny thing is
I don't have anything to give.
So, Chiana and D'Argo,
me being chased around
the galaxy for years,
everything,
it's all for nothing.
Your ranting aside,
we still have no way out.
I wouldn't be so sure.
You have to do something.
Time to transfer the baby.
When I am ordered.
However, I can
give you something
to eliminate the pain completely.
Oh, that would be great. Hurry!
Aah!
Whose orders override mine?
War Minister Ahkna.
I had no choice.
You will die
when I order it.
Okay.
If I knew my word
was useless...
The Luxan stealth craft,
I discovered and destroyed.
The presence of Scorpius who
has already betrayed you once,
and the constant ability of these
creatures to plague us with resistance.
Add these up, and they should
die for our own security.
Scorpius is a commander
in our enemy's armada.
Officer Sun
a former pilot.
Who knows what information
may be coerced from them!
- It's not worth the risk.
- Stop seeing Vitubian vipers in every shadow.
And never countermand
my orders again!
Here, have him!
Did they do anything
to you?
No.
This maintains my portion
of the accord.
Beyond this,
I promise nothing.
With deference,
Your Eminence.
- Who are you?
- Hierarch Yondalao.
Triumvirate Council.
Eidelon faction
of neutrality.
There is no such thing
as neutrality.
You travel with my prisoners,
you are a prisoner.
Emperor Staleek,
you wish power,
acknowledgement of
your personal intelligence,
and to gain acceptance
in the upper echelon
of civilizations.
What do you know of my aims?
Only that there are many
paths to accomplish them.
War is our path.
At the peace table,
we know how we're viewed:
Brutish, ignorant.
Then what greater victory
than to prove them wrong?
And without the loss
of a single Scarran...
life.
I am listening.
Now you will tell me this one
Human holds such fascination
that Scorpius would desert,
the Scarran emperor
would pursue.
And we would all tremble at the
power of his magical wormholes.
Did you not tell me
Crichton was powerless?
His doomsday weapon
a myth?
That was my belief.
This moment, however,
is not without opportunity.
Agreed.
Knowing the emperor's
whereabouts
allows us to negotiate
a peace proposal
before our position
becomes so eroded
as to be laughable.
Yes, my love.
Of course.
It also gives us the opportunity
to surprise the Scarran leader
and decapitate his empire.
The sudden chaos in their ranks
might tip the balance.
And if that fails?
No, I will not be remembered
by history
as the commander under whom
Peacekeeperdom fell.
No, my love.
You will not.
Because despite your station,
you are weak.
I say again that which
I have said before.
Death is preferable to subjugation
under Scarran rule.
They must be defeated.
How?
Chiana.
Father.
Not quite the
Luxan greeting, but...
- What are you doing here?
- Right now?
Saving your life.
Thanks.
Jothee, shouldn't we
be running?
Our concealment technology is
three generations beyond yours.
We could pull up beside 'em and
they wouldn't know we're here.
So, you're in command now.
- He's a cleaver.
- Cleaver?
- Field officer.
- Which means he's got brains.
The rest of us
just like to fight.
What are you doing here?
We've been following
the emperor for quite some time.
And then, there you were.
We gotta take
the crown head out,
but his ship
is pretty well impenetrable.
One would think.
Is this accurate?
Looks like we could
take him out in four shots.
Three.
Yes, that sounds
quite reasonable.
Absolutely. We're walking
into Federationville here.
You cross the T's.
You dot the lower case J's,
and we're good to go.
Emperor,
could you review the accord
- that you wish all of us to agree to?
- Of course.
At the core of
the matter is the perception
that Crichton can create
wormhole weapons.
If I propose an armistice
to the Peacekeepers
with Crichton by my side,
they will naturally assume
he has bestowed a military edge
upon the Scarran Empire.
The Grand Chancellor
is no gambler.
He would indeed
choose peace over a war
he knows he would lose.
Being benevolent,
I will then propose an accord
which favors us in mining rights
and trade balance, whilst
allowing complete self-rule
of all Peacekeeper territories.
And I'm out, right?
You shall be released
upon the signing.
And a great many lives will be
saved by everybody sim...
Do you really wish
to broker peace with an enemy
you are certain to destroy?
What is this?
It is the proper course
of action.
If your kind has a prayer
for the dying,
fill your mind with it now
that you may be comforted.
He's passing over.
The secret of peace is lost.
It's not good.
Stark, give him last rites.
Oh, I cannot.
I'm beneath him.
Astro Boy, you can take his power,
protect his gift.
Oh, no, I cannot.
Stark, you can!
You're a Stykara.
I've seen you do amazing things.
When you pass someone over,
you take what they know.
- Help him help us.
- Quickly before he dies.
No, I cannot!
Aeryn, help me!
No, no!
My mask!
Don't touch me!
- What have we done?
- I don't know.
Something good
or something very bad.
Hey, hey.
We're gonna have to
transfer the baby now.
Now?
- Can you remember what to do?
- I think so.
- You stay with him. Where's the transfer kit?
- Over there.
- Where?
- There!
- It's gas.
- What?
- You gotta be kiddin' me!
- They're entombing us.
Saleek, this is very unoriginal.
What does this do?
- Paralytic embalming agent.
- Stark.
Preserves living tissue
without harming the brain.
Scarrans use it on specimens
they wish to dissect
whilst they're still alive.
Stay with me.
Breathe, Rygel, breathe.
- You've ruined my life.
- I know.
This war is not your responsibility.
How am I supposed to protect you
from the Peacekeepers
and the Scarrans and the Tregans
and the lions and tigers and bears?
This is what you want.
No, Aeryn, it is not
what I want!
It's just that fate keeps
blocking all the exits.
And no matter what I do,
I just keep circling
closer to the flame.
Breathe, Rygel, breathe.
- Rygel?
- Rygel!
He's unconscious. I'm gonna have to
get him up, get him outta this gas.
Gas. Is this stuff
flammable?
Preservatives?
Combustible.
At a very high temperature.
- You can ignite it?
- The gas is smothering my receptors.
Come on, we're gonna get you
to higher ground.
On my count.
One, two, three!
So basically you're going
to blow us up.
Whoa! Whoa!
I can direct it. Find cover.
- What was that explosion?
- Internal. Level 21.
Insurgency teams to containment
quarters. All teams, now!
- Explosion at mid ship on the Decimator.
- Crichton.
- Those are not internal.
- All systems off-line.
Stark, weapons.
We all need weapons.
Feel like killing someone?
Okay, maybe not.
We need more than weapons.
We need a plan.
- We have to transfer the baby.
- Now?
His pulse is slowing.
He's dying.
Okay, okay.
John, Aeryn, are you there?
I'm hearing dead people.
"D," how are you alive?
Long story.
Can I give you a ride?
- Absolutely. In what?
- It's gonna be a big surprise.
You stay put. We got a fix
on you. We'll come to you.
You heard him.
This is the Alamo.
Brace.
Go!
Chiana, call Peacekeeper Command,
confirm our coordinates.
Go!
Good luck.
Luxan commandoes
confirmed aboard, sir.
Secure my ship!
Aeryn, we gotta hurry.
I'm losing a pulse here.
- Here they come!
- Ready when you are.
Man, am I glad
you're not awake for this.
All right. You might feel
a little pressure.
Hold still. Hold still!
- War Minister Ahkna, report.
- Positioning to cut them off now!
I'm really sorry
about this, baby.
Just get it right
the first time.
- Nobody gets it right the first time.
- Wait!
Are you okay?
I'm pregnant.
- I'm running out of ammunition.
- As me.
- Well done.
- Thank you.
Rygel, you all right?
Thank you.
- He's out again.
- What is this?
Whatever you put in
my head is gonna explode!
You're not gonna be the only thing around here
exploding if D'Argo doesn't show up.
Stop acting like a bunch
of losers and look down!
Hey, the cavalry's here.
Okay, stand back.
It's no good.
We can't get through.
It's Dorian ore.
It's pulse resistant.
How are we supposed
to get to you?
I don't know. All the lifts are sealed.
We better make it quick.
Our surprise is wearing off.
Stand aside!
Get back!
All right,
ladies and children first.
You look great.
- I'm pregnant again.
- Congratulations.
Don't you touch me!
Catch!
Feel free to stay and cover our retreat.
Holy crap!
It's good to see you, Jothee.
Yeah, who'd have guessed?
Good to see you too.
We done?
Quick! Go, go, go, go!
Get out! Go!
Get outta here! Move, move!
Damage repair immediately.
The Peacekeeper armada
is sure to be on its way.
And we are sitting fodder! Move!
Coming through!
Here.
Go, get in!
You guys are a mess.
Everybody hang the frell on!
You've grown, dude.
Yeah? Well, it's the armor.
I'll take over, Sergeant.
You take care of the engine.
Sir.
So was this
a planned reunion?
You got any backup
out there?
Well, they can't maneuver
or fire so we're good to go.
Nice work, Cleaver.
Yeah. Well, the old man
had a lot to do with it.
Peacekeeper armada confirmed
on scanned perimeter.
Tell me.
When will we stop
following this Human
and start imposing
our agenda on him?
We already have.
Crichton insists he will
not build a wormhole weapon.
He insists he can't.
Human insistence.
Nothing more than a futile attempt
to avoid action they insist
they will never take!
He will help us?
Never.
But he will help Aeryn
and his new child.
Luxan penetrator out and away.
See you back in Kajargan.
- Safe journey. Can I speak to Jothee?
- Sure.
You need a guide to get through
Peacekeeper-controlled space.
Chiana was the first person
since your mother
that I really cared about.
I'm glad you and Chiana
are back together.
Day by day.
Trust takes time.
Yes, it does.
I'm not worthy.
Can't do that, can't do that.
I can't do it.
John, where are you going?
We can see the comms are open.
Would you answer please?
Frell.
Scarrans continue to fight.
It is clearly
Staleek's vanguard.
We're outnumbered
and under attack.
The command carrier
is heavily damaged.
We are unable to defend it.
Ma'am, the grand chancellor
is dead.
A great tragedy for our people.
Arrange a ship-wide
memorial service.
And set a course
for Captain Braca's location immediately.
With respect, ma'am,
High Command is sending
Vice Chancellor Vosler...
Don't let the belly
fool you, Lieutenant.
You were aware of my status?
Commandant, ma'am.
- Within this battle group, who outranks me?
- No one.
Then send apologies
to the vice chancellor
for the extra distance
he will have to travel.
And set a course
for Captain Braca's location now.
Ma'am.
Your assumptions
were correct, Excellency.
My spy informs me that the water planet
Crichton previously visited
was populated by a species
called Eidelon.
Yes.
Same as the frelling creature
they brought on board
to cloud my mind.
Obviously a plan
to defeat us with trickery.
All speed to the water planet.
Crichton is no longer
our only threat.
Inform me when every single
Eidelon is dead.
It's time!
Indeed.
Unlock the knowledge.
I have to make peace.
- Time...
- Flies.
- Bandits.
- Time...
- Wounds all heals.
- Rosemary and...
Time...
Time ends.
Crichton, you possess it,
don't you?
Don't... touch me!
The secret to victory.
The violent path to peace.
Congratulations, John!
Damn, it's big!
It's bigger than big!
These wormhole weapon plans
are complicated.
But I think we can build it
to budget.
- My head is killing me.
- Give the man a hard hat.
Oh, you MBA types.
I didn't get this
for you.
Ladies.
This project, John,
is for both of us.
"Coming this year,
Wormhole weapons to the stars.
Harvey and John's Construction
and Engineering. "
John and Harvey.
I can make us a new sign.
You agreed to do the job.
Now we gotta build it.
We're on my time table.
You're fired!
You went there, didn't you?
I went the whole way there.
- I didn't want you to do that.
- Yes, you did.
Everybody wants to see
the great big wormhole weapon.
I want to see war
turned into peace.
War and peace. War and peace.
Did you know that
Woody Allen's version
is better than Tolstoy's
because it is funnier?
And absolute power
corrupts absolutely.
Where the hell's my pen?
Where's my pen?
This is what you want.
This is what you want!
No, Aeryn, it is not
what I want!
It's just that fate keeps
blocking all the exits.
And no matter what I do, I just keep circling
closer to the flame.
Then pull back.
This war is not
your responsibility.
You and the baby
are my responsibility.
And how am I supposed to protect
you from the Peacekeepers
and the Scarrans and the Tregans and the
lions and tigers and bears?
With this?
This gun?
No gun is big enough.
We still have Stark
and the Eidelons.
It's not enough.
This is enough.
Wormholes.
What's inside my head.
This is ugly,
and it is malignant.
- But it will protect you and the baby...
- Ah, you see?
You don't just protect me.
We protect each other.
Did you feel that?
It kicked.
I can really feel it
alive inside me.
Here, Starky.
I don't remember
him being like this.
Nobody does.
Toad, what's with
the waterworks?
- I miss the baby!
- What baby?
- He had a baby?
- It's kind of a twisted story.
It's the chemical imbalance
in his system
from carrying the child.
He will recover
eventually.
Are you all right?
I'm quite fine.
I can't do this
without your help, Pilot.
Or is it Moya's?
This will be used
as a weapon against others?
Worse case scenario, yeah.
If I understand correctly,
it has the power to kill
tens of thousands.
For starters.
Are you capable
of using this?
Yes.
Then I don't know you
as I thought.
So you'll be starting
with me then?
Someone points a gun
at your head, what do you do?
You defend yourself.
And that is why
we have to build this.
No one has a weapon pointed
to your head.
God, Pilot! Everybody's got
a weapon pointed at my head!
There are other options.
Explain that to the millions who will die
in the meantime.
Is that truly your concern?
Or is it Aeryn and
your un-birthed offspring
you wish to protect?
That's my family, Pilot.
Everything begins
with family.
Scarrans!
- What the hell is happening?
- We're in a crossfire.
What are the Scarrans
doing here?
Pilot,
get us out of here.
How're the Eidelons holding up?
Their city
is also under attack.
There are too many of them!
What? No hailing? Not even
on our part to surrender?
Pilot, what are you doing?
Not me! It's Moya!
She's heading
into the ocean!
Crank!
See? Fate.
Can Moya do this?
She's done it.
She should be watertight.
Should be?
Harpoon holes
notwithstanding.
Don't fool yourselves.
The pressure differential
down here
compared to the vacuum
of space is huge!
We will flood!
Pilot, where is Moya intending
to go exactly? Pilot?
Welcome to the bottom.
Pilot, we have
light showers in here.
What are we seeing
everywhere else?
Sikozu's assessment
is accurate.
Many tiers
are taking on water.
If we're going to make peace, we have to get
Stark to the Eidelons.
- Okay. How do we get back to the surface?
- Transport pod.
If Moya's not watertight, then
transport pods won't be either.
We'll have to make one
watertight. Come along.
Where is Stark?
I can't locate him, Commander.
Yeah, right here.
Don't get
your minivox in a twist.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
But Stark went
completely fahrbot
when he heard the Scarrans
blowing the Hedsmana
out of the Eidelons.
- Where is he?
- Don't know.
I'm on tier 7.
Hard to track him
through the water.
I'll check the lower tiers.
I got topside.
We're going to need
more weapons on the surface.
- I'll raid the armory.
- Right. Be careful.
I'm pregnant,
not incapacitated, John.
Right. Pregnant.
Come on, Stark!
Give it up!
You act like you're high
half the time,
but we got an ocean
ten feet above our heads.
Holy crap.
Anybody see him yet?
Nope, but when I do
you're gonna know
because I'm gonna
rip his arm out.
He's not on the lower tiers.
All right.
You go to the bow.
- I got the aft.
- My pleasure.
Stark, I know
what you're feeling.
You got something in your head
that everybody wants.
Something that never should've
been there in the first place.
I promise you,
we'll get it out.
We damn well
better get it out.
Approaching water planet.
One damaged command carrier
on scans.
Multiple Scarran ships
bombarding her.
Do we have surprise?
From all indications, no cannons
swiveling to our vector.
Have you isolated
the emperor's vessel?
Not yet.
Then target all craft equally.
Shock wears off quickly,
ladies and gentlemen.
You know how I change my mind
about things sometimes?
I get so excited.
I say I'm gonna do it
and I really...
frelling mean it.
And then I change my mind
completely.
Yes.
Hyneria.
I'm gonna do it...
with you.
- You know why?
- Because you like Hynerians?
Not so much.
But I like you.
Can you hear that?
That's just the sound of a DRD.
And that is the sound of
our ship, Moya, under pressure.
And this...
is the sound of an AKR maximum
load ammo pack being chambered
into a full-grade
field ranger pulse pistol.
Are you all right?
Yes. The baby
is just kicking a lot.
I should go and help
find Stark.
We said no to John.
I know.
Moya and I will have
no part of mass murder.
None of us
want to, Pilot.
But if we don't,
the outcome will be worse.
Are not Stark
and the Eidelons
preferable
to the wormhole weapon?
Of course, but I'm not sure
they can do it.
You know, we all want
the same thing, Pilot.
Peace.
Hello, D'Argo.
I found him. He's in
the lower maintenance bay.
I'm sorry I ran like I did.
It was mindless of me.
Are you okay?
Fine actually.
Remarkably fine
given the responsibility
that now resides within me.
So it worked?
It's inside you?
Yondalao's knowledge.
We really
have to get outta here.
We're in awfully deep,
aren't we, D'Argo?
Please, Stark,
we have to go.
Water.
Yeah, there's lots
of water.
More water.
Get down!
Breach on the lower tiers
where D'Argo and Stark are!
I'm close and moving.
Where are they?
Here. Over here!
D'Argo, no.
Look after him.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
I saw the most amazing thing
before I almost died.
What?
The vision?
The light?
- Your ancestors?
- No.
I saw a big wall of water
and the ground
as my nose was scraping
along the floor.
You're lying.
It's not your regular brand.
Eidelon. Crichton,
I'm not afraid anymore.
Hold that thought 'cause
we're going to the surface.
Grand Chancellor Maryk.
Get us into that battle!
Nothing matters
but the carrier.
You all right?
It's beyond me why women would choose
to do this more than once.
- They say three is the magic number.
- Three is a scary number.
Come on, move! Let's go!
Stark, come with me.
We're too late.
We don't know that yet.
Come on.
- Where are the Eidelons?
- The Scarran term is nullified.
Sergeant Learko,
this is Cleaver Jothee.
Sergeant, are you there?
More like here, sir.
What's the situation?
Scarrans control
the whole of the city.
Isolated pockets of
Peacekeepers,
but they're
being steadily neutralized.
- What about the Eidelons?
- Slaughtered, even in surrender.
The rest of our men are
on the other side of the city
searching for survivors.
We have to get Stark to them.
Captain Braca,
are you still alive?
- Very much so, sir. Good to hear your voice.
- Your location?
The great temple.
We're holding out
with a band of Eidelons.
My requests for reinforcements
have been unheeded.
There's some on the way.
Stay tight.
Yes, sir.
Let's move.
You're on point.
Sergeant Learko,
you go with him.
Stark is now
our number-one priority.
Stark? How's that for
an inversion of normalcy!
Don't get shot up too much.
I was thinking the same thing
about you, old man.
Why can we not immolate
that city?
Weapons systems is inoperative from the
Luxan attack, Excellency.
Excuses aside,
I want every single Eidelon
eliminated.
It is being attended.
That chair becomes you.
Reports from prior
to our arrival suggest
that Crichton and the Leviathan
perished in the ocean below.
Would you agree?
I would rather have
his head as proof.
Once the Peacekeepers
have been defeated,
I intent do oversee larger
galactic governance issues.
Bring me Crichton's head
and all differences between us
will be resolved.
Paving the way for you
to assume my position,
Empress Ahkna.
Why no opposition
on this path?
Scarran shock teams containing
a small number of troops,
delivering a high body count.
Looks like they went street by street.
Extermination pattern.
Now they're down there.
How hard's it gonna be for everybody to leave
each other alone?
Impossible, I'd say.
I would like you
to name the baby Rygel.
Maybe... if it's a girl.
All right, folks, when things
go to hell in a hand basket,
we meet here.
It's a good spot for Moya to
pick us up with the docking web.
Okay, everyone,
let's move out.
Very impressive subjugation.
I dread my cities
looking like this.
Hi, Grunschlk,
going somewhere?
Oh, I suspect you have
some serious issues.
- Shoot the traitor.
- I'm not a traitor.
Someone relayed our location
to the Scarrans after we left.
Someone else.
Have you signaled to anyone
that we're here?
Signaled?
I'm trying to get away.
From a Scarran weapon.
So? We use that trick
all the time.
Look, Missy New Eyes,
my dealings with the Scarrans
are purely financial.
Okay, enough talk. Either we
kill him or we take him with us.
- Take him.
- Scarrans.
- Okay, down.
- Go! Go!
We can take
those Dreadnaughts on.
A pulse blast
would bring 100 Scarrans.
They don't know where we are.
I wanna keep it that way.
Don't move.
There's enough here
for both of us.
Go.
Scorpius, there's
movement outside the temple.
Yes, Captain, we're on
approach so hold your fire.
Thank Juka.
We were worried it was another
Scarran insurgency team.
Braca, open the door!
Good to see you.
You're the reinforcements?
No, we're the band.
Looks like Kiss
was your opening act.
Frell, I'm in the wrong band.
Report.
Six of our troops,
two trained Eidelons, four
others who refuse to bear arms.
The Diagnosan,
minimal munitions.
At least the Scarrans don't know
we're here.
Let's keep it that way. Sergeant?
He's a spy.
Watch him.
I am not a spy!
I report, my spy is trapped
inside one of the city's
largest edifices.
Most interestingly,
with Crichton.
- So, he lives.
- Rectified shortly.
I continue to keep
your future seat warm for you.
Stark, you're the reason
we came.
Is Muoma here?
Yes, she's
around the corner.
Do you have a plan?
We had a good plan
till your guys shot us down.
I don't suppose they'd loan us
a ship, would they?
No, I'm afraid Commandant Grayza's focusing
on other issues.
The grand chancellor's dead.
I suggest we observe operation silence.
Fortify our defenses.
Doc!
Your water just broke.
That means the baby's coming.
Doc!
- Big baby. That's good.
- The timing isn't.
Considering the amount
of fire power it takes
to drop a single Scarran,
we're in trouble.
We should disassemble the weaker munitions.
Make our own shot grenades.
Arts and crafts.
She's gonna be a great mom.
She's right about
the fortifications.
Captain Braca, Scarrans.
Take cover!
Small arms,
but a lot of weaponry.
Everyone, help me
close up this door.
War Minister,
the structure is surrounded
and prime for takeover.
Excellent.
When we attack, the Peacekeeper
female is to be left for me.
I just spoke to Pilot.
Said he won't be ready
till dawn.
At least a couple of arns.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
You've done enough already.
If this was a Sebacean
child, a pure one,
it would've
been born long ago.
So, how long
is this going to take?
On Earth it can last days.
I have killed men for less.
Hey, baby birthing was not
part of the original deal.
Hey, we will be renegotiating.
How's it going?
I'll explain the processes
as best I understand it.
- When they finish meditating...
- We are ready.
High Priestess,
prepare yourself.
The legends are true.
Our heritage,
Yondalao's knowledge,
lies within me.
It has left me completely.
- Will you be able to educate the others?
- Of course.
And make peace?
Our numbers are too few.
Many more are necessary
to make a lasting contribution.
We might be able
to do something about that.
- Jothee, pick up the phone.
- Hello, Crichton?
Noranti, what the hell
are you doing?
Rescuing Eidelons.
What are you doing?
Where's Jothee?
Gone on reconnaissance with
his men. Their comms are off.
What's the situation there?
Any Eidelon that isn't dead
appears to be hiding with us.
Upwards of 100, I'd say.
I'm in charge, Crichton.
Jothee has made me
an honorary commando.
- Tell me he didn't give you a gun.
- Most certainly.
But pulse packs are in short
supply so it's not loaded.
Moya won't be able to pick them
up all together.
She'll barely
be able to take us.
Listen, Grandma,
call us when Jothee gets back.
There's a lot happening.
I'll try and remember.
I have to go now.
We can get you 100.
If we were all to be reunited,
peace is possible.
Just keep doing your thing.
We'll get you there.
Fantastic job.
You're the Johnny Appleseed
of detente.
Thank you. Thank you.
Johnny Appleseed?
Enough! Don't touch me!
Everything he does causes more pain.
This woman could chew
her own arm off.
What is going on?
No, no. No hablo Diagnosan.
What the hell's he saying?
The baby's turned round.
In a bad way.
Tangled in the cord.
And the translation
is extra!
Entangled. Breached.
Must manipulate.
But you can fix it,
right?
They're here!
Return fire!
Aeryn, get down!
You have to give birth!
Key for
their muzzle fire.
Frelling Scarrans!
They will charge!
Use your weapon!
Need your help.
Stay down!
We're way outnumbered.
Our number's about to grow
by one. Can you help Aeryn?
- I'll do it myself.
- The baby is breached.
I can't birth her narl.
I don't want a narl.
I hate narls.
I'm still a narl myself.
- You helped Moya give birth.
- I blew out a wall and three tiers.
I concur.
The baby's head is up.
It has to be down.
Don't make any structural
changes. I'll be right back.
Mind if I borrow your knife?
Careful, it's sharp.
- How are we looking?
- Stay here. We're not looking too good.
Scarran experts, what are
our tactical options?
In this position,
very limited.
A distraction and a break.
Some make it, some don't.
We've got to stay. We've got
no choice. Pilot isn't ready.
You heard the man. Batten down
the hatches. We stay and defend.
Uncooperative.
Twisted up.
She's having it.
- I need you. I need you to reload my weapon.
- I'm here, baby.
- If she keeps firing it past my head, I quit!
- Fine!
If she doesn't stay still,
I can't do this.
If I don't fire, we're dead.
Sweetheart, for once
let me cover you.
- Can you do this?
- Yes. Maybe if she stays still.
Shooting makes me
feel better.
Honey.
All right!
But do it quickly.
Come on.
One, two, three.
Jothee, you're back.
We were worried about you.
Biggest threat so far is this
crazy old witch you travel with.
- How're things going?
- We're deep in it.
We're gonna try to make a break
for Moya. You guys got a plan?
Found a nice Scarran
transport vessel.
Should hold
all the Eidelons.
Good luck!
I believe one of our empty troop
vessels is under attack.
Comms went silent after
an initial transmission burst.
We have others.
Ignore it.
How long before your
engineers are ready here?
Moments, Minister.
They're charging!
Fall back! Reinforce
the defense perimeter.
Move back! Move back!
Hey, all right, listen.
- We gotta get you in the fountain.
- What?
- Into the fountain.
- You get in. It's the most exposed position.
It's better for the baby.
It's cleaner, safer.
Hey, do you want this thing
out of you or not?
Hold your positions
and fire!
John, get these!
Come on, hurry up!
Move it!
- Hey, you all right?
- You all right?
Okay.
- We're gonna get you up, in the fountain.
- No.
- Build a barricade.
- Yes, sir.
Learko.
Say hello to the... cleaver
for me.
Tell him...
Tell him
it was an honor to serve.
Up.
Soldier, your wounds
mean nothing!
Attend to your position!
Untie me. Give me a weapon.
I'll only shoot myself.
Honest!
Leave the dead!
Reload.
Careful.
- Captain.
- Yes, sir?
We need as many weapons as
possible to the breach holes.
Sikozu, I have something
for you to do.
- Astro.
- We're...
Just a few scratches.
How long
till first light here?
Another arn at most.
Pilot, where are you?
I am here, Commander.
Yeah, and when
are you gonna be here?
Preparations are almost
complete.
Perhaps in an arn.
Hopefully we'll be there.
- Come on, in you go.
- No!
Come on.
Come on, in the fountain.
Listen, we need raslak.
Lots of it.
Come on, in the fountain.
Here we go, here we go.
Okay. I've untangled
the baby.
You gotta get her
in the fountain.
She pushes, you pull.
I'm done.
You're fired!
In the fountain.
You like this?
It's very inventive.
I've never met a spy
more resourceful,
more tenacious.
Scarran comms device.
What did you expect?
How long have you known?
Long enough for you
to service my desires.
Unfortunately, your desires
no longer serve my needs!
They promised
to free my people
from their servitude!
They will not,
and you
have blown something unique.
What are you doing?
Hold still.
All right, Aeryn,
we have to get ready.
Great. I'll cut it out.
No! It's for your clothes
and for the cord.
Oh. Right.
Whoa, whoa, easy, easy.
All right, breathe.
Breathe with me. Inhale.
Exhale. Does anybody have a plan
that doesn't involve the word surrender?
There's absolutely no way we
can withstand another assault.
Agreed. Let's go on
the offensive.
Bring me every weapon
we have.
I'm gonna create
a little diversion.
Exhale.
With me, with me, inhale.
Sir, where's Sikozu?
On her final mission
for the Scarrans.
Get down!
Everyone get down!
Too much fun.
Can we go now?
I think it's time to push.
- I can't!
- You can! You can!
Push!
Here.
- I'm helpless.
- You're not helpless. I'm here. Come on, push!
- Wait. Stark!
- What?
- Come here.
- Do you want me to take your pain?
No. I want you
to marry us.
What?
- Now.
- Aeryn, we can go to Vegas tomorrow.
- No!
- Marry us!
Wait, wait, wait.
What?
Ah. Here.
It was with the crystals.
I kept it moist for you.
- It's my mom's ring.
- That's wonderful!
You didn't think I'd go back
into that cold ocean for nothing!
Quick, quick!
Come on!
Idiot! That's a Shayan
prayer for the dead.
What?
Dobian puberty right.
Okay, okay.
You two love each other?
Yes!
Enough to
be married forever?
Yes!
Then you are.
Congratulations.
Thank you!
He's alive!
Here, stick him in this bag.
We'll carry him.
Father, I don't think we're
gonna be able to get to you.
If we're gonna make it to Moya, it's gonna have
to be further away from the battle.
Can you get past
the Scarran lines?
Yeah, we got a chance. Yes.
Just one more time!
Oh!
Now push!
Push, push, push, push!
Push!
Its head.
Wow!
We have a son.
We have a son!
- We did it.
- I love you.
I love you too.
Hey.
- Could you do me a favor?
- You name it.
Can you get us
out of here?
Done.
Fall back!
Take high positions!
Ambush them in the street.
Fool.
Where are they?
Pilot, we're on the move.
I have to bring Moya's
propulsion
up to maximum to break free
of the seabed.
No one I'd rather have
in charge.
We'll be there.
How's your honeymoon?
Well, the brochure was better.
There's too many boot prints,
and they're fresh.
We're not alone.
Inside!
Get back! Get back!
There's too many! Take cover!
Come on, go, go, go!
I hear Bolivia
is perfect for a honeymoon.
They're pinned down,
War Minister.
Supply the troops
in the buildings with missiles.
We get hit with any more of
those missiles, and we are Spam!
We'll try for that building. Set
up a crossfire so we can move.
Go! Cover fire now!
Go! Move out!
I'm out!
All right, one through twenty.
We are lifting off now!
- You can be at the cliff when Moya arrives.
- Not 'til we clear this path!
Oh, that'll be easy.
- Sounds like you guys could use some help.
- Son!
We thought you were gone.
- How far away are you?
- A lot closer than you think.
Okay, everyone down, down.
Get down!
Again!
You're good to go.
I wish I could pick you up.
But along the way,
I rescued some stragglers.
You gonna be all right?
Yeah. Moya's on the way.
Thanks for the help.
I'm proud of you, son.
It's all genetics, Father.
It's like the Luxan lottery.
Okay, get outta here.
I'll see you weightless.
Y'all be careful out there.
That means you.
Let's move.
We'll wait for a signal.
Now you cry?
I'm fine. Fine.
At least you die.
It's a boy... in case
you were wondering.
We're gonna have to get to the meeting point.
Can you make it?
Hurry up!
D'Argo, hurry up.
Come on.
None of that. Someone has to
be here. May as well be me.
No way. Hey.
We'll fix you up.
- We have to go.
- You'll be fine.
- Come on.
- More Scarrans will be here before Moya is.
I'll stay, you go.
No!
Yes. This won't heal.
It won't fix. It won't...
I'll take your pain.
No. Pain is good.
Means I'm still alive.
Then let me help you
to the other side.
This is the other side.
I was hoping to go back.
Come on, Rygel.
Hey, hey.
Come on, let's go.
- No.
- Let's go!
Give me some pulse rifles.
Give me some pulse rifles!
Okay.
It's gonna get uglier soon.
You better get going.
You're the closest friend
I have.
You could've done better.
Nowhere in the universe.
You got a lot of life
to lead, John.
Two big things.
Do me a favor?
Name it.
I'll look after her.
I'll take care nothing's
gonna happen to her.
Go away.
I wanna speak to Chiana.
I'm gonna miss you.
Stop it. No laughing.
Don't make him laugh.
Hey.
Please don't die.
- We all die.
- No.
- I love you.
- No, no...
Take this.
- Take this, take this.
- I don't want it.
Take it!
John.
Take it.
- Don't leave me.
- I'll find you.
- I love you.
The first Scarran you see,
you tell him who his daddy is.
Tell him, D'Argo!
I'm almost to the surface.
Moya senses there are still many
Scarran attack ships out there.
Get ready to jump.
What?
It's safer to fall into the web than risk being
scooped up by it.
- Give me the baby.
- No.
I'll be hovering.
I won't fall.
He's safer with me.
I'm your daddy!
Let's do it.
Good luck.
We'll need it.
On my count.
One, two, three... jump!
- Pilot, have we heard from Jothee yet?
- Safe.
As is the ship they commandeered
to rescue the other Eidelons.
How soon can we rendezvous?
We have to get Muoma into play.
We can't, Commander. We're on opposite
sides of the battle zone.
I'm doing all I can to keep us
from being destroyed as it is.
I don't care what you say.
He's got my nose.
The frellings
killed my D'Argo.
He wanted you to survive.
You have to keep your wits.
Come on.
Even if these three Eidelons on board
are enough,
- I propose...
- Not now!
Pilot, have we heard from Staleek
or the grand chancellorette?
No, Commander.
How the hell
did this get here?
The DRD's built it
to your specifications.
What changed your mind?
Not what.
Who.
It's operational?
As far as I can tell.
This will make
a wormhole weapon, yes?
I thought this
is what you wanted.
At the time. Not now.
Not ever really.
Pilot, can we run?
We're too damaged to starburst.
And the Peacekeepers
and Scarrans seem as intent
on annihilating us
as they are each other.
Jothee, can you hear me?
Pretty tight over here.
I can't make it to you.
Cut loose. Get clear.
You understand me?
Copy. Everybody safe?
It's a little crazy around
here for roll call now.
Just get as far away as you can.
We'll catch up.
Hey, come here.
Kill the frellings.
And kill them others too.
If you can
kill them slowly, do it.
Back off.
Keep away!
D'Argo's dead. Do you think
I frelling care what I do to you?
Yes.
D'Argo is dead?
Yes, Pilot. Saving us.
Is there another way?
I don't see one.
Do you?
It's worse than you think.
Is it worse than D'Argo
being blown to pieces?
Is it worse
than our son dying?
than living with this?
Come here.
Closer.
You wanna see it?
The thing you've been chasing my
ass all over the universe for?
Torturing me, my wife,
my friends for?
Formidable weapon.
You wanna see it?
Yes.
- Beg.
- I beg you.
That's not good enough.
Say please.
Please.
- Pretty please.
- With cherry on top.
Happy birthday.
Now get outta my sight.
Behold, the wormhole weapon.
That?
Yeah.
Ain't it beautiful?
Is this some kind
of joke?
Cosmic.
Keep watching.
Blink and
you'll miss it.
There.
Isn't that sweet?
Baby's gonna grow.
Pilot, are my comms open?
It's time for a birth announcement.
Comms are open, Commander.
Attention, ladies and gentlemen,
and all ships at sea.
If you look out your
front window,
you will see,
by special request,
your very own
wormhole weapon.
Crichton, what's happening?
The end of all this crap.
Hey, Emperor Sleestak,
you big upright iguana.
What does it look like
from the Death Star?
Sir, do you wish
to respond?
Yes. Increase fire power.
Increased rate of fire.
And begin reverse thrust.
Pull us out of here.
Reverse thrust,
one quarter.
Can I get a huzzah from
the grand Peacekeeper bitch?
Wormhole at 12:00, Lucy.
Ignore that hail.
Continue all guns
against the Decimator.
That object is beginning to exert
a gravitational pull on us.
Steady retreat
while continuing to fire.
Unbelievable.
Nobody has anything to say.
How big is that thing
gonna get?
Big.
Okay, boys and girls,
here are the rules.
Find a penny, pick it up.
Double it.
You've got two pennies.
Double it again. Four.
Double it 27 times,
and you've got a million dollars
and the IRS all over
your ass.
Round and round
and round it goes.
Where it stops, nobody knows.
But it all adds up... quick.
What do you mean
we cannot reverse thrust?
Because it's just
not working.
We're trapped here, ma'am.
Pilot, how you doin'?
Acceptable, Commander.
Though Moya and I
are beginning to question
whether it makes any difference.
We have tried to retreat
from the wormhole,
but are unable to escape.
I know.
Our destinies are no longer
in our own hands.
Give me my world.
Cease fire!
Ma'am, your orders?
Hold all salvos.
Silence the guns.
What have you done,
Crichton?
What did you ask me to do,
Sparky?
"Crichton, please make the wormhole so we
can all have peace.
"Crichton, you gotta make the wormhole.
We all want peace!
"Crichton, make the damn wormhole.
We gotta have peace!"
How many times
did you say that, Sparky?
Wormhole. Peace.
Peace. Wormhole.
How many times, mister, I beg you,
"Please with a cherry on top"?
I'm sorry.
I tried to explain it.
I tried to tell them all.
You do what
you have to do.
Kiss me.
Here's how it lays out.
Are you listening, Staleek?
I am listening.
Yes.
Wormhole weapons
do not make peace.
don't even make war.
They make total destruction.
Annihilation.
Armageddon.
People make peace.
Can you stop it?
I don't know.
Maybe.
It eats the whole galaxy.
Monumental black hole.
Giant, swirling headstone
marking the spot
where we all used
to live and play
and slaughter the innocent.
This is insane.
God!
Four years on
and you're finally getting that.
You will not go through
with this.
- I already have!
- I agree.
You are weak.
You will not sacrifice
the woman and your offspring.
Our son will be raised
in peace.
Amen.
You hear that, you bastards?
All or nothing.
Wormhole doubles two more times,
Moya goes first.
Twenty seconds later,
you join us.
Either way, this war is over.
Peace.
For the sake
of our children,
I will agree
to a settlement.
May the spirit of peace
descend on Staleek.
Save some for me.
I don't know.
If it is the largest
black hole,
then it's a death
worthy of a Dominar.
Peace.
Agreed.
The Eidelons participate?
A real peace?
Agreed.
Stop this thing.
Somebody help me!
Wake up!
Wake up.
No!
Whenever we cross paths,
I leave the encounter
transformed.
And no more so
than on this occasion.
Thanks to you, I have found
my own internal peace.
Remember me, John.
Till we meet again.
Did he suffer?
Are you kidding?
They suffered.
Are you going to Hyneria?
He wanted you to have this.
I had toyed with
Slim Pickens on the bomb.
But this feels far more
appropriate to the moment.
Don't you think?
Now that Einstein has removed
all wormhole weapon knowledge,
my purpose is fulfilled.
We've done everything
we can together, John.
Somehow
you'll have to make all your
future decisions on your own.
My eradication program
has begun to remove
all vestiges of me.
Soon... I'll be nothing
but a pleasant remembrance...
of the good old days.
Good-bye, John.
Thanks for your memories.
You did it, John.
There's no more dying.
You know, it's strange.
It almost took me losing
this little one
to fully understand
motherhood.
And I love it.
And all of a sudden
three is not such
a scary number.
Here we go.
But no matter
how wonderful this is,
I will not accept it
as a trade-off for losing you.
What are you doing here?
Did I scare you?
'Cause you scared me.
Crichton's don't cry...
often...
or for very long.
Where's your mother?
That's it,
open your eyes.
You see all these stars?
They're yours.
Except that one.
That one's yours.
Hi. Let's do this.
There you go.
Come here, buddy.
Yep.
Your father and I
want you to have the name
that means courage
and strength.
So we have chosen
Little D, we don't know what
life has in store for you,
but whatever it is,
you'll figure something out.
But you will never
walk alone.
And God willing,
you'll never know war.
Instead...
Come here.
Your mother was right.
Your mother is always right.
Get used to that.
You ready?
This is your playground.
Subtitled By JR Media Services, Inc.
Burbank - CA