I get it, Frank.
I get it.
Guys like us, paranoia is second nature.
I get that.
You're wondering if I'm some kind
of a decoy to lure you out.
I'm not. I'm not. It's safe here.
So no need for any of this Marathon Man stuff.
It's definitely safe, okay?
You don't need to interrogate a man
that's waited months just to talk to you.
Oh, come on.
I get it.
I get it. You wanna--
You're trying to intimidate me.
And I'm not like, uh...
reassuring you, or...
Are you...
You know, you risk botulism doing that.
You always talk this much?
I guess I talk when I'm nervous.
Well, guess you're not as stupid as you look.
- What is that?
- Shit.
Okay.
Okay, this place is rigged.
What do you mean it's rigged?
What is that?
It means, I don't type a code
into the central terminal, then...
kaboom.
That alarm means we got three minutes
before it gets awful warm in here.
- Ah, no. That's bullshit.
- Do I look like I'm lying to you?
- You really wanna take that risk?
- What's the password?
Only takes a retinal scan.
What? You really wanna die together?
Come on!
Ninety seconds. We're both gonna die
feeling pretty stupid here, you know that?
Oh, you...
Come on!
- I'm gonna say it one time--
- Are you gonna help me out?
- Oh, yeah. No bullshit.
- Yeah?
I'm warning you.
I forgot it was-- I forgot it was there!
- What is that? What is that?
- I forgot it was there!
- Nice and easy, Lieberman.
- Okay...
Hey, what are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Retinal scan.
Go on.
- Disable it.
- I can't! It's hardwired.
Piece of shit.
All right.
Oh, are we still doing this?
Come on.
Yup.
We are most definitely still doing this.
You're an idiot.
You don't know a goddamn thing.
The same people that killed you, killed me.
Is that right?
Start talking.
You know, I got an idea, man.
Why don't you get me some pants?
Yeah. I could make us some tea.
We could do this like--
Yeah. Does that hurt?
Oh, yeah. I get it.
That's just stimuli.
You're reacting to it.
You get used to that.
Pain. You can get used to pain, Lieberman.
You can adjust to it.
You can adjust to pretty much anything.
Just as long as there's routine, right?
Routine. Human mind, it craves it.
Needs it.
But if you take that away, that...
That's when you start to lose your shit.
When you take away day and night and food.
No water, no patterns.
You know what's crazy, Lieberman?
Even though you know what's happening...
I'm telling you that it's happening...
Even though you know it...
rationalizing it won't do shit.
People think that torture is pain.
It's not pain.
It's time.
It's time to slowly realize
that your life, it's over.
It's over, Lieberman.
Now all you got is the nightmare.
You and me, we got time.
I was a, uh... NSA analyst.
I was working on Afghanistan intelligence,
which, uh...
Maybe you know it's just an oxymoron
because, uh...
our basic tactic is to pay anyone
we can to tell tales.
You know?
"Hey, kid. Tell me a story,
I'll give you some money."
So they did, you know?
And, uh... my job was to, uh...
assess this shit pile
for, uh, actionable intelligence.
It was a monumental waste of my time.
Till one day, uh...
they sent me something interesting.
I just don't understand.
What is that disk?
Why did they send it to you?
I'm the analyst.
That's what they're meant to do.
They send me actual, real intelligence
and then I, you know, I assess it
and decide how to deal with it.
It's actually... I could do my job
for the first time in five years.
But you should...
You should give it to your section chief.
Pass it up the line of command
so it's not on you.
If he buries it? What then?
- Then that's on them.
- Mom, did you get juice?
Yeah, honey.
Yeah, come in here. I'll get you some.
If you go around the chain of command,
neither of us is naive about what it could mean.
- Should I get a cup?
- Yeah, yeah, get a cup.
- Hey, Leo, you want some juice, honey?
- Yes, please.
All right, you guys,
get into your pj's. Time for bed.
I finished my homework.
Oh, your father will look at it
before you go to sleep.
- All right.
- Thanks.
- Go. Go.
- Thank you.
- To bed.
- Love you. Good night.
- Love you.
- Good night.
- Good night, baby.
- I really wanna do the right thing here.
- Mmm-hmm.
You want me to tell you it's okay
so that if this all blows up,
it won't be your fault.
David, I just...
I can't do that.
You know, everything that we teach them
about being good human beings...
that's what this comes down to.
This is why I took this job.
This is why we are here and I'm not...
writing apps in Silicon Valley.
How am I supposed to look these guys in the eye,
knowing that I didn't have the guts
to do the right thing?
Look, hey... hey.
Come here.
Mmm.
You do... what you think you should.
Hmm.
Your turn, Dad! Dad?
David.
Oh, sorry, you guys. Um...
- Is it a quadruped?
- What's a--
- Four-legged animal. A quadruped.
- You know that.
Sorry. Uh, yes.
Okay, so we got a non-jungle-dwelling quadruped.
- Vegetarian.
- Four-legged vegetarian animal
that does not live in the jungle.
- And...
- This is painful.
- Are we gonna be late?
- No.
No. No, no, no.
We should be fine, you guys. I think.
Everyone has the same idea we do.
I wanna make it there in time.
Make it to that haunted house, before the line.
- Stay in the car.
- What?
- No matter what happens.
- What are you doing? Babe?
- Dad? Dad?
- What are you doing?
- Stay in the car.
Understand? Stay in the car.
- Stay in the car. I'll be right back.
- Dad?
David!
Don't move!
- Lieberman, get on the ground! Now!
- Look, this is a mistake, all right?
Whatever your orders, I'm not a criminal.
I'm an NSA analyst.
Get down!
- I'm an NSA analyst!
- He's got a weapon!
No, I don't. No, no, no, no, no!
- That's not true!
- David?
This is a mistake, okay?
This is a mistake.
Sarah, go.
- David!
- Drop the weapon!
- Sarah!
- On your knees!
- No, no, no.
- David!
No, no, no! Sarah, go!
- Go, go, go, go!
No!
No! No!
Cell phone saved my life.
I went underground.
They, uh, rewrote the narrative.
Planted evidence, painted me as a traitor.
Picked my life apart.
Made life hell for Sarah. For our kids.
You know, she said you were brave.
- Hmm.
- Brave and stupid.
And here I am, tied butt naked to a chair.
So, uh...
Yeah.
Are we still doing this?
Could I at least have a glass of water?
Autopsy report.
- Unless Wolf shot himself in the leg...
- Hmm.
...busted his own face and broke his own neck,
I think it's fair to say
that we're looking at murder here.
- God.
- Well, torture, then murder, to be exact.
I think the killer came down the chimney.
Motion detectors never picked him up.
Wolf comes home, turns off the alarm
and bam! The guy hits him.
So we're looking for Bad Santa?
The press knows he's dead.
No statements. Not yet.
This is going to be a jurisdictional cockfight.
NYPD and FBI?
They're both already trying to jump onboard.
Screw 'em.
He was one of us.
Why you gotta be so quiet?
Like a damn cat.
I could tie a bell around my neck
or something, if that'd help you out.
Yeah, you do that.
- Want some coffee? It's fresh-brewed.
- Sure.
So, what brings you down here?
Personal delivery.
Thank you.
I'm honored, Mr. Russo, sir.
Kiss my ass, Curtis.
So, uh... how's it all going here, anyway?
Ah, you know, it's good.
Your money pays the rent.
Keeps the homeless guys in coffee and soup.
And occasionally, we talk about being a vet.
It helps.
Some of them, I think.
They keep coming back
so that must mean something, right?
You always were good
at putting people back together.
You should stay.
See what you're paying for.
- Yeah. Yeah, I don't need that.
- Which is why you should stay.
It'd be good for these guys to see
someone like them who made a second life.
I'd feel guilty that I got out in time.
These guys, they...
they got problems that I don't.
I'm way too selfish to do what you do.
There's nothing selfish about this.
It means a lot.
- So how's business?
- Pretty good, actually. As you ask.
A mover and a shaker.
A man of wealth and taste.
You always knew you were destined
to do greater things, I'll give you that.
What?
I just... I can't tell if you think
that's a good thing or not.
No, I... I'm proud of you. I really am.
You know there's always a job for you at Anvil.
Instructor's job.
You're still the best corpsman I ever saw.
Hell, I bet you'd have stitched
your own damn leg back on, given a chance.
Hell, yeah.
If you could find it.
But is that why you're here?
We still good for tomorrow night?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll be there.
Good.
You should come work with me, Curtis.
You know I'd look after you.
Yeah, I'm sure.
But I got out in time, too.
Even if it did cost me a leg.
I ain't got no plans on going back.
Guess that makes us the lucky ones.
Who's coming, Lieberman, huh?
I know someone's coming.
Tell me who it is.
- No, no, no, someone's coming.
- Nobody's coming.
- I don't believe you survived on your own.
- Yeah?
Tell me who it is.
I survived for the same reason that you survived.
'Cause I'm good at this stuff.
I know that it makes it easier for you
if you make me the enemy, but I'm not.
Hey...
I'm the only friend you have, Frank.
Hey!
If somebody was coming, who would it be?
Success here is a matter of perspective.
It can't be measured
in battles won or land claimed.
Gentlemen, I'm here to offer you freedom.
To wage the war that must be waged
to finally win this thing.
What we will do is dirty and tough,
but it will speed an end of this war
and safeguard our nation.
Major Schoonover.
You were all handpicked
'cause you're the best at what you do.
Inter-unit rivalry has no place here.
Berets, Delta, SEALs, Force Recon...
I don't give a shit.
This is who we are now.
This is Operation Cerberus...
and you are my dogs of war.
The enemy operates
without regard to honor or rules.
So neither will we.
Our mission is simple.
We capture, interrogate
and execute high-value targets.
Sounds like the Phoenix Program.
Do we have a problem with that, gentlemen?
Not if Congress doesn't.
They're fine with it.
I'm the only authority you will need.
I point, you shoot.
Castle and Russo are team leaders.
They'll post all assignments.
Any questions?
Sir... does this mean
that Ann-Margret's not coming?
I mean...
Jackass...
Play any Kenny Rogers on that thing?
Well, it's, uh...
it's not really my speed.
Gunner Henderson.
You're leading my team.
I've heard good things.
Yeah, likewise.
Jack Kimber, he's a friend.
He calls you the best breacher he ever saw.
I'm excited to watch you work.
All here to serve the Lord's will, my friend.
Hmm. Fair enough.
We're the sword of the righteous.
Our aim must be true.
"Righteousness keepeth him that is upright
in the way,
but wickedness overthroweth the sinner."
It's Proverbs 13:6.
Okay.
Your face. I'm messing with you, boss.
- All right, man. Nice to meet you.
- All right, man. You, too.
- He seems fun.
- Oh, yeah.
How's, uh... how's your team look?
Ready for bear.
Hey, you notice that our fearless leader
didn't even give us a name?
Yeah.
Heard some of the guys call him Agent Orange.
- I like that.
- Do you?
What, you don't trust him?
Ours is not to reason why, Frankie boy.
Ours is but to do or die.
That's from a poem about a bunch of guys
who got their asses handed to 'em
on the back of bad intel, right?
- You are shitting me.
- Shit you not.
You read a poem?
Billy, you're so funny, man.
- Seriously, it's hilarious.
- Hey, you never cease to amaze me, man.
All by yourself?
I didn't know you could read.
Sorry about that.
I once took out a machine gun nest,
saw this guy's head explode and...
all I thought was, "Good shot."
I hated the enemy 'cause I had to, but...
but I respected him, too.
They don't haunt me.
One of our Apaches hit some of our own.
Friendly fire.
There is no such thing.
But it's war, right? Shit happens.
Except I then saw some press officer
pass it off to reporters
as an enemy ambush.
Lying pricks.
All I could think was
that it dishonored those men as soldiers.
They were good at their jobs.
They didn't get ambushed like assholes.
It was a lie.
When, um...
I dream, I see that guy.
And it... It's me that he is lying about.
Me that he is turning into an asshole.
Like it all meant nothing.
What do you do when you can't trust your own?
Take matters into your own hands.
- Oh, here we go.
- No, no, no, no. I agree with O'Connor.
First time for everything, right?
About time you saw sense.
We take matters into our own hands.
We are not the only soldiers
to feel let down by the country we serve.
I have friends who have been betrayed
in ways that you guys can't even imagine.
Everything taken from them.
A good man risked his life to save mine.
Yeah.
And I decided not to throw away
that gift he gave me.
So I got a job... started my second life.
And now I take pride in living that life well.
What the hell is it that you do anyways, Curtis?
I sell insurance.
It's a hell of a sales tool.
All right, let's wrap it up, guys.
Read this, kid.
You're right to feel betrayed.
And there's plenty men who feel just the same.
This touchy-feely bullshit
ain't gonna solve nothing.
You gotta spin me around so I can enter the code.
Here's the thing.
There are no explosive devices in this place.
If there were, I would have found 'em.
So, you keep saying, "Believe me,"
but you keep lying to me, Lieberman.
Bravo, Frank, you got it.
No explosives.
No fire.
Spin me around. Let me show you something.
Spin me around! Come on!
Smile, Frank, you're on Candid Camera.
You see, if I don't enter a code,
then all these video feeds,
they get sent to various media outlets
and the world knows you're still alive.
You want that? No? Let me go.
Let me go.
Figured if they ever found me here...
at least I could broadcast my murder
to the world.
Let my family know I wasn't what everyone said.
I would have lost my last chance
of going home and seeing 'em.
This chance. Us.
My family... they're gone.
They're gone because of your goddamn disk.
What about that?
Had nothing to do with what you did, huh?
Hey, you shut your mouth.
- Yeah?
- You shut your mouth.
You followed orders, I did my job.
You tell me what's the difference--
- There's a difference--
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- What's the difference?
What's the difference?
Let me ask you something.
- How many times was Zubair beaten?
- Shut your mouth.
How many times was this innocent man tortured?
He was a good man!
He was an honorable father. He was a cop.
Hey!
- Are you gonna kill me?
- The thought does cross my mind.
- It's crossing my mind.
- You're not gonna kill me.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, I know people. I'm an analyst.
It's my job.
You're not gonna kill me
'cause you're a good man.
You...
You don't know shit. You don't know shit.
Who else knows?
There is still time for you to undo this.
I will help you.
You answer the question.
Do all these men know I am a police officer?
Are they all part of this?
- What's he saying?
- Nothing useful.
We sure he's even got anything?
Are you questioning my intelligence, soldier?
Please, I'm not a terrorist.
I have a family, children--
I am a good man.
If you want your family to see another sunrise...
you will stop talking. You understand me?
If you don't know anything...
Do it.
Please... I'm not a terrorist.
I have a family. I... I have a family.
What are you doing?
We desecrating corpses now?
Frank?
Schoonover said get the bullet.
I'm getting the bullet.
Looks to me like we're hiding evidence.
You good with that?
No one's asking for our opinions.
Not while we're here.
Let's go.
Happy birthday, Frank.
It's a good thing you did...
getting a stone.
Yeah. Figured he deserved
a marker of some kind, right?
Frank would have hated this, this maudlin shit.
I wish he'd...
Why didn't...
Why didn't he come to us, man?
After Maria and the kids?
Why didn't he come to us?
He didn't have to be alone.
We could've helped him.
Yeah, he didn't want any help.
He wanted to kill every bastard
who had a hand in it.
I miss him.
And I could see it.
I could see it.
Even before... what happened.
He was changing.
He was finding it harder and harder to come back.
He said Kandahar was like nothing else.
He said the lines were blurred.
When did he say that?
Uh, just when he was over there.
He called me, you know, to shoot the shit.
Said I was lucky not to be there.
Yeah.
Well...
you were.
Oh.
Yeah, he did not die easy.
You feel guilty for disliking this man.
I wanted him out of my way, Mom,
but not like this.
And now you get to sit in his chair.
Temporarily.
Someone has to become the agent in charge.
Why not you?
- I'm not sure I'm suited to command.
- Really?
You went to Afghanistan
because it was a fast track to promotion.
"A notch on your belt" was the phrase you used
when I tried to talk you out of it.
Well, my priorities changed.
With the death of your friend.
And now you're closing yourself off,
find it hard to trust people.
But this withdrawal is not a good thing, Dinah.
Don't make me the victim of this, Mom.
I'm not.
You want a victim, look at Wolf or Ahmad.
And I'm not withdrawing.
Truth is, I just don't trust anyone else
to get it right.
You want to label me something,
then call it arrogance.
I'm the best. Others will let me down.
Of course they will, darling.
C'est la vie. That's life.
How we deal with disappointments
is what decides the person we are.
Yeah, but I'm not talking about someone
turning up late for dinner
or buying the wrong flowers.
You know what? You are arrogant.
And more than a little self-important.
But you will have to trust someone, sometime.
Though I wonder if it isn't the other way around.
After what happened with your friend,
perhaps you are terrified
someone will choose to trust you.
Hmm?
- Hey, sleepyhead.
- Hey.
Hi.
No!
Happy birthday, Frank.
It's the 15th.
Happy birthday.
I know all there is to know.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
If you cut me loose, I'll buy you a cake.
Come on. Come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on.
You know, sooner or later
you're gonna have to, uh,
get me something to drink or eat.
Or kill me.
What's it gonna be?
Mmm.
You never should have come after me, Lieberman.
I didn't have a choice.
They took our families from us.
Jesus. That's such bullshit.
Your family's alive. Mine's gone.
You threw yours away.
You had a choice. I didn't.
Yeah, you keep telling yourself that.
Maybe someday you're gonna believe it.
You and I both thought
we were serving our country.
- We both thought that.
- Type the code.
And now if I go home, I get my family killed.
You know, you and I together,
we could change that.
Type the code.
I'm sorry, Frank.
Lewis? You down there, son?
You down here?
Dad...
Son...
- Shit.
- Come here.
Oh, God.
- Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- What?
- I could have killed you.
No, no. You didn't. Nobody got hurt.
- Dad, I could have killed you.
- You're okay. I'm okay.
No, I could have killed you, Dad.
Pulled Wolf's bank records.
Thirty million?
Yep. Six accounts. All buried offshore.
- Any indication where it's from?
- Still working on that.
We have to run this up the flagpole, Dinah.
As far as you're concerned, I am the flagpole.
Who else can we trust with this?
I'm new here, you brought me the evidence.
Everyone else is suspect.
And you don't find that kinda scary?
No. Of course not.
Puts you right where you want to be.
And where is that, exactly?
On your own.
Riding cowboy. You against the world.
You speak to Wolf like this
when he was your boss?
That's what I get?
You know, you came in here with a bug up your ass
about a case nobody wanted
and all this "we're not partners" stuff,
- but now you want me to keep your secrets?
- Yeah.
You know...
you were right about one thing.
Trust, loyalty... you gotta earn those.
Stein. Sam.
Wait.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Easy now, Frank.
Hey, don't do that. I wouldn't do that.
I wouldn't... No swift move--
Why don't you sit down?
Have a cup of coffee. Come on.
Time to choose.
- Why didn't you kill me?
- Oh, my God, man.
You didn't listen to anything that I said?
Oh, my God.
You gotta be the most stubborn...
Why didn't I kill you? Jesus.
- The codes.
- Turned that off.
You know, it's like you said.
Routines, right? Patterns.
Jesus Christ.
They lull us into a sense of,
uh, normality, a false sense of security.
We cease to question.
- Even somebody like you.
- You're an asshole.
You know, these men that, uh,
tried to kill us, they have patterns.
Patterns that don't, uh, involve you and me.
- I mean, they think we're dead.
- Lieberman...
I don't do partners.
Get over yourself.
There's no place for emotion here, you know?
You and me have both done things
that we would like to take back.
We can't.
But we're not the bad guys here, they are.
Right?
Yeah.
Shut up.
Oh, I love my wife. I love my wife.
What'd you get?
Springsteen. Playing the Meadowlands.
Lady got me tickets for when I get back.
Huh? Right?
Nice.
- Yo, 29 days and counting, man.
- That's right. You bet your ass.
What about you, Bill?
You got plans?
Yeah, yeah. I got some plans.
Billy the Beaut, huh?
Some things don't change.
You ever think about,
maybe, quality over quantity?
Pick a winner. Settle down.
God made me this way for a reason, bro.
It'd be wrong not to share the wealth,
- you know what I'm saying?
- "Share the wealth."
- You know what we should do?
- What's that?
Know what we should do?
Frank's gonna head home
and read his kids a bedtime story.
At ease.
Need you gentlemen for a briefing.
Five minutes.
Sir.
This terrain means...
we won't be able to land near the compound
without alerting the enemy,
so we're gonna land here,
north of this ridge. Move in on foot.
Once both teams are in position,
we'll hit the compound.
No air support?
This is a clandestine mission, Lieutenant Russo.
Air support would negate that.
You got something to add, Castle?
Sir, this looks like an ambush.
And what do you base
that sound factual analysis on, Castle?
This man has been a target for months.
His whereabouts are finally confirmed.
We're not gonna get this chance again.
So what now? He's just here? He's...
He's just waiting to be caught
where there's no easy exfil?
Where the terrain makes it a death trap?
You got any idea what they call teams like ours?
They call us the American Taliban.
Because we go in, the middle of the night,
people disappear.
We have been doing it for a year, all right?
Now, look, they know about us.
They want us dead.
I think this is a trap.
I think it's a trap
because it's exactly what I would do.
Russo?
I trust Frank's instincts, sir.
And I trust hard-earned,
thoroughly vetted intelligence.
I'll take my information over the vague
notions of the war whisperer over here.
Listen, asshole.
Let me tell you something.
- You don't have operational command--
- This is--
Wind it down, lieutenants.
Last I checked, neither of you were in command.
Sir.
Prep your teams.
I think if we do this, men are gonna die.
I pointed. Now you need to go shoot.
- Sir.
- Dust off at 2300.
- Now get the hell out of here.
- Roger.
Once they get those mortars ranged in,
they're gonna pound us into the ground.
I'm going through that building.
Clear a path for an evac.
- You out of your mind?
- What do you wanna do?
You wanna die here? Like a rat in a jar?
It's about time I had a fair fight.
- I'm going.
- Then I'm coming with you.
You gotta stay here. Keep him safe.
- What are you talking about? That's crazy.
- Bill, you stay here.
Keep him safe. Cover.
Frank.
I gotta get home to the boss. I gotta go.
Move.
How you doing, sir?
Reap what you sow, eh, Frank?
Gonna do some reaping of my own.
You just don't bleed out, you hear me?
I'm gonna get you home, sir.
I'm gonna get you home.
Cover!
Covering!
♪ Country, I was a soldier for you ♪
♪ Did what you asked me to
It was wrong, and you knew ♪
♪ Country ♪
♪ Now I'm just a stranger to you ♪
♪ A number, a name ♪
♪ It's true... ♪
Come on!
♪ Home of the brave and the free
The red white and blue ♪
♪ Well, I wish it was true ♪
♪ Boy, come on out from the cold ♪
♪ You're lost outside there ♪
♪ Don't you know? ♪
♪ It's not what you say ♪
♪ It's what you do ♪
♪ Just keep wishing your wishes ♪
♪ Are true ♪
♪ Well, your dreams ♪
♪ They're reality ♪
♪ There's no pain, there's no misery ♪
♪ Just polish the blood and the bruise ♪
♪ There's just no way you can lose ♪
♪ Well, I wish it was true ♪
Did you get him?
Did you kill the target?
What'd you say?
- What'd you say, you piece of shit?
- Whoa, whoa.
You did this!
- You did this, you hear me?
- Back up!
I'll kill you!
You did this! You did this!
You want to kill the man?
I cannot let you do that.
- Stand down!
- Why you protecting that piece of shit?
I'm protecting you.
Guys like that, it's never on them!
No. No, don't...
Don't touch... Don't touch me.
Open your eyes, man.
This whole thing...
This whole thing is bullshit!
You don't like the way that it smells?
Get out! I am.
I requested a transfer back to Force.
I can't. We... We can't do this anymore!
Let's... let's get out.
I mean, look at us.
Frank!
Look at yourself.
Bill.
You could have ended it all that night.
You didn't, and then they killed your family.
You have to live with that.
But this war that you're waging, I mean, come on.
That's the US military. That is the CIA.
You just got rolled over by one spook
zip-tied to an office chair, here.
I mean, I thought I needed you,
but you need me just as bad.
Look...
I've spent months and months hacking into
every agency and their server.
Phone companies, police departments,
it doesn't matter.
Anything they can throw at us,
I can throw it right back at 'em.
- I've been getting ready for you, Frank.
- What does that mean?
What does that mean? It means that
every missile needs a guidance system.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- Okay?
Without me, you're just a blunt instrument.
Yeah, blow me off. Yeah. Do it.
Blow me off. That's right.
Damn it.
Sit down.
- Ah...
- Get in.
Don't be proud. Get in.
I want to show you something.
- Come on. Get in.
- Ah, damn it.
You son of a bitch.
You know, that heroin was just financing
for something else.
Your Operation Cerberus...
...doesn't exist.
There's no official record.
There's no congressional approval.
It's totally off the books.
You know what that means?
They turned you into a hit man, Frank.
Now, I don't care if we trust each other or not.
I don't wanna be blood brothers.
That stuff is for kids in tree houses.
But you and me, we want the same thing right now.
So work with me.
One condition.
- Yeah, name it.
- They die.
Yeah?
Every single one of 'em. No trials.
No bullshit.
They die.
Yeah, I can live with that.