Hold it
Hey!
What the fuck you're doing?
Disturbing our guests?
You make us look bad.
Ming, you get that fucker to the
back row and keep an eye on him
Freedom in China
Your old man's death had ...
nothing to do with the revolution
My old man died for nothing
I have a little gift for you
Thanks
Just look after my things around here
Fucking asshole, Gwai-Lo ( foreigner)
You want me to do the translation?
Yeah, just answer him for me
Wait! Whose family you're with?
I'm Gum Wong, Kim Wong's brother.
Wang Cho gave me this job, and he...
Please, big brother, please
Shut up.  Go to work.
Hey, homie, this ain't your post
Go back and get another cart
Don't you hear me?
Move the stuff, and remember...
Come
Everyone stays alert
Over here, take care of them, hurry
(Tau) Junior, take care of them!
Hurry, burn down the factory
Hey, remember, don't leave a thing behind
Watch it, coming from the right
Hit him!