This is not
a foundry worker's hand.
If you work with steel,
you should be used to the heat.
I want Rosta! Viktor Rosta!
-He left!
-Where?
Druzhba Cafe!
It's getting harder.
Ten years ago, no drugs.
Now we have a problem.
Another 10 years, it'll be like Miami.
It'll never happen.
You're wrong.
You know your new nickname?
The officers called you Iron Jaw...
...but after the fight in the snow,
they call you Roundheaded.
Actually, I'm circumcised myself.
How's your cold?
Awful. Did your mother teach you
any home remedies?
Try holding a hot rock in your hand.
All right, listen.
You go first and I'll stay behind.
To make sure our men
are positioned properly.
Let's get them.
Everything's okay.
No problem, officer.
Let's go. All of you.
Why do you always
pick on us Georgians?
We are just simple people.
Maybe that is why
we are such easy prey.
What's this country coming to?!
This is like the old days!
We are not guilty of anything!
Where is your evidence?
I got his brother in the leg.
Freeze! You are under arrest!
Drop your gun!
Now!
Handcuffs would be a good Idea.
Our informants...
...say Rosta fled the county
with two other criminals...
...Josip Baroda
and Pytor Tatamovich.
Well find him.
Hell pay far his crimes
against the people.
We're in business.
Yes, top priority.
I'm expecting confirmation.
We'll take extreme precaution.
Take this to Colonel Kulikov
immediately.
Then send for Captain Danko.
He is to report as soon as possible.
Good news, comrade.
America.
Chicago. Gangster.
You are being given
a great responsibility, captain.
Viktor has been arrested
for a minor offense.
His two accomplices
are still at large.
Viktor was organizing a huge
cocaine shipment from America.
Our informants say
5 million dollars' worth.
Bring Viktor home.
Bring him home.
But don't tell the Americans.
I repeat, tell the Americans nothing.
Do not discuss our problems.
Bring Viktor to us.
We will avenge Yuri...
...and protect ourselves
from the poison of the West.
Trust me.
Stand up.
I'm taking you home.
Eat shit.
What is this key to?
Kiss my ass.
Comrade Captain Danko,
this is Comrade Consul Stepanovich.
I am Moussorsky,
your liaison officer.
We're here from Washington.
We took the first flight
when we heard the news.
We need to know what happened.
Moscow must get a full report
when we return to Washington.
There's nothing to report.
Your attitude is disappointing.
He got away.
Get the details from the Americans.
They ask too many questions.
It could be an embarrassment.
Rosta escaped
because of your stupidity.
Rosta will finish his deal
and send the American poison home...
...through his Georgian network.
We are humiliated before the world.
You've failed.
Report whatever you want.
I've already cabled Internal Affairs.
Take the first plane to Moscow
when you leave the hospital.
Your superiors want to see you...
...the moment you land.
Greetings, comrade.
We meet in strange places.