Since Mary, Queen of Scotland, was a child,
the English wanted her
country and her crown.
She is sent to France to wed its next King
to save herself and her people,
a bond that should protect her.
But there are forces that conspire,
forces of darkness, forces of the heart.
Long may She Reign.
Previously on Reign...
I don't know if I'm ready.
To leave here? Or marry the
future King of France?
You will wed young Francis
for your faith, for your
people, for Scotland.
She's here doing her job,
and her job is waiting for me to decide
when you should marry her.
What matters is what's
right for my country.
You don't want to marry me.
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com
We've no quarrel with the English.
We're just farmers. But...
You're welcome to share our breakfast.
You're going to need a lot of eggs.
A few grains should help you sleep.
But only a few and not every night.
What?
Nostradamus.
What are you seeing?
War.
And the cost of war.
- Where?
- I don't know.
But wherever it is, it
will reach inside this castle.
All right, Kenna.
It's your turn. Not your first
but your best kisser.
It was a man, not a boy.
Who? You must tell us.
All I'll say is that there's no point
in waiting for boys our own age
who have no idea what they're doing.
Either find yourself a man or...
Take care of your needs yourself.
Anyway,
I think that it's Greer's turn, isn't it?
My first kiss...
...is in the very near future.
I'm not like you.
My family's not titled.
I can't afford even little mistakes.
But... I think I've found the man.
He's tall, dark and noble.
Tomas, the son of the King of Portugal.
He's here negotiating some
kind of trade deal,
but he's taking his time
about it, and I think it's to stay with me.
Greer, it's dangerous to
get involved with a prince.
You know they marry for alliances.
Your family are commoners.
Tomas is a King's bastard, like Bash.
Favored, too, but with money and land.
I'm not a fool. I know a true royal
would never look at me except to ruin me.
I can take care of myself.
Your Majesty,
Your Uncle,
Claude de guise, is here and wishes
to see you at once.
You look well, Mary.
Your mother sends her
affection. Read it later.
You may be assured the
love is in there, as is the news
of a crisis in Scotland.
- The English.
- They're massing on the border.
And these are not the normal skirmishes.
They're out in number. They're
looking for weakness,
- and if they find any...
- We must respond with strength.
Yes.
Surely my mother has sent soldiers.
Of course. But not enough.
We need more men.
Our strongest ally is France.
- King Henry will help us.
- He's been asked,
and he's been slow to answer.
You were sent here to secure
the alliance by marrying
Henry's son. Now they're dragging
their feet. What happened?
Nothing happened.
They're being politicians.
Francis and his father
aren't eager to commit to Scotland.
They'd rather keep me in a drawer,
like a pair of gloves for cold weather.
And then when the
weather grows cold for France,
they'll take me out and I'll be wed.
They're afraid of what a
permanent bond might mean.
But right now, we have immediate problems.
Scotland needs more troops.
As Queen, you must do something.
Mary.
Your Grace.
We've been...
discussing this business in Scotland.
You have my sympathy.
Father, I believe Her Majesty is
here for more than just sympathy.
Of course. We're sending wagons, gunpowder,
- supplies for your army...
- Supplies are useless without men.
Surely you can spare a few.
- You have so many more soldiers than we do.
- And...
Many more borders as well.
You only have to worry about England.
I have England, Spain,
a hundred Italian and
German principalities...
You are supposed to be our ally.
If our positions were
reversed, Scotland would help.
Mary, I'm sorry.
Eight companies.
- Six!
- I hope I will have
the happiness of seeing you tonight
at the entertainments.
Yes?
I hope you understand
the position you're putting us in.
Lives will be lost.
She only asked for six companies.
And what if we lose those companies?
We look weak in England's eyes.
So we send more and we
lose those. When do we stop?
Before or after England
decides we're soft prey?
At the moment, the
Scottish border is quicksand.
You know this.
A pretty girl doesn't change that fact,
even if she happens to be your fiancée.
And their Queen.
Mary.
Mary, my father just...
- The political situation is complicated.
- Complicated?
People will be dying soon. Isn't
that complicated enough?
Mary, I agree with you.
- You do?
- I think France should help Scotland in this.
We're at a tilting point:
If England invades Scotland and succeeds,
it'll be that much of a
stronger enemy to France.
Then we're on the same side.
For all the good it does.
One day, if things goes well,
we'll rule France and
Scotland and we'll be together.
Now we have no real power.
We have to wait.
No.
I'm tired of waiting.
And if we have no power,
then we must find a way of getting some.
Come play with me?
Happily.
Sometimes you just need to kick something.
You're not like a girl.
What did you think girls were like?
They sit around, afraid
they're gonna mess up their dresses.
You like to have fun.
It's stuck.
Maybe you should
fetch someone with a ladder.
Wait, I've got it!
Your Majesty,
may I present Tomas of Portugal,
lord of palmela? Tomas,
Mary, Queen of Scots.
Hello.
Do you often stroll in trees, Your Majesty?
Um, I climbed up here to
fetch prince Charles' ball,
but I guess he got tired of waiting.
Are you sure? Because from down here,
it looks like Scotland
attacked Portugal without provocation.
Um, turn around
- so I can come down.
- We may have a diplomatic incident here, Your Majesty.
Greer, please get
your friend to turn around.
I can't climb down with
him staring up my skirts.
Your arm!
I'll be fine.
Are you all right?
Yes. I'm so sorry.
Just promise, no more attacks from the sky.
Portugal surrenders.
Greer of Kinross,
I look forward to seeing you tonight.
Your Majesty.
I might not have made a
very good first impression,
but I see why you like him.
Isn't he perfect?
I have it all planned.
The boating party's coming up.
I'll pack a picnic basket,
we'll be out there on the
lake under the moonlight.
And nature will take its course.
Your first kiss. And a beginning, I hope.
Well, good luck.
He definitely looks worth the wait.
Your mind's elsewhere.
Is it slender lady
Charlotte or plump lady Isabelle
- with the breasts like two pigeons?
- If I told you,
you might poach. You've a
liking for pigeon, as I recall.
We should help Scotland.
Not for Mary but for France.
By all means, explain.
When you say that the border is quicksand,
you assume that we'll lose.
England hasn't sent its entire army north.
They're poking to see
what reaction they get.
We could strike fast,
hit back hard and win.
But if we do nothing,
we risk losing the
entire Scottish alliance.
Years of planning, wasted.
So it's a balance of risks either way.
Very good.
Except I've decided the...
Reasons against outweigh the reasons for.
And guess what:
I'm King.
Another round?
You never spar with me.
Is it a good idea for a
King to spar with his usurper?
You mean his inheritor.
If you win,
I shut up about this whole subject.
If I win, you send those
six companies of men.
Very good.
When can they leave?
No one's going to Scotland.
But your word, your wager.
Well, that's what Kings do.
We make promises to everybody,
and whatever works for the realm, we keep.
Otherwise, they never happened.
Lesson for today.
- That's not the way...
- Don't need any more lessons right now.
Bread...the seeded kind.
I'm not talking about everyday black bread.
Chestnut spread. Strawberry tartlets.
Strawberries this late?
I can make you apple tarts.
Everyone has apple. I
wanted something different.
Talk to God.
- He put the strawberries away.
- Fine.
But I want the apple tarts
that have the honey on top.
Baked, so they're golden brown,
not soggy, to taste fresh
and crisp after two
hours in a boat on the lake.
You want an awful lot...
this must be for someone special.
Not that it's
any of your business, but yes,
it's for someone very special.
I expect your best.
- Why don't you just leave the list.
- But who would read it to you?
Greer? I've been
looking for you everywhere.
You said Tomas was in from Portugal
to negotiate a trade deal.
- What kind of deal?
- I don't know.
Something about buying
French timber for ships.
That makes sense.
They're expanding their fleet...war ships,
exploring vessels for the new world.
Of course they need timber.
Why are we talking about wood?
Because it occurred to me
that if a Queen can't
command what she needs,
maybe she can buy it.
May I know where you're
taking me, Your Majesty?
I didn't want to be overheard.
Intriguing.
Is it romantic?
Conspiratorial?
May I have a hint?
It's about timber.
- Timber?
- Timber.
Scotland has trees, too, you know.
Whatever deal you have with King Henry,
I'll do better...if you close the deal now
and if you send us men instead of money.
Your country is in need.
But surely, King Henry will help you.
I mean, the alliance.
I see.
Well, my father
The King empowered me
to make whatever deal I think best.
And I'd be a fool to turn this down.
But... Henry
considers our deal almost made.
And it's not a small thing to anger a King
in his own house.
Meet me this afternoon.
I'll confirm our transaction then.
Now.
The guards are discreet.
I want to be with you completely,
as a woman, but...
...as a girl, I need more time.
How long?
When you're ready.
It's an old church, made by Louis vii.
Meant to last forever,
but... nothing does.
Why have you brought me here?
I wanted your advice.
I sent for this from my ship in the bay.
The new world has brought us wealth...
Beyond imagining.
Do you think these might make a woman
think kindly of me?
I think you might have a chance, yeah.
I'm glad you think so.
I don't understand.
I thought you and-and Greer were...
What does Greer have to do with this?
She's a lovely girl, but...
I've seen you...
And I can't look away.
There is... there's a wildness in you,
as you play...
Ride, as you climb trees.
I see your spirit...
And I believe it's like mine.
Just thoughts I would have kept to myself,
but I see your struggle here in France.
Left to solve your problems alone.
I'd never do that.
Never.
Wed me.
Wed me, and I won't make you wait.
Say yes, and you'll have your men.
Say yes.
Tomas... y-you're kind,
you're handsome,
You're very charming...
I sense a refusal.
But I am a Queen.
And flattered as I am by your attentions,
I must marry a nation,
not a man.
What is this?
My father's been writing
to the pope, arranging to
have me declared legitimate.
My father is dying, and
I'm his only living son.
His grandson is next in line,
and he's only three years old.
My father doesn't trust the regent
to safe guard Portugal.
He wants me on the throne.
The announcement will be made any day now.
So, you see...
I can lay my heart at your feet,
and my country as well.
We can save Scotland.
If you marry me.
Will you?
A real proposal from The Future King?
What does your uncle think?
I haven't told him yet.
Because you're worried
he'd press you to accept Tomas,
and you're not ready to let Francis go?
It's all right to admit it, Mary.
I'd be exchanging a man I...
Admire... For a man I barely know.
And true support for Scotland.
Tomas seems nice. Feelings may come
in time. And what of Greer's feelings?
She had her eye on
Tomas. A crown prince would
never marry her... she's
not even a possibility.
Well, it's entirely possible
that nothing will come of it,
and that Tomas will
return home to Portugal.
I asked him to be discreet
while I considered the proposal.
Your vision.
Do you know yet
how the warfare you saw
will reach inside the castle?
No.
Maybe you saw the fighting in Scotland.
If Mary weds my son
and it causes his death, as you predicted,
this castle will see violence
within its walls
like none before.
Tell me exactly what you saw.
You look lovely.
Is the King still
refusing to send the men we need?
I've pushed as hard as I can.
Well, I know you've done your best.
- Thank you.
- Mary...
Nostradamus.
Why don't you share your
wisdom with all of us.
I don't understand.
Always at my wife's ear.
What do you whisper?
I hear emperor maximilian
has a seer in Prague who can...
Tell fortunes using playing cards.
Tell the fortunes of Queen Mary
and her ladies.
Forgive me, Your Majesty,
but I'm not skilled at cards and
I don't control my visions.
They come and go as they will.
You're not as good
as maximilian's seer?
- Leave him alone, Henry.
- Come,
the man must have
something to recommend him
since you rely so deeply on his counsel.
Each of you pick a card.
Have your question ready.
Will I ever love again?
You'll meet a dark, handsome stranger.
Be wary of flattery.
Life will offer
many challenges.
You'll meet them with grace.
Well, that's not very specific.
Give us a fortune,
not a platitude.
Or is that the best you can do?
The lion will fight the
dragon on the field of poppies.
What?
The lion will fight the
dragon on the field of poppies.
- Who will I...?
- You'll fall in love
with a man with a white mark on his face.
When will I see my family?
You'll never go home.
What do you mean "Never go home"?
That's all I was given.
You know no more than I.
Well,
there's a showman for you.
Musicians, dancing music.
Enough of this foolishness.
Why would you say that to my friend?
Why scare her?
I can only say what I've seen.
Like a dragon and a field of poppies?
Are people fooled by you?
The only dragons are in children's stories.
Then I must be a liar.
But why these lies?
Who gains?
The fortune-telling was Henry's idea,
so it can't have come from Catherine.
Who are you and who do you serve?
The realm... Myself, the truth.
The truth?
Serving the truth at court
is a crooked path.
You know, I don't think I ever noticed
that tiny white scar on your cheek.
It becomes you.
Thank you.
Would you excuse me?
Mary,
believe me, I've argued with my father.
I've explained why politically
it's a good idea.
I've, I've done more than argue.
I've done all I can reasonably do.
Then maybe you should be unreasonable.
I commanded the musicians
to play music from my country.
Allow me.
Why don't you dance like that?
Shut up.
Apparently they do
things differently in Portugal.
I love this Portuguese music.
Keep playing.
Not what I meant by "Discreet."
Greer, don't be upset.
It was just a dance.
I'm not upset because of a dance.
I'm not upset at all.
I'm just going back to my room.
I'm not feeling well.
Please, let's talk.
There's no need.
You're my Queen.
You're rich and you're beautiful
and you're engaged to the crown prince
of France.
I thought perhaps you
could leave Tomas for me.
It's not as if you could marry him anyway.
You knew how important this was to me.
It just wasn't important to you.
No, Greer...
You do have a way of
leaving chaos in your wake.
What was that about?
Tomas asked me to marry him.
He's being declared legitimate.
He says his father wants
him on the throne imminently.
It's not what I want,
but my options are extremely limited.
You went behind our back?
You're making a new alliance with Portugal?
It was his idea, not mine,
and he's willing to
actually get married, too,
which is more than your family is offering.
You can't just
- break an alliance.
- I don't want to.
You said that we had no power,
that there was nothing we could do.
I don't like it but I found a way.
If France won't help us,
then I will have no choice
but to accept Portugal's offer.
His name is Tomas.
You'd be marrying the man,
not the country.
It's what my mother will want...
...and what my country needs.
I never thought, you know.
Thought what?
My first marriage.
I married for love
and I loved her deeply.
She died of influenza.
I'm sorry.
When I learned my father planned
to make me his heir, I thought,
my next union is sure to be arranged,
my life nothing but politics,
but then I saw you in a tree.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Your father is a confusing man.
Yes, he is.
It's not a reflection on you personally,
but my family will need to confirm
all that you've said.
I understand you're not ready to trust me.
You needn't wait for confirmation
from Portugal.
My ship in the bay has several
companies of men.
They can leave for
Scotland on tomorrow's tide.
So quickly?
I know you're the woman I want
and I'll do whatever it
takes to keep from losing you.
What are you doing here?
Returning the basket.
So, how did it go, lady
only the special cheese for me?
Your important friend like it?
Is he a punishing man if he doesn't get
the exact thing he
wants the moment he wants it?
Hard to imagine a more uncomfortable
conversation
- about one's father.
- You don't even know what I'm talking about specifically.
I know exactly what you're talking about.
His attention drifted to you
and now it's drifting elsewhere.
Am I right?
He's not punishing you, he's playing you.
He likes to play and he likes to win,
but know this about him:
A victory without
effort is worse than a defeat.
If the Scottish alliance is worth saving,
we need to send troops.
We've had this talk before.
Not quite.
I see the way that you
look at the Lady Kenna
and the way that she looks at you.
I know your pattern.
Now, I'm not sure that you've
slept with her yet.
What's this?
But I wonder how your Medici wife
and, more important to
you, your French mistress
will react when they find out
that you moved in on a new girl.
I think we both know that
Diane and my mother
have a way of making life very
difficult when they wish,
even for a King.
Finally.
Very well, King in waiting.
- I'm not...
- We'll try it your way.
Win or lose, you will answer for it.
That's what Kings do.
There are six companies of men
quartered between us and the channel.
You'll send our
fastest rider to mobilize them.
Do you know who our fastest rider is?
Send a message to all six captains.
Tell them that
they'll board ship at outreau.
Are you sure you're all right to ride?
I am a riding fiend, little brother.
You'll be happy, Scotland will be happy,
Mary will be happy, and Mary will stay.
Just be careful.
Aren't I always?
Well, if always means never.
Hyah!
So this goat just goes running off.
As for my father, he's
shouting, "Catch him! Catch him!"
I chased that damned goat
over half the mountaintop.
And I decided, no more sheep and goats.
Indoor work for me.
Mind you, when I go home,
that goat still shares
our house in the winter.
There's no escape.
I can't say I've ever lived with a goat.
Didn't think so, where you come from.
But my father keeps hounds.
They're all over the house, all the time.
I think he cares more about the hounds
than my mother and my sisters.
Is that why he sent you so
far away, with Queen Mary?
He sent me here to be married.
I have to marry well, for my family's sake.
My parents made that very clear to me.
The only way to rise in the world
is through land and title,
and for people like us,
the only way to achieve these
things is to marry them.
So, love has no place in your life?
I hope it will,
but I have four younger
sisters counting on me, as well.
If I rise, they rise.
You should have been there when
they saw me off to France.
They looked at me
the way my father looks at an investment,
wondering if I'll fail, or pay off.
Well, I'm sorry you have to live this way.
I never...
I shouldn't...
Nor should you.
You're a servant.
Nothing can ever happen between us.
But it did.
Mary, it's done.
Six companies are on their
way to Scotland tonight.
What? Francis!
But how? You said the
King wouldn't change his mind,
that you'd done all you could.
I suppose I was inspired.
I can't believe it.
I still can't offer to
marry you right away, like Tomas.
You'd have a secure alliance there.
Here, we can only hope.
Some day it will be
right for our countries.
I would rather have hope with you
than certainty anywhere else.
Morning.
What's this?
You've been avoiding me,
so I thought I would try and bribe you
with this new venetian drink.
It's coffee.
I'm sorry.
The truth is,
there never really was
much between Tomas and me.
Some flirting...
all very proper... but that's it.
I wanted to believe there was more.
Well, you know why.
I imagined the whole fairytale.
The perfect first kiss with
the man with the white mark on his face.
Me as the heroine, helping my family.
I know you'll find the right man, Greer.
I know you will.
Should I tell you a secret?
Maybe it's because I've
been engaged since I was six, but
I've never been kissed, either.
Well, actually,
things have changed for me in that respect.
What?! No! Who is it? Tell me everything!
Morning.
I suppose I should send
down for breakfast then.
No. By all means, I'll go.
Coffee?
And we want the sweet butter,
not the other kind.
And try putting some heavy cream
in that coffee, but for heaven's sake,
not goat's milk cream.
I'll take care of it.
Lovely morning, my Lady.
Our men will have
gone north to the channel.
Calais is in English hands,
so our men will take ship at outreau.
Guards?
Quickly!
It's Bash.
The cost of war will
reach inside this castle.
- How is he?
- He's gravely injured.
I can tend to his wounds,
ease the pain, but I make no guarantees.
Father,
the English...
Rode out from Calais
to face us.
We never made it to the ships.
It was a slaughter.
He shouldn't be talking.
I'm give him a potion, put him to sleep.
Clear the room. It's the best
- thing for him.
- Bash?
Bash, I'm so sorry.
Come.
Go wait.
Kings don't apologize.
I didn't know this would happen,
but I knew it was a risk. So did you.
Lives are always at
risk, at our hand, at our will.
For a prince, this was a...
A cheap lesson.
Cheap? Six companies.
Your son... I know you love him.
You were influenced by your heart.
If that happens when you are King,
you could lose 10,000 men.
You could lose France.
The English were ready for us.
- Someone told them.
- Yes.
While Bash was riding to
six different companies,
it appears someone loyal to
the English rode straight to calais
and warned them.
Well, aren't you going to tell Francis?
No. Not today.
It would ruin the lesson.
Let something come of this treachery.
Francis will never trust his heart again.
That's the only way to rule.
Francis?
You did the right thing.
Talk to me.
You should marry Tomas.
My father's right.
- I haven't been thinking clearly.
- That's not true.
You were trying to help.
I can't help you.
France can't help.
There are no more troops to send.
Do what's right for your country.
- Francis!
- Can you say that I'm wrong?
Well...
I suppose you're going to
have to teach me Portuguese.
I'll make you happy.
You already have.
There are eight companies of
fighting men on that ship.
They'll be in Scotland in two days.
The English lion will fight
the dragon on the field of poppies.
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com