Abbot, is he doing it well?
Depending of the mind which, in its discretion that the development
Very self in
Mediation through martial arts.  In his heart,
he is beyond the need for revenge or hatred now
I don't know martial arts,
I don't understand these things
Martial arts is meditation, cooking is also meditation
The theory is roughly the same
WuDao, people need a lot of experiences and practice
I've said it many times
Leave Shaolin, and go see the world
All I know is how to cook
Out there, I'm of no use
I'm not going
A piece of gold, a pile of dirt
Which one is useful?
I pick the piece of gold
And if I gave you a seed?
Don't sell yourself short
Everyone is useful in their own way
CaoMan, you want us to help the foreigners build the railway
But don't forget, Mang Mountain
is the burial plot for our ancestors
Disturbing the dirt will destroy the fengshui
I will not agree
If you are really going to do it, I have nothing to say
I'm just worried that the foreigners are playing us
and making deals under the table
CaoMan, your betrayal of Hou,
We don't care
But he previously said that
building the railway is just a cover
With the intention to take our land
OK, enough talking
HeNan province's interests are not for one man to decide
But looking at CaoMan's attitude, it seems he's already
made an agreement with the foreigners
There was no intention to hear us out
Leave
Listen well.  Going against me
has no advantage
They are fortunate
But their family members
Will die much more horrible deaths
Being my friend or my enemy
is for you to decide
Have a think,
If there is money to be made, no--one loses out
How come he still hasn't returned?
Auntie, stop crying, OK?
Crying won’t bring him back any sooner
What's happened?
Our DaNiu has been missing for over 20 days now
What should I do?
CaoMen builds the railway
We all rely on him
Work quickly
You hear?
Quickly, quickly
Who?
What are you doing?
Commander Hou
Why did you kill this many people?
It was Commander Cao's orders
Leave
Hou is alive, Hou is alive
CaoMan said build the railway
Who knew he was really digging for artefacts for the foreigners
Every one we found, we gave to them
In exchange for rifles and cannons
He was worried it might leak it out,
so he killed all the witnesses
CaoMen still has many workers locked up
After work tomorrow, they're all going to be killed
I'm sorry
Why don't you go home?
Quick, we're going
A Niu, A Niu ...
Go have a look
What is this?
???
Enough
ShenNan
The use of any specific misconduct
How can my daughter be dead?
Purity more numerous data
Learning to let go of everything
Will you understand how to face things
From today, the third refuge in self--protection
???
From now, your Buddhist name is JingJue
amitabha!
Brothers... Brothers..
It's CaoMan; I'm going to stop him
Come back
Sit
Be cool minded
He's come at a good time
In a while, I'll delay him
After sunset, go to Cao Fort
Rescue them
You go
It's suicide either way
If I can exchange my life to save that many
So what if I die
JingJue, you must be careful
Halt
Don't move
amitabha!
Please put down your weapons
Also create extreme evil, all the evil results
That was from my daughter
amitabha!
Still my brother indeed
I knew you wouldn't die that easily
Brother, I think of you terribly
Thinking of me?
If I don't die, you can't sleep, right?
Don't be ridiculous
Nothing of the sort
Don't pretend
You're afraid I will take you down
JingJue's actions are to buy us time
So we can save lives
Your impulsiveness will ruin the plan
Understand?
You taught me
When you're at an advantage, and you stay your hand
The person who dies is you
I remember
Tell your troops to back down, I'll go with you
String the Abbot up
Do anything rash, and I'll send him to heaven
It's OK, all of you backing off
Do it
True beauty
You must deliver it before sunrise to ZhongZhou province
Relax
With Cao's troops, no one will dare block our way
Careful
Move it, move it
Get down, you
Quickly
Hurry
Brother, this is better than before right?
Bringing me here
wasn't just for me to praise you, was it?
Of course not
I was wrong.  Please forgive me
I hope that Brother can once again take me under his wing
Conquer the world, and achieve great things
Brother, look
This was all for you
This royal seat is yours
These imperial robes are also yours
Brother
Is money and power that important to you?
Listen
Don't be like me
False compassion
I was messing with you
Let see how you play
I have something I want to give to you
Bring her out
I found your wife
And kept her alive so you could be reunited
You've suffered
I used to think I was very impressive
and able to care for you
But I ended up doing you harm
Ready
Don't shoot
Steady!!
Fire
Guards stay, the rest follow me
GO
Please help us...
You men, go see what's happening out front
The artefacts are being stolen, chase them
Get off
Hou
Let go of her
Brother
You're crying
Let her go
Even your death
won't satisfy me
You watched your daughter die
Now I want you to watch your wife die
Then I can be happy
Let her go you animal
Let her go
Auntie is so beautiful.  What a shame
You're a monk
CaoMan, stop it
Commander, the monks have stolen the artefacts
and set free the workers
You deceived me
Shoot him!
JingJue, go
Go
1st Master
Go go
Go
1st Master
go
Run away
Christian Brothers University
Christian Brothers University ...
Are you not listening to my orders now?
Leave
Let's go
Go, now let's take her child to run away
What are you doing?
Go back
Abbot
This
Little monk, don't force me
I just want you to go back inside
I don't want to kill children
Sir, please open your compassion
and let us save the Abbot
You will gain wealth and happiness
Sir, Abbot always says
A brave man knows when to change
Let it be.  Go back home
I'm sure your family is waiting for you
What is this nonsense?
You want to resist?  Catch them
amitabha!
Don't fight, I don't know Kung Fu
No more fighting
No ... more ... fighting
I'll fight you with my life
Abbott
Are you OK?
Uncle Master, treat him like you're cooking a meal
Uncle Master, fight him with your noodle making skill
Brother, good!
Abbott... Abbott..
Are you alright?
Let's go back
Okay, go!
It's them
Hu Kwan..
Mum
Father
JingNeng's sacrifice was not in vain
You all, no need to feel guilty
Ladies and gentlemen, please ready and pack your things
We are leaving Shaolin
I know you are scared
I am not
Loved ones gone, families lost
Who wouldn't be scared?
These days
I feel just like you
Shaolin is a place of happiness
And it is our home
It is possible that
Shaolin will end today
But the spirit of Shaolin
Every flower, grass
brick and plate
will stay in our hearts
The spirit of Shaolin
taught me perseverance and dignity
I have something to ask of you
What is it?
For you to lead them out of here
No no no
I've never stepped out of Shaolin
No no no, I'm scared
You're scared
Look at them
They need you
They are more scared than you
I, I am the leader now?
Yes..
Ok! I'll lead!
Move quickly
We must safely escort them to the mountains
JingHai, you go first with the Abbot
JingKong, you lead, I'll follow soon
We go!!
I'll give them my all
Go quickly
You fool, you want to destroy Shaolin?
I'll destroy you
CaoMan, wake up to yourself
You must know!
What you have far exceeds what you will ever need
Let it go.  Do not pursue this violent path
We fight wars; it's always been like this
Don't be like me
Realizing my mistakes after they were done
It's time to stop
Can we not fight?
What do you think?
I lose
They took my treasure.
We need to cut the loses
We cannot allow the news of what has happend to leak out
Kill every one in there!!
Fire!
Shaolin Temple..
Shaolin Temple, should not be humiliated
My god is compassionate
Madam, you can't leave, it's dangerous
Abbot, my child is missing
My child is missing
Mum
Brothers, Brothers
Come on, brothers
Brother
Brother ... A Hai ....
amitabha!
Brothers, Brothers
Brother
Brothers ...
I'll stay; you take them to a safe place
Abbot
It's time you woke up
Don't let go
amitabha!
Psychological and drug
To repent
Why?
Brother, The Temple is no more..
Never mind, the Temple forever in our hearts, can't be destroyed
Let him accompany you
Do you really don't want to go?
CaoMan has came
His fault is my fault too.
Now I want to help him.
You are really different now.
I know..
We really have no chance to live together.
But..
I will stay here waiting for you
Subtitle by Kizoku