Let's get a bit of a breeze going.
That pupil of yours really is naughty.
Look at him playing tricks
right under our noses!
Now I've got to start all over again.
Night shift again, Yilang?
Yeah, worst luck!
Why, you've already been doing
the night shift for a fortnight.
Well, I'm not as fortunate as you.
Go and get some rest.
You have not been vigilant enough.
Now that the manual has been stolen,
what am I supposed to say to the Head?
It's all my fault. I have underestimated
the intruder.
He was in fact very skillful.
Otherwise he wouldn't have invaded
the Shaolin Temple.
I suspect that the manual
is not all he wants.
- He must have an ulterior motive...
- Say no more.
My incompetence is to blame
for this scandal.
- I take full responsibility.
- You mustn't blame yourself.
I am to blame.
As the 32nd master of Shaolin,
I can't even look after a manual.
I am not fit to lead Shaolin.
- Master!
- Do not despair, Master.
We need to come up with a strategy.
When all's said and done, its just a book.
"Just a book"? Do you know what
the book in question is?
- Is it the Seven Deadly Fists?
- The Seven Deadly Fists manual.
The 25th Master outlawed those practices,
for that fighting style is too vicious.
Now the manual has been taken,
it could wreak havoc throughout
the community.
I am sure that the founder of Shaolin
must have invented a counter-style.
The Essence of the Five Fists manual
was lost centuries ago.
As for this theft,
I am guilty of negligence.
I am now going into confinement
to meditate and repent.
I shall be here for 100 days.
I shall leave Master Clarity in charge.
You must all obey his orders.
Yes!
You must be vigilant.
We cannot afford any more mistakes.
Take care, Master!
In the name of Amitabha!
Those guarding the library
are all guilty of negligence.
You shall be locked in
the repentance room for three days.
Yes, Brother Purity's team, please.
- And Yilang as well.
- What, me?
I had nothing to do with it.
I was outside sleeping.
- Go in!
- But...
- But, I'm innocent!
- You're unlucky.
Why me?
- Rotten luck.
- In you go, troublemaker!
- Elder, please...
- Just shut up and go in!
But I really am innocent!
I can't cope
with three days' meditation.
Please help me. I was sleeping.
That's not a crime.
- You were asleep on the job!
- I didn't do it on purpose.
I just fell asleep somehow.
You deserve to be punished.
Go and contemplate your deeds.
But Elder, please... Listen!
You deserve to be punished.
There were five of you,
yet he got away.
Now I've got to suffer in here with you.
I always end up
getting punished somehow.
Meditation and repentance, indeed.
What do I need to repent for?
I am not repenting!
Repent, indeed!
Three days without food?
Don't worry!
I'll eat a tiger the minute I get out.
Be good!
Come on!
Now where are you gonna run to?
Where are you going?
Oops! Now it's gone up...
Smells nice!
- What is it?
- Ah, it smells so nice!
I've gone to a lot of trouble
to make this soup.
The main ingredient is
a hen that's never laid any eggs.
How do you know it never laid any eggs?
Don't interrupt! What else has it got in?
Frog... sparrow... carp...
eels, catfish, whelks, duck,
partridge, earthworms...
Earthworms? Are they edible?
You're such a yokel. Earthworms
were the Emperor's favourite.
- Is it ready?
- Can we eat now?
Let me make one thing clear. I won't be
taking the blame if the Elder finds out.
- No, of course not.
- Let's eat.
- Come on!
- Let's enjoy this.
Mind your manners.
- There's just one thing missing.
- What's that?
- Wine!
- I've brought some.
- Where did you get that from?
- It was for Buddha.
You took it from the altar?
- Don't you want any, then?
- Of course. Why waste it?
- Oh, no!
- What?
- I've forgotten...
Dog meat. It'd be so much tastier
if we had some.
- Of course!
- We'll have some next time.
It's good!
It's divine.
Whose recipe is it, Yilang?
What's it called?
- It's a traditional stew.
- Oh, no it isn't.
It was created by Emperor Qianlong.
- It's called Monk Over The Fence.
- That's a strange name.
It smelt so good that a monk
was tempted to...
Monk Over Fence? That's impossible!
You shall be punished for this.
You're not supposed to be
messing about, Yilang.
Brother...
- Can I have a smaller brush?
- No way.
The whole point of being punished
is that you suffer.
This brush weighs a ton!
Where am I now?
The Holy Scriptures...
I've made a mistake.
I'll have to write it out all over again.
Oh, what a clumsy pig!
It looks awful.
Oh, what the hell.
Damn! Not again!
What's that noise?
What's happened?
What's wrong?
I thought the Elder was going easy on me,
getting me to copy out the Scriptures.
It's turned out to be very hard work.
- Look at my poor hand.
- We're sorry, Yilang.
- But we can't help you.
- No.
- I'm doomed.
- Why?
It's taken me a whole day
just to finish half a page.
I've got to make 100 copies.
It'll take centuries to finish.
Look at how thick this book is.
How many pages do you think it's got?
The Seven Deadly Fists?
Your father went to a great deal
of trouble to get it.
We must win the Martial Master title
next year.
Your father says that this manual
is the key to success.
Father, is this style really so powerful?
It can make one invincible.
You must work hard to perfect
the Seven Deadly Fists style.
Thirty years ago,
your father failed to win the competiton
on account of Shaolin's interference.
So, do you see why he expects
so much of you?
Auntie, I promise not to return home
without the title.
You are very courageous. That's my boy.
Once you've mastered
the Seven Deadly Fists,
the title of Master shall stay
in the Luk clan forever.
Didn't you say that there was also
a counter-style to the Seven Deadly Fists?
The Essence of the Five Fists manual
has been lost for centuries.
That is, unless it has returned to Earth
from Heaven.
- What's happened?
- Run!
Let's get out of here!
- What's that?
- Where did they come from?
Hey! Where are you from?
- Let's go a bit closer.
- Go on, then!
Touch it.
- Why is it so cold?
- It's ice-cold.
Ghosts! Make a run for it!
- All right, all right, what's going on?
- Ghosts!
- There are ghosts up there.
- Ghosts? Nonsense.
- I don't believe you.
- Go and see for yourself, then.
THE GOD OF PERFECT VISION
Buddha, your humble servant is here.
Our temple is haunted.
May I borrow your incantation?
I shall return it straightaway.
Excuse me.
I do beg your pardon.
THE GOD OF PERFECT HEARING
Elder, what are you doing?
These incantations can protect me.
They give me superior
vision and hearing.
If the ghosts ever come again...
I'll catch them. Now, get going.
Come on.
- What's he doing?
- No idea.
- You?
- How should I know?
- Shall we ask him?
- All right, then.
Do you have a headache?
A headache? Only when I lay eyes
on you lot.
- The Head Priest ordered us to come.
- All right, then. Now be off with you.
- What are you doing here?
- We're on night watch.
- There are ghosts upstairs.
- That's impossible.
- We touched them and they were ice-cold.
- You saw them?
- It's true.
- You need to see a doctor.
- Yilang, I'm not going.
- How about you?
- And what about you?
- Ask him.
All right, then, cowards. I'll go on my own.
- It's no joke...
- Come here!
The ghosts have red hair
and they're ready for a fight.
Why can't I sleep?
Is this place really haunted?
I'll get one of them to play with me.
Hey, there. Listen to me.
Be you big, small, greedy, wronged,
stupid, naughty, sleazy or whatever.
Just show yourselves, ghosts!
Are you afraid, or what? Come on out.
I'm known for being a rebel myself,
so we're well-matched.
No response?
I might as well get some sleep, then.
What the...?
It wasn't like this before.
Am I dreaming?
Can breath bend?
It really is haunted in here.
I'd better look for the Exorcist's Scriptures.
Now, which one is it?
Oh, what a mess!
Here it is.
Which book?
These ghosts are afraid of books.
What are you playing at, pervert?
I'm not that way inclined!
Why, this ghost's a pervert!
I was almost strangled to death, there.
Time I was off!
So you think that you can stop me, huh?
Want to play, huh? Let's see where
you're off to, then.
Trying to escape? Let me show you
my Kung Fu skills!
Let's go!
Oh, esteemed Elder, the ghosts are here!
- Ghosts?
- Yes.
- Where?
- Over there.
I can see them.
There are five of them in total.
- Five?
- I'll catch them all.
Demons!
How dare you!
Let's see what you're made of, then.
- What is the Elder up to?
- He must be possessed.
Stop right there!
- What is he doing?
- He's gone crazy!
- Where are they?
- What are you looking for?
- Ghosts!
- He's looking for ghosts.
Why, that incantation
is more powerful than an X-ray.
Where are they?
How eerie! Air on my derriere.
So, Elder, can you really
see something, then?
Of course! I can also hear
the ghosts talking.
Can we have a go?
No. I don't think that you have the ability.
- Perhaps we do.
- No way.
- This is the way.
- What are you doing?
- Give it back to me.
- Come and get it.
Give it back! Stop!
Let's take turns.
I'm done for, now.
- Let me see it.
- Don't tear it.
Wait your turn.
Let me take a look.
Don't be so selfish.
Let's share it.
What's wrong with him?
- He's gone crazy.
- What's wrong?
- Don't go!
- I want nothing more to do with this.
What's wrong? Why is he turning back?
Put me down, put me down!
Please, I beg you.
Ooh, I need to go to the loo!
Oh, my God! Run!
What's that noise?
Seems like it's coming from downstairs.
My leg! Help!
Practising in the middle of the night?
Why, he's got to be mad!
It stinks!
How dare you break wind
in my face!
That looks like fun.
Finished so soon?
Got you!
Try and get out of this!
Just give up... What? There are
four more of you?
They're afraid of me.
Hey, you don't know what
you're up against.
You're messing with the wrong man.
I've got a reputation, you know.
Even the Elders can't cope with me.
Right, then. Get up and get out!
Form a line.
Why are you causing trouble here?
Are you seeking justice for something?
You can tell me everything.
I'll sort it out for you.
Cat got your tongue?
What are your names?
What's wrong?
I asked you your names.
What's this supposed to mean?
Dragon?
Your name is Dragon?
And you?
Snake.
Tiger.
Crane.
Leopard. They're all names of beasts.
Dragon, Snake, Tiger, Crane,
Leopard, come here.
You are on trial. Stand up straight!
Now tell me...
Who tried to strangle me earlier on?
Speak!
It was you, was it?
And who pulled my trousers down?
And who took off my shoes?
You again? That's twice.
I can forgive most things, but I hate
having my trousers pulled off.
Now, line up, and I'll give you
forty lashes each.
Stay there.
Hiding, are you?
Now come out from that crevice,
will you?
I'm going to pee.
Frightened, are we?
Still not coming out? Very well.
The Essence of the Five Fists?
Hasn't this been missing for centuries?
It's so worn...
There you are, you cheeky monkeys!
I've got... Why, you're all in here,
aren't you!
Out you come!
One, two, three, four, five.
All present and correct.
Don't even think of hiding in there again.
I'll teach you a lesson!
Stay where you are!
Still want to run?
Now I know where you hide,
if you don't obey me, I'll
burn down your home, understand?
Do you promise to behave?
I've rumbled you. You know
all the moves in the manual, don't you?
Well, I want you to be my masters
and teach me everything.
Stand up properly.
Don't get too cocky, now.
If you don't teach me properly,
I'll beat you up.
What can I do for you?
I hear that you've been chosen
to compete for the Master's title.
- Is it true?
- Yes, it is.
- Do you have the ability?
- I'm not good enough,
but they think highly of me,
so I'll give it a go.
- I advise you against it.
- Why?
Follow my master, and you'll be rewarded.
- Are you trying to bribe me?
- We're not.
I'm just giving you some advice.
Ignore it at your peril.
The Master's title has to be earned.
It cannot be bartered.
- I will fight for it.
- You won't be able to.
Why not?
Because you'll be dead.
Brilliant!
SHAOLIN TEMPLE
What can we do for you?
Shek Yingfeng, of the Wudang clan,
needs to see your Master urgently.
Please follow me.
Master Shek Yingfeng is here.
MAIN TEMPLE
How are you, Master Clarity?
- Good to see you.
- Phoenix, greet the Master.
How are you, Master?
It has been such a long time.
Miss Shek has grown.
Please come in.
I am temporarily in charge
in Master Wisdom's absence.
I can tell that you have
something important to discuss.
Is this a good place to talk?
- Yilang!
- Yes.
This is Miss Shek's first visit.
Please show her around.
- Me?
- May I, Father?
- Thank you, young man.
- Not at all.
Come along.
Now that we are alone, Master Shek,
you may speak freely.
Do you know that the Seven Deadly
Fists manual is now in the north?
Really? My God!
I know that the Seven Deadly Fists
are a Shaolin speciality.
The manual has recently come to light
once more, after many centuries.
Someone has been exploiting it,
which is why I am here today.
I hope to get to the bottom of this
so that peace can be restored.
If the manual really has been used,
the whole community will suffer.
See? We've got squirrels
and sparrows everywhere.
Why don't you lead the way?
- I don't know this place.
- Let me take you to the river.
- We come here two or three times a day.
- What for?
To get water to wash with.
Here you have the Four lmmortals.
Tall, aren't they?
There's a pond over there.
Look! Isn't it beautiful?
I grew up here, so I know
the place well.
- You grew up here?
- Yes, I did.
Have you ever been outside?
Never.
What's that smell?
Wow! It's huge! And look at all the fish!
Come and have a look.
Are you all right?
- I want to ask you something.
- What is it?
Why do you smell so nice?
Are you a virgin?
- What else would I be?
- So this is what they were talking about!
They tell me I've got to meet
that kind of lady when I leave here.
- Don't be so fresh!
- But that's what my mates told me.
Can I feel your bum?
You'd better stop now, I'm warning you.
There's no need to get mad.
Don't you get fresh with me!
What do you mean. I wash every day,
of course I'm fresh.
Why are you so mad?
So you know Kung Fu, do you?
Me too.
Well, I've got nothing else to do.
Shall we play?
Play, my foot!
I was having a laugh.
Are you fighting for real?
I'll show you what I can do!
Is that how you carry water?
See? I'm very gentle.
Let me show you what I'm really made of.
- What's this?
- This is the Crane style.
- What?
- The Crane style.
Never heard of it.
"Here's my handle, here's my spout!"
You look just like a big teapot!
Are you making fun of my method?
Let's make a bet.
- On what?
- If I lose, I'll kowtow to you.
- If I win...
- What then?
- You'll let me have a feel.
- Go to hell!
You've lost. So, do I get to...?
Phoenix!
Where are your manners?
Father, can you believe that that idiot
thought he could take me on?
Stop that. Master, forgive
my daughter's impertinence.
- That's all right.
- Go and apologise at once.
- Apologise?
- He lost. He should kowtow before me.
Nonsense!
Master Shek...
Master Wisdom will
emerge from seclusion tomorrow.
Please stay here overnight.
It'd be better to discuss
the matter with our Master.
Thank you so much.
Cognition, take the guests
to their rooms.
This way, please, Master Shek.
That's how I lost, Master.
Points six, seven, eight and ten
of the Ten Nevers.
Wow, I've broken four rules
by making one mistake?
"Six: Never underestimate
your opponent."
I admit that I thought fighting
a girl would be easy. I was wrong.
"Seven: Never hesitate."
"Eight: Never lose focus."
You've lost. So, do I get to...?
You know, it was the first time
I met a girl.
I felt dizzy.
"Ten: Never pause between strikes."
Thank you, Masters.
I'll be sure to win tomorrow.
- Morning, there.
- Afraid of me?
Why are you running from me?
What? Want to be beaten again?
Not really. I just want to even the score.
All right, then. Come on down.
Let's go then, you little minx.
Come on!
It's the big teapot, look!
Care for some tea?
Careful you don't drown in the tea!
More tea?
If I let go, you'll have a nasty fall.
Now get up.
How dare you?
Not so smart, are you?
Time for a spanking.
Are you crying?
What's wrong? Stop cry...
You big bully! I'm telling my father!
What's the punishment this time?
Wait, wait! I was only having a bit of fun!
Wait, don't! Wait, please!
It was only a game!
Father! Father! Father!
Father!
- Something is wrong, Master.
- What is it?
Brother Clarity is asking for you.
Master Shek Yingfeng
has been found dead.
I will take care of this, Miss Shek.
I hope that the perpetrator
will come forward and confess.
Do you know how Master Shek died?
- The Exalted Palm.
- But that is impossible!
What, you think I murdered him?
Why would I do that?
The evidence on his body
is undeniable.
- Master...!
- It was you!
Miss Shek, please let the master
deal with this.
Cognition...
You are the only one here
who knows the Exalted Palm.
The fact that Master Shek died here
is a very serious matter.
As Master of Shaolin, I'm
accountable to the martial community.
- Earth! Void!
- Yes, Master!
Escort him to the repentence room.
Yes, Master. Come with us, Elder.
My conscience is clear.
I have no need of an escort.
Our condolences, Miss Shek.
Tomorrow he'll be taken to
Martial Headquarters.
There the judge will look into the matter.
Now please come with me.
Miss Shek!
I knew that you would come.
He murdered my father, Master.
I must seek vengeance.
Please calm down.
Things are getting dangerous now.
You'd better leave with Cognition.
- Leave with him?
- Hm.
- But why?
- There's no time to explain now.
- You'd better leave now.
- Not unless you tell me more.
Take a sniff.
Tell me if you recognise this substance.
Cinnabar dye?
Correct.
The palm print was fake.
The murderer is still at large.
If the Master was in seclusion,
and it was neither you nor I,
are you saying that it was Purity?
We must investigate first
before we accuse anyone.
Leave now, or else you'll both be killed.
Listen. Someone is coming.
Elder, Elder, are you all right?
Elder! Somebody, help!
Somebody, help!
The Elder has been killed!
Someone has murdered him!
- Murdered!
- Help!
What has happened?
I saw what happened. He was killed
by a man clad in black.
The Exalted Palm again!
The killer has struck once more.
Just as I expected, he's gone.
I knew it was him.
You mean Elder Cognition?
What did he do?
He stole the Seven Deadly Fists manual.
He also murdered Master Shek
and Elder Purity.
That's not possible. Elder Cognition is
such a good man.
What do you know? I am right,
without a doubt.
- Well, I'm not sure...
- Master, Master!
- What is it?
- It's dreadful.
Miss Shek has disappeared
and so has Master Shek's body!
- Disappeared?
- Yes.
It breaks my heart to see that
Shaolin has produced such scum.
- Silence!
- Yes!
Tell the Eighteen Monks to go
into town at once.
- Cognition must be captured.
- Yes, Master.
So many have lost their lives
on account of the Seven Deadly Fists.
Those who obey me live.
Those who do otherwise die.
You might want to think about that.
I shall never obey scum like you!
Why, Young Master,
you really are invincible!
The title of Martial Master is all yours.
Who else is left?
Poker Face of the South.
Dragon: agililty, soul.
Snake: evil, heart.
Tiger: viciousness, strength.
Crane: speed, mind.
Leopard: ferocity, power.
Dragon, Snake, Tiger,
Crane, Leopard.
- Who's next?
- It should be Old Man Shek.
Your instructor tells me that you wish
to leave. Why is that?
I want to help apprehend that thief
and murderer Cognition.
I know you mean well, but you don't know
what you're talking about.
- Brother Clarity.
- Yes, Master.
How, when even the Eighteen Monks
have failed,
do you expect this boy to succeed?
- His intentions are good.
- Yes, but is he skillful enough?
- He has made much progress.
- Hm.
Yilang. I shall allow you to leave Shaolin
and see that justice is done in our name.
Do you think that you can pass
the traditional Eighteen Monks' test?
I'd like to try.
Go easy on me.
That really hurt!
Why so serious?
The Master is watching
and this is a serious matter.
This is inhuman.
Here I come!
Hey, get up!
Watch out!
Take that!
Halt!
You have passed the preliminary test,
but you must always be on your guard.
Take care!
Master, please allow me to fight
with short batons.
Elders, I should like to take the whole test.
I shall aim to do my best.
Let go, or else I'll pull your moustache off!
Master, Yilang has passed
the Eighteen Monks' test!
Now you are qualified to leave, Yilang.
- Are you related to Shek?
- My name is Wong.
Master Shek has passed away,
and he is survived by a young daughter.
I am temporarily in charge here.
This is ideal.
Please hand over the Badge.
The Badge?
Now that Shek is dead, we need
a new Martial Master.
- But the rules...
- What rules?
He who has the strongest fist rules!
If that were true, why would we
have an election every ten years?
Let me enlighten you.
The leaders of every school...
that is, the ones who were eligible, have
all been killed by the Seven Deadly Fists.
The Seven Deadly Fists?
Since you wouldn't hand over the Badge,
you too shall sample
the Seven Deadly Fists.
And what about me?
Shek Yingfeng may be dead,
but his daughter still lives.
I'm the one you have to ask for the Badge!
Miss Shek is certainly pretty.
But somehow, I don't think that that's
enough to secure the Badge.
Try me.
Let me through.
Come on.
- Are you ready to surrender?
- Now, why would she do that?
Shame on you, bullying a wee girl.
Come down.
- What are you doing here?
- Why are you fighting?
That's Luk Ching, the Wanderer.
He says he wants to be the Martial Master
and that he wants my father's badge.
- Martial Master?
- Hm.
So you're the Wanderer, are you, then?
Martial Master? You?
Well, let me tell you.
You're looking at the Martial Master.
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
You'll get a heart attack
when I tell you.
I am... the invincible, honourable,
supreme...
one-and-only, unbeatable... Yilang!
This man is pretty vicious, Yilang.
Don't you worry about that. Hold this.
I'll show him what I'm made of.
Upset stomach?
You won't catch me out that easily.
I'm very supple.
Have mercy. Please.
Please forgive my son.
Go home, now!
This stupid son of mine isn't too bright.
Please forgive him.
Actually, he's not bad at all.
The Badge.
Yes, we should hand over
the Badge to you.
However, it is the Shaolin Master
who has the final say in these matters.
So, what say we meet at
the Shaolin Temple in seven days' time
and you can receive it then?
No one can compete with you anymore.
The Badge is yours now.
What's the hurry?
Why, it would ruin your good reputation
should the community mistakenly believe
that you had taken it by force.
Very well, then. I shan't embarrass you.
- We shall meet in seven days' time.
- Goodbye.
Pompous fool.
Elder, you made fun of me.
- How could I be your son?
- I did you a favour.
Otherwise you'd be dead by now.
- I could take him on.
- I doubt it.
It's far better to lure him back
and let the Master take care of him.
All those who do not belong to the Court,
please leave.
Very good, Master!
Cognition!
As a Shaolin disciple, you were
wrong to steal the manual.
You also murdered Master Shek
and Purity on Shaolin ground.
You deserve a harsh punishment.
I have always abided by Shaolin laws
and teachings.
I have been set up.
Please help me to clear my name.
With hard evidence like the
palm print, you won't get away.
If you were innocent, why
did you flee?
My father's killer is still at large,
and now we must deal with Luk Ching,
who is demanding the Badge.
I am not very experienced
and I am unable to protect my father's
honour. So, here is the Badge.
Please help me.
Luk Ching? How old is he?
About thirty. He practises
the Seven Deadly Fists.
- The Seven Deadly Fists?
- That's right.
- You are...
- I am Luk Ching.
I understand that Master Shek
has passed away.
Obviously he must be replaced,
so I have come to claim the Badge.
We must establish where he learnt
the Seven Deadly Fists.
The Shaolin have not practised
them for many a century,
yet you have the nerve to ask me
where I learnt?
How can we allow him to insult us
this way, Brother?
Shaolin would be disgraced
if the public knew about the theft,
so we'd better leave it.
Our master has deigned to come here
and collect the badge.
Anyone who refuses to submit to his
authority had better speak up right now!
What did you say? Master...
This man is dishonouring Shaolin.
Shall we teach him a lesson?
This is not how a Buddhist should behave.
But I am not a monk,
and I cannot take this.
I'll teach him a lesson.
You could do with being less cocky,
you pompous arse!
How about a duel?
You got off lightly last time, loser.
Aren't you afraid?
I'd save as much breath as possible,
if I were you.
There's no telling yet
which one of us will win.
Come over here, if you're a man.
The Starving Crane!
The snake!
The tiger hunts!
Scooping the moon!
Here's a gift for you...
...to enjoy in Hell.
What style is that, Yilang?
Oh, it's...
- The Essence of the Five Fists.
- Oh, is that so?
Stop! No killing in the grounds
of the temple!
You do want to kill me, don't you?
Time for the dragon!
The snake bites!
The tiger hunts!
The crane flies!
The leopard strikes!
Now, all five elements: The dragon...
...the snake...
...the tiger, the crane, and the leopard.
Ching, my son!
Ching, my dear boy!
I know who you are!
You are Luk the Fearless, who lost the
title of Martial Master some 20 years ago.
So, you remember my name.
Back then I defeated all the others
with my own skills.
Yet you bald fools in Shaolin
discredited me for being...
too young and lacking in social standing.
I swore that I would seek vengeance.
So you changed your name and shaved
your head in order to join the Shaolin.
Yes, and I have waited for
thirty long years.
Now I have the manual of
the Seven Deadly Fists.
I wanted my son to become
the Martial Master.
I wanted the Luk clan to rule over
the martial community forever.
I knew something was up
from the moment the manual was stolen.
The fake palm print suggested a traitor
in our midst. But you?
Yes. I killed Shek Yingfeng
and Purity!
- What did my father ever do to you?
- I had to get rid of the strongest rival.
How were you able to kill them
during seclusion?
- There is a secret passage...
- Why kill Purity?
He knew too much,
so I had to silence him.
Why set me up?
Oh, a scapegoat always comes in handy.
Now that you know everything,
it's time for me to right the wrongs
old and new, once and for all!
Prepare for a bloodbath!
I'm the one who killed your son.
Leave the others alone.
The leopard strikes!
THE ESSENCE OF THE FIVE FISTS
Who's there?
What is it?
Where?
Why, go to hell... Who's that
hitting my leg?
Monster!
Who's that tugging on my arm?
Let go of me!
Let go. Let me go!
You don't look so clever now, do you?
Are you afraid of ghosts?
What are you doing?
Get off me!
Let go of me!
Why don't you jump?
You want more?
You're really not helping!
What the heck?
The tiger!
Who's holding me?
Snake!
My poor shoulder!
All Five Elements at once!
Please, Master! No!