Got that?
Oh, Ryu! Good morning.
Ryu!
You're looking strong today.
Is that because you
brought your girlfriend?
Ryu!
I'm writing you a song. Wait a bit longer.
Oh, it's just the stupid foreigner.
If you're a man, show me the evidence.
No? Try not to worry about it!
Good, Ryu.
Your techniques are getting stronger.
Let's leave it there for today.
It looks like they've arrived.
How are you?
Ryu!
What are you doing?
Naughty boy-
Master Goken.
Master, we are ready.
Well...
Hello, Master. Hello.
Master, what is this place?
This is where I came from.
Fire! Fire! Fire! Fire!
Fire? Fire?
Where?
Master,
how did Gotetsu die?
The death of a warrior... in combat.
By knowing where we have come from,
we can better shape where we are going.
You both now hold the torch
that Soke Gotetsu once carried.
Pay your respects to him.
Master Goken?
Are you there?
Goken?
Satsui no Hado...
Gotetsu.
Ansatsuken [Assassin's Fist] style,
teaches three principal special techniques
to generate Hado, with devastating effect.
Tatsumaki Senpu-kyaku,
Shoryuken,
and Hadoken!
Musha ShU9Y°?
The most deadly Ansatsuken techniques
can only be achieved by
embracing Satsui no Hado
and focusing it upon your opponent,
through your mind,
body, Ki, and technique.
So that you not only strike your target,
but aim to obliterate it!
Understood Goken?
Yes!
Understand Goki?
Yes.
Then begin!
From now on, when you fight,
put aside friendship,
you must see only an adversary,
who must be overcome.
Understood?
Understood?!
Yes.
Follow me!
Now...
Face one another'.!
Fight!
Stop!
Your fighting spirits are strong,
your techniques fierce!
I encourage ferocious attack
and belligerent defense.
These are the cornerstones of Ansatsuken.
Stop!
You may well be worthy of
the title "warrior" one day.
Yes.
You are still beginners in the Ansatsuken
killing techniques of Satsui no Hado.
You are both forbidden to practice
this without my permission.
The consequences could be grave.
I'm sure we can handle it.
Then you'll handle being dead!
Betray me at your own risk.
Yes.
Master.
My own brother,
my last surviving Ansatsuken rival,
lost his mind; Driven mad
by abuse of Satsui no Hado.
No one knows if he's dead or alive.
It is important that you purge
your Ki of Satsui no Hado after use.
Through your meditation you must
cleanse your minds and bodies.
Understood?
Y es. Y es.
Look to the In-Yo.
Stop!
Focus, be calm.
Will your Ki to surge into your fists.
Begin.
You are rushing, Ken.
"Power of Nothingness" cannot be forced
into release by anger and frustration.
Quite the opposite.
Ken! 50 push-ups now!
Yes, Master.
Good Ryu, you are close.
Drive your Ki into your hands. Try this...
This allows me to
concentrate the Ki flow
into my hands before
stepping into stance...
You see'?
Amazing!
Come on.
I felt it!
You are on the right path.
Well done, man...
Ken, would you like me
to show you the Kata?
Inside now!
Close the door!
You would be unwise to lie to me.
Okay then, let's talk
about Satsui no Hado.
Means nothing to me.
Who's lying now?
You can go.
Goki.
What do you think you're doing?
You know we are forbidden
to look over Master's scrolls!
What if he catches you?
Let him...
I don't care.
What the hell is up with you lately?
Stop now,
or I will come over there
and you will be sorry.
Interesting...
I'd love to see you try!
Thought so.
I won't wait any longer.
Why shouldn't we learn all there
is to know about Satsui no Hado?
Do you really think Master won't find out?
Just look at you, Goki!
You can't control it anymore.
You hold back if you want to,
but I intend to reach my full potential!
You'd be foolish to stand in my way.
Uncle!
Killing blow.
Again.
Summon your own Ki, like an army,
to unleash hell and destruction!
Goodnight, Master.
Goodnight.
Stop!
Wait, wait, wait!
What are you doing here?
Did you come to fight?
Hmmmmm... I know a fighter when I see one,
but you're just spectating.
1000 yen each.
5000 yen each to fight.
We just want to watch.
What are you doing? Don't worry.
One, two, three.
Disgusting!
Stupid foreigner!
You're underage, you're underage.
Good morning, Master.
Good morning.
Looks like you had a rough night.
Yes.
Master, why is Ken's father really here?
He wants his son to come home.
Is Ken leaving?
That is for Ken to decide.
Oh no, not again...
What are you doing?
Yes.
I'm done...
"Metsu" [Destruction]
Begin!
Stop!
Uncle!
Goken, no!
Stop it.
Goki! In the Dojo now!
Kneel.
Was your intention to kill your brother?
You have become
undisciplined and insubordinate.
Those traits have no place in this Dojo.
You will apologize to your brother.
What am I apologizing for?
"To achieve one's true potential,"
one must bring everything to the fight
"and not hold back under any circumstance."
Is this not the true
teachings of Ansatsuken?
You have betrayed me.
You read the scrolls?
Am I not allowed?
Goki...
Do not test my mercy.
Please calm down.
You're scaring me!
He doesn't know what he is messing with.
Satsui no Hado?
He can't control it.
It's poisoning him.
It is too dangerous.
It will be okay.
Uncle just wants to talk to him...
No!
You just don't get it, do you?
Something must be done,
I'm going to intervene.
Are you mad?
What are you able to do?
Go to your room and stay there
until this is resolved.
You fool!
I can't sit around and do nothing but
watch while this family falls apart.
I'm not asking you, I'm telling you.
If something happens to
Goki, I can't ignore it.
I think you've done quite enough for him.
What's that supposed to mean?
Goken, join us.
Enough talk.
Go to your room.
Goki.
Will you leave here?
Once you decide, there is no turning back!
Understood?
Master...
Brother...
I'm sorry...
This is the end for you
and me as we know it.
Goki.
What do you mean?
You are my brother,
my only flesh and blood,
but also my greatest adversary.
Since we began learning Ansatsuken,
we unknowingly became part of a legacy.
I know now...
that our destinies are defined by it.
Master is trying to protect
you from the truth.
Be quiet!
A truth he knows is inevitable.
There can only ever be one true living
Master of Ansatsuken at any one time.
Silence!
Master is old, he will soon be gone,
leaving just you and me.
Sooner or later, brother
or not, we will have to...
Stop!
That's enough!
You have chosen your own path.
Before the sun sets, gather your
belongings and leave this place.
For if you return,
it will not be as a student or family,
but as an enemy!
Understood?!
I understand.
I thank you for raising me as your own,
and for taking me this far in my training.
I am honored that you
chose me as your student.
It has not been in vain.
One day I will make you proud.
Until we meet again...
in this life... or the next.
Master, please wait.
Is there no other way?
It is decided.
But...
Goki?
Say aka.
What are you doing here?
What has Goki done to you?
Where is he?
How could things get to this point?
He is your brother...
How could you let this happen?
It was not my fault.
The stubborn fool has done this himself.
Master has made his decision.
You'll find Goki outside.
Goki!
What did you say to Sayaka?
I merely told her the truth.
Our destinies are set,
and it's now time for me to leave.
Sooner or later you are going
to have to face the same truth.
A time will come when...
Goki, stop! Just shut up! That's enough.
Master is right, Satsui no Hado
is clouding your judgment!
You can't think straight. You are sick.
Despite what Master says,
and what you have done here today,
you are still my brother,
and I don't want you to go.
Let me help you and I will
beg Master to reconsider.
Goken, come back into the Dojo.
Goki...
is leaving now.
Now!
I guess this is it then.
Yes.
Until the day our paths
are destined to cross again.
Goodbye, Goken.
Train hard and stay strong.
The perfect Hado technique ultimately
requires two opposite components.
First, to generate stable
Hado in an instant,
you must use the "Power of Nothingness."
But to deliver it with power and accuracy,
requires intense aggression and
the desire to overcome and destroy.
Understand?
Yes.
Begin!
Good, Ken. Concentrate.
Ryu, don't let him beat you. Answer back.
Strive for Shinku. [True void]
I know it is within you.
Ryu, throw it!
He has returned.
Are you lost, stranger?
No more lost than you are.
Who are you?
Are you from the monastery?
I am not important...
but he might be...
This little one I found
wandering in the woods.
My duty here is done.
He goes with you now.
Hello, my child. What is your name?
It will take more than that, my friend.
If he has a voice, I couldn't find it.
In time maybe you will...
I know why you don't speak.
You keep your emotions locked deep inside,
so no one can hurt you again.
In time, I will teach you to
open up, and free your Ki.
There is a strength deep within you,
I have felt it.
Your Ki is powerful,
rising like a dragon. [Ryu]
Ryu.
Ryu! Be strong...
Be strong.
Shit... Ken!
What happened?
My Hadoken...
His Ki flow is disrupted.
Get going!
I knew one day you would
come for the old man.
I have long awaited this moment.
I came here for Master...
not you.
His time ended when I sent him to Hell.
Embrace your destiny.
I already have.
Then face me!
My path is different to yours.
I do not wish to fight you.
I walk my own path.
There can be only one Ansatsuken Master.
I once believed that killing you
would bring me peace from the
anguish you brought on this house,
but I realized long ago,
that the path you walk, the path of murder,
can never lead to peace and enlightenment.
You have no choice in your true destiny.
You are wrong! There is always choice.
I took an oath to never
again use Satsui no Hado.
If you want the title of
Ansatsuken Master, then have it.
I will not fight you.
Pitiful.
Get on your knees and
swear your subservience,
then I will spare you,
or else prepare to join
the old man in Hell!
No! Stay where you are!
Master?
Stop!
You dare deceive me'?
First, I will put your cubs down.
They are not your concern.
Fine.
I will fight you,
but today is not that day.
Now leave this place!
When the time is perfect, you will know.
Well then, I shall be waiting.
Goken, the day we next meet
will be the last for one of us.
I promise you.
That writing on his back...
Master, who was that?
"On the field of battle,
there is no friend or foe,"
no room for compassion,
"merely an opponent before
you who must be destroyed."
Such is the essence of Ansatsuken.
I am a veteran of the last
great war of our time,
what do you know of war?
Ansatsu ken was birthed
from the blood, fire,
and massacre of feudal times.
You cannot follow its words literally.
You will never understand,
it is for this reason,
I kept the full contents of
the scrolls from Goken and you.
Why?
It is the only way I can
reach my full potential.
The Shun Goku Satsu, the pinnacle of
mastery of Satsui no Hado, is not a myth!
Why?
To protect Goken and you.
Look at you.
Your body is twisted by
the power of Satsui no Hado.
Yet you think you can
master its greatest prize?
You fool!
I thank you for raising me as your own,
and for taking me this far in my training.
I am honored that you
chose me as your student.
Goki, what is it? I heard
you all shouting in there.
I'm leaving.
What happened?
You know very well,
it's time for me to go.
Go where?
Don't say that.
It's okay. Talk to me.
Don't...
Don't make this any harder
for me than it already is!
We both knew this day would come.
It is destiny that today's
events would unfold.
I have crossed the point of no return.
Master has given me an ultimatum,
and I have chosen my path.
Sayaka...
I wish more than anything
that I could stay with you...
but this is a path I must walk alone,
the path of the true warrior,
the Shin Oni. [True Demon]
Yes.
Goki.
What did you say to Sayaka?
I found her in pieces.
I merely told her the truth.
Whatever our Master says...
Whatever you do...
Goki!
Here.
This is for you.
Something to eat on your journey.
Thank you.
You're too kind to me.
Go back to the house.
You have to...
before they think you are
running away with me.
I know...
But I have one more thing to give you.
Heaven'?
It represents immortal glory.
The person you are striving to be.
I think it will help you see
clearly your journey's goal.
This is my parting gift to you.
Farewell, Goki...
I hope you've chosen the right path.
It's perfect.
The path of the Shin Oni drives me.
I shall not rest until Dark Hado is mine.
I know you don't want to hear it,
but maybe your uncle is right.
I miss him too,
but no one has seen or
heard anything for months.
So you think we should just give up?
Just forget him?
Even if we could find Goki,
when he left he had made up his mind,
he was at peace with his decision.
I still feel you should have done more.
I know you care for him. I do too...
but don't forget he tried to kill me!
He has chosen a path which
no one can follow him on.
We have to accept it, and move on.
This stops now.
Uncle.
What do you mean?
You know what.
You are hindering Goken's training.
How can you all be so heartless?
I'm not getting in the
way of Goken's training.
You are still enamored with Goki.
I'm just worried about Goki.
Shame on you!
You think I didn't know about you two?
What matters now is helping Goken.
Thinking about Goki ends now!
Think of him as dead.
Understand?
Yes.
It is time.
Goki was corrupted by Satsui no Hado.
I'm not sure whether
the ends justify the means.
The risk seems too high a price.
Is there not any other
way to manifest Hado?
Am I not living proof that one can
balance the darkness with light?
A master's teachings are
not to be followed blindly.
Ideas evolve with the times.
Centuries ago Ansatsuken
was a young man's game,
the greatest masters were either destroyed
in battle or consumed by the madness.
They never lived past their 40s.
I came to the conclusion that
to have longevity in this art...
one must balance these extremes.
This harmony is what
the In-Yo represents to me.
For in all life there must be balance.
So you agree there must be other
avenues to explore in Hado?
You must make your own path.
Yes, Master.
Wha... what?
My face...
Master'.!
You were right.
No, not yet.
I have no choice...
I must become stronger.
Nature provides all that I need.
For two years I have trained
in nothing but Satsui no Hado.
Strengthening my body
day by day, in preparation.
I've been speaking to Master.
My training under him is coming to an end.
He has advised me to go on the
Musha Shugyo. [Warrior's Pilgrimage]
You're leaving?
Not for a while,
I still have much to learn,
and...
this is where my heart is.
When I return, I will be
the Master of this House.
I want you with me, Sayaka.
What did my uncle say?
He thinks it will be good for us.
I see.
First you must take the Musha Shugyo alone,
as Goki did.
I'm not like him.
Just promise me...
you'll come back.
It represents immortal glory.
The person you are striving to be.
Farewell, Goki.
One day I'll make you proud.
Until we meet again...
In this life...
or the next.
To conquer Dark Hado,
I must immerse myself in a state of
Satsui no Hado until we become one.
If my spirit is strong
enough, I may survive,
and if not, the process could
consume me, and be my end.
I'll pay the price gladly.
Master?
May I speak with you?
Last night, I felt something strange.
I must have been dreaming...
Go on.
I think I felt Satsui no Hado.
I prayed that this day would never come.
Beyond the mountains, deep in the valley,
I felt a great power never felt before...
An explosion of Dark Hado.
That of Goki.
Are you sure?
He hasn't been heard
from for over two years.
Goki had ambitions of unlocking
the power of Dark Hado,
and ultimately, the Shun Goku Satsu.
You taught us that such a thing was myth.
Unlocking it would require
such focus of Satsui no Hado
that one would become
completely consumed by it.
No one has ever survived it.
It may well have been the death of Goki...
or the birth of something legendary.
Something more darkly powerful
than I have ever encountered.
The birth of an Akuma. [Demon]
So what happens now?
I don't know, but if it is an Akuma,
he will come.
One Master must seek out
another and destroy him;
It is the nature of Satsui no Hado.
I must face him.
Master'.!
I'll face him. Let me.
It is my destiny to face the Akuma.
I created him...
so I must destroy him.
If I fail,
then I fear the balance I have sought
to maintain in Ansatsuken will be lost
and darkness will fall.
Goken...
Look after Sayaka.
Yes, Master.
You must take charge of these scrolls.
Master, I can't.
I understand your reservations
about Satsui no Hado,
but do not be na'l've.
Goki doesn't know everything
written in the scrolls.
Should you ever have to face him,
you will need the full
knowledge in all the scrolls.
Master,
have you felt anything
over the past few nights?
No, nothing unusual.
So...
You think he... didn't survive?
Come, let us spar.
Let me see if I've taught you well enough
to stand up to an old man like me.
Yes, Master.
Akuma.
I feel your dark presence.
Come forth and show yourself.
You survived this long.
I see you have been hard at work.
Yes, old man,
your time is over.
This is the end.
Is that so?
Tonight, there will be murder!
Prepare yourself!
Goken, what is it?
Stay here!
Goken, what's going on?
Is it Goki?
Yes.
Goken!
Master'.!
Prepare yourself.
One instant, a thousand strikes!
This is annihilation.
You were a great master and even through
your defeat you have taught me much...
Shin Oni.
But now a new Master is born.
Goki!
What have you done?
Stop, damn you!
Fight me!
You are not ready.
Goken, stop please!
Say aka'?
Let's take a walk.
Go by yourself.
I'd rather just stay and
finish my painting.
Goken my love,
I have prepared a bag for you.
It is time you left this place and
embarked on your Musha Shugyo.
No good can come of remaining here.
I wish words could explain,
but I can no longer be with you.
I pray that you may one day forgive me.
Be strong.
Goodbye.
Say aka.
Goken, forgive me.
Masterful reversal, Ryu!
Stupid foreigner. You can't do it,
Ryu is too strong for you.
Hey. RY”-.
I've finished your song.
I play for you now.
Shut up! You've been saying that
for a year, you senile old bastard!
Shut up woman. I didn't ask
you to sing over Ryu's song.
Right, I start.
It's perfect.
How was it?
Thank you. I love it.
Do that thing, or this
thing, or this thing,
whatever it is just do it.
From there to there.
That's a pretty long way.
Not sure I can make it that far.
It's too far for the stupid foreigner,
but not you, try it.
Right, I'm watching.
Okay. Here goes!
Ah, stupid foreigner.
It's impossible for you.
You could never do it.
It's coming this way...
It didn't reach.
You couldn't do it after all.
Fine.
I will fight you,
but today is not that day.
Well then, I shall be waiting.
The day we next meet will
be the last for one of us.
When the time is perfect, you will know.
Always fishing...
I don't know why.
Ah, stupid foreigner, are you by yourself?
Is there no one to play with you?
I feel sorry for you.
Okay. Goma will play with you then.
That won't work, I can't
lift this at all. Damn it.
Damn you, look this way.
What are you doing?
Are you daydreaming?
What are you doing? Just look this way.
Hey! Can't you hear me?
I said I'll play with you. Come over here.
Help me, help me.
When did I ask you to kill me?
You keep your Ki and
emotions locked deep inside,
so no one can hurt you again.
In time,
I will teach you to open up,
to let go and be free.
There is a strength deep within you.
I feel it.
Be strong... be strong.
Understood?
Yes.
He'll come at you with everything he's got.
Time to let go of fear.
Show him what you are truly capable of.
Don't hesitate! Let him have it.
Yes, Master.
Go.
Ryu.
Ryu!
Satsui no Hado.
Master'.!
I appreciate what you are saying, Master...
Did you call me?
Resting.
I used to see boys lining
up here each morning,
now I see men... Warriors.
It looks like your gloves couldn't stand up
to the Hado that you both now wield,
so it's time you inherited these.
Traditional Ansatsuken fighting gloves,
strong enough to withstand Hado.
Shall we?
Senzo, thank you.
The honor has been mine, Ryu.
I've poured all of my knowledge
and wisdom into you.
I love you like a son.
Be strong.
As fast as the wind, as
quiet as the forest...
as daring as fire and
immovable as the mountain.
Senzo, let's go!
Did they make the bus to Osaka in time?
Yes, they are safely on their way.
Good.
Join me.
Senzo... I owe much to you.
You guided me towards the Buddhist path
and helped me find peace at a time
when all I knew was turmoil and rage.
You have seen more of the Ansatsuken
legacy than any person alive or dead.
Yes...
I have seen much.
Flames ignited... flames extinguished.
You have dutifully served
my Master's household
as you have served mine.
Whatever debt of honor you owed my Master
has now been paid.
You are relieved of your services to me.
You have my eternal gratitude.
Thank you.
It has been an honor to serve you.
I ask one final thing of you.
He is close.
Yes.
I haven't much time.
I entrust my journal to you.
Whatever should happen...
ensure that you get it to my boys.
It shall be done.
You could no longer resist
the call of your Satsui no Hado.
Your show of force has brought me here.
Brother, look at you, you truly
have lost your humanity.
Lost yourself in darkness.
Lost?
To transcend humanity,
I endured every hardship and loss.
Loss?
You have taken from me everything
lever held dear and sacred.
He is your brother...
How could you let this happen?
You're still my brother
and I don't want you to go.
Goki!
What have you done?
Stop, damn you!
Goken, forgive me.
I've poured all of my knowledge
and wisdom into you.
I love you like a son.
You know nothing of sacrifice.
For the sake of Ansatsuken, I lost
more than you could ever comprehend.
Before the sun sets, gather your
belongings and leave this place.
But this is a path I must walk alone,
the path of the true warrior,
the Shin Oni.
My face...
Would I rather live my life never knowing,
in fear of my true potential?
Or can I truly embrace destruction to find
out, no matter the cost and consequence?
You cannot even comprehend what I
suffered to become Master of Masters.
I walk in the darkness...
even my shadow dare not follow me.
You proved nothing killing Gotetsu!
He died with satisfaction...
for he had lived to witness Shin Oni.
Shin Oni!
His destruction was his release.
Consumed by Satsui no Hado,
you have succumbed to the madness
that took Sensei's brother.
Gotetsu had it wrong, all
the old masters did.
And they died for it.
What are you talking about?
They tried to become utterly
consumed by Satsui no Hado.
And you haven't been?
No. I did the unimaginable.
I consumed Satsui no Hado.
Are you ready to face destiny, brother?
The brother I knew once,
and loved, died a long time ago.
All that remains is Akuma.
I took a vow.
Today, I break it!