More My Movies:
www.thepiratebay.org/user/Movie4All/
Awakened by the sound of an explosion...
...running for their lives.
Police are now pushing...
...the Feds are telling us
it is not a terror attack.
It is most likely an accident.
...the Fire Department is
calling a major emergency.
...wave of unexplained killings
that are sweeping across this city.
Not all things in the world...
are quite as they first appear.
Every seven years in an ordinary town,
an extraordinary event takes place.
You won't know it...
you won't see it...
...but it happens.
Damn.
- You out?
- Yeah.
Don't let it be him, Joshua. not him.
Mr. Harlow!
What's the matter, Mr. Harlow?
Are you out of bullets?
Here, have some of mine!
Whoo-hoo!
No you don't, Mr. Harlow.
Joshua!
To be quite frank with you,
you're a stain on our profession.
I'm beyond fucking insulted.
So...
come on out..
and I'll show you...
the only way to quit this line of work.
Congratulations, man.
Thanks.
I'm glad it was you.
Enjoy your life together.
We have a winner.
...crime rose across the board-
particularly gang-related gun crime,
which is leaving residents
in a constant state of fear.
There were calls last night
for further investment...
in the city's under-manned
police force, as often-
Another day in the borough.
All right, you. Come on.
Out.
You been here long enough.
- Closing time, eh?
- Opening time.
How many times have
I told you about this?
Come on, out.
What did I do last night?
It's not what you did,
it's how much you drank.
You're a disgrace, you know that?
You dirty bastard. Right.
Sorry.
Here. Don't forget this.
Now piss off, Father. You're barred!
Disgusting.
Fuck off.
All right. Venue's stacked.
Visual is coming through. Almost got it.
I'm into the ccTV mainframe.
That is tasty and invisible.
Thank you. Watch and learn.
- Rerouting.
- Thank you.
Rerouted CCTV footage is online.
Confirm complete camera tap.
Rerouted ccTV confirmed
on all grid sections A through to B.
We have coverage of the entire city.
Abso-fucking-lutely.
Good. Visuals on the standby?
All available motion
detectors and hidden cameras
are active and responsive.
- Block coms.
- Blocking.
Emergency calls placed
on permanent hold cycle.
Please hold while we try to connect you.
Emergency radio
frequencies are scrambled.
Lock everything. Prepare to go live.
We're up.
About time. What's our status?
Some of the long hauls
are a little late rising,
but the majority are up and about.
And the implants?
The surgery teams completed overnight.
Good. Make sure the
cleanup crews are ready.
They're going to have a busy day.
Ladies and gentlemen...
welcome to the Tournament.
It is my honor
to be your host for
this legendary event,
being held for the first
time here in Great Britain.
With more CCTV than
anywhere else on Earth,
we shouldn't miss a thing.
now, as you know,
the stakes in this room are high,
but the stakes for our
competitors out there
are the highest possible.
At this very moment,
30 of the world's greatest assassins
are preparing for the
ultimate sporting event.
International killers of
every imaginable discipline
will compete for a
$10 million cash prize
and the honorable title
of the "World's Best. "
our lovely ladies are
standing by to take your bets.
100K minimum stake.
And here are a few of
my personal favorites
you may wish to keep your eye on.
- Visuals online.
- Go to seven.
- Go to seven, Rob.
- And cue.
Lai Lai Zhen, abandoned
at birth and left for dead.
At 17, she was killing for the Triads
and has grown up to become
the number one hitter
in the Eastern market
for the past three years-
a snip at 10 to 1.
Anton Bogart.
An outstanding athlete,
he lives for the thrill of the hunt.
Silent, stealthy, smart-
a lethal option.
9 to 1.
Yuri Petrov, Russian special forces.
An incredible all-rounder
armed to the teeth.
Fists, feet, bullets, bombs-
utterly merciless, he has it all.
Miles Slade, the crazy Texan kid.
An outside bet,
but he's mad enough to rise the ranks.
Reckless, ruthless, wild,
but guaranteed great entertainment.
This is one guy who truly loves his job.
And if you thought it
couldn't get any better,
we have a dramatic late entrant...
a returning champion who I'm sure...
will add something very
personal to the proceedings.
Seven years ago,
Joshua Harlow took
the Tournament by storm
and retired as a champion.
But this year he's back.
For one reason, and one reason only-
revenge.
Joshua's wife was brutally murdered...
in their Miami home four months ago,
and the person who killed her...
is one of this year's players!
Joshua Harlow is our favorite at 2 to 1.
Activate tracking devices.
overlaying and synching positions.
- Tracking bugs online.
- Prepare to go hot.
Hotter than me in a swimsuit.
Cue.
As ever, each assassin...
is implanted with a tracking device,
so we can find them,
and they can find each other.
But this year we've added
an extra pinch of spice.
If we don't have a
winner within 24 hours,
our contestants will discover...
that their tracking device...
isn't just a tracking device.
Well, I know you're all very busy men.
30 contestants...
24 hours...
one rule...
kill or die.
Ladies and gentlemen, place your bets.
The Tournament has begun.
Suck me sideways.
I would kill for a piece of that pie.
Yeah, right.
You'd be fucking dead before
you could lick your lips.
Besides, somebody upstairs
has designs on her.
Oh, yeah? Is that so?
Yeah, kinda.
They go way back. He
nurtured her or something.
Oh, oh, oh.
All right, it is showtime.
Holy shit. Can you do that?
- Wow.
- He just killed an innocent guy!
Fuck! I love this shit.
- Fuck!
- Keep on him.
I'm locked on him. Nowhere to hide.
Miss Hunter, it is showtime.
We have Tomko versus Zhen.
That is England v. China!
Good. Patch it through.
Sir, we're off.
It's Steve Tomko and Lai Lai Zhen.
What the fuck are you up to?
Who is it?
Room service.
Breakfast, madam.
You like that, bitch? Huh?
I just want you to
know, after I kill you,
I'm going to fuck you.
Hey, welcome to the tournament, Rob.
You fucking bitch!
First blood to Lai Lai Zhen.
Her odds move to 7 to 1.
Yeah!
Cleanup crew Delta to the
Ivy House Hotel room 107.
We're on our way.
I still would.
Confirm one body...
Oh, okay, party time.
We have the Frenchman Anton Bogart...
heading into a cluster...
developing on the high street.
- Shit.
Activating all street security cams.
Picking it up on one,
two, three police cameras.
- The cameras live?
- Cameras are live.
We are in on the Gypsy.
Fuck. The Frenchman's gone cold.
I didn't see a fight.
You see him get killed?
No, I didn't see a fucking fight.
Doing a signal sweep.
Check his body heat sensor now.
I'm on it.
Tech. He's back. What did you do?
Must've been a blip.
Run a complete diagnostic.
I don't like blips.
Top you off?
- Coffee?
- no.
Top you off?
There you go.
Yes.
No.
Okay.
You planning to pay for that?
Yeah. Yes.
Credit card?
Here, Father. Allow me.
Enjoy your coffee.
Au revoir.
Thank you.
Hello, Todd.
Hello, Father.
Sorry I haven't been around.
I've been busy. How's your mom doing?
She died, Father.
I... I'm sorry.
She was asking after you.
Is there anything I can do,
like help with the funeral?
That's okay. I've got it all sorted.
- Oh, fuck.
- What?
I think we have another blip.
Shooter on the rooftop just went cold.
No one near her.
We've got a moving
signal but no Frenchman.
What the hell is going on?
- Come on.
- I'm looking, I'm looking.
I fucking hate blips!
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the
fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of
God, pray for us sinners
now and in the hour of our death, amen.
Oh, please, Blessed Virgin, hear me.
I want to be a good man.
I want to be a strong man.
But I look inside my heart
and there is nothing there.
There's nothing there.
Oh, Blessed Virgin, please give me hope.
I know.
What?
Whatever this is, please, please...
What's wrong with you?
What's wrong with me?
Please, hear me...
Why aren't you defending yourself?
I don't have any money, please.
- I don't have any money.
- Shut up.
I'm just a... I'm just a priest.
Please, please...
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost,
goodbye.
I'm going to enjoy this.
Stop!
Stop.
Please, don't struggle.
So much easier when they don't struggle.
What are you doing?
Just let her go!
I've got a gun!
I've got a gun and I'll use it.
Aah!
Don't move.
Or what?
Just... just stay right there.
Stay back!
You need one in the chamber.
- Who are you?
- I'm a priest!
If you lie to me, I break your neck.
I'm not. I'm not!
Where are your weapons?
Who do you work for?
Where do you receive your orders from?
Rome!
No scar.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You're bleeping.
You really don't know what
I'm talking about, do you?
You really are a priest.
Father Macavoy.
This is... was my church.
Well, Father, welcome to the Tournament.
Thank you.
They found the blip.
What is it?
It's our Frenchman.
- Anton Bogart?
- It seems he managed...
to cut out his tracking device,
and it's ended up inside that priest.
I see.
We now have one of our favorites...
running around virtually invisible?
I'm sorry. What shall I tell them to do?
I suggest you shorten his odds...
and follow him.
Yes, sir.
Tech. okay, maintain
visual contact with Bogart.
Don't lose sight of that
slippery little bastard.
Tracking manually. Damn, Bogart's quick.
Go to camera two. Quick, go.
Just got to reconfigure.
Give me a second.
- Holy shit.
- What now?
- It's him.
- You sure?
Oh, there are gonna be fireworks.
All right, Miss Hunter, we have Harlow.
We have Harlow for you.
May I have your attention?
You wanted the greatest show on Earth.
out for revenge,
the greatest assassin of our time.
Cut the shit, Eddy.
Oh, shit.
- What are you doing here?
- I need information.
What have you heard?
I heard someone came for you.
I heard it got a bit messy.
And I heard about your wife.
What did you hear? Who told you?
The crazy American kid, Miles.
He's your one.
Miles Slade, the finger guy?
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Um...
Whoohoohoo!
Eat shit!
Well, that's one more
for the trophy cabinet,
thank you very much.
Hey, boy!
Come here, little fella.
Hey, there's a good boy.
There's a good dog.
Yeah, that's a good dog.
That's a good dog.
Hey, what is this?
What is that, huh?
What is it? Here you go.
That guy is fucked up.
See you later, boy.
Okay, just take it back a little.
Playing out to one.
Jeez, who steals a finger?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, fuck.
That's the emergency line. What do I do?
Answer it.
Hello.
Yeah, hold on. I'll
just put you through.
Just spoke to Lai Lai Zhen.
You tell her you wanted to eat her pie?
- Excuse me, Senator.
- All right.
It's Lai Lai.
Make sure that redneck
settles his marker...
before he has another coronary.
Speak.
We have a situation with a civilian.
Who are you talking to, the police?
Quiet. I know you can
see what's going on.
You know the rules, Lai Lai.
It's kill or be killed.
You're like a child
running back to Daddy
telling me how the big
boy stole your ball.
You're on the battlefield.
There is no going back.
And he's just one of those famous
innocent bystanders you hear about.
- Let me speak to him.
- no, stop it.
- This is Father Macavoy.
- I'll kill you myself.
- Let me speak to him.
- It's not right. He's just a priest.
Personally, I find it kind of apt.
Back in the day we used to
throw Christians to the lions.
Seems that history is repeating itself.
Carry him or kill him,
but don't call back.
What's happened? Are the police coming?
Not really.
Move!
We have to get out of here now.
Move it!
Oh, God!
Someone help me!
Please, help! God!
It's stuck.
Help me with the seatbelt.
- It's jammed.
- Don't let me die!
Come here. Come here.
Wrong day to be a good Samaritan.
When I say "move it", move it!
- Come on!
- What's going on?
You've got a bug inside you.
They think you're a hitter.
This is a competition for assassins.
That last man standing wins.
A game where people kill each other?
Yes, we have to get
the tracker out of you,
otherwise you're a target.
Why don't we go to the police?
Eh? You and I.
You acted in self-defense.
I'll speak for you.
Is it my accent? Do
I stutter? Is that it?
The people who run this,
they are more powerful than the police.
- Somebody...
- They will get you anywhere.
- ... do something!
- But the bodies...
people will see the bodies.
There will be an explanation.
It won't be the truth, but it
will be what people will buy.
A madman with a gun, a terrorist attack,
a natural disaster, a car crash.
That's how the Tournament
remains a secret!
It's insane.
Don't you watch TV, Father?
The whole world is insane.
now move it! Come on!
Sir.
Sir, can we just reconfirm?
You want to make the priest a player?
You want him on the system?
Was I unclear, Mr. Hamilton?
No. No, sir. It's ready. It's ready.
- This is bullshit.
- Shut up and do it.
Ladies and gentlemen, a man of the cloth
has stepped out from the sidelines.
If any of you good people
would like to take a long shot
on a man with a dog collar,
we'll take that action.
Lai Lai. Will you hurry up?
It's not coming up.
How do you know I've
even swallowed this thing?
How else could it be inside you?
Fuck! Fuck!
Everybody thinks I'm an assassin!
Everybody wants me dead!
- Yes.
- oh, fuck!
I don't wanna die.
- It's okay.
- I don't wanna die.
I don't wanna die.
- I don't know how to cope with this.
- You'll be okay.
Trust me.
Okay.
Oh, thank God. Thank God.
Oh, officer, thank goodness you're here.
Nice outfit, Father.
Get down!
Come on!
What's happening?
I'm not sure, but we have
to get out of here now.
A policeman's been killed.
- He's a player.
- A player?
Why would anybody want to
take part in this madness?
Cash prize, revenge, title, excitement.
So what's your reason?
I've seen him before.
- In the cafe this morning.
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
- He cut it out.
Hold on!
Fuck.
Whoo! Here we go.
Yeah. Hi, ladies!
Hurry back.
I love you, baby.
Enjoy your life together.
Where were you?
Host on speaker. Joshua,
I'm deeply sorry about your loss,
but I may have some information
about the person that came after you.
I may know where you can find them.
Oh, shit.
We got another one of
those cluster things.
Jesus fucking Christ.
That's not a cluster.
That is a war zone.
Angel's titty bar? Are you kidding me?
There's nine shooters in there.
Why aren't they attacking each other?
Probably so many people in the place
they don't know who is who.
All right, we got
ourselves a situation here.
We have nine players in one location.
Repeat, nine players in
one shithole location.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a bloodbath about to take place.
Come on, bitches!
Yeah!
Fuck yeah!
Come on, boys!
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
No, you don't!
I see you, bud!
Thanks, sweetheart.
Tindillini and Mitre out.
They're going down
fast. Still taking bets.
Come on, boys!
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
You fucking son of a bitch.
Whoo!
- Ho, ho, ho!
- This is fucked up.
oh!
That's Van de Ven out of the game.
Where you at, boys?
Aah!
Miles. Bring it on!
Yeah! Fuck, yeah!
Whoo-whoo! Whoo!
Was it you, Miles?
Did you come after me?
- Stay still, honey.
- Did you murder my wife?
What the fuck you talking about?
Aah!
No, you don't, honey.
Good night, sugar.
We're experiencing
problems with transmitting.
All units, we have reports of gunfire...
Sorry, we're completely swamped here.
What the hell's going on today?
God, I need a drink.
You drink too much
and your eyes give you away.
You damage your liver.
That's just perfect. That's
just exactly what I need,
health advice from a hit man.
What are we going to do?
We have to wait until it
passes through your system.
The further out of town we go,
the less accurate the tracker.
It will buy us some time.
Do you mind if I ask you a question?
Why are you here?
Why are you playing?
Why all the questions?
Why do you drink so much?
Why were you sobbing
like a child this morning?
Because I'm lost.
You're lost?
Try to be me.
It must be tough playing
God with people's lives.
I don't play God.
If I don't do it, somebody else will.
It's just a job. nothing more.
I don't believe you.
otherwise, why didn't you just kill me?
I don't kill the innocent.
I'm so happy.
Did you feel that?
Please!
Where were you?
Can you hold that for me, buddy?
Huh. Howdy.
Look at you.
Joshua Harlow,
greatest assassin there ever was.
Well, I shit ya,
you're well past your best, ain't ya?
But, hey, look at the bright side-
at least you fell at the
hands of this year's champion.
Look at what I did to that guy.
What the fuck was I thinking?
Jesus, Miles, you're a fucking maniac.
Thanks.
Have a drink, legend.
Trying to quit.
Just to be clear, old-timer,
these are the last few
moments of your life
you're experiencing right now.
You might as well have a drink with me.
Maybe later.
Suit yourself, superstar.
Go on, now, tell me...
how many kills?
See, I love killing.
Just the smell of it.
Why Mary?
Mary?
Yeah.
Mary who? I killed a
fucking million Marys.
You know who.
Miami, four months ago.
I wasn't home.
It was me you wanted.
Why did you kill her?
Give me a second.
Hey, man, let me help you.
Whoa.
That's some nasty shit.
Now where were we?
My wife.
Yeah. Why weren't you there?
You left her all alone.
If I were you...
I'd blame myself.
Bad news, superstar.
This is really going to fuck you off.
It wasn't me.
Don't lie to me, kid.
I am not...
a kid!
Whoohoohoo!
I got me a $10 million trigger finger.
That's as close as you'll ever come,
you fucking amateur.
Here, let me help you with that.
I really wish it was me.
Shit, I really do.
But I wouldn't go take credit
for other people's work.
That'd just be wrong.
Don't you pass out on me, legend.
I'm going to tell you
who killed your wife.
It gives me great pleasure
to know...
that you know who did it
and that you can't do a
fucking thing about it.
Lai Lai Zhen came after you.
Lai Lai Zhen.
She killed your wife.
You're a liar.
Am I?
I think I'll have that drink now.
That's the spirit.
Toast the new champion.
I think we're done here.
You okay?
oh, no. For a minute there
I thought it was all just a bad dream.
You'll be okay.
Oh.
Oh, please.
Please, God, help me through this.
Please give me some strength because-
because I need a drink!
Sorry, I was...
Bless me, Father, I have sinned.
Aah!
Stakes are high, ladies and gentlemen,
a favorite will fall.
You're lucky I got to
you before Joshua did.
He's pretty pissed you killed his wife.
no, no.
Wait, wait.
Please, please stop.
Finish the fucker!
You...
Don't do it!
Please! I'm sorry.
Don't do it. Don't do it.
I'm sorry.
Pull the fucking trigger!
Let's get as close as we can.
Keep him locked. We gotta wait.
He said what?
It's the right thing.
What is it?
No!
Aah!
Hello? Mill's service station.
It's, um-
it's for you.
Hello?
Father Macavoy,
we haven't met,
but I feel I know you intimately.
So you're the sick fucker
that's running all this, are ya?
Such profanity from a man of the cloth.
now I suggest you listen to me
very, very carefully.
Since you deemed it
necessary to interrupt
what could have been a spectacular kill,
I feel I should clarify
the rules a little.
There's a time limit you
really should take note of.
Time limit? What are you talking about?
It's very simple.
You need to start killing
if you want to stay alive.
I'm not going to kill anyone.
We shall wait and see.
It will be your faith
against your desire to live.
That device inside you is
so much more than a tracker,
as you've just witnessed.
There's only four hours
left of the game, Father.
If there's more than
one player still alive
when the clock hits zero,
everyone will meet the same fate
as your American friend.
So let's see if you have any real guts.
It's kill or be killed.
Four hours, Father,
and the clock is ticking.
Thank you.
Well, that's perfect.
Let's bring a replay of that up on one.
Jesus.
We have to do that to all of them
if the time runs out?
No, it takes them out automatically.
What's the priest doing?
If the sat imagery is correct,
he is trying to sort his shit out.
Anything yet?
Nothing's happening. I'm too tense.
It's got to come out
one end or the other.
Can you not wait outside?
I'm staying put. now concentrate.
You're putting me off.
Can you whistle or something?
okay, who's Joshua's wife?
It doesn't matter.
okay.
I thought the way you
reacted when you heard-
Will you just leave it alone?
Bit of a confession in here, really, eh?
Confession can be incredibly hard.
It's painful to admit our sins
and trust ourselves in God's care.
But it helps.
It helps...
sometimes.
Why don't you tell me why you're here?
Hmm?
What's it got to do with Joshua's wife?
The last thing you see
in a target's eyes...
is understanding.
Somewhere, deep inside of them,
they've been expecting it.
Mary Harlow didn't have that look.
She just stared at me,
like you did this morning-
petrified, scared...
bewildered.
I saw in her eyes
that something was wrong.
Please!
My instincts told me to stop.
But I pulled the trigger anyway.
I didn't know it until afterwards,
but she was pregnant.
It's haunted me ever since.
That's why I have to
win this tournament...
so I can get enough money to vanish.
And if I don't win...
then I get what's coming.
Okay, Miss Hunter, the
final few players...
seem to be converging on the motorway.
We got Harlow on the move,
we're tracking Bogart nearby,
and the long shot,
Topuzov, is closing in fast.
Lai Lai Zhen and the
priest are sitting ducks.
We have to get out of here now.
- I haven't-
- Now.
Okay.
Shit.
Quick, get to the car.
Oh, shit.
Come on!
What's going on?
- I'm taking your bus.
- What?
I'm taking your bus.
Drive.
- I can't drive a bus.
- Learn fast!
Fuck.
What about the passengers?
Everybody down!
Come on!
Lai Lai!
Fuck.
They're coming up on the Frenchman.
How is he gonna get in on the action?
Lai Lai! Come and see this.
I'm a little busy
now. Can you handle it?
It's more in your department, really!
Jeez, they're going way too fast.
They're out of control.
That guy's got a ticket.
Maybe not.
Holy shit. Lai Lai's taking a beating.
open the door!
Lai Lai!
Lai Lai, what are we gonna do?
Drive!
What have I done?
You saved me.
I'm gonna be sick.
Shit.
okay, that is confirmed, sir.
Bogart is down and the priest
has officially left the game.
What about Joshua?
Father...
what are you doing still here?
I cannot protect you anymore.
Please go.
I don't wanna go.
Why not?
You didn't abandon me,
so I'm not going to abandon you, yes?
We should go.
Come on.
only five minutes remaining,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let me remind you,
if we don't have a winner
when the time runs out,
we will pay out on the current
favorite, Joshua Harlow.
No cameras.
They cannot see us in here.
What did you say?
There are no cameras in there.
- What about satellite?
- They're indoors.
Did I speak to you?
There are 30 people in
there who paid $10 million.
We're in the final few minutes.
I want everything and anything
pointed at that fucking church!
Wow, that really helps.
okay, okay.
If we can't show what, we
can at least show where.
We'll give 'em something to watch.
You have to get to a hospital.
I want you to pray with me.
of course.
You said your prayers?
I hope you said goodbye.
Please, this is God's house.
no killing in God's house.
God? Why, Lai Lai?
Did someone send you,
or was it personal?
- Just kill me.
- no, no, no.
Get it over with.
Why?
Why'd you come after me?
I didn't come after you.
What?
I wasn't there for you.
I was there for her.
The contract was on your wife.
Why?
Why would anyone want to kill Mary? Why?
I don't know why.
We never know why.
Please, please. Joshua, please.
She's not to blame.
She's not to blame for any of this.
She's a device, like a tool.
- She didn't want to kill your wife.
- no, shut up!
- She didn't want
to kill- - Shut up!
Mary was my life.
Mary was my life! Who hired you?
She was your life. She was your life.
Don't dishonor her now with death.
Who hired you?
- You're dishonoring her with death!
- Shut up!
Who hired you?
You know who hired me.
Joshua, what would Mary do?
What would Mary have you do?
We have a winner.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I want to present to you...
the two-time winner of the Tournament.
Please be upstanding
for the greatest assassin of our time!
Joshua...
I know everything.
Why?
What?
I put on a good show, didn't I?
You can keep all this money that I won,
if you just tell me why
you murdered my wife.
You're delirious, Joshua.
I'm dying, but you're sweating.
now why is that?
What's the matter,
you afraid to admit it?
Come on.
Come on, we're all killers here!
You need a doctor.
You're being absurd.
Why? Why did you murder my wife?
or are you too fucking gutless?
Why?
Because it was necessary.
You didn't want to come
back to the Tournament.
I wasn't going to accept that.
You're the reigning champion.
Look at you, Joshua!
You're a warrior, gladiator.
Men like you don't die in your beds,
they fall on the field.
They give the crowd...
a glorious death.
Why?
Because if I'd have just asked...
you'd have said no.
You needed a little motivation-
pressure...
on that little chink in the armor.
Close your eyes.
You and your wife
will be together soon.
I love you, baby.
Host. Joshua, wait! Wait!
Joshua!
We'll see her together.
Jesus, he took her tracker out.
override. It's gonna blow.
So, uh, I'm going to go home.
Yeah, me too.
newscaster. Terror
stepped up a notch today.
Bombs are believed to have gone off
in both a city center church
and a popular strip
bar on the outskirts...
our little town has been tested,
played witness to events
beyond comprehension,
besieged by darkness.
...many major road accidents,
the worst of which a
mile-long motorway pileup.
And yet, here we are again,
our spirits renewed...
reborn.
...the debilitating lack
of any CCTV footage...
...to increase surveillance
to blanket proportions.
Macavoy. I'm reminded of the words
of the American writer Robert Nathan
when he said, "We must
give thanks to the sorrow
"that shows us pity,
"to the pain that teaches us courage,
"and to the mystery which
is a mystery still. "
Let us pray.
More My Movies:
www.thepiratebay.org/user/Movie4All/