Lafayette Courier.
Got it. Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Cam! You guys seen...
You seen Cam?
Cam? Where in the hell is he?
Tell me where you at, buddy.
Damn.
Cam! Uptown Express, okay?
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You! Come back here!
Sorry about your bike.
Come back here!
Cam.
Cam?
You want your check or not?
Sorry.
Lonnie, I need more runs.
Cam, I'm happy to help you out,
but you need a bike first, man.
Got a friend that can loan you one?
Yeah.
Keep your head up, man.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Hey!
- What?
Where you been hiding?
What you got there, Cam?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
Okay, so, what,
you forget about us or what?
No, I didn't forget.
I just... I didn't have it.
I just got that.
Okay. Well, what else you got?
- Come on.
- Come on, man.
Are you serious?
I am serious.
What is that, 9 dollars?
Yeah, 9 doll... probably.
- Where's all your money going, man?
- To you guys!
You came to us
for a loan, right, Cam?
You accepted our terms.
1,500 on the first
of each month, every month?
I know.
I know. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I missed the payment.
It won't happen again.
No, it won't. Now...
sign this, please.
Jerry, I owe somebody rent.
And what?
You think I'm doing this for fun?
No. I can't...
This is my job, Cam, okay?
I got a boss
just like you got a boss.
Now just sign it, okay?
This is the second time
you been late,
and, uh, that makes us, um...
What does that make us?
- Nervous.
- See? Hu is nervous.
- Yeah.
So you owe us $15,000,
and just don't miss
another payment.
I won't.
Don't miss another payment.
I know.
- You good, buddy?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
You all right?
Yeah, I'm good.
Okay.
Where's your bike?
I, uh... I hit a pothole.
Yeah, looks like
you got bigger problems.
Let's get in here.
All right.
When are we gonna go for a ride?
Car's still broken, buddy.
I haven't had time to work on it.
And I don't have the money
for the parts I need.
Maybe you ought to sell her.
Yeah, maybe.
Joey?
All right, you're good to go.
Thanks a lot, Cam.
You're welcome.
I told you to give Cam his space.
Chillax, Mom, it's all gravy.
Chillax? Sorry about that.
Don't worry about it.
He's a good kid.
Hey, Ange?
Can I talk to you for a second?
Gonna be a little late
on the rent this month.
I'm sorry.
I'll get it to you as soon as I can.
I know you're good for it,
but I'm having a tough month.
Try your best, please, Cam?
I know. I will.
Thank you.
Yeah?
You coming in today or not?
What are you talking about?
Do you not remember?
What do you want me
to do with your new bike then?
What new bike?
The one your girlfriend
dropped off here this morning.
I don't have a girlfriend.
Hey, there, mister
What you want?
We've seen
You before
And, hey, there, mister
What you need?
We've seen you before
And your greed
We've heard it all before
And we've seen it all before
No more
Hey!
Hey, now
You can take her heart
It's you and her tonight
Said, hey, now
Hey, now
Hey, hey, stop! Hey!
What do you want?
To... To say thank you.
- For what?
- What do you mean, for what?
For the bike you got me.
You're welcome.
Do you, uh...
How did you learn
how to do parkour?
What, did I say it wrong?
I gotta go.
Wait, what's your name?
Do you ride?
No. Bike's a ball and chain.
Oh, yeah?
All right.
Well, you know,
anybody can hop up
and climb this thing.
I'd like to see that.
All right. You got it.
Oh, boy.
Maybe you should
stick to the bike.
I'm Cam.
Nikki.
You gonna show me
something else?
Oh!
God.
You gotta learn how to see.
I can see just fine.
If you want to vault the car,
don't look at the car.
Look where the car isn't.
Okay.
Whoa, hey!
How did you get over there?
Nice to meet you, Cam.
Who are you?
What are you
doing here, Dylan?
I'm just looking out
for you, Niks.
So, what? You're just
spying on me the whole time?
You working out alone?
So what?
So you gotta be careful.
That's all I'm saying.
You gotta stay off my ass, Dyl!
Who is this guy?
He's nobody.
Haven't seen you around.
I haven't been around.
Where'd you find him?
He found me.
You following her?
No, no.
Just saw her in the park.
You know, this is dangerous stuff.
You get hurt if you
don't know what you're doing.
Let's bounce.
Wonderful.
Well, some of this stuff
is kind of beat up,
but, uh, I'll give you 450.
Look, my rent's 550.
You got that?
1, 2, 3, 4, 550.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
How much
for the muscle car, kid?
It was my dad's.
I'm gonna have to hold onto it.
Too bad. Nice car.
Hey, Cam.
You saw that, Mom?
Yeah, I did, baby. Come on.
Joey?
Not much to look at.
O...kay.
Watch the potholes this time,
all right?
Hey, buddy.
Looks like somebody's
been practicing.
You should come
work out with us.
I never see you guys around.
We're a tight group.
We like to keep to ourselves.
Loujaine floating terminal
in Brooklyn. You know it?
No.
Pier 62, Gowanus Bay.
I'll see you at dawn.
All right!
Hey, guys.
I'm Dylan.
This is Tate, Jax.
How's it goin'?
- Cam.
- What's up?
This is my sister, Nikki.
We already met.
This is awesome.
What are we supposed to do?
Try and keep up.
Yeah, yeah, wait for me, girl
-  Wait for me
-  Hey!
Wait for me, girl
Wait for me
Hey! Oh-oh-oh
Oh-oh-oh
Take heed
once the sun go down
Oh-oh-oh
Gonna chase that moon
till it come round
Oh-oh-oh
Take heed
once the sun go down
Oh-oh-oh
Gonna chase that moon
till it come round
People, yeah
Oh, yeah
That sugar gonna
bring me back to life
Say oh, yeah
That sugar gonna
bring me back to life
Give me some of that apple pie
Oh-oh-oh
Take heed
once the sun goes down
Oh-oh-oh
Gonna chase that moon
till it come round
Oh-oh-oh
Take heed
once the sun go down
Holy shit!
He's dead, dude.
Hey, there.
You must be Cam.
Dylan tells me
you're new to parkour.
He also said you're pretty good.
Might have to, uh, work
on this jump, though.
I'm Miller.
If you fight with gravity
before you're ready,
you tend to get a beating.
I don't know what I'm doing.
That's the great thing
about parkour, my friend.
There are no rules.
You all right?
I'm good.
Just trying to keep up.
Cam?
That short for Camaro?
You have a learning disability, dude.
Excuse him.
Where you from?
Queens.
Finished with high school?
No, I barely went.
I, uh, tried baseball once.
Did some martial arts.
Yeah, I wasn't much of jock
in high school, either.
Look at you. Hello.
Where'd you do your time?
It's okay. You're not the only one
in here with a record.
Abbott House, Hillside.
Juvie.
Yeah.
Did 6 months in Otisville
a couple of years ago.
No shit. What for?
B&E, boosting cars.
Just bullshit stuff.
You ever go in hard?
Pull some holdups.
No. Didn't want to go that way.
All right.
So what you do for money?
I'm a bike messenger.
50 points for the bike messenger.
What you guys deliver?
Documents, just business stuff.
At least that's
what they tell you.
I don't know. I mean,
they hand me a package, I drop it off.
Sure, but it could
be anything, right?
I guess.
You never look inside the bag?
No.
Never?
No. Why would I do that?
Just curiosity.
It's none of my business.
But you're the one
carrying the package.
Look, as long
as after I drop it off,
they pay me my money,
I don't really care
what's inside the bag.
So what do you guys do?
We do whatever we can
not to get caught.
That looks like fun.
There are no limits, my friend,
only plateaus.
Plateaus?
You've got to constantly push past
what you think you can do,
or you stay stuck.
What else you got?
Well, how about this?
This whole thing, parkour,
free running, tracing,
whatever you want to call it,
it's just a state of mind.
Now, the real obstacles
are not out there.
They're in your head, okay?
Mmm, I don't know,
those obstacles
look pretty real to me.
Well, you're gonna have to start
seeing them differently.
Got it.
So look where the car isn't.
Exactly.
So, uh, how's
that new bike treating you?
It's good. Thanks again.
Where is it?
I left it at home today.
Liar.
Somebody clipped it,
and I didn't want to say anything.
I get it.
You're one of those kind of people.
What... What kind
of people is that?
Who can't hang
onto anything nice.
Guess I haven't
had enough practice.
Don't worry about it.
Should have known better.
I mean, next time, I'll just take
my wallet and burn it.
Hey, Niks! Let's go!
You guys all work together?
See you around, Cam.
Good to meet you, Cam.
Don't let these guys
get you in trouble.
Oh, shit!
Excuse me, is Jerry here?
- Back there?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Excuse me, sir.
Is Jerry here?
You just missed him.
Do you know
when he'll be back?
When he returns.
Okay.
Hey! Hey, hey!
What are you doing?
Hey, Cam!
You didn't tell us you had
such a sweet ride, man.
I have your cash right here!
Here!
- There you go. Take it.
- All right.
We're taking 5 grand
off your tab for the car,
but you got one month
to get us the rest, all right?
How am I supposed to get
10 grand in a month, Jerry?
Not my problem, Cam.
Jerry, cut me some slack,
come on!
You still don't understand
how this works, do you?
If you don't pay,
we don't shoot you.
You got one month, Cam.
Go inside house, Joey, now.
Joey.
Hey, Angie, I'm sorry.
Your friends gave Joey a ride home
from school today, Cam.
Those assholes brought
my son home from school.
I don't know
what you're involved in,
and I don't want to know.
Stay away from us.
I mean it.
Hey, look who's here.
Hey, what's up, buddy?
You okay?
I want in.
You are in.
We don't just let
anybody train with us.
No. I'm talking about work.
Whatever you guys got going on,
I want in on it.
What's your problem?
What, do you guys think I'm a narc
or something? Come on.
Hey, Dylan,
I need to talk to Miller.
Hook me up.
No. It's a bad idea.
Why?
You know something I don't?
We're
in the transport business, Cam.
We move valuables.
People hire us to make
obstacles go away,
change hands,
land with someone else.
The difference is,
I provide assurances
that other people can't.
I guarantee the work.
You want
some evidence to disappear?
We can take care
of that for you.
It's a profession.
We're not thrill-seekers
who pull any score
that comes along.
The key is speed and silence.
In and out, fast and quiet.
We do our research,
plan every move,
work as a team.
Everyone knows their job.
Documents, chemicals,
technology, anything.
We don't take sides.
Now, I've just got two rules.
The first is, if you get in trouble,
I'm your first call.
The second,
stay out of Chinatown,
even if you're not on a job.
Why is that?
I'm inviting you to sit down
at the dinner table.
Show me you know
how to be a good guest.
Nice work!
Dyl!
Turn around!
- Hold him! Don't move!
- I'm not!
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Who do you work for?
I said,
who do you work for, huh?
It's a question!
No one.
What's in the bag?
Tell me what's in the bag!
I don't know what's in the bag.
- Give it to me.
- No!
Give it to me!
Give me the bag!
You tell me
what's in that bag!
what's in that bag,
or I'm gonna blow
your brains out right now,
I swear to God.
What is in the bag?
I just carry the bag!
Good work, Cam.
What's going on?
You pulled some serious moves
out there, pal.
Dude, we heard
about the bust-out. Sick!
You were hauling ass.
Hey, it's all right, buddy.
We just had to make sure
you had our backs.
You're family now.
What do you think?
I think
you're a bunch of assholes,
especially you.
Hey.
Where you taking me?
All right.
Where are the others?
They're busy.
Well, you want to grab
a coffee or something?
This isn't a date.
I didn't...
I didn't mean it like a date.
Let's just get this done, okay?
So how long you been
working for Miller?
Few years.
Did you grow up in the city?
No.
Where'd you learn
how to do parkour?
Here.
You still live with Dylan?
Okay, enough
with the questions, okay?
I'm just trying
to make conversation.
Yeah, but you wanted to be in?
Guess what? You're in.
There's nothing left to discuss.
- What's your deal?
- My deal?
- Yeah. What's your deal?
- I don't have a deal.
Then why are you
acting like this?
There is no deal.
Acting like what?
I don't know.
I just thought we...
Look, I didn't
ask you to come find me.
Really?
Are you sure about that?
You did give me that bike.
Not sure what...
All right, I'm gonna tell Miller
you can work
on your own next time.
You don't need a babysitter.
Okay.
This the new guy?
Yeah.
Good luck, new guy.
Dylan, Jax, Nikki, Tate,
employee of the month, Cam.
Angie?
What are you doing here, Cam?
I'm working.
I know.
I brought your rent money.
I don't care what you brought.
I told you
to leave us alone, right?
Angie.
Angie, please.
Hey.
Please take it.
Okay?
It'll hold you over until you find
somebody else to move in.
This is too much.
What kind of trouble
are you in?
My mom got sick
after she lost her job.
So I borrowed
some money off the street
to try and help
her keep the house.
It wasn't enough,
so the bank foreclosed on her
a week before she died.
You got a good heart, Cam,
but you gotta be careful.
The farther you go
down the wrong road,
the harder it gets
to find your way back.
I have to get to work.
Wait, one sec, one sec.
Can you give this to Joey?
You don't have
to tell him it's from me.
I'm sorry for everything.
I really am.
I won't bother you guys again,
I promise.
Hey!
What do you think, man?
Factory paint, green gray.
14-inch rally wheels.
You got something for us?
Uh, there's not
even 2 grand here, man.
I need 10.
Give me a few more weeks,
I'll get it to you.
Well, that's past
the deadline, Cam.
I was hoping
we could renegotiate.
Look, I got a new job.
You can raise
the vig if you want to.
Oh!
You're still acting
like I'm the boss, Cam.
I'm not, all right?
Chen is the boss.
The money you owe me,
I owe Chen.
You put me
in a tight spot here, Cam.
Now, I don't want
to see anything happen
to your friend and her little boy,
but you don't make this right,
it will.
Those are the rules.
2 weeks, Cam.
10 grand.
Ohh.
Yeah?
We're goin' out tonight.
You want to come?
Work?
More like play.
Hold Tate tight.
Can I get a water?
Hey, what happened here?
- This?
- Yeah.
I bit the wall trick.
Oh, how is the wall?
Check this out.
Got it on a broken rail.
That's nothin', man.
Check this out.
Razor wire.
Dyl, why don't you show them
what happened right here, huh?
Is that from a curb?
- Nah.
- It was a older lady.
- Hello, grandma!
- He loves the cougs.
She was a nice girl.
She was Chinese.
She was real smart.
I met her on the subway.
Whatever, whatever.
I see her walking down
the street one night with this guy.
I assume it must be
her cousin or something,
so I go up to her,
I give her a big hug and a kiss,
and she freaks out
like she's never seen me before.
Goes totally ape-shit.
Turns out the cuz
was her husband.
Yeah, husband,
mixed martial artist.
Bad news for the lady killer.
Is that why we can't
cut through Chinatown?
Nah, that's on Miller, man.
He's got bad blood
with the gangs there.
With the Tongs?
Yeah, yeah.
Since the business went south,
he had to cut a deal,
promise to stay away.
You know,
Nikki's got some cute marks.
Hey, hey!
I don't know
what he's talkin' about.
Not happening.
If I show you,
I'd have to kill you.
He said it.
There she is,
the future Mrs. Jackson Smith
right there.
Oh, yeah?
That's gonna be
my future ex-wife.
Yeah, we're gonna move
to the countryside,
make lots of sweet ginger babies
every night of the week...
- Oh! That's terrible!
- For the rest of our lives.
Ugh!
I know, you're jealous.
You guys know
nothin' about women.
Hey.
Hey, hey.
What happened?
Nothin'. It's just stuffy
as hell in there, that's all.
Do you want to...
You want to get out of here?
You want to go
somewhere else?
Not right now, no. I can't.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Nothin'.
Nikki, what are you afraid of?
Hey, guys.
Sorry I missed the fun.
Had some business
to take care of.
Yeah.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Hey, Cam,
if you need anything at all,
call me, all right?
Yeah.
Coming back in?
No, I'm tired. I'm...
I'm gonna hit it.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to talk to you.
How did you find me?
Why are you living
on the roof?
Why didn't you tell me
you're with Miller?
Dylan got into some trouble.
And Miller made it go away.
So your brother
pimped you out to the boss.
Sounds pretty simple to me.
Miller doesn't own me.
Is that right?
Why are you here?
What's the point?
I should have told you.
It's my fault, but, Cam, you wouldn't
even be here if I hadn't...
So you want me to quit?
You can still walk.
Is that what you want?
I don't want you
to owe Miller like we do!
Do you want me to go?
No.
I heard once
tattoos are like scars
that you wear on the outside
to show the pain
that's on the inside.
Is that true?
I don't know.
Why don't you have any?
'Cause I don't
want anyone to know.
I owe people money, Nikki.
And as soon as I pay them off...
I'm gone.
And this moment
was brought to you
by the sounds of summer
in New York City.
Yeah, or in an overcrowded prison.
- I don't really mind it.
- No?
No. I mean, before I left Florida,
I'd never even seen a town
bigger than 500 people.
Well, you're lucky,
'cause all I've
ever seen is this jungle.
You've never been
outside the city?
No.
I mean,
I don't count my jail time.
I tried to leave.
When?
After my mom died.
When she passed away,
I found out that
she had my dad's old car,
and she never told me
while she was alive,
'cause she was afraid
if I found out,
I'd sell it to try and help her out.
So, uh...
she kept it a secret.
She wrote me a letter.
She said she wanted me
to fix it up,
get it running again,
just hop in
and drive somewhere.
I don't know where, far away.
California maybe.
That was the plan.
Well, where's the car now?
The, uh...
The bank took it.
The bank?
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh.
Guess I'm just
one of those people
who can never hold
onto anything nice.
I'll agree with that.
What?
Where have you been, baby?
I went for a walk.
Anything wrong?
Hmm? No.
Nothing. You know, I just get
nervous before the big jobs,
that's all.
You sure that's all?
You seem kind of distant.
Yeah.
Like you're somewhere else.
No. I'm right here, James.
I don't know
what I'd do without you.
You know that.
I'm just tired.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Sure.
Gettin' better.
Nikki and I were living
on the streets when we found parkour.
We got hooked.
It's like being kids again,
and the whole city
is our playground.
Is that where you met Miller?
Uh-huh, yeah.
Miller raised us,
taught us everything we knew,
got us off the streets.
We'd be nowhere without him.
Yeah, Nikki said that he, uh...
got you out of some
sort of trouble or something.
Nikki said that?
Yeah.
What did she tell you exactly?
Uh, nothing specifically.
Just that you got
in some sort of trouble,
and he made it go away.
Look, she really cares about you.
She doesn't want
to see you get hurt.
Are you in some sort
of trouble, Cam?
'Cause if you are
and Miller finds out,
it's not just you.
That's trouble for all of us.
And he always finds out.
No, I'm all good.
Good.
I got the last one.
Unit 17, code.
All clear! Good job!
Whoo!
That's what I'm talkin' about!
That's how we do it!
Wait.
I'll, uh, catch up with you later?
Sure. Talk later.
Well, what do you mean?
Where's our money?
Payday's next week, Cam.
Same as usual.
Uh, okay.
When's the next gig happening?
Soon.
Hey, you did a good job.
Get some rest.
You don't understand.
I need that money.
Do we have a problem?
No, no. Got no problem.
I've got a big job
coming up next week.
It's worth 15,
20 grand each at least.
Does that work for you guys?
- Sweet.
- Sounds good.
How about you, Cam?
Work for you?
Yeah, that works.
Good.
You look just like your dad.
I get that a lot.
It's a nice, constant reminder
of the amazing father he was.
Well, if it's any consolation,
my dad wasn't exactly
a real winner, either.
Sometimes
it's better not to know.
Yeah.
Just gonna leave, aren't you?
You should come with me.
Yeah, right.
- Why, yeah, right?
- I can't.
Why not?
It's complicated.
Well...
I'm not going anywhere
without wheels.
Hold onto this for me.
Thank you.
Nice spot.
I can see all the way
into the future from up here.
Yeah, what happened
to staying in the moment?
You're a good student, Cam.
Now you're moving
beyond what you been taught,
beyond the rules.
But outside, there's a natural order
to things, you know.
There can only be
one alpha for every pack.
And that, my friend,
I learned the hard way
a long time ago
in the back
of a Chinese restaurant,
trying to beg for my life
with a gun in my mouth.
Is there something
you need to tell me, Cam?
There's nothing.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Should get some plants up here.
Liven this place up a bit.
Pickup tomorrow at 9:30.
Hey, guys.
Where's Nikki?
Gave her the day off.
2 minutes.
You'll be needing this.
Hey, we're goin' in strong?
I told you it was big, my friend.
We're gonna get a cut.
20 grand each, maybe more.
I didn't sign up for this.
Okay, it's up here on the corner.
Hey, we're doing a bank?
Old bank, new money.
BTK bought it.
BTK?
Vietnamese bangers.
This is their Laundromat,
and they keep a big stack.
Couple hundred K.
Well, how do you know all this?
It's my job.
How we gettin' in this thing?
Through the front door.
What?
I'm risking a lot here, man.
Tell your men
to make this look good.
Okay, game time.
Who's got my piece?
You're carrying the baggage.
You'll be all right.
We've done this before.
We don't even shoot these things.
Be safe, kids.
Stay out of trouble.
Masks.
Hand off the gun!
Toss him the gun.
Toss him the gun!
You deaf?
You don't like to listen, huh?
Get on the ground.
You think this is funny?
You think this is a game?
Get on the ground!
Are you deaf?!
Get on the floor!
We gotta get movin', guys!
Oh!
What...
What's the combination?
Break it down!
Tell me how we get inside!
Think this is funny?
Tell me what the combo is!
What, is everybody
deaf and dumb here?
Answer his question!
What's the combination?
I don't have it.
Is there another way in?
Yo, come on!
I can get in.
What the hell are you doing?
I can't see shit with this thing!
We gotta move, guys!
There's nothing! It's empty!
Check again!
Where's the money?
I don't know, Dude!
I don't know!
What are you laughing, big guy?
They picked it up early.
But he wouldn't have known that.
Would you?
- Dude, let's just go!
- You're dead.
Back off!
Aah!
Go! Now!
Oh! Come on!
Aha! Where you goin',
you little bitch?
Fuck!
Go! Go! Go!
You better run!
Aah! Oh!
Aah!
Jax, stay in place!
Come on! Come on!
Freeze!
Stay down!
Put your hands up
where I can see 'em! Now!
Stay right there.
Get down!
How about your dead buddy, huh?
Has he got a name?
I don't know. Might be nice
to let his family know
where to pick up his remains.
He doesn't have any family.
What the hell did you do
to get half the BTK
to chase your little asses
down the street?
Look, if you had anything real
to charge me with, you wouldn't be asking.
The Feds would
like a word with you.
Ooh!
Have fun, kid.
- Miller?
- No sudden moves, okay?
What are you doing here?
James Hatcher.
I'm with the DEA.
You thought jumping a 20-foot gap
5 stories up was a rush.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Just breathe for me,
Cam, okay?
We don't have much time.
Hey, where's Dylan and Tate?
They're in the van
on the way home.
They should be hitting
the tunnel by now.
Wait, do they know about this?
Cam, they all know.
How the hell
do you think I ran this circus?
Miller's the man on the ground...
Shipping and receiving,
HR, transpo.
Hatcher's upstairs... due diligence,
client relations, new business.
Neither one of them
gets much sleep,
but they work well together.
You got to be kidding me.
I been working
for a dirty Fed this whole time.
Yeah, or a clean criminal.
Depends on your point of view.
What about Jax, huh?
Okay, I got bad intel
on this one, okay?
And Jax is gone.
But that's the past.
All we have is the moment,
and right now, in this moment,
New York PD thinks
you're one of my Cls.
That means you get to walk
out of here with me
right now under my protection.
Yeah, so they can find my body
in a dumpster tomorrow morning?
No, thank you.
Cam, I'm not gonna hurt you.
I need your help.
The cops are rousting
the whole gang.
Sooner or later, someone's gonna
talk themselves out of trouble,
and that will lead back to me.
It's time for me to cash out.
Is this your "one last score" speech?
Save it.
It's my exit plan,
but I cannot do it
without your help.
If you want me,
I need my 10 grand today,
right now!
Then we'll talk.
That's not gonna happen.
Fine. Then I'm not
helping you, all right?
I'm out.
The thing is, Cam,
it's not just about you
anymore, is it?
Because you
became part of a family,
so you have to think
about the welfare of others.
Where is she?
I don't want Nikki
mixed up in this anymore,
so you and I
are gonna finish this.
Hey!
Why didn't you tell me?
Hmm?
I told you to get out.
You played me from the start.
No.
- The bike? That was all bullshit?
- No.
This has been a setup
the whole time?
- Cam, I swear, that was all me.
- Yeah, right!
I felt bad for wrecking you out.
I wanted to get you a new one.
I didn't think all of this
was gonna happen.
Well, then what did you think?
You wanted in, Cam.
No, I wanted you.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I wanted to tell you.
I did, but I ju... I couldn't.
Why not?
Because of Dylan.
What do you mean,
because of Dylan?
What did Dylan do that's so bad
that you couldn't
tell me this whole time?
He ju...
You know,
Dylan's your older brother, Nikki.
You don't need to babysit him.
You can let him deal
with his own problems.
Somebody did something
to me, okay?
Back in Florida?
Some scumbag came
into my bedroom late at night.
He started touching me.
Dylan walked in,
and he beat him into a coma.
The cops came after us.
They chased us
all the way over here,
and then I met Miller,
and Miller made it all go away.
Dylan was there
that night to protect me,
and now it's my job
to protect him.
Cam, I was scared to tell you
anything else, because...
'Cause I didn't want you to go.
Look...
if I can get us
a clean exit tomorrow...
will you come with me?
Miller's not gonna
let us just walk away.
Do you want to leave
Miller or not, Nikki?
I told you what could
happen to Dylan and to us
if anything ever went wrong.
Do you remember?
Yeah.
What?
Yes.
I'm getting us out of this life...
and we're gonna start over.
Just you and me
this time, okay?
Where we going?
Guys and I got a plane
to catch when we're done.
We'll drop you on the way
to the airport,
after you get
your 10 grand, of course.
Here.
Put these on.
Let's go.
Nikki and Tate, pull lookout
while we make the pickup, okay?
Where are we?
It's a safe house.
Russians keep their VIPs here.
They stash other stuff, too.
Well, what do you need me for?
It's a two-man job.
Well, why can't Dylan
go in with you?
Dylan's watching our exit.
How are we getting in,
through the skylight?
Copy that.
What's inside there?
A new plateau, my friend.
It's not loaded.
Can't we go in unarmed?
I'm going in with you.
It's you and me together
this time, all right?
You're really down
with this, Dylan?
How about you just
do your job, all right?
Hey, get your head in it,
Cam, right now!
We're doing this for Nikki,
remember?
- Pull over.
- Why?
'Cause I gotta take a piss.
Tate, come on!
- I can't.
- What?
Come on, Nikki.
Everybody knows about you and Cam.
Stop the van, Tate.
- No.
- Pull over!
Would you shut up already?
Pull the fuck over.
Once we're inside,
just do everything I say.
I've got this all worked out.
On 3. Ready?
1, 2, 3.
Be quiet!
Don't move! Don't move!
Sit! Sit down!
What's going on?
Watch them!
Don't move.
What's the exit plan?
Huh?
This is the exit plan, Cam.
Dylan, what are you doing?
- Don't... Don't move.
- Dylan.
Do it! He's got the diamonds!
Dylan.
Dylan, put the gun down!
Don't move!
All units, 10-10, shots fired
at 2-3-1 West 23rd.
Repeat, shots fired.
DEA! I'm taking your car!
No!
Nikki! Nikki, are you okay?
- Huh?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- Come on. Come on.
Come on.
This way!
No, no, no.
I'm done!
Move away, Nikki.
I don't want to hurt you.
I'm not gonna ask
you again, baby.
Move away.
Agent Hatcher.
Chen?
James...
Okay, listen, I can explain.
There's been a mistake.
There has.
You made it.
Yeah, I believe
it was rule number 2.
Stay out of Chinatown.
- You son of a bitch!
- Watch your language.
You're in Chen's house now.
I told you a long time ago
to keep your business
out of my neighborhood.
And I did, Chen.
I did, but this is personal.
So is this.
You've been making
too much trouble
for too many of my friends.
Okay, Chen,
listen to me, please...
There is a boat leaving
for Macau in 2 hours.
Mr. Hu will make sure you're on it.
Time to close you out.
You're dead, both of you.
You're dead.
But enough about him.
You have something for me?
If I were you,
I'd seriously consider leaving town.
Congratulations.
Your debt is clear.
That's it?
We're all done.
Wait.
What about our deal?
Where to?
Let's just drive.
Can I borrow your time?
Am I losing my mind?
My skin is aching
Brittle bones
are breaking, breaking
It's so bracing outside
Showers and showers
of unhappiness
Blowing air to the little, little
Tunnels in my brain
I can hear the familiar voices
rumble, rumble
I can feel my life in those hands
crumble, crumble
I had a dream
that I had heavy feet
And that takes you
from her sleep
Had a dream that I was
crushing sheets alone
I had a dream
that I was told to keep
Oh, I sing from her sleep
Had a dream husbands
did strip the widows' bones