LoveDramasAsia
♪ You
♪ Threw me
♪ Away and
♪ Into whose arms
♪ Have you gone
♪ The scar in my heart
♪ No way to forget
♪ Gone
♪ Beautiful
♪ Shadow of love
♪ Passionate rose colored love
♪ Pain of the dark scar too
♪ Deep within my heart ♪ You left only sorrow
♪ To you ♪ I'm crying quietly again tonight
Episode 1
Wooh! I like it!
I wonder if you ever heard of Sabuk in Gangwondo.
They said it was popular as a mining town.
Back then they said even the dogs in backstreet were carrying a $10 bill...
I wouldn't know that since I haven't seen it, but
what I know for sure is after the mine closed down, it turned into a deserted area, then
one day a casino and a resort came in, and a new world has been born.
Right now it's past 12 a.m.
Still the price of land that jumped up because of the casino
is a modest $20,000 for about 36 sq ft.
Does that make sense?
Anyway, if you don't know me, Heo Yeong Dal, here at Sabuk, you're a spy.
Yeong Dal Oppa!
Why haven't you been around?
Don't do that. - Alright.
Why, you ask?
That, you'll find out eventually.
Where is he? - Over there.
Before I get excited, how about listening to me carefully?
Do my words sound like a joke to you?
What, do I have to take off my shirt really?
Oh my! Ou!
What's wrong with you?
Aigoo, Noonim I thought I wouldn't be able to see you.
They told me you and hyungnim went out, so...
Let's go. Let's get out for now.
If we have come all the way here, we should see Hyung's face before we leave.
Where is he?
Hyungnim! Hyungnim, where are you? Hyungnim!
Yeong Dal. -Jang Soo, go bring hyungnim.
Yeong Dal, let's leave, huh?
What's wrong with you today?
Are you crazy?
How long has it been that you took money that you're acting up again?
Aish, you're talking a bit weird there.
What do you mean take?
--Am I a thug or what?--You bastard.
You won't even be able to be called a thug.
You're trash! Dog waste!
If you come out like this, I won't be able to control myself either.
A human being should have a limit!
Don't you think you're going too far?
Aigoo, scary.
If you can't control yourself, what are you going to do?
Are you saying you want to try me?
Yes, let's do that.
I can't live. You dog trash like bastard!
Wow. You're coming on strong.
Even so, I thought of you and kept my mouth closed.
If you come out like that
let's end it here.
This is a present I'm giving you. Take a look.
You...
Shall I send one to Hyungnim, too?
Do you think I'm the only one who's going to die?You'll die too, bastard!
If I'm scared of that I'm not Heo Yeong Dal.
Let's die together.
Wait a minute.
Wait...
It's the last.
No more.
I'm not an idiot either.
Don't worry.
If you're lonely, call me any time.
♪ Come to see me ♪ Come to see me
♪ When you're lonely ♪ Please come to see me
Did you get it?
Wow, you really are a player.
How did you get her when it looked as if she won't move an inch?
Let's go get a drink.
Let's go to the casino.
Why the casino again?
You'll lose it all on one hand!
I've totally got the feel for it today. I think I'm going to hit the jackpot.
You say that every time.
Yeong Dal,
how about let's just go to the room salon today?
Stop fooling around and follow me.
Ignorant...
I told you not to hit my head!
Metropolitan Area Investigative Unit
There's no need to speak for long.
Yes,
or no.
You have to give me one of two answers.
Easy, right?
This incident
it was ordered by Go Bok Tae.
Isn't that right?
Answer me.
Why are you like this? This case
really has nothing to do with Chairman Go.
I'm asking you for the last time.
It's Go Bok Tae, right?
Wow, you really can't understand a word I'm saying.
-What the?-What was that?
Aish, we've got another problem.
You bastard! -Oh!
Don't!
Let go you bastard! Let go!
Let go of me, bastard!
Lock that bastard up right now!
We've got whereabouts of Go Bok Tae.
Everyone get ready.
Won't we get in trouble without a warrant?
Hey, bastard. Why do we need a warrant for an arrest under exigent circumstances?
I'll take care of everything, so don't worry.
I heard four or five bodyguards wearing sashimi knives are always with him,
shouldn't we call for backup?
Hurry!
Earn your punishment, earn it.
Hey, haven't you figured out the boss's character yet?
I have.
What is it? - He is a total nut job!
Isn't he a nut job?
If we listen to a nut job and something goes wrong, will someone take the responsibility for that?
I'm Jang Dong Soo.
I'm a detective of Seoul Police Department, Metropolitan Area Investigative Unit.
The reason why I chose the metropolitan investigative unit is
entirely to demolish Go Bok Tae.
Go Bok Tae
is the chairman of Chung Jin Group, with 7 branches.
Even though he is known as a businessman who made tens of millions of dollars with apartment construction projects,
once we unveil his camouflage,
with his roots in the gang, he is an underworld boss .
I will talk more about the deep rooted misfortune between Go Bok Tae and myself as time goes on.
The war between me and him so far,
2 defeats out of 2. I have been defeated completely.
I have arrested him twice, but
I have not even been able to touch a strand of Go Bok Tae's hair.
Isn't it where the kids play if it's Chungdang club?
Don't you know?
The owner of that place is Go Bok Tae.
It's not a place that he made for money, but to play with kids.
Ah, dirty bastard.
Oh, come on in.
Sit.
Here.
Have a glass.
About this champagne and caviar...
you girls know Putin don't you, the president of Russia?
I know.
This was specially prepared for that Putin. We went through some trouble getting it.
Wow.
The taste is amazing, right?
Here.
-Cheers.-Cheers.
What the?!
Stay still you bastard!
Go Bok Tae!
I'll make sure to pop your cover today.
Ladies, can you please momentarily leave your seats?
You sure are a persistent ass.
What have you got against me from the past life to continue tightening your grip like this?
Stop talking crap
and let's put on your cuffs.
Did you bring a warrant?
It's an exigent circumstance arrest.
We don't need a warrant for a guy like you.
Exigent circumstance arrest?
You've been going at it for so long so now it's an "exigent circumstance" arrest?
What is it?
For suspicion of instigation of the murder of Donghae company president Yoo Jung Man.
Hey, you bastard, that's not going to do a thing. If you don't want to get humiliated again
then go bring other evidence.
Shut up and come out now!
Okay.
Let's go as far as you can.
Chairman.
There's no reason to be flustered.
Just call Lawyer Han.
Hey, hurry up and get him. What are you doing?!
If you don't want your head to have a hole in it then hurry up and get rid of those bastards!
Hey, wait! Wait!
Stop, stop!
-What is it?-Stay here.
You're Jeong Hee, aren't you?
I'm right, Oh Jeong Hee!
Hey, since when have you been working here?
For...about a month.
Don't linger around and get out.
Oh...o...okay.
Hey...
Wow, you finally got a career going for you.
Go quickly!
Okay...
Who was it?
Ah, her name's Oh Jeong Hee. My hoobae from Hanjoogong.
A girl that went to an all boy's school?
It was a coed school, you didn't know?
Wow, during her school days she used to be last place out of the whole school.
Even if she was stupid she had a lot of popularity because of her face.
Out of all the male classmates,
you can count with your finger the number of guys who didn't date that wench Jeong Hee.
What about you?
That wench is nice to everyone else, but just all tight lipped with me.
Idiot.
You got screwed.
I'm like that I guess.
Heo Yeong Dal you have been banned for 3 months.
What?
Why? -It's the security teams decision, so I'm not sure either.
Maybe it's because of that drinking incident.
Ah, that bastard really is going too far.
Hey,
Ah, just because of that it's not a week but three months of probation? So what do you want me to do about it?
Call the Team Leader.
Go on, call the Team Leader!
Quickly call him! Quickly!
What is the problem?
How can you treat a regular guest like this?
Are you guys really going to come out like this?
Are you going to look down on me like this when I've spent so much money here?
Ahjussi!
Ahjussi, don't you know who I am?
I'm asking if you don't know Heo Yeong Dal you bastards?
If you keep making disturbances we'll ban you permanently.
What? What about permanent?!
- Permanent?!- Calm down, Yeong Dal!
Hey Yeong Dal! Calm down!
- You keep this up, then~- Just wait a second!
Yeong Dal, you really can't do this!
Hey Yeong Dal! Please, don't make a scene.
Wait a moment. What are you looking at?
What are you looking at? Is there a show?
There's no movie, you bastards!
So embarrassing!
Let's just consider we saved money, and go have a drink.
Save what did we save?
I need to go play one.
Where are you going to do that?
Let's just go to Cheulgun.
What do you mean Cheulgun?
LoveDramasAsia
Why is the quality of customers so bad?
Madam Jang, isn't that Yeong Dal?
Should I get rid of him? -What do we need to face
again after we try to get rid of him?
Let them in.
Aigoo, this bastard.
Hello, Hyungnim.
Hey, do you have money?
Ah, so embarrassing. Why are you being like this?
Here, enough?
Hey, buy the chips first.
Okay, let me put that, hey.
How much did you say the max bet was here?
With that piddly $5k, you're looking for the maximim bet?
Just do whatever you feel like because I'll accept it all.
Don't say something different later.
Don't make a scene after losing all of your money.
If you act up again I'm going to bury you.
The picture today is so-so.
Did we ever look at the picture? We just went with the feel.
Right, let's go.
Over there?
Hello, Hyungnim.
Yeong Dal, what are you doing right now?
-Why do you ask?-Why?
Can't you see we're all bankers?
If you go the opposite, are you telling us to all lose?
My gut feeling is saying to play, Hyungnim.
If you want why don't you switch?
Give out the cards.
Card for player, card for bankers, players, bankers.
Come out, come out.
Okay.
Here.
My luck is back, it's back I tell you.
Good, there we go!
Yeah!
Good, good.
Got it!
You got it!
Oh, really...
Hyungnim, what did I say?
I've totally got the Player feel.
Wow.
Player natural 9, Banker natural 8.
Player win.
Yeong Dal, you
can get beaten up by me if you play like this.
-Move seats.-Yes, Hyungnim.
Aigoo.
Let's eat it.
-Hey, Yeong Dal let's take that out. -Aigoo, you're being so unlucky.
Yes, let's go.
Card for player, card for banker, player, banker.
Let's go.
Now...
We got it.
Good.
Good, good.
That's it, let's do that.
It's okay.
It's okay. You can make a connection.
Yes, let's go Dal.
Dal! Dal! Dal!
Open it.
Player 1, Banker 0.
Oh! Oh!
Solo winner dude.
You're doing amazing today!
Be quiet all the luck will fall out.
Okay.
Okay!
You open first.
Yeah! It's going to pay!
Hey, we get it unless it's 9!
If it's not 9, we win. $20,000, 20k!
Flip it. Just flip it!
$20,000, $20k! It's done!
9!
Player 0, Banker 1. Banker wins.
He lost?
They lost.
That was bad.
Hey.
That's why I told you to take out some chips. Why did you have to go all at once?!
I said be quiet.
He will make a mess soon.
Ah, the aftereffects of this one are going to last a while.
Ah, if it weren't for that 9... But how could that 9 pop up and screw us over?
Ah, really!
The feeling that you were talking about wasn't "that" feeling but the feeling to lose.
If we got that and it's $20k, once more then it's $40k...
Another one, it would have been $80k! Dang... I feel the loss, really.
Jang Soo, let's take out some of Gi Chan hyungnim's money.
What?
-Did you make up your mind to die? -Whether I die like this or like that I'll still die.
I mean...Hey.
Why die? Just fill it back up is all.
Ki Chan hyungnim has a long way to go before coming out of the can.
If only you and I keep quiet,
no one will know.
I can't do it.
I don't want to bet my life.
Quickly dig up here.
Yeong Dal, I really don't think this is right.
You bastard, I said dig.
Aish, really...
Wait!
It's done.
Move over.
We can use some of this, and if we just fill it back up without anyone knowing...
What if we can't fill it up?
Just trust me.
Aish, my dad said I can trust a stray dog but not you.
Then drop out now.
Hey, are you kidding.
I came this far, how can I drop out now?
You bastard, are you in your right mind, huh?!
Without a report how can you take care of things on your own?!
I know.
I'm sorry.
Sorry?
You jerk, do you think this will be solved with a simple sorry? Huh?!
We can't even touch that guy and let him off, why did you go and arrest him?
I was sure I could get the warrant.
All the circumstantial evidence confirms murder instigation!
Shut up!
The results tell everything. What else do you need to say?
Dong Soo,
you should now let go of Go Bok Tae.
Why are you being like this, too? Really?!
Then, what's the reason for not letting go even when you always lose?
I heard the provincial Internal audit team have begun investigating you, so
prepare yourself.
Do you take the medicine I gave you?
No.
Why not?
Just because. After I eat them I feel weird.
That's what it's for.
Anyway, it make me feel horrid.
If you're not going to listen to me, then there's no need for us to meet.
Do you want me to honestly tell you what your condition is?
It's fear.
Fear of what?
Even if I don't say, you know that better.
It's me.
No, I'll go.
Yes.
If you can't get rid of that you'll stay at the same spot.
I have an appointment so I'll be leaving first.
Hello.
Wow. I didn't know you were still in the audit team.
Yes, I'm also sick of looking for the wrongdoings of people I work with.
Please help us with your power, Chief.
Hey, where do I have that kind of power?
Greet each other.
Here is my friend who is a crime scene profiler.
I'm Hwang Shin Hye.
I'm Lee Young Do in audit team.
I'm No Sang Neh.
I'll go, so talk to each other.
Yes.
Take a seat.
Chief is your father, right?
Yes.
I worked for him when I was in Jongno station.
Even then, he boasted so much about his daughter.
She's great enough to be bragged about.
She graduated from a reputable Medical University, and even received a doctorate in psychiatry.
But, for what reason did you ask to see me?
Ah, yes.
I have something to consult with you as a psychiatrist.
Police Officer Personnel Record
It's a man named Jang Dong Soo, that we're looking into.
He's a part of the metropolitan area investigative unit.
What's the reason for me making an evaluation?
We think that he has some issues with his head.
What should I say? Anger management?
He's already caused two incidents involving firearms.
On site, there's many times he committed disturbances for being over the top.
Please interview him as a psychiatrist and give us your professional opinion.
First of all, an act of anger is not a mental disorder.
We call the symptom similar to that 'Intermittent Explosive Disorder'.
Intermittent explosive disorder.
Well, then we leave it in your care.
May I ask you something?
You have a picture of him, right?
The clothes that he's wearing are designer from head to toe.
As you already know
he's wearing those clothes from the money he makes as a detective.
What kind of mindset is that?
What do you mean what?
He's crazy.
Come in.
Oh? Dad!
Yes.
Who is this?
Ah...
A friend who will be living with us.
Let me introduce you. This is Jang Dong Soo,
and this is Hwang Sin Hye.
My one and only daughter as well as the maiden that takes care of all the chores.
Wait, because he's two years older than you,
call him Oppa.
Dong Soo is going to take the GED so you help him out.
My Sin Hye never lost first place so
Treat her as your teacher.
In these cases you have to apply the FOIL method.
You don't know the FOIL method?
This won't do.
I think you're going to have to leave high school work,
and start right from middle school.
Why aren't you answering?
I'm your oppa, so why do you keep speaking informally?
Beacause I want to.
Hey.
You...
You like me, right?
Shall I
show you my bare skin?
No.
If you want to see it,
close your eyes.
That...
You don't want to?
If not, forget it.
O...okay.
I'm ready. Open your eyes.
I said open your eyes.
What do you think?
You're totally dirty minded.
There's an eyewitness who witnessed it all.
Yes.
Excuse me,
can I help you?
I'm here to see Detective Jang Dong Soo.
Ah, how do you know Jang Dong Soo..?
What are you doing?
Hurry up and wake him up.
A moment please.
Chief.
Chief!
You've got a guest.
What?
Without even a call, what is it?
I just wanted to see you working.
How about you?
How is it being a criminal profiler?
It's just the beginning.
But,
I'm asking because I'm really curious.
I've been a detective for way more than a decade, but
I don't know what a Profiler does.
What do you do?
I'm not too sure either
Is your husband well?
It's been a long time since I've seen Father.
He always makes the excuse that he's busy.
Why am I living so pathetically?
I...
I've met with people from the audit team today.
Why would you?
I've been asked to evaluate your mental state.
Ah, these bastards!
Now they're making me out to be crazy?
I'm sorry.
From my judgment you need treatment.
Why are you being like this too?
Listen to me.
You already lost your timing to get treated. If you refuse it'll get worse.
-Now isn't too late...-Stop.
Tell those audit team bastards
that I'm completely normal.
I'll be going first.
I've met with people from the audit team today.
I've been asked to evaluate your mental state.
What's with this emotional mood?
What is?
That's why,
when I was telling you I would find a woman for you, you weren't too keen on it, but
now you're lonely?
Is there anyone who is not lonely in life?
That's true.
♪ Lonely
♪ So lonely
♪ I cannot live
Aigoo, you must really be lonely.
♪ Between the sky and the earth
♪ I'm all alone
♪ Because of the love
♪ I can't forget
♪ My heart yearns
♪ No answer
♪ Echoes
♪ Fall in mid air
It's not enough to be sad, now he is in sickly pain.
Hello, Aunt.
Hey, your boss is about to die from loneliness.
It seems you should be his drinking buddy a little.
Aigoo.
I'm lonely, too.
Shall we date?
Get lost you rascal.
You're here.
I've not seen you around lately. Where have you been hiding?
I've been resting.
Huh, bastard.
It must be nice you can talk like that.
Should I order you one? -I'm fine.
Hey, make some collections today.
I don't do things like that anymore.
What?
Doing things like that to make money
I'm really sick of it now.
Find someone else.
Yeong Dal!
You, Officer Gook was looking for you.
I was going there anyway.
Hey, what's up with him?
Did he eat something wrong?
Why aren't you saying anything when your father is talking to you?
I'm eating what's wrong with you?!
You go out in his place and make the collections, jack ass!
Hello.
Sunbaenim!
I heard you were looking for me.
What is this?
How can I come empty-handed when I'm coming to see you?
(Drink it) fast.
Okay.
But, rumors about you are quite strange.
Rumors?
You spend money so much, that it doesn't fit your status.
Did you cause trouble again?
Am I at an age to cause trouble?
I.. after seeing you, Detective Gook,
am living everyday diligently.
You little bastard and your tricks.
I'm sorry.
You can just take him.
Come here.
Hey, Oh Byeong Tae. How many times is this? How many times are you going in and out of this place?
Noona, who are you to say? Just stop caring
Hey, I am your noona and take place of Mom and Dad.
Ugh, so annoying.
What? Hey, you.
Why are you being so annoying?
This little...
What are you doing?
Stop caring and go on your way.
Stop caring and just go?
This rude, little kid.
Why are you hitting me?
I am hitting you because you deserve it.
Because you deserve it.
What are you?
Who are you to hit my little brother?
Well because, he was so rude.
Why do you care if my brother is rude or not rude?
Let's go.
In my judgment, you need some treatment.
Why are you being like this also?
Don't get excited, and just listen.
You lost your opportunity to get treated already, and if you just let it be, it will only get worse.
Ok, I got it.
Detective.
Why?
I found the line for money laundering for Go Bok Tae.
What is it?
I was told Go Bok Tae is the biggest hand in the VIP room of the casino in Sabuk.
Money laundering line is there?
No. Loan sharks who lend money there.
Let's go. -Right now?
Come out quickly.
Well, I heard Sabuk is your home town.
Yes.
Does anyone live there?
No, nobody is there.
The last time I went was 15 or 16 years ago.
Why?
Is there any reason for that?
Ay, it didn't go in.
Let's go to Cheulgun today and play.
Hey, there's rumors around that you're using loads of money.
Is it okay?
If I'm scared of rumors when am I going to win?
Don't worry and get ready.
Hey, I need to stop by somewhere so I'll meet you there.
They where are you going in the middle of playing billiards?
Hey, hey what about the game fee?
You're working hard.
What brings you here?
Yes, I'm the one who called. Jang Dong Soo from the metropolitan area unit.
Oh, yes. I'm Detective Gook.
Yes.
I'm Detective Gook.
I'm Tak Jae Gul.
LoveDramasAsia
Slowly.
Let's do it softly.
You acted as if you wouldn't see me again.
What's up?
I also want to kill myself.
Hurry up and shower.
Should we do it together?
You know those loan sharks that lend money around the casino?
Someone who knows all about the loan sharks,
we need an informant like that.
If that's what you need
I have someone that I know.
Who's that?
Hey, open the door.
Hey, open the door you bastard!
Who is it?
Hurry up and open the door you bastard!
Who are you, you bastard?
Aren't you going to open up? Open up.
This little...
Hey, aren't you going to open the door!
Hey, open the door!
Oh.
Seriously.
Oh. He's over there.
Over there. It's that guy.
What is that guy doing wearing only underwear in the middle of the day?
I'm about to go crazy.
Hey, don't come. Don't come.
Oh.
Come on, stop. What's this? - Stop already! Why are you doing this?
Don't follow me!
Wait. Okay, okay.
What?!
Who are you to follow me?
Hey! I'm about to go crazy.
Don't follow me please!
Okay.
♬ Just one day, just one day ♬
♬ If I could erase it ♬
♬ Late night with thoughts of you I can't even get to sleep ♬
♬ Tomorrow again I cannot get to sleep ♬
♬ To long for ♬
~Preview~
Find out the movements of honchos or loan sharks around the casino and report to me, that's all.
You look really lonely today. A guy named Heo Yeong Dal.
I'm sorry.
Long ago we used to live the same house.
It's not race. It's raise.
Race is a term used when a dog or a horse runs.
I'll make sure to absorb all information.
I still have an unfinished deal with Oh Jeong Hee.
We made it!