Subtitle By 4H5@N
I always wanted
to be many things.
A doctor...
...astronaut...
...a diver.
To start a band,
be a hugely successful
Latin music star...
Create a blog...
that I'd sell a year later
for a million dollars.
To adopt a stray dog,
paint a picture, learn Spanish...
“Yo no hablo espanhol
pero me encanta Rio”.
To invest in the stock market...
Start a campaign
against land mines...
and cluster bombs.
Write a book...
A book?
No. A movie script?
Start a revolution, be a Che!
Or maybe not...
while in doubt,
I enjoy my favorite pastimes...
...pornography...
...and video games.
Or, if you prefer,
videogames and pornography.
“KICKING ASS IN MIAMI BEACH"
I have just come back
from a short time abroad.
I spent two years there.
It was fun.
But it was time to come back.
And now that I'm back...
I've just found a purpose...
...a path...
...mission to accomplish.
It's Edgar.
Hey, What's up?
A long time ago,
in a galaxy far away...
...I had a bright future.
I always had a connection
to electronic stuff.
It started with remote controls...
Atari, Odyssey, Master System,
then MSX, 286, 386.
I was the family genius,
a big nerd.
When I was in college...
while my friends were drowning
in booze and women...
I practiced things
that were absolutely useless.
Then, my first job.
Say... What are you doing
this weekend?
Well...
...let's just say that.
I felt a certain incompatibility
with the corporate world.
Good morning.
So, is everything ready?
Wait a minute.
Fuck me!!!
You call this shit a layout?
And a certain difficulty
to cope with critics.
“My boss”.
"Me."
People called him the bomb-man!
He is an evil visionary!
He asked me to tie him up
and slap him also...
I like his insanity a little bit.
Asshole!
Douche!
He's an antichrist!
Liar!
A loser, loser. Totally a loser!
They even said he was a faggot,
I don't know.
I'm out of it...
A guy like that has
no plan for his life?
I do have a plan.
A fucked up plan, to be honest,
but it is a plan.
- What's up?
- How are you, kid? You're back?
Yeah, I guess.
So, Ching-Ling brought my stuff?
Let's go there.
Ching, you've got a customer.
How are you?
Your toy!
Open it.
I'm curious to see.
Look at this beauty.
I'll tell you.
- Hold this.
- Okay.
Now, walk that way.
Go ahead.
Right there, it's ok!
Now, come slowly...
What is this, man?
This one...
...when it gets near to this one...
It discharges an electric current,
a proximity sensor.
And what are you doing with it?
What I'm gonna do?
My idea is quite simple:
justice.
To kill two rabbits
with just one blow.
“TWO RABBITS"
This plan has been dancing
in my mind for quite a while-.
It was before I went to Miami.
But I perfected it there.
I just need some sort of a click,
to find that last piece of the
puzzle and see the whole picture.
Hey, you! Punk!
You moron!
Retarded!
Nice to meet you.
My name is Edgar.
Wake up, man! Give me your watch.
Hurry up, you ass!
You wanna die? Wanna be shot at?
In the head? That's it.
Where's the money? I said money!
You call this money?
Give me your money, come one!
What is that thing over there?
- My cell phone.
- Give me that.
- What else do you have? What else?
- Nothing.
Nothing?
Have a nice day, pal.
Shit! I was mugged!
What if he'd get a shot off?
It could've been fun.
What could I have done
for him to shoot me?
What if I did this?
Or this?
Oh! FON FON, the teddy bear.
You fucking vagabonds!
Hey, D’Artagnan. Wake up.
Come eat something.
Man, drop that fucking
magazine and come eat something.
I'm coming, bro.
- Come on!
- Just a second, man.
- Mrs. Te. I'm here.
- Come on in.
I've brought food for the guys.
It's all there.
At least the food, I'm starving.
You don't work
And you wanna eat?
Maicon called.
He said it's all good.
Business is up.
- So?
- Uncle Maicon's words: close shop.
- Close shop?
- God knows what he means.
This is Bola, aka Carioca.
He's Maicon's right hand man.
Who's Maicon?
I'll tell you later.
The right question now is:
what are these guys doing...
looking at the Persian carpet
in their living room?
Take the carpet up.
Come on, hurry.
Take her, guys.
This is Miss Puhn.
P + U + H + N
But, why is Miss Puhn buried
alive in this fethid hole?
It was because of her mother
Mrs. Célia, or Mrs. Puhn.
P + U + H + N
Bling, Bling! Bling, bling!
The Geush Brothers!
Mrs. Celia is a trusted employee
of the Geush Twins...
who got rich with a cheap
TV auction show.
Mrs. Celia is particularly
close to Sasha...
The oldest
and the gayest of them.
So, it happens that Sasha
besides trusting Miss. Celia
her love affair secrets,
trusted also
the company's vault secret.
And it was exactly that secret that ended
up placing Miss. Celia and her daughter
in that, let's say,
difficult situation.
Now you have your money,
where's my daughter?
Where's my daughter?
Easy, easy!
Gimme the glasses!
Fucking coward.
You've shit your pants.
Fuck!
Answer the fucking door!
Everybody quiet!
Hands on your heads, come on!
Easy, man!
There's a child here.
Shut the fuck up!
What's this?
Where's Maicon in all this shit?
Wait, wait, it's not the time to reveal
who Maicon is.
Later...
DISTRICT ATTORNEY'S OFFICE
I need 144, please.
I think it's December
if I'm not mistaken.
Thank you.
Julia?
- How are you?
- Hi, Rodrigues.
- I'm fine. You?
- Where did you have lunch?
In that new Indian restaurant
down the street.
Is the Indian good?
- It's okay.
- I know, very spicy stuff.
- Shoot, say it.
- I'm gonna have to transfer you.
Internal affairs.
They're pressing for
an administrative investigation.
It's come from the top.
But why?
They've found evidence
against the Maicon guy's gang.
We've been after him for 3 years.
Now things will be tough for him.
We've linked him to the jewelry
robbery, the Jew's case...
At least eight homicides, armed
robbery, kidnapping and more.
That's okay by me. If they want
it like that, it's their call.
Nobody doubts your honesty...
but many people are annoyed
by this whole story.
Who else will be transferred
with me?
I don't know yet.
But I'll keep you posted.
Okay.
Hi, hi, it's me.
Things got ugly here.
Yeah, come here, now.
No, come here, now.
I'm not waiting.
We must see him, alright?
Okay, we.
Julia thinks she's dying,
but she isn't.
She's just having
a panic attack.
Julia loves the sea...
She loves the sun...
a man's hand...
the wind
birds...
Julia?
My car is here.
You're singing that song again.
Come on, let's go!
This song soothes me!
- You want to take a pill or something?
- No, I don't.
I wanna get over this by myself.
I need to learn how to control
these crazy thoughts.
I can do it.
Julia and Henrique make
a perfect couple.
She is a prosecutor,
he is a criminal's lawyer.
At least in crookery
things seemed to be going well.
Julia has exclusive information...
that only people inside the
Prosecutors Office have access to.
With this information,
our friend Henrique...
orients his clients,
creates alibis,
and prepares
his bullet-proof cases.
Come on, Henrique!
That's okay.
What's up Henrique!
How's it going?
- Well, and you?
- Cool, man, I need to talk for a second.
Go ahead I'll be right there.
But where are these two going now?
They've come to see their
biggest and only client...
...Maicon.
So who is this Maicon, anyway?
Where's Maicon in all this shit?
I'm here, boss...
Here I am!
- Are you all right, my friend?
- Yes.
Did you do it alright?
Did you wash your hands?
Your zipper is open.
You don't need anything else?
You want a kiss from Bola?
Let's come back.
At first sight,
Maicon is a “nice” criminal.
But who said there
are “nice” criminals?
So, anyone else want
to go to the bathroom?
Now, the pressing
question here is...
who are you again?
This is Roberto,
also known as Tanajura.
He is a policeman who works as
security for the Geush Brothers.
Roberio planned the whole
robbery at the Geush company.
Then he decided to hire Maicon's gang
to do the job.
So you're Tanajura.
You fucking Bozo!
Nice to meet you.
We haven't had the chance
to meet in person.
- You know why we're here.
- No, I have no idea.
Well, my friend...
I delivered it
on a tray for you...
to get the Chinese woman
and her daughter.
- So, where's the money?
- There's no money.
There's something else...
she's not Chinese,
she's Japanese.
No, Maicon, she's Korean.
Shut up!
What?
She's Korean.
She's not Japanese or Chinese.
- Let's get it right...
- Shut up!
- So, she's Korean.
- I don't fucking care!
Fuck, I've come all this way
to this shithole
just to settle this shit down!
To settle it “up”.
Well, brother, you must know
that everybody is onto us...
the police know...
So relax. Relax.
Get the man a beer.
Stop fucking around!
If you've fucked this up
and whacked the Chinese girl...
that's your problem, fuck it!
I took the risk, so now I'm leaving
without the money, you know?
You do that.
Or else I won't answer for myself!
- You have the money, right?
- Right.
So, where's our share?
I like that, Tanajura's
not fucking around.
Hey, guys, learn with him.
He came here to solve
his problem, right?
But you came at this hour?
- You wanna solve this right now?
- What?
You have working hours now?
From eight to six?
Boss, let's make a deal...
Fuck your deal! Fuck your deal!
I'm not a fool,
Look, I know you...
I know you wanted to stab
me in the back, you fucking rat!
- So, you've heard?
- Where's it, you son of a bitch?
If there's one thing Maicon
respects, it's his mother.
And, my friend, if there's one
thing that makes him crazy...
that's when someone
calls him son of a...
What did Maicon do?
Well, we'd better back off
to get the whole picture.
Fry the fish, Bola!
Fuck, man!
You jumped all over me!
In the cat's mouth, boss!
Maicon had it all planned.
I'll watch the game somewhere else.
He framed Roberio.
The dude shit himself.
He broke the saint's head, man!
- Okay, twelve years.
- Right.
You're a cheat!
All of a sudden a magic envelope
appeared in the Prosecutor's Office.
“OPEN IT “
“URGENT”
Photographs, phone calls,
documents.
They delivered a busload
of evidence on a tray,
connecting Maicon to Geusch's theft,
Puhn's death, and
the police officer Roberto's murder.
This takes us back to the meeting
with Julia, Maicon and Henrique.
I was just trying
to explain to Maicon...
that the Prosecutors Office
Will come for him very hard.
- He got that, right?
- Right.
And now I want a suggestion
from you. What do I do?
In fact, Maicon,
we have lost the initiative.
The evidence is incontestable,
they will beat you up.
So now I'm fucked.
I want some alternative.
You are right.
You must have alternatives.
My hands are tied there!
They're onto me,
I might get busted.
We've gotta find another way to get
information and plan everything.
It can't be with me.
Look, they'll have a warrant
for year arrest by next week.
You must hurry,
they might even get it this week.
Really? And what the fuck
should I do?
Should I lay low,
maybe run away?
No, running away
is just like pleading guilty.
Julia knows a person
who might help you.
Yeah, I know someone.
It might work, or it might not.
The man is a state deputy.
He has contacts in the police,
in the judiciary and shit.
- Will he come over to the dark side?
- He's already on the dark side, baby.
The man loves money.
He has helped a lot of people.
Remember that whole
bingo halls scheme?
- Well, this is the man.
- If it weren't for him there...
wouldn't be a single
bingo hall open.
But now they're
all closed down.
Okay, they were open
for ten years.
Well, we must be quick.
So, give me a figure...
how much are you willing
to put on the table?
I don't know,
I've got no funds now.
Listen to me.
I'm your lawyer!
I told you not to open
this goddamn parking lot.
This is an investment, man!
I'm renting the upper floor
to a church.
Wait, wait.
Listen to me.
We'll try to get
a politician's help, okay?
I would say Julia has a talent
for influencing men.
- Dad.
- Hi, son.
- How are you?
- I'm fine, thanks.
- The restaurant is beautiful.
- Do you like it?
But how much are you paying
that girl...
to scare the clients away?
- The receptionist?
- The “deceptionist”.
- So how are things going?
- Fine. With you?
- I was robbed.
- What? Robbed?
- Did they do anything to you?
- No, no.
- Are you alright?
- Sure.
What did they take?
They took my watch,
my iPhone and 15 bucks.
It's the end of the world.
What about Walter?
What about him?
Look, son, it's okay.
I've talked to him.
I told him you were back.
There's no problem.
I think he understood.
I'm sure he has forgiven you.
He's calmer. I think you should
sit down and talk.
- Yeah, it's a good idea.
- You do that.
If he accepts you apologies,
great.
If he doesn't,
that's his problem.
The most important thing
is us, the family.
That's right, Dad.
- We've helped him enough, right?
- True.
Alright, I think I'm going.
What do you mean, you're going?
You're going nowhere.
- I'm going to have a dog...
- No, you'll have lunch with me.
- You're eating food.
- I miss the hot-dogs up there.
Hot-dogs? Don't you miss
your father?
How long were you away?
Come on!
You're having lunch with me.
I've got something special for you.
Minced meat special.
How about that?
- I hate that.
- I'm just kidding.
Afonso? Prepare
that dish I told you.
That's right.
Steak and French fries?
- That's right.
- Correct?
This is Walter.
He's a college professor.
But what is a college
professor doing...
working as the cashier
at my father's restaurant?
Well, it's quite
complicated, but...
right now I would like
to focus on a man...
who's equally important
to my plan.
This is Jader Kerteis,
the state deputy...
that Julia and Henrique
suggested to Maicon.
Mr. Jader, ten years ago,
a politician full of good intentions.
No no, this is not Jader,
this is Zacharia's double
and, ins his party's political
broadcast...
he appeared right after
a Zacharia's impersonator...
who was so bizarre that got
people's attention.
Jader slipstreamed it and was elected.
So was Zhacharias, by the way.
Jade is dignity,
Jader is respect...
Jader is honesty.
Jader, 888886.
With “Bem Te vi, 88”.
After he was elected...
within a few months
he got a taste of reality.
When he noticed, he was
involved in schemes...
to approve skyscraper construction
in restricted areas...
to favor companies in the
bidding to supply school meals...
and so on.
The other day...
I saw the government's
Party political broadcast...
And this is what was said,
the TV host speaking solemnly...
“When the disease came, we treated
it the best way we could”.
They can't be serious!
This is such cheap advertising!
This is an advertising text
that says...
“The health care,
we offer the people...
Is really rubbish!”
Not to say crap.
Now moving on to another issue...
Hello
I'm home.
More or less.
No, not yet.
This is Sofia, Jader's wife.
I'm putting it on now.
Okay?
Me too, bye!
And she's not so happy with Jader.
- Jader?
- Just a second.
- What, Sofia?
- Your jacket.
I'm not wearing a jacket.
Say it, what time?
And now, while he east
his medium rare steak...
accompanied by an elegant
gratin galettes...
he's about to receive a phone call
that will change his life.
- Yeah?
- Jader?
- Hi, this is Henrique.
- Hi, Dr. Henrique.
My assistant
told me about your case.
Some more water, please.
Thank you.
So, man, due to his history
this is a complicated deal.
I know, that's why my client
needs your expertise...
Your influence.
But, my friend
this caliber is too high.
I'll have to think about it,
see what I can do to help.
Listen, deputy, I want you
to know in advance...
that both my client
and my group...
we are ready to pay
a small urgency fee...
I know, everybody
has urgency...
Besides, we have the election
next year, I'll be very busy.
I have to think about it.
We'll see.
But this is not the right
place to discuss this.
- Tell me, do you enjoy jogging?
- Jogging? I do, I do.
The probability theory
tries to quantify the notion
of mathematically probable.
- What's up, man?
- Hey, how are you?
- A hot-dog with two sausages.
- You got it.
But I guess not even
such complex formulas...
would be able to quantify
the probability...
of my meeting the asshole
who robbed me 24 hours later...
right at my favorite
hot-dog stand.
Things are good here, huh?
- Hello.
- How are you?
I want the usual, with...
“Fon Fon the Teddy Bear”.
With mash and fries.
Good afternoon,
Agent Márcio, please.
- Edgar?
- Edgar.
Hi. We got the man.
Come take a look.
He went to eat the wrong hot-dog
at the wrong place.
I bet that gave him indigestion.
Take a look.
See if it's him.
Velinha woks really hard.
He's a delivery guy
for several food places...
all of them with fancy
Italian names...
Pizza Molto, Watashi Watakaro,
Il Pazzo Capperi.
Ilshawarma Dihere and son on.
In fact, he's the owner
of all these pizza places...
because none of them
really exists.
They are all a facade
for his scheme.
No, this guy has a Fon Fon
teddy bear tattoo...
- No, he is not the guy...
- Fon Fon teddy bear?
The guy who robbed me
had a Panda bear tattoo.
- He's not the guy.
- Are you sure? Take a good look.
This guy is a friend of a delivery
boy who works for my father.
- He's a working guy.
- A friend?
DEAD END STREET
- Your down, punk!
- Easy...
Here, here If you try
anything, I'll kill you.
Easy, easy.
I just need to talk to you.
- Who are you?
- I just need to talk to you.
- I just wanna talk, man.
- What are you up to?
- You like following muggers around?
- Fuck!
- Is this your kinky fantasy?
- I saved your ass today!
- You didn't save shit!
- I'm just want to make an offer...
Are you high, man?
Why are you laughing?
- I have a proposal.
- A proposal?
Loads of cash.
It's a good deal.
Get up, get up.
Get up. Talk.
Wanna spend the rest of your life
delivering pizza...
stealing cell phones
at traffic lights?
A tough guy?
Are you a tough guy?
You followed me here
to laugh at me? Is that it?
You've got one minute to
convince me.
Come on.
There's a bag full of cash.
I know where it's going.
I know the time and the place.
- Whose money is that?
- Car smugglers'...
Mercedes, Lamborghinis,
you know?
Rich people's cars?
You like cars, right?
The guy likes them too.
Tell me more.
I'll tell you the time and place,
we go there and split it.
Split what?
What are we splitting?
This hurts, man...
What?
Am I laughing?
Do I think it's funny?
Am I laughing, asshole?
- Man, it's a lot of cash.
- How much?
- Two million.
- Two million Reais?
Dollars.
No, man, that's too much!
He's “chicken thief”, Jader!
Don't talk shit. I know how
much they stole from the Jews.
Two millions dollars?
Fuck, that's some serious dough!
I'm telling you,
It's the real deal.
You're fucking with me.
- That's too much money.
- I'm serious. I only want half.
One million's yours.
You bet.
Let's talk about it.
Come on.
- Just point that away.
- Shut up. Keep your distance.
Alright? Keep your distances.
Let's talk about over pizza.
Get my helmet.
Who's this guy?
This is Edmar.
Good old Edmar.
- Edgar.
- That's right.
He has a good deal going.
He's offering only 50%, man.
But this is something else.
What is there to eat?
There's pizza.
Like always.
I've got the munchies, man.
The munchies?
Then you'll eat with us.
But I'll tell you what,
30% of the deal is yours...
the rest is ours.
Hey, man, you don't even
know what the deal is.
So what?
There's just two of us, man.
You're doing it alone?
Who made you Superman?
Alright, man? This is Clayton,
my partner, my right hand man!
I'm fucked. I'm fucked.
- I'm fucked.
- I'm telling you.
30% alright.
Can I have my cell phones back?
What cell phone?
I'm just kidding.
Here it is.
A cool one.
Do I need to give it back?
Hot pizza, mate.
- Now you're talking.
- Is there extra virgin olive oil?
Fuck you.
Eat this shit.
The only extra virgin
here is you, bitch!
You realize that Edgar
had to come back to Brazil.
- This was inevitable.
- I know.
But...
we have to forget
this whole story.
It's all right.
Good.
That's really good.
Do you like working here?
I do.
Why?
You're not thinking
about quitting, are you?
No away.
I like the people here.
- Are you considering firing me?
- No, don't even think about that.
No, you've been
very valuable to me.
And money?
Everything ok with your pocket:
Are you in need
of some extra cash?
Money is always good, but...
for what I need,
it's enough to live on.
Alright. But if you need something,
You can ask me, Okay?
- Okay,
- Alright?
If you have any problems,
you can talk to me.
I'm asking you to talk to me.
Alright?
Well, I think it's time to tell
Walter's story. And mine.
Our story.
Walter's story is divided
into B, E, and A.E...
Before Edgar and After Edgar.
Well, this is my cue.
This is the exact moment
when I enter Walter's life.
Ironically, the accident
brought Walter near my family.
My father was very touched
by his situation...
and offered him a job
at his restaurant...
as Walter had quit
being a teacher.
I managed to escape
prosecution...
and went for a break
to Miami, Florida, USA.
Velinha, here's the deal.
Pay attention.
Right.
The car with the money
is an armored car.
- The guys will be armed.
- We'll figure it out. Don't worry.
This fucking air conditioner
isn't working. Fuck that!
Man, I think we were born
in the wrong country.
- I hear you, man.
- You know where we could be?
Norway, what do you think?
New Zealand maybe.
- Yeah, New Zealand!
- New Zealand is cool.
Norway is cold,
and New Zealand only got kangaroos...
- Kangaroos are in Australia!
- Are you crazy?
- Look at that. What a beauty!
- What a ride, man!
- How many could we buy?
- Four. 500 grand a-piece.
- In Brazil...
- And where are we, man?
If you're abroad
you would buy in euros, dollars...
Euro!
He says it like a gringo, “euro”!
- Asshole!
- What's he doing?
- Run!
- Easy, this car is armored.
Don't worry, man
I'm gonna run him down!
- Motherfucker!
- Fuck you, asshole!
Get the motherfucker!
Wait!
Fuck, man!
This isn't water!
This is gasoline!
- Let's get out of here!
- Hurry!
I don't have it!
Come on, Pelé!
Hurry!
You go! I'll cover you!
Go on! Get to their car!
Come one you fagot!
Assholes!
Fucked.
Go, Pelé!
We're gangsters, son...
You've lost, nigger!
Drop your gun. Do it!
Come on!
- Where's the money?
- There is no fucking money.
Where's the fucking bag?
- Where?
- Over there.
Don't point, nigger!
- It's over there.
- Show it to me.
- Don't point! Move your ass!
- Fuck you, kid.
Go on!
Open it, nigger!
- There's a locksmith down the street.
- You're a funny guy?
- Shit.
Where's the key?
- It's in the car over there.
- You're a tough guy?
Come one!
Move your fat ass!
- Move it.
- You'd better kill me.
- Go ahead and kill me.
- Open it!
You open it.
It's armored.
Suck this, motherfucker!
This fuck armored!
So this is armored?
- Watch him!
- Go on, go on.
- Don't move!
- Motherfucker!
Wait, I'm opening it.
Wait, easy!
- Please, be patient!
- Come here.
Who will suck it now?
Wait! Easy, man!
Come on!
Easy, easy!
- Wait!
- Come on!
Motherfuckers!
Those guys robber us
on a shitty little motorbike!
Put your fucking arms down.
Fuck that shit!
We're fucked!
Hi!
- Is it here?
- Fuck no. Are you crazy?
Want me to walk around
with the candy?
It's in my car down there.
- Let's go.
- Come one, naughty boy.
Hi.
I'm where we have arranged!
What?
Are you kidding me?
What do you mean with
“ they've stolen the money”?
That's way to weird!
I haven't told to anyone,
not even to my wife.
Ok! Ok!
We talk later, bye.
Son of a bitch!
It's so weird!
Holy fuck, man!
I'm telling you, you loony.
Be careful with that.
Do you know what's in there?
This is not for kids.
I'm not playing around.
Thanks, man.
You take care.
Time's runnin' out, man.
Things are tough.
I know, Maicon, but...
I don't know what to tell you.
Who would've thought this
could happen, you know?
- Do you have any more money?
- No, I don't. What?
Even If I had.
I say that cos' were the same
situation as the Portuguese guy.
What Portuguese guy?
- The one from the toilet joke.
- What joke, man?
The Portuguese guy dropped
a 10-dollar note in a toilet.
But it wasn't a clean toilet...
It was like a gas station one
covered in shit.
He didn't have the balls
to fish the note out.
You known?
What did he do?
He took a 50-buck note
and dropped it in the shit, too.
You see?
Then it all changed.
He changed the way
he saw things...
because now there were 60 bucks
there in the shit...
and for 60 bucks he was willing
to stick his hand in...
and that's how
he got all his money back!
That's really funny.
But you're here to solve
a very serious problem.
- Another problem.
- Fuck...
Your wife robbed me.
No, Maicon, Julia?
No, Josiane.
Do you have another wife?
No, Maicon. Not Julia.
Julia, your wife.
That fucking snitch.
No, you're making a mistake.
She has nothing to do with it.
And to prove you're not
together with her in this...
You're gonna finish her.
No, Maicon, Julia is my wife...
Maicon, my wife!
For God's sake!
You must be kidding me!
Am I fucking with you?
Do I look like
I'm fucking with you?
Am I fucking with you?
You choose, Henrique.
Either you finish the cunt...
or we do you
and then we do her.
Don't do this!
Look at me.
Look at me, you fuck!
Stop crying. You point
this gun in her face...
- No, Maicon.
- And you shoot.
Shoot her in the face,
do you understand?
Shoot her in the face.
Here. This is your job.
Hi, is it open?
Ju?
I need to talk to you.
Where are you?
Mr. M wants to see us.
It's because of the robbery.
He didn't want to talk
over the phone.
He sent me a text
with GPS coordinates.
He's getting meaner.
Where are we?
It's really far.
I'm just following the GPS.
No, Julia, don't tell me
you're having a fit again.
I can't breathe.
I'm scared.
- Scared of what?
- Of having a meltdown.
Relax. This is just your head,
you're fine. Let me grab you a pill?
- Ju!
- What is this?
- You ruined our lives!
- Are you crazy?
- Why did you do it?
You're pointing a gun at me!
- Shut up!
- Stop it! Turn away!
Why did you...?
Turn away from me!
- Turn away!
- Calm down...
You ruined our life!
I didn't do anything!
Let me explain what happened!
Calm down!
Let me speak. Listen.
Calm down, remember everything
We've been through.
Let your heart calm down.
Are you calmer now?
What's wrong?
Where are you going?
Come here! Wait!
Henrique?
Dear God.
That piece of shit robbed me
and he wanted to kill you!
- What are you saying?
- I found out.
It was this piece of shit
who planned the robbery!
- There's more...
- Are you crazy?
I called him and told him...
...that it you have
robbed the money
and to prove his innocence he'd
have to shoot you in the face.
- Asshole!
- Stop it, baby!
Are you crazy?
Asshole!
Why did you do this?
To be sure you were not
part of the scheme.
What if he had shot me?
I wouldn't let him do that
to my child.
- Don't touch me.
- It's a blessing in disguise.
Don't touch me.
- I need to talk to you.
- Excuse me.
Go check upstairs.
- Well...
- I miss you.
The baby is yours, I'm sure.
I know.
Woman's intuition, right?
- Yeah, you could say that.
- That's great, Julia.
So, what are you doing?
Have you talked to him?
Of course not.
Are you crazy?
- I'll fix your problem first.
- Don't worry about it now.
We need to be patient, baby.
You'll be so sexy, baby.
Don't even think about abortion.
- Hi, man.
- What's up, Henrique?
- How's it going?
- How you doing?
Your wife was telling me
about the solution to our problem.
- I was saying that...
- Let's take a seat.
- Come here...
- Get off me!
Look, you think
you're so clever, right?
So clever! How can you be so sure
that he planned this robbery?
Here, my love. Here!
Here, nigger. Look.
That easy?
There's even an address.
I'm calling Maicon.
We found this
at the asshole's office.
- So what?
- And the prick wrote down...
the number of the idiot
who did the job!
You're an idiot.
You're fine people, but nobody's
going rip me off like that.
- You're the idiot!
- No way.
Where's your money now?
Where is all the fucking cash?
- Tell me!
- Take it easy, baby.
It's taken care of.
Let's go home.
Let's get lost.
Did you see
the TV show last night?
What TV show?
The reality show.
Do you know who was eliminated?
It was the sexy blonde girl
or the queer.
I know, the show you were
talking about the other day.
Yeah. Did you see who got eliminated?
- I don't watch it.
- I think it's all a set up.
The dude's kicked out
and the blonde will...
What happened, man?
Talk to him.
They grouped together
to eliminate the guy.
What guy?
They grouped together
to eliminate the guy!
What guy, man?
They grouped together
to eliminate him!
What are you saying?
Do me a favor.
Bring me my cell phone up here.
No problem.
Where is your phone?
I don't know.
It's on the table somewhere.
- Say, you're taking it.
- I'm taking it up there.
- Say you're going up.
- I'm going up.
I'm coming.
The roof caved in!
Don't move, man!
Don't move!
Shit! Son of a bitch!
- What's up, Velinha.
- Who are you?
Santa Claus.
Bringing you a present.
Santa Claus doesn't do shootings.
Brother, I'll give you
just one chance.
I don't kill you,
and you give me my money.
Whose money, man?
I don't even know you.
- Who are you closed with?
- I'm gonna close you, nigger!
- Give me my fucking money!
- What are you talking about?
- Clayton!
- He's gone, my friend!
- What did you do to my brother?
- He's sitting on the Devil's lap!
Hey, loser, take this.
Let's fucking
tear the place down!
- Wait, brother!
- Want another round?
Look here! I'm done.
Let's talk this out, okay?
- You want some pizza?
- Son of a bitch!
What, it jammed?
That's one ballsy nigger!
Where is my money?
You're giving me the finger?
I'm gonna cut it off.
Bring me the sword.
It's in the car, Bola.
I didn't think
we were gonna use it.
We're in the middle of the slums,
it's dangerous out there...
And you want me
to go fetch a sword?
What's that in your hand?
Go get it.
Gonna do a fucking schedule
for the usage of this dawn sword.
Let me cut his head off.
You wanna cut his head off?
The finger is mine.
Deal.
So, are you telling me or not?
Will you wait for the sword to arrive?
Go look around, go on.
The fucker's not talking.
Hey, nigger, I'm gonna
castrate you like a poodle.
Get it?
Bola, I found the money!
You see?
It didn't take me very long.
He put the suitcase
inside the oven, man!
- It's nice and hot.
- Way to go.
Why did you change bags?
THE BAG
Velinha? Velinha?
Hey man! Come on in!
Velinha, Edmar came
for his portion.
- This is my friend Edgar.
- What's up?
- Who's that?
- That's good old Fininho.
He's my boy, you known?
A great partner.
Hey, what's that suitcase?
I told you.
We're sharing the cash...
but this Louis Vuitton bag
is for my mother.
With this kind of cash you can
buy the whole Louis Vuitton factory!
- Look at that!
- Fininho...
Look at all that cash, man!
Fininho, thanks for that day
you helped me, okay?
- Velinha, man?
- Right?
- Thanks, man.
- What's the fuck, Velinha?
- What is this?
- Come on, Clayton!
This is for your mother, too.
She was there when I needed her.
It's all ours, brother.
You deserve it.
Fininho, come here.
Give it back.
US$ 600,00 for me,
you take the rest.
- Okay! Look at me!
- 007 in the house, man!
- Look at me!
- Shit, man!
- Totally 007!
- It's all ours.
- It was a pleasure, man.
- Thanks.
Good luck.
Just lost my patience with you.
One or two?
- One.
- Two.
Motherfucker!
- Suck it up your ass.
- Shit, man.
- Give me the cell phone.
- Fuck.
- Give it to me and shut up.
- Be quick, I'm low on credit.
Big Boss?
- Good evening, everybody.
- Good evening.
Today I would like to talk to you
about a theme that is always relevant...
at least in our country...
we're gonna talk about corruption.
Hello? Hi.
Okay, I'm putting it on now.
Okay?
Overbilling.
Tax evasion.
Buying elections.
Nepotism.
Buying judges, buying cops...
Bribery.
Money concealed
in underpants...
why the hell have we
heard those words...
and lived with those words...
for 10, 20, 30, 40, 50,
100, 500 years.
Why don't we do anything?
Why doesn't the situation change?
Suggestions?
- Hi.
- Deputy?
Hi, talk to me.
Maicon, here, I have your money.
This time it's for real.
Alright. Where will it be?
What do you mean?
The usual place.
- Jader?
- What, Sofia?
Your jacket.
- Hello?
- I'm not wearing a jacket.
- Deputy?
- Okay.
- Say it, what time?
- 11:30 h.
I'll be there. Alright.
Bye.
I was watching you on TV.
You know that deputy
that was with us in Manaus?
- What's his name?
- That's Hernandez.
Hernandez, that's right.
Hernandez.
I thought he was mocking you.
You known, when you
went up to speak...
I think he started to badmouth you
with that other guy...
He's just a queer.
Do you want anything, Sofia?
A little money.
- May I?
- Of course!
I'll give it to you.
How much do you want?
One, two hundred...
Well. I must go now.
Okay?
Bye!
Your ass is still nice and firm!
You will see what's good!
Ouch!
That's a sexy little ass...!
- Calm down. No, no, no.
- Why not?
- The play is over.
- Are you cooling me off?
Just for now, because you're late.
Did you forget?
Alright.
- I'm really late.
- That's right.
Come here.
No matter what happens,
I love you. Okay?
Bye.
Stop, stop.
Julia, come here.
Come with me to deliver this suitcase.
Hop in.
- Why is that?
- Cos you're beautiful, perfect.
Come on.
Are you asking me
or ordering me?
Deputy, this is Maicon.
Listen, we're changing the place.
Okay, Alright.
I know where it is.
I know.
I'll be there shortly.
Bye.
Julia?
TWO YEARS BEFORE
Julia loves the sea.
Hi.
I love the sea, you know.
She loves the sun.
A man's hand.
The wind.
Do you want it?
No.
I love you.
What did you say?
- I didn't say anything.
- Yes, you did.
I heard you speak.
- Did I?
- Yeah.
- Say it again.
- I love you.
I love you.
I said I love you.
- You can't say that.
- I can. I love you.
Out of the blue?
- It was not out of the blue...
- Why are you saying it now?
- I said it because...
- I know why.
Because it's important...
You're saying that now
because you wanna fuck me.
I'm warning you...
taking me over to your place
might me dangerous.
Why?
Oh, why?
Because we met in a shrink's
waiting room, baby.
So, we can be the Xanax couple.
Mr. and Mrs. Rivotril.
What do you say?
I'm in.
Yeah.
You wanna be that?
A couple of loonies
around town?
- Fuck!
- Watch out!
You suffered a big blow
to your head.
You need to stay
in the hospital overnight.
Son...
- Julia...
- Calm down, son.
- Calm down.
Two people were killed.
A seven-year old boy
and his mother.
You'll have
to be strong now, son.
Justice in Brazil is peculiar.
People kill and steal...
but there's always a way
to escape imprisonment.
The sentence is commuted
for good behavior...
or you only serve
one third of it.
Sometimes you don't
even go to jail.
That was my case.
It was this friendly justice
that let me walk free...
with a little help
from deputy Jader.
Besides, in my case the judge
didn't want any problems.
He had other interests.
Boats.
So?
You didn't like my teddy bear.
I loved this bear.
I think he's cute.
But I want this bear now...
who will never ever leave me.
What?
Say it.
What do you wanna say?
- You didn't miss me, did you?
- I really missed you.
No, you didn't. You were very
well looked after. By two men.
- Yeah, but I was thinking of you.
- I know.
Hey, it's true!
I was thinking about you.
Why did you have to leave?
Well, let's go over the plan
one more time. You must...
No, I don't want to go over
this plan again. I know all about it.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
THE PLAN
Ok, let's go over it.
First I plant one ideas
on Maicon's head.
You must be cold...
with respect to this case.
If you messed up and lost the money,
it's your problem, man!
Fuck it!
After chaos has taken over,
I collect all the evidence...
and hand it to Rodrigues
at the Prosecutor's Office.
He'll love it.
That's when my situation
there will tighten up
and so will Maicon's, consequently.
At the Prosecutor's Office
there's no more way.
- They're watching me.
- I'll need to transfer you.
- Then enters Deputy Jader.
- Two million.
- Reais?
- Dollars.
When the deal is set,
you find someone to get the money.
Ok. I'll do my tricks.
Then what?
Well, with the money
in our hands...
I'll find a way to link
Henrique to the robbery.
I can plant something
in his office.
I don't know,
I 'II think of something.
We take the money and disappear!
Freedom, man...
I'm worried, you know.
About what?
I fear what Maicon
might do to Henrique.
I like him,
he's not a bad person.
Nobody is bad.
Henrique is not bad.
Is Maicon bad?
Is the deputy bad?
Nobody is bad. People just
go the wrong way sometimes.
That's why I believe in punishment...
in real justice.
- What?
- Punishment is the way...
What do you mean?
Are you crazy?
What are you talking about?
You're not God.
You're doing this
for the money, baby.
At least I am.
I don't want this life.
I want to be happy.
I want to be free,
I want to love you.
Don't you agree?
Why are you so quiet?
Why are you quiet?
You tell me now.
Are you hiding
something from me?
- Of course not.
- I knew it.
Little kitten, come on.
Do you swear?
I do. I do.
Do you swear that
we'll get this money and leave...
...and be happy, you and I?
You and I
and this little being right here.
I had forgotten.
Really?
I can't be smoking!
I must stop this shit.
Can I tell you something?
You can.
I want a girl.
I really do.
Answer... Answer...
Aren't you going to answer?
Who is it?
It's the bank manager,
I won't answer the phone.
Answer it, girl...
It's them.
Let's go!
Julia, stop!
Stop!
Stop right there!
Not one more step!
Drop that suitcase
and get out of there!
He's armed! He's armed!
What's up?
Here.
Hi.
This is very fragile.
You must place it in something
that he always carries with him.
Do you think you can?
Of course.
Who is this fuck?
Down!
- Maicon, Bola was shot!
- Julia!
Edgar!
- Come with me, Julia.
- You're gonna die, “Menudinho”!
Fucking Stop right there!
Oh, you punk!
Come on!
Stop! Stop!
Get out of the car!
- Get out!
- Get him!
Get down! Fuck!
Stop! Stop!
Come on, deputy!
Go, go, go!
What's that noise?
- There's a bomb in the suitcase.
- What?
What the fuck was that?
- Put the suitcase up here.
- I'm not touching it!
- Put it up here!
Or else it will explode,
it has a proximity sensor!
What?
If the deputy gets near it,
the suitcase will explode.
Put the suitcase up here!
Your Honor!
That's your million dollars right here!
See you there!
This is an ungrateful world.
I saved this asshole,
and this is how he thanks me!
He's getting near us!
This thing is gonna explode!
- I'm not on his tail.
- Faster, faster!
The bus!
Watch out! Stop!
Where did you
fucking learn to drive?
- The fucking bus got in the way!
- Drive! Drive!
Where did he go?
Fucking punk!
- Over there! That's his car!
- That's my suitcase!
- That's my money!
- He must've run.
Where is the prick?
Get you suitcase
and let's beat it!
My money... My Money.
What? A faggot?
No, never! He's a real man!
It's a God's man!
It's my hero!
It's amazing his capacity,
it's marvelous!
Exemplary citizen!
It's terrific! He's a champion,
a total champion.
Call me, Edgar.
Got my number?
We have confirmed that
the man killed in the explosion...
this morning
in Baixada do Glicério
was really the state deputy
Jader Kerteis.
Holy crap! Holy crap!
Are you aware
that we are fucked?
How could you place a bomb there
and not tell me?
And I know this Maicon,
he is crazy!
He'll go to the end of the world
to get his money!
He'll do anything to get his
money. You know that, don't you?
He knows who I am.
- Give me the cell phone.
- I don't have it.
- Where is it?
- In my pants.
- Dad?
- Hi, son.
I need to talk to you now.
What's going on?
Where are you?
- Is the restaurant full?
- More or less.
- Walter didn't come to work.
- Don't leave there.
Don't leave, no matter what!
I'm coming over.
Bye.
I'm going to the restaurant.
I can't leave my father alone.
- You want me to go with you?
- No, you stay.
- Are you sure?
- You stay here.
- Will you be careful?
- Stay here.
I'll be back soon.
Dad?
- What happened, Edgar?
- Come with me.
- Why? What happened?
- I'll explain on the way.
Explain what?
Something happened to Walter?
- Is that why he didn't come?
- Yes and no...
- What do you mean?
- I'll explain.
Explain what?
What's going on, Edgar?
- What happened?
- We can go.
Dad.
Shut it.
A presidential suite, son?
Julia?
My son, where did you
get the money for this?
Dad.
Julia?
She must've gone out
to buy something.
Julia?
Were you calling me, Edgar?
Nice photo, huh?
What have you done with Julia?
That's what I ask you,
my friend.
Where is my money
and that whore?
I don't know anything about
any money or any whore.
I'll ask again.
Where is my money
and that cunt?
Get his old man!
- Get him!
- What is this?
Calm down!
- Don't! Don't!
- Hold him down!
- Bring the old man here.
- Stop! Let me go!
Wait, man!
- Wait!
- Hold him!
- That's enough!
- Wait! Let's talk!
- Hold him down!
- Wait!
Gag him! Come on!
- Gag this old prick!
- Dad!
Dad!
- That's enough.
- We'll only bleed you a little bit.
- Scalpel, Rato.
- Scalpel.
Where will it be?
- The spleen.
- I can get the appendix here.
The appendix will bleed
too much and he will die fast.
It can't be...
- So? Appendix or spleen?
- Spleen.
- It's not easy to get it right.
- Just fucking do it!
Dad! Dad!
Dad...
- Injection, Rato.
- Alright.
- Done.
- One down.
Edgar?
Your father suffered a small
incision in his spleen...
he will bleed a little...
but with this injection
he will live for more six hours.
Okay?
Is your father diabetic?
Son of a bitch!
Well, this way
you make my job harder.
- We need to check his pressure.
- Six hours, Edgar.
I'll wait for your call.
- Bring the old man.
- We need to check his pressure.
Fuck his pressure!
Just bring him!
But we need to monitor him.
Cut it! Just do it!
Come on!
Julia! Where were you?
- Where were you?
- Are you ok?
Where were you?
I was buying
some fresh clothes for us.
I was looking from the hall.
- Did you see my father?
- I did.
They pierced my father
with a fucking sword!
Is your father alive?
Is he dead?
- I don't know...
- Is your father alive?
- Are you hurt?
- I only have six hours...
You're limping.
Did they hurt you?
Walter?
- They took my father.
- Why all this shit?
I need to do that thing
I asked you.
Do you understand?
Do you remember
everything I said?
Can I trust you?
Here, boss.
Say it, boy.
Bet my balls that you would call.
So, I want to make a deal
with you.
What deal? I'll give your
money back, what else?
But now your situation's
got worse.
Who told you
I just want the money?
- There's one more thing.
- Say it. I'm listening;
The girl is the only thing
that's non-negotiable.
The girl is mine.
Right?
So, that's what I have in mind.
You are free. You and your father
can go to hell, I don't care.
I only have half the money.
- What about the other half?
- I've spent it.
I got you.
It's your compensation
for the girl, right? Okay.
I'll let you have half the money,
pretty boy.
Is that a deal?
I choose the place,
and only one car...
If I see a second car, I quit.
And fuck you all!
They're here.
Come on, pickup the old man!
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Stop right there, Edgar!
Dad?
- Get the woman here.
- Get off me!
- Give me the bag.
- Edgar!
- I missed you, baby.
You shouldn't have done
that to me.
So, Edgar...
did you enjoy my girl?
You have balls indeed,
you'll keep half the money.
Unfortunately, you won't
be able to use it.
Guys, to wrap it up...
I would like to read a passage
from a text I really appreciate...
a text about death.
“Death gives meaning
for our life...
and even more importantly...
death creates
a special value for time.
If our time in this life
were undetermined...
life itself would
lose its meaning.
We would probably be butt-naked
and wielding spears.
Death is nature's
most powerful agent...
it comes to take away the old
and make room for the new. It is true.
Our efforts to avoid it...
and turn our short stay here into
something minimally memorable...
is our reason."
isn't it?
That is, there is life
only because there is death.
"La muerte".
See you tomorrow,
ladies and gentlemen.
The boy traded you,
did you know that?
He sold you for half the money.
That's the jungle, baby.
Every man for himself.
But did you really think that
after all this I'd let you walk?
Especially if you have
my son in your belly.
- Maicon?
- What?
Can I tell you something?
Say it, baby.
I lied to you.
What?
The baby is not yours.
It's Edgar's.
And there's one more thing.
It's a girl.
- Julia!
- Crazy chick!
Stop! Stop!
Stop this shit!
Listen, son!
What about that red thing,
what the fuck is that?
Well, this one is different,
want to see? I'll show you.
This one, have a look...
We connect and then...
It works the same, but as inverse.
Right, the same,
but I didn't get shit!
Bye, see ya!
Thanks, auntie!
What happened, Maicon?
I don't believe it!
Son of a whore!
Now I'm gonna kill this bitch!
Sometimes we need stand away
from the paper...
...to understand the whole sketch
with more clarity.
2 YEARS LATER
Subtitle By 4H5@N