Lake Baikal - Li Jian
Timing &amp; Subtitles brought to You by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
♫  In my arms, in your eyes  ♫
♫  Over there the spring breeze was captivating and the green meadow was so inviting  ♫
♫  The moonlight sprinkled love all over the lake  ♫
♫  The bonfire for two lighted up the whole night  ♫
♫  Years later, we wandered like clouds  ♫
♫  The ever-changing footsteps, have made it difficult for us to hold hands  ♫
♫  This life is too short  ♫
♫  to prove the deep feeling that can melt the snow ♫
♫  Then one day, you suddenly reappeared  ♫
♫  You are so clear yet mysterious, by the Lake Baikal  ♫
By Lake Baikal sung by Li Jian  Translation: Ke Renshi @inmymelody.wordpress.com
Episode 6
You let him to leave alone.You should stay with him.You should go accompany him!
Hurry up!You should go with him together
Hurry up!
Tell me, how to do with this?
How come she's still asleep?
Yue Ya reason for not able to wake up. Because
Because of this paper's person spell.Yue Ya is under her control
trapping her in a dream
What?
a dream?
Young Lady!
Young Lady! what's wrong?
Where is the one named Duan?
San lang
San Lang died
died?
San lang died!How did he die?
Young Lady!
Young Lady wake up
Because in a dream encounter is a different things.
Yueqi Luo said
If the paper person ruined, Yue Ya will also be dead.
It seems to be in the wake of like a person sleepwalking.
Then what do we do now?
We can't just wait for this.
You say, who knows when she wake up?
Master
You said that Yue Qiluo path to travel actually is outstanding.
I'm afraid this Yue Qiluo really have this ability to take people's mind away.
You say, this Yue Qiluo want to kill Yue Ya?
Why did she want to do that?
Misuse of time and effort wasted again.
I doubt she's afraid of the same thing.
What is that?
This is the town of one hundred years of her character. I guess Yue Qiluo will fear this.
So she didn't dare to close Yue Ya body, I thought of this approach.
Paper by the hands of people to control Yue Ya.
This stuff, how come is really good.
No.
Then you also give me a whole chant. Huh?
Your home well have a few good one too.If you want get your own.
No. You...
San lang
San lang already died
not possible
How would I? How would I commit suicide?
You shouldn't be like this
But he really is dead.
Your lover died
How can you live alone?
It's not right! The person I love, he is not going to commit suicide.
He is not that kind of person!
As long as rewarding to be alive.He died on nothing.
People who commit suicide, they are coward.
He is not! I'm not also!
You're not just more than a coward. You simply have a heart of stone. Watched the person you love to die.
Actually indifferent.-I'm not!
I'm not!You caused his death
It was you
It wasn't me
It was youyou made him die
You're a murderer!
Murderer
Murder
To accompany him to die together
To accompany him
Die with him
On his funeral day, you go to pull him.
He was killed in his coffin.
You can go together with him.
This way, he will know that you love him
love him
What are you up to?
I've thought of something
You have to think about this approach.Don't complained it to God.
There's a light in my hand
Huh?
What light?
Found from paper person of Yue Qiluo spell.
You can't see through it.
We didn't see Yueya wake up for a little bit before isn't it?
If she continues to fall asleep
I'm thinking if in real life Yueya can't wake up, then
How about going to her dream?
In the dream she will wake up.
What do you mean?
What I mean is, since this light can bring Yueya into a dream
Isn't it said that can also bring other people into a dream.
I'm going to try.
Do it,faster
What now?
What is it? Hurry up
Hey, can't you do it?
What are you doing?
I guess I'm afraid, I'm not ordinary person to do this after all.
That's also right.
Isn't it said that It will work on ordinary person.
No. What do you mean with this? Don't look at me.
I'm not a normal person
I'm a person with identity!
When you find Yueya, tell her that she is dreaming and to quickly return
Hey, it's strange. Dress up like that.
Take a look at him.
He has no braids.
This person is not wearing the same clothes as us.
Yes, He is a monster.
He looks quite nice.
i gotta find Yueya
Thats right
I gotta find Yueya
Yueya!
Miss!
San lang
Yueya! Out of the way!
San Lang, wait for me
I will be with you
Yueya!
What are you doing?
San Lang died.
I'm going to accompany him
What San lang are you talking about? Right now you're in a dream, Wake up!
If you don't wake up, your brother will have a sudden death.Yueya!
My brother?
You..who are you?
I'm Gu Xuanwu, Lord Gu
Lord Gu
Yueya, what's wrong?
I'm called Yueya?
If you're not called Yueya then what is it?
No, this isn't right
I'm Yueqi Luo
What Yueqi Luo?'
Yueqi Luo
She is Yueqi Luo!
Catch her and give her to me! Don't let her run!
My son died because of her!
Run quickly!
Get her!
Out of the way!
Don't run! Catch him!
It's bad.
You have to wake up.
Yueya, listen up you are not Yueqi Luo, you are Yueya
This is all a dream, you will soon wake up
Wake up, your brother is waiting for you
Yueya!
You're called Yueya,not Yueqi Luo Remember!
Quickly wake up! You're Yueya!
You're not Yueqi luo, you're Yueya!
You're not Yueqi luo, you're Yueya! Who am I?
Who am I?
Don't run! Catch her!
Catch this bitch to go back!
Okay. Go! Go!
You're not Yueqi luo, you're Yueya!
I am Yueqi Luo
Who am I?
Yueya!
Did you see Lord Gu?
Wake up Yueya
Yueya!
Wake up!
Things are like this
Right now Yueya thinks she is yueqi luo
Yueya in fact is trapped in Yue Qiluo memories.
So it is like this
Hey,
If you really want to recall, actually have to terminate her sleep.
That is recall to end it.
Yueya isn't it will wake up?
No, Lord Gu.Yueya now is experiencing
Yue Qiluo's past period.
You forgot what kind of fate Yue Qiluo have in the end?
The end?
Alive nail in the coffin and sleep for a hundred years.
Could it be that Yueya will sleep for a hundred years?
Furthermore,
Yue Qiluo, she's to set about
You thought is it was simply just to let her sleep?
You also say it.
Yueya want to commit suicide wholeheartedly in her dream.
What I'm most worried about right now..
If she dies in her dream,
In real life she will also.
What happened? Something wrong with Yueya. Quickly called a doctor!
What?!Yueya breathing and pulse are weak!
Quickly called a doctor!You wait for me! I'll be right back!
Hurry up!
Go in! Go in! Wicked scoundrel!
Little slut! Kill a person! Pay it with your own life!
You wait and see!
No! No!
Our Miss...Give our young master home to be buried with you!
I'm begging you!
Let go of our Miss,she's a good person
She and Duan's son are really in love.
I'm begging you, let her go
I'm begging you!
Yueya, you remember.You're not Yue Qiluo. You're Yueya.
It was all a dream. You should wake up immediately.
You quickly wake up!Your brother is waiting for you at home. Yueya!
Yueya!
Yueya
Wait after I make money, I'll treat you to eat.Help you to pay money to live inn.
Your kindness reported that kind of a bread.
What do you think of the house?
Is your house I'm staying?
Okay. Staying.What do you say is allright?
Live a life chant
Hate
Yueya
No!
To avenge Young Master! Go!Kill the person to pay for a life!
To pay for a life!Come! Come!
Get up!
What are you doing? let me go!
Miss! Miss! -Also arrested her!Let me go!
Let me go! What are you going to do?
What are doing?-Little slut!-Change her clothes!
Lets go!
No,let me go Don't capture me
Let me go!
Who are you people? Let me go!
Take them away!
Come down here.
Devil woman! You confused my son and make him died!
what do you have to say for yourself?
San lang died because of me
But I really don't want him to die.
He wholeheartedly want to commit suicide.
He is dead
I grieved the same as all of you because I love him.
I want to die with him
Then why are you still alive?
I'm begging you, please forgive me
Sister
Younger sister apprentice?
How could I'll be your younger sister apprentice?
Also, you can either go out by exploding the wall.
From now on, you're no longer my younger sister apprentice.
I don't understand what you are talking about?
I don't deserve to be in Duan's home.  What about you?
Why did you caught us?
Evil creature!
To the imminent death, you still dare to misleading the will of people here.
Keep your magic bar!
Did you think
that you could fool me?
Little woman obsessed with sorcerers.
Ruined how many lives
Today, this poor Taoist should punish your town repression.
You also didn't dare to let your scourge dead.
Start working! Yes!
Miss Let us go!
Don't arrest my family! Miss!-Let me go!
Let go of me!
Miss!Let go of me!
Master,what do we do about this servant?
The servant? She's the one to administered the magic dolls
Casually disposed of it.
Yes
What are you doing?let me go!
Drag her down!Yes!
No,let go of me!
Let me out!
Let me go! Let me go!
Let me out
Push her down!Yes!
No! Let me out!
Let go of me!
Let me out!
No!
Don't!
Help me!
I'm not an evil spirit! I'm a person!
Let me out!
I beg you guys, let me out! Let me out!
Come you guys!
Come you guys! Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out!Help me!
Why are you glanced sideways?
You're not afraid your eyeball fly! What's the matter with her?!
Old man...Old man really have no ability.
What did you say?
If your sister wake up,
I'm afraid that...
I'm afraid that is only a stick of incense.(small chances)
It's kind of you to say it again one more time!
You said it again one more time! Say!
Commander, I have tried another way again.
If she really wake up again. I...
You remember, you have already handle this for years. Dogs have long to go up right itself!
Let me tell you. If you don't cure my sister, I will shoot you!
Commander Gu..
Spare me! Spare me Commander Gu!
Spare me!Take a hike! Quickly go away!
Let me tell you. Do not let me see you in Wen County!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Let me out!
let me out!
It's all over. Let me out!
Why are you still good at struggling?
The more struggling, the more pain.
Only dead is a real relief.
Dead
On what it is settle?
Also no worries,No fear, No pain.
Whats the use?
Even if you fine one, Yueya still wont wake up
She is not sick
How would the doctor know how to treat it?
Then, why you let me go to find a doctor?
I can't just watching her straight in here.
Yue Qiluo said. Once the paper is ruined,
Yueya will also died.
Now, the paper person increasingly have a weak spot.
Yueya pulse also has become increasingly weak.
I'm really afraid in case this little bit of light will die out.
Yueya won't ever wake up
Earlier, I used my own blood when burning the paper person.
Yueya could also feel the pain. There is also sign of awake.
But
But what?
But if Yueya will wake up to every
rays of light if we re-light the paper person to shine.
No, what do you want to say?
What I want to say is this paper person before have a strong light.
It prove that it is full of energy. So it can suppress it to live.
Yueya!
Did you see lord Gu?
Who am I? Wake up
Yueya!
Who am I?
The paper person is now have a very weak energy.Maybe, this is the time to let go and gamble it.
what are you doing?Calm down, dont be rash
I'm not fooling around. This is the only way.
Now, the paper person energy is very weak. I still can wake her up if later then it may be too late.
You ruined the paper person.
Is my sister not going to be destroy?
Isn't it exhausted?
Dont lie to yourself anymore
You're tired
Just sleep
Death is not terrible.
But entering it's nothing, just a quiet sleep.
Dead.  It is all free.
The paper person ruined, Yueya will die.You can do nothing then. Yueya certain death!
Let go!Calm down, there must be another way
you..
Yueya is not breathing.
Also not even the pulse.
this..what should we do?
I don't believe.I will not let you get away.
Yueqi Luo, return Yueya to me!
No!
I can't die.
Die you will get nothing.
No
Let me out!
Yueya
There's a reaction
I cannot die
I can't die
Yueya!
Why are you so persistent?
Why are you not obediently die?
You are Yue Qiluo.Yue Qiluo in this respect blocked in the well.
No
I'm not Yue Qiluo.
I'm not Yue Qiluo!You are!
Im not Yueqi Luo
Then who am I really is?
You are not Yue Qiluo
I am.
Are you not sympathize with me?
You've now seen my life
Don't you think I'm very pitiful?
You and I meet by chance on the street.You can take me home for my room and board.
But now, you see my destiny is so tragic.
Don't you think, I should also have one chance to live again?
The man you like,I also like
But he didn't even look at me because you're standing in the middle.
I also can for you to love him. For you to accompany him to live.
As long as you die
What is the end of it?
No
What are you still struggling?You are destined to die in this.
No!
Why should I give in a bit to you?I had the day I want to own myself.
Myself too?
You even don't know who you are.
Yueya!
Yueya
Thats right
right
I am Yueya
Yueya!
This sound
I will invite you to eat a banquet feast.You still avoid that half of kindness.
Our home. Isn't it good?
Since I met him
I finally know
What is pain?
In the future if she really marry him
I'm also not lose
Is him.
Is him
Wuxin
Yueya
I'm here.
I've already been awake.Wuxin.
You've awake.
Wuxin.You've awake.
Yueya
Go to sleep
I won't sleep
I'm scared if I sleep
I won't wake up
Don't worry,that wont happen
I will be here with you, not going anywhere
Okay
Master
What is it? Is Yueya asleep?
Just lie.Lord Gu,
I have to trouble you to help me look after her.
Okay
What is it?
I have some things to do, i will be back soon
Huh? No.
Yue Qiluo, you listen.
I'm not a saint who have a heart to punish.
I don't care whether you're a demon or ghost
But you do not dwell endlessly.
Do not pester me! And not to pester Yueya!
Otherwise next time, I will not let you.
These words, tell your boss about it.
You see, you just have a little good spirit and scrapped it own. You don't work up.
Chat with me.
Also doing a live chat. Come! Come! Come!
I wont give
Okay
Then you say, what do you want to talk about?
Lord Gu say, your dream is because of Duan San Lang commit suicide.
Is it true?
Yes
But this Duan San Lang looks exactly like you
I see him dead.
My heart just..
Hey,it was just a dream
What are some strange things? Playing tricks on the brain.
Can't be serious.
Give me
Give me!
Give me! I won't give!
You say, this day you have this dream to think about. Isn't it this what you mean?
Aiyooh, I don't want to say to you again.Give me! Give me!
I won't give
If you wont tell me, I wont give you
You say, this day who is it that you're thinking?
Hate.
Sister! Master!
Open the door! Sister!
Mastermaster..dont be like this
My little sister is sick, Im here to see her
Yueya! brother is here!
Lord Gu is here
Little sister!
Brother brought some good things
See if you like it
Look at the good things brother bought you
Do you like it?
I'm also nothing major. No need to spend a lot of money, Lord Gu.
What are you saying? Specially frightened sister.
Brother is buying something. What is that about spending a lot of money?
Oh, that's right. Two days ago, to meet with a little evil spirit
Really scary right?Oh, I'm fine.
This time, I came here to find you two.Just wanted to bring you two up to the mountain to go to Hot spring bubble.
Hot spring?Yes.
That hot spring is not that absolutely right away that kind of boiling forever hot spring.
That is below surface unsolicited hot spring. It can also cut the face pressure to be alarm.
Hey, there is still have that kind of hot spring?
That's right. Can I take a bath directly?
I tell you, our house have a few old smelly lady.
Let me take them all day to go to the hot spring.I'm not taking them.
I absolutely not take them along.
I tell you, that is called can play a role with the beauty.
Thats good
It's only about the bath, I feel a lot of ashamed.
Its better that I dont go
What are you feel ashamed? I'll tell you
It's just like going with your own family, the same kind of.
That's also okay.
Hey
Come with me
Little sister, i'll be leaving then
Master,wait
What is it?
I say, you don't want to take us to the hot spring just to soak it.
I really want to take both of you to soak in the hot spring. You two go with me. Good eat, good drink, good entertainment.
How about it?
Wont go master,hold on
Wu Xin, Yue Ya
I see you guys, certainly want to refuse a toast only to be forced to drink a forfeit. ( to hesitate to do something until forced to do even more )
The Longest Journey - by Li Qi
Lyrics translation: musicindividual86
♫ The wind brings him along for the longest journey, ♫
♫ Following the rays of night, never once stopping. ♫
♫ Embracing the warm starlight, it’s also kissed the flower of the night before. ♫
♫ All along the way, the melody wanders. Does it still remember its hometown? ♫
♫ Let life wisp through the corners of time as it wills. ♫
♫ It silently watches people love and hate. ♫
♫ It drifts along with time, no matter if it has forgotten or remembered. ♫
♫ The memory of him leaving her continuously lives on. ♫
♫ Let life wisp through the corners of time as it wills. ♫
♫ It silently watches people love and hate. ♫
♫ It drifts along with time, no matter if it has forgotten or remembered. ♫
♫ The memory of him leaving her continuously lives on. ♫
♫ The memory of leaving her continuously lives on. ♫
Wuxin : The Monster Killer
Preview
What is your name?
Yueqi Luo
Can I follow you home?