Also, I'm leaving for Daejon tomorrow.
She's leaving because of me.
You know, right, that I'm leaving
because I don't want to see you?
Hye Rim, too, is leaving because of me.
When I was young, even my
mom left because of me.
Let's not see each other again, Soo Hyun.
♪ Everyday it's only you ♪
♪ You're that kind of person to me ♪
♪ Without you I feel like I'm going crazy ♪
♪ I can't even breathe, you are
the only person in my heart ♪
Everything is because of me.
I'm the problem.
I have to disappear.
Episode 15
Are you still feeling cold?
Did it get any better?
Thanks to you, it got better.
What was that sound?
It's the doctor. What do we do, Noona?
What do you mean? We
have to get out quickly.
Doctor, you're back?
Yeah.
Yoo Rim, you're here?
Yes.
What's wrong with him? It's past 12 am and he
doesn't find it strange that I'm at your house?
For now, let's get you out. Hurry.
Doctor.
Doctor!
Doctor, Doctor!
What's wrong? Why would he drink so
much when he can't hold his liquor?
- Goodbye.- Goodbye.
Oh my, Chairman.
I thought I should repay you
for the debt I owe you.
It's okay if he joins us, right?
Yes.
Madame Go, can you help me out?
This guy wants to marry my daughter,
please look into his
personality and fortune.
Ah, Doctor Choi, since you're a
psychologist, you'd also know, right?
Please look into it together.
Asking a psychologist to look into a person's fortune
and to evaluate him seems to be a severely biased view.
His drooping eyes make him appear
as a mild mannered person.
On top of that, being so stiff in an identification
photo is evidence that he's not a crafty person.
Being raised by a single mother bothers me a bit
but... Wow, his credentials are really impressive.
Seeing that he's done a lot of volunteer work shows that he
seems to have a lot of consideration for others as well.
He seems like a decent person. More
importantly, Yeon Woo likes him.
Not all people with drooping
eyes are mild mannered.
Among the most violent criminals, many have
drooping eyes. And being raised by a single mother?
It's already an established theory that the presence of one's parents
doesn't have much relevance in that person's life. Most of all,
the fact that you're asking a fortune teller to
evaluate this person to begin with is wrong.
A fortune teller uses their senses
to just barely tell someone's fortune. They
can never know what's inside that person.
Doctor Choi, you're as fastidious as ever.
But, from what you both have said, I
will have to meet him one more time.
What do you think? Madame Go,
would you also like to meet him?
I don't have time. I'm going
to leave the cafe soon.
But, why? Is something wrong?
Yes, there was something that happened. Also,
there's an unni in Daejon who tells fortunes.
Since it's the new semester, it's the
peak season and she asked me to help.
There's a chance I won't be coming back.
But, why?
She will be immigrating to Australia soon
so she asked me to take over the cafe.
The location and earnings are
better than where I am now.
That's why I'm thinking
about moving for good.
That's such a shame.
You'll come running when
I ask for you, right?
What?
Did you hear, Doctor? Right now, Noona
Hye Rim is packing her bags and leaving.
Choi Soo Hyun didn't even go to work. What lingering
feelings do you have left to keep looking back?
The doctor is going to come soon.
What will he do when he comes? Will he hold on to her and
ask her not to leave or kneel down and beg for forgiveness?
Your doctor will never do such things. Even
if he does, my sister will leave either way.
Right Unni? You won't look back, right?
Of course.
Ji Ho take care of yourself. Yoo Rim,
I will contact you when I get there.
Where did you say she was going?
What?
Where is Hye Rim leaving from? Where is it?
Daejon42,500 Won ($42.50)
Excuse me, where is the bus to Daejon?
It left a moment ago.
It's the elementary school I went to.
I stayed here until the fifth
grade and moved to Seoul.
So that's why you bought
a house on Jeju Island.
I remember the old times and
I can also practice here.
Would you like to hear it once?
Doctor, you can play piano, too?
I just took a short course,
so I'm not so good.
But still, I practiced very hard.
Bach, The Well Tempered Clavier
The melody line attached
to this song is Ave Maria.
Is that so? No wonder it was so nice.
I think if a woman plays this,
she will look so beautiful.
I got it wrong.
Doctor, by any chance
is this what I earlier...
Yes, you're right. Because
you liked it so much...
Wow, I'm touched.
I'm sorry for liking you.
No, Doctor, why would you say that?
Without making it obvious
or calling attention to it,
I wanted to keep it inside
of myself as a gift.
Doctor, do you know how to play chopsticks?
Just a little.
All I can do is play with both of my index
fingers. Doctor, you do the accompaniment.
Here I go.
One, two, three. Two, two, three.
Congratulations on your achievement.
Thank you.
It is thanks to your kindness.
I wish you good luck wherever you go.
So, can my child attend the
university in Seoul next year?
Marie Antoinette said the mom
is holding the child back.
So, you need to let go.
What? But still, I'm the mom.
"I believe in you, stay strong, everything will
be okay." She said never to say such things.
As a matter of fact, your child is probably feeling burdened and
if you interfere too much, you will make it even more difficult.
So, let your child feel
loved, but keep silent. Okay?
Yes.
It's so tiring, how many more left now?
Three people. But after two hours,
five more people will be coming.
What the heck? I don't
even have time to eat.
Besides that, do you have any
thoughts of going on a blind date?
A blind date?
It's my friend's younger brother. He's
good looking and runs a large restaurant.
Also, he has two cars and
as a bonus, he has a child.
A child? Is he a divorcee?
Of course, you are a divorcee, too. Are you
going to act greedy and ask for a bachelor?
If you do that, you'll be punished. You should
know when it's appropriate to be greedy.
Move.
Soo Hyun, I did wrong.
I won't ask for forgiveness, so
can you meet me one more time?
Doctor, aren't you eating?
I'm not eating.
You didn't eat yesterday, either.
It's okay. When my clients
come, let them in.
Yeah, Won Ji Ho.
Hyung Seung Chan, about the doctor...
Doctor.
But, why did you suggest
coming here so suddenly?
Now that I think of it, I think
you were also on her bucket list.
While walking on the blue
shores of Jeju Island,
she said she wanted to link arms
with a cool man and pick sea shells.
Ta-da! Here's a seashell. Isn't it pretty?
Oh my, it's pretty.
Here, give me your arm.
No, I'm okay.
Everyone does this here.
What's on your bucket list?
The first wish, I think
half of it has come true.
Go on a backpacking trip to
Peru to see Machu Picchu...
Go to Las Vegas and gamble 10 million won.
Go to a club and dance my
heart out all night long.
Lie down in an igloo and see
the Aurora Borealis in Alaska.
See the Aurora Borealis...
There's a lot of traveling overseas.
If you're going to do that, then you
need to go to Incheon Airport first.
Also, you need to go to Seoul
to pack your things first.
Doctor, I think you need
to come with me to Seoul.
No, I just want to be here.
How can you do that alone here?
Come with me to Seoul
first and prepare. Okay?
And, Doctor, you have to help my hyung.
What about Doctor Choi?
Unni!
Yoo Rim!
What are you doing here?
I came to film a restaurant
in Daejon and stopped by.
Cheers!
Nothing much going on in Seoul?
Mm, well...
Oh right, Choi Soo Hyun is totally not
himself right now. Isn't it exciting?
Well, I left. If he eats and
sleeps well, is he a human?
Choi Soo Hyun, you are not in your
normal state of mind right now.
You need something now.
Something that will never leave you,
betray you, and only follows you around.
Now, what should I name you?
How's Go Hye Rim?
Hye Rim. Hye Rim.
Come on, give it to me this once. So I can
send a text message to Soo Hyun. Huh?
I told you so. Now that you are drunk
you want to contact him again!
You can't. You absolutely can't.
You're right. Why should
I call the likes of him?
Tell him to have a nice
life for all I care.
Come on, just once. Just once,
let me talk to Soo Hyun! Huh?
I want to hear his voice!
I said you can't!
Yes?
Hyung! Who do you think came?
Doctor Choi, have you been well?
Doctor.
You didn't clean out my office. I worried that
you might have turned it into a storage house.
I knew you'd return.
I heard you and Hye Rim broke up?
Yes. She found out about the experiment.
I heard she went to Daejon. Don't you think
you should go see her at least once?
She was only the main
subject of the experiment.
Are you eating well? What about sleep?
Yes, there's nothing wrong with me.
Are you lying in front of me?
Or are you being truthful?
If I were in your situation, I think
tearing up would be the natural reaction.
I usually don't cry.
Did your meeting with your mother go well?
You have to understand your mother.
Your mother also...
I know, that she's nothing
but an ordinary person.
I don't think that a mom
is a perfect person.
When she scolded me as she left, she
probably did that by mistake as well.
You're saying everything
that I was going to say.
But, how do you feel right now?
You might think that way with your head, but
your feelings are fluctuating right now.
Feelings are stronger than you think.
They don't get sorted out just by
trying to understand it with your head.
Right now, if you suppress
yourself like this,
your feelings may explode someday.
The same goes for Hye Rim and your mother.
I have to overcome it. I can endure it.
Eat a lot.
What?
You want to take a walk?
Where? Hey, that's too far.
Even so, you really want to go?
It can't be helped. If you
really want to, then let's go.
How did you know to come here?
I heard from Seung Chan.
I came to walk my puppy.
All the way to Daejon?
Yes, is that weird?
Then, do you think that's something
you would do in your right mind?
She wanted to go on a drive.
What's with the puppy?
I just adopted her. Her name is Go Hye Rim.
Hye Rim.
Do you like your new job?
The atmosphere is nice.
Oh, a poster of a seagull. Good,
because it relieves you of feeling stifled
while subconsciously helping you feel free.
It will be able to console you.
Why are you suddenly talkative?
Were you nervous?
No. Why would I?
Please give me a cup of coffee.
It's been a long time. Can
you tell me my fortune?
Of course, I know you're a
fake, but you have intuition.
What do you think will
happen to me in the future?
Do you think things will turn out well?
I don't know about your future, but I
think I know how you feel right now.
You didn't come for a
walk, you came to see me,
but your pride wouldn't
allow you to just come, so
you made up a ridiculous
excuse about your puppy.
The same goes for your attitude right now.
Afraid that you might not be able to control
yourself in case you reveal your feelings,
afraid that you'd collapse, you're keeping
yourself guarded, aren't I right?
That's right.
Then, what do you think I have to do?
I'm going on a blind date.
I'm going to meet a nice man who is totally
different from you and start a new life.
So, there's nothing you can do for me.
Thank you. Please come again.
Goodbye.
♪ Everyday, it's only you ♪
♪ You're that kind of person to me ♪
♪ Really, without you I think
I'm going to go crazy ♪
♪ I can't even breathe ♪
♪ The only person in my heart ♪
♪ Because every single day is painful ♪
♪ Because you're not here ♪
♪ Because you're not here,
I'm crippled so please ♪
♪ Please come to my side ♪
I did something out of character.
Going after the experiment's main subject after
the experiment has already been scrapped
has been confirmed to be nothing
but a waste of money and time.
The only way to block the dopamine that's
still being produced and spread is
to be absorbed in work. Let's start anew.
Experiment Log: "Blueprint for new
second preliminary experiment."
Don't you think Hyung is in a serious state?
He still doesn't sleep these days, right?
Yes. In the past, he would at least
turn off the lights and lie down.
Maybe he's given up. These
days, all he does is read.
Why are you worrying about a person like that?
He even did an experiment on my sister.
That's right. You're family.
The results are out! They're out!
What is?
The documentary festival. I
filmed Ji Ho and submitted it.
The homepage is...Excellence
Award: Go Yoo Rim
Yay! Ah, what to do? Thank goodness!
Congrats, Yoo Rim.
But shouldn't we buy some choco-pies and congratulate you? (Korean tradition of
making an instant cake using chocolate covered marshmallow cakes and toothpicks)
Ah, what to do? This is so great!
Seung Chan, today, it's my special treat.
Then I'll buy the cake. Wait a moment.
Thank you!
Oh, what to do? I'm so happy! So happy!
Please get those two to stop.
They've been like that since a while ago and
it's embarrassing me to death, seriously.
I'm sorry.
Um, Ji Ho. Yoo Rim.
Find the main test subject for our second preliminary
experiment from far away. Our experiment's failure,
I mean the one that got scrapped was
because Go Hye Rim was too close.
So, you have to find someone whose residence
or workplace is far away from where we work.
Yes.
But Doctor, the hypothesis of this experiment is that
there is no such thing as true love for a woman,
but I think that there
is such a thing as love.
Why?
I'm dating Noona Yoo Rim,
but when I see that noona, she
treats me with true sincerity...
That's love that lasts only three years,
fake love that is maintained by hormones.
The problem comes afterwards.
Is there a guarantee that Yoo Rim will keep
liking you after three years has passed?
If there is, prove it.
A woman will abandon a man
at some point or another.
So, you too...
Soo Hyun, it's Mom.
Let's meet one more time, okay?
I'm at the pasta restaurant
where we dined previously.
I'll be waiting.
Please come to the
consultation office by 5 p.m.
Doctor, your mother...
Seo Yeon Hee is here.
You hated me a lot, right? I...
Why did you break up with Father?
We weren't a good fit from the start.
He was too self-righteous and
only wanted to keep me cooped up.
Then one day, I met a man.
See? You can't trust a woman's love.
But, I really loved you. So...
You said you have another
family in the States, right?
So why did you come here?
I saw your article and
wanted to see your face.
Then, that means you're going back soon.
Everything is as you please.
You leave as you please and come to see me as
you please. And again, you leave as you please.
Did you ever think of me
who would be left alone?
I worried.
I did, but since you're a psychologist...
I thought that you might
understand me a little bit.
Just because I'm a psychologist, do
you think my heart is made of steel?
We're the same as everyone else. The only
difference is that we can analyze the mind.
It doesn't mean we don't
get emotional scars.
I don't remember anything
from when I was young.
The trauma from when you abandoned me when I was
young was so big, it even sealed off my memory.
Also, it's been thirty years. You have
a family, but to me, I had no one.
I grew up lonely with a father who
hated me as much as he hated you
along with a mother who only looked
after my younger brother, but...
Calm down, Soo Hyun. This person
is also just an immature human.
One by one, let's go about this slowly.
That's the correct answer.
What were you going to do
after coming to see me?
I thought it would be good to
keep in contact with each other,
even though it's not as happily as before.
Calling each other, and occasionally
having meals together...
When I was young, do you
remember when you abandoned me?
Don't you remember what you
said to me as you abandoned me?
What...
Mom, back then, you scolded me.
"Don't let your ice cream drip." That if I
kept doing that, you wouldn't come see me.
So I held on tightly to my ice cream.
In that hot weather, while wiping off the ice cream
I dripped, I was diligently waiting for you, Mom!
But in the end, you didn't come.
That memory became branded into me.
"I did something wrong."
"Because I dripped ice cream,
Mom didn't come." That's why I
hurt whenever I get hit by water droplets.
Because I remember what I did wrong,
it hurts as if I'm punishing myself!
But you can't even remember that?
I lived for thirty years inside that agony!
On rainy days, I couldn't go outside and trembled.
But you, the perpetrator, can't remember it?
Does that make any sense?
I-I-I'm sorry, Soo Hyun!
I did wrong!
What did you do wrong? Abandoning
me and leaving? Divorcing Father?
Lying about coming back?
What are you sorry about?!
I just wanted to see your face, that's all.
I wanted to see, just once,
how well you grew up.
That's right, I did and
don't ever come back.
Please enjoy.
Welcome...
Doctor, how are you here?
It's been a long time. Can
we talk for a moment?
I heard that Soo Hyun's
mom came to see him, but...
This time, I think she touched upon a
very painful part of Professor Choi.
It was the first time seeing
Professor Choi that agitated.
You were upset because of
the experiment, right?
You also knew about the experiment, Doctor?
Yes. I'm sorry that I couldn't stop him,
but do you know what that
experiment means to Professor Choi?
He probably did that to write his thesis,
get awards, and to become famous.
There's that, but above all that, that experiment
is Professor Choi's defense mechanism.
What?
If he proves that there's no such thing as true love for
women, his mother who abandoned him also had no love,
then he can relieve a bit of
the pain from being abandoned.
Then, whenever Soo Hyun is
abandoned by someone...
He blames himself.
On the outside, he reasons that it's because of
women, but on the inside, he's fooling himself.
Also, inside that perpetrator
is not only his mom,
you are also there.
What? Why me?
Because in the end, you also
abandoned Professor Choi and left.
But, looking at Professor Choi's state right
now, it doesn't look like he was hurt only once.
Was there anything else between you two?
In the middle of the experiment, I
told him that I wanted to break up,
but Soo Hyun was the first
who wanted to make up
and I accepted a purple tulip.
A purple one? Are you certain?
What color does the tulip appear to you?
Plum-colored? Is it not? Purple?
Purple?
When he was an undergraduate, Professor Choi
talked about the meaning behind tulips.
Purple and plum are similar colors, but the
meanings of the flower are complete opposites.
The meaning of the purple tulip that you
chose is love that does not last forever.
Professor Choi might also have
accepted the implication with it,
that love with you is not eternal.
Did anything else happen besides that?
It's 12 o'clock. Time's up.
What to do, Soo Hyun?
Cinderella's magic has worn off.
Cinderella
You still don't get it?
Everything was a lie.
"I love you, Soo Hyun"? How ridiculous.
Why would I?
But, Doctor, I also received my
share of scars from Soo Hyun.
You know that. For a period of
four months he experimented on me.
But, you know that Professor
Choi really liked you.
That experiment, was
important to Professor Choi.
He was also going to submit a thesis to the world's most prestigious
academic journal, JPSP.(Journal of Personality and Social Psychology)
If that were to be canceled,
other projects or
an award from the world psychological
association would all have gone down the drain.
But, Professor Choi really
wanted to stop that experiment
because of you.
The problem is now. Professor Choi
is currently in a really bad state.
It's because of his mom who abandoned
him and left and also because of you.
He is probably feeling abandoned twice.
If you leave him like this, it's dangerous.
You have to help him.
Hey, Go Hye Rim. Don't you
think I'm a bit strange?
I took three sleeping
pills, but I'm not sleepy.
I also barely ate,
but I'm not hungry.
Where are you going?
- I'm taking a walk.-
At this time of night?
The time doesn't matter.
A healthy mind belongs to a healthy body.
I will become healthy.
The important thing is that
I've realized that I'm weird.
That's the start of
treatment for everything.
So as of now, I don't have a big problem.
If I dig a bit more objectively
into my problem...
Should I become a paper airplane as well?
Freely?
Hyung!
- Hyung, what's wrong with you? Are
you out of your mind?- What about me?
What did you do on the edge of the roof?
Did you have a death wish?
I was just thinking of
something else for a second.
Are you okay? Do you
want me to support you?
No. Leave me alone. I can go alone.
What? He went up the roof to die?
Yeah. The pose was exactly one of suicide.
Why is Soo Hyun really doing that?
Why is he becoming so broken?
Can you come up here?
Suddenly, his biological
mother came and even you left.
If it were me, I don't think I
would be in my right mind either.
I also heard from Ji Ho.
Hyung started a new experiment.
What?
The experiment that he did on you is considered scrapped and
this time, he's really preparing for it with all his might.
I think he already got the
experiment's main test subject, too.
Professor Choi is a man who grew
up not knowing what love is.
Even when he loved, he
didn't know it was love,
so he used the experiment as an
excuse to confirm if there was love.
He thought that women
would always leave him
and from his mother to you, he
really has only been abandoned.
And so now, he's almost beyond repair.
Right now for Professor Choi, he probably
feels as if he's standing on a cliff.
Then the only person to rescue
Professor Choi is you, Hye Rim.
Fine. Even if I shatter to
pieces, I'm just going.
Excuse me. You came to hear about the explanation
of the psychological experiment, right?
Yes. Are you Doctor Choi Soo Hyun?
I thought he would be a man.
No. I'm a person that went
through that experiment once.
You came thinking that it's about the relationship
between your ideal type and your immune system, right?
That's a total fake. It's actually a
psychological experiment on love.
Excuse me?
It's an experiment where three men will approach you
under false pretenses to find out who you will fall for.
It's a really horrible experiment.
Do you want to do it?
How did you come here?
You came to see the new test subject
to do the experiment on, right?
I'm sorry, that person left.
I told her what the real
experiment was about.
Since I came back, you're happy, right?
Why did you come back?
Because I missed you.
I'm sorry, but I'm not going to
fall for Cinderella's story twice,
so if you're here to act again...
I'm not going to do that anymore. I'm
really here to see you Soo Hyun.
Oh right, there is another reason why I came
here. There is a project I wanted to do.
It's called the 'Choi Soo Hyun
rehabilitation project.' You'll help, right?
You guys, I'm here!
Oh, Hye Rim!
How are you here?
What do you mean how? This is
the place where I used to live.
Is it weird that I came
back to my own house?
Soo Hyun, come here. I have
something to tell you.
What's going on?
Hye Rim's here. She's with Hyung.
Choi Soo Hyun rehabilitation project, phase
one. To start with, eat all of this.
Hye Rim, I don't know what you
heard that made you come, but...
You aren't happy I came back?
You aren't at all happy? Just so-so?
Should I just go back?
No.
Then eat a spoon of this.
I came all the way from
Daejon to feed you this.
Consider me. Okay? Eat just a little.
Good job!
Now, let's try a big spoonful.
Here, you upload photos and images of yourself
throughout daily life in a natural way.
You used to always say this, Soo Hyun.
When someone is natural,
they are in the best state.
Hye Rim, I don't really do SNS.
What should we use to make your ID?
Go Hye Rim Love?
Good.
The password will be my birthday.
Ta-da. It's all done now.
What picture should we upload?
This is good.
Hye Rim, aren't you going to unpack?
Fine, today's tasks end with this.
Tomorrow, we're going to start with phase two
of the Choi Soo Hyun rehabilitation project.
Go Hye Rim came back. Go Hye Rim came back.
Go Hye Rim came back.
Don't you think they'll
stop me at the entrance?
No Doctor, you look like
you're in your twenties.
Just cover your eyes with sunglasses.
- Fighting!- Fighting!
Go in. Yes, go on in.
Wait a minute.
How old are you?
I'm in my twenties.
Really?
I'm in my thirties.
Then let me see your ID.
Why are you like this to my girlfriend?
She's your girlfriend?
Let's go, Mi Ran.
Girlfriend?
She's not his mom? Mom?
Here you go, Doctor.
What about cups?
Here you just drink it out of the bottle.
What's wrong, Doctor?
Because a carbonated drink suddenly
went down my throat, it really stings.
If you come here, you dance right?
Teach me how to dance.
Yes, since you made up your mind to party all
night, you have to take good care of yourself.
You wench, now you're
receiving awards like this.
I was so proud earlier
that I was about to cry!
But, Ji Ho really didn't come?
I'm not sure.
What is that?
Follow me
It's Ji Ho. That's
definitely Ji Ho's doing.
What are you doing? Why are you
playing with a drone here?
Will you marry me?
The universe is such and such, mathematical formulas are
this and that... Now I don't need things like that.
I just like you, Noona.
Noona, will you marry me?
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
You guys already want to
get married at your age?
How long have you been dating? Just
a little over two weeks, right?
But, marriage? Does that make any sense?
I've liked Ji Ho since long before!
You know that.
But he didn't!
Why is the duration so important?
Love conquers all.
The very quality of how much I liked
you then and now are different.
If you were a pebble on a beach,
Noona Yoo Rim is like a great ocean.
If you were a small shooting star,
Noona Yoo Rim is like a huge universe.
Look, even the way he talks isn't normal!
How could you...
Why are you making a fuss when
we're the ones who are in love?
Why, are you scared that
we'll turn out like you?
Yes, you're right.
You saw me get married at twenty one and totally
get ruined. Yet you're still acting this way?
Just like you go to middle school at fourteen, and just like you go
to high school at seventeen, there's also a proper age for marriage!
Stop worrying! We won't turn out like you.
Right, Ji Ho? You won't betray me, right?
Of course I won't.
If you're going to act this
way, get out of my house.
Unni!
I don't need a little sister who doesn't
listen to me, so pack your bags and leave!
How much money do you have?
Why?
I have 60,000 won ($60) in cash and about 2,000,000
won ($2,000) in my bank account. What about you?
I also have around that much.
Alright, then we can hang
on for six months so...
Unni, I have chosen to
go live with Ji Ho now.
Come find us when you're
ready to bless our marriage.
These two...
The person you're trying to reach cannot pick up the
phone so please leave a message after the beep.
Fine, let's see how many days
you two can survive out there.
It's obvious you two will come crawling
back in a week completely broke.
Hello.
Oh, yes. Hello.
I came because I had an appointment here, but Soo
Hyun's consultation seems to be running late.
I've been waiting for a while.
I don't know if you know this, but
I am currently dating Soo Hyun.
Yes, I guessed so.
What's this? Why is she still being so
calm after I've told her we're dating?
Why did you come to see Soo Hyun?
There are also many psychologists in the States
to ask that favor, so why does it have to be...
While I'm at it, it's good
to ask someone I know.
And, I also missed Soo Hyun.
When you were dating Soo Hyun, wasn't
it you who wanted to break it off?
A person's heart is always bound to change.
I don't have any thoughts about
interfering in your relationship.
I won't try to force myself in it, either.
Then...
But, I will not back off, either.
I've already told you, that
I'm already dating Soo Hyun...
You know, don't you? That the power
of nostalgia is very strong.
Between Soo Hyun and I, there are many
memories that you don't know about.
I came back because I
missed those memories.
Also, I believe that Soo Hyun
would feel the same as well.
Has Claire left?
Yes, quite a while ago.
I heard you dated her in the past?
How did you know that?
Marie Antoinette told me.
Did you like her a lot?
No, not really.
It looks like you liked her a lot.
You liked her more than me?
Why? Are you jealous?
You know why I came back, right?
Even though I was tricked by your lies, I
came back because I worried about you.
You have a responsibility in
repaying me for my kindness.
And how should I do that?
Look at this for an hour.
Why these?
A person named John Brad
wrote a book called Hurt...
Something like that.
He stated that it was important for people with emotional
scars to start by experiencing childhood feelings.
First of all, it's not John
Brad, but John Bradshaw.
The Korean title is Treatment of the Hurt Inner
Child. In English, it's called The Inner Child.
Anyway, look at your childhood pictures and
try to experience those feelings again.
You can also write a letter to yourself now
in the point of view from your child self.
I'm a psychologist, I already know those
methods. That's why they don't work on me...
But you only know them, you've never
tried the methods before, have you?
I'll come back in an hour,
so do your homework by then.
- If you keep on dripping ice cream...
- Mom!
I won't come on your birthday.
Mom!
Soo Hyun.
I wish you came to find me.
I don't want to be alone here.
I can't see any shooting stars, they said
there would be a meteor shower today.
It's probably because
today's weather was cloudy.
Then, what do we do if it's like this when
we go to see the Aurora Borealis in Alaska?
The Aurora Borealis is...
Us?
We're going to see it together?
Of course.
Then were you thinking of going
somewhere nice like that alone?
Thank you.
It's nothing.
Then, should we make a schedule...
Make a schedule...
Yes.
But, Doctor.
Please get the surgery.
How did you know?
You can't go like this.
We don't know if something might happen
before we see the Aurora Borealis.
So, Doctor, get the surgery,
and after your body
recuperates, let's go together.
I'll take care of it.
Doctor, I'll take you home
on the scooter so hop on.
Did you look at your childhood pictures?
When did you come?
Did you write the letter?
You didn't, did you?
Hye Rim, please stop this.
I'm a psychologist.
I'll take care of myself
after knowing my state...
You said you met your mom.
How was it?
What are you going to do if you know?
I've also abandoned Do Gyung before.
After I fought with my husband,
because I was so angry,
I forgot about the fact that I had
a child, and just wandered around.
But I came back to see her crying
in front of the refrigerator.
Next to her were half eaten
pieces from a loaf of bread.
Come to think of it, I realized I
had starved her for the entire day.
I was that kind of a bad mother.
So, what do you want to say now?
But it wasn't because I
didn't love my child,
because even if you love
someone, mistakes can be made.
When your mother abandoned you...
Who is trying to teach whom here?
What you said
comes from the contents of
psychological counseling 101.
If you're a fortune teller, act like one.
Don't think of teaching a psychologist.
But you
just know this intellectually.
Right now, you need courage.
Instead of knowing it and sweeping it under the rug,
you should look into your problem, acknowledge it,
and you need the courage
to actively fix it.
Fine,
I have fear of abandonment
and lack of affection.
My mother abandoned me at a young
age and I developed a trauma.
To defend myself against that, I made
up a thesis that love doesn't exist.
Also, to prove that, I even
did this damn experiment!
Does that satisfy you?
You know well,
but if that experiment succeeds,
do you think you will be happy?
You might be happy for a moment
that you have proven that love doesn't exist, and you
will be able to rationalize your mother's abandonment.
But that's only rationalization.
It's nothing but a wall you created
so you wouldn't feel the pain.
So, you'll deteriorate even more. Why?
Because that's not how you truly think,
because deep in your heart, you're
waiting for someone to really love you.
Look here.
What does a fake fortune teller know?
I'm going to break down that wall.
And so you can truly acknowledge your pain,
and so you can truly be healed, I'm going
to shatter this experiment to pieces.
I'll prove to you that
true love does exist.
This...
What color do you think it is?
Purple?
No, it's plum-colored.
It symbolizes eternal love.
I love you, Soo Hyun.
I'm different from your mom.
I will never
leave your side.
♪ Everyday it's only you ♪
♪ To me, you're that kind of person ♪
♪ Really, without you I
think I'll go crazy ♪
Madame Antoine~Preview~
- Whether I treat him well or console him, he
gets angry.- What Choi Soo Hyun needs is...
Is the fortune teller from
downstairs counseling me?
How do you feel?
Just so-so.
There's only one answer. Just going for it.
I'm pregnant!
Are you in you're right mind?
Oh, Son.
Now you want to be treated as a father?
How dare you?
Do you know how not having anyone on
my side and being alone in this world
feels?
Are you really dating? You
hated fortune tellers.
Now, I think Soo Hyun will also leave me.
I thought there might be
an error in my hypothesis.
There is no true love for a woman.
Is that what you're saying?
The one who pulled me out
from my emotional scar
"So, I should change", the one who
also made me think that is...
If she loves you,
she will come back to you.