We were born in space.
They told us the ground was uninhabited.
But they were wrong,
and we've been fighting
for our lives since the moment we landed.
Some of us have been broken by it,
but most of us are still here,
searching for other survivors from the Ark,
trying to build something real and lasting
out of the wilderness... a home.
Our leaders believe that to survive,
we need to make peace with the Grounders,
but peace is a foreign concept here.
Clarke: I'm not going in.
Clarke...
Seeing their faces every day
is just gonna remind me of what I did
to get them here.
May we meet again.
We're going to the city of light.
Take this leap of faith
with me, John Murphy.
A.L.I.E.: Welcome, Thelonious.
I've been waiting for ages.
My name is A.L.I.E.
I tried to stop her. I'm so, so sorry.
[Gunshot]
[Door closes]
Voice: Containment door sealed.
Come on. Come on.
Come on!
Man: Chris, where are you, man?
Chris? Chris?
Chris!
Different man: I knew
it. The news was wrong.
It wasn't China.
The stupid son of a bitch let A.L.I.E. out.
Help me. The radiation's coming.
Unless we want to share
this place with a corpse,
we need to get him outside.
Come on. Ugh!
Arrgh!
I tried to stop her, but I lost control.
I'm so, so sorry.
[Gunshot]
2051. Becca, meet A.L.I.E.
Chris, I got to get back to work.
We are working.
A.L.I.E. wanted it to be a surprise.
Hello, Becca.
Who did this?
I did. You don't approve?
As you know, I didn't think
I needed an avatar.
You did.
Why not my creator?
[Echoing] Why not my creator?
Please state your core command.
My core command is to make life better...
[Echoing] To make life better...
To make life better.
Becca: How would you do that?
By fixing the root problem.
Waah!
[Echoing] By fixing the root problem.
By fixing the root problem.
Rebecca: What is the
root problem, A.L.I.E.?
Too many people.
Um, too many people?
Ah, well, you certainly took
care of that, didn't you?
Yaah!
86 days,
on my, um, last box of food, so...
really never thought I'd
miss the Ark this much,
but anyway, Jaha, if you're seeing this,
that would indeed mean you're not dead,
so screw you!
[Inhales]
Oh, come on.
I...
mm...
[Door opens]
Voice: Containment door released.
[Whoosh]
Wait! Get back here.
Uh!
[Panting]
Jaha: John.
There you are.
- Jaha.
- Welcome.
We have so much to talk about
and so little time.
I found it, John.
The city of light is real.
You let me live!
Ok.
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
WEB-DL resync by kinglouisxx
- www.addic7ed.com -
Uh!
Oh!
Ah! Uhh...
Ohh!
Yah! Hah!
Huh!
He had me, but he was too aggressive.
Whatever you say.
[Laughter]
Quitting so soon?
Mapping run, sector 7.
Harper, let's get this over with.
Council wants you to have that.
I'm trikru.
Uniform doesn't change that.
This is our home now, Lincoln.
We fought for it.
Too many of our friends died for it.
In the Ark, the uniform
meant something different.
Down here, it means what we make it mean
together.
My sister will understand that eventually.
Pair up and fight now.
Hey, sector 7, that puts you
right at the ice nation border.
Yeah. I know.
Just because Azgeda was part
of the commander's coalition, doesn't mean
they respect the cease-fire.
- I should be on that scout.
- I wish.
We all do, but until the commander agrees
to lift the kill order on you,
you're more trouble than you're worth.
[Door opens]
[Knocks on door]
This is the first sleep the
chancellor's had in two days.
I'll be quick, then.
We're going into sector 7.
I think we should arm the entire unit.
Permission granted, but the rules
of engagement still apply...
nonlethal response.
Copy that.
Bellamy, there hasn't been an attack
since Mount Weather.
It's 3 months.
Our people believe that this is real peace.
Try not to screw that up.
Yes, sir.
Abby: He's come a long way.
It's a work in progress.
I was dreaming we were in the Ark
before we sent the kids down.
[Exhales]
Maybe she's in sector 7.
We could send out another search party.
They wouldn't find her,
not unless she's ready to be found.
Sir. Ma'am.
I have patients to see.
Sir, we just got a signal
on a secure channel, 3 clicks.
3 clicks.
She wants to meet.
Monty, why aren't you ready?
I am. He's not.
What should we do?
We should leave him this time.
He's not getting better.
Maya's death broke him.
He needs this.
[Exhales]
Take an arm.
- Come on. Uh!
- Ohh!
Uhh...
Gina: Zeke, I said produce first.
Art doesn't go bad.
Monty, he's all yours.
Hey, easy run?
I hate that place.
I know.
Got you something, though.
You said your mom used to read this to you.
Thought you'd like it.
I do. Thanks.
[Slam]
Raven: Hey! Take it easy.
Good morning to you, too.
Ah! Uh...
What's the point if we can't shoot them?
We can, just not to kill.
That goes for everyone.
Where's Octavia?
We're going outside the wall.
You honestly think she'd miss that?
Ah!
Sorry. Was that too cold?
Aah!
No gun for you, not till you're sober.
Don't want one.
Let's do this.
Mm!
Uh... Mm.
Be safe.
- She's too good for you.
- Shut up.
Jasper: Careful. Monty might melt her.
Enough!
Raven, take us out.
[Engine starts]
Guess we found her.
Try to keep up.
Hah.
Gordon Gano: ♪ Day ♪
♪ After day ♪
♪ I will walk ♪
♪ And I will play ♪
♪ But the day ♪
♪ After today ♪
No way.
If you're gonna ride shotgun,
you can't just disappear.
Gano: ♪ I will stop ♪
Hey, it's ok. It's a long ride.
Gano: ♪ and I will start ♪
[Violent Femmes' "Add It Up" playing]
♪ Why can't I get just one kiss? ♪
♪ May be some things I wouldn't miss ♪
♪ But I look at your
pants, and I need a kiss ♪
♪ Why can't I get just one screw? ♪
♪ Believe me, I know what to do ♪
♪ But something won't
let me make love to you ♪
♪ Day after day ♪
♪ I get angry, and I will say ♪
♪ That the day is in my sight ♪
♪ When I take a bow to say good night ♪
♪ Don't shoot, shoot,
shoot that thing at me ♪
♪ You know you got my sympathy ♪
♪ But don't shoot, shoot,
shoot that thing at me ♪
Aah!
Whoo!
[Beeping]
[Music stops]
Tracking beacon from the Ark.
Hey, that was the best part.
Who is it?
Farm station.
What? After... after 4 months? How?
We'll find out. Where are they?
[Door opens]
Don't tell me I missed the party.
Sector 8.
That's ice nation.
What about it?
Protocol says we go home,
let the chancellor decide what to do next.
Screw protocol.
The chancellor's not from farm station.
Monty is. So is Miller's boyfriend.
It's your call.
Let's do this.
You have to ask?
Try to keep up.
Yah!
[Geese honking]
[Classical music playing]
[Glass clacks on table]
[Exhales]
Jaha.
[Whistles] Hey, wake up.
A.L.I.E.: Thelonious isn't here, John.
He's in the city of light.
I know what you are.
It's refreshing to be around people
who understand technology again.
Let us explain.
That's a good idea.
Why don't you start with why you kept me
locked in a bunker while you were here
living like a king?
The outside world means nothing.
In the city of light, we're all kings.
Here I thought I was
the one losing my mind.
A.L.I.E.: It's the truth. I can show you.
Ok. You do know she's the one who launched
the bombs that ended the world, right?
Wrong.
She didn't end the world.
She saved it.
I'm so out of here.
Let him go. He'll come around.
These woods must be the border.
So where's all the ice?
Much further north.
Azgeda stretches for a thousand miles.
Good thing we only have to go 200 meters.
Slow down.
Remember, rules of engagement
are nonlethal force.
Tight formation on my command.
- Raven, you stay in the rover.
- Yeah, right.
We need every gun we've got.
Monty: They're coming.
120 meters... 110.
They're our people. What are you doing?
We hope they're our people.
On my command.
[Horse neighs]
[Man shouting orders]
Ice nation?
Yes. White war paint.
Whoa!
Stay calm.
_
Skaikru.
They think we're looking for wanheda.
- Who's that?
- I don't know.
Monty: The light. That's the beacon.
[Beeping]
Hey, get back here.
Monty: Jasper, what are you...
what are you doing?
- Jasper...
- It's ok. I got this.
Tell them we observe the commander's truce.
Do it now.
[Octavia speaks trigedasleng]
This belongs to us.
_
Hold your fire!
Jasper, get down. Hah!
Kane, on radio: Rover one, come in.
Repeat, rover one, come in now.
- What now?
- Bellamy, where are you?
I had him.
What the hell were you thinking?
We got the beacon, didn't we? Uh!
Yeah, but where did they get it?
Oh, he needs to get to medical.
Bellamy: We had to shoot
3 ice nation scouts.
Covert, sector 4. Copy.
Can you tell me what's going on?
Kane: When you get here. Over and out.
Raven: Sector 4? Why is
Kane so far outside the wall?
Bellamy: Take him home!
I'm fine. Thank you for asking.
- Miller...
- Yeah?
Get one of their horses.
Raven, since you can't ride,
you're on the back.
Monty, you're with me.
- Let's go.
- Ok.
You were right about Jasper, ok?
Is that what you want me to say?
Quiet. Keep your eyes peeled.
I could've said no.
He's getting worse, isn't he?
I mean, getting drunk every night
is one thing, but smiling
with a knife to your throat,
that's next-level damaged.
Who's he with?
- Indra.
- That's Indra?
He must've told her we broke the truce.
Sir, before you say anything,
there was a good reason...
We'll deal with that later.
This is about Clarke.
- What about her?
- She's being hunted.
- By who?
- By everyone.
[Growling]
Aah!
[Roars]
Uh! Ah!
[Roaring]
Uh! Uh!
[Panting]
Ow...
_
Man: Open the gate!
Octavia: Jasper's hurt.
What took you so long?
Oh, what happened?
Ice nation.
Nngh!
Get him to medical.
I got you. Keep pressure on it.
Clarke?
_
You want me to take them?
It's ok. I'll... I'll bring her in.
You can't get down, can you?
Ok. Come here.
Ah ah!
Ok.
Uh... Ah. Uh!
Thanks.
- Raven...
- I'm good.
[Panting]
[Tires screech]
[Slam]
I'm still getting used to it myself.
Monty: Sir, we're almost out of range.
Are you sure you don't
want to tell the chancellor?
I'm sure. I don't want to worry
Abby until we know something.
We know there's a kill order.
You people are big on those.
Indra: It's not a kill
order. It's a bounty.
Clarke's a symbol.
She's known as wanheda...
the commander of death.
The ice nation guys we killed
asked about wanheda.
They're looking for Clarke. Why?
My people believe that
when you kill someone,
you get their power.
Kill wanheda, and you command death.
She's just one girl.
So was the commander.
What Clarke did at Mount
Weather weakened her.
The ice nation is emboldened.
Their queen wants Clarke's power.
If her people believe she has it,
she'll break the coalition and start a war.
I can't let that happen.
[Beep]
Welcome to sector 7. Where to now?
If she's here, she'll need supplies.
We'll start at the trading posts.
_
I would wait,
give them the chance to clear out.
Have that drink.
Why are you helping me?
My mother was taken by the mountain.
You ended the reaping.
You wanted to see me?
Yes. I'm considering making
another run to Mount Weather
for medical supplies.
You want my advice?
That's why you're here.
The last one just got back.
If it looks like skaikru
is colonizing the mountain,
the truce will break, and we'll be at war.
Jasper, wait.
Whoa!
He hasn't been discharged.
- I'm fine.
- He's not fine.
Shut up, Raven.
Ok, ok. Enough.
If you promise to come back in the morning,
I will examine you then, ok?
You're just gonna let him go?
That'll be all, Lincoln. Thank you.
I'll be in there in a minute.
Abby, we have 12 patients waiting,
including 4 contraceptive implant removals.
You'll be right in.
Abby, he had a knife to his throat,
and he smiled.
I want to talk about you, Raven.
How's your hip?
You don't have a broken compressor, do you?
When did the pain start?
After the explosion at the dam.
3 months.
It's nothing I can't handle.
You're not handling it.
You're lying to your friends.
You're lying to your doctor.
You pushed Wick away because
he was trying to help.
- Don't.
- Raven, you don't...
Fix yourself, Abby.
Maybe if you weren't
so busy being chancellor
and doctor to avoid your own pain,
you'd realize you suck at both jobs.
Good talk.
[Water trickling]
The cat got the worst of it.
[Chuckles]
No kill marks.
My back's not big enough.
Tell me about the mountain.
There's nothing to tell.
I did what I had to do. That's all.
That's all? You killed our greatest enemy.
You wiped them out by yourself.
Niylah, would you mind not talking?
No.
Mm...
_
Hey.
There can't be an us or
them if we want to survive.
You're being naive.
Those people aren't like you, Lincoln.
Kane and Abby aren't like most people.
They're trying to forge a
lasting peace, and so am I.
They're using you.
"Look at that nice
Grounder in his uniform."
They think it proves we can live together.
It does.
What if I don't want to live together?
And don't tell me about the kill order.
We can go far away.
Luna's clan will take us in.
No. They won't.
Luna's hiding for a reason.
She won't risk the attention.
Hey, hey...
_
Hey...
And nothing can take that away from us.
That uniform does.
[Sniffles]
[Ship's horn blasts]
You're leaving, huh?
So are you.
Not with you, I'm not.
I'll be right there, Gideon.
Murphy: I see you've made a new friend.
I'm sorry we kept you in the bunker, John.
Is that what you want to hear?
Well, the truth is, I knew you were safe,
and with all the things that we had to do,
I needed the time.
Yeah. I could tell you
were pretty busy back there.
We converted a nuclear warhead
into a power source.
With the added power, A.L.I.E. was able
to complete the work she began
with her creator a hundred years ago.
Whatever. Look. I'm still
leaving this place in a rowboat.
I need you.
Of course you do,
more food for the sea monster, right?
Let me prove to you what we can do.
Listen to me. I've seen what she can do.
No. You haven't,
not even close, son.
Now, how is it possible you
sound even crazier than before?
I can tell you about the city of light,
but you won't understand
until you experience it yourself.
And that's supposed to take
me to the city of light?
No pain, no hate, no envy.
No, thanks.
- John...
- No.
Pain, hate, envy...
those are the abc's of me.
Hey, get rid of them,
and there's nothing left,
so why don't you get
that thing out of my face?
Take care of yourself, John,
and decide later.
[Ship's horn blasts]
John?
I don't believe it.
Emori?
What are you waiting for? Come on.
- Change your mind?
- Bite me.
Emori, who'd you steal the boat from?
A.L.I.E.: Told you he'd come around.
Not so fast.
I say we float him.
Come on. What do you guys want for it?
One song.
Done.
♪ Day ♪
♪ After day ♪
♪ I will walk ♪
♪ And I will say ♪
♪ But the day ♪
♪ After today ♪
You were right.
I am spread too thin.
I'm still not having that operation.
Raven, that's...
Are you here as my chancellor or my doctor?
Because I don't want to talk to one of you.
I'm here as your friend.
♪ I've given you a decision to make ♪
♪ Things to lose and things to take ♪
Good.
Shut up and drink.
♪ Just as she's about
ready to cut it up ♪
♪ She says, "wait a minute, honey ♪
♪ I'm gonna add it up ♪
♪ Add it up ♪
♪ Wait a minute, honey,
I'm gonna add it up" ♪
♪ Day ♪
♪ After day ♪
♪ I get angry ♪
♪ And I will say ♪
♪ That the day ♪
[Gasps]
♪ Is in my sight ♪
♪ When I'll take a bow ♪
♪ And say good night ♪
♪ Oh, mama, mama, mama, oh, mama ♪
♪ Take a look now at
what your boy has done ♪
♪ He's walking around
like he's number one ♪
♪ Went downtown, and
you got him a gun ♪
♪ And you said, "don't you
shoot that thing at me ♪
♪ Don't you shoot that thing at me ♪
♪ You know that you've got my sympathy ♪
♪ But don't you shoot
that thing at me" ♪
♪ Day ♪
♪ After day ♪
Hey, hey, relax.
♪ I get angry ♪
These belong to people.
- So did that piano.
- Jasper. Jasper!
Grave robbers!
Get off of him!
Hey.
- Ok. Stop. Stop.
- Take it easy.
Enough!
We have to move it.
Wait. It's been cut down.
Bellamy: You don't know that.
[Creaking]
We do now.
[Gasps]
Hello, Wanheda.
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
WEB-DL resync by kinglouisxx
- www.addic7ed.com -