Can I have your last hug?
I used to think that
I need to bear it being with you in the palace.
But now,
I can't stand it anymore.
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, Nanadc1
>> facebook.com/ingfakirataJJ
What's the reason of the Forest Palace's renovation?
I always thought that you like it.
I'm concerned that it is quite old, not modern enough.
I would like to change it, Your Majesty.
But I disagree.
Do you have any valuable memories in it, Your Majesty?
That palace has the memories of every Crown Prince including you as well.
No.
It should only be you.
But please don’t worry. I'll try to preserve its condition as much as possible.
I'll change only the parts that need changes.
And do you know who was the guy the Princess went out with?
The Princess went out with his father, Your Majesty.
Do you believe that?
I trust my wife more than the thief who stole the car, Your Majesty.
Nevertheless, this palace belongs to the Crown Prince.
It is my right to do whatever I want.
I just come to inform you.
Excuse me, Your Majesty.
Why does he want to break that palace down?
The Prince used to ask me about
the history of that palace, Your Majesty.
I can never understand what is in his mind.
Why does the Prince suddenly want to renovate that palace?
I don’t know as well.
Suddenly, the order is announced.
Letting him use that palace frequently is already too much.
Definitely, I will not let him do whatever he wants.
Prince Inn.
How dare you order to destroy the Forest Palace!
Don’t you know how much His Majesty loves that place?
Strange!
There are only two persons who disagree
His Majesty
and The Royal Consort.
It seems this palace is not that simple palace after all.
People know well
that the Forest Palace is the palace for every Crown Prince.
As well as it is an important place for the country's history.
Some parts of history don't deserve to be memorialized.
Just by thinking of the hidden story of that palace,
I feel nauseated.
That I almost want to vomit it out.
What are you talking about?!!
Do you think others don’t know?
That the Crown Princess flirted with the second Crown Prince until he's crazy for her,
and he almost had an affair with his own brother’s wife?
I wonder why the late Crown Prince passed away by car accident.
Probably because he found out such disgusting affair,
until he didn't want to live anymore.
You don't know anything!
How dare you speak to me like this?
This matter is easy to figure out.
No matter what,
I will abolish such disgusting place from Bhutin land.
Excuse me.
Cocky kid.
You'll never know that you are burning yourself.
I have to thank the Royal Consort for covering Nakhun's matter.
You are blamed like this, it might be giving you a hard time.
I'm alright, Your Highness.
I'm glad that you two become good friends.
Nakhun had to stay alone outside the palace all this time.
It's only me who was beside him.
When I was out of the palace, I sometimes spared him the time.
But life inside the palace is different.
How is it different?
In the palace,
there are many regulations.
As well as complying with traditions and culture.
We are in front of people's eyes all the time.
Private life?
Forget it?
When I was the Crown Princess,
I was so stressed,
til sometimes, I wanted to run away from here.
But you couldn't do it, right?
I'm not a brave person.
All I could do was being patient for my kid.
When I was out of the palace,
I felt a bit glad.
Think about it.
Life with freedom is so sweet.
To follow your dream.
To forget about the regulations.
To love the one I want to love.
Actually I'm a bit lucky.
The former Crown Prince loved me so much.
But if I had to be you,
to live
with someone who doesn't love me at all,
I couldn't bear to stay here for sure.
I probably had divorce a long time ago.
Don’t you know you are so strong?
I admire you for it.
Your Highness.
You are here.
I have to thank again, Your Highness.
So, I'm leaving.
See you Nakhun.
What did you talk about, Mom?
I'm helping you now.
Have you ever had any dream?
If you are thinking about this matter.
I suggest you to give up.
Tell me what is in your mind?!
"This will be the last chance.  If you tell them what you truly feel.
People will feel you and have pity on you."  *Nakhun
Inn.
Have you ever had any dream?
Yes, I have.
But it's no meaning.
If you are thinking about this matter.
I suggest you to stop.
Why?
Whenever we have to stay together.
whatever you dream about,
It's impossible.
You should admit
that our marriage this time
is changing our lives forever.
Nope.
No need.
We don’t have to stay together.
We got married and we can get divorce either.
I know,
you think about this all the time.
I know
you don’t want to stay here.
But when I said that our marriage could change our lives forever,
it's either to stay together
or divorce.
If you are still thinking about the divorce,
I can make it happen.
Your Highness!
Everything is ready.
Please believe me once.
We are going to get an interview.
I don’t know what you are thinking about
but...
I beg you,
don’t speak about the divorce at all.
Here comes an important question
which people of Bhutin would like to know that
about the heir, what is your plan about this, Your Highness?
Probably we have to wait until our graduations.
Those people are all waiting to see little prince and princess,Your Highness.
And the last question,
I would like to know about your life after marriage.
How is it going, Your Highness?
I...
love my princess with all my heart.
Although both of you have just met each other not so long, Your Highness?
At our first meeting, I didn't believe in myself.
It's the feeling which seems impossible.
But it has already happened.
So romantic, Your Highness.
How about you, your highness?
Divorce...
You are saying “Divorce”, aren't you?
No, I'm not.
I didn't mean that.
As we know from the very start,
the Princess was just a normal student
who suddenly needs to spend her life in the palace.
At the beginning,
she felt really confused for a period of time.
But why does this come to the point of divorce?
Okay.
Actually we sometimes both used to talk about the divorce but...
She is strong enough
struggling with patience.
She knows that dreams and freedom
only exist outside the palace.
I want you all to continue cheering her on
to overcome this situation same as what I'm doing right now.
Thank you.
How did you let this clip release out?!
I apologize, Your Majesty.
And what is in Princess’ mind? She dared speak about that divorce!
Is she planning to overthrow the dynasty?
Please calm down, father.
It seemed the Princess had no bad intention.
She might be excited and it's just a slip of the tongue.
Such an important matter to be slipped out?
So what really happened?
His Majesty wants your attendance now, Your Highness.
Tell me what are you thinking?!
I have done wrong, Your Majesty.
Does this matter relate to the man who stayed with you that night?
And can you tell me now who was that guy?
I absolutely can't tell you, Your Majesty.
You are such...
You know well, right? If the truth is you have an affair,
your penalty is to be discharged from the position and be deported from the palace.
I don't have any affair, Your Majesty.
Alright!
No matter what, I will know the truth anyway.
And when the time comes,
don’t blame me for being heartless.
What's wrong with this two?
They got married for a long time but they always have problems.
How can I support him to be the King?
After this issue,
I believe Inn will adjust himself.
By the way,
Inn doesn't have any qualification of being Crown Prince at all.
Nakhun is better.
Will you support Prince Nakhun to be the Crown Prince?
Seriously speaking, Rachawadee.
Prince Nakhun is more suitable to be the next King than Inn.
Is it because your heart is still related to the Royal Consort, isn't it?
What are you talking about, Rachawadee?
Do you really think I don’t know?
I will never accept this.
If someone contends the Crown Prince position from my son,
I swear to protect it at my best!
I have something to talk to you.
What kind of relationship do you have with Nakhun?.
Prince Nakhun and I are just friends, Your Majesty.
You think carefully before you answer me!
This matter is very important to the dynasty.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Prince Nakhun and I are really just friends.
You think only that, don't you?
Yes.
I can confirm, Your Majesty.
How about Prince Nakhun?
Does he think the same as you?
Khun Ratree!
From now on, don’t let Prince Nakhun meet the Princess at all.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Well done, Nakhun.
If you have anything new, you propose to me again.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
the Great Britain has already acknowledged the cooperation of the travel and movies production.
Prince Harry himself will come for the treaty signing.
The Government would like to invite Your Majesty to be the President in this treaty-signing ceremony.
May I propose, Your Majesty?
It'll be good to allow the Crown Prince to accompany you, Your Majesty.
I made my decision.
Nakhun will go with me.
But this is the big event.
It'd better for the Crown Prince to accompany you, Your Majesty.
I have my own reason.
Firstly, this treaty has been made possible by Prince Nakhun.
Secondly,
the Crown Prince has some things to deal with.
You have to find out who's that guy the Princess stayed with that night.
If you are unable to take care of your own wife,
you can't do anything else.
Get yourself ready for this, Nakhun.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Why didn't you speak out?
I'm the Crown Prince.
I will not abash myself to speak such matter.
Abash?
If you take good care of your wife’s heart better than this,
She won't be hurt like this.
you are the one who must take care of your heart anyway.
Restrain your mind.
It's a qualification of being a Prince, isn't it?
For a Prince who never cares about his wife's heart, he is not a Prince as well.
Princes Nakhun.
Think carefully before doing it.
Don't think on fighting over for the Crown Prince position at all!
And I’m warning on you.
Stop doing things that will discredit the dynasty by doing unsuitable matter to the Princess.
I never think about fighting over the Crown Prince position.
But about the Princess,
I can't restrain myself, Your Majesty.
Prince Nakhun.
Do you know what are you saying?
I apologize.
Excuse me, Your Majesty.
I don't want it.
It's your desire.
Not mine!
Your Highness.
What's matter?
I saw your face and I'm worried about you.
Are you worried that His Majesty let Prince Nakhun go to the event instead of you?
I think that
if you show your real intention,
I believe that his majesty will see it soon.
No matter how good I am,
he probably won't see me better than Nakhun.
Don't think like that Your Highness.
You have been following His Majesty for a long time,
it's impossible for you to not know this.
Your Highness.
This story is a long time ago.
But seeing from the last picture,
I am sure that
time can't delete this story from him.
But it's just a picture.
I can't remember the last time His Majesty took a picture of mom
or maybe he never did.
So
II'm not surprised
why he loves Nakhun more.
Your Highness.
Therefore, don't stop me
from destroying that dishonorable palace.
Welcome, Your Highness.
The Royal Consort summoned me, what do you want me to do?
According to the ancient tradition, there is one custom
that is called a Royal Pardon.
The one who misbehaves to the Royal Family
is going to get down on their knees in front of the King
asking for the Royal Pardon
until the King forgives.
Until the King forgives?
Yes, Your Highness.
And is there anyone who did it successfully?
This way is may be a bit hard.
It's up on how much determination you have.
The progress of the project is going well.
- The staff think that it will be finished this week.
- Your Highness!
You can't enter.
Get out of my way.
Your Highness.
I ask to kneel down in front of the King to ask for a Royal Pardon.
The Royal Consort,
go back to your palace immediately.
I will go back if Your Majesty will pardon me.
Do you think from what you did, I'll forgive you?!
What you have done is too much.
About the interview and that night. You were with who? You didn't answer me.
Moreover, you used your father as an excuse.
A crazy excuse like that, you think that Bhutin's people will believe?!
Your Majesty, please calm down.
How did you know the Royal Pardon custom?
Who told you?
The latest person who knelt down here took 3 days.
No matters how long, I will do it.
For your mistakes,
two hundred days are not even enough!
Your Majesty.
Prince Inn.
tell the Royal Consort to stop doing this.
Why is she causing troubles non-stop?
Grandma.
Nakhun, let Khaning stay with Prince Inn.
Mom,
it's you who told Khaning to do this, isn't it?
I just gave her an advice,
she decided everything by herself.
But the Royal Pardon custom is very tough.
She can't endure it.
Don't underestimate the Royal Consort.
Pardon me, Your Majesty.
What's the matter?
I feel so worried about the Royal Consort.
Can I make a little set of food for the Royal Consort?
Ratree.
Only a few people know about this custom
but if one dares to use it,
no one can interfere unless His Majesty forgives.
The dinner this evening looks delicious, Mother.
I can't eat.
No one can pressure me about this!
Everyone knows how this custom works!
How wrong the Royal Consort is, everyone knows even more!
That night, who she went out with...
if she doesn't tell the truth,
don't hope that I'll forgive her!
That night,
the one who was with the Royal Consort is me.
Nakhun!
What did you say?
Nakhun.
Nakhun, you probably didn't...
That night, the Royal Consort was very upset.
I just followed her to comfort her as a friend.
Nakhun, answer me now.
Do you have any inappropriate thoughts towards the Royal Consort?
No, Your Majesty.  No of course!
Right, Nakhun?
No, right?!
I love the Royal Consort with all my heart.
- Queen Mother.
- Mother.
What the heck did you do?
You know both Khaning and you will be in big trouble.
It's better than to let Khaning get in trouble now
but it will get more complicated.
I don't care what you think
but I will tell Khaning that everything is over!
Khaning,
Khaning.
Stand up.
It's over.
I told everybody the truth.
What truth?
I told them that I was with with you that night.
What the hell did you do?
I can't endure seeing you hurt because of me.
Nakhun,
you misunderstood.
I didn't do it for you.
I did ask His Majesty to forgive me.
Because I don't want Prince Inn to misunderstand.
I...
never think of you more than a friend.
Nakhun, follow me now!
I said now!
What were you thinking?
Answer me!
What were you thinking
or you weren't thinking that's why you said that?
It's over,
the throne that you want is gone
because of your infatuation.
I never want the throne
and I am not infatuated with her.
I love her.
Nakhun...
be conscious.
Think carefully if it's worth it or not?
If you are the Crown Prince,
you will have whatever you want.
Better than her,
more talented than her,
more suitable than her.
You can have any woman in this world.
But I don't want anyone else.
I just want the one I love.
Oh.. Nakhun.
And what will you use love for?
What can love do for you?
What I'm getting for you
is the throne!
I don't want it.
It's your desire.
Not mine!
It's a desire of others' properties.
It's selfishness.
And what about you wanting the Royal Consort, doesn't she belong to other?!!
I found her first.
I found her before Prince Inn.
My love happened before all these.
I will not abandon it.
Oh... Nakhun.
Nakhun. Don't you hear what she said?
She doesn't love you, Nakhun! She doesn't love you!!
I heard
and I understand
but I will not be like what you are.
What?!
I won't abandon my love.
If Khaning doesn't love me,
I will try to understand and leave here.
But I won't let your obsession hurt anyone anymore.
Nakhun... Nakhun!!
Come back!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Come back!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Come back now!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Khaning!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Khaning!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Khaning!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Be patient!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
The Principal Secretary,
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
where is His Majesty?
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
He went to the Forest Palace, Your Majesty.
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
If you don't know how to feed your child,
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
then you can let me do it instead.
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Then don't give them a time.
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
Do it immediately!
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
From the behavior of the Royal Consort, there is only a way left,
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ
which is a permanent deportation.
English Subtitle by ingfakirata, P'Ann, Eveyy_jj, Clishe, nanadc1
>>  facebook.com/ingfakarataJJ