Echo Three to Echo Seven.
Han, old buddy,
do you read me?
Loud and clear, kid.
What's up?
I finished
my circle.
I don't pick up
any life readings.
There isn't enough life
on this ice cube...
to fill a space cruiser.
Sensors are placed.
I'm going back.
Right.
I'll see you shortly.
There's a meteorite
that hit the ground near here.
I want to check it out.
It won't take long.
Steady, girl.
What's the matter?
You smell something?
Rrraaah!
Chewie!
Chewie?
All right!
Don't lose your temper.
I'll come right back
and give you a hand.
Solo?
No sign of life
out there, General.
The sensors are in place.
You'll know if anything
comes around.
Commander Skywalker
reported in yet?
No. He's checking out
a meteorite that hit near him.
With all the meteor activity
in this system...
it's going to be difficult
to spot approaching ships.
General, I got to leave.
I can't stay anymore.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Well, there's
a price on my head.
If I don't pay off
Jabba the Hutt...
I'm a dead man.
A death mark's
not an easy thing to live with.
You're a good fighter, Solo.
I hate to lose you.
Thank you, General.
Well, Your Highness,
guess this is it.
That's right.
Well, don't get
all mushy on me.
So long, Princess.
Han!
Yes, Your Highnessness?
I thought you had
decided to stay.
Well, the bounty hunter
we ran into in Ord Mantell...
changed my mind.
Han, we need you!
We need?
Yes.
Well, what about
you need?
I need?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You probably don't.
And what precisely
am I supposed to know?
Come on!
You want me to stay
because of the way you feel about me.
Yes! You're
a great help to us.
You're a natural leader.
No! That's not it.
Come on.
A-ha!
You're imagining things.
Am I? Then why are
you following me?
Afraid I was gonna leave
without giving you a good-bye kiss?
I'd just as soon
kiss a Wookiee!
I can arrange that.
You could use
a good kiss!
I didn't ask you to turn on
the thermal heater.
I merely commented that it was freezing
in the princess's chamber.
How will we
dry out her clothes?
Oh, switch off!
Why did you
take this apart now?
I'm trying to get us out of here,
and you pull both...
Excuse me, sir.
Put them
back together now!
Might I have a word
with you, please?
What do you want?
Well, it's Princess Leia, sir.
She's been trying to get you
on the communicator.
I turned it off.
I don't want
to talk to her.
Well, Princess Leia is wondering
about Master Luke.
He hasn't
come back yet.
She doesn't know
where he is.
I don't know
Nobody knows
where he is.
What do you mean,
nobody knows?
- Well, uh, you see...
- Deck Officer!
- Excuse me, sir, might I...
Yes, sir?
Do you know where
Commander Skywalker is?
I haven't seen him.
It's possible he came through
the south entrance.
It's possible?
Why don't you
go find out?
It's getting
dark out there.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
Might I inquire what's going on?
Why not?
Impossible man.
Come along, R2,
let's find Princess Leia.
Between ourselves...
I think Master Luke is
in considerable danger.
Sir, Commander Skywalker
hasn't come in the south entrance.
He might have
forgotten to check in.
Not likely.
Are the speeders ready?
Uh, not yet. We're having trouble
adapting them to the cold.
We'll have to go out
on tauntauns.
Sir, the temperature's
dropping too rapidly.
That's right,
and my friend's out in it.
Your tauntaun will freeze
before you reach the first marker.
Then I'll see you
in hell. Hyah!
Rrraaah!
Grrrr!
Graaah!
You must
come along now, R2.
There's really
nothing more we can do.
And my joints
are freezing up.
Don't say things
like that!
Of course we'll see
Master Luke again.
And he'll be quite
all right.
You'll see.
Stupid little short circuit.
He'll be quite all right.
Sir, all the patrols
are in.
Still no...
Still no contact
from Skywalker or Solo.
Mistress Leia, R2 says he's been
quite unable to pick up any signals...
although he does admit
that his own range is far too weak...
to abandon all hope.
Your Highness, there's nothing more
we can do tonight.
The shield doors
must be closed.
Close the doors.
Yes, sir.
R2 says the chances
of survival are 725 to 1.
Gahhh!
Actually, R2 has been known
to make mistakes...
from time to time.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
Don't worry
about Master Luke.
I'm sure
he'll be all right.
He's quite clever, you know,
for a human being.
Luke.
Ben?
You will go to
the Dagobah system.
Dagobah system?
There you will
learn from Yoda...
the Jedi master
who instructed me.
Ben!
Luke!
Don't do this, Luke.
Come on,
give me a sign here.
Not much time.
Ben.
Hang on, kid.
Dagobah system.
Whew!
This may smell bad, kid...
Yoda.
But it'll keep you warm...
till I get the shelter up.
Ben... Dagobah...
Ahhh!
Ah! I thought they
smelled bad on the outside!
Echo Base, I've got something.
Not much, but it could be a life-form.
Commander Skywalker,
do you copy?
This is Rogue Two.
Captain Solo,
do you copy?
Commander Skywalker,
This is Rogue Two.
Good morning.
Nice of you guys
to drop by.
Echo Base, this is Rogue Two.
I've found them.
Repeat, I've found them.
Master Luke, sir, it's so good
to see you fully functional again.
Thanks, 3PO.
R2 expresses
his relief also.
How ya feelin', kid?
You don't look so bad to me.
You look strong enough...
to pull the ears
off a gundark.
Thanks to you.
That's two
you owe me, junior.
Well, Your Worship...
looks like you managed to keep me
around for a little while longer.
I had nothing
to do with it.
General Rieekan
thinks it's dangerous...
for any ships
to leave the system...
until we've activated
the energy field.
That's a good story.
I think you just can't bear...
to let a gorgeous guy like me
out of your sight.
I don't know where you get
your delusions, laser brain.
Hah hah hah!
Laugh it up, fuzzball...
but you didn't see us alone
in the south passage.
She expressed her
true feelings for me.
My...
Why, you stuck-up,
half-witted...
scruffy-looking
nerf herder!
Who's scruffy-looking?
I must have hit
pretty close to the mark...
to get her all riled up
like that, huh, kid?
Well, I guess you don't know
everything about women yet.
Headquarters personnel,
report to command center.
Take it easy.
Excuse us,
please.
Princess,
we have a visitor.
Picked up something outside
the base's Zone 12 moving east.
It's metal.
Then it couldn't be
one of those creatures.
Could be a speeder,
one of ours.
No.
Wait.
There's something
very weak coming through.
Sir, I'm fluent in six million
forms of communication.
This signal is not used
by the Alliance.
It could be
an imperial code.
It isn't friendly,
whatever it is.
Come on, Chewie,
let's check it out.
Send Rogues 10 and 11
to Station 38.
Grrr!
Gahhh!
I'm afraid
there's not much left.
What was it?
Droid of some kind.
I didn't hit it that hard.
Must've had a self-destruct.
An imperial probe droid.
It's a good bet the Empire
knows we're here.
We'd better start
the evacuation.
Admiral.
Yes, Captain?
I think we've got
something, sir.
The report
is only a fragment...
from a probe droid
in the Hoth system...
but it's the best lead we've had.
We have thousands of probe droids
searching the galaxy.
I want proof,
not leads.
The visuals indicate
life readings.
It could mean anything.
If we followed up
every lead...
But, sir...
the Hoth system is supposed to be
devoid of humans.
You've found something?
Yes, my lord.
That's it.
The rebels are there.
My lord, there are so many
uncharted settlements.
It could be smugglers...
That is the system.
And I'm sure Skywalker
is with them.
Set your course
for the Hoth system.
General Veers,
prepare your men.
Admiral.
Groups 7 and 10 will stay behind
to fly the speeders.
As soon as each transport is loaded...
evacuation control will give clearance
for immediate launch.
Right, sir.
All right!
That's it.
Try it.
Oh! Turn it off!
Turn it off!
Sir, it will take quite a while
to evacuate the T-47 s.
Forget
the heavy equipment.
There's plenty of time...
to get the smaller modules
on the transports.
Take care, sir.
Thanks.
Chewie, take care
of yourself, O. K?
O.K., O. K!
Hi, kid.
There's got to be
a reason for it.
Check it
at the other end.
Wait a second.
You all right?
Yeah.
Be careful.
You, too.
General, there's a fleet
of Stardestroyers...
coming out of hyperspace
in Sector Four.
Reroute all power
to the energy shield.
We gotta hold them till
all transports are away.
Prepare for ground assault.
What is it, General?
My lord, the fleet has moved out
of light speed.
ComScan has detected
an energy field...
protecting an area of the sixth planet
of the Hoth system.
The field is strong enough
to deflect any bombardment.
The rebels are alerted
to our presence.
Admiral Ozzel came out of light speed
too close to the system.
He... He felt surprise
was wiser.
He is as clumsy
as he is stupid.
General, prepare your troops
for a surface attack.
Yes, my lord.
Lord Vader.
The fleet has moved out of light speed,
and we're preparing to...
Aaugh!
You have failed me
for the last time, Admiral.
Captain Piett.
Yes, my lord?
Make ready to land our troops
beyond their energy field...
and deploy the fleet so that
nothing gets off the system.
You are in command now,
Admiral Piett.
Thank you,
Lord Vader.
All troop carriers will assemble
at the north entrance.
The heavy transport ships will leave
as soon as they're loaded.
Only two fighter escorts
per ship.
The energy shield can only be opened
for a short time...
so you'll have to stay very close
to your transports.
Two fighters against
a Stardestroyer?
The ion cannon
will fire several shots...
to make sure that any enemy ships
will be out of your flight path.
To make sure that any enemy ships
When you've gotten past
the energy shield...
proceed directly
to the rendezvous point.
Understood?
Good luck.
O.K. Everybody
to your stations.
Let's go.
Their primary target will be
the power generators.
Prepare to open shield.
Sir, rebel ships are
coming into our sector.
Good. Our first catch
of the day.
Stand by, ion control.
Fire.
The first transport is away.
Feeling all right, sir?
Just like new, Dak.
How about you?
Right now I feel I could take on
the whole Empire myself.
I know what you mean.
Echo Station
Three-T-Eight.
We've spotted
imperial walkers.
Imperial walkers
on the north ridge.
Echo Station Five-Seven.
We're on our way.
All right, boys,
keep tight now.
Luke, I have no approach vector.
I'm not set.
Steady, Dak.
Attack pattern Delta.
Go now.
All right.
I'm coming in.
Hobbie,
you still with me?
That armor's too strong
for blasters.
Rogue Group,
use your harpoons and tow cables.
Go for the legs. It might be
our only chance of stopping them.
All right.
Stand by, Dak.
Oh, Luke, we've got a malfunction
in fire control.
I'll have to cut in
the auxiliary.
Just hang on.
Hang on, Dak.
Get ready to fire
that tow cable.
Ah!
Dak?
Dak!
Yes, Lord Vader, I've reached
the main power generators.
The shield will be down
in moments.
You may start your landing.
Rogue Three.
Copy, Rogue Leader.
Wedge, I've lost my gunner.
You'll have to
make this shot.
I'll cover for you.
Set your harpoon.
Follow me on the next pass.
Coming around,
Rogue Leader.
Steady, Rogue Two.
Activate harpoon.
Good shot, Janson.
- One more pass.
- Coming around, Wedge.
Cable out.
Let her go!
Detach cable.
Cable detached.
Come on.
Hah! That got him!
I see it, Wedge.
Good work.
I don't think...
we can protect
two transports at a time.
It's risky, but we can't
hold out much longer.
We have no choice.
Launch patrol.
Evacuate remaining ground staff.
Gahhh!
No, no! No.
This one goes there.
That one goes there, right?
R2, you take good care
of Master Luke now, understand?
And do take good care
of yourself.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
All troops will debark
for ground assault.
Prepare to target
the main generator.
Rogue Two,
are you all right?
Yeah. I'm with you,
Rogue Leader.
Well, set harpoon.
I'll cover for you.
Coming around.
Watch that cross fire, boys.
Set for
position three.
Steady.
Stay tight and low.
This is it!
Aah!
Hobbie!
I've been hit!
You all right?
Why are you
still here?
Heard the command center had been hit.
You've got
your clearance to leave.
Don't worry. I'll leave.
First I'm gonna
get you to your ship.
Your Highness,
we must take this last transport.
It's our only hope.
Send all troops
in Sector 12...
to the south slope
to protect the fighters.
Imperial troops
have entered the base.
have entered...
Come on.
That's it.
Give the evacuation
code signal.
And get to your transports!
Oh! Wait for me!
Begin retreat!
Fall back!
Distance to power generators?
17.28.
Target.
Maximum firepower.
Transport, this is Solo.
Better take off.
I can't get to you.
I'll get her out
on the Falcon.
Come on.
B-B-But where are
you going?
Come back!
Wait!
Wait for me!
Wait! Stop!
How typical.
Come on.
Gahhh!
Hurry up, goldenrod.
You're gonna be
a permanent resident.
Wait! Wait!
How's this?
Would it help
if I got out and pushed?
Captain Solo!
It might.
Sir, might I suggest
that you...
It can wait.
This bucket of bolts is never gonna
get us past that blockade.
This baby's got a few surprises
left in her, sweetheart.
Come on! Come on!
Switch over.
Let's hope we don't have a burnout.
See?
Someday you're
gonna be wrong...
and I just hope
I'm there to see it.
Punch it!
R2!
Get her ready
for takeoff.
Good luck, Luke.
See you at the rendezvous.
Don't worry, R2.
We're going.
There's nothing wrong, R2.
I'm just setting
a new course.
We're not gonna regroup
with the others.
We're going
to the Dagobah system.
Yes, R2?
That's all right.
I'd like to keep it
on manual control for a while.
Gahhh!
I saw 'em! I saw 'em!
Saw what?
Stardestroyers,
two of 'em coming right at us.
Sir! Sir!
Might I suggest...
Shut him up
or shut him down!
Check the deflector shield.
Great.
Well, we can still
outmaneuver them.
Take evasive action!
Prepare to make the jump to light speed.
But, sir!
They're getting closer.
Oh, yeah?
Watch this.
Watch what?
I think we're
in trouble.
If I may say so, sir,
I noticed earlier...
the hyperdrive motivator
has been damaged.
It's impossible to go
to light speed.
We're in trouble.
Horizontal boosters!
Gahhh!
Alluvial dampers.
Ow!
That's not it.
Bring me
the hydrospanner!
I don't know how we're gonna
get out of this one.
Ow!
Chewie!
That wasn't a laser blast.
Something hit us.
Han, get up here!
Come on, Chewie!
Asteroids.
Oh, no.
Chewie,
set two-seven-one.
What are you doing?
You're not actually going
into an asteroid field?
They'd be crazy to follow us,
wouldn't they?
You don't have to do this
to impress me.
Sir, the possibility of successfully
navigating an asteroid field...
is approximately 3,720 to 1.
Never tell me the odds!
Look out!
You said you wanted to be around
when I made a mistake.
This could be it,
sweetheart.
I take it back.
We're going
to get pulverized...
if we stay out here
much longer.
Ain't gonna argue with that.
I'm going in closer
to one of the big ones.
Closer?!
Gahhh!
Oh, this is suicide!
There's nowhere to go.
There. That looks
pretty good.
What looks pretty good?
Yeah,
that'll do nicely.
Excuse me, ma'am,
but where are we going?
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Yeah. Me, too.
Yep, that's it.
Dagobah.
No, I'm not gonna change
my mind about this.
I'm not picking up
any cities or technology.
Massive life-form
readings, though.
There's something alive
down there.
Yes. I'm sure it's perfectly safe for droids.
I know! I know!
All the scopes are dead.
I can't see a thing.
Just hang on.
I'm gonna start
the landing cycle.
No, R2, you stay put.
I'll have a look around.
R2?
R2!
Where are you?
You be more careful.
R2, that way.
R2!
Beeep!
Oh, no.
Are you all right?
Come on.
You were lucky
to get out of there.
Anything broken?
If you're saying
coming here was a bad idea...
I'm beginning
to agree with you.
R2, what are
we doing here?
It's like... something
out of a dream or...
I don't know.
Maybe I'm
just going crazy.
Yes, Admiral?
Our ships have sighted
the Millennium Falcon, lord...
but it has entered an asteroid field,
and we cannot risk...
Asteroids do not
concern me, Admiral.
I want that ship,
not excuses.
Yes, lord.
I'm gonna shut down
everything...
but the emergency
power systems.
Sir, I'm almost afraid to ask,
but does that include shutting me down, too?
No. I need you to talk
to the Falcon.
Find out what's wrong
with the hyperdrive.
Sir, it's quite possible
this asteroid is not entirely stable.
Not entirely stable?
I'm glad you're here
to tell us these things.
Chewie, take the professor
in the back...
and plug him into
the hyperdrive.
Sometimes I just don't
understand human behavior.
After all, I'm only
trying to do my job.
- Let go.
- Shh!
Let go, please.
Don't get excited.
Captain, being held by you...
isn't quite enough
to get me excited.
Sorry, sweetheart.
I haven't got time
for anything else.
Ready for
some power?
O.K.
Let's see now.
Put that in there.
There you go.
Now all I gotta do
is find this Yoda...
if he even exists.
It's really a strange place
to find a Jedi master.
This place
gives me the creeps.
Still...
there's something familiar
about this place.
I don't know.
I feel like...
Feel like what?
Like we're
being watched!
Away put your weapon!
I mean you no harm.
I am wondering...
why are you here?
I'm looking
for someone.
Looking?
Found someone you have,
I would say, hmmm?
Right.
Help you I can.
Yes, mmmm.
I don't think so.
I'm looking
for a great warrior.
Ah!
A great warrior.
Ha ha ha!
Wars not
make one great.
Put that down.
Hey! That's my dinner!
How you get so big
eating food of this kind?
Listen, friend, we didn't mean
to land in that puddle.
And if we could get
our ship out, we would.
But we can't,
so why don't you...
Cannot get your ship out.
Hee hee hee!
Hey, get out of there!
Ah!
No! Ooh!
Hey, you could
have broken this.
Don't do that.
Oh!
You're making a mess.
Hey, give me that!
Mine, or I will
help you not.
I don't want your help.
I want my lamp back.
I'm gonna need it
to get out of this slimy mudhole.
Mudhole? Slimy?
My home this is...
Wha... Mmm!
R2, let him have it.
Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
R2!
Now, will you move along,
little fellow?
We've got a lot
of work to do.
No! No, no!
Stay and help you I will...
find your friend.
I'm not looking
for a friend.
I'm looking
for a Jedi master.
Oh. Jedi master. Yoda.
You seek Yoda.
You know him?
Mmmm.
Take you to him I will.
Yes, yes, but now
we must eat. Come.
Good food.
Come.
Come, come.
R2... stay and watch
after the camp.
Oh! Where is R2
when I need him?
Sir, I don't know where your ship
learned to communicate...
but it has the most
peculiar dialect.
I believe, sir, it says
that the power coupling...
on the negative axis
has been polarized.
I'm afraid you'll have
to replace it.
Well, of course I'll
have to replace it.
Here!
And, Chewie...
I think we'd better replace
the negative power coupling.
Hey, Your Worship,
I'm only trying to help.
Would you please
stop calling me that?
Sure, Leia.
You make it
so difficult sometimes.
I do. I really do.
You could be a little nicer, though.
Come on, admit it.
Sometimes you think I'm all right.
Occasionally... maybe...
when you aren't acting
like a scoundrel.
Scoundrel?
I like the sound
of that.
Stop that.
Stop what?
My hands are dirty.
My hands are dirty, too.
What are you afraid of?
Afraid?
You're trembling.
I'm not trembling.
You like me because
I'm a scoundrel.
There aren't enough
scoundrels in your life.
I happen to like nice men.
I'm a nice man.
No, you're not. You're...
Sir, sir!
I've isolated
the reverse power flux coupling.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Oh, you're perfectly
welcome, sir.
And that was the last time
they appeared in any of our scopes.
Considering the amount of
damage we've sustained...
they must have been
destroyed.
No, Captain.
They're alive.
I want every ship
available...
to sweep
the asteroid field...
until they are found.
Lord Vader.
Yes, Admiral.
What is it?
The emperor
commands you...
to make contact
with him.
Move the ship out of
the asteroid field...
so that we can send
a clear transmission.
Yes, my lord.
What is thy bidding,
my master?
There is a great
disturbance...
in the Force.
I have felt it.
We have
a new enemy...
the young rebel
who destroyed the Death Star.
I have no doubt
this boy...
is the offspring
of Anakin Skywalker.
How is that possible?
Search your feelings,
Lord Vader.
You will know it
to be true.
He could destroy us.
He's just a boy.
Obi-Wan can no longer
help him.
The Force
is strong with him.
The son of Skywalker...
must not become a Jedi.
If he could be turned...
he would become
a powerful ally.
Yes.
He would be
a great asset.
Can it be done?
He will join us
or die, master.
Look,
I'm sure it's delicious.
I just don't understand
why we can't see Yoda now.
Patience!
For the Jedi...
it is time
to eat as well.
Hmm? Heh heh.
Eat, eat.
Hot!
Good food!
Mmm, good, hmm?
How far away is Yoda?
Will it take us long to get there?
Not far.
Yoda not far.
Patience. Soon you
will be with him.
Root leaf.
I cook.
Why wish you
become Jedi? Hmm? Hmm?
Mostly because of
my father, I guess.
Ah, father.
Powerful Jedi was he.
Hee hee.
Mmm, powerful Jedi.
Oh, come on.
How could you
know my father?
You don't
even know who I am.
I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
We're wasting our time!
I cannot teach him.
The boy
has no patience.
He will learn patience.
Hmm...
Much anger in him...
like his father.
Was I any different
when you taught me?
No.
He is not ready.
Yoda.
I am ready.
Ben...
I can be a Jedi.
Ben, tell him I'm...
Ready, are you?
What know you ready?
For 800 years
have I trained Jedi.
My own counsel will I keep...
on who is to be trained.
A Jedi must have
the deepest commitment, hmm?
The most serious mind.
This one a long time
have I watched.
All his life
has he looked away...
to the future,
to the horizon.
Never his mind
on where he was...
hmm?
What he was doing.
Hmph!
Adventure.
Ha!
Excitement. Ha!
A Jedi craves
not these things.
You are reckless!
So was I,
if you remember.
He is too old.
Yes, too old to
begin the training.
But I've learned so much.
Ahh...
Will he finish
what he begins?
I won't fail you.
I'm not afraid.
Oh...
You will be.
Aah!
Sir, if I may venture
an opinion...
I'm not really interested
in your opinion.
There's something
out there.
Where?
Outside in the cave.
There it is.
Listen. Listen!
I'm going out there.
Are you crazy?
I just got this bucket
back together.
I'm not going to let
something tear it apart.
Then I'm going
with you.
I think it might
be better...
if I stay behind and guard the ship.
Oh, no.
This ground
sure feels strange.
It doesn't
feel like rock.
There's an awful lot
of moisture in here.
I don't know.
I have a bad feeling
about this.
Yeah.
Watch out!
It's all right.
Yeah, that's what
I thought... mynock.
Chewie, check the rest
of the ship...
and make sure there are
no more attached...
chewing
on the power cables.
Mynocks.
Go on inside. We'll clean them off
if there are any more.
Han!
Aagghh! Go away, go away,
beastly thing!
Shoo! Shoo!
Wait a minute...
Let's get out of here!
The Empire is still out there!
I don't think...
No time to discuss this
in committee!
I'm not a committee!
You can't make the jump to light speed
in this asteroid field.
Sit down, sweetheart!
We're taking off!
Look!
I see it.
We're doomed!
The cave is collapsing.
- This is no cave.
- What?
Run!
Yes! A Jedi's strength
flows from the Force.
But beware
of the dark side.
Anger, fear,
aggression...
The dark side of
the Force are they...
easily they flow,
quick to join you in a fight.
If once you start down
the dark path...
forever will it dominate
your destiny.
Consume you it will...
as it did Obi-Wan's
apprentice.
Vader.
Is the dark side
stronger?
No, no.
No.
Quicker, easier,
more seductive.
How do I know the good side
from the bad?
You will know
when you are calm...
at peace...
passive.
A Jedi
uses the Force...
for knowledge
and defense...
never for attack.
But tell me why
I can't...
No, no.
There is no why.
Nothing more will I
teach you today.
Clear your mind
of questions.
Hmm...
Mmm...
There's something
not right here.
I feel cold...
death.
That place...
is strong with
the dark side of the Force.
A domain of evil it is.
In you must go.
What's in there?
Only what
you take with you.
Your weapons...
you will not need them.
Hmph...
Bounty hunters.
We don't need
their scum.
Yes, sir.
Those rebels
won't escape us.
Sir, we have
a priority signal...
from the
Stardestroyer Avenger.
There will be
a substantial reward...
for the one
who finds...
the Millennium Falcon.
You are free to use
any methods necessary...
but I want them alive.
No disintegrations.
As you wish.
Lord Vader.
My lord,
we have them.
Oh, thank goodness
we're coming out of...
the asteroid field.
Let's get out of here.
Ready for light speed?
1...
2...
3!
It's not fair.
Gahhh!
Transfer circuits
aren't working.
It's not my fault!
No light speed?
It's not my fault.
Sir, we've just lost
the main rear deflector shield.
One more direct hit
on the back quarter and we're done for.
Turn her around.
I'm going to put all power
in the front shield.
You're going to
attack them?
Sir, the odds of surviving
a direct assault on an imperial...
- Shut up!
- Gaahh!
They're moving to
attack position.
Shields up.
Track them.
They may come around
for another pass.
Captain Needa, the ship
no longer appears on our scopes.
They can't
have disappeared.
No ship that small
has a cloaking device.
Well, there's no trace
of them, sir.
Captain, Lord Vader demands
an update on the pursuit.
Get a shuttle ready.
I shall assume full responsibility
for losing them...
and apologize
to Lord Vader.
Meanwhile, continue
to scan the area.
Yes, Captain Needa.
Use the Force.
Yes.
Now, the stone...
Feel it.
Concentrate!
Oh, no. We'll never
get it out now.
So certain are you.
Always with you
it cannot be done.
Hear you nothing
that I say?
Master, moving stones around
is one thing.
This is totally
different.
No! No different!
Only different
in your mind.
You must unlearn
what you have learned.
All right.
I'll give it a try.
No! Try not.
Do.
Or do not.
There is no try.
I can't.
It's too big.
Size matters not.
Look at me.
Judge me by my size,
do you?
Hmm?
Hmph!
And well you should not...
for my ally is the Force.
And a powerful
ally it is.
Life creates it...
makes it grow.
Its energy surrounds us...
and binds us.
Luminous beings are we...
not this crude matter.
You must feel
the Force around you...
Here,
between you, me...
the tree...
the rock...
everywhere!
Yes...
even between the land
and the ship.
You want the impossible.
Mm...
I don't...
I don't believe it.
That is why you fail.
Apology accepted,
Captain Needa.
Lord Vader, our ships have completed
their scan of the area and found nothing.
If the Millennium Falcon
went into light speed...
it'll be on the other side
of the galaxy by now.
Alert all commands.
Calculate every
possible destination...
along their last known
trajectory.
Yes, my lord.
We'll find them.
Don't fail me again...
Admiral.
Alert all commands.
Deploy the fleet.
Captain Solo,
this time you've gone too far.
Gahhh!
I will not be quiet.
Why doesn't anyone listen to me?
The fleet's beginning
to break up.
Go back and stand by
the manual release...
for the landing claw.
I really don't see
how that's going to help.
Surrender is a perfectly acceptable
alternative in extreme circumstances.
The Empire
may be gracious enough...
Thank you.
What's your next move?
If they follow standard
imperial procedure...
they'll dump their garbage...
before they go to
light speed...
and then we just
float away.
With the rest
of the garbage.
Then what?
Then we got to find a safe port
somewhere around here.
Any ideas?
Where are we?
The Anoat system.
There's not
much there.
No. Well, wait.
This is interesting.
Lando.
Lando system?
Lando's not a system.
He's a man. Lando Calrissian.
He's a cardplayer,
gambler, scoundrel.
You'd like him.
Thanks.
Bespin. It's pretty far,
but I think we can make it.
A mining colony?
Yeah, a tibanna
gas mine.
Lando conned
somebody out of it.
We go back a long way,
Lando and me.
Can you trust him?
No. But he's got no
love for the Empire...
I can tell you that.
Here we go, Chewie.
Stand by.
Detach.
You do have your moments.
Not many of them...
but you do have them.
Concentrate.
Feel the Force flow.
Yes.
Good.
Calm.
Yes.
Through the Force,
things you will see.
Other places.
The future. The past.
Old friends long gone.
Han?
Leia!
Hmm...
Control, control.
You must learn control!
I saw... I saw a city
in the clouds.
Hmm...
Friends you have there.
They were in pain.
It is the future you see.
Future?
Will they die?
Difficult to see.
Always in motion
is the future.
I've got to go to them.
Decide you must
how to serve them best.
If you leave now,
help them you could...
but you would destroy all...
for which they have
fought and suffered.
No, I don't have
a landing permit.
I'm trying to reach
Lando Calrissian.
Wait a minute!
Let me explain!
You will not deviate
from your present course.
Rather touchy,
aren't they?
I thought
you knew this person.
Gaah!
That was
a long time ago.
I'm sure he's forgotten about that.
Permission granted to land
on Platform 3-2-7.
Thank you.
Nothing
to worry about.
We go way back,
Lando and me.
Who's worried?
Oh. No one to meet us.
I don't like this.
Well, what
would you like?
They did let us land.
Look, don't worry.
Everything's going to be fine.
Trust me.
See? My friend.
Keep your eyes
open, huh?
Gahhh!
Hey!
Why, you slimy...
double-crossing,
no-good swindler.
You've got a lot of guts coming here...
after what you pulled.
Ha ha ha ha ha
ha ha ha ha!
How you doin', you old pirate?
So good to see you!
Well, he seems
very friendly.
Yes.
Very friendly.
What are you doing here?
Ah, repairs.
I thought you could help me out.
What have you done
to my ship?
Your ship?
Hey, remember...
you lost her to me
fair and square.
And how you doin',
Chewbacca?
Gahh!
You still hanging around
with this loser?
Gahhh!
Hello.
What have we here?
Welcome,
I'm Lando Calrissian.
I'm the administrator
of this facility.
And who might you be?
Leia.
Welcome, Leia.
All right, all right,
you old smoothie.
Hello, sir. I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
My facilities
are at your...
Well, really!
What's wrong
with the Falcon?
Hyperdrive.
I'll get my people
to work on her.
That ship saved my life
quite a few times.
She's the fastest
hunk of junk in the galaxy.
How's the gas mine?
Still paying off for you?
Not as well as I'd like.
We're a small outpost
and not very self-sufficient.
I've had supply problems
of every kind.
I've had labor difficulties.
Ha ha ha!
What's so funny?
You. Listen to you.
You sound like
a businessman...
a responsible leader.
Who'd have
thought that, huh?
Seeing you brings back
a few things.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm responsible
these days.
It's the price you pay...
for being successful.
Ooh. Nice to see
a familiar face.
E chu ta!
How rude!
That sounds like
an R2 unit in there.
I wonder if... Hello?
How interesting.
Who are you?
Oh, my! I...
I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't mean
to intrude.
No, please don't get up.
Gahhh.
Luke, you must complete
the training.
I can't keep the vision
out of my head.
They're my friends.
I got to help them.
You must not go.
But Han and Leia will die
if I don't.
You don't know that.
Even Yoda cannot
see their fate.
But I can help them.
I feel the Force.
But you cannot
control it.
This is a dangerous
time for you...
when you will be tempted
by the dark side of the Force.
Yes! Yes!
To Obi-Wan you listen.
The cave.
Remember your failure at the cave.
But I've learned
so much since then.
Master Yoda, I promise to return
and to finish what I've begun.
You have my word.
It is you
and your abilities...
the emperor wants.
That is why your friends
are made to suffer.
That's why
I have to go.
Luke, I don't want
to lose you to the emperor...
the way I lost Vader.
You won't.
Stopped they must be.
On this all depends.
Only a fully trained
Jedi knight...
with the Force
as his ally...
will conquer Vader
and his emperor.
If you end
your training now...
if you choose the quick and easy path,
as Vader did...
you will become
an agent of evil.
Patience.
And sacrifice
Han and Leia?
If you honor what they fight for... yes.
If you choose to face Vader...
you will do it alone.
I cannot interfere.
I understand.
R2.
Fire up the converters.
Luke!
Don't give in to hate.
That leads to the dark side.
Strong is Vader.
Mind what you have learned.
Save you it can.
I will.
And I'll return.
I promise.
Told you, I did.
Reckless is he.
Now...
matters are worse.
That boy
is our last hope.
No, there is another.
The ship's almost finished.
Two or three more things
and we're in great shape.
The sooner the better.
Something is wrong here.
No one has seen or knows
anything about 3PO.
He's been gone too long
to have gotten lost.
Relax.
I'll talk to Lando...
and see what
I can find out.
I don't trust Lando.
Well, I don't
trust him either.
But he is my friend.
Besides...
we'll soon be gone.
Then you're as good as gone,
aren't you?
Gaahh!
What happened?
Gahhh gahhh.
Where?
Gahhh!
Found him
in a junk pile?
Oh, what a mess.
Chewie, you think you can repair him?
Gahhh!
Lando's got people
that can fix him.
No, thanks.
I'm sorry, am I
interrupting anything?
Not really.
You look
absolutely beautiful.
You truly belong here
with us among the clouds.
Thank you.
Would you join me
for a little refreshment?
Everyone's invited,
of course.
Having trouble
with your droid?
No, no problem.
Why?
You see, since we're
a small operation...
we don't fall into...
the jurisdiction
of the Empire.
So you're part of
the Mining Guild, then?
No, not actually. Our operation
is small enough not to be noticed.
Which is advantageous
for everybody...
since our customers
are anxious to avoid...
attracting attention
to themselves.
Aren't you afraid
the Empire's going to find out...
about this little operation,
shut you down?
It's always been a danger that looms
like a shadow over everything we've built.
But things have developed
that'll ensure security.
I've just made a deal that will
keep the Empire out of here forever.
We would be honored
if you would join us.
I had no choice.
They arrived
right before you did.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Gahhh.
No, 3PO's with them.
Just hang on.
We're almost there.
Gahhh!
Oh ah ooh ah.
Im trbly srry.
I dndt mn to
intrddd.
No! Secret.
Stormtroopers?
Here?
We're in danger!
I must
tell the others.
Oh, no,
I've been shot!
Aaah!
Aaaaahhh!
Lord Vader.
You may take Captain Solo
to Jabba the Hutt...
after I have Skywalker.
He's no good to me dead.
He will not be
permanently damaged.
Aaaahhh!
Lord Vader, what about Leia
and the Wookiee?
They must never again
leave this city.
That was never a condition
of our agreement...
nor was giving Han
to this bounty hunter.
Perhaps you think you're
being treated unfairly?
No.
Good. It would be
unfortunate...
if I had to leave
a garrison here.
This deal is getting worse all the time.
Oh, yes, that's very good.
I like that.
Oh!
Something's not right
because now I can't see.
Oh, oh, oh,
that's much better.
Wait! Wait!
Oh, my!
What have you done?
I'm backwards...
you flea-bitten
furball!
Only an overgrown
mophead like you...
would be
stupid enough...
I feel terrible.
Gahhh.
Why are they
doing this?
They never even asked me
any questions.
Lando.
Grrr!
Get out of here, Lando.
Shut up and listen!
Vader's agreed
to turn Leia and Chewie over to me.
They'll have to stay here,
but at least they'll be safe.
What about Han?
Vader's given him
to the bounty hunter.
Vader wants us
all dead.
He doesn't want you at all.
He's after somebody
called Skywalker.
- Luke.
- Lord Vader set a trap for him.
And we're the bait!
He's on his way.
You fixed us all
real good, didn't you?
My friend.
Stop!
I've done all I can.
I'm sorry
I couldn't do better...
but I've got
my own problems.
Yeah.
You're a real hero.
You certainly have
a way with people.
Ah... Ah...
This facility is crude...
but it should be adequate
to freeze Skywalker...
for his journey to the emperor.
Lord Vader, ship approaching,
X-wing class.
Good.
Monitor Skywalker...
and allow him
to land.
Lord Vader, we only use this facility
for carbon freezing.
You put him in there,
it might kill him.
I do not want...
the emperor's prize
damaged.
We will test it
on Captain Solo.
If only you'd
attached my legs...
I wouldn't be
in this ridiculous position.
Now remember,
Chewbacca...
you have a responsibility for me...
so don't do anything foolish.
What's going on...
buddy?
You're being put
into carbon freeze.
What if he doesn't survive?
He's worth a lot to me.
The Empire
will compensate you...
if he dies.
Put him in.
Rrrah!
Rrrah! Rrrah!
Stop, Chewie,
stop, stop!
Yes, stop, please!
I'm not ready to die!
Hey! Hey! Listen
to me, Chewie.
This won't help me.
Hey, save your strength.
There will be
another time.
The princess...
You have to
take care of her.
Do you hear me?
Huh?
Gahhh...
I love you.
I know.
Gahhh!
What's going on?
Turn around!
Chewbacca,
I can't see.
Gahhh.
Oh, they've encased him
in carbonite.
He should be quite
well-protected...
if he survived the freezing process,
that is.
Well, Calrissian,
did he survive?
Yes, he's alive.
And in perfect hibernation.
He's all yours,
bounty hunter.
Reset the chamber
for Skywalker.
Skywalker has
just landed, lord.
Good. See to it
that he finds his way in here.
Calrissian, take the princess
and the Wookiee to my ship.
You said they'd be left in the city
under my supervision.
I am altering the deal.
Pray I don't
alter it any further.
Gahhh!
Luke! Luke, don't,
it's a trap!
It's a trap!
The Force is with you,
young Skywalker.
But you are not
a Jedi yet.
Well done.
Hold them
in the security tower.
And keep it quiet. Move.
What do you think
you're doing?
We're getting
out of here.
I knew all along.
It had to be a mistake.
Do you think that after what you did
to Han, we're going to trust you?
Grrr!
I had no choice.
What are you doing?
Trust him! Trust him!
We understand, don't we,
Chewie? He had no choice.
I'm just
trying to help.
We don't need
any of your help.
Haaa...
Grrr!
Ha... Ha...
What?
Han...
It sounds like Han.
There's still
a chance...
to save Han...
at the east...
platform.
Chewie.
I'm terribly sorry
about all this.
After all,
he's only a Wookiee.
Put Captain Solo
in the cargo hold.
R2, R2, where have you been?
Wait. Turn around, you woolly...
Hurry! Hurry! We're trying to save Han
from the bounty hunter.
Well, at least you're still in one piece.
Look what's happened to me.
Oh, no! Chewie,
they're behind you!
You have learned
much, young one.
You'll find
I'm full of surprises.
Your destiny lies
with me, Skywalker.
Obi-Wan knew this
to be true.
No.
Aaah!
All too easy.
Perhaps you're
not as strong...
as the emperor thought.
Impressive.
Most impressive.
Aaah!
Obi-Wan has
taught you well.
You have
controlled your fear.
Now...
release your anger.
Only your hatred
can destroy me.
Ohh!
The security code
has been changed.
R2, you can tell
the computer...
to override
the security systems.
R2, hurry!
Attention. This is
Lando Calrissian.
Attention. The Empire has taken
control of the city.
I advise everyone to leave
before more imperial troops arrive.
This way.
Well, don't blame me.
I'm an interpreter.
I'm not supposed to know a power socket
from a computer terminal.
Ah! We're not interested...
in the Millennium
Falcon's hyperdrive.
It's fixed!
Just open the door,
you stupid lump!
I never doubted you
for a second.
Wonderful!
Ouch! Oh! That hurts!
Bend down,
you thoughtless... Ow!
Leia!
Go!
I thought that hairy beast
would be the end of me.
Of course
I've looked better.
You are beaten.
It is useless to resist.
Don't let yourself
be destroyed...
as Obi-Wan did.
Uh!
Aah!
There is no escape.
Don't make me destroy you.
Luke...
you do not yet realize
your importance.
You have only begun
to discover your power.
Join me...
and I will complete
your training.
With our combined strength...
we can end
this destructive conflict...
and bring order
to the galaxy.
I'll never join you!
If you only knew
the power...
of the dark side.
Obi-Wan never told you...
what happened
to your father.
He told me enough.
He told me
you killed him.
No.
I am your father.
That's not true.
That's impossible!
Search your feelings.
You know it to be true.
No!
Luke.
You can destroy
the emperor.
He has foreseen this.
It is your destiny.
Join me, and together
we can rule the galaxy...
as father and son.
Come with me.
It is the only way.
Ben.
Ben, please.
Leia.
Hear me.
Luke.
We've got to go back.
- What?
- I know where Luke is.
What about
those fighters?
Chewie, just do it.
But what about Vader?
All right, all right!
Alert my Stardestroyer
to prepare for my arrival.
Look, someone's up there.
It's Luke.
Chewie, slow down.
Slow down.
We'll get under him.
Lando,
open the top hatch.
O.K.
Easy, Chewie.
Gahrrr.
Lando?
O.K., let's go.
Oh, Leia.
All right, Chewie,
let's go.
I'll be back.
Stardestroyer.
All right, Chewie.
Ready for light speed.
If your people fixed
the hyperdrive.
All the coordinates are set.
It's now or never.
Punch it!
They told me
they fixed it.
I trusted them!
It's not my fault!
They'll be in range
of our tractor beam in moments, lord.
Did your men deactivate...
the hyperdrive on
the Millennium Falcon?
Yes, my lord.
Good. Prepare
the boarding party...
and set your weapons
for "stun."
Yes, my lord.
Lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
Noisy brute. Why don't we just
go into light speed?
We can't?
How would you know...
the hyperdrive
is deactivated?
The city's central
computer told you?
R2-D2, you know better
than to trust a strange computer.
Ouch!
Pay attention
to what you're doing!
Luke.
Father.
Son, come with me.
Ben.
Why didn't you tell me?
Chewie!
It's Vader.
Luke, it is your destiny.
Ben.
Why didn't you tell me?
Alert all commands.
Ready for
the tractor beam.
R2, come back at once!
You haven't finished
with me yet.
You don't know how
to fix the hyperdrive.
Chewbacca can do it.
I'm standing here
in pieces...
and you're having
delusions of grandeur!
You did it!
Luke, we're ready
for takeoff.
Good luck, Lando.
When we find
Jabba the Hutt...
and that
bounty hunter...
we'll contact you.
I'll meet you
at the rendezvous point on Tatooine.
Princess,
we'll find Han.
I promise.
Chewie, I'll be waiting
for your signal.
Take care, you two.
May the Force
be with you.
Gahhh.
Ow.