Planet Desire... I've dreamt of it
For you, tomorrow,
Get free access to riches
Who needs to save?
Warning: This movie has been paid
for by inserted Advertisements.
It doesn't change the world
but it contributes
French Petrochemicals Products
" Welcome into the brave new world "
Everything can be bought
Love, Art, planet Earth
you, me
particularly me
Man is a product, like other things,
with a sell by date
I'm a publicist
I'm a part of those who make you
dream of things you'll never have
sky always blue
wenches never dumpy
perfect photoshopped happiness
You believe I make the world prettier?
Wrong: I screw it up
Everything is temporary
Love, Art, planet Earth
You, me
particulary me
That's it, it's done
The corner is turned
I can look back on my life
It's cool
For example I had completly
forgotten how much,
when very young,
I loved sophisticated pictures
- Arch your back!
Show me your butt!
- Octave, honey,
Dinner's ready!
- Yes mummy, I'm coming!
I've always been 'set apart'
I was really made for that job
- Beat it
Fuck, it's shit!
I'm on a bad trip
Sorry Stephanie, you're alright?!
I didn't know you were here
It's not against you, sorry
You're alright? Wait...
I
To me, everything
had started so well...
the mood was good,
the dj excellent,
pleasant temperature,
superb girls,
alcohol a gogo,
drugs of quality...
Undeniably, my first 33 years
were really successful
But I won't disguise the truth
I'm not a nice boy
- We're closing
I am a big shit
A modern hero
I find my trousers,
in the Italian Vogue
and in the German
Vanity Fair
a month before you can read them.
Concerning my shirts, they come
from New York, Tokio, Bombay, Guetary
I'm sorry to be so much
in advance of you, but...
I'm the one who decides today
what you'll want tomorrow
I drug you with novelty
and novelty's advantage, is that
it doesn't stay new for long
You should ideally hate me, before
hating the era that created me
So here it is, my name is
Octave Parengo
and my dresser is APC
I have spent my life manipulating you
for 75,000 F per month
When, by dint of savings, you'll
be able to buy your dream car,
I shall already have
made it old-fashionned
I always manage
to frustrate you
I penetrate your brain
I come in your right hemisphere
Your desires don't belong
to you anymore
I impose mine on you
There has never been such a devious and
powerful cunt as me for 2,000 years
- Octave Parengo, 312 chamber
- I got that for you
- thank you...
Sorry,
it's ugly
Popular
Here we are in "the Ross"-
Ross and Witchcraft
one of the biggest advertising
companies in the world
Median age: 28 years old
Sales: 1,430,000 F
My open ended job
is copywriter
I write 30 second
film scenarios
and slogans for posters
I say "slogan"
for you to understand
but you should
know that we say
"catcher" or "headline"
For example: Wonderbra
"Look at me in the eyes"
"I said in the eyes!"...
- Ave Octavus!
- Hi to the dorks!
...it comes from me
Arch your back!
Here new territory is being
explored regarding dry sausage
Stan, consolidate the "teen shower"
spirit and the 15/35 year olds.
Alexandra, try to optimize the
strategical approach of seniors' nappies
Funky...
Here is the accounting department,
and she is...
What is her name?
ohhh, nevermind...
Here is Marc Maronnier,
my creative director
After Philippe, the president,
he is the most important
man of the company
- Hi
- Hi, how are you?
- I just spent the week-end
with my man
Four days in Cabourg
I'm so happy!
- Oh yeah?!
- ... A charming little corner
so romantic,
we landed up there,
We dug it so much...
it was great,
I'm so peachy!
- you're fired, take your stuff
right now and beat it!
I am not joking
Marc is like that, for 10 years
he has taught me everything
Alright you stay,
And your out of date language
"We dug it, it was awesome,
we got a kick out of it"
Avoid that, when I'm plunged into a file
it's disgusting to me
And you spend this week-end here,
I want a balance for Tuesday
- Yes Mr Maronnier
- Ok, it's cool, you
can call me Marc
- He is a genius
- You're ok?
You're ready for this afternoon's
presentation for Madone?
- Yeah, we've got something
- I won't be there
Jeff will be
- Wait, Jeff...
- that's the way it is!
I can rely on you?
- Yeah, so, I rely on myself...
- You adore me?!
Creative is not such an easy job,
and that's also why we're so well-paid
To shut us up.
You won't believe me, but
money is not the only reason
I chose that job
I was 17 and a half
when I had my first "ad-shock"
I knew it was what
I wanted to do
When I went to the ciné, the ads
were sometimes better than the film
Some of them were little
treasures of ingenuity
This day I decided
to become a publicist
and I succeeded
Here, on the 14th floor,
is my office
Near the radiator
it's Cuddly,
a blond hamster, picked up
on a filming shoot
and next to it,
this retarded teenager
He's my Charly
He's mine
He's my partner
He is artistic director, my D.A.
or A.D., "Art Director"
as we say in the profession,
because it makes it more American
Hello Thierry, it's Charly,
Hello, sorry to disturb you,
I'm embarrassed with an email
I received, the one with the eel...
the moray eel... sorry
I can't tell if it's a guy or
a wench it's fucking with?
I thought it was a guy...
It's bad...
Oh, you're working now...
As does every creative of every company
in the world, my Charly spend 89%
of his working time sharing
trash pictures via the internet
There, he's now coming out of a great
"Japanese vomit eater" period
- Charly...
- Yes, Octave?
- If I told you, I have the vague feeling
I'm going to blow a fuse inside myself
what would you say?
- Wait, wait, are you telling
me this here?
- Yeah, I'm telling you here
- Ok then, tell me,
I am listening to you
- I simply have the vague feeling
I'm going to blow a fuse inside myself
Yeah, of course
- alright, I understand you completely,
I'd like to tell you many things
- So come on, come on...
- Did you snort, with someone else?
- No I would never do this to you
- So this is me you...
you are provoking me!
- I said nothing, stop, stop
Oh yeah insult me in German
come on, punish me!
- Guys, we're waiting for you, on the stage,
for the shooting in Boulogne...
- Yeah, we're coming, we finish, we go...
- A masterpiece!
- Someone told Steven it's
an ad for sauerkraut?
- Don't know, I really have my doubts...
- Please go and tell him!
- No you!
you, it's better...
- What a bitch that guy is
- like that, yes. You detest me,
despise me with your mouth...
- Steve... Can I talk to you
just 2 seconds...
sorry
It's super good, super glamour,
super sensual...
but could you just give
me a square plan
cuz I have more options,
to make it more classical,
more neutral, you see,
it's not Aubade...
it's sauerkraut...
- Sauerkraut, it's not what you want?
- No, but it's good!
- Turn on the radio!
move, come on move!
there...
Who's that?
- Ooh, it's Jeff
- Hi guys, all is right?
- Be careful, you got a
drooping piece of fabric
- Sorry I don't feel like kidding
You're ready for "Starlight"?
- That's it!
- That's the name! I told you earlier!
- No it's me, I told you!
- Ok, ok, alright,
I don't want to put
pressure on you,
but currently it's super hot
with Madone...
- Yeah, Starlight is now in linear...
What!? I'll call her back...
You don't seem to realize,
though that's normal...
you're artists,
but Madone amounts to 39%
of the Ross sales, so...
Fuck! I'm gonna spit
in your mug!
I told you, I'll see to
that later...
Jeff always owns the
newest rubbish gadget
For example, his telephone
is built into his earphone,
the whole time permanently
linked to his secretary
- This bitch bugs me...
Here, it's my cellphone.
With that I'm permanently linked to her,
so I always know everything
It's very expensive
and it drives me mad...
What was I saying?
It stinks like shit of
sauerkraut in here, no?
- Jeff, let me introduce you to
Sir who produces that sauerkraut.
- oh yes, Jean-pierre Rannu:
Jean-françois Marolle,
Jean-françois Marolle:
Jean-Pierre Rannu
- Sir Rannu, really,
I'm deeply sorry, but...
you know, we have so much stress
with this job, we need to relax...
- Forget it.
He's the floor manager...
- Beat it!
What Jeff doesn't say is that
today is the 12th
On the 15th he will receive the evaluation
report of his work filed by his client
That's to say by Madone
A sort of school report
for adults
So, he freaks out. It's normal,
it's meant to be that way
But it doesn't matter.
That's cool
Moreover, at the Ross everything
is cool... Even the sauerkraut
The Madone executive
would 'dig it' to be... cool
But, it's not easy to tumble about
in schizophrenia land
when your name is Jean Christian Gagnant
with initials engraved on your briefcase
For example, to him this morning
must have been a nightmare
In Madone every product manager
wears short-sleeved shirts...
- Have you received
my confirmation e-mail?
...and neckties with
little animals on them
You have received
my confirmation mail?
To a product manager,
looking cool is hyper important
We shall never forget that
a client has no ideas
and that's why he comes
to our advertising company
- that don't fit,
fuck, fuck and fuck!
fuuuuuuuck!
In those days, giant pictures
were put on the walls,
on bus stops,
on trucks, on taxis
The human eye had never been so much
solicited in all of recorded history
Between birth and 18 years old,
we had calculated that each person
had been exposed to an
average of 350,000 ads
It had taken 2,000 years
to come to this
- Gas Parengo
- Hello sir
- Charles Nagou, we have come
for the Starlight meeting
- Alright, you have an ID card?
- Yes
- Thanks
- We leave you the helmets
- Here are your badges,
1st floor, Veneziano room
- Thanks
- You have some left
Always arrive late to meetings,
A creative on time is not credible
Entering the room, where everybody's
waiting for him for 45 minutes,
he should by no means apologise
Upon reflection, it's true
this afternoon meeting
was even more important than an
interview with the head of the state
This meeting changed my life
I think originally, I wanted
to make good around me
It has not been possible,
for two reasons
Because I've been prevented, and also
a bit because I have abdicated
- We're passing through a deep crisis
in the yoghurt industry
You know only too well,
since the mad-cow disease cases,
yoghurt is threatened around the world
In this eroding market, our
answer is the "Foodament"
The "Foodament" is a food
which would also be a medicament
And then, Starlight innovates and
focuses on a white cheese's new vision
The "bodymaking"
With Starlight, I eat smart, so I am
smart, so Starlight makes me smart
It's when we 'catch' them
It's a bit "head to legs"
The guy that doesn't laugh
at Jeff's "non-joke"
is the one to be convinced.
Alfred Dulère, 51 years old,
Scorpio ascendant ram,
director of marketing
at Madone fresh food division
Suit: Hugo Boss, perfume: Hugo Boss
favourite poet: Hugo Boss
Hasn't touched his wife since 1993.
Votes Republican
Adores karting. At Madone and at Ross
he is feared and dreaded
- Yes, next
- Here, working in this perspective...
of "bodymaking",
Octave and Charly have worked
for several weeks
I hand over to Octave...
- Sorry, I don't know what happened,
I thought the meeting would
take place at the company
You have received
my confirmation e-mail?
- Gagnant, sit down
- Octave and Charly,
we're listening to you
- Right, before beginning, I'd like
to dedicate this film to Tatiana
I met her in a disco, two
years ago, in Saint Barth'
Thanks to her...
- Please, a bit of concentration
Always begin by lightening the
atmosphere with a shitty joke
Drugs help you to gain
this nonchalance,
this needed detachment to
survive that kind of meeting
We all want to change the world,
and in taking part in these meetings
I'm aware of collaborating
Being sat down at this table is
taking part in deadening people's minds
To succeed, a sacrifice is needed
But I was thinking of being,
some day, incapable of it
- Octave, you're high
Octave, you're high
- Yes... sorry
- He's on drugs
- A discovery?
- We're on a beach
- Yes, so... Heavenly beach,
coco palms, turquoise sea,
white sand, the Eden
- Two women,
- Two 'bombs'!
- Of course
are running
on the sand
Long focal length on
the young women
Pamela speaks
" In fact, I consider the exegis of our
mastitis are facing crippling hermeneutics.
Christina answers
Be careful, Pamela. You're slowly
slipping to an ontological paronomasis.
- Not at all, it's just
an allegorical solipsism,
nothing to do with it...
Just look
She bends over an
equation drawn in the sand
- I have made an equation
for you to understand
if we accept the hypothesis
X cube root
varies according to the infinite
- Ah ok
- You just have to
subdivide the set
which will tend
to the asymptote
Exactly, it's good,
I've understood!
They leave laughing.
Packshot: "Starlight to remain slim
except in your head"
- It's good?
- Absolutely
- Now I ask a question;
Why make humour?
- Yes, in fact we thought
it would be interesting...
- No, no, no, I say:
Why make humour?
- Because humour makes
the brand friendly,
excellent for the
product identity memorization
Customers remember easier
what makes 'em laugh
- Days after, people in offices
recall the joke... at dinners...
- No, no, no. Why?
- For it. For you. Think about comedies
that succeed, people going to the cine
They sometimes like
to have fun, people... No?
- Yes, except they don't
eat the reel after
Alfred Dulère is a big asshole
Come on Octave, open your mouth,
once and for all, and shove off
"Listen to me carefully dumb shit,
when you go to the dentist, you
don't tell him how to do his job
you rely on him.
Here it's the same:
You rely on us!"
- So, you have something else?
We're off our rocker,
stop to shoot up, guys
Who the fuck do we sell the
yoghurt to?!
- The housewife
- The housewife is what?
You need to go out, guys!
The housewife is tired...
She is in her suburban supermarket
her kids are bitching
her hands are full of shit,
she's blown-out
She has a bunch of problems,
her husband boozes,
She doesn't feel like having a headache with
ironic references... that nobody understands!
So, before thinking about your
4 friends in Paris you'll make laugh
I'm also a part of this production. Sometimes
it makes me laugh, your bullshit
Before that, you should ask yourself,
"What does she want to see, our housewife?
What does she want to hear?
What does she want us to tell her?"
There, that's all!
That's the question
you should stop lying
to yourself, now...
- Really nice, your
view of the world!
- Me, guys, I have 12,000 tons
of yoghurt to sell off this year,
So, youth: ok
Sexy: ok
and...?
and dream!
What the fuck, we are
dreams sellers!
Yesterday, I went to see my goddaughter,
she had her dance show...
decors were painted by children...
I got off on it
I took off
My kind of 'high', Charly
So, I was wondering, dance, would there
be something to find around dance?
yoghurt, lightness, femininity,
... A dancer wearing tutu?
No?
- Yes
- no, no, we will find,
we will... huh guys
- still with your style,
humor, glamour,...
Now you know, you know why you've
been watching shit ads for years
It's here, at this moment,
that everything's tied up
Creatives don't lack ideas... behind
every shitty ad there's a good idea
thrown in the bin, just because everyone,
me included, shits in his pants
- Excuse me
- You alright?
- No, no because I leave the Ross
I leave that pigsty
I stop working,
I get out of the system,
I stop it all, I piss on you,
I despise you all
I give you my card back
Of course, it's not a resignation,
it's a layoff, of course
you fire me, classic stuff;
indemnities, cash, golden parachute
big money, ok!?
- What's happened to you Octave?
You've recently had a change of drug?
- No, no
- Ah, I see, you're writing a script
on a guy who thrives on depression
Ok, no it's good but it lacks of some...
No it's funny, you're still funny,
but I don't know, the guy...
...could lose everything,
He could become a shit
Think about it
Octave... I adore you,
you know it
YOU
Sophie has worked
at the Ross for 3 years,
She is a part-time planning
manager, Marc hired her
He has always
had good taste
No, no don't insist
to make love in an elevator
with an intern, it's...
far too, "adrenalin" to me
even if I feel you're hot as hell
it's out of the question!
Negative!
I've got a reputation to preserve,
you understand?
Here it's more in the mood,
dirty parking, shabby lights,
very Mike Lee...
we fancy it at this time
piss smell, the real one
What you will do, Sophie?
You'll take your lil' scooter in the rain
you'll return to your lil' husband,
watch the Saturday night show?
That's it, the happiness
he offers you... That's it?
- I'm alone and I don't have a TV
- ok, wait, wait, I know I am a
superficial and arrogant shit
ok I don't deny
But I like you, you understand?
Your hair, your eyebrows,
your small intestine please me
even your rebuffs please me
- If my rebuffs please you...
- Nobody, nobody
ever pleases me
I'm sure if you let yourself be kissed,
it could be relatively... pleasant
It's really what I thought,
you're really a beautiful slut
- Wear them, wear them, so I can kiss
myself a little
Everything's alright,
everything's alright!
Hi, it's Sophie, leave me a message,
and I may call you back
Since Sophie left you,
you wander around your flat,
you no longer
open your curtains,
You only use one
room out of nine
the microwave sets the
rhythm of your week-ends
you order your
ready-meals by phone
since you're living alone,
you fuck a lot of video-tapes
you always have pieces of kleenex
stuck to your fingertips
Being without Sophie
made you ugly
Not only drugs cause
withdrawal
It was easier to have a single
retarded behaviour
when you knew lovely Sophie
was waiting for you
Since Sophie left you
nothing goes on
When was it?
- It's going alright,
thanks a lot!
- Stop it...
You've finished eating?
- I can't with these... Like this I can,
with my hand
- I see that
- With these, I can't,
or maybe if I 'sting'...
You see, if I sting...
- So you've finished now?
- Yes
- So, I got a little
gift for you
Happy St. Valentine Day
Ah yeah, it was that day
- You're unfair, plus
we said no gifts
- But here, it's a little
bit more than that
- What, sorry?
Lot more than that?
- Lot more...
- So, it's a surprise
I open it
It won't blow me in the...
here I go
It smells like pee-pee a bit
- It's a pregnancy test
Positive
I'm pregnant by you
- Holy cow! It was hard
I spilled all my guts,
everything that every man
of the world says to their
pregnant girl, in those moments
- Sir, Madame
Have you finished?
- Yes it's over
- You don't want
a little dessert?
Sophie never told anyone
she was pregnant
except to you
Moreover, at the Ross, nobody
knew you were together
What is she doing?
Who is she phoning to?
Where is she when
she's not here?
Marc and Sophie, didn't fit together,
but they were good together
Which is lot more rare
They go to a full
of stars hotel,
three times per week,
at about 14h15
In order to have sex in
a clean and a central place
Ouch, you're hurt
- Guys, fun's over, joke's over,
good mood's over, all this game is over
I am not joking here!
Dulère just phone me, he never
talked to me that way!
Listen to me!
if we don't have a
new concrete script
before 14 o'clock,
we're all dead!
I tell you, in one hour,
we're all on the dole!
- It's hardly depressing in here,
it looks like 3 Ross' employees...
- President, it so kind to come
to see the small workers
- Hi youngsters!
- Tell me, Jeff, we've been phoned
by Dulère: it's not right
- Jean-François, what stage
are you at with Madone?
- Precisely, we're in
the middle of a meeting
We're on a lot more
federative concept
We're at that stage
- Oh, really, we're
at that stage?
- We got your green
light, Marc?
- it's swotting? uh?
- it's swotting hard!
hey that's good...
- Hey Cuddly is not punchy...
- Stop with it, you idiot,
you're gonna kill it,
stop doing that, it,s gonna
choke, I tell you
- Hey, we should already
be shooting, now!
and your bullshit!
Fuck, we are done now!
We lose Madone,
it's direct layoff...
But you don't give a fuck,
anyway, you'll always find a job
At least, move your ass
for the others!
I don't even
talk about me
anyway, I know you despise me,
you don't like me,
I'm just a little shitty
salesman, that's it?
Think about low wages,
small posts, they will pay the price
Jacqueline, at the accountancy,
with her handicapped kid
45 years old, you think
she will find a job?
She can still dream on!
...and Momo who cleans your shit up
every evening, your coke, your porn mags
He also can still dream on!
Be humans, fuck!
Of course, it feels weird to him,
realising he will shortly be homeless
J.- F. Marolle has been programmed
for a streetless existence
He has accepted being insulted
and humiliated, during 15 years,
by his employers and his clients,
to be able to borrow money from the Bank
in order to acquire 3 rooms
in Levalois-Perret.
- That's fine, come on
we go, uh?
- ok
- Come on, it's good, stand up
He freaks out so much, he would
almost become touching
- So... The last-minute dung, ok?
- Absolutely
- The dung...
- A charming woman,
- neither too old,
nor too young
- neither blonde nor dark
- chestnut?
- dark
- ... Performs small dance steps,
wearing a tutu
- ah no, no, no, a Vanna
White's little shirt
- I take
She is on a beautiful
seaside house's terrace
decorated like in...
- "Friends"
- warm without being flashy
she looks at the camera,
she exclaims with a voice...
- suave but authentical...
- I'm pretty aren't it?
no, I'm told I'm pretty...
I'm said to be pretty,
- but I don't ask myself the question
- I'm quite simply myself!
She grabs a Starlight pot
she delicately opens
- Neither too fast nor to slow,
- before enjoying a spoonful
- She closes her eyes with pleasure,
while enjoying the product
- That's good,
- in passing, plan on 2 seconds,
at least...
- minimum, uh...
- Then, she looks straight
to the camera:
"My secret is...
- Starlight!"
Scuse me...
- Starlight...
- So there you put
the product demo...
with 6 white cheeses, fat-free,
with calcium, vitamins, proteins,
to be healthy in head and body
there's nothing better...
- They will adore...
- She resumes;
Here is my secret,
- but it's no more,
since I told you all!
- Impish laugh,
- Not too much...
- Packshot, "Starlight to stay slim
except inside your head "
- It's awesome;
guys you blew me away!
- it's in your email
- Dulère is gonna shit in
his pants, when he sees this
- You have no self-esteem,
I despise you, bite it
- They're gonna go mad!
- Run away!
- Uh Charly, we gonna bugger
Madone once again...
What?! yeah
I'm coming, bitch...
- Go check your emails out
You idiot,
she's dead
- I'm a daddy,
she's pregnant!
- it's not true!
It's working, it's true?
- You never thought of being a model?
- rather a comedian, it's my dream
I do lots of castings, but
there are too many girls
I heard I'm too "exotic"
- If someday I hear of stuff, would you
like me to pull the strings for you?
You know, I'm an
important person
- I'll make you 10%
on your blow jobs
That's true, to a professionnal like Tamara,
Octave is a puzzling customer
He asks her to wear Obsession,
Sophie's perfume
She appeases him
Tamara is the call-girl
he doesn't fuck
- Come on
wait wait ola, softly,
light, light, cruising,
respect yourself
you got beautiful hair
- That's additions
- You got beautiful eyes
- That's lenses
- You've got beautiful breasts
- It's a wonderbra
- You got beautiful legs
- aah, at last a compliment!
- Stop!
Why are you whoring?
You're unhappy?
- I'm never unhappy
When I do...
- To me it's the opposite, I call you
not to be unhappy
It's beautiful
- You think some day
we'll make love?
- Call me back, Sophie,
I regret...
Octave it's Jeff, I hope you
had my messages on your cellphone,
anyway your voicemail is full,
anyway, I wanted to tell you
I made Tamara come,
the actress you told me about
by the way, she is terrific, if you
can call me back that would be nice
IT'S THE FIRST AND LAST TIME
YOU SEE YOUR DAUGHTER. Sophie
It's 18:00, you can pass by
at the office,
I hope you don't have
personal worries
Octave, It's Jeff again, call me
back, I went out to have a run
I passed by back at the office, I try
to call you on your cellphone
So, Octave, I've called all Paris clubs,
you're not under the tables
It would be nice of you to call me back,
I hope you have no worries...
- Octave! Fuck!
where have you been?
Where have you been?
You have had my mess...?
- Leave me alone!
I'm on a bad...
- Darling, Eric Won the match!
- I scored 3 goals!
- Eric has won the match!
There, honey. A beautiful chocolate bar,
filled with good milk moss for your growth
- Hello!
- Have you seen a cute chick passing, here,
leaving from here, she was in yellow
- ah, ah, Eric has won the match!
- I scored 3 goals!
- Ok, it's over, you can leave, you can
stop, all is over, you can go back home,
All that's here doesn't exist!
Look at yourselves,
you match with nothing,
your aspect, your hairdos,
your white teeth, everything,
the blotch, here; dirt with
clean around, it doesn't exist,
nobody, blotches himself like that,
you understand?
- Eric has won the match!
- Look at your mouths,
you are Danish,
You're overdub
You're not synchro, I am.
I've got a microphone, you understand?
- Eric has won the match!
- I scored 3 goals!
- What match? Fuckin' shit!
What match?
What sort of match? Foot,
tennis, waterpolo? What...?
The numbers of birds in here, it's crazy!
What's your food like?
- A beautiful chocolate bar,
filled with good milk moss
for your growth
- Could you turn that
music off, it's a pain...
- You're walking on crosses,
This orange juice is fake,
this plate is glued, look,
there's a technician here, look
there are cameras everywhere!
look! look, go away...
ah yeah, look!
Look!
What are these rails here?!
we'll tumble down!
- Hello girls
- Hello Jeff
Here, at the Ross and Witchcraft,
the customer is always right
and the customer is you
Stéphanie, give me the call!
Yes, Jean-Christian,
how is the little family?
You'll always have
the last word
Yes, I read your proposition,
It's really a great idea!
Ah yes, it's terrific,
really. Good bye!
See you Wednesday!
Even if it's not your job,
we'll make you feel important
You won't come to us
only by chance
The World is a concept
and your concept will be ours
- It feels good
For my anus, I use R n' W, "Smell and Flavour",
thereby, with one touch
I keep my anus and my breath fresh...
- It's charming... relax, try to
quiet down, it's gonna be alright
try to appease yourself,
I'm here, I'll be just behind
the ambulance...
- He's gonna die!
- it's ok, it's ok,
- Go away, go away!
- Let him breathe!
Here we go
- Prepare me some adrenalin,
- block, block
- Charge
- We're losing him
Octave is back from the dead
To him, life without cocaine
is nearly a discovery
It's a bit like a life
without TV to others
Everything is slower,
and it quickly gets boring
He tells himself, maybe that's the secret
that would save the world:
accepting boredom
...Not easy...
Jeff never held a grudge
towards him for the punch
Finally, he's nice Jeff
- He looks fine, uh?
- Not so much
- Yes, he looks fine
Octave and Jeff could die together...
It would be good for society
- Octave, you're ok?
You look really well today
It's a pleasure
- It's a pleasure to see you
I have something to tell you
- Well, we'll talk in the car
- I'll take your bag
- Him, Octave's new friend...
it's Pyjamaman
Marc Maronnier is dead.
Octave and the other people
from the agency were
shocked by Marc's Suicide
but to say his gesture
surprised them, would be a lie
- I was feeling it coming
- I didn't expect it at all
- I expected it. Now, to speak of
positive things, at Madone they are 100%...
At the agency everything's going as
expected with Starlight
The train of mediocrity,
hasn't run a minute late
Rather, It has even got ahead:
page setting of the dung
presenting at Madone
appreciating at 200%
buying of even more
broadcasting spaces
congratulating
treating genius
- Sophie? You have news?
- Precisely,
- She went away to Canada,
She has resigned
Marc was fired.
At the agency seminary,
on the beach, at sunset
he shot a bullet in his head
In advertising, when one's self joins
up with Spacetime's Matrix
there are no articles in the papers,
no half-mast posters,
no souvenir show,
only unsold stock options remain
When a publicist joins up with god,
he's replaced with a live publicist
Marc, I'll avenge you
- Watch out, it's fragile...
Arriving at the PPM,
PPM it means, in American,
Pre Production Meeting
It's to say the last meeting where all the
details are decided before the shooting
At the top of the meeting syndrome,
the one who's just 34 years old,
and who already speaks to herself.
It's Fabienne, the tv-prod
Always under Prozac,
she always does her best
It's tiring her enormously,
but it's the same for us
- Right, before starting this meeting,
I'd like us to have a moments thought
for Marc Maronnier, who left us
tragically some days ago
A thought for the great professional
he was, but above all for the man
Concerning the Jean Christian's
confirmation mail, shooting list details...
It was phone contacts for the
shooting, everybody agree with it?
- It must be 'yoghurt in your life'
moreover, the laptop on the table idea
for the packshot... it's perfect, it's modern
It makes it catch...
Giovanni what does he think about it?
- Giovanni M. Dulère
Him, it's Giovanni Del Toro, he has
been chosen cause he is very pro
Translate: He bows down to the agency
- If everybody agrees, we can
proceed to casting now, Charly...
Now at this moment, the Client
must choose the human being
who will best embody his product...
it's always a bit of a sensitive point
- These are our 2 choices
for the Starlight woman
Jennifer you can reach at 88-60-90
We love her, she is fresh,
she is modern
- What's that mess?
What's that black?
Jeff, restrain your guys, cuz
we're again starting off with...
Scuse me, I'm not racist, but no...
at a pinch, the day we bring
a Starlight Chocolate out
why not, but here, it's not my fault
if our youghurt is white
Blacks - It's too much segmenting
- it produces too much anxiety
- I'm ok to be open-minded,
but there are limits...
- So we reach too much africanity,
not enough francity, we agree?
- Too much africanity, not enough...
- africanity, not enough francity,
- There, it's better, that's better,
it's even really good,
she is really good that Tarama...
- Tamara
- Yes, Trama...
- Superb, she's totally
in the brand values
- it's Madone's proper image
it's superb
- it's different?
- it's different
Excuse me, she looks less
prostitute than the previous one
- That's right
- It's completely Starlight
- That's no more and no less than
Jennifer Lopez, more junior, more trendy
- It wouldn't be still
too much africanity?
- You can brighten her face
a little, in post-prod?
- Completely, we'll rework the tone,
during the calibration, no problem
- Ok Bingo!
That's her
- So, we optionalize it
The meeting lasted 7 hours,
7 hours of jerk-off
with some piece of bravery...
- Gagnant, anything else?
- Eh, yes, important,
- I'd like us to validate the
green density of the lawn, now
Well in brief, it's bootlickin'
it's titillating, it's nit-picking
it's diddling at night,
as usual,
and during office hours...
- up, up, down,
right, right, up, up, up,...
It looks as if it were nothing,
that small meeting, to you,
completely surrealist and entertaining
and yet...
- It's not for you, there will
be chocolate, after and before
- Not a custard tart!
- It will be after
- Chocolate mousse!
- Stop it kids, stop it,
that's enough kids!
Pay less, less,
it's cheaper for you
- Validated, perfect!
- I think we're totally focused, here
- 7 hours meeting, I think we did a good job
- I personally really enjoyed myself,
- Good, there will be fewer
- really, really good meeting, Corinne,
I like your work a lot
- No but my name is Fabienne,
- Welcome to the Ross
- I've been working here for 5 years
- Look at this! Octave is
already set to go to Miami
He has ready his little bag,
bloody Octave!
- Tamara it's really good, honestly,
come on spit!
There, softly...
- Still respect yourself...
It's really good,
but just a little bit
greedier, please,
offer it to us, give it to me,
greedier,
think about closing your eyes
when swallowing, ok?
- Yes,
- One has to feel the
pleasure in your throat
come on, act it for me,
right, close you eyes
while swallowing
you take your time,
That was good
what you did in the end
really good, more smiley
at the end than at the start
that's the product benefit, that makes
you fresh, happy and blooming, ok?
We're here, we rule,
of course you keep it inside,
but you give to the other, you rule,
you take, without ever...
because otherwise we are...
but, raise the product up
There, mysterious, that's right
look at the product, look at us
and offer Starlight!
There that's it!
We do it again
- it's really...
- It's good?
- Huge, nothing to do...
don't you think?
- Superb
It was the last take of the day,
and the most important for an ad film;
the 'packshot'
Hours of lighting, each minor detail
matters, yoghurt choice, the spoon...
In fact, the jerk-off's Everest
- Best thing is to do a wrap up
on Starlight, I think...
- It's really well done!
- All right
- No, that's shit and you know it
You see the two fuckers, there?
- I've always known we
could count on him
- I want to make them cry.
After the take,
you hang on with the chief
cameraman for 10 minutes
We'll shoot our version
of stuff never done before.
A commando operation
- With what he's put in his turbinate bone,
he won't go far...
- He's an artist, it works
like that with artists
Simple customer,
we'll find another one
Octave I wanted to tell you
how much you impressed me
Thank you, Octave, thank you
for your involvement
I know this script wasn't
your favourite...
You played the game
as a great professional
Obviously, Alfred Dulère
is a big prick even abroad
- See you soon
- See you very soon
- So, we've got a plane to take
- Yes, didn't you want
to salute Tamara?
- Oh, yes Tamara... yes,
Gagnant! I leave you my house keys
Details Diana, details!
- Buddy, come see. You're ready?
- Yes
- You're ready?
- Wait, wait, They propose to us
the creative director post
250,000 F per month, plus expense claims,
paid apartment, company Porsches
company bitches, stock options,
well there, Everests of coke
- No
- But yes, you must say yes!
- No, no, no
- Why?
- Because I've got more of a
turn-on, that's more revolutionary
- That's what?
- After...
- We do the packshot
- No, skip it, this movie is shit
- But it's important, the packshot!
- After Fabienne, after
US
We have succeeded
Our version was in the can,
we were kings, we were the greatest
Here it is, I was a comeback
- That's weird, that stuff
doesn't seem to get any bigger...
- Try again
- May I serve you something?
Tea, coffee?
Madam, sir, would you like a drink?
I stayed cloistered at home,
crying and systematically stumbling
upon Sophie's answerphone
In the meantime, Charly, that fuckhead,
had already answered for us both,
I just had to sign the papers
Visually, Creative Director
initials makes D.C.
Young blood at R.&W.
- ahh, you're no dorks!
You could have smiled a bit more,
but you are no dorks!
It's in behalf of all at Ross that I raise
my glass to our two new Creative Directors:
Octave and Charly
Yes Stephanie, wait, speak louder...
- Come on,
- What the cops!?
- have a drink
- Well, ok, let them come up, yeah
Police want to see you,
They're coming up
- Hello,
- Hello Octave, Mrs and Mr. Lacase
on the phone, Sophie's parents
- Oh hi, how are you?
- Inspector Parretti. We come for
Octave Parengo and Charly
- We heard your messages,
on Sophie's mobile phone
and we don't really understand
Our daughter commited suicide,
Octave
- Wanted for murder
- it's because of you,
She commited suicide in Senegal
with her friend, Marc,
you understand?
She fired a gun's bullet in her face, Octave
- I understand
- It's better. Can I
call you back later?
Cuz I'm here at
a meeting now,
I can't really answer you.
I'll call you back on Tuesday,
ok? Kisses...
- Octave you're fired!
- Now it's too late, it had to be
done earlier, I'm sorry...
- This boy is a real shit
- what are you doing here?
- I quit my life, by myself!
- Get him! he's buggering off!
- Wait, it's ok, it's ok
- Get him!
- it's alright
- I've an idea, I'm gonna...
- You stay here!
- It's locked!
- Tamara, Alfred,
Alfred Dulère,
Tell-me, would you fancy
a small dinner at the silver tower,
one of these evenings?
And I have a little surprise for you
- Put your gun away
- Parengo don't mess up!
Come back Parengo!
Don't do it, I tell you!
Give me your hand,
stop that!
Everything is temporary:
Love, Art, planet Earth
You, me
particulary me.
PROJECTION TEST
You're part of a pre-test panel
Option END n°2
- Octave, fuck, I am in a mid-bad,
an enormous bad... I'm not fine at all
- Yes good evening, do you want
champagne? Amuse la bouche?
- Thanks madam
- I didn't come here to croak with you,
There's a little girl waiting for me
in Morocco. All I do is for her.
- What's that?
- Vomit. You both swallowed
that shit together
- You puked on yourselves
- Fuck, Octave, I believed
we had killed people
I believed we were pursued by the cops,
I was really scared, no joke...
- Me too
- Come here
At this instant, we were beautiful inside
but pitiful outside...
- Stop laughing! Fuck!
Deep inside us, very deeply,
it was a new birth
The universe was offering
us a second chance
- Thank you
- And, there is your bag...
- No, that's fine, I'll take it,
thank you
Dulère had to be blasted...
Then I'd disappear, very quickly
To help me transmit the commercial,
I contacted the AAF guys,
the Anti-Ads Front, a small secret activist
group, Charly dug out on the internet
- You behave exactely like them, here...
Watch out Seb...
- Like them, Why?
- Excuse me to tell you that, but you
do verbal marketing here
- Wait, I'm doing verbal marketing?!
You know what you're saying here?
- A terrorist attack should be tried
Like Hud, he had gotten a good job,
at the Channel 1 Ad section
It's him who broadcasted
the film.
Here it is, Octave is dead,
and so is his car
But I couldn't leave this world,
without savouring my victory
- Excuse me president...
Yes? Well, ok, of course...
Can you turn on the television
on the first channel?
- My pleasure, sir
- It's good, we're watching
- Here it is, thank you
It will be awesome,
director!
We'll rip the other agencies up!
Tests are super positives,
I think we can say it
- Yes my dear
- Finally, they're friendly,
and we live for great things
- Look my dear, I think
it's going to begin
- Sorry... I feel stupid, I'll do it again
- Hello, here is Starlight
A new diet yoghurt that's strictly
without any relevance
So why are we trying
to sell it to you?
Because we've got goals...
We have numbers to make
What did you think?
You think we're having fun, here?
- You know how much it costs to
buy 30 seconds of people's brains?
Who's watching TV at this hour?
400.000 French
So how do we do it all?
With what do we pay for all this?
And our executives,
how do we pay them?
Wait, our CEO for example,
whose salary is nearly a closed secret
Burkina Faso PIB, eh?
What do we pay him with?
Where do we find the cash?
And our shareholders?
The investors?
How do we do it? How do we?
How do we?
- Fuck, that's disgusting!
So now, turn your lil' TV off,
take your lil' coin holder,
and go directly to the
supermarket to buy off the stocks
12,000 tons are to be gobbled up!
Madone. Buy it, otherwise
it won't sell up
Who is slim in his head?
- Anyway, we can't say you give
your customers shit...
I was savouring my revolution,
I was disappearing... Far
learn to live differently
My friend Pyjamaman told
me about the jungle
Each year, the world-wide budget
spent on advertising
exceeds 500 billion dollars.
An UN study estimates that
only 10% of that amount
would be necessary to reduce starvation
in the world by a half