I am actress Milla Jovovich,
and I will be portraying.
Dr. Abigail Tyler
in The Fourth Kind.
This film is a dramatization
of events that occurred October 1st
through the 9th of 2000,
in the northern
Alaskan town of Nome.
To better explain
the events of the story,
the director has included actual
archived footage
throughout the film.
This footage was acquired from
Nome psychologist Dr. Abigail Tyler,
who has personally documented over
65 hours of video and audio materials
during the time of the incidents.
To better protect their privacy,
we have changed
the names and professions
of many of the people involved.
Every dramatized scene
in this movie is supported
by either archived audio, video,
or as it was related
by Dr. Tyler
during extensive interviews
with the director.
In the end, what you believe
is yours to decide.
Please be advised
that some of what
you are about to see
is extremely disturbing.
Just relax,
and I'll ask you questions,
and whenever, whatever
you want to toss in there.
Okay. You all right?
Okay.
I'm going to try
and make this as painless
as possible.
Can you state your
name for the camera?
Dr. Abigail Emily Tyler.
Okay, where would
you like to begin?
I guess..
After what happened with Will,
my husband, I..
I went to my friend, who is
also a psychologist, Dr..
because I was having trouble
dealing with how he..
With how it happened
and who did it.
You don't think you might
need more time?
No, this is something..
I have to do this. I..
I have to remember his face.
I need it for myself to heal.
I have to try, and I have to
know that, for my children,
that I did everything
that I could
to remember.
..to remember.
You know, since that night,
Ashley still can't see,
and I don't think that she's
gonna get her sight back
if she doesn't accept
what happened.
Well, I think you both have the same
problem, just different symptoms.
Yeah, and I think
that it could help
if I could just remember
the face of that man,
so we could somehow..
track him down and..
set the record straight
and find some closure.
All right. All right.
Do you want it on video?
Yeah.
Counseling..
a fellow psychologist is like..
It's like talking to myself.
You always say that.
I do? My God.
All right.
I guess just try to relax and
get yourself comfortable.
Listen to the sound of my voice
as I count back.
10..
9..
8, 7, 6..
Your eyes are getting heavier..
and heavier.
5, 4.
They're almost closed.
3, 2
and 1.
1.
Very good, Abbey.
Very good.
Let's go back in time..
back into the past..
to the night of August 2nd
of this year.
What was the weather like?
Warm.
Warmer than usual,
even though it's raining outside.
Okay, good.
Now, let's go back to when
you were with Will,
just before the intruder
entered your room.
We're making love.
It's nice.
It's so.. It's so nice.
He's falling asleep.
Good. So what happens..
What happened next?
I'm awake.
I'm wide awake,
and we're just
lying here.
What woke you up?
God!
Someone stabbed him
in the chest! My God!
Blood everywhere.
There's blood everywhere.
Try to see his face.
I can't see it.
My husband!
It just feels like I can't move.
I can't see it.
It feels like we're frozen.
Abbey. Abbey,
Abbey. Abbey.
It's all over me!
All over me.
Focus on my voice.
You will be awakened
and conscious
in 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Abbey. Here. Let me.
If I could just see his face.
He was killed, and I
was right there, Abel.
I was right there.
Yeah, you know,
it's as natural to feel guilt
as it is unnatural to
feel it was your fault.
You know that.
Yeah, okay. Okay.
I think you might want to
consider taking some time off.
Real time, you know?
Because it just might help you
find clarity with what happened.
I have to continue this study.
It meant a lot to Will,
and he would have
wanted me to continue.
Now, why did I know
you were gonna say that?
He would have wanted me
to try and finish it
as soon as I could.
It meant a lot to him.
And how long had it been
at this point
since Will had passed away?
2 months.
And you guys were already
back to school,
and the kids were already
back to school?
I had to try
and get some
normality back into life.
I didn't know what else to do.
Is Nome a place you
can drive into or..
No, you have to fly around.
Okay.
You can't get there by road.
Any messages?
No, but Scott's waiting
in your office,
and you have
a 1:00 and a 2:00.
Thank you.
So, how was it coming in?
It was a little bumpy.
You'd think as beautiful
as that sky is
that it wouldn't be so rough.
The stuff that really shakes us..
We seldom ever see coming.
I know, I know.
It's a good saying.
Not every week.
Hi, Scott.
Sorry I'm late.
Hey, Dr. Tyler.
I flew up to Anchorage
this morning,
so I'm having a bit
of a slow start.
Please, sit down and make
yourself comfortable.
How are you?
I'm all right.
Have you been sleeping?
It's.. It's worse.
I wake up in the middle of the night
almost every night,
and I just lie there.
What time does this
normally occur?
Around 2:30, 3:00
in the morning.
And there's nothing unusual
waking you up?
No, nothing.
It's just there's..
There's one thing.
There's an owl at my window.
An owl?
A white owl.
It was just looking at me.
How long was it there?
Hours.
No matter what I did,
it wouldn't fly away.
It wasn't scared of me.
What was it doing?
Just staring at me.
Had you ever seen it before?
Yeah.
Once when I was a kid.
That was the first time?
I guess I've seen it a lot.
How much is a lot?
Every night this week.
Every night?
You mean every time
you go to bed?
I think it came inside.
Was your window open?
No.
I wonder how it got in.
I don't know, but I remember it
looking down at me.
Over your bed?
Yeah, I think so.
I..
It's really hard to remember.
It's almost like..
Like it didn't happen.
Like, you know, in a dream.
Like I just dreamt it.
Can you come see me tomorrow?
Sure, if you think I should,
or if it's important.
Yeah, I do.
I do think it's important,
and it's nothing to be
alarmed at, at all,
but there have been some
strange coincidences here,
and I just.. I feel like I need
to try something new.
What do you mean?
You're not the first patient
I've had
who's experienced
something like this.
I felt so sorry for my baby,
and I feel responsible.
Can you just knock it off?
Conversion disorder
is not a phenomenon
that a lot of
people understand,
and we've had to make
quite an adjustment.
When did Ashley go blind?
After what happened to Will,
she just lost her sight.
Hey, baby.
Hi, Mommy.
How was rehearsal
for the play?
Hey, what's wrong?
Nothing.
Come on.
Come on, cough it up.
What happened?
Ralph called me a faker.
What? A faker?
He said that I could see before,
and now I was just pretending.
What a jerk.
He said that I just wanted
everybody
to feel sorry for me
because of Daddy.
Dear Lord, thank you
for everything we have.
Please continue
to bless our family,
and please continue to help Ashley
overcome her challenges,
and help all of us to heal.
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
Amen.
Hey, what time is the game
tomorrow?
7:00.
And who are you playing again?
I already told you, Browerville.
Well, I'm sorry, sweetie.
I must have forgot.
Dad never forgot.
Yeah, and Dad's not here anymore.
No, he's not.
Can you accept it yet?
Okay, Ronnie, not in front of
your sister, okay?
We'll talk about it later.
What do you mean?
Nothing, honey.
How Dad died.
All right, Ronnie.
What is wrong with you?
You go around helping other
people with their problems..
Stop it.
Stop it!
But you can't even
help yourself.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
Ronnie.
Mommy?
What did..
What does he mean?
And do you think he,
in any way,
may have blamed you for
Will's death?
Yes, he did blame me,
and he said that..
that I couldn't help.. him
or Ashley or anyone,
and he was right.
A small number
continue to experience
debilitating sleep disorders,
and this seems to be the trend
throughout Nome,
and a cause remains unknown.
Even during the night months,
they can't sleep.
We've seen over 300 people
throughout Nome
who are all exhibiting
the same symptoms.
Around 3:00 in the morning, they are
awakened for no apparent reason,
and they wake up apprehensive,
frightened, panicked,
as if something's about to happen.
Whether or not this is related..
Daddy?
To the missing people
or disappearances..
No, my baby,
it's just a recording
of Daddy's voice.
Come over here.
I got you.
Come up on the bed.
My angel.
Okay, you're doing
real good, Tommy.
When I get to one,
you will be asleep,
very, very relaxed.
4, 3,
2 and 1.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
And when was the last time
you had trouble sleeping?
Last night.
And did you see the owl?
Yeah.
Good. And..
what did it look like?
Tommy?
I..
I don't remember.
You don't remember
what the owl looks like?
No.
No, I don't see the owl.
I don't see the owl now.
It's not there anymore.
Did it fly away?
No, I think it's..
No,
I think it's..
I don't really remember it..
ever being there.
There's something outside my door.
It's gonna open it.
The door's opening.
My God.
My God!
No.
What's wrong?
Jesus!
Tommy, what's wrong?
No, no, no!
No, no!
No, no, no! No, no, no!
Okay, Tommy, when I count to 3,
you will awaken.
No, no, no!
To conscious..
No!
3.
No, no! No!
3!
No!
Tommy, it's not happening.
It's a memory.
This is not real.
It is real.
Did I do that?
Yeah, you did, Tommy,
but it's okay. It's okay.
What did you see?
Nothing.
What?
You said you saw something.
No, I didn't see anything.
I didn't see anything.
I'm just trying to help you.
If you want to help me,
get me out of this room.
I need to go home.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Tommy, are you trying
to convince me or you?
Did you see what was
bothering you at night?
Did you see the owl?
Can we talk about this next time?
Yeah, of course.
Sure.
Talk to me when you need to.
Yeah. Okay.
Call in EMTs, Search, everybody.
I want everybody.
Transfer me into that house.
Right now.
Tommy here.
Yeah, what's going on
in there?
I want to talk to Abbey Tyler.
Abbey?
Abbey's not here right now,
but I can help you.
I have to talk to her!
Hello?
I need you down here
at Tommy's house.
August?
He's gone crazy.
He's holding his family hostage,
and he's asking for you.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Bring her up here.
She's here right now.
We'll walk her up to you, okay,
Tommy? It's gonna be all right.
Just give her the phone.
I want to talk to her.
Both arms out.
Both arms out. She's here.
Put her on the phone right now.
I'm gonna do it right now, okay?
Is this really necessary?
I want to talk to her! Can somebody
tell me what's going on?
Where is she?
Take it easy, all right?
I don't see her. Get her up here!
August, what's going on?
I need you to calm him down
and get him thinking rationally.
He's got Sarah, Timothy
and Joe lined up
in the kitchen with
a gun to their heads,
and he wants to talk to you
for some reason, all right?
Watch your step.
Straight this way.
Tommy? Tommy, what..
What's going on here?
I'm so sorry,
but I've gotta do this.
I don't have a choice.
It was completely surreal
to be there in the middle of the night
with all those police trucks.
I don't have a choice.
No, no, no.
You have a choice, Tommy.
We always have a choice.
Not this time.
Please, Tommy!
Yes. Yes, you do.
You have the choice
right now to just..
To just stop.
Just put down the gun, Tommy.
You have it within your power
to just stop.
Please, before somebody gets hurt.
Tommy, look at Sarah, Tommy.
Look at..
Look at your wife.
Look at your children, Tommy.
It's okay.
You would never let anything
happen to them.
You love them so much.
I know what keeps us up
at night.
And if you saw what I saw,
you would understand.
What did you see, Tommy?
It doesn't matter,
because we're not gonna
have to see it ever again.
Just wait, Tommy.
I can help you.
Just talk to me, okay?
We'll talk as long as you need to.
We'll get through this, Tommy.
If anybody's got a clear shot,
take it now.
Negative.
I don't have a clear shot, sir.
The wife is blocking him.
And he wasn't listening to me.
Do you know what
Zimabu Eter means?
And they were going to kill him.
What? Wait. I can't hear you,
Tommy. What?
Has anybody
got the shot?
Zimabu Eter!
What the hell does that mean?
Zimabu Eter? I don't know, Tommy.
Anybody got the goddamn shot?
But I can find out.
Just give me a little time.
I need to know now!
I will find out for you.
I promise.
No, please!
You can't help me.
I love you.
Move, move!
Move, move, move!
Tommy! God damn it!
I'm having a hard time
understanding what
happened here.
I know. I know.
You don't know what he saw?
So you have no idea what he saw?
He didn't tell me.
What did he tell you?
That what he thought he saw
wasn't an owl.
That it was something else.
And that's what was
keeping him up at night?
Yeah.
So he was under hypnosis
when he saw this?
Yeah.
And how do you know what
he saw was real?
I don't know that it was.
So what you're saying is that
Tommy might have done all of this
based on something
that was imaginary.
All I know is that he believed
what he saw,
and there was more fear
in his eyes
than I've ever seen in my life.
Had you not hypnotized him,
do you think he would
have done this?
What do you mean?
I'm just wondering,
without this hypnotism,
do you think he still would
have murdered his family?
That is a ridiculous
and offensive question.
No, what's ridiculous
and offensive
is that an entire family is
lying in a morgue
from a murder-suicide,
and the last
meaningful contact
that the murderer
had was with you.
No, what happened tonight
would have manifested itself
eventually.
He was suppressing something.
Look, in 13 years of practice,
I've never witnessed something
to this extent.
Abbey, why didn't you contact us
if you suspected he was unstable
after an admittedly violent episode?
He was completely coherent
when he left my office.
Now, I had no reason
to suspect..
I called his wife to ask her
to keep an eye on him.
And now she's dead.
Okay, I'm not going
to sit here and listen
to how hypnosis-induced
murder caused this.
Jesus, I am trying to find out..
This is ridiculous.
What caused one of the worst
murders in the history of Nome.
There's something going on in this
town that we don't understand.
There's something happening
to people in their sleep..
Well, I don't know
about any of that!
I don't understand
what you're talking about!
I don't deal in hallucinations.
I don't deal in the visions
in the ether.
What in the hell are you
talking about?
I'm dealing in real flesh
and blood things,
4 of whom are lying on
slabs next door.
How dare you? My husband
was lying on one of those slabs
and you still
haven't found his killer.
Abbey, now, you know damn well
what happened to Will.
That case is closed.
No, you cannot
file things away
without getting to
what really happened.
Now, there are more unsolved murders
and missing people in Nome..
Sit down.
Than any other town in Alaska,
3 years of which have been
under your watch.
Now, what is happening
in this town is very real,
and it must be acknowledged.
Sit down!
You stop whatever this
governmental study is,
this hypnosis, whatever it is,
whatever you and
Will were after.
It's bringing nothing but bad news
to a town that's had enough.
Now, I don't care how
important it is to you.
I don't care how hard you've
worked on it. I don't care.
You're not gonna use the people
of Nome for a goddamn rat study.
I felt responsible for..
death, and his family's.
And at the time,
after all that happened,
I still didn't know why he did it.
All of the patients reported
seeing the same owl,
but Tommy mentioned
that his memory
of the owl was wrong
and that he didn't
see it anymore.
It was some sort of
false recollection.
The question is,
if under hypnosis,
will the others feel the same way?
Will they see what he saw?
We have to proceed
with extreme caution.
What happened here
remains unexplained,
like Will.
Abel?
I heard what happened. I just
wanted to make sure you were okay.
Hey. You flew all
the way up here?
That's all right.
That's okay.
I'm worried about you.
You didn't have to.
I'm fine.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You want to talk?
I can't. I can't cancel
my schedule.
Theresa, good morning. Can you
transcribe this for me, please?
Do you want me to
cancel your meetings?
No, no. Thank you.
So, how you feeling?
I feel like I just need to
start my day.
Yeah.
Maybe it's..
You think it's
time that you, maybe,
stepped back?
Maybe consider it a sabbatical?
I love that word.
It doesn't actually sound like
what it means, which is "time off."
Abbey, listen, you need to step
away for perspective,
clarity on what's happened.
I mean, you can't
continue like this.
No, I can, and I have to.
It's the only thing
I have within my power.
It's all I have left,
is to continue,
to find out what's
causing all of this.
I can't.. I don't..
I don't believe that it can be
just chalked up to coincidence,
what happened to Will, what
happened to Tommy and his family.
I don't.
Not in this town.
Do you mind if I stay on a bit?
Just kept an eye on you,
since you're not too keen
on doing it yourself?
It's all right.
So, lots to talk about.
What happened to Tommy?
I can't discuss..
He's dead. You should be able
to discuss everything.
It had something..
I believe..
that it had something to do
with his sleeping habits.
We're really worried, obviously.
It's the second suicide
in a couple of months.
I understand.
We want you to
hypnotize me, too.
We need to know if there's
anything I'm not remembering,
and I feel..
We feel like the best thing
to do is to face it.
We've already thought it over.
If you want to undergo this,
we're gonna have to go
about this very delicately.
Would it be all right if a colleague
of mine, Dr. Campos,
came in to observe?
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
5. Deeper.
Deeper. You're totally relaxed.
4, 3, 2 and 1.
So, when was the last time
you had trouble sleeping?
Last night.
And do you remember seeing
anything unusual last night?
An owl.
Tell me about the owl.
It's a beige owl.
Its eyes are big, like..
I don't know.
It doesn't look like a normal owl.
Scott?
There is no owl.
It's not..
Honey, honey,
honey, wake up.
You hear that?
Wake up.
She's not..
She's not waking up.
Someone's outside the door.
Tell me what you see.
Something's out there.
Can you see who it is?
Not who, what.
I know what they are.
They come all the time
since I was little.
What are they?
They're gonna open the door.
They get in without
setting off the alarm.
I armed it. I know..
I know I did.
I thought they only come
when I think about them,
but I wasn't thinking about
them tonight.
Okay, Scott, I'm gonna count to 3,
and you're gonna wake up.
1, 2, 3!
Scott! Scott!
Scott, wake up!
Here you go.
Go ahead.
I'm sorry.
It's unbelievable.
It doesn't make any sense.
Scott, you don't have to rush.
Whenever you're ready,
you can tell us what you saw.
I saw them.
Who's them?
They're not from here.
What do you mean?
I can't describe it.
I can't see what's in my own mind.
I can't control it.
All I can see is the owl,
but I..
I know it's not an owl,
I remember the smell, like a..
Like a putrid cinnamon.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
The worst part
was the voice inside my head,
like..
'Cause they
talk to you
so you can hear them,
but..
They also talk inside your mind,
like you're connected
or something.
And they take me away to somewhere,
but I can't remember,
and I can't remember
what they do to me.
Okay, okay, Scott,
that's enough for today.
I'm so sorry.
It's gonna be all right.
Cindy, under the circumstances,
I'm going to contact
Sheriff August
to let him know that we've met
and let him know that
we've had this session.
Yeah, please do.
Okay.
Now, I know why..
did what he did.
Why?
You'd have to have seen it,
felt it, what it is.
What is it?
The worst.
Of what?
That you could..
You could ever imagine.
Come on.
Babe, let's go home.
We're going home.
What the hell was that?
Abel.
Do you believe in
abduction theories?
What do you mean,
like kidnappings?
Yeah.
No. No,
not..
Not kidnappings,
but abduction, as in..
You don't mean alien abductions,
do you?
Well, you know, I think that
might be what we just heard.
When you look at the statistics,
they're pretty impressive.
I mean, Will was kind of into that,
and he did a little research.
You know, there are
over 11 million people
that have either
reported seeing
or know someone who has seen
UFOs since the 1930s.
The idea of any of this stuff
being real is.. You can't..
Come on, Abel.
I mean, when something
boasts 11 million witnesses..
You know, that would win any
court case in the world.
Well, and there are
just as many
explanations and reasons.
Weather balloons,
atmospheric effects,
optical illusions.
In this case, perhaps,
hypnocognic hallucinations.
Listen, we have to deal with hard,
empirical evidence
and facts.
We can't..
Abbey! Abbey.
The tape.
The tape you gave
me this morning..
Wait. Slow down.
Slow down, Theresa.
What is it?
Did you listen to it?
I don't.. I don't know
what this is.
I don't know what's going on.
I don't want to listen to it again.
That was weird.
Abbey?
That's you?
That's not my voice.
That's not me.
After you heard that,
what did you, like..
How did you react?
After the initial shock,
I was in denial.
It couldn't be me,
my voice.
So, what happened next?
I went through what I could
hold onto.
Which were what?
Which were the facts.
I went home to try and recount
what happened during
the recording.
I was sleeping in my bed
when my door opened.
Someone or something came
into my room.
Did it cause that somehow?
Some kind of allergic reaction?
How long had it been there?
But whatever, whoever it was,
I fought it.
But it was too strong,
and it took me away.
The moment it became too real
was when I looked down
at the floorboards
and I saw scratches leading
all the way to the door.
I put myself
back together.
I was determined to figure out
what it was,
what came into my room,
what it was saying,
where it took me,
and what it did to me.
I listened to that
tape over and over
to figure out anything,
something to explain
what it was.
It wasn't Latin.
It wasn't Greek.
It wasn't any language
that I had heard before,
and I felt it was the key
to everything
that was happening
to me, to Will,
and everyone else in Nome.
And then I found exactly
what I was looking for.
Hello?
Hello.
Is this Dr..
Awolowa Odusami.
Yes, this is he.
Hi, I was wondering,
are you familiar with a person
named Dr. William Tyler?
No, I'm not.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
May I ask who's speaking?
I'm..
Will you tell me your name?
Hello?
Listen,
there was a man who
called me from this number.
He called himself John.
There's no John here.
Exactly, I know.
What was he.. Why was
he calling you?
He wanted to have a history
lesson on ancient languages.
Look, I..
That was my husband
that you talked to,
and he's been murdered.
Dr..
I'm sorry..
I'm sorry to hear that.
He listened to me.
Yeah.
He didn't judge me
or try to analyze me.
I just.. I need..
He just listened.
I need you to hear me out.
And then he flew over
to Nome.
I thought it was Akkadian,
but it's not.
It's Sumerian.
I'm sure of it.
This is widely considered
by my peers
to be the Holy Grail of
dead languages,
but we haven't deciphered
the entire lexicon.
"Our creation" is
the last 2 words.
I'm not sure of the first 2.
"Examine" is the 1st word.
The last word is ruin or destroy.
Our creation, examine,
ruin, or destroy.
Ruin, destroy who?
It's an incomplete translation.
We can't be sure of exactly
what's being said.
But whatever it is,
it sounds aggressive.
I'm sorry, but none of this
is any making sense.
It's a
verbalized recording
of the Sumerian
language.
Now, we're talking about the
oldest language in human history
for whatever reason
recorded in your room.
What was happening?
What was being done to me?
What is unsettling is
that whatever it is,
the vocals, they don't sound..
Ordinary.
Human?
Stop. Stop. Stop.
Okay? Let's not fuel
any more of these fires.
Now, there's
any number of reasons
for the distortion in the voice.
I'm not jumping to any conclusions,
but her voice sounded fine.
The tape could have been
recorded over, for one,
and part of the old tape
could still be heard.
No, I don't recycle tapes.
Well, maybe this time you did.
And that still does not explain
why that voice is
speaking a language
that predates
Egyptian hieroglyphics.
Now, I've studied the Sumerian
civilization for most of my career,
and what I have
found is intriguing.
You can go into
any Sumerian exhibit
and see what I am
about to tell you.
Drawings of rockets that look like
Apollo launching into the sky.
Etchings and sculptures
of men in spacesuits
and what look
like oxygen masks.
And this artwork was created
in the 4th millennium B.C.E.,
4,000 years before Christ
walked the Earth.
"Genesis", Noah's ark,
to name a few.
Both of these stories
existed in Sumer
6,000 years before
the Bible was written.
"Genesis" came from
the Sumerian epic of creation.
Noah's ark came from
the Sumerian deluge.
The alien-god legend
has its basis,
its origins, in Sumerian history.
You can find everything I've
described in a museum right now.
You know, it is one thing to
entertain wild theories,
but quite another
to invest in them.
Yes, and you're entitled
to that reaction,
but as I said from the beginning,
I draw no conclusions.
I'm dealing in facts.
Now, this is drawn from
thousands of years
of data research and collection.
How this is put together is
open to debate.
Do you honestly believe
you were forcibly
removed from your bedroom
by members of an alien race?
Hello? Abbey, can you
come over? It's Scott.
Something's wrong.
He wants you to come over. He..
Cindy? Hold on a second.
Just take a deep breath.
Hi, Cindy.
Hey.
This is Dr. Odusami.
He's here to help.
Good morning.
Come in.
Scott?
What took you
so long?
I'm sorry.
I came as quick as I could.
Last night was..
Calm down.
Calm down?
Scott.
How can I?
You don't..
Scott, I'm here, all right?
Now, you've gotta try and breathe
for me. You have to calm yourself,
because I cannot help you
if you're all wound up.
I don't want to talk about it,
but I have to.
Have to, have to, have to..
I have to, I have to, I have to..
Scott, why are you..
I have to.
What is this?
How did you get this?
I don't know. I didn't know
it was there. I just..
Okay. Can we set up
the camera, please?
No, no..
I don't need anyone..
I don't want
this getting out.
Scott, we need to record
what's happening.
We need to record
this session for study,
so we can find out
what's going on with you.
Okay, I don't want to go under.
Well, we don't have to do that.
Just try and relay
whatever you remember.
There's things I have
to remember, but I..
But I can't.
I can't without..
You know what? We can put
you under a very light hypnosis.
Okay?
But if you're worried..
I have to.
I have to remember.
I have to get
this out of my head.
It feels like it's
just dug in there
and I can't think
straight anymore.
It's okay.
I have to..
I'll do it.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Okay.
Are we ready?
It's okay.
Okay?
Relax.
Just relax.
There's a lot of people
in the room with you now.
You're not alone.
Relax.
By the time I reach one,
you will be asleep.
5, 4,
3, 2,
1.
Scott?
But where are we going?
North Carolina.
North Carolina?
What's in North Carolina?
Us, by tomorrow.
But I have a game tomorrow.
Pack your bags.
Hello? I don't think she feels
like talking to you right now.
Mommy?
Yeah, baby.
What's wrong?
Nothing, sweetie.
We're just gonna go take
a little break, okay?
It's Abel.
Tell him I'll call him back.
She'll call you back.
He says he has to talk to you.
I'll call you back, Abel.
He's already on his way.
Are we gonna see Grandma
and Grandpa?
No, baby, Grandma and Grandpa
are gone, remember?
Yeah, they're with Daddy.
I mean Grandpa
and Grandma Lilly.
No, we're not going
to see them, either.
But why not?
Baby, I'm just gonna sit you
down right here,
and you've gotta let Mommy pack,
okay? Thank you.
It's 'cause of Dad?
Ronnie, I really need you
to help me right now, okay?
Please take your
sister into her room
and help her get ready, okay?
Thank you.
Mom?
Yeah?
What did you do?
Hold on!
What happened to Scott?
August, I'm sorry.
He's paralyzed
from the neck down.
3 of the vertebrate in his neck
are completely severed!
I don't know.
You were there.
I can't explain it.
I can't..
Tell me what happened.
How'd he break his back?
I put him under,
and there was something..
something was inside of him
that twisted his body,
and that..
Something was inside of him,
and it twisted his body?
And you have proof of this?
It didn't record.
It was all distorted.
Abbey..
How in God's name am I
supposed to believe this?
I know what I saw.
Yeah, what you saw?
What you saw?
Abbey, what you're doing is
hurting people,
very obviously!
Now, my heart goes out to you,
it really does,
what you've been through.
I understand that,
but you leave me
no choice.
You have the right
to remain silent.
What?
Anything you say
or do can and will
be held against you
in a court of law.
No, stop. Stop.
You have the right to an attorney.
August.
August, please, don't do this.
Ryan!
Sheriff, no.
Ryan, you can't.
Please. You can't..
You can't take me away from my
children. August, please, don't.
August. August, I know what
this looks like.
I know what this looks like,
but I was there.
I saw it.
You were there,
and you saw what?
What did you see?
Well, it's the kind
of thing that..
Well, you'd have
to have seen it.
No. Bullshit.
Now, this woman is not
capable of committing
any physical harm
to any man.
I don't know what
she is capable of..
She's not capable.
You know. You know. Hey!
Just calm down for a second
and hear me out.
I know that what's happening
here in Nome is frightening.
I know it is.
But whatever you do,
you cannot arrest her
for something you
don't understand
just because you're terrified.
Come on.
You're pushing it.
I mean, I was there.
I saw it.
Now you're gonna take her
away from her children
for something
that she did not do.
Come on.
Let's just calm down.
Please. Please.
You will be under
24-hour supervision,
and you will not
leave these premises.
If you touch that doorknob,
I will arrest you!
I understand. Thank you.
You're coming with me.
Thank you.
Hey, look after your mom.
It's okay, sweetheart.
Ronnie.
This is Ryan, sir. I'm stationed in
front of the Tyler home.
Over.
Roger that.
But they said they were
questioned by Chief..
reminded him about
the disappearances..
What about them?
Homicides, missing people.
Dozens of them.
It's been happening
there since the 1960s,
and the FBI have been dropping in
from time to time.
Would you say..
What did they find?
Nothing. It's inconclusive.
To this day,
nothing has been solved.
What do you think it means?
How do you put it in perspective?
They have different categories
for these types of things.
Different levels.
An encounter of the 1st kind,
that's when you see a UFO.
The 2nd kind is when you see
evidence of it:
crop circles, radiation.
The 3rd kind is when you
make contact.
But the 4th kind,
there's nothing more frightening
than the 4th.
You see,
that one is
when they abduct you.
And I think it's all
part of the same thing.
It's all connected,
to Will, the missing people,
to everything in Nome.
If this type of thing
was happening to Nome,
to me, I think
it's happening
to other people.
Not just there,
but all over the world,
in towns, cities.
Most of them
don't even know it.
Know they're abducted?
How could they know?
How could they remember what
they're being forced to forget?
What the hell?
Holy shit.
Where are they?
I don't know.
I tried to tell you..
You don't know?
I want the video played back.
Sir, it didn't record.
It did, but nothing
came out.
Come on! Bullshit!
Ryan, pull yourself
together, man.
Calm down. Mom.
What the hell happened?
They took my baby.
They took her.
Who?
They took my baby.
What is she talking about?
Someone kidnapped
Ashley.
Okay, I want this entire house
searched.
I want everybody
inside, outside
going through these
premises top to bottom.
Ronnie, what'd you see?
Nothing. I came in here
and she was gone.
What's going on here?
August, listen to me.
I'm listening.
A beam of light came down,
and they took her into the sky.
They took my little girl up
into the sky. I saw it!
Through the ceiling?
August, I saw it!
Yes. They took her
through the ceiling.
What is this craziness?
What the hell
is going on here?
I couldn't stop it.
Okay. Everybody clear this room!
I want everybody out of here
except Ronnie and Abbey!
Ronnie, sit down right there,
please. Okay?
Abbey, you sit down.
Please sit down. My baby.
Okay? Sit here.
I want to talk to you, okay?
You just tell me.
Listen, less than 5 hours
after I arrest you,
your daughter goes missing.
I told you.
Yeah, but that's horseshit.
We know that that's not real.
Tell me what happened.
You had an officer
outside my house.
Yes, we had
an officer outside.
What did he see?
He didn't see anything.
He says that the videotape
wasn't playing. Now, just tell me.
Where is she?
Listen, Abbey!
What did he see?
Get him in here right now!
You listen to me now.
You know what's real!
I want to know what he saw.
You know what's real! You had
an officer outside my house!
God damn it!
Where is she?
You were supposed to protect us!
Abbey, where is she, God damn it?
You tell me where she is!
Where is Ashley?
Where is she?
Mom!
Can't you stop?
It's okay.
Please, just stop!
Abbey, you haven't been right in
the head since Will.
You just haven't been
right in the head.
You haven't found his killer.
What?
You still haven't found his killer.
No, Abbey, we have.
Yes, we have.
He's still out there.
No. Listen, I'm removing him
from your custody.
No.
Yes, I am,
and find a lawyer,
because you've run out
of all the goodwill
I've got, okay?
He's not gonna take you away.
Guys, get in here. We're removing
Ronnie from Abbey's custody!
No. No, you're not!
You will not..
Let go!
You will not.
No. No. Let go!
No. No, no.
Baby, baby, no!
Let go. Let go.
No, no.
You're not taking my boy!
I'm sorry.
He'll be safe!
You're not taking my boy!
God!
My babies!
Why are you doing this?
All I realized, that they weren't
going to be able to find her.
That I would have
to do it on my own.
But you couldn't leave.
No, that's not what I mean.
I had to..
To find a way
to go directly to them,
directly to the source.
I know what I saw, but I..
I can't accept it.
I can't.
So please don't ask me to,
because I can't.
I still have to do this.
But Scott, you..
Is this the right way?
I don't know.
I don't have a choice.
Yeah.
I know you don't.
Your eyes are feeling heavier.
7, 6,
5, 4,
3, 2
and 1.
Abbey?
Yes.
Let's go back 3 days,
to Tuesday,
when you were giving dictation
in your bedroom.
Yes.
Good.
Now, what happened after
you finished your dictation?
Remains unexplained,
and worse, unsolved,
like Will.
Are you sleeping?
Yes.
What happened
next?
There's an owl.
The owl.
It's looking down at me.
Is it the same owl
your patients see?
Yes.
It's smiling.
I don't like it when it smiles.
What do you mean, smiling?
I don't know what I mean.
I don't want to know.
Well, it's too late to forget
what you already know.
Tell me what you see.
It's not an owl.
God, help me! Help me!
No.
No! No!
Help me! Help me!
Help me! Help!
Abbey, what is it?
God, help me.
There are too many of them.
It burns. It hurts!
No, no! Please!
Stop it. No.
It's sticking into my shoulder.
So what happened in that room?
They came,
and we were..
We were..
They abducted us.
All of us, but brought us
back that same night.
We don't remember
where they took us
or what they did to us.
Even with hypnosis, it's..
black.
Your voice, or its voice,
said it was God.
What do you believe?
I believe..
It's hard, but I believe
the things I've seen,
the presence I've felt
inside of me
is beyond anything
you can imagine.
It was
hopelessness,
so it cannot be God,
but it can..
It can pretend to be.
And what about Ashley?
What about..
And what about
your daughter?
She..
I had to recover
from that night.
It took me a couple
of days to wake up.
Abel..
It's..
It's okay.
What is this?
Look, I have
to apologize.
I..
I'm sorry, I really hate to
have to do this
when you're in this condition
that you're in.
It's okay.
So,
well, I still have that question
for you, Abbey.
How did Will die?
He was murdered.
No, Abbey.
Abbey, he's going to show you
something that will upset you,
but it has to be done.
Understand?
This is the head of a man
who used this gun.
Okay?
Yeah. It was suicide,
Abbey. It was suicide.
He took a pistol,
shot himself in the head.
There was no intruder.
There was no knife. Just him with
his pistol at the side of your bed.
He's not that man.
He wouldn't do that.
He wouldn't do that to us.
He wouldn't do that to his family.
Tell him he's wrong.
Tell him.
I'm a psychologist,
and I would have known..
Christ.
I would have known
if he was gonna..
Abbey, Abbey.
You can't blame yourself
for something that was
going on in his head.
Who knows what he'd learned,
what he didn't share,
and finally what broke him?
Now you know the reality.
I'm gonna ask you for
the last time. Tell me.
What happened to Ashley?
Tell me. Abbey.
You know what happened.
You experienced it.
But we came back
and she didn't. Abel.
Tell him what happened.
Something took my daughter.
I don't know what.
I don't.. I don't know how.
I don't know what it was,
but you have to believe me.
You have to believe me, please.
Please.
It's difficult to go back.
Go back?
Back over the line from
fiction to reality.
You can't just stop being insane
whenever you want to.
It's the kind of thing that stays
with you forever.
So Will committed suicide?
Yes.
Your credibility. How do you
expect me or the audience
to believe anything
you're saying,
if you actually hallucinated
the murder of your husband?
They weren't hallucinations.
I just couldn't..
It can be difficult
to face the truth,
and with Will,
that's how I dealt with it.
And no matter what you believe,
the recordings do not lie.
We were talking about things that
that.. aren't normal.
Is dead..
back is broken.
And Ashley,
she's still gone.
These are hard facts.
They do appear to be.
No, God damn it,
they are!
You can sit here
and speculate,
but I have to
keep hope alive.
I have to believe
in what we're doing,
my story,
that it will help.
I have to believe
that she's still
alive somewhere,
that she's safe.
I have to believe
that there's a chance
that I'm gonna
see her again,
hold her again,
hear her voice.
I just want
my little girl back.
She's all I have.
Let's stop there.
Dr. Tyler,
we're done for the night.
Someone else is interested
in Nome, as well.
Since the 1960s,
there have been
over 2,000 visits
to Nome by the FBI,
the highest in Alaska.
Second is Anchorage,
with a population
76 times larger than Nome.
The FBI have paid them
353 visits.
In the end, what you believe
is yours to decide.
UFO Reporting Center.
Yeah, I got a doozy for you.
Okay.
Gonna put me into the hospital,
I tell you that.
What happened?
I'm a truck driver.
I had a load to Salt Lake City
from Banning.
I pulled over, didn't.. I got out
of the truck, kind of stretched.
I looked up at the stars,
and I saw these 2..
There were quite a few of them
that were kind of low,
and they were, like, flickering.
You know, what could
they be?
And then it occurred to me,
maybe I'm seeing a UFO.
Portland Air Traffic Control
Tower in Portland, Maine.
Yes, sir.
I guess I have a UFO report.
What they drew, and these 4 people
pretty much agree that,
actually, what they drew,
it looked like a fedora hat..
I saw something spectacular
in the sky last night
that I have no
explanation for.
In fact, I'm sure as many as
50 to 100 people saw it
in different areas
last night.
I'm sure it had as many as
20 pulsating red lights,
one white light in the front of it.
Like I said, it was about
100 feet from me.
To me, it looked about,
like, something..
Like I said, right.. I remember
seeing it, but after that it just..
I don't exactly remember too much.
I could see this
very bright red light,
and it would change
to kind of a blue light,
and the reflection
off the clouds.
Yes?
And I could also hear this
very loud buzzing noise.
My daughter is 7 years old,
and she said it was in
the shape of a square.
She said she's seen
4 red lights in the corner
and a white one in the middle.
Okay. We had an aircraft
at 35,000 feet westbound.
They reported sighting 4 objects.
3 of them were at his altitude
and one of them was a lot lower.
We observed an unknown
phenomenon this morning,
about 1600 Zulu,
and we observed it
for about 10 to 15 minutes.
The targets were
approximately 200 miles
west of San Francisco
over the water.
They flew in what
appeared to be unison,
approximately 90 miles apart.
Their speed was in excess of
2,000 knots.
They did a high-speed run
for about 75 miles,
made a very abrupt slowdown,
and then a 180-degree turn,
and tracked back northbound
in excess of 2,000 knots.
It had fire-engine red lights,
kelly green lights, orange lights.
It would shut all them lights down
and turn a bright white.
It was zigzagging in and out.
It was shooting from one side
of the sky to the other side.
It was almost as if it was rolling.
After 8 to 12 seconds
of this boiling,
we saw an object
come up out of the water
and go straight up into the air.
It was a circular-shaped object.
To give you a brief on it,
I was dispatched
on a UFO sighting.
When I arrived, what I saw
was a real large craft
in the air, circular.
I would say it was
at least 25 yards wide,
or in diameter actually,
it would be,
and it was hovering over a house,
and it was motionless.
They're real bright, like a star,
and when it gets closer to you,
it gets dimmer.
Then when it lands, it goes into
a big, big orange,
kind of like looking at the sun
or something.
And then when
the light goes out,
it's like you turned
down a kerosene lamp.
What exactly happened was,
it was myself and a friend
were flying.
I'm a commercial pilot.
Yes.
And we saw this object,
and it wasn't bright like a light.
It was shining like
polished aluminum,
or polished metal.
Yes.
Like a point source
that was emanating
several shafts of black light.
It was like negative light.
There's gotta be several
hundred people that saw it.
We had an aircraft
that sighted a UFO.
The pilot reported an object passed
approximately 1/8 of a mile
in front of the aircraft.
It was described
as being box-shaped.
And as soon as I pulled over,
this object came straight at us,
straight to our vehicle.
It was huge. This thing was huge.
It was black, huge.
It had these triangle lights on it.
I have never been a believer
of UFOs in my entire life,
and I just seen a minimum
of 9 this morning
with my own eyes,
and, I mean, I am a believer.
One orange, and at least 9 of
the bright, bright moving lights.
I was just staring at it, stopped
in my vehicle,
and it started to move,
and it had lights down
each side of it, like a triangle.
Yes?
And then, next thing I know,
I didn't take my eyes off
the damn thing. It was gone.
My little brother, he's 3,
he'll be 4 next month,
last night he started
talking to my parents,
and I just got done
talking with him.
He told my dad,
"You have to lock the door,"
"'cause the creatures
are gonna come get me,"
and he said,
"The men in the stars,"
he said,
"they're coming to get me."
They follow him.
When he goes outside,
he says,
"The star follows me."
You'd have to experience this
in order to believe me.
I'm afraid to walk outside.
I need help.
I don't know how to deal with this.
It's so strange.
I'm frightened to go to sleep.
What if they come back?
SubText: NoRMITA.326