¶
Santa?
Ahh!
Holy crap, Boyd.
What the hell you doing
back there, buddy?
Waiting on Santa Claus?
Aren't you getting
a little old for Santa Claus?
I'm five.
It's all a sham, Boyd.
The whole Goddamn deal.
I'm the only Santa
you're ever gonna know.
If you know the truth,
it's easy to get through it all.
In fact, let's see
what he brought you.
-  Meet my father,
-  Mitch Mitchler.
All we need is
a couple of Chinese workers.
He was a little
bit complicated.
¶
Maybe I was destined to become
an overcompensator as a dad,
Christmas being the most
obvious manifestation of that.
Alright, here we go.
Okay, lean in, everyone.
I'm also a realist.
I can't control everything--
the weather, for instance.
Look Dad, it's snowing!
Well, Bug,
that's actually fake snow.
Because of global warming.
The warmest winter
on record in the Midwest
assured a non-white Christmas.
The bigger issue by far,
was the Santa conundrum.
Vera was very much on
the fence, Santa-wise.
But Douglas still believed.
Dad, why are there two Santas?
But for how much longer?
That guy's not Santa, Bug.
He probably smells
like pee and burnt hair
because he's a welfare person.
Vera!
Santa's not real anyway.
Santa's not real, Dad?
Of course Santa's real.
No one's not real.
Everyone's real,
including Santa.
Vera, a word please.
Whatever you think you know,
Vera, you don't.
Most kids in my class
don't believe in Santa anymore.
But Madison and me--
I mean Madison and I,
we kinda still did,
except that Madison's sister,
the one who did
the BJ to this kid--
Uh, Vera, you don't
actually know what the B--
what that expression
means, do you?
It stands for butt jam,
and I think it has to do
with jamming stuff
up your butt for money,
but anyway,
Madison's sister,
she showed us this website,
nosanta.org.
Well, Madison's sister is
a deceitful little strumpet.
What Dad means
is that it's okay
for you to decide
about Santa, but Douglas...
He absolutely believes.
And we won't want to
do anything
to spoil Christmas
for him, right?
Oh, right,
I won't spoil it for Bug, Dad.
Sorry.
Thank you.
You are a very kind
and generous young man.
And you are going
to have a very merry
and special Christmas.
Oh ho ho ho!
Hey, you wanna...
I wasn't gonna ask
if you wanna smoke meth
or kill a drifter.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
I just-- I'm exhausted.
I'm with you.
I just thought I should ask.
One day we're
gonna have to, right?
Or, we could just enjoy
the slow descent into celibacy.
How many years
do you think Bug has left
where he walks into the
living room Christmas morning,
he sees the tree,
and presents,
his stomach just drops,
because holy crap, Santa came?
Can you imagine still having
that kind of belief in magic?
Yeah, it's really cool.
Do you think
you're overcompensating
on the Christmas
thing, just a tad?
Overcompens--
on the Christmas thing?
No! I don't think that
at all.
He's six years old.
Okay, this is
your brother, again.
Pass.
You can't keep pretending
your family doesn't exist.
I'm pretty sure I can.
Come on babe, take the call,
before it wakes the kids up.
Hi, Nelson.
- Whoa, that is spooky.
- How'd you know it was me?
We have caller ID,
so your number comes up.
Just right there on the phone?
Boy, that is something.
I gotta look into that.
You know, that's
a miracle of science.
Yeah, you bet.
Hold on one sec, Boyd.
Sorry to call you
so late by the way.
Is it night time
where you are, too?
No, it's 10 here too,
because Chicago and Wisconsin-
What is in the same time zone!
Yeah, we're in
the same time zone.
I don't know if you caught
that, I said it like Jeopardy.
So anyway.
Oh, oh, right. So anyway,
I'm calling to tell you:
I scored myself a kid,
a little boy. I'm a dad.
Really?
He seems to have procreated.
Eeww.
I was calling to say,
I want you to be the godfather.
Really?
We would be honoured.
That is just the best, Boyd.
Jeez, that is so--
I know it's short notice
but the baptism's on the 24th.
Oh, absolutely. We wouldn't
miss it for the world.
Sweet.
Uh, January or February?
No Boyd, December.
December 24th.
Oh, you can't wait for it.
December? What?
Nelson, you can't have a baptism
on Christmas Eve.
It doesn't--
Wait that would mean
that I'd have to spend
Christmas with Dad.
I'll smoke in my Goddamn
house if I want to.
It's my house. Name's right
there on the mortgage.
Right there on the mailbox.
His name on the mortgage, Donna?
His name
on the friggin' mailbox?
No sir, it is not,
didn't think so.
Ipso facto ergo,
not his Goddamn house.
Jeezo!
Man you exhaust me, Mitch.
You know it is
a dream come true for me
to have my family
home on Christmas.
There's no way they were
gonna get a motel room now
at this late date,
and with Boyd's asthma--
Asthma?
Any other restrictions
Captain Wheezy
wants to put on me?
Well, there is one more thing.
I was planning on doing venison
for Christmas Eve supper,
but apparently, Boyd's
family doesn't eat red meat
and I was--
Christ's sake!
Is that all of Douglas' stuff?
Si. What about Vera's?
I hid it
in the car this morning.
Oh, you're aces!
Tu tambien!
So, you ready to see your dad?
Yeah, can't wait. I'm
actually looking forward to it.
Really?
No, I'd rather be
sodomized by an angry clown!
I just want the kids
to have a good Christmas.
Me, too.
Dad?
Hey, hi, what are you doing?
Hi, Dougie doodle.
Who's gonna feed
Dale while we're gone?
Oh, that would be--
Farhad.
Who's Farhad?
Mom's ESL student.
What's ESL?
Remember, English
as a second language?
Why don't you tell him, Dad?
I'll race you upstairs.
¶ Jingle bells, jingle
bells, jingle all the way ¶
¶ Oh, what fun it is to ride
in a one-horse open sleigh ¶
¶ Dashing through the snow ¶
¶ In a one-horse open sleigh ¶
¶ O'er the fields we go ¶
¶ Laughing all the way ¶
¶ Bells on Bobtail ring ¶
¶ Making spirits bright ¶
Son of a bitch.
Mom, Dad said "bitch."
Bitch is a bad word, Bug.
You can use bastard or ass.
Hey, you guys, come on.
Hey, we're twins!
Ha ha ha, merry Christmas!
Licence and proof
of insurance, please.
Awesome.
So, I did clock you doing
67 in a 45, Mr. Mitchler.
Yeah, the bum deal
about that is,
it's a 450-dollar infraction,
but there is some good news.
You can pay online now,
in the state of Wisconsin.
Yeah, it's a real sweet
website, takes Discover,
so you get the cash back
which, you know, helps out.
Alright, kids,
hope Santa treats you good!
Take care! Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas.
You bet.
Oh, where the heck
can they be?
Oh, don't get
your knickers in a knot.
You having a good time, Dad?
Oh yeah, I'm delirious.
I want some milk.
You have to wait 'til supper
like the rest of us, Cale.
Where is the sex offender?
He's not a sex offender!
What should I call him
then, Willy Wanker?
With the help of
our marriage counsellor,
me and Dave have worked
through his transgressions.
So my husband, Dad,
is outside smoking a heater.
Dad, Rance is being a gomer!
Hey you guys, cut it out!
Where the hell did you
get that thing from?
I took it.
Well, put it the hell back
from where you took it from!
Thank you.
Aw, crud,
I can't find my camera.
Mitch, go look for it,
will you?
For cripe's sake,
we're not National Geographic.
They're not some
bunch of bonobos.
Mitch, they have never
been here for Christmas.
Well, whose fault
is that? Not mine.
Boyd's the one who thinks
he's too good for us.
Having my family here
means everything to me.
So quit being such an a-hole,
and go look for my G-D camera!
They're here!
Shut up, tramp stamp!
Mitch, hurry up, Boyd's here.
Boyd!
Hey!
Oh, honey!
Mom!
I love you.
It's great to be home.
You are looking fine as wine.
Can you believe it, Boyd,
all of us together at Christmas!
I know, it's great.
Well, where's the Nel?
Nelson and the baby
are meeting us at church.
Gotcha.
Isn't this perfect,
Boyd? This is perfect.
Stop! Don't hurt me!
Don't-- don't--
Dad, you okay?
I'm fine.
You're welcome,
anytime. You're family.
You okay?
Puba!
Dougie Doodle!
How are you, little bugger?
Everybody get together
for a quick photo,
and then we gotta
get ready for church.
¶ That glorious song of old ¶
¶ From angels bending
near the earth ¶
¶ To touch their harps of gold ¶
¶ ...goodwill to men from
heavens all gracious king ¶
¶ I really don't
know the words to say ¶
¶ So now I don't have to sing ¶
Uh, well, of course most of
you remember my wife, Cindy,
and might have known
that when I was in basic,
over by Fort Digs, she ran
off with this Mexican guy,
who played a little minor
league ball for the Wombats.
Uh, pretty halfway
decent shortstop.
Anyhow, he got her pregnant,
this Mexican guy did,
so Cindy comes by
the house one day, and goes,
"Hey Nelson,
would you mind
"looking after the baby
for a while?"
And I said,
"Yeah, yeah sure, no sweat."
And anyhow, that was
six months ago
and I still got
this kid of hers, so.
He don't have
a name that I know of,
so I've just been
calling him Baby.
But you know, he is
a real, real good boy.
And uh, that's why
I want to name him Boyd,
after my own big brother,
who is just
a heck of a good guy himself.
So, I am presenting
Boyd Jr.
as a candidate
for holy baptism.
Except I figure
I'm gonna call him BJ.
Welcome to the family, BJ.
Dear God,
I look around this table,
and I see a family.
I know we're not perfect,
Lord God,
even though some people
think they are.
We've all got foibles,
peccadilloes if you will.
I'm not gonna name names, Dave;
it's not the time or the place.
Anyhow I just want to
say, thank you, Lord Jesus,
Lamb of God, for bringing
us together here.
And now each one of us
is gonna say something
they're thankful for.
Donna, do it.
Oh, uh,
I'm thankful little
BJ's christening went okay.
But mostly I'm thankful
we're all here together.
That's a dream for me.
Skol.
Skol!
It's a prayer Donna,
not a toast, come on.
Shauna, you're up.
Oh. Uh, I'm grateful
that through the grace
of our Lord Jesus Christ,
I'm able to forgive all of you
for all the pain
you've caused me,
and, thanks to me and
Dave's marriage counsellor,
uh, we are back
on the marriage train,
and we are gonna ride it all
the way into the station.
Right?
Well, I got one.
I thank God that
he gave me the ability
to give 110 percent,
and take first
for the WISEA
under-fourteen regionals.
WISEA stands for Wisconsin
Competitive Eating Association.
Rancer ate 27 Johnsonville
brats in five minutes.
- That's a lot of brats.
- Way to go, Rance.
That is-- uh,
that is really neat.
Let's give it the devil, Rancer.
Come on, pound these back.
Go, Rancer!
Go, go, go, Rancer!
Get it. Go-o-o, Rancer.
Go, go, go, Rancer.
¶
That's what I'm talking about!
Come on!
Wow, that is
really, really neat.
How many hot dogs
can you eat, Dougie doodle?
We're not allowed
to eat hot dogs.
We're a macrobiotic household.
For crying out loud,
Boyd, what's this crap?
You're gonna turn your kids
into a couple of beatniks.
Our kids are fine!
- I know they're fine.
- I'm just saying,
you don't want your boy
to turn into a Sally, do ya?
Don't tell me
how to raise my kids.
what to do in my house!
Is your name on the mailbox?!
I didn't think so!
Oh really,
the mailbox line again, Dad?
Great, you sparked
Nelson's PTSD.
Post-traumatic
stress disorder.
When things get tense,
Nelly gets a little squirrely.
He has to go into
a dark, quiet space.
It's from the war.
What war, Mom?
He fell out of
the back of a Humvee
during basic training
and was discharged.
A head injury!
He got a head injury
serving his country!
Okay.
Mmm! What--
Why are there shotgun
pellets in my chicken?
Dad.
Because it's squirrel.
Honey, no, we're not leaving.
He fed me a rodent
for Christmas dinner.
Well, you're the only
one who ate squirrel.
Ours was really chicken.
You did say that
you could handle anything
as long as the kids
were having a good Christmas,
and the kids are having
a great Christmas.
Think you can just flex
those emotional muscles,
just a little bit,
and think of Douglas?
I want some more dessert!
And that's how
you make 50 dollars an hour.
Puba?
Yeah, Dougie?
I want us to leave Santa
a snack,
but Rance ate all the cookies
in like, 10 seconds,
and then he drank
a whole gallon of milk.
Whoa.
So, I was wondering
if you had anything else
that I could give to Santa?
Of course I do, Bug.
I know something
that Santa loves
a lot more
than milk and cookies.
Dear Santa, Puba said you
would enjoy this bourbon
and asparagus.
I hope you like it a lot.
Love, your very good
friend, Douglas Mitchler.
¶ Shake that ass, bitch,
and let me see what you got ¶
Whoa, that's pretty neat, Pam.
I know, I've got
over 75 hits so far.
Your average is zero stars
'cause you suck, turdbait.
Shut up, jackwipe!
Hey, that's not very
Christmassy behaviour.
Gather up.
So, we have a tradition
in our family
where we read
The Night Before Christmas
the night before Christmas.
Get it?
This is mentally challenged.
Do you think
this is a joke, Rance?
This isn't a joke.
This is Christmas.
We're not two, Uncle Boyd!
I mean, all this
Santa crap is for babies!
Every dumbass knows
there's no such thing!
Shut up!
Shut your mouth!
Shut your big, eating mouth!
Right now, shut it!
Santa will find
me here, right Dad?
Of course he will, Bug.
In fact, Santa
just texted me to say
that he made you
an amazing present!
But you're gonna have to wait
until morning to see it.
Okay.
- Look at this pile of crap.
- This country's so damn excessive
it makes me wanna puke.
Oh put a sock in it,
Mitchler.
Well, they're all down.
Oh that's super, honey.
Good job.
Where's Douglas' stuff?
Oh gosh, buried
in there somewhere.
Everything's out of the car?
I got the last
of it out of there.
Well, none of it's here.
None of Douglas'
presents are here.
No, that's impossible.
You put them in the car
this morning.
I didn't, you did.
No, you gave me the thumbs up!
Meaning you do it,
and you nodded!
Wait, what are you two saying?
Boyd--
Not Boyd, Luann!
Boyd and I left all of
Douglas' stuff in Chicago.
Oh, jeez.
- It's gonna be fine!
- We'll think of something!
Right?
Uh, oh I have an idea.
Uh, what's it called, Toys"R"...
Us.
Babe, the mall closes at six,
all right?
Just sit there and look pretty.
Okay, listen, Randy Sickle
over there in Commercial,
they're open 24 hours,
we'll go over there,
pick him up maybe one of
those singing bass plaques
and a mesh hat.
Hey, come on, he's seven. Throw
in a pack of grape hike shoes
boom,
it's done. What do you say?
The kid's never gonna know the
difference. "Christmas, hey!"
That's exactly
what you would do!
Nice parenting, really nice!
Last time I checked, it
ain't exactly great parenting
ruining your kid's
Christmas, Prime Time!
I should knock
you on your ass.
Oh really? Bring it Sally!
I'd love to see you try!
Come on!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Now if we're gonna do this,
we're gonna need
some ground rules.
I'm going. I'm driving back.
It's not even 11.
That gives me eight hours
until he's up. I'm going.
Boyd, don't go!
You can't do it,
it's too far!
He's not going anywhere,
Donna, he's all show and no go.
Boyd. Boyd, stop.
You've had four hours of sleep.
You're gonna kill yourself!
Any day now,
Douglas is gonna wake up
and realize the world
is a mean, nasty place
where your hopes and dreams
eventually get smashed to bits.
Until then, he needs this.
I'm sorry, who needs this?
If I can just make him
believe for one more Christmas.
Having Christmas
is not about stuff, Boyd.
Look, just wait.
Okay, go tomorrow,
when you've had some sleep.
We'll say that
we delayed Christmas a day.
We'll make it fun.
I understand. Mitch
ruined Christmas for you,
but you have proven
a million times over,
you're not him.
You're such a great dad.
This is just crazy!
Hey, hey.
Look, you're running away
from your father again!
You can't keep doing this!
- Boyd, wait, I'm coming with you!
- Let me just put up some coffee!
It's about
an eight-hour round trip,
which gets me back
here at what, sevenish,
so just make sure the kids
stay downstairs until 7:30.
This is doable,
but I gotta go now.
Be careful, honey!
Merry Christmas.
¶
I made this ornament
when I was a kid once,
out of a pine cone.
It had the googly eyes on it
and the white cotton deals,
you know
what I'm talking about?
Shut the hell
up, you degenerate.
Pervert.
He's not a pervert!
A guy who exposes himself
to a busload of old folks
on their way to Oneida bingo,
what the hell should I call him
if not pervert?
Friggin' pillar
of the community?
I have explained this situation
to you a hundred times.
In Dave's defence,
he was drunk!
Very!
And in his second defence,
someone double-dog dared him
to do it, so that--
Okay. Who wants to look at
some slides? Or, I know,
how about a game of cribbage?
Oh, I've got that.
Hello?
- Is it him?
- Is he okay? What happened?
He's fine, but--
Aw crud.
Dammit.
Looky here. BMW.
Short for
Bavarian Money Waster.
Looks like the sheisse
hit the fan here.
I'm gonna hitchhike.
Really?
Christmas Eve,
no one's gonna pick you up.
Come on, let's go.
I'm not giving up.
You go ahead and go
home. I don't need you.
Yeah, but Douglas does.
So come on.
Get in the truck, Gladys.
We got Christmas to save.
¶ Silent night ¶
¶ Holy night ¶
¶ All is calm ¶
¶ All is bright ¶
¶ Round yon virgin ¶
¶ Mother and child ¶
¶ Holy infant ¶
¶ So tender and mild ¶
¶ Sleep in heavenly peace ¶
- It don't add up, boy.
- You got a guy tootin' around
the whole Goddamn planet
in one night.
That sleigh'd have to be going
25, 30,000 miles per hour,
minimum. Now, if we had
that type of technology, shit,
we'd be blowing the tits
off the friggin' Viet Kong.
It's all a sham.
sham.
what the heck's
up with that son of a B?
You know what he is, right?
Sham.
Damn right.
What kind of creep goes
sneaking into a kid's room
and putting chump
change under a pillow?
What the hell's he need
all those teeth for? Pervert.
The whole world
is full of lies, Boyd.
The only road to happiness
is realizing there's no road
to happiness.
Alright, I'm going to bed.
You finish it up on your own.
Oh yeah, eat me!
First off--
And second,
I have asthma, Dad, asthma.
And it is not
all in my head,
as you have so astutely
hypothesized in the past.
It is an actual
medical condition
that could actually kill me.
So please,
put out the damn cigar.
What the hell's that all
about? You on the friggin' rag?
Come on.
Come on, lighten up, Boyd.
We got all night ahead of us.
Let's have a little fun here.
I bet they're having a ball.
Yeah, yippee!
It does make me feel better
that Mitch went with him.
Them two hate each
other's guts, I thought.
Okay, cut it out,
you guys, we're a family.
And it's Christmas, jeez.
You know, Mom, I, uh,
don't want to make you feel bad
with what I'm about to say,
being that it's Christmas
and all but, a lot
of this is your fault.
Dave and I's marriage counsellor
says that a lot of
my self-esteem problems
come from the fact that
you never confronted Dad
about his drinking.
So it's why I seek approval
from people who treat me
like wet dog crap.
Who needs anything?
We've got leftovers,
we've got hot dish. Beer?
Reeb me!
That's beer spelled
backwards, honey.
Vera.
Yeah, Bug?
Was Rance about to say
that there's
no such thing as Santa?
Rance is a certified
moron, Douglas.
So whatever he was about to say
would have been
certified moronic.
Of course there's a Santa.
Promise?
I promise.
When you see your presents
under the tree in the morning,
you'll believe again, you will.
Now lie down.
Okay.
Wow, 53 degrees.
So much for a white Christmas.
Who needs one?
Yesterday I was golfing.
You would have caught
me in my shirtsleeves.
Kicked Bill Gorsky's
ass, the fat pollack.
I said "if this is global
warming, I'll take it."
Pollack. Nice, Dad.
Technically he's a bohunk.
I got more if you need 'em.
Hi, uh, where's the--
Just past the cheese.
I can guess your nationality
without even seeing you.
European.
You get it?
You're a-peein'.
Ha, yeah, got it.
Ho ho ho.
Hey, you got any bourbon?
Just a--
I wish I did, sorry.
That's okay, that's okay.
So, you having yourself
a merry little Christmas?
I wouldn't say that exactly.
Well, nobody said it
was easy now, did they?
I mean, take my journey
here tonight.
I mean, logic-wise,
that whole deal doesn't really
add up, does it?
I mean my sleigh'd have to be
doing what,
25, 30,000 miles an hour?
Minimum?
But I always make it.
Somehow I always do, you know.
I mean, it's not always
easy, like I say,
but miracles never are.
They're tricky little things,
miracles. Sometimes they look
at you right in the face.
They're right in front of you,
staring at you in the mirror,
and you didn't even see them.
It's crazy.
Um--
Have a merry
Christmas, Santa.
I always do, buddy.
I always do.
Have fun in there.
I'll name it after you.
Hi, can I get
a couple of coffees?
That's your old man?
Virgil Mitch. Ole Mitch, huh?
Yeah, I'm Boyd.
You're Boyd!
Yeah, you're the smart one.
You got a full ride
at the UW.
And now
you're a stockbroker, is it?
Down in Chi-town?
I manage a hedge fund.
Oh yeah, that's right.
But your dad tells me
you make a truckload of money.
I don't know about that.
I work too much.
Well, anyhow, nice
to have a face with the name.
Your pop, that crazy old
son of a ,
he's in here pretty near
once a week,
and I get an earful
about your family.
Uh-oh.
No! Mitch talks a blue streak
about how good you're doing.
Must be nice for y'all to have
Christmas together, ain't it?
Uh, it is.
What do I owe you?
No, come on.
Merry Christmas now, Boyd.
Merry Christmas.
You know how to
drive a manual, tranny?
You don't remember
the day you taught me
how to drive a stick?
Should I?
October 26, 1983, you may
recall, was my 12th birthday.
You may also recall
that you were too hammered
to drive home from my party,
so I drove home.
Is that right?
Well, I must have been
doing something right,
'cause you still remember how.
Yes, it is one of
life's greatest indignities
that you never won
the Father of the Year award.
Hey, careful!
Can't you take a joke, Sally?
- Now you're pissing me off.
- Let's just get this done.
Maybe you need to
piss on the radiator.
Whoa, what was that?
Tit.
Want me to go peek in on BJ?
No, I'll do it, Shauna.
Wait a second, where's Nelson?
Last time I saw him
he was going ape-crap
because Mitch
and Boyd were scrapping.
Well, that was two hours ago.
Oh shoot, Nelson!
Nelson!
Nelson.
Nelson, baby, come on.
Where are you?
Oh, he's not where
he usually goes.
Whenever he gets panicked
he just falls asleep
in the craziest places.
I found him all balled up in
the middle of the road a coup--
Oh my God.
Nelson!
Where are you, baby?
Wake up!
Nelson!
Nelson! Where are you,
Nelson? Wake up!
Donna, be careful!
Nelson!
Oh-- oh, dear Lord Jesus.
¶ Jingle all the way ¶
No, you can't sing low.
I know, high.
¶ Wayyyy ¶
Oh no, stop, stop, stop!
¶ Oh what fun it is to ride ¶
Dude, you just hit something.
¶ ...open sleigh ¶
Good night.
Put your hands down
and let's do this.
Ahem, I love you ve--
I love you very much.
Let's go, come on.
See?
Mom, has Santa come yet?
No honey, not yet,
it's still early.
Santa's got a long
night ahead of him.
Can Dad tuck me in?
Who? Dad?
No, because, uh,
Dad and Puba...
are getting massages.
Oh, okay.
Good night, Mom.
Okay, good night.
So who else isn't tired?
Oh, I forgot to ask you.
Did Santa Claus
accost you in the bathroom?
Excuse me?
You know, the grubby
old guy in the Santa suit
in the truck stop bathroom.
I didn't see anybody
in the bathroom.
Santa's coming home soon.
Gonna bring
you lots of gifts.
Oh, son of a bitch!
Oh!
I forgot to tell you,
the speedometer's off
by about 10 miles an hour.
Oh it's good to know that.
Well I'll be!
Merry Christmas, Mr. Mitchler!
Again.
What brings you gents
out so late?
Well, numbnuts here forgot
his kid's presents in Chi-town.
Numbnuts, that's funny.
Haven't heard that one
in quite some time!
My foster mom, she, uh--
Oh, I see you guys are in the
portable john business, huh?
Indeed we are, sir.
Mitch Mitchler,
North Central Wisconsin
king of the crappers.
For 25 years,
Mitchler's Handi-crappers have
been supplying luxury johns
for all your business needs.
I always say,
if you gotta go, go in style!
I like that a lot.
do you guys do family reunions?
My cousin actu--
We're actually in a really
big hurry, Trooper Zblocki, so.
I could tell, Mr. Mitchler.
Caught old numbnuts
here doing 91.
I'll be back
with your citation, STAT.
Numbnuts.
Funny little elf.
Well, Mr. Mitchler, I did
clock you doing 91, yikes!
It's like, "Arriba,
arriba, andele, andele!"
Bart Simpson.
But, it's Christmas,
so you know what?
I got candy canes
for you three guys.
Three?
Nelson?
Jeez, I must've
fell asleep in here.
Who's that guy?
A child is the most important
thing a mother has, Nelson.
Jeez, I'm sorry
I had you worried, Mom.
If anything
had happened to you--
Aw, jeez.
Mom, could you put
little BJ on the phone?
I want to tell him I'm okay.
He's sleeping
in his crib, hon.
Plus he's not even a year.
Well, maybe just go in
there and tell him I love him?
And, uh, could you sing him that
pretty little song he likes?
¶ Hot tortillas,
crisp tostadas ¶
¶ Best in Me-hi-co ¶
¶ Enchiladas, empanadas ¶
¶ How I love them so ¶
It is a miracle
that you got pulled over,
because I could have froze
to death in there, or worse.
Not cold enough
to freeze to death.
Okay, real quick,
what could possibly be worse
than freezing to death
in a portable toilet, Nelson?
HIV, AIDS, Lou Gehrig
disease, cancer, spina bifida...
Okay, all good ones.
I could think of one worse.
A guy getting his gonads
lobbed off by his wife
because he forgot his
kid's Christmas presents.
Get 'im!
I'm not supposed to
play video games,
but you're really
awesome at them, Rance.
Yeah, I know.
We should totally put your
picture on Craigslist, Vera.
Your judgement
is really questionable, Pam.
You gonna stay up
with us, Dave?
Oh no, I, uh--
I get hungry at night
so I like to make myself a meal
so I have something to eat
between sleep and breakfast.
I call it breep.
Okay.
It's an anagram I came
up with, much like brunch
or NASA. It's a way for me
to remember what I like.
Hon, let's go hit the sack.
Good night.
Night.
Oh, Daver.
Oooh!
You are too good for me.
You know, maybe I will try
one of those
beer-tomato-juice thingies.
Well now you're talking.
One red beer coming right up.
Holy cripes, it's a castle.
You really
are doing alright, Boyd.
You've never seen
this house before?
No, your mom has.
Last time I was here,
you had that apartment
by the lake.
It's going on seven years.
What's this you got
on the walls here?
Is that brick?
Yeah, it's--
uh, it's a brick house.
Boy, that is something.
Yeah.
Son of a bitch!
I left my damn keys
in my damn car!
Hey Hamburglar,
will this help?
The presents
are in the mudroom, so...
Hey Boyd, I gotta
take a squirt.
You guys have a bathroom, or--
Yeah, it's upstairs.
Make yourself at home, Dad.
Yeah.
Dad?
Nelson?
What's going on?
What are you doing in my house?
I am Farhad.
Who are these people?
Ms. Mitchler is say,
my family to sit in the house,
to feed dog--
there, the dog.
To sit in the house.
House-sitting is different
than sitting in my house!
Ah, it's Boyd.
Hi, is everything okay?
- Fine, okay.
- Farhad is here.
Yeah, I gave him the key
so he could feed Dale.
You knew that.
No, but his whole family
is here.
It's like Goldilocks
and the 30 Iranians.
Boyd, they're from Afghanistan.
I don't care
where they're from,
I care why they're here,
in my house!
Ooo, maybe there was confusion
over the translation
of house-sit.
You know,
they're an amazing family.
They've only been
in the country two months,
so, whatever, let them
have a nice Christmas.
You're not saving the world!
What do you think, you're, uh--
you think you're Bono?
I have a law degree!
I'm a teacher!
You're supposed to be
teaching refugees English,
and based upon
my conversation with this guy,
it's not exactly
working out, is it?!
If anyone's
to blame, it's you!
You for being an ass sponge!
I'm the ass sponge?
Yes, you are
the ass sponge, ass sponge.
I'm not having
this conversation.
I am not having
Fine.
Oh my God!
He acts like the sweetest,
nothing-bothers-me guy, but
the slightest little pressure
turns him into a total--
Ass sponge?
He sounds
just like his father.
You know, in case those
guys don't make it back
in time somehow,
maybe we oughtta have
something else for Douglas.
Like what?
Maybe we oughtta
go up to the attic
and wrap some old toys
and that, just in case.
Yeah, okay fine.
Donna, do you have
something else
that maybe
doesn't taste like-- this?
Vodka?
Hey Doug-lass, you wanna
do something really cool?
Yes!
Sweet.
You know, I wasn't
a competitive eater
'til I was like, nine.
If I would have started
at seven,
who knows how much more
friggin' awesome I'd be?
Ah, let's see how fast you
can take these bad boys down.
A whole jar of pickles?
Do it.
Please don't,
Douglas, it's stupid.
You'll be sick for Santa!
You want to be cool
or retarded?
Man or mouse, Douglas?
Yes! Oh my God! Look at him go!
Chug, chug, chug,
chug, chug, chug, chug!
Douglas, stop!
These pickles were canned
during the Nixon Administration!
You're gonna die!
I can't feel my legs.
What the hell?
¶
He erased me.
Ain't that a kick
in the pants?
Presents. Gifts.
Ho ho ho?
Gift?
Gift, yes, yes.
Thank you.
No, Farhad.
Those are Douglas' gifts!
My son! Douglas.
No Farhad son!
No! My son's gifts!
Girls, those are
my power tools!
That's Boyd's power drill
and that is very--
Ahhh! Jesus!
Hey, Boyd.
These your roommates?
Hey Boyd, you got a nail
sticking out of your hand there.
Oh, we've been learning Nari,
which is kind of like Farsi,
over at basic
because my reserve unit
was going to be going over
by Afghanistan--
Oh!
And I fell off
of that Humvee,
and I got just a touch
of brain damage.
But the part that remembers
Nari is just fine.
So, can you tell him
that his family can stay?
I just need Douglas' gifts.
Well, I can sure as shoot try.
Let's see, uh...
- Please, no, no.
- No, no, no, please!
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, it's okay.
You can keep everything.
The only thing I want
is that.
¶
Hey, it's, uh, 3:45,
so we have less than four hours
if we're gonna get back
before the kids get up.
So I need you to motivate.
You don't need me;
you never did.
It's all gonna be okay, Bug.
Boing!
It's okay, Bug.
Boing, hello Rance!
They told me there'd
always be people like you.
I don't know,
I've never seen anybody
this way from pickles!
Rotten food can cause
hallucination, Rance.
Everybody knows that, you dummy.
It's gonna be okay,
Bug, just lie down.
Mmmm, cheese.
How about this for Douglas?
Bridge, like the card game?
For kids?
I don't know,
it seems like a horrible idea.
Boyd loved bridge for juniors,
it was his favourite game!
He did?
Okay, bag it and tag it,
I guess.
That was Mitch's
drink of choice.
Vodka and cranberry juice.
It must have been so hard.
I don't know.
I left a couple times
when it got too hard.
Took the kids
to my folks,
then when his bender
was finished,
he'd call bellyaching,
"Come back, come back.
I'll change, I'll change,"
blah, blah, you know.
He was always...
a very attentive lover,
though.
If you know what I mean?
I do. Yes, wow.
Boyd and I haven't had sex
for six months.
Oh, wow.
That is bad for you.
It's so bad.
It's just, you know,
he works all the time,
and-- or we're tired,
or the kids are around
and you know, it just...
But then he has
this whole thing
about how everything has to be
so perfect, and it can't be.
It's not. It's not perfect.
Do you want me
to talk to him for you?
No, that's okay, thank you.
That would feel
a little inappropriate.
Yep.
What?
¶  ¶
¶ Two days later,
Papa passed away ¶
¶ And I became a man that day ¶
¶ So I told Mama
I'm gonna quit school ¶
¶
I packed
my grandmother's trunk,
and in it I put an apple.
Nice.
God, we used to play
that when we'd drive
to Nana's cottage
up north, you remember?
Mm-hm.
Okay, I packed
my grandmother's trunk
and in it I put
an apple and a bagpipe.
Nice one.
Okay Dad, you're up.
Dad, it's your turn.
Come on Dad,
it's been a crap day.
Everything that possibly could
go wrong already has.
What, you on the rag, Sally?
I packed my grandma's trunk,
and in it I put an apple,
bagpipe,
and a kid
who's so ashamed of his old man,
he cut him
out of a family photo.
Okay, so you're spelling
kid with a C then.
Uh, fair enough.
I don't know what to say, Dad.
Fine, as long as we're being
honest with each other,
yes, I was embarrassed
of you in that photograph.
You were wearing that filthy
Handi-crapper T-shirt
for a family portrait.
I mean come on!
What, you're suddenly sensitive?
Besides, it's not like
you were ever proud of me.
I always supported you,
whatever it was
you wanted to do, always!
Are you high?
What is that?
Oh my gosh!
Hoho!
Is that--
Bea Arthur? It sure is.
Why?
Boyd went through a phase
where he really
got into Bea Arthur.
Like is-- like sexually? Or--
No!
It started with Golden Girls.
Wait, he liked bridge
and Golden Girls?
What did you raise,
a 75-year-old woman?
Look, there's a whole series.
You know how what's-his-futz
just painted blue stuff?
Well, Boyd only
painted Bea Arthur.
This is so silly.
My Boyd who played
football and basketball,
who's a type-A
hedge fund manager?
No, no!
He was real arty-farty
when he was a little shaver.
Well Mitch
must have loved that.
Mitch, he used to
tease Boyd all the time.
I felt terrible about it.
He drilled legs
into the frame of this one.
He turned it into a card table.
He used to play euchre on it
with his drinking buddies.
Look, there's the rings
from the glasses
on the canvas, there.
And I think Bill Gorsky
puked on it here.
That is so mean.
Isn't that so mean?
Lookit, that is so mean!
He was just a little
artist, creating his art,
and that's-- I mean,
it just makes me very sad,
isn't that so sad?
Boyd never really
painted much after that.
Mitch is a bastard!
And I have been trying to
get those guys to reconcile,
but do you understand
how much Boyd hates his job?
He hates it so much,
and all he wanted to do
was be a sweet little
Bea Arthur painter!
Or something.
I just feel like I could puke.
It blows my mind.
You have the capacity to
feel sorry for yourself!
Oh, what a jackass.
If I loused up so bad, how
come you have such a nice life?
Nice house,
nice wife, nice job.
I hate my job!
And I haven't had sex
with my wife in six months!
And you blame that on me?
Jiminy crickets!
Jeez, come on, guys!
I'm sorry I didn't snuggle
or cuddle you enough!
I'm sorry I'm not perfect!
Perfect?
My entire approach
to parenting
is based on what I call
the WWMD principle.
What Would Mitch Do?
I ask myself that question,
and then I do
the exact opposite.
Come on Boyd, you know I
get jittery 'cause of the war!
You didn't go to war!
He's still a hero!
Son of a bitch!
No, no, no, no, no!
No, Boyd, slow down!
We can do it.
Not sure if you can see
me back here, Mr. Mitchler--
See that?
See it!
Come on, Boyd,
you're gonna get us killed!
Pull over, Boyd!
My whole life I've never
been your kind of man,
a man's man, a real man.
Well, let's see who the real man
is now! Hold on!
Shut up, Sally.
You sound like a little bitch.
Yeah, suck on that, Zblocki!
Suck on that! Eat it, bitch!
Yes, yes!
Yeah, go ahead.
Uh, yeah.
Umm, I'm out at uh--
Mr. Mitchler, he...
, everything okay?
Eff this.
Just wanted to wish you
a merry Christmas, Don!
I'm calling her a night.
Gonna head home to the fam.
Roger that.
Oh God, that felt good!
You're not this guy, Boyd.
You're not some idiot who'd
run away from a cop like that.
Hell, that's the kind of
asshole stunt that I'd pull.
You got
the asshole part right.
Maybe you're right about that.
This has been a weird night.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to both of you.
Mainly you, Boyd.
I'm sorry.
Suppose I might
have said it sooner
if I hadn't been so hammered
for most of the last 30 years
but you know?
There it is, I said it.
You're a good man
and uh,
I'm so sorry.
¶
I'm sorry, oh!
What the hell was that?!
Did we hit somebody?
I'm telling you, Boyd,
that was a person!
Nelson, it wasn't a person.
It can't have been a person.
What would a person be doing
in the middle of the road--
Maybe it was a deer.
Yeah, it was a deer!
It wasn't a deer.
Yes, of course it was a d--
Oh no.
¶
Oh God, oh my God, oh my God!
What are we gonna do?
Okay, Boyd, just calm down.
Calm?! Calm?
I just killed a man!
This is not the time to be calm!
We just gotta--
we just gotta call the cops.
No, we're not gonna call the
cops! I just outran the cops!
The last thing
we need are the cops!
Boyd's right, no cops.
My life is over!
No it isn't!
I'm gonna go to prison.
I'm going to prison.
Boyd, just glass-half-full
it for a sec here, okay?
Prison these days
is not half bad.
I'll take the heat!
I mean, come on now,
it's the least I can do,
you know, being shitfaced
and emotionally abusive
most of your childhood.
No, Dad, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Boyd, Boyd, Boyd!
There's other ways out of this.
How?
This guy, uh--
We're not exactly
talking doctor,
lawyer,
Indian chief here, right?
He's off the grid.
So if he umm, disappeared.
I got this friend, Mike Marcort.
You know, we play cribbage,
and he owes me
and uh, he's got a warehouse
down by Campbell Sport
full of HCl.
HC what, Dad?
Hydrochloric acid.
And so?
Well, you know, I'm saying--
not that he doesn't have
value in God's eyes;
I'm just saying that we soak
this guy in a vat of HCl
for a couple of hours?
This son of a bitch
will just fizzle away.
Wait a minute.
We're not really
thinking about this?
He's right, Dad.
Nelson's right.
We don't have time
to go to Campbell Sport.
You're right, it's too far.
What was I thinking?
Dad, do you have a shovel?
Does Flipper pee in the sea?
I got that!
No, no, guys--
Well, do you have
a better idea?
Do you? Because
I'd love to hear it.
No, but have you ever
dug a foxhole before, Boyd?
Because I have and it
takes a super long time!
Oh, he's right!
Nelson's right.
We could-- we can burn him.
You know, like a fire.
Burning could work,
burning's good!
That's good, Nel--
What's going on, Dad?
If we're gonna burn him,
it's a hell of a lot easier
if you parcel him out.
You got any bourbon?
Hey, Doug!
Dougie doodle.
Who said that?
Bingo.
You can talk?
You're seeing
my lips move, ain't ya?
Well then, that would constitute
talking, wouldn't it?
Is this a dream?
"Is this a dream?" Maybe,
maybe it's a dream,
or maybe I'm your subconscious,
secretly trying to
unearth truth for you
in the form
of a waking hallucination.
Listen Doug, let me
get to the gristle
of why I woke you up
here. It breaks my heart
to tell you this, but
Santa ain't gonna find you,
not here, not anywhere.
Why not?
Because he doesn't exist.
Yeah, don't take
it so hard, buddy.
As you get older, you'll learn
there are much worse things
you could be told
than some fat guy
in a red suit doesn't exist.
Alright then,
sleep tight, kid.
And oh uh, Merry Christmas.
Radiator's shot.
Who ya calling there, Boyd?
Luann.
Let her know
we're not gonna make it.
Not gonna make it?
Hold on a sec, Boyd.
Hey look, I know that
we have been through a lot,
well, me getting stuck
in the john
and you getting pegged with
a nail gun by some kid,
and running from that cop,
and trying to figure out
different ways
to dismember a transient,
but it's Christmas,
and if we quit now,
it's like the baby Jesus died
up on that cross for nothing.
I think
that's Easter, actually.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
you're right, you're right.
My point is, you know,
I suppose I don't know much
about being a father yet,
since BJ's only been around
a couple of months
and he's technically
some Mexican's, on top
of that but, you know,
what I seen you do today, Boyd--
go to the ends of the earth
for your son like that--
jeez, that's what being
a father's all about.
And I just don't think
you should quit now.
There's still time.
Hey, uh, I'm really sorry we
almost killed you back there.
I don't suppose you have
a vehicle we could borrow?
'Cause we're about
10 miles from where
we're supposed to
be here, and um--
I don't know how else
to put this, except...
we're hoping for
a friggin' Christmas miracle.
¶ Fall on your knees ¶
¶ Oh, hear the radiant
voices calling ¶
¶ Oh God, oh God ¶
¶ Boom, boom, boom ¶
Oh, shoot!
Luann, are you okay?
I'm okay, I'm okay.
Yeah!
Come on you guys, wake up!
Let's go up
and see if Santa came.
¶
They're breathing. Come on!
Come on, whoa, whoa!
See, I told you Santa's real!
Now we can find our stuff.
Pull up there, there!
What do you
think you got, Bug?
I don't think I got anything.
We can't thank you enough.
Merry Christmas,
it's been a flight!
¶
Where you goin', they're up?
Yeah. He's up. All the kids
have their presents.
So what, go on in there
and give him the thing!
He'll know
there's no Santa, Dad!
Maybe Santa took your presents
to the wrong house, or--
No.
There is no Santa.
Look.
Puba said he loved bourbon.
Merry Christmas.
Good luck.
Oh!
No Douglas, don't!
You must be Douglas.
Are you Santa?
Oh, yes indeed. Yes, I am.
Why'd you drink
all that bourbon, Santa?
Won't it make you drunk?
Well, Douglas,
bourbon gives Santa the energy
that he needs to keep
his appointed rounds.
And asparagus.
Puba told me that.
Yep, asparagus, too.
Smart fella.
Oh my goodness,
I almost forgot your present.
Merry Christmas, Douglas.
Thank you, Santa.
I believe.
And I hope you always do.
Santa, don't you
want your asparagus?
That's okay,
Douglas, you keep it.
Asparagus makes
my urine smell funny.
Merry Christmas.
I think it was a big success.
On second thought
this may have not been
such a hot idea.
No matter how this pans
out, you tried your best.
Bottom line, you're one
hell of a good dad, Boyd.
Thanks, Dad.
Merry Christmas, Bug.
Dad, why did your
massage take so long?
Let me help you.
- Nice wrap job there.
- What is it?
What do you say?
I built it, the whole thing.
I even sanded
the runners myself.
It's really something.
Really something.
Wow, it's pretty cool, huh?
Hmm, neat, but no snow.
Let's see what else there is.
Uh, hey Bug!
Uh, look,
I found this outside for you.
Santa must have dropped it.
Bridge for juniors!
I've always wanted to
learn how to play bridge!
Woo-hoo, alright!
Neato, look at what I got!
I'm sorry.
I'm drunk.
I remain sorry.
And I accept your apology.
Oh for cripe's sake,
Boyd, get a Goddamn room
if you're gonna be doing that.
Dave's the designated
pervert in this family.
He's not a pervert!
Hey, hey!
Rancer!
You think I would
have known better.
Oh, I suppose.
But if we always learned
from our mistakes,
nobody'd ever spend
Christmas with their family.
What the hell good is getting
a sled in this day and age
of global warming? You should
have got the kid a boat.
Shut up, Dad.
Dad, can we go inside
and play some bridge now?
¶
Look Dad, it's snowing!
You're right, Bug.
Probably ash.
¶
¶ More, more, more, more ¶
¶ Can't you hear it? ¶
¶ Love comes through ¶
¶ Give me happiness ¶
¶ You're like the sun ¶
¶ You're my holiday,
my favourite one ¶
¶ More than I wished for ¶
¶ Bum, bum, bum-bum-bum-bum ¶
¶
¶ Ring , ring  ¶
¶ I hear the birds ¶
¶ Sing , sing  ¶
¶ Sweet Noel ¶
¶ Peace for everyone,
be all good cheer ¶
¶ A merry, wonderful
time of year ¶
¶ More than I wished for ¶
¶ Bum, bum, bum-bum-bum-bum ¶
¶
¶ You're my angel and the sun ¶
¶ You are my mistletoe ¶
¶ You're my star
that's shining bright ¶
¶ You are my Silent Night ¶
¶ You're the sweetest
little thing ¶
¶ You are out of a dream ¶
¶ You're my sugar and my spice ¶
¶ You're the naughty
to my nice ¶
¶ You are the one ¶
¶ You're more than I wish for ¶
¶ Bum, bum, bum-bum-bum-bum ¶
¶ More than I wished for ¶
¶ Bu-doo-bum, boom boom ¶
¶ Joy to the world,
the Lord has come ¶
¶ And he's drivin' a
big green bass boat ¶
¶ Circling around
your castle's moat ¶
¶ He's the new favourite
late night talk-show host ¶
¶ That's why we try ¶
¶ To love ¶
¶ Now that you're here,
come gather round ¶
¶ Check out these treasures
that I found ¶
¶ One makes a flash,
the other makes a sound ¶
¶ But none will catch you
from crashing down ¶
¶ That's why we try ¶
¶ To love ¶
¶
¶ Life just kicks you, 1-2-3 ¶
¶ Keeps us guessing him or me ¶
¶ There's always more to see,
always more want ¶
¶  ¶
¶ That's why we try ¶
¶ To love ¶
¶
¶ The weather outside
is frightful ¶
¶ And the fire is so inviting ¶
¶
¶ The sound of sleigh bells
ringing ¶
¶ Is all the more delightful ¶
¶
¶ The sight of snow falling
lightly on her cheek ¶
¶
¶ The things around this little
town aren't so bleak ¶
¶
¶ And the lights are up
on the door ¶
¶ They say it's Christmas time ¶
¶ And I felt this once before ¶
¶ And I can't get it
out of my mind ¶
¶
¶ We can go out walking till
the snow starts to gleam ¶
¶ Do you remember the stories
I told you? ¶
¶ Or was it all a dream? ¶
¶ I still can't believe that you
are with me once again ¶
¶ My dear ¶
¶ Deck the halls
with boughs of holly ¶
¶ Fa la la, la la la, la la la ¶
¶ Tis the season to be jolly ¶
¶ Don we now our gay apparel ¶
¶ Fa la la, la la la, la la la ¶
¶ Troll the ancient
Yule tide carol ¶
¶ Fa la la la la ¶
¶ La la la... ¶
¶ La... ¶
¶ La! ¶
¶ Ah... ¶
¶ ...la! ¶
That's what you gotta commit
to a song.
Okay.
That's why we don't get
first place.