"118:8"
Perhaps this might be too absurd for you,
but I love my wife.
I'm faithful to her.
I want to have kids with her.
I want to grow old by her side.
Got it?
THE INVISIBLE WOMAN
Honey?
Hi, honey!
Love of my life!
I'm home!
Honey?
Where are you?
Hey, gorgeous!
I cleared 3 streets to get here early.
Pedro, I want a divorce.
You want to divorce me? Why?
- You're the greatest guy in the world.
- And?
Our life is tranquil,
harmonious, calm...
- And?
- It's smothering me.
Marina!
It can't be! Why?
Because I wanted more excitement.
But why?
Because women become unhappy
when their leading happy lives.
I can make you unhappy,
if that makes you happy!
I'll do anything for you!
I'm pregnant.
But that's wonderful.
- No, it's not.
- But why not, honey?
Because you're not the father.
What do you mean,
"you're not the father?"
Pedro...
This is Johann.
Listen up, pal. We need to have
a talk, man to man.
He's German and doesn't speak
a word in Portuguese.
- Hallo.
- "Hallo", my ass!
- Ja.
- "Ja", my ass!
- How can you be sure the kid isn't mine?
- I got tested.
We're going to Germany tonight.
He'll send for my things, next week.
- How long has this been going on?
- Six months.
-God, the conference in Fortaleza!
- The conference in Fortaleza!
He came to Brazil
to carry out a merger.
And he did:
Carrying you away from my life!
Marina, ist das alles klar hier?
I'll take her bag. I'll take her bag.
I'll take her bag.
Can I at least have the pleasure
of carrying your suitcase?
Listen!
How could you do this to me?
How could you not see
that I was doing this to you?
- I don't know who you are, Marina.
- You looked at me
and only saw what you wanted to.
I've been dedicating my life for you
for six years.
You live inside your own dream
of a perfect life.
There isn't room for anything
that doesn't fit in it.
I felt lonely. It was as if everything I did,
didn't matter at all.
As if I was invisible.
Come on you zombie. Wake up!
- Wake up.
- Oh, Marina, Marina...
Marina? What Marina?
Marina, the most wonderful woman
in the world.
No! No! Sit up. Sit up.
Sit up. Sit up.
Look at me. Look at me.
I'm with you. Look at me.
Look at me.
Marina is a slut.
Say it. Say it. Let it out.
Let it out: Marina is a slut.
- Marina is a slut.
- Exactly!
And dumped you 3 weeks ago.
Look at me.
She's moved on
and it's time for you to do the same.
Get up.
Get up!
This is crazy!
It's absurd!
It's 8:15 AM!
Pedro, the time is now!
Right now, Pedro!
Welcome to the wonderful world
of bachelordom, Pedro.
Stalk, sniff, attack
and go for the kill, Pedro!
Go!
Pedro!
Sorry, I don't remember you.
Carla. From the 8th grade.
Skinny Carla?
You're looking awesome
with these lights all over your body.
Kiss me on the lips!
Kiss me!
Do you know you're the second man
I've had sex with in my life?
But why me?
I've always thought
you were a sensitive guy.
I've got something to tell you.
You know, I've had it
with datingjiu-jitsu wrestlers.
I see dead people all the time.
Right here, right now.
Right next to you.
I'm going to be your child's mother.
And I'm going to be
your son's mother's wife.
Unfortunately,
I'm not my own son's father.
- Let's go!
- Idiot! Party pooper!
Cops have no life,
cops are always on the job.
Cops do not have kids!
Barata Ribeiro blocked.
TKS.
- Hello!
- I give up!
-Give up what?
- Everything. Tell Nogueira...
that Rio can drown
in its own trafficjams.
Wait a second...
And I don't want to screw
anyone anymore!
Are you... Dude!
Dude, wait!
I don't ever want to see
a woman in my life again.
3 MONTHS LATER
Lonely in time...
Loneliness...
Marina, I never noticed you
because you never existed.
Goodbye.
I'm sorry.
No problem. It's just that no one
has knocked here in a while.
It's all right.
Sometimes I also disappear.
- And you are?
- Amanda. Your neighbor.
I've never seen you before.
I moved in just a month ago,
and you don't get out much, right?
Me? Yeah.
I'm taking a break from the world.
Working some things out.
- I could come later.
- No.
How can I help you?
A cup of sugar.
I couldn't sleep
and when that happens,
I need to have some cake.
Then I realized I was out of sugar
and I was afraid of not sleeping.
Then I thought,
"I'm not going out to buy sugar at this
hour in such a violent city as this. "
I thought I could ask a neighbor.
But I don't know anyone here.
But then I heard some strange noises
coming from your apartment.
- From in here?
- Yeah.
- Oh, it's just that I was... singing.
- That's right!
Then I thought,
"that's what neighbors are for. "
So I decided to give it a shot.
- Do you have any?
- Do I have any what?
- Sugar.
- Yes, come on inside.
Candlelight is beautiful, isn't it?
Yeah. They cut off my electricity
not so long ago.
They also cut my phone, but that's OK.
I never used it.
It's going to be really tough
when they take away the candles.
Sugar...
The food is starting to go bad in the fridge,
but I still have some sugar.
You're funny.
- You think so?
- I do.
My goodness! You're beautiful!
And so are you.
Die, monster, die!
And now...
it's time.
I have killed my sole companion
in this cave!
I killed the wolf,
but I'm going to die alone!
Alone!
Out!
It was astonishing, sis.
Astonishing.
It was a disaster, Lúcia.
No, they're kids. They will have
forgotten it all by tomorrow.
That was a bad idea
to write a play for kids!
What's wrong?
- Márcio got laid off from the bank.
- Oh!
There was a merger, and because
he was over 40, they fired him.
- What are you going to do now?
- He's working for me now.
These kiddie parties are what
are paying our bills, you know.
My God,
that guy is still checking you out.
That's horrible, Lúcia.
It's been only 3 months since...
Since what?
Since the pig died?
I practically killed him.
Because you didn't heed your master's call
when he wanted you to do it?
No, because I was...
eavesdropping on my neighbors
as my husband lay dying.
Didn't the doctor tell you
a million times that it was sudden?
That there was nothing you could do?
It was a massive heart attack.
God, you should go partying,
should be celebrating now,
looking for a new job,
going back to school,
fooling around with...
that incredible man
who can't take his eyes off you.
But if you don't want him,
go screw your neighbor.
He wants to be left alone.
He withdrew from the world
because of love.
This is the perfect moment
to make a move...
because when men don't get any
for a long time,
they go crazy.
The time is now.
I can't simply go and knock on his door
just like that.
Use the old "I need sugar" line.
It works great.
That's ridiculous.
You better do it now
before another woman beats you to it.
Good morning.
Here.
This is going to be good for you.
- Am I supposed to eat that?
- Yes.
- What is it?
- Soup. Chicken soup.
- What?
- Chicken soup. Have some.
- What is this place?
- Your apartment.
- It looks so different.
- I tidied it up a bit.
And you are?
Your neighbor.
Remember the cup of sugar?
What happened?
I'm not sure whether you fell asleep
or just passed out.
I was going to call for a doctor,
but you seemed fine.
You had a smile on your face
the whole time.
- For how long did I sleep?
- A couple of days.
- A couple of days? What about you?
- I left and then came back.
I thought I could take care of you.
I dreamt about you.
I've also been dreaming about you, too.
I mean...
I couldn't help it.
The way we met.
I had this weird feeling...
as if I was part of you.
I'm feeling the same thing.
Then you passed out and I put in bed.
I looked around your apartment
and I decided to help out.
I threw away the pizza boxes,
the empty bottles,
and cleaned up the kitchen.
Then I saw your papers lying around
and I felt like tidying it up.
That's when I saw the photos,
the poems, the letters...
so many letters...
you must have loved her very much.
I envied her.
Please don't talk like that. I can't take it.
- I know. I'll be going now.
- No, wait. Go on. I cut you off.
It's just that...
- I'm embarrassed by what happened.
- Please, go on.
What happened?
I read your letters to Marina.
- You read my letters?
- Yes.
I think you're the most amazing
man in the world.
I think you wrote like a god.
And any woman who reads what
you've written
would certainly
fall in love with you.
I feel great.
I feel great!
Who are you? Who are you?
I am the same as you.
I am loneliness in search of companionship...
I am tenderness
in search of affection...
I'm a woman in search of a husband,
a father for my children...
Someone who wants to love, to build,
to work and to live in peace.
Away from
all the madness in this world.
I want someone to share
the adventure that is life.
And most of all...
I want to make love to you.
I'm sure it will have been the best thing
I will have done in my life.
Praise the Lord!
Amanda, Amanda, my love!
Amanda, my love, Amanda!
Come with me, come with me now...
Amanda!
Amanda?
The traffic
is the blood of this city,
and we are
the circulatory system's defense.
Traffic operators are the white blood cells
that defend the human body.
So you want your job back?
Do you regret your behavior?
You went nuts because
your wife left you,
but now you're saying
that you're fine.
You want to have the privilege to
work at this sacred profession again.
- Exactly, Nogueira.
- I'm sorry!
I can't have a cancerous
cell working for me.
Nogueira, I've worked in this loony bin
for over 8 years.
I'm the best traffic controller
you've ever had.
I came up with 10 out 10 bright ideas
that you've had,
including
the human blood metaphor,
which you've been using for the last 6 years.
So, you must be desperate to have me
because there is no one in this city
who would agree to do that
for this amount of money.
I can't have a nutjob
working for me!
Mr. Nogueira,
accident on Brasil Ave.
Involving a cargo truck,
a beverage truck
five dead
and a school bus.
The truck has tumbled, people
threat to steal the goods.
All right.
You can take over desk number 6.
But I'm warning you.
Any abnormal behavior
and you're fired.
Gentlemen, I'm back!
- So, he's alive!
- Son of a bitch!
Pedro Albuquerque de Morais!
You're looking good.
Have you been getting some action?
That's none of your business,
but I'm not.
From that smile and these sharp clothes
I'd say you've got to be getting some!
If you really want to know:
Perhaps I am.
- Ah...
- No way!
- Oops!
- What's up?
Welcome to the land of the living.
- Sorry. I should have called, right?
- No, no need to do that.
I gave up on you the day
I busted down your door
and found out that instead of dead,
you were drunk
- sleeping on the couch in your undies.
- Well, I'm fine now.
And I've got a job!
Look at you...
looking all self-confident.
You must be screwing someone.
Huh? Huh?
Come on, dude.
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
Who is it? Who is it?
My neighbor.
She knocked on my door asking
for a cup of sugar.
We like the same things,
we read the same books
and listen to the same type of music.
Shit, man!
She makes love like a goddess.
It's like she feels,
she knows exactly what I need.
- I don't believe it.
- Maybe...
just maybe,
it might be too soon to tell,
but I think she might be
the love of my life.
Pedro, you fell for the first slut
you screwed in over 3 months?
We must get to a whorehouse
right now!
Rosalvo,
what's your cousin's number again?
After we finish making love,
we just lie there...
You would have fallen in love
with a 90-year-old lady.
I'm sure you know
nothing about her life.
- What?
- What's her story?
Where did she come from?
Who has she fucked already?
Do you know?
You don't, man.
So, before you say that she is the love
of your life, find out who she is.
- So, what's up?
- So what?
What do you mean what?
Your neighbor.
- What about him?
- What have you been hearing lately?
I haven't been hearing
anything at all.
It's over, sis.
- It's over, before it even started.
- Whatever!
- This man never noticed me.
- Honey, it's impossible not to notice you.
Goodness, he didn't even notice you.
- Let's go.
- Where to?
Where else? To the wall.
I took off my dress.
I was afraid of getting it dirty.
I got carried away
with the cleaning.
It was sorely needed, right?
- So, did you like it?
- Yes.
Stop crying!
I can't hear a word they're saying.
- I bought it so we could celebrate.
- Celebrate what?
Your return to your job.
You got it back, didn't you?
Yes, I did. I told Nogueira that thing
you told me to tell him and he loved it.
I knew it!
We need to talk, Amanda.
Look, a Bloody Mary.
Just the way you like it.
- What's that smell?
- It's the bath I prepared for you.
- You prepared a bath for me?
- I did.
Amanda, we need to talk.
Stop crying. I think he's dumping
the bitch. Come here.
I just realized that
I've told you all about me,
- and that I know nothing about you.
- Pedro, I don't like talking about my past.
I've told you that.
I didn't exist before I met you.
Here.
You told me you weren't
eavesdropping anymore.
It's not for me,
it's for you.
Put this on, please.
I've been spilling my guts to you
after a hard blow.
Pedro, certain things
should be left in the past.
- Not for two people who love each other.
- You're not going to like it.
I can't take it!
Tell me!
What's going on?
What are they talking about?
I can't hear a word she's saying.
My father died when I was 7.
And my mother married an oyster farmer
in Florianópolis.
What is it?
I think she's got a mouthful.
We lived on a deserted beach.
I rarely saw other people.
I think I survived because of the sea.
How so?
I enjoyed swimming in the nude.
It's refreshing, isn't it?
When I turned 13,
my body changed,
and my stepfather started
to take notice.
He abused me
on top of a fishing net.
- How awful!
- I loved it.
Then my mother found out and sent me
to a Catholic boarding school.
That was great, right?
The nuns were no angels.
I ran away to Porto Alegre.
Great. A very nice city.
Not the brothel
I ended up working at.
Oh, my God... do you...
is that what you do for a living?
I stayed long enough
to save some money to come to Rio.
And how do you...
- make a living nowadays?
- I make a living...
as a phone sex operator.
I listen to all the perverts
over the phone.
So?
Do you trust me a bit more now?
Where's your princess?
I already said she'll be here,
and she will. Just relax!
Pedro, a night like this, Pedro!
You've been suffering for that woman
for the last 2 hours.
She said she'd be here.
Well then...
call her up on her cell phone.
She doesn't have one!
Don't pay any attention
to what I say to say to you?
You said you weren't nervous.
Just look at you.
Yes, I'm nervous, so what?
I get nervous every time she disappears.
- Isn't it right?
- She's not supposed to vanish, isn't it?
But she always comes back!
How can this be possible?
She didn't show up
and she won't show up.
She won't.
Oh, my...
Barbara!
Pedro, this is Barbara. Barbara, Pedro!
Who's this guy?
This is Pedro. Crazy Pedro.
It's just Pedro.
There's nothing crazy about me.
Don't worry.
Everyone's a little bit crazy.
Take me for example,
I'm completely stoned.
And my friends just loved you.
Amanda, it's none of your business
where I've been.
I had a very important meeting
with the Norwegians...
Amanda,
it's none of your business.
I had a very important
meeting with...
the Japanese...
Amanda!
It's none of your business!
You're so beautiful!
You...
Honey, you're here...
I'm way too stoned.
Way too stoned.
That's all right.
I made out with two women.
Twins. Both of them.
That's all right.
Doesn't it bother you at all?
I'm very jealous.
I feel like going away.
Don't say that. I can't take it.
I need to in order to exist.
Come here...
I'm naked.
Hey, man!
What's up, stud?
Way to go, man!
Two girls at the same time.
You look rested.
Amanda took care of me.
She was jealous,
wasn't she?
Because of the meeting
with the Japanese.
- I told her everything.
- About the meeting?
No, that I fucked the twins.
For the love of God!
Why did you do that?
Carlos, I made up my mind.
I'm going to marry her.
- Marry her?
- Marry her.
Why are you going to marry her?
What for?
You're going to marry a woman that
I haven't even met?
Everything is cool. I know her and
I'm the one who's going to marry her.
Pedro, she skipped step 1,
where she pretends to like your friends.
She jumped straight to step 3, where
she doesn't even want to see them.
If this is happening now,
when you're just neighbors,
imagine what it will be like
when you get married!
You'll never see your friends again.
Wait until you give her the keys
to your apartment.
I've already done that.
- The keys to my apartment!
- What?
- I've already gave her the keys!
You see?
Do you know what she'll do next?
She's going to convince you
to work from home
and that's just slavery.
Until the day she dumps you
for a German millionaire.
- Enough!
- You didn't like that?
- You're insulting me!
- Am I?
- You're crazy!
- You're the one who's crazy.
Mistaking being horny with marriage.
You're sick!
- Enough!
- You're sick!
- Move it!
Don't honk the horn!
It's my car, I'll honk!
- It's my car!
- You're yelling at me!
What's up, dude?
What's going on tonight?
The Catacomb?
No, I'm going alone.
I mean...
The hunter has just seen his prey.
Ooops!
My God! Are you hurt?
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
I'm sorry that I'm laughing.
But it was too funny.
Laugh all you want.
Be my guest.
But in return, you'll have to go with me
to a party tonight.
I can't believe this.
It's just a party tonight...
at the Catacomb.
I can't believe I fell for that.
Wait...
can I get your number? No?
- What a moron!
- What's wrong?
This Varley is a moron!
The team is losing
and he subs a forward like Herivelto
for Timbinha, a center-half.
He filled the team with defenders.
I think he enjoys losing.
- Who's playing?
- Luisiana vs. Sobradinho.
What?
Luisiana vs. Sobradinho.
A minor league classic.
Now they are tied.
They'll have to decide on the free kicks.
How about some strip-betting?
I'll give you a headstart.
I'm not wearing panties...
Are you sure?
We barely know each other.
It's crazy.
Do you want to go out?
Have a few drinks,
celebrate, party?
You're all I need to exist.
You too!
Carlos... Carlos, look at that.
Isn't that your friend Pedro?
Look, he's totally high!
Some people
don't need any company.
As for me... I need you.
- I saw you yesterday.
- Yesterday?
3:30am, at the Catacomb.
Catacomb?
So you saw me with my sweetie pie?
- My sweet honey!
- What?
- You saw my Amanda? Did you?
- No.
- I didn't.
- You did.
Next Tuesday the governor
will honor us with his visit.
You were all by yourself
on the dance floor,
completely out of it.
Really out of it.
The governor can't get stuck in traffic
on his way here.
- We're engaged.
- Excuse me?
Engaged. Wedding.
Wedding. Engaged.
Pedro... Pedro...
Let's go get some fresh air.
Sometimes, when we don't have sex
for a very long time,
we tend to lie.
That's normal.
But, lying to your brother about
getting engaged is just ridiculous!
I don't understand.
You were high and by yourself
at the club last night.
I saw you.
There's no denying it.
You... You're out of your mind!
- You are completely out of your mind!
- Me?
I'm getting married
at the end of the year
- and you're telling me it's all a lie?
- I'm saying that you can trust me!
You're jealous.
Jealous?
Why do you think I'm jealous?
Of you?
Because I am able to love and you're not!
You'll end up alone.
No kids, no grandchildren.
Alone! All by yourself.
Alone!
Solo!
I'll be right back!
Not you again.
No, it wasn't on purpose.
I ran here and I tripped.
I wanted to give you this.
I made this for you.
Please. Don't leave me hanging here.
Please, accept it.
Please?
Open the origami.
YOU'R E THE DAUGHTER-IN-LAW
MY FATHER WAS LOOKING FOR. CALL ME.
Ok?
I think your friend Carlos
is jealous of me.
You know what he said?
That I need professional help.
- And you really do need it!
- Show me some respect.
Look at the line. Shame on you.
What?
You've never seen a beautiful woman?
Good evening
and enjoy the movie, sir.
-Good evening.
- Enjoy the movie, sir.
- Shall we?
Sir, I'm not unauthorized to hold on
to someone else's ticket.
- What do you mean "someone else's"?
- You gave me two tickets.
Yes, my ticket and the lady's ticket.
And what lady would that be?
Lady... the lady.
Are you calling me a lady, sir?
I'm calling her a lady.
I'm not going to argue with you.
Your name? Jefferson.
Get me your boss, please.
- Good Evening.
- Perhaps for you.
- Your name is?
- Geraldo.
Your employee, Jefferson,
doesn't want to accept my tickets.
There's nothing wrong with the tickets.
I was only telling him
that he didn't need 2 tickets.
- And why not?
- He's alone.
Oh, yes.
Sir, our policy is that
we can't hold on to anyone's tickets.
- Are you alone, sir?
- No, I'm here with my... honey?
Honey? Amanda!
Has anyone seen my wife?
- Have you seen my wife?
- No, I haven't, sir.
Have you seen my wife?
This is the kind of thing that,
if people in Brazil had any scruples...
- Honey? Amanda?
- Oh, my!
- Where were you?
- The movie has already started!
How why did you leave downstairs?
They were giving me a hard time
because of the tickets.
The movie!
What's this? You pervert!
- This is love, lady.
- Asshole!
You're the asshole, man.
Respect other people's feelings.
You're supposed to do that
in the bathroom!
What are you doing? This is outrageous.
Are you waiting for someone?
No, it's just the two of us.
As you wish. Here's the menu.
I'll go get another one.
That guy is not well.
Look, wine...
Honey. Order me some water.
I need to go to the bathroom.
Right now? Please, come back soon.
Pedro...
We need to talk.
Amanda is sitting there.
It's her chair.
Amanda is here, she'll be right back,
then you'll understand everything.
Amanda!
Are you all right?
There's no Amanda here.
I'm Paula, ok?
She must have gone back home.
That's it. That must be it.
Pedro... you're dating
a woman who is unreal.
I think she's amazing too.
No, she's not amazing.
She's invisible.
Invisible. She doesn't exist.
She's a figment of your imagination.
- I'm calling the police.
- No, no, no!
Don't do that.
You're going to end up in jail.
Pedro, listen to me.
I was at the movie theater.
I was there when you arrived.
I saw the whole incident
with the tickets.
Believe me my friend,
you were by yourself!
Are you crazy?
You're out of your mind!
Look...
I'm engaged to her.
For the past 2 months!
All right.
Then show me a picture of her.
Marina took my camera. And Amanda
doesn't like having her picture taken.
Pedro...
here's what you're going to do:
You're going to take a picture of
both of you together.
You just have to press here.
All right?
- Only to prove that you're an asshole.
- Okay.
I'm out of here.
I'll be home if you need me.
What happened? You vanished!
- I don't like that friend of yours.
- What friend?
The one who interrupted our dinner
and who just left your apartment.
Amanda, Carlos is my best friend.
He wants to split us up.
- It's no that. He's just concerned.
- About what?
He thinks that I'm going crazy.
- Are you?
- Crazy about you.
He thinks...
that you don't exist.
Oh, really? What does he want?
That I disappear?
Don't say that, I couldn't take it.
He just asked...
if I could take a picture of you.
- Of us.
- I don't like photos.
I know, butjust one photo...
What for?
To...
To prove that we exist.
I'm not some trophy for you
to parade around
for your sexist friends.
So, did you take a look?
I couldn't open the damned file!
Or were afraid of opening by yourself?
Hey, "Batman". Tell the "Boy Wonder"
that I'm watching him.
Did it open?
- Do you get it now?
- Got it.
Do you understand why
I'm so crazy about her?
I understand that you're
completely out of your mind.
Amanda! Amanda!
- I'm right here.
- Are you?
Oh, yeah? But you're not here.
I can explain.
Explain what? That you don't exist?
I was waiting for the right moment
to tell you.
Oh, really? And when was going to be?
At our wedding?
Better, when our first son was born?
I was just trying to help you
help yourself.
- You fooled me!
- No, you fooled yourself!
You made me look like an idiot!
Didn't want the ideal woman?
I might not me real, but I am ideal.
I was so naive.
Of course! There are no ideal women.
The word is self-explanatory:
Ideal belongs to the world of ideas.
So, I do exist, in your imagination.
Your love is proof of that.
I'm talking to myself in my living room,
as if it were a normal thing to do.
You're not talking to yourself.
What? I can hear you.
I don't want you listening to me!
Pedro, I'll die without you.
- Goodbye, Amanda!
- Goodbye, Amanda?
Goodbye, Amanda.
What do you mean?
Goodbye, Amanda?
I did everything for you!
I lived my whole life for you!
And you think you can end it like this?
You use me and then just throw me away?
"Goodbye, Amanda"?
Is that what you're saying?
Is that what I'm thinking?
- What about our past?
- What about our future?
What about my future?
Is that what I'm thinking?
I may be a figment of your imagination,
but I also have rights!
Is that so? Then call your lawyer!
I love you, Pedro.
- Isn't that what you always wanted?
- Precisely, Amanda.
All I ever wanted was to be loved
by someone,
and not by nobody.
Goodbye, Amanda!
Pedro... no...
Pedro!
Pedro, let me in!
Open the door, Pedro!
Pedro, Let me in!
Pedro!
So, how are you?
Everything okay?
Everything is under control.
- And that little problem of ours?
- Its buried away.
Now you've just got to promise me,
swear that this will stay between us.
- Ok, on one condition...
- Between us.
On the condition that you tell me
if you start dating again. Deal?
- Deal.
Pedro, we need to talk.
What's that look?
Seems like you've never seen me.
Are you going to pretend
that I don't exist?
Pedrão, Pedro...
- Are you sure you're all right?
- What? I'm fine.
So, you're doing fine?
You used me and you're going to pretend
that our love is over?
Pedro!
Pedro! Talk to me!
Please, listen to me.
Pedro, stop, talk to me.
Look at me.
Pedro!
Pedro, I'm talking to you!
Governor, it gives me great pride...
I'll start screaming in here!
I'm honored to introduce you
to the finest traffic controllers.
These men and women who work...
under any kind of pressure.
Shut the hell up! This is insane!
Shut up! Show me some respect!
I'm at work!
My colleagues...
This is unacceptable...
Shut up! Shut the hell up!
You're fired!
You're fired! You're fired!
KNOWING HOW TO LOVE
LOVE YOURSELF AND CURE YOUR LIFE
GIVE A CHANCE TO DESTINY
Pedro, you're not going
to get rid of me so easily.
Pedro, open the door!
I'll keep on knocking!
A last chance to destiny.
Open it!
Get out of here!
Get out of my life!
You're sick!
I'll keep on knocking!
You have to open it!
Pedro, open the door!
You've got to listen to me!
Pedro, open it!
Was there ever any other woman for you?
I'm going to make your life miserable!
No, no, Pedro!
Pedro! Open the door!
Pedro!
Open it, let me in!
Open the door!
Pedro, open the door!
Pedro, please!
Pedro! Open the door!
Pedro! Let's talk?
Pedro!
No, Pedro!
- This...
- Pedro!
Is the story of a man
who fell in love with a woman
who did not exist.
This is the story of a man
who fell in love...
with a woman...
who did not exist.
A CHANCE TO DESTINY
"TRAVELLING CHANGES YOUR LIFE"
No, I don't believe it!
Burying yourself up in Minas Gerais
is simply unbelievable.
That's where we were born.
That's nothing more than
an abandoned farm, Vitória.
I'm going to study, write.
Our parents would be happy.
Is this because of the neighbor?
I don't believe it!
Janete, it's because of the neighbor.
I still don't understand
what you saw in that guy.
- Or heard, for that matter.
- Vitória, what did you see in that guy?
I don't know.
And you're going to run away
without finding out?
It's too late.
The movers are coming in on Wednesday.
So it's got to be today.
He was just himself.
The End.
"THE INVISIBLE WOMAN"
BY PEDRO ALBUQUERQUE
It's only the doorman.
Hi.
I don't think you know me.
I'm your neighbor.
- Neighbor?
- Yes.
I don't have sugar and...
Again!
Good morning.
What's this place? Where am I?
- It's the hospital.
- Why? What happened?
You had food poisoning.
- You're a big fan of canned tuna, right?
- Who brought me here?
Your chart says...
that you came alone.
Strange.
That can't be right.
Calm down and relax.
Are you feeling okay?
- Do you need a sleeping pill?
- Three.
Stay calm, okay?
- What?
- Aw!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I didn't mean to startle you!
- Who are you?
- I'm your neighbor.
The cup of sugar, remember?
- I've never seen you before.
- Right. And that's the problem.
- Are you real?
- What a beautiful question.
Of course I am.
- Did you bring me here?
- Yes.
- What time it it?
- 3 am.
3 am?
What are you doing in my room at 3 am?
I didn't want anyone to see me.
- Do you have a problem with that?
- No.
Listen. I did something terrible.
Let me guess: You used to swim
naked with horny nuns.
No.
I read your story.
- You read this?
- I did.
- I can explain.
- There's nothing to explain.
I know it's poetry...
I mean, pain.
I mean, you turne
your pain into poetry.
That's amazing literature.
The idea of an invisible woman.
You should get it published.
I came here to return it.
I'll leave now.
No, wait!
Wait!
Why did you knock
on my door last night?
Courage finally came to me,
but at the wrong time.
Why didn't you leave your name
here at the hospital?
I didn't want to mess up your life.
Your wife might not have liked it.
- No, Marina left a long time ago.
- I'm talking about Amanda.
- Did you ever meet Amanda?
- No.
But after reading your book,
I feel as if she's a part of me.
I know you've broken up.
How come you know
so much about my life?
How come I know
so much about your life?
Do you mind if I don't answer that question?
- Is it all right if I call the nurse?
- Are you not feeling well?
No. I'm well. I'm feeling fine.
I just want to call the nurse
so that he can see you.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have come here.
Hold on!
Nurse!
Nur... Buddy!
Hey!
Nurse? Hey, pal!
Could you please
get the girl who just left this room?
- Calm down. What girl?
- A very fair girl... She just left!
There's no girl here.
I'm going to give you a sedative.
I thought you were on vacation.
You said you were going away.
Oh, she's back.
No, I haven't seen Amanda
for over a month.
What was it then?
Where you committed?
- Are you still nuts?
- No. I'm fine.
I was even writing.
Writing? What do you mean writing?
As I was writing about my life,
she started to fade away.
I began focusing...
- A moment, please.
- Alright.
I was writing and the more focused,
the more she faded away.
The noise faded away.
I think it's a book.
- People who read it liked it.
- Pedro, listen.
You're a traffic controller that went nuts.
You can't write books.
Carlos, I met a woman...
- A nurse?
- No, you idiot...
- a neighbor.
- Ok.
She's the one who saved me.
She knocked on my door
asking for a cup of sugar.
- What?
- A cup of sugar.
Sugar? Sugar?
Pedro, do you have idea
of what you're saying?
I know. I know. It's starting
all over again. The same story.
But I feel that it's different now.
I just need to make sure.
OK, what do you want me to do?
I want you to go over my place.
Go to my building,
knock on her door and...
And?
And make sure she is for real.
She's on the left,
once you get off the elevator...
Now you have to go there
and finish the job.
He's in the hospital
and I'm leaving tomorrow morning.
That's why. See?
- You finally managed to talk to him!
- All right!
But I found out he loves that other woman
enough to write her a book.
I don't know.
Sometimes I think
you're imagining this woman.
I wouldn't be nuts to suffer
for an imaginary woman.
- Have you ever seen her?
- No.
Did you ever hear her?
I haven't, have you?
He wrote her a book.
Yet another reason why you should go
there and have sex with him.
Before she reads what he has written.
Here, drink up. For courage.
Tonight you'll go to the hospital,
bribe the nurse,
go to his room and fuck him.
At least if he's a bad lay you'll know
and you can take the bus
and bury yourself in Minas Gerais.
You?
Why did you leave like that?
Common sense.
But I'm over that.
Still wondering how I know so much
about your life?
The wall from your apartment
leaks every sound coming
from your living room into my kitchen.
I've been listening in on your life
for the last 6 years.
- And what did hear?
- Everything.
Could you hear Amanda speaking?
Show her what you've written.
It's the most beautiful love story
I've ever read.
I must tell this...
I never want to see Amanda
again in my life.
I just need to be sure that
this is really happening.
Me too.
- Are you sure now?
- Yeah...
- What's your name?
- Vitória.
You're so beautiful.
When I touched the door
to leave the note... it opened.
She's sensational, isn't she?
You saw her, didn't you?
There was no one there.
That's because she was here
when you went over.
There was nothing in the apartment.
It was completely empty.
- What do mean by empty?
- Empty. Nothing.
No one. Not a speck of dust.
You did go to the apartment on the left
when you exit the elevator...
Just like you said.
I had the most amazing night of my life
and the bitch wasn't even real!
You fucked another invisible woman.
Show some respect for a friend
who is going through...
I need to be alone.
You showed up!
- I want you to go away!
- Pedro.
Alakazam!
Alakazam! Alakazam!
Why are you doing that, Pedro?
You don't need to offend me.
This is all a lie!
What about yesterday?
I'll tell you all about yesterday: Nothing!
Yesterday did not happen!
Get away from me! Alakazam!
Excuse me, please.
I'm late for a date.
What date?
You can't be late for a date...
because the only person
you could meet with is me.
And I don't want to meet with you.
Get it?
I don't want to see you anymore.
Get out of my way! Be gone!
For someone who's not real,
you hit pretty hard.
Carlos, this is not a good time.
- Please get me out of here.
- Of course...
I should have told you.
I should have told you that she existed.
- You two were kissing.
- That's the catch.
Does she know that
I think that she isn't real?
No. Not yet. But I'll tell her.
I'll tell her today.
I keep putting it off,
but man, I really screwed up.
- I fell for her.
- You piece of shit!
You know everything
that I've told her.
- I'm going to tell her.
- No, you can't do that to me!
Please, don't do that. Please!
I swear I'll tell her!
Let me be the one to tell her.
Man, I like this woman.
That's why I haven't told her yet.
You were right.
I have never loved anyone in my life.
Man, if I lose her...
I'll end up alone like
you said I would.
Come on, man. I'm your pal.
Have you ever seen me like this before?
Have you?
Come on then. Give me a break.
Let her decide.
A lot has happened in these last 2 weeks
that you stayed in the hospital.
She...
wants me to meet her sister
later tonight.
She also likes me.
It's all right.
Go talk to her,
and tell her
that I want everyone to be happy.
- Are you all right?
- I feel good.
I've decided to go on a trip.
- Can I keep her?
- Yes, you can.
I've got to go. She's waiting.
- Will you marry me?
- Pedro...
Marry me, for real. Forever.
- But Pedro, darling, I don't exist.
- That's just a small detail.
But I am you.
I know, but no one
ever cared for me so much before.
That only means
that you took care of yourself.
I've never felt so happy
before in my life.
I love you, Pedro.
That means that deep down
you love yourself.
- But you're so hot.
- Then so are you.
Go fight for the woman you love.
No. She went out with Carlos.
He is going to talk to her.
Maybe I'll call her tomorrow.
Let's get out of the tub,
let's go to the bedroom.
She's with him because
you were rude to her
and told her to get lost.
You don't say that to a woman.
And, besides, you only said that
because that scoundrel
didn't tell you she was real.
Tonight is a glorious night
for your bastard friend.
Where does he go
to celebrate his glory nights?
Dry Martini at Pietro's.
I feel like going out for a drink.
You look beautiful tonight.
- Carlos, we need to talk about Pedro.
- We have to, don't we?
I saw the way he looked at you.
I think you two are closer than
you are letting on.
- The lovebirds...
- Lúcia, please.
Carlos.
- Carlos, Lúcia.
- My pleasure!
- What a surprise! You didn't tell.
We a nephew on the way.
Or a niece.
- A nephew. A nephew.
- Wonderful.
- Carlos, Carlos.
- I wanted to say that...
The last couple of weeks have been
very special for me.
- For us.
- Carlos, I think you lied to me.
You said Pedro
was merely a co-worker.
Carlos, look at me!
Right. I mean...
We are more than just co-workers.
Pedro is gay. I knew it!
I told you he was strange.
I'm trying to tell you something
very difficult and complicated.
Just say it.
The truth is... Pedro!
Pedro, I'm not real.
- Did you invite the nutcase?
- Of course not.
Sit.
Why is he doing that?
Good evening.
Did he tell you? He didn't?
He didn't? Did he?
- Tell me what?
- Vitória, calm down.
- I was about to tell her.
- Tell me what?
Something about Pedro's illness.
Illness? What illness?
Were you aware he had an illness?
Did you use protection?
- Punch him in the face.
- I can't do that. He's my friend.
He's making you look like a nutcase.
- What's going on?
- What's this, Pedro? What?
- Aw!
- My God!
What's that?
- I'm leaving.
- Leave now? No way!
- It's time she knew the truth.
- Now?
He's talking to the air. Did you see?
Pedro, Pedro, look at me.
Who are talking to?
- I'm talking to Amanda.
- Amanda...
My God,
so that means that the book...
was a biography.
Not only is he gay,
but he's a spiritist too. Let it go, sis.
You punched your co-worker.
He's notjust my co-worker.
Excuse me, Amanda.
He's much more than that.
He's my brother.
And he made me believe that
you were a figment of my imagination.
I've been sitting quietly all this time,
but now I'm going to speak.
He asked me to go to her apartment
to find out if she was real or not.
I went, but no one was there.
I was in bad shape the day
I left the hospital,
My best friend was nuts.
Then my phone rang,
and I answered it.
Of course
I can come by your apartment.
It was the girl I had bumped into
a couple of times in the street.
Apartament number 807...
It was your street, your building,
your neighbor!
Alakazam!
Enough, sis!
From now on the world
will meet a new Vitória.
- He doesn't deserve you.
- I'm not moving away anymore.
- You're not?
- I called the origami guy.
What do you mean
you called the origami guy?
I asked him to come over.
And I'm going to fuck him.
Vitória, for God's sake,
he could be an asshole.
Then he'll be
the third asshole in my life.
Are you by any chance Vitória?
And then this goddess opened the door.
Do you know what she did?
Do you? Huh?
She kissed me.
She said she wanted
to make love to me.
I started sweating, my chest was tight
and I felt like I was drunk.
I realized that I was in love
for the first time in my life.
He's being sincere, Vitória.
That's why I couldn't tell you.
I was afraid you'd leave.
Marry me, Vitória.
Hey wacko,
aren't you going to say anything?
- Come on, Pedro.
- Dear God, what's this?
Go there and declare your love for her.
Fight for what you want.
And I'll go away forever.
- Are you sure?
- You're the one who's sure.
Oh, my God.
I am what you are.
I'm loneliness longing for companionship.
I'm a man searching for a woman,
the mother of my children.
I want someone to share
the mystery of this life.
And more than anything,
I want to marry you, Vitória.
Because I'm sure you're the best thing
I've ever done.
- Wow, Vitória.
- You're both completely insane.
Vitória!
Give me a break.
2 YEARS LATER
- You?
- Sueli.
- Thank you very much.
- Good reading!
To my best friend.
I don't believe it.
Triplets.
- No, no, no...
- Here.
They're gorgeous, aren't they?
- What's the mother like?
- This is a question...
I married Bárbara.
- Big Barbara?
- Yes, Big Barbara, Pedro!
Big Barbara!
- I've hooked, man. Hooked.
- Shameless!
I think we deserve each other.
What about you?
Did you get married?
I hope one day you can forgive me.
That's water under the bridge, buddy.
Have you been seeing anyone?
No, I haven't seen anyone.
I have a gift for you.
A great one.
Traffic tickets!
They're notjust
any traffic tickets.
They're traffic tickets
from Minas Gerais.
Under the name...
Vitória...
Monteiro.
It's got your name on it.
I saw it.
- So, you read it?
- Yes.
- What did you think?
- You didn't have the right to do this to me.
You hated it?
I loved it.
Didn't I tell you
she was going to love it?