It doesn't work.
The tape may be entangled.
No use?
How about the reverse side?
You have imagination, preservation,
and heartlessness called destruction.
These words, in Sanskrit,
are expressed in one word, "Aum".
"Aum" symbolizes
the heartlessness of the universe
which lies at the essence of
absolute truth.
And together with
our pursuit for Truth (=Shinri),
"Aum Shinrikyo" was derived from
these two meanings.
Well now, if you are
in doubt of your existence,
why don't you knock
at the gate of "Aum Shinrikyo"
Truly, this actual world.
This so-called human world
will take us into "Mae".
"Mae" tempts us to believe
that our whole life,
from the moment we are born
through to our deaths,
is as if it were true and unbreakable.
But the reality must be that
many messengers are being sent down.
For instance, there is
the great Yama king appearing
in the Sutras
who exterminates evil people.
March 1996, Tokyo
Aoyama Headquarters
Hey, Araki
It's Nakasone from TV Asahi
Oh, not him again
He wants your opinion
on the Joyu trial today
Always the same question.
Tell him to send it by fax.
Were you close to Joyu?
Close? Well, I respected him.
He worked for the Space Development
Agency.
I used to want to work there too.
How come?
Why'd you want to work there?
What about space interests you?
Well, it's a kind of riddle, isn't it?
A riddle, and mysterious too.
Like where do humans come from
and where they're heading?
Pick up the phone, ARAKI!
Hello.
I haven't heard the details yet, but
there were a lot of inaccuracies
in the indictment. But today
they'll go through all those details.
At the official trial...
It's about today's Joyu trial and
some related issues.
There'll be a lot of questions
today, so let's get them all via fax.
Is this a question?
Do they have one?
They want to talk to you...
Tell them to send their question by fax.
But, they're outside.
I don't care. That's their business.
I'm sorry. But our lines are flooded.
Could you send your questions by fax?
What's that?
Is that rubbish?
Uh. No.
It's vegetable protein.
It's a meat substitute.
We prepare it like this...
You have this everyday?
Everyday, that's right.
Don't you get bored?
No, no.
The hunger for all kinds of different
foods is the influence of carnal desire
on the diet.
I heard about a former believer
who visited.
Asahara arranged a meal.
A surprise - a juicy, red steak.
That's what the disciple must have
wanted to eat.
It would be a sin to eat what you want
elsewhere,
but if Master Asahara gave it to him,
he could eat it without sinning.
I think it's a kind of love.
But, what's the difference?
Even if it's the same food.
There's a difference eating with
or without Permission.
Would you explain your meal?
Not much to explain.
Rice, sesame, and hamburger.
But it's protein, not meat.
What's the egg?
Just a boiled egg.
And this broth?
Just a broth. I think.
You see you can slowly lose
your appetite. Eventually
you break it and you can live
without eating.
So you want to reject those moments
of pleasure that are. I think,
the most fulfilling moments of
human existence.
That's what Buddhism teaches...
Actually, I went too.
To sit in on Nakagawa's trial.
How was it?
Hmmm, well.
I didn't think he'd gone that far.
It was a bit of a shock.
So he admitted to the things that
media's reported?
I just came home, so I haven't seen
the news yet. But probably...
A complete confession?
Yes, that's what it was.
It was a shock?
Yes, what else is it, when you hear
it from a person's own mouth?
In my case, I don't have many of the
worldly joys of the laity.
Worldly joys like marriage and so on.
So, even if I were to quit Aum,
I'd like to get training
somewhere else.
So, more than Aum itself,
you're looking for a place outside
the lay world where you can train.
Hmmm...
It'd be great if there were a system
like Aum, a good training system
but, as far as I know,
there aren't any.
If there were a guru as great as the
Master. I might think differently.
But for now, I can't imagine
anyone besides the Master.
Must be cold out there. People
have their scarves on.
Windy too.
News crews?
What's it feel like from this side?
It's been a year since the subway
gassing. And Aum's first case...
Are you taping?
No, we're not. Would it be a
problem? This guy is.
He's asked us, so we let him.
We're not rolling yet.
It's really about whether we use
it or not.
I haven't spoken to the cameraman.
But, we're ready to roll anytime.
Now, you're saying we can't use it.
Right.
Tell us why.
Because we can't trust your show.
Please trust us.
Why? You don't respond to our
requests.
This is a question of journalistic
freedom.
I don't know if we're filming now,
but if we were, will you let us use it?
You don't know?
I operate independently of
the camera.
So maybe you're filming now?
Perhaps. Our camera is here
somewhere among...
Is that it?
No, they're different.
If we're not filming, we won't use
it, but if we are, then will you...
You said you weren't. How can you
ask that? You need to check first.
But I knew we wouldn't use it.
Please trust us.
If we've got this on film, then we
won't use it.
That should be a given.
I'm sure we're not recording...
I mean. I don't think we are.
"Don't think." There you go again.
Would you mind if we did?
The Nihon TV crew are right here.
Forget it. We can't deal with you.
Whys that?
This is Fuji TV.
What's your problem with Nihon TV?
Not Nihon TV. Just your show.
Are you filming now?
Please don't interrupt us.
Now about Nihon TV?
It's not Nihon TV, it's your program.
Just a bit.
Out of the question.
Even now?
You're shooting without asking?!
But. I just said I'm from Nihon TV.
But I told you not to.
This, neither?
This is why we can't trust you.
I definitely told you.
What's your problem?
You were blocking my view.
I was not.
Weren't you?
Just drop it.
You're the one getting in our way.
When we're discussing it...
Our position...
Convey the position we're in.
I'll relay what you're saying.
But, we also have to evaluate things...
So it may be hard...
Take into consideration my position.
But, I am thinking about you.
Think about my feelings.
Isn't that too much?
This is your job.
And yours too.
I'm being made into the object.
It's my face on TV.
Okay, okay.
Don't use that picture.
It's not my decision.
What I'm... Oh, forget it.
I agree, but the company stance
of journalistic freedom...
So I came to Tokyo wearing
my sports gear
with two bags and a backpack.
Aoyama was crawling
with news crews and policemen.
And me, a nervous country bumpkin,
totally lost in the big city.
The police stopped me, and all of a
sudden started interrogating me,
asking my name and making me open
up my bags. And. That's right when
the media swooped down on me.
With their cameras pointing.
I thought, so this is what the media
do. That was my first impression.
Death is inevitable.
Hang in there!
Show me the jacket?
Asahara 's Hell
Who bought the book?
Well, either Araki or me buys them
when we go out.
What do you think of it?
It's hard to say.
Where's the screwdriver set?
I had it earlier.
Who's singing?
It's the Master.
He's got a good range.
Training does that to everything.
Once everything is explained, you
can understand anything, I think.
Opening up the chakra in the
throat frees the voice.
On good days, they say the Master can
sing the full range of a piano keyboard.
I think that there are actually gods
at the Fuji Dojo.
You feel spirits?
Well. They take the form of humans.
Like who?
They have supernatural powers.
What?
Supernatural powers.
Are they current members?
Yeah. So, here's a frontier
with the gods.
But they won't show regular people.
They're not people in the Dress now?
That's right. They'd stick out if
regular people saw them.
What powers do they have?
They can tell whatever I'm thinking.
Even if I don't say anything.
Something like mind reading?
Seeing the depths of the heart
is what we call it.
They do this all the time.
And levitation?
That's... just a trick.
I have no interest in that, and the
Master says
it will only come naturally.
I used to bind my legs...
I like this
with a seatbelt that I modified.
Why bind your legs?
To get rid of karma from Hell.
So you torture yourself?
Not so much "torturing" as...
You see, I did a lot of killing
when I worked for a company
that dealt in animals. There are times
when you just have to kill.
Pigs, actually. Well, at first I didn't
want to kill animals.
But thinking about my career,
I had to, because
it was a pork company. So, I did.
You know there are
so many ways to kill.
I did that for 12 years.
Not just animals, but flies
and maggots too.
It gets linked to your performance.
So, I'd do it.
Spraying insecticide. And killing.
Now, as a result,
we have poison gas attacks.
It comes back to haunt us.
They're entirely different.
They altered the image.
But you can tell.
If you know who to look for.
It's so obvious.
I didn't get it at first.
Seeing myself talking on TV like that.
I was really taken aback.
I wasn't thinking about what to do
about it.
Instead, I just thought how
strange it all was.
Then, later, I got calls from
my parents...
and from my old high school
and college friends.
They asked what I was doing on TV.
So, I said I was in the PR Dept.
Not really an answer, but...
Your being exposed like that
was because the people before you
had quit. So, it became all the harder
for you to leave.
Even if you did, you'd face a lot of
obstacles returning to the regular world.
So was this a choice of yours, given
that situation?
That's more the issue
that my parents and friends were
worried about.
How would I be treated by society.
Me personally that is.
Of course, I am concerned about
Aum's public image.
That's a completely different burden
I have to carry.
But, at a personal level,
I didn't care about the future
or about the effect of
becoming so public.
Because I'd already refused
society. And left home.
So, in that sense,
I wasn't as worried
as you might expect.
So, you weren't even thinking
that you might one day leave Aum?
Even if I left Aum, I didn't think that
society with its values. Values it would
continue to pursue, was a place I could
ever return to.
So, rather than never leaving Aum, it's
more an idea of not returning to society.
Right.
April 1996
Yokohama Seminary
I am now experiencing with my body
the Buddhist doctrines
that I knew earlier only at
an abstract level,
and I feel that my heart has
found peace.
We're thankful for that.
That's right.
Aum's teachings may be great. But
you have to apply them to make
them your own.
So, although our human rights are
being ignored
and Aum is being abused, treated as
if we're not human,
still, now we can see how far
we've mastered Aum's teachings.
Or, it's a kind of training to see
whether we can learn them.
In that sense, I'm really pleased.
I know it's not a game of Othello
but, still, in Othello
even if the board's all black, you
can win by taking the corners.
That kind of situation can happen.
But even not,
I want to keep being white,
to increase even by one the number
of white pieces.
The Master's brainwaves are still.
That means, counter to media claims,
his subconscious is in command and
there's nothing like "mind control"
going on.
The moment the Master came to the
bank of the pond.
Something happened. I hadn't thought
there were fish living there,
but when the Master appeared, they
appeared in great number
all struggling to get close to him.
Even from my position, I could see
how happy they were splashing
about, how really happy they were.
That scene feels exactly right.
And there were so many birds, too,
which came flying in around him.
The lake was covered with them.
We, the birds, and the fish all
became the Master's audience.
Listening to what he said.
Even the animals can feel his
vibrations.
Right in front of you?
Well, there were actually 400
people there who saw that...
It wasn't a piece of bread?
No, no.
Follow the path of Boddhisattva
no matter how difficult.
The Guru is necessary.
But we also have the doctrines
that the Master interprets for us.
And then there are all the classic
Buddhist texts passed down.
I think that we can't do without
either of them.
But there's no chance that Asahara
will be released.
You won't see him ever again.
Maybe never talk to him.
That's true...
24th April 1996,
Kamikuishiki-mura Near Mt. Fuji
Asahara Shoko
at the opening hearings
News about Aum's Asahara's hearings
coming up.
Hearings of the Asahara Shoho trial
will start at 10 AM in Tokyo today.
The defendant faces 17 accounts of...
I'm sorry all I have here
is a fax
but, I have secured Permission
as you can see.
For the 24th, from 2 to 9 PM
and tomorrow from 9 AM to 9 PM
under certain conditions of course.
Did you ask me about this?
I don't know. Nihon TV put
the request in for me.
It's the first I've heard of it.
You have to get Permission
from Aum first. That's required.
Then, what's this?
You need two. First Permission
from the bankruptcy trustee,
then permission from the residents.
He didn't tell you that?
Nakamura from Nihon TV
arranged it for me.
Then, ask him. But I'm sure
the trustee told him.
The residents need to approve it.
So if I get their Permission, then
I can come in.
Well. You get that from me.
If you haven't been told about this...
It's the first I've heard about this.
I shouldn't have to repeat what is
common sense, but in addition to this
Permission, you also need the
consent of the residents on the site.
You give us these conditions here.
I'm wondering how binding they are.
What's the authority behind
your view?
You mean to just barge in?
That's not what I mean.
That's absurd. This is where we live.
So can I confirm this time?
With whom?
Right here.
Confirm what?
You said that I needed to get your
Permission
to do my report.
Of course.
So. What about this request?
What do you mean? I mean... well
I can't let you in.
I'm not talking to you.
So you're saying that I need to get
your approval, the residents' consent,
then, I submit this request to Mr. Abe
and get permission.
Then, I come back and arrange it to
go in with you.
Yes, this is common sense.
After NHK. We'd like approval too.
We want approval too.
It's not fair for just one crew...
It'd be more efficient to cover it as a
group, rather than just one network.
That's difficult.
The bankruptcy trustee, Mr. Abe...
So, as long as we get Arakis
permission we're OK. And Abe's.
So shut up, we're not asking you.
I was told that we need to negotiate
with you to go in.
From whom?
This fax.
Exactly!
So, I'm making a request...
of you... right now.
You just said you had the
trustee's Permission
and acted like you had the right to...
Not, that's not at all what I meant.
That's what I heard.
No, no, no.
I don't want to blame anyone, but
that lady started talking about
protocol and all.
That's what I had assumed, so my
language was a bit strong. You see?
No, I don't.
All right, I get it.
But now I'm asking you.
It's not practical.
When are we starting?
TV Asahi hasn't finished...
Okay, then.
With all the factors, like this here,
I'm suggesting we all hold off,
and please try to stop this petty
feuding among yourselves
Satiyan #6 is no good, so we'll do
NHK here
Will you let us film, if we promise to
do it without making
any individuals identifiable?
I've never vacillated on this issue.
I respect facts for what they are.
So you mean...
that you accept that certain things
have happened
that some unsolved incidents
have taken place?
My belief in the Master
is unchanged.
I think we need to stop.
When I answer, I must
come across as quite stupid.
Then let's stop.
It can't be understood with the mind.
So, no matter what I say, people are
going to take it
just to reinforce what they're already
thinking. Not what I'm feeling.
It's pointless, because regular people
can't understand the feelings of
people in training.
You're talking at cross-purposes.
This isn't going to amount
to an interview.
Don't say they can't understand.
It's too easy to give up.
No, they'll misunderstand.
So, if that's the case,
I'd rather not say anything.
Well there may be some...
but we can try to avoid them.
Most of what I say will be
misunderstood, I think.
It's really hard to do something
without misunderstandings.
It's the listener who misunderstands.
There are very few people, us included,
who really hear what the other is saying.
Few people have that
kind of a clear heart.
Let's end this.
Was this shot by a member?
We've been trying to record the
investigations as much as we can.
This is Satiyan #10.
How long have you been here?
It's my second time in the order.
The second time?
I was in the order before,
but dropped out.
Why?
My carnal desires won out.
Food, sex. Or desire for fame?
All of them.
Hatred, sex, food, my feelings
towards my parents.
The normal lot.
While I was dropping out.
I spent my time in general seeking
for ordinary happiness.
You made love to a woman?
Yes.
Wasn't it good?
At first, I thought I'd get married.
But along the way
I realized marriage would only
lead to suffering.
If you really wanted to make
each other happy,
you'd grow close, get married,
live the happily married life,
grow old together.
Watching your darling children
grow up.
People try to live this
supposedly ideal life.
But even if they do, it ends
with death.
The more you love, the more
painful death becomes.
Does this relationship really make the
other person happy?
Isn't it instead painful?
Helping someone get beyond
these feelings,
that's giving them true happiness,
I think.
I cut off the feelings of romance and
love that I had.
Not just that.
Instead, I'd teach the path of true
liberation for the self,
Now she's in training.
Is she here?
Not here.
So she is an Aum believer?
I guess she's still in training.
What do you say, now that
the leaders have confessed?
If the Master said we were going
to go save Hell, I think I'd pass,
but I hope
I'll become strong enough a disciple
to go along.
We're all training much harder
than when he was here.
That's a good thing.
That's why this happened.
That's right.
The Master created this predicament
Precisely for us because he is
trying to get us to train harder
I quit university
after my third day.
I quit because I saw the
people around me
and thought there's no
future for Japan
if these are the people who are
going to make up society.
It's no surprise society's in decay.
So, I thought somebody's got to
do something, someone has
to work toward building
an ideal society.
And I thought that I should
renounce the world.
So I entered the order.
I don't understand that leap.
It is a leap. I didn't understand either.
I thought you'd been taken hostage!
Tough, eh? Because you're so sincere.
Maybe, just maybe
someone will start
to understand.
That's right!
Arakis honesty just grabs you.
It's bound to move them.
They wonder how long I'll be doing this.
You are self-pitying yourself.
Like I said earlier, he's matured.
He really has. When the Master
returns,
or even if he doesn't, Arakis
gone up in level.
Guru Reserves Right to Plead
Asahara 's Evasive Deposition
Aum Members Huddle in Seclusion
Yes. That's right.
Today. We also know that
they're watching today's
arraignment on TV.
Deputy Spokesman Araki hasn't
stepped out, so nothing there.
He makes his followers call him
Master and reigns...
someone who ignores the law-governed
state can't be taken seriously.
After a commercial break...
A bad reputation...
What?
- We've got a bad reputation.
It's pretty bad.
It's a test for the disciples.
The disciples' ideas about what the
Guru is are destroyed.
One after another.
This is the point at which you keep
following the Guru
or lose faith and quit.
It's about destroying ideas.
You mean a kind of test, a trial?
An act for the disciples' training.
You're saying some disciples didn't
make it through this ordeal, this trial?
What about you, Konta?
It doesn't shake me.
Through what has happened, I've
always thought it doesn't matter
what kind of person the Guru is.
This is just an extreme I'm asking.
But what if there were a report that
Asahara prostrated himself
apologizing and crying out for help?
No difference.
Is that because you don't believe the
report, or you don't care if it's true?
Even if I saw it with my own eyes,
that wouldn't affect me. You see.
I'm confident only the Master can
offer the final interpretation.
It's not as if we were actually trying
to invade the privacy of the believers.
Concerned about your name?
How about yours? The media's?
But you think badly of us already.
So you don't mind? A bad reputation?
You're just quibbling with us.
I am not.
What kind of conditions
are you asking? Money?
Did you really need to say that?
You're saying the same to us.
What's most important is getting
the residents to agree.
I'm with him, with Mr. Araki.
Together?
Yes.
He's a member?
No. He isn't.
I have a consent form.
What agency are you from?
Freelance.
He claims to deal
with the group directly.
Does he have the right Permission?
Returning alone? With someone?
I'll be leaving alone.
Can I go now?
When I got home, my parents were
waiting for me with these long faces.
They told me to sit down, and I could
already guess what it was about.
Two parents?
"We need to talk," they said.
They Dulled out a book. Sure enough,
an Aum one, "What's this?"
"Asahara Shoko" I said.
So they asked.
"Are you reading this? You've even
underlined it".
"I'm learning from it." I said.
"Are you in this group?"
"Of course, I am. When I do something,
I hate going just halfway".
You said that?
In front of your parents?
It was the first time to broach
the topic.
Maybe I should have
comforted them,
or been a proper child. That's
what they were looking for.
But that's not my role, so I
left and entered Aum.
It's a good thing, I guess, that
I have siblings
so if my parents want that, they
can get it from the other two.
I can't do it. Won't do it
anymore. So here I am.
23rd July 1996, Tokyo
Defense Plea,
Ant-Subversive Hearing
Z3th July 1996, Tokyo
Defense Plea,
Ant-Subversive Hearing
You wear this a lot recently.
Yes.
Is the suit you brought
today your own?
My only one. I brought it with me
from home when I entered Aum.
Just one?
Yep.
When did you use it?
University entrance ceremony. It's
the first and last suit I had made.
Did your parents order it for you?
That's right! You got it!
Araki, your shoes?
Maybe I can get some slippers.
You forgot your shoes?
I wasn't really thinking about it.
We're on a tight schedule, so
there'll be no individual questions
for the speakers.
They'll be giving speeches.
First, we'll hear from
Kaneko Toshiko.
Please step up.
Well, this is to say that,
the explanations from Aum are over now.
So there seems to be said that
Asahara instructed...
Whether it is true or...
79th June 1996, Tokyo
Kameido Headquarters
19th June 1996, Tokyo
It is written in the Bible
that each will go
before Christ to be judged
for the good or evil our
bodies have done
and to receive our due.
They've arrived.
Please step back.
First, let's address the
transfer of leadership.
Who'll lead the order now?
His Excellency Akiteru Rinpochi and
His Excellency Ryokko Rinpochi.
Who're they?
The Master's, um, sons.
His first and second boys?
Yes.
So, your younger brothers?
You're the oldest girl,
Yes.
But the leadership passes onto
your younger brothers.
Yes.
The first through fourth children
are girls, and the fifth and sixth...
Please don't discuss our
private affairs.
Even if you know them. You mustn't.
You're not revealing any ages either.
I don't want my age known.
Are you representing Aum in
some way?
No, I'm not.
Is there a position inside Aum
that you are filling?
We all help the order.
But especially Their Excellencies.
As their older sister.
She's been by her brothers' side,
supporting them
I mean... well, it's natural but...
Not just that, I'm here to
strengthen the Aum position.
What do you mean?
That's right. For one of us
to appear outside, that shows
you how serious we are.
With the change in leader, you'll
need to change your training.
I assume you'll want to.
No, not true.
There is a tradition of teachings.
By that, we mean they are passed down
naturally from generation to generation.
So if you deny the teachings,
there will be nothing afterwards.
So you haven't denied them?
We haven't rejected the teachings, but
there were some misunderstandings
so, concerning our doctrine, we
have. Um mm, been, well...
So you don't deny them, but
some need to be revised?
If we don't, you'll keep finding fault.
We're not "finding fault". During the
trial, some believers say they were
acting according to the teachings.
That's how we heard it.
How much are you changing?
You'll change the posters, and?
The tradition of teachings won't change.
But this poster is related to that
tradition, isn't it?
Related, meaning it's a question of
whom you devote yourself to.
It sounds like you don't understand
the structure of religion.
No one does, so...
sharp. Sharp.
Sharp, really sharp.
Standing firm...
We want to discuss three points
in this Dress conference.
First on the transfer of leadership.
Then...
A little more...
It's a secret.
7th August 1996
Kameido Headquarters
They look like regular children to me.
Trying their best to say something
by heart.
No. You're wrong.
At first glance,
they may look like that.
But, when I concentrate and listen,
even now my mind gets this
cold feeling.
Because you put this tape on.
Well, it started feeling cool
a little earlier.
What do you mean "cool"?
This energy enters...
Your mind?
No not my mind.
Because you're watching this video?
You have a long way to go.
The photos are too small.
Have you met them?
No I haven't, but I'd really
like to.
Till now, it's been the Master
who listened to my worries.
The Master's message was always
intense,
but I really like the children, too.
Their Excellencies the Rinpochi.
Each company can send 5 people
That's for TV.
Newspapers and magazines can
send 2 each.
And let me know if Osada shows up.
I did see Nihon TV's relay van.
The director called.
He's coming?
Those Nihon TV guys!
Shooting from the hilt!
Really?
That's their business, isn't it.
They've got to sell their papers,
and get their shows watched.
I guess it really can't be helped.
There'll be time for questions later?
We expect so.
Expect so? That's no good.
I'll check.
No one can report just this stuff.
As Aum believers, we have become
the subject of these events, and would
like the chance to express our ideas.
How long was that today?
Boy, today was long.
The questions didn't stop coming.
Such dreary questions too.
If told we put sarin in the wells,
they'd believe it and be terrified.
Or that rumor about Ecoli germs.
Jokes aside, I think there's a real
danger of us being demonized.
Starting with the hijacking...
Dad will understand your love
some day
let me hold
your shaking back shoulder
Good night good night baby,
suppressing your tears
Go to bed in silence tonight,
good night
Good night good night baby,
suppressing your tears
Have a dream of happy tomorrow,
good night
Nobody will take away this
finally found happiness
It is for you and me
Let me wipe
your tear-wet cold cheeks
I'm saying that your group is
under suspicion.
You can't just claim that.
What? You forgot about the trial?
I know you're in the cult.
What's it got to do with you?
Since you're in the cult, I want
your name.
Why do I have to tell you?
Everyone in the cult better give
me their name.
I don't have to.
If you don't, you'll look suspicious.
That's entirely arbitrary.
See, you're acting suspicious.
Everyone here will vouch for me.
Get out of the way.
I'm not in the way.
Move away.
My friend's being detained.
Speak up. Why can't you tell me?
You're ashamed of something.
What is it?
You've something to hide?
What is it? Tell me.
Got a warrant?
No. It's voluntary.
The publics got to know
what you've done.
Why won't you tell us? You're
up to something, aren't you?
Are you trying to hide something?
Don't push me. Don't push me.
Hold it...
What's your name?
That hurts. Ahh. It hurts.
You okay?
You alright?
The cop was dragged. Pushed.
You can't treat police like that.
You were being questioned.
Obstructing the police.
This guy tried to run.
Then he dragged our guy down.
He ran for it when we were
questioning him.
Tripped up an agent when he
was under question.
6:35 PM. Arrested for
obstructing the police.
I saw it all.
He's the one who dragged me.
I saw it all. I saw it all.
Stop performing. It's a dirty trick.
Stop this now. Shame on you.
Cut it out, Mr. Araki.
You guys are lying.
No one's lying!
How dare you say that
Should you being saying that?
Yes. I should!
You're at fault.
He's been hurt.
You're full of lies.
A policeman's hurt. Show respect.
You work for the PR Dept., and
you dare say that.
I can't believe you're an official.
I'm telling the truth.
That's no truth.
Are you OK?
We don't know who you are. We
need your name. Without a name,
you can't get treated at the hospital.
Stop being so rough.
Don't worry. He's totally conscious.
Please stop that.
Get his pulse, his pulse.
While the ambulance is on its way,
we're just checking his pulse
Checking to see if he's all right.
Please calm down.
Step back. This is an investigation.
Back off. Please step back.
Hey you, who are you?
Mori. My name's Mori.
I don't care what you call freedom of
the Dress. You've been filming all along.
Good night good night baby,
suppressing your tears
Go to bed in silence tonight,
good night
Good night good night baby,
suppressing your tears
Have a dream of happy tomorrow,
good night
Can't believe this.
I have three questions for you.
How much longer will you be here?
Till the end of the month.
Then you'll all leave?
That's right.
I don't care how you live your
lives. But we're all human.
It's OK to be religious, but
using the name Aum, really...
We are human indeed.
We all have blood in our veins.
We feel exactly the same. Really.
Seeing what happened today, I don't
think you can be a mediator.
And if you can't. Mr. Araki,
then, you should go live a normal
life and find a proper job.
Find a regular place and work hard.
I can understand how unnerving
it is to see a disturbance
like this. But if you'd seen it from the
beginning. You'd understand.
If I'd done that, I'd want
to sock you one.
Become a businessman,
join a company.
Doesn't have to be a big place.
Sweat a bit, 'n work hard.
Bright guys like you don't
need to do this.
If you're smart, what should you do?
Become a boss, take charge of people.
I do try working as a missionary.
But, some of my friends
are really in a bind.
Never had and never will have anything
to do with the bad Dart of Aum.
It's like black and white. Aum is
black, and if you add that to white...
You guys are all black! Black can
never become white.
If you put it through a filter, it can.
That's our duty. What we have to do.
You're a "filter"?
That's right.
Your whole life as a "filter"?
I have to be.
What's your given name?
TA-TSU-YA.
Who?
I'm asking this man his name.
Yasuoka Takaharu.
How do you write "Takaharu"?
The "taku" of Ding-Dong, the "haru"
of "security".
Okay. I see.
I'm calling about Yamamoto. Has he
been released yet?
He was arrested today.
He's being prosecuted tomorrow?
So. He's being prosecuted?
The first thing is stop him being
charged.
If there are any Darts on tape that'd
be good, we'd like to use them.
I don't think I can do that.
We can't do that. We can't show you
...I mean... give you the tape.
We're deciding how to react; I'll let
you know what we decide.
We should act before
the police take advantage of
the situation.
It's the same old pattern; hit, then
knocked down, then arrested for
obstruction while the cop grabs his leg.
I don't want to be useful to the police
nor to Aum. I'm totally neutral.
I need to confirm things for myself.
But can we say there's a tape?
Tell them there's a witness who has
proof. They'll remember.
Good point.
There was a third party with us,
a witness with convincing proof
of what happened.
And that we will be relying on.
Given the inappropriate nature
of what happened, we're requesting
you to process his release quickly.
9th August 1996
Two days later,
Kamikuishiki-mura
9th August 1996
Two days later,
Kamikuishiki-mura
You said I could have some time.
Did you figure out when?
Can we do this later?
It's 10:01 AM on the 12th.
This is the Criminal Division of the
Joto Police Station. We're calling
to speak with you about the video
of the incident in Kameido the
other day between an Aum member
and a policeman.
We'll call again later.
14th August 1996
A week after the incident, Tokyo
About the cameraman, the police.
Well, this really was a set-up.
Using a one-page leaflet, we could
link up to local citizen groups and
groups opposing the status quo.
We're not intimidated by the police, and
we are doing good work individually, but
the authorities get away with more
and more these days...
The prosecutor is debating whether
to Dress charges or not.
Of course, we want to convince him
not to.
We and our lawyer want to negotiate
with the prosecutor.
This is where the video comes in.
In Japan, once indicted, you have a
99.8% chance of being found guilty.
After being indicted, you've got little
chance.
If you're charged, it's all over.
Basically.
And, in his case, the earlier incident
means no suspended sentence.
In media, there's one principle - to
provide the public with information
And prevent it being used for
ulterior purposes.
That's our first resolve.
I know the truth. If I conceal it now,
an innocent person
might go to jail on false charges.
Can I ignore this under the pretense
of making a film?
I thought a lot about this, and I still
am thinking.
As Yasuoka told you,
our decision is this;
We'll provide your lawyer with the tape.
I'm the lawyer.
My name's Mori.
I can understand your position.
I'll only use it in relation to the
court case.
Thank you very much.
It's possible he'll be released before
the trial two days from now
if they accept this as proof.
Thank you for your help.
During questioning, the prosecutor
said a video had arrived.
Then. He left, and I was led back.
But ten or fifteen minutes later, he
rushed me up and released me.
16th August 1996, Kumamoto-ken
Night before turning
Over the temple
There's stranger stuff over there.
They were making pipes.
This is the best Dart.
On! Y special personnel allowed!
This is pretty good too.
They did the cultures here.
Really.
It's got a fan and all. They must've
been doing something here.
A duct.
Maybe a culture room.
Needles, right?
Horse needles.
Who knows if they used them
on horses? What's this water.
Dunno.
Smell it? Maybe it's alcohol.
What if it were sarin.
Stop it.
The police checked it.
That's right.
Whose room was this?
Murai.
His memo books are here.
His memo books.
Please call me_
Murai
"The advance of science and
the change in world view"
The following morning, 8:30 AM
20 dogs are taken away, 10:00 AM
That religion, Aum. And its followers.
Their way of thinking about things
is out of whack.
The lot of them don't produce a
thing. Not a help for us.
Your given name?
Hi-ro-shi.
Your title?
Deputy Spokesperson.
And your age?
The bankruptcy trustee arrives, 7:20 PM
Let's shake.
Araki
Thanks for your advice.
Likewise.
Take care.
What did you say?
I couldn't hear.
That it's the end.
And let's return to society.
I think that's it.
Who spoke first?
I did.
What did he respond?
That we learned from each other.
Maybe I said "each other".
30th August 1996
Giving up
Kameido Headquarters
Turning over the Aum Bldg. To the
Bankruptcy Trustee 8/30
Someone's up there.
The trustees, right?
Is it your first time inside?
Yes. First time.
You're all from the
neighborhood group.
Yes, that's so.
What do you think?
Really filthy!
Are there more?
This is it.
Can our guards go? You ready?
Please let us through.
We affirm there'll be no
disagreement
with however the trustees
choose to dispose of it.
What are the Guru's teachings?
Everyone. Hurry up.
Kamei.
With everyone slowly leaving. I wish
you'd all call your families just
to say you're okay.
It only takes a second to say,
"I'm training"
"and I'm doing fine. Bye."
We do that.
Your parents call desperate...
"I'm doing okay, take care of
yourselves."
That's all it takes.
Whenever you've a chance.
I'll make a point of mentioning it.
I'm asking you formally, okay?
In some cases, they'll be glad
just to know you're alive.
He's a good, quiet kid.
I know his mother, and I'd like
to believe anyone raised
by a mother like that must be okay.
So. I'm asking you, okay.
I understand.
Take care now.
I know your mother.
I met her before.
Really?
Let's just say I really understand
your sense of responsibility.
Convince her of that.
Tough to be responsible.
This'll do for the time being.
We'll learn from our experience
and do our best.
If you're the spokesperson, then
explain what the cult was
doing spreading anthrax!
The police aren't investigating that.
That's not the point.
We want something from you.
Nothings in the open yet.
I want the facts, too.
You're being too
matter-of-fact, Mr. Araki
That smell made people
suffer for real.
I don't know if that was anthrax.
I'm not talking about anthrax.
Your chemicals hurt people.
I want to hear at least an apology
for making people suffer.
I don't know if it was poison or not,
but that's what they say.
Get out. You bastard.
I heard that you were going to give
a response today. I was looking
forward to finally getting a proper
explanation from the Aum side.
But, this is what we get. I'm really
disappointed.
But I'd like an explanation too.
Causing trouble like this,
putting us out like this.
If you can't even apologize for
causing so much trouble.
But I did apologize.
It was really horrible having Aum
here. Their leaving changes that.
Next month, the members will
evacuate the remaining facilities.
This is Araki from Aum
Shinrikyo again.
I'm calling for Producer Morimoto.
Still in a meeting?
What did you eat last night?
Last night's dinner?
Last night was... last night
was white rice.
All by itself?
Curry pilaf that's easy to make!
Put rice on curry paste,
then stir. Voila.
Araki, what did you have today?
Or, haven't you eaten yet?
I've got important work to do.
And when you finish.
Same stuff.
Almost never changes.
Today. Tomorrow, the day after...
Which part is karma? All of it?
You get the pus out of your system.
Impurity is discharged.
Sometimes over the whole body.
Huh? That looks bad.
Have you had this, Yamamoto?
On my hands and feet.
I still have a scar. Where was it?
See here.
Looks scarred.
No, this one's from my motorbike.
I've called many times already, but
I'm trying to reach Producer Morimoto.
Has his meeting ended?
I want to give him my opinion of
his broadcasts so far.
I keep trying to reach him.
Could you give me your name?
You can't give me your name?
What kind of company are you!
I've been told before that he never
got a message from me.
So I want to be able to say who took
the message.
Personal? It's not personal! I'm asking
you as an employee of the company.
They're avoiding you.
Could you give me your name?
I've been forbidden by the company
to give out my name.
You can't give me your name?
What kind of company are you!
I'm very sorry.
I've been told before that he never
got a message from me.
So I want to be able to say who took
the message.
I understand, but I've been told not
to give out personal information.
Personal? It's not personal? I'm asking
you as an employee of the company.
I can't give you my name. I've been told
by the company not to give it out.
"Sunday" Producer, Mr. Morimoto
"since you don't have an adequate
understanding of Aum, I propose... _"
12th October 1996
Before turning over
Fuiijomiya Headquarters
Crimes on your hands, Aum, Get out!
Members. Wake up and Seek Reality!
Counseling for Aum Members
Provided by the City
Your foot's better.
Yes. Thank goodness.
The karma left?
Maybe just part of it.
I thought it would take longer.
Well, compared with before it came out,
before it got bad,
does it feel any different?
My body feels lighter. That feeling
that was Dulling me down has gone.
It looks to me...
like a bad case of athlete's foot.
Athlete's foot?
Maybe. I don't know, some kind of
skin disease.
Well, that may be so. But whether it's
an injury, or artificial, or something
totally accidental, or a disease,
it's a concentration
in one part of the body.
All together, you can see it as karma
that gets liberated.
Can I come up?
Yes.
I convert!
Master, Master, Master
Reject sleep
Reject Lust. Reject Food
Sunday, Sept. 1996
thanks, friends
I want you to look at us closely.
I want you to record us.
We don't have a tradition
of recording things.
Even if we did, people would see
it differently, because we made it.
I want ordinary people,
people who can understand, to
see what they can see,
to hear what they can hear.
Do you think I can see?
...Well...
10th November 1996
Sendagaya, Tokyo
Good morning.
Come on in.
Morning!
Sorry it's so cramped and messy.
So this is the main "hideout".
Hideout #1.
Where you supposedly plot
your strategies.
Hmm.
And you're the radical right-winger!
Why make me a right-winger?
You're the central protagonist.
No thank you.
Who then?
PR Dept. Chief Araki!
Asahara shouldn't
kill insects either. Right?
Well. That point is...
that's a difficult one.
It can't be explained quite so
simply.
Basically, the destruction of
life is not allowed.
Basically? Are there exceptions?
No exceptions. It's just difficult
to put that in words.
Going back to Kamiku today?
I'll stop somewhere on the way.
Are you being followed?
Yep.
I n a car?
The police switch at the prefecture line.
It's my first time not to see you in
robes. Is this your regular wear?
I was meeting a regular person.
"Regular"?
- So-called "regular".
People like Inoue and Hayashi
have testified to the fact.
But, I can't really say for sure.
All I can say is that it might have
happened.
When you read Hayashis
testimony, it's really detailed.
Like what he testified at the trial,
about using the umbrella.
I just think to myself
did he really do that.
Part of me thinks that way.
I can't understand it all.
Human society is so contradictory.
Like all the murder of war.
In war, there's no blame
for killing if you win.
But that doesn't change the
fact of all those deaths.
But no one raises the criminality
of that.
There are so many hypocrisies.
I've always wondered about
these questions
Like is there really a world higher
than our human one,
These are religious questions
I've always had.
And I've wondered who can
really answer them.
Now these are questions I've
had since I was little
but the only one who could convincingly
answer those questions
was the Master.
So the things I learned, the teachings,
and the things I experienced -
The secular world calls it mind
control...
These experiences, these things
I underwent,
even with Inoue's and Hayashis
testimony,
those deeper Darts in me, it's like they
haven't been touched at all.
There's this unshakable part inside
of me.
17th November 1996
Hitotsubashi University
How often did you meet Asahara?
While in Kyoto, I met him 5-6 times
over a year and a half.
After entering the order, I began to
see him regularly.
In Japan, you don't see people
choosing to adhere to values that
others find absurd, or creating unique
lifestyles like Aum has done.
(Masa'aki Hukuda, Professor of law, Hitotsubashi University)
This is a good chance for you all
to review your own values.
We'll start the Q&A with Mr. Araki,
with that in mind.
Would anyone like to start?
I'm happy to be alive, and think
that can be a kind of philosophy.
Wanting to be liberated,
isn't that also a worldly desire?
They say Asahara eats like a cow.
Had kids and even lovers too.
I know it's a caricature, but
it's true he has children.
He rides in a Mercedes and even
has a helicopter!
Talk about worldly desires!
The general attitude condemns
Aum for not apologizing or paying
for its brutal crimes.
After the guilty verdict, don't
you think that you should respond?
Or can you continue to claim that
you have nothing to do with it?
That you were not the perpetrators,
and continue to ignore the case?
You walk kind of sadly.
You're walking with downcast eyes.
Would you like some hot water?
No thanks.
How about apple? Apples grow,
but you can eat them, right?
It doesn't become a tree, right?
The seed might sprout and grow.
The seeds...
Do you have restriction on food?
Yes.
Who took these photos?
I did.
How come?
Well, when I was in Kamikuishiki-mura.
I think the Japanese society
will face much trouble
if the Anti-Subversives Law
goes into effect.
People will lose freedom of speech
and freedom of belief.
"What is most unforgivable of
Aum members is that."
"They do not take joint responsibility
for the numerous crimes."
"Continued existence of this injudicious"
"will allow similar vicious crimes
to follow in time to come."
"They are not human
but aliens with human faces."
"They are the shame
of Japanese people." Wow...
"It's out of the question
to even discuss human rights"
"for a homicide-committing group."
"They would have been all beheaded
if in ancient times."
"They can possibly appear at any time,"
"but our apartment has
5 entryway from"
"where visitors can freely
come in and out..."
They call us 'injudicious group".
Right. Such expressions are used too.
I have no idea why they can say
"not human but aliens with human face".
Crime?
Sa-ba-ki
I see.
Once you are in the order,
husband and wife don't live together?
No, they don't.
They all live apart.
So that means no offspring?
Basically no.
Do you train to lose sex drive?
Training to lose sex drive.
What's that?
Is there such a thing?
Yes. I heard of it.
It might be joy meditation.
I haven't been instructed yet.
What do you mean?
It's only for those who need it.
You mean you don't need it.
I guess so.
It's only for with strong sex drive.
So you don't have much.
First. There is the Universe.
Then Heaven, Arsira, Human, Animal,
Hungry Ghost, and Hell.
This is our structure in Buddhism.
Even gods in Heaven have many levels,
and human spirit is not so superior
compared with the Universe.
However, you can flee from human sin
and weave your way
up to higher stages,
then. You will be happier.
This can be said from our world view.
I'm not interested in having a talk
with a woman
regarding her as a woman.
I felt out of place
to regard women as feminine beings.
I must say that I was
very uncomfortable to be with women.
Have you held a girl's hand?
Well, just at playing
in kindergarten at most.
Kiss?
Don't remember.
Making love?
I'm sure never.
26th November 1996
Sendagaya, Tokyo
Democracy is at Stake!
It's unrealistic to expect
a verdict by year's end
at such short notice.
Normally, you'd have hearings and
discussions. Only 2 weeks for that
means they have their minds set on
using the Anti-Subversives Law.
Thank you for coming today.
As we've announced to the Dress,
the Defense wants to show Aum in its
current state to Drove that this Law
is no longer applicable to the group.
Around l3 media crews, you think?
You mean newspapers?
They're doing interviews. Too?
Questions, yes.
Interviews on camera?
Probably.
Can they show your face?
Ah. Well, preferably not.
It'll look better if we're open.
Well, my folks back home...
What about me. My family will
never take me back.
It's a family affair, but my brother
just got married...
Personally I wouldn't care.
Well. Maybe they can't tell.
It'll be OK.
You're safe even on the wanted list.
Maybe just a profile.
They'll only recognize Araki
So you want us upstairs.
Here are again some documents on
the Anti-Subversives Law.
They're filed up here.
When did you join?
About 2,3 months ago.
Eggs and soy sauce.
Kelp broth.
In the police search...
Lastly, let's take a look
at the first floor.
Here, some shoes...
This may be taken wrong, but
in this kind of situation,
under siege, you know...
Society used to be more
ambiguous for me...
But now I've come to see
society more clearly...
Uh, I mean, I can't explain
it well. But...
What about society?
Well, ah, the hypocrisy, if you may...
December 1996
He's no 8uru, just a
madman to me now.
As the chief perpetrator of the
Aum crimes.
He should get the death penalty.
The 21st century will come,
not Armageddon.
For those who still believe in Aum,
and revere me as Holy Progeny.
Listen to me and disband Aum.
Don't try to fool the people!
The Aum cult is evil!
They strangled the helpless
child and buried him!
Asahara gave the orders!
Why defend Asahara and Aum?
Shame! Leftist lawyers!
Aum murdered your colleague Sakamoto
and his family!
We demand the Anti-Subversives Law
be applied to the devil cult Aum!
So that this killer cult will never
again threaten Japan!
Lover of Aum follower 'fesses up!
Love and sex of a fugitive.
Devil AUM
Stop! The Anti-Subversives Law.
Hunger strike taking place
Araki!
The police don't want it, so
have some tea.
Let me take a photo.
We took print-club photos yesterday.
With this on.
Do you know print-clubs?
Tiny photos made into stickers.
We made them with Prof. Fukuda.
In Shibuya?
Take care, Mr. Araki
We support you.
You support him?
As an individual, sure.
Not the Araki of Aum?
No, Araki Hiroshi himself.
Is he happy for that?
Can't show joy, can he?
Because it'll turn to sorrow.
NO TRESPASSING
The stink in there!
Can't stand it!
What's this?
The engine is running.
It isn't locked.
It's already closed.
I got a phone call yesterday.
They're worried about me.
Who? Your mother?
Yes, my mother.
She said there's still a lot of
antagonism against us.
"Take care." she said.
"There are people who still
despise you."
"Watch your health."
Or rather,
"Watch out for dark alleys."
Can't she come with you?
Court dismisses Aum
Ant-Subversives case
We welcome the dismissal of the
Commission with relief.
Our faith has been safeguarded.
It's over.
Blood was shed.
And, there's no doubt
that Aum was involved.
You mean Aum members?
Yes. Members of the order.
Right? You've seen the trials
and heard the witnesses.
There's no way they weren't
involved in some manner.
What society is asking
from you now is
to react according to the norms and
rules of this world.
Follow the proper courtesies
regardless of your religion.
You caused people trouble,
so apologize.
If you do have any opinion
about the crimes,
society expects you to express
your position.
Well, yes, society. Uh...
So in that situation, ah...
If we start admitting one thing -
that would be like acknowledging
all the images that society has
created about Aum.
That Asahara's a swindler, and that
we're all brain-washed.
I guess it's true what happened was
horrendous...
But can I confirm anything else?
I'm the type who won't
fence-sit.
If they ask why we're still
in the order, I have no reply.
Delighted with the verdict, Aum
members hold a press conference.
You think the issue would be solved
if I go home?
You mean, leaving Aum?
If my mother's worried about me...
Her biggest worry would be resolved.
But other concerns would emerge,
isn't that the course of things?
It is.
Her next concern would be
getting you a wife or job.
There'll be all sorts of anxiety.
But would going home really...
For a parent, anxiety exists
because of love.
So it becomes the toughest thing to
sever, whatever the worries are.
You've got to cut the tie
to end the suffering.
But for a parent, that's
the hardest thing.
It's painful for
the family left behind.
Even if you tell them to sever ties
in order to avoid suffering
your parents will still live
another twenty, thirty years.
Their wounds won't heal in that time.
They'll die with the suffering.
Those left behind can't be redeemed.
They can't break away.
Spiritual suffering befalls those
who are left by the ordained.
If we all could join the faith...
It' s an eternal theological
contradiction.
Renouncing the world is impossible
without overcoming this hurdle.
Renunciation is impossible?
Well, I'd like to leave all behind...
But family does Dull me back...
Where will you be in 30 years?
30 years from now...
We'll be touching it out with
Armageddon...
2 months later
Kyoto, 18th April 1997
Thank you for traveling
with us today.
We're now arriving at Kyoto.
AUM. GET OUT NOW.
Unity until we recover our
Peaceful housing block!
The Truth and lies of Aum!
His photo shouldn't be there.
He shouldn't be worshiped?
Right. He's not.
People can see.
But it doesn't make a difference.
Will the photo be discussed
in the eviction trial?
No, they're just denouncing
everything left and right.
But it makes no difference in
this trial, does it?
You're right.
Are we too nervous?
"Your Honor, I'm on the Anti-Aum
Residents' Committee."
"I'd like to present a personal opinion
that will help the Court."
"The 5 Aum residents have forfeited
collective responsibility for their crimes."
"The stupid cult remains in existence."
"Brutal crimes will again take place
in the near future."
"I. A true Japanese could not reside
alongside this barbarous cult."
"If we let them stay, we will be
the laughing stock of the nation."
"2. By winning this trial, we will
avenge the bereaved and"
"the many who perished at the
hands of the criminals."
"October l997."
This document has actually been
submitted
to the court, through their attorneys.
Eviction Trial
Mr. Araki will join our struggle!
Any changes in your outlook on society,
before and after doing Aum's PR?
I feel like renouncing the world
all over again.
Leaving it behind.
You do?
In a sense, in these 2 years after
entering the order
I had to face the temporal world
more than ever before in my life.
What of the temporal world?
What... hmm?
When I met my mother in Tokyo once,
my grandma was supposed to come.
She suddenly fell ill, and
couldn't visit anymore.
Sick of worry?
She's pretty old.
She has a heart condition.
She doted on you?
Well... I guess...
Our karma is linked.
Is Tanba and Osaka on the same line?
Going to Tamba?
I'm going to visit home.
Who is?
I am.
Tanba? But your parents are
in Takatsuki
Grandma.
Oh, your grandma.
She's dying.
Say what?
It's not that I hate my parents now.
I can explain that to her.
Rather, I want to fulfill the life
that my parents gave me.
I'm here with Aum because I don't
want to die an imperfect existence.
I want to continue on this road.
Aum Most Wanted List
Residents Meeting
7th Report on the Aum Trial
We Need Your He(D!
Aum is Every Resident's Problem
The Truth and lies of Aum!
Aum Wanted List: Three Left!
AUM GET OUT NOW!
GET OUT!
ANTI-AUM COMMITTEE
Residents Meeting
7th Report on the Aum Trial
I walk alone deep in a forest,
To discover myself
On a path that unfolds
With the scent of trees
At times, I am lonely
Singing songs with the mountain birds
My 8uardton angel urges me on,
Telling me to sometimes stop my way
You mustn't give up
Aim for the Msuji Mountain
And the cedars point
Strai8ht to the sky
Down and to the left
The path leads back to my native land
Up and to the right
It opens onto a new departure
It's been fifteen years now
Since I turned my back on my hometown
My parents have left this world
I hear their voices echoing
People put the peaks before them
And read the direction of the wind
No one to teach me,
I decide myself
People put the peaks before them
And read the direction of the wind
No one to teach me,
I decide myself
By yourself alone, you overcome
The road you take