[Meet Me @1006]
I met you in order to save you.
I can't think of a better
explanation than destiny.
I think I'll sleep on it.
I'll answer you tomorrow.
Zhou Da Jun, I'm you from the future.
Ask for leave and stay home tomorrow.
Someone may sneak into your place.
Where's Jia Le?
Oh, the merging is over.
How did it go?
I know. You told her with masculinity...
"Don't worry, Jia Le."
"I'll get you back from Death."
Then you gave her a kiss
before the merging ended.
Are you still an adolescent?
Grow up, will you?
What do you have on Zhang De Pei?
I went to the training center.
But he didn't even show up today..
Then I went to his place.
I rang the bell, but no one answered.
I'll have to go again tomorrow.
We've wasted another day.
Time is running out.
[Tie]
I have to get this.
Not bad.
Let me feel it.
It's cool.
A new hairstyle changes your mood.
You've never met me
in such a quiet place.
I can't go to the pub anymore.
Although I'm on probation
for abandoning a corpse...
some still think I'm the
killer and try to avoid me.
It's normal.
But I think I'm better than I used to be.
You got too many girls.
God is punishing you and
forcing you to take a break.
Didn't you tell me you
were in love with a girl?
What happened?
When did I tell you
that I was in love? Nonsense!
I can see it from your face.
I'd help you if I weren't
busy with the lawsuit.
So? What does the girl
you love look like?
Was she that good?
I realized that she wasn't
who I had expected.
So I gave up on her.
Xiao Wei, are you available this weekend?
I have something important to tell you.
Xiao Wei, can you have
dinner with me this weekend?
Cheers.
Are you drunk?
- No, I'm not.
- Really?
- One plus one equals three.
Are you feeling something?
Naughty girl.
[Bo]
You don't answer the phone?
Are you with a girl?
Yeah, you're forcing me
to go to your place.
Tie?
The door's open.
And the music's loud.
Tie? I'm coming in.
You'd better get dressed now.
I'm coming in now.
Are you drunk?
Yeah, you're drunk.
Is he your type?
Of course not.
I don't like those boys
who think they're popular.
What kind of girl was she? Just tell me.
I thought she was an angel.
But a fallen angel has a dark side too.
That's what those girls are like.
You're such a neat freak in love.
Everyone has a dark side,
including you and me.
But I don't think you're
a bad guy because of that.
Really?
Don't jump to conclusion.
What? You're frightening me.
Just kidding.
Judging from my experience
even a silly girl can be complicated.
But you don't have to get to know her.
Like you can play a video game
without knowing how it was designed.
You can have a good time playing it.
Was Xiao Wei a toy for
you to kill time with?
You're weird today.
Yeah, if you're comparing her to a toy
she was one I wanted
to cherish for life.
But...
So I'm upset now.
They haven't caught the killer.
I don't know what's
wrong with the police.
Hello?
What time is it? Where are you?
I'm almost at the office.
I'm sitting on your
motorbike near your place.
Yeah, I'm heading out now.
Hold on a second.
Zhou Da Jun, I'm you from the future.
Get rid of the black coat
that you wore today.
What do you want, sir?
I want the surveillance video.
I'm the owner of this building.
He did go out that night.
2:02 a.m.
Why was he so nervous? He even threw up.
Hey, Jia Le.
Here.
These paintings are all unfinished.
It's been hard for me to calm down.
Even if I do
I don't want to go on.
I want to start anew.
If you can start anew...
you won't have to apologize to me, right?
By the end of the interview,
you said sorry to me.
I'm the one who should say sorry.
Why do you have to say sorry?
I think you knew all along
who killed Cheng Hao.
But you didn't want to tell the truth.
That's why you felt sorry.
What makes you think that?
Ji Rou...
What are you doing?
On the day of the murder,
you threw the butt away.
So you think I was trying
to hide evidence?
And the owner of
the butt is the real killer?
Zhang De Pei doesn't smoke.
There was someone else at the scene.
On that day...
was it a cigarette like
this that you saw?
These are my cigarettes.
I use them sometimes for inspiration.
If the cigarette butt was yours
why did you move it?
Did I?
To be honest, I don't
remember doing that.
I don't believe you.
Cheng Hao knew that I smoke.
When I'm in a bad mood, I paint
and do household chores,
putting stuff away.
But he can't stand up for me now.
You even want Cheng Hao to
back you up when you lie.
And Ke Zhen Yu too.
He tries to defend you and you
don't tell him the truth.
You use the men who love you
to solve your problems?
You get a sense of achievement from that?
Many people's futures
depend on this case, Ji Rou.
Are you jealous of me?
It's all right.
I'm used to people being jealous of me.
But do you think it's easy for a widow
to mourn for her husband
while being slammed
at the same time?
I'm trying to keep calm
and answer your questions
because I see you as Cheng Hao's sister.
You're family.
Don't be so ungrateful.
I'm not buying your
tricks as a journalist.
You think that I killed my husband.
You think that I'm having
an affair with De Pei.
Now you think that I had an accomplice.
If you see my brother smoking
will you think he's the killer?
You saw him beating Cheng Hao.
You can make up a story about
his grudge against him.
It's what you journalists
are good at, isn't it?
You haven't seen me smoking. Is it weird?
Can I talk to you, Miss Cheng?
Believe it or not,
I was trying to help you.
You're best friends. It must
be hard for you to ask her.
But don't you think she
was dodging my questions?
I'm not talking to you about this.
I have some personal questions for you.
I admit that I've misjudged you.
About what?
I talked to the future me
on the phone yesterday.
I realized that he...
is really in love with you.
I told you to talk to
the future you about it.
You don't have to tell me.
Do you know that you're going
to die soon, Miss Cheng?
If the girl that he loves dearly is dead
do you know what he's going to do?
To tell you the truth, I don't know.
The girl that Mu Si Ming told you about
committed suicide in college
and I lost myself for a long time.
But you're his Miss Right.
If you're...
I don't know what he's going to do.
I don't think he'll be so single-minded.
Are you happy about it?
Would you be happy if you
knew you were going to die?
Okay, a piece of advice for you.
You don't have much time.
If you love him
just give him a romantic
night and then disappear
letting him know that you're not serious.
If you don't, just ignore him.
He'll know that it's
just wishful thinking.
What the hell are you thinking?
Are you arranging a one-night
stand for yourself?
Why do I have to do that?
You'll break his heart
if he loves you so much.
Just say no to him.
Time will mend all wounds.
He'll forget you.
I don't want you to ruin
my future, Miss Cheng.
Please.
What did he mean by that?
Even if he knows it...
he will...
Did he light a cigarette here?
[Hsinchu Detention Center, Agency of
Corrections, Ministry of Justice]
Hi, Dad.
Yeah, I've seen Ji Rou.
What do you want me to do?
I have a new lawyer.
Yeah, I see. Please have faith in me.
Yeah.
Hello?
The DNA matched.
Yeah, thanks.
It was you who called me, Wu Han Wen.
[Private Number]
Hello?
I know what you did on
the morning of September 19th.
Who is this? Is this a joke?
Who the hell are you?
Hold on a second, please.
[Private Number]
Did you get the picture?
A volunteer at the animal shelter told me
that Xiao Wei's parents
want the killer badly.
But no one knows that you're
the killer, Zhou Da Jun.
I'm sorry, but I don't know
what you're talking about.
Really?
Let's put it this way.
At 12:40 that morning, you
went out in a black coat.
You came back home at 2 a.m.
but you didn't notice
that the cuff was stained with
the pretty girl's blood.
So it was you who broke into my place.
I'm sorry, but there's no
bloodstain on my coat.
It's good to be confident
but please think harder.
Maybe it was stained when
you pulled out the knife?
Damn, you crazy bastard!
Are you feeling guilty already?
[Private Number]
What do you want? Why did
you send me the pictures?
Don't you recognize it?
It was Xiao Wei's hairbrush.
I went to her house and asked her parents
to give me one of her hairs.
Think about it. If I
give that to the police
and they compare the DNA
with the bloodstain
what do you think will happen?
Yeah.
All right. What do you want?
[Taipei International Airport]
At 8 a.m. tomorrow morning,
I want you to pick up something.
[Private Number]
- Hello?
- Have you seen it?
What is it?
It's one of Jiang Cheng Hao's trophies.
Please give it to Ke Zhen Yu
and tell him that it's the murder weapon.
The police don't know where
it is, but you found it.
But it's not the real murder weapon.
This is ridiculous.
Yes, it is.
But you're the best friend
and assistant to the lawyer.
I think it'll be easy for you
to make him believe it's
the real murder weapon.
And I'm sorry.
The handbag doesn't match your outfit.
Quit searching.
If you do this for me, I'll
never bother you again.
Come in.
He's the one you said can give us a clue?
Tell us. What's the important clue?
Wait. Can I get the money first?
You won't get a cent if
you don't tell us now.
It's up to you.
I was drinking with a bunch of friends
and I heard it from
a drunk friend of mine.
He said...
A judo coach name Lin
hired him and his brothers
to kill someone named
Jiang Cheng Hao, but they failed.
Then Coach Lin hired someone
else nicknamed Big Head
to kill Jiang Cheng Hao in his home.
But Coach Lin got busted for
the drugs and ran away.
Big Head didn't get the money,
and he had to run away.
He wanted my friend to get
rid of the murder weapon.
It was a huge trophy.
We've been here all afternoon.
Are you sure your metal detector works?
What's in your pocket?
Yeah, it works.
Then the informant lied to us.
We've been here all afternoon.
There's no trophy here.
Something was wrong with him.
He deceived us.
It's weird.
He said the trophy was cleaned and buried
in the hills around Jiang's house
near some satellite station.
I think it's here.
Maybe someone found it before us?
Go over there, Zhen Yu,
and I'll search here.
I have something here, Zhen Yu.
Be gentle. Don't damage the evidence.
Come on!
I've found it at last.
I have a chance to turn the tables.
Now we'll analyze
the fingerprints and the blood.
Then we'll have sufficient evidence.
What's wrong?
When I asked Ji Rou about
the cigarette butt yesterday
she was unusually indifferent.
She blamed us for suspecting
her, not Cheng Jia Le.
With the trophy,
we'll finally find out the truth.
Maybe Ji Rou has been telling the truth.
Jiang Cheng Hao was killed by a gangster.
There was no one else at the scene.
Go get the camera, Da Jun.
Are you all right?
Stop that. You scared me.
I'm fine.
Thank goodness.
That complacent idiot didn't
suspect the fake trophy.
So everything will happen
earlier, but it will happen.
The merging won't be affected.
Yes!
What is it, Da Jun?
Nothing.
I was thinking...
Even if we can turn back the clock
we won't necessarily change everything.
Can we really change our fate?
You'll have to ask Him.
But when you have the chance
you try your best to
change your fate, right?
For example, we're not idiots
but we believed the fake
information so easily.
And...
I don't want to admit it, but...
I think Ji Rou is hiding
the truth to protect someone.
Who do you think it is?
Think about it.
If the murder was caused by the drugs
Ji Rou doesn't know Lin Bo Yu that well
while Zhang De Pei is
her old acquaintance.
But I don't think
that Ji Rou cares for
Zhang De Pei that much.
There's only one person
Ji Rou would be willing to protect...
and risk being suspected as a killer.
Who's that?
Wu Han Wen.
Oh no!
A girl can't even dress herself
properly before a date.
I think you have a nice figure.
It'll be good to get a bit sexy.
I won't avoid you anymore.
Come home now.
There's something new in my memory.