Reesa from Manhattan,
you're on the air.
I date a lot of guys.
I mean, a lot.
I've had more blind dates than
a seeing eye dog. You know why?
- I'm on tenterhooks, shoot.
- I'm looking for the real thing.
...you're talking about,
but I wanna feel love.
The kind where you're so delirious
you can barely breathe or eat.
I'm waiting for Prince Charming who
will pick me up, sweep me off my feet...
- Slam me into a wall, and bang my...
- Let me stop you right there, Reesa.
First, I don't think love
is supposed to deny you of your food.
...or oxygen supply.
Love is supposed to nourish you.
Well, I'm just saying
I want the fairy tale.
I want the excitement, the romance,
you know?
Yeah, I do. This Prince Charming
of yours doesn't exist.
He's good for a few nights in the sack...
...but his charm will run thin,
which is what charm does.
Well, I hear ya, Dr Lloyd, but what
I'm saying is that I want to be deeply.
- And passionately in love.
- You want to be passionately in love.
I see. You know who's a bigger flake
than your buddy, Prince Charming?
His brother, Prince Passion.
Reesa, if you are truly serious.
...about wanting to find real
and lasting love in this town...
I'm gonna have to dish out
tough love to you now.
- Uh-oh.
- This serial dating of yours.
...is a waste of time. You can't
find something when you don't know
what you're looking for.
You're playing the field, right?
Hoping that somebody will want you,
when it's you who needs to figure out.
what it is you want.
Anybody can fall in love...
...but what you deserve is a man with
the emotional maturity to stay in love.
Don't settle for a boyfriend
when you can demand a manfriend.
I'm not really the demanding type.
Don't go there, Reesa.
Hear what she's doing, listeners?
That is the sound of a woman
who settles for second-best.
Why do we do that? I mean,
deep down we know we deserve better...
...so why do we keep lowering
our standards?
I devote a chapter
to this in my new book, Real Love...
which come to stores on Wednesday.
I've finally learned that unless
you demand real love for yourself...
...you're going to get
seriously hurt out there.
But how am I supposed to know
if love is real or not?
Spell it out for yourselves.
Is he responsible?
Is he your equal?
Is he an adult?
- Are you freakin' blind?
- And most of all, L: Is he loving?
- That's a ridiculous call!
- Know anybody like that?
- Not really.
Hold out for it, Reesa.
You'll be so glad you did.
Oh, Dr Lloyd, you are such a lifesaver.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
All right, next caller.
- Patrick! Come on!
- Where'd she go?
Hopefully, she went to buy you a muzzle.
Keep your mouth quiet next time.
- Move it, move it.
- If there is a next time.
Showtunes.
- More showtunes.
- I like showtunes!
- Obviously. It's sad.
- Oh, there's the love doctor.
- I hate that lady.
- My lady loves this.
- Mine, too.
- Your... Your who?
I mean my mother.
- What is that?
- You're a beast.
Next caller.
Sofia of Astoria, you're on the air.
- Hi. Hi, am I on?
- Yeah. Yeah, here we are. Let's go.
I'm supposed to be getting married this
weekend, and I'm having second thoughts.
- Second, third, fourth?
- What do you mean?
Thinking about calling
this off a while?
Well, I took your online compatibility
test, and I scored a 12.
OK. That test helps predict
long-term compatibility, caller.
- You're right to consider this...
- Sofia?
...very, very carefully.
Forty-three per cent
of marriages end in divorce.
All right? You don't want that.
How long have you known this guy?
About five months, but he's
a really good guy and all, and...
But... But... Five months?
Sofia, are you scared of being alone?
- I guess so, maybe, yeah.
- 'Cause you know what's scarier.
...than being alone?
You know what's worse?
Being alone with the wrong guy
for the rest of your life. You got it?
Doesn't sound like
an average case of jitters.
Wait, are you saying
I should call off the wedding?
I'm running out of time, caller,
but you know, deep inside...
what you need to do.
Thank you for calling.
Good luck.
Knock-knock.
- Mm, who's there?
- This is your publisher speaking.
- Mm, we don't want any.
- Read 'em and weep.
- Oh, really?
- There's only one way to find out.
No, no. I'm too nervous.
You read it.
"The doctor is in.
The first book from local talk radio
sensation Dr Emma Lloyd, Real Love...
...establishes Lloyd as the latest
khoja of modern romance."
- Latest what? What did they call me?
- Khoja, apparently.
I don't know what that means.
I don't know how to spell it.
- K-H...
- What kind of word is khoja?
...O...
- It's just showing off, really.
- OK.
- For a popular magazine.
...to review a self-help book
and pull out a word like "khoja"...
"from the Turkish 'hoca':
A, a title of respect for teacher.
- B, a wise man."
- Or woman.
Oh! Or "C, a sub-sect.
...of ancient Ismaili assassins." Hm.
- Lets go with A, for teacher.
- I don't know.
The assassin thing,
I wouldn't throw that out.
- I love New York Magazine.
- Geniuses.
- Should I write a thank-you note?
- Send a fruit basket.
Mm. I love fruit.
Yeah, well, that's
why I'm marrying you, my khoja.
We're not done.
We're not done with comments...
- Ah.
- OK.
OK. Let's see.
"Dr Lloyd's analysis of love's
dos and don'ts is both insightful.
- And trenchant."
- Trenchant! What does that mean?
Is that some kind of fancy word
for "full of shit?" Trenchant?
- Direct and incisive.
- Gimme a break, smart-ass...
What? I saw it on Jeopardy.
Why didn't they just say,
"Read the book, ruin your life?"
Read the sports page to us, huh?
"Physical gifts can offer
such insightful observations.
...into the human heart
is a thing of wonder."
- Whoa. Trouble, one o'clock.
- "She is chicken soup for the heart."
Oh, my ass!
- Hey! Hey, Sofia! Sof!
- Uh-oh. Here we go.
I'm reading about that lady that helped
you plunge a knife through my heart.
- Very trenchant stuff.
- I can't talk right now...
- Because I gotta be someplace.
- We'll give you a ride.
Hey, fellas! Stop the truck!
Sof, come on.
You haven't returned any of my calls.
- Well, I've been busy.
- Sofia, give the guy a break.
Talk to him, Sof.
Oh, don't do that, Sof!
Come out here! Sofia!
Please come out here
so that we can talk.
No, no, no, not you, sir.
You can put your hands down.
- Firemen. We don't arrest people.
- We'll hose you down.
Sof! I'm not gonna go anywhere
until you come out here.
I don't understand. You know,
one minute we're gettin' married...
...talkin' about names for our kids,
and the next, because some fruitcake...
- She's a doctor.
- Of what, Sof?
Of what? Talk to me, here.
Patrick, it's over.
I'm sorry.
OK? It's over.
I gotta go.
All right, show's over, folks! Let's
keep it movin'! What are ya lookin' at?
I met someone I like, but all
my friends tell me he's wrong for me.
- What do your friends say?
- We have nothing in common.
It's just the sex.
I'm just running away from many more
appropriate men who pursue me.
- Because...
- Afraid of the real thing?
So they say.
- There's Patrick!
- Oh, Patrick!
- Patrick...
- Quiet! Leave the man alone.
Can you not see
that his heart is broken?
How can he eat when the woman
that he loved abandoned him forever...
...virtually without explanation
and may be, at this very moment...
...cuckolding him with some other man.
- Good night, everybody.
- Cuckolding? What's that mean?
- Hey.
- I'll be right with you.
I'm giving Ann Coulter's
frequent flyer miles to Michael Moore.
Ajay, come on, man.
This hacking's getting out of hand.
- You can get into serious trouble.
- Too late. Bon voyage, Mr. Moore.
See the clipping
on love doctor's wedding?
Who in their right mind
is gonna marry her?
- Whoever we want.
- What do you mean?
Check this out.
- Who's that?
- That's her.
- The love doctor?
- I got it off her birth certificate.
- Oh, I don't know about this, Ajay.
- What are you talking about?
All you ever do is walk around muttering
about giving her a piece of your mind.
...or letting her have it
or fixing her wagon.
OK, for one, I've never said,
"Fix her wagon."
If you've moved on, that's different...
...and I'm happy you
finally put this behind you.
Wait, whoa.
Maybe me tellin' her how I feel
and holdin' her accountable would be...
...you know, important for my growth
or whatever. What do you think?
What am I, your yogi? I thought
you just wanted a little payback.
- Let's do it.
- Nice.
Oh, no.
Now you're married.
I'm married.
- I'm what?
- Already married.
- According to who?
- "According to whom."
- The state of New York.
- That's impossible.
- I have never been married.
- You must have the wrong Emma Lloyd.
Emmaline Willing Lloyd?
Your real name is Emmaline?
A lot of things
you don't know about her.
- How do we fix this?
- Annulment forms. Fill them out.
Have them notarized. Bring them back.
- I can't believe I didn't know.
- Your husband needs to sign them.
- Fiancé.
- Husband.
- I don't have a husband.
- Then who is Patrick Thomas Sullivan.
- Of Astoria, New York?
- Who is he?
- I don't know.
- He's your husband.
His address is right there.
- Astoria?
- Queens.
I know a lawyer
who can sort this out quietly.
- I'm sure that won't be necessary.
- It will. I've got a book to launch.
Yours, I might add.
- You don't think I was married.
- No. It's not that.
It's just the timing
of this could not be worse.
- I know.
- I'm recalling 70,000 copies.
...of a moving memoir
by a new author that we've trumpeted.
...as the next Maya Angelou who turns out
to have plagiarized... Guess who?
...Maya Angelou.
- I forgot about that one.
I didn't. The headline
"Love Doctor: A polygamist"
- Just flashed before my eyes.
- Hold these.
On top of everything,
Bollenbecker take-over.
They haven't announced which publishers
they'll keep and dump.
So one self-help author
who can't seem to help herself.
...from being married,
Abdington Books could be history.
I understand completely. Trust me.
I'll take care of it.
Everything will be fine...
Oh, no, darling. Naughty choc-y.
- You don't need this.
- You're right. Moment of weakness.
- Go get 'em.
- Taxi! Bye, sweetie.
Hello?
Hello? Excuse me?
You're not Patrick Sullivan, are you?
- You are? No.
- May I help you?
- I hope so. Is this 230133rd Street?
- Yes. It is.
I'm looking for someone who lives here
by the unlikely name, Patrick Sullivan.
Patrick.
Keep going, tall lady! Keep going!
Excuse me?
Excuse me, sir? Officer?
Hello!
Hey. Hey, I'm sorry...
No, no, no! That's fine. Um, can you
tell me how I can find Patrick Sullivan?
- We couldn't get that lady out.
- She weighed 500 pounds!
- She knocked you with her skillet.
- Frying pan.
- Patrick?
- Yeah. Ah!
You won't believe this.
That home-wrecking lady.
...from the radio walked in here.
- I believe you.
- Can I help you?
- What's she doin'?
- Looking for Patrick Sullivan.
- I was told he might be here.
- Right over there.
- She looked over.
- What are you havin'?
- Um, whatever he's having.
- I'll bring it right over.
It's walkin' right this way.
- It's takin' its coat off.
- How do you do?
It just looked at me again.
It's comin' over here.
It's comin' right for me.
What does it want?
Patrick Sullivan?
You're not an easy man to find.
- I'm Emma Lloyd.
- It thinks I'm you. Help me out.
Hey, I, uh... I dropped my chalk.
I'm Patrick Sullivan.
- This is my opponent, Larry Berlson.
- Oh! Mr. Sullivan. Mr. Berlson.
How do you do?
I'm here for the oddest reason.
- We all are.
- Here you are.
- Mine?
- Mind if I interrupt?
- Knock yourself out.
- I didn't mean...
- Don't play?
- Yes.
Then you're stripes.
Down the hatch.
- No, no, Mr. Sullivan. I'm here to...
- You don't drink? You don't play pool?
Perhaps I can get you an herbal tea?
Nine in the corner.
We need another round.
Mr. Sullivan. Something
very unfortunate has happened...
- And it could make a mess of my life.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- It's certainly not your fault.
- It's your shot.
Um, all right.
Well, how can I explain?
You see, um, uh,
I'm about to be married.
That is too bad!
Congratulations on the other thing.
We got a bride in our midst.
Thank you. That won't be necessary.
It's necessary. I feel a toast
coming on. Wait a second.
- I know you.
- Excuse me?
Yeah, yeah.
Real Love With Dr Emma Lloyd.
- You're that lady I hear on the radio.
- Yes, of course. You found me out.
- Have you ever been on television?
- Um, no, but I have a book coming out.
- I love television.
- My girlfriend never misses your show.
Oh, well, has it been
helpful in your relationship?
Oh, you have no idea.
It's completely changed our lives!
- Oh, really? That is so nice to hear.
- Yeah. Tony! Here you go.
- To the bride and ever-changing life!
- To the bride!
To the bride!
Mr. Sullivan, as I was saying,
you see, I'm about to be married.
Be careful. Forty-three per cent
of marriages end in divorce.
That's right. It's all
about picking the right partner.
- So true. It's so true.
- In order to do that, my fiancé...
Richard, and I,
need a license from New York...
- Richard from dispatch? Asshole.
- So on an otherwise lovely morning...
- we go to city hall...
- To Emma and Richie!
Richard!
- And I don't want any more.
- Hey, you're right.
Don't want Richie to see
you hammered before your wedding.
Tony! Give me
that herbal tea over here.
Herbal tea, coming up!
Very funny, Mr. Sullivan. Very funny.
- I'll have you know I don't get drunk.
- You don't?
No. My father taught me a good trick
to hold one's liquor.
You simply recite
the presidents' names in order.
- Out loud?
- Forwards or backwards?
Watch and learn, gentlemen.
To Washington, Adams, Jefferson...
Madison and Monroe.
- Carter!
- Reagan!
- Bush!
Do you think maybe we
should pour you into a cab?
- Maybe your fiancé's worried.
- Oh! That's right!
That is exactly what
I came to talk to you about.
- OK.
- Yes, Mr. Sullivan...
- it seems we're married.
- Come again?
We... Are married!
- I thought you were marrying Richie.
- Exactly!
- I'm over here.
- Right!
Uh, yes, it seems that we,
I mean we...
...are victims of a glitch in some
computer, somewhere, somehow...
I don't know, has married us.
- A glitch?
- Mm-hm. I'll say. A big one.
- Oh, boy.
- So, um, if, um, you'd just be...
...so kind as
to sign these papers I'd...
Ow!
Washington, Madison, Adamson...
- Are you a fireman?
- Indeed, I am.
I always liked you guys.
Lights are out now.
Sorry about that.
Oh! Ouch!
Hello? Oh, no!
Oh, no! Oh, no!
Oh, my God!
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Excuse me.
- Good morning, Dr Lloyd.
- Good morning. Wait!
- Someone had a rough night.
- Oh, yeah.
Excuse me.
- Oh, my.
- I need the emergency outfit.
- What?
- The emergency outfit!
Outfit I keep for emergencies.
Richard called six and a half times.
Last time he hung up.
He was looking desperate.
Worried about Bollenbeckers?
- Can you get him for me?
- On the phone?
- Why do you do that?
- It's fun.
- The outfit?
- Not here.
- I had a date.
- Oh!
You know we're not remotely
the same size?
- Richard. Aspirin. Coffee.
- Oh, and your father's...
- Now!
- Please hold. Richard, line one!
Richard, sweetheart.
I am so sorry I didn't call.
I was in Queens so I thought I'd stay at
my father's and go over wedding stuff.
- Why didn't you call?
- He brought you in this morning.
- with your mom's dress.
- He brought me back in.
- with my mom's wedding dress.
- And your father's here.
- She knows it.
- What about Sullivan?
- It's beautiful.
- Emma?
- Yes! I found Sullivan.
- Coffee, Wilder?
- I'd love some.
- Aspirin?
- I've got the papers.
- Welcome.
Not on me.
- Coffee filters?
- I don't work here.
I know they have to be notarized.
Can you get that?
- Sure.
- Don't worry.
You have enough on your plate without
having to worry about this. Don't...
Emma, your husband would
like a few words with you.
- Who?
- Patrick Sullivan?
...have them on you?
- Sweetheart, can you, um?...
Can you hold please? Not a word.
Hello? You there? Hello?
- Ah! Mr. Sullivan?
- Hey.
Let me get to the point. I left some
very important documents in your...
- Richard! Phone!
- Uh, can you just hold on.
- One second? Don't go away.
- Yeah.
Richard, sweetheart,
I am so sorry to keep you holding.
- What's going on?
- I'll explain at the cake tasting.
- I can't. I'll meet you tonight.
- But you promised. All right.
Husband! Cell!
Oh! Mr. Sullivan? Mr. Sullivan!
- Wilder, here.
- Mr. Sullivan? Hello?
- Your father on two.
- Gotta run, darling! See you later.
- Gonna wait for your coffee?
- Nobody's got that kind of time.
I don't know what
you're smirking about, Wilder.
I'm just glad
to see you're having some fun.
Does it look like I'm having fun?
Wait.
You drove all the way in
just to bring Mom's dress?
Actually, I was hoping
to lure you over to Bemelmans.
- For a banana split like the old days.
- Bemelmans has been closed for years.
Ah, well, my timing's
always been a little off.
Don't keep your husbands waiting.
- It's not what you think.
- I know.
Mr. Sullivan?
Thank you so much for calling back.
- Excuse me?
- What do you want?
- Car's downstairs. You're late.
- Mr. Sullivan.
- Yes.
- Yes, about last night.
- Yeah.
- What exactly happened?
I tell you this, you do one hell
of a Riverdance. It was quite a night.
- That doesn't sound like me.
- That wasn't the good part.
- What do you mean?
- I'm here.
You're where?
Hey, I'm losing you. Hello?
Can you hear me now?
Look, forget last night.
What I want is a rather large stack
of papers I need you to sign.
- I got 'em right here.
- You do! Thanks. You made my day.
- Coffee?
- Thank you.
- I know a notary not far from here.
- Right now?
This appointment
took me three months to get.
- Sounds important.
- Cake tasting.
- Like I said, important stuff.
- It's the wedding cake...
...and she's Marilyn Hirschfield,
a respected cake maker.
- These appointments are hard...
- I love cake!
- What are you doing? Hey!
- Scoot over.
- This cake is fantastic!
- Shh! Please, please. Be quiet.
- Can I get another slice of this one?
- You've already tried the butter cream.
It's my fiancée. She's on the fence
about the butter cream.
- I am not.
- Have any milk?
- Sure.
- After this, we go to the notary?
- Yeah, absolutely. How much is this?
- It's free, sir.
Bullshit! It's free!
- Here you are, sir.
- Here's my milk.
- Would you like a sip?
- No, thank you. I'm not six.
Holy crap! Cake down.
I need a spoon. Don't worry about it.
I got this.
Here we have our dark Belgian chocolate
with vanilla mousse torte.
- Thank you.
- It's awesome.
Oh, my God! Do you know
if you mix these two together...
...it tastes like a Ring Ding!
You gotta try this.
No, no, no. That's all right.
I'm not your baby. No, no, no, no, no!
- Ah! Ah!
- No!
- Mmm?
- Ah?
- Mm. It's yummy.
- It's super-duper.
Mm-hm. Um, may I, um... May I just
have one more glass of milk, please?
Attagirl! Milk for my bride.
In fact, milks all around.
Milks all around.
- Hey, where you ladies from?
- Germany.
Wow! You must really like cake.
Yeah, you gotta try this,
and mix these two together.
Hey, hey, can we get, uh, some
Ring Ding things for the gals over here?
Darling, I am certain
everyone is being attended to.
Baby, I got this covered.
Don't you worry about it.
- Quite a handful you got there.
- That he is.
Impulsive, unpredictable. You never
know what he's gonna do next.
- Full of surprises.
- But that's the fun of it, isn't it?
- Of course it is.
- It is, trust me.
- Here you go, ladies.
- He reminds me of my husband.
when we first met. Everybody
thought we were a total mismatch...
...but we had so much fun.
And we still do 25 years later.
Hey! What are you ladies
talkin' about over here?
- Talking about the men in our lives.
- Ah, boys.
- Never mind.
- How did you two meet?
Oh, honey, you tell the story.
You tell it a lot better than I do.
No, no, no, no, no. No, you tell it.
You're the good, uh, teller of it.
- Please?
- All right, all right. Sure.
- You ladies heard of pro wrestling?
- Stop! Kidder!
Oh, he's such a kidder. Kidder.
It was a, um, uh... A blind date.
- Oh?
- Yeah, yeah, we were fixed up.
Yes! Fixed up.
But not with each other.
It was two separate blind dates
in the same bar.
- Both goin' terribly.
- Horribly!
Think about those people who set us up.
- Susie and Allen.
- What the hell did they know?
- I don't know. I guess he noticed me.
Well, I mean, come on. Look at her.
- A guy would have to be blind.
- Noticed me suffering on my bad date...
...and then the band started playing this
song, and it was my favorite song.
And suddenly he was next to me and
he asked me to dance, and... I said yes.
- What was the song?
- Song?
- Mm-hm?
- Oh, yeah, the song.
- Oh.
- # Over night scenes.
# Dinner and wine
Saturday girls.
# I was never in love
Never had the time.
- Honey, Every Woman in the World.
- Every Woman in the World.
# Laughing myself to sleep.
# Waking up lonely
I needed someone to hold me.
# Oh, oh, oh.
# Girl, you're every woman
in the world to me.
# You're my fantasy.
- # You're my reality
- That's it! Uh, that's the song.
That was totally
off the top of my head.
Known each other for two hours
and we already got a song.
We don't have a song.
How long is this gonna take?
Emma Lloyd, Deepak Manaam Chaturvedi.
- Mr. Manaam Chater...
- Deep. Deep.
- Mr. Deep.
- I recognize you.
The passed-out lady
Patrick carries around.
Yes, that would be me.
- I brought you a little something.
- Oh, how very thoughtful.
Do we have to do this right now?
Delicious.
- It's not unlike a Ring Ding.
- What'd I tell you?
I'm sure you'd really love
a glass of milk with that...
...but I have to get home
and changed for my book party.
- If you don't mind...
- Don't rush. I'm a notary public.
- I took a test.
- OK, I'm sorry.
Um, how long do you
think this will take?
Let's just review, hm?
Signatures... Check.
Dates... Check.
My seal and you'll be
on your way in ten minutes.
- Oh!
- An hour.
A year.
As long as it takes.
Who can say?
Anything you can do to hurry?
I don't mind paying extra.
- Trying to bribe a public official?
- Oh, this is ridiculous. I'm late!
I'm late, and I'll send
a messenger in the morning.
That will be more than enough time.
- I could bring it by the office.
- Oh, no. I will send a messenger.
Thank you, Mr. Sullivan,
for your co-operation.
Well, thank you for thanking me,
Mrs. Sullivan.
- A year?
- Patrick, I'm out. Out.
You had your fun. This is too far.
You should be ashamed.
- A nice lady like that?
- I wanted to give her a taste.
...of her own medicine, period.
And then I... I don't know.
- She's starting to grow on me.
- No. Look, no growing, OK?
No growing on anyone by anyone.
No knees weakened...
...no shines taken to, none of it.
Not on my watch.
Now, go. You and Ajay
have caused enough trouble.
Out!
Dr Lloyd! This way, please!
Dr Lloyd? This camera, please.
- Smile, please.
- Beautiful, thank you.
- Hi.
- Eye contact, please?
- Sign this.
- This way, please.
- And where's Richard?
- Right over there.
Thanks.
- Hi! Oh!
- Not too shabby, huh?
- It's wonderful. I can't believe it.
- Sign these.
OK.
- I have so much to tell you.
- Did you get the papers?
- Um, they're at the notary.
- Excellent. Karl Bollenbecker's here.
- Make that out to him.
- Oh?
He wasn't coming, then his
office said he was. Good or bad?
How could it be bad?
He hasn't even met you.
- You look stunning.
- Thanks.
- What happened to your head?
- Oh! Bird accident.
A pigeon flew into me.
I'll go take care of it.
- Emma? You remember Dr Benton?
- Yes, hi. Nice to see you. Hi, Judy.
No sooner do we leave you then, bang,
I see your picture big on the bus.
Oh! From the cake tasting!
I felt so foolish, I went
and bought your book immediately.
- Oh, that's unnecessary.
- Later I was reading.
...your very sensible observation
and your clinical judgments...
- Are they good things?
- I'm sure some people find them useful...
...but I was surprised that a helpless
romantic can give such practical advice.
- Me? Helpless?
- Oh, yes, you.
Hopelessly helpless,
but let me finish.
So my husband, Karl, returns
to the home and on top of his paper...
...there is an invitation to this
very party. Isn't it amazing?
When you say Karl,
do you mean Karl...
Bollenbecker.
- It's a small world, isn't it?
- Yes!
Teeny. Like a marble.
Or a gumball.
I had to drag Karl
by the ear to come here.
- It is a girly book.
- Oh, no. It's not that.
Karl can be very girly. Only that he
doesn't like to socialize with someone.
- whose company he intends to liquidate.
- Liquidate?
- Who, Richard?
- Yes, but we can fix that.
After this party, you and Richard
will join us for dinner.
If Karl sees the man I saw,
Abdington Books will be safe, I'm sure.
That is unbelievably kind of you...
...but you see, Richard and I made plans
and so we're supposed to...
Only one thing
you're supposed to do, Emma...
...and it's to bring your fiancé to dinner.
Let's find Richard. Karl is waiting.
Oh! Oh, oh, my husband hates you,
but you saved our marriage. Do you mind?
Not at all.
Um, who shall I make it out to?
- To...
- Richard!
Um... Thank you.
Oh, hey, hey.
I brought your papers.
Richard! Sweetheart.
Please go with me on this, OK?
- Remember Greta Bollenbecker?
- Cake lady!
- It's a small world.
- So small. Constantly shrinking.
- It must be the global warming.
- I want to introduce you.
- To my husband.
- Her husband, Karl...
...is Karl Bollenbecker,
who just acquired Richard's...
...your publishing house and he's thinking
of dumping you, Richard, and it.
- Wait, I own a publishing house?
- Yes, and you're my fiancé...
...so please just focus, concentrate.
Got it?
This is him.
- You must be the cake dunker.
- You got me.
- That's my Richard!
- Casual Fridays?
I actually just came
from soccer practice.
- You play football?
- Well, I'm no Lucas Podolski.
Podolski!
Well, nothing could beat Podolski!
I own his team and he is a magnificent
pain in the ass, but a genius.
You own the Bayern München club?
Why don't you use Klose on defense?
He's been under-utilized.
- That's what I told that stupid coach.
- Klinsmann? Gotta go.
- We agree.
- Excuse me. My name's... Ow! Jesus!
- What?...
- Hand noogies!
We give each other hand noogies.
This is my brother, Carl.
Your name is Carl as well?
This is a small world!
Yes, teeny! Like a gimlet. Yes, my tiny,
teeny little brother, but not small.
No. Big. Older, but not by much.
- Carl, who I love so very, very much.
- How's it goin', bro?
- Wine?
- I'm sorry, I'm suddenly very thirsty.
- Carl? Carl?
- Carl.
This is Karl Bollenbecker
and I'm Greta, his wife...
- And we're so charmed by your sister.
- And her outspoken fiancé
who seems to find fault with
every player in the Bundesliga.
- But not Podolski.
- But never Podolski!
So, you sound English,
but your sister...
- Can I borrow Emma?
- Yes, but we both had... I'm sorry.
A hand noogie!
Who is that man out there
pretending to be me?
- I can explain.
- He's wearing sweatpants.
- Sullivan! Honey, you're stress-eating.
- I'm not. Go on.
I wasn't at my father's. I was with
Sullivan. Not "with him" with him...
...but in his apartment drunk. That sounds
worse. I assure you I was fully clothed.
Beyond that, I'm not certain,
except he showed up today.
with papers when I had
to go to the tasting...
which you refused to go
because you're busy...
- Get back to the Bollenbeckers!
- Right. Fine.
At the cake tasting,
there was this sweet lady.
And she thought Sullivan was my fiancé
and I just couldn't disappoint her.
But this lady wasn't sweet at all.
She was Mrs. Bollenbecker...
- which I didn't know.
- You certainly know now!
I do. Had I known I wouldn't
have let the whole thing continue.
But it did continue until everyone
was quite taken with him...
...especially Mrs. Bollenbecker
when he sang.
- He's a singer?
- No, no, no. He's a fireman.
- Darling, are you sure you want that?
- Yes. Yes, I am. What is he doing here?
He came to bring me
the notarized papers.
But then there was Mrs. Bollenbecker.
I'm Emma Lloyd, so he's my fiancé.
- And I am tiny brother Carl.
- Oh, Richard, I'm terribly sorry.
But, uh, oh, look! Mini-cupcakes.
Look, Emma. I only got
about half of what you're saying...
...but this seems to be something
that can be cleaned up easily.
So before you harpoon what is left of my
reputation, I am gonna go in there...
No, no, no, you can't!
They're going to exterminate you.
- What?
- Not you, Abdington Books.
Terminate! No, liquidate! That's it.
Yes, chop it up in little pieces...
...sell it all off! Everything must go!
That's why Karl wasn't coming.
- But he did come!
- Because Mrs. B made him come.
She made him come so he could meet you.
Oh, look. I think he's
really starting to like you.
Oh, all right, I...
Let me think now.
Man owns so many entities, I can buy
a year before our paths cross...
...so we just have to get through this.
A few more minutes?
And a dinner. Tonight. It was Mrs. B's
idea, so Karl could get to know you.
- He's gone.
- Karl?
- No, Sullivan. He's gone.
- But the dinner!
- Get him there!
- Oh, uh...
- Is Sullivan even in here?
- I don't see how he'd fit.
Not now, Marcy.
- Find the lioness within.
- Now, you've read my book?
Mr. Sullivan, Emma Lloyd here.
Here's the deal.
My entire career, and my marriage to
Richard, probably, are at stake here.
Frankly, I need you.
I really need you... Tonight.
- Hello?
- Say "yes" if he's there...
- "Oh, my God" if he's not.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
- Don't overdo it.
- You got hit by a cab?
- Good, nice touch.
What hospital are you in? I'll be
right there. He was hit by a cab!
- Who was hit by a cab?
- Is that Sullivan?
Oh! So it was only your foot?
And you're fine, promise?
Oh!
Carl, he got...
a cab ran over his foot Yeah.
- Carl can't catch a break.
- Drink lots of cocoa. Bye-bye, darling!
Richard, I was beginning to think a man
who would leave his fiancée un-attended.
...for so long might not be
as charming as I imagined.
But, no matter.
Please, join us for dessert.
Karl, I know how important
this dinner is to my future.
with the Bollenbecker Group...
...but I've got this family thing.
And where I come from,
family comes first.
So I'm just here
to invite you to a party.
- Could be a lot of fun.
- To family! Above all else!
To family!
You look beautiful.
Nice crowd for your upanayanam, man.
- What's with all the white people?
- Party crashers.
- Even that one?
- No, that one's with me.
Welcome, Emma.
Get up there.
Oh, I love my husband
but he snores at night...
...and it only gets worse...
My husband snores all the time.
I just, tight slap.
- Tight slap.
- You look really cute.
- Why do they snore?
- Check your mehndi for hidden messages.
It's part of the tradition.
When marriages were arranged...
...the groom would search his bride's body
on their wedding night to find initials.
Ah! That's naughty.
- Did I happen to say thank you?
- You did, and you're welcome.
You're not the person
I thought you were, Patrick.
Likewise, Dr Lloyd.
I can't. I have to go.
Wilder? It's me. Can you come get me?
- Hey.
- Hey. Got any beer?
- You did good tonight.
- Thanks.
You gotta tell her, man.
Girls are way into honesty.
All right. Goodnight, you two.
Oh, um, honestly, Wilder.
What am I doing? Running around
Queens in the middle of the night...
...crashing Indian bar mitzvahs two
weeks before my wedding with a man.
- who's technically my husband.
- Beats me, Em.
- Would you like another one?
- Mm, yeah.
- I used extra eggs.
- Thank you, Daddy.
- I wish Mom were here.
- Yeah, me too.
She'd know exactly what to tell you,
wouldn't she?
You're doing all right, actually.
- You still make a mean breakfast.
- I second that.
He also makes amazing smoothies.
Is there time for one?
- Um, no. Uh, Lauren, this is Emma.
- Emma!
- Oh, my God.
- Hi.
My mom loves you. I'd listen to your
show, too, but I don't have a radio.
Which reminds me, is there a mall here,
or a Best Buy or something?
Oh, there's a Toys "R" Us.
Maybe they'll have something for her.
Nice to meet you.
Wilder, it's been real.
Um, excuse us a minute.
- Is there something wrong with you?
- No, no, nothing.
I'm just late and I have
to go meet Richard, so...
- Dont jump to conclusions.
- No.
Thanks for breakfast, Father.
Sorry I can't stick around
for the smoothie.
You don't know everything
there is to know.
No, like some things never get old,
and, um... My car is here.
Look, this time, you're
really wrong, Emma. You are.
Goodbye, Wilder.
Bye, sweetheart.
Daddy loves you, nonetheless.
The golf tee white is stylish,
but, um, I just, it's been done.
And it's not as common as the
picket fence white, which is safe...
...but it's a bit boring.
The Navajo white is bolder,
but it's sort of in-your-face white.
I don't know, um...
They all look the same to me.
- In what way?
- In that they're all white.
Yes, but different,
I mean, wildly different.
Are you not going
to ask me about last night?
Well, I assumed it went pretty well.
Bollenbecker Group just renewed my
contract five years, thanks to you.
Now, all we need to do is file those
papers and we'll put this behind us.
Um, well...
I don't have the papers.
- What's going on, Em?
- I don't know.
He had them at the book signing.
Between the dinner and the upanayanam...
Indian bar mitzvah, don't ask,
I misplaced them.
- I had them in my hands!
- Don't worry about it.
- It's so unlike me.
- It's all right.
I'm gonna take care of everything
from now on.
A white lie is still a lie.
It may be a subtler shade of truth...
...but anyone's who's looking
can see it on the wall.
So I should tell him the truth.
I'm saying that a cream-colored,
ivory-hued, matte-finished, half-truth.
will erode the foundation
of your relationship.
- You're getting married soon, right?
- Yep. That's right.
Your fiancé must be a lucky man
to know he has you to keep him honest.
We're both very lucky.
Brother Carl.
Didn't know you played.
Let's drop the bullshit, shall we?
It's Richard.
- Richard Braxton, as you well know.
- Patrick Sullivan, as you well know.
Hell, we're practically family.
You behaved like a real gentleman
over a rather odd period.
Emma tells me you did me a good turn.
- And I appreciate that.
- It was fun.
I have to play the spoil-sport
and ask for those papers.
- So we can go separate ways.
- I'll bring them by the office.
- No, that's not gonna happen.
- Why's that?
She and I have a life
which doesn't include you...
...and I want to keep it that way.
So I'm asking you man-to-man.
- Not to see her, call her, text her.
- I'm not much of a texter.
Somebody in your circle seems
to have a gift for technology.
- What do you mean?
- The more I look into this glitch...
...as Emma calls it,
the less accidental it seems.
You might be technologically-challenged.
Anyone close to you.
- Might be able to pull this off?
- Not off the top of my head, no.
I intend to find out who did this.
[# Nouvelle Vague: Ever Fallen in Love.
Something wrong with him.
I know you've been there.
We've all been there.
Sounds like a crush. You're a grown
woman, let's call it an infatuation.
...far bigger problems
than what you have now.
You're dreaming! Wake up, girl. Do you
share the vision of the future?
Is he dependable?
You have to ask yourself.
Smart, successful, beautiful women
cannot live on kisses alone.
You may think the chemistry
has commonality with friendship.
Take a look at the compatibility
quizzes in my book, chapter seven.
- You'll find it illuminating.
- Thank you.
Thank you, caller.
Hi, you're on the air.
I'm reading your book, too.
You call this a self-help book.
- Or does that term offend?
- Uh, not in the least.
- Who does it help, exactly?
- Well, it...
See, the thing is, I, um... I haven't
gotten to the helpful part yet.
- Perhaps you're a slow reader.
- No, it doesn't tell you how
...to find somebody to love, or how you
get somebody to love you back.
All it does is tell you what's wrong
with the person you're in love with.
That to me, well,
that's not very helpful.
Perhaps it is you who are wrong for
the person you think you are right for.
What is it you know about me
that would make you say that?
- I don't know you.
- You bet you don't.
I don't. Since you called,
here's some advice.
Instead of blaming others
for your problems...
- Consider looking at yourself.
- I'm looking right at my problem.
- Well, stop fogging up the mirror.
- Nice.
- Did you just hang up on a caller?
- I did not just hang up on a caller.
Hello? Hello? Uh, hello?
I think we've been disconnected.
It must be those cell phones,
those nasty cell phones.
Thanks to my caller for calling
and I will be seeing you tomorrow
...for the next
Real Love with Dr Emma Lloyd.
Are you crazy? How dare you come to my
place of work and make prank calls?
I'm flipping through this
and it was so full of crap.
- That maybe I ought to call in!
- I see you actually bought my book.
- No. I stole it from your party.
- Stole it. That makes sense.
And I took your compatibility quiz.
- Really? How did you do?
- According to this...
...my lifestyle is wholly unsuitable to
any freak who would buy or write a book.
- Like this.
- Surprise. Those tests don't lie.
New York City Fire Department.
Official business.
Please exit the elevator.
Come on, ladies. Sir, thank you.
- What are you doing?
- Unsuitable?
Is that really what you think of me?
I don't think of you.
You want to see unsuitable?
Hey, security...
- what's the story with the elevator?
- Holy!
- My wife loves her show.
- Delivery.
I can't even get a guy
to hold a door for me.
- Step back, please.
- Can you fix the focus on that?
- Zoom in a little bit.
- There you go.
I've had enough of this. Excuse me, sir?
Doctor? Doctor?
I'm gonna have to ask you
to please stop. Stop what you're doing.
Come down to the lobby immediately.
Stop it.
Stop it now, please.
- Sorry about that.
- Which part, exactly?
- Kissing you thing.
- We just got caught up.
- Carried away.
- Lost our heads.
I'm getting married.
Yeah.
You love him?
I only ask this because...
...being that I'm your husband and
you're my wife, I have this...
I have this vested interest
in seeing you happy.
I want to be happy. Don't you?
What is happiness anyway?
I don't know.
You tell me, you wrote the book.
I guess I don't know.
- Patrick...
- It was nice being married to you.
You, too.
- Thanks.
- Goodbye, Emma.
Oh! Oh, oh!
I'm sorry I'm late.
I know, I'm always so prompt.
Don't worry. When I arrived, I told them
to bring the drinks in ten minutes.
- How's that for timing?
- Oh, what a day. You have no idea.
Actually, I kind of do.
I heard your show today.
- That was Sullivan, I take it?
- Yes.
The good news is I got the papers.
Everything but page 127,
and I'm sure it's in there somewhere.
- We'll never see him again.
- So why don't you look happy?
I am.
Well, I've got something
that might cheer you up.
Harry Winston finished our rings.
Now, wanna have a look?
Wow!
See, the circle of eternity
came out great, don't you think?
- No. They did mine wrong.
- What are you talking about?
- It's perfect.
- It says "Do I? Do I? Do I?"
Not "I do, I do, I do."
Em, you're under a tremendous
amount of stress at the moment.
It's not stress, Richard.
I just don't know.
I'm really confused.
Well, I'm not confused, Em.
I know exactly what I want.
I think you and I are the perfect team.
Never doubted it for a moment.
But I am not gonna
talk you into marrying me.
Take a few days
and figure out what it is you want.
In fact, why don't we
begin that right now.
Richard.
We had a really
nice time. Good conversation.
He was sweet and funny,
but I don't know. Something's missing.
- There was no... Exactly.
- Spark?
Yeah, let me
tell you something about sparks.
Sparks cause fires and fires
will burn your house down.
Keep searching for good ol' Sparky,
you're sure to get burned.
Trust me on that, OK?
Oh, I'm so hungry!
Wilder!
Your girlfriend's wearing my robe!
Actually, his girlfriend's daughter
is wearing your robe.
- Hello, Emma.
- Aren't you my?...
So, um, why the big secret?
I wanted to tell you.
Your father thought you wouldn't hire me.
...as caterer
if you knew we were dating.
- Is that what you call it?
- That or this is an elaborate ruse.
- Of yours to get out of paying my bill.
- You have been worth every penny.
There you go again,
always saying the perfect thing.
You've been together for almost a year.
Why didn't you tell me?
You've met so many women over the years,
I thought I'd hold off.
...on this introduction
until we were sure of each other.
- And are we?
- Well, I am.
I can't even keep track of all
the things I've misunderstood.
Sorry.
Dad? I know I never asked you...
...but, um, what do you think of Richard?
Do you like him?
Well, sure, honey. What's not to like?
I mean, he's perfect, isn't he?
- Is that a compliment?
- You don't need compliments from me.
I've never told you
how to live or who to date.
That's always been in your department.
So, what if I'm, uh,
losing my footing in my department.
...and I'm asking for a second opinion?
Well, I think Richard is a...
...a good, safe bet. You know?
He's the kind of guy
that you've always gravitated toward.
...and advised other women to pursue,
isn't he?
Probably the type of fellow that my
brand of fatherhood pushed you into.
Look, honey, I mean...
I've made some big mistakes in my life,
some real whoppers...
...but if I hadn't I probably wouldn't have
been able to recognize the real thing.
when it came along. You don't
have to be so right all the time.
It's OK to make a couple mistakes.
- Hello, tall lady!
- Oh, Emma!
Emma, you're drenched.
Come, darling.
- Move, she has to eat something.
- Quiet!
Can't you see that she's not here
to eat or watch telly or chit-chat?
She's come for the man she loves.
Here you are with your "come, come"
and your "sit, sit" and your "eat, eat".
You're standing in the course
of true love. Stand aside, I say!
Through the beads,
up the stairs, two flights.
What?
Yeah, it's raining.
Figured you'd have the day off.
Come in.
Oh, here you go.
Let me, uh,
let me get you some dry clothes.
- Patrick?
- Yeah.
I think I called off my wedding.
Emma, I...
I need to tell you something.
- What?
- It can wait.
Oh.
- How's it going in there, babe?
- Great!
- We're having toast!
- I'll be out in a minute.
OK.
# You're my fantasy.
# You're my reality.
# Every woman in the world.
What is this? And this? And this?
Are you some sick stalker?
No, Emma, it's not what you think.
Emma!
- Emma! Emma, wait!
- I can't believe this.
I saw the invitation. You're married?
- No! No, I'm not married!
- Liar. Stay away from me!
Emma! Emma, I can explain.
Yeah? What, that this is no accident?
There was no glitch?
No, you. You are the glitch.
You Googled me, invaded my life...
...invaded my privacy,
ruined my relationship.
I almost called off my wedding for you!
I trusted you! I had sex with you.
You're just some sort of con man,
scam artist, deranged fan?
- Know what? Don't flatter yourself.
- I... What have I done?
Richard warned me about you. I warn
people about men like you every day!
- I'm worse than my own callers.
- Emma! Stop!
Thank you.
Can I show you something? Please?
Do you know her?
- No, I don't.
- Yeah, you don't. Come here.
That's Sofia, as in "You're cordially
invited to the marriage.
...of Patrick Thomas Sullivan
and Sofia Idelia Maria Chechagua."
She's Dominican. We met on the job.
She almost blew up a building.
...polishing those nails of hers.
I carried her down 15 flights of stairs.
...and sat next to her hospital bed
until she woke up.
- What does this have to do with me?
- She was a big fan of your show.
Listened to it every day.
One day, she called in.
- You probably don't remember.
- No, I don't.
- You told her to call off the wedding.
- Patrick...
Someone you don't know and can't
remember, you changed her life.
...and mine forever.
I guess I wanted
to educate you about that.
About what it's like to have your
life ripped out from under you.
I wanted to knock you down a peg.
- You did.
- Emma, I...
- Goodbye, Patrick.
- Emma.
Emma.
It's beautiful.
I was just thinking how... How it's
too big for me without you here.
Are you here?
If you'll have me.
Do you mean you still
want to get married?
I do.
I do. I do.
As many of you have heard,
I'm getting married.
People keep asking me if I'm nervous.
Well, I'm not.
My eyes are open and what I see
is not the man of my dreams...
...but the man of my reality.
He's who he says he is,
there where he's supposed to be.
If you want to close your eyes
and jump in...
...try the high-diving board at the YMCA.
There's a generation of men
and women roaming New York City.
...in search of the
holy grail dream partner.
But until we learn the difference
between romantic love and real love...
we're just searching in vain for
something that doesn't even exist.
Here we are. Until next time.
Ask yourself serious questions.
Couples shouldn't have to hide.
Play with fire, get burned.
Irresponsible. Dependable?
You can't trust what you lust.
Does he give you a stable universe?
Love has to be earned, not yearned.
Stop obsessing about this old girlfriend
of his. Got it? All right. Next caller.
It's a hard decision.
Am I right? Well, caller...
Trust me on that. Next caller.
Based on what? What?
Trust me on that, OK?
OK, well...
Um... I don't know.
What do you want from me?
- Real Love is just a theory.
- A theory, yes...
...but based on ten years of research
and study of sociological, psychosexual...
...statistical analysis of men and women
and their relationships.
What if you're wrong?
Hello? You still there?
Take that one.
Trust me, she needs to take that one.
It's 15 minutes after the hour and
you're listening to Real Love with me...
Dr Emma Lloyd.
Uh...
Yep, we got time
for one more caller. We've got...
Patrick of Astoria.
- Patrick of Astoria.
- Oh, really?
I thought for a second
you weren't gonna put me through.
Thousands of people are listening. Let's
not waste their time. How can I help?
There's... There's this girl that I'm...
that I'm falling for.
That I have fallen for.
And, uh, well the trick is she's...
she's getting married tomorrow.
And if that's what she really wants,
then I'm happy for her.
That's very generous of you,
Patrick from Astoria.
There's one other thing that...
...that she doesn't know.
- We're almost out of time.
The thing that
I didn't tell her is, um...
- The thing she doesn't know...
- Come on.
...is that I love her.
You know, I, uh, I look at her
and I see, I see my whole life.
And I just thought
she should know that.
I'm afraid that's
all the time we have, caller.
This is Dr Emma Lloyd.
And you're listening to Real Love.
Where's she going?
- Get in there.
- OK.
Let's see, we got, um, Chuck.
...on line four is looking
for his soul mate...
...and Maria on line two
just got dumped. So, Chuck?
- Yeah?
- Say what's up to Maria.
How you doin'?
Well? Do you really like it?
- Perfect. You're perfect.
- I'm fucked.
It's an interesting segue.
- Did you listen to the show last night?
- Yes.
- He loves me.
- I know.
The entire tri-state area knows.
The car's here.
- What am I gonna do?
- Well, first thing we should fire her.
- I heard that.
- Sister at the keyhole...
- Just what you always wanted, huh?
- I did, didn't I?
Instead you got you and me.
We didn't do too badly, did we?
We were a disaster.
Yeah, we were.
But I see a comeback in the making.
Yeah?
For a guy who's waited
this long to marry my daughter...
...he sure is cutting it close,
don't you think?
- Do you know how I know I love you?
- How?
Because nothing in the world would
make me drag you to the altar again.
We don't want
to press our luck, do we?
I should go see how Emma's doing.
Let me know if he gets here.
- Take it off, Marcy. It's crooked.
- Let me try.
Oh, so this goes like this.
And this... Goes here.
Here comes the bride.
I can't do this.
Excuse me, ladies.
Could I have a moment?
- Richard...
- Wow.
Look at you.
Seems kind of silly, though, huh?
Me in this dress, veil.
Bridesmaids. It's like
some sort of play or something.
No, you don't look silly.
Well, you look extremely not silly
and handsome yourself.
I'm sorry I'm late. I had to go back
to the city and get something for you.
You forgot to file them.
You should know by now,
I'm not really the forgetful type.
No, no you're not.
Ever since you gave me these, I've been
putting off filing them for some reason.
Why do you think that is?
I love you, Em.
I'm clever enough
to know when I've lost.
I should have asked you
to marry me a long time ago.
Well, maybe we just missed our moment.
If you marry me today, you'll
always be looking over your shoulder.
You'll never be completely happy.
- You need to be happy, Em.
- I can't stand it.
Oh, Richard.
It'll be all right.
I'll be all right. As soon as we
can get past that angry mob out there.
Oh, yeah, them.
I'll handle this.
Really?
No, not really. In fact, this time you
should worry. I have no plan.
Come on, help me up.
Give me that candle.
Would you just wait until I've left
the room. I might need this suit again.
Richard?
Engine 41,
this is Great Neck dispatch.
We've got a fire alarm and sprinkler
activation at Saint Paul's church.
Great Neck?
It's not even in our district.
Listen, I know it's out of your
district, but here's the thing.
You guys have sort of been requested.
- How you doin'?
- I had to talk to you!
You could have just called.
So, what's up?
This.
When I was a kid...
I used to have a hard time
believing in happy endings.
The heroine rode off into the sunset
with what I thought was the wrong guy.
One day, my dad found me crying.
I was watching Lady and the Tramp.
...and he asked me what was wrong.
I said, "Dad, those two dogs.
...don't stand a chance. They're wrong for
each other. They have nothing in common.
The movie's gonna end, they're gonna
break up and be heartbroken forever."
He pulled me in close and he said to me...
"Em, sometimes when you're really in
love you don't sweat the small stuff."
Are you saying
we should run away together?
Are you insane?
You're old enough to be his mother.
- Wait till he gets out of school.
- Who is this?
- Good day to you, madam.
- You were going to behave.
I don't know how you do this. People
drive me crazy. It won't happen again.
- Where was I?
- Don't sweat the small stuff.
I didn't appreciate
my father's advice for a long time.
You have to figure out those things
for yourself. But enough about me.
It's a quarter past the hour and now
for a word from our sponsors.
This is Dr Emma Lloyd, you're listening
to Real Love. Please, don't go away.
Haven't you got any
cats to pull out of trees?
That only happens in cartoons,
Mrs. Sullivan, as you well know.
Indeed I do, Mr. Sullivan.
What can I do for ya?
Happened to be in the neighborhood,
thought I'd stop by and say hello.
- Why don't ya come here for a second?
- I can't leave my desk.
- I have to be back on any second.
- Oh, come on. They can wait.
Just stand up and walk towards me.
- You didn't come to see me at all.
- Of course, I did.
OK.
And we're back
in five, four, three, two, one.
This is Dr Emma Lloyd.
We're back with Real Love.
Susie from Morningside Heights,
you're on the air.