BANDAI VISUAL, TV ASAHI,
TOKYO THEATRES,
WOWOW and OFFICE KITANO
Production
Ponder this question.
Yes, master.
Fast runner Achilles races
with slow Tortoise.
Tortoise runs only 1 meter per second.
Achilles runs 1 0 m per second.
If Tortoise starts 9 m ahead of Achilles,
will Achilles ever catch up
with Tortoise?
Of course, he will.
Can he really?
It will take 0.9 seconds for Achilles
to reach where Tortoise started.
By then, Tortoise will have run
0.9 m further.
Indeed.
Then it would take another .09 seconds
for him to reach where Tortoise was.
But Tortoise will have already run
another .09 m further.
Indeed.
In order to reach the point
where Tortoise was,
Achilles would need
another .009 seconds.
Tortoise will have again run
another .009 m further.
Thus the chase goes on infinitely...
and Achilles
can never overtake Tortoise.
ACHILLES AND THE TORTOISE
Let me hear
those sweet words
Tell me
your old stories
Say these words
over and over
"Je vous aime"
I'm home!
Come on in.
Bring me the wine!
We're back.
- How many days did it take?
- Nine days.
So tiring!
Terrible food.
Was it cold there?
Freezing.
I hate cold weather.
Maestro, you painted this 10 years ago.
Remember?
Of course, I do.
Frankly I didn't know
what I was doing at the time.
Didn't know if I wanted to be
Picasso or Matisse.
You really helped me out then,
buying my paintings.
I was dead broke then.
Mr. Kuramochi even took you to France.
You were so lucky.
I appreciate that.
Maestro, in the art world,
the talented need patrons
to support their rise to fame.
Behind every genius
is someone understanding.
Artists can't live
without people like you.
That's right.
Thank you so much, Mr. Kuramochi.
What's Machisu doing?
He's painting in his room.
He's painting again?
He must have inherited
my passion for art.
- What kind of paintings?
- The usual.
He's only a kid.
Could I see them?
- Really?
- I'd love to!
Might be a good experience for him.
They're amazing!
So free and powerful for a kid!
At this rate,
he'll soon be better than me.
Machisu, who's this?
Her.
My goodness!
Stop fooling around, son.
Machisu,
a flounder's eyes are vertical,
not horizontal.
Observe closely when painting.
Oh yes.
Machisu...
A gift for you.
It may be too big now,
but you can wear it when you're older.
Aren't you glad, Machisu?
A gift from the maestro!
Lucky you, Machisu.
Machisu had a dream
of becoming a painter.
Or rather he was made
to have one.
FUKUMI ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
Have a good day.
Okay.
...and make the denominators even.
2 times 2 is 4.
1 times 2 is 2.
We now made denominators the same.
Then add up just the numerators.
Not the denominators,
only the numerators.
This is very important.
The denominator remains at 4.
The numerator adds up to 3.
So the answer is 3/4. Understood?
Yes.
Next.
1 /2 plus 1/3.
Teacher!
Kuramochi is drawing again.
Don't mind him.
His father will take him to France
and make him a painter.
Is this my portrait?
How courageous!
This kind of courage
makes a good painting.
Where are you going?
Outside to paint.
Class, work on that.
Maestro, how should I sell this?
Sell to Kuramochi.
Say it's an Impressionist.
He wouldn't know.
Right.
Bye.
Stupid ass, what are you doing?
That's dangerous.
Move!
That's Mr. Kuramochi's son.
Junior...
Could you paint somewhere else?
It's not safe there.
Junior, can we pass?
Kuramochi,
you have to let them pass.
Okay.
A flounder's eyes are vertical,
not horizontal.
Is this really Blue Mountain blend?
Yes.
It doesn't taste good at all.
That coffee guy must have
added something extra.
He doesn't understand
coffee is culture itself.
I hate that pathetic hick.
What's Machisu doing?
He's out painting.
Junior!
It's hard to make chickens cooperate.
Look at him and stay still.
Junior is trying to draw.
Maestro brought this from France.
This guy needed quick cash
so I arranged the money for him.
This is what I got in return.
What's his name?
I can't tell you now,
but he'll be famous very soon
and the price will surely rise.
Really?
Yes, sir.
All the silkworms are dead?
We have to shut down all the factories?
Can't a French trader
send us the silkworms?
We tried, but they are out of season.
Now what?
What are we going to do?
Bank President!
Mr. Chairman, what shall we do
with our bank tomorrow?
What about it?
Shall we open?
Why wouldn't you?
People will storm the bank!
Complete havoc!
We don't have any choice, do we?
"Cocoon Wipe Out"
"Kuramochi Silk Stock Drastic Drop"
"Kuramochi Bank
on Verge of Bankruptcy"
I guess it's over for us.
I must have put you
through some hard times.
We're not through yet.
Don't be a wimp.
Drink up, Manager.
We've identified the bodies.
Risuke Kuramochi, male.
Michiyakko, a geisha.
Double suicide.
Kuramochi's company just went bankrupt.
Good evening.
Excuse me.
My condolences.
Take anything that looks valuable.
There are four paintings
in the living room.
What else is there?
The widow's ring.
Show me your hands.
Only this for the wife of Kuramochi?
- What's in there?
- Kid's room.
Nothing valuable.
Kid's paintings.
Not worth shit.
Of course not.
Nothing of worth here but tin toys.
Forget it.
Idiot!
Those could bring in money.
Art dealers trick people
into buying them.
Move it, brat!
I forgot something.
That's what you went back for?
Yes.
Don't cry.
I'm sorry.
How selfish can you be?
I'm his brother,
yet he refused to lend me money.
He even ignored my calls.
I'm sorry.
And you...
Didn't you marry for money?
He's not even your own kid.
Now what?
He went bankrupt, so you want out?
And you want us to raise him?
I'm so sorry.
Why not give them a break?
They're in trouble.
He's still a young child.
Just for a couple of years.
That's all!
Listen.
Do what your uncle tells you.
Be a good boy.
I promise I'll come back for you.
His belongings.
Thank you very much.
Don't just stand there!
Clean the front yard.
We've got a lot of work.
Then feed the chickens.
Is that clear?
What an annoying brat.
Who told you to draw chickens?
I told you to feed them.
We give you food and shelter.
Be grateful and do some work.
Useless bastard!
He's still unknown.
But he's a master.
He tragically died at age 1 2.
Now the prices are rising.
What's his name?
I can't tell you now.
It's complicated.
How so?
Sir,
the greater the mystery,
the more valuable the painting.
Matazo.
Let's go home.
It's getting cold.
It's time for dinner.
The landscape will be there tomorrow.
Thanks for the meal.
Clear the table when you finish, idiot!
What about his schooling?
He doesn't need it.
He will only be here temporarily.
Why should I tend to that?
We can't afford it.
Let's go.
Hey you!
Do as you're told.
Clean up the kitchen.
Hear me?
Let's play.
I'm Matazo.
What's your name?
I'm Machisu.
Machisu?
Strange name.
What's this?
The rain will wet it.
He hasn't cleaned up.
Didn't I say to clean the kitchen?
You haven't done a thing.
Stupid brat!
Honey, come and see.
The kid really loves to paint.
Why don't you let him?
We should let him go to school too.
Why should I?
He's weird.
It's freezing but he wears shorts.
What a weirdo.
A new friend to our class...
Machisu Kuramochi.
Nice to meet you.
Okay, first period is grammar.
Today we'll learn more
about Chinese characters.
Take out your notebooks.
Yes.
First, let me give you a problem.
- How do you read this?
- Mouth!
That's right.
Add one line and
it makes a different character.
What is it?
Miss Aoi.
- Day.
- That's right, 'day.I
- And adding two lines makes?
- Eye!
That's right.
Adding lines to 'mouth'
creates a different character.
Another example is
the character for 'rice field.'
See if you can come up
with other examples.
Mr. Okada.
Figure.
'Figure.' That's right.
Anything else?
Miss Aoi.
Add another 'mouth'
and we have 'turn.'
That's right.
'Turn' as in turn around.
Anything else?
Mr. Ueki.
Four.
That's right, the number 'four.'
As in one, two, three, four.
You've all done your homework well.
What are you doing?
No drawing in class!
Not like that.
You're not good.
Look.
I want to draw trains and buses,
but they pass too quickly.
They stop if you stand
in front of them.
It's coming.
Assholes!
Don't stand in the way.
You're blocking the road!
Junior...
It's me, Aki.
Thank you for coming.
My duty because she has
no relatives?
Even her burial?
My brother was a jerk!
Why should I pay for her funeral?
Terrible.
How could you?
Selfish!
What do we do with that?
He should have arranged
a decent tomb.
Then he wouldn't be buried
in this dump.
He only cared about money.
At least his wife is beside him.
Let's go home before the sun sets.
Hurry up.
Come on.
Save electricity and go to bed.
Gross!
Honey, come up here!
What now?
Look at that.
You little asshole.
Drawing a picture like that!
Get out, you ungrateful bastard!
Got a grudge against me?
Don't blame me for her death!
Hear me?
How was it?
They told me to bring the kid
right away.
It turns out that my rich jerk brother
supported orphanages.
So why didn't he help us?
All he cared about was his reputation.
Well, I'm relieved.
You wrote the letter?
To Sunflower Orphanage
Here...
Give them that.
Don't paint all the time
and do as you're told.
Asshole! What the hell!
Why jump out in the road?
He came out of nowhere.
Matazo from Watsuji Village!
The imbecile who painted
everywhere he went!
Good morning.
MACHISU
Machisu reached young manhood.
He held on to his dream
of being a painter.
We're back!
Eat breakfast quickly.
Thanks.
Hello.
What?
They're not delivered yet?
He left a while ago.
I'm sorry.
I've been telling him.
It happened again?
I'll be right there.
Kuramochi!
Kuramochi, I already told you.
Finish your deliveries
then you can paint all you want.
We got complaints again.
Let's go. I'll help you.
Our fathers worked together for years.
It's interesting how relationships
can be passed on.
No offense, but you can find
landscapes like yours anywhere.
They're going out of style.
We want something with more impact.
Or they just don't sell.
Any painter with decent skills
can paint like that.
Try something more unique.
You've studied art, haven't you?
No, only on my own.
You must go to art school
unless you're a born genius.
You could learn a lot.
Realism, Impressionism, Cubism,
Fauvism, Contemporary.
Art has changed throughout history.
Please seek proper training.
You can find those
in any public bathhouse.
Even house painters
can paint like that.
Learn more about modern art.
I'll keep that one,
in case someone wants it
for their shop.
Excuse me,
I'm thinking of quitting.
Why?
I want to study art properly.
You can work here and study.
I'm thinking of going to art school.
I need to take a day job
to pay for the tuition.
I see.
So you're an art student?
Yes. I want to be a painter.
But painting costs money.
Since I don't have any relatives,
I work to pay for tuition
and supplies.
I admire artists so much.
If only I had talent.
I'm no different.
I just love to paint.
That's why you always wear a beret.
I've always wanted to be a model.
Really?
Sure.
Call me anytime.
Is it any good?
He said it's Impressionism.
They make us pay
and teach us nothing.
That teacher...
He was famous for living in France.
They finally realized he had no talent
and he ended up here.
What's his name?
Takanawa, I think.
If you'll excuse me.
It's no use learning
how to sketch anymore.
But it's the basics.
Aren't we supposed to learn the basics?
You can depict something as it is
by taking a photograph.
Sketching is for making replicas.
That might have been needed before,
but today we have cameras and copiers.
Skilled sketchers aren't needed anymore
for replicas.
Modern artists should be more creative.
It looks nothing like it.
Not at all!
You guys have no taste.
Check out how the Cubists painted faces.
Why paint that way?
They painted with their souls.
You sketch with your soul?
Hell yeah.
Not with charcoal?
Shut up, Mohawk!
Stop laughing!
What are you doing?
Sketching with my soul.
Shut up, Mohawk!
Bon appetite!
Watch his nose!
We want something hot!
Dangerous Cigarette Smoking!
We'll light up
with this huge firecracker.
Is it lit?
Time for Ziplock Zen!
Some plastic sheeting...
See you in space!
Have a safe trip!
Turn on the vacuum cleaner.
Air is coming out of the bag.
He's done it!
Back to earth!
Leave it for tomorrow.
Okay.
Goodbye, sir.
We're off tomorrow.
Are you free?
I'll be painting with friends.
Artist friends, how nice.
Can I come along?
We're trying something wild.
It's too dangerous for girls.
How about tomorrow night?
Mie will pose for me,
so I can do some figure painting.
What's that about?
I could pose for you.
Mie is just a model to me.
There's nothing between us.
How do you see me?
I like you.
Fine, then.
Check this out.
Put this on.
Itagaki, that's not art.
Sideways.
Sideways?
This way.
Photo time!
It's not intense enough.
We need more impact
for action painting.
Do your parents have a car?
Why?
We can crash it
and splash paint on the wall.
Why use our car?
Dumb ass!
It's for art's sake!
You're the only one with a car.
We'll do it tomorrow.
Kuramochi?
I got work at the factory.
Forget work, dumb ass.
Which is more important,
the factory or art?
Can I put my clothes back on?
Yes.
You didn't really need me,
did you?
Kuramochi.
Follow me.
This doesn't look too good.
CLOSEOUT SALE
It's a closeout,
but you went too far.
It has more impact.
Impact is not the issue.
Flyers shouldn't look so sinister.
The clients were furious.
I'm sorry.
You've been acting strange.
Draw something normal.
Can I take the rest of the day off?
What's the matter?
I'm working on a project
with my friends.
Art may be important,
but you're paid to do a job.
We're not doing this for charity.
Cool!
Try other colors.
- Yellow!
- Blue!
Try yellow and blue.
More!
Now which colors?
- Green.
- Orange.
Try green and orange.
The bicycle broke.
It broke?
Then carry it.
What colors?
Whatever.
Yeah, whatever!
Bicycle did well. You'll do better.
You think it's safe?
Car's safer.
- Don't worry.
- Go on!
Right.
Show some guts!
Where's Machisu today?
His friend had an accident,
so he took the day off.
Look at that.
Is that me?
That's what he painted.
Does that look like me?
It's amazing.
Art is so deep.
Everybody laughed when they saw it.
It's so embarrassing.
The owner wanted to hang it.
Looks nothing like me, right?
You have to use your imagination.
Screw imagination.
I look like a meatball.
I hate it.
I won't pose again.
Then I will.
I understand his art.
Want to try some?
What is it?
It gets you high.
No thanks.
Maybe I'll go to America.
Now that he's dead,
I'll go back to my hometown.
The talentless pack up and go home.
Who knows when talent is unleashed?
Maybe it just hasn't awakened!
If it hasn't woken up by now,
it will never wake up.
Are you crazy?
I'm leaving.
We tried crashing the car
to splash paint.
Art isn't produced by accident.
Famous artists can control chance.
Being famous has nothing
to do with talent.
All this talk about art...
Go to Africa,
and show the starving
a Picasso and a rice ball.
Everyone would choose the rice ball.
Art means nothing to a starving person.
You're no different.
- I'd choose the Picasso!
- Don't be so naive.
Art is just one big hoax.
Room 1 02
Machisu and Sachiko Kuramochi
Machisu married
an understanding partner.
I'm off.
Good luck.
You're copying Mondrian.
That resembles Klee.
I advised you to study, not imitate.
This is imitation.
Bad ones, at that.
Is that Miro?
Yes, it's Miro.
Whose next?
Hundertwasser.
Doesn't look like that.
That's even worse.
What's that?
I call it "Mr. Arakuma."
And?
I saw him in the street.
Named him Mr. Arakuma.
A bit weird.
At least it's better than imitating.
I need money to buy paint.
Did the paintings sell?
What are these?
Mr. Arakuma's whole family.
Who's that?
Grandfather.
Not grandmother?
Who's that?
Father.
Not mother?
Who's that?
Big brother.
And that?
Younger brother.
Sister.
And that?
Cousin.
Second cousin.
It makes no sense at all.
They are all the same.
I say one good thing
and this is how you react.
Too ordinary.
Try to be more experimental.
Try not using a brush.
You must think differently.
Machisu reached middle age.
His paintings still didn't sell.
I'm home.
You're late.
I need help.
Okay.
- What are you doing?
- I'm coming.
It needs to be done quickly.
Put this in.
Which color?
Put in the paint and I'll hit.
Mom, can I have some money?
We're not exactly rich.
Can't do it.
I know.
Thanks to your stupid art!
How long do I have to put up
with this shit?
I'm the laughing stock in school.
What horrible parents
make their daughters work?
Keep going.
Go on.
Go!
Slow and easy.
Good.
You're outside the line.
Get back inside.
Okay.
Come back.
Too slow.
A little more like this.
What?
You're moving onto the road.
Like this?
Yes.
You're wobbling.
Nice and smooth.
One more time.
Watch out.
Once more.
- Over the white.
- White?
- Where there's no color.
- No color?
Watch for white areas.
That's good.
Nice and smooth.
Don't get off the bike.
Watch out.
Stay off the line.
You better stay off.
Go over the edge.
Right there, quick turn.
Beautiful.
On your right.
Again!
Over the white.
What's this?
You just splashed paint
onto canvas.
It's been done before.
Try something different.
You knew this guy, didn't you?
"New York Raves About Todd Sato,
The Japanese Basquiat!"
It's not done with sprays, is it?
No, it's brush.
I paint with you at night,
and work during the day.
When will I sleep?
Forget it.
What the hell are you doing?
So you're the ones!
Repaint everything
or come down to the station.
It's your choice.
Which is it?
We'll paint.
Thanks.
You almost done?
I'm done.
Will this do?
I guess it has to.
We're very sorry.
We would've been famous
if we had finished.
They don't understand art.
Painting on storefronts?
The whole neighborhood is laughing.
It's so embarrassing.
Once more and I'm leaving.
What's this?
Self-portrait.
Who wants to buy
a portrait of an unknown painter?
What's that?
I was going to paint a white rhino.
Why the white rhino?
Endangered species.
Great idea.
Making a statement with art.
But it's like advertising, not art.
More like a poster
for an animal rights campaign.
Not bad.
Art with a specific concept.
Excuse me!
Can you hammer over this house?
Sure.
That's enough.
I said that's enough!
Enough!
Stop it!
I gave you a little extra.
Enough ink?
Start walking slowly.
Leave your footprints clearly.
That's fine.
Now go back.
Wait!
The other way around.
Turn around.
Don't tread over the others.
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
No. Go back.
They go all over.
Go in one direction.
You stepped on a footprint!
Never mind.
I call it "Black Continent."
Africa, trampled by white men.
Sensational concept.
But that looks like African trampling.
You should have painted Africa black
and the footprints in white.
Looks like African footsteps.
Africans trampling their own continent.
And barefoot?
White men would wear shoes.
Excuse me.
Can you drive over this?
What's that?
We want to paint your wheels
to make red tracks across it.
That's disgusting.
It's inspired by an accident in which
a car crashed into a line of kids.
We think this painting will
help raise awareness on safe driving.
Don't remind me about that!
Who would help you?
Watch out, asshole!
Ambulance.
Wait, wait!
Hold this.
What do you think you're doing?
"Freaky Art Couple Sketches
at Crash Site"
What's this?
I'm too embarrassed to go to school.
I'm leaving!
Mari!
Leave her alone.
She'll come back.
Don't worry about it.
See, we're almost there.
We are.
Getting original,
but you need more madness.
Another's mortality is one thing.
Confronting your own is something else.
Push yourself to the limit
when you think.
Confront art in that state of mind.
Please start.
Please hit her a bit softer.
What happened?
Fight back.
Go.
You must fight back.
Body blow, please.
Fight, fight!
Hit him!
Here's your money.
Thank you so much.
Are you okay?
Yes.
My turn to push myself
to the limit.
What will you do?
I'll hover between life and death.
Push real hard.
Lack of oxygen will really inspire me.
Then I can just paint.
- Let's start.
- Okay.
Can you draw?
It's no good.
I need to get a little crazier.
You want me to push harder?
How's that?
It's not working.
Hold me down harder.
I have to be almost dead
to get some great ideas.
Do it right.
I'll push harder.
It's not what you think.
I didn't...
I didn't do it.
Honey?
We should split up.
Huh?
I can't take it anymore.
Mari has left home.
We can't go on like this.
I want to think about my future.
You won't give up your art,
will you?
No.
Wait there. This won't take long.
How may I help you?
I don't want anything.
What is it?
Lend me some money.
What?
I need money to buy paint.
What father would borrow money
from his prostitute daughter?
Take it.
You're pathetic.
Some artist!
I can't stand it.
Take this and lighten up.
Thanks for waiting. Let's go.
Want to try me?
You've just hustled a client.
Huh?
You've hustled a client.
You new here?
Give it to me.
Give me the money.
No business here
without my permission!
You do have the money,
you bastard.
You have a lipstick?
Lipstick?
Honey, stop.
You're insane.
You've lost it.
Not even human.
You're not even human!
He's out of gas.
Fire!
Are you up?
Take care.
- Lots of stuff.
- We could sell something.
We could.
What could we sell?
What's this?
200,000 yen for an old can?
It looks kind of cool.
Are you crazy?
It's just garbage.
Is it?
I'll buy it.
Let's go home.
And so Achilles did catch up with Tortoise.
BEAT Takeshi
Kanako HIGUCHI
Kumiko ASO
Yurei YANAGI
Produced by
Masayuki MORI and Takio YOSHIDA
Cinematography by Katsumi YANAGIJIMA
Lighting Design by Hitoshi TAKAYA
Production Design by Norihiro ISODA
Sound Design by Senji HORIUCHI
Music by Yuki KAJIURA
Calligraphy by Kouji KAKINUMA
Written, Edited, Directed and Paintings
by Takeshi KITANO