Re Adaptation By: Ali Nabawy
ÖÈØ æÇÚÏÇÏ ÇáÊÑÌãå : Úáì äÈÜæì
ÌãÇÚÉ Çáİä ÇáÓÜÇÈÚ ÈÇáÇÓßäÏÑíÉ
http://wwwsevenart.blogspot.com/
Alynabawy@Hotmail.Com
analazyz@yahoo.com
PAULY SHORE:
My name's Pauly Shore,
and I've been rocking
and rolling
for over two decades now,
and I ain't stopping.
Most guys my age
are married with children.
But not me.
I'm still playing
with the little babies!
I'm buzzing around Tinseltown,
having a blast,
hitting red-carpet events,
hanging with celebs,
and fooling around
with some of them too.
Don't tell Tommy.
Mwah!
I have a brother named Pete
who's the opposite of me.
He likes to take girls to plays,
and I like to play with girls.
And one of those girls
that he took to a play,
he settled down with, got
married and started a family.
So I have a niece and nephew,
which means I'm an uncle.
Of course, I'm not the uncle
that's allowed
to take the kids out
for the weekend.
I'm the creepy uncle.
Recently, Pete and his family
came in from Chicago
to visit my mom, and since
I was part of the family,
I was invited too.
And while I was hanging out
with my niece and nephew,
I then realized after
all these years of partying,
I've been missing out on true,
unconditional love.
Right then I decided, "No,
I'm not going to get married!
"I'm going to have a kid
of my own.
"I mean, who's going to take
care of me when I get old?
Definitely not this bitch."
WOMAN: Oh!
PAULY:
And since I don't have a vagina,
I'm going to adopt a kid.
So then I went to an adoption
agency in L.A.,
and they said, "Absolutely not."
And then I thought, "Where are
all the other celebrities
adopting their kids?"
¶ I'll be last night's man ¶
And when it comes to celebrities
adopting children,
there has been
a pecking order.
First there was Angelina,
then Madonna.
And now--
Who's your daddy?
Pauly!
Yes.
¶
It's okay.
Hello.
¶
Straight.
All right, all right.
¶
Unlike Madonna and Angelina,
who probably had their people
call ahead
to the African embassy
to find their child,
I decided to improvise
and just hit the streets.
Can I take him?
(Crying)
You know, Angelina Jolie,
Brad Pitt, Madonna.
What they do is they come
to Africa
and they just meet a baby
like this,
and they actually just pluck it
and take it back.
This isn't my baby.
I just found this baby,
but I'm going to find
my own baby, okay?
I want to spend some time
with the baby.
I want to test-drive
with the baby
and go see
if we even get along,
see if we're compatible,
right?
(Crying)
(Sighing)
Oh.
He doesn't
want to come with me?
He's perfect.
I've flown all this way
to take a baby from Africa
and bring him
to Los Angeles with me
to fall in love with me.
(Crying)
I'm going
to go back to America
with a beautiful
baby boy or baby girl.
What's up, bro?
Peace.
Trying to find your way
around Africa
is like the Beckhams trying to
find their way around a Walmart.
So I hired a driver
named Val,
who's a cross
between Elizabeth Taylor
and the lead singer
of Quiet Riot.
What would you do if you were
to adopt a baby?
I mean, it's best to go through
the right channels.
Right.
So after thumbing through
Us Weekly
and watching several episodes
of Access Hollywood,
there was only one place for me
to go to find my child.
This is the Oprah Winfrey
All-Girls Leadership Academy.
We are here in Africa, and I'm--
You know, this is the place
that I thought would be perfect
for me to actually
possibly adopt a beautiful girl,
bring her back to the States.
I need someone
to run my company.
Hey, guys.
What's up, buddy?
My name's Pauly Shore.
What's the word
on the street?
What's up?
It's all good.
Is this the Oprah Winfrey
School of Fine Arts?
Yeah.
Is it called the Fine Arts
Oprah Winfrey School?
Yeah, it's the Oprah Winfrey
School.
I know, but is it called the
Fine-- Is it called Fine Arts?
Is Oprah here?
No. No, she's not.
She's not here?
Are you serious?
I just came all the way
from Los Angeles.
She fucking said
she was going to be here.
No, she's not.
She's not here?
No.
Has she been here before?
Yes, she was here.
Did you guys
get an autograph?
No. We are not allowed.
You're not allowed to speak to
her because she's the princess.
Do you bow to her?
Who do you bow to?
Nelson Mandela?
My name, I think,
is on the list.
MAN: Okay.
Yeah.
So if I can just make sure
it's okay?
Okay, let me check.
One minute.
Where are you going?
Let me rub the head.
I know it's weird for a white
man to rub a black man's head
unless he just scored
a lay-up.
What's his name? You want
to come home with me?
I can adopt you.
(Laughing)
Can I adopt you?
No, sir.
Everybody scream,
"Oprah! Oprah!"
Oprah! Oprah! Oprah!
She's going to give us some
money and take us away!
Oh!
I came here to--
Can you please do that
outside the gate?
(Man speaking indistinctly)
Did John Samuel tell us--
Tell them you were--
We were coming?
For clarification,
John Samuel
is Oprah Winfrey's
right-hand man.
Well, let's go here.
Let's go out here.
I knew it was time to leave when
Louis Farrakhan's boy showed up.
What's your name?
Hi.
WOMAN: Hi. May I help you?
No, I'm waiting For Dexter.
Yeah, he called me.
Oh, he did? Oh, okay.
Sorry. How's it going?
Pauly.
Sorry.
I don't want to be filmed.
You have to put that down.
Okay, you guys, don't film.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, throw the cameras.
WOMAN:
That's not fair.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, it's okay. It's okay.
My name's Pauly.
Pauly, hi.
My name's Fruhana.
I'm John's PA.
Oh, okay. Perfect.
John doesn't have
any appointments, dear.
Really?
Yeah, not this morning, no.
No, because we called--
Do you know who contacted him?
No. Well, I had
my assistant contact him
and basically say
that I'm coming here to--
To-- To Africa
to possibly just
interview the girls,
so that was the whole--
Yes. No, I understand
what you're saying,
but I haven't received
anything from anyone.
So there's no way I can talk
to any of the girls right now?
No. I'm so sorry.
Just to interview them?
I'm from America, okay?
Yes.
Oprah's from Chicago.
My brother lives in Chicago.
Okay?
Yes.
So I'm, like, really close
with her, and--
Have you seen me before?
No.
(Laughing)
No?
No, I'm sure you're great.
I'm a funny guy.
I do this weasel thing.
I go crazy and stuff.
Okay, thank you
for having us.
Dexter!
Later, bro!
Adopting a child from the
Oprah School was my only plan,
so I had to go to Plan B,
and I didn't have a Plan B.
Come to think of it,
I didn't even have a Plan A.
Okay, be careful.
Lock the doors.
I will.
And if you hear me scream,
you know,
call George Bush.
(Laughing)
What's up, bro?
What's up, dawg?
I came all the way
from California.
You came to do what,
exactly?
PAULY:
Meet a child.
Meet a child to take her back
to California for a better life.
VAL:
I have Pauly Shore with me.
He's here in Africa
to adopt a baby.
Can I have him now?
Can I take him with me?
You sell the chicken?
I'm selling him.
That's tight. T.I., T.I.
How much for a--
If I want to adopt a child,
how much for a child
instead of a chicken?
A child.
I want to buy the chicken,
and I want to adopt a child.
(Laughing)
Do you have any babies
available?
No?
How did Angelina Jolie
do it?
How did she do it?
Remember Madonna?
How did they do it?
What did they do?
Just wanted to say,
"What's up?"
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Los Angeles.
Sí.
Can I take this baby?
WOMAN: No.
It's your baby?
No.
It's my baby?
It's his baby?
Give me a hug. Oh!
The problem is,
is all these kids have parents,
and they won't let me
take them.
(Sighing)
Anything?
Have you gotten anything?
Yes, I did call a few,
one or two.
Yeah?
Refused to see us.
I flew all the way over here
because I'm interested
in adopting an African child
to bring back
to the States with me
for possibly a better life.
What you mean by
"better lifestyle"?
Well, why--? Yeah, why do they
say that, then?
That's my question.
Publicity stunt.
Why come all the way here
when there are so many
other people over there
going through the same thing?
So then I should just go home.
Just adopt someone from home.
Fuck this. I'm going home.
(All laughing)
MAN:
That's what I'm saying.
So we're straight, right?
We're all straight?
No, no, no.
Nothing,
we're straight.
PAULY:
You know, maybe I'm going
about this the wrong way.
If I'm going to find a child,
I'm going to need to break bread
with these people.
But there's only
one problem:
when it comes to germs,
I'm worse than Howie Mandel.
Is that clean?
It's okay? No problem?
MAN:
Don't use too much.
PAULY:
This first,
then this?
No, no.
And then that
and then that?
Show me. Show me.
Let me show you.
Dude!
What the fuck, bro?
MAN 1:
Show him. Show him. Show him.
MAN 2:
Get that. Enjoy it.
And also with--
(Speaking foreign dialect)
It's hot. It's hot.
(Laughing)
I need my soda!
Can I try it on?
Is that okay? No worries?
Right. No worries.
That's good, right?
Sure, sure.
PAULY:
Spending the day in Africa
is like spending the day
in Venice Beach
but with no winos
or Filipinos.
Have you seen
Dave Chappelle?
I heard he's hiding in there.
(All laughing)
You got to like the music
of America.
You like Dr. Dre,
Snoop Dogg, 50 Cent?
That's my boy, 50 Cent.
(Laughing)
PAULY:
I was having such
an amazing time.
But with all this excitement,
I almost forgot why I was here.
It was time for me to say
goodbye to my new friends
and continue my quest
for my child.
Hi.
WOMAN: Hello. How are you?
I'm not doing too good,
actually.
Well, do you guys
have babies here?
What are you, you're like
a witch doctor?
Sangoma.
What's a Samgorma?
Come. Come, come, come.
PAULY: Come?
WOMAN: Come.
Let me show you, my son,
how to throw the bones.
Here he goes.
(Blowing)
Can you get diseases
by holding the bones?
No.
Okay. Don't get mad.
I'm just asking a question.
(Both laughing)
That's not good when bone--
(Laughing)
Is that good
when one bone stays?
WOMAN:
No, it doesn't matter.
PAULY:
Oh, it doesn't matter?
Has that happened before?
Yes.
Okay.
This is the babies?
Yes, it's the baby.
This is a baby?
Oh, this is the girl?
Yeah, it's a baby.
This is a baby?
Yes.
Oh, the baby! Oh, the baby!
Oh, the baby!
Breast-feed the baby.
Mwah, mwah, mwah, mwah.
This is my little girl.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Here's the problem:
I don't know where to go,
and I just want to take the baby
for one afternoon.
And I can take the baby
for a little test-drive?
Really?
Yes.
Here's what I'll do,
is I'll text you my number.
Okay.
Okay? See, you have cellphones
here in Africa.
A lot of people
don't even think that.
I know.
You're, like, modern, babe.
Yes.
(Laughing)
Is that a BlackBerry?
The new--
The new BlackBerry Curve?
Oh, it's a Nokia?
Those damn Japanese.
Nokia!
(Imitating speaking Japanese)
(Laughing)
Let me touch your Nokia.
So I got my reading from
Miss Cleo, and I was on my way.
I'm going to get a baby, bro!
I'm going to get a baby!
I couldn't believe it.
Within the next 12 hours,
I was going to have a young girl
or boy by my side.
Am I ready to take on
this responsibility?
Am I ready
to become a father?
Time will tell.
So the Sangoma texts me
on my BlackBerry
and said, "These are the rules:
3 days, 3 kids.
Have them home before dark."
I text her back--
She texts me back--
Okay, I'm going to go fetch
the baby.
Good luck.
Okay.
You're funny.
Are you sure you weren't
in a rock band,
like, in the '70s or '80s?
VAL:
No.
PAULY:
This place doesn't look
like an adoption agency.
It looks like a place to score
medical marijuana.
(Door buzzing)
Morning.
Hi. Yeah, I'm here to see,
is it--? It's Ellen?
Ellen?
Allen is in.
Come inside.
Is it Allen?
Yes, it is.
Ellen?
Is she here?
He's here.
He's here?
Yeah.
Come through.
Okay.
I have a meeting.
ALLEN:
Hi, Pauly.
I've been expecting you.
I'm Allen.
Hey, nice to see you.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Thank you for having me.
Sit down.
Thank you.
We can have a talk
about visit to our country.
I'm interested to possibly,
you know--
I just love
little black children.
All right.
You know what I mean?
I think they're adorable.
I think they're sweet.
And to possibly, you know,
take them back to Hollywood,
maybe raise them
at the Comedy Store.
That's why I'm, like,
think I would be perfect for it.
Are you in a normal
family setting?
Are you married with--
Do you have a house
of your own?
I mean,
it's serious stuff.
I mean, it's--
Talking about an application.
You know what I have,
is a big heart.
I have a niece
and nephew.
If I were to get a kid,
what would he be?
Their nephew
or their niece?
Well, first of all,
adoptions, per se,
means that it becomes
your child.
The child will actually
have your surname.
Right.
It is your child.
So it would be,
like, Mutumba Shore?
Well, should you qualify
for the adoption.
So you don't think
I can qualify for one?
Men-- Well--
I mean, what do you--?
I mean, what--?
We screen.
But what do I--? Okay.
So I'm here. I want a child.
Give me a child.
What do I do?
You know what?
You can have my passport
for collateral,
because then I'm not leaving
the country,
so you know, like,
I'm not going to, like,
take the kid
and all of a sudden, like,
next thing you know, I'm in,
like, Florida somewhere.
I would consider,
I mean,
sending Odwa with you
for the day.
Oh, is that the kid's name?
Yeah.
So you've already
picked one out for me?
I just want to--
I understand.
Normally, I would not
have done this. Odwa!
Odwa is a sweet,
young, caring boy.
How are you?
PAULY:
Hi. Wait. Hold on. Wait.
Hold him back.
Hold him.
Hold him back one second.
Seriously.
ALLEN:
What--? What's your problem?
There's no problem. I just
didn't-- Here, you can come now.
Well, I don't like
what I see.
Odwa, have a seat here
next to Uncle Pauly.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
One sec, one sec.
Because, I mean,
because I didn't take my shots
or anything.
He can sit down.
I didn't get my--
My yellow fever.
Odwa, I want you to spend
the morning with Pauly.
You want to sit down?
It's okay?
I don't know what you know
about Africa, but--
Well, yeah,
tell me about it.
Well, I think you're totally
misinformed as to--
Well, you know what?
You should go out
in America
and see what they think.
When you met me, you didn't
have to put those things on.
Same for Odwa.
You don't have to.
You can take it off.
Okay, I will, in any case,
I will hear from you
and from Odwa
how was the exercise.
I don't have a mask on.
I don't have anything.
I know, but you've been here
a while.
There's nothing wrong
with Odwa.
Okay. Well, then, let's go.
All right, we're going to get--
Get going.
Just remember, you will be back
before dark.
Yeah.
Please.
No problem. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
And hold the passport.
Okay.
No problem.
Here we go.
There's just no way
that-- I hope you everything
the best.
Thank you.
ALLEN:
Thank you, Odwa. Thank you.
Bye.
ODWA: Bye.
(Door closing)
PAULY:
So I fetched my first child.
He was plump and juicy,
like a little version
of Cedric the Entertainer.
Now tell us,
what's your name?
And how old are you?
You're a good boy?
Okay.
I don't know if he is.
¶ I'm hoping, praying that this
hill will start sloping ¶
So I was thinking we'd go
rock-climbing to start it out
because I live
in the Hollywood Hills
and there's a place called
Runyon Canyon,
so if I wind up adopting you,
you, me, and my dog Butter
are going to--
ODWA:
Oh, stop this thing.
What? We're going to go--
Butter.
(Laughing)
PAULY:
This is it. We're here.
Rock-climbing.
We're here!
VAL:
Yay!
ODWA:
Son of a gun.
Yeah, you do.
(Laughing)
There you go.
Yes.
(Groaning)
It's a 3.
They will fit.
Let me do this.
It'll be like our first
kind of father-son--
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Here, put your--
Son, put your--
Put your foot--
How do you--?
(Laughing)
Yeah, but you're not--
Wait.
Son, let me do it.
Oh, I can get it.
I can get it.
¶ There's so much
going down ¶
PAULY:
I didn't expect to bond
with Odwa so quickly.
Kiss your father, son.
Kiss your father.
Mwah.
If it were between me
and a cheeseburger,
he'd probably choose me.
You have to take off
all this--
PAULY:
Nah, come to think of it,
he'd probably choose
the cheeseburger.
This is the wall you guys
are going to climb.
PAULY:
Okay.
Well, this'll be fun.
Are you up to the challenge?
Whoa.
Yes. You go first.
Make sure he's okay.
I just took him
from the orphanage.
So are you going to go down
and then I'm going to go up?
I'm down already,
so no need to go down,
so you're going to go up.
Go to the top, son.
This-- The top is America.
(Grunting)
What else does he do?
He can go higher.
What?
No, you have to keep going.
Keep fighting.
(Laughing)
WOMAN: Watch your hands.
Watch your hands.
No. No, no.
WOMAN:
Let go with both hands.
PAULY: Whoa!
WOMAN: Okay?
PAULY:
That's my baby.
Push off the wall
with your feet.
PAULY:
You did good.
You did good, son.
Ow, ow, ow!
Oh, that was great.
Bye. Thanks very much.
You did good. You made it far.
What do you think, huh?
What?
Now where do you want
to go now, son?
He was amazing out there.
Still in one piece?
Yup.
And?
It was fun. Come on.
Where are we going?
Say bye to the kids.
Bye!
VAL: Let's go, let's go.
PAULY:
So where do you want to go now,
son?
Game farm.
The game farm?
Mm-hm.
PAULY: Val?
What?
Take us to the game farm.
(Laughing)
Say, "Who's your daddy?"
Pauly Shore.
Ow. Yes.
That's good.
(Laughing)
PAULY:
When Odwa told me he wanted
to go to the game farm,
I thought it was going to be
a farm with Donkey Kong
and Missile Command.
Lions and tigers and bears.
Oh, my.
Are you ready for your big
safari, young man?
Yep.
Yeah?
PAULY:
So they can't come and get us,
right?
No. Only if you misbehave.
This is it. We're going
to go see the animals.
WOMAN: You ready?
Yep.
Yeah. This is going
to be exciting.
It's going to be like the Never
Neverland Ranch, you know?
Like Michael Jackson?
Yep.
Right?
And I'm going to hold your body,
huh?
I'm going to hold your body
like Michael Jackson.
(Odwa screaming and laughing)
(Elephant trumpeting)
Ah!
WOMAN:
Would you like
to go see some lions?
ODWA:
Yeah, baby, yeah!
Yeah!
All right, guys.
This bit of road
gets slightly bumpy,
so please hang on.
PAULY: Hold on.
We don't want you
popping over the sides,
because, the lions
might eat you.
PAULY:
Holy shit.
WOMAN:
All four are there.
The four adults.
PAULY:
They're starting to wake up.
Those lions are starting
to look hungry.
I hope they like chocolate
better than vanilla.
Shh.
They're quite all right.
They're sleeping.
Shh.
Scared that Odwa and I were
going to get eaten by the lions,
we disguised ourselves
as Mother Teresa and Yoda.
Ow. Ow.
Wait, stop, stop,
stop, stop.
Wait. Stop the car.
WOMAN: Something wrong?
No, no. Here.
Listen, whatever he says,
whatever he does,
keep driving, okay?
I'll meet you guys
about 100 yards ahead.
Just keep going.
You guys, just keep going.
Pauly!
¶ In another time ¶
(Lion roaring)
(Elephant trumpeting)
Stop the truck, you guys.
You're going to have to stop.
Hey. What's up?
Hi.
How's it going?
WOMAN: Hi.
¶ Da da-da da, da da da ¶
(Laughing)
¶ In another time ¶
I'm Lauren.
What's up? Pauly.
Wow. It's beautiful.
LAUREN:
Mm-hm.
I got a neck like a giraffe.
Feel it.
This is good.
LAUREN:
Beautiful, long neck.
WOMAN:
Daddy will be back.
He just met
that nice young lady
that he saw
on the other vehicle.
So I saw you in Entourage.
Oh, yeah,
it's a good show.
Yeah, that scene
when you got kicked out
of the Playboy mansion.
And yourself, what are you doing
in Africa?
I'm here actually
adopting a kid.
That's sweet.
So, yeah.
The single-dad thing
could work for you.
Maybe we should meet for a drink
down at the entrance.
Okay.
All right.
Pinkie swearing?
Pinkie swear.
(Laughing)
Mm.
There's more
where that came from.
WOMAN:
Think you'll see any animals
in Los Angeles when you go
and live with your new daddy?
Yes.
(Howling)
I'll see you later.
¶ Going to blow my mind
in another time ¶
Yeah, and you know what?
He promised me
to take me along.
Everybody took off,
and here I am, all by myself.
Here we go.
Thank you so much.
It's a pleasure.
I hope you enjoyed that.
Yeah, it was great.
Be careful.
Ah. Oh.
That's good.
I'm chowing down.
Sorry about him. Hi.
Are you Pauly?
Yes.
Yeah, she's been waiting
quite a long time for you,
but, unfortunately,
she left already.
She left no phone number?
Nothing.
Nothing?
No way to get
ahold of her?
Sorry, no.
All right. Thank you.
All right.
PAULY:
In my time, I have been stood up
by many chicks,
but not south of the equator.
VAL:
Chasing a girl.
PAULY:
I'm not chasing any girl.
I met a girl out there.
VAL: Yeah?
PAULY: Yeah.
So now it's time to go back
to the hotel
and show Odwa what his life's
going to be like with me.
I want a Snapple!
Oh, my son.
My potential son.
(Laughing)
¶ Too close for comfort,
you changed my mind ¶
¶ Changed my mind again ¶
VAL:
All right, guys. Here you are.
PAULY:
Thank you.
All right, we'll see you
a little later.
Good. Enjoy.
Bye.
Be good.
Bye. See you.
Run, run, run, run, run, run,
run, run.
Wow.
It's cool, right?
Hello. How's it going?
(Odwa speaking indistinctly)
The top. Yeah!
(Gibbering)
Ah!
Paradise!
Give a child some love, yo.
Tell them,
"What's up, what's up?"
'Sup, 'sup?
PAULY:
All of a sudden, I'm starting
to feel like Mr. Drummond
from Diff'rent Strokes,
and Odwa is my new,
improved Gary Coleman.
"What you talking 'bout, Odwa?"
What do you want
with me?
What do I want with you?
Yep.
Why do you want me?
That's a good question.
Because you
need to be wanted.
Plus, you know, I feel
that you would be part
of an American culture,
which it seems like
you're already Americanized.
But I am already L.A.-alized!
I am the king of Queens!
You know what's weird?
If I adopt you, it's like
I'm adopting an American boy.
You're already
Americanized.
Get the hell
out of my suite.
(Both laughing)
Yeah!
Have you been a good boy?
Why have you been
a good boy?
(Laughing)
Oh, wait. One more time.
I almost got it.
Here. Here we go.
From the chocolate?
(Laughing)
Yeah!
How does that feel
right about here?
Whoo-hoo!
Daddy. Whoo-hoo!
¶ I love the tubby ¶
¶ I love everything ¶
Are you ready for your first
scrub from Daddy?
Yes.
Huh?
One of many cleanings
that I do for you.
Lift up your arms, son.
There you go.
Get that real good.
Man, if I choose Odwa,
it's not going to be like
I'm adopting a child.
It's going to be like
I'm adopting a roommate.
Between the grocery bills
and the rehab bills,
this kid's going to break me.
Not to mention
all my girlfriends
he's going to have sex with
behind my back.
Mm, mm, mm, mm, mm.
(Chuckling)
Whoo-hoo!
Daddy. Whoo-hoo!
Hyah! Whoo-hoo!
(Seagull squawking)
PAULY:
Yum!
This is a--
An autobiography
about a very funny comedian
named Don Rickles.
(Laughing)
So, when a kid
from the neighbourhood
learns he's going to
the White House, he's excited.
"The President could be
a peanut farmer,
"but this kid's
still excited.
In fact, the President
was a peanut farmer."
(Laughing)
Peanut. Peanut farmer.
What the heck is that?
Open this for me.
PAULY:
All in all, Odwa and I
had a great time.
He brought out an innocence in
me that I haven't experienced
in a while,
a childlike quality
that I lost somewhere
along the way.
And I brought a dirtiness
out of him,
a disgustingness that he's never
experienced before.
Whoa. Whoa!
Hey.
What's that?
¶ Hot one ¶
¶ Hot one, hot one, hot one,
ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay ¶
I got to get it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa. Stop.
Turn this--
What are you watching?
You know what?
Forget it, all right?
Just-- Just stop. Pack it up.
We're packing you up.
We're rolling you
to the orphanage.
Let's go back.
Odwa's a beast!
He's just like
his potential old man.
He's like an African Mini-Me.
And you want to come
to America for sure?
I just want to make sure
you're into it.
Yes.
You want to come for sure,
right?
Yes.
Okay.
Is there anything else
you want to know about me?
No.
You're good, right?
Yes.
So, you'll pack your bags?
Okay.
All right.
Just make sure
you just don't say anything.
Yes.
Okay.
Bye.
Later.
¶
It was weird.
I went from a child to a parent
within a moment's time,
and I was cool with it.
I was totally cool with it.
¶
Last night
I could hardly sleep,
thinking about how much fun
I had with Odwa.
But today's a new day,
and I'm ready to experience
what life would be like
with another child.
Did Odwa talk to you?
Did he say it went well?
He said it was good.
How was the day
with Odwa?
You know what? He's--
He's a fantastic child.
You think so?
You know, but I do want to--
You know, I do want to be able
to see someone else.
Well, I said to you I'll--
Yeah,
I'll arrange another.
Not that I don't like him
and not that he's not
in the running.
This is like
speed adopting.
Like, "Who's my next child?
Who's my next child?"
Well, I'm not into the business
of speed adopting.
It's like almost like,
I don't know, a pair of shoes.
You know, you buy a pair
of shoes, and then, like,
you know, a week later,
you're, like,
"Shit, I wish I would
have got Adidas.
Instead, I got Nikes."
Not that the Adidas aren't good
or the Nikes aren't good.
With respect, we do what is in
the best interest of the child.
But I've arranged for you
to meet Summila.
Is that a girl or a boy?
It's a young boy.
Okay, okay.
Summila.
Come in.
Yes. We have here.
My young boy, come in.
Oh, my God.
How's it going?
What's his--? He's cute.
Summila, have a seat.
I like him.
I think I like him better
than Odwa.
Odwa's a little crazy.
He's a little nuts.
Like, I'm nuts too, and I don't
need-- You know,
he seems a sweet child.
Son, look at your father.
Look at your father.
Do you like it here,
or do you want to go?
He likes it here.
So this is going to be hard
for me to crack him.
So I got to hurry.
You know, I don't want to spend
any more time in your office.
Let me get going.
We just--
You know, it's all good.
Summila.
Hey, thank you for letting me
take your kids.
Yeah, well, thank you.
Oh, God. All right, he'll--
He'll be safe.
He'll be in good hands.
I trust you.
PAULY:
Tell him you'll be
in good hands.
In good hands, eh?
All right.
ALLEN: Thank you.
PAULY: Thanks, guys. Bye.
It looks like the tooth fairy
forgot to look
under somebody's pillow.
No sweet corn on the cob
for this kid.
I had no idea
they had hockey in Africa.
But it's okay, because I'm going
to take him to Dr. 90210
in Beverly Hills
and get him some veneers.
We're going to do some radio,
okay, buddy?
This is what we're going to do
in the States.
(Woman speaking foreign dialect)
We've got celebrity Tuesday,
which means--
PAULY:
Celebrity Tuesday?
Who the hell did they have here
last week, Vanilla Ice?
We've got our guest here in
studio with us: Pauly Shore.
Nice to see you guys.
So tell us about the friend
that you have here with you.
Hello. Hi.
Hello.
Hello. What's your name?
Summila.
Why do you have Summila
with you today?
I'm looking to adopt
an African boy.
You too?
And why so?
What made you decide
to come and adopt
an African boy?
Because, you know, it's just--
It's in my heart.
Okay. So let's hear what
the callers have to say.
Who have we got
on the line?
MAN:
Hey, what's up?
Do you think it's a great idea
for Pauly
to adopt
a kiddie from here?
You know what?
I think Pauly
is going to be a great dad.
Pauly, do not worry about
all the other people.
As you guys call it, haters,
you know?
PAULY:
Exactly.
If Clay Aiken can be
a good mother,
I could be a great father.
(Speaking foreign dialect)
(Imitating foreign dialect)
Nothing to do
with calamari.
PAULY:
Summila's smart.
He's good-looking.
He's like baby Obama.
I'd vote for him.
Say, "I'm going putt-putting
with my new potential dad,
Pauly Shore."
I can't say it.
You wait, okay?
I'll do that.
PAULY:
Come on, son.
Let me give you your first
golf lesson, okay?
Hello. Good.
What colour do you want?
MAN: Pick a colour.
What colour?
Blue. Okay, we're going to have
two blue balls.
(Laughing)
See? My kind of guy.
(Sighing)
Sir, is this the age
that Tiger started around?
This is the age
that Tiger started.
Why do you think
I'm down here with him?
Get down on your stomach.
Come here, son.
Son, get on your stomach, son.
Here we go. You ready?
Huh?
Play pool.
There you go, my son.
PAULY:
There you go.
All right.
Are you coming with me?
Yes.
You are?
Go.
Yay!
¶ Can I say just one more thing
before I go ¶
¶ That I think that
you should know? ¶
Ow. Ow.
(Laughing)
¶ All the times
and all the laughs ¶
Where are you?
Where are you, Summila?
¶ Because I never liked you
anyway, hey, hey ¶
¶ La, da-da da-da da-da
da-da-da ¶
It's beautiful, huh?
Right?
(Laughing)
Isn't it?
If I take you back
to America with me,
we'll definitely come back here
and build sand castles, okay?
Pinkie swear.
Pinkie promise.
All right?
Let's go to that thing
that goes up on the mountain.
¶ La, da-da da-da da-da
da-da-da ¶
PAULY:
Summila's great. Odwa's great.
I might just have to adopt
two kids.
They'll be like
my Tupac and Biggie.
Okay, we're going
on the cable car.
We're going
Look at us.
We're going up the mountain.
Isn't this awesome?
Summila, do you want to look out
the thing?
(Tittering)
Are you excited
to be with me?
SUMMILA:
Yes.
PAULY:
Fun.
MAN:
Thank you, everyone.
Enjoy your stay on top
of the mountain.
We all made it.
(All applauding)
This is good stuff.
This is Summila.
Say hi to the people.
Hello.
Aren't the girls pretty?
Look, they look like
Britney Spears.
(All laughing)
Hug them.
Hug the girls.
Hi!
PAULY:
See?
Isn't he beautiful?
GIRLS:
Yes, he is very cute.
Oh, look, I have a piece
of steak on the barbecue.
Huh?
(Whimpering)
(Laughing)
Okay. Ow. Ow.
I got nieces and nephews.
Yeah.
So I got a--
That's great, because,
that's what kids--
She had the body of Beyoncé
and the head of a midget.
WOMAN:
Are you all right?
Just stay with the lady
for a second.
Okay, I'll--
Just hold on to him.
Hold on to him, okay?
Okay.
I'll hang on to him.
All right, thanks.
'Sup?
Hey.
How's it going, girl?
Oh, good. How are you?
Good.
What are you doing over here all
alone, little African princess?
So do you know much
about America?
I like
how your green stuff
matches with the green stuff
there.
Thank you.
What's your name?
Angela.
Nice to see you. Pauly.
Nice to see you.
Hold me like that.
(Laughing)
Feel. See my giraffe's neck?
You were telling me
what your favourite food was.
What is it?
I was on Entourage recently.
You see that HBO show
Entourage?
Yeah.
I got, like,
a really big part on that.
I'm, like, reoccurring
through the whole thing.
Wow, I'm impressed.
Yeah.
Maybe you should teach Pauly
some Xhosa.
Wouldn't that be fun?
Can you go
wine-tasting?
Right now?
Yeah.
Let's do it.
You'll love it.
You'll be okay.
You just wait here.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
You like it?
Yep.
You do?
Yeah.
Speak any language.
(Speaking foreign dialect)
Yeah.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
I left my kid! I left my kid!
Oh, my God!
I left my kid!
Summila!
Oh, my God.
We got to turn it around.
Can we turn it around, please?
Turn this thing around.
Is there another tram?
MAN:
There's another tram,
but it's on top now.
It's coming down.
Oh, my God.
How long does it take for these
things to go back up?
MAN:
It's probably an hour
to get here, yeah.
An hour to go back up?
Once again, my little head
thinking for my big head.
You didn't mention
you had a kid with you.
PAULY:
I forgot.
You came up to me and you said,
"Let's go wine-tasting."
ANGELA:
You should have told me.
PAULY:
I forgot the kid was up there.
MAN:
Do you want to go back up?
Yes, I want to go back up.
Can these things
go any faster, please?
Can they go faster? Huh?
Where's the opening?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I lost my son.
Summila!
Did you guys
see a little boy?
A little boy, like,
this big with orange?
He's wearing this orange--
So you saw him?
Yeah, I saw him.
Huh?
Oh, my God.
ANGELA: You lost him.
Unbelievable.
As big as this girl is,
you'd think she'd look
over people and find him.
I can't believe this.
I'm such an idiot.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
It's my fault.
Hey, I'm the one
invited you.
I know.
It is your fault.
So, Lisa Leslie and I searched
for hours and hours
on top of the mountain.
You didn't see him?
The little boy?
And finally, through God's will,
I found my boy, my child,
sitting next
to Weezy Jefferson.
My son!
Phew! Thank you so much
for watching my son.
Oh, my God.
You nearly got lost.
Thank you.
No, I left him,
like an idiot.
Thank you, sweetie.
Hey.
Thank you very much.
Thank you
for watching my son.
How are you going to be a good
father, losing your son?
Give me a hug,
my son.
Oh.
Now that I have Summila back,
we're one big,
happy family.
So now it's time
to get drunk.
(Speaking foreign dialect)
That sounds Spanish.
Ask Summila what kind of wine
he wants.
He's going to have a little too,
since he's my son.
I'll get you arrested
for that.
No, my African princess.
(Laughing)
I'm kidding.
(Both laughing)
Oh, we got a real Eddie Murphy
in the car.
ANGELA:
What do you think about me?
You? You're the shit.
You're beautiful.
The first time I saw you,
I thought you were Beyoncé.
Really?
Yeah.
(Laughing)
You're kidding.
PAULY:
Yeah, Beyoncé
with the head of a midget.
So show me the way.
I'm just going to follow
your lead on it.
Hello.
There you go.
Swish it up, son.
Swish it up like this.
ANGELA:
Yeah. Shake it a little bit.
PAULY:
Shake it up.
ANGELA:
Good.
Drink to family right here.
Here, come on.
Take this.
Wow.
This is nice.
PAULY:
It's very-- I taste a lot
of stuff in it.
So it's, as I said,
been made for a long time.
Wow!
That's bam!
Man, this chick
drinks more than me.
She's like an Afro-aholic.
Can you be his mother
for a second?
ANGELA:
Let me try.
If I can't handle him,
I will tie his hands.
Let's drink.
PAULY: Where did he go?
ANGELA: Right here.
PAULY:
Come on. Get back here.
ANGELA:
Okay, don't go up.
Get back here! Yo!
Somalia!
You know what I think
it is? I think it's--
Uh-huh?
Mm.
I think it's because he doesn't
have any teeth or something.
Doesn't have tooth?
No, you should look at it.
It's funny.
What do you mean,
he doesn't have tooth?
He lost his teeth.
I don't know what it is.
In a boating accident
or something.
Is it?
What do you mean,
doesn't have any teeth?
He has everything.
PAULY: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Shit.
Oh, my God.
What's your name?
Inga.
PAULY:
No!
I can't believe this. Ah!
VAL:
What happened?
What the hell have you done?
Unbelievable.
What are you doing here?
Picked up the wrong kid.
I'm not going back there,
wasting my bloody time,
my fuel, my car.
PAULY:
And who do you think's paying
for her fuel, her car
and her time?
Me! I don't need to hear this
from Val right now.
I'm the star of Bio-Dome!
ANGELA:
I mean, really,
what were you thinking?
What were you thinking?
How can you be a father,
yet you can't even take care
of a kid for just one lousy day?
You are just so lousy!
You just make
a lousy father.
You're the whole reason
why this thing happened
from the beginning.
Hey, don't blame me for this,
okay?
You are just a lousy father!
No, you're the reason,
because you were looking at me
and you said, "Come over here."
(Shouting in foreign dialect)
You know what? Screw this.
You know what? Drop her off.
Val, stop the car.
Stop the car.
Get out of the car.
Huh? Go. Come on.
(Angela shouting
in foreign dialect)
You know what I mean?
I do. I do understand.
Let's just go
to the radio station.
Okay, I'll take you there.
Sorry about that.
We got to get on the air.
(Speaking foreign dialect)
Where are your parents at?
Come on.
We're on in--
Okay. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's going on now?
I got to get on the air.
Pauly Shore just ran
into the studio here.
Whoa.
What is going on?
I got to get on the air.
What are you doing here?
Why did you just burst in here?
If there's anyone out there
over at Cable Mountain,
please call
if you've seen a kid
on top of the main mountain
with no teeth.
Please, someone call up.
WOMAN:
So if someone finds a boy
without the teeth
on Cable Mountain,
tell them to bring him here
over to MFM studios.
PAULY:
I've got to find
this guy's parents.
What's your name?
Please come and fetch him here.
Are you stupid or something?
How could you lose a kid?
Just keep an eye on that one.
Just don't lose that one.
PAULY: Don't let him go.
Hello, MFM.
Good evening.
MAN:
Pauly, man, you suck.
What's wrong with you?
I-- I made a mistake.
Do you think all Africans
look the same or something?
(Laughing)
Is that a joke to you?
Okay. No, it's not a joke.
Find Summila.
Someone bring him along.
Thanks, you guys.
Okay, cool.
Thanks for having me.
Please go wait outside now,
because you've messed up
the show now.
And just look after this one.
Don't lose him now as well,
please.
I can't get arrested
for this, can I?
Well, you lost a kid.
You lost a kid.
It's called negligence.
PAULY:
I guess the moral of the story
is don't drink and adopt.
(Speaking foreign dialect)
That idiot!
Oh, my God!
PAULY:
I've bathed a kid,
I've stolen a kid,
I've lost a kid.
I've mistreated
more black children
than the justice system.
Inga. Inga, baby.
This is my son, man.
You can't
tell the difference?
Your child is not
up for adoption?
No! You can't adopt children.
You don't just steal them
like that.
Please, get away from me.
Hey, before I go
and call my family.
That's my kid!
Oh!
Look at him!
My God!
SUMMILA: I don't like this.
PAULY:
I don't care what anybody says.
These two black kids
look alike.
Come on.
Just leave me.
I was able to bring Summila
back to the orphanage
the next morning
because Allen fell for the bit
"Whenever a kid is sleeping,
don't wake him."
Pretend I'm Allen.
Hey, so how was the day
with Pauly?
Did he lose you?
I heard he lost you.
He was good, right?
Let me see the teeth.
(Laughing)
And while I was talking
to Allen,
he told me how expensive it was
going to be for me
to actually adopt a kid,
so I called my agent
back in L.A.
to book me a one-nighter.
The show's tomorrow night,
so I had to go back to the hotel
and get some sleepy.
Nighty-night!
¶
I just hope Allen gives me
another kid,
preferably one that comes
with a GPS.
ALLEN:
So you okay?
I see you look tired.
Yeah, it was--
What's your problem?
Well, just we slept a lot.
It was good.
We just hung out together
all day.
Look, you said
on the one hand,
Odwa was a bit mad.
And now you say you slept
with Summila.
I didn't sleep with him.
It wasn't like
I slept with him.
No, I didn't mean--
We just kind of, you know--
It's just--
You fell asleep.
I definitely like Summila
a little bit better that Odwa.
He's nuts, this kid.
Summila is--
Is a sweetheart of a child.
Are you not perhaps nuts?
Let's see who else you have.
I've got Faith for you.
Who is it?
Faith is her name.
Oh. So a girl.
Beautiful girl, yeah.
Okay, cool.
Faith!
Oh, my God.
Wow!
Hi.
Nice to see you.
How's it going?
Your name's Faith?
Is that your real name?
Have a seat.
Really? Wouldn't she have, like,
more of an African name?
Well, many African people
have names like "Faith"
and "Beauty," and I've come
across a guy
with the name
"Astonishment."
Astonishment's his name?
Yes.
Who's your favourite singer
or rapper or anything?
Oh, Beyoncé?
See, I know Beyoncé,
and I'm friends
with Jay-Z.
I'm down with the whole
East Coast crew, so, like,
if this thing works out,
like, I swear,
like, within a month,
she'll be in a Beyoncé video,
probably playing her daughter
or something.
Well, I don't want to go there.
PAULY:
What do you think about that?
Look, she's smiling.
ALLEN: I see you smiling.
(Laughing)
Is that cool? She's quiet.
ALLEN:
Thank you, Pauly.
You know what it says
about the quiet ones?
Those are
the mischievous ones.
Excuse me.
Are you mischievous?
You are, right?
(Pauly laughing)
Okay, here we go.
Okay. Have a good time.
Okay.
I love her hair too.
It's beautiful, by the way.
I hate when, like, people put--
Like, the girls,
they put all the stuff
in their hair.
This is à la naturelle.
African-za-za-za-style.
Okay, Pauly. Thank you.
PAULY: Here we go.
Bye, Faith.
She's going to be
in a hip-hop video, yo.
Later.
Just when I thought my heart
was filled with the two boys,
my heart opened up
to a new passageway.
This is probably
how George Bush felt
when he met Condoleezza Rice.
Have you ever seen a stand-up
comedian before?
No? Do you know what
a stand-up comedian does?
You don't?
No.
He grabs the mike,
and he goes onstage
in front of all the people
and he tells jokes.
That's what I do.
(Scatting)
Since my show
was later that night,
Faith and I stopped by a local
bar to do a warm-up set.
(Indistinct chattering)
All the way from Hollywood,
California,
you've seen him in such movies
as Encino Man,
Bio-Dome, Jury Duty,
Son in Law.
You got to give me
an introduction,
because I can't come out
without introduction, right?
If you've ever seen Russell
Simmons' Def Comedy Jam,
those brothers keep it real.
If I'm going to impress
my daughter,
I can't back down
like a punk.
I'm in Africa. I got to come
at these brothers hard.
Yeah, you know, actually, a lot
of people think I came here
to Africa to tell jokes.
I actually came here to get HIV.
Did someone just throw a drink
on me,
or is that piss
rolling down my leg?
I've been eating that--
That goddamn meat that you have
on the boards.
(All laughing)
I go to a lot of clubs
in Los Angeles.
I hate going down
the red carpet.
They always ask me to go down
Here in Africa,
you don't have carpet.
(Inaudible)
I'm just kidding.
You guys have carpet.
It's just been urinated on.
Anyways--
MAN:
Oh.
But--
Security to the stage.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Okay. But thank you guys
for having me in your beautiful
establishment,
seriously, and I'll see you
next time.
Come on, babe.
Thank you, guys.
Bye.
That was fun, huh?
Yeah.
That was the first time
I ever played a room
with a two-tooth minimum.
VAL:
Have they recognized Pauly?
PAULY:
If I'm going to wind up
adopting Faith,
she's got to be fashionable,
so I told Val to take us
shopping.
Plus, I heard Madonna say
that in Africa,
Ed Hardy shirts
are half off.
This doesn't look like
there's a place
that there's a mall
around here.
Is there a market,
an African market?
What is this place?
Yeah, we'll-- There is for sure
some markets
and shopping places.
PAULY:
Man, this place is scary.
Where's Val taking us?
I had no idea there was
a South Central in South Africa.
VAL:
Here we are, guys.
This is what
you were looking for.
This is a market.
Go. Get, get, get, get, get.
Go, do shopping.
Spend all your money.
This is an authentic market.
Promise me you'll bring me
something, please.
If you come back
without something for me,
there's trouble.
Get!
This place smells like urine
and chicken.
Is this an authentic
African market?
No.
This isn't it.
We got to get the hell
out of here.
This isn't the place
that you were talking about.
Stay. Bye, bye, bye, bye, bye.
PAULY:
No, no, no.
What the hell is this
Elizabeth Taylor,
lead singer of Quiet Riot bitch
doing now?
She can't leave us out here.
It's like we're chum
and these people are sharks.
Oh, I guess
Pauly Shore is Dead
isn't going to just
be a movie anymore.
Is this an authentic
African market here?
I'm just in town.
I'm adopting a child
from Africa.
And I'm supposed to take her
shopping today, and--
Where do I get a taxi from?
A taxi?
I just need to call the taxi
and just have them meet me here.
If they meet me here, then I can
tell them where to go.
Okay.
PAULY: Yes.
Where are you from?
I'm from Los Angeles,
California.
In the United States?
Yes, from the United States.
(Whistling)
And I was wondering if you have
a telephone
we can use
to call a taxi?
Mm-mm. No way.
PAULY: No?
Do you think I can get
killed out here?
Yes.
And when I realized
that the black man
was trying to keep
the white man down
when it comes to hailing a taxi,
I decided right then
it was time for Faith and I
to do a little shopping.
(Speaking in foreign dialect)
Those look good.
Hey, hey, hey!
PAULY:
I think I just found
Flavor Flav's mom.
So after Faith and I
were shopping,
we got a little hungry,
so we decided to stop
by the mall's food court.
Is this like
Panda Express?
Let's keep walking.
Hopefully, we won't get stabbed.
Faith and I even bumped
into a famous musician.
Macy Gray, fantastic Grammy
Award-winning artist
on Epic Records.
She's-- Look at that face.
Hi, baby.
So these are your three kids?
Can I take one?
Yeah.
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe,
catch a tiger by the toe,
if it hollers, let it go,
eeny, meeny, miny, moe.
(Grunting)
All right, I'm grabbing kids
left and right.
Come on, Faith.
You got a sister.
It was like
I was an adoption junkie.
Every kid I came across,
I had to grab.
Hi, I'm going
to take your son.
And in the middle of my crazy
euphoria, I realized,
"Shit, I've got to be onstage
in less than two hours."
And at that moment,
Faith and I stumbled upon
our guardian angel.
What's up, my man?
Hello!
Hello.
Are you the main guy here?
Hey.
Are you the president
of this area right here?
His name was Peter Mata.
He stood 6'4".
A giant with a heart to match.
And word on the street was he
won sexiest man of Africa.
But more importantly,
he had a phone.
So I can use your phone
to call a taxi, right?
Okay.
Are you on Verizon or AT&T?
You've got the penthouse suite.
You're like the P. Diddy
of African-za-za!
I want to see your spot.
Show me your spot.
This is tight work in here.
PETER:
I'm staying here.
PAULY:
This is it.
Yes.
Do you have a phone
I can use?
This is my room.
This is good.
I like it.
There you go.
That's how you roll, right?
I like your headquarters.
I like this hook.
Do you bring girls here?
Yes.
Have you gotten girls pregnant
in this room?
Yes.
You've gotten girls pregnant
in here?
(Laughing)
Oh, Peter Mata!
Peter Mata,
you're so big!
Oh, you're so big,
Peter Mata!
Oh, do it to me good,
Is that what you do to them,
huh, you bastard?
So, Peter called us a taxi
and sent us on our way.
Bye, Peter Mata.
We'll see you later.
Bye-bye, bye-bye.
You're living large.
He's a nice man,
that Peter Mata.
So after walking
for hours all day,
it was going to be nice
to sit back and relax
in our own taxi.
Can you take us to the beach?
No problem?
Okay, come on in,
sweetie.
It's rainy out there today.
How's it going? Good?
Are you guys
going to the beach?
Want to smoke some herb?
(Police siren wailing)
Uh-oh, here they come.
They're coming to get us.
We've got
the blood diamonds.
Right?
Yeah, bro. We're getting
blood diamond, boy!
(Speaking gibberish)
Click, click, click, click,
click, click, click, click!
Hi.
(Laughing)
The smell that I was
experiencing
was somewhere between
the perfume section at Barneys
and horse shit,
and that smell was me.
Either way, Faith and I were
happy that we got picked up
by the Boston Celtics:
Kevin Garnett,
Paul Pierce,
Rondo.
They were all there.
Because I'm down with them,
and they don't want
to leave their little teammate
in the streets.
All right, thank you.
Bye.
ALL: Bye.
One more "click, click."
(All clicking tongues)
(Chuckling)
Later.
Even though I was running late
for my show,
I needed to stop by and get
my mom a blood diamond.
After all,
it was her favourite movie.
No, you don't want
to get blood diamonds.
Oh, you don't?
No, you don't.
I thought that's what
you guys had.
WOMAN:
No, no, no.
PAULY:
I wanted to get Faith
a blood diamond,
but I didn't want
to spoil her.
And to be honest,
I might not pick her.
I like to buy things for people
that actually talk to me.
Thanks.
All right, sweetie,
thank you.
(Seagull squawking)
So I talked to the orphanage,
and they said I could bring you
home a little late.
So you'll be here okay
by yourself at the room?
Yeah, don't worry.
I'll be all right.
Aw.
Just go make people laugh.
Is it me,
or does Faith's hair
look like Darth Vader's helmet?
(Clicking tongue)
Aw. Okay, bye.
Okay, bye.
Sweetie, this is your place,
so enjoy it.
Okay.
Bye.
RADIO HOST:
Yes, African mutts.
If you know what it is, it's all
about the hardest-working party
in the continent.
And tonight, it's all about
Pauly Shore, man.
Don't forget Pauly Shore was in
some of these great,
great movies,
like the Son in Law,
Bio-Dome, Encino Man,
and, most recently,
on HBO's Entourage.
And I hear that Pauly Shore
wants to adopt a baby, man.
Yes, that's great.
We've got a caller on line.
Boom! Hello, caller.
CALLER:
I just wanted to say when
I heard that Pauly Shore
was coming down to Africa,
I was pretty excited,
because I've always
been a fan of Pauly Shore.
RADIO HOST:
Yes.
CALLER:
He's the funniest white cat
I know, and he--
And not a lot of white
comedians can make me laugh,
but Pauly has a little bit
of Africa inside him,
I can tell you that.
RADIO HOST:
Yeah, I know he does.
Thank you, caller, huh?
CALLER: No doubt, man.
Pauly Shore!
(Radio host laughing)
RADIO HOST:
Boom, dynamite.
(Cheering and applauding)
What's up, Africans?
Jesus, where are all
my brothers at?
How are you guys? How are
you guys feeling tonight?
(All applauding)
I knew Africa had rhinos,
but not albinos.
Are you guys sick of actresses
coming over here
and adopting your babies?
(All laughing)
Tired of Angelina Jolie
coming over here,
taking your children.
What she doesn't realize
is someday
these kids are going to grow up
and rob her.
(All laughing)
(Cheering and applauding)
Like, "Quick, Maddox, let's get
the fuck back to Jo'burg."
It's weird.
Here I was on the other side
of the world
making thousands
of people laugh.
But all I really wanted to do
was go back to my hotel room
and do my clicking sound
with Faith.
Am I growing up?
Have I turned a new leaf?
I was truly moved
by the children of Africa.
That's my time.
Thank you guys so much.
Thank you! I love you!
Peace!
(All cheering and applauding)
¶
What?
You guys were the one
that wanted to come here
and have sex
amongst yourselves.
Oh, my God.
That's what you said.
Sweetie, I'm back. I've got
to get back to the orphan--
She robbed me.
Who?
Holy shit.
She took all my clothes.
She did!
(Laughing)
Oh, my God.
There should be some stuff.
I got fucking robbed.
This is unbelievable.
Oh, Pauly,
that's so cute, man.
Don't tell me
she stole the--
Oh, my God.
She stole the diamond.
She took my mom's diamond.
She stole my computer,
my shoes, my condoms.
Condoms?
Yes, my condoms.
No condoms?
No, they took everything.
Well, we were going to rock
your world, but, you know,
this is Africa, man.
You guys are not
from Africa.
Wait, wait, wait.
No, no, no.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, baby.
Oh.
Don't go. Come on.
It would have
been great.
You guys, don't leave.
Come on.
We've got to go.
I've been here a week.
I haven't got any action.
People waiting for us.
Things to do.
Please.
It's been good.
If we were back in the States,
this would not
be happening.
Don't these girls know
who I used to be?
¶
It has come time
to form my opinion.
I had to make a choice.
Was it going to
Odwa, Summila,
or that little bitch
that robbed me?
¶ Once again ¶
I felt like a contestant
on elimiDATE.
No. No, no.
¶ Is this all there really is? ¶
Put your feet-- Whoa!
WOMAN:
Okay, now you can push
off the wall with your feet.
You did good.
You did good, son.
¶ Once again ¶
Shh, shh.
¶ I asked myself ¶
You want to go over?
No.
Are you sure?
Yes.
(Laughing)
¶ This is not me ¶
Ow. Ow.
Where are you?
Where are you, Summila?
¶ I am diving ¶
¶ I am running ¶
This is Summila.
Say hi to the people.
Hello.
Aren't the girls pretty?
Look, they look
like Britney Spears.
(All laughing)
Hug them.
Hug the girls.
Hi!
Isn't he beautiful?
WOMEN:
Yes, he is very cute.
¶ Lift me up
to higher grounds ¶
¶
(Speaking foreign dialect)
Yes!
¶ Get away from me ¶
ALLEN:
All right. So you're here.
PAULY: Hi.
Welcome. Great.
How was your week?
Have a seat.
Well, I had a very busy,
busy schedule.
I know. There's lots of stuff
going on in Africa.
It's crazy down here.
It's fun, though.
There's, like,
so many things to do.
It's like a fair every day.
Well, I can just tell you,
I've actually consulted
your references,
and we did the screening,
and we find you to be credible,
so thank you for those
kind of details
that you provided for us,
thank you.
There's-- All my gym's paid.
All my car payments.
My-- My rent.
So they would not
have a problem at all.
All right,
so that's the information I got.
I just want to hear from you.
I thought about it a lot.
I tried to figure out
what the best child is for me.
Which one
have you decided upon?
And my choice is Summila.
I'm shocked.
Well, I know.
You would probably think
I'd like the chubby one.
I don't like you
to refer to Odwa
as "the chubby one," please.
I don't like that.
Well, no, I don't mean, like,
"chubby" in a bad way.
Listen, let me just--
I just mean
that he's a little bit--
He's a little bit hairy, so--
You took my Summila.
You know what my information is?
That you lost that child.
Summila.
If we can wrap it up here
and just kind of
get out of here.
Hey, buddy. Yo, my man.
Tell me.
Do you want to
go with this man?
No.
PAULY:
Summila?
ALLEN:
You don't want to go with him?
Wait, can I have an intimate
moment with my son?
Summila, look at me.
I'm not going to allow you
to interrogate my child.
Summila?
Did you brainwash him?
No, this child--
Summila?
ALLEN:
Okay, you can go.
Summila.
I understand that
you're not interested
in going with this man.
I hope your teeth never grow
back, you son of a bitch.
(Door closing)
I actually didn't want him.
I wanted the chubby kid.
I didn't want to say it
in front of-- No, no.
All right, listen here--
I didn't want to say it--
No, I didn't want to--
Odwa, come in.
ALLEN:
You have been in a bar.
Yes. Number one.
Number one!
Yeah, yeah!
ALLEN: You want me to trust you.
Odwa, you tell me.
PAULY:
My man, number one.
ALLEN: How are you?
Good.
Do you want to go
with this man?
No!
Now, this child does not want
to go with you either.
What?
ALLEN:
This child does not want
to go with you.
You can go. Thank you.
Ow! Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
ALLEN: Odwa.
Step back.
Yo, my man.
It's amazing.
You must have brainwashed
these guys or something.
I find it strange that you don't
ask me where Faith is.
Faith actually robbed me,
which I wanted to talk about.
Faith is still gone.
I'm just going to go.
You should be in prison.
Yeah.
I actually think-- Listen.
This is your passport.
Take your passport
and please leave my office.
Do you have any other kids
in the pamphlet that--
Even if I have children
on the pamphlet,
even if I have
other children--
I'm going to go.
Yeah, leave my office.
You're not good
for this country,
you're not good
for its children,
and thank you very much.
You've wasted my time.
Thank you.
All right, take care.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
I've just had enough of him.
I just can't believe
that I've exposed myself
to such horrendous activity.
Unbelievable.
PAULY:
I don't understand
what happened.
I mean, you said I was going
to be a good dad.
You said everything
was going good.
You threw the bones, you had
the one thing with the girl.
With the girl, if you know where
she is, I need my stuff back.
So, what happened?
I know. It's just--
So now what
am I supposed to do?
You're trying to hook me up
with your daughter?
Really?
I mean, it would be nice to have
dinner with a nice girl,
I mean,
if she's a nice girl.
I mean--
Do you have
a cellphone number?
You've got the --
You still have
the Nokia phone?
You haven't gotten--
You haven't upgraded it
to the BlackBerry yet?
Can I throw the bones
one more time?
Letting us know if I'm going to,
you know,
hook up with your daughter
or not.
I can--
¶
Hello. Are you Pauly?
Yes. Who are you?
I'm the Sangoma's
daughter.
PAULY:
If the Sangoma is her mother,
then Sam Jackson is my father.
How is she your mother?
Well, I've been adopted.
Interesting.
She told me lots
about you.
And what was that?
That you're a nice guy.
Yes.
Sweet.
Mm-hm.
Good-looking,
so I was quite excited.
Don't be shy now.
Come on.
(Laughing)
So, what's your name?
Dawn-Mari.
Look at your lips.
(Both laughing)
They're beautiful.
Thank you.
So did you come here
for a special reason?
Well, actually,
I want a green card.
Done.
So, what do I get from it?
Sex.
So if I get you a green card,
you'll have sex with me?
Just the two of us.
(Both laughing)
PAULY:
Here I was,
having dinner and drinks
with some hot blonde
that was using me
for something.
It was like
I was back in L.A.
Finally, I felt at peace.
But through
this whole experience,
I did learn just one thing,
but I can't think of it
right now because, damn,
this bitch is hot.
And you know I love
to be surrounded
by the little babies!
And as far as Faith
and my mom's diamond,
I found out later she was
in cahoots with my driver, Val.
Vijay, we got the diamond!
PAULY:
They were like Africans' version
of Thelma and Louise.
Oh, well done!
We're rich! We're rich!
Thank you, Pauly!
Well done. Well done.
Off we go.
PAULY:
But what Val and Faith didn't
steal from me
was the experience
that I gained in Africa.
All those faces.
Look at your face!
All those places.
Ah!
Click, click, click, click,
click, click, click, click.
And that goddamn meat
on the boards.
(All chattering in foreign
dialect)
I need my soda!
So it was time for me to leave
Africa and head back to L.A.
But halfway through the flight,
I realized,
"Hey, wait, Africa isn't
the only place
you can go adopt babies."
(All chattering in foreign
dialect)
So I wound up in Cambodia.
I figured it was
the next best thing.
(Girl sobbing)
Oh, okay, okay.
She doesn't want to go. Here.
Okay. Sorry, sorry.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
I thought she wanted to go.
You said she wanted to go.
(Sighing)
There's no way Madonna
and Angelina had it this rough.
¶
¶ The dawn is a mystery
waiting for discovery ¶
¶ Hold on to something ¶
¶ It's bound to get bumpy ¶
¶ I'm hoping, praying that
this hill will start sloping ¶
¶ So that I can finally say ¶
¶ That it's all downhill
from here ¶
¶ And I'll sing la-di-da ¶
¶ Uh-huh ¶
¶ La-di-da ¶
¶ Awaiting confirmation
from space station ¶
¶ Oh, here I come ¶
¶ Setting course towards
the one and only place ¶
¶ She can get to me,
the burning sun ¶
¶ And the world woke up
to work its life ¶
¶ With a paper cup
and a butter knife ¶
¶ This world, she acts just like
a tired wife ¶
¶ Who ain't no fun,
won't give me none ¶
¶ That's okay, because I never
liked you anyway ¶
¶ La-di-da ¶
¶ Uh-huh ¶
¶
¶ And the world woke up
to work its life ¶
¶ With a paper cup
and a butter knife ¶
¶ This world, she acts just like
a tired wife ¶
¶ Who ain't no fun,
won't give me none ¶
¶ That's okay ¶
¶ Because I never liked you
anyway ¶
¶ La-di-da ¶
¶ Uh-huh ¶
You have the right
to remain silent!
Anything that can be held,
will be held against you
in the state of law.
You have an option
to an attorney
if you want one
appointed to you.
Down on the ground!
(Laughing)
This is not
racial profiling.
This is the real deal.
Down on the ground, son!
Who do you think you are?
Huh?
Down on the ground, son!
So Val and I decided to take
some time out of our busy day
to stop by and say hi
to Chris Rock's friend.
Hi.
What's up?
My name's Pauly Shore.
Nice to meet you.
I'm friends with Chris Rock.
Yes.
Chris Rock.
Do you know Chris Rock,
the comedian?
He said that I can come here
and say hi to Nelson Mandela.
Okay.
Is he here?
Who?
Nelson?
Nelson is not here.
Where is he at?
Nelson Mandela Foundation.
Oh, it's the foundation?
Yes.
But he's not here.
He's not here.
His pictures are on the wall,
though.
Yes.
I saw his pictures on the wall.
That's cool.
WOMAN:
Hello, can we stop the cameras?
Can we stop the cameras, please?
Thank you.
I was-- No, I was here
to give you money.
No, no, no?
(Laughing)
Ah!
I need the lion.
I need it!
I'm going
to snap your neck.
That's it. It's over.
(Imitating bones cracking)
Ah, you're dead now!
I killed you!
(Laughing)
(Grunting)
Son, listen.
Since you're a big fellow--
Listen, since you're
a big fellow, right--
You're a big fellow, right?
If I get older and-- And not
able to control myself,
will you be my security guard,
as well?
Yes.
(Grunting)
Mr. Lion!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Don't ever do that to me.
Ah, I won't, son!
Why are all
the American celebrities,
Angelina Jolie, Madonna,
they always take the baby,
and they say,
"Oh, we're going to take them
out of Africa."
I mean, that's terrible,
correct?
That's correct.
(Laughing)
Exactly.
How much is a baby?
I think you can spend
less than 10,000.
10,000 American?
Yes, but American
can spend more than 20,000.
So now it's all of a sudden
20,000.
Do you have any babies
you want to sell?
Yes.
Let me go and take him.
Okay, bring him over here,
and you're going to--
You're going to let me
buy him?
Okay.
I'll wait here
and watch your shoes.
You guys,
we're like warriors.
Say it like this.
¶ Warriors,
come out and play ¶
¶ Warriors, come out and play ¶
I'm going to take you to see
some pretty girls.
Go on.
You like pretty girls?
Go on, yes.
I'm going to have
your own room.
You're going to have
Go on.
I'm going to, you know,
take you shopping and stuff
and buy you iPods and computers
and all those things.
Go on.
I'm going to introduce you
to the G-Unit.
Go on.
(Laughing)
(Screaming)
Because a lot of these
other people,
they come and they just
take the kid,
so I'm here to spend time.
But the thing is, I don't want
to, like, just meet the child
and take him back
to America.
I want to spend time
with the child.
Yeah, get to know
the child a bit.
Yeah, exactly, because the kid
might not like me.
Yes.
You know what I mean?
He might get back to L.A.
and be, like,
"This guy's an idiot.
Get me back to South Africa."
Yes.
You know what I mean?
To spend for how long?
Oh, here?
I'll spend for a while.
Until I find someone that,
you know, is good.
I mean, I might, you know, just,
you know, see what happens,
and then I have to do
the paperwork and stuff.
Okay.
Hello, everybody.
I'm Steven Moolman.
I played the role
of Allen.
Well, we may joke about
a very serious matter
called adoption of babies and,
particularly,
people of Europe and America
adopting children in Africa.
Well, in Africa, adoptions
is a real issue, and it's--
(Laughing)
Oh, sorry.
(Both laughing)
Yeah, but it is real, guys.
Oh, my God.
Well, let me-- Listen, let me
start talking, then.
Okay. Okay, take two.
Hi, everybody,
this is Steven Moolman--
Sorry, sorry.
Hi, everybody.
I'm Steven Moolman
here in-- I don't want to say
where I am.
Should I actually say
where I'm in charge?
Yeah. Say where you are.
Sorry.
Wait, come on.
Wait, let me just get
my composure.
How do we find a better way to
kind of, you know, help this--?
Communicate the need
that there is.
Okay. Sorry.
(Both laughing)
What's your problem?
I can't help it.
You started it.
Yeah, right.
Basically, the message is
wear condoms, right?
I mean,
that's not the message?
No, no, no.
(Both laughing)
What's the message?
So for me--
We need some more resources
to do it well.
Yeah, so for me,
it was an enlightening
experience.
I had a great time coming here
to Africa, you know.
It was good working with you,
yeah.
I had a great time,
and the people are beautiful.
You know, the people here are
honestly beautiful people.
And I definitely
will be back.
And I had an amazing time
with all these guys
that shot the documentary.
Thank you guys so much.
It was nice
working with you guys.
Thank you very much.
You guys are awesome.
Thanks, everyone here
in the crew and everyone.
I can only hope that,
through our experience,
you know, we've developed
a relationship
where we can actually hear
from one another again.
Thank you so much
for having us.
Thank you.
Bye.
God bless. Bye-bye.
Re Adaptation By: Ali Nabawy
ÖÈØ æÇÚÏÇÏ ÇáÊÑÌãå : Úáì äÈÜæì
ÌãÇÚÉ Çáİä ÇáÓÜÇÈÚ ÈÇáÇÓßäÏÑíÉ
http://wwwsevenart.blogspot.com/
Alynabawy@Hotmail.Com
analazyz@yahoo.com