ISHIDA Hikari
ANDO Masanobu
ADRENALINE DRIVE
MATSUSHIGE Yutaka
TSUNOGAE Kazue
JOVIJOVA
Directed by: YAGUCHI Shinobu
You should've gone right.
What?
Oh, right.
Whoops.
I guess you were right.
You marked it on the map.
I thought so. Boss, remember last
time we delivered the car?
We went way out of our way.
So I marked it on the map.
Why... why didn't you tell me
that back there!
Well, I thought
I might be wrong.
Of course not! You marked it
on the damn map!
Guess you're right.
Can't you be more direct.
It's a pain in the ass.
Yeah...
Don't "yeah" me.
You don't trust me, do you?
I trust you.
No you don't.
Yes I do.
Then why'd you talk to
Hosoya about quitting?
Um, I...
That's not right.
Got a problem, come talk to me.
I'm sorry.
I really don't get you.
Am I that tough to talk to?
No, that's not true.
No, I know.
You hate me, don't you?
That's not true.
It's OK, you can tell me.
You hate me, right?
I don't hate you.
I told you, it's OK.
I won't blow up.
Listen, we're only human.
Nobody's perfect.
Don't you hate it when
I harass you like this?
Um, well, alright,
maybe a little...
Told you so.
You hate me. You want to quit.
But I'll never let you.
What's that look for?
That's it. You work late today.
Why?
We need to have a little talk.
Um... tonight's not really...
Just spit it out!
God, you're irritating!
Don't you ever lose it?
What?
Come on scream at me.
Just once.
- Stop it!
- Look out!
Please stop it!
You're gonna hit something
unless you scream!
I said, cut it out.
What did you just say?
What? Nothing.
Say it again, dammit!
No, I...
Just joking.
Scared you, huh.
See? You can do it if you
really try. Hang in there.
Idiot! Look what you've done!
Hide the company name.
"RENT A CAR"
Can't drive on an empty road?
I'm sorry...
I'm in a rush. What's your number?
One of the gang will pay you a visit.
Um... Well...
No way out of this one, guys.
Um... um, a telephone number?
- Yeah.
- It's 0774436.
That your work number?
Yes.
0774436, huh?
The address? An address!
Oh my address. Yes.
2293 Kasumigaura Hatano City.
That was tricky.
You made it all up.
Made what up?
The number and address.
I'm not telling him the truth.
He might come to the agency.
These thugs are so dumb.
Hey.
What was that number again?
Yes.
0776655...
You said 4436.
You made it all up.
I'm sorry.
Your license.
Oh, sorry.
I don't have it with me.
Not you, the other one.
Come with me to the gang's office.
I'm not going.
What! Why not?
You're the one that hit his car.
You go. I'll go on back.
That's not...
You go ahead.
Besides, he's got your license.
You've got no choice.
Hey, get moving.
It's your problem now.
- Can you believe she got married?
- How'd she land him?
Bet she jumped a gut at a club.
She's always partying.
Way possible.
Where's she get all
that energy.
By the time I'm done,
I'm too beat to go anywhere.
I never guessed it'd be like this.
Can you believe how
early it still is.
My horoscope sucks this week.
What's it say?
"Your social habits
will delay matrimony."
- They're right.
- Why?
While you're making up your mind,
your guys get hitched to somebody else.
That's ancient history now.
Shizuko, have you got,
like a boyfriend.
Well, I'm too busy to...
Right? You too, huh?
No boyfriends here either.
I just wish something exciting
would turn up.
I want some money.
Life would be so much better.
Money's great, but... I want a
thrill to really shake things up...
Like an outrageously romantic...
good looking guy.
A guy, huh?
You always want a guy.
Exactly, of course.
Handsome is good, but...
- Money! Rich! He's got to be rich!
- Gotta have fun in life!
What are you going on about?
Sorry. We'll get to work.
Finished those reports?
Almost done.
You've got a mountain of work.
No dawdling.
Shizuko, shouldn't you go home?
Take off early
now and then and relax.
If you're not efficient, your
personal life will go down the drain.
All work and no play,
you'll end up like me.
You two will be fine, I'm sure.
Work hard, now.
What's that supposed to mean,
we'll be fine!?
Scary. She's keeping tabs.
She's onto us.
Old eagle eyes on the look out!
Shizuko, what's your sign?
I'm a Leo.
- I'll read your horoscope.
- That's not it.
Here it is.
"Serious and shy by nature,
you seek an opportunity to change."
"Now's your chance to
meet your new self!"
"Step out and take a chance!!"
Go for it, Shizuko.
It's your week!!
There's all this great stuff
about stepping out,
How about going, right now!
Like to the convenience store!
Can I come along?
We're still finishing up here.
You go get us something.
Shizuko's such a wimp.
Wasn't there one in your class?
Always studying.
Her shift's over.
She should go home.
There's lots of people like her.
She'll always be like that.
I wonder what she sees in life.
Exactly.
- Hey!
- Yes.
Don't just stand there.
Make some tea.
Um... no... I'm...
- Shut up and do it!
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Making tea...
Get over here.
- You a student? You work?
- Yes.
- So what do they pay you?
- What?
What's your salary?
Oh, um, 190,000 yen.
Huh. Can't make much these days.
The recession and all.
Know what that money's from?
They're bookies - horse
bicycle and boat races.
Today alone, over a dozen guys
have brought in money.
That money is our lifeblood.
It's our business.
You make legit money.
We make it under the table.
Under the table's better.
What are you, idiots!?
I said make some tea!
Answer me, goddammit!
What the fuck is it with you!
It's your job to educate them dammit!
- So, what can you pay?
- What!?
What's so shocking?
It's our business. I told you.
At least this much.
What! Five?
Not 500,000.
We're talkin' Jaguar here.
5,000,000...
Obviously there are limits
to your personal finances.
We could talk to your boss...
No, I...
Show me your hand.
Your hand, spread your palm.
Want a discount?
Want another discount?
You OK!?
I'm fine.
- What happened?
- I don't...
What is this?
What happened?
No, I... just got here myself.
And you?
I work at the General Hospital.
I was nearby when...
Can you help us out?
Make sure he gets to the hospital.
Get it together!
You're a nurse!
OK, let's go.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Where does it hurt?
Stretcher coming in.
Take care.
What happened!?
Ayakuza den...
Yazuka!?
The police will have questions.
No, um, I...
What the hell...
Hey!
Are you OK?
No, I'm not a...
I hit a yakuza's car and I...
I was there by chance.
I swear.
Hey!
What are you doing?
Is that your money?
It's yakuza money.
He said it was under the table.
What are you doing!?
It's nobody's now.
Nobody's?
Ouch.
Are you OK? Lie down.
Put your legs here.
Broken left finger,
lacerated right leg. No burns.
You're OK?
Are you OK? We heard
there was a terrible accident.
Oh, yeah. I'm fine.
Your glasses broke.
An organized crime ring?
How scary. Gang war?
- Just a gas leak that blew up.
- Just as well.
They'll leave us alone.
Hey, weren't you
going to the store?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I forgot...
That's OK. Emergency said
you were carrying something.
I'm sorry.
Nothing from the store.
Forget it. We're taking off,
aren't you?
Yes I am.
Is something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
Shizuko! Shall we get someone?
I said, I'm fine!
Excuse me!
I have to change too.
See you later.
Bye bye.
What's up?
Just checking on the patient.
He's fine. A simple fracture
and four stitches.
Say, you've skinned your knee.
Here, do it yourself.
There you are.
Both of you, actually. The police
want to ask you some questions.
"Suddenly, the ambulance
had an accident."
"We were thrown by the impact as
the ambulance hit a vehicle"
"parked in the left lane."
"Shortly thereafter, from the
riverbank 30 yards away,"
"we watched the ambulance
sink into the Maruko river."
"At 9:43..."
Can I get you something?
I'm sick of coffee...
an iced cocoa.
No such thing.
Yes there is.
No way.
You're right.
"So... at 9:43
the police car arrived..."
"and took us to
the General Hospital."
Is that statement accurate?
Yes.
We may question you again
after we recover the ambulance.
The ambulance is still there?
It'll take some time.
The current's pretty strong.
But it's hard to fathom
an accident on that clear road.
Um...
You say the gangster was
unconscious throughout?
Yes.
Yes, he was.
Are you sure?
Well, everything happened so quickly...
I'm not really sure...
I understand. I'm sorry.
Sign this please.
Thanks for your help.
It's already lunch time.
Sorry we kept you so long.
- Excuse me...
- Yes?
Did any of the gang survive?
No one.
You think we're OK?
We're fine. As long as we
don't mess up.
Where is it?
In my locker.
I guess we should
move it somewhere...
You have a place?
I share a room in the dormitory.
So, my place OK?
It's tiny, but...
Um... sure.
Excuse us.
Yes!?
Any lunch recommendations?
What? Oh...
Try the daily special.
Oh, thanks.
Daily special huh?
I'll stick to noodles.
Can you lock it?
C'mon in.
215.
Million and...
320,000 yen.
Split it?
What?
Sure.
If we split it...
107 million, 660,000 yen.
Maybe we shouldn't
see each other again...
Try to act like nothing's changed.
Oh well.
I guess you're right.
Do you have a bag or something?
Yeah, wait a second.
Here.
I'll give it back later?
You can keep it.
Oh, OK.
Well, I...
Um, say...
What?
Aren't you hungry?
How about a bowl of noodles?
Sure.
Wait a minute, OK.
All this money and we eat noodles.
We should've gone out.
Nothing's open...
Sleep over somewhere?
Nothing like that.
What then? A guy, right?
No.
What is that?
A little unusual, no?
It's nothing...
Another emergency patient.
Shall we run?
Forget it. What a pain.
Oh!
You know him?
Boss... there was this huge
disaster at their office,
and I can't work for a while.
I'm quitting.
I mean, my hand's fractured,
I was the one driving, so I guess...
Um, I'm just not right for the job.
I'm just not right for it.
Hello... Suzuki speaking.
Oh! It's me.
Thanks for yesterday.
Sorry to call you back.
This won't take long.
Are you sure this is him?
Yes.
I'm positive.
He's in bad shape. We'll
question him when he recovers.
And that'll be that.
But if he hurt you, you
should sue him.
Say it wasn't the accident
that caused your injuries...
If he inflicted them intentionally.
No... nothing...
I see...
In that case, fine.
Should we turn in the
money to the police?
Let's run away!
Some place far!
Run away...
But what about that guy...
It'll take him awhile to recover.
We can get away.
Excuse me. Your car's in the way.
Move it please.
What happened?
And you are?
It's our office.
I see. There was a gas explosion.
It's off limits now.
Explosion?
Yes.
What exploded?
No idea.
Why'd it explode?
They took the wounded
to the nearby hospital.
All burnt up!
- All burnt up!
- All bummed out!
Wanna fight?
Wanna fight!
Excuse us.
How are you?
They only showed this room.
The others...
All dead?
The really croaked?
Sorry, it's only a light.
Something to write with!
Use this.
Paper, paper!
"GET THE MONEY BACK"
And Suzuki... who?
How do you pronounce it?
Satoru.
Who's that?
Get the money back?
What are you doing here?
You can't be here.
He's not allowed
visitors yet, get out.
Be quiet... I'm closing it.
I'll get away with it...
With what?
Tossing the leftovers...
Who gives a shit.
Awesome! I can quit the gang.
There's nothing left to quit.
That asshole beat me up.
Shut up, he'll hear you.
Stop that!
Just copping a feel. Bitch!
I'll call security!
Mind your own fucking business!
So sorry to bother you!
"Suzuki Satoru"
I'm not home right now.
Please call back.
I'm taking a break!
What? I see.
Gee, I'm really sorry.
But hey, it wasn't so bad.
Friend of mine hit a Mercedes.
Got soaked for 2 million.
Um...
I still want out.
How you gonna make it
with no job?
I received some damages.
I'll be fine.
I don't know how much
you got, but it won't last.
Life is tougher than you think.
But...
Hey, Suzuki. Sounds like
you had a hell of a time.
Yeah, well...
You OK?
Did he threaten to come here?
No...
Is that really broken?
Did he break it?
Um...
Something wrong?
No, he's fine, just fine, right?
He's just babbling
about wanting to quit.
I've made up my mind.
You just keep repeating yourself.
I paid for the car repairs.
Be a little grateful.
What's this?
The cost of the repairs.
If that's not enough I'll bring more.
Don't you sass me, Suzuki.
Try hitting me
if you really want to quit.
See, bet you can't.
Hit me back, hey. Hit me.
This kid's hopeless.
Huh?
Hey, you know...
the Harumi apartments?
Harumi...
This is the address.
Well, you see, um...
Turn right there, and...
Why don't you just take us...
I'm in a rush, sorry...
Oh, please!
- Sorry.
- Oh, please!
That's enough godammit!
Oh, c'mon, come with us.
Where is it?
Um, the right...
That right?
Oops? Oh, I'm sorry.
I don't know where I am.
I think I'm lost.
You're useless.
I'm sorry.
Forget it.
Oh, excuse us.
Where are we?
Harumi Apartments. Turn right up
there and you'll see them.
Wrong way.
We were right.
I'm sorry.
We're there.
Got it, got it!
- What!?
- Shhhh!
What?
Jump down from there.
Why?
Yakuza!
See, it was right here,
that dumb nurse.
Dumb nurse.
Hello... hey, it's open.
No way he's here.
Took off, huh.
Excuse us...
Layout's like mine.
Want a drink?
Any beer?
Guys, we should get that
money back and keep it.
We earned it, man.
We gotta give it back, man.
Back to who?
The asshole Kuroiwa?
Forget it, man.
But it's Kuroiwa.
I'm not scared of him anymore.
Look at the shape he's in.
You don't know him, man.
He's a monster.
Tell me what's so scary?
You won't be able to
take a piss at night.
I don't piss at night.
Just tell us.
Fine. You know that gut Nanba?
That pachinko parlor owner who...
Run!
Wow!
Hey man... the money!
Hold it down, man!
Chill, man.
Little bitch!
Where the fuck!
Goddammit!
I'm over here!
Run!
"He gave me a ride, and we
drove through the summer night"
"He gave me a ride and I came
to a town at the end of the line"
Where are we going?
No idea, man.
To the beach!
What beach?
We're surrounded by fields!
To the mountains!
Which is it?
Hot springs!
- Oh oh!
- What's the dif, man.
We're never gonna find them.
I know this one.
Excellent tune.
Golden Oldies. Not cool.
- No Rock?
- Cut it out. It's a great tune.
"The cool morning sea..."
"reflected like a mirror"
- You sing too!
- No way man.
- I said, sing!
- No way.
It's cool, man.
No it's not!
"To keep the sadness at bay..."
What happened!
What did he do?
He told me I have
three holes in my nose.
Hey, what's going on?
I'm sorry, but I can't handle
that patient anymore.
I'm sorry but
he's too much for us.
Fine, go back then.
I'm sorry.
How are you?
I get grandma, huh.
If you're well enough
to insult me, we don't need this.
Gimmie a cigarette!
There's no smoking.
You'll have smoke coming
out of all your stitches.
What are you up to now.
Get this fucking stuff off of me.
I will not. These machines are
what's keeping you alive.
Get me the fuck outta here!
Who cares about my life!
Out of the question!
We're working hard
to save that life.
Don't forget, you're not living,
we're keeping you alive!
Oh, all right.
Excuse me for screaming.
Are you passing?
What?
Shit, I mean.
Forget it.
Are you embarrassed?
Ridiculous!
Let's move you
over and check.
Who cares what
this grandma, sees, right?
I'll be your host 'til 6 o'clock, with
Brand New Day, Brand New Song,
An afternoon of music
and conversation...
It doesn't feel real.
We did it!
We really did it!
I just can't believe it.
I can't believe I really did it.
Hey, stop it...
Yes, hello.
Hi, it's me.
Where are you?
Head nurse is furious.
It's Shizuko.
I've decided to quit.
Are you serious!
You really quit?
Yeah.
So I'm not coming
back anymore.
Something happened?
What? No.
Are you with someone?
Yeah.
Who is it?
That car rental guy?
Yeah...
I got it!
You're getting married!
What!?
Um... yeah.
Go girl!
I'll tell the head nurse for you.
It's the first time in my
whole life I ever felt this way.
I know. I know how you feel.
You do? You really do?
Got any real food here?
Aren't we perky.
Yes.
May I help you?
Um... do you have a room?
Double or single?
Is there a suite?
A suite?
We do have a suite
but the cost may be...
We'll take it.
But...
What is it? Money, we've got.
You want cash up front?
How much.
I'm terribly sorry.
Can you sign here please?
Signature?
We're married...
"Mr. And Mrs. John Doe"
A marble bathroom!
Hey, look...
What is it?
And tell your father
you got married.
OK, I will.
Where are you?
A suite in the Art Land Hotel.
We'll call again, OK?
OK.
Are you listening?
I found a safe.
I'm fine.
I'll hold onto mine.
Why?
Why? Don't you
want to spend it?
Sure, but...
Are you sure?
You can't trust that safe.
The staff can open it.
It's a combination lock.
I just press those numbers?
Yeah.
Then I'll steal your money.
No you won't.
So you trust me?
You sure... about me?
Let's get room service.
Oh, let's go out on the town.
Come in.
Welcome. How can
I help you?
Um... Um...
An engagement ring?
What size?
Size?
One size fits all?
Say, where are you going?
So?
Um...
You were really pretty.
Is that a compliment?
No, no.
- No?
- No, I mean, um...
Step a little closer to the bride.
OK.
Look happy.
"We got Married - We're so Happy"
They'll look like this.
Great. When will they be ready?
Today.
Can you deliver them
to the Art Land Hotel?
- I will.
- Thank you.
Why the cards?
Don't worry.
Can you believe I've
never been on an airplane?
The head nurse and I were
the only ones who hadn't.
I've never either.
Yes sir!
Hawaii, here I come!
Hawaii...
I want to go.
Mail the cards from there.
Oh...
Oh! Say, are you OK?
Shall we go back to the hotel.
How crude...
So that's your motive.
Get me drunk and...
Motive... what motive?
That's what I'm asking.
There's no motive.
So, where shall we sleep?
I knew it. You wanted
to sleep together.
What do you mean "I knew it."
You started this.
I did no such thing.
You brought it up.
Bathroom break.
Excuse me! Another bottle!
Your most expensive wine!
Um... this is...
I want to...
May I sit down?
I'm Shimada.
I run a little hotel here.
I see.
You're not from
around here are you?
We're traveling.
You're so beautiful,
I couldn't help noticing.
I was working in
a hotel in the city...
I see.
But France seems to
suit me better.
So I'll soon quit.
Oh, this is Shimada san.
He used to be a sommelier.
He knows everything about wine.
Hello.
Are you her brother?
The Romanee Conti 1978
complements the food beautifully.
Oh, really?
I get it. Thanks.
Thank you kindly.
Well, excuse me then.
Why were you so rude?
He thought I was your brother!
So what! The married thing's
just a cover.
I'm not your property, so there!
For me?
What are you doing
you idiot!
You're unbelievable!
Excuse me, nurse.
Yes?
What is it?
That guy Suzuki from my ambulance.
Has he left?
Oh, he married one of our nurses.
They're away on a trip.
Married! To that nurse, Shizuko?
That's right. She was in
the ambulance, too.
Where'd they go?
That I don't know.
I see.
Is that all?
Hey! You got a cell phone?
Cell phones aren't allowed.
Bring me the pay phone.
That's a little...
These machines that sensitive?
No, actually the sensitive?
Stuff is in the other wing,
but they can't be bothered with
making certain areas on or off limits,
so they're not allowed anywhere.
Just ten minutes?
I'll pay you later. Please?
I'll go get mine
from my locker.
Please don't tell head nurse.
She'll scold me.
"SATO Shizuko"
Hello. Nurses' dormitory.
Oh, hi. This is the
delivery service.
Is Sato Shizuko in?
Oh, that's too bad.
She asked us to forward
a package to her parents' house.
But the address is illegible.
Do you have their address
and phone number?
Hello. Is this the Sato residence?
Your daughter took care of me.
Yes, congratulations.
I'd like to send her
a wedding present.
I thought you might know where she is.
That idiot!
What are you doing?
Shimada san!
Hey!
Goddammit!
Give it back.
I said, give it,
back.
What's going on back here?
Are you OK sir?
He tried to steal this.
No, that's wrong.
Sit down, you're drunk.
Wait a minute.
What the...
Excuse me.
I'm getting off here.
What's wrong?
- Are you OK?
- An ambulance...
I'll go call one.
Hey! Give me back my bag!
What are you doing?
You can't walk around.
I have something to take care of.
You can't just walk out of here!
Just one day?
I promise I'll come back.
I said no. You can't go
anywhere in such shape.
If you let me go, one day,
just one day, I'll pay you...
A million.
You're really trying
to bribe a nurse?
OK, two million.
For three I'd think about it...
OK. Three million.
If the hospital
finds out, I'm fired.
I'll take care of you.
You can barely
take care of yourself.
That'll change.
Excuse me.
Really tasty.
Amazing.
Delicious.
You marinate the pork?
You must, it's so good.
And the eggs are
just the right touch.
Special eggs?
Regular eggs.
And the soup is divine.
I drank mine all up.
What's in the stock?
Pig's feet.
How dare you!
Feed us pig's feet!
You expect to be paid for that!
That's ridiculous!
What the fuck!
What do we owe?
About 2,000 each?
I only have small change...
Hey!
A security camera recorded,
these images of a woman who
chased a bus three miles...
after her bag was snatched.
She caught the suspect,
when he collapsed
in cardiac arrest.
She saved his life by
performing CPR.
She turned out to be a nurse.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Can I go now?
Oh, yes, thank you.
No?
What?
No reward?
Sorry we don't do that.
Fine, I'll go then.
But tell him he shouldn't
be drunk on the bus.
Next time, don't take
matters into your own hands.
Call the police first, OK?
Good evening.
Do you have a reservation?
No.
I'm staying in the Suite.
Oh, excuse me!
Welcome back.
You have a message.
"Congratulations!
- Mom and Dad"
There's also a package
for you.
Front Desk speaking.
She just came in.
Shall I put you through?
There's a call for you.
Hello.
Idiot...
Never thought
I'd travel at this hour.
Once in a while,
this sort of place is nice.
Can you get me a coffee?
Oh, sure.
Sort of like the morning after.
Wait here a minute.
Bastard!
"We Got Married"
Where's the nurse
who was on the news?
What?
We're friends of the
purse snatcher catcher.
Here for the ceremony?
Ceremony?
What ceremony?
Hey, you guys
Suzuki's friends?
"Good bye"
Surprise!
In here.
Hey man!
Been lookin' for you, man.
Didn't recognize you.
The money?
He... took all the
money and split.
Liar.
Open it.
I don't know how.
Don't fuck with me!
Fine. I'll just wait
for him to come back.
Answer it.
And no funny business.
Talk.
Yes, hello.
Police, ma'am.
We're in the lobby.
Oh. I'll be right down.
We'll wait here.
Oh, yes.
What's going on?
Last night I caught a thief.
I'm being commended.
What the hell... are you serious?
I'll be waiting here.
So we finally meet, Suzuki.
We'd almost given up.
So,
where's the money?
Don't know.
The girl's got it, right?
She nabbed a purse snatcher.
It was on TV.
What?
Cut it out!
What have we here?
- Give it back!
- An engagement ring.
Give it back!
Wait! She's here.
You keep watch.
Please have a seat.
We've got your guy...
We'll swap the guy for the money.
After your purse was
snatched, you chased and...
caught the suspect.
We hereby commend you and
express our gratitude.
Sleepin' on the job, you jerk!
What's the combination?
I'll help you.
Untie me first.
You got that wrong.
I saw the girl at the hotel.
I know the score.
0774436.
That better be right.
The pinhead can't
even keep watch.
Say, I'll give you
the money if you help me.
Help you?
That guy's here.
That guy...
who was hospitalized
after the explosion.
- Kuroiwa...
- Oh my God!
You can have all the money
if you help me.
Who needs a seat belt.
Shut up, man.
My foot hurts!
Turn the AC up.
Hey, move over.
Hey!
What the fuck!
You asshole!
I don't see Kuroiwa!
How do you open this?
You punch in the numbers,
but it won't work.
Just bring the damn thing.
The whole safe?
No way, man.
There's enough of us.
We'll torch it open later.
You come too.
Why? You have the money.
Let's move it,
Suzuki might come
back for the money.
Out the back.
Look, the minivan.
You promised. Open the safe.
What's going on!
I don't care about the money.
The number, goddammit!
Go on. Open it.
You knew after all.
Go for it!
Those guys...
The money was the problem.
I wish it had burned
in the explosion.
No, no, you're wrong.
You OK?
I am not OK.
Your visit's been
quite a disaster.
We'll be going now.
Let us know if we can
be of further assistance.
Excuse us.
It was kind of... like a dream.
I don't know how
to tell you this.
What?
Come with me.
Sorry.
"We Need Help"
Where to?
Anywhere at all.