♪ ♪
♪ it's cold
♪ a plain
diamond ♪
Diamond ♪
♪ nobody's here,
just empty space ♪
Just empty space ♪
oh, Sylvia.
Oh, Sylvia.
♪ it's all moving,
breathing ♪
Breathing ♪
♪ stuck to the ceiling
this is suicidal plagiarism.
♪ And what we had
don't mean a thing ♪
Don't mean a thing ♪
♪ oh
♪ oh-oh-oh-oh
♪ oh-oh
♪ oh
♪ oh-oh-oh-oh
♪ oh-oh
♪ oh
♪ oh-oh-oh-oh
♪ oh-oh
♪ oh
♪ oh-oh-oh
oblivion receding,
the abyss opening,
the screaming dirt of chaos
blinding.
Blinding.
Strong meter, Amy.
Strong words.
Thank you.
Mazel tov.
Josh?
You're up next.
Good.
I love your words.
This is "emerald ambrosia:
An ode to absinthe."
Picture it with no punctuation,
picture it with no punctuation,
because there is none.
On campus.
Your turn.
Oh.
[ Both chuckle ]
Whoa!
Yep.
Just...Okay, yank it.
Are you still a virgin?
No, no, I'm not, actually.
It's beautiful.
Your poetry is really beautiful.
I feel like I can see inside of
you.
You.
[ Chuckles ]
I want to
be inside of you.
Be inside of you.
Here?E of you.
Mm-hmm.
[ Rattling ]
What was that?
Nothing.
Wait, wait, wait.
Just relax. Just relax.
[ Laughs ]
What are you doing?!
Easy, easy!
Come on! It's art!
Stop! Whoa whoa!
Amy...
Your dirt metaphor's a cliché,
and your poetry sucks!
[ Siren wails in distance ]
[ Playing fight song ]
I hate that song.
Me too.
[ Sighs ]
By the way, what a
by the way, what a
misogynistic pig.
Misogynistic pig.
You should have castrated that
you should have castrated that
guy.
Guy.
[ Scoffs ]
I don't even care anymore,
you know?
You know?
I'm resilient.
I'd like to share something with
you.
"Amnesiac magazine grins,
feeding from the mall,
polyblend combustion burning
on the escalator to nowhere."
On the escalator to nowhere."
Oh, my God, I think I just
oh, my God, I think I just
got my period.
So haunting, so ahead of its
time -- it's practically
ancient.
Ancient.
1989.
Shit.
Soon, we'll be free of this
hellhole.
[ Rock music plays ]
♪ ...In a golden cage
as the days died early,
she longed escape from her cage.
She longed escape from her cage.
♪ ...In the rain
♪ ...in the rain
♪ white bird
in a golden cage ♪
In a golden cage ♪
thanks, mom!
Here, honey.
These were on the printers.
You have a lot of submissions.
There's a small reading fee
there's a small reading fee
for a few of the reviews.
For a few of the reviews.
Small? How small?
Well, um, a lot of the
well, um, a lot of the
reviews have prizes.
Reviews have prizes.
Like, the finger lakes' prize
like, the finger lakes' prize
is $1,000, and I'm a shoo-in.
Is $1,000, and I'm a shoo-in.
You're only eligible if you're
you're only eligible if you're
an unpublished, female poet
under the age of 25 from upstate
New York.
So...Hello.
Hello!
Hello.
Dad, can I get some stamp
money?
Money?
Amy, you know we believe in
your talent, and we know how
special you really are, but, um,
we can't afford to subsidize
your poetry career.
Your poetry career.
Okay, I know it seems like
okay, I know it seems like
I'm not really doing anything
right now, but I am writing
nonstop, all the time.
Nonstop, all the time.
Things are pouring out of me you
things are pouring out of me you
wouldn't even believe.
Wouldn't even believe.
I could have a volume of poetry
in a week.
In a week.
I mean, I'm feeling a lot.
I'm thinking a lot.
I'm...I'm inspired, dad.
I'm inspired!
Sweetie, you've got $90,000
sweetie, you've got $90,000
in student loans, and you've
already spent a couple of
thousand on these submissions.
Thousand on these submissions.
So, we can give you an extension
so, we can give you an extension
for another week, but, after
that, no more.
That, no more.
We just have to cut the
we just have to cut the
umbilical cord.
Umbilical cord.
So...
Let's see what happens with
those.
And here's some stamp money...
[ Birds chirping ]
Just until you win the pulitzer.
I love you.
Thanks, dad.
I will suffer through this!
Yes.
Twice a week would be
wonderful.
Wonderful.
I could pay you $4.25 an hour.
It was a sign...
Literally and figuratively.
[ Car beeping ]
Hi, hon.
Need some help?
No, I-I...I didn't mean to
no, I-I...I didn't mean to
come in.
Come in.
You come about the job?
No! No, no, no, no.
Not at...
Sorry.
It won't bite you.
Oh!
[ Laughs nervously ]
[ Door slams ]
[ Car beeping ]
Ew!
[ Panting ]
[ Engine turns over ]
Nope. Sorry.
We're not hiring.
I could be a real asset here.
I know everything there is to
know about poetry.
Know about poetry.
Rat billings is doing a signing
rat billings is doing a signing
here at this bookstore?
Here at this bookstore?
Yeah, you like him?
Like?!
"The squalor of splendor" is one
"the squalor of splendor" is one
of my favorite poems ever
written.
Written.
He was 18 when he did that.
It's the best thing he ever did.
He's a good training-wheels
he's a good training-wheels
poet if you're not ready for the
great ones yet.
Great ones yet.
Rat billings is the great.
Salinger worked in a
meat-processing plant.
Meat-processing plant.
Stanley, this nice, young
woman has come in about the job.
Woman has come in about the job.
My friends know where I am!
Sorry.
C-come on.
Go on. Don't be afraid.
Got any experience working
retail?
Retail?
Actually, no.
Oh.
Are you at all familiar with our
are you at all familiar with our
inventory?
Inventory?
More or less.
Tell her about our insurance.
Insurance?
Does this mean I got the job?
We try to take care of our
people, so we provide some basic
health coverage.
Health coverage.
Thank you.
[ Both laugh ]
My darling.
Pretty much a mom-and-pop
operation.
Operation.
Mary Anne likes to do the
ordering.
Ordering.
I know the merchandise
better.
Better.
I had a question.
When do I --
when do I --
you get paid on Fridays,
every two weeks.
Every two weeks.
Great.
Hi. I'm Alex.
I'm the manager.
Amy.
Nice to meet you.
And I'm Rick.
Hi.
Rick.
We talked about this.
Rick doesn't work here.
And you should probably wash
and you should probably wash
your hand.
Your hand.
I'm just kidding.
Okay.
[ Dog barks in distance ]
I got a job.
That's great!
What?
See, Todd?
Oh, that's wonderful.
Welcome to the adult world.
[ Coughs ]
So, aren't you gonna tell us
so, aren't you gonna tell us
what it is?
What it is?
What are you doing?
It's kind of an underground
it's kind of an underground
art magazine type of thing.
Art magazine type of thing.
I don't like you working
downtown after dark.
Downtown after dark.
That's racist.
[ Barking continues ]
I just want to take a minute
to explain our filing system
here, called "sparfs."
Here, called "sparfs."
It's sexual preference, age,
it's sexual preference, age,
race, fetish, size -- kind of
like the Dewey decimal system
for erotica.
For erotica.
[ Chuckles ]
Anyway, this one right here,
they're old, they're black, and
they're gay.
They're gay.
But they wouldn't go in the
but they wouldn't go in the
"old" section.
"Old" section.
They'd go in the gay area,
they'd go in the gay area,
'cause they're gay.
That's the sexual preference.
[ Softly ] Oh, my God.
And then...
You know, and then it'd go in
the "old" section and then the
"black" section, the "black"
subsection of the "gay, old"
section.
Section.
Anyway, like any great rule of
anyway, like any great rule of
thumb, there are a few
exception to sparfs.
Exception to sparfs.
A green dot...
Who puts on the dots?
No one knows.
It's a mystery.
[ Laughs ]
It's really easy to remember.
Sexual preference, age...
Race, fetish...
...Race, fetish...
...race, fetish...
...Size.
...size.
I memorize it just, like, by
the rap.
The rap.
♪ sexual preference
♪ age, race, fetish, size
it's pretty easy to remember
that way, if you do that.
That way, if you do that.
I'm doing it in my head.
I don't want to do it out loud.
When this gentleman wants to
when this gentleman wants to
check out a video, you get his
card.
Card.
That's got membership info,
that's got membership info,
notes written by employees.
Notes written by employees.
What are sticky video
what are sticky video
returns?
Returns?
[ Snorts ]
What?
Really? Okay.
When that happens, we give him a
when that happens, we give him a
copy of our customer policies.
Copy of our customer policies.
There you go.
Reread that. Thank you.
Here you go.
Bye.
Happy first day.
Thanks.
Have fun with your esoteric
have fun with your esoteric
reading.
Reading.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah!
Bye!
Drive safe!
Thanks!
Hi.
Wow. It's an old one.
Got to be 20 years old.
Thank you.
All right, who's next?
Hello.
Hi.
Uh...What's your name?
If you don't want to have
if you don't want to have
your book signed, can you just
step out of the way, so that
people --
yeah, I'm sorry.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry!
I got it. I got it.
I got it.
No, I got it.
No, just -- let me just do
no, just -- let me just do
this.
This.
[ Door jingles ]
It's fine.
Excuse me, Mr. billings?!
Hi!
I am an enormous fan, like,
crazy-big fan of yours!
Crazy-big fan of yours!
Thank you.
It's so nice to meet you.
We met inside.
I mean...You remember!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just wanted to say ignore
the reviews.
The reviews.
Your new book is tremendous.
The New York times really has no
the New York times really has no
taste anymore.
Taste anymore.
I know.
It's kind of a badge of honor,
it's kind of a badge of honor,
really.
Really.
I just love your work.
I just want to smash your head
open and take everything in
there!
There!
That's...Lovely.
It really speaks to me.
What does it say?
It says, "wake up.
Break free from the chrysalis
break free from the chrysalis
of middle-class ennui that's
imprisoning you."
Imprisoning you."
You're paraphrasing, of
you're paraphrasing, of
course, huh?
Course, huh?
Yeah.
Well, I can't believe we're
well, I can't believe we're
bantering like this.
Bantering like this.
This is so cool!
Life is surreal, kid.
Your work -- the first time I
your work -- the first time I
read it, I remember it so
clearly evolved me.
Clearly evolved me.
[ Engine turns over ]
What did it evolve you into?
An artiste.
Try not to use the pupa
try not to use the pupa
metaphor again, for the record.
Metaphor again, for the record.
Um, you know, I thought maybe
um, you know, I thought maybe
we could get together sometime.
We could get together sometime.
You can give me some advice or
you can give me some advice or
let me know how you got started.
Let me know how you got started.
It's in the books.
Well, maybe we can get a
well, maybe we can get a
coffee.
Coffee.
You know, I stopped drinking
you know, I stopped drinking
coffee 'cause my adrenal glands
are totally shot.
Are totally shot.
Maybe we can just talk poet
maybe we can just talk poet
to poet.
To poet.
Perhaps.
You're an inspiration.
You, my dear, are an
you, my dear, are an
apparition.
Apparition.
Au revoir.
[ Panting ]
Au revoir, rat billings.
[ Glass shatters ]
[ Engine turns over ]
Hey, hey!
[ Tires screech ]
That is not your -- come back
that is not your -- come back
here!
Here!
Hey!
Shit!
Shit, shit, shit, mother, shit!
[ Sighs ]
♪ He knows your name, boy
♪ I'll write it down
♪ under Bridges, into town
♪ and watch it rusting,
your father's crown ♪
Your father's crown ♪
♪ and your mother...
♪ And your mother...
Would you like personal
would you like personal
lubricant or a key chain to go
with your sexist videos?
That's very charming.
You sure you're old enough to
you sure you're old enough to
work here?
Work here?
Yeah, I'm an adult.
I swear.
[ Knocks on counter ]
See you, Mary Anne.
Bye, Roy.
Later.
Policemen shop here?
Sure, same as everybody else.
Well, yeah, but they're
well, yeah, but they're
policemen.
Policemen.
So?
We're not doing anything
we're not doing anything
illegal.
Illegal.
Yeah, but he's a person of
yeah, but he's a person of
authority participating in the
subjugation of women.
His wife was in a skydiving
accident.
Accident.
She plummeted 10,000 feet, and
she plummeted 10,000 feet, and
her chute didn't open.
Been in a coma for two years.
He rents porn to stay faithful
he rents porn to stay faithful
to her until Jesus takes her.
[ Laughs ]
I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
Oh, okay.
A lot of people like the
a lot of people like the
old-school feel of browsing the
real shelves.
Real shelves.
Plus, we have a ton of vintage
plus, we have a ton of vintage
stuff you can't find online.
And the sex toys -- sometimes
people don't want to wait.
People don't want to wait.
Or have their mom open a fedex
or have their mom open a fedex
box with their fleshlight in it.
Box with their fleshlight in it.
Oh.
Who's on bathroom duty?
Not I!
Not I.
I am.
Oh.
All right.
The brush is under the sink.
[ Door opens, closes ]
[ Urinal flushes ]
Oh, my God, there was --
anybody ever tell you it's
rude to stare?
Rude to stare?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't -- I wasn't staring.
I was, but I didn't mean to.
So inappropriate.
Hey! Be cool.
Amy's all right.
Amy, rubia.
Rubia, Amy.
Hi.
So, your shift's over.
Do either of you guys know
do either of you guys know
which bus goes to dewittshire?
Which bus goes to dewittshire?
Oh, perfect.
Of course that's where you're
of course that's where you're
from.
From.
Why are you taking the bus?
My car was stolen.
Shit. Are you okay?
Pretty sure I'm traumatized.
Man, I'm sorry.
I think the 5:15 goes that
route.
Route.
The 5:15 what?
[ Laughs ]
It's the bus route.
Oh.
Rubia, you go that way,
right?
Right?
She can show you.
Oh, that'd be great.
Really?
[ No audio ]
I'm gonna rip your nuts off.
You know that?
Give me my battery, please.
What is this?
It's a battery.
From where?
A Cadillac.
You, like, paying your way
through beauty school?
What?
Why you work at a porn store
why you work at a porn store
downtown?
Downtown?
Oh, um, I'm a poet.
Get out? Seriously?
I'm probably gonna get
published pretty soon.
Writing shit about new snow
for the rich is not art.
It's like my favorite haiku.
That's cool.
I get my battery, please?
Yeah.
[ Grunts ]
Gracias.
This is where you live?
Yeah, it's that glam building
yeah, it's that glam building
down the alley, number 666 --
El diablo!
Back door, Becky!
Good night!
Hey, you forgot something!
Powder.
Good night.
Riding the bus is like being in
mogadishu.
Um, I've been on the phone
all day, and apparently someone
canceled the theft policy on
your car.
Well, that is bizarre.
I said, "that's a mistake,"
and then they sent me the signed
letter of cancellation, and it's
a poem.
That is a series of couplets.
Is that the mail?
The new yorker!
Please, please.
Rejected.
Amy, do you know how
difficult this year has been?
Difficult this year has been?
Why do we keep getting
why do we keep getting
student-loan bills that are past
due?
Due?
Why did you cancel the insurance
why did you cancel the insurance
on your car?
On your car?
I don't have enough money
for car insurance!
For car insurance!
We give you money for your
we give you money for your
insurance, and you spend it all
on literary contests!
On literary contests!
It's an investment in my
it's an investment in my
future.
Future.
Stop being such a child.
Everyone needs to stop
everyone needs to stop
calling me a child!
Calling me a child!
You are a child.
♪ When you were small
and crawled out the river,
we thought you were an animal ♪
We thought you were an animal ♪
♪ then you were ten
♪ your parents house,
it felt
like a thousand years ago ♪
♪ LA LA-LA-LA-LA-LA
♪ and waters fall
and living underwater ♪
And living underwater ♪
♪ at the bottom
of a great black sea ♪
Of a great black sea ♪
♪ silent and floating,
there with my brothers ♪
There with my brothers ♪
♪ now it don't mean much to me
♪ LA...
All right.
This is my last stop.
Okay, um...
You think you could drop me off
you think you could drop me off
where you dropped off my friend,
you know, the guy -- the girl.
You know, the guy -- the girl.
Rubia?
Yeah, that would be great.
♪ in the radio's hot sun
♪ we felt its light
right behind our eyes ♪
Rubia?
Ms. rubia?
It's me, Amy.
Remember?
Hello?
[ Sighs ]
My parents kicked me out.
So, why'd you come here?
I don't know any other bus
routes.
Routes.
Jesus Christ.
Come in.
Thank you.
[ Up-tempo Latin music plays ]
You're not sleeping on my
bed.
Bed.
That's -- that's fine.
Mm-hmm.
I'll stay out of your hair.
I promise.
What is that?
It's crack.
Oh, cool.
[ Laughing ] I'm just
[ laughing ] I'm just
kidding.
Kidding.
It's medical marijuana.
It's for my tmj.
Oh.
I don't do drugs.
You a poet?
Take a hit.
You need to chill out.
Come on, suburbia.
[ Coughing ]
You're pretty.
I'm a diva.
Out of my way, please.
Sorry.
Say something.
You look like a cheap hooker.
Oh, my God.
I didn't mean to call you a
whore.
Whore.
I mean, a hooker.
I...
You're not either.
Shit, I do look like a
hooker.
Hooker.
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I said that
stuff.
Stuff.
I think the drugs are talking.
Don't get cray.
At least I can trust you to be
honest.
My teeth feel so big in my
mouth right now.
Mouth right now.
It's just pot, okay?
It's not acid.
Don't your teeth feel huge?
Ginormous.
And sharp -- they're really
and sharp -- they're really
sharp.
Sharp.
You need to get them sanded
you need to get them sanded
down.
Down.
Teeth, teeth, teeth, teeth.
♪ took a long time
to dig it ♪
To dig it ♪
♪ but I found out
you don't really dig me ♪
You don't really dig me ♪
♪ mm-mm-mm
[ Laughs ]
So, get your heels
so, get your heels
a-clicking!
A-clicking!
[ Laughs ]
♪ baby, your light is out
♪ oh, baby, your light is out
[ chanting ] We are the 99%!
We are the 99%!
Candace!
Oh!
Oh, my God, you got my message!
How are you?
I'm so glad you came.
You look great.
Oh, my God.
Hey, Pablo, can you help her up?
Please come up.
I'm getting up.
One, two, three!
Oh, my God.
How are you? Oh, my God.
It's so good to see you.
I'm so glad you're here.
How are you?
I'm so good. I'm so good.
After, like, Cuba and Darfur, I
after, like, Cuba and Darfur, I
just realized that this is where
I needed to be, you know what I
mean?
Mean?
In our own decaying country
in our own decaying country
instead of everywhere else.
Instead of everywhere else.
Right!
Well, great.
I'm so happy for you.
Oh, my God. Sorry.
Pablo?
Pablo, this is Amy.
Oh, hi.
Pablo and I met hiking across
Ecuador.
We met at the airport.
No, we didn't.
We met in Ecuador, with the
we met in Ecuador, with the
organic chicken farm.
Organic chicken farm.
Remember?
We met at the airport.
No. He's so crazy.
All right, I'm gonna go.
I have to go.
I have to go to work.
No, no, stop.
Come on. Join the movement.
Maybe next time.
No, we need you.
It seems awesome, so, um,
it seems awesome, so, um,
maybe next time.
Maybe next time.
But I'll see you this weekend.
Let's get together.
Love you.
Good to see you.
Nice to meet you, Pablo.
Hell, no, we won't go!
[ Vacuum humming ]
Um, I gave you a $100.
$75.75?
You're right.
I'm so sorry.
I wasn't thinking.
Don't worry about it.
Everyone makes a mistake
everyone makes a mistake
sometimes.
Sometimes.
There you go.
Thanks.
Enjoy!
Awesome.
[ Door opens, closes ]
You okay?
Every literary review in the
every literary review in the
country hates me.
Country hates me.
They don't hate you.
I promise.
Oh, they do. Look.
Rejection letters, all of them.
The new yorker, Harper's.
Even the Southern Tallahassee
even the Southern Tallahassee
poetry review hates me.
Poetry review hates me.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm running out of time.
Can't be a wunderkind past 22.
A lot of great writers
a lot of great writers
weren't even recognized till
after they died.
After they died.
I know.
I've been thinking about that a
lot lately.
What do you think of that?
I think it's horrific.
The previous model, which
the previous model, which
didn't even talk, sold like
hot cakes.
Hot cakes.
I'm really beginning to think
that everything in this world is
cheap and plastic.
Cheap and plastic.
Nah! These are high-quality.
It says so right on the box
it says so right on the box
there.
There.
"Voice activation is initiated
"voice activation is initiated
by penetrating one of the three
lifelike cavities."
Lifelike cavities."
[ Laughs ]
Do you want to do the honors?
I don't want to touch her.
No!
[ Rubber squeaking ]
Up and to the right, right?
Do you know?
I don't know.
I think that's what I heard.
Can you please stop doing
can you please stop doing
that?
That?
Ahh!
Oh, God!
[ Laughing ] Oh, my God!
Give it to me.
Oh, yeah.
Give it to me good.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Give it to me good.
It sounds like your dad.
Ew!
This is just so not how my life
was supposed to turn out.
I was supposed to do great
things.
Things.
I mean, I got good grades.
I won awards.
I stayed true to my art and
didn't let myself get distracted
by all that trivial stuff.
By all that trivial stuff.
Like what?
You know, like, guys and
stuff.
Stuff.
[ Siren wails in distance ]
Wait.
Never?
You a virgin?
You work at a porn store,
surrounded by dildos, and you're
a virgin?
I assure you, the irony isn't
lost to me.
Lost to me.
Well...
You need to find somebody to
help you along and teach you
shit, somebody with connections.
Shit, somebody with connections.
I had someone...
Miss rowanna Sykes.
She was a wonderful woman.
She taught me everything I know.
How to sing from my diaphragm,
how to sing from my diaphragm,
how to walk, how to love, how to
talk mahjong.
Talk mahjong.
[ Laughs ]
She passed away.
I'm sorry.
I still feel like an orphan.
Go to bed.
Wow! A blizzard!
I need a letter from a past
landlord.
Landlord.
It's such a crock!
Well, you should ask your dad
well, you should ask your dad
for a letter or something.
For a letter or something.
Yeah, right.
Maybe you can pretend to be my
maybe you can pretend to be my
mom or something.
Mom or something.
No, I could be your sister.
You know, I'm 19 on craigslist,
you know, I'm 19 on craigslist,
right?
Right?
[ Gasps ]
Oh, my God.
It's rat billings.
Who's that?
My favorite poet in the
my favorite poet in the
world.
World.
I'm obsessed with him!
Go talk to him.
What are you doing?
Why are you hiding?
Hey, bubby, how you doing?
How you doing, sugar mouth?
Ooh, brown-bagging it.
You're a thug!
You know, girl.
What are you doing?
Stop doing that!
No, no, no, no, no!
We just found you a mentor,
we just found you a mentor,
girl.
Oh, God, this is a bad idea.
Aah!
[ Up-tempo Latin music plays ]
So, who is this guy?
What's the story?
He's dark, and he's brooding.
You would think he was so sexy.
Seriously?
Seriously.
He kind of looked like
he kind of looked like
Dracula to me.
Well, that's kind of hot,
well, that's kind of hot,
though, don't you think?
Though, don't you think?
My thighs are gonna get real
my thighs are gonna get real
after this.
After this.
My God, hold on.
[ Gasps ]
Hold on!
Whoa!
Aah!
[ Sighs ]
Come on. Keep going.
I'm trying!
Oh, my God!
I'm just trying to help.
We're gonna lose him.
No, I got this.
We're not gonna lose him.
We're not gonna lose him, Amy.
We're not gonna lose you!
He's turning.
Here it is.
This is it.
Go!
Go! Just...I believe in you.
You can do it.
No, you're right.
Wait a second.
Let me clean you off.
Go.
Carpe diem!
Hi!
Excuse me.
Hi.
I'm Amy, the poet.
Oh, yeah.
From the other day?
Um...
I do. I remember that.
I was just in the
neighborhood, and I thought I
would stop by and say hi, and...
Would stop by and say hi, and...
How did you find out where I
how did you find out where I
live?
Live?
Well, you -- I saw you
well, you -- I saw you
driving.
Driving.
Oh.
Did leyner put you up to this?
Did mark -- is this...
Come on.
No.
What do you want?
Um...Okay.
I was wondering if maybe you
would be willing to read some of
my poetry.
My poetry.
You're a writer.
Yes, I am, and I --
yes, I am, and I --
oh.
Oh.
And I'm really good, and I
and I'm really good, and I
just...
Just...
Been writing long?
I've been writing my entire
life, to be honest.
Life, to be honest.
That long, huh?
Great, great.
Okay.
You're my favorite living
you're my favorite living
poet, I just want to say.
Poet, I just want to say.
Thank you.
You'd be my favorite dead
you'd be my favorite dead
poet, too, but, obviously you're
not dead yet.
Not dead yet.
I mean...
No, no.
Sorry.
Working on that, though.
Thank you so much.
I'm gonna bring some of my work
by.
By.
I'll just drop it off.
Or I can read it online.
You know, I'm just gonna drop
you know, I'm just gonna drop
it by.
It by.
It's no problem.
I'll just come drop it by.
Is everything okay?
Are you thinking?
Yeah.
Yeah, I was thinking.
Well, what were you thinking?
I was thinking you'd be the
type of muse I'd get.
Type of muse I'd get.
No, s-- are you serious?
I mean, I meant that
sarcastically, okay?
Sarcastically, okay?
Don't stand out here.
I want to close the fucking
door.
Door.
Okay.
Muse?
Ha!
Here you go -- first
paycheck.
Paycheck.
Social security, taxes,
social security, taxes,
medicare -- how am I supposed to
afford rent with this?
Afford rent with this?
I don't know, but figure it
out.
Out.
Are you kicking me out?
Yes.
No!
I don't mean to offend you.
I mean, I'm sorry.
Why?
I can't host with you there,
Amy.
You're kind of a pain in my ass,
you're kind of a pain in my ass,
and I don't mean that in a good
way.
Way.
Don't you like having me
don't you like having me
there?
There?
No.
Why?
You talk like, like -- look
you talk like, like -- look
how you talk.
How you talk.
Talk like what?!
[ Mockingly ] Like that.
Just...Get a real roommate,
okay?
Hi.
No pets, no rap music, no
parties, and no fireworks or
gunplay.
Gunplay.
What do you think?
Oh, this?
[ Laughs ]
It's a shithole.
My parents would be horrified.
We're bohemians.
[ Sighs ]
[ Rings doorbell repeatedly ]
Are you completely mad?
Hi!
Like insane?
It's me, Amy.
[ Chuckles ]
I don't know if you remember.
I just moved in down the street,
actually, so I thought I would
bring you a little housewarming
gift.
Um...
I hope you like kiwis.
There's a lot of kiwis.
You want to come in, kid?
Thank you.
Here you go.
Yeah, you can just put that
yeah, you can just put that
right down.
Can I get you something to drink
or nosh on, maybe a shasta or a
triscuit or a trinket of some
kind?
Kind?
I'm fine.
Thank you for that.
Um, I put some of my poems in
the basket.
The basket.
Great.
[ Up-tempo jazz plays
[ up-tempo jazz plays
in background ]
In background ]
That's great.
I'll look at those at some
point.
Point.
Why on earth would you want to
why on earth would you want to
be a poet, Alice?
Be a poet, Alice?
It's Amy, actually.
I...I really feel a lot, you
know?
Know?
Even if things are just
even if things are just
happening around me, I feel like
I really internalize it.
And I want to be able to speak
and I want to be able to speak
for all the people that suffer,
that feel the pain that I feel
every day.
Every day.
You know?
Yes.
Why me, Alice?
Why choose me?
Why come to me?
It's Amy, but you can call me
it's Amy, but you can call me
whatever.
Whatever.
Um...Well, you're unique.
Your work -- it's real, and it's
your work -- it's real, and it's
honest, and it's very partially
subtle, but then very
in-your-face, you know, loud.
In-your-face, you know, loud.
And it speaks for an entire
and it speaks for an entire
generation.
Generation.
No, no, it doesn't.
Yes, it does.
I don't know what that means.
I'm glad people still like some
of the stuff I did, you know,
back in the day.
Back in the day.
I'm just gonna throw
something out there.
Something out there.
Throw it out there.
See what happens.
Yeah, throw it on the trash
yeah, throw it on the trash
heap.
Heap.
See what sticks.
Well, okay.
I would love to be your protégé.
My what?
Your protégé.
My protégé.
I haven't heard that sober with
my pants on for a long time.
My pants on for a long time.
That's okay.
What would that entail?
I'm an excellent speller.
I could proofread for you.
I got a spellcheck.
Oh, of course.
I always imagined you at a
typewriter.
Typewriter.
[ Chuckles ]
What about readings?
I could do readings for you in
your place when you're feeling
sick or you're hung over or
something.
Something.
I feel kind of sick right
now.
Now.
You want to try that?
Give me -- read something.
It's strindberg -- some passages
it's strindberg -- some passages
from strindberg I thought were
kind of cool.
Kind of cool.
[ Clears throat ]
"There are discords in this life
"there are discords in this life
which can" --
whoa!
Whoa!
Not -- not in that voice.
Try it -- just -- can you do it
try it -- just -- can you do it
in your own voice without the...
Sure.
What kind of voice was that?
That was my
that was my
speaking-out-loud,
reading-out-loud voice.
Reading-out-loud voice.
Yeah, don't use that one
yeah, don't use that one
because it doesn't sound like...
Because it doesn't sound like...
It doesn't sound like...
It doesn't sound like you.
How do you feel about failure as
a concept?
A concept?
'Cause, you know, all the best
'cause, you know, all the best
people are failures these days.
People are failures these days.
I failed many times.
That's good.
Continue to fail.
Beckett said, "if you want to
make art, you have to fail."
Make art, you have to fail."
And so, the artist's job is to
and so, the artist's job is to
fail better.
Fail better.
Yeah.
You should make t-shirts.
This has been really good.
I'm happy that you came by.
Okay.
What about if I organize for
what about if I organize for
you?
You could euthanize me.
Um...
I could clean.
I could come over whenever you
need me to and just clean...
Like a maid.
Yeah?
Chop, chop!
Amy!
Hey!
Guess what?!
I got published!
In anarchist quarterly.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I'm so excited.
It's, like, the first time I
it's, like, the first time I
ever sent anything in.
Ever sent anything in.
Awesome.
I know!
It's, like, not a big deal.
It's just, like, some stuff that
it's just, like, some stuff that
I wrote down about the strike
and stuff.
And stuff.
But they're gonna give it, like,
but they're gonna give it, like,
the front page, it says.
The front page, it says.
[ Straining ] I'm so happy
[ straining ] I'm so happy
for you.
For you.
Thanks.
I'm gonna go frame it.
[ Laughs ]
I think they might have
spelled your name wrong.
Spelled your name wrong.
Just double-check.
Aaaahhhhh!
Amy?
Are you working on a new
book?
Book?
Uh...Excuse me?
Is that part of your new
book?
Book?
Oh, yeah.
Just a, uh...
Just a little -- shitty, little
anthology I'm putting together,
you know?
You know?
Don't want to but got to pay the
don't want to but got to pay the
bills.
Bills.
What kind of stuff are you
what kind of stuff are you
putting in there?
Putting in there?
Mostly unknowns.
Really?
I'm going to go out and come
back.
Back.
So, carry on.
Okay.
[ Door closes ]
"The fright oblivion,
deep night.
Deep night.
Spring kills with its might.
Might I delight?"
Question mark or exclamation
question mark or exclamation
point?
Point?
Sorry, man.
[ Cash register beeping ]
Um...
Thanks.
All right.
What are you doing?
Why are you not paying
why are you not paying
attention?
Attention?
I am paying attention.
Amy, what are you doing?
Amy, what are you writing?
What's going on?
[ Laughing ] Stop it!
What are you doing?
Nothing! I'm sorry!
Hey, guess what?
What?
I got a job.
I'm working for rat billings.
Are you quitting?
No, no.
I still need to work here.
He doesn't believe in money.
So, he's paying me in
so, he's paying me in
mentorship.
what are you doing for him
that you're not getting paid?
Um...
Well, I'm kind of his protégé.
Oh.
A lot of great writers get
a lot of great writers get
their start under the tutelage
of another great writer.
Of another great writer.
You know, like Ford madox Ford
you know, like Ford madox Ford
took James Joyce under his wing,
and Joyce may never have been
discovered otherwise.
Discovered otherwise.
Wait!
I just remembered something.
Lepassion.
Call for entries.
"We need erotica written by
"we need erotica written by
women about their sexual
experiences."
Yeah.
I know it's not Harper's or
the new yorker or whatever, but
it's writing, right?
It's writing, right?
It's a publication.
Alex, I'm not gonna peddle
porn.
Porn.
Amy, hey, you're working in a
porn shop.
Porn shop.
Um, Alex, the girl on the
um, Alex, the girl on the
cover?
Cover?
One of her boobs is bigger than
one of her boobs is bigger than
my entire face.
My entire face.
You do kind of have a small
you do kind of have a small
face.
Just trying to help.
Desired reality desires
desired reality desires
itself,
invents a body of lightning,
bends over, and looks at itself.
Bends over, and looks at itself.
Jaguar waves and skull,
two eyes fixed on two eyes,
idols always the same eyes."
Idols always the same eyes."
South Americans are awesome,
aren't they?
Who would like to read another
bit of octavio paz?
All right.
My assistant, Adrian, will read.
[ Clears throat ]
[ Dramatically ] "Dawn.
Cold, rapid hands draw back
cold, rapid hands draw back
one by one.
One by one.
The bandage of dark.
I open my eyes.
Still, I am living at the center
still, I am living at the center
of a wound still fresh."
Allison?
This guy is still in a wound
this guy is still in a wound
so fresh.
So fresh.
I mean, so much pain and
violence.
Violence.
Yes, yes, but try not to be
yes, yes, but try not to be
quite so literal with it.
Quite so literal with it.
That is quite a literal
that is quite a literal
response.
Response.
Wait.
So, is that gonna be on the
so, is that gonna be on the
test?
Test?
Yes.
You'll be tested.
You'll be tested every day and
you'll be tested every day and
for the rest of your life.
For the rest of your life.
And you know what?
You'll fail.
That's it.
Have you, perchance, found
the time to check out any of my
poems?
Poems?
I mean, I know you're busy.
No, but I will.
So, keep working on them.
Was it hard to get off
heroin?
Heroin?
You know, your "opiated blues"
you know, your "opiated blues"
days, when you were homeless and
hustling?
Hustling?
Well, in actuality, the smack
well, in actuality, the smack
came later, after I wrote it.
Came later, after I wrote it.
So, you made all of that up?
Hey, you got to blur the
hey, you got to blur the
lines, kid.
Lines, kid.
[ Cellphone ringing ]
You really are a bizarre, little
you really are a bizarre, little
creature, aren't you?
Creature, aren't you?
Hello?
Richard Simmons?
Why are you getting mail
why are you getting mail
addressed to Richard Simmons?
Addressed to Richard Simmons?
Well, I wasn't being mean.
I was being honest.
Oh, my God.
"Rat" is a nom De plume.
More of a nom De guerre, but
more of a nom De guerre, but
don't tell anybody, or they'll
skin me alive.
Skin me alive.
Of course!
They can't take a little
criticism without going to the
Dean.
Is that what you're telling me?
[ Sighs ]
All right.
I'll do whatever you want.
No, I won't do that, but...
We'll -- we'll -- we'll talk
about it later.
About it later.
Bye-bye.
You're right to be hard on
you're right to be hard on
them.
Them.
They need it.
I know -- generation mundane.
How about a little negative
how about a little negative
advice before I depart?
Advice before I depart?
Love.
Love until you hate.
Then, learn to hate your love.
Then, forgive your hate for
then, forgive your hate for
loving it.
Loving it.
Wow.
On that note, do not wait to
on that note, do not wait to
strike until the iron is hot,
but make it hot by striking.
But make it hot by striking.
That's William Butler yeats.
You're dumb, but you're not
you're dumb, but you're not
stupid!
Stupid!
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Sighs ]
Time is so weird.
Being 22 is so weird.
It's weird.
Super-weird.
It's like this neverland, you
it's like this neverland, you
know?
Know?
Like, we're not quite kids.
We're not quite adults.
It's like we're marginalized
others or something.
Others or something.
Just cured my insomnia.
[ Coughing ]
[ Laughs ]
It's so cool.
You have such diverse friends,
you have such diverse friends,
Amy.
You have something on your face.
[ Laughing ] You have something
[ laughing ] You have something
on your face.
On your face.
Yeah?
Come dance with me.
Come on. It'll be fun.
[ Groaning ]
Okay.
It's floor dancing, floor
it's floor dancing, floor
dancing.
Her need for release exploded
in a violent, lustful vengeance,
as the stock boy finally took
her to the edge of oblivion.
Her to the edge of oblivion.
She lay plundered, fighting for
she lay plundered, fighting for
her next breath.
Her next breath.
[ Knock on door ]
Hey. What's up?
Nothing. Just writing.
That's cool.
You gonna drink all that by
you gonna drink all that by
yourself?
Yourself?
Not all of it.
[ Chuckles ]
Put some posters up, maybe.
Paint.
I could help you with that.
And stuff.
Hi.
Ow.
[ Laughs ]
You're so funny.
You're funny.
A second ago, I was teaching
him how to do, like, the dance
moves.
Moves.
It's cool.
You should join, seriously.
I'll pass, thanks.
[ Both laugh ]
Okay.
Sweet.
All right. Have fun doing...
What you do.
[ Door closes ]
[ Clears throat ]
[ Sighs ]
"For your consideration, here's
a taste of some of the erotic
prose I've been working on.
Prose I've been working on.
Sincerely...
Evelyn...Renoir."
You whore.
Ew.
Hey.
Who's the dead girl on the wall?
Sylvia.
Oh, how'd she die?
She stuck her head in the
she stuck her head in the
oven.
That's bananas.
Mm-hmm.
Did you ever feel invisible?
No, not really.
Hey, I know what's wrong with
you.
Hey.
I've been wanting to do this
ever since I met you.
Ever since I met you.
What?
[ Up-tempo Latin music plays ]
Whoa.
She's a snow leopard.
[ Door slams open ]
I need a drink.
[ Mid-tempo jazz plays ]
Holy mother of God.
I can understand that.
Sure.
Come on in.
Make it a stiff one, Buster,
and make it snappy.
You look lovely tonight.
What are you doing out here this
what are you doing out here this
late?
Late?
It's the witching hour.
Maybe I'm a witch.
Ran right into that one.
[ Cigarette sizzles ]
[ Bottle cap rattles ]
A-ha!
[ Slams bottle down ]
Why are you dressed like a
hooker?
Hooker?
And so began our torrid love
and so began our torrid love
affair.
Whoops.
Oh, my God.
[ Sighs ]
Jesus Christ!
[ Exhaling loudly ]
I want you to deflower me.
I've chosen you, rat billings,
to open the bud of my womanhood.
To open the bud of my womanhood.
I only ask that you treat me as
you would treat a poet.
You would treat a poet.
What, you want me to slap you
what, you want me to slap you
around a little bit?
Around a little bit?
I want to be picked like an
exotic flower, like a rare
breeze.
You actually are a pretty
girl, aren't you?
Girl, aren't you?
Do it to me!
Do it to me good!
Oh, come on.
Don't use that voice.
Do it to me!
Do it to me good!
That's when you're losing me,
that's when you're losing me,
with the "do it it to me,
do it to me good."
Do it to me good."
I thought people liked that.
No, I don't believe anything
no, I don't believe anything
you're saying, sweetheart.
You're saying, sweetheart.
Have sex with me.
No.
No to the voice or no to the
no to the voice or no to the
sex?
Sex?
No to both.
What, do you think I'm ugly
or something?
Or something?
No, no.
I think you're psychotic.
[ Scoffs ]
You're just a kid.
I am a woman.
You're a little snickers bar.
You're a little snicks.
I'd like to read you
something I wrote for you.
Something I wrote for you.
You're a little snick-snack.
You're an asshole.
[ Clears throat ]
"In squalid ether,
"in squalid ether,
digital-surveillance nightmare.
Digital-surveillance nightmare.
[ Loudly ] Shattered wings
[ loudly ] Shattered wings
catapult the vast vulva of
shattered oblivion."
Shattered oblivion."
It's astonishing.
Tell me what you really think
tell me what you really think
of it, poet to poet, mentor to
protégé.
Protégé.
[ Normal voice ] Tell me the
[ normal voice ] Tell me the
truth.
Truth.
Do you think I could be a real
do you think I could be a real
poet?
Poet?
Snicks.
Do you?
[ Sighs ]
Tell me!
[ Coughs ]
[ Moans ]
Snickers? Snicks?
Well, you're off to a good
start.
Start.
Oh. There's more.
Can I use the bathroom?
Yeah.
[ Coughing ]
So, where'd you go last
night?
Night?
To an awful, terrible place I
to an awful, terrible place I
may never recover from.
May never recover from.
What happened? Are you okay?
I messed up.
I'm such a failure.
Whatever it was, I'm sure it
wasn't that bad.
Wasn't that bad.
Trust me. It was bad.
Well, I've done some really
well, I've done some really
stupid shit.
Stupid shit.
Last night?
No, last night I left right
no, last night I left right
after you did.
After you did.
Your friend Candace is kind of
your friend Candace is kind of
an...Octopus.
An...Octopus.
[ Laughs ]
I had to escape her
testicles.
Testicles.
[ Laughs ]
Tentacles!
I've been working here too long.
Really, though, I've done things
really, though, I've done things
I wish I hadn't.
It's part of life.
But if you need anything, let me
but if you need anything, let me
know.
Know.
[ Both laugh ]
Thank you.
That's really nice of you.
You're welcome.
What do you want to bet that's a
what do you want to bet that's a
bachelorette party?
Bachelorette party?
[ Door closes ]
Hi.
We're only in here because
we're only in here because
we're going to a bachelorette
party.
Party.
A bachelorette party?!
Yeah.
Oh, my God!
And I was wondering if you
and I was wondering if you
had, like, some kind of package?
Had, like, some kind of package?
I have a package.
Good.
I'll be right back.
Thanks.
Oh, my God!
Amy?
Amy Anderson?
Oh, my God, Maggie!
Hi!
How is it going?
I didn't see you.
Amy used to go to my middle
school.
School.
She thought she was gonna be
she thought she was gonna be
this famous poet.
This famous poet.
I'm actually, um, I'm still
working on that.
Working on that.
What's it like working in a
what's it like working in a
dirty-video store?
I bet you see a lot of freaks.
You know what, Maggie?
You're a freak!
O...Kay.
Rat?!
I'm not receiving any
visitors today.
Visitors today.
It's life-or-death.
It's creative life-or-death!
I am so sorry that I vomited
upon you, but I need to know the
truth.
Truth.
Truth's subjective, Amy.
Cut the bullshit, okay?
I am in physical and emotional
pain right now.
Pain right now.
I need to know what you thought
of my poems.
Well...You're in pain?
How much -- what -- what kind of
how much -- what -- what kind of
pain are you in?
Pain are you in?
The worst pain I've ever been
the worst pain I've ever been
in.
In.
Oh, okay, well, on a scale,
oh, okay, well, on a scale,
what would you say you are, on a
universal --
on the wong-Baker
facial-grimace scale?
Facial-grimace scale?
This is the death of a loved
this is the death of a loved
one, all right?
One, all right?
It's a 10.
No.
It's worst pain possible.
That's like Auschwitz.
So, I mean, I think it's -- you
so, I mean, I think it's -- you
would be somewhere...Somewhere
in here, I think.
In here, I think.
If you go like that...
And, then, you're like that, and
and, then, you're like that, and
that's Amy.
That's Amy.
Here, you know, where it's on
here, you know, where it's on
this side of it, maybe in
Cleveland.
Tell me!
I read your poems.
And?
Credit to your tenacity.
What's this?
It's a map.
Russia and Mongolia.
Just, I want you to go there
just, I want you to go there
one day and write something.
One day and write something.
Anyway, I found them exceedingly
anyway, I found them exceedingly
special.
Special.
I found them uniquely you.
I found them...Most like you.
You really think so?
Yeah, yeah.
In fact, I'm putting together a
in fact, I'm putting together a
little anthology, a little,
shitty, little, shit-filled,
shit-stained anthology of new
work.
Work.
And?
And it's not anything major,
and it's not anything major,
but, if you want, I can include
one of your shitty, little --
oh, my God! Yes!!
Oh, my God! Yes!!
Yes!
Oh, my God, thank you!
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you!
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
All right, all right, all
all right, all right, all
right.
Right.
Yes, yes!
This is the best day ever!
Oh, my God!
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
Thank you, thank you!
Whoo!
[ Humming ]
All right, I'm gonna go.
[ Door slams ]
Thank you!
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
[ Exhales sharply ]
Come on, darling.
Good night.
Good night, darling.
♪ white bird,
in a golden cage,
on a winter's day,
in the rain ♪
In the rain ♪
♪ white bird,
in a golden cage,
alone ♪
♪ and she must fly
you asshole!
You asshole!
♪ she must fly
hi.
Hi.
Hey. What's up?
Did you just see what just
did you just see what just
happened?
Happened?
What?
That asshole just stole a
that asshole just stole a
bunch of shit.
Bunch of shit.
You didn't even notice.
I-I'm sorry.
I was rearranging some DVDs.
You know, you're lucky to
you know, you're lucky to
have this job.
Have this job.
Any other place would have fired
any other place would have fired
you by now.
You by now.
And you get to do anything you
and you get to do anything you
want here, and we don't say
shit.
Shit.
And you just take advantage.
It's bullshit.
Okay, I'm sorry, but...
It's not like this is a career.
It's a stupid job in a stupid
it's a stupid job in a stupid
place.
Place.
This place is how Stan and
this place is how Stan and
Mary Anne make their living.
It's how I make my living.
And it really pisses me off that
and it really pisses me off that
you think that you're better
than that.
Than that.
What are you trying to say?
I'm saying go find yourself
another stupid job.
Fine.
[ Voice breaking ] You know, I'm
[ voice breaking ] You know, I'm
up for a lot of awards right now
and accolades, and I don't need
a job that's for losers, okay?
A job that's for losers, okay?
Especially not in this...This
especially not in this...This
porn hole!
[ Horns honk in distance ]
Yeah?
The napkins that I had over
the napkins that I had over
there that I moved over here
that I was working on, the white
ones?
I don't know about those.
What do you mean you don't
what do you mean you don't
know about them?
Know about them?
They were here, and then you
they were here, and then you
cleaned up, and then things got
unorganized.
Unorganized.
The manuscript's on the napkins
the manuscript's on the napkins
that were with the coasters that
you moved over from over there
when I told you don't clean,
don't clean, don't clean.
Don't clean, don't clean.
And you did, anyway?
I can't find them.
Oh, napkins, napkins.
There's napkins there.
I know.
I'm not looking for these.
I'm looking for these.
This has got this.
This is this.
Where are they?
I told you not to clean up.
If you put them back over here,
if you put them back over here,
I'm gonna be very upset with
you.
You.
Here they are.
I found them.
I must have accidentally put
them in my purse.
Them in my purse.
I don't know why. I'm sorry.
Here you go.
What were they doing in your
what were they doing in your
bag?
Okay.
Are you gonna be mad?
I'm already mad.
I thought that it was trash,
like, doodles or something.
Like, doodles or something.
Do I look like a doodler to
do I look like a doodler to
you?
You?
[ Sighs ]
Not now you don't.
Okay, so, that's bullshit.
I thought it would be cool to
have something of yours for when
you die.
You die.
I'm not gonna die...
Ever!
You idiot.
I really wouldn't have taken
them if I thought they were
important.
Important.
All right, look.
You can have that one.
Thank you.
This is really good.
This one's -- you should keep
this one's -- you should keep
this one.
This one.
This one's really good.
You were so young when you
you were so young when you
became famous.
Became famous.
You and rimbaud, both so
you and rimbaud, both so
talented, and younger than I am
now.
Now.
Fame's your generation's
fame's your generation's
black plague, kid.
Black plague, kid.
That's really good.
Who said that?
I did just now, me.
I said that to you.
Alex hates me.
Men are really delicate.
They get their feelings hurt
easy.
Easy.
Oy!
Here.
[ Sighs ]
I want my job back.
You like Alex.
What?
That's absurd.
You're all like, "what's
you're all like, "what's
tomorrow gonna be like?
Tomorrow gonna be like?
And what will people think of
and what will people think of
me?"
Me?"
You're gonna be blind to what's
you're gonna be blind to what's
right in front of you.
Right in front of you.
Forever is comprised of "nows."
Emily Dickinson, bitch.
Get my fat toe.
Hey...
Alex.
Are you here to rent a movie?
No.
Then, you'll have to excuse
then, you'll have to excuse
me, because I have a very
patient customer waiting.
Patient customer waiting.
You want a 3- or a 5-day rental?
What do the green dots mean?
Uh...
It means new release.
Alex, I'm sorry.
I am not too good to work here,
and I didn't mean any of those
things that I said.
Things that I said.
Do you have the antimicrobial
do you have the antimicrobial
anal beads?
Anal beads?
Sorry, buddy, we're all sold
sorry, buddy, we're all sold
out.
Out.
There should be more coming in
there should be more coming in
Monday, though.
[ Scoffs ]
I'm not better than this,
and I don't think working here
is for losers.
Is for losers.
I want my job back.
Why?
So, I can find out who puts
so, I can find out who puts
the dots on.
The dots on.
[ Snorts ]
Do you have any of those
leather masks that are
flame-retardant?
Flame-retardant?
What the fuck is with...
No, we don't. I'm sorry.
She took the last one.
They're awesome.
I'm gonna let you deal with
that 'cause that's your
punishment.
Punishment.
Thanks.
What's your name?
Max.
Okay, Max.
Max...Max.
"Cougar den."
"Dorm girls."
This is the wrong Max, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, I brought you some
hey, I brought you some
turtlenecks.
Thanks, mom.
You're welcome.
They're all-cotton.
Dad says hi.
Does he hate me?
Mm-hmm.
We both do.
No, he doesn't hate you.
We love you, but we're a little
we love you, but we're a little
worried about you.
Worried about you.
What?! I'm fine.
I have a good job now.
Things...Things are really
things...Things are really
looking up.
Looking up.
But are you happy?
Mother, an artist's life...
It really is a life of solitude.
[ Clears throat ]
That is, um, bullshit.
It's almost your birthday.
Let's just plan a party, okay?
You haven't had a birthday party
you haven't had a birthday party
for a while.
For a while.
Dad wants to see you.
I want to meet your friends.
I always used to meet your
friends.
Friends.
I'll make you a cake.
What kind of cake do you want?
Cheese.
I can do that -- cheesecake.
Anything else?
Sprinkles.
Good!
That's -- now we're talking.
Rainbow, not chocolate.
It's gonna be fun.
You're very skinny.
I'll make you two cakes.
Whoo!
Yay!
Whoa-ho! Happy Birthday!
[ Laughs ]
Hello?
Hi!
Hi.
I'm so happy you came.
Oh, we just thought we'd stop
oh, we just thought we'd stop
by.
By.
Sorry we didn't wait for
sorry we didn't wait for
cake.
Cake.
Happy Birthday.
Thanks.
This is my friend yumi.
She's a theoretical linguist.
[ Laughs uproariously ]
This is Amy, the girl that I
this is Amy, the girl that I
told you about.
Told you about.
[ Continues laughing ]
[ Chuckles ]
Um, do you want some cake or
um, do you want some cake or
something?
Something?
Sure.
Drinks?
Yeah.
This is my family.
This is rat.
You must be Mrs. Anderson.
How are you?
No, I am Mrs. Anderson.
I know!
Todd Anderson.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
What's your name?
Rubia.
I'm sorry?
Hi.
Alex.
Would you like something to
would you like something to
drink?
Drink?
Yeah, do you have any wine?
Sure do, yeah.
'Cause I think yumi likes
'cause I think yumi likes
wine.
Wine.
[ Chuckles ]
Red is fine.
Okay.
And I'll have -- do you have
and I'll have -- do you have
coffee?
Coffee?
We have coffee.
And red wine for the yumi,
and red wine for the yumi,
and can you bring the cake
cutter?
Cutter?
You need a cake cutter.
So, a cake cutter and...
Yeah.
That was really amazing,
that was really amazing,
what you did for Amy.
What you did for Amy.
I haven't done anything to
Amy.
Well, no, but you see how
well, no, but you see how
talented she is.
Talented she is.
That's amazing.
For a girl like her, there's
for a girl like her, there's
nothing she wants more.
Nothing she wants more.
She's a good kid.
She's just, as my father used to
she's just, as my father used to
say, "free of all knowledge."
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
Somebody knows what they're
somebody knows what they're
doing.
This is for you.
I don't want you to open it in
front of everybody, 'cause then
they're like, "oh, it's from
Alex" and "what is it?"
You know, that's weird.
"Letters to a young poet."
Yeah.
I know you probably read that,
like, a thousand times, but...
Like, a thousand times, but...
No, I haven't.
I haven't read this one.
Sweet.
Score.
"Amy, Happy Birthday.
I thought of you when I saw
this."
This."
No! Shh! No.
You're not gonna read that.
No.
I'm a dork.
It's embarrassing.
Thank you. I love it.
You're welcome.
Seriously, it's a really good
seriously, it's a really good
present.
Where's rat?
Oh, he had to leave, honey.
Seriously?
Yeah, but he left you a
yeah, but he left you a
present.
Present.
"Here it is -- rat."
It's a galley of the book that
it's a galley of the book that
I'm in.
[ Gasps ]
Oh, my gosh! Open it!
Open it!
[ Groans ]
I can't do it.
I got nails.
Careful with the paper,
careful with the paper,
please.
Let me see.
"Shit poetry -- an anthology of
"shit poetry -- an anthology of
bad verse," edited by
rat billings.
Rat billings.
Well, what is this?
My poem.
"Hilariously awful" --
Joan didion.
"So bad, it's good" --
"so bad, it's good" --
zadie Smith.
Zadie Smith.
"So terrible, I laughed and then
"so terrible, I laughed and then
I cried" -- Jonathan franzen.
Oh, my God,
oh, my God,
Jonathan franzen!
Amy...
Amy?
Amy, come on.
Amy!
Amy, stop.
Amy.
Come on, honey, it's your
come on, honey, it's your
birthday.
Birthday.
Amy, it's really not that
bad!
Bad!
Honey?
♪ well, it was nothing
♪ it was nothing to me
♪ it was nothing
♪ baby, baby
means nothing to me ♪
Means nothing to me ♪
aaahhhh!
Aaahhhh!
[ Horn honking ]
You miserable son of a bitch!
Where are you?
Problem?
"Shit poetry"?!
"An anthology of bad verse"?!
It's just a silly, little
it's just a silly, little
book for the urban outfitters.
Book for the urban outfitters.
You know, hipsters are gonna
you know, hipsters are gonna
love it.
Love it.
They're gonna be reading my
they're gonna be reading my
poetry while taking a shit!
Poetry while taking a shit!
You said you wanted to be
you said you wanted to be
published, didn't you?
Published, didn't you?
Not in a book that people
not in a book that people
are gonna read while they're on
the toilet!
The toilet!
How do you think I feel?
It's probably gonna outsell
it's probably gonna outsell
everything I've ever written.
Everything I've ever written.
Aahhh!
All right.
Who anointed you the arbiter
who anointed you the arbiter
of poetic quality, anyway,
huh?!
Huh?!
It's not quality.
It's poetry that's so bad, it
it's poetry that's so bad, it
goes around the world, and it's
kind of good.
Kind of good.
The rat billings that I
the rat billings that I
admired?
Admired?
He is dead!
You're a big, fat phony, and you
you're a big, fat phony, and you
know what?
Know what?
You're old!
You're an old, phony man!
That's what you are!
An old phony!
An old, washed-up phony!
Why?!
I want to know why you would do
this to me?!
This to me?!
Why?! Why?! Why?!
Because somebody needs to
because somebody needs to
tell you the goddamn truth, Amy.
Tell you the goddamn truth, Amy.
I thought truth was
subjective.
Subjective.
No, it's not subjective.
Not everybody can grow up to be
not everybody can grow up to be
beyoncé or the president.
Beyoncé or the president.
Not everybody's talented, okay?
And fame doesn't mean shit.
Amy, if everything was great,
nothing would be great.
Nothing would be great.
Nothing would be special.
I am special!
I got straight a's!
I scored in the 97th percentile
on my s.A.T.S!
On my s.A.T.S!
Thank you very much!
The s.A.T.S don't mean shit.
That's like believing in
that's like believing in
scientology.
Scientology.
[ Roars ]
Easy, easy.
You're bullshit.
Nobody cares --
nobody cares --
you all right?
You all right?
She's a monster.
Get her out of here!
Come on.
All I wanted was your advice!
You're a phony,
you're a phony,
Richard Simmons!
Don't take my -- don't take
don't take my -- don't take
my napkins!
My napkins!
Get the fuck out of here!
Don't take those napkins!
Don't take my napkins!
[ Door slams ]
Yeah.
You shouldn't care what anybody
thinks.
Thinks.
It doesn't matter.
Zadie Smith thinks I'm an
zadie Smith thinks I'm an
idiot.
Idiot.
No, she doesn't.
And rat probably hates himself.
I can't face anyone.
I don't want to go back to my
parents' house.
Parents' house.
I just don't want to see anyone.
You want to go to my place?
[ Sniffles ]
Yeah.
♪ headlights
through my window at night ♪
Through my window at night ♪
♪ white lights on my baby,
all right ♪
All right ♪
♪ and when I see her,
she's a stranger to me ♪
She's a stranger to me ♪
♪ in the floating world
♪ oh-oh
just make yourself at home.
Just make yourself at home.
Want some water?
♪ I'd be stuck
in the floating world ♪
In the floating world ♪
[ Water runs ]
♪ in the floating world
♪ oh-oh
did you do these?
Did you do these?
Yeah.
Yeah, don't look at that.
No, no. Hey, hey.
It's not finished.
I don't know what that is,
actually.
This one is so beautiful.
Thank you.
Have you shown these?
No.
Why not?
You could be famous.
[ Sighs ]
Well, it's not really about
well, it's not really about
that.
That.
For me, it's more kind of just
for me, it's more kind of just
something that I like to do, on
my own, you know?
Don't you have anything that you
just wrote for yourself, and you
didn't want to show anybody?
No, not really.
Huh.
I should go.
Um...
You want me to drive you?
That's okay.
Okay.
♪ Stand up in the blue room
♪ off the window
flashing red and blue ♪
Flashing red and blue ♪
♪ but I don't live here
♪ I'm the occupant
♪ I reside
in the floating world ♪
In the floating world ♪
♪ in the floating world
♪ mm-mm-mm
♪ oh-oh
[ inhales, exhales ]
♪ It's cold
♪ a plain
diamond ♪
Diamond ♪
♪ nobody's here
trey, let me call you back.
Trey, let me call you back.
I got a problem here.
What?!
Relax.
I'm not gonna do anything.
Are you sure?
I promise.
What do you want?
I read some of your work.
It's, uh...
It's beautiful...Some of it.
It's heartbreaking.
It's too bad you're such a
colossal asshole.
Colossal asshole.
Yeah.
Oh, thank you for saving me a
oh, thank you for saving me a
lot of time and agony, but you
didn't have to be so terrible
just because I suck.
Just because I suck.
You don't suck, Amy.
You don't anything yet.
That's the point.
You might be a great writer
you might be a great writer
someday.
Someday.
I don't know.
You haven't even lived yet.
Go to jail, you know?
Become a nun.
Right now you're just a
right now you're just a
suckling, little piglet.
Suckling, little piglet.
Just go out and live your life
just go out and live your life
and get your heart broken and
get out of mine!
Get out of mine!
Please.
For a little while.
Okay, rat.
Okay.
I'm not done.
You got to stop taking yourself
you got to stop taking yourself
so seriously.
So seriously.
[ Sighs ]
The world is full of
the world is full of
innocuous mundanity, and people
are literal and stupid.
Are literal and stupid.
But you're a fighter, you know?
A rebel.
Did you rehearse that one?
Maybe.
Yeah.
It doesn't quite work yet, does
it doesn't quite work yet, does
it?
It?
You know what?
There may not really be a place
there may not really be a place
for poetry left in the world,
Amy.
The literal may have triumphed
the literal may have triumphed
and conquered all, but we...
And conquered all, but we...
We press on, right?
We press on.
Now give it to me, and...
[ Whistles ]
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
You give it to me good, man.
Give it to me good.
You know what I mean?
Because, like, this is it.
This is the moment.
Rat...
Stop taking yourself so
stop taking yourself so
seriously.
I want to tell you something
right now.
The culture around us is
disintegrating.
Disintegrating.
But you are not a part of that.
You stand against the tide, and
you stand against the tide, and
that is no small thing.
You will always be a hyena, Amy.
Arthur rimbaud.
Ah!
You're a thief...
Regal and ragged!
♪ Her dress was dark
and clean ♪
And clean ♪
[ Laughs ]
No, stop!
You're gonna rip it!
I win.
Do you need help?
Yeah.
♪ like you were caught
in the wind ♪
[ Chuckles ]
What?
You have paint on your face.
I do?
Hang on.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, God, no.
Hey, hey!
What?
Oh, it's really embarrassing.
There's a few of them here.
It's really embarrassing.
Come on.
No, I like them.
They're cool.
I like that one.
I was worried you would think
that was creepy.
That was creepy.
It's not creepy.
It's cool.
[ Laughs ]
I like them.
♪ We hardly knew summer,
and it goes to show ♪
And it goes to show ♪
♪ we hardly knew each other,
and it goes to show ♪
♪ oh-oh, evangeline
are you gonna take off your
clothes?
Clothes?
What is this?
[ Laughing ] I'm wearing two
[ laughing ] I'm wearing two
shirts.
♪ Nah-nah-nah,
nah-nah-nah ♪
♪ nah-nah-nah, nah-nah-nah
being with him was as perfect
as a sonnet.
As a sonnet.
[ Laughs ]
Did I just say that out loud?
Yeah.
You do that a lot.
[ Laughs ]
I like it.
[ Cellphone ringing ]
Don't get it.
[ Laughs ]
Why are you getting it?
Whoa!
[ Laughs ]
Hello?
This is she.
Really?
Oh, my God, I can't believe
that.
That.
Really?
Okay, yeah, just send over the
okay, yeah, just send over the
contract.
Contract.
Okay.
Yeah, that sounds great,
yeah, that sounds great,
actually.
Actually.
Cool.
Okay, thank you.
Bye!
What is that?
Is everything okay?
[ Chuckles ]
You're never gonna believe this.
[ Laughs ]
I'm getting published.
What?!
I know.
It's -- it's gonna be on the
it's -- it's gonna be on the
website later today and in the
magazine next month.
Magazine next month.
Oh, that's amazing.
And I got $500.
Score.
What magazine?
I'm numb.
I want to read it.
What magazine is this?
Lepassion.
Lepassion?
What?! You submitted?
Yeah.
Oh, my God!
That's amazing.
And you're gonna be published...
Again.
Yeah.
Yeah, this time it's good.
[ Chuckles ]
It's very good.
This is good.
Yeah.
We should celebrate.
What is this place?
Just a place.
You're so cryptic.
♪ Where did the future go?
Hey, Alex, what's up?
Hey.
♪ I was feeling down
♪ I was feeling so low
got that?
Got that?
Yeah.
Hi.
♪ Here it comes
[ Laughs ]
♪ the frozen land
♪ I'm never going back there
♪ it was a lie
whoa!
Whoa!
♪ itself, oh-oh
hi.
Hi.
She's new. Be nice.
♪ I saw the light,
saw the reconstruction ♪
Saw the reconstruction ♪
♪ and I will go
♪ I will go
out in the heat and the rush ♪
Out in the heat and the rush ♪
♪ and they push us by a knife
♪ your little heart
is gonna be sewn ♪
Is gonna be sewn ♪
♪ where did the feeling go?
♪ Where did the feeling go?
♪ it comes and goes
♪ comes and goes
♪ here it comes
♪ don't be repatriated
Alex, you should really show
your work.
Your work.
Yeah, I don't know.
I'll probably just end up
working at a porn store the rest
of my life.
Of my life.
Really? Me too!
[ Laughs ]
You should really keep
you should really keep
writing, though, because you
kind of suck at your day job.
As long as I'm not boring.
You're not boring.
You're a weirdo.
You are not normal.
[ Both laugh ]
And it's inspiring.
It's cool.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
[ Chuckles ]
♪ I feel alone
♪ I feel alone,
but it feels all ri-I-ght ♪
But it feels all ri-I-ght ♪
♪ I feel alone,
but it feels all right ♪
But it feels all right ♪
♪ I feel alone,
but it feels all ri-I-ght ♪
But it feels all ri-I-ght ♪
♪ I feel alone,
but it feels all right ♪
But it feels all right ♪
♪ I feel alone
♪ I feel all right
[ Chuckles ]
[ Up-tempo dance music plays ]
♪ Well, they're an army
of thieves ♪
Of thieves ♪
♪ they've got everything
they need ♪
They need ♪
bend the other leg, too.
Bend the other leg, too.
Both legs?
Yeah, you like that?
Oh, God, that's sexy.
I'll get something to go with
her.
Her.
♪ what about us?
♪ What about us?
♪ Because it's time after time
♪ we're stuck behind the line
♪ what about us?
♪ What about us?
♪ and they won't admit defeat
when it pulls into the street ♪
When it pulls into the street ♪
♪ so, what about us?
♪ So, what about us?
♪ what about, what about us?
♪ What about, what about us?
♪ what about us?
♪ What about us?
♪ what about u-us?
♪ What about u-us?
[ Crowd cheers ]
Thank you.
Hello?!
It's over.
Go home.
♪ break my heart
♪ I've been living life so long,
I know there's nothing wrong
with this ♪
With this ♪
♪ come on and break my heart
♪ break my heart
♪ I've been living life so long,
I know there's nothing wrong
with this ♪
With this ♪
♪ come on and break my heart
♪ break my heart
♪ I've been living life so long,
I know there's nothing wrong
with this ♪
With this ♪
♪ come on and break my heart
♪ break my heart
♪ well, let's stay
♪ this evil, little world
♪ break my heart