Are you going to take the TV, too?
-Yeah.
Saara can have the kids' old one.
It's good enough for her.
Could you be a dear,
and get my kettlebell from upstairs?
This pink one must be yours.
We can take that one, too.
Saara never uses it.
What happened?
Sorry.
Your... thingy is here.
Excuse me. Nice to meet you.
What are you doing home?
-I thought you were coming at three.
At one. Why are you lurking here?
We've been here an hour.
I was just working out here.
I was wearing headphones,
so I didn't hear you at first.
I thought it's embarrassing
to suddenly announce myself-
so I started to clean a bit
under this rug.
Right. Well, seeing as you're here,
can you lend a hand?
After all, you're a real powerhouse.
Thanks.
Remember, mum is bringing you Pussy
to look after in a couple of weeks.
Me? why?
She is used to being here.
It's your mum's cat,
she should be with you.
I didn't want to burden her
with the divorce or moving out news.
But I won't be at home!
I'm starting my new life.
I'm going to a camp-
with handsome, smart guys,
who understand women.
We will have discussions
and make love on hot rocks.
Do you want to be young once again?
Do you want to think about who
you are and what you want to become?
Do you dream of a spiritual growth
course or a coming-of-age camp?
Do you yearn for conversation,
or even debates?
Are you curious to see
how others view life?
Do you want to heal the world
and stand for equality and justice?
I'm a certified
personal growth coach -
with a Kerala Diploma
of Human Growth -
and I invite you to Turku
to a meaning of life camp for adults.
The price includes the camp
programme, a delightful room -
gourmet-level full hoard,
and a growth guarantee.
Invest in yourself and experience
the greatest week of your life.
I will not be looking after Pussy!
Hi! Excuse me, can I get
your autograph'! -Sure you can.
Can I help in any way? -There's
no need. just clear the gangway.
Fantastic! We have a great group!
Take a good look at each other.
These people
are going to change your life!
This is going to be a great week!
I'm Kalle, I'll be your escort,
but you will make this a journey.
I think we are all here.
-Not everybody is here yet.
Kokko, Saara.
Kannisto, Alli.
-I am. That's me.
Then registered together are
Vilen, Viivi and Häkkinen, Jouko.
Viivi has not yet arrived.
I'm sure you understand that
there can be no refund at this point.
But she does want
to come to this camp.
Are you Kalle?
-Yes.
Why is there less money
for provisions than agreed?
I gave the amount we discussed.
But can we get back to that?
Let's not bother the campers
with money talk.
Darling, here's your bag.
Tepsi and I are heading home.
I'll see you...
See you when you come.
So I don't catch the gay.
Now you could also come.
There was a cancellation.
He's lying. I know when people are
lying. You can see it in their aura.
I'm missing you a little.
Yours is quite weak.
Kind of messy. Have you let someone
do something to you? Trample on you?
Nobody's trampled on me. Excuse me.
Hi.
Has she been yowling the whole time?
-Only when the rocking started.
She's probably scared.
Are you scared?
I don't like the sea. My mum drowned
in the Estonian cruise ship disaster.
I'm sorry.
-Well, it was twenty years ago.
It's annoying
that we're going to an island then.
I want to take part
in the revolution camp.
Revolution? Isn't it coming-of-age?
No, we'll talk about societal issues
and justice.
I don't think this has anything
to do with politics.
The video was about coming-of-age
camps. Camps for growing up.
Oh. Well, damn.
What am I doing here then?
Welcome.
-Thank you.
I can help you.
What's this pussy's name?
-Pussy.
Careful now. Nicely done.
Is it clear for all
that this is a dry camp? -What?
This is my seventh camp.
It's really important to meet on
an alcohol-free plain at these camps.
This is champagne.
It's drunk for the taste.
I have cheeses and strawberries, too.
Not everyone can afford that. Did you
consider those who are less well-off?
There are people
who do real work here.
Did you really think proletarians
can afford champagne?
Wonderful!
Do you see how genuine
your communication is already?
As camp leader,
I should make myself unnecessary.
But because of that, and
despite that, we will remain sober.
I can't make these disappear.
-We'll hold onto them for you.
At least let me have the cheeses.
It smells good,
and I'm sure it is tasty, too.
The lavatories are over there,
around the corner.
The sauna is heated every day.
It's a good place to get clean.
Now for an important announcement!
The well water from the taps
is not drinkable.
It contains a bacterial strain.
We brought enough drinking water
from the mainland. just ask me.
The indoor toilets are not in use.
For the common good,
I recommend you keep this in mind.
Go ahead.
-Where are the horses?
There are no horses here.
There were in the video.
Right! The horses!
Yes. My dear friends -
those horses symbolise a free mind.
This is where the lodgings are.
How about you take this room?
You brought your beloved pet?
-No. This is not beloved at all.
But you brought it anyway. Room mate,
you don't have allergies, right?
You could go here.
Let's go this way, men.
I was supposed to share
a two-person room with Viivi.
Who is this Viivi?
The lady who was late. It's supposed
to be a two-person room.
These are,
but you can easily fit three persons.
If I get my good friend to come,
can we have a two-person room?
Anything can always be arranged.
Petri will surely switch if you want
to take the upper cabin with me. -No.
Eyes closed! Here comes Boss Pig!
Boss Pig is going!
Little piggies, open your eyes
and guess who's under the blanket.
Whoever answers correctly gets
to be the next Boss Pig.
Is it Mervi under there?
-Mervi works in the kitchens.
It's... What was her name?
-Alli.
No, I am Alli.
It's that Pussy's mum.
What was her name?
When you have reached your own goal,
you can pop the balloon.
How can we help to achieve this goal
of 'break from pussy“?
All of us women could stay far away
from this person. Would that help?
These camps are free of intoxicants
and sex. That's a useless goal.
You don't have to stay away.
I'm sick of nobody being interested
in what I'm thinking.
Women only see me
as a sex symbol and a rock star.
It's really tough.
I don't want women to beg for sex
or make a fuss about who I am.
Excuse me, but who are you?
-Don't you know?
It looks like
I reached my goal already.
Darling, call or text me.
I'm concerned.
You can't come here
in the middle of everything.
And I still don't understand why you
wanted to come here in particular.
But I'm now here
and you are God knows where.
I can see that you have
unresolved issues.
Yeah, absolutely.
You are filled with fear,
and that causes you to lie.
I see lies as different colours
when they come out of you.
It's interesting that you're fearful.
That usually reduces with age.
What do you fear? -That I'll have
to listen to your shit for a week!
Stop! Shoo, evil energy be gone!
Here is a crystal surface,
and its rainbow light repels evil.
Are you saying grace?
Yes.
Unbelievable. That's really great.
Help yourselves.
Get off!
Excuse me, cook.
Could you please present the menu?
For starters,
there is bread and butter.
The main course is minced meat sauce,
potatoes, carrots, and cauliflower.
For dessert, there is coffee and
a slice of coffee bread. Thank you.
What about the vegetarian menu?
For starters,
there is bread and butter.
The main course is potatoes, carrots,
and cauliflower. You can add butler.
For dessert, coffee
and coffee bread. Thank you.
Thank you.
Are you trying to kill me?
You had slipped in garlic,
even though I informed I am allergic.
There was no garlic.
Was this in it?
Isn't that chili sauce?
Don't you read the label?
It says 'garlic'.
I've never heard of a garlic allergy.
You have my apologies.
That's not much help
when my throat closes up.
I'm a nurse. What symptoms
do you have? -My ears are itchy.
Nothing else. My ears are itchy.
Then it's nothing fatal.
I didn't pay to come here
and have itchy ears.
The food was wonderful
Thank you, cook.
No. Come now.
Are you playing horse?
-No.
This is useless.
Do you want my help?
Do you want me to take the photo?
I don't know. This is ridiculous.
I want to go home.
We've only just started.
The sea is wonderful, there
are lovely rocks and people, and...
Even if there are no horses here.
I've been lying.
I miss my kids terribly.
Do you have children?
-Yes. Four.
And before you ask,
yes, I am Laestadian.
Okay. How come you are
at this kind of camp?
I'm supposedly at a riding camp.
I'm trying to send
deceptive photos home.
I just want to know what people
think and what they believe in.
I don't meet anyone
from outside the community-
and I've been really tired.
Then when I saw the horses
in the advert -
I told myself that this isn't
such a big lie, but it really is.
Does this lie mean
that you'll end up in...
Where will you end up? In damnation?
Hopefully not.
Are you in this room?
-Looks like it.
Then lam not.
Bloody hell, come on now!
...60.
Sorry, I didn't mean to startle you.
I'm just having a work-out.
I've been thinking.
I have those really nice cheeses -
and the strawberries
are not half-bad, either.
Do you fancy going for
a row to watch the sunset?
A little picnic.
With me? -Yes, you. It would
be nice to get to know you.
I'm not keen on strong cheeses.
You two should go.
That cat can't come in the boat.
Sure she can.
-No, she can't.
I switched rooms with Alli.
I can't share a room
with that intolerant idiot.
If I go out, my curls will get wet.
I'm not going out. I'm not.
Let me hold you.
So soft...
It's mine. I want it.
What SPF is that?
"Tepsi went into labour."
The number can't be reached.
"Tepsi went into labour.'
Is Tepsi the dog?
-I guess so.
What will we do now?
We'll order a taxi, go home,
and demand refunds.
I can't just leave. We've paid,
so it must be okay to stay.
I'd also like to stay.
You know what?
I think this is our guru's method.
By disappearing,
he is making us rely on each other.
This is actually quite ingenious.
Now we can do whatever we want.
Let's play truth or dare,
and get to know each other properly.
I have a lot of experience in running
these kinds of camps.
If you want, I can take over here.
Let's make this
a politically aware camp!
I'm a child of the summer
I'm wild by nature
My worries are all gone
Nothing beats these summer nights
There are no tight belts
when I run towards the sea
The summer state of mind is wild
I would want to fall in love
with everyone
I would really want to kiss you
My heart is beating
I see you coming
This tastes like life
You are cute.
I bring you a message.
Our theme is time -
and we're living in the wrong order-
so could you turn the food
arrangements on its head? -How?
Dinner at lunch time
and breakfast at supper time.
There's no difference.
Right. There isn't.
When Emma took charge
of the programme -
she put an end
to us having our phones.
I have one phone call
that I really have to make.
Can I leave this here with you?
Kalle left. Did you know?
He left in the night.
His dog went into labour.
I'm not sad to see that homo gone.
-Come on, now.
How much did you pay for this camp?
-800 euros.
My Lord!
He's made out like a bandit.
He can't be left with much after
the rent, food, and your wage.
This place doesn't cost anything.
The main building has damp.
He's pulling in at least six grand.
You've been paid, right?
-Yes. I'll do what I agreed.
Put the phone on the shelf.
I'll keep an eye on it.
You are a nice person.
What's going on? Swimming costumes
off. This is a mixed sauna.
It's still a mixed sauna like this.
Unashamed nudity is the best way
to clear all the erotic tension.
Okay. Get to it.
I can't come in
because I've had a small operation.
So let's get to know each other
better on the veranda.
Pants off!
It's far too hot in here.
What do you do, in civilian life?
Jouko, come and swim
if it was too hot!
Hey, we've swapped pants.
-These did feel a little different.
Do you want them?
-Let's swap in the sauna.
What the hell, this is icy cold.
Just get in there!
Do you think
you're younger then me?
Jouko, why are you there when
everyone else is in order of age?
Saara, you can't decide
how old somebody else feels.
It's not like I'm as old as you,
but I am in a spiritual sense.
I can't help it that men are more
fertile than women later in life.
If you feel you're on the Eastern
side of the hill, it can't be helped.
Whose phone is on?
Just because you can procreate,
it doesn't mean you're 20!
Look next to you!
They could be your kids.
My children are still small.
I'm in better physical condition
than I was at twenty.
Young women still find me
to have great performance.
I have more time ahead of me
than behind me. So I'm standing here.
What are you talking about?
Men have a lower life expectancy.
A realistic place for you
would be over there!
You have a gut, even though
you exercise in the bushes.
And you eat butter and sausages
just like old men do.
You'll fall into your grave, even if
you're with a five-year-old woman!
Look what the menopause can cause.
You have the menopause in your pants.
I'm sorry.
Saara, this cat is suffering.
I smell the urine
of a stressed out animal.
She always smells like that.
Against my will, I can read animals.
That cat is depressed.
What breed is it'!
-Norwegian Forest cat.
Of course. She hates being inside,
imprisoned.
She's an indoors cat.
She lives in a flat.
But here, she can smell
the forest and the sea.
There are forests
and the sea in Norway.
Do you normally clean that
in the morning? -In the evening.
This day is turned on its head.
You don't seem to grasp that.
Neither does this cat!
Am I supposed to push these turds
back into her?
Think. Who was your outburst for?
Who are you angry at?
That's an important key for you.
Hey. Are you going to bed already?
Would you come to the rocks with me?
The rocks that are
in the sun all day?
I guess.
-I'll come, I'll come!
I just need to throw Pussy's...
I'm coming.
I thought you might want
to watch the news, too.
The internet works fine here.
What's wrong? Are you in pain?
No. I've just had a tiring day.
It's my own fault.
I've not drunk enough.
It's easy to forget when you can't
get it straight from the tap.
I always have water in this.
Have some.
Do you feel better?
-It helped straight away. Thank you.
What do you have...
Something was taken for a test.
Globally, the world
is shockingly unequal.
Today, we get a glimpse
into how the other half lives.
This makes sense.
One of you is a rich Westerner.
Two of you are quite poor,
the other five are really poor...
Would you swap?
I read a magazine article
about poverty.
It was a good depiction of what
happens in a person's head -
when they must turn down everything
and live a crushing routine.
They become exhausted and lose hope.
A person without hope is dangerous
because they have nothing to lose.
What is your wage, for example?
In general or for this week?
-For just this week.
It's none of your business, but 700.
700! -It's not too much. I work long
days and the hours are not recorded.
Shockingly little. After taxes,
you're left with barely anything.
Don't worry about that. This backdoor
boy pays under the table.
You have to pay tax. Taxation
is the best thing that Finland has.
We have to report this.
How could we do that without her...
I don't know. I'm going fishing
to get ingredients for the fish soup.
Here are the kitchen keys.
Help yourself to the water.
Has Alli been put
on the hunger squad?
We drew lots, like in real life.
Don't you talk about things
you know nothing about, sour fish.
You weren't born a garlic princess.
You've been raised like that.
Oh, like that.
-Try it.
This party platform is not going
to work when we're so hungry.
My blood sugar is so low, all my
energy is going into basic functions.
That sounds like you don't believe
the poor are capable of democracy.
I didn't say that.
I want honest answers. Put your
hand up if you have missed Kalle.
Who is Kalle?
-Right.
We're doing what he said.
He made himself unnecessary.
What the hell!
Who has got their phone on?
Marika Lammi is calling.
Nobody knows who she is?
There's no need to call this number!
I'm switching this off if nobody
owns up that it belongs to them!
The revolution has begun! I
commandeered the means of production!
If you want to join me, follow me!
When a person is a person
They need some bread
Idle talk doesn't repel hunger
or make empty full
So left, one, two
Where is your place, do you know?
Proletarians are marching here
You are a proletarian, too
What do you know about proletarians?
My dad did hard work for a low wage,
and provided for me by himself.
Sol probably know more than you!
What's with him?
-Revolution.
What's next'! I represent
high finance. Should I be concerned?
You should.
Your day in the sun is over.
You bloody fool.
Was that the key to the kitchen?
Did you have the key to the kitchen?
-Yes.
Do you morons realise
that was the only key'! Get it!
I'm not a strong swimmer.
-You only need to be able to dive.
I'm not good at that, either.
-Anyone can get to the bottom.
Where did it go?
-Over there, somewhere.
It's dark under the surface.
Far-sighted people can't see.
Don't come and whip up the water!
The landlord is sending another key.
We have to wait until the morning.
Let's break the window.
That's one way to get in.
You'll smash the place up
over my dead body.
We can all survive until the morning.
This was in our room.
Is this all the water we have?
I'm really disappointed.
You came to a communal camp -
and you are being anarchic.
-I came to a different camp.
Is Jouko's champagne in your room?
-We could go and get it.
It's mine.
And it wasn't exactly cheap.
In a crisis, you might consider
your Bible teachings.
Everyone was fed
with five loaves and two fish.
Of course I will give it
for communal use.
My body rejects alcohol.
That's good.
It leaves more for the others.
But the water is for Alli.
If someone saves some,
the others don't get any!
I wish it was at least organic.
Even though wine also contains
alcohol, and my body resists it...
...the production process of wine
is age-old and really natural.
Luckily, even a delicate person
can somehow manage to drink it.
Can I use this as kindling?
-Go ahead.
How did these people end up here?
The weirdest bunch ever.
There is a video advert online.
As to why somebody came here,
only that person knows that.
Why did you?
My mum died in the spring.
I cared for her for ten years,
in addition to my own work.
I'm not complaining,
but that was the life I had.
Then when she died,
I didn't really have anything.
Do you have children?
-No.
Do you have a man?
-That hasn't worked out for me.
Do you have?
-Nobody has wanted me.
Probably too ugly.
-You're not ugly. Not at all.
Do you have children?
-No. I don't really have anything.
There's no slowing you down.
Do you want some?
Play something that we can dance to.
That's good, keep going.
Listen to my body and go with it.
Play on!
I need to take a piss.
Teach me, too. I don't know how to
tango. -Sorry, the band's on a break.
Come and play some more.
It looks really bad when an old goat
is all over a young lassie like that.
Don't bother taking
your frustration out on me.
Charisma has nothing to do
with how tight your trousers are.
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
You followed me into the bushes.
For the exact same reason as you.
Can I please pee in peace?
-No.
I want to check out
the competition's equipment.
Get the hell out of here.
Come on, don't be shy now.
Get the fuck out of here!
The fuck! Stop that, bloody hell.
How ridiculous!
Seventh grade boys fight like that.
He has a need to show off.
Besides, she is married.
A Laestadian mother-of-four.
I knew that.
We've talked about everything.
She's not into either of you.
She has a good relationship.
How do you know'!
What makes you think
she'd be interested in you?
You have nothing in common.
-Is that so?
She is smart, friendly,
empathic, and damned attractive.
You definitely
don't have that in common!
You are boring, ugly, and old.
And not particularly wise!
Prick.
It opens your mouth
to the highest thank you
Stick up for yourself.
Taking wouldn't help at all.
I have a history.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you terribly thirsty?
-I'll survive.
Let's go to the rocks.
I can teach you something.
Hi, it's me.
There's no reason
to send suspicious text messages.
The raging leader of this camp
answered my phone.
Good night, darling.
Write something nicer next time. Bye.
Hi, darling. I'm wondering why
I've not heard anything from you.
I should be offended that you stood
me up and didn't tell me why.
But I'll see you when I'm back.
Bye then.
Hi, it's me calling.
We're having a break, so I thought
I'd ask how you are doing.
I miss the sauna and my own bed.
And you. Say hello to the kids.
This is the day when the sky is clear
Full moon, late at night
The moonlight shines on some kisses
Hey, sweetheart,
I got hot like a supernova
I'll bring you stars
if you'll come to the dock with me
Teach younger ones
to talk about their feelings
So they'll make it when they notice
How many candlelit nights there are
You can keep the soul you took
Tonight it's magic and wishes
Tonight, tonight, tonight
It'll happen when the gate opens
Tonight it'll happen
You can get the overtones
by making your mouth an echo chamber.
Did you hear?
This is so unreal.
I've never stayed up this late,
apart from when breastfeeding.
You are amazing.
Four kids and still your tit...
...thinking is so open.
I'm grateful for the chance
to get to know someone like you.
People have the opportunity
to get to know all kinds of people.
They don't.
A meat ring of pushy broads has
formed between me and the world.
I'm unable to reach
the place where real people are.
Is not every person a real person
and just as valuable?
At least in God's eyes.
Yes, naturally. You are so clever.
Will you be my soul sister?
I don't smoke.
You don't drink, either.
Today is different.
Isn't it God's will,
if he doesn't give us water?
Even Jesus drank wine.
Try it. Then at least you know
what you are turning down.
I want to turn that down.
Let's try that overtones thing again.
I want to hear your overtones.
Do you forgive me?
I guess that is less harmful
than drinking or smoking.
So can I try it again?
I've only ever kissed
my husband like that.
I've never kissed anyone like that!
It's never felt that good.
You poor thing. I was just thinking
it's good that I tried this.
Because it feels the best
to kiss my husband.
I want you.
-What a shame.
Can't we put this experience
on the same tab?
That tab is not open.
I love my husband.
You mean you're turning me down?
-Yes.
Don't you realise how offended
it makes you feel to be rejected?
You knew there was that risk.
-I didn't. Nobody's ever rejected me.
I'm going to bed. Good night.
I'll pray that you will also find
joy and peace.
This could leave me
with a lifelong trauma.
If I can no longer get it up, it's
your fault! -I'll pray about that.
Would you like some good sex?
Can we go on the hot rocks?
-No. It's bloody cold there.
Have you got any rubbers?
Wait, I'll take this off.
Could you put it on?
-Yeah.
Ignore it. He talks in his sleep.
Quiet down!
Can't we have a single night
where he doesn't start that racket?
Mercy! Not the Saarenmaa waltz.
What are you fiddling about for?
I'm shagging.
-Go somewhere else to shag.
What's up?
-I forgot Pussy.
Now she's out there, alone.
Have you seen Pussy?
-No.
Pussy!
Another example
of the power of prayer. -What?
You aren't impotent,
even though I shot you down.
Apparently.
Why did you have to do that?
I was pissed off. I'm sorry.
I don't understand why someone
has to shag all the time.
You no longer even realise
the purpose of shagging.
Can I pray for you?
-You can.
Where's Maya: Hwy gone'!?
Sorry, did I interrupt you?
-No. It was a very short prayer.
Dear Lord,
make Ville slightly less stupid.
She hasn't slept in her bed.
It's wonderful to watch someone
do physical work. -Yes, to watch.
Could you mow carefully, so Pussy
doesn't end up being scythed?
Has anybody seen Emma?
You've been busy. You had Saara
under you a few hours ago.
Shut your face!
You released her, didn't you?
-Why would I release your pussy?
You wanted to get back at me.
Besides, she's my ex's mum's,
and I'll never be forgiven for this.
Don't worry. Cats always come back.
it's Emma who is missing.
Should we look for her?
Or do we just accept
that we disappear, one by one?
Okay then.
Thank you.
What fun do we have in store today -
at this camp that is free
of intoxicants and sex?
Have I shagged someone?
-No.
I've let myself down,
and also you and mother earth -
and I've soiled my body's temple.
As a repentance exercise, I declare
that this is now a silent retreat.
What does that mean in practise?
Should I warm up the sauna?
Not everyone smells of roses.
This is my cleanest shirt. [thought
there'd be a washing machine.
You haven't even bothered to text me.
If you want us to continue,
meet me at the harbour.
The time and place is in the email
about the camp. Goodbye.
Do you have regrets?
-About what?
This. It's comforting to see
that even angels can fall.
What those photos show does not
hurt anybody. -I'm sure it doesn't.
When they are published, you might
think about who you go with.
This is worth more than the gossip
magazine's standard 50 euro fee.
I can't even get dry logs
to light on fire.
I wouldn't say that.
The air pressure is too low.
Can I have a go?
He secretly took photos
when you kissed me.
When we were kissing.
He'll sell them to a magazine.
My lie will be revealed.
What? Who?
-Jouko.
Oh Christ.
Jouko, give me your phone.
It's an emergency.
For who?
-Kaisa-Leena.
What the...
-Don't come here!
Wait!
What the hell?
What are you doing?
You've ruined my life!
You won't destroy Kaisa-Leena's.
You let Pussy out! -I didn't!
I released the cat. She's a forest
cat. She should be free!
You fucking idiot!
What right did you have to do that?
Do you understand
anything about anything?
This affects my, my ex's,
and my ex's mum's life!
Do you ever think about anything
other than yourself?
You're an attention-seeking grump.
I know that everybody here
agrees with me.
You are the most detestable person
I've ever met! Bloody hell.
This makes no sense.
What are we doing here?
Why are we here?
Why are we not leaving?
Mervi, order me a boat.
I want to get out of here.
You can want all you want,
but you can't.
The weather forecast tells that
no boat will be able to dock here.
It looks like your spiritual growth
course has not finished.
One of you cannot speak
and another is having a tantrum.
The only thing you can do
is try to grow!
What is it?
I'm scared. I'm scared of lightning.
Let's move the bed
away from the window.
Oh, it's attached.
Come here for the worst of it.
Everything's fine,
there's no need to be scared.
Hey, excuse me.
The power is out. I thought you
should know, if the food... -Yeah.
Try to calm down.
It's a perfectly normal storm.
We need to find Emma.
-Yes. I'll go to save the food.
A big branch has fallen and brought
the guttering down with it.
Doesn't seem to be a problem
with the power lines.
Come now!
Emma.
Lightning! Take me!
-She's in the sea, near the sauna!
You can't go in the water
during a storm!
God of Thunder, come and get me!
I'm stupid and detestable!
I'm sorry!
Help! Saara fell into the water!
I'm coming to rescue you!
I'm going to drown.
I'll rescue you soon.
Petri! Get up!
I rescued you!
Is that Mervi?
There is a boat. We are saved.
Where are you going?
There were calls for help.
You could just as easily walk
to the shore from here.
Mervi.
How come you were there?
I thought you were in the kitchen.
I was fetching the generator,
but we'll make do without then.
Why do you have your bag with you?
Take her to the common cabin,
and let's get the fire started.
Go and change into dry clothes.
I don't have any. They are all wet.
Surely someone will lend
some clothes?
I don't think our trousers would fit.
You have dry underwear, at least?
Why are you angry at me?
I can't help myself.
Anything goes in an emergency.
I'm so tired that I'm going to
collapse. I have to go to bed.
Good night.
-Good night.
I see and know so many things,
and I just want to help -
but everybody hates me.
Can you really help people? Everyone
needs to make their own mistakes.
It's easy for you to say.
You are flawless and beautiful.
You don't pass out at the campfire.
I have nothing.
You are all doing better than me.
We are not.
-I'm the flawed one here.
I'm filled with guilt.
I'm here and I have lied.
You have a husband, family, and
unrestrained relatives. You're happy.
What do you know about my happiness?
Ville, you got to kiss her.
Women find you interesting.
Answer honestly.
Do any of you find me interesting?
I knew it.
Are you not interested in me,
even this much?
I am, as a person.
-As a person.
Why doesn't anybody respond
to me as a man?
People don't respond to me
even as a person.
Nobody remembered my name
when we played Boss Pig.
I'm a grey back wall.
-No, you're not.
I rescued you.
You are a mother figure to me.
I really want to be the mother figure
for a man in his thirties.
I'm all alone. I don't have anything.
You don't have anything?
You're a millionaire.
You only need to snap your fingers,
and you get whatever you want.
You're kidding me.
You're Peter Manner!
I'm a leftist though.
Money means nothing to me.
That's why I wanted to hide it,
so I could speak politics for a week.
I'm on the side of the poor.
A leftist millionaire who can't swim.
Being rich is shit.
I don't have time to spend
any of my money.
Being rich is like being dead.
I can't dream of anything.
I can't even dream
about becoming rich one day.
I know what you mean.
I feel the same about eternal life.
If you go to heaven after you die,
then what next?
It just continues and continues,
forever.
You can't ever leave.
That's the terrible thing
about faith.
There is no end.
The happiness just continues.
My happiness doesn't continue.
My husband left me
and my kids have left home.
I don't have a clue
what I am without them!
It's not like anybody here
looks particularly happy.
Guess what this reminds me of.
-What then?
The Devil took Jesus up a mountain,
and showed all he could have.
But you stay strong, like Jesus.
-I really don't.
Looking from this mountain,
what would you want?
You, you, you.
Don't. It would be easier
to become your soul sister -
if you cut out that desire.
My self-esteem is completely trashed.
Would it help if I blew you?
Sorry. I couldn't help it.
You're so predictable.
That's cruel.
-I'm sorry.
Tell me, why do you
constantly think about sex?
I don't know. Maybe it's the most fun
thing I've ever done.
You poor thing.
You've not experienced much.
Some melted ice cream,
as a thank you to the yard clearers.
Do you want me to still lead
this camp day?
You're at least better
than that guru bloke.
It's not going to charge when
there's no electricity -I'm sorry.
Can I leave it here,
in case I get a call? -Yes, you can!
I thought I might take a look
at the power switchboard -
because it doesn't look like
any lines are down on the island.
I don't want there to be
any more accidents here.
I'm a certified electrician.
I have my paperwork in my wallet,
but it's a bit damp.
If you manage to fix the power -
you can choose any treat
for the evening party. I'll make it.
You're quite a guy.
The power came on! We have power.
Thank you. You are remarkable.
What did you want then?
Can I have this?
The dress?
-Yes.
Can I have it?
-Yes, yes.
Alli! It's your phone.
Yeah. In a week
or on the coming Monday?
To the same counter
as when I came for the biopsy?
It's not your fault.
Thank you. Goodbye.
What?
What was it?
Cancer. The aggressive kind.
I'll go into hospital on Monday.
No...
What do you mean, "no"?
If you don't want me when I'm
healthy, don't grope a dying woman.
Alli, I...
-Go to hell.
The table has been set.
Not yet.
Don't die.
Promise me that you won't die.
Thank you for yelling at me.
Your aura is much brighter.
And sorry about the cat.
-I'd already forgotten about that.
What am I going to say
to my ex's mum?
My dad used to say, when you're
in a tight spot, try the truth.
Do you plan on trying the truth?
-I will try.
It's not a problem for you.
I admire your courage to face things
and show your emotions.
Thank you. It was nice.
You're a really good listener. I wish
I'd have had a mother like you.
You're pretty attractive for your
age, and scary when you get mad.
This was a compliment, by the way.
You are practically everything.
Versatile, fun, optimistic, and open.
You're a chill person.
Easy to be with.
Iron rusts in time
And wreaths also wither
On the journey
The scenery changes
Ice and snow on the sea melted
It's getting lighter
On the shore of the sea
The field wind feels warm
Look, there is wind in the willows
It doesn't end here
This should cover it.
-Yes, thanks.
Emma, wait over there.
I'll go and get my car.
When do you need to be back home?
-In the morning. I'll take the train.
We have a gig at Verkatehdas.
We can take you to Hämeenlinna.
You can take the same train
from there. -Should I?
It's God's will or we wouldn't have
a gig that's on the way to Oulu.
You can put your things
on the back seat.
Why are you wearing a dress?
-There was a huge storm.
Did you lose your pussy?
-Yeah.
There's a picture
of a cat on that post.
Jouko, come out. You've been spotted.
There's been some new info. Give
me the key. This marriage is over.
Someone's got the wrong end
of the stick.
“There's talk of divorce.'
Bollocks. How many of us are there?
The key! -And here.
That was two years of my life!
I've been with him for 23 years.
Take that.
Was this the key for the garage
or yours? -Don't fucking ask me.
Saara. My lift was cancelled.
Or lifts.
I saw. Look.
“Your new life starts here"?
Could it be Kalle's message?
Could you give me a lift somewhere?
Where were you thinking of going?
How about I come to yours?
No way!
Where am I going to go then?
-How should I know?
Are your parents alive?
Mum is. In Mikkeli.
Don't open it.
- What the hell?
I don't want to see you.
Your mum's cat ran away,
but was found. Here are the details.
Don't touch the door.
I'll leave the carrier here.
What are you up to?
Tell your mum about the divorce and
take responsibility for your life!
Subtitles: Dominic Cullen
BTI Studios