[cheering]
[labored breathing, heart thumping]
[clock ticking fast]
Let's go!
- I'm open, I'm open.
- I don't see it!
- Take your time!
- Run!
- Go, go!
- Let's go!
- [Audience] Defense! Defense!
Come on,
man!
- Hustle, hustle!
- Control that ball!
- Bolton! I'm open!
- Set it up! Let's go!
All right, let's go!
Let's move! Let's move!
- Watch the run in.
- Watch the back door!
- Get it!
- [Buzzer rings]
[announcer] That concludes
the first half of play
in our final game,
with the West High Knights
leading defending champion
East High Wildcats 47 - 26.
Sixteen minutes remain in the game.
All right! No more X's and O's. OK?
Forget about the scoreboard because
here's a number that matters.
Sixteen. There's 16 minutes
left in this game, guys.
There's only 16 minutes
left in the season.
And for the seniors
on this squad... guys...
You've only got 16 minutes
left in a Wildcat uniform.
So make them count.
Sixteen minutes to be a team.
Captains!
All right.
Hey, guys.
Now, you heard Coach.
We're all gonna remember
the next 16 minutes
for a long time
after we leave East High.
So it's now or never.
Chad.
- What team?
- Wildcats!
[cheering]
# Sixteen, 16, 16 minutes left
Better get it done
# Sixteen, 16, 16 more minutes
Get ready, game on!
# Sixteen, 16, 16 minutes left
Running out of time
# Sixteen, 16, 16 more minutes
And it's on the line
# Sixteen, 16, 16 minutes left
Got to get it done
# Sixteen, 16, 16 more minutes
till we're number one!
# W-I-L-D Wildcats!
Huddle up! Let's go!
Come on, come on
Ready?
Break!
# W-I-L-D Wildcats!
Now's the time
# Got to get it inside
Down low, in the paint, now shoot
# Score!
- # Gotta work together.
- Defense!
# Give me the ball
# Fast break, keep the ball
in control, let it fly from downtown
# Three more
- # Show them we can do better.
- # No way!
Come on, boys!
# The way we play tonight
is what we leave behind
# it all comes down
to right now, it's up to us
- # Let's go!
- # So what are we gonna be
# T-E-A-M
Team!
# Gotta work it out
Turn it on
# This is the last time to get it right
# This is the last chance
to make it our night
# We got to show what we're all about
- # Work together.
- Time out!
# This is the last chance to make
our mark, history will know who we are
# This is the last game so make
it count, it's now or never
- Hey! That's a foul!
- Oh, dear.
[heart thumping]
- You OK?
- Come on, Troy!
Let's go, buddy!
# Troy
# Right now I can hardly breathe
# Oh, you can do it
Just know that I believe
# And that's all I really need
- # Then come on.
- # Make me strong
# it's time to turn it up
Game on!
# Wildcats gonna tear it up
Go, Wildcats, yeah, we're number one
[groans]
Foul!
- Yeah!
- All right!
- What?
- Yeah!
# Let me hear you say
Hey, hey, hey, yeah
I'm tripled-teamed.
I can't get a shot off.
- What do you want to do?
- Let's put in Rocket Man.
Rocket Man?
- Troy, you're two points away from...
- I know.
- Just get me the ball.
- OK.
Rocket Man! Come on!
Come on, Rocket Man! You're in!
- Get in here!
- Go!
- Let's go!
- Move!
Go, go, go! Move!
Yeah! Oh, yeah!
Calm down, OK?
- All right, keep your eyes on me.
- # Game on!
# This is the last time to get it right
# This is the last chance
to make it our night
# We gotta show what we're
all about, team! Work together
# This is the last chance
to make our mark
# History will know who we are
# This is the last game so make it count
it's now or never #
Come on!
Shoot it!
Yes!
We won, dude! We won! You OK?
[gasping]
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about. Yeah!
I'm pushing.
- You better be.
- I'm pushing!
- Push harder!
- Chad, tree!
Home sweet home.
- I'm saving for a new fuel pump.
- Mm-hm. Save faster.
[pop music plays]
Hey, turn it up, Kels.
- How you doing, girl?
- I'm good!
- Great comeback!
- Thanks.
- Watch that tail. It's dangerous.
- You know it!
- Amazing! We won!
- I didn't think they'd come back.
Hey!
- Congratulations!
- Thanks. Can I fix you a plate?
- I want one of everything!
- Are we celebrating?
What's up, Hoops?
- Back-to-back champions!
- Yeah, thanks.
Coach, got a couple
of empty lockers at U of A?
Hopefully not for long.
Charlie Danforth
will suit up next season.
Front row seat will be fine.
That teamwork I saw tonight, that assist
where you gave up the final shot,
that's the kind of players
I'm looking for.
We're going to see you
in Redhawk uniforms?
- Done deal.
- Amen to that.
- Go have some fun.
- OK.
- Congratulations, Troy!
- Hey! Thanks.
- Yo!
- Hey, dude!
Sweet game!
Hey, Troy. Great house, bro.
Your room is way cool.
Thanks, man. You were in my room?
Well, yeah. I just took a picture. Look.
- I'm doing mine the same way.
- Great.
We should hang out tonight.
Get to know each other or something.
I just gotta grab the championship
trophy I left it in my truck.
- Don't sweat it! I'm on it!
- OK.
Hi!
So, another top-secret hiding place?
You're the second girl I've had up here.
The first was my mom.
She only climbed up here to get me down.
Well, I'm honored.
This place is so cool.
Me and my dad built it.
[Gabriella] That the coach
from U of A down there?
- Yeah. He's at my house.
- Yeah.
Crazy.
I bet he's already got
your name on a locker.
It's always been my dad's dream. Now
I'm going to end up at his alma mater.
Did I just say that?
My mom and I have been talking about
Stanford pretty much since I was born.
And you're already in. That's so cool.
Except she won't stop talking
about it. It's embarrassing.
Come on. She's proud of you.
I'm proud of you.
The thing about Stanford
is it's a thousand and fifty...
Fifty-three miles from here.
I know.
It suddenly seems like the rest
of the school year is coming so fast.
Yeah. I wish it would all just stop.
At least just slow down.
# Can you imagine what would happen
# if we could have any dream?
# I'd wish this moment
was ours to own it
# And that it would never leave
# Then I would thank that star
# That made our wish come true
# Oh, yeah
# 'Cause he knows that where you are
# ls where I should be too
# Right here
# Right now
- # Right now.
- # I'm looking at you
# And my heart loves the view
- # 'Cause you mean everything.
- # Everything
# Right here
# I promise you somehow
# Somehow we're gonna
# Tomorrow can wait
for some other day to be
# To be, but right now
there's you and me
# Oh, we know it's coming
# And it's coming fast
# it's always you and me
- # So let's make every second last.
- [Giggles]
# Make it last
# 'Cause right here
# Right now
# Yeah, I'm looking at you
# And my heart loves the view
# 'Cause you mean everything
# Right here
# I promise you somehow
# That tomorrow can wait
# For some other day to be
# To be, but right now
there's you and me
- # You and me.
- # You and me
# You and me
# But right now there's
# You and me #
Is this a pirate's wheel?
No.
[laughs]
Very cute.
I haven't played
with Robo-Rob since third grade.
- I'm Robo-Rob. I am...
- Don't break him. Don't break him.
- That's Chad's.
- Sure it is.
Now it's just like kindergarten.
Troy? You have guests.
Don't make me come up there
and get you again. Hi, Gabriella.
We'll be right down, Mom.
She really will come up here
if we don't go down.
Oh, OK.
Right there, right there. OK,
come on through. Come on. There you go.
[sighs]
Wow.
[whistles]
Hey, Troy.
So, when's the big game?
[cell phone rings]
Uh, yesterday.
Oh, well. Good luck.
- Wow.
- She's so sweet.
[boy gasps]
What are you? I mean, who are you?
Good morning, Ms. Evans. I'm Tiara Gold.
I transferred
to East High from London
and I noticed on the board you're
in need of a personal assistant.
Yeah, with finals, prom, graduation,
I need someone tracking
my appointments and assignments.
Most important, I need someone
to run lines for the musical.
- That's a theater term for...
- Learning your role. I understand.
It's best to keep
science and math books together,
since those are
first lessons of the day.
How do you know my schedule?
I took the liberty of checking,
simply to make certain
I'd have your nonfat, no-foam,
soy latte ready for free period.
- One packet of sweetener?
- Organic.
I'll e-mail you my wardrobe choices each
morning so that our outfits won't clash.
If you own any orange, get rid of it.
By the way, like the accent.
It's... sweet.
Troy, my brother.
Can I have your gym locker?
- What?
- Like starting next week.
I'll be running the team next season
and it'll help me out with the guys.
- Yeah, why didn't I think of that?
- I don't know.
[school bell rings]
Tardy again. Later, bro!
Are you serious?
What about her... Hey.
All right, everyone. Settle down.
We are all excited about our Wildcats'
- top-to-bottom championships.
- That would be "back-to-back."
Whatever the case,
it was a grand slam. Well done!
And our student body president
and co-editor of the yearbook,
Taylor McKessie,
has important announcements.
Senior trip committee meets tomorrow
and reports Thursday to prom committee,
headed by Martha.
Pick up your tickets from her.
This year's theme is "The Last Waltz."
But don't be last to pick up tickets.
Graduation committee convenes Monday.
Picture deadline is Thursday
and finals study groups alternate
with all of the above. Questions?
What's the lunch special
in the cafeteria?
New York deli. Anyone else?
Moving on. Ms. Sharpay Evans, four-term
president of the drama club,
spring musicale report.
Well, with prom, finals,
everyone is so busy.
I was thinking
I'd select something modest.
Perhaps even a one-woman show.
A little light on the sign-ups, Kelsi?
No. We're actually doing pretty well.
Well, well, well.
Almost the entire homeroom.
[Sharpay groans]
How inspiring!
I will happily see all of you
at free period to discuss the show
and to make a very special announcement.
[school bell rings]
[chattering]
I'll be retaking my finals two or three
times. I'm moving into the library.
I'm working on my truck every day.
I've got five recipes
for Family Science final.
We've got a yearbook to edit, so no.
Sorry! Jeez. I thought since it was the
last show, everyone would want to do it.
- You're wrong.
- We just don't have time.
Hey. Hey, you guys, listen up.
Kelsi's right. We should do this.
This is our last chance
to do something together.
All of us. Something really fun.
Oh, yippee.
So, what do you say, Wildcats?
No, I still don't think
it's a good idea.
- Guys, come on! It's our senior year!
- Troy.
We're all in this together.
This is our senior year.
I'm in.
What?
- It will be fun.
- Yes!
- Oh, boy.
- How much time will it take?
Yeah. And what the heck
is the show about?
You, Mr. Danforth.
Me?
The spring musicale is all about you.
Hold up. If it's about me, then
can I have my ball back? Please?
- It's about all of you.
- Go!
And all of you will create it.
A show about your final days at
East High. We'll call it Senior Year.
Genius.
Uh-uh-uh! Playing a role is easy,
but being yourself,
now that's a challenge.
Miss Darbus, exactly...
Kelsi will compose,
Ryan will choreograph
- and I will direct.
- Thank you.
Now, I have
some very important news from...
The Juilliard School
in New York City,
America's preeminent college
for the performing arts.
And for the first time
in East High history,
Juilliard is considering four of you
for one available scholarship.
- Miss Sharpay Evans.
- I'm already packed.
- Mr. Ryan Evans.
- Dance.
- Miss Kelsi Nielsen.
- What? They got my letter?
They certainly did.
And, lastly, Mr. Troy Bolton.
What?
Juilliard will be sending
representatives to observe our show.
So good luck to our four applicants.
Yeah, nice. Nice, guys.
That's pretty funny.
So... who's the big comedian?
- Is there something wrong?
- Yeah. Yeah, I didn't apply.
- I've never heard of Juilliard.
- Well, that may be, Mr. Bolton,
but evidently Juilliard
has heard of you.
And as you create this show,
you must dig deep
and think about your aspirations
and dreams for the future.
Line up, downstage, please.
Let's begin with Mr. Danforth.
Step forward, please.
Your future.
It's easy. It's U of A.
Hoops all the way.
- Yeah.
- Miss McKessie.
I'm going to be the President
of the United States.
Oh.
I'm going to finish
college first, of course.
Martha Cox, you're late.
I'm sorry, I just thought maybe
we could use a few more dancers.
[group gasps, chuckles]
I feel a show coming on already!
Mr. Bolton.
- Mr. Bolton.
- Hmm?
- Your future.
- Oh, yeah, uh...
You know... uh...
I've been thinking about...
Uh...
I think we should stage
the perfect prom.
Golly gee, how adorable.
What do I want?
Gosh, I wouldn't know
where to begin.
But I know where it ends.
Center stage.
A single spotlight.
A huge marquee that reads...
New York deli platter, please.
- How can you think about food?
- Maybe because it's lunch time?
No pickles.
Throw that Big Apple parfait in.
OK, this show is our last shot, Ryan.
Sharpay's meal, please.
Thanks. That's great.
Troy pretended
to know nothing about Juilliard.
- Give me a break.
- He seemed surprised to me.
The theater fairy magically
sent in Troy's application?
Performers can't fool me. They're
deceitful, ambitious and ruthless.
- Aren't we performers?
- Exactly.
- Hmm.
- [Scoffs]
# imagine having everything
we ever dreamed
- # Don't you want it?
- # Maybe
- # Can't ya see it?
- # Kinda
# imagine first audition
after college I get the lead
- # A part for me?
- # Well, of course
- # Yeah, right, keep talking.
- # You gotta believe it
- # You and I, all the fame.
- # Sharpay and what's-his-name
- # Sound exciting?
- # Inviting
- # Let's do it then.
- # Listening
# Personal stylist
agent and a publicist
- # But where do I fit into this?
- # With you, we can win
- # Win the part?
- # Think bigger
- # Become superstars?
- # That's better
# Don't you see that bigger is better
# And better is bigger
# A little bit it is never enough
No, no, no
# Don't you want it all?
# You want it
You know that you want it
# The fame and the fortune and more
# You want it all
# You want it
You know that you want it
# You gotta have your star on the door
# You want the world, nothing less
# All the glam and the press
# Only giving you the best reviews
- # Say it!
- # I want it all
# I want it
I want it, want it
# My name in lights at Carnegie Hall
I want it all
- # Can't you see it?
- # Yeah
- # They're gonna love me.
- [Clears throat]
# I mean us
# Red carpet, rose bouquets
Crowd waiting backstage
# I'm with her, don't stop me
I'm not the paparazzi
# invitations
Standing ovations
- # Magazines.
- # Yes, please
# Gonna be celebrities
# Photographs, fan club
Give the people what they love
- # Now you're excited.
- # I like it
- # Let's do it then.
- I love you!
# Times Square, jetsetter
Sequels pay better
# New York today
Tomorrow the world
- # Sold out shows?
- # Think bigger
- # And the Oscar goes to...
- # That's better
# Don't ya see that bigger is
better and better is bigger
# A little bit is never enough
No, no, no
# I want it all
I want it, want it, want it
# The fame and the fortune and more
# I want it all
I want it, want it, want it
# I gotta have my star on the door
# I want the world
Nothing less, all the glam and the press
# Only giving me the best reviews
# I want it all
I want it, want it, want it
# Radio City Music Hall
We want it all
# Here in the spotlight
we shine, look at who we are
# When Broadway knows your name
- Get out of the way!
- # You know that you're a star
# Oh, dance
- Madison Square Garden!
- They love you.
Thank you! Thank you all!
It's Oprah calling.
Again.
She wants you on the show.
They're going to get back to you.
- You know how fast you were going?
- Officer Chad!
Hey, it's Ms. Evans.
How you doing? Follow me.
# I want it
I- I-I want it, want it
# I want it, I want it
I- I-I want it all, yeah
# I want it
I- I-I want it, want it
- # I want it, I-I-I want it.
- # I want it all
# I gotta, ooh, I gotta
I want to, I have to, I want to
# I want it, I want it
I have to have it
# I want it, I have to
- # I want it all.
- # I want it, want it, want it
- # The fame and the fortune and more.
- # I want it all
# I want it, want it, want it
# I gotta have my star on the door
# I want the world, nothing less
All the glam and the press
# Only giving me the best reviews
I want it all
# Paris, London, Rome, Toronto
# L.A., Sydney, Buenos Aires
# Tokyo, Moscow, Bollywood
# New York City
# We want it...
# All #
[applause]
It's ours, Ryan.
Wait a minute. Miss D said that
there's only one scholarship.
There's two of us.
We're twins. They're going
to have to take us both.
Listen, Kelsi always writes her
best songs for Troy and Gabriella.
So you make certain we get those songs.
How?
Polish her glasses, buy her some
ruby slippers, take her to prom.
I don't know.
Just do it.
- Hey, Tay.
- Morning, Sunshine.
- You going to rehearsals today?
- Uh, do I have a choice?
You got us into this. I don't
understand. You might not be here.
Told anyone you're up for
Stanford's Freshman Honors?
No.
You're gonna hear from them any day.
[cell phone rings]
- Hello?
- Taylor, these things take time.
- Hey.
- [Troy] I need you right away.
- What?
- Look up.
I have to go.
This has two weeks detention
written all over it.
Have fun.
I really need your help.
Which one do you think I should wear?
Because?
Because you're going to have
a pretty dress, so I want to look right.
I've never been asked to a prom, but
this almost sounds like an invitation.
This one.
I've never been to a dance,
much less a prom.
But I was hoping these
might be a good start.
Do you think we're going
to have to waltz?
Because I have no idea how to do that.
All I know is what my dad
taught me when I was a little girl.
I'd stand on his toes, and he'd
waltz me around the living room.
Come here. I'll show you.
- What?
- Come here.
- We're on the roof.
- [Giggles]
Come here. You'll love it.
# Take my hand
# Take a breath
# Pull me close
# And take one step
# Keep your eyes
# Locked on mine
# And let the music
# Be your guide
- # Won't you promise me.
- # Now won't you promise me
- # That you'll never forget.
- # We'll keep dancing
- # To keep dancing wherever we go next.
- # Wherever we go next
# it's like catching lightning
# The chances of finding
# Someone like you
# it's one in a million
# The chances of feeling
# The way we do
# And with every step together
# We just keep on getting better
- # So can I have this dance?
- # Can I have this dance?
# Can I have this dance?
# Oh
# No mountain's too high and no
# Ocean's too wide
# 'Cause together or not
our dance won't stop
# Let it rain...
# Let it pour
What we have is worth fighting for
# You know I believe
that we were meant to be
# it's like catching lightning
The chances of finding
# Someone like you
# it's one in a million
The chances of feeling
# The way we do
# And with every step together
# We just keep on getting better
- # So can I have this dance?
- # Can I have this dance?
# Can I have this dance?
- # Can I have...
- # This dance?
# Can I have this dance? #
- So is that a yes?
- In every language.
[says "yes" in different languages]
Yes.
- [school bell rings]
- [Gasps] Oh, come on!
Where's our clothes?
- Yo, Rocket Man.
- Oh, there they are.
- Thought you wanted our lockers.
- It's moving day.
Oh, sweet.
- Good job.
- Thanks, man.
Perfect timing, Bolton.
We weren't just given these lockers.
We had to earn them.
Right. Right. Thanks, man.
- Chad, what's the combo?
- What's the combo?
It's like he said.
You got to earn them.
What's that supposed to mean?
Hey, guys! Come back.
What are you talking about?
- Not cool, guys!
- Hey, Bolton! Danforth!
[laughing]
Hey, stop playing games!
This isn't funny, guys!
Chad, up top.
- I got it.
- Spike!
- Let's go! Out!
- Give me my clothes!
- This isn't funny, guys!
- Just give me my clothes, man!
Look out. Coming through.
Hey, those are new jeans!
I need those back!
Arms, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
You're really stressing me out.
I need to breathe.
And I don't know what Ryan is doing.
He's doing some kind of
yoga Fosse thing.
Two, three, four... What are you doing?
...six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, great,
five, six, seven...
Troy, just give me my clothes!
- Yearbook opportunity.
- Photo op.
Smile!
Wow.
- Hi.
- Bold choice, gentlemen.
We all must have the courage
to discover ourselves.
However, at East High,
we will discover ourselves
whilst clothed.
But welcome to our drama club
and our spring musicale.
Yeah, welcome.
The stage crew can use
your help during detention...
Painting sets.
Throw a sheet over them.
Ryan!
OK. All right, guys,
let's go back up to the top.
Jason, why don't you come
down here and help me out.
[engine rumbling]
Fuel pump...
Work in progress.
If my truck falls apart
because I'm spending my time onstage,
it's your fault.
You think I'd be spending any time
at all up there if it wasn't for you?
You know what? I do.
- What?
- You're so good.
I watch you in rehearsals. You love it.
Why is that so hard for you to admit?
It isn't, to you.
But to my dad? To Chad?
Yeah, it's a little hard.
It shouldn't be.
They're happy as long as
we're all talking about U of A.
You chose Stanford. U of A
was sort of chosen for me.
I haven't talked
to anybody about this, but...
I've had offers from other colleges.
- I'm really listening.
- I get it, Troy.
I still have decisions to make, too.
Like what?
I thought I heard you. I was just making
some snacks inside. Are you guys hungry?
- I interrupted something, didn't I?
- Just talking, Mom.
- Homework.
- OK.
Speaking about homework... come on.
I was joking.
[Taylor gasps]
Compliments of Zeke.
Be careful, they're still hot.
He doesn't know they're gone.
Eat the evidence.
Kissing up to the yearbook editors.
Very smart move.
Chad's hoping for two pages on himself.
Maybe even a third page,
just for his hair.
Hey, what's right is right.
Hoops, by the way, could you take me
after school to check out that tuxedo?
Tuxedo? For what?
For prom.
Honey, if that's
what you call an invitation,
you'll be dancing with yourself.
[chuckles] Ohh.
[school bell rings]
- Yo, yo, yo. It's lunchtime.
- Come on, people. Go!
- You ready?
- Yeah.
It's now or never, man.
The Garden Club is rooting for you.
Mmm.
- OK. I'm going in.
- Go get her.
- Troy, I really just...
- No, we're doing this now.
How long have you been up there?
- Hair's great.
- Don't...
I know. I heard that, too.
- Yes, good.
- Yes. OK.
- Your turn.
- So... Hey.
I was kind of wondering if you'd...
Maybe go with me.
Oh, hey, Chad. They have Tuna Surprise
on the menu. It's good. Really good.
Dude.
Taylor.
Hey, I'm asking you to prom.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you
because it's so loud.
- Did you hear something?
- No.
- Neither did I.
- Excuse me. Excuse me, everybody.
- What are you?
- Yo!
[Chad] Oh.
My friend has something to say.
Taylor McKessie.
Will you please be
my date to the senior prom?
[all] Aww...
- I'd be honored.
- [Everyone cheers]
Dude, I need to go shoot
some hoops or something.
You nailed it!
# Guess now it's official
- # Can't back out, can't back out.
- # No
# Gettin' ready
# For the night of nights
The night of nights, all right
- # Don't panic.
- # Panic
# Now do we have
to dress up for the prom?
# Dude, I don't think we have the choice
# Yeah it's the night of all nights
Got to look just right
# Dressin' to impress the boys
# Do I want classic or vintage or plaid
- # Where's the mirror.
- # I think this tux is too baggy
# Too tight
it makes me look weird
# Should I go movie star glamorous
# Sassy or sweet
# Don't know, but no one better
wear the same dress as me
# it's the night of our nightmares
# it's the night of our dreams
# it's too late to back out of it
- # Hey, makeovers, massages.
- # Don't know what a corsage is
# Been waiting all our lives for this
- # it's gonna be a night.
- # Can't wait
- # To remember.
- # Oh, man
# Come on now
Big fun, all right
- # it's gonna be the night.
- # I guess
- # To last forever.
- # Lucky us
# We'll never ever ever forget
- # Gettin' ready.
- # Get ready
- # Get, gettin' ready.
# Gettin' ready
# Get, gettin' ready
Go
[man] Hey, you've been in there an hour.
# So, what should I do with my hair?
- # Where's my shaver?
- # I love it
- # I look like a waiter.
- # Should I fluff it?
# it's getting later already
Should be there
[doorbells ring]
# Her mother opens the door
I'm shakin' inside
# He's here, it's time
The hour's arrived
# Don't know why
her father's starin' me down
# Where's my purse, lip gloss?
Now I'm really freakin' out
# Then something changes my world
# The most beautiful girl
Right in front of my eyes
- # it's gonna be a night.
- # Oh, yeah
- # To remember.
- # That's for sure
# Come on now
Big fun, all right
- # it's gonna be the night.
- # Here tonight
- # To last forever.
- # Forever more
# We'll never ever ever forget
Guys, right here. Guys!
# Who's that girl? She's so fine
# Who's that guy? I don't recognize
# Who's that girl?
She looks so good, yeah
# Guess you never really noticed
But you probably should
# Big fun
- # On the night of nights.
- # All right
# The night of nights
Tonight
# Let's dance
# On the night of nights
You know we're gonna do it right
# it's gonna be a night
To remember
# it's gonna be the night
To last forever
# it's gonna be our night
To remember
# it's gonna be the night
To last forever
# it's gonna be our night
You know it
# To remember
For all time
# Come on now
Big fun
# it's gonna be the night
We love it
# To last forever
The rest of our lives
# We'll never ever ever forget
# it's gonna be our night
Oh, yeah
# All together
Say it loud
# Come on now
Everyone, that's right
# it's gonna be the night
Yeah, the night
# To remember
Hear the crowd
# And never ever ever
# Never ever ever never ever
# Never never forget #
Bravo! Brava! Lights, please!
Kelsi, splendid music.
Ryan, your choreography
is quite inventive.
- Thank you.
- And, Jason,
we do not chew gum in theatre or prom.
See me at detention.
Lighting crew needs help.
Excellent work, everyone.
Costumes on the rack.
I will see you all tomorrow.
Kelsi's writing something amazing
for Troy and Gabriella.
A song, most likely.
- Just find out what it is.
- OK.
Hi, Boi! How was I? Thank you!
- Hey Troy, good job, man.
- Dude, stop doing that!
I'm sorry.
Look, there's Sharpay.
Now, you didn't hear this from me,
but she has a secret crush on you.
- A secret crush on me?
- Shhh!
Shhh.
- Should I talk to her?
- Yeah.
OK. All right.
Mr. Zara.
Yo! You can call me
"Rocket Man" if you want to.
How generous.
Mr. Zara, since you have become
such a dedicated presence,
I'm making you an understudy. Miss Gold!
- You as well.
- Nice.
I'm in!
I'm playing "The Understudy."
- Congrats.
- Right. What's up?
"Understudy" isn't a role, you moron.
You go on if one of the leads
can't make the performance.
Well, I hate to break it to you, sister,
but you're one, too.
The difference being I can carry a tune.
Listen, I wouldn't sing with you
if my hair was on fire
and you were the last bucket
of water on Earth.
I wouldn't sing with you
if I were starving
and you were
the last pickle at the picnic.
Want to go to lunch sometime?
Gentlemen, start your engines.
That's what I'm talking about, bro.
Yo, come check out these guitars.
[humming]
What is this?
[gasps]
"Stanford's Honors Program cordially..."
- [screams]
- Oh, my gosh.
Oh, my goodness! "You and 29 students
are invited for early orientation."
Oh, my gosh, that's huge.
Your mom must be so proud.
Taylor, you're the only one that knows.
But you've already accepted, right?
I'm throwing a going-away party.
This is huge!
You can't get rid of me that easy.
We've got a yearbook to do.
- Back to work.
- OK.
- These are Sharpay's yearbook photos.
- Of course they are. Thank you.
- This better be good.
- They select only 30 freshmen
from the entire incoming class. It's
a special three-weeks Honor program.
How prestigious.
But the program starts in two weeks.
She'd miss our sh... your show.
Oh, my goodness. What to do?
The show must go on, mustn't it?
[honks horn]
[piano music plays]
[hums]
- Morning.
"I just wanna be with you."
[hums]
[giggles]
# I got a lot of things I have to do
# All these distractions
# Our future's coming soon
# We're being pulled
# A hundred different directions
# But whatever happens
# I know I've got you...
- It's beautiful.
- Thanks.
I mean, really. This,
the prom number, everything.
It's going to be a great show.
- Speaking of prom, what are you doing?
- It's two days before the show.
I'm writing orchestrations and fixing
charts. I still have to write lyrics.
Great. I'll pick you up at 8:00.
# You're on my mind
You're in my heart
# it doesn't matter where we are
# We'll be all right
# Even if we're miles apart
# All I wanna do
# ls be with you
# Be with you
# There's nothing we can't do
# Just wanna be with you
Only you
# No matter where life takes us
- # Nothing can break us apart.
- # You know it's true
# I just wanna be with you
- Great!
- Awesome.
# Just be with you
# You know how life can be
it changes overnight
# it's sunny then raining
but it's all right
- # A friend like you.
- # Always makes it easy
- # I know that you get me.
- # Every time
# Through every up through every down
you know I'll always be around
# Through anything you can count on me
# All I wanna do
# ls be with you
# Be with you
# There's nothing we can't do
# Just wanna be with you
Only you
# No matter where life takes us
# Nothing can break us apart
# You know it's true
# I just wanna be with you
# I just wanna be with you #
Bravo! Great rehearsal. Pity
the actor that has to follow you.
I believe that actor is you,
Mr. Choreographer.
Oh, really?
- OK, let's take five and run it again.
- Yes!
- Ryan!
- That's five, everybody.
Did you get a copy
of that song from Kelsi?
No. But I'm taking her to prom.
Brilliant. Keep your friends close,
and your enemies closer.
Now get me that duet.
Uh... Sharpay, you are not Gabriella.
Zzztt!
Don't be so sure.
[horn honks]
- [Chad] Hey, Bobby.
- Hey, the boys are back.
- [Troy] Hey, Bob.
- How are you?
- Mr. Riley.
- Troy.
There is nothing like the purr of
a well-tuned engine. That wasn't it.
Yeah. My fuel pump's deceased.
You have a radiator cap for me?
- Heard of duct tape?
- That's what I got on it now.
Dig around over there.
I'm sure you'll find what you want.
I am so excited about you boys
playing at the U of A next year.
I bought my season tickets.
I got to take off early today,
so lock up when you're done.
- Yeah.
- You know where the key is.
- Say "hey" to Coach.
- Will do.
Did you hear that? He's got season
tickets. Time to start practicing.
Take a breather, LeBron.
Feel like your future
is laid out in front of you?
- What is your point?
- I don't know.
I just want my future
to be my future.
Do you see what happens when you
do a show? You're, like, five people.
Yeah, but what's so bad about that?
We used to come here as kids,
we'd be ten people.
We'd be spies, superheroes, rock stars.
Hold this. We were whatever we wanted
to be, whenever we wanted to be it.
It was us.
Yeah, we were, like, eight years old.
For the record, I was
a better superhero than you were.
# Take it back to the place
when you know it all began
# We could be anything we wanna be
# We can tell by the noise
that the boys are back again
# Together making history
# it's time to show how
# To be a superhero
# Just like a showdown
# Will Smith and Bobby De Niro
# We're the best, no doubt
# Doing it like we used to do
# This is our town, yeah
# And I'm telling you
# Oh, the boys are back
Hey, the boys are back
# That's right
# The boys are back
Gonna do it again
# Gonna wake up the neighborhood
# The boys are back, yeah
The boys are back, all right
# Climbing up the walls any time we want
# The word is out
The boys are back
# The boys are back
# Back to save the day
# Oh, yeah
# Keep coming with the right
Win the fight, every single time
# Undefeated here in our house
Yeah
# We can rock, we can shock
Any time we like
# And tonight we're going all out
# it's time to show how
# To be a superhero, oh
# Just like a showdown
# Keep the pedal to the metal
Go!
# We're the best, no doubt
# Doing it like we used to do
# This is our town
# And I'm telling you
Oh, look out
# The boys are back, hey
- # The boys are back.
- # That's right
# The boys are back, gonna do it again
gonna wake up the neighborhood
# The boys are back, yeah
- # The boys are back.
- # All right
# Climbing up the walls any time we
want, the word is out, the boys are back
# Here to change the world
# To solve the mystery
Fight the battle
# Save the girl
# No one
No one can stop us now
# We're the ones that make the rules
# Oooh!
[engine revs]
[both scream]
# No, no, no, hey!
No, no, no, no! Hey!
# The boys are back
# Oh, yeah
# The boys are back, hey
the boys are back, that's right
# The boys are back
Gonna do it again
# Gonna wake up the neighborhood
# The boys are back, yeah
The boys are back, all right
# Climbing up the walls any time we want
# No need to worry, 'cause...
# The boys are back
Hey, the boys are back
Gonna do it again
# And we make it look good
# The boys are back
Yeah, the boys are back
# Tearing down the walls
any time we want
# I'm sure that you know by now
# The boys are back #
What are you gonna do
if Juilliard says yes?
- I don't know.
- That's not what I wanted to hear.
I'm getting your butt back
in the gym tomorrow. Got me?
So I can whup your butt?
- Dream on.
- With my eyes closed.
[school bell rings]
Ohhh!
What's up, man?
- Hi, Troy!
- [Gasps]
I realized I haven't
offered my congratulations.
Oh, thank you.
I'm glad the season's over, so...
I didn't mean basketball, silly!
I meant Gabriella.
- What?
- Her missing the show
is a little disappointing, but being
selected for Stanford's Honors Program,
that is amazing for her
and for East High.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Everyone else does.
The whole school's buzzing.
The honorees spend time with Stanford's
top professors starting next week.
- Next week?
- Look, right there.
You really didn't know?
OK, this is a little awkward.
I guess her not telling you means
that she's on the fence about it.
But who better than Troy Bolton to
encourage her to accept the honor?
Since the only thing possibly
holding her back would be... you.
Well, I'll see you at rehearsal.
Toodles.
[cell phone rings]
Hello?
Hello. Somebody order a pizza pie?
- I didn't order a pizza.
- Special delivery!
Margherita pizza!
Shh.
Just the way you like it.
Let's not forget,
what's a picnic without
chocolate-covered strawberries?
It wouldn't be right.
Do you want the last strawberry?
Hmm...
Come on. This might very well be the
best strawberry in the whole world,
you wouldn't know
because you're not gonna eat it.
Fine, then.
Mmm!
You were right.
So here's the thing.
Your Honors Program at Stanford...
- How did you hear about that?
- A lot of people heard about it.
But I wasn't one of them. Why?
Because I knew what you would say.
Of course you should do
the Honors Program.
Is that what you were trying to tell me?
In the backyard the other day?
One of the things.
What else?
I've been thinking about trying
to talk my mom into staying
in Albuquerque another year.
I'll just take some classes here
and go to Stanford when I'm ready.
You can't just put off something
as amazing as Stanford.
You got to go. It's the right thing.
I always do the right thing. Maybe
I want to be a little crazy this time.
Everything about my life has
always been full speed ahead.
I told you, I wish it
would all just slow down...
To a stop.
We're going to graduate.
That's going to happen.
Nothing is going to slow down.
I guess my heart just doesn't know
it's in high school.
- Well...
- Shh.
You don't have to say anything else.
I'm a lot better at goodbyes than you.
I've had a ton of practice.
Why are you saying goodbye?
We still have prom.
We still have to graduate.
I meant "good night."
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- Good night.
[engine revs, doesn't start]
# I guess I should've known better
# To believe that my luck had changed
# Oh, I let my heart and forever
# Finally learn each ether's name
# I tell myself this time
it's different
# No goodbyes
'cause I can't bear to say it
# I'd never survive the one
that's coming
# if I stay
Oh, no
# Just walk away and don't look back
# 'Cause if my heart breaks
it's gonna hurt so bad
# You know I'm strong
but I can't take that
# Before it's too late
# Oh, just walk away
# Walk, walk, walk away
# I've got to let it go
# Start protecting my heart and soul
# 'Cause I don't think
I'll survive a goodbye again
# Not again
# Just walk away
Oh, and don't look back
# 'Cause if my heart breaks
it's gonna hurt so bad
# You know I'm strong
but I can't take that
# Before it's too late
# Oh, oh, oh
# Just walk away
# Walk, walk, walk away
# Walk away, walk away, yeah
# Walk away, walk away
# Walk, walk, walk away
# Oh, ohhh #
All right, everyone!
Attention, please! Listen up.
As some of you know, Miss Montez
is no longer available to us.
However, the show must indeed go on.
So, Sharpay, you will do
Gabriella's duet with Troy.
Tiara, ready to step in for Sharpay?
Those sparkling shoes
are impossible to fill.
- Don't worry. Kelsi will work with you.
- Hmm.
Come on, people. Let's rise to
the occasion. We're all pros here.
Let's do it for Gabriella. OK?
Kelsi, Troy, Ryan. Play piano.
All right, we have a lot of work to do.
There are sets to paint.
Drill that second number. Let's go!
Come on people, double time!
- Hey.
- It's late.
- Yeah.
Hear from Gabriella?
Yeah.
She's knee-deep in geniuses out there.
Believe it or not, she says
the food's better at East High.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
She still coming down for prom?
Yeah.
How's that big show going?
You don't want to know.
When were you going
to tell me about this?
Juilliard.
There's nothing to tell.
Maybe there is.
I heard you're talking to other schools.
I mean, is this serious?
U of A isn't the only school
that's talked to me. You know that.
But it's the only school
we talked about.
Chad would be disappointed
if you changed your mind.
No, Chad would get over it.
Would you?
We've been going to U of A games
since you were a little kid.
You talked about wearing
a Redhawks uniform.
But I'm not a little kid anymore.
You raised me to make my own choices
and I need to make them.
Not you or Chad or anybody else. Me.
Hey.
Troy, come on. Troy!
[distant thunder rumbling]
# The day a door is closed
# The echoes fill your soul
# They won't say which way to go
# Just trust your heart
# To find what you're here for
# Open another door
# But I'm not sure anymore
# it's just so hard
[distant cheering]
# Voices in my head
# Tell me they know best
Got me on the edge
# They're pushing, pushing
They're pushing
# I know they've got a plan
But the ball's in my hands
# This time it's man to man
I'm driving, fighting inside a
# World that's upside down
# And spinning faster
# What do I do now without you
# I don't know where to go
What's the right team?
# I want my own thing
So bad I'm going to scream
# I can't choose, so confused
# What's it all mean?
I want my own dream
# So bad I'm going to scream
# I'm kicking down the walls
I've gotta make 'em fall
# Just break through 'em all
I'm punching, crashing
# I'm gonna fight to find
myself, me and no one else
# Which way, I can't tell
I'm searching, searching
# Can't find the way that I should turn
I should turn right or left
# it's like nothing works without you
# I don't know where to go
What's the right team?
# I want my own thing
So bad I'm gonna scream
# I can't choose, so confused
What's it all mean?
# I want my own dream
So bad I'm gonna scream
# Yeah, the clock's running down
Hear the crowd gettin' loud
# I'm consumed by the sound
ls it her, is it love?
# Can the music ever be enough?
# Gotta work it out
Gotta work it out
# You can do it
You can do it
# I don't know where to go
# What's the right team?
# I want my own thing
# So bad I'm gonna scream
# I can't choose, so confused
# What's it all mean?
# I want my own dream
# So bad I'm gonna scream
# Aaah! #
Miss D?
I know I'm not supposed to be here.
Aren't you?
Nor should I be at this hour I suppose,
but I am trying to rebalance a show
in which Sharpay now plays
the role of Miss Montez.
And the reason for your visit is?
I don't know. I think I feel
like this is a good place to...
- Scream? Feel free.
- Or just to think.
The stage can be a wonderful partner
in the process of self-discovery.
You seem comfortable up there.
I do?
Which is why I submitted an application
in your name to Juilliard.
It was you.
Better to consider opportunities now
than in ten years when life
may limit your choices.
If I overstepped, I apologize.
No. No, I'm not mad.
I'm just confused.
What a life in the theater
has taught me is
to trust one's instincts.
And that takes courage.
A quality you don't seem to lack.
Last one out turns off the lights.
So walk, walk, walk. Jump in.
Around the world and spin out.
See? You got it.
- You're easier to dance with than her.
- My turn.
OK. Here we go. From the top.
Walk, walk, walk.
Jump down. Around the world.
- Heads up! Heads up!
- [Screams]
All right, everyone. Let's just
take five, all right? Take five.
You two. House up.
[whistles] Hoops Man. Over here.
You look like you're having
the time of your life.
I'm messing up the dances.
I'm messing up all the songs. I'm sorry.
It's all of us.
And all of us pretty much know why.
If it wasn't for Gabriella, this musical
would have been another "Sharpay Show."
- It'll be fine.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Mama!
- Hi.
Wow.
Gorgeous!
I'd like to take credit,
but Gabriella picked it out.
I ordered that corsage you showed me.
It's going to be perfect.
- Thanks, Mom.
- [Cell phone rings]
- You did good.
- Thank you.
It's Gabriella.
Hey! I just showed my mom the tux.
We need to talk.
I can't be a little adult right now,
Troy. I'm hoping you understand that.
No, don't even say that.
Gabriella. Prom is in two days.
You're supposed to be on a plane now.
It's taking me two weeks to
get used to being away from you.
- From East High and all my friends.
- I know. I know.
So, what, I come back,
go to prom and leave again?
And then it's graduation,
and leave again?
- That was our plan.
- I don't think I can do it, Troy.
I think I've run out of goodbyes.
Why do you keep saying goodbye?
I love you, Wildcat.
But I need to stay
right where I am. I'm sorry.
Gabriella.
She's not coming back, man.
- Is she going to miss prom?
- No, she's not coming back at all.
Wow. That's lousy, man.
It really is.
But, hey, man.
Everybody knows you don't bring
the girl with you after high school.
Look, Gabriella is already
one step ahead. As usual.
Right now you got
to snap out of it, dude.
She's off to Stanford.
And, look, I am right there with you.
Taylor's heading to Yale.
And you and me are going to U of A.
It's a new ball game.
Maybe I don't see my life
as a ball game anymore, man.
Look.
You're gonna go to the prom with us,
be with your friends.
You're gonna have
a good time. All right?
I don't plan on missing my prom.
There we go.
I figured you'd be the last one
out of the building.
I don't believe this.
I took a wrong turn on the way to prom.
So did you.
You are so crazy, Wildcat.
And what is it with you and trees?
I guess I see things
more clearly from up here.
You look handsome.
Prom is tonight in Albuquerque.
It's a thousand miles away.
My prom is wherever you are.
If I'm going to have a last dance
at East High, it's going to be with you.
# Take my hand
I'll take the lead
# And every turn will be safe with me
# Don't be afraid
Afraid to fall
# You know I'll catch you through it all
- # And you can't keep us apart.
- # Even a thousand miles
# Can't keep us apart
# 'Cause my heart is wherever you are
# it's like catching lightning
# The chances of finding someone
# Like you
# it's one in a million
# The chances of feeling
# The way we do
# And with every step together
# We just keep on getting better
- # So can I have this dance?
- # Can I have this dance?
# Can I have this dance?
- # This dance
# Can I have this dance? #
You know... I'm not the only one
that changed when you came to East High.
Kids that I used to just pass
in the hallway... we're friends now.
And we're supposed to
be doing a show together.
The problem is, East High
changed when you got there.
And now it's changed again
because you left.
You might be ready
to say goodbye to East High,
but East High's not ready
to say goodbye to you.
[man] Ladies and gentlemen, this is the
final call for curtain. Find your seats.
[cell phone rings]
Hey, Mommy and Daddy,
how was Africa? No, I mean India.
Oh, fabulous. The show is starting soon.
You're in the lobby?
OK. Toodles. And I love the roses!
Hey, what's up? We haven't formally met,
but I feel like I know you
in sort of a vibe-y level.
I'm Jimmy "The Rocket" Zara.
"Jimmy The Rocket"?
What are you? A Muppet gangster?
Oh. What is that? Is that
your cologne or a toxic spill?
Oh, yeah. It's called "Babe Magnet."
Bought it just for the show.
- You like it?
- [Sneezes]
Eww! That is so gross.
Hello! Send Troy in to see me.
I need to run the song.
[clown horn cell phone ring tone]
Yo! Dion.
Troy Bolton just sent me a text.
Probably just checking in.
"Been driving all night.
I'll try to make it for the second act.
- Break a leg."
- "Break a leg"? What does that mean?
Dude, that's show biz
for "you're going on tonight."
- As Troy?
- Yeah.
- Onstage?
- Oh, no.
- Get it!
All right. Notify Sharpay. I will
take care of Kelsi and the orchestra.
Hold up, Miss D.
I think he stopped breathing.
Well, then give him the Heimlich!
It's showtime!
- Go get 'em.
- Come on.
- Hello, Mrs. Evans.
- Hello.
- Enjoy the show.
- Thank you.
It's so wonderful, yes.
Seats right here.
Thank you for coming. Enjoy the show.
[orchestra warms up]
[person shouts]
# it's our last chance
to share the stage
# Before we go our separate ways
# High school wasn't meant
to last forever
# it's our last chance for us to shine
# To bring you music one more time
# So come on
Come on, come on
# Come on, come on, come on
[whistle blows]
# W-I-L-D Wildcats!
You know you're on
Come on, come on
# East High boys
Let's make some noise
# Oh, yeah, W-I-L-D Wildcats!
Now's the time
# This is the last time to get it right
# This is the last chance
to make it our night
# We got to show what we're all about
# Work together
# This is the last chance
to make our mark
# History will know who we are
# This is the last game so make
it count, it's now or never
# Yeahhh #
- [knocking]
- Entre.
Good evening, Miss Evans.
Two minutes till places.
Tell Troy to come up.
I want to rehearse the kissing.
Hasn't anybody told you that Troy...
Go!
# I want it all I want it
I want it, I want it
# I gotta have my star on the door
# I want the world
Nothing less
# All the glam and the press
Only giving me the best reviews
# I want it all
Want it all, want it all
He's the choreographer.
# Kick it, girls
# I want it all
Want it all, want it all
# Want it all, want it all
# We want it all #
My band! Thank you!
East High, you're amazing! Good night.
Yeah!
[man] That's my boy!
We have to save something. I'm at
the balcony, don't forget the special.
You forget the special. Where's Troy?
OK, he's around here somewhere.
Oh. Cute pants. Oh.
- You're on.
- Oh.
Ma! Ma! [Does voice gurgling]
# Oooh
# Yeah, yeah
# Yeah
# I got a lot of things I have to do
# All these distractions
Our future's coming soon
# We're being pulled
a hundred different directions
Focus, Jimmy. Come on, man. [Exhales]
# You're on my mind
You're in my heart
# it doesn't matter where we are
# We'll be all right
# Even if we're miles apart
[murmuring]
# Even if we're miles
and miles and miles apart
I think we have a problem.
# All I wanna do
# ls be with you
# Be with you
# There's nothing we can't do
# Just wanna be with you
Only you
# And no matter where life takes us
# Nothing can break us apart
[sneezes]
- # I just wanna be with...
- Eww.
# You #
Yeah!
Thank you very much.
- [man] You rule!
- [Jimmy] Best crowd I've ever had.
Hey!
Perfect. Go for it.
Save the day. Whoopee!
What?
You guys got to see this.
[Jimmy] No, you guys are awesome.
Thank you.
- They're here!
- Kels!
- Let's go! You're on!
- Oh, man. Hey!
That's my dress!
I had one made just like it.
Only better.
I'm playing Sharpay, remember?
You're not a singer.
You're a London schoolgirl.
Yes. London Academy of Dramatic Arts.
I took the job with you to learn
the ropes at East High. Now I have.
Now, step aside. I need to warm up
and give a good first impression.
Since it will be
my drama department next year.
But you were so loyal. So sweet.
That's called acting.
You should try it sometime.
Toodles.
[Troy] # You know how life
can be, it changes overnight
# it's sunny then raining
but it's all right
# A friend like you
# Always makes it easy
# I know that you get me
# Every time
# Through every up, through every down
You know I'll always be around
# Through anything you can count on me
# All I wanna do
- That is Troy Bolton.
- # Is be with you
# Be with you
# There's nothing we can't do
# Just wanna be with you
Only you
# No matter where life takes us
# Nothing can break us apart
# You know it's true
I just wanna be with you
# You
# I just wanna be with you
# The sun will always shine
# That's how you make me feel
# We're gonna be all right
# 'Cause what we have is real
# And we will always be together
# All I wanna do
# ls be with you
# Be with you
# There's nothing we can't do
# Just wanna be with you
Only you
# No matter where life takes us
# Nothing can break us apart
# You know it's true
# I just wanna be with you
# All I wanna do
# All that I wanna do is be with you
# All that I wanna do
# I just wanna be with you #
[applause]
Sharpay Evans, I believe
you're in the wrong costume.
# Who's that girl?
She's so fine
I don't recognize
# Who's that girl?
She looks so good, yeah
# Guess you never really noticed
but you probably should
# Big fun
On the night of nights
# The night of nights
Tonight
# Let's dance
On the night of nights
# You know we're gonna do it right
- # it's gonna be our night.
- # You know it
- # To remember.
- # For all time
- Surprise.
- # Big fun
- # it's gonna be the night.
- # We love it
- # To last forever.
- # The rest of our lives
# We'll never ever ever forget
it's gonna be...
- # My night.
- # Oh, yeah
- # All together.
- # Say it loud
# Come on now
Everyone, that's right
- # it's gonna be a night.
- # You can bet
- # To remember.
- # Hear the crowd
# And never ever ever
Never ever ever
# Never ever never
ever ever forget #
- Thank you so much.
- It was such a great show.
See them out, please. Thank you.
# Together, together
Together, everyone
# Together, together, come on
Let's have some fun
Ladies and gentlemen! Our seniors!
Kelsi Nielsen, the Juilliard
School Scholarship Recipient.
Music.
Jason Cross.
You did it. You graduated.
Whoo hoo hoo!
Taylor McKessie, Yale University,
with honors, Political Science.
And I am pleased to announce that due
to the excellence
displayed here this evening,
the Juilliard School has made
an extraordinary decision.
Another senior is being offered
a Juilliard scholarship.
Congratulations,
Mr. Ryan Evans, Choreography.
And congratulations, Miss Sharpay Evans.
University of Albuquerque,
Performing Arts.
Miss Evans has agreed
to return to East High next fall
to assist me in running
the Drama Department.
And now a senior who I believe
has a decision to make.
Mr. Troy Bolton. Troy.
I've chosen basketball.
But I've also chosen theater.
The University of California,
Berkeley, offers me both.
That's where I'm going
to be attending next fall.
But most of all, I choose the
person who inspires my heart.
Which is why I picked
a school that's exactly 32.7...
Miles from you.
Miss Gabriella Montez,
Stanford University, Pre-Law.
Next, Mr. Chad Danforth.
University of Albuquerque,
Basketball Scholarship!
He's gone.
Mr. Danforth.
He goes up for the shot and it's good!
East High Wildcat victory
for the record books!
[mimics crowd cheering]
Once they hand us that diploma,
we're done here?
What makes you think
we're getting diplomas?
One question: does Berkeley play?
Oh, yeah. We're scheduled to kick
some Redhawk butt next November.
Game on, Hoops.
Yeah.
Oh! One more steal. The final point.
Danforth! Bolton!
You get out there and you get onstage!
I never thought I'd hear
my dad say that.
# We're all in this together
# Once we know
# That we are
We're all stars
# And we see that
East High is a place where teachers
encouraged us to break the status quo.
And define ourselves as we choose.
Where a jock can cook up
a mean crme brle.
And the brainiac can break down
on the dance floor.
It's a place where one person...
if it's the right person...
Changes us all.
East High is having friends that
we'll keep for the rest of our lives.
And I guess that means
we really are all in this together.
Because once a Wildcat...
Always a Wildcat.
- Yeah, man.
- Thank you!
Thank you, sir.
Thank you very much.
[drum march plays]
[cheering]
# Looking forward from center stage
to graduation day
# Time to get the future started
# What we leave what we take
with us no matter what
# it's something we're a part of
we learned to fly
# Together side by side
# I just hope the rest of my life
# Will feel as good as my
# High School Musical
Who says we have to let it go?
# it's the best part we've ever known
# Step into the future
# But hold on to
High School Musical
# Let's celebrate where we come from
# The friends who've been there
all along, just like
# A High School Musical
# improvisation without
a script, no one's written it
# And now we have the chance to
# But some day we'll be looking back
memories we'll have
# All the songs that we lived through
# The best of times
So why leave them behind
# Why can't the rest of my life
# Be like my
High School Musical?
# Who says we have to let it go?
# it's the best part we've ever known
# Step into the future
# But hold on to
High School Musical
# Let's celebrate where we come from
# The friends who've been there
all along, that's right
# Now we finally realize
# Who we are
it just took some time
# We had to live
and to learn to see the truth
# Learn to see the truth
# That nothing's ever impossible
into the future we all free fall
# But forever
we'll always have high school
# Time to party now
Celebrate
# Because the world's one big stage
# Any part you want can be yours
# Everybody sing
# But the show is never going to close
# it's what got us here, we know
# High school lives on forever more
- # High School.
- # High School Musical
# High School Musical
# Who says we have to let it go?
# it's the best part we've ever known
# Step into the future, but hold on to
# High School Musical
- # Let's celebrate where we come from.
- # Celebrate
# The friends who've
been there all along
- # Oh, yeah.
- # I wish my life could be like a
# High School Musical
# Who says we have to let it go?
# it's the best part we've ever known
# Step into the future but hold on to
# High School Musical
# Let's celebrate where we come from
# All together
Makes it better
# Memories that last forever
# I want the rest of my life
to feel just like a
# High School Musical #
# High School Musical
# Who says we have to let it go?
# it's the best part we've ever known
# Step into the future, but hold on to
# High School Musical
# Let's celebrate where we come from
# All together
Makes it better
# Memories that last forever
# I want the rest of my life to
# Feel just like a
# High School Musical! #
# Remember that time
# I've heard those words before
but now they're mine
# Every memory of the sweet sunshine
# ls living here in my heart and mine
# Oh, oh
# Every laugh
# We share together
Yeah, we still give back
# Can you believe
all the fun we've had
# Oh, yeah
# Just getting ready for the other half
# You know a friend
becomes a part of you
# Part of you
# Like this dream is finally coming true
# Coming true
# it's all good, alright
# See ya later doesn't mean goodbye
# 'Cause it ain't over
There's time to fly
# Time to fly
- # And we're just getting started.
- # Just getting started
- # Oooh.
# Let's celebrate
# Life is coming
Yeah, and I can't wait
# it's a ride
that all of us get to take
# We're gonna help each other
find our way
# Oooh
[man] Cut, cut, cut.
Guys! Guys!
We forgot our pants.
Guys, go!
[laughter]
Oh, perfect! Good!
I don't know what I just said.
What are you doing?
Three, four... I like it!
Six, seven, eight.
- Hi, Troy!
- [Object clattering]
- My light just fell.
- [Man] Cut.
Oh, my gosh.
Mark!
# it's all good, alright
# See ya later doesn't mean
- # it don't mean goodbye.
- # It don't mean goodbye
# There's time to fly
# And we're just getting started
# it's all good, alright
# The world is changing
That ain't no surprise
# But that can't stop us
Just let it fly
# 'Cause we're just getting started
# Yeah
# it's all good, alright...
# Take it back to the place
when you know it all began
# We could be anything we wanna be
# We can tell by the noise
that the boys are back again
# Together making history
# it's time to show how
# To be a superhero
# Just like a showdown
# Will Smith and Bobby De Niro
# We're the best, no doubt
# Doing it like we used to do
# This is our town
# And I'm telling you
Oh
# The boys are back
Hey, the boys are back, that's right
Gonna do it again
# Gonna wake up the neighborhood
# The boys are back, yeah
The boys are back, all right
# Climbing up the walls any time we want
# The word is out
The boys are back
# The boys are back
# Back to save the day
The word is out, the boys are back
# Here to change the world
# To solve the mystery
Fight the battle
# Save the girl
# No one
No one can stop us now
# We're the ones that make the rules
# Oooh!
# The boys are back, hey
The boys are back, that's right
# The boys are back
Gonna do it again
# Gonna wake up the neighborhood
# The boys are back, yeah
The boys are back, all right
# Climbing up the walls any time we want
# No need to worry, 'cause...
# The boys are back
Hey, the boys are back, look out now
Gonna do it again
# And we make it look good
# The boys are back
Yeah, the boys are back
# Tearing down the walls
any time we want
# I'm sure that you know by now
# The boys are back #