THE TWO AND ONLY
Nice to do something healthy
for a change. - It's bloody cold.
What a little darling!
Aren't you cute!
Is it a girl? - A boy.
He's a little charmer.
Aren't you? Adorable cheeks.
Yeah, they're nice.
His technique is wrong.
He'll strain his back.
Let's get some hot chocolate. - Now?
Here we go.
I thought we'd have hot chocolate.
- There's some chocolate in it, too.
These guys are
past their sell-by-date.
Yes, Timo is out, too! - Yippee!
His wife is at some seminar.
- I'll always find something.
Hi! Having fun?
Can I offer you girls
something? - Sure.
That can't be so easy!
- Picking up men, you mean?
Look, he needs a snorkel.
You could have anyone,
but you're too picky.
I'll only have the one and only.
You're really pretty.
- Thanks. And you're really young.
Thanks!
I've been to the army already.
So your testicles
have descended then?
From where?
Hi! You want a ride?
- No thanks, I don't have a long way.
Whore.
I'll teach you to refuse a ride.
Run all you like, it won't help.
Whore!
Are you a robber or a cop?
Did you hurt yourself?
Are you okay?
- That car just now...
Did he do something to you? - No...
You're an excellent...
creep repellant!
I've been hollered at
from cars before -
but this guy really
gave me the shudders.
Where exactly are we going?
- I'll be fine from here on.
Do you really think I'd leave you
at the mercy of perverts?
I have the same song in my head!
- Really? I don't even know it.
The time is right
And you just might
See the rising sun...
And I hear you
Calling me
That's how it goes.
What? - That song.
It was playing in that pervert's car.
We met ten minutes ago,
and we already have a song.
It's my and the pervert's song!
We stopped.
- Yeah. I live here.
Then you're safe.
- I think you need to walk me inside.
There are still many dangers.
- Like those stairs.
They look really steep.
I have a lift, too.
- Many have become stuck in those.
And the door needs to be opened.
I'm out of responses.
But that doesn't sound safe either.
Hey, Sisu!
What's in there? Hey, love!
Hanna, I had amazing sex last night.
- Me too.
The guy was more vigorous
than he looked.
I didn't sleep a wink.
- Me neither.
Hold on, Attila the Hen is here.
Maybe a little work?
- It's Kimi Räikkönen's wife.
And I'm Mika Häkkinen's girlfriend.
- Imagine, I'm Jenni Räikkönen.
I have to go, but you need to do
something about your life.
It's more boring than...
I don't know who to compare you to!
Try having joyful sex
with no strings attached.
It's cathartic when your pussy
gets a good pounding.
I know.
See you on Friday. - Can't wait
for you to torture me again.
All right.
How does it look? - Good.
Jenna is progressing as expected.
She's a tough girl.
Luckily she was fit to begin with.
- That's nice to hear.
Come on!
- Alright. Thank you. Bye!
Yes. Your appointment
is still with Doctor Pitkänen.
Yes, that's right. Goodbye.
Thanks. - You're welcome.
Have you been a bad girl?
Let's just say
I needed the morning off.
Any dirty details?
Can you take care of those
right away? - Sure.
Hanna?
How are you doing
with Jenna Miettinen? - Fine.
Now that her mother trusts me enough
not to intervene. - Now, now.
The Prime Minister's sister
is an important customer.
You're going somewhere.
- So are you.
What? - I was wondering
which was better.
What we did just now,
or when in August '97 -
Dennis Bergkamp scored
his first hat trick for Arsenal -
and finished it with
an incredible goal -
in which he took the ball
in his control with one touch and...
You know what's funny? - What?
I know almost everything
about Dennis Nicolaas Bergkamp -
but about you, I know just
the surname on your door.
Well, my name is Hanna.
- Hanna...
I'm Markus.
Can we leave it at that?
Joyful sex with no strings attached
suits me perfectly.
You're married.
Most definitely not.
That wasn't exactly
what I expected.
But I'm not going to be the first man
in history to refuse such an offer.
An order of joyful sex
with no strings attached coming up.
Who said anything about one order?
Are you a nymphomaniac, Miss?
- Hold that face!
Morning. - Where the hell are you?
Celibate and on a retreat?
This is so amazing.
That guy is so amazing!
Casual single sex is so amazing!
Elli, you're a genius.
You can't be serious!
It's the First Lady.
You fucking idiot,
what are you playing at?
He's the man of your dreams.
You're head over heels in love!
You're right.
I'm in love. He's the man
of my dreams. What do I do now?
Tell him tonight, when he comes over
with some plant in his mouth.
I told him: Nothing serious.
- He may just be waiting to propose.
Some men are like that.
When they get some pussy -
they start dreaming about your
wedding dress or future children.
It's bloody irritating.
Hanna?
Hanna!
Male strippers at the Market Square.
- Did the First Lady tip you off?
Looking at her is almost
like having a life of my own.
We're making
a fur hat from that cat.
First, tell us again that you really
picked up a man from the street -
took him home and screwed
his brains out. You! - Me.
Hanna, honestly.
Was he really that good?
He rubbed his stubble
against my neck without asking.
Oh crap.
Read it again.
"Morning, Hanna. Thank you
for another amazing night."
"I know you don't want more
and this arrangement suits you."
"I thought it suited me too, but..."
"I watched you this morning
while you were sleeping -
and one thing became
very clear to me."
"I want to wake up
next to you every morning."
"The ball's in your court now."
"If you don't call,
I won't come round again -
although I'll probably have to
chain myself to a radiator."
Poetry.
Go on.
- I can't make out the end.
There's still the best bit.
"Call me if you feel that
this could turn into something."
"We could do something fun today.
Go to the cinema or...
...buy a house in the country
and have ten children."
Show it to me. - You saw the number
before the vase tipped over?
Maybe for a second.
- What was the number? Say it!
Could that be a five? 5, 3...
Give it to me.
I know what it says. - What?
"Your tits are too small but
your arse is great." -You're awful!
Do you have a picture of him? - Yeah!
I could print it and
put it on our noticeboard.
It's all blurry.
You should've snapped his willy.
Elli might have recognised it.
Your archives are extensive.
- And now, breaking news.
Prime Minister Ismo Majuri
was seriously injured -
in a car accident near Mäntsälä.
The Prime Minister was
on his way home to Lahti -
when his official car
collided with a lorry.
His bodyguard, who drove the car,
suffered the worst injuries.
Firemen are still
removing him from the car.
How terrible.
- Yeah. That Majuri guy is quite hot.
Yeah, I'm worried you won't
get a chance to bed him.
Screw you. - The Prime Minister
visited our studio this morning -
for a talk show that was
scheduled to be aired tonight.
He left the studio
straight to Lahti.
Don't worry, love,
we'll find him.
No one can disappear
from the world.
RECOGNISE THIS MAN?
- Could it be Jesus?
Help me find Markus!
Handsome, tall, dark, handsome...
6842...
MP Mikael Jungner.
Give me a Markus update.
- There's nothing to update.
If that guy ever shows up,
I'll kill him. - Me too.
Here we go.
So Timo can't make it tonight?
- They're spending the night at home.
Pizza, sauna, and all that.
Sorry.
This almost turned out
to be a good evening.
It's become quite an obsession.
- You think?
This works. - Is Markus
disappearing from your head?
Markus who?
Hey, what's the matter? Well?
It's nothing. - Kimi...
This just brought back memories.
My dad died in a similar accident.
Same-coloured lorry and all.
Except he drove an old Mazda.
Elli, let's practise.
I'm going to miss you guys!
You got a postcard. "In Thailand
we put the flag up for you."
"Here's something for Cortex's
boring break room. Elli and Paula."
Annika wants to see you.
She's with the PM's aide.
The one who's been on the news.
Anders something.
"Thoracic vertebrae injured,
partial paraplegia, Th12..."
You have the most experience
with these sort of injuries.
Anders, I, and Ismo's sister Sari
have chosen you -
as the Prime Minister's
personal physiotherapist.
Let me just say...
that trust is essential.
The Prime Minister
is not a regular patient.
You can't talk about the treatments.
- That goes without saying.
This looks good. That is, if Hanna
agrees to the other conditions.
What conditions? - Ismo won't be
rehabilitated here, but at his home.
It's undoubtedly helpful
that the therapist...
...and the receiver of treatment
are in vicinity of each other.
He means that you need
to move in with Ismo. - In Lahti?
Yes, is it a problem? - You'll be
duly compensated, of course.
Let me just say that
in addition to your normal salary -
we'll pay extra.
A considerable amount.
I've always liked Lahti.
Prime Minister
at the power plant opening
Bodyguard still in coma
Are you sure someone
won't have a little accident?
Leather seats.
- I'll try to hold it.
Lake Vesijärvi.
Let me just say that they're
a little simple here in Lahti.
They named their lake
"Water Lake" -
so they'd remember
what it contains.
Let me just say that
the view is worth mentioning.
It seems our torture chamber
meets all the necessary criteria.
It'll do.
But as an inquisitor,
I have to make a complaint -
about the lack of stretching rack
and whipping pole.
Not to mention pliers.
- Ismo Majuri.
First names are fine. I don't want
to be formal with a woman -
who wants to pull out my teeth.
Hanna Palo. I thought I'd start
by tearing out your nails.
Is everything alright here?
Alles in Ordnung?
We've already noticed
a few shortcomings.
I can assure you that all
the equipment has been delivered.
There's no stretching rack.
- Stretching rack...
Pliers.
- Breaking wheel.
Whipping pole.
- Thumbscrew.
I'm familiar with
Ismo's sense of humour -
but I expected a little more
from a healthcare professional.
That was a misjudgment from you.
Left hand forward,
right foot forward.
Good. Put your weight on it.
And straighten.
There, the other hand.
Left foot. Move your weight.
And straighten.
The hand comes after that.
Are you sure you want to begin
at six a.m. Every morning?
And another session at seven p.m.
I thought we were done
with the inquisition jokes.
You don't understand
the big picture.
I'm technically on sick leave,
but in reality I'm not.
I'm running things from here,
but that can't go on forever.
The idea is to return to office
as soon as possible.
It's going to be really hard.
- I'm prepared for that.
I'm not sure if you are.
You haven't used these muscles
for weeks. They'll become sore.
I have a high pain threshold.
There's a little Dudeson in us all.
Right, Anders? - A what?
Goddammit! Bloody hell...
If you weren't so damn nice,
I'd send hit men after you.
Don't mess with me, or I'll put
a video of you swearing on YouTube.
Let me just say that
there should be a limit to humour.
Shower.
- Yes, please.
Hi! Are you in Finland already?
- We've been here for hours.
Give us a Markus update.
There's nothing.
I've missed you terribly.
Where are you? We thought
you'd be at the bar waiting for us.
I'm in Lahti.
- Who kidnapped you?
The Prime Minister.
...the same reform
we suggested two years ago.
Now they're presenting it
as their own -
as if they'd found
the philosopher's stone!
Let me just say that this hygiene
between the coalition partners...
Delete
Hi! Wonderful to see you!
- You too, darling!
What a palace! Let's stay here.
- No, we won't.
Has he hit on you yet?
- Don't be silly.
It's a good customer relationship
and maybe... - Sexual.
Friendship! - Yeah, right.
Neither of us thinks about
anything else. - Except fucking.
Stop it! - We were
at the local last week.
I did the PR for this new movie,
and the producer was with us.
He kept rubbing Elli's thigh
under the table.
Supposedly in secret,
but everyone saw it. - Including Kimi?
The producer went to the loo,
and Kimi came to say to Elli:
"If that guy doesn't take
his hand off, I'll rip his head off."
What happened then?
- I went to bed with Kimi.
Finally! - I couldn't very well
sleep with the producer.
Why not?
- I had fucked him already.
For the first time, it was sexy
when a man lost his hard-on.
I'm sorry. - We were trying out
something with toys...
Mary had a little lamb...
- Do you want to hear this or not?
Yes. - It hurt me a little,
and I told that to Kimi.
He stopped, put my hand
on his limp dick and said:
"See what happened when you said
it hurt? I'll never hurt you again."
Oh, Kimi!
- Are you together now?
I can't fuck him for the second time.
- I would if I were you.
Looks like I'm alone in the hotel.
Want to stay there? - Food first.
We haven't talked about you.
What's new with you?
Nothing much. - Darling!
Timo! - Nothing much, huh?
He's left Marianne.
- For good.
We're moving in together
and trying for a baby.
So nothing new with you!
Couldn't you sleep?
- I was waiting for you to come home.
Technically, this isn't my home.
I knew you'd forgotten the gate code.
- Why didn't you text me?
Okay, I was worried.
There was no sign of you,
and the bars closed hours ago.
Ismo, I'm an adult.
So it's okay to get blind drunk
and stir all kinds of talk.
What talk? - Well, talk.
You're working for me,
and if the press finds out...
My job is not public.
Anders has made that perfectly clear.
Right.
What's your problem?
- You really don't know?
No.
Jealousy is my problem.
I'm madly in love with you.
I miss upstairs.
- The view will wait for you.
I know you don't return my feelings.
That's because I've never
thought about you like that.
It would be
really unprofessional of me.
Of course,
you may be in love with me -
but I can't know that for sure,
and neither can you.
You may have Stockholm syndrome.
You're my hostage.
I make unreasonable demands
and cause you pain.
You're in my control.
- That may be so.
Why don't we finish this project
and take it from there?
If my feelings haven't changed then -
I'll ride to you on a white horse
and offer you half the kingdom.
And who else can offer that?
Stop pouting, Hanna.
I think you shouldn't go
roaming around Helsinki.
It could set you back by weeks.
When a man wakes up from weeks of
coma, I can't just send a postcard.
I feel responsible for all of this.
Good afternoon.
Hello! - The press has no business
in the patient's room.
He's not in the condition
to judge for himself.
So that's not negotiable.
- Not a problem.
Could you please wait downstairs?
Let's have a small
press conference later. Thank you.
Are you coming?
- I'll wait here.
Great!
Thank you.
I walked upstairs
without stopping once.
Wow. Pity I didn't get to see it.
I'm going back to work.
On Thursday.
- Finally someone talks sense.
We'll have the press conference
at the Government Palace.
Then they'll see me climb upstairs
to chair a Government session.
Sounds good, if we agree
on a couple of things.
You'll wear a support corset -
take enough painkillers,
and use crutches.
The corset is good. It tickles
the Marshal Mannerheim in me.
This is not a joke.
- I could enter on a horse.
On an ass. - The preparations.
Parliament, press, bulletin.
If you're going back to work,
my work here is done.
I'll tell Cortex to start
booking appointments for me.
Something needs to end
for something new to begin.
The view will wait for you.
Once we've taken your bags upstairs,
let's go eat somewhere.
Now you stop working for me.
- I guess so.
In that case...
No, stop! - I'm sorry.
Let me just say that...
I forbid you to lift anything heavy.
I'm a typical politician.
All promises and no action.
We talked about this.
Besides, this form of rehab
has only just started.
You mean there's
more sweaty business ahead?
Absolutely.
But before that...
Where's the food I was promised?
Well, technically the Government
didn't promise food, but stated -
that there's a possibility of food
if things progress as desired and...
Have some.
These are good.
Hi, honey. - Goddammit, woman.
You're on a magazine cover!
WHO'S THE PM'S SECRET LOVE?
It looks like Ismo picked up
a drunken prostitute -
and is trying to hold her up.
I'll be frank. I understand something
like this happening to Hanna.
She's not used to publicity,
but how did you fuck up like this?
I wanted to be a regular guy in love
for a moment. - A fool in love!
It's Paula. - Hanna...
This isn't so bad.
You look good in this picture.
Hi. - Hi.
What a circus downstairs!
A picket line of reporters.
Your bodyguard is rattled.
- It's good they have something to do.
I'll get it.
You know what's going on.
I just wanted to tell you
everything's under control.
The party headquarters is making
a statement denying everything.
You can't even tell who
these people are in this picture.
Anders, Elli from The Evening Paper
and Paula from PR agency Amatson.
The Evening Paper?
- We hired Paula as Hanna's publicist.
Tell headquarters everything is
under control. - The Evening Paper?
The public needs
true information about the romance.
Otherwise, we'll get headlines like:
"Fit for a hit of love".
That's a good headline, Paula.
I suggest you give Elli
an exclusive interview and tell all.
What the hell is going on?
- Hanna, you'll wear this.
Shall I wear a suit? - Don't.
You're the only politician
who doesn't look silly in jeans.
I apologise for my colleagues.
Hanna got your arse into shape.
You need to show it to the people.
Thanks. - Ismo...
Let me just say that
these women are raving mad.
I don't see anything good
coming out of this.
LOVE HIT LIKE A LIGHTNING!
You have a lot to learn, son.
This kind of publicity is never bad.
"I'm sure they're a good match"
Timo...
PASSION IN THE POOL!
Pesonen, goddammit.
Why is this bottle in the picture?
The beer bottle was removed. - Good.
What are these?
Did you order these? - No.
Hi, honey. - Timo left me.
Too bad this isn't champagne.
You would've deserved it
after getting rid of that creep.
You must be Elli. You can guess
I've heard a lot about you.
Kimi hasn't brought
his woman to meet me -
so I had to check out
his girlfriend for myself.
I'm Jussi, Kimi's father.
Oh, hi.
Can we talk in private?
- I'm busy.
It's not every day you meet
your non-boyfriend's dead father.
I just tried to get
into your pants. - What?
I tried to get into your pants.
Pity is as good a way as any.
Just out of curiosity...
How did I die?
Kimi told her you were
hit by a lorry in an old Mazda.
I've never had a Mazda in my life.
Hey... Don't be mad at the boy.
He's a fool, but you should hear
how he talks about you.
Your girlfriend?
Me, your girlfriend?
I'm nobody's fucking girlfriend!
Kimi's mum took off
when he was about a year old.
His raising was left to a guy
like me. - You did a really good job.
This is a beautiful room.
I was an easy catch
for the estate agent.
He let me stand here until he got
my signature and dragged me out.
I didn't even see the rest.
I see...
Rehabilitation continues.
Again, sorry we rushed here
unannounced.
We're going to our cottage tomorrow
and thought we'd come to see you.
You saw me all right.
I hope you weren't traumatised.
- I hope you weren't either.
I'm going to need therapy.
My development was disturbed.
Jenna has progressed wonderfully.
We're very grateful.
For everything.
We feared that Jenna
would never walk again.
My parents were upset.
They accept that there won't be
any more grandchildren -
but losing Jenna...
My ex and I got tested
when she didn't get pregnant.
My sperm count is low,
and even the few are lazy swimmers.
And the accident
didn't improve things.
It didn't affect
your little swimmers.
We've figured out ways
to keep them moving.
Many commendably good ways.
Did you think
that if you told me -
I'd take off to find a virile man
to impregnate me?
Something like that.
Maybe I'll finish this wine first.
- And after that?
We can always adopt.
Stop fucking
and bring out the glasses!
I thought you had security here.
- So did I.
Paula is knocked up. - Yeah!
I can't believe it!
Congratulations.
I'm having a baby!
I mean, we're having a baby!
I thought that was nice.
- You can't be serious. Are you nuts?
Your mum is nuts.
Hi. - Hi.
What's this
emergency meeting about?
If you don't know that, the PM
needs a more suitable girlfriend.
I'll ask Ismo who's next in line.
The Independence Day ball
is two months away.
Exactly, we're late.
We haven't even chosen the designer.
I thought I'd just
buy a dress off the rack.
From a bridal store.
Or, the dress I wore
at my school ball may still fit.
A national costume? - Don't talk dirty
in front of my baby.
Be serious.
What kind of dress do you want?
Something with pockets.
I'll get it!
Hi.
You're early. We're trying to
hide her hump and cover her scars.
Hi! - Hi.
I need to have a word with her.
Okay. We can take a little break.
And maybe go to that café nearby.
Paula...
Hi. Why did you come so early?
Well, I thought that... Oh Jesus.
Sorry, I'm messing you up.
- That can be fixed.
Come on!
- I want to hear this!
We're going for coffee now!
Aren't you supposed to
ask me something?
Does it fit?
I'm so nervous about the ball
I'm going to wee my pants.
And now I have
half a kingdom on my finger.
Not everyone needs to
know about it yet. - Thank you.
Turn up the volume.
There they are! - Now one of
the most anticipated couples -
Prime Minister Ismo Majuri
and his lady friend Hanna Palo.
Our fashion expert gives
a nod of approval to her dress.
Absolutely gorgeous. If someone else
becomes the belle of the ball -
her dress really has to be
something special.
Happy interference day.
- Happy Independence Day.
What did she say? - Did she say
"happy interference day"?
I knew you'd be here.
- Where else would I be?
Marianne and I separated.
- Oh. Again?
No... This time it's final.
Marianne moved in with
her personal trainer.
Kicked me out. - Who?
What? - Who kicked you out?
Marianne or the personal trainer?
You said "happy interference day"
to the President. - Forget that!
Okay, honey. Let's talk about
how you're always on camera.
They probably have one
following just you.
Hopefully not right now.
Hey, buddy! A pint of lager,
a double whisky, and...
...a glass of red wine for the lady.
Jussi, this is Timo,
my ex-colleague.
Timo, this is Jussi, my...
The father of your future child.
If you were here, you'd get
a big scoop for tomorrow. - No!
But don't publish it, okay?
- I won't, I won't.
Paula!
They're engaged! - Wonderful!
Who are engaged?
- None of your business.
Honey, don't...
- You have no honey here.
Not even sugar or syrup.
Here's the thing. There's
absolutely nothing for you here.
It's time to move on
to the dance floor.
People's eyes will surely be
on the Prime Minister and Hanna Palo.
I want to introduce you to someone
who's returned to work.
Markus... Hanna Palo.
Markus Rinne, my bodyguard.
Good evening. - Evening.
Nice to meet you.
- Happy "interference day".
I have a headache.
My head's about to explode.
Markus? Send for the car.
Hanna is ill, we're going home.
You don't have to leave.
Are you sure? - Of course.
Alright. Markus will drive you.
- I'll take a taxi.
You're not taking a taxi in that
condition. Markus will drive you.
Wait.
I need to tell you this.
I was unconscious for a long time
after the accident.
My brain was swollen,
and they kept me in a coma.
Then one day, my friend
visited me in the hospital -
and brought me the paper.
You were on the cover.
With Ismo.
Fate played a cruel trick on us.
Excuse me, Mr. Prime Minister.
How about a little interview?
We heard from a reliable source
that you've got engaged.
You shouldn't have told me
about the letter.
I know. It was selfish and stupid.
Had I not known, I could've
left you alone. - Could you?
No sandwiches this time.
No. Not this time.
I'm not hungry anyway.
I figured you probably
need some time to think.
About Ismo and everything.
Hanna, last night was...
Yeah... - I've never...
I have a lot to think about.
Maybe it's best that...
Because I have a lot to think about.
Bye then.
Hey, everything's going to be fine...
Oops.
Are you ready to get dressed?
We need to go soon.
Where? - To Ismo, of course.
Let me just say
that he's frantic -
because someone hasn't
answered her phone all morning.
We need to work out this situation.
What situation?
ENGAGED!
Oh, your paper's little bird just
happened to ask if we're engaged -
since the tip came
from a reliable source?
Where else?
I thought I could trust you.
We would've given you an interview!
Put Paula on, now!
Of course it was Elli!
She couldn't help dropping a hint.
Why are you defending her?
You're defending her!
Have fun in your little club,
you two! Bye!
There's a lesson for you.
You should be more careful of
what you tell people.
You're a little too naive.
What should we do?
You could start by...
congratulating us.
Yes. Congratulations.
What's this?
- You're the Prime Minister's fiancée.
You have an official status
and a bodyguard. Me.
No, I don't. Shut up.
- The Prime Minister asked me himself.
He thought this would be an easy gig
after my sick leave.
What happened to the gentleman
who wanted to give me time to think?
He left you in the morning
only to read from a headline -
that he had just banged
the Prime Minister's fiancée.
The gentleman quit.
- I forgot all about it.
Your own engagement?
- I saw you and...
You forgot you'd announced your
engagement? - It wasn't like that.
I'll get a ticket soon.
Would you please get in?
I'm not getting in that car.
- Come on!
Soft seats and tinted windows.
We can pick up where we left off.
The ring didn't stop you then.
Or does it work best on your finger?
Magically. It can tell the difference
between gentlemen and arseholes!
Your own car and driver.
Dating the country's number one man
has its advantages.
It sure has.
I've got myself into a total mess.
What am I going to do?
We know. - But can't help.
Because you won't talk to us.
- Markus doesn't look half bad.
Be quiet!
- Did you say something?
I said be quiet.
This is a good song.
The time is right...
When I read about
your firm's history, it struck me -
how in many ways,
its old operations models -
would still be perfectly
applicable today.
Maybe this is the secret
of your longevity and success.
You haven't followed others,
but led the way.
Even internationally.
I wish I could see more of
the same confidence in this country.
Cool party.
- Right up your alley.
Markus isn't half bad,
by the way.
Are you okay?
- Of course.
Are you sure?
You looked a little pale in there.
I'm feeling a little weird.
Must be the shrimp pizza
I ate earlier today.
Are you already tired of being
the Prime Minister's other half?
I might be, if I were only that.
Last time I checked,
I still had a job.
You must be good at what you do.
You should hear how Ismo praises you
when you're not around.
He says he'd still be
in a wheelchair without you.
I doubt it.
My physiotherapist was a guy.
Two metres tall and 130 kilos.
If I didn't walk across the room,
he'd throw me over there.
He did a good job.
You look fine. I don't think
there are even any scars.
Yes, there are.
Where?
How did I not notice this
the other night?
We were a little occupied.
What's the matter?
Did the cat tip over your vase?
Are you really so childish
that you believed the cat tale?
Can you book me a gynaecologist?
Soon. - Is everything okay?
Yeah. I just... My ovulation
has been a little painful.
Cortex clinic, how may I help you?
Good morning.
Leena could see you at one.
He's available from three onward.
When's the next appointment for
Tarja Virtanen? - Painful ovulation?
Are you going to push your ovaries
out? She's our best obstetrician.
Just find the appointment, please.
- Next Thursday at two.
Do you want this? - Yes.
We need to talk. About us.
- So there's a "we" again?
How about we get in the back seat?
Or we could go to your place.
Wild sex whenever it's convenient
and you take off the ring.
Breathe! I'd hate to have to give you
mouth-to-mouth in the street.
In the street is fine, too.
Enough! You were the one
who took off.
I looked all over for you.
You just didn't realise what we had.
I didn't realise?
Why couldn't you wake me up
and tell me you loved me?
Don't feed me any more of that...
...cat-vase-
worldwide-search-of-Markus crap.
When I started to get mushy,
you found your casual sex elsewhere.
RECOGNISE THIS MAN?
- Supersharp pictures, great price!
I have to tell you something.
I know this will break your heart
and mine too.
But I... Goddammit!
I'm pregnant,
and the baby is not yours.
Here stands
the happiest man in the world.
I ran into your boss.
She congratulated me.
She didn't realise I didn't know yet.
All those swimming lessons
didn't go to waste.
When do you think it was conceived?
- Around Independence Day.
Oh, then.
Put the flowers in a vase, Mummy,
and Daddy will have a whisky.
Bring me one too, Daddy.
Hi. How was the performance?
I'll walk. - Hanna...
I'll walk!
Hi. Want a ride?
- No, thanks.
Are you too good for a ride, whore?
What are you doing, whore?
Put the phone away!
I'd like to report a stalker in
a car. His registration number is...
You neglected your duties
by letting Hanna wander off alone.
Ismo, I simply refused a ride.
I needed some fresh air.
You have to promise
it won't happen again.
You're responsible for
an extremely important package.
Hanna and I are having a baby.
Congratulations. To both of you.
You must be
very careful from now on.
Markus!
Don't say a word.
What could you possibly say?
Tell him. - You have to tell him.
It's yours! - The baby is yours!
I don't really see the point of
this interview. - Are you kidding?
You're too modest.
The police are so impressed
that you helped catch that stalker.
Attila the Hen is excited
about the story. - Yes, I am.
Hello.
You were famous here even before
you started dating the PM.
Yes, through Elli.
Where is she, by the way?
Or did she escape
when she found out I was here?
I know you've fallen out of love,
but don't you know anything?
Elli is on a leave of absence.
To be honest, I...
I haven't forgiven her for
leaking the engagement news.
To you.
- I received a text from... her.
And I got a call
from Timo Aalio. - Timo?
An old friend
from my advertising days.
Your own talk show!
How could I have missed that?
The ads start running next week.
- It's been great.
The only annoying thing is
I can't swear on prime time.
Are you sure you've forgiven me
for blaming you? - Almost.
What would it take to forgive me?
You and Ismo coming as guests
for my first live show.
I don't know...
- Elli has a good reason.
You just have to.
Okay! It's okay by me,
but Ismo may have an opinion, too.
Give us an Ismo update.
- No, a Hanna update.
I'm pregnant.
- What the hell?
What's the matter with you two,
breeding like rabbits?
Elli, you cannot bring this up
at the interview. Promise?
I promise. Of course I won't.
Maybe you believe me this time.
Oh dear.
Don't worry, Daddy will be with you.
We should go already.
We're not talking about this
on the show. Promise me!
Yeah, yeah. If you promise to wear
something a bit more feminine.
Camera two, now! Three, now!
We're almost out of time -
but I won't get home alive
if I don't ask you the big question.
When's the wedding?
Let's just say you won't find
an invitation in the post tomorrow.
Do you want a big wedding?
- We haven't really talked about it.
I don't want to make
my dreams public, but...
If you want to know, I don't care
about the size of our wedding.
As long as I make an honest woman
out of her as soon as possible.
Are you going to live
both in Lahti and Helsinki?
They're having a baby!
Ask if they're having a baby!
Yeah, I think so.
If we're going to be married,
I'm sure we'll move in together.
The two of us and my cat, Sisu.
- We need to redecorate anyway...
Oh, you have a cat? - Yeah.
I've always been a cat woman...
cat lover. - Let the PM talk!
I know I promised you,
but this atmosphere is so warm.
My heart is full of love...
- You said your cat's name was Sisu?
I have to tell you that Hanna and I
are having a baby.
Ten years ago, my ex-wife and I
were trying for a baby.
We found out that my sperm
is not exactly first-rate.
The doctors said I should stop
dreaming about biological children.
That it would be a miracle,
but here's that little miracle now.
Hanna didn't want to
make this public yet -
but a safe amount of time has passed
since our engagement day.
It may not be yours. - What?
What did she say?
What's going on?
Is it mine? - Markus!
Hanna, his name is Markus.
Is he your Markus?
Is it mine or not? - Let it roll!
Don't go there! This is great.
Why didn't you tell me
you found him?
I'd never have let you
make a fucking fool of yourself!
Don't swear, this is prime time!
- Tell me the truth. Is it mine?
Hanna, is it his?
Camera one, now!
Yes.
It's probably his.
HANNA CHEATED ON ISMO!
Fuck.
Was it planned?
- How did this happen?
Elli, this is my job!
- Pesonen, this is my friend.
Where's Markus?
- Aren't you ashamed?
Whore.
Leave it be. - No, I won't.
This must be yours.
These letters are useless.
Can we play in Polish?
If you can form a word from these,
you may come in.
"Vhyckru". - That'll do.
Evening. - Do you want something?
Tea? Whisky?
One pregnant bloody idiot?
I talked to Ismo. Looks like the baby
is 90-percent certainly mine.
That's right.
I want a DNA test
as soon as it's born.
If it's mine, I absolutely want
to be a part of its life.
I want joint custody!
- It's my child.
You can see it sometimes, but...
You would've given my child
to another man!
If I had a choice, do you think
I'd ever want to see you again?
I tried to tell you! - You tried!
You're a bloody good trier!
You're a bloody bad listener!
I think my water just broke.
You've been drinking.
- You don't have a licence.
How's Paula?
- She's working hard in there.
Can you let me know
if everything went well?
I want to know one thing.
Did you just use me as a sperm donor?
- Is that what you think?
Ismo can't have children,
and I was conveniently there.
Yeah, I threw you my keys
so you could come wank into a mug.
I want to be present at the delivery.
- Paula doesn't want you there!
At our baby's delivery!
- Absolutely not.
Besides, Elli is already coming.
You're coming to my delivery.
No fucking way...
would I ever miss it.
"I've lost a whole family"
Ismo Majuri opens up:
"A loved one's betrayal hurts!"
Surge of sympathy in Gallup polls
You're doing great, Hanna!
Don't give up!
What do people
usually yell in here?
Nothing usually, but sometimes
mothers yell "goddammit".
There! - Shut up, goddammit!
This one's tough for you both,
but go for it.
It's coming!
- I can see the head.
You won't believe what's going on!
You'll never recover from this!
Enough. Well done. There...
Wave at your godmother.
Tell me if he needs to be
strangled or something.
Perfect.
Red and wrinkly.
She looks a hundred years old.
Perfect.
Why don't we take the sample now
and get it over with?
This won't hurt at all.
Help me a little.
There, good. That was it.
Try to have some rest.
Let's wait for the results
before agreeing on the joint custody.
I hear we need another sample.
Let me just say... that she's right.
The party wants to be
absolutely sure. - The party?
I mean Ismo.
Thank you.
You open it.
Okay. First, take this stuff
and put it in.
And put that one on properly.
Here are all the sheets and stuff -
and she'll need this
when she goes to bed...
Bye, darling.
Bye bye...
Hey, where's her bottle?
Thanks for coming.
The fever has gone down, but she
would've run wild at your place.
This is fine.
Mummy, where are you going?
- Out with your godmothers.
Is your boyfriend coming too?
Risto and I are no longer together.
Okay, bye.
Hi! What weather!
You look gorgeous.
I'll bring you more soon. - Stay away.
We're having a girls' night.
Here he comes.
- Opposition leader Ismo Majuri.
Did they come together?
Oh my God!
The rumours are true.
The ex-PM's date -
is the main owner of Cortex clinic,
Annika Lund.
What did she say?
Did she say "happy interference day"?
- Oh, she did, too?
We shouldn't have left the local.
- Or home.
Have we become old? - No!
Happy Independence Day.
You've practised that.
Hanna!
Go ahead.
If I asked you to visit me in Lahti,
would you come?
To look at the view.
Did you ever love me?
- Yes, I did.
But not enough.
You have some nerve.
Do you think you're forgiven?
Silly you.
You've messed up a couple of lives.
Can you turn back time? Can you?
If you can, do it.
You little rascal.
Hi. - Hi.
It's Hanna. - Yeah.
I got your letter. - What?
The one you left between the vase
and the salmon sandwiches.
Oh, that. - You know what?
I'd love to go
to the cinema tonight.
Or move to the country
and have ten children.
LET'S KEEP FINLAND AFLOAT!
Ismo Majuri for President
Peace for the Middle East
Subtitles: Minna Franssila
Broadcast Text International