Watch full movies online for free at www.awooh.com
Do you want to know what this is all about?
You can say it's about drugs, or guns
disaffected youth or....
Whatever you like...
But this whole thing is about parenting.
It is about taking care of your children.
You take care of yours, I take care of mine.
I'm sorry I don't understand
What does that mean?
That's all I have to say about that subject.
Next question?
Your son was a drug dealer?
Drug dealer? No.
Did he sell a little weed? Yeah.
A little weed? He was a major supplier
in the San Gabriel valley.
I don't know anything about that.
What about the D. A. 's assertion that
your son got his marijuana from you...
and that you have tied to organized crime?
What is this amateur night bullshit?
That isn't an interrogation.  Alright?
I am a taxpayer and I'm a citizen.
And you are a jerk-off.
Did I tell you that?
Come on Johnny, why don't I feed you behind
if you're busting hard work I'm fucking your
Mom and your sister....
ahh Shit! What's that Tiko?
What did you say?
I heard you say you want to suck my cock right?
Primero would have to grow.
Shit, mines got so big it's got a name
5 foot, 3 hung like a flea.
It's hot out there
-What you doing, Elvis? Is it dark outside?
-What?
I'm paying you for a full day right?
I've been here since 10 o'clock this morning.
I hate that shit.
I asked you a question.
D'you see the fucking moon, Elvis?
-It's definitely daylight.
-Hey! I'll show you my moon.
Johnny, I did everything that you say.
The house is clean. I went to the store.
There is food and beer in the fridge.
The wash is done. Adolf's fed.
The grass is cut.  It is all done, man.
Well, I guess you shouldn't finish so fast huh?.
Shut the fuck up!
-Hey, never mind that!
-Never mind that!
Get back to fucking work!
You want something to do. .
Go wash the floors, scrub out the toilets. .
or better yet pick up all the dog shit
that's in the back yard.
And if you finish too fast...
-dump it out and...
-Pick it back up again
-Shut the fuck up, bitch!
-Get you a pooper-scooper
-Touchy
-It's messed up, man.
-What?
When am I going to get my money, Elvis?
When?
I get my cheque on Thursday
Well, how much is the cheque?
I don't know. It depends on the hours.
Well, how many hours did you work, bitch?
I can't remember.
Fucking dead beat, man.
Go on! Get the fuck outta here!
The walk of shame...
The walk of shame, man.
-Robby?
-Hold up, bitch!
$8, 500
All of this, huh?
Surprise! Surprise!
-Yeah
-Okay
So?
So. . I've got this guy
He wants 5, plus my regular 2.
So, I figure I'm gonna need 7.
I don't know.
I don't like having that much shit out
I'll see my guy Monday and
I'll clear you right out, man.
He's good for it, Johnny
You don't need to tell him
I'm good for it, man.
I'm not looking for any fucking favours, JT
If it makes sense. Do it!
If no, fuck it.
Alright
We'll try it.
-Where you going, Ray?
-That's what I'm talking about
But come Friday....
I don't want to hear any fucking stories.
You won't.
Be ready, be ready.
Nice. Nice.
Its big league stuff right there, baby.
I will throw you a couple.
-Hey!
-Hey.
-What you say, Tarzan?
-I need 7.
-7? 7 to who?
-Bobby 911.
-That could be put together.
and when you're picked off.
-Alright
-Knows where he's been?
-Yeah... I know. . it feels good.
Alright.  It's on you anyway, right?
Always is, pop.
Look at this kid, how handsome he is.
Look at this!
You must be knocking them dead.
Are you knowing them dead?
No. Let go!
What you doing tonight?
Chasing tail?
No. I'm just chilling.
On Friday. night?
-Sonny?
-I know.
You make me wonder about you, kid.
You sound like half a fucking fag.
-I always had my suspicions.
-Just make the fucking call!
Wait a minute, ok?
Remember what I told you...
Men are not supposed to be 'monopulous'
It's in our nature to spread the seed.
Yeah, very poetic. Come on
Angela is a nice girl but you
gotta plough some fucking fields.
Do ya hear me ya fucking fruitcake
-He is a great kid.
-Yeah, he is
Hello? Hi.  I didn't expect to see you
Come on!
-Howard
-Yeah
There's plenty of food.
-I like your hair, Jakie.
-Thank you.
-You look handsome with a little hair
-How is going on with the job?
-I had a lot of sales.
Busy, everything's going really... great
How is your mother?
Wonderful. Thank you.
-Tell her I said hello
-And Wanda?
She's fine and err...
could I talk to you for a second. . ?
Yeah.  Sure.
Excuse us.
I need to borrow money.
-I thought we'd talked about this.
-Yeah.
You haven't paid me back for the last time.
I know.  I'm sorry.
It's not the money,
you know that don't you, son?
I just can't keep bailing you
out all the time.
I know. Do you...
You think I would fucking be here is
this wasn't the last stop on earth?
How much?
$800.
-What is going on?
-Dec wants to borrow money.
How many times are we going to do this, Bud
The kid comes in here, stoned out of his mind
and you keep throwing money at him because
you don't want to deal with it.
I'm working.
I have a job
I'll pay you back.
No. No, I can't do it, son.
Right. Sorry. Go back to
your perfect little family.
-That that's not fair.
-Don't touch me
Hey. Can I come with you?
No, kid.  Not tonight.
I've got some shit to do.
Are you ok?
Are you alright?
Yeah.
Okay. Well, page me later.
-Yeah. Yeah
-OK
-I love you.
-Yeah.
Punk ass bitches
Look at those fucking stupid fucks
With their fucking guns and
their fucking gold chains.
-They're nothing-Worthless
-Shit
The only thing those mother fuckers
are shooting are music videos, dog.
-That's what I am saying
-The same thing
-That's what I am saying, dog
-That's what I am talking about
-Now I am feeling it.
-Now you're feeling it?
-No Shit!
-Don't want that shit. No
Dance! Dance!
You wanna call me out?!
-OK. I'll call you out
-Shit
-I wanna call you out
-That's disgusting.
-You know he has herpes, right?
Bring it on.
Fucking high, you know
I can't even see right now
Come on, Elvis. Come here.
You can't dance, bitch!
Come here.
Give me a fucking beer.
Will ya get a beer?
I'll get you a beer.
Don't worry, Angie.
I got it. I got it.
I got it, Johnny.
-Run, bitch!
-I'm thirsty
Look at that slave-ass mother-fucker
"I got it, Johnny"
He's like a spook, man.
You loves Johnny
He does.  Don't you, Elvis?
Mother-fucker!
Johnny, yeah I loves him a lot.
I owe him a lot.
I do.
No, no, no, no.
I don't mean like that.
I mean you fucking looooove him.
-You'd fucking do anything for him.
If he asked you to sucks his cock,
you probably would.
Shut the fuck up.
No, no, no.
Tell the truth, Elvis!
Tell me you wouldn't drop to your fucking
knees and suck Johnny's cock in two
seconds if he asked?
You give it a kiss on the tip....
-No, I wouldn't.
-You wouldn't?
-Johnny? Come on.
-Ahh, you see that?
Full on, dick in the mouth, balls across
the nose, dildo up the ass...
You're a faggot!
100 percent
Don't talk to me anymore, ok?
I fuck bitches.  You're a homo.
Don't!.  That's it.
Shut the fuck up!
-Suck my fucking cock!
I'm dead serious.
Suck it, bitch.
-Suck my fucking cock!
-The fucking door!
I got it.
Come on do it!
-I got it, alright?
-Suck my cock!
Pretty soon it is gonna come out, Elvis.
-You're gonna come out, Elvis.
-That you're fucking gay.
What's up, Jake?
Try calling a mother-fucker before
you just show up, ok?
You Jews just don't have no respect.
Can I speak to you for a minute?
Yes, it is Friday.
Let's go in here.
So, what's going on homie?
You know that thing I told you I was going
to take care of for you down in San Diego?
-Yeah
-It's a wash out
Really? What Happened?
Well.  I go down there and put the screws on him
and tell him something bad is gonna happen to him unless
he comes up with your money
and like . .  FAST...
Which he doesn't because he is fucking tacked.
But he is scared so he rings round his neighbour and
I'm walking the guy for a hundred and fifty bubs
So?
So, the bubs are no good
The X was fucking punk.
And I had a line to take it all, man. We would
have made so much money on that shit.
But you said that you would take care of it.
You said it was your debt.
-Are ya coming here trying to nigger talk me?
-Now, what could I do.
I couldn't exactly go back to the guy I
ripped off and say 'you're shit was no good'.
Okay, but I still gotta get paid.
No.  Come the fuck down.
I got $800 here and I thought...
-that we could split it
-You thought we could split it?
Fuck that. You pay me!
All of it.
-I'm trying.
-How?
You make dog give ya a fucking job
-Be careful Johnny. I'm not fucking Elvis.
-Yeah, well you're short asshole.
Watch you're fucking mouth ya little fucking bitch
I'm not one of your little faggot friends.
Remember who you're talking to.
Get this fucking bitch off.
Who you think you're messing with
you fucking cock-sucker.
Leave me.
Sit the fuck down! You crazy bitch.
-Piece of shit
-Hold it! God damn it, man.
Hey, come on man.
You pointing that thing at me
you better pull the fucking trigger.
Well, come on you fucking pussy!
Do it!
Come on, bitch!
-Don't you fuck me
-I will
-I love it
You have everyone else fooled around
here but I ain't fucking buying it.
Get this fucking piece of shit
outta my house!
Get the fuck out bro.
Alright Johnny.
Ain't no turning back now.
-Get the fuck outta here.
-Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Woooah!
Fuck me.
Shut up!
What's going on?
-Who's there?
-It's Zack.
-Who? It's fucking midnight.
-It's me, Zack.
Get in here!
What ya doing you fucking maniac?
Okay, go put on some clothes.
Heil, sir.
-Do you want a drink?
-Yeah.
...and she is always telling
me what to do
...like, what clothes to wear and what girls
she thinks are pretty...
Like, I couldn't fucking figure
it out for myself.
That's you're Mom.
It's Olivia.
Come on.  She loves you
You're her baby.
Yeah. I know.
It's embarrassing
Do you know that we have
"home work parties"?
-What?
-Homework parties with little hats.
-noooo. Like...
...for birthdays
Yeah.
Another thing...
I was sleeping, right...
...and she'll wake me up
by looking at me.
Like, I open my eyes and she'll be right there
looking at me, like...
Fucking 'A'
It's god damn creepy you know.
Like she is in love with me
and breathing on me
You're lucky, you know that?
I mean, my Ma she never...
...boohoo of me.
Yeah, I know.
But...
I would trade you.
I gotta get out.
I gotta smoke.
Well...
...look at the boy Zackie, all grown up.
Is that one header or stress weed?
Shut up.
Take a drink!
Like a pro.
One minute.
-It is Olivia.
-No, no fucking...
Alright...
Yeah he's here.
No, we're talking.
I said we are talking.
Don't get you're panties all in a waddle
I'll drive him home later.
Yes, I do know what time it is.
Thank you.
crack
Yeah, okay
Okay.  Alright!
You've gotta get home.
-No.
-Wait, stop.
Tonight, we ride.
Shit.
Let's go.
Jake... hey, Jake.
-Am I fine?
-Yes sir
-You're the best.
-Yeah?
-hmmm.
No, you're the best.
You wanted him.
You got him.
Bye.
You're a real son of a bitch, you know that?
Let's go.
I was fucking my dog, and...
No, no, listen.
Look at the ass of that one
I could crack it open like a peach.
You fucking kidding me?
You are a fucking dinosaur , Cosmos.
Come on! You're dead.
You can't do anything.
Ya balls are all wrinkled up.
What?
What? You deaf fucker
I said you're old.
I'd knocked the bottom outta her.
You don't even know where the bottom is.
You don't know what to do.
Hey, waitress.
-What can I do for you?
-What have you got in mind?
Just get another round of drinks.
-You haven't finished the last one.
-I didn't ask you that.
-Just get us some more fucking drinks.
-Get us some drinks, bitch
I pay. Hey, I got it.
-You got it hey?
-Yeah
It's a special occasion
-Come on, Cosmos, let's go.
-Come on!
Johnny, watch yourself.
-Say Jake that we stopped by.
-Oh! I will.
When I told Jake what happened he fucking
flipped out and I had to calm him down.
He's gonna kill Johnny. Jake's like that.
He is a very passionate person.
But I told him: if you're gonna do something
you've gotta fucking hit him where it hurts.
Johnny had a class storm
I mean two of the quantities
...he was trying to collect on
the insurance money...
Jake comes in. Salts the whole fucking deal.
Sharon's company catches wind of it
They don't pay out.
Cost Johnny 30, 000 dollars.
'cause Johnny had to retaliate...
It's fucking business.
Mr. Johansson wants to see you.
Want to see me?
Sit down!
What's up Pete?
You're probation officer called.
Mr. Lampington?
It thought he was out of town.
Yeah, well I talked to him.
He said you've been getting
into trouble again.
Breaking into houses. .
Using drugs... speed mainly.
It's not true.
-Yeah, it is.
-No, it's not.
Pete, I swear to God.
Dude. Dude!
It's.... .
I feel you.
I'm right here...
Don't look at me that way.
I'm telling you the fucking truth.
I'm totally fucking straight, man.
I mean I'm a litt...
Mr. Lampingtons' so full of shit...
He's outta fucking town
How would he know what I am doing?
You disappoint me.
Pete.
-Pete, I swear to fucking God
-Need you to take a drugs test.
Pete, come on...
I need the job.
-I really need this job.
-Fill it up.
I need this fucking job.
Fuck you!
-Fuck off!
-No.
Get the fuck outta here.
You're fired
Get out!
Don't come back in here.
Get the fuck outta here.
I will take a gun to your fucking head.
I will take you to hell with me.
Do you want to play some (?), Truelove?
Let's play some fucking games.
You called my PO (probation officer)
You called Mr. Lampington?
Mother-fucker!
Fuck that!
Where's the mother-fucker?
-Where you at?
-Johnny.
-Check the bathroom.
-Johnny
Jake.
Truelove.
-Shit, look at his fucking TV.
-Fuck the TV
Shut the fuck up!
Fuck the fucking dog, man.
What the fuck are you doing, man?
Fuck. You shitted.
Be careful, you'll step on the shit
fucking cock suckers
That asshole pays me.
Let's go.
The neighbourhood is safe again
Yes, mother fuckers.
Are we ready?
Ohh. What the fuck, dude?
We're moving, bro
-Moving?
-God damn right!
Too many assholes know where I live.
Did ya see this?
Holy Shit.
Johnny, what happened, man?
Came home last night...
My windows busted and my TV's missing
-Fuck, right?
-Fuck.
-Tell him about the shit!
-The shit?
Crac
Fucking crack head Mazursky took a
sideways shit on the living room carpet.
-What? Where?
-Right here.
On the wet spot
A big fucking steaming crap.
Long ways, like this.
Then it left.
-That's fucked up.
-Is that nuts or what?
What's the mother fuck wipe his
ass with...? His hand?
I don't know fucko
I told you I wasn't here.
Whatever, that is fucking nasty, man.
Check this shit out
Sunday 12 AM
This is just the beginning, baby
This is shooter.  Thanks
I know where ya fucking lives
D'ya hear me, you're fucking dead
Domination. Domination.
-Mazursky right?
-Can you believe that shit?
After everything I've done
for that mother-fucker.
Look, Johnny!...
Fuck him.
Let's get the hell out of Dodge
and go to fiesta, fuck some bitches.
-That's what I'm talking about.
-Right?
Let run through some shit.
Schmidt, we're gonna go the Springs for
a couple of days.  You stay here and get
everything boxed up.
I don't want to see shit
here when I get back, Ok?
-Alright.
-Alright. I want a receipt too.
Yeah and maybe if you guys are still
there when I get finished...
-I'll cruise down there
-Okay and maybe, you can blow me
Fuck you, bitch.
I want to come
Yeah, yeah, just make sure you get
the shit smell outta the carpet. Bitch!
I don't get it.  What are we doing?
Go break this fucking guys head.
Mazursky.
He's not here.
I'm telling you he's gone.
Look his cars not even here.
Don't give me shit.
There aren't even any fucking lights on.
How can the lights be on?
It's the middle of the fucking day
What the fuck are we doing?
I don't know but I am not standing
here like a fucking idiot
-What are you doing?
-I'm kidding.
Well stop fucking around.
Hey, OJ
Check it out!
97 miles per hour, mother fucker
Let's see what you got
Manny Ramirez, mother-fucker
You guys are fucking idiots.
Ooh, Jesus! Make more noise!
He's 15. Remember when you were 15?
For once in your life,
your tennis match will wait.
Why do you have to be such a fucking
pussy? What are you thinking?
-What are you getting crazy about?
-I am not crazy...
If you were ever here, you
might notice that.
Great! Let's just let him turn
out like the other...
Like what, Olivia.  Like Who?
Say it! Like Jake?
Hey.  What's going on?
Come here.
Your Mother found this in your room.
It's a pipe
I know what it is. It's a bone.
Want to tell me about it?
-No
-You smoking pot?
-Now look at me, we have to talk.
-I don't want to fucking talk.
-We that's too bad.  Sit down!
Dad! I just fucking woke up.
God Damn! Wait 'till I put
some fucking clothes on.
God! Fucking dick!
Yes, we should punish him.
Do something for God's sake.
You never do anything.
Zack come down here!
Zack.
-Are you fucking kidding me?
-What?
-That's his brother.
Pull over!
Hey, what's up?
Come here!
Come here, fuck-face.
What the fuck are you running for?
Come on, let's go.
What the fuck you want?
I didn't do anything.
Shut the fuck up and get in, Bitch.
Fucking idiot.
Just take him to your place.
I can't take him to my place.
My Dad's there.
I thought you said he was cool?
Bitch, he is cool, but you didn't
tell me we would be bringing
along a fucking hostage.
He is not a hostage, alright?
I told you I don't know what I
am doing right now, alright?
-I'm thinking.
-Well, think!
Hey, we've got to take him some place.
Alright.  I know somewhere we can go.
But you have got to be fucking cool.
What is there?
-Hey, what's up, man?
-Chucky
-A lot of dudes, bro.
-I know that.
Bring 'em in.
Hey, Chuck.  This is Truelove;
the guy I was telling you about.
Hey, what's up, man?
Do you have a room we can use?
-A room?
-Yeah
Yeah, I've got one down to the left.
Thanks
So, what's up, man?
We're just chilling, man.
-Getting high, getting ready to go to fiesta.
-Smoking weed.
Thanks, man.
So, how you been?
Been good. Chilling, ripping
waves, hanging out.
What the fuck is going on back there?
Do you want me to go check it out?
Yeah, I mean, 4 dudes I have never
met are in my fucking bedroom.
Give me the tape!
What the fuck are you doing, man?
Are you nuts, you can't do that.
You guys are out of your fucking mind.
-What the hell is this?
Who the fuck are you?
-Shut up
Hey Chucky, they got a kid tied
up in your room.
-Calm down
-He's a kid
-Johnny is just a little crazy right now.
-A little crazy right now?
We stole this kid...
I thought I told you to shut your mouth?
And you: Mind your fucking business.
Mind my business?
This is my fucking house.
Frankie, you better put your boy in check.
Tell him what fucking time it is.
-Like that huh?
-Just like that, bitch.
I get it. Hey, Lump...
Let's get out of here.
I'm going to fucking fiesta...
when I get back, none of you
Mother-fucker better be here.
-Let's get out of here girls.
-Let's go!
Fucking shit-head.
Chucky, man... I'm really sorry
about all this, bro.
What's going on?
Why aren't you guys ready.
What are we going to do with the kid, man?
Who cares.
Leave him in the fucking closet.
Pick him up then. I don't give a fuck.
Johnny, I have a date back in the valley.
I have to get back, man.
Me too.
You've just remembered now, huh?
-Yeah
-Yeah, man.
My girl gets mad if I don't fuck her.
You pussies wanna go home?
Fine! Take the fucking van.
Listen! You don't have to do that.
You can put me in a fucking closet.
I'm not going to run anyway.
Do me a favour: Shut up, before I
shut you the fuck up.
Why is this mother-fucker talking anyway?
I thought we taped him up?
He couldn't breathe.
Just drop me off on the strip.
I'm going to fucking fiesta.
I'm not going to let this little
mother-fucker spoil my weekend.
-What about me?
-No
-No, what?
-He stays with you.
-What?
-I said fucking queer as a deaf mother-fucker
-Why me, dude?
-Because I fucking said so.
Don't fuck around man.
I can't fucking take him to my
Dad's house like that.
Well then, untie him, genius!
You heard the kid...
-You aren't running are you?
-What?
No.
Go home, tell Juergen that he's your new little
butt buddy and he is spending the night.
Meanwhile, I'll talk to Mazursky.
He must be going crazy, right now.
Hey, what's going on?
It's a mad house.
Your brother is scaring the shit
out of all of us.
Did they call the friends?
Maybe he has a girl?
We tried everything. Friends,
cops, hospitals... nothing. .
Don't you think the kid is out
just fucking around?
I mean you can't keep the kid
locked in the house forever
Maybe, I don't know.
We did have an argument this morning.
OK, well that's what it is then, right?
I hope so.
-Well, what do you think?
-I don't know.
But...
We can't rule anything out.
I'll have to ask you a few questions, ok?
Do you know anyone who
would want to hurt Zack?
-No.
-You?
-Me what?
-You've a beef with anyone
I oughta know about?
That person you owe money to?
You owe somebody money?
Jesus! Just tell me how much and
I will write the cheque.
-It is not really like that, Olivia.
-Really? What's it like?
Tell me what it's like, god damn you!
Fuck. Bring him back.
Please relax.
Bring him back!
Back here!
I am going to find him.
I promise you.
I promise.
I will find him.
Where are you going?
Where's Johnny?
Don't know Dog, is he here?
-That is what I am asking you dog
-Excuse me. We were talking.
Klemash, where the fucking kid?
I ain't seen him, dude.
What the fuck is that?. . Behind your back
when you turn away from me?
-What's the problem here?
-Shut your big ass
Don't touch her!
Asshole!
If anybody sees...
Johnny Truelove...
Tell him that Jake Mazursky
is looking for him.
Thank you.
Back the fuck off me, man?
I am informing you.
-I want a beer. Do you want one?
-Yeah, sure.
Here you go.
-Cigarette?
-No. I don't smoke.
Fuck that! It's good for you.
Hey, man...
...what if I said; you could walk
over there right now...
...jump on a bus, catch a ride home...
I turned my back and tell Truelove...
...you fucking ran away or something...
What do you think about that?
I don't know, Frankie.  I mean...
I don't wan to cause any problems
for my brother, you know?
So I think; I'm just going to ride it out.
See what happens
Alright?
Alright.
Right.
Dad.
Frankie?
Good to see you, boy...
-My little son loves his dad.
-Don't.
Let's go to bed.
I love you.
-I want you to meet...
-Alright
-Hi.
Give the kid a kiss
Dad!
Dad, No...
Leave me be.
Come on, smoke with your old man.
-Have a drink?
-No
Something?
No. Come on.
Who is your little friend?
Are you babysitting?
Fuck you.
Use the sofa.
Wake up.
Come on you've got chores to do.
Let us go!
-Hello
-I fucking hear you
There's coffee but Bessy got up late so
I need you to straighten up the house.
I'm supposed to clean up after your party?
I know I moan like a bitch.
Don't argue with me. I am in no mood.
Look, I came home yesterday and
your shit is all over the house.
We had a deal remember?
Get a job, pay rent...
Alright! Fuck!
Get out of my room!
Nice fucking mouth.
Fucking dick.
Hey. Don't worry about it.
I'll help you with the work.
Juergen is botanical. He grows
everything we eat right here.
Tomato, cucumbers, corn.
Fucking spices and shit.
Fucker is a full blown alcoholic,
smokes like a chimney...
...but, Goddamn, if we don't eat healthy.
Look at this shit right here.
Daddy's pride and joy.
Cause the greedy bastard will smoke 'em
all but it's Frankie's job to take care of them.
Water them, throw some egg shells
on them every now and then.
Well fuck it
Let's get to work.
Shit. I'll be right back.
-Hey Girl!
-What's going on?
-Nothing. Working.
Are you guys coming over?
You got that shit?
You know I do.
Mom.  I'm going to Frankie's.
-Did you talk to him?
-It's all good.
-When will you be home?
-I don't know. Late probably.
Darling, can you stay with Julie
and Sabrina tonight? It's your father
and my anniversary
Anniversary!
-You gonna have a little sex or some...?
-That's disgusting.
Whatever! I'm interested.
I mean, really, are you going to go down on him?
-Give him a little tube stick boogie?
-No!
Oh come on! Live a little.
You guys have been married what. .
...500 years?
Keith Straten! I will knock the
shit out of you, you little skunk!
OK We're leaving.
Get your keys? Lets go get
Sabrina and Julie.
Yo! Youngblood.  Come here, man.
Ladies...
Dick Wad, Fuckweed
Susan.
Hi.
Sabrina, Julie,
Dick Wad
OK.  OK, let's go smoke some
fucking weed, man!
But, hey, listen.
No-one messes up my shit, alright?
This house ain't never been
so fucking clean
You fucking blow this game.
I don't fucking blow. You just died, man.
-I thought I was the other guy.
-That's me.
I thought I was playing the other dude.
-Suck my balls!
-Fuck you. Suck my balls, man
You suck it bitch.
So, how old are you?
How old do I look?
About 12.
Well, I am 17, but I do look really young.
I am going to kill your ass, kill your ass.
-Stop the game.
-No! Go answer your phone.
Suck it!
Fuck you
Yo Johnny! What's up?
Did you talk to anybody?
-Not yet, why?
Look, man, I can't keep the
kid here much longer.
-Why? What up?
-Nothing, just having some people over.
-Who?
-Nobody. Shut up
Nobody, just some people.
Chill Out, dog!
-Get them the fuck out of there.
Alright, alright, I'll clear it up.
I need you to do a favour for me, bro.
Johnny is coming and I need the house.
Will you watch the kid for me for a little while?
Watch him?
Keep an eye on him, no phones...
...and no leaving him alone.
No phones?
I don't get it.
Alright, look, if I tell you something
can you keep your fucking mouth shut?
Yeah, 'course, man.
Yeah.
The kids brother owes Truelove money...
...and Johnny's holding him like a
marker or something until he gets paid
That's fucked up.
No, no, Bitch. It's not like that.
The kid knows what's happening
and he's cool with it.
I mean, look at the mother-fucker.
He ain't going no where.
Just take him some place, hang out,
bring him back in a couple of hours.
Can you do that for me?
I don't know, man. I'm...
Sounds pretty fucking dubious.
Keith...
...who the fuck are you talking to, man?
If I tell you something is good
then that's what it is.
Are you going to take care of this for me?
Or not?
Susan, I swear to God,
It's cool. Trust me.
-Hey fuck you. Let go of me
-Calm down!
You're not supposed to know any of this.
Jesus, don't say anything.
You are going to get me
in a lot of fucking trouble.
From who, Keith?
From your little gangster friends?
-Oh! I'm really scared.
-You fucking should be.
You are a little fucking faggot,
you know that?
Whoa guys. What's going on?
-This kid has been kidnapped
-No, he hasn't.
You mean like 'abducted' kidnapped?
Fucking stolen! Ask him.
Yeah, yeah they took me but...
It's ok.
-They took you why?
-His scumbag brother owes
Johnny Truelove money
-Shut up!
-Wooah! Fucking hot.
Dude, so you're ransom or something.
Yeah.
Stolen boy.
-You don't look stolen.
-Yeah.
Dude, I want you to know that you
can do anything you want, ok?
I don't play that shit
Shit!
-If you wan to fucking leave, go for it.
-Shut the fuck up, you fucking bitch!
Hey guys! Whoah!
-Fuck
-Susan
Hey! Hey!
-I'm gonna knock you fucking face off
-Hey fucking chill out!
My God. . My brother...
-My brother is going to pay the money, ok?
-See!
So, like, in the mean time your on vacation?
-Yeah, yeah why not...
-Fucking awesome!
...like another story to tell my grandkids
That's so fucking cool.
Dude, this shirt is fucking cool,
Bob Marley is cool...
You guys think that kidnapping is cool?
Yes, Susan, it is fucking exciting!
I think it is romantic that he is
doing this for his brother.
-Are you insane?
-Susan, chill out!
This is fucking wrong.
Crac
Doesn't anyone else think
this is fucking wrong?
-No
-Susan, take a fucking valium!
-OK? It isn't any of your business.
-He is in my house!
Oh Jesus!
Calm the fuck down.
I am going to roll us the biggest
fucking joint anyone has ever seen.
You guys ok with that?
-Absolutely
Hey! What's up you black-dick faggot?
You're looking short, bitch.
Make yourself busy, baby.
Gotta talk some business.
-Can I get you guys a drink?
-Pina colada?
This ain't a bar, baby.
There's no fucking pina colada.
-Not even in little cans?
-No, but I have got wine I can
make you a spritzer
Sit down!
What's the fucking deal?
I don't know what to do.
-What do you mean?
-About the kid.
We could be in a lot of trouble.
-Trouble?
-Yeah.
Big ass, serious as shit, trouble
I mean, you can't just take a
kid and have no one notice.
boy without being noticed.
That's what I told you?
Didn't I say that?
-You did, alright...
-Fuck
-But still...
...We are were we are.
Right here, you know?
It's a big problem and we have to fix it.
So, what do we do?
I don't know.
There is an answer, a solution, to this
but I am just not seeing it.
I don't know, maybe we are fucked.
We are not fucked.
-What do you mean 'fucked'?
-Jail 'fucked', mother fucker.
If we let the kid go, he runs back to
Mummy and Daddy and rats us out.
Not to mention 'Tattoee'.  Who knows what
that crazy mother-fucker is going to do...
Crac
We are going to be looking
over our fucking shoulders.
I don't think the kid will spill.
I really don't.
Yeah, but what if he does?
-Fuck that shit.
-See what I am saying?
I am not fucking going to prison!
I just wont!
Me neither, bitch, what the fuck do
you think I am talking....
I'm not fucking kidding, John.
This is really fucking bad.
The best for us to do is get a hold of 'Tattoee' and
straighten him and this shit out once and for all.
Well,  where is that mother fucker?
Who the fuck knows!?! I don't know,
he is probably laying low looking to
shot me in the fucking head. .
Think about it! That's what I would be doing.
Stop! Already, alright.
You know how I get with this anxiety shit.
I swear to God, man,
I am hyperventilating.
I want to ask you something...
What? Fuck!
Hypothetically, alright?
This isn't real right?
We are just talking here....
But...
...what would say if I offered you
$2, 500 dollars just to kill the kid?
Kill him?
Yeah, fucking wax him.
Are you fucking insane?
I am not going to fucking kill the kid.
That's a fucking joke right?
Of course it's a fucking joke, man.
You're so fucking stupid
-You're an asshole, man.
-Okay, man, I was just playing.
Well, stop fucking around.
Look man, can't we just grease the kid?
Tell him he can hang out anytime.
That he's our boy.
Throw a fucking arm around him or something.
Give him a few bucks?
Right!
Tell him to say, when Mummy and Daddy ask,
that he ran away with some girl or something.
-Yeah, Maybe, yeah
-We have to get the story straight, but
we can make it work, man.
We just grease the kid
and then it's taken care of.
Then we are not running around here
like a bunch of fucking chinamen
Done.
See, that's what I love about you, man...
...you're smarter than me.
Whoa.  Let me see that?
Come here!
-Does it hurt?
-No
I can talk to you alone for a minute?
I just wanted to say sorry
about all this shit.
I know it's a big pain in the ass. This
whole thing is really fucking ridiculous.
Yeah.
Are you ok?
Is everyone treating you alright?
You got enough to eat?
-Yeah
-Yeah?
Need anything?
Need some dough?
No, I am good.
-Are you sure...?
-No, I'm really good.  Really.
I know that is hard but...
...it's all going to get squared away soon.
I promise.
Okay, cool.
Alright.
I gotta jet but I...
...you know something...?
you're....
You're a pretty stand up guy.
-Thanks.
-Your brother's a dickhead
He's my boy, and I love him but
he's just...
...you know, he's acting a
mother fuck right now, you know?
Yeah, I know.
Yeah, well.... .
...anyway's... tomorrow...
This will all be over by tomorrow.
Hi baby, what's up? I thought you
were spending the night out?
Yeah, I was.  I just...
I really needed to talk.
Talk?
What now?
Kind of.
One night.  I ask for one night out of
the whole fucking year to make love...
...to your father and you won't
even give that to me.
I'm 'X'ing right now. I can't understand
anything you're saying.
-Sorry! Mom?
-Fuck
He was wearing a brown shirt, a blue
sweatshirt, brown tennis shoes
...and his grandfather ring with a red stone.
You got a phone call.
I'll take it upstairs.
Excuse me.
Yo! It's me.
"Midget"
You go some set of balls calling me here.
What's the matter? You don't answer
a mother fucking page?
-We got nothing to talk about?
-Oh, I think we do, don't you?
Straighten out all this shit, once and for all.
There is nothing to straighten out,
mother-fucker, I know it was you.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Johnny, I know.
I know!
And you're dead.
-Don't threaten me.
-Fuck that, it's a promise.
No matter where you go,
No matter what you do,
I am going to hunt you down.
I am going to hunt you down
then I am going to slit your throat.
Then I am going to cut you open, then
I am going to eat your mother fucking heart.
You better pray, Johnny,
you better fucking pray...
...that the cops find you before I do.
Get on your cock sucking knees and pray!
...Johnny Truelove on 2
Hey "cock and balls" what can I do for you?
Question for you:
Let's say that someone I know owes
someone money and won't pay.
So, that someone I know...
... has his boys snatch the dead-beats kid
brother until he does pay...
What kind of problems is he looking at?
Big Ones.
If he has an arrest he is looking at life.
Are you there cock?
-Life?
Life, yeah
So what does he do?
I don't know
He probably digs a deep hole...
Why? What's the matter?
Who's in trouble?
What the hell is he still doing here?
You have to chill the fuck out, Susan.
The way you keep running your fucking mouth,
Truelove could go to jail and we could wind up dead.
Fuck you, you don't know.
The mother fucker's crazy.
Yesterday he offered me $2, 500
to kill the kid.
What?
Yeah, right.
Kill him.
Oh Jesus
First you give me fucking mouth and
now you give me fucking tears?
Do me a favour Susan,
have a period or something.
Of course I am not going to do it...
I told him.  I am just saying that
is how spun he is.
I got it under control.
I got it under control. Alright?
Say it!
Say 'you, Frankie, have it under control'
You, Frankie, have it under control
Right. Now say...
"I, Susan, am a whiney fucking bitch..."
...and 'you, Frankie, have it under control'.
I, Susan, am a whiney fucking bitch and
you, Frankie, have it under control.
Right. Worse comes to worse I tell
everybody to go fuck themselves.
Put $50 in the kids pocket
and stick him on a bus.
You promise?
I swear.
See, bitch. Johnny.
Hey.  What's the word?
Great! What time?
Between 8 and 8:30.
Listen, man, I am going to have
to take him to a hotel or something.
Who's there?
My Dads bitch girlfriend up my
ass with a fucking broom.
-Let me know when you get there.
-Alright
-Okay?
-Alright, man.
I will call you when I get straight.
The kids going home.
-What's up buttheads?
-Buddy, buddy, buddy
We needed to borrow your Mum's car.
Moving?
Yeah, moving.
Hold it right there.
Yeah, let's go, yeah!
You kids have a good time.
What up?
When the fuck am I getting paid?
Get in there!
-You like this shit, yeah?
-Oh yeah.
-Everybody out!
-Get the fuck out of here!
Don't you see me on the toilet?
-When I say get the fuck out...
-Let go of me!
What the fuck you doing?
Jesus!
Listen to me, Ziggy, I say you
pays me today.
Oh? You don't have it?
Listen!, Let me tell you something.  If you
see me, you don't want to fucking see me.
Yeah, it is like that bitch.
-Fuck you!
-I'm getting off
-Is that guy giving you a problem?
-Yeah, why?
Let's kick his ass.
All of a sudden you're a tough guy?
I can fight him. I am fucking
black belt in Tae-Kwan-Do.
You're ass?
I am.
-Looks like a picked the wrong man
-No shit.
Shit! Come here you little fucker.
Let's go bitch!
How's that feel?
Zack, you're hurting him
Give him a little kiss.
Fucking dumped it everywhere.
The hell no, bitch
The hell no.  You size me up?
That was fucking awesome!
Awesome!
This little bitch can fight.
Amazing
Open the door!
We are fighting.
There is no room for bitches.
-or fucking queers
-Let that sack of monkey shit in.
-Don't call me a sack of monkey shit.
Jesus, what happened to your shit man.
-I don't know, but we are out of booze.
-Already?
Tell your little freeloader friends to slow the
fuck down then dude. I'm not made of money.
I need a cigarette.
Alright!
Everybody, keep everything under control.
This is him...
Zack, this is Elmer
Watch how fast I can down this shit.
Holy.... mother...
Nice.
You should see me with a beer bottle
Quit staring at me. You try!
Okay. Ready?
Go!
-So you're really stolen?
-Yeah, really am.
He's cute.
-You got a girlfriend, stolen boy?
-No
-How old are you?
-17.
-17?
This mother fucker is 15 years old.
Dude, what's your fucking problem.
I'm sorry
Jesus
They don't care anyway, man.
Ever been laid, stolen boy?
-It's my birthday.
-Happy birthday, girl
-You guys give us a second?
-Why?
-I need to talk to Elvis, something private.
-Hurry
So?
So what?
What do you think?
-What do I 'think'?
-Yeah, what do you think?
What do you mean 'what do I think'?
I mean about this whole thing.
I think no more music videos.
That's what I think.
Right.
Fuck it.
-Do you need anything? Money?
-No
Got gas?
I got gas.
Okay then.
Truelove.
Are you ready to drink?
On my birthday.
Where is he going?
I hate it that you have to work so late.
Happy birthday, Angie.
Eat a piece of cake for me.
What are you doing?
This is the middle of the night, get in
Turn around.
-I don't get it?
-Just turn around.
Start counting
1... 2...
...3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...10,
ready or not here I come.
-Marco?
-Polo.
You don't know every wish.
-What?
-I want to suck your cock.
Oh shit.
Wait, the wish is coming true.
The wish is coming true, oh Lordy.
My wish is coming true.
-Wait. I have to go make a call.
-No, you don't.
No, no,  why?
Bad.
-He's bad.
-Open the gifts.
What's happening, Zack?
I'm kinda busy.
-Johnny?
-I am on my way
-Great. How long?
-Half an hour. Get everyone out, alright?
Yeah, you got it. You got it.
Hey, Hey. Zack's going home, party over.
All you mother fuckers got to go.
Bye Zack,
I am glad you got home.
Thanks.
Now you got something to tell.
-Call me sometime.
-I will.
You'd better.
Good-bye, stud.
And wipe that smile of your face,
you're a dead fucking give away.
Don't fucking move.
What?
Hey dude, just hang out with us.
-Man I was going to catch a ride home.
-He has love weed.
-Fuck
-Love it
-Whoop you, ladies.
-See you guys later.
Drive really fast with your eyes closed.
You're an asshole.
Roll up!
Bye, gorgeous.
Took his virginity, baby.
We did it. We did it.
We love you a lot of Zack.
-Sonny?
-Hey, Elaine, how you doing?
-Is my boy here, I am looking for him.
-No, they went out for Angela's birthday.
Something's come up. Do you mind if we wait?
What are you doing here?
Outside.
What's the deal, Elvis?
Are you driving the kid home or what?
-What
-What?
-That's right.
What the fuck are you talking about?
-What the fuck?
-The kid ain't going home.
-But I thought that Johnny was...
-You thought wrong.
Fuck that, Johnny didn't tell me shit.
The decision's been made.
Fuck you!
Fuck me?
Johnny sent me here to take care of something
and I am going to fucking do it...
... with you or through you.
Who is sucking who's cock now, Frankie?
-Fuck that, I'm not...
-Fuck that. You're fucking in.
I'm up here cleaning up your mess and
you are going to fucking help me. .
...or the whole world is going to
come down on your head.
Alright! Fucking let go of me.
What the fuck do you want me to do?
We needed some tape.
-Fuck that
-Dig?
Dig this bitch!
-What you going to do. . ?
-Fuck that. No fucking way.
No fucking way, Elvis.
I am not digging.
Fuck you. I did my shit.
This is the line, mother-fucker. Everybody's
got one and mine is a fucking grave, alright?
You want to shoot me? Shoot me right
fucking here. I don't give a fuck.
Hey... excuse me.
Where's Frankie?
I need a ride home.
-What's going on, man?
-Come on! I need your help.
What the fuck do you need
duck tape for, dude?
Where is everybody?
Keith said he needed a ride home
so that guy gave him one.
What are you watching?
-Austin Powers.
-Alright.
Shit. So funny.
This shit has been going on for like...
2 minutes.
Do you want to run to the store for me?
Get me some cigarettes.
Dude, I am too young and they
wont sell to me.
Let's take a drive, go somewhere.
You wanna?
No.  I am cool.  I just want to watch a movie.
-Angela,  what did you do?
-Nothing
-Are you alright?
-She's fine.
-We are going in the other room...
-Fuck that. It is my birthday
-We are going, right now.
-Party's over...
. . wait a second.
-Fuck
-Don't you talk to your mother like that
We are trying to help you.
-Where's the kid?
-Who?
-Where is Mazursky?
-I don't know what you're talking about.
Dad, I swear.
Fucking get off me.
Stupid.  Stupid, John.
Don't you fucking get it, you moron?
There's missing person poster
on every street corner....
You're in deep shit, Johnny.  If the cops
pick you up, you're doing 25 to life.
-Don't you think I know that?
-You've fucked your life up so bad.
The only way to un-fuck it is for you to come
clean now, John. You come clean!
-Right now.
-Calm down.
Let me talk to him, alright?
Look, everybody is getting excited here.
What your Father is trying to say...
is that we have a plan.
You bring the kid home.
We have a sit down.
Me, you, the mother the father, everybody
Sonny brings his cheque book and
we settle it right there.
-It will never work.
-I'm not saying it will.
You are probably looking at some jail time.
But if that is the only option then I'll walk you
right through custody.  We will do it the right way.
I guarantee you do minimum sentence.
Be smart, kid.
-Let the spooks do the hard time.
-Fuck that! No jail.
2 years? Piece of cake.
Winter, summer, winter, summer, done.
No
Then tell us your plan, Einstein
You tell us how this all turns out.
-Hey Keith, what's up.
-I fell.
You fell?
Don't fucking touch me.
What's up?
What's up, buddy?
You're Zack, right?
Yeah
Well, I'm Elvis and I'm going
to take you home, man.
You coming?
You gotta do this, man.
It has got to be unanimous.
If the kid goes home,
everybody is looking at life.
-Life?
-Life.
We talked to a lawyer, man...
and there is no way around it.
Life, for what?
For taking care of the kid?
For letting him sleep at my fucking house?
You were there from square one. You sat on him the
whole fucking time, you think you're gonna walk?
God damn!
Life?
There it is.
I mean, I like the kid.
Who's not to like?
He's 15.
He's just too much of a liability.
Think about it. We sent the kid home,
you've got Jake looking for you.
You don't want that. You don't go along,
Johnny don't trust you and he's coming after you. .
and you sure as shit don't want Sonny
Truelove knocking at your door.
We don't have a choice man.
My parents are going to fucking kill me.
I can just see my Mom...
She's just fucking...
Oh God.
Hey? Guys?
Listen, I would never rat you guys out.
You guys and me are like... like this.
Frankie, you know that right?
Yeah, we know that man.
Good.
I'm probably just going to say that...
I ran away or something to like...
...Bakersfield or Fresno, or some place.
Fuck it, you know?
Hey. Does anyone know where Bakersfield is?
Say you were with a girl.
They would believe that.
Yeah, like Julie.
You know, when I get back...
...I am going to start fresh, you know?
I just want to start completely fresh.
D'you ever feel like that, Frankie?
-What's that?
-Like...
I don't know, like, go to Europe or something.
Or take a class or something like that.
or learn to play and instrument...
like guitar.
It sounds really fucking hard
to play guitar, but...
... it bugs me that I don't know
how to do anything.
I'm pretty sure I could, I'm...
Johnny, call it off
Nothing is going to happen. These guys are such
fuck ups the kid is probably loose right now.
Get in the fucking car!
What are we doing?
Meeting somebody who is
going to take you home.
Oh. Cool
You know? I think I am going to
start being nicer to my Mom
It's kinda gay, but...
... if you think about it. . she is the shit,
she is like my best friend, you know?
Fuck it. I can't do this man.
I gotta fucking go home.
Dude, what's going on?
You're crying.
Get away from me.
What's the matter with him?
Him?
Frankie, what's going on?
Frank?
Frankie?
Dude?
-Oh, man.
-Ready? Let's do this.
-Man, please.
-Move!. Shut the fuck up!
-Please, I pray to God
-Relax.
-Frankie?
-Relax, Okay.  It's not what you think.
Yes it is. , Frankie.
Please. I thought we were boys.
-We ARE boys.
-Frankie, there is nobody up there.
Nobody's picking me up.
Yes, there is, ok?
Just stop freaking out.
-You promise?
-I promise.
Zack, everything cool. On my life.
Okay? I swear to God.
Come on.
I swear to God.
-Alright, man.
-Come on, man.
-Just walk.
-Alright.
We are just going to take a walk.
Come on, man.
Frankie, oh please?
I won't tell anybody, I swear to God
We are not going to do this, right?
I mean, we are not really going to do this. .
-Shut the fuck up.
-You ain't going to do it.
-Shut your fucking mouth.
-He's crazy.
-This is stupid, man.
-God damn, it you got a conscience?
I won't tell my Mom about anything.
Shut his fucking mouth or
I'll fucking shoot him.
-Alright, alright
-I'll Shoot him
-I'll never see you again, I swear
-Hey!
Look little man, you gotta calm down, alright?
-Everybody is nervous, right?
-I don't want to die, Frankie
Everything is ok.
-Alright?
-Frankie!
So what's the tape for, Frankie?
I would never hurt you Zackie, alright?
-Okay
-But I'll have to tape you up. .
So give me your hands
-Okay
-Everything is going to be alright.
-Hey, hey... I am your boy.
-I know.
-Okay
-Alright?
Everything is okay.
I don't want to die, Frankie.
I don't want to die
Now, I am going to have to
tape your mouth up, ok?
Alright. Okay
You're my boy.
I wouldn't hurt you
-Everything is okay.
-Alright.  I know
-Are you ready?
-Yeah.
What the fuck are you doing?
Oh fuck.
Jesus fucking Christ
It was 6 o'clock in the morning...
Several... black cars pulled up and ....
There were men in suits....
And the... door bell was just ringing.
'We found your son'... they said
'We found your son'....
'... and it's.... '
...bad news. '
They said.
What about the funeral...
-Jake didn't show?
-No.
He said it was out of respect for me.
That's a crock.
He just didn't want top get hit.
Sorry, I don't understand.
Shot, killed, murdered.
I happen to know he owes
$50, 000 to one drug dealer.
They have their own rules in the drug world.
They killed my son
for 1200 dollars.
>I am so sorry for your loss.
>I mean I cant even imagine
When my son died,
I died.
I always loved him.
Every single day of my life...
and I wasn't afraid to show him.
What made you try to kill yourself?
You know....
It seemed like a long time to my natural death.
I don't know
You know, all three times...
...I tried to commit suicide
there was alcohol involved.
When I tried to kill me myself
in the hospital... I did wrong.
You know, your supposed to ...
do it like this.
Maybe it was the pills.
It's all bullshit anyway.
They say...
. . there is a reason for everything.
Well, if that God has got a purpose for me...
...he better get the fuck down
here and tell me what it is.
Because I don't see it.
I think that might be enough for today.
Okay?
Thanks
-Was that okay?
-Yes.
Okay
Sorry.
Jo!.  What's up?
Zack's dead
How'd you know that?
I had nothing to do with this.
I never laid a finger on him.
I didn't know this happened, Susan
I can't believe it happened.
-What the fuck is going on, Frankie?
-I don't know.
-Tell me the truth!
-I don't know. I think I am getting set up.
-Did you fucking take him home?
-Yes, I dropped him off in Pomona.
Where? What street?
At his father's fucking house?
I don't know, okay?
I dropped him off in Pomona.
You'd better get yourself a good lawyer.
Fuck you.
Can't come in here, man.
I'm serious, man. Get the fuck out of here.
I'm in trouble, Pick.
No shit.  With my Mom's car, man
-Why'd you do it, huh?
-Sorry
Mother fucker! Do you know how
much shit I've been through with this?
I'm fucked, Pick. You got to help me.
Can you just give me your car?
No, man.  Fuck that.
-Can you give me a ride out of town.
-Get the fuck out of here, man
-Where the fuck do you want me to go?
-It's your fucking problem.
Man, you got to let me use your phone.
I got to call Johnny.  Please?
Please?
Look, man... I love you
but your on your own.
Keep your hand in the air or I'll
blow your fucking head off.
Get down! I'm not fucking
with you asshole. Get down!
Down, on your knees now!
I can't believe it.  They got Tiko too?
Tiko, Elvis, 911. They got everybody.
For what?
What the fuck do you think, baby?
That kid turned up dead.
Hey the captain and Tennille
-What can I do for you guys?
-Hey.  I 'd like to trade that for that.
-You want to trade this car for that car?
-Yeah.
Alright.  Let's go get you a loan out.
Wait, we don't have to do that.
You wanna fuck?
Alright
-Something wrong?
-No
No?
Your dicks not even hard.
-It's getting there.
-Getting there?
-Yes it's getting there.
-It's like a piece of bubble gum.
Then do something about it, bitch.
Unbelievable.
I hadn't seen Johnny since junior high.
I mean what a coincidence.
I look up and he is right there.
>Did he tell you want happened?
He told me some friends of his had
done some bad shit and he
was going down for it.
He said he was in big trouble and
needed help to get out of the country.
>And you agreed to drive him, just like that?
Yeah.
He's my boy.
He was stuck.
>Alright.  Go on.
Alright.  So we go up by 25, right. . ?
...and this guy is acting fucking weird, dude.
Talking about God and forgiveness.
All kinds of crazy shit.
So, we get to the border crossing...
And he starts flipping out...
...going crazy and I'm like
'dude, fucking calm down, bro'
'...we stop, we pull over, you get
in the trunk, it's all good...'
and he is like 'no, no, they know, they know'
You should have seen it.
He was going out of his mind.
So, we turn around, We turn around again.
Now he wants to go to Mexico.
So, we go all the way back down, drive
all the way back down and get to Cheyenne...
...and he changes his mind again.
I'm like: 'All right, dude.  That's it'.
'I can't do this forever. '
'Where the fuck do you want to go?'
I'll be right back.
I mean it, right?
5 minutes.
Alright, I wait for you.
It's been 4 years since your sons escape and,
you know what, I think you helped him.
I think you know exactly where he is?
There it is: the million dollar question.
What you, the cops, the feds, the
DA wants to know, right?
Somebody had to help him get out of the country.
Somebody has to be sending him money.
I do not know where my son is.
And if I knew, do you think I would
tell you and this fucking camera?
I think he is lost.
What?
The day he was dropped off at my house,
I reached into the fridge to get a sandwich...
I turned around and he was gone.
-Come on!.
-I am telling you, he's lost.
I think he is right
I mean, I ain't seen him.
He ain't here.
Must be lost.
Now, get the fuck outta my house!
Watch full movies online for free at www.awooh.com