She's the person I told you about...
back then.
Then you mean...
she's the person you love?
Yes.
The live-in helper...
who has a child?
Yes, you're right. That's her.
Why are you so shocked?
What? Oh, I'm sorry.
Then her husband.
Is he dead?
That's what I heard.
I see.
Why did you ask about her?
Sorry. I just blurted out a few questions.
I apologize if I offended you.
No, it's fine.
Are you both leaving for Japan together?
No, I'm going alone.
Aren't you two getting married soon?
Well...
We aren't able to get married.
Some things don't happen
however hard you try.
But there is someone I love.
Is there?
Will you marry her soon?
I would like to,
but it's one-sided at the moment.
She doesn't know I like her yet.
I plan to tell her soon.
Who's the young lady that you were with?
She's the person I told you about...
back then.
(CEO Jung Jae Man)
Come in.
Dad.
Se Young. Are you back from class?
Yes. Is Jeong Wook out meeting a buyer?
Didn't you see him?
He went to Shinchon so
I told him to see you.
Did you? I didn't see him.
Maybe I just missed him.
Maybe.
Dad, about our wedding.
Se Young, we'll talk about that at home.
I'm working now.
Se Young.
You're home.
Are you going out?
Yes, to the bank.
Did you ask Dad about my wedding?
I practically begged him yesterday,
but he won't budge. Wait a little longer.
How much longer? We've been
engaged for four years.
Your dad needs time to think.
What's there to think about?
It's my wedding, not his.
If he won't give permission,
I really will leave home.
We'll move out and register our marriage.
Will you stop it?
Okay, Se Young.
I'll talk to your dad once more.
Don't say that again, okay?
My goodness.
(Daehan Bank)
I can't believe I have...
a bank account in my name.
I never thought this day...
would ever come.
How can you live without an account?
I didn't have time to open one.
I always lost the money I earned.
You can be so silly.
From now on, save up your monthly salary...
and don't waste it.
Okay. Let's see how it feels to save up.
Ever since I met you,
I think I was born again.
I'm yours now.
What's he doing over there?
- I'm your parasol.
- I'm fine.
Your arms will hurt.
- Let's go.
- My goodness.
Did that fool just give away his money?
What should I do with him?
Man Pyo.
Do you want to talk to me?
You and that Seol Hee woman.
What were you two at the bank for?
Did you give her money?
I did not.
She said I needed a savings
account if I wanted to save up.
She helped me open one.
You fool. Don't you see
she's waiting until...
you save up so she can take it?
Seol Hee's not that kind of person.
I bet she is.
Did she tell you I gave her money?
Do you know she took it and
agreed to break up with you?
Money?
Do you mean this?
Why do you have it?
Seol Hee said you dropped it
when you visited her cafe.
My goodness. Did you try to...
pay her off to leave me?
Here, take it.
I didn't touch a bill. It's all there.
Don't doubt Seol Hee.
I'm really embarrassed for you now.
How could you do that?
I'm not doing this for me.
It's for your sake.
Sook Hee, when in my life did
I ever open a bank account?
Here. See for yourself.
Thanks to Seol Hee, I own a bank account.
I'm becoming a decent person.
Can't you appreciate Seol Hee a little bit?
Honey, are you really
trying to torture Se Young?
She hasn't been eating. She might faint.
Go and bring her over.
Right now? What for?
What will you say to her?
Just go and get her.
Sit down.
You two can get married.
Do you mean that?
Yes. The children always win in the end.
Thank you, Dad.
Thank you.
Se Young, why are you crying?
Because I'm happy. I'm so pleased.
What's that look about?
You got permission to marry.
Are you not pleased?
I am.
Thank you, Father.
Let's hold the ceremony soon since
that's what Se Young wants.
Call your family.
Yes, I will.
We're getting married at last.
It doesn't feel real yet.
You're right. It doesn't.
Leave all the preparations to me.
You're busy. My mom and I
will take care of things.
Okay. Why did you cry earlier?
I told you. Because I was happy.
I was really afraid Dad
wouldn't let us get married...
for a while longer.
Were you in the Shinchon area?
Dad said you'd come to see me.
Why didn't you?
I couldn't because my meeting ran late.
Did it?
Yes. You must be tired.
You should go downstairs.
Okay. Sleep well.
Then her husband.
Is he dead?
That's what I heard.
Who's he?
My son.
You look smart. What's your man?
Ji Hoon.
Soo In's son's dad is dead?
(Shinchon Cafe)
Why did you want to see me?
I met Chungil's Mr. Kim yesterday.
You and his relationship. I had
no clue even when I saw you...
in Madam Cho's office.
I'm not sure you know, but Taesan...
has done business with Chungil for years...
and for many reasons the
companies work closely together.
So what?
I'd heard that Mr. Kim was
upsetting his grandmother...
because he wanted to marry the
live-in helper who had a child.
I just can't believe that woman was you.
How could this be?
What is it you want to say?
Se Young thinks you're
married to a rich man.
What happened?
She got the wrong idea.
She saw me with Mr. Kim...
and assumed that we were married.
Your son.
Who's his dad?
Why do you ask?
Why should I tell you that?
Is he...
my son?
- He isn't.
- Are you sure?
Yes. He isn't yours.
Then tell me who his dad is.
Who's the dad?
He's dead.
He's dead? Is that the truth?
Yes.
If the child's dad really is dead,
why did you live in hiding for so long?
Why didn't you come to Incheon?
Wasn't that because your son is mine?
How many times must I say he isn't yours?
I don't think we have a
reason to keep meeting up.
You and I broke up long ago.
Don't come here ever again.
If the child's dad really is dead,
why did you live in hiding for so long?
Why didn't you come to Incheon?
Wasn't that because your son is mine?
Soo In, where were you?
Who came to see you?
Ms. Baek said she'd never seen him before.
It was someone I used to know.
Was it?
Are you okay?
You don't look good. Are you sick?
No, I'm fine.
Jung In, I'd like to take Ji Hoon home.
Home?
To Incheon?
Yes.
You're doing the right thing.
Everyone knows about Ji Hoon now.
There's no reason you can't visit.
Ji Hoon must be pleased he
gets to visit his relatives.
You should go now.
I will.
Find out about Soo In and her child.
She was born in 1953. When
was she married and to whom?
I want to know everything.
As soon as possible.
Really? She's bringing Ji Hoon to visit?
Okay, okay.
Soo In's visiting home?
Yes, today, with her son.
That's great news. How long
has it been since she left?
Four years?
Yes, something like that.
I'd been missing my grandson
and was thinking of...
visiting Seoul. I'm glad they're visiting.
Mr. Bang. Can I leave early today?
Of course you can. Go and
welcome your grandson.
Don't worry about the store.
Go and enjoy the boy's antics.
I will. Thank you.
10 receipts each for 10,000 equals 100,000.
Please check.
It's all there. I checked.
Did you get the money?
Yes. Thank you so much
for your help, Mr. Jung.
Well done.
I was afraid he'd suspect something.
It all worked out because you
have an amicable relationship.
He's in no position to suspect anyone.
He needs to grab onto whatever
lifesaver he can find.
I guess so.
I'm glad we're off to a good start.
Our next target is Director Jung.
Madam Cho filled the board
with people she trusts.
It won't be easy to find a weakness.
If I can't find one, I'll make one.
That's the way. I trust you will do well.
Do whatever it takes to set something up.
Yes, sir.
This is the budget for the Japan office.
Tell me what you think.
Okay, I will.
You haven't been back for long
and you calculated the budget?
You're really quick.
Once the office opens,
we'll have to live apart for a few years.
I don't quite like the idea.
I won't be away too long.
Once the office is up on track,
I can leave someone else in charge.
I promise I'll visit you often.
I see. I said something I
shouldn't have and upset you.
It's okay.
We both get off work early.
How about we have dinner at home together?
I was planning just that.
We can go home together.
Good. It's been a while since
we left work together.
Did you pass the budget to Madam Cho?
Yes, I just did.
Mr. Jang.
Yes, sir.
I thought about how I'd decided to
take you to Japan to work with me.
I think I should take Mr. Han instead.
He can help me open the new office.
What do you mean?
Did I do something wrong?
No. I'm just worried about Grandma.
She'll be alone once I leave.
I'd like you to look after her.
Right. I understand what you mean.
I won't be able to fill your empty place,
but I will do my best to
care for her and her health.
Don't worry, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Jang.
There's so much shopping to do.
- Isn't there?
- You silly thing.
Why did you have to rush things?
There's barely enough time...
to get our head around what we must do.
Don't you get sick of saying that?
Can't we enjoy doing
what we must do anyway?
You always know what to say.
I'll drop by to see Hee Ja.
You head home first.
Why do you want to see her?
She recently married off her daughter.
She'll know which stores to go to.
- See you later.
- Okay.
Mom, where is your house?
It's just up ahead. Why? Do your legs hurt?
No, I'm okay.
Then let's go. We're almost there.
"Mom"?
Is that little boy her son?
She should be here by now.
I should have gone to pick them up.
No. She's visiting for
the first time in years.
Instead of treating her like a visitor,
we should let her find her own way back.
I see what you mean.
Seeing that Soo In decided
to bring Ji Hoon over...
makes me think she made up her mind.
Right. It can't have been easy.
I think she's very determined.
I was actually more
worried about Dong Chul.
I thought he might ban
Soo In and Ji Hoon...
for fear of what the neighbors would think.
I wonder why he hasn't made a peep.
I think it's because of Ji Hoon.
He doesn't show it, but he adores Ji Hoon.
Why wouldn't he? Ji Hoon's
his first grandson.
Hello.
- Welcome.
- You're here at last.
We were wondering where you were.
Hello, Ji Hoon.
Hello.
- Are you well?
- Yes.
You must be hungry. Let's eat.
Okay. I'd like to go out after that.
Where do you want to go?
To Mom's grave.
Oh, of course.
I'll look after Ji Hoon while you're gone.
Okay.
You haven't been in a while
because you were busy here.
Go and visit Soon Ok with Soo In.
Okay, I'll do that.
Se Young. Se Young.
What's wrong?
Do you know who I just saw?
What's this about? Who did you see?
Tell me the truth.
Did you know that Soo In has a child?
Who told you that?
Did you know already?
Who told you?
No one did. I just saw
them with my two eyes.
What? Where did you see them?
In the street after we parted.
She's visiting with her son.
What? Soo In's in Incheon? Is that true?
Now talk to me straight.
Why didn't you tell me Soo In had a child?
It's not important.
Why isn't it important?
You'd been acting strangely.
You yelled at Jeong Wook...
and wanted to rush the wedding.
Isn't that all because of Soo In?
It's not. What are you talking about?
Are you sure? Does it really
have nothing to do with Soo In?
It doesn't.
Then tell me who's the father of her child?
I told you that Soo In's
married to a rich man.
Are you sure that man fathered her child?
How many times must I say yes?
I need to check for myself.
This won't do.
You're so good at drawing.
Who is this?
Mr. Kim.
Mr. Kim?
Do you mean Seon Woo?
Yes. I want to see him,
but he won't come to see
me so I'm drawing him.
- Ms. Hong.
- Hello.
What are you doing here?
I came out to do some shopping
and dropped by for some soup.
Who's this little boy?
Hello.
Hello there.
Grandma, I'll draw Mom now.
Okay.
"Grandma"? Do you have a grandson already?
Is this Soo In's child?
Yes.
Is she married?
Why did she get married so secretively?
I had no idea.
Is Soo In visiting you?
Yes. For a short while.
Did her husband come with her?
No.
The boy's quite big. How old is he?
Hey, how old are you?
Ji Hoon! Ji Hoon.
You're early.
I came straight over here to see Ji Hoon.
Look who's here.
You're Taesan's Ms. Hong.
Are you here to have some soup?
Well... Yes.
Honey, can you take Ji Hoon home?
I'm having trouble serving
customers with him around.
Okay then.
Ji Hoon, let's go home with Grandpa.
Come along now.
Jeong Wook. Jeong Wook.
What's the matter, Mother?
Are you... Are you...
What?
Never mind. Is my husband in?
No, he left to see a buyer.
Did he?
Did you have something to say to me?
No, no. You can get back to work.
The small stars are sparkling everywhere.
In the eastern sky.
You're such a good singer.
In the western sky.
Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
How I wonder what you are.
Well done. I'm proud of you.
Sit on my lap.
You must be tired. Put him down.
I'm not tired at all. He's
as light as a feather.
Ji Hoon, do you like sitting on my lap?
Yes.
How come you answer like such a big boy?
I told your mom already.
Instead of suffering alone in Seoul,
why don't you come home to Incheon?
Honey, leave that to her to decide.
She can relax with her family around...
and we get to see Ji Hoon's
antics all the time.
I only just started working...
and agreed to live with Jung In.
I think I should stay in
Seoul a while longer.
I'll think about moving back after that.
Okay. People already know what happened.
Don't worry about the gossip.
Come back whenever you want to.
I will.
Hello?
Hi, Se Young.
What are you up to?
What do you mean?
What are you doing in
Incheon with your son?
Am I not allowed to be here?
This is my hometown and
my family lives here.
Why can't I visit?
You never came here once.
Why are you here now?
I know what you're worried about.
Don't you think it's better
if I were to visit often?
The more I hide, the more people will talk.
I'm going to bring Ji Hoon
to Incheon when I want...
and see my family.
Uncle Dae Bong told me
you're getting married.
There will be no problems
once you're married.
Stop worrying about us
and focus on living...
a happy life with Jeong Wook.
We'll get on with ours.
(Incheon Cafe)
Soo In.
Like you said, I hope we never have to...
see each other again.
Right. That's what I want.
Jeong Wook.
I met Soo In for a chat because she
came to Incheon after so long.
I see.
We'll head home first. See you.
He's so sweet.
I can't get enough of him.
He's my own grandson.
There's a reason they
say "apple of my eye".
I don't think I can do without him now.
Seeing you love Ji Hoon so much...
makes me feel so happy.
Why wouldn't I love my grandson?
I've been thinking about something.
How about we register Ji
Hoon as Dal Ja's son?
As if he's adopted?
Yes. Right now he doesn't exist on paper.
That might be the best
for Soo In and Ji Hoon.
I'm not sure. I think we should
ask Dae Bong and Dal Ja first.
We don't know what Soo In will say either.
It's not an easy decision to make.
Dal Ja can't have children.
If she were to adopt him on paper,
it might make her feel better
and Soo In benefits too.
Let's give it some more time.
Okay.
Soo In's spending quite a
long time with her friend.
I'll wait for her outside.
Okay.
Why are you out here?
Because you were so late.
What did Se Young want to talk about?
She just wanted to catch up.
Did she?
Was it not about anything else?
No. Where's Ji Hoon?
He's sleeping in our room.
You must be tired. Go to bed.
I will.
What do you want to say?
Why did you see Soo In?
Why do you think? She's my friend.
Can't friends meet up?
"Friends"? You know what I'm talking about.
Why did you meet up?
Why do you care?
Se Young.
This is really upsetting me.
Do not ask or even care
about Soo In anymore.
Not unless you still have feelings for her.
Taesan Noodles.
Do you have something?
Yes. In April of 1973, Yoon
Soo In went to a clinic...
where she was recorded to
be four weeks pregnant.
Is that true?
Yes, and in December of the same year,
she had a son at Somang Hospital in Seoul.
Okay, thank you.
Have you lost your mind?
You know that Jeong Wook
and Soo In had a child...
and you still want to marry the man?
Mom, please.
Se Young!
Hello, mister.
Why are you here?
I wanted to see you.
If Mr. Choi knows that Ji Hoon is his son,
might he not come back to you?
Give it back.
You don't even have a dad.
Ji Hoon.
What? Ji Hoon's missing?