Oh, well, none of us can live forever.
Remarkable man, the colonel.
A girl's earring.
Remarkable.
What a lovely sunrise.
Too bad he just missed it.
Hello.
Yes, this is Mr. Tony Ryder.
He did?
When?
I see.
I see, yeah.
Thanks forcalling.
- Bad news, sweetie?
- Yeah. My uncle, honey.
Look, you... You better leave,
sweetheart.
- Get going.
- But don't...
- But, Tony...
- That's all right.
- You call me later.
- But, Tony...
Goodbye.
But, Tony, I live here.
- Take a look, Mr. O'Hara.
- I'm looking.
The Ryder Building.
Fifty stories of glass and steel.
With a statue ofthe colonel
on the top.
In solid bronze.
Holding one ofhis magazines.
Your magazines now.
- He left everything to you, me boy.
- Even you.
I'll do me very best to serve you with
the same devotion I did the colonel.
Tell me something.
How do you follow a man like that?
It won't be easy, lad.
You know, I've got to prove to them
that I'm as good a man forthis job
as my uncle was.
- Yes, sir.
- That won't be easy.
- No, sir.
Well, you know, in five minutes
I'm going to head up
my first board meeting.
- You think I'll get away with it?
- Sure you will, Mr. Ryder.
That's one ofthe advantages
ofbeing at the top.
Anybody who tells you you're making
a mistake is making a bigger mistake.
Sure, and I feel betternow.
I still can't believe he's not going
to walk through that door
and tell us what's wrong
with the latest issues.
He'stelling it to that big publisher
up there.
What about young Ryder? Do you
think he'sthe right man to take over?
We don't have much choice.
He'sthe only relative.
Gentlemen.
- Good morning.
Greetings, my boy.
Welcome, welcome.
Mr. Albright, Mr. Baker,
Mr. Carter, Mr. Weaver.
How do you do?
Oh, no, no, no. Excuse me.
The chairman ofthe board sits here.
The colonel's chairfor you, my boy.
Thank you.
Well, now, then, I'd like to make
my position absolutely clear.
My late uncle and I, we hardly...
Oh, sorry.
Hardly knew each other.
In fact, we were practically strangers.
Some of you may think
the only reason
I'm the new chairman ofthe board
is because I'm his only relative.
Oh, not at all, not at all.
Nevertheless, it's true. Anyway, I'll
do the best I can, and that's about it.
You'll do fine, Tony. Believe me,
your past reputation is behind you.
From a useless life to a life of use,
that'sthe way I look at it.
Nothing like responsibility
to give a man backbone.
- And initiative.
- And drive.
You may not be much,
but you're all we've got.
Thank you, gentlemen,
for your vote of confidence.
Now, what's our problem fortoday?
The colonel.
He picked a critical time to die.
What about our overseas
expansion program?
We've been trying to float a bank loan
for $5 million. Now what?
We'll open our European branches
next month, right on schedule.
What do we use for money?
Oh, I took care ofthe bank loan
overthe weekend.
I called on an old skin-diving buddy
of mine, Pudge Hamilton.
Hamilton? OfHamilton Trust?
His son. Anyway, the bank is willing
to back us on the colonel's reputation.
That's wonderful news, Tony.
Of course, they'll have to ratify it
at theirfinance meeting Wednesday.
In the meantime, I jotted down some
figures on the expansion program.
Afew more here.
Didn't win a bet that day.
Oh, shot a 76.
That was all right.
Mr. Ryder.
Amortization. Profit potential.
See what you think ofit, fellas.
He's a very commonplace man.
He said it was important.
But I don't know
any house detectives.
Did he happen to mention
any particular city?
- Like London? Paris? Omaha?
- No, sir.
Just that there was
a young lady involved.
Oh, well, it's probably just a case
of mistaken identity.
I'd better see him,
straighten this out.
I didn't know he could even spell
"amortization. "
Mr. Ryderwill see you now,
Mr. Lasker.
Gloria?
Jeanie?
Jackie?
Mr. Ryder, I think there's
something you ought to know.
Now I remember. Quebec.
Chateau Sans Souci.
Yeah, I can explain about that girl
in my room that night.
She said she was a ski instructor.
I didn't find out till later...
It wasn't Quebec.
Palm Beach. Mirador Hotel.
Mira...? Mirador?
Well, that's where my uncle
always stays.
- Or stayed.
- Oh, yes, sir.
With him being youruncle,
his reputation and all,
I figured you didn't want
this kind ofthing to get out.
Has she contacted you yet?
Who contacted me?
Your uncle's girlfriend.
His girl...?
Look, you'd betterfill me in.
I don't know what you're...
Sit down, won't you.
Sure. Sure.
You see, I was on duty
early Saturday morning.
I got this complaint that there was
a disturbance on the ninth floor.
I went up to investigate. When
I got halfway down the corridor,
I spotted this girl running out
of your uncle's bedroom.
Oh, well, I could think of a million
innocent explanations forthat.
She could have been a manicurist.
- At 3 a. M?
- Three a. m.
Wearing a Turkish towel?
A masseuse.
You know, Turkish towel? No?
- What did you do? Did you catch her?
- I tried.
But she beat me to the elevator
and got away.
When I got back, your uncle's room,
the place was all a shambles.
The furniture was knocked down,
the lamp was broken.
He was in bed.
Dead.
He was smiling.
Smiling?
Have you told anybody else
about this?
No, no, sir. No, no.
Only the manager.
He thought it would be betterfor
everybody if we just kept this quiet.
- Did you ever see this girl before?
- No, sir.
- Did you get a good look at her?
- Yeah!
That is, I'd recognize her
ifl saw her again.
Say, maybe this'll help.
It's an earring I found
on the floor nearthe bed.
I checked.
That inscription means
"good" in Chinese.
Chinese.
Look, I'll keep this.
Do you think you could stay around
fora few days?
The boss said to do
anything you asked.
Youruncle was
a very good customer.
Good. Well, my secretary'll
get you a hotel room.
I have a hunch this girl's
gonna show up,
and I want you to identify her.
Oh, it'd be a pleasure.
In the meantime,
consider yourself on the payroll.
We'll just charge it offto...
- Research?
- Research.
These are very interesting figures,
Tony. We'd like to talk to you...
He was a remarkable man.
He was a more remarkable man
than you think.
Sam, you were
the colonel's oldest friend.
Thirty years' worth.
Did he have any love affairs, I mean,
after my aunt died? Did he ever...?
Never. The colonel had
only one love, his work.
He built his whole empire
on fidelity and chastity.
Well, now, Sam, there was
that lady dentist in Seattle.
Purely platonic.
Anyway, we paid her off years ago.
Well, what about
that female archeologist?
That tall woman with the pith helmet?
Threatened to expose him
to the National Geographic?
You notice she stopped that kind
ofirresponsible talk in a hurry.
Yeah.
The minute we paid her off.
Boys, I've got a flash for you.
The colonel died with
an undressed girl in his bedroom.
I'm not certain about her occupation,
but I have a hunch that payoffnumber
three is right around the corner.
And the house dick at the Mirador
said he saw a girl running
from Uncle Charlie's bedroom
wearing this.
- Just an earring?
- And a Turkish towel.
This means "good" in Chinese.
And 10-to-1 that the mate
to this says "luck. "
It ought to. That young woman
has us over a barrel.
Blackmail.
I can see the headlines:
"Founder ofFamily Magazine Dies
in Love Nest with a Naked Nymph. "
And a smile on his face.
The bank loan!
Lfthey hear about this,
we won't be able to borrow a quarter!
- What are we going to do?
- Buy her offlike the others.
Where do we find her?
I have a funny feeling she'll find us.
I can draw you a picture ofher.
She's young, beautiful, sentimental,
especially about money.
I can even spot her entrance.
- Where?
- At the funeral.
Where's a better place
to show the world
how much she's gonna miss
the colonel?
So we will know Thursday.
No, that'll be too late.
The bank committee meets
Wednesday.
- We'll have the funeral Tuesday.
- That'stomorrow.
What about all the preparations?
We were going to give him
a military ceremony.
Some four-star generals were
coming up from Washington.
We wanted him to go out in style.
Sam, he went out in style.
Katie! Hi!
Hello, Marge.
Welcome back
to the decompression chamber.
- Well, how was Palm Beach?
- It was all right, I guess.
All right? Is that all you've gotta say?
What'd you do there?
I got a tan and lost an earring.
Palm Beach, moonlight, millionaires,
and all you lost was an earring?
Didn't you get to meet any
ofthose millionaires?
- What made you ask that?
- Just my feminine sense of greed.
- Well, did you?
- Yes. I met a millionaire.
What's that? Who sitsthere?
The new researcher. Aman.
Imagine.
I haven't met him yet.
Research, Robbins.
Hi. Guess who this is.
Well, I'll give you a hint.
I'm tall, witty, good-looking...
...and you're simply mad about me.
- Warren.
Oh, how sweet of you to call.
What'sthe matterwith yourvoice?
You ought to see a doctor.
But, honey, I am a doctor.
It's nothing serious.
Just something I picked up
from one of my patients.
- How was Florida?
- Oh, it was all right.
- But I'm glad I'm back.
- So am I.
And so will Mom and Dad be.
- Oh, yourfolks are in town?
- Just got in this morning.
They can't wait to meet you.
- Well, I hope they like me.
- They'll love you.
Oh, well, that makes me feel better.
How about the four of us getting
together, say, Wednesday night?
Oh, that's fine. Fine.
I'd love to.
- I'll see you then.
- Goodbye, dear.
Bye.
Now, then, old man, let's just
make sure this isn't psychosomatic.
Say, 'Woof, woof. "
You know, you're sure lucky to be
marrying a professional man
who owns his own business. I don't
know why you even went to Florida.
Oh, I went to think it over.
Warren's a wonderful man, Marge,
but I don't know ifl, well...
- Love him?
- No. Deserve him.
Every girl deserves a man,
whethershe deserves him or not.
Katie, come on, come on.
We're keeping them waiting.
- Who?
- The brass, the brass.
You're on the bargaining committee.
Oh, no, Harry.
I'm on Health and Welfare.
You've been kicked upstairs, kiddo.
Union-wise, you're in the big time.
But I've been working on pink paper
towels forthe ladies' lounge.
Chicken feed, chicken feed.
Now we're gonna hit them
with some real stiff demands.
We'll probably be knocking heads
right through lunch hour.
Oh, but, no, I have to do some
shopping during my lunch hour.
You see, I have to have a "good"
to go with my "luck. "
Now, don't be upset
if I do some table-pounding.
And wheneverthey make a demand,
you just shake your head
and look worried.
But I am worried.
The union committee is here.
- This way, please.
- Thank you.
Oh, this is Mr. Ryder.
Mr. Ryder, Mr. Lane, Mr. Kowalski.
How are you?
This is Katie Robbins,
the new member of our committee.
Joe Kowalski.
Katie, this is Mr. Ryder.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
Katie.
All right, now, let's get the ball rolling.
- Here'sthe union proposal.
- Absolutely ridiculous.
This is no proposal.
It is a knife at ourthroat!
Don't you think
we should read it first?
Strong medicine, eh, Mr. Ryder?
Seems pretty reasonable.
It seems reasonable on the surface.
- But can management live with it?
- No!
That's not an answer,
it's an ultimatum.
- Take it or leave it!
- It's a knife at ourthroat!
- I said that.
- Gentlemen, please.
What do you think, Miss?
Robbins. Katie Robbins.
I'm in Research.
Research? Oh, that's one of our more
vital departments in the organization.
- Where is it?
- Forty-fifth floor,
behind the water cooler.
"Cooler. "
You could hardly call it that,
the way it's been working lately.
I was just saying the other day in
Health and Welfare, we really should...
Is that with two B's?
What, cooler?
No, Robbins.
- Yes, two B's.
- B's, B's.
Miss Robbins, we've got
a very important agenda here.
I'm sorry.
Severance pay. Seniority rights.
Fringe benefits.
She said she was sorry.
When it comesto fringe benefits,
I'd say the union's getting
all the benefits and management's
left holding the fringe.
- Well put.
- All we want's a fair deal.
- Ashare ofthe profits.
- And a new water cooler.
Well, I mean, on a hot day,
really, our morale...
Will you forget the water cooler.
Look, if you don't wanna negotiate,
we're walking out.
- All right, walk.
- Gentlemen, gentlemen.
This bickering is getting us no place.
Now, I suggest we adjourn
to a subcommittee oftwo,
to feel each other out.
Mr. Dunning, why don't you
meet Harry afterlunch.
Oh, just a minute.
I have a better idea.
Now, a subcommittee oftwo is
an excellent suggestion,
but any feeling-out process should
logically take place between members
ofthis group who haven't displayed
antagonism towards one another.
In otherwords,
between Miss Robbins and myself.
Now, you don't feel antagonistic
towards me, do you, Miss Robbins?
Well, no.
Good. Nor I towards you. So it seems
logical that you and I should meet.
You and I meet?
- Oh, now, orafter lunch?
- During lunch.
No use wasting
valuable working hours.
Meeting adjourned.
Yeah, well, keep looking.
Gotcha.
I'll be back, but if I get
any out-of-town calls...
Oh, I...
I will be so glad to take them.
Don't take them.
Oh, don't take them. Gotcha.
Don't... Don't take them.
Gotcha.
Oh, pardon me.
What'sthis, Marge?
I don't know. It came
for you a few minutes ago.
It must be that bathing suit
I bought in Palm Beach.
They were having a sale
at this little place...
Marge, somebody made a mistake.
Oh, my dear, I wish I did.
This isn't my coat!
"Miss Katie Robbins. "
Well, it's another Katie Robbins!
"Ryder Building, New York,
New York. "
Well, it's another New York!
I guess it is my coat, isn't it.
Marge.
- Yes?
- Can you keep a secret?
Oh, Katie, I'd just love to.
Just give me the chance.
I wanted to be by myself
on my vacation,
you know, sort ofthink things over,
about Warren
and getting married and all.
Well, it's too important a step
to just rush into like that.
I know that, I know that, Katie,
but, now, what about the coat?
Health and Welfare found me
a nice motel nearthe beach.
It was 7 dollars a day,
including a continental breakfast.
Florida is a wonderful place,
if you're a grapefruit.
Or half of a twosome.
Not that I didn't get offers.
But I wasn't interested in
that kind oftraveler's aid.
So I tried to find things
I could do alone.
That eliminated just about everything
that's any fun.
During the day, I went to the beach.
I read a lot.
That is, I tried to.
But fiction sounded pretty dull
with all the juicy nonfiction
going on around me.
At night, though, Palm Beach
was lovely,
with that big tropical moon
and those dark, velvety clouds
filled with romance and mystery.
There I was, trespassing
in the garden
of an exclusive hotel,
pretending to be one ofthe elite.
With all the romance around me,
there I was with my partner,
a very romantic sort of fellow.
Full of air.
- Help! Help!
- Suddenly I heard someone
calling for help.
There was a man in the pool.
- He seemed to be drowning.
- Help!
And I was wearing my
flowered chiffon that cost me
two whole months without dessert.
My partnerwas useless, and I
remembered my Girl Scout training.
Aperson goes down
only three times.
- Help!
- And this one was on his fourth.
Help!
I realized at once that poor
Mr. Hackett had been drinking.
That was his name, Kirby Hackett,
ofHackett Industries.
I couldn't leave him there,
he was chilled to the bone.
So I decided to help him
up to his room.
That was my first mistake.
My second mistake
was playing Good Samaritan.
I bundled him up
so he wouldn't catch pneumonia.
And then I realized I was
the next likely candidate for it myself.
In my wet chiffon,
I felt like a clam at low tide.
As long as he was sound asleep,
I decided to get dried off.
That was my third mistake.
While I'd been playing
Good Samaritan,
Mr. Hackett had been
playing possum.
I said, "Mr. Hackett!
Please, I'm not dressed!"
And he said, "But, sweetie,
it's not as if we were strangers.
You saved my life!"
No, no, no, no, now, you stay right...
Mr. Hackett!
So I said, "Goodbye, Mr. Hackett. "
I didn't know where I was going,
but anything was an improvement
overwhat I'd just left.
I went through some curtains.
It was dark, but I could just tell
I was in another man's bedroom.
This just seemed to be my night
for it. There was a man in bed.
- And you know who it was?
- Frank Sinatra.
Oh, Marge. Colonel Ryder!
- Our Colonel Ryder?
- Yes.
Oh, you are sly.
That isn't even the half ofit.
Oh, I'm perfectly willing to listen
to the other half.
Then it wasthe colonel
who gave you the mink coat?
No, he couldn't.
Don't you see...?
Lfhe didn't, who did give
you the coat?
Mr. Hackett!
Bright and early the next morning,
I got a phone call.
It was Mr. Hackett.
Anyway, on the phone he said he
was sending me a mink coat
for saving his life. And he did,
and this is it. And I'm returning it.
- Why?
- Because I don't deserve it.
Listen, Katie, there's
no need to be so noble.
Even Dr. Schweitzer
takes donations.
Oh, Marge. Back it goes.
I refuse to be obligated to a man
who practically drowns himself
just to get me up to his room.
Okay, okay, now, what about
Colonel Ryder?
- You were in his room...
- Katie.
Oh, it's Harry.
More later.
That young Ryder's on his way down
the lobby to meet you.
Now, I got some last-minute
negotiating instructions for you, kiddo.
Now, you get to the pension plan
before you finish yourfruit salad.
- Important.
- Pension plan, fruit salad. Yes, Harry.
You might have to give him
a hard sell on seniority rights,
so order something that'll take
a long time, like roast duck.
Seniority rights, roast duck.
Yes, Harry.
Now, here's our proposal
in black and white.
- Yes.
- Now, don't forget, stand pat.
Stand pat.
Thank you.
This pension plan looks
very interesting.
- You match us...
- Penny forpenny.
Employee and employer
moving forward
shoulder and shoulder,
hand in hand.
That's a very good idea.
By the way, where do you live,
Miss Robbins?
- Pardon me?
- Well, you know, subcommittee work,
I may have to get ahold of you
in a hurry some night.
463 East 76th.
Thank you.
- May I ask you a personal question?
- Certainly.
If your uncle hadn't been
Colonel Ryder,
what do you think
you'd be doing now?
Playing golf, I guess.
No, what I mean is, you don't seem
like management to me.
You mean, would I be in the
publishing business? Yes, I would.
Well, you're lucky to be able to start
at the top.
I started just one step below.
I worked as a messenger,
then a stock boy.
Printer's devil fortwo years.
Then I worked in the promotion
department, advertising, sales.
I moved into the editorial department.
I had the experience, but I had
to keep proving to the Ryders.
If you're a relative,
you're supposed to be an idiot.
I started at the top the hard way.
Still, it must have been nice to have
Colonel Ryder behind you all the time.
I worked for a rival chain.
Well, that's enough about me.
Now, you ordered roast duck.
Oh, yes, roast duck.
Seniority rights...
Excuse me.
Seniority rights.
There are the figures.
Oh, right here?
Yes.
Seniority rights are a basic issue,
you know, Mr. Ryder.
An old man is like an old car.
Just because his carburetor
gets rusty
and his spark plugs get stuck,
you don't just...
Voilà.
- Isthat a roast duck?
- Oui, from Normandy.
Petite, but delicious beyond words.
But it's so small.
Madame, petite mais délicieuse.
Well, I'lljust have to talk faster,
that's all.
- Where was I?
- Your spark plugs were stuck.
Yes.
You don't just throw an old man
on the scrapheap forthat.
No, you refuel his fuel pump
and you tighten up his confidence.
And then you give him
another chance.
Voilà, madame.
Seniority rights, fringe benefits
and pension plan.
It's all right here in black and white,
Mr. Ryder.
- Now, speaking forthe union...
- You are standing pat.
That's right, we're standing pat.
Thank you.
Hey, it's 2:30.
What do you say we take
the rest ofthe afternoon off.
I think we've earned it.
I'm curious about something.
Why did you pick on me
to do the negotiating?
I suppose because you were
the prettiest one there.
But you don't have to be pretty
to negotiate.
No, but you're brainy too.
And the nice part about that
is your brains don't show a bit.
Thank you.
But you see, I'm in Research,
Mr. Ryder,
and I've been doing quite a bit
of research on you.
And I'm afraid I'm not yourtype at all.
I know you like tall, svelte,
sophisticated blonds.
You're a good researcher, but don't
believe everything you read.
I said we earned an afternoon off,
so let's take it.
Now, what would you like to do?
Well, I would like to do
some shopping.
Shopping. Okay.
Just what I had in mind.
Why don't you use my car.
My chauffeur, O'Hara, he'll drive you
anywhere you wanna go.
And I'll drop off at the club,
take a cold shower.
- May I be of assistance?
- Yes, thank you.
You see, I thought that...
I thought that this was a bathing suit
that I had bought...
...on sale in Palm Beach.
Just one moment.
But when I opened the box,
I discovered
it wasn't the bathing suit
I bought on sale in Palm Beach.
- It was Mr. Hackett's mink.
- Mr. Hackett's mink.
Yes. Now, I saved his life,
and Dr. Schweitzer
or no Dr. Schweitzer,
I'm afraid I can't accept this coat.
Dr. Schweitzer. Excuse me,
this is a matterfor our manager.
- Mr. Carruthers, please.
- Yes. Yes?
There seems to be a problem
with this lady's coat.
No, there's no problem.
It's just that I can't accept this.
Isthere something wrong
with the coat?
Oh, no, not at all.
It's just beautiful.
But, you see, it's not mine.
It's Mr. Hackett's. He sent it to me.
- Oh, Mr. Kirby Hackett?
- Yes, that's right.
And you're Miss Robbins?
Oh, yes. Well, there's been
no mistake. The coat's yours.
Oh, but there is a mistake.
You see, I don't want it.
I see.
You want the money.
No, sir, I do not want the money.
But the coat is yours.
It's already paid for.
I haven't done anything to earn it.
Oh, I mean, all I did wastake him up
to his room and put him to...
He'd been drinking, you see,
and it seemed like the only place
we could...
- I saved his life! Well, I did.
- Yes, yes.
Will you tell Mr. Hackett
I returned the coat?
I'm afraid that might be a bit difficult.
He left for Europe this morning
on the Liberté.
I don't care ifhe went
to Devil's Island in a canoe.
Please, may I have a receipt
forthe coat?
I'm sure this is not what
Mr. Hackett had in mind.
I know what Mr. Hackett had in mind.
- How much is the coat?
- Eleven thousand dollars.
- Eleven thousand dollars?
- Oh, that includesthe tax.
Well.
There's $10.
I would like to pay $5 a week.
Are you sure you wouldn't
like to think this over?
Why, at $5 a week,
it'll take you 45 yearsto pay for it.
I'm in no hurry if you're not.
You'll be through paying
for it in the year 2005.
Well...
There's another 5.
I'll have to try it on again.
And then I saw her buying a mink coat.
She paid cash for it.
Must have been thousand-dollar bills.
How can she afford a mink
on her salary?
Overtime.
Overtime?
Oh, no, not Miss Robbins.
No.
Bye, ladies.
- Bye, Marie, see you at 6.
- Bye.
Thank you.
- Now, what did you do about the coat?
- Nothing. I have to pay it off, that's all.
- But how?
- Ten dollars a week.
It's the principle ofthe thing, Marge.
I wish somebody would test
my principles.
Hey, I see you found a "good"
to go with your "luck. "
No, they didn't have a "good. "
I had to buy another "luck. "
"Luck-luck"?
As long as you keep out
of Chinese restaurants.
Pardon me.
He was a wonderful man,
the colonel.
Oh, wonderful.
He paid the lowest salaries in town.
Oh, Marge, that was
just his business sense.
Underneath, he was a sensitive,
idealistic and very lonely human being.
Are we talking about
the same Colonel Ryder?
Rememberwhen we ran
his biography?
When I was doing the research,
I came across some ofthe poems
he had done in college.
- Poems? The colonel?
- Yes.
Of course, he wouldn't let us use any
ofthem. But talk about raw emotion!
Keep moving.
Expressto the 30th floor.
Love is like a wild volcano
Seething with dark desire
Well, if you don't mind, I'd rather
remember him for his low salaries.
Hey, kiddo. I've been looking for you.
Come on.
I got a cab, we're gonna be late.
- Forwhat?
- The funeral. Union's got three seats.
- You're one ofthem.
- Oh, Harry, I couldn't possibly.
- Why not?
- Because I'm very emotional, I'll cry.
Go ahead.
Afew tears won't hurt us a bit.
But, Harry, you don't understand.
It's not just tears. I mean, I cry.
At weddings, at funerals.
Once I even cried at a hockey match.
I don't know what it is orwhy I do it,
but I'm very emotional.
Just like my wife, only she giggles.
- At funerals?
- Yeah.
And I'll tell you one thing, kiddo:
She better stay away from my funeral.
And in World War I, what happened?
The great man that we have gathered
to honortoday
volunteered once more
for military duty.
And in six months ofhard,
grinding toil, he brought chaos...
He brought orderto the chaos
that beset our overseas
parcel-post service.
And that Christmas,
I may now reveal,
not a single dough boy
in the front lines...
...not one...
...had to do without a slice
ofMom's fruit cake.
Easy on the waterworks, kiddo.
I'm sorry, Harry, I can't help it.
Once I even cried at an auto show.
And then, at long last,
came theArmistice.
It's gotta be her.
And ifl were to summarize
Colonel Charles J. Ryder's career...
...in one apt phrase, I would say:
"First in war, first in peace
and first in the publishing game. "
You go on, Harry.
I wanna dry off a little bit.
That's our girl.
- You recognize her?
- Even with her clothes on.
And the earring too.
It's a perfect match, see?
That about wraps it up.
She's our blackmailer.
No, not Miss Robbins.
She's not the type.
They never are. We'll be hearing
from that young lady.
I don't see why you're so upset.
If a person can't even sniffle
at a funeral...
Marge, it wasn't a sniffle,
it was loud.
I practically did a duet
with the bugler.
Well, it is perfectly natural.
Especially in your case.
There's no use arguing.
I'm going straight upstairs
and apologize to Mr. Ryder.
Now, to conclude report.
Cased blackmailer's apartment.
Lives alone, except for small bird.
Think it was parakeet.
Might've been canary.
Couldn't make out
through binoculars.
You mean you were spying on her?
Orders from the board, sir.
- Our orders, Tony.
- That's right.
Blackmailer came home
about 7:12 p. m.
Made dinner. Ate dinner.
Washed hair. Washed dishes.
Went to bed.
No visitors?
No visitors, no phone calls.
Well, that's about the size ofit.
Better get down to work.
Will you please leave
by the side door.
I still can't believe she did it.
- Oh, no.
- Mr. Ryder.
The bank is postponing the meeting
about our loan until tomorrow.
Gentlemen, I'd say Miss Robbins
had us over a barrel.
We're lucky ifwe don't end up
in one.
Now, let's be fair. Are we sure
this isthe girl we're looking for?
- Of course we are.
- Lasker identified her, didn't he?
People have been hanged
on cases of mistaken identity.
- Mr. Ryder...
- And I say that a person is innocent
until proven guilty.
How do we know she's guilty?
- Those earrings.
- Could be a coincidence.
They probably sell thousands
ofthese. Ten thousand!
And here's something else.
If she really wasthe blackmailer,
where would she be now?
In my office waiting to see me.
- Mr. Ryder.
- Yes?
Miss Robbins is in your office
waiting to see you.
In my office, waiting to see me.
She said it was important.
To see me...
Careful, Tony.
This is sticky business.
- And she's plenty tricky.
- Sticky, tricky.
Good morning, Mr...
Good morning. I think I know
why you're here, Miss Robbins.
- Sit down, please.
- Thank you.
- Sit down.
- Yes.
I wanted to come up and get it
overwith before I lost my nerve.
Thank you. I know what you
must think of me, Mr. Ryder.
But honestly, I couldn't help
what happened.
- It was all my uncle's fault.
- No, it wasn't anybody's fault.
Oh, believe me, I didn't wanna go.
But afterall, he wasthe head
ofthe company.
- And you were dazzled, huh?
- Dazzled?
Orshall we say, impressed?
Well, that is a betterword, I guess.
But, you see, the real trouble,
Mr. Ryder, sir,
isthat I'm...
I'm too sentimental.
Sentimental. Oh, I'm sure you
could think of a betterword.
Well, how about emotional?
That's what I am.
That's it, I'm over-emotional.
Especially when I think about all those
wonderful poems Colonel Ryderwrote.
- Po...? He wrote poems?
- Oh, yes.
Oh, they were so sensitive
and passionate.
Passionate poems?
Love is a wild volcano
Seething with dark desire
And you and I, the twain...
That means 'the two. "
I get the idea.
Miss Robbins, how many poems
are there?
- Dozens.
- Dozens?
Yes. You know, your uncle was a very
warm and tender man, Mr. Ryder.
Oh, you should read his letters.
- Letters too?
- Yes, would you like to see them?
No, thanks, and I wouldn't want
anyone else to see them, either.
Oh, well, you mustn't worry about that.
I have them in a safe place.
I'm sure you do.
Mr. Ryder. Suppose we published
all ofthose letters and poems
so that the entire world could see what
kind of a man your uncle really was.
Well, it was just a suggestion.
Miss Robbins, I've had enough
ofthis cat-and-mouse game.
Well, it was just a suggestion.
We both know why
you came up here, right?
Now that we know
where we both stand...
Yes.
Well, I'll get back to work.
- No, we'll talk.
- Talk?
What'll we talk about,
fringe benefits?
- We'll talk about loyalty.
- All right.
My uncle's reputation and the Ryder
Enterprises are very closely linked.
If anything should happen
to destroy this company,
hundreds ofpeople would be
thrown out of work.
Now, you wouldn't want that
to happen, would you?
- Why, no.
- Good.
Then your loyalty
will be suitably rewarded.
I didn't come here to ask for any...
- In the form of a raise?
- I don't want...
Shall we say $50 a week more?
- Fifty dollars?
- A hundred dollars?
I think you're a little unstrung
by the funeral. If you...
Two hundred dollars a week.
Take it or leave it.
- Oh, I'll take it, I'll take it!
- Good, good.
Now, remember, don't talk
about thisto anyone.
Don't worry, I won't.
But I think you should.
Talk.
To a doctor!
Well, why don't you
look it up yourself.
How do you like that?
Some wise guy trying to tell me
we had a president
named Andrew Johnson.
I realize that you're new
in Research, Mr. Lasker,
but ifthere are any more phone calls,
especially about presidents...
...I'll be glad to take them.
- Oh, gotcha.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Oh, by the way...
...do you and Mrs. Lasker bowl?
I do. She doesn't.
There is no Mrs. Lasker.
Oh, that is peachy.
That you bowl, I mean.
I love bowling.
It's so healthy.
And maybe some night
you could join Katie and me
- and her boyfriend some night.
- Oh, sure. Any time.
Tonight?
Marge. The strangest thing
just happened.
- Hello.
- Miss Robbins, this is Mr. Lasker.
- Mr. Lasker, this is Miss Robbins.
- How do you do?
And guess where we're
all going tonight. Bowling.
Oh, Marge, I'm sorry, I can't tonight.
I have a date with Warren.
This fella, Warren,
does he work here?
No.
Dr. Kingsley's a friend of mine.
He's herfiancé.
They're going to be married.
Oh, marriage is
a wonderful institution.
When'sthe happy event?
Oh, we haven't even set the date yet.
Dr. Kingsley's folks are in town.
Katie's afraid they won't like her.
I'm not afraid, exactly.
But they're from a small town.
You know, sort of strait-laced.
Small town, strait-laced.
Rememberthat.
I hope I make a good impression
when I meet them tonight, that's all.
Why shouldn't you?
Because it'll probably be days
before I can pull myselftogether
afterthat ten minutes Ijust spent
with that nut upstairs.
- Which nut upstairs?
- Tony Ryder, that's which nut.
Then somebody called Research
and Miss Robbins got too busy to talk.
I wonderwhy she called Tony,
excuse me, Tony, a nut.
I don't care what she
called me orwhy.
We haven't learned a single thing
from that electronic house dick.
We have a lead that could be
very good forus, Mr. Ryder.
We found out that this babe is
engaged to a very respectable guy.
- So?
- So get her married off and bingo,
she's off your back and out
of your cash register.
Sure. "Miss Robbins, how would
you like your husband to know
about that little episode at Palm
Beach?" I guessthat'll hush herup.
Counter-blackmail is an ugly word,
gentlemen.
Suppose we're on the wrong track.
Suppose this Dr. What's-his-name...
- Kingsley.
- Suppose he'sthe brains
behind this blackmail scheme and
Miss Robbins is nothing but a pawn.
- That's hardly likely.
- Likely or not,
I intend to do a little investigating
of my own.
I wanna meet this guy, size him up and
see what we have to contend with.
- Yes, sir?
- Would you get me the address
- of a Dr. Warren Kingsley.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you. Meeting adjourned.
Amateurs.
Well, there you are.
Have you any idea how you're
going to get in the place?
Simple. He's a doctor,
I can have a stomachache.
Careful, or you'll end up
with your appendix missing.
Very funny, Mr. O'Hara. Now, you
wait for me down the street there.
Now, cheer up, Bobo.
The nice doctorsays it's all
in your mind. Yes.
Come on, Bobo.
Hey, son, do you mind ifl borrow
your dog for a few minutes?
I'll give you a quarter.
What do you say?
Gee, thanks.
But, mister, it's not my dog.
You mean it's not your horse.
Emergency case. I'd like to see
the doctorright away.
And what isthe nature
ofthe emergency?
Well, it's rather personal.
I'd preferto see the doctor.
Oh, doc!
Young man, you're finally out
ofthe woods.
You just stick to that vitamin therapy
and you'll feel like a new dog.
Thank you, doctor.
- Yes, do you have an appointment?
- Emergency case, very important.
Come on, doc. Oh, doc.
Now, you take it easy, old boy.
Good old doc'll fix you up. Attaboy.
Did you have an appointment,
Mr?
Heminschlogger.
Julius T. Heminschlogger.
Yeah, and as I mentioned,
this is an emergency case.
I see. What seemsto be his problem,
Mr. Heminschlogger?
Well...
...amnesia.
- Your dog has amnesia?
- It happened all of a sudden.
I wastaking him fora walk,
and he gave me
that 'who are you?" look.
- The 'who are you?" look?
- Yeah, like this:
Don't mind telling you
it shook me up.
Canine amnesia. That's very rare.
I don't think they everwrote that up.
Well, now's your chance, doc.
Not only to help me,
but advance the cause of medical...
Will you hold still, Julius.
What are you...?
Not in the pocket, Julius.
You see there, doc?
He thinks he's a pickpocket.
Julius? Isn't that your name?
Is it? Yeah, it is.
Well, this is Julius Jr.
I'm the sentimental type
and we're very close, you know.
See, doc?
Now he thinks I'm Lassie.
Kind of a memory block, huh?
- May I?
- Yeah.
All right, now, Julius, just calm down.
You're among friends now.
Just relax. Just relax.
Tell me, Mr. Heminschlogger,
has he had a physical lately?
Well, not in six months. You better
check him over. Take yourtime.
- Lfthis doesn't work, we'll try analysis.
- Oh, anything.
Long as we get my buddy back
on his feet.
"Kansas Institute
of Veterinary Science. "
That must be a wonderful
old school.
Sure is.
My father's the president.
Oh, he is?
Now, let'stake a look at
those tonsils. Now, now, Julius.
Biting won't solve anything.
Just relax.
Oh, doc. This picture,
I've seen this girl before.
- Where?
- Well, isn't she a chorus girl
at the Copacabana?
No, I'm afraid not.
That's my fiancée.
Oh, well, I could be mistaken.
No, my family's very strait-laced.
I'm afraid they would never allow me
to be engaged
to a girl from the Copacabana.
Rocky! Rocky!
All right, where is he?!
What do you want?
This is a respectable clinic.
I'm looking fora dognapper,
that's what I'm looking for.
- What's in there?
- You can't go in there.
- Police!
- Who snatched my dog?
- Get out ofthere.
- Police!
- Rocky, baby.
- Keep your hands offmy patient.
- Police!
- You dognapper.
I want words with you.
I don't know what you did to my dog,
but I want everything
put back the way it was.
- Police!
- Thanks forthe advice
about my parakeet, doc.
I'll keep him out of drafts.
In there, officer. You'd better hurry.
Oh, doctor. Dr. Kingsley.
- Hello.
- Well, here we are.
Won't you come in. How do you do?
How are you?
Happy to know you, Miss...
What wasthe lady's name?
- Miss Robbins.
Happy to know you.
Come right in.
Well, thank you.
I'm delighted to know you.
Miss Robbins, this is Mother.
Oh, I'm delighted to know
your mothertoo.
Oh, I mean...
She's my mother, Katie.
I know, Warren, I know.
I meant to say that...
Did you hearthat, Mother?
Girl here thought you were
Warren's grandma.
No, I didn't. Honest, I didn't.
You're too old.
I mean, you're both too old.
Oh, what I mean is...
I'll explain it later.
Could we sit down?
Yes, of course, sit down.
Could I take yourwrap?
No, thank you.
- Your hat?
- Yes, put it anywhere.
Well, isn't she everything
I said she was?
I'm sorry I don't have
any more room.
No, no, it's very nice.
In Kansas, we have 30 acres.
Well, I could use some
ofthose here.
That's very funny.
Well, I would say that
refreshments are in order.
What have you got in mind?
Well, I made a nice big pitcher
of cold mar...
Hot chocolate.
Of cold hot chocolate. Yes.
That's right.
So you have your choice
of cold hot chocolate
or hot hot chocolate.
Hot, please.
Well, I'll have cold, I guess.
That'stwo chocolates.
One hot and one cold,
coming right up.
Isn't she nice?
I forgot.
I'm all out of chocolate.
Oh, would you like olives?
Would you like an olive?
No, thanks.
No, thank you. They stick in my...
No, thank you.
Yes.
Well, I guess we're off
to our little French restaurant.
Oh, little French restaurants,
that's all we've had on thistrip.
It seems to me we ought to go
to some big noisy nightclub.
Do you know any nightclubs,
Miss Robbins?
There's the Martinique.
But I've never been there.
Never.
I've heard about it. Let's go there.
Dad, it's very popular.
I doubt if we'd get in.
You just tell them
that your dad heads up
the Kansas Institute
of Veterinary Science.
That'll make them sit up and bark.
Yeah, sit up and b...
Did you hearthat, Mother,
"sit up and bark"?
- She said she's never been there.
- No.
I'm a working girl. And working girls
just don't have time for nightclubs.
That's right.
Yeah, well, should I get your coat,
Katie?
Thank you, Warren.
I don't need...
- Mink?
- May I?
May I have a feel ofthat?
Oh, my. Tourmaline mink.
They run into money.
What is it you do for a living?
Research.
Obviously pays very well.
Katie, where did you get the coat?
I bought it on time, Warren.
I wastrying to explain.
Ten dollars a week.
I wanted to surprise you.
Yeah. You surprised me.
Shall we go?
Oh, do you know that I...?
Oh, I beg yourpardon.
- What's the matter, darling?
- Nothing.
I just have a little business
to take care of.
Could we have a table forfour,
please?
I'd be very happy to accept
a small bribe tomorrow night.
Next week would be even better.
- Oh, but we...
- Tonight is quite impossible.
Oh, it is?
George, do me a favor, huh?
You see that girl there, with
the fur coat? That's Miss Robbins.
Now, she's got to get married.
Yeah, and they love each other.
Now, we've gotta play Cupid.
See, we'll get her a good table,
some good music and real fine wine.
Then let nature take its course,
you understand?
Perfectly.
Let's go to the Stork Club.
Motherand I have neverbeen there.
Well, I'm more than glad to be leaving.
This isn't my kind of place.
You're so right, Mrs. Kingsley.
It's not my kind of, either.
Miss Robbins.
One moment, please.
- Me?
- Athousand pardons.
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
Me?
Captain, table 30
for Miss Robbins and herparty.
Us?
But I've never been here before.
Katie probably looks like one
oftheir regular customers.
Whose name just happens
to be Robbins?
Champagne.
Oh, we didn't order any champagne.
For Miss Robbins.
Compliments ofthe Martinique.
Oh, well, I know.
I'm probably the one millionth person
to come in here tonight.
- Tonight?
- Well, I mean, since it opened,
or something. You know, how
they're always giving things away?
No. No, I don't.
Well, they do. All the time.
Just last week there wasthis girl,
and she was crossing this bridge
in this car,
and they gave it to her.
- The bridge?
- No, the car.
Anew one too, that is.
She was probably the ten millionth
person to cross the bridge.
Orwas it a tunnel?
Yeah, well, Mom, ifKatie says
she's never been here before,
- she's never been here before.
- No, I haven't.
And it was a tunnel.
And this girl...
To the Veterinary Institute in Kansas.
I'll drink to that.
Everything satisfactory, Mr. Ryder?
Yeah, I think we've given Cupid
a good start.
Now, you keep those arrows coming.
I heard them say they were going
to the Stork Club from here.
Good.
Come on, honey,
let's go to the Stork Club.
We can't keep ourfriends waiting.
We don't have any friends
at the Stork Club.
- We'll make some.
- I liked it here.
Oh, darling, I forgot my purse.
Oh, I'll get it for you.
I'll meet you out in front.
Heminschlogger!
It's Heminschlogger.
I'll drink to that.
No, Dad, it'sthat crackpot
I told you about.
- Where?
- Sneaking out.
He waved at me.
I believe he was waving at me.
Don't be silly, honey. How would
you know Heminschlogger?
Heminschlogger?
That's not Heminschlogger.
- That's my boss, Tony Ryder.
- Oh, no. No, you're mistaken.
How could I be mistaken about
a man that just this morning
gave me a $200-a-week raise?
- Two hundred?
- Aweek?
I'll drink to that.
But I didn't take it.
And I've never been
to this place before,
and I'm so sorry
we came here again.
Warren, couldn't we go someplace
else for dinner and have supper?
It's just making me
very, very nervous.
Yeah, I'm a little nervous myself.
Waiter. Check.
Never a check for Miss Robbins.
I'll drink to that.
Me too.
One forthe road.
Hail to thee, O Kansas Institute
Of Veterinary Science.
With your students scattered wide
- I wonder if we could get in here.
- Really, Warren.
She only had two drinks, Mom.
It's just that she never had
champagne before.
I wonder.
They're always ready
With needle and insecticide
We'll go quietly, officer.
Perhaps some othernight, sir.
Or better yet, some afternoon.
- But thank you, sir.
- Oh, no.
We're not tourists, old man,
you know.
I should say not.
I happen to be the president ofthe
Kansas Institute of Veterinary Science.
- That's right.
- He is. He's the president.
No luck, huh? All right.
Are they always this snooty?
I don't know, I've never
been here before.
Either.
That's the party I told you about.
Oh, yes, sir.
Come on, honey,
let's get out ofhere.
It's getting awfully stuffy.
Let's go back to La Martinique.
Miss Robbins.
Please forgive the captain.
He's a new man. It's nice
to see you again, Miss Robbins.
It's nice to see you...
It's nice to see you again.
- How're the wife and kids?
- Just fine. This way.
She's never been here, either.
Thank you very much.
- She's a great girl.
- Congratulations are in orderfor me.
I'm the ten millionth lady
to cross this bridge.
Hail to thee, O Kansas Institute...
Ryder, Tony Ryder.
Yeah, I'm sure he'll talk to me.
They're trying to reach Pudge.
Good. Try and find out
what's holding up that loan.
Now, about getting ourblackmailer
married off, I think that...
Not a chance, Mr. Dunning.
Not for a long time, anyway.
How do you know?
Talked to the waiter
at the Stork Club.
He told me Mrs. Kingsley and her son
were very unhappy
about Miss Robbins
doing the cha-cha in the kitchen...
...with the cook.
Oh, it'll be a cornless day in Kansas
before that girl gets married.
Let's face it, gentlemen.
Cupid-wise, we are in trouble.
Our counter-blackmail scheme
doesn't have a prayer.
We've got to get that young lady
out ofthe way.
I know a gangster.
Well, he's not really a gangster.
He's my wife's brother...
Hello. Hello.
Oh, hi, Pudge.
What'sthe good word on our loan?
Oh, I see.
Well, could you tell me
what kind of a hitch?
I understand, Pudge. Thanks.
Well, they've decided to hold off
on the loan.
Gentlemen, I guess I'm not
the best man forthis job after all.
Now, this is no time to give up, Tony.
Didn't yourfriend Pudge give you
any reasons?
Well, he said they were
checking on a rumor.
- Didn't know what it was.
- Arumor?
We have got to keep her
from talking, orwe're sunk.
What ifwe tried
this little thing again?
Let the little lady incriminate herself.
We've already tried that.
She wouldn't talk.
With me we tried,
and with me she wouldn't talk.
But what if we got somebody else
wired for sound?
Somebody suave, clever,
good-looking, huh?
Somebody she could really go for.
I've got a cute little spot
in the Village.
Ridiculous.
Looks like you're drafted, Tony.
I'd like to help you...
- Mr. Ryder.
- For personal reasons, I'd rather not.
Listen to this.
"Dear Mr. Ryder, I've been thinking
about the $200-a-week raise
you offered me.
Of course, I can't possibly accept it.
Naturally, I realize you
must have been joking. "
- Joking?
- Go on, go on.
Oh, here's where she slips
in the knife.
"I suppose next you'll be offering me
the Ryder Building,
lock, stock and magazines. Ha! Ha!"
"Ha! Ha!"?
See for yourself.
It's "ha-ha," all right.
Well, this girl is going to "ha-ha" us
right into the poorhouse.
Not if we move fast.
'Yourstruly, Katie Robbins. "
Well, Tony?
How do you wearthis thing?
Good boy! Good boy!
Now the question is:
Where should he go into action?
I think Mr. Ryder ought
to take her someplace
where she thinks they'll be alone.
Just the two ofthem.
Then she'll really open up.
I think I know just the spot
where I can catch Miss Robbins
with her "ha-ha" down.
My apartment, tonight.
And a little champagne to loosen
hertongue, eh, Mr. Ryder, huh?
Yeah, and ifthat don't work,
I can alwaystry torture.
That's very funny. Torture.
I'm not in a funny mood, Mr. Lasker.
As far as Katie is...
Miss Robbins is concerned,
I may be involved
in this underhanded scheme,
but I certainly don't have
to enjoy it.
Oh, yes, sir. Yes, sir,
I see what you mean.
Good luck.
I'll get it, Kim.
Now, look, after you've served
dinnerto the young lady and myself,
you get lost.
Same like always. Get lost.
No, no, this is business.
Same like always.
Monkey business.
- I hope I'm not late.
- Oh, no, not at all.
Come on in.
Thank you.
I realize I shouldn't have worn mink
to a business meeting,
but it's my very first one.
I'm sure it won't be your last.
"Ha! Ha!"
- Pardon me?
- "Ha! Ha!"
Oh, yes. "Ha! Ha!"
Oh, my.
This is a lovely room.
Oh, are there just the two
ofus again?
Surprised?
Oh, well, no.
No, it's just that you...
When you called me
about the urgent company business,
well, I had this bowling date,
and I thought...
Well, I don't know what I thought.
Health and Welfare, maybe.
Your health and yourwelfare,
Miss Robbins?
No, everybody's health and welfare.
"Ha! Ha!"
"Ha! Ha!"?
Oh, this is beautiful.
It's a Remington.
Yes, he painted this around 1.900.
Oh, I forgot. You're in Research.
No, my father used to collect
Remington sketches.
Of course, he could never afford
the original oils.
Isn't this beautiful?
Shall we? Nothing like a little
champagne to loosen yourton...
Whet your appetite.
Champagne?
Well, I'm not very thirsty, Mr. Ryder.
Matter of fact,
I'm not very hungry, either.
So why don't we just get our business
overwith, and I'll run along.
Oh, what'sthe rush?
Well, I'm not in a rush,
but I thought maybe you were.
Oh, no, I'm not in a rush,
Miss Robbins. Here.
Drink up.
Oh, your uncle certainly was
a strong man, wasn't he?
Yeah. Strong like a bull
and weak like a man.
You remind me ofhim.
You have the same strength.
You see? The jaw.
I mean, it's similar.
Oh, your power's going.
Oh, I really can't stay.
I have this bowling date,
and I'm sort ofthe anchorman... Girl.
Relax, Miss Robbins.
On a beautiful evening like this,
it's no crime to enjoy the view
and sip champagne
before we settle down
to more important matters. "Ha! Ha!"
All right.
Here'sto crime!
How'sthat fora "ha-ha"?
- "Ha! Ha!"
But, Warren, I was in the office when
he called, and he said it was business.
When a man like Tony Ryder asks
a girl like Katie up to his apartment,
you know what kind ofbusiness.
Step on it, driver.
But I asked Mr. Lasker
to go bowling.
Why can't we bowl without Katie,
and mind our own business?
Because Katie is my business.
But just an hour ago, you said
you were through with her.
Well, that was an hour ago.
Suppose we get there
and there's nothing going on.
There better be.
Oh, what a beautiful view this is.
There'sthe Triborough Bridge
and the Brooklyn Bridge
and the Queensborough Bridge.
And the Brooklyn Bridge again.
Again?
Oh, that's their problem.
Here we are.
I really shouldn't. Like I said before,
I'm the anchorman.
But...
Now, then,
let'stalk business.
Oh, good. I could listen
to you talk business all night.
I'll lay my cards on the table,
Miss Robbins.
Katie.
I'm Katie, and you're Mr. Ryder.
Cards? What cards?
I thought you wanted
to talk business.
Let's face facts, huh?
No beating around the bush.
Bush? What bush?
You haven't answered me yet
about the cards.
And I could listen
to you play cards all night.
Let's get to the point, Miss Robbins.
Katie.
All right, I know when I'm licked.
Now, it's your move.
You name the figure,
and I'll make out the check.
I could listen to you make out
checks all night.
- Please, Miss Robbins.
- Please. Katie.
All right. Katie.
What do you want?
I want...
I wanna dance.
And even though I'm the anchorman,
I think that you had better lead.
Of course.
Oh, me.
Ajug ofwine, a loaf ofbread
And thou beside me
Singing in the wilderness
You know, that's one ofthe prettiest
poems your uncle everwrote.
Orwas it youruncle?
No, that was Khayyam.
Omar Khayyam.
Born 1.157, died 1.906.
Oh, orwas that the Chicago Fire?
I don't know.
As long as I'm not on duty.
You know, ifit weren't for my uncle,
we could have met under more
pleasant circumstances.
Oh, I think this is very pleasant.
Circumstantially, that is.
Love is a wild volcano
Seething with...
You may kiss me, Mr. Ryder,
if you'd like to.
It's perfectly all right.
Oh, Heminschlogger, you're slipping.
Katie.
Oh, Mr. Ryder. Mr. Ryder.
First time I ever kissed
an anchorman.
Oh, excuse me.
I'm sorry, it'sthe champagne.
Oh, I really shouldn't have done that.
You see, I'm sort of engaged.
At least, I was until last night.
I think I'd better go.
You know, I don't think you've seen
the rest of my Remingtons.
Oh, but I saw the one
in the living room. I saw that one.
I have a few more
that I'd like you to see.
Here's one ofhis most famous
paintings, Pursuing the Indians.
Well, I can sympathize with them.
Oh, there are more this way.
Here's my favorite one.
His famous card game.
Yes, I have seen this reproduced
so many times, it's like an old friend.
Did you know he did
a few bronze statues?
Yes, he's just as famous for
his bronze as he is for his paintings.
And there's anotherbeauty
overthere.
But I can barely see it.
I know.
Most men have etchings,
and you have Remingtons.
Yeah, but most men aren't
as lucky as I am.
Especially right now.
Mr. Ryder, you know
what you should do?
You should turn this into a theater.
Atheater in the round.
Your lighting effects
are most effective.
Most.
You have this system
in all yourrooms?
Every room except the kitchen
and in there.
You wouldn't really need it
in the kitchen and in there.
No, you wouldn't.
I really must be going, Mr. Ryder.
We came here to have a meeting.
We're having one, Katie.
Yes, but I feel very embarrassed.
I only came here to talk.
Of course you did.
Katie, let's forget the past.
What's done is done.
The important thing is I love you.
I didn't wanna fall in love with you,
but there it is.
Mr. Ryder.
Tony. I forgive you.
You're so sweet.
Forgive me forwhat?
For everything, darling. Florida.
- Florida?
- And the hotel.
- The hotel?
- The rendezvous with my uncle.
The rendezvous with your uncle?
I forgive you
forthe whole ugly scheme.
You think I had a rendezvous
with your uncle?
Forget that.
You met my uncle.
He was old and lonely.
You felt sorry forhim.
You're a very emotional girl, right?
Right! There's only one small detail
you've missed.
I didn't happen to meet your uncle,
I planned it that way.
- You planned it?
- Beautifully.
You mean you heard
he was lonely...
I heard he was loaded.
And after Cosmo...
- Cosmo?
- That beatnik bongo player
I used to be engaged to.
He was great on the bongos, but very
low on the dough, like all the others.
- There were a lot of others?
- You wanna count baseball players?
If you do, then there
were quite a few others.
I was crazy about baseball players.
I used to like jockeystoo,
only I kept growing and they didn't.
That's in the past.
I don't wanna hear it.
Now, prizefighters are the worst
because you have to catch them
when they're not in training.
Well, I forgive you. We're all
a little weak. And I'm a little weak.
Well, I'm not. I'm strong.
Now, back to that rendezvous.
Why did I do it?
- Blackmail?
- Blackmail?!
Yeah, but I forgive you.
That's all in the past.
Well, thanks a lot!
And one more thing, Mr. Ryder,
once a blackmailer,
always a blackmailer!
- Katie!
- I want money. Real money.
By the time I get through with you,
you'll be selling your magazines...
Let go! On a street corner!
Katie, you can't leave me now.
No!
- Katie.
- Let go or I'll punch you in the nose!
Good evening.
Good evening, Mr. Ryder,
Miss Robbins.
I hope we're not interrupting anything.
- Well.
- And they say bowling
isthe most popular indoorsport.
I was helping herwith her coat.
Well, was she crawling into it?
Warren, don't just stand there.
The man insulted me.
Hit him! Sock him! Knock him down!
- Well, he is down.
- Well, then, kick him!
Oh, well...
Let me help you.
He's up now, Warren,
give him the old one-two.
Oh, well, I would, but I have
to operate in the morning, my hands.
Mr. Ryder, you'll have to excuse Katie
because she's not used to champagne.
And you know who plied me with it?
Your precious Mr. Heminschlogger.
And you know what else?
He called me a blackmailer.
- Ablackmailer?
- Yes.
Look, he's even stolen
my other shoe.
Yeah, well, I think an explanation
is in order, old man.
Oh, I agree with you, young man.
Do you think I'm a blackmailer,
Warren?
I never heard of anything
so ridiculous in my life.
Oh, I can always depend on you.
- Take me out ofhere.
- Oh, Katie...
As for you, my fine-feathered
Heminschlogger,
you're very lucky my fiancé didn't
beat you within an inch of yourlife.
I know, I'm not lucky, but...
Come, darling, let's go.
Katie. Katie!
Research. I mean, hello.
Marge, you bettertake it.
- Katie, please.
- Mr. Ryder.
- Are you in for Mr. Dunning?
- Take the message.
- Katie!
- Mr. Ryder, he says it's urgent.
He hasto talk with you.
Hello. Look, I'm very busy.
We've got the loan.
Yeah.
You know what held it up?
The bank thought we hired Lasker
to watch you.
I was beginning to think so myself.
Katie, please!
Katie, you've got to listen to me.
- Pardon me.
- Katie.
Please, you've got to listen to me.
Nothing you can say interests me.
I'm going to marry the man I love.
Not him, him.
I can't let you make
that terrible mistake.
- See this?
- It's a gun!
No, not a gun, madam.
It's a tape recorder.
Before you think ofmarrying
this young lady,
I'd like you to hear something, doc.
- You didn't!
- I didn't, huh?
You may kiss me if you want to,
Mr. Ryder. It's perfectly all right.
First time I ever kissed an anchorman.
Oh, Mr. Ryder.
Alittle further.
And one more thing, Mr. Ryder.
Once a blackmailer,
always a blackmailer!
Blackmailer?
Oh, come in, ladies, you're just
in time to hearthe next chapter.
I can explain everything, Warren.
Really, I can. I can explain it all.
I want money, real money!
When I'm through with you,
you'll be selling your magazines...
- Let me go!
- Very interesting, huh, doc?
On a street corner!
Well, that's about the size ofit.
Sorry.
This could never have happened
in Boston.
Katie.
I think I'll... I better get on home.
It's a little late for bowling,
and I've got a basset hound
tonsillectomy in the morning.
Warren. You don't believe
all that silly nonsense, do you?
Oh, no. No, of course not.
Well...
Well, what about tomorrow evening?
Oh, well...
Oh, I've got a meeting
at the dog medical center.
But I'll... I'll keep in touch with you.
Okay?
It was bound to happen.
I knew it as soon
as I met his mother.
There, there, Katie.
I'm sorry, but I had to
show him up forwhat he was.
We'll just have to find you
somebody else.
I don't want somebody else.
And you, embarrassing me like that
in front ofthose sweet old ladies.
They thought I was some kind
of a criminal.
I'll admit I shouldn't have done it.
But even an idiot deserves
a second chance.
I know you're not a blackmailer.
I never believed you were.
I couldn't fall in love
with a blackmailer.
That's the important thing.
Oh, no, the important thing...
Where are you taking me?
- Up.
- But I don't wanna go up.
I neverwanna see him again, and
I neverwanna see you again, either.
But first I'm gonna tell you what
really happened that night in Florida.
I was running away from
some drunken lunatic I had rescued
from the swimming pool
and had helped up to his room.
I came through some curtains,
and it was dark.
And I knocked over some furniture.
There I was,
in another man's bedroom.
And there was a man in bed.
Your uncle, Colonel Ryder.
I thought he was asleep.
Well, I was in and out ofthere
in about five seconds flat.
And that must have been
where I lost my earring.
I started down the hall,
looking for a stairway
ora freight elevatoror something,
when, suddenly, the house detective
yelled at me.
- Hey!
- Oh, I kept right on running.
I hadn't done anything, but racing
around a hotel with practically
nothing on can give a girl
a terrible guilt complex.
Like I told you, that's all in the past.
I never believed it for a minute.
Stop that.
I told you, we're through.
- Of course, we're through.
- Well? So goodbye.
Goodbye.
I neverwanna see you again.
But you'll have to, darling.
We'll be on our honeymoon.
You mean you're...
...asking me...
Oh, Mr. Ryder.