So like you said, when
you come face-to-face with
something like that, what
are you supposed to do?
SWEET DEE: Oof!
Oh, hey, buddy.
Yeah, what's
going on there, pal?
Oh, my God, I
just found a rat's nest.
Slaughtered about 200 of 'em.
200? Couldn't be. That's...
Jesus Christ...
Oh, it's like, it's like
whole generations of those
things have died at my hands, and...
mothers, fathers, grandfathers,
little baby rats.
Mmm, yeah.
Wow.
Well, you know, keep up the good work.
Yeah.
Sometimes I wonder though, if
our lives are really more valuable
than theirs, you know what I mean?
- Yeah.
- They are.
Yeah.
- Our lives are definitely...
- Yeah. without a doubt.
- Yeah.
- Without a doubt.
If that makes you feel any better.
Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, well, I suppose I oughta...
- Get back to it?
Yep. Jump right back
in there, tiger.
Get on the horse.
Charlie, bash, bash 'em up.
- Do what you do best.
- Alright. Thanks, guys.
Yep. Oh, God.
I just gotta go to the bathroom.
- Sure, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Alright, man.
He touched me with it.
Ugh! God, what a life, huh?
- Today's his birthday.
- Are you kidding me?
Poor guy, on a day like this.
We oughta do something nice for him.
- Mm-hmm. Definitely.
- Yeah, absolutely.
Oh! You want to get
him a new rat stick?
That's a good idea.
Abso... I was thinking maybe we
should throw him a surprise party.
He is really bummed.
I guess we could do
something nice for him.
Definitely. Listen, for one day let's
make the poor bastard feel special.
For one day let's make this lowly
rat killer feel like a king.
Yes.
In the simplest... Easiest...
way. ...easiest.
I'm tired today, you know?
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Here it is. I got it!
I'm thinking we go with a
Hawaiian
trip-hop, underground luau theme.
- Huh?
- What is that?
- What even is that?
- Well, you know...
I'll even hang around with this guy
Duncan from under the bridge....
And he runs with this rough crowd
and they're all into
Hawaiian underground shit, you know?
And I made a little list of stuff
that would really support that theme.
"Fill bar with sand.
Roast wild pig.
Invite Duncan and crew."
Ooh, this seems like
a whole lot of work.
Uh, does anybody really even
like surprise parties anyway?
You know?
I don't.
What the hell's the matter with you?!
- How did you get so cynical?
- Cynical?
You can't even get excited
to give your friend a party!
I mean, giving somebody a
birthday party, a surprise party
is one of the greatest
things you can do for him!
Okay, Frank.
Alright.
Alright, alright, well, maybe
we are being a little cynical.
Clearly, this means a
lot to you, so, fine.
We'll jump on board with the party.
What's the plan?
Alright, the plan is you
guys execute this list.
Mm-hmm.
I am gonna take Charlie to the
spa for a day to distract him.
Hold on a second.
Why do you get to spend the day at
a spa while we do all the legwork?
Because I got these two
coupons in the mail.
Okay, I'm pregnant, and you
haven't offered me coupons or
spa days or roasted pigs or
surprises or any-any of those
fun things.
Oh, oh, okay, well, in the
interest of not being cynical
and, you know, doing shit for
other people, I'm gonna suggest
that we give the two coupons to
Dee and she does the spa thing.
Surprise. Perfect.
Thank you.
Alright, cool.
I will take this coupon and sneak out
the back so Charlie doesn't see me.
- Wait, wait.
- What, what? What?
No, you have to take Charlie
with you to the spa.
That's the whole thing.
You have to distract him.
Oh... Shit.
Yeah, Frank, you might be right
about us getting cynical.
I just, I just jumped straight
to default and was gonna throw
this second coupon in the trash.
But the Charlie thing, yep,
we're doing the Charlie thing.
Okay, I got it. I'm on it.
Okay.
Hey, Charlie!
Okay, hey, listen, uh, you've
been really stressed, so I
thought I would take you for
a spa day, just you and me.
A what day?
A spa day.
What is this word "spa"?
I feel like you're starting to say a
word, and you're not finishing it.
Are you trying to say "spaghetti"?
Are you taking me for a spaghetti day?
No, Charlie, I wasn't trying to
take you for a spaghetti day.
Oh, God, you know what?
It doesn't matter. It's okay.
That's alright.
I'm doing something nice here.
I tell you what.
Let's go to a movie.
Want to go to a movie?
Dee, I go to movie or
a spaghetti place with you
you know and ***?
What if I guarantee you
that nobody out there will put you
into a bag and bash you
against a telephone pole?
Would that comfort you at all?
Nope. That's a guarantee you
can't make, Dee, alright?
Alright, I tell you what...
That's why I'm building this little puppy.
Yeah. Don't do...
And no one's getting bashed.
Okay, I tell you what, Charlie.
If you don't come with me to
the movie, I'm gonna take this
raccoon of yours and I'm gonna
bash it into a telephone pole.
No! I can't take any more
bashing today, alright?
Okay, let's go, let's go.
This will be fun!
Alright, let's go.
- Dennis.
- Yeah?
Why don't you check that box of tiki
torches, start setting those up?
What this?
Yeah, that box there.
What is this?
We didn't put this in here.
Surprise!
What is that? What'd you do?
I got you a present, bro!
I'm trying to be less cynical,
and Frank is totally right.
The surprise is the way to go!
So you got me a gift?
Yes! Yeah, while we were
picking out the decorations, I
slipped out and I got you something
I think you're gonna gonna like.
Okay, alright. Ooh!
Ooh! Okay. Uh!
Ah!
Oh! Oh, a shirt!
I love this shirt!
Oh, that's great, man!
Thank you.
Hey. No, this isn't the
shirt that I picked out.
Yeah. No. Well, no.
What is this?
It's the shirt that I...
that I picked out.
But that's cool.
Here's the thing, man.
I-I got a little suspicious
when you slipped out earlier,
and so I followed you into the
store, and I saw that you were
about to make a really bad
choice, and then you did make
that choice and you bought that other
shirt, and it was a bad shirt.
It was an ugly shirt.
Hideous really.
So I grabbed that shirt out
of the bag when you weren't
looking and I returned it and
bought myself this shirt
which isn't hideous.
And so, surprise.
That was a good shirt.
No.
This brings me no joy at all.
I feel nothing.
I feel...
I feel like you just, you stole
money from me, and then you
bought yourself a shirt.
A shirt with your money.
Yeah.
No, that is what happened.
That is a ridiculous
price and you know it!
Supposing I bought a pig unseasoned
and dressed it myself?
Then what? What then?!
Well, that's not what Jerry
Carelli said, asshole!
Ha! Pitting two pig dealers
against each other.
Ah, sure.
Frank, are you sure
about this luau thing?
I mean, it's a ton of work.
Yeah. Does Charlie even
know what a luau is?
I doubt Charlie can even
say the word "luau."
I mean, how do you know that's
what he wants?
Because I read it in his dream book.
In his what? His dream book?
Yeah. Charlie keeps a book
of dreams and aspirations.
They're mostly in pictures
and symbols, but he has been
obsessing about this luau thing since
we met Duncan under the bridge.
Okay, now, my first instinct:
When you say things about
meeting people under bridges,
it's to, it's to berate you
for hanging out with people
under a bridge and to say to
you, "Why do you hang out with
these... with these people?
You and Charlie shouldn't be..."
But I'm not gonna say anything because
I don't want to be cynical anymore.
I'm not going to say anything.
I'm just...
Maybe the bridge is exciting.
No.
The bridge is awesome.
Ooh.
It's probably pretty cool.
Hold on a second. Hold.
Hey, it's the other pig guy.
Ah, so you come crawling back,
you cheap sack of shit.
Oh, you can't bring food into the theater.
No, I'm not. I bought it over there
with that food.
- No, you didn't.
- How do you know that?
Because we don't serve spaghetti...
and I just watched you walk in with it.
You call my bluff, sir.
I shall dispose of this ***
A moment, please.
Dee, do me a favor and pop
this in your purse real quick.
No, absolutely not.
No. Why do you have to
bring spaghetti...?
You caught me hankering for
spaghetti and I want it.
Just eat it, then.
Eat it fast and we'll go.
No, I want to enjoy it
and watch the movie.
It's going to make a mess in my purse.
I'm leaving because the spaghetti
is the whole deal for me.
Goddamn it. Just... Goddamn it.
Just put it in. Be careful.
You are... this is so stupid.
And there we go!
- Got rid of it.
- Great. Thank you.
Okay.
Look at this place, Dee.
Look at the size of the place.
What does 3-D even stand for?
Third dimension.
Just... please stop talking.
Third dimen...
What dimension are we in?
Shh! Charlie, I don't know.
Shh!
Isn't stuff, like,
supposed to pop out at us?
I don't know. I'm not sure.
Let's watch and find out, okay?
Whoa!
Did you see that?
Yeah. Yeah, I saw that.
That came, like, right at you.
Is this safe?
Are you kidding me?
I don't know.
Take the glasses off if
you're uncomfortable, okay?
But then everything's, like, blurry.
Then put the glasses
on and shut the hell up.
- Shh!
- You shh!
See, then, stuff's not safe.
Uh-oh.
Whoa.
What happened to my meatball?
Hey, would you shut up?
Oh, no, you know what happened?
When I...
- I bet it flew off when I...
- Okay, you are a sleuth.
You've gotten to the bottom of it.
That's very exciting.
Now shut up.
Let me just find it.
- I'm sorry, did you see a meatball...
- Charlie, sit down.
Oh, my God, Charlie.
I swear to God, if you don't sit
down and shut up and watch the
movie, I'm going to attack you.
I don't care how pregnant I am,
I am going to get out of this
seat, I'm going to attack you.
- I got it, got it, got it...
- Oh, you got it? Okay, good.
Sit down.
- Got the meatball.
- Sit down!
- Quiet down!
- The movie's boring.
You... You...!
How could you...
You're not watching the movie.
Ugh. Uh-uh.
Aah, you're not gonna like this.
What happened?
Ah, nuts.
Some-some spaghetti kind of like
spilled in your purse a little bit.
Oh, shit.
Want your spaghetti, Charlie?
Want your spaghetti?
Here's your spaghetti.
Oh, don't dump it on
the ground like that.
Shut up and watch the movie.
I don't want to shut up
and watch the movie.
Can't eat spaghetti,
can't follow the movie.
Doesn't make sense.
I'm going back to the bar.
Good. Good. Go to the bar.
- I'm taking the spaghetti with me.
- Excuse me.
Are you kidding me?
Dude, I just saw another rat.
Yeah, I know.
There's definitely a ton of
rats in here, that's for sure.
I see him! I see him!
Oh, shit.
- We gotta distract him.
- Yeah.
I'll tell him the keg exploded.
No, that's a stupid idea.
That's a stupid idea.
We're going with the burst pipe.
Uh, I like the keg idea.
Your idea is so stupid...
Let's go with the burst pipe...
♪♪♪
Hey, Charlie, Charlie!
Charlie boy!
Hey, where'd you get
those glasses, bud?
Oh, these?
They're just, like, third
dimension glasses, you know?
Don't really work, though,
'cause I feel like I'm still
seeing stuff in whatever
dimension we live in.
Right. Well, listen, um, you can't really
go in the bar right now, bro.
Why not?
Well, because a keg exploded.
Holy shit. Can that happen?
A piece of metal flew off the keg
and hit Dennis right in the dick.
Holy shit. Are you okay?
Yeah... No, I-I'm fine.
I'm fine. I got lucky.
It mashed right into it.
We all thought he was gonna lose it.
Charlie, it lumped it up and
mangled it like a chicken
potpie down there.
Dickless Dennis.
That's what we should call
him now... Dickless Dennis.
No, no, no.
It's totally fine.
Oh, Dickless Dennis.
Oh, Dick... But it doesn't apply
because my totally went back to
normal, and it's fine now.
I'll show it to you.
I don't want to see it.
Anyway, moving on, how was the spa?
Spa?
Oh, spaghetti?
How's my spaghetti?
Dee threw it on the floor.
No, no, the spa.
The spa that Dee took you to.
Oh, no, she took me to a movie.
Yeah, it was lame.
I couldn't understand it.
Made no sense.
That cynical bitch.
Hello. I would like to redeem
this coupon and go ahead
and toss this one in the trash for me.
Busted!
Ah, see!
Oh, busted, Dee.
You're so busted.
What?
What are you guys doing here?
I'm taking Charlie to the
spa because he's stressed.
A keg exploded in the bar,
blew Dennis's dick off.
No, no...
Oh, it's a mess down there.
No, my...
My dick is fine, Dee.
Let me have those coupons.
No, you said I can have them.
Dee, you were supposed
to take Charlie.
Yeah, I tried to take Charlie,
but he refused to go.
What is your spaghetti policy here?
Are you hearing this?
He doesn't belong in a
place like this, you guys.
Alright, come on,
we're wasting time.
Go get Duncan and the bridge
crew and bring them to the bar.
I'll occupy Charlie.
No.
Where's the robes?
I think this is it, right here.
This is sketchy as hell.
Yeah.
Hey, um, yeah, we're
looking for Duncan.
Oh, let's go.
Oh, yeah, we should take
that as a sign, right?
Yeah. Oh.
Come on.
Yeah?
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
You pregnant.
One more time.
What is happening in here?
I don't know.
Come on, no Alright, uh, Mr.
Duncan,
we were wondering if we
could talk to you about...
I ain't no Duncan.
It's this nigga right here about
to go level three and shit.
That's Duncan.
Oh... you're Duncan.
Uh, Mr. Duncan, we were wondering if you
could come to a surprise party for Charlie.
Who?
Charlie.
He's Frank's friend.
It's my understanding you guys have
all been hanging out under a bridge.
Oh, yeah, Frank.
I know that bitch.
Okay, hey, listen, Frank
mentioned that you might be
willing to...
Oh, shit!
Level three, son!
Yeah, level three!
This is bizarre, okay?
Charlie should not have anything
to do with these people.
No.
They are deranged.
You know what? Frank has too
much influence over this whole
thing, alright?
I think we gotta stop and think
about what Charlie wants.
Yeah, I think we need to get
our hands on Charlie's dream
book and we need to figure out
what that kid wants ourselves.
Mother pus bucket.
You piece of shit, you broke my wall!
We have company here.
Should we call the police?
Oh, you know what, let's
just go, let's just go.
No, no, no, no, no.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Alright.
Charlie, let's go.
Get in here.
Oh, oh, oh.
Hey, guys, the management needs
everybody to get out, because
they caught a guy jerking off in
here and they're going to send
in a crew to wipe down the loads.
Go ahead, go on, let's go.
God, it's terrible.
It's really disgusting.
Get rid of all the strange dongs.
Ah.
Yeah, a little bit.
I don't get it, man.
What's so relaxing about sitting
around in a hot, wet room?
It's all about opening
up your pores, Charlie.
Yeah.
Yeah, take your robe off.
Yeah, that's it.
You got your clothes on.
- Get your clothes off.
- What? No.
I can't get naked in public.
Suit yourself, alright?
I am gonna roast like a pig.
OK, I'm gonna eat the spaghetti.
Oh, guys, guys, guys.
Hey, this is it.
Dram... Dram bak...
***
Yeah, look at this...
Pictures and symbols.
I don't see anything about
our stupid luau, but, uh...
This looks weird.
What is that?
What do you make of it, guys?
Looks like a drawing of a pair of
jeans, a plus sign and a chicken.
Denim... chicken.
Denim chicken.
Okay, guys, my gut is telling me
to throw this book in the trash.
Well, yeah.
It's absolute nonsense.
Uh-huh.
I think we're all feeling the
same thing, but I think we need
to fight that instinct.
We have to throw a party for Charlie.
It's so simple.
If we can't do that, what
does that say about us?
You're right, you're right.
This isn't about us.
Let's not be cynical.
Let's do what the kid wants.
Yeah. If he wants a worm...
hat... Worm hat.
Worm hat.
Okay, how do we get him a worm hat,
'cause I don't know what that is.
Maybe there's a drawing, or...
What is that?
- That's a bird with teeth.
- It sure is.
Okay, look, we don't have a
lot of time, so let's just
figure out the best we can do.
We can do it, we can do it.
Alright, we'll do these things.
We'll do these things, okay.
Dude, how much longer do
we have to stay in here?
Come on, just relax.
Take your clothes off.
I feel trapped in here, Frank.
Huh?
I'm trapped like a rat.
Holy shit, I'm trapped
like a rat, aren't I?
- No, you're not, Charlie.
- I'm a rat in here.
I'm a rat!
I'm trapped like a...
I got to get out of here.
Calm down, Charlie.
I'm tired of being in weird places,
Frank, 'cause I'm trapped like a rat.
Calm down, Charlie, calm down.
- Relax.
- Okay, alright, alright.
I got to get out of here!
Now calm down.
How do I get this off?
Charlie, no, no.
Take it easy, Charlie.
Just bash me, Frank.
No, I'm not going to
bash you, Charlie.
Just bash me like a rat.
Bash me like a rat and get it over with.
Oh, sorry guys.
Just let me know when you're done.
I'm the guy who wipes down the loads.
I'm not wearing the stupid
thing, and that's it.
It's a lei.
Surprise!
What the shit is this?
Where's my luau?
Well, we went around you, Frank.
Yeah.
- Happy birthday, Charlie.
- Happy birthday.
Happy birthday?
Oh, is that why you guys were doing
all that weird shit with me today?
Yeah. We were trying to distract
you so we could plan your party.
Thanks, guys.
Yeah.
It's not my birthday, though.
Huh?
It's not your birthday?
Nope.
No, dicks, it's my birthday.
What?
Are you kidding me?
No, I'm not kidding you.
Wait, wait a second.
Were you trying to get us to
plan your surprise party?
Why wouldn't you just
plan it yourself?
Well, that's lame.
I mean, this way I get my
surprise party and I give you
the satisfaction of doing
something nice for somebody.
Oh, my God.
That is not doing something nice.
That is tricking us.
Son of a bitch.
Where's Duncan?
Where's Dunc...?
You should not be hanging
out with Duncan.
You should not be associating
people like that.
I'm saying, I don't care.
It's coming out of my mouth.
Those weird bridge
people that are like...?
Yeah. All that, like,
Hawwoowin lauow?
I knew it, I knew he couldn't say it.
Luau, luau.
Luau.
What is it, you know?
I mean, it's the weird...
Hello?
Hang on.
Oh, yeah.
What do we got going
on over here, guys?
Okay, well, Charlie, when we
thought it was your birthday, we
went through your dream book and
we tried to recreate some of the
stuff we found in there.
Yes, that's... okay.
Um... denim chicken?
Yes!
Denim chicken.
Now I got to reroute the pig delivery.
Nobody gives a shit.
Okay.
And I'm assuming the
teeth are fake, yes?
Yes, well, they're not real
human teeth if that's what
you're asking.
No, I mean, did you discover a
bird with teeth in this fashion?
That does not exist in nature.
Okay.
I'm not sure about that.
But either way, good glue work.
Do any of you assholes
want to know how old I am?
Whatever, Frank.
Nobody... Alright so...
So, Charlie, this is my favorite part.
We weren't quite sure what
a worm hat was, right?
So we made a few of them.
This is the first one.
It's a hat made of worms, okay?
And then option number two
is a hat that you put on
and if you do that you look
like maybe you're a worm.
Right...And then the third one... and
this is the best one, Charlie...
is a hat for your worm.
Oh, your teeny tiny little worm gets a teeny
tiny little hat. If you want him to be fancy.
So which was is it? Which one were you
talking about? Yeah, who's right?
Well, I don't recall
every writing worm hat.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it was in
your dream book. Your...
Oh...
"Wormhat."
Yeah, that's a German guy.
His name is Hans Wormhat.
He appears in my dreams.
He drive a biplane and he shoots it
at me and I run through a field.
You know what, you guys blow.
I'm gonna go find Duncan.
Go, go!
Go!
Guys, wow, the denim chicken,
the bird with teeth,
Wormhat's worm hat.
I mean, I don't know what to say, man.
This is just what I needed today.
Guess what, buddy?
There's one more thing.
Is that what I think it is?
That's a new rat stick, dude.
And you can bash up a whole
bunch of rats with one quick
strike, so it's more humane.
Yeah?
Oh, man.
Well, what do you...?
Oh, you like it?
What do you think?
I love it.
I mean...
Ah.
I don't know what to say, 'cause
no one's ever really, um...
I don't know what to say, guys.
You don't have to say anything, man.
Maybe I could give it a quick
whirl around the basement and
see if I can kill a couple rats.
Yeah, absolutely.
You've earned it.
You should, you should.
Go bash 'em up, buddy.
Whoo!
What a life.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com