Man, this thing rides smooth.
- It's very nice.
- Yes.
It's like riding on
the ass of an angel.
I mean, I wish I could have
sold a crossover like this.
I wouldn't have been able
to keep them in stock.
♪ I'm gonna race you
to the other side ♪
♪ The win embrace
I'm on a brand-new ride ♪
Did you know that there are
5,000 teenagers here ...
between 15 and 18?
- Hmm.
There's four high schools.
Three private schools.
Nice. The average
income's over $100,000.
♪ I'm gonna bet you that
there's more to this ♪
♪ More than will reach the human eye ♪
- How many courses?
- Three private. One public.
Looks like I'll be
getting my swing back.
♪ I promise you'll remain anonymous ♪
♪ An honest lover under an evening sky ♪
♪ Then I let you go ♪
We are gonna do some
damage in this town.
What do you think,
kids? Huh?
♪ Slip of the tongue and
I'll just walk in here ♪
♪ And all the melodies that disappear ♪
♪ I'm gonna put you
on a righteous path ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you clean
and I'll be back ♪
♪ And I let you go And I let you go ♪
- And we're home.
- I think this looks good.
- Mick.
- I got it.
Huh. This is it, huh?
Wow. It's huge.
- Yeah, this is pretty nice.
- Quick, quick.
- Okay, I'll get a video.
- Let's get in.
Oh. Hey, sir, um, do you
mind helping us out?
- Sure.
- Just wanna get a quick video.
- No problem. │- It's real simple.
Here's the viewfinder.
Hit the button. Then I can
send the video to my grandma.
- No kiddin'.
- Yeah.
- Is this new? What is this?
- Yeah, its the new HTC.
This is great.
- All right.
- Okay, everybody smile.
- Hi, Grandma.
- Hi, Grandma!
I am an incredibly
powerful salesperson,
constantly climbing
the ladder of success.
I'm an incredibly
powerful salesperson,
constantly climbing
the ladder of success.
I am an incredibly powerful sales ―
person ― Put your shoes on, Larry.
We've gotta go welcome
those new neighbors right now.
Don't you think we should at
least let the people settle in?
I will never become an
Omega Strata Robustion ...
Cosmetic Associate waiting
for people to settle in.
Please, boo-boo.
I am an incredibly powerful
salesperson, constantly ―
climbing the ladder of success.
Neighbors.
Hello!
Well, hi.
Um, we're the Symondses
from next door.
I'm Summer, and this
is my husband Larry.
Hey, neighbors. I just wanted to
bring you this welcome gift ...
of various samples from the new Robustion
Aphrodite line of beauty products.
But I'm sure you're
in no mood for guests.
- Don't ― Don't be silly.
- Come in. Come in.
- I'm Steve Jones.
- Hi.
- Aw.
- Nice to meet you.
- Steve.
- Uh, Larry Symonds.
Pleased to meet you.
- This is Jenn and Mick, and I'm Kate.
- Hello.
- Hi, Mick.
- Nice to meet you.
- So nice to meet you.
- You too.
Do you have kids? Because they should
come over and meet Mick and Jenn.
Actually, we don't. I was, uh ―
I wasn't able ―
Oh. What?
I know that with a big
move in "conduction" ...
with a woman's naturally
fluctuating hormones,
it can leave your skin a wreck,
but you'll find that
the Aphrodite line ...
of beauty products can
really give you a glow.
I bet. Look at you.
You're a vision of beauty.
Well, thank you.
You're welcome.
Larry, wanna grab a cold one?
Come on. Okay?
Sure. Yeah, sure. Okay.
Come on in.
- Well, would you like a tour?
- Sure.
- These rooms are divine.
- Thank you.
You should come over to our
house, and we can talk decor.
Oh, I would love that.
Boy. I'm very "impassionate"
about interiors myself.
So what line of work
is your husband in?
Well, you know, he does a little
of this and a little of that,
and mostly he works
on keeping me happy.
- Ahh. │- Oh, you're right.
This is really a good beer.
I told you that
would hit the spot.
Hey, that was a, uh, nice visit ...
with the Symondses today, wasn't it?
- Yeah. It was.
I think that you may have
overdone it a little.
What do you mean?
Uh, "a vision of beauty"?
Aw, come on. I was just having fun.
And she loved it. Made her day.
- Well, I love your enthusiasm.
- Thank you.
I just think you need to go slow.
Oh, this is a soft, soft bed.
I could really get
used to being in it.
Mm-hmm. It's nice.
- Sweet dreams.
- Good night.
All right. This is a very big day.
Your first day of your new school.
- Important you make a good impression.
- I have my sweater right there.
- Good morning.
Morning.
So what are you doing today, Daddy?
I am, uh ― I'm gonna try
to scare up a golf game.
- What are you gonna do?
- Oh, you know, a little mani-pedi,
maybe a facial, get my hair done.
I think we're gonna do
really, really well here.
But you guys are
gonna be late.
- Oh! We are.
- Let's get going. Here you go.
Thank you.
See you later.
It's not just created. He pulls it
from the air around him, from the ―
May I help you?
Hi.
We have a new student
joining us today.
This is Jennifer Jones.
It's Jenn.
All right, Jenn.
Choose any available seat.
Thanks.
- I love your shoes.
- Thanks.
The biatch borrowed 'em from me.
♪ Let's all meet up
It's after midnight ♪
Hey, Jones!
Jones!
Steve.
- Hey, Larry.
- You, uh ― You playin' today?
Uh, no. You know, I haven't
really met anybody. So ―
Well, you can play with me.
I'm paired up with a couple of guys,
but there's room for a fourth.
- I wouldn't want to impose on you.
- Don't be silly.
- You can ride with me.
- Really? Thanks, Larry.
- No problem.
- Thank you.
Hi. You've got
glistening teeth.
Thanks. See you later.
- Bye, sweetie.
- Thank you.
New client.
Are you Kate?
- Yes.
- So sorry about the wait.
You know how it is. When the mouth
starts going, there goes the whole day.
I'm "Billay."
Welcome to my salon.
You're not from
around here, are you?
Hmm.
I just saw that YSL bag ...
come down the runway on style.com,
and I know you didn't
get that around here.
- We just moved here yesterday.
- Ah.
So how on earth
did you find me?
Well, I ... do my research,
and anyone who's anyone knows you're
the best. Isn't that the truth.
And there isn't anyone who's
anyone that I don't know.
Mm-hmm.
So. What are we going to do today?
I'm a mess from the move.
I think I need an overhaul.
Sugar, if this is a mess, then
I want whatever you're taking.
- Whoo.
- That'll play.
Nothin' wrong with that.
- Clean livin'.
- Yeah.
- Nice shot.
- Thank you.
- Have you seen these new MP-52 irons?
- I don't believe I have.
They have a lower,
deeper center of gravity,
so they're more forgiving.
- Really?
Yeah, so if they'll forgive me ―
they'll forgive anyone.
- Very nice.
Excuse me.
- Hey, baby.
- Hi, baby. How's your game?
My game's great. How's your game?
- Fantastic. I was just missing you.
- Bye-bye, Kate.
- It was great meeting you.
- You too, Sylvia.
And I'll see you tomorrow for that
hot yoga class. │- Right. Bye, sweetie.
- I see you're making some new friends.
- Well, I'm trying.
- That's hot.
- Oh, I love this.
- The phone's great, but I was talking about
the husband. │- He's pretty yummy too.
- Hello?
- Don't come home too tired.
- Oh.
- Bye. Love you.
I love you.
- You lucky bitch.
- I know.
You know what I'm gonna do for you?
I'm gonna have a special lunch
to introduce you to my ladies.
- I would love that.
- You got it.
Hello?
How'd it go today?
- Very well.
- Did you make friends?
I did. I made friends.
Oh. Did you get their,
uh, contact info?
Of course I did.
Great. Well, your dinner's
in the fridge.
You like that?
- Jenn?
- Ow!
- Come on. Let's go.
- Shit!
- Let go of me!
- Kate ―
Get your clothes on.
- Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- I'll handle this.
No. Nothing happened.
Ladies, come on.
Goddamn it, Jenn. We told them that
this was not going to happen again.
- What, are you jealous?
- Oh, that's ridiculous.
Now, hold on!
If you're not gonna
do him, why can't I?
- Do you want me to call KC?
- Freak's back in action, huh?
- Fuck you!
- Mick, stay out of this.
Go get in your room now.
Night, Dad.
Shit.
- Why did you let her in your room?
- Come on. I was sleeping.
You're not blaming me?
She's got a problem.
What am I supposed to do?
Well, we're not gonna
solve this tonight,
so we're gonna discuss
it in the morning.
Good morning. You have a nice
glow about you. Did you sleep well?
- That's very funny.
- Hi.
- I really think we should talk ―
- Good morning.
Good morning.
We should talk about ―
What happened ― Morning.
Good morning.
What happened last night?
Jenn, do you have something to say?
- Oh, yeah. I'm so sorry.
You know, you're new and I totally
took advantage of the situation.
I shouldn't do that.
I'm so sorry.
This really wasn't covered
in my orientation.
- Well, we may not be a normal family ―
- You think?
but we do have to
operate as a team.
We have a huge
opportunity here.
I'd like to see us
keep our focus.
- Our first review is in 30 days.
- Gotta sell, sell, sell.
- All right. Can I get a
ride with you? │- Bite me.
- Kate, this is why I need a car.
- I don't wanna hear it.
Mick, wait.
I'm gonna be late
for my hot yoga class.
- Oh, you know, sure. That's really ―
- Have a nice day.
You have a nice day too.
Hi. I'm Steve Jones.
You can call me Steve.
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ My right from wrong ♪
- Or Mr. Jones. │♪ I won't sing ♪
- Steve's fine.
♪ No broken song ♪
♪ Now some say love ♪
♪ Is a splendid thing ♪
♪ But ain't nobody ♪
♪ Gonna clip my wing ♪
♪ I'm singin'
Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Till I turn you around ♪
♪ I'll set your blood
on fire ♪
♪ I'm gonna break it all down
Gonna break it all down ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ Up from down ♪
♪ Ain't nobody ♪
♪ Gonna push me around
Gonna push me around ♪
♫ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♫
♪ I'll set the world on fire ♪
♪ I'll set the world Set the world ♪
♫ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♫
♪ I'll set the world on fire ♪
♪ I'll set the world Set the world ♪
♪ Come on ♪
- Bye.
- See ya, Jenn. Bye, Jenn.
All right, then.
I'm sure you're all eager
to hear your results ...
from our first month of sales.
Let's start with Steve.
Total sales in this first month ...
up three and a half percent.
Boo-yah!
- All right.
- Here are a few highlights.
Sporting goods, 4% increase.
Watches, up 2%.
Golf-related merchandise, 3%.
- Nice.
- Okay, Mick ― Overall sales up 16%.
Yes.
Video games, up 13.
Whoa.
- Sportswear is up 21.
- Cool.
Excellent. Way to open
up the market, Mick.
Good work.
And Jenn ― Up 14% overall.
- Solid work, my dear.
- You did good.
- Hey, you're still two down.
- Kate ―
- Congratulations on being our
top producer. │- Thank you.
Up 20%.
Wow. Okay.
Wow. Thank you. Thank you.
Cosmetics, up 24.
Great form.
Thank you.
Are you focused?
Am I focused?
Yeah, I'm focused.
You know, you were
a great car salesman.
People trusted you
and they liked you,
so they bought what
you were selling.
But you're not selling
things anymore.
To succeed here, you
can't just sell things.
You're here to sell a
lifestyle, an attitude.
- Right.
- If people want you,
they'll want what you've got.
Um, do the clients know
how this works?
Of course not. That's why it's
called "stealth marketing."
The fact is, we get results.
How we go about that
is our business.
The question you have
to ask yourself is ―
How far are you willing
to go to get what you want?
It's called killer instinct.
If you can find it,
you could have anything you want.
Anything.
Thanks.
I don't think he's got it.
I think we may have to bag him.
No, no. I ―
I know he's green.
He just needs some time.
And-And I ... I can deal with this.
I warned you not to pick a rookie ...
in your first "head of household."
You've known me a long
time. I can handle this.
I'll give you 60 days.
But this is your ass
on the line, not mine.
Thank you.
Thank you. You won't regret it.
We'll see, won't we?
We're in a terrible
situation right now.
Why are you talking
about spending?
Have you read my new book?
- I have, and I disagree with
you completely. │- Oh, okay.
Looks like sales for luxury items have
been up for the last two months.
You think we're
in a bull market?
That's what I said.
Spend, spend, spend.
Bull market's
around the corner.
I understand that bulls are bad.
Anyone can see how upside-down
the entire market is.
Foreclosures at an all-time high ―
That's true. About four million
foreclosed homes this year.
The dollar is on its way up.
I'm telling you.
If you want to spend your way out,
the dollar will end up
the same way as the peso.
- Hey.
So we need to step it up, so I've
decided that we're gonna throw a party.
Jesus. Look at Larry.
He is a miserable bastard.
My guess is they sleep
in separate bedrooms.
Yeah, I know how that feels.
This is serious, and I'd
really like you to focus.
- Okay?
- Hmm?
I mean, we really need
to pull out all the stops.
I'd like to put our
contact list to good use ...
and start to showcase
all we've got.
It's a good time for me
to wear the YSL dress.
I'd really like to roll out
the Van Cleef earrings.
I think you have some of
those Costume National that ―
- Oh, ho, ho, ho.
have a chance to ―
Thank you.
I really have some
things that I'd like ...
to ... to talk to you ―
S-So I ... There's some
things that I want ―
- Hey, Larry.
- Come on. Come on.
- Hey.
- I'm on poop patrol here.
- Nice. Mind if I ask you a question?
Hmm?
Think Kate'll like these?
- Cha-cha, bling.
- Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
- What's the occasion?
- No occasion.
- Oh, geez. Summer would love those.
- Yeah.
- Well, business is good, isn't it?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- Terrific. Absolutely.
- This is what it's all about.
- Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so. You, uh ...
Are you gonna play today?
Oh, uh, no.
You know, I pulled ―
I kinda pulled a muscle.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Kate and I are into this
new tantric sex thing.
I don't know how I got in the ―
But it, you know ―
- It went too far.
- Yeah.
Well, l, uh ―
- I sure haven't pulled any
muscles lately. │- No?
You know how I keep it fresh
between Kate and me?
Uh, good listening?
No. No, no.
It's about me never really
believing that I have her.
Being full of surprises ...
and a steady stream of gifts.
- It's great to see you.
- Hi. How are you?
- Have you tried this yet?
- Yes, and ―
I think you're gonna love it.
- How are you ladies?
- Are you enjoying that Pomtini?
It's good, yeah?
Well, we'll just, uh, make
sure we'll keep 'em coming.
This vodka is either ― It's either
from Mexico or Antarctica.
- How are you guys doing?
- Hi. │- Hey.
Oh, those earrings are gorgeous.
Thank you. Steve surprised me.
- What was the occasion?
- It was a Tuesday gift.
Tuesday? What's a Tuesday gift?
Just for being Tuesday.
- Oh, my.
- That's so romantic.
Makes me want a cannelloni.
- These are delicious.
- You like 'em?
- Mm-hmm.
- Who does your catering?
Chef Robert.
- No.
- Really?
Excuse me. Will you show that?
- I didn't know he was doing frozen
food. │- Can you believe it?
- Ooh. │- You know, we had the most
incredible chicken "fricazini,"
homemade, at the
Robustion spring gala ―
Oh, I've got to try the sushi.
Ohh! Now, this is one thing
you won't find in your freezer.
Oh, yes, it is.
Wataru flash-frozen sushi.
This is the view from base camp.
I can't believe you
actually climbed Everest.
The Sherpas are the key, you know.
You don't wanna do it
without the Sherpas.
Man, this system's great.
Yeah, with the bundle of services,
you get the clearest HD picture.
All your personal media
is just a click away.
You can see it ―
What are you boys up to?
... best HD picture.
Are you showing off your new toy?
Guilty. Yeah.
And ... who's your favorite toy?
You are.
Mm-hmm.
All right, can I get
you guys another ―
No, no. I'm good.
It's a little hot in here.
Thank you.
- Maybe a big boy drink?
- No, I'm good, thank you.
- Do you want something?
- Um, I'm ― I'm ―
Nice.
Where were we?
Watch for the guy on
the top right now.
All right. Shoot him.
Shoot him now.
- Oh, awesome!
- Told you this was easy.
What kind of shit did your parents
do to get you that thing?
- What are you talking about?
- Oh, I know a guilt gift when I see one,
and that one's got "I'm sorry
for being a fucked-up parent" ...
written all over it.
Yeah, I guess so.
- I'm Naomi.
- Mick.
- I know.
- Hmm?
You have this whole cult
following at school.
- I do? │-Yeah. You've been
there, what, two months?
Everyone's drinking your Kool-Aid.
So, why are you here?
You a friend of Jenn's?
Yeah, right. Yeah. Can't you
see me with that crowd?
Mmm.
- Nah.
- No, not really.
- I'm here with my parents.
- Mmm.
Wanna get high?
Sure. Yeah.
- Wow.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, it must be really big
to be called "the hammer."
Well, yeah. I'd love
to show it to you.
Really?
Yeah. You'll have to stop
by the marina one day ―
soon.
- I would love to.
That'd be great.
Yeah. You know what?
I'm gonna have to go.
Well, it was nice
meeting you, Mr. Bayner.
You too. Bye, now.
Oh, there you are, sweetheart.
How's it going? You have a good time?
And her hair was not ―
Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- Mingling.
Maybe you might wanna go and
show the girls your room.
Yay.
How are you guys doing?
This sushi is incredible.
You guys are so wonderful.
Nobody throws a party like you do.
Well, we'll have to do it again.
- Troublemaker.
- Hey, look who's here.
You know who this is.
The lady of the evening.
- Hey, Naomi?
- Mm-hmm.
Do you wanna know why all those
people are in my house right now?
- It's a party. Duh.
- Yeah.
No, it's so my so-called "family" ...
can show off all their shit.
And you know all those people ...
are fucking blown away by it all.
Yeah.
That sounds like something
my parents would do.
- Aren't you two the sexy couple?
- Oh.
Don't forget about lunch next week.
Good night.
Um ― l, uh ―
- I think it went ― went great ...
tonight. │- Uh-huh. Yeah.
I mean, I personally didn't feel
like l, uh, connected with Melanie.
I don't know if you ― Did you
speak with her husband, Alex?
Don't ― Don't ― Slow down. Slow
down. It was fine. It was perfect.
You were perfect. You ― You know, you
don't realize the effect you have on people.
Thank you.
- Um, just, uh, doing my job.
- Yeah.
You might want to lay off the
Robert hors d'oeuvres though.
- Why? What do you mean?
- Oh, God. Loaded in garlic.
- Are you kidding? Really?
- No, not kidding. No, no, no.
- Oh, my God.
- Good night.
Some party tonight, huh?
Oh, my God.
That house. I could die
for that dining set.
Think she'll buy any
of your products?
They seem to buy
everything else.
I think I can make her if I ...
concentrate on it hard enough.
You look really beautiful tonight.
Honey,
you know that my inspirations need to
be my last thoughts before I go to sleep.
This is how I get what I want.
You should really try it sometime.
I think it could
really help you, Larry.
Shh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
- Hey.
- Mind if I join you?
Sure, come on.
- Want some burrito?
- Ah.
- Chef Robert. │- No, thank you.
I ― I ate something earlier.
- Yeah? │- What did you have?
- A protein bar.
- A protein bar?
- Yeah.
Mmm, tasty.
So I was just looking at
the numbers since the party.
- And you're-you're really
improving. │- Great.
I thought maybe we could talk about
ways that you could do even better.
- Mmm.
- Kate, come on. It's our day off.
I thought maybe we
wouldn't talk shop.
But this is really important.
I mean, you're still selling to indi-
viduals and what you want to create ...
is a ripple effect where you get other people
selling for you. │- You should maybe relax.
Is there anything you
like to do to relax?
- Like go shopping or watch some football
or get a massage? │- There's always people ...
who others look to for advice ―
- You like massages, don't you?
or the inside scoop.
And then they become the connectors
that reach the consumer on your behalf.
Do you know what I mean?
What?
I just thought we'd have a normal
conversation like normal people today.
I don't know if you
understand the pressure.
I mean, you know, this isn't
about me selling my products.
I have to ensure that my unit
is selling their products.
You have a unit?
That explains why we're in
separate bedrooms perhaps.
You're not a great salesman. You're
a charismatic guy and that's great.
But if you don't apply yourself,
then that's all you're gonna be.
- So this is just business, huh?
- Yeah, this is business.
And I'm your boss. I don't ―
I don't need to be friends.
Oh. Okay. Boss.
Ripple effect.
Connectors. Unit. I got it.
- Glad we could talk.
- Great.
Yeah, Bill Johnson said
you turned him on to these.
Can't stop talking about how
great the polarized lenses are.
- Yeah, those are sweet.
- I know you'll love 'em.
- Thanks. Put them on my account.
- Great. No problem, gentlemen.
I think I'm gonna get some too.
- Anything I can help you with, Mr. Jones?
- I'd like to book a lesson.
Sure. No problem.
Let's see. I can get you in
on Thursday with Bob Senior.
No, no, no. I would like to
book a lesson with you, Will.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm. You teach, don't you?
Well, yeah, mostly to kids.
I saw you out there the other
day. You got a sweet swing.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey.
Sorry.
- How was your day today?
- Fine.
- How was yours?
- Good.
You know, I wanted to talk to
you, uh, about our conversation.
Oh, forget about it.
Business is business.
Okay, nice. A little more weight
on your back foot there.
- Back foot?
- Yeah.
Nice.
Will, I do believe you just
added 40 yards to my drive.
You're a magician.
Let me see that driver.
Will, thanks for pairing me up
with those guys today.
- Hey, no problem, Mr. Jones.
- Who am I playing with tomorrow?
- Don't worry. I got a great threesome
lined up for you. │- You the man.
- Cool shirt, by the way.
- Oh, thank you. Under Armour.
If you're looking for drivers,
these are the best.
I was on the course today, and
Mr. Jones drove a 320. It was awesome.
Whoa, nice shot, Charlie.
I wish I could take credit.
The kid in the clubhouse turned
me on to those new Mizunos.
That kid's got the
scoop on everything.
- Tennis, huh? │- Yeah, doubles
with Melanie and the girls.
- Cute outfit.
- Your numbers are looking good.
Thanks, boss.
- Great, Steve.
- Thanks. Don't mention it.
Hand rolled from Cuban seeds.
Hey, you want to join
us for drinks later?
Uh, what, are you kidding?
First round's on me, boys.
Nice watch.
Hey, whoever dies with
the most toys wins.
No, don't be silly. Let me ―
Let me help you with this.
Well, I'll invite
some friends over,
and then you can bring whatever
mask over that you'd like to try.
We're gonna absolutely help you get some
new customers, and we'll have a nice time.
All right, Summer. No problem.
Yes.
Doesn't it feel wonderful?
It's the Robustion
"Replenishingister" Mask,
and it's got ginkgo
and wasabi extract.
This house is gorgeous.
Can you get over the furniture?
- More champagne, ladies?
- It's all the latest Ethan Allen.
He's got fabulous things.
I know because I was just at the design
center myself yesterday looking at new things.
Ladies, I just came
from the washroom,
and the toilet seat
raised up and waved to me.
- Well!
- Whoo!
Well, I hope that you
introduced yourself.
Huh?
- To Toto, my Tokyo toilet.
- Toto?
Well, if that's Toto, then
just call me the Wizard.
'Cause it gave me a power wash to my
undercarriage, and a happy-ending blow-dry.
Whoo-hoo!
And let me just say,
with a friend like Toto,
that you are never lonely.
Where is that fabulous
husband of yours?
Ah, golfing, where else?
- A man's work is never done, huh?
- Never.
Honey, I am home.
- Speak of the devil.
- I missed you today.
Well, hello.
- Oh.
- Hmm.
Good afternoon, ladies.
- My, my.
- That's what I'm talking about.
So, what was that?
Just applying myself.
Don't tell me the ladies
weren't impressed.
Wh ―
Hey, Jones. Terry was
totally checking you out.
Him? Please.
- What's wrong with him?
- Yeah, he's hot.
- I date men.
- Excuse me?
- Who's "The Hammer"?
- What?
You guys are gonna have
to go on without me.
- No way. What are you doing?
- I'm gonna go see a friend.
Is he cute?
Don't get kidnapped.
Hey, do you have any more
of those diet pills?
♪ Yes, oh, yes That's the best ♪
♪ Do you wanna go on Tilt-O-Whirl ♪
♫ Come on, girl ♫
Have you seen these guys
before? They're pretty good.
Yep. My brother's really into them.
You'll meet him when he comes home.
Cool.
I gotta go.
I can't be late for my
therapist appointment.
Oh, shrinks, no.
No, shrinks suck.
Yeah, well, it keeps my
parents off my back so ―
Yeah, I guess that's important.
♪ I like it when you say you've got a gun ♪
- Hey, can I ask you something?
Sure, what?
How come you've never
tried anything with me?
I don't know.
I like you, Mick.
You're not like the rest of
those lame posers around here.
Well, I like you too.
♪ Do you like my ponytail ♪
- Good.
♪ My sideways ponytail.
It's true, it's true ♪
What are you doing?
Hey.
- Um, I thought you guys
had already ― │- What?
- Left.
- Yeah, we're just about to leave.
Well, um, then can l
borrow some L'Artisan?
- Why do you want it?
- I'm going to a party.
Well, I mean, there are gonna be
kids from other schools there,
so I thought I'd work every angle.
Is that a brand you really think
they'd be interested in?
Oh, God, yeah, Kate. I mean, kids these
days are totally wearing upscale brands.
- Huh. Okay.
- Thank you.
Good luck.
And where are the Joneses
taking the kids for break?
Oh, well, we're so excited.
We're going on safari in Kenya.
Yeah, yeah.
It's this amazing outfit.
Spaulding and Kent Tours.
They do everything for you.
They've done all of our
family trips. They're the best.
- Really?
- Oh, yes. I mean, every time.
- You should give them the contact.
- Oh, I will.
- I'm going to the ladies' room.
- Okay.
Steve? Steve Cerrilla.
It is you. I couldn't believe it.
I just saw you from over there.
How are you doing?
Where you been, man?
I'm an old friend of Steve's.
My name is Henry.
- Cerrilla? Where you been?
- I'm sorry to interrupt.
Excuse me, but I ― I think you're
sitting in my wife's seat.
Wife? This guy was the biggest
stud in Scottsdale, Arizona.
- Excuse me, this is my seat.
- Oh, you're serious?
Oh, my goodness.
I ― I  This is ―
You finally tamed the savage
beast, huh? Unbelievable. Come here.
- I'm sorry.
- I am so happy for you.
You know, l, uh ― I'm Henry.
I'm an old friend of Steve's.
I wish that I knew you, but I think you've
got me mistaken with somebody else.
- I think you've made a mistake.
- I don't think ― Are you ―
- I'm not that guy.
- What?
Could you please come with me, sir?
A breath of fresh air.
- I don't need air.
- Walk this way.
What are you talking about?
I don't get it.
That's not cool, dude.
I am terribly, terribly sorry.
- Please enjoy your dinner.
- Whoa.
- That was odd.
- That was weird.
That is like the third time
since we've been here ...
that somebody's mistaken you
for this Steve Cer ―
- Has it been three times?
- Yes.
- I get mistaken for someone
a lot, but ― │- Really?
it's usually Tiger Woods.
- Anyway ― │ - Do you have some
kind of secret life going on?
Baby, you bet I do.
- To secret lives.
Cheers.
- You look like you could use a drink.
- Thank you.
I think the kids must
be working late.
You know, Jenn, I ― I don't know
if she's taking my advice,
but I ― I actually think that
she's starting to get it.
Oh, you smell great.
It's L'Artisan.
- Oh, yes.
- You like that, baby?
Here you go,
super-stud of Scottsdale.
Well, it's not as big of an
achievement as it sounds.
It was more of a
retirement community.
You know the great
thing about this job?
What?
You get to be whoever
you want to be.
Yeah? But I'm not
Steve Jones, you know.
I'm a single, 45-year-old,
failed golf pro, car salesman,
pretending to be someone I'm not.
I know who you are.
Stop.
- What?
- We can't.
Why not?
This part is pretend.
- Is it?
- It has to be.
Good night.
What? Larry, what?
Hey, hey, Steve.
Look at you.
- You're kidding. That is awesome.
- I thought I'd go with the red.
Just a little bit hotter than
the gray, what do you think?
I'm jealous.
You look different.
- You dog.
- Oh, yes.
- Holler at a player, yo.
- Steady stream of gifts.
- Sweet.
- I'm taking care of the luxuries.
- Okay, that's great.
- I got something for you too.
- You didn't have to do that.
- It's top of the line. Laser guide.
No, I can't ― I can't take that.
No, seriously, Steve. I insist. I really
want to thank you for helping me out.
What are friends for, right?
- Enjoy it.
- Well, thank you.
You bet. Take care.
- Say hi to that wife of yours.
- All right.
Do you mind just looking into the
camera and stating your name?
Steve Cerrilla.
So let me ask you.
Tell me about yourself.
I ― You really came very,
uh, highly recommended,
and your resume is very impressive.
- Thank you.
So you would be the ―
the one who was, uh,
playing the role with me.
Um, yes, I would.
Have you ever worked for a woman?
Well, it's something I've thought
about a lot recently.
- Because I have never been married ―
- I saw that.
Either real or imaginary.
In all seriousness,
I've ― I've thought ...
what it might be like
to meet a woman ...
who I would be a better person for.
That just hasn't happened, so ―
Hey, you know, I got an idea.
Why don't we see a movie today?
I don't get it.
What would we sell there?
Nothing, it's just,
you know, for fun.
- Movie. Fun.
- Oh.
- Yeah, well, I'm busy.
- Sorry, dude.
It's their day off.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
What were your other
12 husbands like?
There weren't 12.
Okay, 10. Whatever.
Please, there were six.
Six? Okay, Henry VIII.
What were they like?
- I don't know. │- You don't know?
You spend a year with a guy,
pretending to be husband and wife
and you don't get to know him at all?
Well, you know, you've seen one
Mr. Jones, you've seen 'em all.
- All right.
- You can laugh.
All right, well, I'm gonna ... take my
coffee down to the basement, all right?
See you later.
- Bye.
- Have a nice day off, okay?
- Merry Christmas, everybody.
- Merry Christmas.
As you can see, these are the products
our clients are pushing for the holidays.
And it's up to you to make sure ...
they're under every
tree in town. Nice.
Well, I can't, uh ― I can't
say that I'm hating this.
- I'm glad that you like it.
- You have excellent taste.
- Thank you.
- Is this for me?
No. They're for your
girlfriend, Naomi.
She'll be selling to her little counter-
culture friends without even knowing it.
If she's gonna be with you,
she's gonna need some style.
- Do I look like Elton John?
- Jenn.
Kate tells me you don't have a boyfriend
yet, which is unusual for you, no?
It would be nice
if you could have ...
a romantic interest
by Christmas, huh?
Working on it.
This has been in the stores 10 days.
"Rudy's Rum Punch."
Mmm, 17% alcohol. Ow!
Not for you.
- A bit lowbrow, don't you think?
- It's up to you to change that.
Uh, there's one other thing I almost
forgot. Steve, wanna come outside?
Enjoy.
- The all new Audi R8.
- Yeah?
It's for you. I thought
you deserve a little bonus.
Your numbers have shown
tremendous improvement.
Keep it up and this cell
could make icon status.
Go on. I'll bet you
look great in it.
Whoo.
Hey, Mick. Check it out.
Get in.
Is something bothering you?
- I don't know.
- You know, if, uh ―
if you want to talk about something,
anything, you know,
you can always just,
you know, talk to
your fake mother,
or you can talk to me.
This whole act, it just ―
it gets to me.
Who's acting?
I love this car.
That's not what I meant.
Just think of it this way.
We're making a match ...
between great products and
the people that want them.
It's a service.
Hey, Larry.
♪ We at it again.
Everybody on the dance floor ♪
Wow.
♪ We at it again ♪
- Lookin' good, Steve.
- You too, player.
♪ We at it again ♪
♪ Everybody on the dance floor ♪
I think you just ruined his day.
Oh, sweet.
Sweet, indeed.
I just wanted to remind you that we
have dinner reservations at 8:00.
Oh, good. That sounds good.
Want to hit a few?
- Golf? No.
- Yeah, come on. I'll teach you.
That's what I did before the job
at the dealership ― I taught golf.
Hang on to that.
You're gonna hit some golf balls.
Have you ever done it before?
- No. Uh ―
- Okay. Perfect.
Your knees bend in a little bit.
Weight on the inside of your feet.
- Straight back with the butt
out a little bit. │- Butt out?
- Very nice.
- Okay.
- Well, the hair. I'm just ―
Okay, go ahead. │- I ― I got it.
Go.
What does icon mean? Oh! Whoa!
That's a no-no.
I spoke on your backswing.
- Where did you hear that?
- KC said something about it.
Exactly what did she say?
She said something about making
icon status or something like that.
- Do you know what that means?
- No.
It's the top tier
of the family cells.
I mean, we'll be bringing
high-end goods to market first.
LifeImage is gonna be
looking for our input ...
before proceeding
with any products.
You and me. Do you know how long that
I have been working towards this?
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, wow. That's ―
- Oh. I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
Geez. I should say "icon" more often.
I love boats. I just wanna ...
go away with you forever.
We could sail the Mediterranean.
You wouldn't believe
how beautiful it is.
Mmm.
I can imagine.
Where are the Bayners?
Are they ... habitually late?
I have a confession to make.
Um,
I don't think they're
gonna make it tonight.
Alex is actually
working late and ―
- Really?
- Yeah.
- So it's just me and you?
- Yep.
I mean, I was thinking that, uh,
I really wanted to treat you
and just say thank you ...
for all your hard work
and your improvement and ―
- But I am okay if you want to ―
- No, no.
I will suffer through it.
I appreciate that.
Is ― Is this technically a date?
Well, you could say that. I mean, we are
out in public, and people can see us.
So would it be inappropriate
if I were to reach over ...
and tuck your hair behind
your ear like that?
Would that be something that was
acceptable on a night like this?
I suppose that would be okay.
And what about if I told you ...
that you look beautiful
this evening?
Would that be ―
- l ― l ―
- Would that be ―
No. I ― I would be, um ―
I'd be okay with that tonight.
Okay.
And I might even ...
go so far as to tell you that ...
when you want to, you
can be quite handsome ...
and extremely charming.
- Well, I want to.
- Okay.
Something to drink!
- Nice. Hey, hey!
- Hey!
- Another round?
- Another round.
Oh, my goodness.
We are out of control.
This shit is good.
- It's delicious.
- I told you.
I gotta pee.
- You go pee. You'll be all right.
- Okay, I'll be back.
We'll save your place.
We'll save your spot.
- Hey, you want one?
- No, I'm good, man. I don't drink.
- You sure?
- Yeah, yeah. Thanks though.
Hey, is that ―
is that your TT outside?
- It is. │- Man, I gotta check
that thing out, dude.
- Let's go.
Open her up. Let's go.
Go, go, go!
Whoo!
Mick?
Are you serious?
You ever get tired
of the imaginary stuff?
You want a real ...
house and kids and ... husband?
- I'll have that someday.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
- When? │- Well, I think
when I'm ― when I'm ready.
As a matter of fact, I actually
think that I am a lot like you.
How's that?
I think there's a life I was
living that I didn't want.
And until I can figure
out exactly what I want,
I think this substitute
life is, um, is not so bad.
I get it.
To icon.
Icon.
I just like saying it. Icon. Icon.
Icon, icon, icon.
Does it have an effect
on you in any way?
Yeah! Whoo!
That's it. Open it up.
Here we go.
What'd I tell you ―
This thing's awesome!
Go, go, go. Make this light.
Make this light.
- My baby.
- I could get used to this, man.
- Absolutely.
- Appreciate it.
- Yeah, no problem. │- That was
great. You're pretty cool, Mick.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
So, uh, anyone home?
- No, my parents are out of town.
- Yeah.
What a night, man.
- What the hell, man?
- I'm sorry. I just thought-
Get the fuck away from me!
You son of a fucking bitch!
- Bitch.
- Fuck!
- Listen, man. I didn't ―
- Fuck you!
Shut the fuck up, you faggot!
I thought you were down for it.
Fucking ―
Maybe we should stay in tonight.
This doesn't make sense.
It just keeps saying that all
of our cards are unbalanced.
You did make the payments,
didn't you?
I'm sure it's just a mistake.
I'll straighten it out.
These cards are my foundation,
Larry. I need them for the gala.
I've got stuff to pay for.
How am I supposed to do that?
- The linens, the bartenders, the gazebo.
- All right. I'll take care of it.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
Don't worry?
Larry, you did not make the
house payment last month.
Why would you tell me that
I don't need to worry?
Seriously, you gotta fix this today.
Do you understand me?
- Mr. Jones?
- Yes.
I'm Detective Gardner,
Third Precinct.
- I'd like to have a word with you.
- Oh. Well, okay.
It seems like there was a
party near here last night ...
where some alcohol was
being served to minors.
Now, some of the kids said that
your son Mick brought the alcohol.
Oh, no, no. That's ―
That's impossible.
Is everything all right?
You know a young lady by
the name of Naomi Madsen?
Yeah, she's a friend of our son's.
She left the party drunk
and got in a car accident.
Oh, my God. Is she okay?
She'll be all right.
Could have been worse.
Right now, I'm concerned about
where that alcohol came from.
Is your son home?
Uh, no. He left about
half an hour ago.
But I ― I could try him on his cell.
- Please.
- Thank you, honey.
Is that a cop?
Yes, it is.
- What happened to your face?
- It's nothing.
- What's going on out there?
- We're trying to save your ass.
So why don't you just get
upstairs and stay out of sight?
What?
From father to father,
I trust you're gonna deal with
your son appropriately, right?
- Ooh, I'm gonna deal with
him appropriately. │- Okay.
I just got his voice mail.
But, um, he's very good about checking
in, so I'm sure we'll hear from him.
Just to let you know,
these cases often result ...
in some sort of civil liability.
- You may want to be prepared.
- Thank you for the tip.
- Yeah.
- Sir.
- Appreciate that.
- Yeah. Nice meeting you.
- Detective.
- Thank you.
What are we supposed to do now? Has
anything like this ever happened before?
So what's going on?
Naomi Madsen's in the hospital.
- She got drunk and got into
an accident. │- Is she okay?
It sounds like she's gonna be okay.
- I want all of that punch out of here
immediately. │- Don't worry. It's gone.
I can't believe you
gave it to minors.
- It's my job. Who do you think drinks
that stuff? │- That's not the point.
Weren't you with her at the party?
You must have seen she couldn't
drive. Why didn't you take her home?
- I didn't know she was that drunk.
- Some friend you are.
Shut up, Jenn.
I wasn't even there.
- Then where were you?
- I took a ride.
Oh, so you were
driving drunk as well.
- No. Tim drove.
- Who's Tim?
- Tim.
- Isn't that Naomi's brother?
So you both left her? Why would
you do something like that?
No, no, no.
I got it.
- You were hitting on the wrong guy ―
- Fuck you!
Oh, my God. I knew it.
Thank you for that.
You know what? Screw it. I shouldn't
have to hide this shit anymore.
I'm gay.
At least I'm not a slut.
So-So, what?
I'm sorry to spoil the
coming-out party here, guys.
- I've got someplace to be.
- Where are you going?
No, no, no. We all need to
get on the same page here.
I don't care what
page you guys are on.
I'm gonna go see my boyfriend.
And while we're all sharing here,
it's Alex Bayner.
- Melanie's husband?
- Yeah.
- Alex Bayner.
- This family's fucked up.
- Where did we go wrong?
- We're finished.
It's gonna get around that
Jenn's out of control.
- We've got the police asking
about Mick. │- But there's ―
The company doesn't tolerate
this kind of thing.
Hey, come on. And I am
responsible for this unit.
No, we will figure
this out together.
There is no "we", Steve.
I have to go now and file a report.
Me.
- It's natural that a family has
problems. │- We're not a family.
A unit?
Knock, knock.
Hey, sexy.
You hiding from me down there?
I'm waiting.
Looking for someone?
What are you doing here?
It is my boat.
- He doesn't love you.
- Oh.
Well, aren't you something?
You poor girl.
You actually think you're special.
He's met dozens of girls like you.
You're a plaything.
He's had his fun, and now it's over.
Please.
Stay away from my husband.
He doesn't want anything
to do with you.
You wish.
I couldn't do it.
♪ There must be somethin'
in the water tonight ♪
♪ Little girl you just
don't look right ♪
♪ Stand and deliver ♪
♪ Get rid of that shiver ♪
Hey.
Hey, baby.
Look, you can't
ever call me again.
What?
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ Hey ♪
This is Alex. Please leave your name
and number even if you think I know it.
♪ Play in the grass ♪
♪ In the field ♪
I got it.
♪ Must be somethin'
in the water tonight ♪
Ouch.
Yeah.
♪ You can write me a letter ♪
♪ If it makes you feel any better ♪
♪ Run along now ♪
♪ Why don't you go do it tonight ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
Hello?
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Hey, don't be so hard
on yourself♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Play in the grass ♪
♪ In the field ♪
All right.
Let's get you home.
Come on.
♪ Must be somethin'
in the water tonight ♪
♪ Little girl you just don't ♪
♪ Feel right ♪
Hi, Steve.
KC. That's a surprise.
Kate didn't mention
you coming by today.
- I'm here to see you.
- Really?
Okay.
- I've got good news.
- Yeah?
Your numbers have
gone through the roof.
We're aware of some of
the issues in this cell,
and we think you could do
better in a different cell ―
an icon cell.
Well, uh, look,
I appreciate the offer,
but I think this family can
make icon status together.
They're holding you back.
You need a better
team around you.
I know you like her.
It's her job to
make you like her.
She's a businesswoman,
and she's ambitious.
Don't think for a minute ...
she wouldn't leap at this
opportunity and leave you.
What do you think happened
to the last husband ...
when she got offered this job?
I appreciate it. I do.
But I think I've got
a good team around me,
and I'd like to try to
make it work with them.
So where are you gonna go
for vacation? Really.
I haven't decided yet. You?
Kenya.
No. I'm gonna go to Arizona,
visit my old man.
- That's nice.
- Yeah.
I'd like you to come with me.
What do you say?
I say let me think about it.
- You know what's really crazy?
- What?
I don't even know
your real last name.
Well, a girI's gotta have
her secrets, doesn't she?
Can I buy a vowel?
Hi. Hi, everyone.
Thank you so much
for coming. Hi.
Ripple effect. Ripple.
Thank you. Hello. Hi.
- Well, come on in here.
- Oh.
- Ripple. Ripple.
- Look at that.
- Hi.
- Martini ripple at 3:00.
Thank you for coming
to my Robustion gala.
Really. Come in and sit down.
- Relax, 'cause I just want you all ―
- Shh.
to enjoy the show.
Now, is this you?
Robustion lndustries is proud
to present their new product ―
Robustion Trois.
I'd love to really give
this my full attention,
but I'm gonna go see Larry
and tell him I'm gay.
contains all the "must haves" ―
- Larry.
- Larry?
- Steve. Steve.
- Have a drink with me.
- Bottoms up. Go ahead.
No, thank you.
... for all skin types that are
concerned about the signs of aging.
- What?
- She's furious at me.
This moisturizing
formula is proven ―
She is beautiful, though, isn't she?
Yeah.
I just, uh ― I just
wanted her to be happy.
Well, she is happy.
Just look at her.
You two have a great life.
You don't know
about my life.
You have everything.
... proven to retard the
signs of photo-aging.
Wait till she finds out
they're gonna take the house.
I have samples for everyone.
Don't be shy.
What?
That's right.
Can you say "foreclosure"?
Yeah, but, Larry,
you're doing so well.
You're buying all this stuff.
Yeah. It's bigger
than yours, isn't it?
Is that why you
can't pay your bills?
Are you jealous?
Is there any way that you can return some
of this stuff to pay down your mortgage?
That's it.
You're jealous of me. Huh?
You, uh ― You can't handle not being
the center of attention for one night.
Is that it?
Oh.
Um, now what I'd like
you all to do ―
Look, you don't understand.
All my stuff ― I don't pay for it.
- I don't pay for that stuff.
- Me neither. Not for six months, right?
- "Zero payments for six months."
- No, that's not it.
- Zero payments ― │- That's not
what I mean. You don't get it.
Shh, guys. She's doing her thing.
You're supposed to be paying
attention. You guys are so loud.
Why don't you come over
and ― You know what?
Just a minute, sweetie.
- One minute. Okay.
- One ― Okay.
Oh.
What? Oh, I get it.
- It's her money?
- Oh.
Your secret is safe with me, buddy.
Nice work.
I want you to socialize and
have a wonderful time ...
and just have wonderful
memories of Robustion.
Okay.
- It's terrible. You know, he's
a great guy. │- I know. I feel bad.
I actually think that ...
Summer did well tonight.
And I broke down. I even
bought some of her stuff.
That's nice of you.
Thank you.
This needs something.
Hold that.
Treats.
Let me put some in for you.
Oh, no, no.
- No, that's not right.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's just ― │- It's so good.
- That's just all wrong.
Mm-mmm. Wait.
Just the perfect bite.
What about Arizona?
- What about it?
- You gonna come?
Wouldn't it be a little weird?
I mean, how are you
gonna introduce me?
Like ―
"This is my pretend wife that I' ―
"My co-worker. My" ―
As my boss.
The job comes with great benefits.
That mean you'll come?
Hmm?
- Mmm! Mmm!
- I'll come.
What the ― Larry?
Larry.
Larry?
Larry! Larry!
Larry!
Help! Help!
♪ I had a perfect world ♪
♪ I can't remember it now ♪
♪ The world that I wanted ♪
♪ Don't want me no more ♪
Summer! Call 911!
Call 911!
♪ It's finally clear ♪
♪ All that I needed ♪
♪ Was sitting right here ♪
♪ A fool and his money ♪
♪ How quickly we part ♪
♪ Oh, how I'm missing you ♪
♪ I should've listened to my heart ♪
Hey. You did everything you could.
No, I didn't.
I lied to him.
Here's your coat.
I lied to all of you.
- Steve.
- I'm not Steve Jones.
- That is not my name.
Holy shit.
What?
- This is not my wife.
- Don't. Don't do this.
- These are not my kids.
- Steve, please.
- That is not my house.
- Settle down, Steve.
No, listen to me, goddamn it.
You all have to listen.
I get paid to show off
the cars and the clothes.
I get paid lots of money to lie
and pretend that I'm your friend.
We have to leave.
So that people like all of
you ― people like Larry ―
will go out and want to buy
the stuff that I have.
Me and my perfect family.
I'm sorry.
Come on. Let's go.
Not so fast, sir. I need to
get some information from you.
That was crazy of him.
It's gonna be okay. I promise.
I'll take care of you.
- Is this accurate?
- Yes, it's accurate.
We might need to ask you a
few more questions later on.
I think that's all.
Thank you, Mr. Cerrilla.
It's time to go, Steve.
Where'd you take them?
They've been reassigned.
She took the deal, like
I told you she would.
If you want a fresh start,
my offer's still on the table.
- Hello!
- Hi!
- Hey, Mary Beth.
- Come in.
This is great. This
is great to do this.
Thank you so much.
Come on in.
Here, let me grab your coats.
- Ken, how about a beer?
- Sure, sure.
Imported okay?
- Welcome to the house.
- It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Honey, by the way,
super job tonight.
- Thank you.
- Dinner was excellent.
Is everyone ready for coffee ...
and perhaps some, uh, dessert?
- Sounds great.
- Okay.
Help yourself to some more wine.
Kate.
Is ― Is everything okay
in there, sweetheart?
What are you doing here?
Well, I wanted to see you.
Sorry.
Kate? You all right?
I've got, uh, guests here.
We belong together.
You should have thought of that
before you opened your mouth.
- That's why I opened my mouth.
- Honey ―
Well, uh, who's this?
It's, uh, a friend.
Oh. Well, hey, I'm Bob, Bob Jones.
Drop the act, Bob.
I'm her last husband.
- What? What's going on?
- Nothing.
- Am I getting fired?
- You don't have to do this anymore.
- But my numbers are good.
- I think you should leave.
Right now? No.
- Bob.
- Yes?
Just calm down and go
back to our guests.
- Go on, Bob.
- Go!
- Um ―
- Everything's fine.
- You certain?
- Yeah. Wine.
Oh, sure.
I'm sorry. You were saying?
I want you to come join
me in the real world.
This is my real world.
What are you gonna do when you're too
old to be a mother to these teenagers?
Are they gonna find a
grandparent cell for you?
What kind of life is that?
What kind of joy are you gonna have?
Whose photos are you
gonna hang on your wall?
Who's gonna be there
at the end for you?
We had something, Kate.
It was just a
beginning, but it ―
It was real.
I felt that.
I'm hoping you felt it too.
I think you did.
You deserve to be happy, Kate.
You deserve to be loved.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Steve.
- Hold up.
- Hey, Mick.
Hey.
How are things?
Things are good. Yeah.
I get to be a college student now.
Yeah. And I'm out, which ―
Well, it makes life a lot easier.
- That's great.
- Yeah.
I don't have to lie anymore.
I'm happy for you.
Thanks, Steve. It's been real.
Hey, uh, they've been
looking for that.
Ah.
I'm gonna miss that car.
He came back for you.
- Where to?
- Arizona.
- Seriously?
- Is that all right?
You're the boss.
♪ No, you can't keep lettin' it
get you down ♪
♪ And you can't keep draggin'
that dead weight around ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ooh, ooh ♪
♪ If there ain't all
that much to lug around ♪
♪ Better run like hell
when you hit the ground ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ooh, ooh ♪
♪ When the morning comes ♪
♪ You can't stop these
kids from dancin' ♪
♪ Why would you want to ♪
♪ Especially when you're
already gettin' yours ♪
♪ 'Cause if your mind don't move
and your knees don't bend ♪
♪ Well, don't go blamin'
the kids again ♪
♪ When the morning comes ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Let it go ♪
♪ This, too, shall pass ♪
♪ You know, you can't keep
lettin' it get you down ♪
♪ No, you can't keep lettin'
it get you down. Let it go ♪
♪ This, too, shall pass ♪
♪ You know, you can't keep
lettin' it get you down ♪
♪ No, you can't keep lettin'
it get you down. Let it go ♪
♪ This, too, shall pass ♪
♪ When the morning comes ♪
♪ You can't keep lettin'
it get you down ♪
♪ You can't keep lettin' it get you
down. When the morning comes ♪
♪ You can't keep lettin'
it get you down ♪
♪ No, you can't keep lettin' it get you
down. When the morning comes ♪
♪ You can't keep lettin'
it get you down ♪
♪ You can't keep lettin' it get you
down. When the morning comes ♪
♪ You can't keep lettin'
it get you down ♪
♪ No, you can't keep
lettin' it get you down ♪
♪ When the morning comes ♪