Put it in fire to get bigger.
They like fire.
It would be better if we were
eating than sitting next to the fire.
- Reminds of me the Black Sea.
- It doesn’t smell that much.
They told me not to go to Egypt.
I don’t feel safe here.
They came from Egypt.
I sold them all. Fifty.
Why is it so cold at Sinai?
Its southern than
USSR.
I'll sell her too.
They came from Cairo or Port Said.
Look at this girl.
She's very pretty.
Silence, they're talking about us.
Give me a cigarette.
She's a doll.
She worth 2 thousand.
She worth 13,000.
Maybe more.
Like my father used to say...
"'Whoever doesn’t open the scene?
Is at the worst situation. "
1.000 pounds. And she
worth 7.000.
She's a doll. She's freezing.
You want me to warm her up?
Its cloudy.
Its going to rain soon.
Do they think they're on vacation?
Its cold here.
We are still far away
from the Israel borders.
The last time the
soldiers didn't bother.
Egyptians or Israelis?
Bring more woods.
At the airport they said I am
going to a 5 star hotel.
We are here for generations
with our camels.
Desert is our home.
The others were just
passing by.
Firstly the Turks came,
then the English...
Egyptians and Israelis.
But we were here always.
What’s happening? Are we
going to stay here all night?
If God wants, in two days
we're going to be in Israel.
- Pick her up.
- There is barbed wire.
Throw the bags.
Come and get it/her?
Lets go Igor!
- They are not Bedouins.
- At least they look like Europeans.
Come on! Move!
Come!
I think they're stopping.
Who are those disgusting people?
They're doing circles.
I don’t like that.
I don’t like lights.
- What’s happening;
- Don't start.
- What they want?
- Don't start!
- What are they?
- They are Russians.
At least they are not Bedouins.
Look at these guys.
Scumbags, bastards.
- I'll kill them.
- Chill out...
Girls, come out!
Hurry up, bitches.
Come here.
Fast.
Come on sweetie. Get out.
You too. Stand here.
Move it, dolls.
Move.
Stand in a line.
Stand there!
So, the first one.
What you think about her?
Three is not enough for her.
She's beautiful and young.
- 4,5. How much;
- Five.
- 5,5.
- What did he say? 5,5 for him.
Next.
Get the kerchief off.
She got short blonde hair.
Five. Six.
What you think?
- 6,5.
- How much are you giving. All right seven
Look at her breast. Its
beautiful. She's smiling.
Seven thousand? All right seven.
Put her in the truck.
- Next. Where are the others?
- The redhead.
- Red hair, short, nice.
- I want to see her first.
Nice breast, cute.
Seven thousand. How much?
How much are you giving?
Where is the other buyer;
- How much you giving?
- One moment.
Did you say five;
7.500, all right.
Alla, next.
Long hair, very small...
She's a doll.
We'll take her.
Next. Redhead.
She's a bit wild...
How much are you giving?
That's her. How much are you giving?
Four?
- How much are you giving?
- 6 thousand.
Nice ass. Obedient.
Look how nice she is.
7... 7,5 thousand
and I’ll take her now.
- Eight thousand?
- I give eight.
All right, take her.
Where are the other girls?
Tall, slim, dancer.
She’s a dancer.
- I'll take her with 5 thousand.
- He's giving 5.
6... How much are you giving?
Where is the other one?
- I'll give 6,5 immediately
- Seven!
- 7!
- 7,5 thousand!
Don’t hurt her!
How much?
All right, eight for her.
She’s experienced
The most experienced.
8,5! 8,5 thousand!
She's the most experienced.
Obedient. Nice ass!
- How much;
- 8,5.
- Curly haired, blonde.
- Let me go!
Don’t hurt her.
- Six thousand. How much are you giving?
- I give six.
Forget her.
We'll take her.
Is there another one?
That’s all?
No, look at her.
Village girl.
- I give seven for her.
- Virgin.
She's the youngest.
Don't push me.
Nine thousand?
Ten?
How much are you giving for the other one?
Twelve.
How much did you say?
- She’s virgin! Young, beautiful...
- I give thirteen.
- He said twelve already.
- You're giving too much.
All right, fifteen.
We're done.
Are we done? All right.
Step away.
Heat does me good.
Luckily we completed the
delivery successfully.
In two-three days we're going
to have another delivery.
- This was the last one.
- You think so?
Where is the driver going us?
Kristina, where are you going?
I can see stone buildings.
And Arabic signs.
- What do you see?
- Ruins.
Ruins from a city.
One moment, I can see a sign.
Ramala.
- Is anyone out?
- No one is around.
- Are we in another country?
- I don't know
Quiet.
Take her.
Get up and get dressed!
Hurry up.
Fast!
Calm down, do not resist.
Don't resist.
Come on, we are in a hurry.
Take her with you!
Move, everyone is looking at us.
Hurry up!
People are laughing at us.
Move!
No one will touch me!
I feel like I relive this.
- Give me a beer.
- Why for?
- What did you say?
- No one will touch me!
- That won't help.
- Anyone who touch me will see!
You better look at the
hotel than saying bullshit.
"She is small, She is big...
I'll beat her now", they said.
They are going us to Eilat.
Red Sea.
They brought us here.
Let's go! Hurry up!
Move.
This way! Come!
All right.
Leave the bags
and get naked!
Igor, tell them.
Put your clothes off.
- Put your clothes off.
- Put their clothes off.
- Leave them all here!
- Move it, put your clothes off!
When you do it, come
here one by one. Come!
Not you,
bring the girls.
Tell them to hurry up.
Help her get naked!
You, come.
Move.
Get in line.
All right Igor. The shower.
- What is she doing?
- Catch her!
I want more pressure.
Open the water.
Can we make it warmer?
Split them in the place.
Don't let them be all together!
Split them!
Sacha, move on!
- Do you hear me?
- Stand there.
This one didn't finish.
All right. Bring towels.
What are they doing here?
Arrange her.
Move on.
Igor, bring me my clothes.
They torture us on purpose?
Move it!
Dry your hair!
Are we going to go half-naked
to the club?
Are you done? Take this.
No, you already have.
Who doesn't have pants?
Here.
- Perfect!
- All right.
- Faster!
- I'm trying.
Put this on.
- I need a bra.
- Who said that?
Here you are.
Is everyone all right?
One moment, my bag.
Go to hell!
Move on!
Let's go!
Is Sacha down?
Where are the others?
Bring all the girls here.
Get dressed.
Where are the others?
Bring them here.
Igor watch them.
I'll bring the make-up.
Where is the make-up?
Put off the towel.
Girls...
Prepare them.
Igor, where is the make-up?
Take it.
If sharks were humans...
they would build huge cages
in the sea...
and fill them up with
goodies for the small fish...
and they would keep them clean.
Next.
For example...
If a fish got injured on the fin...
they would put him
a sticking immediately...
so it won't die immediately,
but stay alive...
till it end up in sharks belly.
Next.
Stop crying.
I cant put you make-up.
Stop.
I'll treat you good.
I know... I also left the homeland
years ago.
I was born in Germany,
near borders and I live there.
I was doing really good there...
I did what I wanted.
I was doing shows.
And then I fell in love with a
Hebrew...
but he didn't feel
good in that country...
and he wanted to go at Israel.
I followed him.
When you are in love, you
follow your other half.
No one can restrict
you from loving him...
Its like electric load.
It creates a new world for both...
But you have to load him, or
you lose everything.
Maybe if we had a child...
That was it.
We didn’t have a kid so we
broke up.
Then I met another one,
Yussuf...
He showed me a new life and
I thought...
that life is composed by
many roads...
that I wanted to discover.
I didn’t know where they were going me.
So...
I don’t live with him anymore.
But we are still collaborating.
Simple collaboration.
He got the north,
I got the south.
Like the Queen.
- You remind me someone...
- Who?
I don't know.
Must be my sister...
- Stop crying.
- I'm so scared.
I want to calm you down.
I'll be good with you.
I want to be good.
Stop crying.
I don’t have much to give you.
Only this maybe, which I like.
Look what I’m going to give you.
Here, take it.
Its hard to give it to you.
I cant put it out easily.
Here you go. You're going to
work for me all right?
Imagine it as a job.
Only as a job.
Don't think you are a whore
you're just working.
I'll be always good with you.
What happened to that girl?
I think she died...
maybe not.
What are you looking at?
Mind your business!
- Listen to me!
- I'm not interested.
I'm not hitting on you. I only
want to talk to you. Listen to me.
- I'm not interested.
- Only you can help me!
You're the only one.
I won't see you again.
You've got to help me.
We are eight girls.
They brought us here
without our willing.
They hit us. We can't
even breath, Listen to me.
You've got to help me.
You're the only one who can.
Look at me! Imagine your
sister here...
and people touching her, and
fucking her and she crying.
- You have to help me.
- How?
I beg you, you'll think something.
Take me from here.
Help you to run away?
Find money
to pay someone.
I won't see you again.
I want you to come back...
- Why are you telling me all that;
- Only you can help me.
Please.
I can't do anything.
I'm sorry. I have to go.
Promise me you'll think about it.
Come back. That’s what I’m asking.
Its a foreign country,
I can't speak the language.
You'll think of something.
Come back.
I can't do anything.
Only think about it.
Who is that doll?
She is kissing with passion.
Look at Igor.
He's in the mood.
That was the club in Eilat.
She was looking at us.
She was there when
Bedouins were selling us.
- Maybe she wants to accompany us.
- Maybe she likes to look.
- She might help us.
- I talked with her. She might help us.
Help.
Welcome to Haifa.
Get lost.
Are they all here?
Bring them.
Cover up with that.
Rose, are you all right?
Don't frown.
- I didn't hear you.
- I said, don't frown.
Don’t frown?
Here?
You're so beautiful.
Like an angel
Are you sick?
Physically, no.
I'm all right.
Get some rest...
- Water...
- Rain.
It rains a lot here.
All the time.
I can't believe that this is winter.
It's only raining.
Whenever Igor hit the sack...
I felt like he was
hitting one of us again...
and slowly we bowed to...
and accepted to be things,
statues or paintings.
Yussuf and Hezi were fighting
in a hebrew-arabic mixture.
They only agreed when they
were planning our future.
For how they were going to use us.
We were far away from the
landscapes of our child years.
Estonia looked far away.
We were just waiting to
finish, with one way or another.
Come on Katya. Come.
- That's Katya.
- I know.
- It's cold.
- It's cold, damn it!
Stop cursing, Katya.
Everyone get out of here!
You're disturbing our work!
Get out of here!
Now everything's all right.
I'm free!
Wait!
Its time to reborn...
Its time to bow...
its time to get together...
Time to love...
Time to hate.
Time for war...
Time for peace.
What’s the profit man
has from all this work?