Jason.
It's like this.
We live in claustrophobia,
a land of steel and concrete
trapped by dark waters.
There is no escape, nor do we want it.
We've come to thrive on it
and each other.
You can't get the adrenaline pumping
without the terror, good people.
I love this town.
You've been listening to WGAZ,
the electricity of Manhattan.
This request is going
all the way out to Crystal Lake
and the senior class of Lakeview High.
- That's us.
-All right.
They'll be graduating
on the 13th of this month,
and we wish them
the best of luck and success
when they come to visit
our seductive city.
Our lure is a great one,
young friends, but beware.
The city of lights
casts many shadows indeed.
- I love you.
-I love you.
- Gotta throw the anchor over.
-Okay.
- Hey, what's wrong?
-Nothing.
Come on, Jimmy,
something's bothering you.
Just that we're right around
that summer camp
where all those murders took place.
- What murders?
-You don't wanna know about it.
- Tell me.
-Forget about it, Suzi.
The guy's dead now,
somewhere at the bottom of this lake
if you believe the stories.
What stories?
There was this boy
named Jason Voorhees
who drowned in Crystal Lake
about 30 years ago.
None of the counselors heard him.
Help!
A bunch of years went by,
and everyone forgot about it.
And that's when the murders
started to happen.
Jason did it?
His mother blamed the counselors
for her son's death,
and she tried to kill them all,
but she got her head chopped off
by one of them.
Legend has it that Jason
came back to get even,
vowing to kill every teenager in the area.
And every now and then,
the murders just start up.
Forget about it, Suzi.
They're just stories.
Did you hear that?
- Hear what?
-Come on, I'm serious.
All right. I'll go check it out.
Jim?
Jimmy?
Stop screwing around, Jim. I mean it.
Got you good, Suzi.
All right, all right, so I'm a major ass.
- And you'll never do it again?
-And I'll never do it again.
- Come on, forgive me?
-No.
Jason?
No! No, please, no!
No. No. No, please, no!
No! No!
Well, Toby's been
awful quiet back there.
Yeah, I guess he's a little nervous
about the trip.
Here.
Go on, open it.
Stephen King supposedly
used it in high school.
I don't know what to say.
Rennie, you are the best student
I have ever had.
You have a real gift.
And if there's anybody that can
make use of that pen, it's you.
Hi!
- Hello, Charles.
-Colleen.
You know, this cruise was your idea,
so at the very least,
you could show up on time.
- Has everyone checked in?
-No.
Jim Miller and Suzi Donaldson
never showed up,
and I'm more than a little concerned.
Well, don't be. They probably
decided to explore each other
rather than New York.
That's nice.
We're running five minutes late already.
There's someone else coming, too.
You never should have
brought her here.
It's up to Rennie to decide
what she wants to do.
She doesn't know what she wants.
She never had a stable life
till she came to live with me.
Well, she ceﬂainly doesn't
have one now, either.
I'm her legal guardian,
not you or anybody else,
and I know what's best for her.
End of discussion.
No, I think it's just the beginning.
Have you decided
on your departure protocol, Admiral?
Actually, I thought
I'd leave that honor to my son.
Dad, I don't...
I don't think that's necessary.
Relinquishing command
of the motor vessel Lazarus
to Captain Sean Robertson.
But before you take the helm, take this.
Something old and something new.
I used that sextant when I was your age.
Now they got those goddamn
computers that do all the work for you.
Have you decided
on a plan of departure, Captain?
Okay-
How about we start up the engines
and come around 180 degrees?
Aren't you forgetting something, mister?
Send out
the international maritime signal,
followed by a security broadcast
warning other ships
that we are underway.
This voyage is doomed.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Bye !
- Have fun in New York!
-Bye!
- Rennie.
-Hi, Sean.
I heard you weren't coming.
We changed our minds.
- I got you a present.
-But I didn't get you one.
Forget it. It's a dumb little thing anyway.
Sean, I love it.
You see, I thought when we got there,
maybe we could hike
to the top of the statue
if you felt like it.
It's supposed to be 22 stories tall.
That sounds wonderful.
Mr. Robertson,
your father was looking for you.
I guess I'll see you later.
What are you doing here?
We've already been through all of this.
I'm sorry, Uncle Charles.
Please don't be upset with me.
I'm not upset. I'm just concerned.
Is this ax awesome or what?
Too cool, J.J.
Your parents really came through.
No lie.
Hey, I hear there's
this big power room downstairs.
We can get supreme concert-hall echo.
So come on down and shoot
a basement tape on me, okay?
Yeah. But I gotta get some
shockumentary footage first.
Oh, man. Don't tell me
you're still trying to scam on Tamara.
How long have we known each other?
Don't be a dweeb, Wayne.
She's not interested in you,
only what you can do for her.
- She is a user.
-She's sexy.
So what? So is this guitar.
Yeah. Well, I'll talk to you later,
all right?
There's a big storm
predicted for tonight.
Rennie, you're making a big mistake.
It's not too late to put you back on shore.
If Miss Van Deusen
knew how afraid you were of...
She didn't push me into this.
Rennie, why are you doing this
to yourself?
I don't even know what I'm afraid of,
Uncle Charles.
I can't even remember when it started.
Don't you think it's time I found out
and got over it?
Facing your fear
doesn't always conquer it.
I'm staying.
Okay-
Man, this place is aching for a video!
Wayne, you're an asshole.
Help!
So, what do you think?
Time for some personal experiences
to fuel our minds?
I agree.
Mommy?
Help! Help me!
Help!
Toby!
- Come on!
-Yeah!
Come on.
Is that a muscular bod or what?
One more, one more!
He's undefeated, you know that?
Julius is the only senior
I'd even consider doing it with.
He is so good-looking.
Gorgeous guy at 10 o'clock.
Look sensual.
I think it's time
for some recreational activity, girl.
Have you seen my niece anywhere?
Yeah, I think she's motivating
downstairs, Mr. McCulloch.
What's the problem?
Well, senior predictions
staﬂed five minutes ago,
and she hasn't shown up yet.
Well, maybe some of us
don't want our futures predicted.
Well, in your case, I'm sure that's true.
Nighttime is the right time.
No, thanks.
Don't be a lightweight.
This is top-dollar toot.
It's not that. It's just, you know,
if we get caught, I could lose
my science scholarship and everything.
You're talking to the prom queen, Eva.
Do you really think
I'm gonna risk getting caught?
- Jesus!
-Have you guys seen my dog?
I think he came this way.
No, we haven't. Did you care for a hit?
No, thanks.
Real space cadet.
I wonder if she'll narc on us.
Here, boy!
Oh, yeah.
Ready to party and then some.
- What are you doing in here?
-Nothing.
Are you girls using drugs?
Do you think I would use drugs,
Mr. McCulloch?
We're just exploring the ship.
I'll be coming around to your stateroom
in exactly 15 minutes, Miss Mason,
so you better have your biology project
ready, or I'll be phoning your parents.
They're out of town.
Well, I'll make sure
that you remain on board
while your classmates
are out seeing the sights.
- Now what?
-Relax.
I've got McCulloch covered.
That narcing bitch niece of his
is a different matter.
Rumor has it she's a teensy bit
afraid of the water.
Nice fight, Julius. Guess I need
to work on my left-right-left combo.
Hey, listen.
No hard feelings, man, okay?
What do you say we track down
those babes later?
Julius?
- So are you having fun yet?
-Yeah, a lot.
Come on, level with me.
Hey, if you can't trust me,
who can you trust?
It was an accident, I swear.
Stay calm
and grab the life preserver, Rennie!
I've got you. Come on. I've got you.
- That was truly excellent.
-Yeah.
Come on. Time to check out the waiters.
Look, I think I'll pass, okay?
- What?
-I'll see you later.
Some friend you are.
- Come on, grab her hand!
-That was close.
It's okay. It's okay. Come here.
Come here. Sit down. Sit down.
- Grab her some towels, okay?
-Okay.
She's fine. She's... Just go back to what
you were doing, okay, everybody?
Care to talk about it?
I can't swim.
No kidding.
You ever thought about taking lessons?
It's not that simple.
Good God!
- Take it easy, Charles. She's all right.
-I can see that.
You've done a wonderful job
of supervising the kids.
What the hell happened here?
- It wasn't her fault.
-Give me those towels.
You stay away from her. Both of you!
He's come back,
and you're all gonna die.
Just leave me alone.
Help me! Help me!
The door's open.
I'm in no mood for any more
of your stall tactics, Miss Mason.
Where is your final project?
Wouldn't you like
a glass of champagne first, Charles?
Where did you get this?
Well, I packed it just for us.
Well, that's it.
You're not stepping off this ship
until we return home.
But I haven't even shown you
my biology project.
Hey...
What do you think you're doing?
I mean...
Now, you stop that!
I mean, really.
Take a closer look, Charles.
I wanna make sure I've labeled
all my organs correctly.
Get... Get off of me! I don't believe this.
What do you think you're...
I'm your teacher, young lady.
Well, now you've gone and done it.
Not only are you going home,
but I will... I will see to it personally
that you spend next year
back in a high school classroom.
What is going on here?
- Did you get anything good?
-Oh, yeah. Very kinky.
- Give me that tape. Give it to me!
-Come and get it.
You're going to be very, very sorry,
young lady.
And as for you, you can forget
about attending any film school.
Ever!
Relax, Wayne.
He's not gonna risk trying a thing.
Yeah. Yeah, I guess you're right.
Listen, this is gonna sound
supremely lame and I know it,
but I've had the major hots for you
since our sophomore year, Tamara.
That's so sweet, Wayne.
And I really would love to stay and chat,
but I really am pressed for time.
So let's be sure to get together later.
Okey-doke?
- Yeah, I just thought...
-Yeah.
But I... Maybe we could...
Wayne, you're an asshole.
Oh, no! No!
No!
No! No, no!
Let's kick in the stabilizers, Mr. Carlson.
Keep the seas off the quarter.
Yes, sir.
These kids are
in for one hell of a storm.
Yeah.
- How old is your boy now, Carlson?
-Nineteen months.
Tremendous age.
Take some advice.
Don't push him too hard.
Yeah.
- Take the helm, would you, Jim?
-Certainly, sir.
I double-checked
those lifeboat stations, too.
Oh, my God!
Can he really take us home?
He can call
a Coast Guard cutter for you.
What about you? Are you staying here?
I'm never gonna be
what he wants me to be,
so I guess I'm going with you.
Oh, Jesus.
Dad?
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
-No.
Attention, everybody. Attention.
This is Sean Robertson.
Miles, have you seen J.J.?
She's supposed to be jamming
-down in the power room, but...
-Just...
What I mean... This is an emergency.
I want you all to come to the bridge.
What the fuck is this?
mayday-
Mayday!
Shit.
This is the motor vessel Lazarus.
Sean, what's going on?
Jesus Christ.
Please, can anybody out there hear me?
This is the Coast Guard cutter Dallas.
What's the nature
of your problem, Lazarus?
Thank God.
Hello?
- Hello, are you there?
-I demand to know what is going on!
Christ.
Sean, I'm...
Where's the radio?
It's dead.
You're all gonna die.
You're the last ones.
He's come back for you.
- What the hell are you talking about?
-Jason Voorhees.
You're insane! Jason Voorhees
has been dead for years.
He came down the river,
and he's gotten on board.
He walks this ship here and now.
Yes, a killer walks this ship, all right.
And it's certainly none of us,
-you bastard!
-What are you... What are you doing?
You're the one who's insane.
That lunatic has been spouting off
about Jason ever since he came aboard,
and it's no coincidence.
But that doesn't prove that he's the one.
Walking corpses are not real.
Oh, yeah? Yeah, well, these dead
bodies are sure enough real, all right?
Now, I say we regroup
and let's go find this motherfucker
before he finds us, huh?
- Are you with me?
-Watch your mouth, young man!
And you'll do no such thing.
I'm in charge here!
School is out, McCulloch. Okay?
Let's go.
You come back here!
Christ. Where's Rennie?
She's dropping the anchors.
You had me worried to death.
But Sean said
that we needed to drop the anchors.
I'm the one you should be listening to.
Do you think dropping an anchor
in the middle of a storm
makes any sense whatsoever?
Come on.
Tamara?
Tamara, did you hear
the announcement?
Help me!
I managed to scrounge this shit up
in the game rooms and the hallways.
All right, grab what you want.
- What are you taking, Julius?
-Nothing
but this gun.
J.J.?
Are you down here?
You got a major problem, Wayne.
Shit, I can't see a damn thing.
No.
J.J.?
Did you find Rennie?
She's locked safely in her room,
no thanks to either of you.
Have you brought her
back on course yet?
He's doing the best he can.
He's the son of a captain,
for Christ's sakes.
He ought to be able
to operate this thing.
Well, do something.
- It worked. We're back on course.
-Good.
- What's that?
-The fire alarm.
We've already thought about that.
Nobody could possibly see
a flare gun in this storm.
There's only one person
who needs to see it.
I'm gonna find that deck hand.
But what about the fire?
- How do we know there really is one?
-What are you talking about?
USE some common SENSE.
Setting off a fire alarm causes panic,
the same kind of panic
caused by suggesting
that Jason Voorhees is alive
and aboard this ship.
Enough is enough.
Help me;
Help! Help me!
Rennie.
I don't understand
what's happening to me.
- What is that?
-The power room.
All right, listen, everybody.
I want you to stay here until I get
back with the others, all right?
- You understand?
-Yes.
Water's gotten into the engines.
We have to get everybody off the ship!
Rennie! Hang on!
Sean!
Rennie! What the... Let go of her!
She never should have set foot
on this ship. It's all your fault!
This is Jason's fault.
Not another word about Jason,
do you hear me?
No, I don't!
It's time you listen to me
if you want off this ship alive.
Thank God. I just lowered the lifeboat.
We have to go.
Wait! I left the others in the restaurant.
There is no more restaurant.
Come on, honey.
Get back!
Son of a bitch!
Come on, Charles.
Here, grab my hand!
- Come on, now.
-Come on!
Hurry HP!
Watch it. Watch it. Hurry, now.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
- Sean! Careful.
-Come on.
Grab on to my arm. That's it.
- Stall rowing!
-Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Julius!
Pull him in.
Keep rowing!
I hope you can find shore soon, Captain.
We all don't wanna drown out here.
Do you have any idea
where we are, Sean?
Hey. Hey, Sean.
Come on, man. I made it. So can you.
All right, man.
Hey, man. Yo. Yo, wake up.
Shit! Check it out! Damn!
We're in New York!
You did it, man! You did it!
We are in New York. New York City!
Yeah!
I don't believe it. We made it!
If I can make it there
I'll make it anywhere
It's up to you, New York, New York
There must be a phone
around here somewhere.
Wonderful choice of places
to dock a boat, Mr. Robeﬂson.
Wonderful.
- I can't believe we made it.
-I can't believe we're still alive.
We are all very lucky.
Give me your money.
Everybody, shut up
and give him the money. Now!
Give me the money. Come on.
Here.
Got some good shit here, holmes.
You got that right.
Give me your wallet. Come on!
- Now, ain't that sweet?
-Bastard!
Go ahead, Superman, be a hero.
- Hey, come on, now...
-You got a problem, dad?
No!
- Please don't hull her.
-Hull this princess?
Would I do that?
You look like a real party girl, princess.
You wanna go on a date
with me and my friend?
If you're free, that is.
Follow us, we blow her fucking head off.
So, what, we just gonna stand here?
Let's go.
Julius! Calm down, will you?
You heard what he said. He'll kill her!
We have to find the police.
Now, look.
I think we'll be more productive
if we split up, okay?
- All right, but, Charles, suppose we...
-Colleen, no discussions now, please!
Help! Stop it! Help!
Somebody help me!
Shut the fuck up!
Welcome to the casbah, princess.
Please, don't hull me.
Loosen up, baby.
You'll feel way better if you're stoned.
Better slang us some more 'caine, JoJo.
We only got a half load here.
We're in for a long night.
It's your parade, princess.
It can be smooth. It can be rough.
It's your choice.
Come on, baby. Lay back and enjoy it.
I think I'm in love.
Forgot my money, holmes.
Who the fuck are you?
You're dead, fuckhead.
Shit!
Help!
Come on.
Operator, this is an emergency.
Give me the police.
Use the combos, keep the feet light.
This is it.
Take your best shot,
motherfucker.
- Rennie? What did they do to you?
-He's here, Sean.
- Jason is here.
-Oh, God.
We have to find the others now.
- Freeze!
-it's okay. She's with me.
My apologies, miss. Are you all right?
Hey!
Rennie! Rennie. Rennie. Thank God.
Are you okay?
Mr. McCulloch,
Jason is here in New York.
- Rennie saw him.
-Just shut up about Jason, will you?
Is it true, Rennie?
You're right. I find it a tall tale indeed,
but you seem like honest folk,
so I'm inclined to believe
at least some of what you say.
Yeah, well, first order of business
is to find Julius.
I'm sure he'll pop up soon enough.
I'll call for backup.
Oh, Jesus!
Dispatch! Dispatch!
- Open the door!
-There aren't any handles.
No handles!
Hold it! Rennie, what are you doing?
For God's sake, Rennie, slow down!
Come on!
Rennie, quickly! Let's move!
Miss Van Deusen!
It's so pretty today.
Yeah.
Perfect day for swimming.
You know, young lady,
you've been coming out here
every summer for the last three years
and you still haven't learned
how to swim.
I'll take some lessons this time.
I promise.
Now, that's what you said last year.
I think the time has come
for your first swimming lesson.
You don't wanna end up drowning
like that Voorhees boy, do you?
He never learned how to swim, either.
And he's still in the bottom of this lake.
- He is not.
-Yes, indeed, he is.
And he's ready to pull down
anybody who falls in and can't swim.
You're telling a lie.
Am I? Let's find out.
You better swim, Rennie,
before Jason pulls you down.
- I can't!
-Yes, you can, and you will!
Come on! Rennie, swim!
You pushed me into the lake.
Rennie, I...
I was only trying to teach you.
You almost killed me. I was drowning.
I pulled you out. I saved your life.
You son of a bitch.
He was down there.
Rennie!
Just keep away from her!
You. You.
It's... It's not possible.
Please! Wait!
I'm begging you! Please!
I was at school when they told me.
"Rennie, your parents died
in a car accident."
It just seems like everybody I care about,
I lose.
That's not gonna happen this time.
Help!
- What are you doing?
-What is this?
- This isn't my stop!
-Come on!
Get it moving!
It's over.
- Somebody please help us!
-Go!
You're dead meat, slimebag!
Yo, man. It's cool. It's cool, man.
It's cool.
Times Diner. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We're open till 3:00 a.m. like always.
Look, you've got to call the police.
There's a pay phone in back.
But it's broke.
Look, you don't understand.
There is a maniac trying to kill us.
Welcome to New York.
Son of a bitch.
Come on!
What the hell are you kids
doing down here?
Can you help us get out of here?
Sure can,
but we haven't got a minute to spare.
- What do you mean?
-Toxic waste, son.
The sewer floods out with the stuff
every night at midnight,
less than 10 minutes from now.
Come on, follow me.
You didn't get me in the lake,
and you're not gonna get me now.
Sean. Sean, get up!
Get up, Sean!
Go!
Climb!
Mommy! Don't let me drown!
Mommy!
Help! Help!
I hear there's a statue here
that's 22 stories tall.
Toby!