Cleaning the bathroom
is the most
- valuable thing you do.
- I quit.
I deserve this jacket. It represents
my total unemployability.
I'm just expecting
a text from Brett.
Maybe... be mature
and text him?
Uh... no!
At least you could contact Brett.
I can't even find Jane.
- Who's ready for another?
- Think I'm good.
Yeah, you wouldn't
wanna have a second beer.
You might crash into somebody
on the walk home.
Give her a break.
We gotta wake up early
to prepare for our big bash.
This is the first party we've ever
thrown together as a couple.
All of our grad school friends
are gonna be there, so...
Doctor dorks
and law dweebs
this party's gonna be like a
national geographic special
on the mating rituals
of the socially challenged.
You're funny.
Is it okay
if I bring somebody?
- Who?
- Brett?
- Ruh-roh.
- What?
When was the last time you even
talked to that hipster tool?
Not since
the ravioli party,
but after my little
social disease scare,
I realized that
I kind of like him.
Wow, a Tina
"I like him"
is the equivalent
to most girls'
"I'll slit my wrists in a warm
bath if I can't have him."
- [Chuckling]
- Anyway.
I thought
I would reach out,
and, you know,
tell him how I feel.
Oh, it sounds like
our little girl's growing up.
Or maybe a sign
of the end times, you know,
when the clouds start bleeding,
and animals start talking.
- All: [Chuckling]
- Okay.
We're out.
So we'll see you guys
- tomorrow night?
- Yep.
Retainer and
headgear optional.
- Ha, ha.
- Heh.
Actually, I should
probably crash too.
- [Whining]
- I'm taking...
This placement test
at a temp agency tomorrow.
Seriously, if I don't start
scrounging together
some money soon, I may be
kissing Brooklyn goodbye
- and my parents hello.
- Well...
Maybe you'll meet
a nice girl in St. Louis.
You know, one who loves golf
and making bread.
Sporty and yeasty?
Doesn't sound
too bad to me right now.
God, the only girl I've actually
liked in forever was...
- Both: Jane.
- Yeah.
Steals your pants,
leaves a fake number, Jane.
If we're gonna have
this conversation again,
I'm gonna need something
harder than a beer.
Sorry.
Well, hopefully by the time
you see me tomorrow,
I will be an employed,
tax-paying member of society.
You will be, Jay.
And I'll be with Brett.
Caveat... unless he's gone
full williamsburg
and trained his moustache
into a Salvador Dali.
Then I'm gonna have
to reevaluate.
I wonder what those
look like in the morning.
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.Addic7ed.com/
[Groaning]
Accuracy below limit.
Ugh, damn it.
Come on.
Fail.
Ugh.
[Cell phone vibrating]
JB?
Hello?
Hi, Jason,
I have JB for you.
Wow, you guys finally got a phone
that can transfer calls.
All right, Jason, you're on
the line with JB brown.
Not JB brown.
The "B" is the "brown."
Jesus, Roger.
Give it to me.
Hey, good news, Jay.
Mama dog has a bone for you.
A week-long role
that you would be perfect for.
Role? Like,
an acting job?
Yes, perfect for a young,
average weight, average height,
vaguely unimpressive
guy like you.
$500 for the week,
and it starts this afternoon.
- Are you interested?
- Yeah, totally.
- You had me at $500.
- Fantastic.
So now I have everything
for my champagne punch.
The secret is
the orange zest.
Great, and I have
everything I need
to make my vodka
gummy worms.
The secret is
they get you wasted.
Really? Vodka worms?
I mean, this is our
first party as a couple.
I was thinking cheese plates,
my punch...
People falling asleep
in flutes of your punch.
"Classy cocktail"
is code for boring.
Our first party
should be a banger.
Got a DJ app on my iPad,
we'll get a keg...
A keg? Are the pledges
gonna tap it?
We're having
a cocktail party.
Shouldn't our first party
as a couple
have stuff
we both like?
You're right.
We'll do this
my way and your way.
It'll be the best
of both of us,
instead of just,
you know, the best.
Why do I always get Turkey?
I'm so bored of Turkey.
- What'd you get?
- Turkey.
So it's happening. Today.
I'm gonna go surprise Brett
- at his weekly shuffleboard game.
- Wow.
That's so
rom-com of you.
Is there a way you can
make sure it's raining
when you run
to each other and kiss?
I know, but it'll
be exciting, you know?
He'll be like,
"whoa, Tina."
And I'll be like,
"hey, Brett, I missed you."
Only not in those words,
'cause I have dignity.
- Do I look okay?
- Yeah.
You look great.
Cute, sweet,
but willing
to do the weird stuff.
Thanks.
I'm a little nervous.
So what about you?
What's up with your gig?
I don't know much.
JB cast me in something.
It starts this afternoon,
I'd get $500 for it.
I'm trying to figure out
what I'd cast you as.
Young lesbian coming to terms
with her sexuality,
or corpse #2
in a zombie film.
Hey, I'm corpse
#1 material,
but I don't care what it is.
I got a job.
I'm so happy,
I could kiss JB
right on the tip
of the penis.
Welcome to day one of five,
my foodie thespians.
Now your job is
to hit the streets,
and  out
restaurant week flyers.
I want you bastards
to be friendly.
No one wants a flyer from a taco
acting like a turd.
Yeah, I'm talking
to you, Joan.
You got an attitude problem.
Adjust it.
Remember, you are responsible
for your own costumes.
Ruin them,
and I dock your pay.
Okay, big smiles.
Aren't you glad you decided
to blow off law school
and become an actor?
So, uh, have you
done this before?
Yep. A lot of us
work the flyering circuit
pretty regularly.
I've been a hammer,
a cell phone...
Once I was a tampon.
- Ew.
- It was okay.
It rained.
I absorbed it.
Hey, wanna bake
your cake later?
Makes the day fly by.
So I guess any guy
in a food costume will do,
- is that it?
- Don't talk to me, Jimmy.
Let's keep
this professional.
Come on, Brett.
Boom!
Nice shot.
Oh, sweet.
My old strobe light.
Now it's a party.
Sweet, a seizure party.
- Check out what I got.
- You...
Bought a bag
of severed hands?
They're vintage
and artistic.
The guy at the flea
says it's really trendy
to use them as bowls.
I guess we can use
these trendy hands
to hold my guacamole.
We're serving guacamole?
I was thinking more
- cheeses and crudite.
- Listen...
If we're putting out
your hands,
they're gonna
be holding my guac.
That sounded dirtier
than I meant it.
I'm gonna go shower.
Need a hand?
Check out
restaurant week.
restaurant week?
Check out
restaurant week.
Get a job, dude.
This is my job.
- Check out restaurant week.
- Thank you.
Jane.
Jason?
- Hey.
- Excuse me.
It's, uh...
It's good to see you.
You too.
So, um, what's
going on here?
I know what
you're thinking:
Why didn't I tell you
when we first met
that I was
an undercover cop?
[Laughing]
Nice disguise.
Easy, easy.
- You might blow my cover.
- Oh.
Are you on
a stake-out?
Trying to take down
a corrupt muffin?
Yeah, it's the tip of
a massive illegal pastry ring.
[Laughing]
Actually...
There's something I'd kind of
like to know, so...
That morning,
at my house, you...
Uh, you...
Hey, I got a coffee.
We should go
to the meeting.
Oh, Jason, this is
my coworker grant.
Oh, uh, sorry, hi.
I didn't realize you were
talking to a friend.
I've never met
a professional cake before.
Is this, like,
what you do?
Oh, no, no.
I don't do this...
I mean, right now, yes,
I do do this.
I've done other things.
I was an
assistant before.
Not that that's
necessarily higher
on the evolutionary
chart, uh...
I'm just sort of in a
transition phase, you know?
The recession and all
has sort of messed with
my five-year,
uh, plan, and...
This is, um...
This is, you know...
It's like a... temp thang.
Cool. So, uh...
We should probably
go to that meeting.
- We're gonna be late for the 5:30...
- Yes, right, shoot, um...
Sorry, I gotta run.
Bye, Jason.
Oh, okay.
Uh, bye... Jane.
What was up
with that?
I'm ready
to bake my cake now.
Damn it, Jay,
answer your phone.
What is wrong
with you?
Hey, your eyes
look sad.
Not red and squinty
from drugs sad,
but emotion sad.
Like I'm gonna
tell you my problems
so you can
call me a whore.
Come here.
I call this
forgetting juice.
Thanks.
For what?
Get it?
Forgetting juice.
[Chuckling]
Here, I've had enough.
Yeah, I want
more than enough.
I knew I'd
find you here.
I can't believe you brought
another guy to our spot.
Nothing's going on, Jimmy.
Not that it's any of your
business, because we're over.
Watch your ass, man.
God, I think
I smoked too much.
My heart's beating
like a hummingbird's.
Yeah, sometimes my brother
puts extra stuff in there.
Salvia, ketamine,
cat tranqs.
Our shift's almost over.
Come on.
A drink will
mellow you out.
Alcohol isn't helping.
I feel weirder.
Just roll with it.
I'm gonna go
to the bathroom.
I don'think
I can roll.
Geometrically impossible.
I had a Brett once.
Her name was Shyamala.
Our love was hot.
We used to do it everywhere.
Like sex rabbits.
And she told me
I was the one.
But I must have been
one of many
because I caught her
with my friend Johnny Gupta
up in her big bosom.
All up in them.
- Oh, that sucks.
- I know.
[Phone ringing]
Jay, finally.
Teen, I'm
really wasted,
and I saw Jane, who thinks
I'm a piece of crap
because I'm
a piece of cake.
Slow down.
You saw Jane?
What happened?
Well, I didn't
sweep her off her feet
to go live
under a rainbow.
- God, I am such an idiot.
- Just breathe.
Where are you?
E coaster says
windfall pub.
- So... windfall pub.
- Okay, I'm on my way.
Just drink a lot of water
and, uh, think happy thoughts.
Oh, and do not look
at your hands.
It freaks you out
when you're high.
Okay. Bye.
Ugh.
I've got to go.
Hey, how did you
get over Shyamala?
I give Johnny Gupta
food poisoning.
Really?
No, no,
I would never...
[Laughing]
- Thanks, Bobby.
- You're welcome, Tina.
I mean, whore friend
of Jason.
Okay, music is on,
guac's in the hands,
punch is out.
Can I just take
this entire lighting scheme
from boring...
To awesome?
Okay, this is... bad.
Like we have a secret room
where we cage humans
and harvest their skin bad.
Okay, don't panic.
We can still save this.
We'll just go back
to our regular lighting
and put the keg
in the hallway.
I was talking
about your creepy hands,
and I don't get it.
You don't even listen
to this enya-type stuff.
Sometimes I do.
- [Snickering]
- Okay, fine, I don't.
But what about you?
When we went
to my cousin's
birthday party
at Rutgers last month,
it was exactly like the party
you're trying to throw,
and you kept complaining
that you were too old for this.
Fine, listen,
you're right, but sometimes...
I just wanna show people
that we still know how to party.
I want to show people that
we've moved past just partying.
But I don't know
why I thought
that involved
punch and easy listening.
Look, we're gonna throw
tons of parties, all right?
So tonight, we'll show everyone
how mature we are.
And at our next party,
we'll prove to everyone
that we can
still throw down.
Sounds great.
But I'm in charge
of the music.
And no hands.
- The hands must go.
- Okay.
- Up top.
- Yeah.
You're dehydrated.
This'll make you feel better.
Yeah, well, maybe
this'll make you feel better.
No, thank you.
Sorry, I misread that.
Thought you
were feeling me.
You wanna just
thumb-wrestle instead?
Whoa, Jay, nice look.
Are you too depressed
for me to mock
the full Betty Crocker,
or can I go for it?
Tina.
Uh, pull it
together, Jay.
Man, I thought
I was messed up.
You saw Jane like this?
I don't wanna
talk about Jane.
This is corn, she's so nice.
I really like her,
which is weird,
'cause usually I hate corn.
You know
who I hate? Brett.
He was basically dry-humping
some shuffleboard slut
when I showed up.
It was brutal, Jay.
That's horrible.
Oh, my God, the world
is a horrible place.
This place is
a horrible place.
Let's get out of here and go
to Stacey and Eric's party.
- Aww.
- Hey, C, you wanna come?
Really? You still
wanna go to that?
The idea of being around
happy couples right now
makes me feel like
I wanna shave my head
and fashion my hair
into a noose.
Hey! Sully just told me
you kissed my girl.
You and me.
Outside. Now.
- Jimmy, no.
- Shut up.
Hey, don't talk
to her like that.
Mind your
business, bitch.
Hey, don't talk
to her like that.
Yeah, whose got your back?
Cake guy does.
[General gasps]
Jimmy.
- You're an animal.
- [Lascivious snicker]
- Jay, are you okay?
- Oh!
Ooh.
- [Whimpering]
- What hurts?
My wallet.
The costume's ruined,
JB's gonna make me
pay for it.
I can't pay for it,
not with money.
Okay, we should go
to Stacey and Eric's.
If anybody can get a stain
out of synthetic fabric,
it's Eric.
How much does
my party rock?
So much. I-I feel
like I'm on Jay-Z's yacht.
- I'm gonna go mingle.
- Mingle.
Uh, hey, lench.
- Great party, doctor.
- Thank you, sir.
So, uh, any single girls
here for me,
or anyone here
into the lifestyle?
- Uh, what... what lifestyle?
- You know.
Sharing and caring.
No rules, no hang-ups.
- I don't think so, lench.
- Come on.
We can talk
like men, man.
Don't make it weird just because
I used to date Stace.
In fact, we can talk
about that, if you want to.
I have stories.
Uh, yes, she told me the one
about the baby carrots.
She told you that?
Well, look, you think that
embarrasses me?
That doesn't embarrass me.
I'm proud of that.
There's, like,
five people on earth
that can peel a carrot that way.
[Doorbell ringing]
I gotta, uh, get this.
- Hey, uh...
- Where are your soaps?
Why are you a cake?
What the hell
is wrong with Jason?
Stacey, you look
really pretty.
I might kiss
your pretty little wife.
You know, Brett
kisses other girls,
so maybe I should
try it, right?
Ass-head hipster idiot.
Hey, punch!
Tina. I thought
I smelled sassy.
Lench, I will
cut out your retina
with the jagged lid from a can
of soup, I swear to God.
Relax, I'm just
being friendly.
Be friendly from at... at least
three feet away from me.
Tina, so you...
I'll catch up later.
Hands! Hands!
Stace!
[Laughter and murmurs]
Uh, I-I-I...
I couldn't get the stains
out of my costume
'cause of
the tub of hands.
Um...
I'm gonna
make a toast.
To Stacey and Eric.
You two have it
all figured out, I mean...
You're in love,
you know what you want.
How do you know?
I have no idea.
Uh, okay, uh, Jay,
I-I think that...
No, Eric, no.
See most of us, we don't
just get to figure it all out.
Get a cool job,
meet a girl who poops
chocolate ice cream.
Some of us are the losers
of our friends.
That's me, in case
you were wondering.
We think we're
corpse #1 material but...
Maybe we're only
cut out to be cake.
Point is...
The point is...
Tina you're... making me lose
my train of thought.
Somebody should
videotape this.
I mean, it's
just soft stuff,
but as kissing vids go,
this is golden.
More tongue.
Tina.
- Tina?
- Uh...
'Ugh. Advil.
My mouth
tastes like pennies.
Hey, you guys.
- Good morning.
- [Evil laugh]
Before you guys yell,
and you have every right
to be mad at us,
but maybe you could
just write, like, an email
with a lot of exclamation marks
instead, 'cause...
A loud noise
could kill me right now.
Did we totally
ruin your party?
Oh, doesn't matter.
Next one's an Eric party.
It'll more than
make up for it.
No, it's fine.
Half my law school friends
took undie pics of you,
and posted them
on... everywhere,
so everyone
still had a good time.
So, teen, lench
your boyfriend now?
If I wasn't
so hung-over,
I'd say something witty
about your manjamas, but...
I am, so I'm just
gonna go pee.
Ugh...
[Groans]
No!
Oh, good,
you're here.
Listen, I know we kind of
hooked up last night,
but I can't really be
in a relationship right now.
I respect you enough
to tell you...
Get out of here,
I have to pee.
Oh, I'm good.
It's cool, I won't look.
Ugh. Oh, God.
I might look.
Just being honest.
I respect you enough
to be honest with you
about looking
at you pee maybe...
If you...
It'd be... whoa!
Oh, who sent me
the sad stripper?
You know, you're supposed
to jump out of the cake,
- not carry it.
- I ruined the costume.
I'm sorry,
I will pay for it.
I don't know how.
I may be...
Sending you installments
from the lemonade stand I set up
outside my parents' place,
but somehow, I will pay.
I knew you'd come begging
for your job back.
Huh? No, no, no,
I'm not...
Because if
what you're doing,
if it counts as begging,
then yes, you can have
your job back.
Yes.
Yes, I am,
I'm begging
- for my job back.
- Then say please.
Say, "please, I beg you, JB,
sweet, merciful God of thunder."
Please?
All right.
Come to mama.
- [Chuckling]
- Oh.
So you...
You fired Roger.
No, he quit.
Something about
a hostile work environment.
Oh.
Welcome home, puppy dog.
Welcome home.
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.Addic7ed.com/