Telephone.
It's Comrade Malenkov.
Stalin knew one thing: Force.
During his reign,
20 million people lost their lives.
6 million were exiled,
18 million were shipped off to the Gulags.
Stalin...
he's to spend his evenings at the Bolshoi.
Or ironically, watching American Westerns
in his own private screening room.
Later, before he retired to bed,
he'd sign death warrants,
sometimes for up to 6,000 people.
And even then, even then,
he would write in the margins "not enough".
Make no mistakes.
During the years of terror
the witch-finding general was Stalin himself.
He said, "To choose one's victims,
to prepare one's plans minutely,"
"to slate an implacable vengeance,
and then go to bed."
"There is nothing sweeter in the world."
Who are these people?
What's their problem?
They called themselves "Aurora"
They are run by an old school
KGB hardliner called Vladimir Mamantov.
Yeah, he tried to man a coup
against Gorbachev.
Yeah, I interviewed him when
he came out of prison.
He still thinks the age of Stalin
is the golden era.
I apologize on behalf of [...].
Follow me to bus please.
Hey, Professor.
You think you know all
about Comrade Stalin.
Let me tell you,
you don't know shit.
Follow me to bus, please.
So here we are, with our degrees
and our double doctorates,
swirling around Moscow
confronting the past.
And the Russians don't want to hear about it,
you know,
because they're still
scared shitless of Stalin.
- Oh, come on.
- No, Fluke has a point.
Unlike Hitler, he was never exorcised.
They never had a Nuremberg, or Truth Commission,
like they did in South Africa.
Hooten's the new Czar.
This is his generation.
Mobile phones, martinis, and Hugo Boss.
[---] Stalin's into them.
Yeah, but who's the generation
that doesn't live out their mistakes?
Do you know what they're saying
to each other out there?
Josef would know how to deal with
these terrorists.
Let me see if
I can get a table.
You wanna go somewhere else
for dinner?
Why do they call you Fluke?
Because I was a mistake.
My mother had me
when she was 46.
Somebody said the name
summed up your career.
That just isn't nice, is it?
Italian or sushi?
You know... I think I'm just gonna
stick with the group.
Maybe another night?
I [---].
What do you want?
I want someone to hear the truth.
I was there the night
Stalin laid dead.
There I was driving Comrade Beria,
Chief of the Secret Police,
Stalin's head chief man.
We left the [---] with the key,
drove to the Kremlin,
straight to Stalin's private quarters.
Stay.
Why did Beria choose you?
Well, I was a new boy...
in the city.
A boy who would...
keep a secret.
What did he find?
He came from the room...
with a... folder.
A notebook inside.
Then I drove him to his house.
But why didn't Beria kill you?
I mean,
he'd killed thousands for less.
He was a... clever bastard.
But he made a mistake...
...thinking everyone else was stupid.
But 3 months later
they buried him.
So what happened to you?
They beat me, and other things...
...but I never break.
So then they sent me
to the Gulag.
I came out in '69.
The day the Yankees
put a man on the moon.
First... first thing hit me.
Where was Stalin?
No pictures, no statues.
There was disrespect.
Papu, if this book really exists,
it's a piece of history.
What use is history to me?
Well, history like this can sometimes
be worth a lot of money.
For you,
for you and your family.
I have no family.
Only slut daughter.
Who screws men like you
in clubs.
Well, she won't have to anymore
if this is worth what I think it is.
To Stalin.
I'm just...
Wait!
Tomorrow we must meet in lobby
by 11 sharp.
No one must be late, please.
For bus. [---]
Oh, my God,
what happened to you?
Research.
What was his name?
Was an old man. He had a story to tell.
Sounds like a setup.
Yeah, why would he run out on me?
Because he doesn't want it
to look like a setup.
Wants you to track him down.
Persuade him.
That's the psychology of a clutter fraud.
Remember the Hitler diary?
I think he's for real.
'Quod volimus credimus libenter'
Which means?
Yeah, I know what it means.
We always believe what we want to believe.
Thank you, Adelman.
You don't want to hear that, do you?
You want him to lead you to
Stalin's unpublished memoirs.
You'll make millions of dollars, rewrite history,
and a choir would sing you praises at Harvard Yard.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have coffee and tea in the annex.
Gentlemen, R.J. O'Brian,
Moscow correspondent of SNS.
How are you doing?
In a full month,
we have boring people in a boring conference.
You're Dr. Kelso, right?
I read your last book.
What was it? 3 years ago?
4.
Actually, I believe it was 5.
If we are gonna nitpick, it was 6.
Why don't you took turns, Frank,
you would know something to say.
- It is out of date.
- Yes I know. Is it possible that I can renew it?
I'm a professor.
I'm writing a book.
Fill in form.
Send the mail.
Yeah, but I'm leaving Moscow tomorrow.
Can you help me please?
I will talk to supervisor.
Are you the Kelso who wrote the book
on fall of the Communist Party?
Ah... yes!
Yes I guess I am.
- Great work! You really [---] the bastards!
- Thank you.
- You are?
- [---] Elena [---].
I need everything you've got
on the death of Stalin, Elena.
- Statements, eyewitness accounts, please...
- She will not approve this.
Does she have to know?
Thank you.
"Vladimir Mamantov"
I found another one.
Page 512.
Thank you.
So umm... you went to
Moscow State University?
I did, yes.
I spent a lot of time in this library
with a girlfriend. It was warm.
Is this your address?
No. It is where Beria lived.
You know they found
the human remains in the basement... bones.
He's a very busy man.
Ah... I wrote an article on him a few years ago.
I'm Dr. Kelso.
I have something
very important to tell him.
Hmm... I remember you.
You wrote shit about me.
About what?
About a notebook...
belonging to Josef Stalin.
You better come.
Turn around.
Hands up.
What is it?
Take it out.
It's just... I use it for making notes.
I wasn't... gonna...
- Thank you.
- Go in.
So you are part of
the gathering of thieves.
Ah... I want a story,
I'm... I'm not a thief.
Imagine if your country sold its
national archive
for a few miserable dollars.
Viktor!
The same sickness Reagan had.
I... I'm sorry.
Ah... keep your pity.
So... Stalin's notebook.
Sounds like bullshit.
No. It was mentioned in
Volkogonov's biography.
His source was Aleksei Yepichev.
A man you knew well.
You wrote his entry in
the Book of Heroes.
Yes, I was with him at the end,
when Gorbachev came to power.
A good time for
a decent communist to die.
Did he ever mention that book?
Who told you about this?
An eyewitness...
from that time?
Yes.
Name?
No, I rather not give it to you.
So why are you here?
I want to find out
whether it's true or not.
(Chuckles) If it exists, it belongs in Russia,
not in some Californian University.
We're talking about a great man.
I'm sorry.
I don't share your admiration.
Really? I think you do.
When you saw his portrait,
you almost salivated.
Stalin inherited the nation
with wooden ploughs,
and left us an empire
armed with atomic weapons.
The man who came after him
pissed away...
He saw it coming.
He told them, "After I've gone...
...the capitalists will drown you,
like blind kittens."
You'd like him back,
wouldn't you?
Hello!
Maggie, it's Fluke.
Look, I'm not getting back on Friday.
I'm gonna stay in Moscow,
something's come up.
So ah... tell the boys I love them,
and that I will make it up to them.
- You know this place?
- It's a club.
Disco. Many girls.
Thank you.
Winston Churchill once described Russia
as a...
...riddle, wrapped up in a mystery, inside an enigma.
Well I like to feel that the last few days
we've solved the riddle,
and unravelled the mystery,
and we're left with the enigma,
which, I believe is the...
It's kinda a last night thing.
I didn't think you liked me.
I don't like your type.
And what type is that?
Wonder boy. You said you're
used to dazzling people.
You think the talent and looks
are your God given rights.
Well, it's a long time since
I've dazzled anybody.
I just want to get laid
before I go back to Princeton.
OK.
Meet me by the lift.
After you.
Look, just hold this a second,
would you?
I'm sorry about that.
You total shit!
Hi, I'm looking for someone,
Rapava, works here.
I'll ask. What are you drinking?
[---], no ice.
Bribing bartenders, smart.
Get served first, impress the ladies.
Remember me? Met you this morning.
R.J. O'Brian. How you're doing?
- You're alone?
- Yeah.
You won't be for long.
The good ones ask for $400,
offer 2, settle on 3,
but be careful of the real babe,
they maybe spoken for.
The other guy's Russian,
walk away.
- I'm not looking.
- Oh, come on, everyone's looking.
Here... these girls have class, OK?
Tell the Professor what you do for a living.
[---] Scandinavian businesses.
See that.
You see that girl,
Masha over there, red hair.
Works for the Moscow Currency Exchange.
Where's Alisa?
She's a radiologist.
- She was shot, R.J.
- Seriously?
Oh, Moscow may have its maximus, but is still dark city.
Though, I bet you're just
more interested in the old days, eh?
I heard you're chasing down a story.
Ghosts from the past.
Who told you that?
- Adelman. Said you're really juiced.
- It's a dead end.
The bartender said you asked for me.
Ah... you're Rapava.
Looks like you're covered, Professor.
We'll talk soon.
So how do you hear about me?
It doesn't matter.
- 400.
- 2.
- 3.
- OK.
Ah... my name's Fluke Kelso,
what's yours?
What name do you like?
What's your wife's name?
I don't... actually have one
at the moment.
- OK. What's your hotel?
- Ukraina.
- What a dump...
- Look, actually, I don't want to sleep with you.
Although that would be a...
very attractive proposition.
but I need something else
from you.
Whatever you want,
it's still 300.
I need to find your father Papu.
Look, just take me to where he is.
Please, I... I'll still give you the money.
Please.
- 400.
- Fine. Great. Thank you.
You're studying law!
- Money.
- What?
Money.
Half now, and then half later, yes?
I can get another fuck, Mister.
Can you get another ride?
Block #9, Apartment 12, 5th Floor,
the door code is 3131.
You not gonna come up with me?
He doesn't like the way I dress.
- Will you wait?
- If you want.
3131.
Bitch!
Hello?
Please empty pockets.
- What?
- Everything, passport, wallet, tie.
Look, I have given my statement.
I'm a witness, I'm not a suspect.
I'll give you a receipt.
OK, right, I wanna call the embassy.
I wanna know my rights.
Shoelaces.
- Mr. Kelso?
- What?
I'll give you a ride.
Your plane, leave Sheremetyevo at 1:30.
And you'll be on it.
You know what, this is outrageous.
I report a dead body,
I'm mobbed while I'm calling the police.
I didn't kill the old man.
Oh, but you did.
When you told Mamantov
you had a witness from the old times.
That was his death sentence.
I didn't give a name.
He didn't need a name.
He already knew it.
I didn't.
I have to dig for the old KGB files.
And what did you find?
I found Papu Gerasimovich Rapava.
20 years after
he came out the Gulags,
they arrested him again.
And he was questioned by
the head of the Directorate,
Vladimir Pavlovici Mamantov.
You see now...
He precisely knew
who you were talking about.
There were no other witnesses
from the old times.
They're all dead.
So you bugged Mamantov's apartment?
Yes, we bugged Mamantov's apartment.
We'd like to know what he did
with 500 million rubles.
This we found out from the KGB files.
Yeah! But this is murder,
why didn't you bring him in?
Professor, why don't you
go back home?
Play your game of history
in your own country.
What, so you can find Stalin's files
and bury them?
Mr. Kelso, I'm totally sick of
people like you.
Throwing the past in our faces.
And I'm sick of people like Mamantov,
trying to make gods out of monsters.
I'll take you back to your hotel.
Listen... the old man,
he didn't break in '53,
or in the Gulag,
or later when they hold him in.
What if he didn't break last night?
So what's your point?
I want to talk to his daughter.
Maybe you should get to her first.
Rough night, Professor?
I've had worse.
Well, when I saw you leave
the Ju Ju Club with that lovely Zinaida...
That wasn't her name,
I didn't catch it.
Well tell me, did you get any action
before you got arrested?
How the bloody hell
did you know that?
Professor, when a high profile westerner
ends up in a cell,
I get a call and somebody gets [---].
Look, you made Page 3.
"Body found in bath of blood"
Don't worry, you weren't mentioned.
Cops give you a hard time?
I was sprung.
Excuse me.
And a wank calls, wearing a cashmere coat,
hand made shoes.
It's Intelligence. FSB.
So, did he want to know about
Stalin's notebook?
Adelman told me.
Adelman's a prick.
I'll tell you how much
of a prick he is.
The guy tried to rope me in.
He says I find the book, we go 50-50
and leave you out of the loop.
You academics! One sniff of a scoop
and you make the paparazzi look like
a bunch of choir boys!
It doesn't make any difference.
I'm being deported.
I'm not.
Give me what you got.
It's dead.
Died with the old man.
Oh Geez! Today customs wish
to open every bag.
Oh, this is not good!
I bought an icon!
You worry, Fluke?
Got the Stalin diaries
tugged in your underwear?
Have you told everyone?
Well, in all honesty,
I didn't take it too seriously.
You know what, Frank.
Screw you!
How did you find me?
I went to your hotel,
they said that you've checked out.
Look, um... I've got to
get on a plane to New York.
I'd love to help you,
but I... I don't know how.
I don't ask favours,
I never ask favours.
So why are you here?
When I got home last night,
there was a note from my father.
It says there is something valuable,
and you can tell me what it is.
In a tool box.
Look, come here.
Mr. Kelso!
When did you last see your father?
3 days ago.
Before that, 8 years.
He came to the club, he saw my dress,
and called me a whore.
I don't think he wait 8 years
just to tell you that.
I don't care.
I don't want him in my life.
He has always been a bastard.
Why would he change now?
Zinaida, your father is dead.
We should go.
Who killed him?
They think a man called
Vladimir Mamantov.
He knew your father
from the old time.
What was in my life
that old time?
Here.
That you?
I'm surprised he kept it.
I don't actually know
what I'm looking for.
It's underneath you.
Hold that.
What is it?
You know about guns?
It was my father's.
In Makarov, when I were little
he told us how to
strip, clean, and fire it.
Hey! Hey! Wo!
Put your hands on your head!
Hey!
Ah, Professor, can you do me a favour
and just ask her to put that thing down.
What the hell are you doing here?
Look, I was curious to see
if you got on that plane.
And you didn't!
And... OK...
Now she's starting to freak me out.
Put it down.
Wait, I know you from the clubs.
You're Zinaida, right?
You...
Why is she here?
She's Papu Rapava's daughter.
So what are you guys doing?
Making some home improvements?
What's that got something
to do with that?
You'd never gonna shake my ass
off of this.
I'm a pitbull, Professor,
so we may as well partner up.
You two can split
whatever loot you make.
Is it valuable?
If it's what the Professor
thinks it is,
it could be worth
half a million, yeah.
Dollars?
That's right.
Let's open it up.
Wait, I want to capture
this moment.
- You don't drive a BMW?
- No, it's not my style.
We were followed by a 7-series.
7-Series?
Sounds like a Mafia car.
Or a cop on the take.
- Jesus, you live in here.
- I didn't beg, dad.
Look, you do this,
as long as you keep her name out of it.
And you don't show any of this footage until
we get that thing properly forensically analyzed.
Anything else, Professor?
Yeah, you can stop calling me Professor.
- Can I call you Doc?
- No.
What is it?
Well...
It's embossed with the seal of
the Soviet Union,
which would suggest
it's something official.
Well, it's not Stalin's writing.
What are you talking about?
It written about Stalin...
but it's... it's not his writing.
Oh great,
press just take a nosedive.
Console Unit #2 display their paces.
We marched across Red Square,
and as we pass beneath him,
his glance fall upon us,
like the rays of the sun.
It's the writing of a young girl.
I remember the day the comarde
from Moscow came to visit,
the leader of the local party
met him at the station.
He had the biggest car in Archangel.
The comrade explained,
that since the parade in Moscow,
I had been selected for special task
relating to high party leadership.
If I accept,
I must return to Moscow with him.
And stay there for a year.
My father says,
if it is the will of the party,
he will not prevent me.
I'm so happy
I could die.
We went south through the forest...
...Konosha, Vologda, Yaroslav.
Last time there were 20 of us,
silly laughing girls.
Now there was only me.
I'm a little afraid, so far from home.
I will take care of this.
That's alright.
She's been covered.
Let's get out of here!
Go to my office.
Comrade Stalin has asked that from now on
I'm to bring him breakfast.
[---] till he falls asleep,
wherever he finds himself.
How I wish that people could
see him like this;
so humble, so dedicated to their welfare.
That's great!
What's the date of the entry?
It's 21st of October.
She got there on the 12th, I mean...
she's been there for... what... 8 days.
And he still hasn't jumped her.
When I leave the room
I hear him cursing.
He has cut himself.
That's it?
That's all?
See for yourself.
The last pages have been torn out.
Oh shit.
What are all these doodles?
Look, it looks like a wolf's head.
Stalin used to draw the heads of wolves
in the margins of official documents.
So this is genuine?
Un... until I have it forensically tested,
I just... I just can't say.
Bottom line, Doc,
I hold you up against a brick wall
with a gun, what's your opinion?
It's genuine.
Good.
What about all these other stuff?
Hey, look, be careful!
It an NKVD report.
It's their family's medical history.
Teeth... blood group...
no genetic disorders...
The old bastard only screws
prom queens?
Why would he keep her diary?
Obsession, infatuation.
On the train she says that that was
the worst day to travel because it was that time.
Meaning what?
She had had period.
And last night when
he called her to his room,
it was 10 days later.
- She was fertile!
- That's it.
That's what the medical report is about.
He was looking for
the perfect mother for his child.
You know what we gonna do,
we gonna find this girl.
Find her?
She'd be dead.
Oh you can't be sure.
She'd only be about... what... 70.
Yeah, but that's not the point.
She wouldn't have died of old age.
Who do you think we're dealing with here,
Prince Charming?
Maybe, but this is a huge story.
We gonna run this down.
We gonna go to Archangel.
I... I can't go to any airport.
Look... we'll head straight up the M-8,
it's about 7, 8 hundred miles.
We'll take the war wagon.
A flask of coffee, a few uppers,
a stack of CDs... loving it... Louise...
I'm not going anywhere.
Oh, no.
You have to.
If you stay in Moscow,
they'll find you and they'll kill you.
For what? For this?
Your father died because
he wouldn't tell them where it was.
Because he wanted you to have it.
Not worth die for.
Stubborn old fool!
He died because he wanted to
leave you something of value
so that you can get out,
so you can stop being a...
A whore?
Like you and O'Brian.
Look, um... he's a hack!
He not going to sell this,
we have to ditch him.
Is that what he said is the truth?
It's worth a lot of money?
Yeah, a lot of money.
You supposed to be in
St. Petersburg tomorrow.
We've rescheduled this twice already.
Why don't we just dump it?
I'll talk to the chief.
We're gonna get some warm clothes.
OK, but...
let's try and leave before dark.
Where about is your place from here?
North. 20 minutes.
Good.
We'll get your stuff and keep going.
Although we're not going to
get very far on this.
No need.
Here's O'Brian's.
- We steal?
- We steal.
What did she say?
She says there's someone in there.
Right, well, let's go.
We'll buy some clothes on the way.
There's something I need.
Do you know him?
Of course not.
Let's go.
I told you
there is something that I need.
What are you thinking?
How many men I slept with
to get this cash?
No. Just wondering how you
find the time to study law.
Archangel.
Founded by Peter the Great,
named after the Archangel Michael,
the "Warrior Angel."
Until the fall of communism,
it was a forbidden city closed to
all outside visitors.
They had nuclear subs there.
They leaked.
Why are we slowing down?
The car behind us.
It's the Militia.
Shit.
O'Brian didn't waste much time, did he?
It's OK.
They're not interested in us.
Ah... I don't know if I can
handle Rock & Rap for 500 miles.
The whole area was used for
nuclear weapons.
Oh, listen to this,
travellers' tip.
When arriving at the railway station,
check the digital radiation meter.
If it is 15 microrads or below, it's safe.
Sounds like a fun place!
2-and-a-half thousand dollars.
Was that round trip?
One way!
When can he leave?
10.
Tell him he's got a deal.
OK, he'll be there at 9.
Yes. Yes, of course, cash, yep.
R.J., I think you're crazy!
Weather's bad, it's getting worse.
Yeah, that's why I have to leave tomorrow,
or I'll never get in.
What do I tell head office?
You're going off radar leaving them
with a $2,500 tap for a charter.
I give them a taste.
Book me some satellite time.
Very sheik!
Well there's not much call
for Versace out here.
And I don't think we will
find a sushi bar either.
These small towns are forgotten.
The old die, the young leave.
And you leave Moscow and you realize
Moscow is a treasure.
You smoke too much.
- I know.
- How old are you anyway?
- 27.
- You?
Older.
I prefer to go with older men.
Safer...
...and less exhausting.
Ever pay for it, Fluke?
Once.
When I was 16.
I needed to lose my virginity.
It was weighing me down.
You should do that more often.
- What?
- Laugh.
Come on.
We've got a long way to go.
The victim was later identified as
Papu Gherasimovici Rapava.
A 73 year old survivor
of the Gulag
...the whereabouts of a secret diary
belonging to Josef Stalin,
and this knowledge
may have cost him his life.
R.J. O'Brian, SNS News, Moscow.
'cuse me,
can you tell me where the pilot is?
God!
The plane is older than me!
So fuck it!
Are you the pilot?
- Mr. O'Brian?
- R.J.
- Lev.
- Ready to go?
Mmm...
Right.
- Here you are.
- Thank you. Let's go.
You know what
the weather's like in Archangel?
- I risk it if you will.
- Shouldn't we have a navigator, or somebody?
- No, afraid not.
- Ah ha, that's great! Ah! Just terrific!
Take a seat. [---] it's First Class.
Hey! Hey!
- Hmm?
- Road block ahead.
And my visa's run out.
I'll handle it.
How'd you manage that?
I gave him a month's wages.
Wait!
OK.
Nicer foulups.
Eat, it's not bad.
The party,
[---] an office, won't they?
We should check their records.
To find out about this girl
is very important for you, yeah?
More important than anything,
I guess.
- Yeah.
- For me, history is dead.
It tells us what happened,
not what happens next.
That is what I care about.
Well, that's wrong.
You think because Russia has MTV and
MacDonald's and accepts American Express...
...that it's just the same as
everywhere else.
Well, that's bullshit. Because you won't
understand Russia until you understand its past.
Thank you for the lecture, Professor.
Just tell her that we've travelled
an awfully long way. We're very discreet.
And we... we just need to see
some records of Party members.
Why would you be interested in
someone from this remote place?
I'm researching a book.
On what subject?
On the residual power of the Communist Party
in rural Russia.
Excellent subject.
Wilfully ignoring the West.
Take our situation here.
We have people who have got rich, millions.
We also have organized crime, unemployment,
AIDS, prostitution and drug addiction.
Such progress!
Not like in the good old days, eh?
We had work, we had pride,
now we have free markets and rich [---].
I see you've read
comrade Mamantov.
I was with him 2 days ago in Moscow.
It's incredible,
they haven't thrown anything away.
Like they're waiting for
the second coming.
Most curious, the [---] from 1950 and 51.
Anna's here.
They were transferred to
the Central Committee in Moscow.
On whose authority?
General Poskrebyshev.
Comrade Stalin's private secretary.
I'm impressed.
Dead end?
The Party file is listed
Mihail and Varvara Safanov.
The parents.
When did they die?
Mihail died in 1988.
They wouldn't pay her Party [---]
She's still alive!
Maybe it was just a routine check.
Maybe they haven't connected us with the car.
Maybe it too many maybe's.
- Oh, Jesus.
- How did you get the scratch on my bumper, Professor?
How the hell did you get here?
It wasn't easy,
you son of a bitch!
Get in, we can't stay here.
Why'd you cut me
out of the loop, ah?
All I wanted was the story,
you get the rest.
- Book deal, lecture tours, ...
- Get in!
Did you find Anna?
- We found her mother.
- Oh, you got to be kidding!
So, where is Mr. O'Brian now?
He had to charter a plane because
those guys stole his jeep;
which really pissed him off
because he's married to that thing.
So, your boss is following them?
Where?
North.
Archangel.
Archangel?
Why?
Because that's where the girl lived.
What girl?
Yeah, yeah. I got to go, Todd.
Alright, I'll catch up with you later.
- Who's Todd?
- Have you ever used one of these?
- Who is Todd?
- Wanna to call your girlfriend?
Ah, Todd...
Todd is a guy in the newsroom.
And what were you asking him?
Just asking him about the World Series.
I got some money on it.
O'Brian, how did you hook up
with this at the lockup?
OK, I got a tip that
you were at the morgue.
From who?
No idea.
It was a voice on the phone.
Well, keep a lid on this
until the time is right.
That was the deal.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You got it.
No problem.
She seemed to have
opened up to you.
Perhaps too much.
She must have been told
never to speak of these things.
Dear, a long time ago.
People in Russia don't lose
their fear because they get old.
Maybe she's holding all these.
Maybe once we leave,
she makes a call.
Maybe you should stay here tomorrow
and make sure she doesn't.
Why me?
Let O'Brian stay.
Well, if I do that,
he's just going to call the office.
At least this way I can
keep an eye on him.
We'll be back by nightfall.
OK.
But you should know something else
that she'd told me.
Her husband wanted to
meet his grandson.
He took off the same way
that you are taking.
He never came back.
They killed her, didn't they?
After the baby was born?
Yeah.
Yeah, they did.
Look I'm... I'm gonna go in now.
It'll be a long drive tomorrow.
Is this road on the map?
Only on a dotted line.
What's that up there?
Married couple.
Soldiers.
It's incredible.
A whole colony of people posted down here
in the widlerness to look after one life.
Hang... hang on.
Hold it... hold it.
Oh, my God!
Oh!
- You alright?
- Yeah.
Like somebody's uh...
somebody's build a tank trap!
I'm never gonna get out of this thing!
Isn't that the point?
No sweat. We got the phone,
we got food, we got water.
Hey, hey, we got company.
Umm, I think we may have
taken a wrong turn.
Uh, our map is out of date.
If... if you can just help us get out,
we... we can get back to the main drag.
You are the ones, I think.
You believe you know
who I am?
Yes?
You want proof?
No. No, no.
No, we don't need proof.
We trust you.
Imperialists!
All those sweet words!
And then they kill you for a [---]
Come.
Come!
Well...
we found him.
OK, we got 2 of us and 1 of him.
You think you can get that rifle off him?
Don't even think about it.
Suvorin.
Order of the Hero of the Soviet Union.
What was that all about?
He said his time is coming.
What's that mean?
It... it means we were expected.
Well, looks like we're not the first
people to have come here.
These people came here?
Yes.
They say they're tourists.
What are they looking for?
Wolves?
No. They were surprised.
I have their confessions here.
They denied it first.
But admitted it all by then.
These look like bloodstains.
Think we have to make confessions?
Capitalism is thievery.
We protect ourselves from these capitalists,
these stinking,
crawling thieves of all mankind,
only by ferocious vigilance.
Tell me about the Chizhikov's, comrade.
He brought you up like
you were their child.
He was a soldier and a hunter.
When he drank, he beat me.
Comrade, until I'm in blood.
How did he die?
He was so drunk,
he fell into one of his own traps.
[---] death.
And his wife? She must have been
like a mother to you.
She was.
When she was old, she couldn't work.
It was a hard thing to do.
But for the best.
Would... would you like to see a picture
of your real mother?
I have one here.
I have pictures of my father,
that is all I need.
My father used to make
his comrades dance.
Dance for me!
Dance!
Ah! Jesus!
Ah!
Hey! wake up! wake up!
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
I don't know if he gonna
make us breakfast or kill us.
You know I'll be a lot happier
if somebody in this world knew where we are.
Guess we're not prisoners.
We're meant to be here.
Too many coincidences.
Ah, what do you mean?
You got a tip,
a voice on the phone.
That the Beria mansion has literally
a door left wide open for me.
The old man at Communist HQ,
he dust off all his old files 'cause I give him
some bullshit story about writing a book.
Mamantov is behind this.
OK, I've got a blinding hangover.
What are you saying?
His whole... platform is based upon a
"Return to Stalinlism"
And what do you think the dispossessed
and disaffected is gonna do
when he wheels out
the New Messiah?
No one is going to give a shit,
the guy looks like Davy E. Crock...
He's Stalin's son.
That man's father is responsible for
more deaths than
Adolf Hitler, Pol Pot, and
Genghis Khan combined.
And that is a conservative estimate.
30 million Russians think
that man's dad did a good job.
Ah shit!
There's just too many trees.
This far north you gonna have the dish
at really lower angle to send a signal.
We need more space.
You know, I think we gonna need
an escape route.
Maybe you want to...
go down there and see if there's a boat,
or a canoe of some kind.
All right.
Watch your step.
He's got traps, remember?
There you go, R.J.
Alright, you should be getting
the unedited material now.
Then I'll do an actual intro, OK?
I'll talk to you in 5.
Here in the northern tundra of Russia,
a story is unfolding which will shake the world.
For 50 years,
this forbidden wilderness
has hidden a secret,
known only to a handful of
fanatical, hardlined communists
faithful to the memory of Josef Stalin.
What the hell are you doing?
You can't put that out there.
That's what they want.
You heard what the old log chopper said, huh,
"His time is coming!"
Any minute he going to
polish his boots and march into town.
Turn that camera off.
Now, look, look, this is my story, Doc.
And your book.
Well I not gonna write it.
Nah, just, come on...
Press! Press!
You should have gotten on
that plane, Professor.
Where is he,
the man you came to see?
He was here when we left.
Look, I.. I would just want to say
that I am a acredited journalist, OK?
And my bureau does know that
I am here, alright?
Then they'll wonder
what happend to you.
Run!
- You OK?
- No! My shin! my shin!
Hello...
Hello, can you...
Da. I'm afraid he is.
- Where is O'Brian?
- He's dead.
What?
There were soldiers.
Then how safe are we now?
I don't have anybody left alive to report back.
So that's just give us a couple of hours.
Did Mamantov send them?
No, the Kremlin.
Mamantov wants me alive.
- Is it him?
- Yes.
So what does it mean?
It means that poor old O'Brian
let the genie out of the bottle.
Come on!
Where is the rest?
I got you out of jail.
This is yours.
Explain to me why did Mamantov
want you to find this?
This has no credibilty
if it is suddenly produced by
an old school hardliner like Mamantov.
It stings of forgery
and self interest.
And me, I'm a Western academic.
I'm a published author.
And... and I... I'm an objective...
expert on all things Stalin.
And my father was a part of this?
Yeah.
So why did he die?
He didn't... follow the script.
When I told him
how valuable this was, he...
...he only wanted to leave it to you.
I tell you it's cursed.
It's yours.
It's ours.
When we get to Moscow,
we go straight to the American Embassy,
and we'll get out of Russia.
We?
Come with me,
to New York.
Nice fantasy.
You awake?
The only time I ever
connected with my father
was when he taught me
how to use a gun.
He hardly spoke
to my brother and me.
He could not touch us.
Never hold us.
He was brutalised.
Many of us were.
I was...
too young to understand.
My mama always did.
Even his silences.
Or his drunken rages.
She'd always shown compassion.
She understood what
they've made him.
Dr. Kelso, come please,
and...uh, bring it.
Come on, please!
You... would destory this?
You are historian.
You have this burning urge to
preserve every historical document.
This for you, is the way back,
better than your wildest dreams.
Getting famous all over again.
You go on television, lecture college campuses.
Screw many girls.
It's your way back!
That's the problem.
No. It is all mutual benefit,
this whole plan.
Good plan.
I used KGB funds
to buy Beria's mansion.
I financed conferences
you speak at.
First class tickets, free vodka,
how could you resist?
Tortoruing and killing old man,
was that part of the plan?
And what about those psychopaths
running around in the woods?
A glitch. But everything turned out good
for both of us, huh?
Win, win. Yes?
Well let's see.
You got a mad man on the loose.
And maybe suffering from a
major congenital defect.
You think you can control him?
If he's his father's son,
which I truly believe he is.
You could be one of his first victims.
Maybe he's right, comrade.
Maybe I play gramophone,
and make you dance.
We're stopping at the next station.
- Where are we?
- Vologda.
- They let you go?
- Mamantov's on the train, with Josef.
My God!
Jesus Christ!
It's already started.
Listen, get off this train now.
Pay someone to drive you to Moscow.
Go to the airport and get on a plane.
- To go where?
- Anywhere.
Huh, and where are you going?
To do what they want.
Hey, what's going on?
Have you seen R.J.?
- R.J. is dead.
- What?
- Can you put that on me?
- Yeah.
Film this guy.
I am Professor Christopher Kelso.
This...
This whole spectacle has been contrived
and stage managed by a man whose
only goal is absolute power through torture and...