Episode 20
In order to cure my daughter Laobusi's illness, I concocted eight herbal tablets.
I never thought you would steal them and eat them!
Your daughter's name is Laobusi (never-die)?
She will never die, even when she's old!
Isn't it a lucky name?
Can't you even comprehend that?
Sorry,
I didn't know those pills were for your daughter.
How about this? You can get the famous Dr. Ping to cure your daughter's illness.
I don't need you to tell me that.
I know that better than you!
So that Ping Yizhi would cure my daughter's illness,
I ran to his home and killed 5 people!
Only then, Ping Yizhi had no choice but to help diagnose my daughter.
He found that my daughter has had this illness since she was in the womb.
So, he gave me a prescription for the eight herbal life-extending tablets.
Otherwise, how would I know how to make pills?!
You killed five people in his family, and he still helped you?
Why are you so stupid?
Do I have to spell it out for you?!
Ping Yizhi doesn't have many enemies.
His patients have already killed off most of them for him.
Do you know who Ping Yizhi hates the most in his life?
His mother-in-law.
But Ping Yizhi is scared of his wife
and couldn't do it himself.
So I killed his mother-in-law
for him.
Afterwards, Ping Yizhi was super happy
and agreed to help treat my daughter's illness.
So that's what happened.
No matter what is said, you've already drank my medicine so now I'm in a desperate siuation
Since you just drank the medicine, it's still in your blood.
Drinking your blood is just the same.
Father, who is that person?
He's not a person.
He's your medicine!
Medicine?
Right.
Father's eight herbal life-extending tablets are extremely potent.
He drank the tablets, so we're going to take his blood.
Don't, father.
Why not?
Father, he's a person. It will really hurt him.
No, he's not a person.
He's your medicine.
He won't hurt.
Father, don't.
Did you know, daughter? For you, for your illness, for an early cure to your illness,
do you know how I've spent the past decade?
The eight herbal tablets
are the result of my painstaking efforts!
Father
No matter what, even if this is wrong, I have to do it!
- No, don't, father!- Be quiet!
You will get better.
Don't, don't, father.
My daughter,
even if this is wrong, Father must do this.
Kid, to save my daughter, I will take your blood to treat her. Are you afraid?
If you want to kill me or slice me, then do it! Cut the crap!
Good, a tough guy.
Don't, don't father.
Even if I'm wrong, I don't care!
Stop!
Zu Qianqiu?
You have the face to show up here?
You can't hurt Linghu.
If I don't take his blood, my daughter has no hope!
Old man, listen to me.
Speak.
Mr. Linghu, I am muddleheaded.
If Heavens didn't have eyes and send Zu Qianqiu here,
even if I died 1,000 times or 10,000 times, it wouldn't atone for my crime.
You...
What are you guys up to?
I was really too muddleheaded.
I didn't know you were such close friends with our savior.
If I had known, I wouldn't dare take a single drop of your blood
to cure my daughter.
Old man, really.
Fortunately this Mr. Linghu is the bigger person.
But I really hope your tablets will benefit his health.
Then you would have done a meritorious deed.
Your deed is greater than mine.
Ok ok I know I'm wrong.
I shouldn't have stolen your eight herbal tablets.
But, look.
I found lots of ginseng at the nearby pharmacy.
Caterpillar fungus, reishi mushrooms, and more. I think you will find them useful.
Better than nothing.
You two are known as the "Yellow River Ancestors", right?Yes
Although you have good intentions to treat my injuries,
but you lied to me!
Then you acted recklessly!
Hero Linghu is indeed righteous and noble
Thanks, it's nothing
Actually, you can have my forgiveness.
But I have a question
which you must answer truthfully.
Of course, of course.
Please ask your question.
Who exactly ordered you to give me this royal treatment?
You really don't know?
How would I know?
Mr. Linghu, you don't know...?
Then we can't say anymore.
No we can't.
Really, even if you killed us, we wouldn't dare say.
Is that so? Then pardon my offense.
What are you going to do?
Don't be like this!
- I'll be like this if I want to!- And I thought Linghu Chong was a gentleman!
I never thought he would force himself on girls!
Yue Buqun, do something about your disciple! Yue Buqun!
I'm telling you, don't move!
If you move around, I might kill you with my blade.
No...no...!
- Don't force me!- Yue Buqun, what is your disciple doing over there?
That girl...is he forcing her to marry him?
Rather than her, why doesn't he marry me?
Miss, what a coincidence! We meet again!
Looks like you're in a great mood.
Ugly freak of nature!
...Handsome man, I came here looking for you.
But I got caught in a trap. Hurry, help me down!
You just called me ugly freak of nature.
If I were to let you down then wouldn't that mean I'm easy?
I'm not letting you down.
No,
to hit and scold means you love someone.
I only said that because I like you.
What did you say?
- No no no, the line before- To hit and scold means love
To hit and scold means love.
Then I really want to express my love for you!
Is that expression of love enough?
Let me down!
That woman out there...
Who did this?
- Linghu...- Father!
Your precious daughter!
Don't, don't look!
If you don't want to humiliate me, then stay out of this!
- Old man!- Father!
- Daughter! - Stay calm!
This...
Here, be careful with your wound.
- Daughter...- Father, he lost a lot of blood.
He already forced me to drink two bowls of his blood.
He was going to make me drink more.
Mr. Linghu!
Old man has nothing to repay you with!
Ok ok stop crying.
Let's help him outside.
Here, slowly.
Is it Chief Yue of Huashan Sect who has arrived?
Please show yourself.
Yue Buqun, someone's looking for you! Come out!
Mr. Yue, your disciple Linghu Chong is seriously wounded. Please come with me inside to rescue and treat him.
May I please ask for your name.
I am Ji Wu Shi.
So you are the night owl Ji Wu Shi.
That's right.
Mr. Yue, saving his life is critical. Inside please.
Hey, handsome man, come over! Come over quick!
Quickly!
Let me ask you, how did Linghu Chong get wounded so bad?
Just now, didn't you say you only liked me?
How can you start asking about another man's injuries so soon?
Are you a slut?
No no. That Linghu Chong owes me a lot of money.
I just want him to be healthy, so he can pay me back.
Then I can marry you.
Really?
You're adorable!
I really want to express my love for you again!
Hey, what are you going to do?
I already said, I want to love you again.
Chief Yue, please.
Ji Wu Shi, let me down!
Mr. Linghu
Surely enough, Huashan Sect's Violet Mist Divine Skill lives up to its reputation!
Master, you're here?
Chong'er, since you're wounded, you may dispense with the formalities.
You risked your life to save my daughter.
Even my own life is not enough to repay you.
Don't say that.
My internal injuries can't be cured by most medicines.
I took your eight herbal life-extending pills by accident.
It is truly an insult to your miracle drug.
I hope that after this girl drinks my blood, her illness will take a turn for the better.
Consider it my way of making it up to her.
Look how open-minded and righteous Mr. Linghu is.
Even Sacred...
Even saints fall short of our Mr. Linghu.
Thank you all for treating my disciple kindly. We should be leaving now.
Hero Yue, since we brought Mr. Linghu here,
I think we should take him back.
Yes yes yes.
Ji Wu Shi! Let me down!
I won't call you freak anymore from now on!
She's my friend.
We will release her immediately! Immediately!
Chong'er, how do you feel?
Much better, thanks.
Tomorrow morning, I will definitely come with you to Five Hegemon Hill.
Five Hegemon Hill?
Linghu...
We're only passing through.
I don't know if we've offended the Wulin people here.
My daughter and a disciple named Lin were taken away by two people dressed in black and white.
Do you happen to know anything about this?
This...
You three...
Mr. Linghu, is anything the matter?
If you know anything, please tell them
to release my junior sister and brother, ok?
We will definitely obey.
Please take the trouble.
Rest well.
We're leaving now.
- Heroine Ning, we will be leaving.- Goodbye.
Blue Maiden
Blue Maiden, what do you want?
- I...- What?
I'm serious...
What? Serious about what?
Serious about loving you.
Maiden
I admit it was my fault for hitting you
but I really have no interest in you, at all.
You're lying!
I'm not lying!
To hit and scold is to love. You hit me twice!
You must love me.
Yes.
This is the most important thing to me.
I want to give it to you.
If you accept, then I will follow you to the ends of the earth.
But if you throw it away, then from now on I will break all ties with you!
Maiden, you said so yourself.
As long as I throw this away or smash it,
then from now on we go our separate ways. You can't latch onto me anymore!
You wouldn't really smash it?
I...
You really smashed it!
I smashed it! Yes, I did!
Maiden, you said so yourself.
As long as I throw this away, you won't latch onto me anymore.
Of course!
From now on, I won't latch onto you anymore.
But you should at least open it up and see what's inside.
Right right right, you should look.
Open and take a look.
- Qianqiu! This..- This is my jade cup!
From Northern Song!
Ji Wushi, you bastard!
How could you just smash it?!
I didn't do it on purpose.
Pay for my loss!
- Don't run!- I didn't do it on purpose!
Qianqiu!
To mess with me, you're still too inexperienced!
Actually, Sister Lan, to love someone...
Remember,
all beautiful women have tempers.
Father, mother!
Master, master's wife.
Shan'er, are you alright?
They were so mean!
They beat us and scolded us.
They said lots of bad things about senior brother.
Mother, they even said they would steam and eat me.
Silly girl, they were just scaring you.
No, they're really cannibals.
Last night, the black monk had a plate of meat and asked me if I wanted some.
I saw clearly it was a human hand.
Then why didn't you tell me?
I didn't want to scare you.
They must have been the "Desert North Duo"
They're bandits from the desert north of the Great Wall.
One is called White Bear, the other is Black Bear.
They rob peoples' houses, and exclusively eat human meat.
Then did you eat it?
Ok, don't talk about this anymore.
Let's hurry on our way to Fuzhou.
What do you want?
As long as you hand over the Bixie Swordplay Manual, we'll let you live.
That manual doesn't belong to you.
You've had it for so long, you must have memorized it by now.
Why do you still hold onto it?
I already told you! I don't have the manual!
Stop talking! Just kill him.
Stop.
You're fighting two against one. That's really unfair.
Interfering in our business?
What's your relation to Yu Canghai?
He's my enemy.
I have an irreconcilable vengeance against him.
I must kill him myself!
Who's this little boy? You want to kill Yu Canghai?
I am Huashan Sect disciple, Lin Pingzhi.
You're from Huashan Sect?
Then where is Linghu Chong?
I am Linghu Chong.
Do you have some business with me?
Mr. Linghu!
Guests, please enjoy.
- Here- Thanks
We've heard many jianghu friends mention your name
so we have great respect for you.
We traveled here night and day
to have a glimpse at your presence.
We didn't expect to meet you here. This is great.
You're too polite. Let me toast you.
Our jianghu friends have already arranged
to meet you tomorrow at Five Hegemon Hill.
It will be a lot of fun.
Mr. Linghu, you have to come.
I might not be able to make it.
Why?
Because I have to go to Fuzhou with my master.
Chief Yue is also here?
Yes, he's sitting right next to us.
Thanks.
This elder must be Chief Yue?
I don't deserve this.
Chief Yue, I heard that lately, you injured many formidable opponents with just one stroke of the sword.
Your name shakes the jianghu!
Humble junior bows in admiration.
Hey, why are you saying so much rubbish?
Mr. Linghu won't go to Five Hegemon Hill.
Mr. Linghu, you must come tomorrow.
As far as I've heard there will be many different leaders and heroes of the pugilistic world going in order to greet you
You show such great hospitality in inviting me. What exactly is this for?
We prepared some miracle drugs for Hero Linghu.
We plan to present them to you.
Just go!
Is that so?
Actually, I'm just a nobody.
You treat me so well, I feel guilty.
But I'd really like to know on who's behalf you're doing this.
Can you tell me?
Hero Linghu, you will find out when you go to Five Hegemon Hill tomorrow.
Hero Linghu, if you don't go, everyone will feel really bad.
No, I...
Linghu Chong! It would be ungracious to refuse.
Not going would be improperI...
So many jianghu people will be present. I'm going too.
Go! Just go!
Ok ok, then I accept.
Ok?
Then we will be waiting for your arrival tomorrow at Five Hegemon Hill.
See you tomorrow.
Stop here
They came
Come on
Hero Linghu, I'm here to escort you to Five Hegemon Hill.
Really? I still haven't thanked Brother Sima for those jars of fine wine.
You're too polite.
It's just wine. Don't mention it.
It's almost time. Please get on the carriage.
Brother Sima, please wait a moment.
I'll be right back.
Are there any good-looking guys at Five Hegemon Hill?
What do you need good-looking guys for?
Look at me, I'm so beautiful, if I were to remain unwed
Then that would be so tragic
Which is why I must find my Mr Right so that we can live happily ever after
I see.
The saying goes "everyone has different tastes"
All the heroes will be there.
I don't know what type you like.
But you'll find out once you get there.
I will go pick the best one!
Chong'er I think it's best you don't go
Whether it's a blessing or a curse is unknown
With an uncertain moral alignment
Your master's already upset that you're friends with those people.
But master-wife, I don't think they have any ill intentions.
And I really want to know who's behind them.
Master-wife, please relax
Master, I will be back very soon.
Senior
It can't be predicted what this event will bring for Chong'er
This time, all the evil heretic sects are gathering at Five Hegemon Hill.
Who knows if they're plotting something detrimental to our Huashan sect.
I think we should go with him to check it out.
Denuo, you three go to Fuzhou first
Your master-wife and I will arrive shortly
Yes, Master
Be careful-Yes, Master-wife
Open!
Big!
Good!
Six! You lost!
Drink!
Hero Linghu has arrived!
Go!
Greetings Hero Linghu!
Friend Linghu  Greetings everyone, this is Linghu Chong
Here are all the brothers of Five Hegemon Hill.
Hero Linghu, we have prepared the best wine
We're prepared to drink with you for three days and nights!
It's so hot outside. How about we go rest inside the tent?
Everyone, please wait a moment.
Master-Chong'er, look at this place
These are not upright people.
I think you should leave now.
Master, they've treated us with respect.
I don't think they have any malicious intentions.
I don't think they have any good intentions!
They just want you to join their heretic demon sect!
Chong'er your master has a point
If you don't turn around before it's too late, you will bring ruin and shame upon yourself, and be eternally doomed!
Sect leader Yue, Hero Linghu, let's talk inside.
Hero Linghu, all the brothers want to pay their respects to you.
We also prepared a miracle drug for you.
Brothers! Show Hero Linghu the way!
Please! Let's go.
Master, master-wife, I'll be right back!
Don't worry!
Let's drink!
Junior-wife, seems like we should find a hideout to keep a close watch on them.
See what they're really up to. Let's go.
Everyone toast!
Dear friends, I am just a nobody.
I really have no way of repaying your kindness to me.
Cheers everyone! From now on, we share our fortunes and misfortunes together!
Excellent!
Don't drink!
What are you people doing?
Forcing Hero Linghu to drink...
you want him to die sooner?
Dr. Ping  Sit down
Sit sit sit.
Dr Ping, this...To live or die is decided by the heavensYou've already been troubled twice because of me
You really don't need to bother with me anymore.
Master, within one day you consumed numerous potent supplementary tonics
Old man, you gave Hero Linghu the eight herbal tablets.
Are you trying to kill him?!
I...
Dr. Ping, don't blame him.
I took it by accident myself.
The eight herbal tablets are for women born with vital energy deficiencies and anemia!
You have no vital energy deficiencies. In fact, you have too many energies!
Then on top of that you took potent supplementaries
Just think, the river is already overflowing, and you want to pour in more water!
How can it not turn into disaster?!
I deserve to die.
Old man, don't say that. This has nothing to do with you.
It's my fault, all my fault.
I deserve to die!
This is all my fault!
Stop blaming yourselves, ok?
Consuming supplementary tonics is one thing...
Now tell me, how are you supposed to battle anyone ever again?
You also lost a lot of blood.
Such a show of bravery
How will this benefit your life?
Others hold you with such high regard yet you don't even know how to love yourself
For a gentleman to beget revenge after a decade it's not too late
Why the need to be so hasty?
Ping Yizhi!
No, no, no. I didn't mean anything.
Look, what I mean to say is that this has nothing to do with Hero Linghu.
It's all my fault.
I deserve to die.
What's wrong with you? Saying that again?
This has nothing to do with you!
I caused this!
- No, I deserve to die.- You two!
Shut up!
Dr. Ping!
Then just tell us what we can do to heal his injuries!
If he only took pills by accident, I might have a way to save him,
but unfortunately...
What?
Last time I took your pulse, although your injuries were very severe, your heart was full of vitality.
But why are you now disheartened?
You don't want to live anymore?
Based on your pulse, this has something to do with love.
Hero, you're usually carefree and uninhibited,
why get hung up on love?
Your condition has taken a turn for the worse.
Even the immortal Daluo Jinxian can't help you.
But to extend your life by a few months, or even a few years,
I have a way.
But you have to do as I say!
First, give up drinking.
Second, don't be so restless and frisky.No women!
Third, give up fighting.
No drinking, no women, no fighting.
Then you can live a few more years.
Life is already hard enough as it is.
If I can't drink, look at women, or fight back when I'm bullied,
then what's the point in living? I'd rather die!
You!
But if I can't treat you, my reputation will be ruined!
Dr. Ping, I know you're an excellent doctor,
but I'm bound to die!
It's perfectly normal if you can't cure me!
Linghu Chong!
Dr. Ping?
Your illness must be cured!
Then let's all drink!
He's incurable.
What?
Dr. Ping, you're the renowned killer doctor.
If you can't cure him, you're destroying your own reputation!
Don't talk nonsense.
Renowned killer doctor?
If I can't cure...
if I can't cure him...
Dr. Ping!
He ran away just like that?
Chase after him!
Why should I take orders from you?
Did you forget? Dr. Ping said so.
If anything happens to Dr. Ping, I will hold you responsible!
I only listened to you because Dr. Ping told me to.
Now that he's gone, why should I listen to you?
Aren't you afraid of your face turning ugly again?
Look out for cute guys for me.
I'll be back.
Sorry about that.
Let's forget all about what just happened.
Life is short. I'm going to die sooner or later anyways.
Might as well drink to our hearts' content today!
Til we get drunk!
Good!
- Bad news- What is it?
How much did he drink?!
We were having fun drinking
but...Sacred Lady had to throw a fit.
Actually, all we wanted was for Hero Linghu to recover soon
so he can be a perfect couple with Sacred Lady.
I really don't understand why Sacred Lady would be so furious!
You don't understand?
We did go overboard at Five Hegemon Hill.
Actually, it's very normal for man and woman to be in love
Only a beautiful woman like Sacred Lady would be good enough for the dashing, chivalrous Hero Linghu.
But what's puzzling is...why would the extraordinary Sacred Lady act shy and embarrassed like an ordinary girl?
She clearly likes him, but won't allow others to mention it.
Or see it!
I really don't understand.
Although Sacred Lady is an extraordinary lady from Black Wood Cliff, she is after all still a young girl.
She likes a man for the first time
and is too embarrassed to say it. That's perfectly natural.
Makes sense.
Do you know why our plan to suck up to Sacred Lady totally failed?
- Let's hear it- Because we're a bunch of boorish men!
We don't understand a young girl's heart.
Pity!
There were quite a few women at Five Hegemon Hill
but they were all like men!
At the gatherings of the heroes on Five Hegemon Hill, all the flattering and the Sacred Lady's anger...
If word of these were to spread, wouldn't it have become a laughing stock to those orthodox sect dastards?
Laughing stock?
What's there to laugh at?
Sacred Lady is our savior.
We have to repay her kindness
All we need to remember is to wish for her lover's speedy recovery
A true man should live in conscience and clearly distinguish kindness and hatred
We pay our debts, for the kindness or grudges
What's wrong with that?!
If anyone in the jianghu dares laugh at us,
I will break his bones
and rip out his skin and tendons!
Well said old man.
We're indebted to the Sacred Lady
If we can get them together and make her happy ever after, even if we have to die, there's nothing more to regret
So what if we were snubbed at Five Hegemon Hill?
What I'm worried about is...Hero Linghu is Huashan Sect's eldest disciple.
They have irreconcilable differences with Black Wood Cliff.
I'm afraid...
I'm afraid this union will be extremely difficult.
What are you reckless guys talking about behind my back?
Greetings Sacred Lady
Sacred Lady, we were just talking nonsense.
Please don't take it seriously.
Yes, we've already decided
we're heading west tomorrow. We will never come back to the central plains again.
Yes, we will disappear from your sight.
Who told you to go west?
I won't look any further into the incident today.
But I need you to do something for me.
Sacred Lady, please give us your command. We subordinates will spare no effort.
Sacred Lady, please give us your command.
I want to kill someone
Spread the word. If anyone in the jianghu can kill this person for me,
I will reward him generously.
Sacred Lady is our savior
We wouldn't dare accept any reward.
If Sacred Lady wants this person's life, we will chase to the ends of the earth to find him.
But...who is this criminal
who risks universal condemnation to offend Sacred Lady?
It's not enough to rely only on the few of you
Immediately pass the word
onto everyone.
Yes
Hurry
We still don't know who it is Sacred Lady wants to kill.
The person's family name is Linghu, surname is Chong
He's HuaShan Sect's eldest disciple
His existence tarnishes my clean reputation.
Everyone thinks I like him, I want to prove that I don't
If you help me kill him, you will help me vent my anger.
Sacred lady
I dont know where this Linghu Chong has gone
Take your time
But you have to spread the word first, understand?
We will do as you ordered
Let's go
This is all your fault
that everyone in the jianghu is laughing at me.
As if no one wants to marry me
and I'm so desperate to be with you.
What's so great about you?
Now I'm ashamed to show my face in front of others.
I only told Zu Qianqiu &amp; Co. to spread the word so that you will stay with me forever,
and never leave me.
Everyone, Brother Linghu is benevolent and righteous
but Sacred Lady ordered us to kill him.
What should we do?
Yeah! What should we do?
Hero Linghu treats me so well
I cannot kill him
But Sacred Lady ordered us
I dare not disobey!
What are we supposed to do?
Alright, I have a good plan
After I kill Hero Linghu, I will commit suicide
Don't do it  What now?
It's useless. Latouzi, you better not commit suicide
Why's that?
Think about it, Linghu Chong was sitting right next to Sacred Lady.
Why would she say she can't find him?
How would I know?
Your numb skull is really stupid.
Sacred Lady doesn't really want to kill Linghu.
Clearly, she likes him but is too shy.
So she orders us to tell everyone she wants him killed.
That way, it will seem like there's nothing between them.
You're right!
This Sacred Lady of ours is just too proud to admit that she has fallen for him
The more she tries to conceal it, the more obvious it is
Everyone, just pass on the message as she ordered.
But we will have it seasoned with some extra details
In this way, everybody gets the point while we can also save the Sacred Lady from embarrassment
It will be easier for us to report to her too
This is an excellent plan.
But what if some dumb person doesn't understand the complex meaning of this message,
and actually kills Hero Linghu?
Don't worry, even you understood it.
Who else could be dumb enough to risk their life doing something foolish?
What! What does that mean?!
Junior-wife, can you see Chong'er
There's too many people, I can't see clearly
Lets follow them
We'll find out later