*
Chaubier, France.
Raw cow.
Each washed rind by Cleo
seems to be a variation
on a theme held together
by the notes of regional citrus
present in the character
of all his work.
La Ventana curado, Spain.
Raw goat.
Created in the 16th century
by a community
of Benedictine monks.
The goats grazed
the base of the volcano
at La Ventana.
*
Le Guise, France.
Raw cow.
Washed daily in the
traditionally prepared bath
of salt water and pumice wine,
from grapes hand-picked
by the sons of the house
of Guise.
*
At the age of 23
a world of possibilities
had been narrowed to just two.
I could return to the typist
position at my father's gallery,
or I could follow Frederick
to the farmstead,
where I would spend
every day in the sun
learning to make wheels
of reblochon.
I came to my decision
rather quickly.
I took the position as a typist.
(liquid bubbling)
(squeaking)
Compound A.
Dilutions of three to one,
two to one, and one to one.
Compound A.
Pork and beans.
One to one, wafting.
One-to-one, wafting,
pork and beans.
Whoo.
That'll singe your nose hairs.
(bottles rattling)
One-to-one elimination
due to acrid smell
uncharacteristic
of target material.
Nose hairs.
Two-to-one, wafting.
(buzzing)
It reveals no acrid smell.
Uh, uh--
The two-to-one wafted.
Tasting.
(buzzing)
Tasting compound A,
two-to-one,
target material pork and beans.
Elimination due to overtly
pronounced bean characteristic.
Overly pronounced--
Overtly.
Be pronounced.
Overtly pronounced bean
character.
Wafting three to one.
(buzzing)
Three to one.
None.
Uh, three to one wafted.
Tasting.
Tasting compound A,
three to one dilution,
target material pork and beans.
Eh, the beans are less
intrusive.
Uh, unobtrusive beans.
I have pork character.
You have poor character.
Pork character.
Compound A.3-1 cleared.
To the next sampling groove.
A.3-1 cleared.
(buzzing)
Orange juice.
My orange juice.
Oh.
Yes, sir.
(bottles clinking)
(gargling)
(spitting)
(sighing)
Mm.
*
The woman who worked
to my immediate left
seemed to derive
a great deal of pride
and satisfaction
from her typist position.
The same could
not be said of myself.
*
(car horn blowing)
(engine puttering)
*
I began to lament
my day-to-day struggle
as if I were reading it
in poor fiction,
a pitiable character
put upon by circumstance.
(engine puttering)
*
Is, uh, this
small business loans?
That's Debbie now,
starting today.
Thanks.
*
You're leaving?
Oh, yeah.
I got placed back--
Can I have your chair?
Um--
It has armrests.
Can I have your chair?
Hey, that's mine!
Um, I'm not leaving just yet.
Ooh, that's perfect.
Uh, no!
Hey!
I brought that from home!
*
Is this small business loans?
(sighing)
That's Debbie now,
starting today.
*
(sighing)
(clock ticking)
(horn honking)
*
(engine puttering)
(goat bleating)
*
Here we go.
(laughing)
Mrs. Aldrich lived two miles
from my father's summer home
in Normandy.
She made fresh
neufchâtel with milk
from her two does
and served it with parsley
and new onions.
It was from those afternoons
that I did fall so deeply
in love.
(groaning)
You ready?
Yes.
(laughing)
Go on.
Go.
Okay.
Oh, my--
This is like the one I had
in my summer abroad.
Gosh.
I wish we had walnuts.
We had camembert and wal--
I know.
(sighing)
I looked for this everywhere
when I got back!
You can't get it here.
It's unpasteurized.
It's from raw milk.
Hm.
It's illegal here.
Illegal?
Mm-hmm.
Where did you get it?
Um, I know people.
*
(siren wailing)
(dog barking)
(cart crashing)
(engine clicking)
Look.
*
Look at this.
(goat bleating)
Be careful.
It's a goat.
It could be dangerous.
(groaning)
(goat bleating)
(laughing)
Hello, my name is Artois.
If I am alone, I am lost.
Please make return
of me to address.
Farm Road 60.
(goat bleating)
Do you think they'll come back?
I don't know.
Maybe we should take him--
Where'd be go?
(goat bleating)
Hey, baby, I found it.
I had to process this thing
today, this application.
A married couple about our age.
You got a bottle opener?
Packed.
Already packed.
(sighing)
I think I have one in my pants.
Um, you know where my pants are?
Oh, thanks.
They want...
over by that pet store
at Bit Street.
They want to open
a cupcake shop.
Uh, a bakery?
No, a cupcake shop.
That sells cupcakes?
Yeah.
She wants to get out of teaching
and open a shop
selling cupcakes.
That's stupid.
Oh, here it comes.
Don't get any on the mattress.
I didn't.
Okay.
Um...
glasses.
I think--
Packed.
Yeah.
(clinking)
(paper rustling)
I--I mean, I can make
a pretty mean cupcake.
It doesn't mean that I'm--it
doesn't mean
I'm gonna quit my job.
It doesn't mean I think
I can make a go of it
as a professional.
What?
Some people
are so stupid.
Yeah?
Still though, I can see us
doing something like that.
Like what?
Like that.
You know, open a place.
You could make the cupcakes
or whatever.
I could do the books.
We could go to work together
every day, you know?
(laughing)
Yeah.
I--if you're gonna do it,
if--if you're gonna do it right,
you don't just serve cupcakes.
Hm.
I would serve coffee and tea.
Create a place
where people can read,
work, whatever.
(laughing)
Make sandwiches.
You could serve wine in the
evening!
I don't--
Yeah!
Hm.
If you're gonna do it,
you gotta do it right.
I agree.
Yeah.
And as for the people,
the couple,
did they get the loan?
No.
It was the denied.
(sighing)
Yeah.
Some people are so stupid.
*
(growling)
(laughing)
(sniffing)
(groaning)
*
(slurping)
They're watching me.
This I am now certain.
Who?
Your Food and Drug
Administration.
Your fascism and Drug
(laughing)
Right.
Three days.
Three days I have seen this man
in the same spot.
*
I am pretty sure he's homeless.
(trash rattling)
Well of course, he looks
like he's homeless.
What's with your face?
Uh, your--your glasses.
Oh, yeah.
Artisanal Market.
*
(siren wailing)
(cart slamming)
This is very special.
One of the last in the world.
*
Whoa.
So, you like?
*
What is this?
Notes on the Production
of a Superior Goat Cheese,
by Eva Verrane.
Translated into 12 languages
since 1945.
Eva Verrane.
The chèvre divin, French.
Raw goat.
From legendary cheese maker
Eva Verrane.
She's dead now.
This is from the very last
season.
I'll wrap some up for you.
*
"All that I am is born from my
work.
Nothing is equal,
nor is anything more essential
than the joy that is knowing
this is mine, I created it,
and it is good."
But is it internally flawless
or externally flawless?
That's what they don't tell you,
and if it is internally
flawless, how do you know?
Did you get a second opinion?
After Chesterfield proposed
to me,
I had this ring rated
by three different jeweler's
by week's end.
Isn't that right?
Right, right.
Three.
Wonderful.
(laughing)
And of course, Angie
will be my maid of honor.
So, do you two still plan
on making a go of this?
(laughing)
Yes.
Of course.
-How?
-Mom.
We'll talk on the phone,
and I'll go up there and--
sometimes, and she'll come
down here sometimes.
Mm-hmm.
And how long do you think
you can keep that up?
Virgil brought something!
Just for us.
Yes.
Yes, yes.
He brought something.
It is an aged goat.
There's actually a very
interesting story
behind this cheese.
In France--
Uh, no thank you.
I'm not eating dairy.
We're not eating dairy.
Right, right.
So, Angie, in Detroit
during your internship,
were there a lot of men there?
Boys your own age, I mean.
(coughing)
Oh, uh, so, I don't know
if you remember a little thing
we worked on about,
um, three months ago,
flavor 242-240.
Not specifically.
Target material was raspberry
sorbet.
I--no.
Wrap your eyes
around this, my friend.
Seven-hundred
and thirty-two dollars.
And nine cents.
Your contractual percentage
of the sale of 242-240.
Uh, raspberry sorbet.
Confederated out of Michigan
bought it up.
Thank you.
(laughing)
You're welcome.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Oh, uh, in a related matter,
I'm sure you'll be delighted
to hear that you'll be going
to Detroit after all.
What?
Detroit, the transfer
you put in for?
Really?
Really.
(laughing)
Oh, God.
Oh, thank God!
Sorry, sorry.
It just said it would be another
year--another year
before anyone left the gourmet
sensations line.
The what now?
The gourmet sensations.
Um, this offer didn't come
from the gourmet sensations
line.
But I--I didn't--I don't think
I applied anywhere else, did I?
It looks like we're
headed up there
to open up...
the sorbets line.
Sorbets?
No, no.
Sorbitz.
(making Z sound)
It's got a Z in it.
Confederated pharmaceuticals
brings you, Sorbitz.
Registered trademark.
The only cough drop
that combines the soothing
action of synthetic eucalyptus
with the fresh taste
of raspberry sorbet.
Flavor 242-240, your work.
It's mine?
It's yours.
You created it.
*
Is it good?
I don't know.
*
Thank you.
Thanks.
*
(gagging)
(spitting)
(groaning)
It's bad.
(crashing)
I thought of you, I did!
I can't!
So, do--don't think that I
just--
I don't understand!
He handed me the pen,
and he asked me to choose.
He asked me "yes or no?"
And I thought of you.
I--I did.
You tried, right?
You--you told him--
Of course!
My mother's asleep downstairs.
She is asleep.
Of course.
Of course I--every week,
every other day I'm in there,
I'm asking again.
Fitznicholas tells me
nothing's changed!
You said anything!
If anything opened up,
anything--
But this--
But this?
Not this, then what?
If we beg, Virgil, if we beg,
then we do not choose.
This was the one, the only one!
Why not this?
(clearing throat)
There was this cheese--
Pardon?
There was this cheese.
Yens gave it to me,
and I tasted it.
It was goat.
It was really good,
and then this book--
-I read this book.
-A book.
Uh, this lady in France
with goats, she's dead.
It doesn't matter.
Uh, but I tasted it,
and it was so good
that it made, uh...
it reminded me of something
that I had forgotten,
and then the lady, that--
-Dead lady?
Yeah, France, she said,
"You are what you create."
You see?
(laughing)
Like it was a trap.
Like they had planned
it this way.
Fitznicholas, he has me taste
them, and they're awful.
They're bad.
"You created them!"
And so, you know,
and--you know, I--and I--
(laughing)
And so you turned it down?
And--and I--no!
Okay, no, no.
There's this beautiful
and magnificent cheese,
and then there are these cough
drops that taste like poison,
and--and I had to choose.
And so you turned it down,
and I am still going
to Detroit alone.
No.
Yes.
Virgil--
(sighing)
Never mind.
I'm sorry.
Virgil?
I've done a really stupid thing.
I'm sorry.
(sighing)
What's that?
This.
Seven-hundred and thirty-two?
I will use this money
to buy you a ring.
An engagement ring?
I know it's not a lot, and a
job.
I'll--forget Fitznicholas
and cough drops.
I'll start looking for new jobs
in Detroit.
I'll find one.
I will.
What's a Sorbitz?
I love you.
I'm sorry, and I will
make my way back to you.
When?
Soon.
(wind blowing)
(beeping)
Hey, babe.
I hope you're outside.
It's finally getting warmer
here.
It's a gorgeous day.
Oh! Did you hear anything
from Wienerbaum?
I had a good feeling about this.
Well, anyway, I love you.
I miss you.
Bye.
(beeping)
Hey, babe.
I hope you're outside.
It's finally getting warmer
here.
It's a gorgeous day.
*
(gasping)
(paper crumpling)
*
"I pondered the question
for some time before applying.
I knew that my answer
would not satisfy
the sensibilities of this
particular periodical,
so I responded simply and
honestly.
The greatest cheese I ever
tasted
was the first cheese I made
myself.
*
I took great care in the
selection
of my starter culture.
These bacteria
will not only sour your milk
but will go far in determining
how your product ages.
*
I paid a local butcher
to slaughter a succulent kid.
Once dried, we are able
to extract from its stomach
what is needed.
Hopefully the technologies
of our modern age will promise
a less distasteful alternative
to this rather brutish process.
*
The digestive enzyme rennin
coagulated the liquid milk
proteins into solids.
I achieved a clean break
after about four hours.
The milk had separated
into solid curd and liquid whey.
*
I prefer to hand ladle
so as to maintain the integrity
of the individual curds.
*
I allowed the press
to act upon the curds
for a full 12 hours
so as to extract
as much of the remaining whey
as possible.
*
It is of the utmost importance
that the press is left
undisturbed during this period."
(crashing)
No!
No, no, no!
Oh, no.
No.
(crashing)
(wind blowing)
*
(yelling)
(rubber stretching)
*
It is...
good.
Hm.
(sighing)
(laughing)
You did this with milk
from the grocery store?
Uh-huh.
Hm.
What?
Teats.
Teats ?
Teats .
What?
Teats.
All great cheese
comes from raw milk,
not this pasteurized bullshit.
Raw?
Straight from the teat.
Teat.
The problem with teats
is that they are usually
attached to cows.
I would not know where
a fellow like you could find
a teat.
(car engine revving)
(goats bleating)
Howdy.
Twenty dollars American,
and he's yours.
Hey there, guy.
Better watch out now.
He'll piss on you.
Oh.
Ah.
Uh, thanks.
Yeah.
That's my piss rag.
Twenty dollars American.
No, no thanks.
I don't think I have much use
for a bull goat.
Buck goat.
For a buck goat.
Not at the present moment.
Uh, that's fine.
I call him Artois
after my pawpaw
and like pawpaw he's gonna
make a great stew.
(goat bleating)
*
Virgil, you still there?
Wh--what? Yeah.
-Yeah, yeah.
-Your birthday?
I thought I'd come and visit
you for your birthday.
Oh, that'd be good.
(goat bleats)
What was that?
What? Uh--
(goat bleat)
Who is that?
Are you alone?
Yes, of course.
Uh, that was, uh,
the radio--the TV.
Okay. Something wrong?
No, no, baby, I'm just
real busy right now.
Um, got to get some more
applications done.
Workin' hard. Goodnight.
(sighing)
The unique character
of my cheese would result
from a confluence
of many elements.
Perhaps none more important
than the selection
of the location
of my farmstead.
*
The land, the terroir,
it would be the constitution
of this grazing foliage
that would determine
the character
of the milk produced,
and consequently,
the ultimate flavor
and complexity of my cheese.
*
The land should be glorious
and fertile.
Grasses and cloves,
alfalfa, wild flowers,
and water.
The character of the land
is the character of the cheese.
*
Unexpected new cheeses
come from unexpected new places,
places that the world
has not yet tasted.
*
Hello?
(glass breaking)
*
(clinking)
And I suppose that your company
has a great deal of experience
in setting up these types
of operations?
-My what?
-Your company?
I--you mean my job?
Thank you for coming.
But--no, please.
I don't think you quite
understand
what it is I'm trying
to do here.
All right.
What is it you're
trying to do here?
Well, I...
Thank you for coming.
May the confused steps
that brought you across
my property
carry you doubly quick
in the opposite direction--
-Wait!
-Yes?
I'm supposed to go
to work tomorrow.
Yes.
I can't go back now.
Do you know how it is
that you came to find me here?
Well, I...
Basset hounds.
Basset hounds?
Basset hounds!
When I was a young lad,
not far removed in age
from yourself,
I had the firm
and resolute intention
to become a champion breeder
of these most beautiful
and noble creatures
which scuttled majestically
across the earth.
Basset hounds.
Oh, I read the books.
I learned the trade,
and I decided that just as soon
as my time as a claims adjuster
had afforded me sufficient
financial security
that I would go to my brother,
resign my position,
and purchase attractive land,
not entirely dissimilar
to this one.
Took me 31 years to achieve
what I have set out to do.
Just a hair longer than outlined
in my five-year plan.
Perhaps it would be
best if I just--
And then!
And then I did
a very silly thing.
Walked out on my brother,
I walked out on my career,
on my life, and I spent
everything I had
on this muddy little corner
of nowhere.
It was at this point
that I made a rather
disheartening discovery.
*
I don't give a damn about
basset hounds anymore.
There is something
about pushing a rock
up a hill for 30 years
that will take all the romance
out of what is essentially
just a floppy-eared dog,
and take all the romance
out of everything.
All I can see
when I close my eyes
are rising liability rates
in the new year!
Uh-huh.
*
You have a girl?
Pardon?
Yes.
Marry her.
Get yourself a dog
and some neighbors,
because one thing that
you don't want to be
is a 55-year old man with--
with what amounts to little more
than a 200-acre cemetery plot
and no reason to get out
of bed in the morning,
save habit...
and a desire
to figure out where the hell
you're gonna spend
the rest of eternity.
*
I haven't slept above ground
in so long I can't remember.
(yells)
Oh!
I've dug 100 holes all around!
And it is my firm
and resolute intention
to put at least one
of 'em to good use!
Okay.
And what I don't
intend to do
is to allow some mumbling,
bumbling child--
to go trembling,
scattershot
all over my final
resting place!
And certainly not
with any goats!
*
No!
(panting)
Angie?
Virgil.
Ms. Dickenson?
Uh, oh, I'm sorry.
I was trying to reach Angie
up there.
Just a moment.
It's him.
Virgil?
Angie.
I got your message.
Is your mother--
She's staying
with me for a bit.
She just showed up?
I called her.
I asked her to come.
I've just been
a little lonely lately.
Me too.
You know,
I can't wait to see you.
I still have the money,
the money for the ring.
About that, Virgil,
my mother doesn't think
that's such a good idea.
That what's a good idea?
Your birthday.
She thinks...
I really should
be focusing on my job.
You're not coming.
We'll talk later, okay?
Bye.
(car swerving)
Listen!
(slam)
Listen.
Listen closely to what's
about to be said.
It is my firm
and resolute intention
to found and operate
my own farmstead
from which I will produce a
superior artisanal goat cheese.
Is that all?
I may not have capital,
I don't have experience,
nor do I have
any intention
of asking
for favors, pity,
sympathy from you
or anyone else.
What I do have, however,
is a sound
business proposal.
(sighing)
I'm listening.
-One wheel.
One wheel, two goats.
-Two goats.
You permit the grazing
of just two goats
on the northeastern end
of your land,
out of sight
and out of mind.
-How long?
-Not long.
The few months requisite
to produce
a single wheel of cheese.
-Single wheel?
-A single wheel.
Why would I be in any way
inclined to accept?
Because in six months
the International
Cheese Consortium
will hold their bi-annual
conference in this city,
and I will retrieve for you
a contract for the production
of goat cheese
on this very property!
For how much?
$50,000.
-How?
-I will.
I just need
the go-ahead from you.
Where are the goats?
$731, $732.
(goat bleat)
(panting)
Let's talk goats.
(goats bleating)
Guten Morgen.
Good morning.
Coffee?
Oh, thank you.
So, this is it?
(goat bleat)
Yes, this is it.
What does your Angie
think of all of this?
Angie has stopped calling.
(phone ringing)
(goat bleat)
Hello?
Hey, Virgil!
Virgil, uh--
(paper crinkling)
Gurdies!
Yes, hi.
Uh, this is Ronaldo Reid
calling from
the Wienerbaum Food Labs
in Detroit.
I've got your application here
and I was wondering--
we've had something open up
and thought maybe we could
get you in here for an interview
sometime next week.
How does Thursday sound?
(clunking)
How about Friday?
(dial tone)
*
After I was relieved of my
position with Artisanal Market
I bummed around Asia
for a while.
Through a series
of what could, in retrospect,
be viewed as poor decisions
on my part, I found myself
in the indentured servitude
of a Nepalese man named
Wop Sang.
Cruel task master, yeah,
but prior to my being liberated
by the friars of a nearby
Tibetan monastery,
he was able to impart to me
the ancient techniques
of effective vaccimulgence.
*
The yaks I milked
were much larger of course,
but the principal
is the same.
*
The grains will keep
the beast pacified
while I clean
and massage the teat.
*
Are these cheerios?
Yeah.
They were all I could procure
on short notice.
*
(liquid squirting)
Einz.
*
Zwei.
Drei.
*
Vier.
Fünf.
*
Sechs.
Seiben.
Acht!
*
Nuen.
It is complete.
*
You and me will change
the bandage on alternate days
for the first couple of weeks
till the cheese has formed
its own rind.
If that's okay with you?
*
Come in when you need to.
Be warned.
We see all.
(screams)
(coins clinking)
(knocking)
Hey.
*
(beep)
Virgil, pick up the phone!
I was locking up
the shop tonight
and the man with
colorful hair was--
(beep)
(sighing)
What?
Hm?
You came all the way here.
You wanted me here
for your birthday.
Yeah.
What--what--when?
It's your birthday.
Today's your birthday.
I guess I must have--
(laughing)
I thought you said--
Hm?
What about what your mom--
(sighing)
Things were so
busy back then,
and I was lonely.
My mother...
I told her.
I told her that I love you
and she couldn't do
anything about it.
I tried to call you.
I tried all week.
Oh.
My phone's been giving me
some problems.
And I think I need
to get a new one.
What now?
Now?
Now.
Now we go and...
I thought you were going
to take me to find a ring.
Uh--
*
(laughing)
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's just such
a beautiful day outside.
It'd be a shame
to waste it.
Cramped up in a jewelry store
all day long.
You know, there's always
tomorrow.
Okay.
Yeah?
It is a really nice day.
Yeah.
And I know just
where I want to go.
Where?
I feel like I haven't
been here in forever.
Yeah, me too.
Great weather.
What?
Nothing.
Uh, great weather.
Great weather.
Is anything wrong?
No.
You seem...
I don't know,
strung out.
I know why you're frustrated.
Working so hard to find a job
in Detroit and getting nowhere,
filling out all those
applications
and sending them off.
So many.
And I'm the one putting
the pressure on you.
Really, don't beat yourself
up about it.
Sometimes I forget how lucky
I am to have you.
Babe?
Yeah.
About all that.
Yeah?
There's kind of sort of
somethin' I--
(goat bleat)
Jesus!
Baby!
-It's a goat!
-Yeah, it's a goat!
No, no, no,
don't do that!
No!
Why not?
It's an animal.
It could be dangerous.
I think--yeah!
I think this is the one
we saw before.
Really?
No.
I think that one
had more hair.
Virgil?
Yeah?
This goat has
your name on it.
"V. Gurdies."
Well, that could be
any Gurdies.
Not necessarily me.
What?
Wow.
Same name as me.
Mm-hmm.
You know, we should
look him up in the phone book
when we get home.
Speaking of heading home,
I'm a little bit tired.
I think we should get
heading home.
You know, and that's where I
keep my phone book after all,
and speaking of phones,
I need a new cell.
You think Circuit Center's
still open?
I bet if we hurry
we can make it.
Angie?
You awake?
(yells)
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Oh, hi.
Sorry.
Uh, I think I might--
I'm looking for
a Virgil Gurdies.
No, no.
You have the right number.
He's not here right now.
(door creaks)
Hey, babe.
Come on cheese!
I just went to go--
I mean, you ruined
the surprise.
Surprise!
Um, yeah.
I went to the place
down the street,
the one you like.
Your phone works.
Oh, yeah?
You got a call
from a Ronaldo.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah, a Ronaldo.
Wienerbaum Food?
He says he's been
trying to reach you.
Oh, huh.
It may be some good news.
It may be some good news
about a job maybe.
Uh, maybe.
I mean, I--I'll have
to check I guess.
Shame they didn't
send you a letter.
Yeah, seriously.
Did you want one of these?
Sausage?
Maybe a letter
like this one.
-What--what's that?
-It was open.
It was on top of
the fridge so I--
"Dear Mr. Gurdies,
Thank you so much
for your application.
We would love--"
What is this?
-Angie--
-Why are you lying?
I--I--Angie, I can explain.
That's it?
Yeah.
Why?
I don't remember.
All I...
I have a lot of time
up there.
I have a lot of time.
You know, that apartment
is like a little gray box.
I thought I could make it
into a home and I waited.
I left you one side
of the closet empty.
I know what it sounds like.
I--I know
what it looks like.
It wasn't the waiting, Virgil!
I could handle the waiting
because I knew--
because I thought
that you were doing
everything you could
to get back to me.
I was!
I am.
But maybe I have to do this.
How long until you're done?
Tonight.
With this, with all of this?
Look, um, I'm gonna see
my mother before I leave.
That's where I'll be if...
That's where I'll be.
Angie.
Angie!
Angie, wait!
Stop, Angie!
*
(cracks)
Ready?
Ready.
Don't worry.
We'll be back real soon
to get the rest of your books
and your cooking stuff.
-Real soon.
-No need.
No?
No, I think I've got that out
of my system for a while.
Let's go.
(train horn)
*
Lots to manage, there.
Yeah.
*
-I like it.
-Yes?
Yeah, no, I do.
Yes, yes, yes!
-Do you need a hand?
-No, I got it.
-Okay.
-I just--never mind.
*
And then we can billow through
your closet.
I can't believe you're here!
(laughing)
So, where's the bedroom?
It's that way.
*
(bass rumbling)
(dog barking)
The first day
is always the hardest.
I'm sure you'll fit right in.
I'm only a phone call away
if you need me.
I think I'll be fine.
I think I'll be more than fine.
Yeah?
Yeah.
New job, new place, new town.
I think it'll be different.
Different is good.
Anything different is good.
Bachelors in chem...
...and bio chem.
Two years internship.
Two years apprenticeship.
Everything looks in order.
I'd say we can get you
started right away.
Mr. Fitznicholas?
No.
It's Nitzficholas.
Mr. Nitzficholas, to you.
Compound A,
dilutions of three to one,
two to one,
and one to one.
(sighing)
Compound A.
Camembert and walnuts.
One to one, wafting.
(police sirens)
*
Do you--
is that the brown rice
or the white?
The white.
Oh.
*
You--
The white.
*
What's this?
Cheezewhirl.
-Cheesewhirl?
-No, no.
Cheezewhirl.
("Z" sound)
It's got a "Z" in it.
Cheezewhirl.
New camembert cheezewhirl.
They picked up
the flavor profile
for their new gourmet
international line.
Yeah.
I bet.
Try it.
No, thanks.
(cheezewhirl spraying)
*
I'll, uh, hit you up
with the details inside.
This is only the beginning!
Do you know
anything about cheese?
No.
This is what they got us
tryin' to tackle next.
Goat cheese.
I can't make heads or tails
out of it.
Tastes a bit off to me.
This is supposed
to be the good stuff, too,
so they say.
Chèvre d'Eva.
Tastes a bit off to me,
but I suppose
I can stomach a bit more.
*
Hey!
Be careful with that,
that's expensive stuff.
Get away.
-Give--
-Get back!
You can pry this out
of my cold, dead hands
because I will not let
another ounce of this
go down the gullet
of a goon like you!
*
Why you little--
I'm gonna kill you!
(gasping)
*
(police siren)
(thunk)
(groaning)
(angelic choir)
*
(speaking French)
I'm sorry,
I don't speak French.
Is this better?
Yes, thank you.
A writer writes, Virgil.
A painter must paint.
What, then,
must a maker of cheeses do?
*
Come back.
Come back!
It is you who must come back.
*
Virgil?
Hey.
I must go back.
I must create something.
Something
that is good,
and without that,
I have no pride.
Without pride
there can be no respect.
Without respect--
there can be no love.
I'm going back.
(sighing)
-I can't go with you.
-I wouldn't ask you to.
-I can't wait for you.
Not without some end in sight,
and I can't know that.
No.
No, you can't.
But I will return.
I'll prove to you
I'm someone worth loving.
I will.
I'll prove it to myself first.
I'll become something I'm not.
Not yet.
What's that?
You'll know it when you see it.
I'll see you?
*
(gun click)
(goat bleat)
No!
No, please!
Please!
No!
No, please.
$20 American.
Seven--
I've got eight.
No!
(gun shot)
(goat bleat)
(creaking)
I have a plan.
The International Cheese
Consortium,
do you still have your contacts
in the inside?
Yeah.
The conference,
how much time do we have left?
Three weeks.
That's not much time.
Not enough for a hard cheese.
The cheese press is--
is out of order
at the present moment.
Out of order--
what happened?
That's not important, okay?
Okay.
Change of plans.
We'll get started right away.
Get started?
Get started on what?
I have an idea.
Yens, buy me a bottle of vodka.
Here's some money.
Virgil, I don't think
that's very constructive.
Just get me the bottle.
I'll get started here.
Get started on what?
I'm gonna pick blackberries!
*
(goat bleat)
Notes on the production
of a goat cheese.
The goats are walked daily
through the same sections
of the northern meadow,
so that they may forge
through the blackberry bushes.
It is from the terroir
that the milk
and consequently
the cheese
will be given
uniquely regional
characteristics
and complexities.
*
(liquid squirting)
The layer
of carbonized ash
reduces the acidity
of the cheese,
permitting
the growth of mold to ripen
and develop the flavor.
*
Time constraints
have forced us
to shift from a hard,
aged cheese
to a soft,
fresh Neufchatel .
As such, we will set the milk
at a lower temperate
so as to maintain the larger,
softer curds.
*
The wild blackberries,
native to the land,
are integrated
at this early stage
to allow the flavor
to develop fully
into the curd.
*
This is it.
I give to you
the blackberry chèvre.
This is mine.
I have created it.
And it is--
(crash)
(gasps)
What's goin' on?
What the hell is goin' on?
No, no, no!
No, no, no, no, no!
Be careful!
Are you Yens Berlin?
Was?
Are you?
Yeah.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
I'm Agent Brown
with the FDA
and you're under arrest
for conspiracy to import
and distribute illegal,
unpasteurized cheese.
Oh, my God.
Shizer.
Yeah, yeah.
I told you--
told you they were watching me.
Take 'em away.
(gasping)
I told you
they were watching me!
No, no--
I'm sorry.
Yens!
Yens, Yens!
You wouldn't listen!
Oh, God.
Confiscate everything.
Take that cheese.
No, no!
Give it.
(yelling)
No, my cheese!
Don't forget the goats.
This operation is goin' down.
What--no!
No, no, wait.
Yens had nothing to do with it.
This is mine!
I--I created it!
It's mine!
Save it.
No!
You can get it all back
after we finish
with the legal proceeding.
How long will that take?
About six months.
No--no, no, no.
I--I need it.
I need it!
Everything depends on it!
We're outta here.
(helicopter taking off)
(goat bleating)
Artois.
No!
Oh, my God, no!
No.
(goat bleat)
(sighing)
God.
(goat bleat)
The Pecorino Clermont.
Its unique aging process
originated
in the 8th century A.D.,
when the township of Clermont
was set upon by marauders.
Refusing to give in
to the marauder's demands,
they buried
their wheels of cheese
beneath the ground
so that even
if their lives were taken,
that which they held most dear
would remain untarnished.
I must pause here
to remark
that upon first encountering
this story,
I could not help but draw
the obvious parallels.
My first attempts
at the making of reblochon
had failed.
I was faced with the prospect
of returning to my position
as a typist
at my father's gallery.
As I sat at the train station,
ticket in hand,
I considered,
was my cause any less
worth fighting for?
Had I given up the fight
without unsheathing my sword?
Would I prefer my position
as a typist to death?
My struggles seemed
so trivial compared to theirs,
but sure enough,
the township of Clermont
was able to repel the marauders,
though not without
some loss of life on both sides,
and when they exhumed their
precious wheels of pecorino,
they rejoiced
in their discovery
that the process
of being aged underground
had imbued them
with a unique and wonderful
character and complexity.
So from that day onwards,
each season
in the last 1,200 years,
they've buried their cheese
beneath the ground
to uncover them
on the anniversary of the day
they repelled the onslaught
and won their future.
Virgil?
Are you listening?
Yes.
Go.
It is your destiny.
*
(thunder clapping)
(ground crumbling)
Angie?
There's someone here to see you.
Miss Angie?
Yes.
I have special instructions.
I am to deliver this in person.
Yes?
(thunder clap)
*
(yelling)
(angelic choir)
*
Is this small business loans?
It is.
I have an application.
A guy about my age,
he wants to make cheese.
*
(sniffs)
That's stupid.
Yup.
*
(singing in French)