Senator, we're making
our final approach into Coruscant.
Very good, Lieutenant.
[Droid Beeping]
[Grunts]
We made it.
[Man]
I guess I was wrong.
There was no danger at all.
Cordé.
Milady, I'm so sorry.
I've failed you, Senator.
No.
Milady, you're still
in danger here.
- I shouldn't have come back.
- This vote is very important.
You did your duty.
Cordé did hers. Now, come.
Senator Amidala,
please.
I don't know how much longer
I can hold off the vote, my friends.
More and more star systems
are joining the separatists.
- If they do break away--
- I will not let this Republic...
that has stood for a thousand years
be split in two.
My negotiations
will not fail.
If they do, you must realize
there aren't enough Jedi
to protect the Republic.
We're keepers of the peace,
not soldiers.
Master Yoda.
Do you think it will
really come to war?
Hmm, the dark side
clouds everything.
Impossible to see
the future is.
[Speaking Huttese]
The Loyalist Committee
has arrived, Your Honor.
- Good.
- [Huttese]
Send them in.
We will discuss
this matter later.
Senator Amidala,
your tragedy on the landing platform--
terrible.
Seeing you alive
brings warm feelings to my heart.
Do you have any idea
who was behind this attack?
Our intelligence points to disgruntled
spice miners on the moons of Naboo.
I think that Count Dooku
was behind it.
He is a political idealist,
not a murderer.
You know, milady,
Count Dooku was once a Jedi.
He couldn't assassinate anyone.
It's not in his character.
But for certain,
Senator...
in grave danger you are.
Master Jedi,
may I suggest...
the senator
be placed...
under the protection
of your graces.
Do you really think that's a wise
decision under these stressful times?
Chancellor, if I may comment,
I do not believe--
The situation
is that serious?
No, but I do, Senator.
I realize all too well
that additional security...
might be
disruptive for you...
but perhaps someone
you're familiar with.
An old friend,
like Master Kenobi.
That's possible.
He's just returned
from a border dispute on Ansion.
Do it for me, milady.
Please?
The thought
of losing you...
is unbearable.
I will have Obi-Wan
report to you immediately, milady.
[Senator Amidala]
Thank you, Master Windu.
You seem
a little on edge.
- Not at all.
- I haven't felt you this tense...
since we fell into
that nest of gundarks.
[Scoffs] You fell into
that nightmare, Master...
and I rescued you,
remember?
Oh... yes.
[Laughing]
[Chuckles]
You're sweating. Relax.
Take a deep breath.
I haven't seen her
in ten years, Master.
Obi? Obi!
Mesa so smilen
to seein yousa!
- Good to see you again, JarJar.
- Senator Padmé.
Mesa palos here!
Lookie, lookie, Senator.
Des a Jedi arriven.
It's a great pleasure
to see you again, milady.
It has been far too long,
Master Kenobi.
Ani? My goodness,
you've grown.
So have you.
Grown more beautiful, I mean.
Well, f-for a senator,
I mean.
Ani, you'll always be that little boy
I knew on Tatooine.
Our presence here will be invisible,
milady, I can assure you.
I'm Captain Typho
of Her Majesty's security service.
Queen Jamillia has been informed
of your assignment.
I am grateful you are here,
Master Kenobi.
The situation is more dangerous
than the senator will admit.
I don't need more security.
I need answers.
I want to know
who's trying to kill me.
We are here to protect you, Senator,
not to start an investigation.
We will find out
who's trying to kill you, Padmé.
- I promise you.
- We will not exceed our mandate...
my young Padawan learner.
I meant that in the interest
of protecting her, Master.
We will not go through
this exercise again, Anakin...
- and you will pay attention to my lead.
- Why?
What?
Why else do you think we were assigned
to her if not to find the killer?
Protection is a job
for local security, not Jedi.
It's overkill, Master.
Investigation is implied in our mandate.
We will do exactly
as the council has instructed.
And you will learn
your place, young one.
Perhaps with
merely your presence...
the mystery surrounding
this threat will be revealed.
Now, if you'll
excuse me...
I will retire.
I know I'll feel better
having you here.
I'll have an officer stationed
on every floor, and I'll be in
the control center downstairs.
Mesa busten wit happiness
seein yousa again, Ani.
She hardly even
recognized me, JarJar.
I've thought about her
every day since we parted, and...
she's forgotten me completely.
Shesa happy. Happier den
mesa seein her in a longo time.
You're focusing on the negative, Anakin.
Be mindful of your thoughts.
She was pleased to see us.
Now, let's check the security.
I hit the ship,
but they used a decoy.
We'll have to try something
more subtle this time, Zam.
My client is getting impatient.
Take these.
Be careful.
They're very poisonous.
Zam, there can be
no mistakes this time.
Captain Typho has
more than enough men downstairs.
No assassin would try that way.
- Any activity up here?
- Quiet as a tomb.
I don't like just waiting here
for something to happen to her.
- [Beeping]
- What's going on?
Ah, she covered
the cameras.
I don't think
she liked me watching her.
What is she thinking?
She programmed R2
to warn us if there is an intruder.
[Obi-Wan] There are many
other ways to kill a senator.
[Anakin] I know, but we also want to
catch this assassin, don't we, Master?
You're using her as bait.
It was her idea.
Don't worry.
No harm will come to her.
I can sense everything
going on in that room.
Trust me.
It's too risky.
Besides, your senses aren't
that attuned, my young apprentice.
And yours are?
Possibly.
You look tired.
I don't sleep well anymore.
Because of your mother?
I don't know why
I keep dreaming about her.
Dreams pass in time.
I'd much rather dream
about Padmé.
Just being around her again
is... intoxicating.
Be mindful of your thoughts, Anakin.
They betray you.
You've made
a commitment to the Jedi order,
a commitment not easily broken.
And don't forget, she's a politician,
and they're not to be trusted.
[Anakin] She's not like the others
in the senate, Master.
[Obi-Wan] It is my experience
that senators...
focus only on pleasing those
who fund their campaigns...
and they're in no means scared of
forgetting the niceties of democracy...
- in order to get those funds.
- Not another lecture.
At least not on
the economics of politics.
[R2-D2 Beeps]
[Beeping]
And besides,
you're generalizing.
- The chancellor doesn't
appear to be corrupt.
- Palpatine is a politician.
[Obi-Wan] I have observed
that he is very clever...
in following the passions
and the prejudices of the senators.
I think he's a good man. My--
I sense it too.
[Gasps]
[Whirring]
Stay here!
Are you all right,
milady?
Ah!
- [Horn Honking]
- What the--
[Cursing In Huttese]
Jedi poo doo!
- What took you so long?
- Oh, you know, Master.
- I couldn't find a speeder
that I really liked...
- There he is.
with the open cockpit and
the right speed capabilities.
If you spent as much time
practicing your saber techniques
as you do your wit...
you would rival Master Yoda
as a swordsman.
- I thought I already did.
- Only in your mind,
my very young apprentice.
- Pull up, Anakin. Pull up!
- [Laughing]
- You know I don't like it
when you do that.
- Sorry, Master.
I forgot you
don't like flying.
I don't mind flying,
but what you're doing is suicide.
Anakin! How many times
have I told you-- Ah!--
- Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
- stay away from power couplings!
That was good!
Where are you going?
He went that way.
Master, if we keep this chase
going any longer...
that creep is gonna
end up deep-fried...
and, personally, I'd very much
like to find out who he is
and who he's working for.
This is a shortcut.
I think.
Well, you've lost him.
I'm deeply sorry, Master.
That was some shortcut,
Anakin.
He went completely
the other way.
- Once again you've proved--
- If you'll excuse me.
I hate it when he does that.
[Grunting]
- [Engine Accelerating]
- [Grunting]
[Shouting, Grunting]
[Onlookers Murmuring]
Anakin!
- She went into the club, Master.
- Patience.
Use the Force. Think.
- Sorry, Master.
- He went in there to hide, not to run.
- Yes, Master.
- Next time, try not to lose it.
- This weapon is your life.
I try, Master.
Why do I get the feeling
you're going to be the death of me?
Don't say that, Master. You're
the closest thing I have to a father.
- Then why don't you listen to me?
- I am trying.
[Cheering, Shouting]
- Can you see him?
- I think he is a she...
and I think she
is a changeling.
In that case,
be extra careful.
- Go and find her.
- Where are you going, Master?
For a drink.
Thank you.
You wanna buy
some death sticks?
You don't want to
sell me death sticks.
- I don't want to sell you death sticks.
- You want to go home...
- and rethink your life.
- I want to go home and rethink my life.
- [Patron Shouting In Huttese]
- [Patrons Laughing]
[Cheering]
- [Screaming]
- [Patrons Gasping]
[Moaning, Grunting]
Easy. Jedi business.
Go back to your drinks.
- [Groaning]
- Do you know who it was
you were trying to kill?
[Moans]
It was a senator from Naboo.
And who hired you?
It was just a job.
Who hired you? Tell us.
Tell us now!
It was a bounty hunter called--
[Gagging]
Wee shahnit... sleemo.
Toxic dart.
[Yoda] Track down this bounty hunter
you must, Obi-Wan.
Most importantly,
find out who he's working for.
What about
Senator Amidala?
She will still
need protecting.
Handle that your Padawan will.
Anakin, escort the senator back
to her home planet of Naboo.
She'll be safer there.
And don't use registered transport.
Travel as refugees.
As the leader of the opposition,
it will be very difficult...
to get Senator Amidala
to leave the capital.
Until caught
this killer is...
our judgment she must respect.
- Hmm.
- [Windu] Anakin, go to the senate...
and ask Chancellor Palpatine
to speak with her about this matter.
I will talk with her. Senator Amidala
will not refuse an executive order.
I know her well enough
to assure you of that.
Thank you,
Your Excellency.
And so, they've finally
given you an assignment.
Your patience
has paid off.
Your guidance
more than my patience.
You don't
need guidance, Anakin.
In time, you will learn
to trust your feelings.
Then you will be invincible.
I have said it many times: You are
the most gifted Jedi I have ever met.
Thank you,
Your Excellency.
I see you becoming
the greatest of all the Jedi, Anakin...
even more powerful
than Master Yoda.
I am concerned
for my Padawan.
He is not ready to be given
this assignment on his own yet.
[Yoda] The council is confident
in its decision, Obi-Wan.
[Windu]
The boy has exceptional skills.
But he still has
much to learn, Master.
His abilities have made him,
well, arrogant.
Yes, yes.
A flaw more and more
common among Jedi.
Hmm.
Too sure of themselves
they are.
Even the older,
more experienced ones.
Remember, Obi-Wan,
if the prophecy is true...
your apprentice is the only one who
can bring the Force back into balance.
[Padmé] I'm taking
an extended leave of absence.
It will be your responsibility
to take my place in the senate.
- Representative Binks,
I know I can count on you.
- Hmm?
Mesa honored to be taking on
dissa heavy burden.
Mesa accept this with muy, muy humility
and, uh--
JarJar, I don't wish
to hold you up.
I'm sure you have
a great deal to do.
Of course.
Milady.
I do not like
this idea of hiding.
Don't worry.
Now that the council
has ordered an investigation...
it won't take Master Obi-Wan long
to find this bounty hunter.
I haven't worked for a year to defeat
the Military Creation Act...
to not be here when
its fate is decided.
Sometimes we must let go of our pride
and do what is requested of us.
Anakin,
you've grown up.
Master Obi-Wan
manages not to see it.
Don't get me wrong.
Obi-Wan is a great mentor.
As wise as Master Yoda and...
as powerful as Master Windu.
I am truly thankful
to be his apprentice.
In some ways--
a lot of ways--
I'm really ahead of him.
I'm ready for the trials...
but he feels that
I'm too unpredictable.
He won't let me move on.
- That must be frustrating.
- It's worse.
He's overly critical.
He never listens.
He-- He doesn't understand.
It's not fair!
All mentors have a way of seeing
more of our faults than we would like.
It's the only way we grow.
[Sighs]
I know.
Anakin.
Don't try to grow up too fast.
But I am grown up.
You said it yourself.
Please don't look
at me like that.
- Why not?
- It makes me feel uncomfortable.
Sorry, milady.
- Be safe, milady.
- Thank you, Captain.
Take good care of Dormé.
The threat's on you two now.
He'll be safe with me.
- You'll be fine.
- It's not me, milady.
I worry about you. What if they
realize you've left the capital?
Well, then my Jedi protector
will have to prove how good he is.
Anakin.
Don't do anything without first
consulting either myself or the council.
Yes, Master.
I'll get to the bottom
of this plot quickly, milady.
You'll be back here
in no time.
I'll be most grateful for
your speed, Master Jedi.
- It's time to go.
- I know.
Anakin, may the Force
be with you.
May the Force
be with you, Master.
Suddenly I'm afraid.
This is my first assignment
on my own. I am too.
Don't worry.
We have R2 with us.
- [Laughing]
- [Beeping]
I do hope he doesn't
try anything foolish.
I'd be more concerned
about her doing something than him.
Someone to see ya, honey!
Jedi, by the looks of him.
- Obi-Wan!
- Hello, Dex.
Take a seat.
I'll be right with ya.
- You wanna cup o'jawa juice?
- Oh, yes. Thank you.
Hey, old buddy!
[Both Laughing]
Ohhh.
[Coughs]
So, my friend,
what can I do for ya?
You can tell me
what this is.
Well, whattaya know!
I ain't seen one of these
since I was prospectin'...
on Subterrel,
beyond the outer rim.
[Obi-Wan] Can you tell me
where it came from? Thank you.
[Dex] This baby
belongs to them cloners.
What you got here
is a Kamino saberdart.
I wonder why it didn't show up
in the analysis archives.
It's these funny little cuts
on the side that give it away.
Those analysis droids
only focus on symbols. Huh!
I should think that you Jedi
would have more respect...
for the difference
between knowledge and...
[Laughing]
wisdom.
Well, if droids could think,
there'd be none of us here, would there?
Kamino. I'm not familiar with it.
Is it in the Republic?
No, no. It's beyond
the outer rim.
I'd say about,
uh, 12 parsecs...
outside the Rishi Maze.
Should be easy to find,
even for those droids in your archives.
[Chuckles]
These, uh, Kaminoans
keep to themselves.
They're cloners.
Damn good ones too.
- Cloners. Are they friendly?
- Oh, depends.
Depends on what, Dex?
On how good
your manners are...
and how big your, uh...
pocketbook is.
[Chuckling]
Hmm.
Did you call
for assistance?
- Yes, yes, I did.
- Are you having
a problem, Master Kenobi?
Yes, um, I'm looking for
a planetary system called Kamino.
- Kamino.
- It doesn't show up
on the archive charts.
Kamino. It's not a system
I'm familiar with.
Are you sure you have
the right coordinates?
According to my information, it should
appear in this quadrant here...
just south
of the Rishi Maze.
[Beeping]
I hate to say it, but it looks like
the system you're searching for...
doesn't exist.
Impossible. Perhaps the archives
are incomplete.
If an item does not appear
in our records...
it does not exist.
- Hey, you! No droids!
- [Beeping]
- Get outta here!
- [Raspberries]
- [Beeping]
- Thank you, R2.
- [Chirping]
- Must be difficult, having
sworn your life to the Jedi...
not being able to visit the places
you like or do the things you like.
Or be with the people
that I love.
Are you allowed to love?
I thought that was
forbidden for a Jedi.
Attachment is forbidden.
Possession is forbidden.
Compassion, which I would define
as unconditional love...
is central
to a Jedi's life.
So you might say that
we are encouraged to love.
- You've changed so much.
- Ah, you haven't changed a bit.
You're exactly the way
I remember you in my dreams.
[Yoda] Reach out.
Sense the Force around you.
Use your feelings
you must.
Younglings.
Younglings!
A visitor
we have.
[Together]
Hello, Master Obi-Wan.
Hello. I'm sorry
to disturb you, Master.
What help can I be,
Obi-Wan? Hmm?
I'm looking for a planet
described to me by an old friend.
I trust him, but the systems
don't show on the archive maps.
Mmm. Lost a planet
Master Obi-Wan has.
- How embarrassing.
- [Children Giggling]
How embarrassing.
Hmm?
Liam, the shades.
Gather round
the map reader.
Clear your minds...
and find Obi-Wan's
wayward planet we will.
It ought to be... here...
but it isn't.
Gravity is pulling all the stars
in the area towards this spot.
Hmm. Gravity's
silhouette remains...
but the star
and all the planets...
disappeared they have.
How can this be?
Hmm? A thought?
- [Yoda] Anyone.
- [Boy] Master?
Because someone erased it
from the archive memory.
[Yoda Chuckles]
Truly wonderful
the mind of a child is.
[Chuckling]
The Padawan is right.
Go to the center
of gravity's pull...
and find your planet
you will.
Hmm. The data
must have been erased.
But, Master Yoda, who could
empty information from the archives?
That's impossible, isn't it?
Dangerous and disturbing
this puzzle is.
Only a Jedi
could have erased those files.
But who and why,
harder to answer.
Meditate on this I will. Hmm.
I wasn't the youngest queen
ever elected...
but now that I think back on it,
I'm not sure I was old enough.
I'm not sure
I was ready.
The people you served
thought you did a good job.
I heard they even tried
to amend the constitution
so you could stay in office.
I was relieved when
my two terms were up.
But when the queen asked me
to serve as senator...
I couldn't refuse her.
I agree with her.
I think the Republic needs you.
I'm glad that you
chose to serve.
[Padmé] If the senate
votes to create an army...
- I'm sure it's going
to push us into a civil war.
- [Man] It's unthinkable.
There hasn't been a full-scale war
since the formation of the Republic.
Do you see any way
through negotiations...
to bring the separatists
back into the Republic?
Not if they feel threatened.
My guess is they'll turn
to the Trade Federations
or the Commerce Guilds for help.
It's outrageous, but after four trials
in the Supreme Court...
Nute Gunray is still the viceroy
of the Trade Federation.
I fear the senate is powerless
to resolve this crisis.
We must keep our faith
in the Republic.
The day we stop believing democracy
can work is the day we lose it.
Let's pray that day
never comes.
In the meantime,
we must consider your own safety.
What is your suggestion,
Master Jedi?
Oh, Anakin's
not a Jedi yet.
He's still a Padawan learner.
But I was thinking--
- Hold on a minute.
- Excuse me.
I was thinking I would stay
in the lake country.
There are some places up there
that are very isolated.
Excuse me. I'm in charge
of security here, milady.
And this is my home. I know it
very well. That is why we're here.
I think it would be wise
if you took advantage of
my knowledge in this instance.
Sorry, milady.
[Queen Jamillia]
Perfect. It's settled, then.
There it is, R4, right where it
should be. Our missing planet Kamino.
[Whistling, Beeping]
[Thunder Rumbling]
Master Jedi.
The prime minister
is expecting you.
- I'm expected?
- Of course.
He is anxious
to meet you.
After all these years...
we were beginning to think
you weren't coming.
Now, please, this way.
May I present Lama Su...
prime minister of Kamino.
And this is Master Jedi--
Obi-Wan Kenobi.
I trust you're going
to enjoy your stay.
Please.
And now to business.
You will be delighted
to hear that we are on schedule.
200,000 units
are ready...
with a million more
well on the way.
That's good news.
Please tell
your Master Sifo-Dyas...
that his order
will be met on time.
I'm sorry. Master--
Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas is still
a leading member of the Jedi Council...
is he not?
Master Sifo-Dyas was killed
almost ten years ago.
Oh, I'm so sorry
to hear that.
But I'm sure he would have been proud
of the army we've built for him.
- The army?
- Yes.
A clone army, and I must say,
one of the finest we've ever created.
Tell me, Prime Minister...
when my master
first contacted you about the army...
did-- did he say
who it was for?
Of course he did.
This army
is for the Republic.
But you must be anxious
to inspect the units for yourself.
That's why I'm here.
We used to come here
for school retreat.
We would swim
to that island every day.
I love the water.
We used to lie out on the sand
and let the sun dry us...
and try to guess the names
of the birds singing.
I don't like sand.
It's coarse and rough
and irritating...
and it gets everywhere.
Not like here.
Here, everything is soft...
and smooth.
No.
[Gasps]
I shouldn't have done that.
I'm sorry.
- Very impressive.
- I'd hoped you would be pleased.
[Lama Su]
Clones can think creatively.
You will find that they are
immensely superior to droids.
We take great pride in our combat
education and training programs.
This group was created
about five years ago.
[Obi-Wan] You mentioned
growth acceleration.
[Lama Su]
Oh, yes, it's essential.
Otherwise, a mature clone
would take a lifetime to grow.
Now we can do it
in half the time.
[Obi-Wan]
I see.
[Lama Su]
They are totally obedient...
taking any order
without question.
We modified
their genetic structure...
to make them less independent
than the original host.
And who was
the original host?
A bounty hunter
called Jango Fett.
And where is
this bounty hunter now?
Oh, we keep him here.
[Lama Su] Apart from his pay,
which is considerable...
Fett demanded
only one thing:
an unaltered clone
for himself.
- Curious, isn't it?
- "Unaltered"?
[Lama Su]
Pure genetic replication.
No tampering with the structure
to make it more docile...
and no growth acceleration.
I should very much like
to meet this Jango Fett.
I would be very happy
to arrange it for you.
Magnificent, aren't they?
- I don't know.
- [Chuckles]
Sure you do.
You just don't want to tell me.
You gonna use one of
your Jedi mind tricks on me?
They only work
on the weak-minded.
All right.
I was 12.
His name was Palo. We were both
in the Legislative Youth Program.
He was a few years older than I.
Very cute.
Dark, curly hair.
Dreamy eyes.
All right, I get the picture.
Whatever happened to him?
I went into public service;
he went on to become an artist.
- Maybe he was the smart one.
- You really don't like politicians,
do you?
I like two or three...
but I'm not really sure
about one of them.
[Both Chuckle]
I don't think
the system works.
How would you
have it work?
We need a system where the politicians
sit down and discuss the problem...
agree what's in the best interest
of all the people, and then do it.
That's exactly
what we do.
The trouble is that people
don't always agree.
Well, then they
should be made to.
- By whom? Who's gonna make them? You?
- I don't know. Someone.
- Of course not me.
- But someone.
Someone wise.
Sounds an awful lot like
a dictatorship to me.
Well, if it works.
- You're making fun of me.
- No.
I'd be much too frightened
to tease a senator.
[Creature Bellowing]
[Anakin]
Whoa, whoa!
[Laughing]
- [Bellowing]
- Oh, whoa! [Grunting]
- [Lowing]
- [Grunts, Groans]
Ani! Ani, are you all right?
[Laughing]
[Both Laughing]
[Beeping]
Boba, is your father here?
Yep.
May we see him?
Sure.
Dad, Taun We's here.
[Thunder Rumbling]
Jango, welcome back.
Was your trip productive?
Fairly.
This is Jedi Master
Obi-Wan Kenobi.
He's come to check
on our progress.
Your clones are very impressive.
You must be very proud.
I'm just a simple man
trying to make my way in the universe.
Ever made your way as far into
the interior as Coruscant?
- Once or twice.
- Recently?
Possibly.
Then you must know
Master Sifo-Dyas.
Uh, Boba,
rood eht so-heeck.
Master who?
[Obi-Wan]
Sifo-Dyas.
Is he not the Jedi
who hired you for this job?
Never heard of him.
Really?
I was recruited by a man called Tyranus
on one of the moons of Bogden.
Curious.
Do you like your army?
I look forward
to seeing them in action.
They'll do their job well.
I'll guarantee that.
Thank you for
your time, Jango.
Always a pleasure
to meet a Jedi.
[Thunder Rumbling]
What is it, Dad?
Pack your things.
We're leaving.
And when I got to them, we went into
aggressive negotiations. Thank you.
"Aggressive negotiations"?
What's that?
Uh, well, negotiations
with a lightsaber.
- [Laughing] Oh.
- [Laughing]
If Master Obi-Wan caught me
doing this, he'd be very grumpy.
From the moment
I met you...
all those years ago...
not a day has gone by
when I haven't thought of you.
And now that
I'm with you again...
I'm in agony.
The closer I get to you,
the worse it gets.
The thought of
not being with you--
I can't breathe.
I'm haunted by the kiss
that you should never have given me.
My heart is beating...
hoping that that kiss
will not become a scar.
You are in my very soul...
tormenting me.
What can I do?
I will do anything that you ask.
If you are suffering
as much as I am, please, tell me.
I can't.
We can't.
It's... just not possible.
Anything is possible, Padmé.
Listen to me.
No, you listen.
We live in a real world.
Come back to it.
You're studying to become a Jedi.
I'm-- I'm a senator.
If you follow your thoughts
through to conclusion...
it'll take us to a place
we cannot go...
regardless of the way
we feel about each other.
Then you do feel something.
I will not let you
give up your future for me.
You are asking me
to be rational.
That is something
I know I cannot do.
Believe me, I wish that I could
just wish away my feelings...
but I can't.
I will not give in to this.
Well, you know, it...
wouldn't have to
be that way.
We could keep it a secret.
We'd be living a lie...
one we couldn't keep
even if we wanted to.
I couldn't do that.
Could you, Anakin?
Could you live like that?
No. You're right.
It would destroy us.
Tell your council that
the first battalions are ready.
And remind them,
if they need more troops...
it will take more time
to grow them.
- I won't forget, and thank you.
- Thank you.
- R4!
- [Beeping]
Scramble code five to Coruscant,
care of the old folks' home!
[Beeping]
I have successfully made contact
with the prime minister of Kamino.
They are using a bounty hunter named
Jango Fett to create a clone army.
I have a strong feeling
that this bounty hunter...
is the assassin
we are looking for.
Do you think these cloners
are involved in the plot
to assassinate Senator Amidala?
No, Master.
There appears to be no motive.
[Yoda] Do not assume
anything, Obi-Wan.
Clear your mind must be...
if you are to discover
the real villains behind this plot.
Yes, Master.
They say Master Sifo-Dyas
placed an order for a clone army...
at the request of the senate
almost ten years ago.
I was under the impression
he was killed before that.
Did the council ever authorize
the creation of a clone army?
No. Whoever placed that order
did not have the authorization
of the Jedi Council.
Bring him here.
Question him we will.
Yes, Master.
I will report back when I have him.
Blind we are if creation
of this clone army...
we could not see.
[Sighs]
I think it is time
we informed the senate...
that our ability to use
the Force has diminished.
Only the dark lord of the Sith
knows of our weakness.
If informed the senate is...
multiply our adversaries will.
No.
Mom, no.
Don't. No.
No.
Don't go.
I don't want to disturb you.
Your presence is soothing.
You had another nightmare
last night.
Jedi don't have nightmares.
I heard you.
I saw my mother.
She is suffering, Padmé.
I saw her as clearly
as I see you now.
[Deep Sigh]
She is in pain.
I know I'm disobeying my mandate
to protect you, Senator...
but I have to go.
I have to help her.
I'll go with you.
I'm sorry.
I don't have a choice.
[Thunder Rumbling]
Dad, look!
Boba, get on board!
- [Jango Shouts]
- Oh, not good. [Grunts]
[Driver Speaking Huttese]
- Wait right there.
- Okey-okey.
Da wanga!
Chut-chut, Watto.
[Speaking Huttese]
Let me help you with that.
What? What do you want?
Wait! You're a Jedi!
[Grunts]
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
Ai!
[Grunts, Sighs]
I'm looking for Shmi Skywalker.
- [Fly Buzzing]
- Ani?
Little Ani?
Nahhh.
You are Ani! It is you!
[Laughing]
You sure sprouted, huh?
Wee-hoo!
A Jedi! Whattaya know!
[Chuckles]
Hey... maybe you could
help with some deadbeats
who owe me a lot of money.
My mother.
Oh, yeah. Shmi.
Uh... she's not mine-a
no more-a. I sold her.
- You sold her?
- Years ago.
Sorry, Ani, but you know,
business is business, huh?
[Chuckles]
Yeah, I sold her to
a moisture farmer named, uh, Lars.
At least I think
it was Lars.
Believe it or not, I heard
he freed her and married her!
Can ya beat that, eh?
[Chuckles] Yeah.
Do you know
where they are now?
Ooh, long way
from here.
Someplace over on the other side
of Mos Eisley, I think, mmm.
I'd like to know.
Eh, sure. Absolutely!
[Chuckles] Let's go
look at my records, huh?
[Chuckles]
Mmm.
- [Beeping]
- Dad!
I think we're being tracked!
[Jango] He must have put
a homing device on our hull.
Hang on, son.
We'll move into the asteroid field...
and we'll have a couple
of surprises for him.
[Cackling]
[Beeping]
Seismic charges!
Stand by.
[Beeping]
He doesn't seem
to take a hint, this guy.
Watch out!
- [Rapid Beeping]
- Get him, Dad! Get him! Fire!
Oh, blast!
This is why I hate flying!
- We got him!
- We'll just have to finish him.
- R4, prepare to jettison
the spare part canisters.
- [Beeping]
- Fire them now!
- Well, we won't be seeing him again.
- [Chuckles]
- Well, R4, I think
we've waited long enough.
- [Beeping]
There's an unusual concentration
of Federation ships over there, R4.
[R4 Beeps]
[Beeping]
- [R2-D2 Whistles, Beeps]
- [Padmé] Stay with the ship, R2.
[Beeping]
Oh! Um, uh, hello.
How might I be of service?
I am C--
- 3PO?
- Oh, um--
The maker!
Oh, Master Ani!
I knew you would return.
I knew it!
And Miss Padmé. Oh, my.
Hello, 3PO.
Bless my circuits!
I'm so pleased to see you both.
I've come to see my mother.
Oh. Um, I think perhaps
we'd better go indoors.
Master Owen, might I present
two most important visitors.
I'm Anakin Skywalker.
Owen Lars. Uh, this is
my girlfriend, Beru.
- Hello.
- I'm Padmé.
I guess
I'm your stepbrother.
I had a feeling
you might show up someday.
- Is my mother here?
- No, she's not.
Cliegg Lars.
Shmi is my wife.
We should go inside.
We have a lot to talk about.
[Cliegg] It was just before dawn.
They came out of nowhere.
A hunting party
of Tusken Raiders.
Your mother had gone out early,
like she always did...
to pick mushrooms
that grow on the vaporators.
From the tracks,
she was about halfway home...
when they took her.
[Sighs]
Those Tuskens walk like men...
but they're vicious,
mindless monsters.
Thirty of us went out after her.
Four of us came back.
I'd be out there with them,
but after I lost my leg...
I just couldn't ride anymore
un-until I heal.
I don't want
to give up on her...
but she's been gone a month.
There's little hope
she's lasted this long.
Where are you going?
To find my mother.
Your mother's dead, son.
Accept it.
You're gonna have to stay here.
These are good people, Padmé.
You'll be safe.
Anakin--
I won't be long.
[Machinery Clanging]
[Man #1] We must persuade
the Commerce Guild...
and the Corporate Alliance
to sign the treaty.
What about the senator
from Naboo?
Is she dead yet?
I am not signing your treaty
until I have her head on my desk.
[Man #1]
I am a man of my word, Viceroy.
[Alien] With these new battle droids
we've built for you...
you'll have the finest army
in the galaxy.
[Man #1]
As I explained to you earlier...
I am quite convinced
that 10,000 more systems...
will rally to our cause
with your support, gentlemen.
[Speaking In Alien Language]
What you are proposing
could be construed as treason.
The Techno Union army...
[Electronic Warbling]
is at your disposal, Count.
The Banking Clan
will sign your treaty.
[Man #1]
Good. Very good.
Our friends from the Trade Federation
have pledged their support...
and when their battle droids
are combined with yours...
we shall have an army
greater than any in the galaxy.
The Jedi
will be overwhelmed.
The Republic will agree
to any demands we make.
[Growling]
[Snarling]
[Growling, Snarling
Continue]
[Growling]
[Moaning]
Mom.
Mom? Mom?
Ani?
Ani? Is it you?
I'm here, Mom.
You're safe.
Ani?
Oh, you look
so handsome.
My son.
Oh, my grown-up son.
I'm so proud of you, Ani.
I missed you.
Now I am complete.
I love y--
Stay with me, Mom.
Everything--
I love--
I-- I love--
[Groaning]
[Shouting]
[Screaming]
[Qui-Gon Jinn's Voice]
Anakin! Anakin! No-o-o!
What is it?
Pain, suffering...
death I feel.
Something terrible
has happened.
Young Skywalker is in pain.
Terrible pain.
The transmitter is working,
but we're not receiving a return signal.
Coruscant's too far.
R4, can you boost the power?
- [Beeping]
- We'll have to try something else.
[Beeping]
Maybe we can contact Anakin
on Naboo. It's much closer.
Anakin?
Anakin, do you copy?
This is Obi-Wan Kenobi.
Anakin?
He's not on Naboo, R4.
[Beeping]
I'm going to try
and widen the range.
I do hope nothing's
happened to him.
That's Anakin's tracking signal,
all right...
but it's coming
from Tatooine.
What in the blazes
is he doing there?
I told him to stay on Naboo.
[Beeping]
We haven't got
much time.
Anakin?
Anakin, do you copy?
- This is Obi-Wan Kenobi.
- [Creature Screeching]
[Static,
Obi-Wan's Voice Breaks Up]
Retransmit this message--
[Garbled Audio]
Anakin, do you copy?
Anakin--
My long-range-- [Static]
has been knocked out.
- Retransmit this message to Coruscant.
- [Beeping]
I brought you something.
Are you hungry?
The shifter broke.
Life seems so much simpler
when you're fixing things.
I'm good at fixing things.
Always was.
But I couldn't--
Why'd she have to die?
Why couldn't I save her?
I know I could have!
Sometimes there are things
no one can fix.
- You're not all-powerful, Ani.
- Well, I should be!
Someday I will be.
I will be
the most powerful Jedi ever!
I promise you.
I will even learn
to stop people from dying.
Anakin.
It's all Obi-Wan's fault!
He's jealous!
He's holding me back!
- [Object Clattering]
- [Sniffling]
What's wrong, Ani?
I--
I killed them.
I killed them all.
They're dead.
Every single one of them.
And not just the men...
but the women...
and the children too.
They're like animals,
and I slaughtered them like animals!
I hate them!
[Anakin Exhales]
To be angry
is to be human.
I'm a Jedi.
I know I'm better than this.
[Cliegg] I know wherever you are
it's become a better place.
You were the most loving partner
a man could ever have.
Good-bye, my darling wife.
And thank you.
I wasn't strong enough
to save you, Mom.
I wasn't strong enough.
But I promise
I won't fail again.
I miss you...
so much.
[Beeping]
R2? What are you
doing here?
[Beeping]
It seems that he is carrying a message
from an Obi-Wan Kenobi.
Hmm. Master Ani, does that name
mean anything to you?
[Beeping]
Anakin, my long-range transmitter
has been knocked out.
Retransmit this message
to Coruscant.
I have tracked the bounty hunter,
Jango Fett...
to the droid foundries
on Geonosis.
The Trade Federation is to take
delivery of a droid army here...
and it is clear
that Viceroy Gunray...
is behind the assassination attempts
on Senator Amidala.
The Commerce Guilds
and the Corporate Alliance...
have both pledged their armies
to Count Dooku and are forming a--
Wait. Wait.
- [Lightsaber Whooshing]
- [Obi-Wan Grunting]
More happening on Geonosis, I feel,
than has been revealed.
I agree.
Anakin, we will deal
with Count Dooku.
The most important thing for you
is to stay where you are.
Protect the senator
at all costs.
That is your first priority.
Understood, Master.
They'll never get there
in time to save him.
They have to come halfway
across the galaxy. Look.
Geonosis is
less than a parsec away.
If he's still alive.
Ani, are you just gonna sit here
and let him die?
- He's your friend, your mentor. He's--
- He's like my father!
But you heard Master Windu.
He gave me strict orders to stay here!
He gave you strict orders
to protect me...
and I'm going to help Obi-Wan.
- If you plan to protect me,
you'll just have to come along.
- [Engines Power Up]
I'm not worried, R2.
It's just I've never flown before.
The Commerce Guilds are preparing
for war. There can be no doubt of that.
[Palpatine] Count Dooku
must have made a treaty with them.
[Speaking In Alien Language]
The debate is over.
Now we need that clone army.
Unfortunately,
the debate is not over.
The senate will never approve the use
of clones before the separatists attack.
This is a crisis.
The senate must vote the chancellor
emergency powers.
He can then approve
the creation of an army.
But what senator would have the courage
to propose such a radical amendment?
If only...
Senator Amidala were here.
Mm.
[Screeching]
[Grumbling]
Traitor.
Oh, no, my friend.
This is a mistake, a terrible mistake.
They have gone too far.
This is madness.
I thought you were
the leader here, Dooku.
This had nothing to do with me,
I assure you.
I will petition immediately
to have you set free.
Well, I hope it doesn't take
too long. I have work to do.
May I ask why a Jedi knight...
is all the way out here
on Geonosis?
I've been tracking a bounty hunter
named Jango Fett.
Do you know him?
There are no bounty hunters here
that I am aware of.
The Geonosians
don't trust them.
Who can blame them?
But he is here, I can assure you.
It's a great pity that our paths
have never crossed before, Obi-Wan.
Qui-Gon always spoke
very highly of you.
I wish he were still alive.
I could use his help right now.
Qui-Gon Jinn
would never join you.
Don't be so sure,
my young Jedi.
You forget that he was once
my apprentice...
just as you
were once his.
He knew all about
the corruption in the senate...
but he would never have
gone along with it if he had
learned the truth as I have.
- The truth?
- The truth.
What if I told you
that the Republic...
was now under the control
of the dark lord of the Sith?
No, that's not possible.
The Jedi would be aware of it.
The dark side of the Force
has clouded their vision, my friend.
Hundreds of senators
are now under the influence...
of a Sith lord
called Darth Sidious.
I don't believe you.
The viceroy
of the Trade Federation...
was once in league
with this Darth Sidious...
but he was betrayed
ten years ago by the dark lord.
He came to me for help.
He told me everything.
You must join me, Obi-Wan...
and together
we will destroy the Sith!
I will never join you, Dooku.
It may be difficult
to secure your release.
[JarJar] It's-a clear
desa separatists made a pact...
wesa desa
Federation du Trade.
Senators, "dellow felagates":
In response to this direct threat
to the Republic...
mesa propose
that the senate...
give immediately
emergency powers...
to the supreme chancellor.
[Shouts Of Approval]
Palpatine! Palpatine! Palpatine!
[Shouting In Alien Language]
[Senate Chairman]
Order! We shall have order!
It is with great reluctance...
that I have agreed
to this calling.
- I love democracy.
I love the Republic.
- [Applause]
The power you give me...
I will lay down
when this crisis has abated.
[Cheering, Applause]
And as my first act
with this new authority...
I will create a grand army
of the Republic...
to counter the increasing threats
of the separatists.
It is done, then.
Hmm.
I will take what Jedi we have left
and go to Geonosis and help Obi-Wan.
Visit I will
the cloners on Kamino, hmm...
and see this army they have
created for the Republic.
See those columns of steam
straight ahead?
They're exhaust vents
of some type.
That'll do.
Look, whatever happens
out there, follow my lead.
I'm not interested
in getting into a war here.
As a member
of the senate...
maybe I can find
a diplomatic solution to this mess.
Don't worry. I've given up
trying to argue with you.
[Whistling, Beeping]
My obtuse little friend,
if they had needed our help...
they would have
asked for it, hmm?
You obviously have a great deal
to learn about human behavior.
[Beeping]
- [Beeping]
- For a mechanic...
you seem to do
an excessive amount of thinking.
- [Beeping]
- I am programmed
to understand humans!
[Beeping]
"What does that mean?" Oh!
- That means I am in charge here!
- [Raspberries]
Where are you going now?
You don't know what's out there.
Have you no sense at all?
Oh! Idiot!
- Please wait.
- [Beeping]
Do you know
where you're going?
Wait.
[Squawking]
Oh, my--
Oh, oh, oh!
- [Screaming]
- Padmé!
Ah!
[Grunts]
Oh, my goodness!
Shut me down!
Machines making machines.
Huh! How perverse.
[Grunts] Oh!
Calm down, R2.
I almost fell.
You'll get your chance--
Oh! I'm scrap.
[Grunting]
It's a nightmare!
Oh, I want to go home! Ahh!
Oh, what did I do
to deserve this?
[Beeping]
[Whistling]
- [Padmé Grunting]
- [Geonosian Screeching]
Ahhh!
- [Whistling]
- Hmm. I wonder what happened
to poor little R2.
He's always getting himself
into trouble. Oops.
Oh, no!
Uh-oh.
Oh!
Oh, I'm so confused.
Oh, not again.
Obi-Wan's gonna kill me.
Don't move, Jedi!
Take him away.
Don't be afraid.
I'm not afraid to die.
I've been dying a little bit each day
since you came back into my life.
What are you talking about?
I love you.
You love me?
I thought that we had decided
not to fall in love...
that we would be forced
to live a lie...
and that it would
destroy our lives.
I think our lives are about
to be destroyed anyway.
I truly...
deeply love you...
and before we die,
I want you to know.
Eeyah!
[Loud Cheering]
[Cheering]
I was beginning to wonder
if you'd got my message.
I retransmitted it just as
you had requested, Master.
Then we decided
to come and rescue you.
Good job.
[Cheering]
[Speaking In Geonosian]
Settle down. Settle down.
[Cheering Subsides]
[Speaking In Geonosian]
Let the executions begin.
[Cheering]
[Roaring]
[Screeching]
I've got a bad feeling
about this.
- [Shouting]
- [Bellowing]
[Creatures Roaring]
[Crowd Cheering]
[Snarling]
- Just relax. Concentrate.
- What about Padmé?
She seems to be
on top of things.
[Roaring]
[Bellowing]
- [Screaming]
- [Snarling]
[Chuckling]
[Yelling]
[Creature Yelps]
She can't do that!
Shoot her or-- or something!
[Whimpering, Snarling]
- [Shrieking]
- [Roaring]
[Hissing, Growling]
[Screaming]
[Subdued Growling]
- Whoa! Yah!
- [Growling, Roaring]
Hyah! Hyah!
[Cheering]
- [Snarling]
- [Bellowing]
Jump!
Hyah! Hyah!
[Shrieking]
- [Cheering]
- [Shouting]
This isn't how it's supposed to be!
Jango! Finish her off!
Patience, Viceroy, patience.
She will die.
Master Windu,
how pleasant of you to join us.
This party's over.
Brave but, uh, foolish,
my old Jedi friend.
- You're impossibly outnumbered.
- [Scoffs] I don't think so.
- We'll see.
- [Heavy Footsteps Approaching]
[Synthesized Voice]
My legs aren't moving.
I must need maintenance.
[C-3PO]
What's all this noise?
A-A battle!
Oh, there's been
some terrible mistake!
I'm programmed for etiquette,
not destruction!
- [Roaring]
- [Obi-Wan Grunts]
[Roaring]
[Groaning, Yelling]
[Yowling]
Die, Jedi dogs!
Oh! What did I say?
Hah!
Oh, dear.
I'm terribly sorry about all this.
Ohh!
Excuse me. I'm trapped.
I can't get up.
You call this
a diplomatic solution?
No, I call it
aggressive negotiations.
- Uh-oh.
- Roger, roger.
[Growling, Screeching]
[Creature Shrieking]
- [Beeping]
- R2, what are you doing here?
[Beeping]
What are you doing?
Oh, stop that!
You're going to strain
something. My neck!
- Now where are you taking me?
Oh, this is such a drag.
- [Beeping]
[C-3PO]
Oh, I'm quite beside myself.
R2, please be careful!
You're singeing my circuits!
- [Beeping]
- Yes, but is my head on straight?
[Dooku] Master Windu,
you have fought gallantly...
worthy of recognition
in the archives of the Jedi order.
Now it is finished.
Surrender,
and your lives will be spared.
We will not be hostages
to be bartered, Dooku!
Then, I'm sorry, old friend.
Look!
Around the survivors
a perimeter create.
[Beeping, Chirping]
Oh, I've had
the most peculiar dream.
If Dooku escapes...
rally more systems
to his cause he will.
Hold on!
Aim right above
the fuel cells!
Good call,
my young Padawan.
[Viceroy Gunray]
The Jedi have amassed a huge army.
That doesn't seem possible.
How could the Jedi
come up with an army so quickly?
We must send all available droids
into battle.
There are too many.
[Speaking In Geonosian]
Our communications have been jammed.
- Pilot, land in that assembly area!
- Yes, sir.
Sir, I have five special commando units
awaiting your orders, sir.
To the forward
command center take me.
Attack those Federation starships!
Quickly!
Master Yoda,
all forward positions are advancing.
Very good.
[Viceroy Gunray]
This is not looking good at all!
We must get the starships
back into space.
[Speaking In Geonosian]
We have to order a retreat.
My master
will never allow the Republic...
to get away
with this treachery.
[Speaking In Geonosian]
I'm sending my warriors
to hide in the catacombs.
The Jedi must not find
our designs for the ultimate weapon.
If they find out what we are planning
to build, we're doomed.
[Geonosian]
I will take the designs
with me to Coruscant.
They will be much safer there
with my master.
[Alarm Blaring]
Concentrate all your fire
on the nearest starship.
Yes, sir.
Move all quadrants
to sector 5-1 -5.
Look over there!
It's Dooku!
Shoot him down!
We're out of rockets, sir.
- Follow him!
- We're gonna need some help!
There isn't time!
Anakin and I can handle this!
[Beeping]
- [Padmé Yells]
- [Anakin] Padmé!
- Put the ship down!
- Anakin!
Don't let your personal feelings
get in the way! Follow that speeder!
- Lower the ship!
- I can't take Dooku alone!
I need you! If we catch him,
we can end this war right now!
- We have a job to do!
- I don't care! Put the ship down!
You will be expelled
from the Jedi order!
- I can't leave her!
- Come to your senses!
What do you think Padmé would do
were she in your position?
She would do her duty.
Hmm.
The droid army
is in full retreat.
Well done, Commander.
Bring me a ship.
[Anakin] You're gonna pay for all
the Jedi that you killed today, Dooku.
- We'll take him together.
Go in slowly on the left.
- I'm taking him now!
No, Anakin! No! No!
[Anakin Screams]
As you see, my Jedi powers
are far beyond yours.
Now... back down.
I don't think so.
Master Kenobi,
you disappoint me.
Yoda holds you
in such high esteem.
Surely you can do better.
[Moaning]
[Groaning]
Are you all right?
Uh-huh.
- We'd better get back to
the forward command center.
- No. No.
Gather what troops you can.
We've got to get to that hangar.
- Get a transport. Hurry!
- Right away.
[Moaning]
Ah! Ahh!
[Anakin Shouts]
Brave of you, boy.
But I would have thought
you had learned your lesson.
- I am a slow learner.
- Anakin!
[Grunting]
- Master Yoda.
- Count Dooku.
You have interfered with our affairs
for the last time.
[Growling]
Powerful you have become,
Dooku.
The dark side I sense in you.
I've become more powerful
than any Jedi.
Even you.
Much to learn you still have.
It is obvious that
this contest cannot be decided
by our knowledge of the Force...
but by our skills
with a lightsaber.
[Yelling]
Fought well you have,
my old Padawan.
This is just the beginning.
[Speaking In
Droid Language]
[Panting, Moaning]
[Sighing]
- [Grunts]
- [Obi-Wan Groans]
[Padmé]
Anakin!
The Force is with us,
Master Sidious.
Welcome home,
Lord Tyranus.
You have done well.
I have good news
for you, my lord.
- The war has begun.
- Excellent.
Everything is going
as planned.
[Obi-Wan] Do you believe
what Count Dooku said...
about Sidious
controlling the senate?
It doesn't feel right.
Joined the dark side
Dooku has.
Mmm. Lies, deceit...
creating mistrust
are his ways now.
[Windu] Nevertheless, I feel we
should keep a closer eye on the senate.
I agree.
Where is your apprentice?
On his way to Naboo,
escorting Senator Amidala home.
I have to admit that
without the clones,
it would not have been a victory.
[Yoda]
Victory?
Victory, you say?
Master Obi-Wan,
not victory.
The shroud of the dark side
has fallen.
Begun the Clone War has.