Hi, sis.
Michael, if I could just get you
to sign this right here...
...which gives you the contents
of the safe deposit box.
Thank you.
And this one which clears the bank...
...of all responsibility
for the contents.
It's kind of exciting.
Maybe we'll find out
that your mother had secret millions.
Why don't we get started?
Your mother is interred...
...at the Cedar Heights Funeral Home
until arrangements can be made.
I thought it was arranged.
-There's a problem.
-What problem?
Your mother left explicit instructions
to be cremated.
-I don't understand it either.
-When did she decide this?
Apparently just before her death.
-I don't know anybody who gets cremated.
-Lots of people do.
Nobody in my family did.
Dad bought plots at Prairie Hills...
...one for him, one for Mom.
-The will clearly states...
-I don't care what it says.
Maybe Mom was delirious. Maybe
she didn't know what she was saying.
If she wanted to be cremated, why
the hell did she let Dad buy 2 plots?
She was very specific.
She wanted her ashes to be thrown off
Roseman Bridge.
-What?!
-Bizarre!
Mr. Peterson, are you sure
Mom wrote all this?
It was notarized and witnessed by
Mrs. Lucy Delaney.
-Maybe you could ask her.
-Who the hell is she?
I remember her, I just don't...
I don't care if it's legal. We're
not cremating her or throwing...
...her ashes off some bridge
where we can't visit her...
...because she'll be blown all over!
-And people driving all over her, dogs...
-We're not doing it.
I'm not even sure
it's Christian.
Maybe it's an Italian thing.
She was Italian.
Doesn't matter!
Move on.
We can come back to this.
Why don't we open the box?
Michael, look at these.
Have you ever seen these pictures?
It was in this envelope from 1965.
She's not wearing a bra.
That's the Holliwell Bridge.
-In case anyone's interested.
-Why are there 2 deeds here?
This is for the additional acres
he purchased in’59.
And this?
Those were bills of sale
from equipment your mother sold.
-This is for the original land parcel.
-Beautiful picture of her.
What?
Could you come here for a minute?
Where are we going?
She say anything in there about me?
About leaving me anything?
No.
What's going on?
We were just wondering
if it might be better...
...if Carolyn and I
looked at this stuff ourselves.
We don't want to keep you
waiting around.
I'll contact your office
about the legal work.
"I struggle to...
...put it together in a way
that allows me to continue...
...knowing that we're
on separate roads.
But then, I look through the lens
of my camera and you're there.
I start to write an article
and I find myself writing it to you.
It's clear to me now that we
have been moving towards each other...
...towards those 4 days,
all of our lives."
I don't want to hear anymore.
Burn the damn thing.
I don't want to hear it.
Throw it away.
What's he saying now?
He just goes on about how
if Mom ever needed him...
...she could reach him through the
National Geographic Magazine in D.C.
He was a photographer.
He promises not to write again.
And then, all it says is:
"I love you, Robert."
Robert!
Jesus!
I'll kill him.
That would be some trick. He's dead.
That's what this letter is...
...from his attorney.
He left most of his things to Mom.
And requested...
What?
That he be cremated and his ashes
thrown off Roseman Bridge.
Damn him! I knew Mom
wouldn't have thought that up herself.
It was some damn perverted...
...photographic mind influencing her.
When did the bastard die?
'82.
Wait a minute, that was...
...3 years after Daddy...
Do you think...?
I don't know!
I'm completely in the dark.
That's what I get for moving away.
We were kids when this happened.
I can't believe it.
Do you think that she...
...had sex with him?
Must be nice inside your head
with Peter Pan and the Easter Bunny.
Don't talk to me like that.
She was my mother!
Now I find that she was...
She was a...
A what?
Don't say that!
What am I supposed to think?
I can't believe she never told me.
We spoke at least once a week.
How could she do that?
When did she meet him?
Did Dad know?
Is there anything else in that envelope?
No, I don't think so.
You read it.
"January, 1987.
Dear Carolyn:
I hope you read this with Michael.
I'm sure he wouldn't be able
to read it by himself...
...and he'll need help
understanding all this.
First and most of all...
...I love you both very much.
And although I feel fine,
I thought I'd put my affairs...
...excuse that word, in order."
I can't believe she's making jokes.
"After going through
the safe deposit box...
...I'm sure you'll find your way
to this letter.
It's hard to write this
to my own children.
I could let this die
with the rest of me, I suppose.
But as one gets older...
...one's fears subside.
What becomes more and more important...
...is to be known.
Known for all that you were
during this brief stay.
How sad it seems to leave this earth...
...without those you love the most
ever really knowing who you were.
It's easy for a mother to love
her children, no matter what.
I don't know
if it's as simple for children.
You're all so busy being angry
at us for raising you wrong.
His name was Robert Kincaid.
He was a photographer
and he was here in 1965...
...shooting a National Geographic
article...
...on the covered bridges
of Madison County.
Remember when we got that issue,
when we got the subscription...
...how we felt like celebrities?"
That's Roseman Bridge.
That must be Robert Kincaid.
And that's Mom's medallion.
"I don't want you to be angry with him.
I hope after you know the story,
you think well of him, even grateful."
-Grateful?
-"It's all there in the 3 notebooks."
"It was the week
of the Illinois State Fair.
The two of you were going
with Dad to exhibit...
...Carolyn's prize steer.
It was the Sunday night you left.
I know it sounds awful..."
But I couldn't wait for you to leave.
You were going to be gone until Friday.
4 days.
Just 4 days.
Richard! Dinner!
-What I tell you about the door?
-Sorry.
Would you like to say grace?
Grace.
More sauces.
A piece of bread.
Thanks.
Damn drawer.
Here.
You can't get mad at it.
Sorry. Didn't mean to yell.
I want you to stay away
from anything too spicy.
And you promise me.
I swear. Only filters.
No more than half pack a day.
-I've got my orders.
-Doc Reynolds said so.
I know, I'm only kidding.
-Are you sure you don't want to go?
-I'm positive.
What are you going to do
as a woman of leisure?
Same thing I do as a hired hand,
except with less help.
I won't be able to sleep. I can't sleep
without you next to me anymore.
It's only 4 days.
Oh, God, where have you been?
You missed them.
They already left.
Why do you love me so much?
I don't like you.
Get down.
You like that song?
It's just you and me.
Just you and me.
Hi.
I get the distinct feeling
that I'm lost.
You supposed to be in Iowa?
Then you're not that lost.
I'm looking for a bridge.
One of those covered bridges
in this neighborhood.
Roseman Bridge?
That's it.
You're pretty close.
It's only about 2 miles from here.
Which way?
You go that way and come to Cutter's
and turn left.
To Cutters?
Cutter's a farm.
Small house, close to the road.
Big, mean yellow dog.
Mean yellow dog. Okay.
Then you go along that road
until you come to a fork.
It's only...
Less than half a mile.
And then where, after the fork?
The right.
And then you...
No, no. Not that fork.
Excuse me.
You pass Peterson's.
Peterson's.
Peterson's is a farm.
Past the old schoolhouse, you turn left.
It'd be easier to tell you...
...if the roads were marked.
It certainly would.
I can take you if you want.
Or I can tell you.
I can take you
or tell you.
It's up to you.
I don't care.
I wouldn't want to take you away.
No, I was just going to have
some iced tea, and then...
...split the atom,
but that can wait.
Okay.
I'll just get my shoes.
I wasn't exactly expecting company.
Where are we headed?
Out. Then right.
Out...
...then right.
Wonderful smell to Iowa. Kind of
particular to this part of the country.
You know what I mean?
No.
It's kind of hard to explain.
I guess it's in the loam of the soil.
That kind of rich, earthy...
...alive...
Well, maybe not alive.
You don't smell it?
Maybe it's because I live here.
Yeah, I guess so.
Smells great though.
Are you from Washington?
I lived there till I was in my mid-20s.
I moved to Chicago
when I got married.
When did you move back?
After the divorce.
How long have you been married?
Long time.
Long time, huh?
Where are you from?
Do you mind me asking?
I don't mind your asking.
I'm from...
-I'm born in Italy.
-Italy?
From Italy to Iowa.
Where in Italy?
We lived in a small town
on the eastern side.
No one's heard of it.
Bari.
I know Bari.
I was on assignment to Greece...
...and I went through Bari
to get to Brindisi.
I was looking out,
it looked like pretty country.
So I got off the train
and stayed a few days.
You got off the train
because it looked pretty?
Yeah, I did.
Excuse me.
Care for a cigarette?
Sure, I'll have one.
So tell me, how long
have you lived in Iowa?
Long.
You just got off the train...
...and stayed
without knowing anyone there?
That's it.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, this is great.
I won't shoot this today.
I'll just do a little prep work.
Shoot it tomorrow.
The light's no good right now.
So I'll just wait.
I don't mind.
Go on down here.
This is about as good a place
to start as any.
Beautiful bridge.
Beautiful.
You out here much?
No.
Always this hot around here?
Oh, yes. This time of year.
There's some sodas in the truck
if you'd like one.
-Would you like one?
-Not right now.
I'll go get one.
There you are.
You caught me.
I was picking you some flowers.
Men still do that, don't they?
I'm not out of date, am I?
Picking flowers
as a sign of appreciation?
No, except those are poisonous.
I'm kidding!
I'm sorry.
I'm just kidding.
I'm so sorry.
Are you sadistic by nature or what?
I don't know why I did that.
-Here.
-They're beautiful.
I'm sorry.
You're looking for something specific?
There's not much selection.
I had a station out of Chicago earlier.
Played good blues.
It's 1410.
That's nice.
Care for another cigarette?
Sure.
Is that the mean yellow dog?
-Is it white?
-No, it's yellow.
I want to thank you for all
your kindness, Mrs. Johnson.
Francesca.
Robert.
Would you like some iced tea?
Yeah.
Now I'm alone with you
Yes, sit down.
-You like lemon?
-Sure.
Maybe...
...a little bit of sugar?
You bet.
If you want more...
Thanks.
Aren't you afraid to have those in here?
I'm so sorry I did that.
I don't know why...
...why I said that.
Where are you staying?
Some place with small cabins.
Something or other motor inn.
I've got it written down,
but I haven't checked in yet.
And how long are you here for?
I don't know, maybe 4 or 5 days,
a week on the outside.
As long as it takes to do the work.
Where's your family?
My husband took the kids
to the state fair.
My daughter is entering a prize steer.
How old?
A year and a half.
No, I meant the kids.
Michael is 17.
And Carolyn is 16.
That's nice, having kids.
They're not kids anymore.
Things change.
They always do.
One of the laws of nature.
Most people are afraid of change,
but if you look at it...
...as something you can count on,
then it can be a comfort.
There's not many things
you can really count on.
I guess.
I'm one of those people
it frightens, I think.
I doubt that.
Why do you say that?
From Italy to Iowa,
that's a big change.
But Richard was in the Army there.
I met him
when I was living in Naples.
I didn't know anything about Iowa.
I just cared that it was America...
...and, of course,
being with Richard.
What's he like?
He's very clean.
Clean?
No. I mean...
He's other things too.
He's a very hard worker...
...very caring...
...honest.
He's gentle.
He's a good father.
And clean.
Clean.
And you like living here in Iowa,
I guess?
Go ahead.
I'm not going to tell anyone.
I'm supposed to say:
"It's just fine. It's quiet
and the people are real nice."
And all that's true.
Mostly.
It is quiet.
And the people are nice.
In certain ways.
We all help each other out.
If someone gets sick or hurt,
all the neighbors come in.
They pick the corn, harvest the oats
or whatever needs to be done.
In town, you can leave your car
unlocked, and let the kids run around.
Don't worry about them.
There are a lot of nice...
...things about the people here.
And I respect them for those qualities.
But...
But?
It's not...
...what I dreamed of...
...as a girl.
I scribbled something down
the other day.
I often do that
when I'm out on the road.
Kind of goes like this:
"The old dreams...
...were good dreams.
They didn't work out,
but I'm glad I had them."
I don't know what it means.
I thought I might use it someday.
Anyway, I think I know how you feel.
Would you like to stay for dinner?
There's not much in town.
And you'd have to eat alone.
So would I.
Yeah, I'd like that.
I don't get a home-cooked meal too often
out on the road.
Okay.
This is ridiculous.
Do you mind
if I put some film in the fridge?
-No, go ahead.
-This heat out here isn't too forgiving.
Anything I can do to help?
-To help? What, cook?
-Yeah, men cook.
Okay, sure.
What can I do?
You can scrape the carrot.
Scrape the carrots.
And grate them.
Make a nice salad.
Scrape the carrots. Like that.
How's that?
Very good. Very nice.
Not bad, huh?
Don't forget to pick off the end.
Pick off end.
Let me get these...
Excuse me.
I can take the ends off of these too.
Yes. That's a good idea.
This the way you do it?
That's good.
But don't use your fingers.
Then they smell like...
I'll get you some lemon.
Would you like a beer?
-I've got some in the car.
-I would love a beer.
Anything to get out of a little work.
Very nice.
No, wait a second.
It gets better.
You must picture this:
I have 3 cameras around my neck...
...and I've got a tripod,
and my pants are around my ankles.
I'm behind a bush, and then
suddenly I see this gorilla.
A huge gorilla,
staring right at me...
...with the most lascivious look
you've ever seen.
More than any creature
with that much hair.
I freeze, because that's
what you're supposed to do.
And then
it started coming towards me.
And what?
What?
My God!
I can't...
You're blushing.
It's a very painful subject.
A very sore...
...sore subject matter, really.
-What happened?
-We became engaged.
You should really...
...write these stories down.
I would, except this is a female
gorilla. It had on eye shadow...
...and a little lip gloss on
and it was so nice...
We still write.
I don't want
to put this stuff down.
I'm afraid...
I'm afraid my writing's
a little too technical.
The trouble with being a
journalist too long is...
...you stop allowing yourself
to invent.
I'll just stick to making pictures.
Making pictures.
I like that.
You really love what you do.
I'm obsessed by it, really.
Why is that, do you think?
I don't know.
I don't think obsessions have reasons.
That's why they're obsessions.
You sound like an artist.
I wouldn't say that.
National Geographic
likes their photos in focus...
...and not too much personal comment.
I don't mind really.
I'm no artist.
That's one of the curses of being
too well-adjusted, too normal.
I don't think you're so normal.
Really?
I didn't mean it in the way...
...in the way that it sounded.
We'll just chalk it up
to a compliment...
...and move on.
Did you just love teaching?
Yes, when there was a particular student
who can make a difference...
They're all supposed to, but they don't.
You tend...
...to single out 1 or 2 who you think
you can contribute something to.
-And did you?
-I hope so. One went to medical school.
Why'd you quit?
My children, my kids.
And...
...Richard didn't like my working.
But you miss it, obviously.
I never think about it.
What's the most exciting place
that you've ever been?
-Unless you're too tired to talk.
-Most exciting...
You're asking if a man's tired of
talking about himself? Been out much?
Didn't mean to make
it sound like a dumb...
Maybe it's a little dull for you...
...telling this to some housewife
in the middle of nowhere.
This is your home.
This isn't nowhere.
And it's not dull.
Let's see.
I guess I'd say that the most exciting
place I've been to was Africa.
Because it's another world.
It's not just the cultures
and the people.
That's great, but it's the air.
The colors from dawn to dusk.
There's something tangible about it.
The cohabitation of man and beast,
and beast and beast.
Who'll survive and who won't.
There's no judgment about it either.
There's no imposed morality.
It's just the way it is.
It's beautiful, really.
Just nothing like it.
It's...
...a voyeur's paradise.
I'd love to see that.
There's safaris.
You can ask your husband.
Yeah.
It's a beautiful evening.
Would you like to take a walk?
You've got it all right here.
I'm serious. This is as nice a place
as I've ever been.
"The silver apples of the moon,
and the golden apples of the sun."
Yeats.
"The Song of Wandering Aengus."
-Good stuff, Yeats, huh?
-Yes.
Realism,
economy, sensuousness...
...beauty, and magic.
All that appeals to my Irish ancestry.
-Something wrong?
-Would you like something to drink?
Coffee?
Maybe some brandy?
Maybe some both.
Yes?
Let's.
Sure you don't want me to help?
No. I'm not going to wash them now.
I'll rinse them now. I'll do it later.
Francesca.
You all right?
Yeah.
What?
We're not doing anything wrong.
Nothing you couldn't tell your kids.
To ancient evenings and distant music?
He's getting her drunk.
That's what happened.
Maybe he forced himself.
That's why she couldn't tell us.
He did not.
-He's such a nice guy.
-Trying to sleep with somebody's wife?!
I don't think so.
And that doesn't make you a bad person.
He reminds me of Steve in a way.
Steve's...
...weak, immoral and a liar,
but still a nice guy.
He just shouldn't be married.
At least not to me.
I'm hungry.
Are you getting hungry?
I had no idea it's that bad, sis.
Please, don't feel sorry for me.
Nobody's forcing me to stay.
Why do you?
-Do you mind if I ask you a question?
-No.
Why did you get divorced?
I was never around.
So, why'd I get married?
That's a good question.
I guess I needed a home base.
Roots.
You can kind of get lost on the road.
So what happened?
I never got lost.
I was more at home everywhere
than just in one place.
Kind of like a citizen of the world.
-Must get lonely sometimes.
-No. I never indulge in that.
I've got friends all over the world
I can visit from time to time.
Women friends too?
I'm a loner, but not a monk.
You really don't need anyone?
I think I need everyone.
I love people.
I'd love to meet them all.
That's the thing about Iowa.
You tend to meet the same
kind of person repeatedly.
So when Mr. Delaney has an affair
with the Redfield woman...
...the whole town wakes up.
There's a lot of that going around.
It seems to me there's too much of:
..."This is mine"
and "He or she is mine."
There's just too many lines being drawn.
You know?
Doesn't it scare you though?
Being alone?
I don't think so.
I think I embrace the mystery.
Do you ever regret it?
-What?
-The divorce, I mean.
No.
Do you ever regret
not having a family?
Not everyone's supposed to have one.
How can you live for just what you want?
What about others?
-I love other people.
-But no one in particular.
-But I love them just the same.
-It's not the same.
I know it's not the same...
...but what you're saying is
it's not as good, it's not normal.
That's not what I said.
I have a problem with
this American family ethic...
...that seems to have hypnotized
the country.
You probably think of someone like me
as a displaced soul...
...destined to wander the planet
with no TV or self-cleaning oven.
Because someone decides to have a
family doesn't mean they're hypnotized.
Never having seen a gazelle stampede
doesn't mean I'm asleep in my life.
Want to leave your husband?
No. Of course not.
I'm sorry about that.
I apologize for that.
What made you ask that?
I thought that's what we were doing.
Asking questions.
We were having a conversation.
But you ask me questions...
...reading these meanings into them
I must be too simple to interpret.
I'm sorry.
I apologize.
Roseman Bridge at dawn.
I better be going.
I'm sorry.
I apologize.
You must forgive me.
That was a very indiscreet question.
It was...
...dumb.
I feel something's been spoiled.
It was a perfect evening,
just the way it was.
Perfect evening...
...a nice walk.
Thank you for the...
...company and the brandy.
You're a good woman, Francesca.
Keep the brandy forward in the cupboard.
It might work out after a while.
And don't kid yourself, Francesca.
You're anything but a simple woman.
Johnson's.
Richard, hi.
Everyone settled in okay?
I said, "good."
Hi, it's Robert Kincaid.
Hi.
Got your note.
W.B. Yeats and all.
I didn't read it right away
because the light was changing.
I had to get my shots.
The light was changing.
But I do accept your invitation.
It'll have to be later though.
I'm going to the Holliwell Bridge
and shoot over there.
After 9, how about that?
Your work's what's important.
I'll make something nice
we can warm up.
Maybe you'd like to come along with me.
Yes, I would like that, but I...
I'll drive my pickup and meet you.
All right?
-All right.
-What time?
How about 6?
Okay.
Great.
-God, it's Lucy Redfield!
-Apparently Mrs. Delaney caught them.
There's a seat here,
if you'd like.
Thank you.
Kind of hot out, isn't it?
Yeah.
Are you ordering anything?
No.
Thanks.
I've changed my mind.
How about this one?
I don't know, I don't
know, I don't know.
I haven't bought a dress
for myself in so long.
I'm just buying a dress.
It's not for a special occasion.
I'm just shopping for
a new dress is all.
That might work.
And if he's still mad, tell him
you married him out of pity.
That always works for me.
Hi, it's Robert.
Listen, I'm running a little late.
But I'll still...
...be there.
I don't want this
to sound the wrong way...
...but I wonder
if this is a good idea.
I had lunch in town.
And I crossed paths
with that Redfield woman.
I guess you got the whole story.
The cashier at the grocery store
was most generous.
He's running for town crier next year.
I know more about the Delaney affair
than I knew about my marriage.
If it's going to be a problem for you
to see me tonight, don't do so.
I'm not too bright
about people's reactions.
I wouldn't want you to be put
in a compromising situation.
Yeah, I understand.
That's very kind of you
to think of that.
Robert?
I want to come.
Okay? So I'll meet you at the bridge
like we planned...
...and don't worry about the rest.
I'm not.
All right.
I'll see you then.
Okay.
Beautiful here.
Make yourself at home.
I have to knock off a few shots.
Look at the butterfly.
Got you!
Come on.
No, don't take my picture.
Go ahead, give me a pose.
One of those French model looks.
-I can't.
-Like Gina Lollobrigida.
Can I help?
No, I've got everything under control.
I'm just going to go...
...clean myself up a bit.
I'm going to take a bath.
What happens if I set the table?
That's fine. Sure.
Good.
Would you like a beer...
...for your bath?
Yeah.
That's nice.
Dinner will be ready...
...in half an hour.
I realized that he had been
here just a few minutes before.
I was lying where the water
had run down his body...
...and I found that intensely erotic.
Almost everything
about Robert Kincaid...
...had begun to seem erotic to me.
What's wrong?
You look stunning.
If you don't mind me saying so.
Make-them-run-around-the-block-
howling-in-agony stunning.
Hi, Madge.
No, I was just...
...fixing something to eat.
No, what?
Yeah, I heard about him.
I hear he's some kind of
photographer or something.
Hippie? No.
Is that what a hippie looks like?
I was just going to step into a bath
when you called, so maybe...
They don't get back till Friday.
Maybe I'll call you then, okay?
If you want me to stop, tell me now.
No one's asking you to.
"He told me he wouldn't apologize
for what was going to happen."
What's the matter?
I'm going to get some air.
Take me someplace.
Right now. Take me someplace...
...that you've been.
Someplace on the other side
of the world.
How about Italy?
Yeah.
How about Bari?
Tell me about that time...
...you got off the train.
You know the station.
You know the little restaurant
with the striped awning...
...serves arrancino.
Arancino.
And zeppoli.
I know that place.
I had coffee there.
Did you sit...
...by the doorway
or near the front of the church?
I was near the church.
I know, I sat there once.
I sat there once...
...on a day like this.
It was very hot and...
...I'd been shopping and I had
all these packages around my feet.
I had to keep moving them.
Then what?
You make me forget my story.
Lucky me.
I had thoughts about him...
...I hardly knew what to do with.
And he read every one.
Whatever I felt.
Whatever I wanted,
he gave himself up to.
And in that moment...
...everything I knew
to be true about myself, was gone.
I was acting like another woman...
...yet I was more myself
than ever before.
We decided to spend Wednesday
away from Winterset...
...away from Madison County.
Away from pastures and bridges
and people too familiar...
...and reminders too painful.
We let the day take us
where it wanted.
Is that India?
It's beautiful.
Look at this one.
Look at their expressions.
Beautiful.
As if the camera isn't on them.
They're not photographs,
they're stories.
You should publish these,
have your own collection.
Nobody'd buy it.
Why do you say that?
6 publishers have told me so.
No big deal.
Whatever it is...
...that makes an artist
look like one to the world...
...is just a feature I don't have.
Maybe you have to
convince yourself first.
Maybe.
Maybe you have to ask yourself
why it's an obsession.
What's that?
I had this the other night,
after you left.
It was made for me in Assisi.
I got it for my 7th birthday.
"Francesca."
Keep it.
A musician friend of Robert's
told him of a place off the interstate.
A place, Robert assured me,
no one I knew would see us.
Thank you.
Cheers.
What were you like as a young man?
Trouble.
-Why?
-I just wondered.
Why were you trouble?
I had a temper.
What were your mother and father like?
I don't know if I can do this.
What?
Try to cram in a whole lifetime
between now and Friday.
For all we know
We may never meet again
Before you go
Make this moment sweet again
We won’t say good night
Until the last note
I'll hold out my hand
And my heart will be in it
For all we know
This may only be a dream
-Where'd you go?
-Bar in town.
Did you call Betty?
Maybe you should.
I found out who Lucy Delaney is.
Remember the Delaneys
from Hillcrest Road?
Yeah, but I thought she died.
He remarried.
Lucy Redfield.
Apparently, they were having an affair
for years.
The first Mrs. Delaney
was a bit of a stiff.
You mean...
...she didn't like sex?
Mom could have helped.
Oh, boy!
I've resented not living the wild life
in some place like Paris.
I could have moved back to Iowa.
Are you drunk?
Not yet.
Want to get out of here?
I think I better.
I'll take the keys.
I'm driving.
I've never cheated on Betty.
Not once we were married, I mean.
-Did you want to?
-Only about a thousand times.
What do I do now?
What's good enough for Mom
is good enough for me?
What gets me...
...is I'm in my forties.
I've been in this crummy marriage
for over 20 years...
...because that's what I was taught.
You stick things out.
I don't recall when he made love to me
so intensely...
...that he sent me to Africa.
Frankly, I don't think he ever did.
Now I find out that in between
bake sales, my mother was Anais Nin.
What about me?
I feel really weird.
Like she cheated on me, not Dad.
Isn't that sick?
When you're the only son
you sort of feel...
...like the prince of the kingdom.
In your mind, you think...
...your mother shouldn't want sex,
because she has you.
You're right, that is sick.
If she was so unhappy,
why didn't she leave?
Can I...
...read it now?
Did I miss anything important?
She just took him to her room.
Dad's room?
All right, you can skip that part.
Let's just start...
...here.
"Robert lay asleep in the bed.
I was up all night that night.
What happens tomorrow?
He will leave
and everything new and unknown...
...that had become so familiar..."
...would be gone.
Did you sleep well?
Thanks.
Good.
-More coffee?
-Sure.
I hope you don't mind my asking,
but I feel I should.
What?
These women friends of yours
all over the world, how does it work?
Do you see some of them again,
or do you forget others?
Or do you write to some of them
now and then?
-How do you manage it?
-What do you mean?
I just need to know the procedure,
so I don't upset your routine.
Want some jam?
What are you talking about?
There's no routine.
Is that what you think this is?
Well, what is this?
Is it up to me?
You're married with no intent
to leave your husband.
To do what?
Go off with someone who needs everyone,
but no one in particular?
What would be the point?
Pass the butter, please.
I was honest with you.
Yes. Absolutely!
You have this habit of not needing,
and that's very hard to break.
In that case, why sleep?
You don't need rest.
Why eat?
You don't need food.
What're you doing?
I'm not cut out to be a world citizen...
...who experiences
everything and nothing.
How do you know
what I experience?
I know you.
What can this possibly mean
to someone who doesn't need meaning...
...who just goes with the mystery,
pretending he's not scared to death?
Let's stop this right now!
After you leave,
I'll have to sit here all my life...
...and wonder what happened to me,
if anything.
I'll have to wonder if you're in some
housewife's kitchen in Romania...
...telling her of your world of good
friends, including me in that group.
What should I say?
I don't want you to say anything.
I don't need you to say anything.
I want you to stop this now.
Fine.
More eggs? Or shall we fuck
on the linoleum one last time?
-I won't apologize for who I am.
-No one asked you to.
-I won't feel like I did anything wrong.
-You won't feel, period!
You've carved yourself a part
in the world as a voyeur...
...a hermit, a lover
when you feel like it.
The rest of us are supposed to feel
grateful for this...Go to hell!
It isn't human not to be lonely
and afraid!
You're a hypocrite and a phony!
I don't want to need you.
Why?
Because I can't have you.
What difference does that make?
Don't you see?
Robert, don't you see?
I just have to know the truth.
I have to know the truth,
because if I don't, I'll go crazy.
So just tell me, either way.
I can't act like this is enough
because it has to be.
And I can't pretend not
to feel what I feel...
...because it's over tomorrow.
If I've done anything...
...to make you think that...
...what we have between us
is nothing new for me...
...is just some routine...
...then I do apologize.
What makes it different?
When I think...
...of why I make pictures...
...the only reason
I can come up with...
It just seems
that I've been making my way here.
Seems right now,
that all I've done in my life...
...was making my way here to you.
And if I think about
leaving here tomorrow...
...without you...
Don't let go.
My God, what are we going to do?
Where's your truck?
It's out behind the barn.
I'll go...
...upstairs.
-Hi, Madge.
-I made some brown betty.
Sent Floyd and the boy to town.
I said...
..."I'm visiting my girlfriends
for the afternoon."
He said, "Who will make lunch?"
I said...
..."I'm taking a sick day.
Eat at the diner."
Isn't that hilarious?
He didn't dare raise an eyebrow.
I don't even want to tell you
how late he was out.
Sorry 2 days passed before I came by.
With the boy home, time escapes me.
Have you heard from Richard?
God, it's hot.
Yes. It's hot.
Come with me.
Come away with me.
Care for a beer?
No.
You're not coming with me, are you?
No matter how many times
I turn it over in my mind...
...it doesn't seem like the right thing.
For who?
For anyone.
They'll never be able
to live through the talk.
And Richard...
Richard will never be able
to get his arms around this.
It will break him in half.
He doesn't deserve that.
He's never hurt anyone
in his whole life.
He can move on.
People move.
His family has had this farm
for over 100 years.
He doesn't know how
to live anywhere else.
And my kids...
They're practically grown.
You said they hardly talk to you.
Yeah, they don't say much.
But Carolyn is only 16.
She's about to find out
about all of this for herself.
She's going to fall in love...
...and she'll try to
build a life with someone.
If I leave...
...what does that say to her?
What about us?
You have to know...
...deep down...
...the minute we leave here,
everything will change.
Yeah, it could...
It could get better.
No matter how much distance we put
between ourselves and this house...
...I carry it with me.
I feel it every minute
we're together.
And I will start to blame loving you
for how much it hurts.
And then, even these...
...even these 4...
...beautiful days will seem just like
something sordid and a mistake.
Do you think that what happened with us
just happens to anyone?
What we feel for each other?
We're hardly...
...hardly 2 separate people now.
Some people search all their life
and never find this.
Others don't even think it exists.
You're going to tell me...
You're going to tell me this
is the right thing to do? Giving it up?
We are the choices
that we have made, Robert.
You don't understand.
Don't you see?
Nobody understands when
a woman makes a choice...
...to marry and have children...
...in one way, her life begins,
but in another way, it stops.
You build a life of details...
...and you just stop
and stay steady...
...so that your children can move.
And when they leave...
...they take your life of details
with them.
You're expected to move on,
but you don't remember what moved you...
...because no one's asked you
in so long, not even yourself.
But you never think...
You never think love like this
will happen to you.
But now that you have it...?
Now I want to keep it forever.
I want to love you the way I do now
for the rest of my life...
...but if we leave...
...we lose it.
And I can't make
an entire life disappear...
...to start a new one.
All I can do is
try to hold on to us...
...somewhere inside of me.
You have to help me.
Don't lose us.
Don't throw us away.
Maybe you feel this way.
Maybe you don't.
Maybe it's because
you're in this house.
Maybe tomorrow, when they come back,
you'll feel differently.
-Don't you think that's possible?
-I don't know.
Look, I'm going to be here
a few more days.
We can talk later.
We don't have to decide now.
Robert, don't!
Don't do this.
I don't want to say goodbye now.
We don't have to make that decision.
Maybe you'll change your mind.
Maybe we'll see each other
and you'll change your mind.
If that happens
you have to decide...
...because I can't.
I'll only say this once.
I've never said it before.
But this kind of certainty
comes just once in a lifetime.
Look!
-You got it.
-I couldn't sell him.
I know.
I knew you would win.
-Good girl. Proud of you.
-Thanks.
-Hi, Mom.
-Hi, darling.
-Did you eat?
-Yeah. I ate.
Hey, there.
How you doing?
It didn't take you too long to get here.
-We had fun.
-Are you hungry?
I got something for you.
The fair was great.
You all came home.
And, with you...
...my life of details.
A day or 2 passed,
and with each thought of him...
...a task would present itself
like a lifesaver...
...pulling me further away
from those 4 days.
I was grateful.
I felt safe.
Put me out of my misery.
I can’t stand the suspense.
I'm not talking about you.
I know I'm a goner.
I can’t stand the suspense. Shoot.
I don’t even need a blindfold.
Condemned man’s dinner.
Chicken, peas, watermelon.
-Do you want anything special?
-How about that brown sugar meat loaf?
For a moment,
I didn't know where I was.
And for a split second, I thought
that he didn't really want me.
That it was easy to walk away.
Robert leaned over as if to get
something from the glove box.
8 days ago, he'd done that...
...and his arm had
brushed across my leg.
A week ago I'd been in Des Moines,
buying a new dress.
That truck's a long way from home.
Washington State.
I'll bet it's that photographer
they talked about at the café.
What's he waiting for?
Come on!
Oh, no!
The words were inside of me.
"I was wrong, Robert, to stay,
but I can’t go.
Let me tell you again
why I can’t go.
Tell me again why I should go. "
I heard his voice coming back to me:
"This kind of certainty comes
once in a lifetime. "
What's wrong, Franny?
Will you please tell me what's wrong?
I just need a minute.
Dad, you bought the wrong feed!
I was grateful for the
silence that night.
I realized
love won’t obey our expectations.
Its mystery is pure and absolute.
What Robert and I had...
...could not continue
if we were together.
And what Richard and I shared
would vanish if we were apart.
But how I wanted to share this!
How would our lives have changed
if I had?
Could anyone else have seen
the beauty of it?
I'm Francesca Johnson.
And I...
I feel awful that I haven't visited
sooner. Is it a bad time?
Am I interrupting anything?
Is it too late?
No, not at all.
We became inseparable,
Lucy and I.
The funny thing is, I didn't tell her
about Robert until years later.
But for some reason,
being with her...
...somehow made me feel...
...it was safe to think about him...
...to continue loving him.
This town loved talking
about the two of us, but we didn't care.
And neither did your father.
It's time.
Is better?
Is better.
Franny.
I just want to say...
...I know you had your own dreams.
I'm sorry I couldn't give them to you.
I love you so very much.
After your father died,
I tried to get in touch with Robert...
...but he had left National Geographic.
No one seemed to know where he was.
My only connections to him
were the places we'd been that day.
And so, each year on my birthday...
...I'd revisit them.
Then one day,
I received a letter from his attorney...
...with a package.
There has not been a day since
that I have not thought of him.
When he said that we were no longer
2 people, he was right.
Bound together as tightly as
2 people can be.
If it hadn’t been for him...
...I could not have lasted on the farm
all those years.
Remember my dress you wanted, Carolyn?
The one you said I never wore?
I know I was silly...
...but it was like you wanted
to wear my wedding dress to the movies.
After reading all this...
...I hope you can now
understand my burial request.
It was not the ravings
of some mad old lady.
I gave my life to my family.
I wish to give Robert
what is left of me.
Hey, Dad.
Can I talk to you?
You've been gone all night.
Do I have the right to ask where?
Do I make you happy, Betty?
Because I want to.
More than anything.
Hi, Steve. It's me.
Good.
You?
Listen, we have to talk.
How about now?
I've decided to stay here for a while.
I don't know how long.
No, I'm not angry, Steve.
I'm not.
I'm not angry at all.
I gave Lucy his photography book.
If you're interested, take a look.
If my words still leave
some things unclear...
...perhaps his pictures can illuminate.
After all,
that's what an artist does best.
I love you both...
...with all my heart.
Do what you have to
to be happy in this life.
There is so much beauty.
Go well, my children.