* ooh, ah,
who got da funk? *
* flav, original mack,
here we come *
* we found a star
with Veronica *
* here we go *
* a new star *
* feel the funk
with the flav *
* nonstop rocking you *
* keep me rockin' you... *
radio: all right, y'all,
you're jammin' with Dr. d
on the number one station
in decatur, Georgia.
I want to see y'all
down at my club,
the gold tooth,
the place to be on
Saturday night with Dr. d.
Coming up next, we're
going to give you the 411
from mtv vj idalis,
so stay where you're at.
* so, sit back, relax *
* we're making
all of the money-- *
* yeah *
* no one can make me *
* feel the way you do *
* ain't nobody,
ain't nobody *
* no one but you *
* no one I'd rather *
* be with than with you... *
why did you have
to burn my toast,
baby?
Now, you know
you said you wanted
everything well-done.
And you know I did.
All right
there, Nate.
Captioning made possible by
new line home video
girl, don't
pay him no mind.
He think
he dolomite.
* with you,
my baby, maybe *
* with all the pleasure
and joy you bring *
* to me, my love *
* every chance I get *
* happy *
* I close my eyes... *
woman: what's
good on the menu?
Nothing.
There you go,
Nate.
Just the way
you like it.
Radio: hey, Georgia,
this is idalis from mtv
with a hot tip
for you Southern gals.
Heavy d is looking
for one special girl
who can dance,
has a great spirit,
and loves to travel,
to be the video
dance girl of the world
for his new video,
and get this,
the lucky winner
gets $10,000 in cash.
You heard that right.
Auditions are
this week in L.A.,
so get
a pen and paper...
Nisi?
You're daydreaming again.
No, no, no, I was
taking their order.
Uh-uh. it's my second time
i done told you.
I'm taking $10 out
of your doggone pay.
Ohh, Mr. Johnson!
Ohh!
$10?
I don't want to hear
nothing, nisi.
Not another word,
another phrase,
another syllable.
Hey! shut up!
I'm the captain
of this doggone ship.
If it's too hot
in the kitchen,
nisi, leave.
If the shoe fit,
wear it.
If it too tight,
take it off!
* out with the old *
* in with the new... *
I can't believe
Ali and James
stood us up again.
I'm through
with them, girl.
Now, you see
what I mean?
I ain't got
nothing to lose.
What you mean you ain't
got nothing to lose?
You talking about using
all the money we have
to go to some audition
in California.
Nisi, you ain't
even a dancer.
I am a dancer, and I'll
be dancin' my butt off
for some $10,000.
Now, if I get
this job, Mick,
we're going to have
more than enough money
for the salon
and the restaurant.
You ain't using
our life savings
to go to California
on some maybe mission.
Your life is right here.
We don't deserve this.
We deserve the best.
Man: that's
why you got me.
And you...
You got me.
Aw, come on, baby,
I'm sorry I'm late,
but, you know,
sometimes businessmen
stuff can't wait.
Well, you can just
keep your "sorry,"
'cause you're
a sorry excuse
for a boyfriend.
Hold on, hold on,
hold on now.
You ain't know
why we late, girl.
I do know that y'all
couldn't show up
here on time
to walk us home
from work.
We've been checking out
this classic 1935 Ford
Eric's grandfather's
selling.
That's right,
and he's gonna
sell it to us
half the price.
If he was giving it away,
it still wouldn't matter.
Y'all ain't got no jobs.
We've been thinking about
putting applications in
for the last month, baby,
but, you know, the buses
don't run everywhere.
But, look here,
we're gonna
buy the car,
and we're
gonna start our
own page-a-cab
luxury
cab company.
Oh, no.
Come on, Mick.
Bye.
Hey, come on, come on.
Nisi, why you
act like that?
Ali, I guess I'm tired
of hearing about
all your pipe dreams.
If you really
cared about me,
you'd get rid
of that tired perm
I've been telling
you about forever.
Oh, I don't
cut my hair!
I ain't cutting
the hair, no.
If anything, I'm gonna
bring the perm back.
Woman: I was so mad,
i just walked out.
Second woman:
And he said
that was his cousin?
That's what he said.
Man: ha ha ha!
Nisi: ...Bopping
around here with that
cracked-up perm he got.
Mickey:
you know he's wrong.
Girl, why won't he
let you cut his hair?
I don't know. I've
been trying forever.
Now, I'm
a hairdresser, right?
And my man walking
around here
looking like
a broke-down superfly.
No. no, superfly's
little brother.
Right, right.
Superflea.
Ha ha ha!
Ow! please
stay on the head.
Shoot, you said you
wanted these pompoms,
so you got 'em.
Girl, we need
to move on,
and we need to get
us some new jobs.
TV: hey, what's up, kids?
Idalis kickin' it mtv style.
Listen, y'all,
i got the inside scoop
on the biggest
video audition
to hit the airwaves
since the artist formerly
known as prince was looking
for that special girl
for his video,
the most beautiful girl
in the world.
Remember that?
Well, heavy d is doing
a unique video himself.
He's going to be shooting
this video all over the world
in beautiful, exotic places
like Brazil and Italy.
He's looking for that
oh, so special girl...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Go back.
Idalis: ...A great body,
a great smile,
and that twinkle
in her eye.
He's looking for...
Nisi: look!
Mickey: Huh?
So, that's
the same audition!
Girl?
I think it's
a sign from god.
My mama always told me
good things come in 3.
I heard it on the radio,
now read it in a magazine,
and now it's on TV!
This is it, Mick!
Nisi, you buggin'.
But what if I ain't?
Come on, Mick.
Let's go to L.A.
Let's do it.
Hell, yeah...
'Cause there ain't
nothing but some fine
young rich men in L.A.
Aah!
ha ha ha!
I feel like partying
right now. Come on.
Partying? we've
got to try to save
every penny now.
Uh-uh. it's
Tuesday night.
You know
what that means.
Ladies night
at the gold tooth.
We get in free!
* go, go *
* git it, git it *
bouncer: I want
everyone to have
their I.D.S ready.
[Dance music playing]
It's just
so ridiculous.
Everybody in here
wants to be a player,
pimp, hustler.
Not me.
I just want
a simple woman.
That's you. I'm
telling you it's you.
Oh, really?
You're very special to me.
Mm-hmm?
You see, I never met nobody
like you before in my life.
Your name is etched
in my heart.
Shakima, right?
Keesha?
Mm-hmm...
I went to school
with her.
All right, step forward.
[Metal detectors squeal]
* how you gonna do it *
* if you really
don't want to dance? *
* by standing on the wall *
* get your back
up off the wall *
* 'cause
i heard all the music *
* get down on it...
Ooh, damn!
What--hey--
heh heh.
Heh heh heh.
Fine and vivacious
and beautiful.
Look good in a mug,
that's what he's
trying to say.
Thank you.
Nisi, ain't
you thirsty?
Uh-uh.
Mm-hmm.
Oh!
Oh, uh...
Yeah, let me get
4 hurricanes, bro.
Ooh, now,
y'all look good,
not like
these hootchy girls.
Y'all got class.
Like waitresses
or something.
Heh heh heh.
That'll be $16 even.
Hell, no. Let's go.
I ain't thirsty.
Come on, let's go
to the bathroom.
Huh!
Hey, hey, hey,
wait a minute.
Hold it--hold it, girl.
Now, look, it was
ladies night, right?
Y'all didn't have
to pay to get in.
Y'all could have
bought our drinks.
Uh, not in this life.
Now, hold on. I ain't
finished talking to you.
Will you let go
of her arm?
You ain't
her damn daddy.
Shut your ass up,
you play-headed heifer.
Get off me.
Hey, what you--
what did I do?
Oh, what you gonna do,
captain save-a-ho? Hmm?
God damn!
Oh, no, it's on now,
brother.
Get on up!
I'll knock your ass
back down again.
Ali:
come on, here.
I swallowed
my gold tooth!
[Whining]
Coming through here.
Ladies, ladies,
ladies.
Ali: hey, my man,
let me hear 4 of them
hurricanes, partner.
Oh, he good for it.
They good for it.
Bartender:
that'll be $16 even.
Oh, hell, no!
Come on, Mick.
Come on,
it's ladies night!
Nisi!
y'all got
in free.
Nisi!
What's your problem?
Why you treating me
like some stepchild?
'Cause I deserve
better than this, Ali.
Don't you think
i know that, baby?
I'm a businessman.
I'm trying to make
things happen.
You've been trying
to make things happen
forever now.
You can't even keep a job.
I want a real man,
a man with ambition,
goals, real dreams.
I got dreams.
What you think
my page-a-cab luxury
cab service is?
You ain't even got
a driver's license.
* I'll be loving you *
* forever *
* deep inside
my heart you'll leave... *
like your dreams are
just wired for sound
and ready to roll,
right?
Owning a hair salon.
That's you and
Mickey's problem.
You need to get
a grip on life.
I ain't never
heard somebody
owning a restaurant
with a hair salon
in back.
What kind of
bullshit is that?
Oh...all right.
Well, that's gonna happen.
You'll see.
Nisi, nisi, nisi,
I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Come on, baby. They're
playing our song.
Come on.
Mm-mmm.
Used to be our song.
* you're always mine *
* when I'm in need *
* when trouble's
on my mind *
* you put my soul
at ease *
* there is no one
in this world... *
[airplane engines roaring]
Nisi, do you think
you overdid it
with our hair?
Mm-mmm. nope.
I sure don't,
'cause we're going
to Beverly Hills.
Now, if I'm going to do
good at that audition,
we've got
to look like stars.
Nisi!
what, girl?
Can't you see I'm trying
to read up on our manners?
I know, but we're going
to need more than manners
'cause right here it says
that the rich
and famous people
hang out
at the Polo lounge.
So?
So?!
Man:
oh, shit.
We don't know nothin'
about playing no damn Polo.
Then look up
in the book
and see if you can find
a basketball lounge.
Yeah!
yeah!
[Giggling]
Flight attendant:
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentleman,
our in-flight movie
is about to begin.
Please lower your shade
if you're sitting
next to a window.
Thank you.
Mickey:
where my thing at?
Hey, I can't see.
Miss?
Man:
what's going on?
Man: what's blocking
the screen?
Man: I paid good
money to see this.
Woman: I can't see!
Please, can I have
another seat?
I'll pay you any
amount of money.
I'm sorry. The flight
is all booked up.
Aw, fuck!
Hello?
Ladies, would you mind
lowering your hair?
Man: hey, you
with the hair!
No problem.
Woman: I paid money
to be watching this.
It's beautiful.
Maybe you overdid it
just a little bit.
Maybe I did, huh?
Man: can I get my money back
for these headphones?
Woman: there.
That's much better.
P.A.: the white zone
is for the immediate
loading and unloading.
[Gasps]
[gasps]
Mickey:
oh, shit, lady, look!
Both: aaah!
Mickey: nis, look!
Ll! ll!
Ll! Ll!
Aah!
aah!
Damn! lady love
in the flesh!
Ain't nothing
like a brother
who practices
what he preaches.
Remember we read
in right on magazine,
he done married
his baby's mama!
Sure did!
You're
a good man, too.
I know that mookie's
been throwing
that ass at you, too.
I know! Remember
when tit-tit said
she slept with him?
Precious, too! She said
he got it goin' on!
She sure did!
Ladies, ladies, ladies,
it's nice to meet y'all,
but I got to go
to the studio.
Ok. ll!
I'm gonna be
in the heavy d video!
I'm about to blow up!
Boo yeah! She is!
Well, check it out.
I don't mean to be
rude or anything,
but, unfortunately,
i gotta go. I'm
running late, ok?
Ok, uncle l. Ok.
All right.
Ok, baby.
Keep licking
them lips!
Oh, and I know
you're with
your baby's mama,
but if the shit
don't work out, you
know you can come--
girl! let's go get
our luggage! Go!
Ooh!
Girl, you said good
things come in 3s.
That's sure
what my mama said.
Ow! if I see
ll 2 more times,
it's on!
Come on! We just saw ll!
Bring on the band!
Nisi: we're
the first ones here.
For real? You're about
to get this job, girl!
You're gonna get this!
Ooh!
[Giggling]
Man on megaphone: Will
number 865 please step up?
Will number 865 please
join the group over there?
Nisi: oh, girl, I'm gonna
blow this audition up!
You got to,
'cause we only
have enough money
for one night
in a motel room.
I'm gonna get this.
Get this.
Oh, look at her
trying to show out.
Come on. Mm-hmm.
She thinks she
got it going on.
You the bomb.
I got this.
Oh, yeah.
No problem.
Eww, she wrong for that.
Uh, uh,
that was good,
but you might want
to go on home now,
'cause I'm here.
No, stay, 'cause we're
going to need a few
extras in the video.
Heh heh.
Excuse me.
Ooh...
Mmm...
[Humming]
That's my girl!
Yeah!
Baby, we got this!
Boo yah!
Girl, can you believe
he gonna accuse me
of hitting everybody
with my hair?
I didn't hit nobody
with my hair.
I did hit a few
of them, though,
'cause I was rooting for you.
I wanted you to win.
I ain't like
that song no way.
Come on, let's
just find a hotel
so we can get out of here
in the morning.
Where are we going
to find a taxi
around here anyway?
[Italian accent]
Excuse me.
I couldn't help
to notice you earlier.
You are
a very good dancer.
Uh-huh. well, they
ain't think so.
My boss is doing
a music video.
I thought you'd
be perfect for it.
Hold up.
How many c-notes
we talking here?
Uh, c-notes?
Cash money?
Room and board
in his Beverly Hills
mansion
and $10,000.
A mansion?
$10,000?
Where he at?
Follow me.
Nisi: come on, girl. We got
to take care of business.
Wait, wait,
wait! Don't!
Don't ring
the doorbell yet.
It say right here
in my etiquette notes
that if they say,
"how are you?"
We say...
Livin' large
and takin' charge,
big boy!
I don't want you doing
that kind of stuff.
We're in Beverly Hills,
so when they say,
"how are you,"
we smile sweetly...
And say,
"very well, thank you.
And yourself?"
You cool?
Ring the doorbell.
[Doorbell chimes]
How did you get past
security at the gate?
Begging is not permitted
in Beverly Hills.
Oh, well, that's cool,
'cause where we come from,
crackheads
be beggin'
all the time.
Snap! we can't even
walk down the street--
[door closes]
Oh, no, see, it's on!
It's on now
in Beverly Hills!
Mick, we're not
doin' no fighting--
ladies, welcome.
I'm Isaac blakemore,
and you are?
I'm Denise, and this
is my friend tamika.
You can just
call me nisi
and her Mickey.
Uh, sorry. Please,
come on in.
I'm sorry.
How very rude of me.
I just have to finish up
a phone conversation.
You know,
just looking at you,
I can tell you're exactly
what I've been looking for.
So, I got the job?
Well, yeah.
It certainly seems
that way, doesn't it?
Well, manley here
will be happy to show you
up to your room.
You can just relax,
you know, freshen up
a little bit.
Just make yourself
at home,
then we'll
meet again shortly
to go over the terms
of your contract.
Thank you!
Oh, good.
Good, good, good.
I'll see you in a bit.
Nisi: thank you.
Thank you.
[Giggling]
[Classical music plays]
Follow me.
Wow...
Ooh...
Mickey, look!
Ooh, he got
a little one!
[Clears throat]
Ooh, look!
Check this out!
It's a real
famous piece.
They done
pay crazy cash
for this.
For that?
Some ugly woman
he tried to hook up?
If she was ugly, he
should have left her ugly.
She looks like
loquisha Jenkins
with a bad hair weave.
[Clears throat]
You need some
throat lozenges
or something?
Lead the way,
Alfred.
The name is Mr. manley.
Manley will do
very nicely, thank you.
Who is Alfred?
You know.
Batman's homeboy.
Oh, you right, girl.
I see what
you're saying.
You would be so good
in the sequel!
Oh, he'd be phat!
He would!
All you'd have to do is say,
"Batman to the cave!"
And everybody would
lose their job that day.
And you'd get that job!
Ha ha ha!
Both: to the batcave!
[Giggling]
Nisi: ask him
to say it, Mick.
You do it.
I already called
the man Alfred.
Oh, come on.
No. I just want
to know where
we're sleeping tonight.
Hi.
Wait in there.
What kind of welcome
is that?
[Pompously]
"wait in there."
Come on.
Ohh...
ahh....
Mick!
Come in here.
Look at this.
Ooh, it's pretty,
ain't it?
It's beautiful.
Hey...
Why they got
2 toilets?
You know
how rich folks is.
They got to feel
like they got a choice
in everything they do.
Now, that one right
there looks like
it's for number one...
And that one looks
like it's for number 2.
How do you
flush number one?
You just turn these
2 handles right here.
Whoa! oh!
Oh, no, girl!
What did you do?
The water's getting
all over the floor!
Do something!
Hurry!
I'm trying!
Turn it off,
nisi!
Turn it off!
Nis, let me!
Ok!
Ooh! oh! Woo-ooh!
I'm gonna turn it off!
Mick, sit on it!
Sit on it, Mick!
They're gonna throw us
out of here, Mick!
Come on! Ok! Ok!
Ok!
Girl,
that's my back!
Girl, you're
on my back!
You're on
my back, girl!
Come on now!
Manley: is everything
all right in there?
I say, is everything
Mick, the intercom!
Hurry up, girl!
Come on now!
Manley: hello?
Hello, ladies?
Oh!
Oh, shit!
Manley: are you
all right in there?
Damn!
talk to the man!
Manley: is everything
all right in there?
Yes...everything is fine.
Have you got a mop?
Mr. Isaac
will see you now.
Mm-hmm. we'll be down
in 5 minutes.
Mickey: 5 hours!
Shut up, Mick!
Ooh!
oh!
Together.
together.
Isaac: over here.
[Laughs] wait, wait.
Slow down. Slow down.
I don't want you to trip.
Hi. please have a seat.
How do you like your room?
Oh, snap!
This whole place
is the bomb!
It's lovely.
Now, uh, before we begin,
well, there's
just one little thing
i have to tell you.
I'm not making
a music video.
I just didn't know how else
i was going to find...
An actress like yourself.
I can act, too!
This job involves...
An old man who is
dying from cancer.
Oh, that's sad.
Know what's
even sadder?
He was never able
to marry the one woman
that he truly loved.
Why come?
Because he's white...
And she was black.
She was the housekeeper
at the family's estate.
Her name was Lily.
Oh, that's who
I'm going to play?
Well, not quite.
Um...
When his family discovered
their relationship,
they separated them.
They immediately
married him off
to a white woman.
And he never saw Lily again.
Anyway, he's dying,
and the only family that
he has left is his nephew.
That's me.
Sorry. I'm his nephew.
Uh, and when I learned
that he has less
than 2 weeks to live,
well, I decided
that maybe I should
try and find the love
of his life. Find Lily.
That is so
sweet of you.
Well, it was also
impossible.
But, seems I have
managed to find...
Lily's granddaughter.
Oh, that's who
I'm going to play.
Yes. yes, exactly.
Well, my idea was...
You know how much
your grandmother loved him,
so, you show up here
out of the goodness
of your heart.
You just do anything
and everything
that you can
to make sure
that his final days
are filled with--
with kindness and love.
Bravo.
Man.
That's beautiful.
Aw, I'm glad
you think so.
So, if you'd
be so kind
as to follow me.
Right this way.
Uncle Don, I have
a surprise for you.
I'd like you
to meet Denise.
Denise is Lily's
granddaughter.
Why didn't you tell me
they were coming?
How dare you bring them
in like this.
How dare you!
[Coughing]
No.
Put--get--
get out.
Get out.
Mickey: nisi,
let's not get scared.
We can handle
that old man.
We going to get
this $10,000
and make all
our dreams come true.
[Gasps]
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, my god.
This is the bomb.
It's the bomb.
Ok.
We going to get
this money.
Let's go to dinner.
He said it was this way.
Come on!
Isaac: I'm sorry
i scared you.
I meant it
as a surprise.
Mr. blakemore:
It's all right, Isaac.
Just don't ever
do that to me again.
I won't.
Oh.
Oh, well.
Well, hello there.
Have a seat.
Mm-hmm.
Forgive me
for my behavior
earlier.
I'm sorry
if I was rude.
I--i don't
like surprises.
Hmm.
So,
I can't tell you
how happy I am
to have you
in my home.
The first years
of my life
were touched by
the magic of Lily.
I welcome you.
I suppose she told
you all about life
on the estate.
[Slurps]
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, she did.
What exactly
did she say?
Uh...
[Slurps]
Uh, well, she...
Told me about
the trees.
There were
wonderful trees.
There was this
beautiful, majestic oak
as you drove--
that's the one.
The oak.
She told us about
the oak, didn't she?
[Slurps]
Ah, here's dinner.
Thank you, manley.
What's this?
I'm only permitted
to eat certain foods.
No wonder why you sick.
I don't mean to be rude,
but you ain't dead yet.
You can still eat hearty.
What she mean is
you can still
eat hearty and
be healthy, too.
You sound
just like Lily.
There's no food
like soul food.
You right about that.
Ain't no food
like soul food.
Excuse me.
Give me your plate.
What?
[Sniffs]
Ahh.
Yes.
Radio: 92.3 the beat
with Jesse Collins.
Off the request lines
from L.A.
* oh, you're
my kind of... *
do you think
Ali and James miss us?
I don't know,
but I know
i miss my man.
You need to scoot over,
'cause I ain't got no problem
sleeping on this expensive
white carpet,
'cause I know
it's poodle hair.
[Knock on door]
Excuse me.
I must talk to you.
Oh, yes,
Antonio!
I'm coming!
Hold on.
Antonio.
Mickey.
Perhaps we can go
someplace private.
Mm-hmm.
Hold on.
You need to go
take a cold shower
like I told you to.
Come with me, bellissima.
* hey hey *
* hey *
* show me your look *
* and you give me shivers *
hey, hey!
You said we came
down here to talk.
No more lies.
I felt that maybe
you were feeling
the same thing
that I feel for you.
You were?
We are destiny,
I'm convinced.
We are?
Si, bellissima.
But I have a secret.
Well, go on ahead,
Antonio.
You could tell me.
My family is very wealthy.
For real?
I came to America
to find somebody
who likes me for me.
Somebody like you.
You got some money?
More money
than you can spend
in one lifetime.
Oh, please let me try
in this lifetime,
please.
I will. I promise.
I need to go now.
Until we meet again.
[Speaking Italian]
Arrivederci.
Aria derchi to you, too.
And some mozzarella
and fettuccini.
Hell, yeah.
Ooh.
Mickey: I swear to god
it ain't no dream.
I know you think
he's just hired help,
but it's all an act.
Well, if he's so rich,
why did he have to come
all the way to America
to find his wife?
I don't know.
But I ain't got
no rock on my finger,
so I say
we keep shopping
for our babies' daddies.
And may the fattest
wallet win.
Manley: I tell you,
master Isaac,
they're disrupting
Mr. blakemore's diet.
They're poisoning him
with this soul food,
as he calls it.
Mm-mmm, he love
Mickey's soul food.
My soul food is created
to nourish the soul, ok?
I ain't used pork since
Thelma was on good times
about to marry ebay
the African prince,
'cause he didn't eat pork
in his food,
and I said no, no, no.
I'm waiting on
my African prince
to be my baby's daddy,
so I stopped using pork
because I started using
chicken broth.
I could be doing that.
So I don't know
what you talking about.
See, what I cook
is much healthier
than that bird stuff
Alfred is cooking for him.
The name is manley,
thank you.
I spoke with
the nutritionist
this morning.
And he warned me
that this so-called
soul food has been known
to clog the arteries,
cramp the colon,
and eventually
stop the heart.
Is that true?
Mm-mmm, not the way
she do it.
Good grief,
would you look at that?
Yes.
Let me have that
from you.
You're alarming me
a little bit.
I want you to relax.
[Whispering]
i think you're
overreacting.
Ladies, I want you
to continue to cook
whatever you think
is going to make
my uncle happy.
And if there's anything else
you need from the store,
well, I'm sure that manley
will be more than delighted
to go get it for you.
You think
he could go by
the record store?
Oh, sure.
And don't forget
my ice cube cd, manley.
Good morning, everybody.
How are you?
Isaac, good to see you.
Ah, I don't know what
you put in that meal
last night,
but I feel great.
Excuse me.
Mmm.
What's for breakfast?
[I can't wait plays]
Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
I wonder if
you could help me.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You're looking for
the classical section
back there by the jazz.
No, no, no, no.
I am not looking for
the classical section.
I'm looking for
the rap section
as follows:
"2 pac, too short,
the dogg pound,
"ice cube, ice t,
bitch betta have
my money,
and pull up to
the bumpa, baby."
All right, right, right.
Ok, you trying to get
your groove on.
Right this way, dog.
Got that too short
player's style right there.
Yeah.
What else? We got that
mack 10, baby, yeah.
West Toni!
Yeah, what you know
about that?
Got that east coast
busta Ron's in the house.
What you know, boy?
Hoo-haa!
Yeah, what else
we got here?
Ah, got that
mighty Biggs, baby.
What you know about that
Luke Skywalker, huh?
* uhh-uhh,
get it, get it *
* get it, get it *
check it out.
We got the bomb
in the back, though.
Hey, you know
dre left death row, right?
Manley: what?
[Live for love intro plays]
* oh oh oh oh oh oh *
* oh, I live for your love *
* oh oh oh oh... *
all right for you.
Oh!
Whoo!
Nisi: now who's
got the ball?
Mr. blakemore:
I hear you.
Ah ah, I got the ball now.
You can't shoot
from there.
Whoa!whoa!
My shot!
Oh!
Mr. b shoots.
2, chalk up 2!
Nisi: oh!
Tie score.
I shot 2.
4 seconds, 3 seconds.
Here we go around.
Whoa!
Whoa.
Whoa, Mickey.
You all right?
Mickey: my hair.
Ohh!
My hair got wet!
Oh, god!
Mickey!
Mmm.
I told that girl
she should wear
a swimming cap!
What's the problem?
Nothing.
She done got her
hair wet.
Now she's mad 'cause
she going to be nappy.
I tell you what,
send for the car
and make an appointment
at a hair salon I know.
Have them call me
and charge it
to my account.
Wait, I got a better idea.
I can use some new clothes.
What say we--
we go on a shopping spree?
A shopping spree?
Ooh!
Today must be
my lucky day!
[Laughs]
I'm going on
a shopping spree.
I never been on
I'm going on
a shopping spree!
* let me take you to a place
i know you want to go *
* it's a good life *
* hey hey hey, yeah *
* I want to stand
around you *
* just don't say no *
* no-no, no-no *
* good life, good life *
* good life *
[camera clicks]
[Camera clicks]
[Clicks]
* it's a good life *
* hey hey hey, yeah *
* I wanna stand around you *
* just don't say no *
* no-no, no-no *
* I got a feelin'
that you're gonna like it *
* what I'm doin' to you *
* ooh ooh ooh ooh *
* what I'm doin' *
* I'll be doin'
what you want me to do *
* hey hey hey *
* love is shining *
* life is thriving... *
Isaac: i--yeah,
yeah, yeah.
[Laughs]
Would you relax?
Relax.
Stop worrying
about those girls.
Because they're idiots.
They're not going
to suspect anything.
No, they won't.
Look--look,
all you have to do--
just be set up
on your end.
Everything's
going to be fine.
Because I know it will.
I already have
all the pictures
I'm going to need.
Just get a grip
on yourself.
You're going to be
very wealthy
very, very soon.
Yeah, that's true.
I won't be so
badly off myself.
Mm-hmm.
Look, I'll talk
to you later.
Ok, bye.
Good.
Ohh, you trippin'.
You diggin' hard on
Antonio, ain't you?
Yeah.
[Laughs]
I wish I could
find me a man.
You will. You will.
Well, I ain't
found one yet.
And we leaving here
as soon
as Mr. b die.
I can't believe
we waiting around
for some man to die.
It don't feel right.
And he's such
good people, too.
I know.
Ooh, we done missed
our stories today, girl.
Ooh, and today was
the day we was going
to find out
who killed
Adam's wife.
I know.
It was the housekeeper.
No, it was
the stepdaughter
'cause she jealous.
No, no,
she ain't smart enough.
No, it was that ho Jillian.
That Jillian.
She is a nasty
piece of work, isn't she?
You watch the stories?
Oh, yes.
I videotape every episode.
Get the fuck
out of here.
I beg your pardon?
Who killed Adam's wife?
It was that
dirty, rotten swine
Dr. Matthew.
I always did
suspect him.
I knew it.
I knew
he did it.
Dr. Matthew.
Thank you,
Alfred.
Manley.
Valet: I'll take
your ticket, sir.
Woman: nice to see you,
Mr. blakemore.
Man: Don blakemore,
I haven't seen you
at the golf course lately.
Yes.
[Speaking German]
Mr. blakemore,
good evening! Welcome!
Thanks for coming.
How are you?
Alex, always good
to see you.
Now, I want one of
your choice tables
for me and my guests.
That'll be no problem.
Ladies?
Excuse me,
I'm going to wash
my hands, ladies.
Ok, follow me.
Right this way.
Here we go.
Right up here.
Mickey:
Howard Hewitt!
Oh! oh!
Oh, I been
a fan of yours
for so long.
Since you was
with shalimar
and you had
the big afro.
Oh, I'm such
a big fan of yours.
You got
to sing for me.
You got to
sing something.
Not here.
Oh, yo, yeah, here.
I ain't letting you go
till you sing something
for me.
Ok, ok, ok, listen.
* you know
i love you, baby *
wunderbar.
The show is over.
Thank you very much.
I'm so sorry,
Mr. Hewitt.
It was nice
that you sang.
Oh, bless you for that.
Listen here,
you can't be acting
like no fool, ok?
We in a fancy place.
We got to have class.
We in a classy place.
Oh, Leon!
Ooh, I loved you
in waiting to exhale.
I want to exhale.
Please, please,
let him exhale.
Oh, Mr. Leon,
I'm so sorry.
Please--
thank you for coming!
Ooh, girl. Leon.
Your table is ready.
You got us
in trouble.
You getting us
I know how to act.
I know how to act, too.
Look. oh!
Heavy d!
Ooh, heavy,
heavy, heavy!
You the main reason
that we here in L.A.
At that audition,
i didn't do
the best I could.
Wait a minute.
Ain't you that girl
that hit the other girl
in the face with your hair?
Uh-huh.
Oh, I seen
all you can do, hon.
No, she can really dance.
No, I seen all she can do.
She could hurt somebody.
No, she can dance.
And I'm the next monifa.
She is.
Oh, you're
the next monifa?
Yeah. look,
let me get remixed.
Check this out.
Oh, no, this
is not necess--
* it's been too long
since you been gone *
* feels good,
i want you *
* I miss you *
please, no!
Mr. Booty!
Oh, Mr. heavy d,
I'm so sorry.
I did not mean
for this to be heavy,
you know what I mean?
It's ok.
It's all right.
No problem.
Your table
is waiting!
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
I didn't mean it.
I just wanted
to show you.
We'll call the office.
Heavy d: Have
a good night.
Diddle-Lee-Dee,
diddle Lee-Dee.
C.e.o.c.e.o.
C.e.o.!c.e.o.!
Aah!aah!
Oh, good to see you again,
Mr. blakemore.
Whoa, no,
what a night.
Will there be anything else
for you, Mr. blakemore?
No, thank you, Albert.
I'll have
the check, though.
Thank you.
You know what,
Mr. b?
This food
ain't all that.
They should've
had Mickey
up in the kitchen.
Mickey:
amen.
Nisi, do you cook?
Mm-mmm. I do hair.
That's my thing.
Really? so did Lily.
Who?
Ahem.
Oh, grandma.
Yeah, Lily.
Grandma could
grease a scalp,
couldn't she?
Uh-huh.
Tell me more about her.
It's been so long.
Uh...
Let's see.
Grandma.
Oh, Lily,
she have a big--
[mumbling]
Take care, Mr. blakemore.
I hope everything was
to your satisfaction.
Thank you.
[Mumbling]
Nisi: oh, Ali, stop.
[Giggling]
Mm-hmm, I miss you, too.
You know, I'm sorry
things got kind of crazy
before I left, you know?
But that's how that go.
What?
Oh, so you think I'm going
to come crawling back?
Oh, uh-uh.
I hope them negative words
taste real good
rolling off your lips,
'cause one day you're going
to have to eat them.
Is everything
all right, miss?
[Ring]
Now, then,
who could be calling
at this time of night?
It's my boyfriend.
[Ring]
Shall I answer?
This is the blakemore
residence.
One moment, please.
It's for you.
[Whispering]
you tell him I'm through
with his sorry ass.
Go on, tell him.
Hello, sir.
She's through
with your sorry ass.
I wonder, would you mind
repeating that, sir?
Thank you.
He says you're tripping
'cause you're in Hollywood,
and he hopes
you don't get played.
Oh, I'm tripping,
and he hope
i don't get played?
Tell him he better hope
his mama don't get played.
Hello, sir.
She hopes your mama
don't get played.
Wait a moment, sir.
Yes, she is,
as a matter of fact.
What?
He asked if you were
biting your lip.
Yes, yes.
But that's truly
extraordinary, isn't it?
All right, sir,
i will.
Good night now.
What he say?
Well, he said he's sorry,
maybe he's tripping,
but he misses you
very much on the real.
Good night, miss.
Real.
[Laughter]
Mickey: mmm.
Antonio: ohh.
Ooh--aah!
This little piggy
ate the ravioli.
Whoo!
Aah!
Hey.
Why you wearing them gloves
in the house?
Because, my love,
your skin is too soft
to suffer
the roughness of
my hard-working hands.
You are so sweet.
[Speaking Italian]
Wait, wait, wait, whoa.
Wait.
I ain't doing that
till I get married.
You putting a ring
on this finger?
A ring?
Mm-hmm.
I already
have a ring.
You do?
Come with me.
Mr. blakemore
was kind enough
to let me keep the ring
safe in here.
Ready?
Yes.
I can't open it.
Oh, ok.
Well, let me try.
Let me try.
What's the combo?
5 left.
Zero right.
And 10 left.
10 left.
It's not opening,
is it?
That's not it.
Ohh!
It's all right,
bellissima.
I will verify the code
with Mr. blakemore
in the morning.
Promise?
Promise.
Ok.
Have a good night.
Sleep tight.
Radio: welcome to
the British overseas network.
The following BBC program
can be heard again
on Thursday at--
[crash]
[Thud]
Manley: aah!
[Crash]
Oh, so you
stealing, huh?
Uh-huh.
I'm going to have
to beat you like you
stole something then.
Oh, I'm going to
have to hit you hard,
like Tyson.
Nisi?
Ooh, what?
Ooh! ha ha ha.
What?
Tyson wouldn't
hit him like that.
He wouldn't?
No. he'd hit him
like this.
Ohh!
Oh, no, no, no.
You ain't seen
his last fight,
'cause you was
in the kitchen
getting popcorn.
Tyson...
would do it like--
ohh!
this!
No, Tyson...
Would really
hit him like--
this!
Ohh!
Ohh.
Whoo! ha ha!
Yeah, come on.
Ohh.
Antonio.
[Footsteps]
Isaac: what's
going on here?
What is this?
Help me out.
Help you out?
I'm calling
the police.
The three of you
are stealing
from my uncle.
Manley: no, the girls had
nothing to do with it.
It was Antonio.
Antonio.
Isaac, our plan
can still work.
It will be our words
against theirs.
Her fingerprints are
still on the safe, man.
I beg your pardon?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
What plan?
I'm calling the police.
Oh, my dear,
I'm so sorry.
Look what you've done,
you little skeezers!
Skeezers?
Uh-huh.
Ohh!
[Thud]
Now, I'm going to
have to spank that ass
like Tyson.
Police officer:
I said come on!
Stay on your feet!
[Groans]
Manley: and he was there,
and he hit me from behind.
Well, that was that.
I'll report more fully
to you in the morning,
and, uh, I promise
I'll be there
as early as I can.
Thank you so much,
officer.
Oh, for goodness sake,
let's go.
Officer: I'll
read you your rights.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Hello? you there?
Come on, look at me.
[Antonio groaning]
Officer: look at me!
Antonio: did you say
right or fight?
Officer: right.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say
can and will be
used against you
in a court of law.
Good night.
Nisi:
i don't know how he
slept through all that.
You think
he's still alive?
I don't know.
Maybe we should
check his pulse.
Wait a minute,
you took a cpr class,
didn't you?
Yeah. 'cause all
the cute guys was in there.
No!
Didn't you
learn anything?
No. but i
did meet James.
We're going to check
his heart to see if
it's still beating.
Go on, you check it.
You check it.
[Sighs]
It's on your side.
He's alive.
I'm going to bed.
Nisi?
Whoa!
[Thud]
Nisi?
[Doorbell chimes]
That's ok. We got it.
Hello.
Good morning.
I'm Tracy Shaw,
Mr. blakemore's attorney.
Look, here,
we ain't had
nothing to do
with what
happened last night.
I swear to god.
Oh, I know.
And if anybody
says differently,
you make sure you
have them call me.
Tracy: everything
is ok now.
Thank god we caught this
before Isaac went too far.
I received this package
from his attorney
this morning.
Mr. blakemore,
Isaac has filed documents
of incompetency against you.
I guess once he got
the photos he needed,
the girls were no longer
of any value to him.
He claims you befriended
2 girls from the ghetto
after you caught them
trying to break
into your home.
You then moved the girls
into your home
and, for a lack
of a better phrase,
you've been allowing them
to Rob you blind.
How dare he!
Nisi: girl, I can't
believe Isaac would do
this to Mr. blakemore.
Mickey: yeah, that
is kind of messed up.
Mickey, nisi,
it was a pleasure
meeting the both of you.
How's he doing?
Does he want
something to eat?
I think he just needs
to rest right now.
[Sighs]
He'll be fine.
Good-bye.
All he needs
is energy.
Remember when I told you
my grandmama used
to make my granddaddy
a special drink
that would get him going?
Yeah?
But didn't you
tell me that it
not only got him up
but that
it got him...Up?
Up is up.
[Sighs]
I don't know how
we're going to get him
to drink
all them egg yolks.
The same way
my grandmama did.
Ladies, I didn't
hear you come in.
Hi.
hi.
Hello.
We decided to make you
a breakfast drink.
You didn't
have to do that.
But we wanted to.
We're sorry about what
happened last night.
Yeah.
Yeah, so am I.
Please have a seat.
Ahh.
Money.
Money makes people do
the strangest things.
Isaac brought
you here for his
own selfish reasons,
but did he promise
you anything?
Like a fee?
Mm-mmm. wasn't no fee
involved, was there?
No.
We here because
we want to be.
Which is all
the more reason
why you should
have these.
$50,000?
Holy shit!
I mean shoot.
Uh-uh, Mr. b.
Ain't no way
we could take this.
We're here because
we want to be.
You know, until
this very second,
the only person
i ever totally trusted
in my entire life
was Lily.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
I feel like dancing.
[Music plays]
Go, go!
Get it! Get it!
* shout it from
the highest mountain *
* open my heart for
all the world to see *
* gonna raise my head
and thank the heavens *
* 'cause your love
is shining down on me *
let's get this
party jumpin'!
[Different song plays]
* giddyup, giddyup,
giddyup *
* whoa *
* let's make
that Booty bounce *
[yelling]
* come on, come on,
come on, come on *
* go left,
go right *
* go left, right,
left, right *
* my baby says my
belt's too tight *
* my Booty shakes
from left to right *
* go left,
go right *
* go left, right,
left, right *
* my baby says my
belt's too tight *
* my Booty shakes
from left to right *
* go left,
go right *
* go left, right,
left, right *
* my baby says my
belt's too tight *
* my Booty shakes
from left to right *
* go, go, go, go, go *
* giddyup, giddyup,
let's fly *
the roof!
The roof!
The roof
is on fire!
* giddyup, giddyup,
let's fly *
* bring it like this,
bring it like that *
* break down,
don't break your back *
* movin' them hips
from left to right *
* can you
get high, y'all? *
* work that body
all night long *
* do that dance
while I sing this song *
* go bang, bang,
choo-choo train *
* let me see you
do your thing *
* whoa *
* let's get this party
jumpin' *
* whoa *
Mr. b, you ok?
Uh-uh. uh-uh.
Let's go sit down.
You don't look so good.
You feeling
kind of dizzy?
Let's sit him down
right here.
Right here.
Ok, I'm fine, really.
You sure?
I just got a little
short of breath
for a second. I'm ok.
You was getting down
out there, Mr. b.
I think it's time
for us to go home.
Yeah, 'cause manley's
embarrassing us.
So that's why we
made you fall out.
Let's go.
Come on.
[Laughter]
Mickey: we had
no idea you could dance
like that, Mr. b.
I haven't had this
much fun since I used
to dance with Lily.
You girls
are truly amazing.
Ah, Lily.
Lily, what a lady.
Nisi: what a lady.
Oh, I'm sorry you
didn't meet the man
of your dreams tonight,
but maybe next time.
That's ok.
I've known him since
high school anyway.
Oh?
His name is Ali.
He's back
in Georgia.
I really
love him, too.
What's the problem, then?
Ali don't
have no dreams,
no drive,
no ambition.
Nothing.
Just like me.
No, it's true.
I almost lost
all of my dreams
when I was
a very young man.
Fortunately,
there was a--ha ha--
a skinny, bowlegged girl
who was filled with dreams.
Everything I have today
is because of her.
I mean,
i had no ambition.
But she had enough
for the both of us.
What do you
mean by that?
Well, she always
dreamt about becoming
a clothing designer,
and I loved her
so much that--
oh, so that's how
you got interested
in the fabric business.
Yeah.
Well, who was she?
Your grandmother.
Oh.
See,
that's what I'm...
Taking about.
Ali is different.
Nisi...
There is no fortune
worth the loss
of a true love.
Some things
are priceless.
[Snoring]
Where have you been?
You know, you've
been acting strange
ever since
we got home.
What's up with you,
nisi?
Nisi?!
What? I've been
thinking, ok,
about how we going
to get up out of here.
What?
Don't act like
you don't know, Mickey.
The guilt,
the guilt
of what we doing.
Now, that old man down
there is a nice old man.
And he ain't got nothing
around him but people
trying to use him,
like you and me.
I know.
Why do you think
i got up and left.
We should've been
done got up and left.
D, don't you think
that we could at least
say good-bye?
We can't.
Why?
'Cause if I go to him
and I say we leaving,
he going to say, "why?"
And I'm going to
have to tell him
that you and me
been a part of this
whole big lie.
I can't do it.
So we're going to
write him a letter,
and we're going to
tell him the truth...
Everything.
Everything?
Everything!
What time is it?
12:15.
Why are you still up?
I guess I can't sleep.
You go on,
go back to bed.
Flight don't leave
for another 7 hours.
I'm going to
be downstairs.
Hey, d,
what we going to do
when we get off that plane?
We ain't got no money,
no apartment, nothing.
We worse than
when we started out.
Maybe,
but maybe not.
Some things
is priceless,
you know, Mick?
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
* I'll be loving you *
* forever *
* deep inside my heart
you'll leave me never *
excuse me, miss.
It was never my intention
to involve myself in
your private affairs
or to come off
like a player-hater,
but I have become
a kind of a middleman,
and I think
it's high time
that you two
talked with each other,
face to face.
* you are my life *
* and you're the last
thing on my mind *
* before i
go to sleep at night *
* you're always around *
* when I'm in... *
I took your advice
and decided
to help myself.
* ...On my mind *
* you were my soul
and you... *
how'd you
get here, Ali?
Your boy Alfred
hooked me up.
He called me
late last night
and insisted
that we come out
right away.
We? James here, too?
Yeah.
Nisi, I don't know if
you want to stay here,
if you want to go home,
or what you want to do.
All I know is
I've had one dream
and one dream only
since high school...
And that's--and
that's to be with you.
* even if you
took my heart *
* and tore it apart *
come on, they're
playing our song.
* I would love you still *
* forever *
* we've had our fun *
* and we've made mistakes *
* but who'd have
guessed along that road *
* we'd learn
to give and take? *
* give so much more
than I could ever... *
James:
you know what?
Everything you said
about me was true.
I do need to change.
So from now on,
I promise you,
I'm going to change.
For real?
For real.
[Sighs]
This--this is
the kind of stuff
you deserve.
[Sobbing]
But I just--
i just can't
give it to you.
I mean, you--you
deserve nice stuff.
You deserve a big
old house,
and--and--you--you--
you--you--deserve
your--your own
backyard.
And--every--
everybody else got
a little white dog.
Why--why you
can't have one?
[Sobbing]
I want to take you
out to dinner,
and--and every time
we go out,
we got to watch...
Other people eat.
Hell, I want to
eat, too.
And you need--you
need some clothes.
Why--why should you
have to wear your
Sunday clothes
on--on Wednesday?
Now, look, girl,
don't think--
don't think
the brother a punk
because he crying
like a little girl,
but...
You're my queen.
And...
I...love--love you!
James, you ain't
never said nothing
like this.
Don't say it
if you don't mean it.
I mean it!
Ohh!
Girl, what's
wrong with you?
I'm sorry, James!
I said I mean it!
* I want you
to know that *
* I can't eat *
* I can't sleep *
ha ha ha ha.
[Sirens]
Come on!
Oh, dear. Hurry, hurry.
Oh, oh!
Thank you! Thank you!
Sir, please,
can I get in there?
It's all right.
Don't panic.
Manley's here.
Nisi, hurry up.
They just took Mr. b
to the hospital.
Come on, hurry!
I'm glad you came.
Um...
I--i want to thank you
for everything
that you've done.
I, uh...
Uh-uh.
You was the one who was
about the money, not us.
I can't believe that
Mr. b is related--
speaking of relatives,
how's Lily?
Oh, Mickey, nisi,
come, please.
You're going to be ok.
Mr. b...
I, uh, um...
[Stammering]
Uh, i--
I ain't Lily's...
Mr. b?
Tracy:
we're losing him.
Get Dr. Russell
in here now.
Doctor: get me
Dr. Jennings down here
immediately.
Give me a hand,
will you, doctor?
Uh, nurse,
get a respirator
over here.
Doctor: Mr. blakemore,
can you hear me?
Nurse:
oxygen, oxygen.
Mr. blakemore?
Nisi: I didn't
get a chance
to tell him.
About Lily?
You didn't have to.
He already knew.
You see, Lily never
had any children.
[Vacuum cleaner running]
Go up there and
look at the picture.
Look at the picture.
Now, who the picture
remind you of?
Uh...
Both:
loquisha Jenkins!
Yecch,
that's so ugly.
There she go,
right there.
This all your
stuff here?
Don't drag it.
I'm not gonna
drag it.
You ready to go?
Wait a minute.
I...
[Clearing throat]
I wish you
a very pleasant journey.
Flying first class
is extremely comfortable.
So I've been told.
We shall miss you.
We're gonna
miss you, too.
Thank you
for everything.
Manley.
Alfred will do very nicely,
thank you.
We should get going.
Tracy: not yet.
I'm glad I caught you.
This will only
take a second.
Please,
come with me.
I just have a document
I'd like to review
with you all.
Good morning to you.
Oh, you're
still here.
Good morning, Isaac.
This is Mr. blakemore's
last will and testament.
"First..."
Mr. blakemore states...
"I'd like to thank
my b.A.P.S nisi and Mickey
for making the last days
of my life as pleasant
as my first years."
Oh, that's sweet.
B.a.p.s?
Black American princesses.
Uh, yeah. Please continue.
They have a plane to catch.
Of course.
"Second, I,
Donald William blakemore...
"Being of sound
heart and mind,
"hereby request
the affairs of my estate
"to be incontestably
implemented as follows:
To my b.A.P.S I leave..."
[Orchestral music swells]
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm Jesse Collins,
and we are broadcasting live
at the only salon-restaurant
in Beverly Hills.
There are the owners.
Let's give 'em a big
round of applause.
[Applause and cheers]
Ali: I am
this impressed!
James: Roger that.
Brother,
check out the name.
What the name say, huh?
[Both reading sign]
And we got numerous
slogans like...
Now, if you really must
be there, but you feel
you're underage...
Don't hesitate to give
one of us a page.
And if you're
tired of riding
that raggedy-ass bus,
I ain't got a problem
with you pagin' us.
Now step to the side
while we hit the street,
then turn to your left
and check the fleet.
[Cheers and applause]
* whoa-oh-oh-oh *
* hey-ey-ey *
* oh-oh-oh-oh-ohhh *
Jessie Collins: This is
the grand opening of Lily'z,
the only spot in Beverly Hills
where you can get
bangs 'n' bacon,
weaves 'n' waffles...
And eggs and extensions.
* oh, yeah *
look.
Whoa! rod-man!
You know, I'm gonna
have to take you close.
You ever get tired
of that guy
who has
the beeper company,
beep me. I'll
take care of you.
I'm tired. Already.
Downtown Julie brown:
Can we talk about
the girls?
Manley: oh, the girls
are enchanting!
Yes, they are.
Ahh! there you are!
The telephones
haven't stopped ringing.
They want an exclusive
on the grand opening
in New York next month.
Well, tell e.T.
They can have
the Paris opening.
Absolutely.
and give mtv New York.
Yes.
And please make sure
that everybody comes
to the grand opening
in decatur, Georgia.
Ahh, of course.
Collins: welcome again,
ladies and gentlemen,
the owners of the place
to be in Beverly Hills,
Lily'z!
Now that the owners are
here, nisi and Mickey,
it's time to kick off
the grand opening!
Ladies, come on up here.
Come and
get in your party!
Ha ha ha ha!
* 'cause your love
is shinin' down on me *
* oooooh *
* shine on! *
* whoo-hoo-hoo-ooh *
* oh-oh-oh-oh-ohh *
* shine on *
* wanna shout it
from the highest mountain *
* and from my heart
for all the world to see *
* wanna raise my hands
and thank the heavens *
* 'cause your love
is shinin' down on me *
* wanna shout it
from the highest mountain *
* and from my heart
for all the world to see *
* wanna raise my hands
and thank the heavens *
* 'cause your love
is shinin' down on me *
captioning made possible by
new line home video
captioning performed by
the national captioning
institute, inc.
Public performance of captions
prohibited without permission of
national captioning institute