I'm That Franck Amory. Pretty in pictures but less real.
I work at Publisher Schaudel, who spends a lot of comics.
As a child I was fond of drawing and especially manga.
The two next to me are my best friends.
We are all changed ... Yet almost all of them.
The guy with the Ray-Ban is Sam.
He works at Manpower. Since he works
the number of female workers has increased from 32 to 80%.
This is Alex, the nicest guy I know, but also the weirdest.
He works as a courier, to the chagrin of his boss.
He loves speed and Fast and Furious.
Today is June 25.
A special day for me because it's my birthday.
Happy birthday, Franck. Kisses.
Day Sonia. Thanks. See you soon, I hope.
Happy birthday.
Thanks, buddy. That's sweet. - Please.
Just kidding. It is a package for Aurelie Goudart.
Look what I found in the van.
Should you deliver anywhere? - As long as he does not claim it ...
Fantastic, eh.
And such a great zoom.
I'll see you, fatso.
What a fat guy. - I have to go.
See you for the groceries. Day.
That's like me. This guy takes me to his home.
He starts to fuck me. But then his girlfriend inside
while we are doing. You would not do that.
She's gonna freak out, "You fucked my friend."
I said, "Wait a minute, I fuck him, so he is my love."
And you know what she said? "What is your problem?"
I say ". Nothing What is your problem?" And when she held her tongue.
I fuck him, that's all.
Estelle, I ... - I fuck him, he fucks me, nothing more.
Wait, Mom. What?
I have to see the boss. - Why?
Hope for a better life. - Hurry.
I'm going to do everything alone.
Sorry, what did you say?
What floor are you going?
Is that Scream 4?
And then? If you have no friends, go on Facebook.
What are you gawking at me like that? I'm not your sweetheart.
Get out of here.
Imbecile.
Sidney's cousin is the killer.
Goodbye, pus.
The rear is cut reason. A lousy courier.
Not really? On the contrary. I do not want to arrive in a wreck.
At one time we both have a break I want to take advantage of the convertible.
I have to show. Kiss.
What are you doing here? Are you new?
I've been working for two years at the reception. I'm Franck Amory.
What are you doing in my office?
I draw comics. I work here and hope I can show my drawings.
And today I thought, "I'm just going to ask and" ...
Thank you for calling me back.
ASAP.
Why, a week? It's just a mirror.
But it just depends what loose.
I come to you, I'll be there in five minutes.
Mr. Schaudel?
Do a squirrel after.
And now a dinosaur. - No.
Come on. One million views on YouTube, you get money.
Your grandmother is a prehistoric animal.
Come on, Sam, please. - Stop it.
My camera, now look.
Boys, so much alcohol?
You are 30. You want us to buy Kidibul?
But so much.
Laure comes. That there are already 33 - 33?
Who all? - Sandrine, Laure, Lucie, Claire ...
Who? I know of no one. - That's nothing. They are handsome chicks.
Especially Lucie, new on the job, with huge boobs.
She is married, but we forgive her.
Are there any chicks you do not like handsome? - Yes, your exes.
That is not love for your mother.
This is not for my birthday. You organize this party for you.
Well, if not confirm your friends ...
Who has not confirmed? - Sébastien, Sylvain, Sonia Lamar ...
Sonia Lamar, who does not.
Who is that? - My ex.
She also worked at Schaudel. Now she sells cupcakes.
I do not know her. When was that?
Last year, on her farewell drink.
She kissed me on I Want You Back by The Jackson 5.
His long you been together?
Yes and no ... - When did you see her last?
At her farewell drink.
That was quite a relationship. - Many plans made sure?
Just stop. I gotta get back to work.
And do not laugh, you. You must pay for your chicks.
That again is not love for his mother.
Hi, honey. Everything good? - Yes .
The babysitter was attacked in the subway.
That's terrible. - Yes, they can not come three weeks, .
No, I mean for us. Who is the little fit?
If you go alone, I watch out Remi.
But it is the night of the publishers.
Everyone comes with his partner. What about me?
I'll find a solution. Big kiss.
My best Franáois, that's good.
Franck. - Also good. Do you have plans tonight?
Yes. - Okay, you come watch my son.
That is difficult. My birthday and ... - Franáois.
Would you like me Monday show your drawings?
Yes, but ... - Perfect.
19 hours, Rue de la ferme 7 in Saint-Germain-en-Laye.
We have everything in the house, but what could I say?
This opportunity I can not pass up.
Besides, can you bring me? - Where is it?
Rue de la ferme 7 in Saint-Germain-en-Laye.
Forget about it. I do not have my passport. - Is it so far?
Yeah, who's there? - Hello, I'm babysitting .
Franáois day. - Franck.
Sorry, Franck. I'm Claire.
Thank you for coming fit Rami.
You're welcome.
Franáois day. That lasted long.
It is far away. Half hours.
Had said that, you could have a ride with me.
Good. I'll show you the house.
Come on in.
Can you take off your shoes? - Sure.
Thanks.
There is an artist in your son. - That's mine.
I paint since I stay home for Rami.
This is the sitting room, the remote controls
the television, the DVD player
the blinds, the curtains, and the fireplace.
The fish I have given food.
And Phoenix also.
A beautiful beast. - Marc is fascinated by ornithology.
A rare species. He has him for twenty years.
He got him before we knew each other.
There is the kitchen.
Rami takes morning Nesquik, a roll with Nutella.
Why in the morning? - We come back tomorrow around 18 hours.
Ah so? - I forget the most important.
Rami has asthma. This is his puffer in the case of.
In the cabinets ...
No, you can put anything on the cabinet.
That sign is all that Marc has his father.
He is extremely attached to it.
Your room is upstairs next to the playroom Rami. I will call him.
Rami, you can just come down?
This is Franck.
Say day, Rami. - Day Rami.
He is shy, within two hours is about.
Go give your daddy a kiss? He is loading.
Why does not he? - Please, darling. He's busy.
As usual. - What are we waiting for?
What's wrong? - You should come to the football.
I have to it for my work, not to play golf.
Next time I will definitely participate, I promise. - But it is the final.
The next time then. And I buy a sweater from PSG. Okay?
The pot.
I buy everything he wants and he is still not satisfied.
That's for you. We'll call you later.
Thank you. - See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow. Good trip.
That's cool.
Mr. Schaudel! - Yes?
Your hedge is over seven feet tall.
I'm going to complain to the town if you do nothing about it.
Well you said, sir Monet.
Zagevent.
Rami?
Au, damn.
Who said you could come in?
We are not so well begun, but that does not matter.
It's not too late. Will you come watch a movie?
Within 3 count my room if I say that you've been to me.
What? - One.
Two.
I hope everything goes well.
Do not worry. He's a serious guy.
I mean Rami.
Why would not it go well?
He becomes difficult.
This is normal. For example, children of his age.
We were rebellious when we were ten years.
He is disappointed about the football match.
We can ask the babysitter to take him.
Which car? Your brand new 4x4?
My Range? You can see that from here.
It's not the final, but you see him play again.
My dad never came to see the rugby and I've still a successful life.
Speaking well?
Take off your shoes.
Your shoes.
I have your old man well known.
Do you know that he is deceased?
I did not know. How did he die?
Everything okay, Rami?
Do you need something? - That was his weakness .
How do you know?
Do you want to watch the movie? - I tell you that he had a weakness .
Listen ... - He could be someone .
You should not ... I know you ... - Take me to the carnival.
No. I stand before you and I do not want you getting hurt.
Watch for The Departed. A good movie.
No. That I have seen.
DiCaprio dies at the end.
Hello? - It is Claire .
Day Claire. Arrived safely? - Yes, thank you. Everything goes well?
Yes, very good. - May I speak Rami ?
He sleeps all.
Already?
We have played a lot, so he sleeps very well.
Then at least he's good. - Yes, indeed .
Okay, tomorrow, Franck. - See you tomorrow. Thank you.
Where were you?
I walk you search for an hour. - I wanted to know how it was with Rami.
Patronize him not so. Here.
Who is it? - No one, to take a picture of me.
Come on, quickly, quickly.
You look beautiful. - Thank you.
Yeah? - Hello, Mr. Schaudel ?
Yes. - This is the police .
If you live on the Rue de la ferme 7?
Yes, why?
There's been an incident tonight at home.
An incident? What happened?
Difficult to explain on the phone. - Is Rami?
Is it our son? - Your son
Yes, he is at home with the babysitter.
I'm sorry, but there's no one here. - Why, no one ?
Hello? - Franck, it's Claire Schaudel .
No, ma'am, the police again.
Apparently the babysitter left his phone at home.
What's ...
What happened?
Commissioner Laville.
Mr. and Mrs. Schaudel? - Yes.
Have you found my son? - Not yet.
There is a crisis created and sent out an APB.
Emitted at 3 am.
This is a nightmare. - Who warned you?
Your car was involved in one-run. That's why we were here.
My Range? - Yes.
This is agent Caillaud.
He proposes profiles of criminals.
The babysitter might have abducted our son?
That's hard to say now.
He is not known to the police and he has no criminal record.
But the biggest psychopaths often are not.
The biggest psychopaths? Do you mean child murderers?
Not required. Also rapists or organ traffickers.
Then we'll find them alive.
But not too optimistic that brings misfortune.
Did you have a dispute with the babysitter? - No.
This was below the bench. Perhaps a clue.
Is this yours? - No.
Enter here, it's maybe a snuff movie.
What is a snuff movie? - A murder filmed with an amateur camera.
We're going to watch it directly.
Connect it at that.
Quiet.
Ready, boss. - Can we start?
Go ahead.
Good evening everyone and welcome to Alex TV
"Laughter blown" with the aim of one million views on YouTube.
I know. What does he do for my home? - Who is that?
Idiotic courier who hit me yesterday.
Let you format a PV?
No, I have no points on ... he ran.
We go over to our reporter, Sam.
This is a big night as we come to the birthday of our size Franck.
Is he crying? Laugh? Crying with laughter?
We'll now explore.
Exciting. - His boss there is well-off .
He pays no taxes and put everything in Swiss accounts.
He pays workers in black.
That is not true. What nonsense.
Yes, what nonsense.
There he is. Happy birthday.
What are you doing here? - Your birthday.
You want me to get fired?
And the small sleeps. - I love children.
"I love children." That does not sound good.
Sonia comes. - Sonia? That's a joke?
No, they confirmed on Facebook. - No way. Get out.
Call her to cancel.
I got her number. - Say it like it is here.
Let us inside. - I have the little fit.
We have thought of everything.
What is that? - A sedative.
Are you crazy? Why not ecstasy?
Ecstasy is too dangerous for a child.
A sedative as well. - It is vegetable.
Give him half a different dose.
No way. No party and I stand by.
Goodbye.
Are you sure he does not wake up? - They sleep until tomorrow.
Hold on. It's still risky. I hope it is not dangerous.
What time did Sonia come? - That there will be.
What a piece.
The mother is super handsome. But he does not get out.
He seems to be Gollum. - You are a bastard.
Why? - You insult Gollum.
They drugging my son and laugh at me. And I'm Gollum?
Wait till they encounter Gollum. On their bakkes.
And I'm Gollum?
Who is Gollum anyway?
I don’t know.
Damn, calling the mother.
Put them my regards.
Silent. From the room. - Madam, I love you.
Silence you. - I did not say anything.
It's Claire.
Claire day. Arrived safely?
Yes, thank you. Everything goes well?
Yes, very well.
May I speak Rami? - He sleeps all .
Now all?
We have played a lot so he sleeps very well.
Then at least he's good. - Yes, indeed .
Okay, tomorrow, Franck. - Until tomorrow .
Sleep well, Adolfje.
Leave him alone, damn.
That's still not bad.
What is that? - The bell.
Sonia?
What is all this? You said only Sonia would come.
No, she would come. Not that she was the only one.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Good evening, everyone. Excuse.
It is very nice that you have come for my birthday.
And for the beer ...
And for the beer. A small problem. I fear that ...
Franck day.
Happy birthday. - Sonia.
What is she doing there? - Who is that?
She has worked for me. Until last year.
Sonia Lamar. I never forget a face.
Love that you came. - I had nothing else to do.
Well ... Welcome everyone.
Can you take your shoes off?
I told you he was funny.
No, really. Can you ... I mean it.
Where can I put this? - The kitchen is there.
Have you had problems with her? Dismissal, sexual harassment?
Not at all.
Rigot, I want the number for that Sonia Lamar.
This resembles the case Pascal René.
The case Pascal René? - A child that has disappeared.
Have you found him? - Yes, but not in one piece.
Look at the labels.
Just old wine. All expire. Look.
Stop it. I do not feel well. - What is it?
Have you seen Sonia? - Yes, and then?
Turn that off.
What's wrong with Sonia? - What a killer bitch.
I would leave my family for her. - You have no family.
Then it is less painful for them.
That you can not do Franck tonight. - I know.
Tomorrow. - You're right, I'm stuck.
Tonight I see Lucie, a married woman.
What do you do? - I'll take what Ruinart.
You take nothing with it. Back to top. - One bottle.
Put that back. Upwards. - What are we drinking?
Come on, Alex.
Have they given you drink?
It's nice, but far. - Yes.
Sonia, my friends, Sam and Alex. - Hello.
Hello.
This is Ernest. My sex buddy.
But no, he is my cousin. He is married.
And love. Hello.
Pleased to meet you. Sonia talks a lot about you.
Sylvain here, there Sylvain Sylvain did this ...
My name is Franck. - I see.
That's not bad. You also see a nice guy out.
Who wants a drink? Sonia, I Ruinart.
No, I do not drink alcohol anymore. - Why not?
I'm really freaked out at my farewell drink at Schaudel.
I was so drunk that I remember nothing more.
Nothing at all? - A total blackout.
I want a glass of Ruinart.
Not prefer a Schweppes? - No, Ruinart is good.
Everything okay? - Yes.
Want a drink? - Yes.
A chicken. - A goat.
A velociraptor. - Yes.
Earlier, the mother of Franck. - I can also imitate a tortoise.
That is cool.
Great.
I'm a fan.
Amazing what you do with your body. - I can do much more.
I can well imitate a sea lion. - Display.
The sea lion.
You will also work with Manpower? - Yes.
My wife also. - That's cool.
There is the Ruinart.
You go mobile, Sonia.
That's my friend. - You have a boyfriend?
Did you want me maybe decorate?
Sonia, I'm sorry. - Simpleton.
Sorry. Where he flew against?
My mouth. What a fool.
I am sorry - Now you've got it all made.
You're bleeding not?
I am sorry He flew right out. I do not often open bottles.
Is it? - It goes, it goes.
It's all right.
I'm going to open it. - Do you see anything?
Surprise. - Where's the party?
Damn, guys. You believe that?
Is not it a costume party? - No, sorry.
Great. - We are so come by subway.
Here, with this being the better.
I knew nothing. I organize not.
We sound at Franck and our student years.
With Blanchard. - The Professor economy?
Yes. - The sex bomb of the class.
The brunette. Anyone who fucked.
What a mattress. And no entrance fee.
The slut.
She ate a pig, but she went himself as a beast rampage.
What was her name? - No idea.
Myriam? - Yes, Myriam Elalaoui.
That's my sister. - Really?
I'll see if the minor is still asleep.
Grease Lapps.
Same name. - We have fucked his sister.
We fucked his sister. - I've also fucked.
Bastard. - Everyone has been served.
Look, Gérard de Gaulle.
What a ridiculous mustache.
Happy birthday, Francky.
Happy birthday, Franck.
Say happy birthday, Coco.
Would you like to drink? Are you thirsty? Wait a minute.
Here, that is Ruinart.
Nice, huh? Okay, enough, or you are still addicted to the drink.
What? Want some?
Damn, he does not move. I think he's dead.
We have slain him? Damn.
Now what? - We have to resuscitate him.
Quick, before Franck sees.
Put it in your briefs. - That stinks.
And then? He's dead, he still smells nothing.
What are you doing here? Is he dead?
No. - Yes, he seems dead.
No, not yet.
Wait. One, two, three, four ...
five and six. One, two, three, four.
It's an animal. Do mouth-to-mouth resuscitation.
One, two, three ... one, two, three ...
one, two, three ... one, two, three ...
Wake up, Coco. Wait, I'm going to take his pulse.
We have to think of something.
Wait, do not move.
Fly, Coco.
Commissioner Sonia Lamar is unreachable.
Leave a message. Ask if they call back.
The whole house has been searched. No trace of the child.
Have you looked in the freezer?
No, it's not true. - That can not.
Enough is enough.
Now blown fuses? - Happy birthday, buddy.
Blow them out.
Forward.
Good job.
Take it, I made them.
Really? - Yes.
Take it, I've made myself.
What is it? - That's vanilla and chicken.
That is chocolate and chilli.
And the pink is ratatouille and blueberries.
Is it good? - Yes, very nice.
Delicious. - Really?
Come on, a speech. - Speech, speech.
I do not give speeches.
Thanks for coming to my birthday. - And for the beer.
But I must ask you to leave.
This is the house of my boss and I only here on his child.
I hope you understand that. I am sorry
That's a joke. - Very funny, though.
I'm looking for the owner.
Good evening, police. I'm looking for the owner.
I am that. No, but it's complicated. Why?
Are you or not? - No, but I pass on their child.
There is a complaint from neighbors about the noise.
I need to speak directly to the owners.
Do not bother, that people just went away.
Have you been drinking? - Just a little.
While you can fit on a child? - A glass ...
You come along. - That is not necessary.
Everyone went away. What do you do?
I swear. Those people were just leaving. That is no joke.
Happy birthday, buddy.
Happy birthday, buddy. - I filmed everything.
You enjoyed it, huh?
I wanted to be in your place. - That will do.
Do not worry, I've found another shirt.
Gang bastards. Something to do with Sonia there.
It was to laugh. You are still enjoyed it.
With an ass of a stranger in my face, with Sonia there?
I have not enjoyed it. I can imagine nothing worse.
Franck? - What is it?
Behind you.
He does not sleep.
He sleepwalking fixed. That must be it.
Rami.
Rami! Wait!
I will explain.
I am 30 and this was the idea of ??my friends.
I try to send them away.
I wish your father knows nothing of. Can you remain silent?
Of course. But then I want 300 euros.
What? - 300 euros. Or I call my father.
How do I get 300 euros?
My parents still give you money? You have three seconds: one ...
Rami, are you crazy or what?
Otherwise, I'll call my father.
Satisfied? - 100 euro too little. I'll call my dad.
Wait, I have not.
Wait in your room upon me.
Would you borrow me some money?
Of course, Sylvain.
I'll pay you back definitely. - How much? Do you have a pen?
What do you want? Money? - No, no, never mind.
I only have five euros.
Rami, I have 30 euros.
Rami? Where is he? - No idea.
Rami? - Rami?
Your mobile phone is on that chair. - Damn.
What is all this? - What is it?
13 missed calls.
The pus. He has a text message sent to all women.
What text?
You want to fuck your ass.
Apparently there is someone interested.
I killed him. I make him.
I killed him.
"I killed him."
Amory goes to a psychologist?
No idea. I hardly know him. I've seen him twice.
You said you knew him well. You let our child to a stranger?
Is it my fault that your babysitter us in the lurch?
Are you crazy? Your evening goes on Rami?
You're the most selfish man I know.
I would not be so self-centered?
You call your name when we make love.
Rami?
Is he in the garden? - No .
Sam. The small is gone. Come and search it.
Do not worry. I find him.
Rami.
Where is that little pus?
That bedroom is crazy. - Where are you? It's not funny.
She would have seen me? - Yes, I've seen you.
I'm sorry, Sonia. - Not very.
I've seen her panties.
Sam, have you seen him?
Searched everywhere, nothing found.
Day guys. What's the plan? Want to play Scrabble?
No time. We are looking for a child.
Rami? - Yes.
The small, sweater, red hood? - Yes, that's him.
No, not seen.
I was joking. He is at home with the bike.
This is his home. - I do not know where he went.
A runaway. That there is still lacked.
I get a car and then go look for him.
Damn.
I have found a car.
What a container. I go in the front.
Where are you going? - The small is off.
You're not serious. - Yes it is.
Wait, I'll go.
Come on. I'll explain.
We have a problem and have to leave.
Can you anyone outside of work?
No problem. - Everything is under control.
Thanks, guys. Forward. Get out.
Where can he go?
We have to be in place. Where would he go?
I am as a child once runaway. - To where?
After 3 days, still they missed me not.
I then went home.
Look there.
The carnival. Of course. There we go.
And we look for that kid later.
Damn, I had forgotten her.
Who? - Lucie, who married woman.
As my wife is too. - A married woman?
To help the couple. She's frustrated.
What are you sympathetic. - Exactly. Look how happy she is.
Hello? -? Hi
Plans have changed. The party is over.
I was just about to leave. Will you come to my house?
I'm far from the 15th arrondissement.
That is not far. I come from there. At most 25 minutes.
I can be there in 25 minutes.
Perfect. My husband is still not home.
Are you sure? - Yes, very definitely .
He is with his niece to a party in Saint-Germain-en-Laye.
Hello!
Ha.
I'm going to show. - Give that phone here.
Lucie? - Ernest ?
Poepie, is that you?
Yes, it is poepie, slut.
I'll make you fall!
I could not have known. - You fuck my wife.
Quiet. - I want to get off.
Stop immediately, I want to get off.
Sam fucks the wife of Ernest.
Stop filming.
The door. - The door, damn it.
Ernest, is it? - You can go to hell.
Nice friends you have.
Wait, Ernest. It is a misunderstanding.
A misunderstanding. Lucie's 15th who calls her husband Poepie.
I Poepie. And you fucking my wife.
Ernest, come back.
The cops. Also that yet. Hold this, Sam.
I did not know.
Good evening. Can you shut the engine down
and give the papers of the car? - Of course.
No problem. - Stop!
Alex, what are you doing? - Everything under control.
Nothing in control. - Stop, Alex!
I have no license and no papers of the car.
No papers? Where did you find that car?
In the garage of the family Schaudel.
I'll bring it tomorrow to the garage of a friend.
Guys, there Rami.
Turn back. - The cops are behind us.
This can not be. - Stop!
Damn, there they are.
Good evening. - Stop immediately.
Yes, we are going to stop. Stop, asshole.
I have my identity not. Stop, please.
Stop the car, now.
I do not see you, I do not see you.
I do not see you. I do not see you.
Stop, Alex. Please.
Alex, if we crash, I'll kill you!
Do not worry, I'm going to lose them.
I've fucked.
I'm going to give everything.
Sam, look.
Who's Sebastien Loeb of the woods? IK.
Now you really should stop. - Stop, damn it!
I have everything under control. - The rear!
Look how I maneuver. A rally, left, right.
It's fast!
I've shaken. Can not thank you wonder?
Fortunately, he is not broken.
Do not pull that face.
It does look impressive, but it's not so bad.
I got them anyway shaken off, huh?
I want to die.
And I want you dead.
Now just find Rami, somewhere dead in the woods.
And then it's done. - Do not worry.
He is now eating solid candy. We're going to look for him.
The cops are coming. We gotta get outta here.
Look, it's down there. There's the fair.
Fast. - I see nothing.
Hurry up, they are going to be so here.
What have they done to my Range?
You Range can be stolen. And your house too.
Are there not more important things?
Who is it? - Your mother.
For APB. Do not you take on?
No, it's bad enough.
I did not mean it. You know her. That will take hours.
I had more to her to listen.
And? - He does not answer. He gets home?
Sam, now you can go to his wife.
Shut up, Alex.
What a mess.
Are you sure it's down here? - No idea.
And all the men here? Is there a parking lot?
Parking for dicks.
This is a bunch of prostitutes.
Really? - Yes.
Good evening. - Good evening.
I was there for an investigation. - A large study.
What?
Good evening. - Good evening.
Where are we?
Here we are.
Watch out.
Thank you.
Did you see how she looked at me? - It was a whore.
And then? What do you know of women?
She looked at me. - It's a whore.
She looked at you like that? No. Well then.
That's not bad. It's a whore.
She would make me want to. - 50 Euro.
She does that for 25 euros.
In that case, ...
That reminds me of the time I was carefree and silly.
Last week?
Let's go find Rami and then we're gone. Come on.
Rami.
That's not him.
I found him there.
Rami ...
Excuse me, sir. There he is.
Rami. - Franck.
Make me so worried. Home.
No way. - Yes it is. Come on.
Stressful enough for today. Get out of here.
Enough played with my balls. We're gone.
Go. Let me go.
Help. I get kidnapped. - Stop that. Come on.
Help, they are pedof ... - It's okay. I'm going to let go.
He makes a joke. Does not it?
We eat a waffle.
Eat your waffle on because we do not stay long.
It's nice here. Do you eat him. That will relax you.
I do not want your waffle. - Yes, to excuse me.
I do not want. - Please to excuse me.
Okay, very funny. What we have fun.
Say rather what attraction you want.
There!
Since you're too small.
If there is someone, do it.
But I tell you that it should not.
Come on, I want to do this. Do not be a sissy.
You're not very brave.
Franck is not brave. I'll go with it.
No, I'll go. I just do not think he is ill.
Where can I buy tickets? - There.
You know you can do from there? - Yes.
Would you like? - No, you know.
Because then I ask it.
Relax, Franck.
I am relaxed.
What power.
There are women who orgasm in something.
Really? - Yes. We can go together if you want.
Do you have something need to make a girl orgasm?
But no, it's just ...
Something to make orgasm a girl. - But no.
The loser.
Have you done in your pants?
Franck, it is against you.
Have you done in your pants? - No.
Are you OK? - So cool. Watch the video.
That face.
A stretchy mouth.
You were more afraid than I am. Look, you're scared.
You see well that you're more afraid than I am.
Look, yes.
Makes you sick in. We do not do that anymore.
Where do we go?
I do not know.
Oh shoot
What was that? Is it done?
I do not feel so good.
Is that for me? - What do I get in return?
A kiss.
Have you seen a ghost? - Here.
Can I exchange it?
No, there are some nice attractions. - Come on.
What is a dark room? - There it is dark.
What? What is it?
Along true?
What was that? - I walked from somewhere.
Careful. - Alex, where are you?
Right behind you. - Who is that?
I am that. - That is Sonia.
I see nothing. - Me neither.
What did you think of the attraction?
I've never had so many jitters.
Really? - Yes.
Do you like it? - I would do it again.
Why are you laughing?
I filmed everything. - Wow say.
We will see the show, but promise you're not going mugs.
No problem. - What?
It was to laugh. - I see the humor in it.
Come on.
I should be angry. You do not notice that you're a man coast.
Great. Nice atmosphere.
And Rami, what would you be?
Your boyfriend. If you're still looking.
Dreams can not hurt. - He's right.
What is your dream, Alex?
Okay, thank you, Alex.
The last 30 minutes forgotten. - Remember that now anyway.
Publishing his own comic. - I can forget.
Seriously now, Rami. A real dream ...
My father is watching as I play football.
I do not like football.
What is your dream, Sonia? - So much .
Have a penis for an hour, to know what that is.
A cupcake chain open worldwide.
A beautiful experience love with a good man. For once.
And Franck and Sam stop mugs. - Yes, I agree.
Okay, what an atmosphere. Great.
What will you do?
What did you ask? - Something that makes you smile again.
What then? - Come on.
No, I'm not. - Come sing. Come on.
Forward, Francky. - Just like old times.
I can not sing. - Come on.
No, I can not sing.
â ™ ª When I had you to myself I did not want you around â ™ ª
â ™ ª Those pretty face always made you stand out in a crowd â ™ ª
â ™ ª But someone picked you from the bunch, one glance was all it fired â ™ ª
â ™ ª Now it's much too late for me to take a second look â ™ ª
â ™ ª Oh baby, give me one more chance â ™ ª
â ™ ª show you That I Love You - Will not you please let me â ™ ª
â ™ ª Back in your heart - Oh darlin ', I was blind to let you go â ™ ª
â ™ ª Let you go, baby - Will not you please let me go â ™ ª
â ™ ª â ™ ª Okay
â ™ ª I want you back â ™ ª
â ™ ª Tryin 'to live without your love is one long sleepless night â ™ ª
â ™ ª Let me show you, girl, That I know wrong from right â ™ ª
â ™ ª Every street you walk on, I leave tear stains on the ground â ™ ª
â ™ ª Following the girl, I did not even around for â ™ ª
â ™ ª Oh baby, give me one more chance â ™ ª
â ™ ª Will not you please let me â ™ ª
â ™ ª Back in your heart? â ™ ª
That was great. - Very fat.
Not bad.
You're jealous. - Thanks.
It was still funny. You have to let go some more.
I'm not a stiff rake. - Then this button loose.
I'm not going to eat.
Do you remember all of your farewell drink.
Why did you say to the contrary?
Because you never called me back.
Surely you've got a friend.
If you can call it that. I know him from yesterday.
How far is your house? - 30 minutes.
What a bad luck, too bad we do not have a car anymore.
At the dinner for idiots gonna be all alone.
What are you doing? - Ernest.
Ernest, come down there.
What is it? - What's the problem?
Are you his size? Do you know him?
Yes, why? - Pay no. Drinking beer.
He eats fries. He keeps me fooled.
What do you mean no? - Nothing.
You laughing at me? Is that your boyfriend?
He says he has eaten and drunk and refuses to pay.
We laugh you out. We did not understand.
We're going to pay you. How much is it?
This is for ...
Ernest, you idiot.
My goodness. - Come Rami, get out.
That was quite a blow.
Hide. There. - Yes, there.
Are you crazy? - He fucked my wife.
The fairground behind us. - Those are not normal.
Even Chuck Norris let the fairground alone.
There they are. Hide.
They are gone. We can go. - I can not.
What is it, Rami? - Got my puffer at?
You puffer? I do not have to.
His asthma. - It'll be okay.
This is serious. My brother is so dead.
I do not want to hear.
He is deceased ... - What do we just say?
I've been saying nothing.
We have to call the fire department. - Then stand the fairground here.
And calling his parents.
Another 30 minutes steps. Now what?
30 minutes, that is. - Shut up.
There are go-karts. - Yes, go-karts.
I think not. Forget about it.
Do you have a better idea? - Forward.
I drive super good.
Do not touch me.
What an idiot. I do not know if he can drive.
Leave the camera here. - Hurry up, hurry up.
Hurry.
Beware, Sam, behind you!
Accelerate, accelerate. Grab the camera.
What are you doing? We have to help Sam.
No, he can well judo. We can not do anything there.
You have to flip. - I flip.
Film job, awesome is that.
Watch out!
Out of the way!
Out of the way.
This is fantastic!
Fast and Furious, Sonia, Fast and Furious.
Vin Diesel can not compete here!
Watch out!
Where is Sam? - Who had a problem.
What kind of problem?
The fairground. Throw away the banana. - What?
You banana. Throw your banana to them.
Well done.
Look out for you. Watch out.
Great. Is this your dream, Sonia?
How is Rami?
We must not dawdle.
Help me with his helmet.
Is it? - Yeah, you know, why?
Puts his helmet. Come on.
Come on, boy. Here we are. Come on.
Hold on, it'll be fine. - Out of the way.
Sorry, Rami. That was not intentional.
But we're there and you're a strong boy.
Very strong. - Ernest is knockout.
What is going on here?
What's this? - We must do something .
Make some place and give me the puffer.
Out of the way, damn it. - Rami.
Breath, Rami. Again.
Going, Rami? - Super Cool, that go-kart.
I have 14 pizzas for Franck Amory. Do you know who that is?
No idea. - He should pay me.
Mr. Schaudel! Now!
You're like that old cartoon from that.
Yes, from Up. - From Up .
Come on, people. The party is over.
It's done. It's done. Done drinking.
What a mess. Get out and done drinking.
Come on down. What is that?
And samurai, come on down.
You are not there. - Why not?
You have no bracelet. - No.
Then you will not be there. - I know the owner.
Look, the fish eat ecstasy.
Look, he smokes a cigar with his ass.
Hi, I'm Mr. Schaudel.
I stink out of my mouth as I have a strontkop.
Where did you find that? - Quiet.
Where did you find that? - In the cigar box.
I told you to stop.
Turn off the music.
Girls, which is a leather seat. Come off it.
The party of the weirdos.
No. Done drinking.
Hey, dude. Want some stuff?
Get out of here with that trade.
What do you do? No, that's not ...
I found a child.
Paul, I'll break your neck.
Franck, I was just about to call.
Hopeless, people do not want road.
I will ask again to leave.
No, we go in the jacuzzi. - Yes.
Let those little alone.
Let those little alone, I say.
This may in the sangria?
No. Where did you find that? - In the basement.
Stay down there.
Where is the jacuzzi anyway?
They're going to throw him out the window.
Going, Rami?
Stay there, I'll get you.
Fatso. That's for those dirty fuck SMS.
No one comes to my ass. Fuck you, fatso.
And stop filming me if I'm doing my dog ??fuck your mother.
Alex, help me to get it out.
Come, Rami.
Is your camera waterproof?
My camera. - Your camera can not care.
Do you think we have to do anything else?
Thank you, ma'am.
We're going to dry in your room. - Excuse me.
What is that smell?
You're an asshole, I got you through. In line like everyone else.
What are you doing? - There he is.
He gets a sausage for his birthday.
Damn, that burns. - Okay, away.
You away! Everybody out!
Everybody out. Everyone away. Fuck off, everyone!
What's that?
What a battlefield.
Forward, home. - No Christmas presents for you.
Yes.
Get out. Go home to sleep.
Look. Look.
Look what you've done.
Come on, get up. Go home.
This is your fault. I hate you.
It's just a bit messy.
I'm home now, but tomorrow at 9 am I'll help clean up.
And what about all that is broken? As the car ...
That is stolen while you slept and you have not heard.
And for the house you say ...
That men Greenpeace invaded.
That they all might smash as Schaudel not recycle.
You did what you could, just for the bird was too late.
The bird? - I think they have him break them .
Rami is saved. - The pizzas are paid .
Yes? - You do not remember.
Alex, you've slain the parrot? - No, that was Greenpeace.
What happened to it? - It was Greenpeace.
What's with the parrot? - It is ...
Franck day. You'll see this video ever do receive.
I want to thank you. I have never been so well amused.
Even though you are sometimes annoying.
I would like to have a dad like you want.
Someone who does nice things with me and play with me
and who thinks of me, not to himself.
So if you are looking for work, I take you as dad.
Not the easiest profession
but you get paid well.
And you get shorter working hours.
Rami, where are you? - I'll be .
Where are you? - On the crapper. I'm coming.
That's what I meant by annoying.
I have to go. Happy birthday.
This was it.
I hope you liked it with us.
Franck, a balance for your birthday?
Perhaps my last because tomorrow I'm dead.
I do not know what I can expect.
Please. - Thank you.
Drink and go to bed, because tomorrow we get up early.
I'm hungry. - Would you like a cupcake?
No, I'm not such a big appetite.
What's that noise?
What's this?
There are still people out there? - No.
My camera. My camera, fast.
Common, common.
To vultures.
Look, the gentleman from Up.
Real. - I want to talk to Mr. Schaudel.
Leave him alone.
I want to speak to Ms Schaudel.
Done with that nonsense. Stop laughing.
There is a problem. - Yes, you!
Like that guy from Up.
What is here?
Stop him. Let the balloons empty.
Throw stones at!
Shooting, Rami.
This is the craziest thing I've ever filmed.
This will definitely get a million views on YouTube.
It flashes? The battery is flat.
Back to square one. Now we know nothing yet.
On the contrary. I think we know more.
He lacks a father like you.
That's possible, but we do not know where the little one is.
I have it!
What? - Gollum, from earlier.
We did not know who it was.
That's the ugly monster from the movie Lord of the Rings.
Caillaud. - Yes?
Go wait in the office. What quickly.
Even the painting of the boy is spoiled.
That is not the boy, damn it!
Ok
They had to get up early this morning.
Do you know why? Apparently not to clean up.
Wait ...
What are you looking for?
I know where they are.
Franck, I am.
What a hell to stand on. Such headaches.
I have a product to the walls.
Mr. and Mrs. Schaudel, you're back.
What happened here tonight ... Unbelievable.
Men Greenpeace invaded here.
We have seen the video.
Listen Mr. Schaudel,
it's gotten out of hand, but we have a lot saved.
Your board example, where you are so attached to.
I'm sorry.
That's because Golblem.
Damn.
Let me go. I will not say anything.
The Franck's his fault.
I swear. Let me go.
Come on, Rami. Come on.
Hello.
Back already? You would only be back to 18 hours.
Is the ceremony went well?
Good job.
Coming just on or have you been home?
Listen, it's not what you think.
Men of Greenpeace ...
Maybe it's not ... - Shut up.
I could not save you from my wife. Do not mess with me.
Now that's a football match.
I forgot the dog.
Marc ... - Mr. Schaudel.
I'm not here for you. They did.
You will not be picked up here.
I do not want to ruin the final. They wait for you.
Range Rover: 85,000 euros.
A Steinway piano: 24,000 euros.
22 bottles of grand cru, a shirt
and moral damage to the board and the parrot.
You're in the shit. Listen carefully ...
No, you listen to me.
Okay, we made some fur in your home.
But Rami is completely blossomed.
Without us you were not even here today.
Besides, I have no money to pay you back.
One more thing: You do not come Monday.
What did he say?
I should not come Monday.
Given a day off? Cool. Cause I'm broken.
Young man, I have a signature?
Papa.
Have you seen my goal?
Yes, I've seen it. And against such opponents.
Have you seen it, Mom? - Yes, honey.
Will we?
Okay, we gotta go.
Mr. Amory, we have to discuss.
Wait a minute please.
This evening I will not forget.
Stay there.
That's me, Franck Amory.
Pretty in the drawing, but even better in real life.
I can realize my dream
thanks to a highly motivated publisher.
Good day."
Good day. Lots of people.
But autograph.
What's your name?
Rami, we must go if we are late.
Franck day. - Success for the contest.
Yes.
Please.
You're welcome. Have a nice day and goodbye.