Oh, baby! Yes!
I give you sex day.
But you do not deserve it.
I'm so naughty.
When should I fuck you harder.
Be as good! Taste my thunder!
Yes!
Do you like it?
Yes! Give it to me, Derek!
More!
Like my rock hard cock?
I like to have your
baby creates inside me. Yeah, baby.
I'll do the ovaries so tender.
I do not respect you, bitch.
But there! How filthy am I?
So dirty.
So unclean that dad must punish you.
Go to it, baby!
Excuse me.
No, it's perfect, you little bitch!
Excuse?
Do not you like to be my bitch?
Do something about it, then.
Okay.
Rice me.
What the hell is this?
Derek. I'm so ugly mouth.
Okay.
Like what?
Samantha.
Like it, Samantha?
Insert it into.
Where? It is physically impossible.
Run Luther up my ass, Derek.
You call the Luther?
Please, Derek. I'm so close!
Bible studies, I'm sorry.
What the hell, Derek?
What the hell? Yeah, what the hell?
I was so close and you know
how long ago it was the last.
We can run again for a while.
You said that the border went on the ass.
There are so vanilla.
Vanilla is a classic taste.
I mean seriously, Derek.
I still love you.
If I can not satisfy you,
then there is a big problem.
I give you free cards for tomorrow.
Exemption card? There is nothing like that.
Jo.
It does. Let loose and
let things get crazy and strange.
It's the bachelor party is for.
Crazy and strange?
You've never tried.
Come on, I know you'll love it.
Ever since we met, I visst-
That you were incapacitated solved bomb of
sexual energy ready to explode.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
You must let loose, for our sake.
Be mad, use drugs, get drunk,
fuck bitches. It is your mission.
Oh fuck bitches?
Yes. For my sake, please.
Okay.
I will.
Hello, Amanda! Hey, Derek. Derek?
What is it with Derek?
We have a deal.
And that man will I
you must ensure that it works.
Ok ...
Make sure he has fun.
That he has a lot of company.
I give Derek exemption card.
Is this a trap?
No.
Wait in the car, Derek!
Adrian, how long
have you been Junior Partner?
Three years, five months and 22 days
without including weekends and overtime.
Obtain Derek sex, then you will
Senior Junior Partner on Monday.
Promoted me?
Do you know when I got an orgasm last?
Is this okay for Derek?
Derek is Derek.
This can save our relationship.
I can not force him.
I certainly will not fuck him.
You do not.
Please. I know that you take
of him. Take care of me too.
All right, I do it.
Good boy.
Turn about.
Who's the boss?
You're the boss.
You must mean it.
You're the boss!
boys,
get kukke their wet now!
I know what you talked about.
I will not do it.
Doing what?
You know.
What? It does not happen.
Do you really implement this?
Yes, with the bachelor party.
Absolutely.
Yes ... bachelor party.
Are you sure about this, Mitchell?
Sue, you can trust me
for I do.
Remember
that if you know a desire, so ...
Go down on your knees and pray?
It's them.
They make you well not gay again?
I do not know.
You must be strong for my sake.
You are of my eye.
My little pumpkin.
My little pumpkin pie.
Will I be your pumpkin latte?
Medium.
Lord, watch over him.
Mitch, what the hell are you wearing?
Not one word from you, bitch.
Was it Sue?
Yes, you know how many girls ...
... who will fuck gay out of you?
Relax, hussy.
Mitch has brought cosmos!
So wet it was here.
Mitch, I've always loved you.
Sue, so nice.
It's bullshit and you know it.
Alright.
$ 1,000 to the
protecting kukke my tonight.
Let me make this clear. Going
pay me to drop sex tonight?
Yes.
What the hell is wrong with you?
What do you mean?
You've got a gift.
Fun that you say it, girl.
I have to call Frank.
Frank?
Yes, he comes and pays for everything.
Why Frank?
Do not stop, girl. Wait a little.
Adrian! How is the drive?
Good, it is about two hours left.
You should have flown.
Nothing is better than flying.
Do not do it.
When do you think you are in the hotel?
Wait. When we land?
About half an hour.
Do not stop without me.
Plane lands in half an hour.
Okay, top.
I'll call back.
Get it back.
Sorry, but what can I say? I am
a rebel, I do not follow the rules.
God, I should ... Now there
Time for your flyunderholdning.
OMG ...
Captain has turned on belt sign. we
begins the approach to Las Vegas ...
Ensure that their tables and chairs
standing erect ...
You are shaved, I love you.
... And locked.
OMG ...
We in staff will thank you
chose to fly with us ... God!
Why, Frank?
Amanda invited him, they are friends.
Yes, they are friends. "They dated".
Who is Frank?
For he sounds cute out.
Focus, this being the best
weekend ever. Vegas, baby!
Yes, damn.
Look at the place, it took hours
to find it. Blackjack, poker ...
Gentlemen, welcome to Vegas.
As if we had never been here before.
I've never been here before.
Quiet, it's what you say here.
It is a kind tradition.
Armed bandits!
Is he gay?
It's complicated.
It need not be.
There he is!
What is it? Come, kjekking.
Do not hug me.
Looks good. Pilates? Yes, it is.
So how did Amanda it?
Still as crazy in bed?
Has he told?
Amanda and I used to fuck.
Please, Frank.
The wound I know you? I'm kidding only.
Put your hands up.
Now I take you. Come, boys.
Tonight is savage and wrong.
Nicely!
Thousand dollars ... no problems.
Gentlemen. Welcome to the suite.
God, look at the view!
Should he do it everywhere?
Take it easy. What is his problem?
Guys, save it for later.
Shots, we gotcha shots. Mitchell!
Now we started. Listen, motherfuckers.
Tonight there is not the word no
in vocabulary.
This is starting to be too much for me.
Derek, just because you marry ...
... You do not get your balls cut off.
What the hell do you mean by that?
That night takes us where it wants!
Ok, for one night we all
probability forget. Cheers.
Frank, are you ready for tonight?
I have a surprise for Derek.
Really?
Yes.
Want to see?
Is that what I think it is?
No, it's just ecstacy. Good shit.
Amanda said that he probably was tense.
And I heard about you little plan.
He should get one as soon as evening
get started, what it will do.
In more than one way.
What?
Go to hell!
Measure eleven.
What?
Damn, two o'clock I meant.
Okay, collection. We need to get them here.
Let them have their bachelor party.
No, no way.
This I do. I go there
with someone like having shaken it.
Mitch, no.
Take it easy, do not you trust me?
It's not about trust. we let
them chilling bit before we turn to.
Wrong. This I do. I bid
them drinks, then it is resolved.
How do you know that they will be checked?
All girls want it.
There are four girls in a bathing hut.
Where is your testicles, man?
I think that there is some sleskt.
Listen. A wise man once said:
Can not they handle us as bad,
they deserve us not as the best.
Was not that Marilyn Monroe?
Fun that you noticed it.
Too late. No chance tonight.
That is what happens when you lose focus.
Calm down, Frank.
That's how it works.
Hello, boys.
We've been looking for you everywhere.
We thought that we would meet here.
No, idiot. Come on.
Thank you saved us.Thanx By Nikul pipariya
They were real idiots.
No problems, girl.
I'm Amber.
This is Casey to marry.
Sienna, bridesmaid and Tatiana.
I called Adrian, this is Mitchell.
Frank and groom Derek.
Hello, nice to meet you.
Shots?
Kind, but it's not necessary.
Nothing stops him,
then let him bid you on drinks.
Speaking of drinks, refills?
So what are you doing tonight?
Wish I knew.
Adrian and Frank keeps it secret.
It sounds mysterious.
Yes, and it scares me.
I'm back.
Where do you come from?
LA.
Cult.
Shit.
Well done, idiot.
Do not blame me.
It's okay. We are here, what?
Just go there and say something.
What should I ...
Amateurs.
Ladies. Tonight .... let me guess.
Dinner and Thunder Dicks?
How did you know?
It is a common stag parties.
Australian hunker.
Not that I blame you.
Okay, what would you have done instead?
Velvet Atheneum.
There is a strip club.
And?
You get much more fun with us
there than at Thunder dicks.
You see, Velvet Atheneum
is ... wild. Unanticipated.
You may also receive look sausage.
Sausage?
Yes, underlivsvesler,
shells clubs, taco clamps.
Thunder Dicks has wrapped meat.
Frank, how do you know?
Velvet Atheneum is special.
Up there, only ladies.
So much sausage.
Sausage sounds pretty fun out.
Wait a little.
We have them.
We have everything plans.
Let them have their own evening.
What are you doing, Frank?
Dinner and Thunder Dicks? So common.
You say it just because he said it.
Was not such a fucking wimp!
We go to the strip club anyway,
what makes it that they are with us?
Two stag parties.
How sweet is that?
It sounds a bit wild.
Maybe you're right.
It does not affect our night.
Clear that I am right, kukkhode.
We do not know them even.
See, they look so harmless out.
I'm on it.
Even Mitch the Bitch is on.
You have no idea.
They are so gracious.
Look how hard they try.
And it would keep idiots gone.
Why are they like that?
Derek, are you sure about this?
Is this what you want to do?
Why not? It suffers a bit dangerous.
Yes!
Tatiana?
Sure.
So, boys. We are with.
Good, we thought that you should say no.
I'm so excited!
Come over for drinks afterwards.
What a wonderful night out!
Guys, I know we said yes and that,
but we should do it here?
What?
This with them. We need us.
Who cares, they invited us.
They ask literal about it.
Are you afraid
to fuck someone tonight?
Hey.
Hello, boys.
Come in.
For a nice suite.
You must wait. Amber and Tatiana
is not clear, then turn you down.
Come, Mitchie. Choose our dresses.
We need a gays smaksråd.
What is that accent?
Russian.
Delightful. This will be fun.
OMG, Tatiana.
The dress fits you excellent.
Do you think?
Yes, your breasts are great in it.
OMG, I'm so envious of
tits yours. Mitchie, they are not nice?
It's not my thing, cutie.
Interest objectively.
Not something one real push-up bra
would not do even better.
Good point. Know them.
Excuse?
Fine.
Please ...
That yes. Good boy.
Soft and robust.
Fine breasts.
Come on, they're perfect.
Amber, then. You are much more beautiful than I am.
You've flawless skin.
It is not true.
Jo.
You are perfect.
No.
What is happening?
Sienna? Thank you.
Why?
For that you went with this.
You were clearly against it ...
... But we have to have fun.
I just want Casey to have fun.
We can also have fun.
There we signal our.
Here it is.
Velvet Atheneum.
This place has something for everyone.
I'm so hard now.
Here we are.
Gentlemen come.
Ladies, this road.
Where do you think you should?
Yeah, Mitch. Have fun up there instead.
Yes, fun with your girlfriends,
your damn rævpirat.
Hell!
OMG ...
Hi, I'm Providence.
Hey, Derek.
Nice to meet you, Derek. will
go to Champagne room with me?
It is not.
Yes, he would like to go there and have fun.
He's just a little shy.
Providence, give my friend ...
... one of everything. I'll pay.
When he comes back,
has metamorphosis his begun.
I wonder how it goes
Mitch up there with the ladies.
Too much dick there.
Enjoy it.
I have so much fun!
So what do you want me to do?
What you normally do?
Like my body?
You are fighting beautiful, yes.
I can not do this.
Let me guess, a stag?
Excuse me.
You are an alright kid.
She must be awesome.
Here, purchase a drink and make
to give your friends a thumbs up, okay?
Thank you.
OMG ... That there is too much dick.
I want a drink.
I'm going with.
Thank you.
We go and look at her.
She has huge breasts.
I'm here, but thanks anyway.
Come on, Casey. Let's have fun.
I have,
but I need a little sausage break.
Can we stop calling it that?
Come on, it's your big night.
Yeah, that's it.
See, that's Derek. Derek!
Perfect, I'm sitting here and talking with
him while having fun so we'll see next.
Okay.
Cheers.
Shit.
Damn cardboard call.
You are angry because
Thunder dicks, what?
Let me buy you a drink.
No thanks, you've done enough.
Or not.
Seaman, you can fix a drink?
Yes, Captain.
Vodka with tranebærsjus.
Can you be more stereotypical?
Excuse?
A gay ordering vodka cranberry?
But ... I'm not gay.
That's the point.
I do not understand.
I do it to approach girls.
So they use me
as a kind of sexually project.
A sexprosjekt? Wow.
You are a real idiot.
Yes, one can question it.
A gray area, but layers drink now.
For your information, I like
whiskey with water, and I'm gay.
No, I'm sorry. I did not mean ...
No, of course not.
I'm not homophobic or anything.
Why I got that impression?
I have many friends gays
hanging in my home.
Is that true?
Good, then I make your drink, okay?
Be careful, they are properly strong.
I like them strong.
Can you keep up with this?
Excuse me.
Thank you.
It's wet my pants now.
Morn, buddy.
Who are the lucky type?
Derek.
There are rumors that he is busy.
You can not get him.
What is it? Vodka cranberry? Cult.
So it was Mitchell, what?
Yes, we met earlier.
Exactly. What the two of ...
... goes out, pull some fresh air
and talk a little.
Yeah ... no.
Another time?
Maybe, I guess.
You are a bit close.
I can get closer.
I do, baby. Where should he?
Okay, this does not feel so good.
Good, another time then.
Another time ...
Bartender! Give me a whiskey with water.
I've never been on a
strip club before. Dad was against it.
Here's a wedding present for you.
And where is mine?
It seems as if
I bet all the ladies on drinks?
It's ok, we can share.
No, I am pure from sexual
transmitted diseases and stuff.
I'll go up and look at men
with real balls.
Sexually transmitted diseases?
Not that it matters.
We are engaged.
No, we are not engaged.
I know it,
I just think that you are safe.
One can not be too sure.
Cheers to that.
So tell your husband.
Boslov?
He's a really good guy
when getting to know him.
What does he do?
He is an entrepreneur.
He has some clubs and travel a lot.
He does not like to talk about it.
How did you meet?
On his club a few months ago.
He asked if we wanted to dance
and refused to hear an answer.
You get him next time.
He knows what he wants.
Yes, he takes good care of me.
The best bachelor party ever.
Allows that you met a good guy.
Exactly. He's a good guy.
One must keep on the good.
Yeah, cheers for that.
Cheers.
So how is your prospective bride?
Amanda.
There are American.
Yeah, she's amazing. As Boslov.
She knows exactly what she wants.
I knew I wanted to marry me then
I was 30 and Amanda are good for it.
She fits into the plan.
Absolutely.
As you said, one must stick to something
good. One does not just younger.
I feel completely.
Yes, do so it rains on me.
Who is your father?
Was not that sexy, Mitchie?
Yes, so much sausage in the face.
Kill me now, girl.
Now I will have a lapdance.
Sure you will.
Your hussy.
What I give you one?
Rain on me, girl.
I have a better idea.
Tell me, man. Are they a good couple?
Excuse?
Come on, you can tell me.
Derek is happy,
and it is the most important.
Tull. You know that the answer is no.
And?
He's your best friend.
Yes, but I do not decide.
I support him no matter
what I think. You then?
No way. Casey commits
a big mistake. She knows him hardly.
And yet here we are.
Yes, we do.
Thank you for talking with me.
Come on, there's more to do in Vegas
than mope at a strip club.
Shall we grab the other and pull?
Very happy.
What about strippers, coke and hookers?
If it makes you happy then.
This money is to you.
Money for you.
OMG ... I think
that we met before.
Frank, we're leaving.
Go to hell!
I mean, seriously, come on.
Getting Providence join?
Hello.
No, Providence must work, what?
I can come after my second job.
She is an angel, Adrian.
A fucking angel, god ...
Have you seen Mitch?
Yeah, he's over there.
How the hell ...
I really like him. He is wild.
What do you think, Providence?
I think he has some dark secrets
that can give him major problems.
As I said, she is an angel!
Hands.
Excuse
but I can not help it.
All together. Mitch, we go.
Frank, I mean seriously. Come on.
I can not find Casey and Derek.
What?
Sorry, we miss one prospective bride
and grooms. He is 1.90 and slim.
She is 1.80, has short brown hair
and looks like a budding bride.
I saw their friends. They were away
and fucked almost at my bar.
Casey would never ...
Derek would not ...
Whatever the chattering about to marry,
so I sent them supply
Little Whites to solve it
and get them out of here.
Little Whites?
Yes, wedding chapel down the street.
Hell!
We must go.
What is love?
It is patient, kind and soft.
Love is joy, peace and happiness.
It knows no hatred or anger.
Stop!
Damn.
Excuse me.
No, Tatiana, they are real.
Mitchell, they are real.
We walked right into a wedding
which was not theirs.
I do not know what we should do.
So embarrassing.
We are truly sorry.
Believe it or not, but it is common.
We lack a prospective bride
and grooms. They came certain here tonight.
Many passes here every night.
Sounds Derek and Casey known?
Was you with them?
So when do you remember them?
Do you think that this place is a joke?
This is God's household
And we believe in
love true power.
I would think that I remember all
who come here and marry -
-but it had been a lie.
They came here a while ago.
I forget them never. Keep it as
a souvenir and if you excuse me.
I have a photo booth to wash.
Look at this.
Where is Casey? OMG ...
OMG!
She sucks him.
OMG.
We find them, it resolves itself.
No, do not dissolve.
Boslov going to kill me.
Who the hell is Boslov?
Casey fiance.
And my cousin.
Boslov said it happened Casey something should
he take me in the desert and kill me.
Come on, it's like you just saying.
No, he does really.
Probably you and Derek too.
Pardon?
So Derek went with one that is going to marry
with a Russian mafia boss?
He is the mafia boss and my family
does not allow it.
Who cares? Hell.
I did not know either about it.
Casey talking never about him.
Should not we learned that before?
I do not know you.
Hell.
What does it matter?
She could handle him and he is crazy!
It's best that they do not marry.
Will someone someone to marry?
You have at least that choice.
Shut up, Mitchell!
Okay, if everyone just calm down themselves.
We just have to find them, okay?
How do we do it?
You're right, we follow the tracks again.
They are perhaps back at the hotel.
Well thought.
They can be in one of the suites.
Yeah, ok ...
You girls go back there now,
then we go if they stray.
We meet their room, okay?
What is it with you, Mitchell? Cease!
We meet.
What the hell is wrong with him?
He is a little away only.
Come on now.
Hell! Damn!
Okay, I'll drop say it,
but someone must call Amanda.
And I mean man
and I mean you. Do it.
Hi, this is Casey. Sorry that you
miss me, but have a great day.
Leave a message.
Casey, answer or returned to
room! I will not die, Casey!
Do not reply. Do not reply.
Hello?
Hey, Amanda. It is Adrian.
I know, Adrian. I see it
just like any other with mobiles.
Is it fixed?
I ... what?
Got Derek be?
Fantastic news.
You are a great asset to the company.
You're a hussy.
Good job, fag.
There you solved nicely.
We should go back to the hotel.
Mitch starts to get thirsty.
Relax, Sienna.
It's not your fault.
I can solve the problem.
How it?
I send pictures to my brother,
Dimitri. He finds missing people.
Dimitri? Boslovs honor?
Da.
Hell. Boslov get to know it.
Relax, I asked him
do not tell it to anyone.
What is it?
Nothing. There is nothing, Boslov.
Are you sure?
Boslov, I'm sorry.
Where is Casey? Come on.
The party's over for Boslov.
Some progress?
What is the opposite of progress?
I do not think that there is something like that.
Tatiana sent a photo to his brother
that is with Boslov, so ...
... Everything feels top.
Hell.
So this does not seem to me?
Do not you think he kills me first?
He does not care about anyone.
My whole family is terrified him.
I tried to call Casey, but she
did not answer. You got Derek?
Have not you tried calling him?
What kind of friends are you?
I see, okay?
Derek?
Who is this?
Who are you? Where is Derek?
And how would I know?
You have his phone.
Your friend left it on my place.
When they went?
Recently.
They said where they were going?
Give me your address there.
I'll pay you, please.
Sure. Just do not nap me.
Alright.
58 East Balm. It called Darcade.
Okay, thanks. See you soon.
Okay. Derek was last seen in a place
called Darcade. We begin there.
What the hell are we waiting for?
What the hell.
Much energy there.
She fears for life, Mitch.
It's a bad time, Adrian ...
... But she is heltent you.
Not now, guys.
And thanks for your help!
Best Friends.
Where are you going?
Helping.
I was just curious.
So fucking stupid. I should
not released her sight.
You're not stupid.
Do not touch me.
So clearly you say it.
What the hell do you mean by that?
You let it happen.
Had we just followed my plan ...
Do not blame everything on us!
I find her, I die.
Do not you think that I will find Derek?
You do not care a shit about him.
What the hell do you know about it?
If you were his true friend ...
... Had you stopped their wedding!
So now you're guarding honesty?
Now all up!
Do not touch me.
Now jump all into the cab.
Now, come on.
Do you feel good?
No.
Okay, time for the next gift ... my.
What have we here? A gag!
The suits a hussy you.
Shut up, it's you who is hussy.
I know.
Can not we try it?
Now.
OMG ...
You know how it works?
Amanda Bryce. There she is.
Well done, my friend.
Eye for an eye, you bastard.
You will get
another surprise immediately.
But now ...
Okay.
Okay, girls ...
I'm looking for Amanda.
Amanda?
Hello.
She has been properly naughty.
Yes ... bind and punishment her.
Really?
I will punish her.
I've been so naughty.
You get punish me as you will.
Shut up.
Nicely.
Thank you.
You're going to love it.
Your little hussy. You know that you are there.
Your little hussy.
Do not pick too much dick.
OMG. Cheers! Cheers!
Reis! Reis! Bye, Amanda.
It was intended
that to happen?
Here it is.
It looks closed.
All great places to do so.
Here it is.
Excuse me, I spoke with
a woman on the phone about ...
What do you want?
We talked earlier.
I'd grab the phone.
You said nothing about a bankruptcy.
Come with me, alone.
Wait!
I have money.
Anyone else?
No.
Come on.
What kind of place is this?
A place where fantasies become true.
First romm, ordinary stuff.
Girls. Sometimes two, three.
And this is a little more specialized.
Was it a goat?
I do not judge.
It is private, purse.
I apologize.
If you do, bust you out. Do you understand?
Yeah.
How many rooms there are?
This is the last.
OMG! No, get them to stop!
What happens there?
Listen, I fill a void strippers
do not do. People want certain things.
Such things they can not find elsewhere.
Please!
And I give them a safe place.
And you ask too much.
Hell! Dennis! Not again.
Stop sucking on anal plugs.
That is why one has kuleknebel.
May I come in there?
Go ahead. I come afterwards.
What the hell!
Tell me about your friend.
He is tall, around 1.90. Styled hair,
slim. Most often a kind and quiet boy.
Kind or quiet?
There they are for about an hour ago.
I often get couples here.
OMG ...
It's them.
People always come here and fucking
but they left without paying.
Said where they were going?
Many places in Vegas is free ...
... but not this. We have rules.
One must pay to play.
Kind boy? What?
I took some money for cleaning
and a little more like penalty.
Let he left his wallet too?
Idiot would leave the pants here.
No reason. Get out now.
Are you ready?
Frank?
Yes.
Do you feel good?
It is the best night of my life.
Best night of my life ...
I saw God in there.
He had blue eyes
and short, dark hair.
He was definitely higher than 1.80.
Everything went so quickly.
She was right there and he ...
Everything was so wrong.
They will probably not that we should strip.
What do you think happens back there?
Amber, be still.
Are not you curious?
No.
When the woman opened the door
smelled tramp dick.
So where are they? She said something?
They are not here.
They have benefited.
I'm sorry.
There is no danger, it dissolves.
Let Uncle Mitchell say anything.
We just might distinguish storage
And keep jobs, what?
Let them come to us.
It's actually a really good idea.
Yeah, that's it.
Okay, Frank.
Go back to Velvet Atheneum.
You three go back to the hotel.
It's going to work, it's not true?
Why is he like that?
Who the hell cares?
Because he has taken ecstasy.
Frank? What did you just say?
I fixed his drink earlier.
Derek too.
What is wrong with you?
Stop! I'm tired of you, kjekking.
So Derek and Casey
quite high and helpless?
Somehow.
No, it's good.
Everyone goes to their records.
Sienna and I are here, there, -
And so they become abstinent småningom
and find their way back.
We do it, come on.
It's my fault. This had never
happened if we went to Thunder dicks.
We're going to find them, okay?
We still have time.
Hell.
Hello?
Sienna?
I'm coming after you.
Boslov, let me explain.
It's not necessary. Greet Derek
I have a gift for him too.
Derek, help! He is crazy!
I am bound and gagged!
Well done.
You might live.
What the ...
OMG ...
Wow.
Do not touch me. I'm so tired.
Do not give up.
I need you.
I'm an idiot.
He kills both me and you.
Request a miracle, because we need it.
God?
Even better, baby. this is
Jackrabbit Rabbit Ranch.
brothel,
family restaurant and warehouses.
Jack Rabbit?
Yes, exactly.
Listen, I have a problem with
your friends Derek and Casey with me.
Is Derek and Casey there?
Yes, I think so.
I lyrics address.
Okay, we're coming. Thank you, Mr. Rabbit.
OMG!
Come on.
You are a freak.
Hello?
Found them. Sending coordinates.
Okay. I am there within an hour.
If it does not work with Derek ...
... I can marry you.
Brilliant news, yes ... No,
I have it much better. It spans.
I know, I never looked away.
No,
let me tell them that, ok? Yes.
Adrian, I'm sorry tonight.
I'm really sorry.
Yes, I love you too.
Good news, ladies.
They have found the missing pair.
So delicious.
Okay, what the hell?
What are you doing?
Excuse me.
Not meaning to offend you.
It is not true.
Pretty girls that you go not only
around and massaging each other naked.
It is absurd.
No, do not hide you.
There's something I must tell.
I'm not gay. never
been there, I'm sorry.
I just wanted to get to know you
and it is correct diseased.
That's right sick.
But I did not expect me this.
But honestly, do you think
we did this for our sakes?
What?
We just wanted to fuck around with you.
You are so cute, but trying too hard.
did you
that I was not gay all the time?
Okay, how?
So what do you say?
Sheets are cold.
Make room for me, ladies!
Has not been a long day?
Yes, it really has.
You were drugged and everything. Poor Mischka.
Relax.
Tatiana and I'll take care of you.
This is ...
Not yet. Drinks first.
For an exceptional experience.
Cheers to that.
What is in it?
It is the ugliest shoes
I have seen. Is the Italian?
It was time.
Damn, you feel good?
No, I do not feel good.
They drugged us.
Quiet!
I do not care about who drugged
whom. They owe me $ 5,000.
$ 5,000?
You heard me.
They requested services
from my finest kegs.
Cans?
An internal expression meaning whore.
I counted it.
And they used my best whore.
Tax! Come in.
Hey.
Providence?
Gee, Providence!
Is there anyone who does not know you?
No.
Excuse me. sometimes surprises
her horniness even Jackrabbit.
She is such a whore that they
second whores call her whore.
It can swear.
Whatever came idiots in here ...
... recognize Providence who took
them and said that they pay later.
I take it not so easy,
for when they had finished, -
They began to cry.
"I can not find your wallet!"
"Boslov going to kill me."
So I chained them fixed -
For they do not go from here
without paying $ 5,000.
He says you should pay.
Can you pay him, Adrian ...
... Before he kills us?
He's not going to kill you.
It's not over yet.
You're not going to kill them.
No, I'm not going to kill them.
And no, I have not 5000 ...
Who the hell walks around with $ 5,000?
Frank, old friend. What do you do?
Do not, what happens? Did you find them?
Yes, we did.
Listen, I have a little problem.
You must bring $ 5,000
to a place I lyrics.
No, it does not.
I'm a little busy right now.
Frank, we need money, your monkey.
I can not hear you, Adrian.
It is correct noisy here!
The storm is on the way!
Hell! Is the storm on the way?
With 90% chance of rain.
Can anybody beat me in the face?
For some tits! We need shots!
Come back. Ouch, my back.
Frank, hell ...
Whoa, baby.
I know how you can pay
debt. You and your friend setpoint
Be in one of Jackrabbits known
amateur porn movies. What say you?
Absolutely not.
I do not think you have much choice.
There must be another way.
You receive $ 5,000 in cash ...
... which you give back to me
to pay their friends of Charges
And since you can go home.
There is a good deal, believe me.
It is.
What?
In college I played in one like that,
but got only $ 500.
What?
Exactly. Listen to the sexy lady.
We have no time to discuss,
so let's just do it.
Are you sure about this?
Yes.
Relax.
I promise it will be elegant.
Okay, all down to the studio.
We solve this, okay?
I hate him.
You do not do this.
Okay, are you ready?
Yes.
That's what they always say.
Okay, silence! Light.
Sienna.
Just do it.
Be so good.
Look at me.
Come on, show tits.
Let me do it.
Nicely.
Have you seen?
This is gold.
Oh yes.
Movie Magic.
This is so fucking weird.
Quietly, I said!
Cut!
Boslov?
Derek?
Amanda?
What is going on here?
Okay, everybody. We begin again.
Go to them.
What are you doing here?
Now you should talk.
Boslov.
Adrian and I ...
I do not care Adrian.
What did you do with my fiance?
She has not done anything.
Do you speak again, it becomes
last time, I promise.
Boslov, she was drugged.
Both became. Ecstasy or something.
The thrust and we found them here.
Really?
And what is it here? A celebration?
No, they ended up here ...
... And we pay a debt.
Who the hell is he?
Wait a little. I was the director here.
She speaks true.
Just put down the weapon.
Stop, Boslov! I'm glad I have
Set the coward you really are.
It is over.
You.
You betrayed me.
I took meh you and you cheated on me!
Is this over?
Well.
And now you will all get to pay.
So who will die first?
Some?
Not? Come on.
All may well not be wimps?
Ole dole ...
... duh ...
Same it, I'll start with you.
No!
Providence? Frank was right,
you are a true angel.
I'm no angel, but a whore.
Who the hell is this?
My former fiance.
Good answer.
Okay, I think we're done here.
The debt then?
Relax.
I can make money in other ways.
It was quite a night.
It's probably a bit of an operation.
Adrian.
Wait a little.
Listen, it did not
as planned last night.
You still did what I asked for.
It must have been difficult.
Difficult?
We almost died together.
That's why I promotes you.
Congratulations.
Was that all?
Yes, that was all.
There is something right sick with this.
Do I get a minute?
Of course.
It was interesting.
Yes, I would say.
So did you do it?
If I was drunk, geezer ...
... and fucked hussy? I think so,
but it is not correct my thing.
Derek, I think that ...
I know. You and Boslov?
Yes, it's crazy.
It's your thing.
Derek, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
What do you think he said to her?
I think we're ready here, huh?
I think so.
You're a great guy and I'm sorry
I pushed you too much.
It's ok.
Ok ...
I must call her girlfriends
and say that I'm not dead.
Ok, so you are not with us?
No, I'm calling a cab.
I'll never use fabric again.
Was it that bad?
Well ...
I canceled it.
Do you know how much I
not remember of last night?
Derek, I'm sorry
I did not support you anymore.
No, it's ok. This was nevertheless
something I had to do yourself.
I'll talk to her.
Yes.
Come, we go.
Hey.
Thank you.
So it was your fiance?
Yes, that was it.
Boslov seemed nice.
Excuse me. I found
you said that he was a contractor.
Yes ... I did not realize
that it was code language first.
Then I realized it was me
too scared to leave him.
Afraid of him? Come on.
Had we ...
One forgets certainly not everything.
No.
So do you think that we could try?
Endeavour ...
Are you asking me really like?
Yes, damn. I do.
Will you?
That's what she said.
I mean seriously. Jump into the car.
You want a drink? Water or something?
What the hell happened last night?
I can think of a few things.
What happened at Jack Rabbit's ...
What about it?
It was weird. Proper strange.
But only at the beginning and the
is not something I usually do.
Porn ie. I do not,
but I really like you, sex.
Having sex with you, or love.
Or, heck too.
Thank you.
You are an alright guy, Adrian. Thank you.
And it's not something I
would otherwise have done either.
Okay?
We blowing in cameras this time.
Agreement.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
For an exceptional experience.
Awake.
No, it's not polite to talk
before has been presented.
I will introduce you
for my friend, Luther.
Will you meet him?
I love this job.
Corrected By KANA
Enjoy.....