What's wrong with this city?
Somewhere there are ashes
and somewhere smoke.
Why doesn't someone say something?
Why do we endure smoke quietly?
Now it's the limit of endurance.
Let's bring this reckless act to an end.
Smoking at public places is prohibited.
Violation will lead to penalty.
Don't smoke.
Or let others smoke.
You will have to pay
a heavy price for smoking.
'Bang-Bang'
'When something really wild & exciting is about to happen'
Colonel Nanda.
Jai Hind. - Jai Hind.
This is Richard Parker, MI6.
You have a gift for my country.
Indeed.
- Please come.
How was he apprehended?
At Heathrow airport, carrying fake documents.
Omar Zafar, India's most wanted criminal.
We've been looking for him for many years.
What was he doing in London?
There's a private island near the Russian Coast.
We heard he was here to buy it.
The business of terrorism has no recession, right?
- Thankyou Sir.
Yes mom. - Viren?
- Yes... - You arrived?
I'll call you back soon.
- Everything Ok? - Yeah, all Ok.
Wearing your sweater? - Yes mom...
- I'm sure you're not. - How did you know?
I really know my sons. Listen Jai said...
- I'll call you back, bye.
Permission granted.
Good luck. - Thanks.
The Kohinoor diamond is ours!
Bring back our Kohinoor!
Permission granted.
Ahh..
Welcome Colonel Nanda.
Your search for me has been very intense.
I would've stood up and saluted you.
But as you can see, I'm having pizza..
..and I'm a little tired today.
Would you like a slice?
No.
You eat it.
Once you get to Tihar..
..your next pizza will be on the day of your
execution.
As your last wish..
..with extra cheese.
Wake up Colonel.
This isn't your Delhi, it's London.
Tell me something..
..how many criminals have actually been..
..extradited to India from London?
None. Not even one.
A new extradition treaty is being prepared as we
speak.
According to which, any criminal..
..will be extradited to his homeland within 72
hours..
..without an appeal.
Very soon you're going to be begging for mercy..
..in an Indian court of law, Omar Zafar.
And then.. then what?
This for the public prosecutor.
This for the judge.
And this, for the police and ministers.
Your country is starving, Colonel..
..and it's full of corrupt people.
A country where everyone's begging for something.
And your ministers are always willing..
..to forsake their integrity
and sell their souls.
So tell me, what are you?
Are you corrupt like them or just faithfully
following orders?
Welcome to the Omar Zafar show.
Permission granted.
Any last wish?
Maybe some pizza with extra cheese, huh!
But you don't have 30 minutes.
Because the countdown to your end has begun.
Those who serve their country..
..start the countdown to their death from their
very first breath.
You must have taken many lives, Zafar.
But take a good look in these eyes.
There is no grief..
..or fear of death.
There's only pride.
Soon, you'll see your death in similar eyes.
Your countdown will begin..
..as soon as you press the trigger.
ZERO
Would you like to speak to your mother for the
last time?
Hello? Viren, I was saying...
Viren?
Viren what happened?
Are you alright?
Viren, are you alright?
Viren?!
Viren!
Viren I can't hear you son.
What's wrong?
Hello?!
Hello? Noone is saying anything...
Viren!
Viren talk to me!
Pankaj!
Something has happened to Viren!
Viren talk to me my son!
Viren?!
Talk to me!
Have you heard about the new treaty?
- I have.
Our men won't be safe anywhere,
if this treaty is signed. - It won't be signed.
There's an old wound which hasn't healed yet.
We'll just revive it.
The Kohinoor!
Stealing the Kohinoor is impossible.
Make it possible.
I want the Kohinoor!
And the thief should be Indian.
In a population of 1.2 billion, there must be
someone who can do this job.
Find him!
So we now have official confirmation..
..that the Kohinoor has just been
stolen from the Tower of London.
How was it possible?
The Kohinoor was stolen despite
the Tower of London's heavy security.
There are reports of a leak in
the Tower of London's security.
But the MI6 is denying any such rumours.
When the collection was
opened for inspection..
..they realized that only
the Kohinoor was missing.
The footage from around 500 CCTV
cameras is being inspected.
This investigation will hopefully
clear up a few details of the theft.
And now we would like to show you..
..the amazing Kohinoor's colourful history.
It is believed that the Kohinoor
was discovered in Tamil Nadu..
..and was then owned by
rulers from the Delhi, Rajput..
..Mughal, Afsharid,
Durrani and Sikh dynasties.
When the British ransacked India..
..and Queen Victoria was declared the Empress of India.
Against everyone's wishes..
..India's beloved Kohinoor was
sent all the way to Great Britain.
Sorry for the interruption.
There was one unidentified male
found in the Tower of London..
There are neither fingerprints nor images.
This isn't the work of a common
thief but of a criminal mastermind.
The thief is being touted
as the 'Hero' of neither fingerprints.
So who is this man?
Invisible Thief, 'Kohinoor Thief'.
These are some of the
names people are calling him.
Who is this?
Who will win this game between
the thief and the police?
This century's biggest robbery
and there is no lead..
..but the entire world is..
..waiting with bated breath to
get a look at the thief's face..
..who managed to steal
the Kohinoor with great skill.
Who is he? How did he disappear?
When will he be caught?
The police search is on.
But noone knows where he is.
Harleen!
Oh.. you're bathing!
Grandma, go out.
Grandma, please go out.
Quiet.
I've seen you grow up.
I've bathed you, changed your nappy.
Grandma,
I'm not a kid anymore. Go out!
That's what you think.
Don't miss the spot behind your ears.
Grandma..
Listen, did you know that..
..someone has stolen the Kohinoor.
Please pass me the towel.
Jewel thief!
It's hard to find such
youngsters these days.
Ashok Kumar,
Dev Anand.
I just want to meet a man like that..
..someone, who steals diamonds and hearts.
He has stolen my dream..
So then please go to his bathroom.
Hand me my towel.
The Kohinoor is India's property!
If someone returns this jewel to India..
..then, he should be honoured
with the 'Bharat Ratna'.
Bless his soul, whoever stole it!
Grandma, you're completely crazy.
I wish you were crazy too, like me.
You're so boring. You're always alone.
While all the girls your age
have a boyfriend.
Grandma,
I haven't found the right guy yet, Ok?
But why are you so choosy?
When I was your age,
I had at least 30 affairs.
Excessive quality control isn't good.
I don't want to deal
with complications of love.
You don't know what love is.
Love is..
..when your heart skips a beat,
when your eyes lock..
..and someone steals your invaluable heart.
Morning, boss.
Who stole it?
Sir, when you spread the word..
When you spread the word..
..about a reward on the Kohinoor..
..he was the only one who replied.
Through whom?
- Shoaib!
He said Sayeed sent him.
Wasim knows him.
And he's also done a job for Saqlain.
I am not asking about
Pakistan's batting line up.
Is he Indian?
Only an Indian can perform such a miracle.
Feeling patriotic?
Sorry.
He'll contact us as soon as
the diamond reaches India.
Price?
5 million dollars.
Fine.
Should we pay by cash?
Sure.
Load it in a truck and take it. - Yes.
Bloody fool.
Open an anonymous account in Mauritius.
As soon as you get the diamond
transfer the payment into his account.
Don't open your mouth.
Get to the bank and open an account.
Hello madam.
Thankyou Harleen.
No problem.
Hey Harleen, thanks for the coffee.
You're welcome.
Hello, Bank of Shimla.
Speak here please.
Hello.
Bank of Shimla.
Sorry.
How can I help you?
Which way is the vice-president's office?
It's the third cabin in the corridor,
to the right.
But he has resigned.
There's noone in the cabin.
Now there will be.
- Who?
Me. Karan Saxena.
Bank of Shimla's youngest vice-president.
And anyway, this is my uncle's bank.
Oh, I am so sorry, Sir.
No problem.
Name?
- Harleen Sahani.
Married? - No.
Boyfriend?
No.
Wouldn't have mattered if you had one.
Come to my cabin.
We need to discuss the finance strategy.
Strategy?
But.. I am a receptionist.
Do you want to be
a receptionist all your life?
Making the right friends..
..is also a strategy, darling.
Understood.
If you want to turn your luck around,
then come see me.
Sitting all alone with icecream..
..while your friends are at a
romantic candlelight dinner..
..with Mr. Right, right now?
But you don't worry..
..because your life is about to change.
www.trueluvv.com
A site where a new, exciting
and romantic life awaits you!
So what are you waiting for?
Register now.. on trueluvv.com
..or your life will melt away..
..like that tub of icecream.
Friends, Mrs. Sharmin Kapadia..
..is finally retiring from
our bank after 30 years.
Miss..
- What?
Miss Kapadia.
Who's that?
- That's me!
You aren't married yet?
Wow!
Here.
She had no time for marriage.
She spent her entire life in the bank.
Never took a day off in 30 years.
She never came late and
she never left early.
She stayed single all her life.
And she'll be single for
the rest of her life.
Harleen! Harleen!
What is it, grandma?
Come here quickly!
What happened, grandma?
- Look.. the jewel thief.
So it's you.
If you have what I think you have..
..then I am who you think I am.
Abdul's here.. with your order.
Roasted mutton, kebabs, halim..
..and our favorite, firni.
Did you order this?
Hey, Abdul,
you're serving the wrong people again.
That order's for table No. 7.
Mistakes can happen. Sorry.
5 million dollars is waiting for you..
..in an account in Mauritius.
One swipe of my finger..
..and your fate will change forever.
What's the hurry?
Let's discuss a few things first.
I am hungry too.
Let's eat something.
Abdul!
Grandma,
I am not going to fight a war.
I'm just going on a date.
You're finally settling down.
Now I can die in peace.
Enough! I'll be late.
Look.
Here you go.
Grandpa's car!
It was your grandpa's
most prized possession.
Yes, grandma, I know.
You two went on your first date
in this car.
I found my true love in this car.
And today you'll find
your true love in this car.
Bye grandma, Ok?
- Bye!
You can eat after we leave.
I can't think on an empty stomach.
What's there to think about?
The price has been decided.
Give with one hand and take with the other.
My hands are dirty.
Threats can be expensive.
How expensive?
5 million for each.
All three of you made a mistake..
..so now the price is 20 million dollars.
Wrong.
Now the price is zero.
Quietly hand the diamond over to us.
Wipe your noses all of you.
There's a drug in your buttermilk.
In exactly 5 seconds,
your mouths will be frothing..
..and you'll all be unconscious!
Oops!
I mixed up the orders.. again!
You ordered the buttermilk, right?
Thankyou Abdul.
Get him!
There he is!
On the roof! Shoot him!
There he is.
Get him!
Hey stop!
He's trapped.
Yes Sir. Sure.
We're under pressure from
the Prime Minister's office.
Even the opposition
is extending their support..
..on the Kohinoor issue.
This is going to affect
our Extradition Treaty.
They are fools!
The Extradition Treaty can't be
put on hold at any cost.
Sir..
Finding the Kohinoor diamond is imperative.
Sir.
Sir, there's been firing
on Mall Road in Shimla.
So. That's the police's problem.
But Sir, you should take a
look at the CCTV footage.
Yes ma'am. How may I help you?
Umm.. I'm Harleen.
I..
You're here to see Mr. Vickie, right?
Right. How do you know that?
We have a tie-up with trueluvv.com
This way, please.
Have a seat.
If you want to know anything..
..about your special friend, then..
..this.
Have a nice time ma'am.
Ladies and gentlemen..
..are you ready to win the Shimla Dance Festival?
Be there tomorrow at 7pm.
Bring your partner.
Have a great time.
Vickie?
Hi, I'm Vickie.
Harleen.
Hi Harleen. Nice to meet you.
You're very late.
And you're very beautiful.
I'm sorry.
I'm so late I...
Please sit.
So.. have you done this before?
What?
In a restaurant.. with a beautiful girl?
Once or twice.
Internet dating.
trueluvv.com
trueluvv.com?
Well, no..
First time.
It's my first time.
Mine too.
So why did you choose me?
Really?
Look at you.
But.. I didn't post my photo.
Aha.. ofcourse.
But the way you described
yourself so beautifully, I was just..
I just wrote two words.
Bank receptionist.
Exactly.
There's a story hidden behind
those two words.
Whose story?
My.. grandma's story.
My grandma.. was a bank receptionist too.
She made a living receiving calls at the bank..
..and raised all of us.
And then one day,
after transferring her last call..
..she passed away.
I'm so sorry.
What would you like to drink?
Some wine?
Thankyou.
- You're welcome.
Shimla.
Ahh.. French!
It's Indian, Sir.
From Nasik.
Pour it.
Enjoy, madam.
- Thanks.
So you travel around a lot.
I have to.
To save the world.
Huh?
From mosquitoes.
I work for Odomos.
And you?
Do you travel?
No.
I was 10 years old..
..when grandma brought me here from Canada.
My mom and dad passed away
in a road accident.
I've been here since.
Never been anywhere.
But one day I want to quit my job..
..get a round-the-world ticket and travel.
One day.
But how will you know that your
'one day' is here?
I live in a small city.
It's not easy to do what I want.
I live with my grandma.
She's my responsibility.
One day.
So you like dancing?
Yeah!
Well..
Here?
- Yeah!
No way.
I just dance sometimes when I am alone.
Harleen.
Come closer.
A little more.
Don't you think
that your 'one day' means never?
Today it's your grandma
you're responsible for..
..tomorrow it'll be your husband..
..and the day after, your children.
I think you should do what
you want right now.
I treat every day as my last.
So all I have is.. one day.
The day you start your bucket list..
..that day will be your 'one day'.
But..
Close your eyes.
Huh?
Trust me!
Harleen!
This one's for you!
Such a breeze has blown..
..that it took my breath away
from me and towards you.
And then I had this feeling that..
..you've started becoming mine,
I've started becoming yours.
I've started becoming yours,
you've started becoming mine.
How did this happen?
Neither I nor you have any idea.
But my heart has started
saying for some time, that..
..you've started becoming mine,
I've started becoming yours.
I've started becoming yours,
you've started becoming mine.
Neither I nor you know..
..how this miracle has happened.
What I had has gotten lost.
It seems as if I've gotten
something that's yours.
When my heart got to know that..
..you've started becoming mine,
I've started becoming yours.
I've started becoming yours,
you've started becoming mine.
Sometimes my heart says..
..this is the only atmosphere..
..the only way in which I want to live.
That I live every moment to the fullest.
In which this strange world
comes and embraces me.
In which you walk and the
whole world walks with you.
And the night softly
whispers in your ears!
That now it seems as if..
..you've started becoming mine,
I've started becoming yours.
I've started becoming yours,
you've started becoming mine.
Such a breeze has blown..
..that it took my breath away
from me and towards you.
And then I had this feeling that..
You've started..
You've started becoming mine,
I've started becoming yours.
I've started becoming yours,
you've started becoming mine.
You've started becoming mine,
I've started becoming yours.
I've started becoming yours,
you've started becoming mine.
He's so cute.
All the girls at the bank
will be so jealous.
Don't you think that your 'one day'
means never?'
I think.. you should do
what you want right now.
Vickie.
He's so calm..
..so simple..
..so cultured.
Yes Harleen Sahani.
He's right.
This moment will never come again.
Where is he?
Thankyou trueluvv.com!
What's all this?
It's your trueluvv.com, madam.
trueluvv.com?
Harleen?
I'm Vickie.
So sorry.
My mobile had a flat tire..
..and my car battery died.
But where's the other Vickie?
The other Vickie left this bill.
So long.
Who's going to pay for the furniture?
Your uncle?
You'll have to pay up, madam.
And anyway, this bank belongs to my uncle.
Uncle..
My uncle.
This is his card.
He'll pay you.
Sorry.
trueluvv..
If he ever shows up,
I'll run him over with this car!
Oh shit!
Oh..
I'm sorry!
Are you Ok?
Yeah. I'm good. I'm good.
You! - Hi.
Rajveer.
- What?
My name.
- Yeah, sure.
Like I am going to believe
you after all the lies.
I lied about my name, but I swear..
..everything else was true.
Ok. Don't move. One second.
You need a doctor!
I don't need a doctor.
Maybe..
Maybe what?
..a kiss.
Kiss?!
You're crazy.
I'm leaving.
I seriously think you need a doctor.
They saw you at the restaurant with me.
Who?
They think you know something.
What do I know?
- Nothing.
But they don't know that.
They don't know that I don't know anything.
No, they think you know something..
..but they don't know that
you don't know anything.
What do I know? - Nothing.
So do they know that?
- Stop!
This bullet won't kill
me but this confusion will.
Harleen Sahani.
So you're saying that
the girl was with him.
Yes Sir.
And this is her uncle's card.
Sir, please help us recover our money.
Karan Saxena.
Listen to me.
I stole something.
What?
I took the bullet out.
You just need to stitch it up.
Stitch?
So.. hold this torch,
point it right here.
Here.
I can't do this.
Ofcourse you can.
Come on.
Help.
Hold on.
Ok.
Steady... Steady.
Perfect.
Excellent.
I have never seen anyone hold
the torch so perfectly before.
Thanks.
Steady. Steady.
- Done?
Steady.
Almost done.
It's really good.
Thankyou so much for helping me.
Ok.
Done.
Here. Drink this.
What was in this?
Who are you?
Rajveer Nanda, international criminal.
Pathologically, psychopathic schizophrenic.
I need psychiatric help.
What?
I don't, but that's
what they're going to say.
What was in the water? - Sedatives.
Why?
Now listen to me.
Two kinds of people will approach you.
First the government agents.
And second, those who aren't
government agents.
They'll both ask you about me.
When you don't tell them anything..
..they'll say that they're
taking you to a 'safe' place.
Why are you stressing on 'safe'?
Listen to me.
There will be a gun hidden in the car..
..which they'll use to transport you.
Gun?
If it's a Skoda,
it'll be under the left seat.
And if it's a Toyota,
then it'll be under the right.
Ok.
Take the gun out and use it
to scare them and escape.
Escape?
And if they ask about me..
I don't know..
You don't know me.
I don't know you..
Perfect.
I don't know anything.
Let me go!
Where is Shoaib?
I don't know any Shoaib.
Forgive me!
I swear on my uncle!
And he's still alive!
What does this code mean?
Harleen, bank receptionist.
What code?
Harleen?
That's not a code word.
Our bank receptionist is named Harleen.
Yes.
Good morning ma'am.
Absolutely.
Boss...
We can transfer the funds.
The consignment will be there.
Goodbye.
What's this nonsense?
Boss he got away from us!
Got away?
Who wanted to catch him?
You just had to pay him and
take the diamond!
That's it.
Shoaib tried to take it with force, but..
But.. he couldn't.
Boss, there was a girl with him.
Don't you think that your 'one day'
means never?
The day you start your bucket list..
..that day will be your 'one day'.
What's the matter?
What time did you get home last night?
I am not old-fashioned
like your parents, silly!
Who was it?
Rajveer.
I lied about the name, but I swear..
..everything else was true.
I don't know.
Don't know?
How strange!
You spent the night with him
and you don't know his name!
Even I am not that modern.
I get it.
Your heart's finally been stolen.
Ahh,
there was a little empty space in my heart.
Ahh, you came and acquired it without rent.
I couldn't say a thing.
How is this helplessness?
Thus silently came an uninvited guest.
Ahh,
there was a little empty space in my heart.
I don't know when nor how he came.
What did he whisper to the heart?
Ahh,
there was a little empty space in my heart.
You came and acquired it without rent.
I couldn't say a thing.
How is this helplessness?
Thus silently came an uninvited guest.
Ahh, in my heart..
In my heart..
Ahh,
there was a little empty space in my heart.
What would you make me do in dreams?
How many colours should
I change for no reason?
My poor, foolish heart flutters
in the skies like a balloon.
Gently you called.
Wherever you go, it follows.
It just went with eyes closed.
Slowly following you.
Little by little it pulls you.
Whether you look or not.
I don't know when nor how he came.
What did he whisper to the heart?
To say, it's because of you..
..the whole world seems to be a new place.
Everyone knows and everybody has an idea..
..what ever happened to us.
See, now you also stop giving excuses.
Give me the gift of heart for heart.
Ahh,
there was a little empty space in my heart.
I don't know when nor how he came.
What did he whisper to the heart?
Ahh,
there was a little empty space in my heart.
Oh madam!
Oh madam, what's going on?
This is the office, not your home.
The phone's ringing, answer it.
Hello, Bank of Shimla.
No Sir, wrong number.
Hi, how can I help you?
Open..
What?
A big account needs to be opened.
Sorry, Sir.
Since you must have been paid big money..
..for what you did last night.
Excuse me..
..what nonsense!
Maybe.
Maybe to get rid of your loneliness..
..you visited that site..
trueluvv.com
What happens on this site?
I visited that site once.
It gets really interesting at night.
No.. it was only for the investigation.
Investigation.
Nothing more.
Zorawar Kalra, government agent.
We need to have a little chat
about what you did last night.
Some Q & A.
But, if you prefer, we can talk right here..
..in front of everyone.
Ms. Sahani,
the man you were with last night..
..is an international criminal.
Mentally unstable and pathologically..
Psychopathic schizophrenic?
He told me you would say that.
Just like I thought. He's too smart.
He's using you.
Just have a look.
Criminals like him are very charming.
He can drug you.
He can kill you. Take your life.
Excuse me.
Sir.. we passed the police station.
Yes.
Your life's in danger,
so we're taking you to a safe place.
Safe place?
Yes, but why are you saying it like that?
No reason.
If it's a Skoda,
it'll be under the left seat.
And if it's a Toyota,
then it'll be under the right seat.
What car is this?
It's a Honda.
- Why do you ask?
It's nice.
What's the mileage?
10-12 on the highway.
It also depends on the driving.
If we're chasing someone..
..we use the brake and accelerator more.
In a situation like that the
mileage drops to around 7-7.5
Yes, Sir.
- Are you trying to sell it?
No, Sir.
Sorry, Sir.
Yes.. we're just getting there.
Stop the car!
The girl's got a gun.
Where did you get that gun?
Stop the car!
Keep driving, she won't do anything.
Come on, give me that gun!
I didn't do that!
- Give me the gun!
I don't know how to fire a gun!
- Come on.
Sir, that bike's missing a rider.
Oh God!
Where did he go?
Where did he go,
Sir?
There he is, Sir.
Hey!
Stop that girl.
Hey girl.
Stop her! Stop her!
I will kill you. Stop!
Mummy, mummy.
What is it, son?
Hey... Harleen!
Hey trueluvv.
What?
Closer! Come on, you can do it.
Flip..
What?
Come on!
Hey!
The wire.
Careful.
Hurry up.
Left.
Drive faster!
Mind if I drive?
- Huh?
Shift Harleen.
Trust me. Shift!
- Hold on a second.
What's up?
Are you crazy?
Ram him!
Don't let him get away.
What are you doing?
Please, stop the car!
Rajveer, stop the car!
Have you lost your mind?
Rajveer..
Don't get out of the car.
Help!
This man's crazy.
I am not with him.
I'm with you.
What did I say?
Don't get out of the car.
What did you do?
- I got out of the car.
Harleen, understand.
Either you're safe with me..
or 'safe' with them.
Safe or.. - Safe. Safe.
Good. Hold this.
Shift a bit.
Thankyou.
Please stop killing people!
Please..
You're in shock.
I understand.
Wait here, and I'll go explain
a few things to them.
Yes.
Ok.
Actually you know what, I won't lie.
I'm just going to shoot them.
By the way,
you drive really well.
I mean..
You saved our lives today.
I just.. I want you to know that.
I'm really impressed.
Wait here,
I'll.. I'll be back.
Safe.
Harleen!
- Karan.
Harleen, Harleen.
I've been looking for you.
Karan I'm in big trouble.
Trouble?
They slapped me because of you!
I was shot at!
They drank my expensive champagne.
Who?
- Government agents.
But why?
- Because you work for Shoaib.
Who's Shoaib?
Omar Zafar's right-hand man!
Who's Omar Zafar?
Excuse me,
who are you?
That's him.
He's the reason you were slapped..
..and I was shot at.
Rajveer, what are you doing here?
Rajveer?
Rajveer who?
The one that's going to smack
you if you don't shut up.
Now listen carefully.
I'm taking your car.
Hello..
Rajveer Zafar,
don't you dare look at my car..
..or I'll break your hands.
I am a green-belt in kung fu karate.
My flying kick is so fast that
I can knock a flying bird out of the air.
Oh uncle..
You shot him!
You shot me!
Harleen, get in the car.
Why did you shoot him?
- Why did you shoot me?
Harleen, get in the car.
- Don't get in the car Harleen.
Flesh wound.
Nowhere close to the bone.
Good shot huh?
Very good. But why?
You were about to use your
flying kick on me.
Couldn't take a chance.
Now listen.
Count to 100 after we leave.
Then you can call the police,
ambulance, everyone.
Ok.
If you call them before you count to 100..
..I'll come back and shoot you.
But how will you know?
I'll shoot you even if
you ask stupid questions.
I'll count to 200.. swear on my uncle.
Good.
Please fasten your seatbelt.
One.. uncle..
Two..
Three.. uncle..
By the way,
I didn't want to shoot him.
Then why did you?
Those who don't want to shoot, don't shoot.
That bullet's going to make him..
..the hero of this city.
You're crazy.
You're insane.
You just shoot at anyone.
That's just not normal.
That's not normal by any definition.
I know what I'm doing.
Please stop the car.
I want to go home.
Away from you.
Relax Harleen.
Just calm down.
Maybe I was safe with them.
What did you just say?
And you're scared to be with me?
I should never have trusted you.
Really?
Oh.. Ok.
Ok then.
Megha, listen to me.
Listen to me.
I don't want to talk to you. - Why not?
I don't want to talk to you. - Why?
I don't want to.
- Ok, I am sorry.
Please.
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
How can you just leave me like this and go?
Answer me!
Why did you shoot Karan
if you didn't need me?
And why are you stealing that car?
Why did you steal this one,
if you didn't need it?
And you say you're not crazy?
What do you want?
You've a problem if I'm with you.
Now I'm going away,
and you still have a problem.
Look, I am really sorry
that we have to be together..
..but it's only to ensure you stay alive.
If I'm not with you, you're dead.
Do you understand that? Dead!
And maybe you'll find this strange..
..but I've other things to do
apart from saving your life.
And they are quite important.
And..
You know what?
I don't really care any more.
Here's the key, there's the car.
Drive home.
A for Assam, J for Jammu.
Check every white BMW in the city.
The suspect is in HP-51-AJ 7739.
Look...
To this day I've never been the..
..cause of death of an innocent person.
I don't want you to be the first.
Especially when you've been
waiting for that 'one day' all your life.
Your dreams would've died with you.
Are you hungry?
Let's eat.
Do you have money?
Don't you work in a bank?
That's so stupid.
What if I worked at a hospital?
Would I be carrying medicines?
Now what?
Shoot someone.
You like that, don't you..
shooting people?
If he doesn't give you free food,
shoot him.
Again? Really?
I shot them to save your life.
Please can we move on from that now?
I never asked for your help.
I can manage.
Can I take your order, Sir?
My life was perfect until I met you.
Perfect?!
No wonder you were begging on the internet.
Me Harleen, bank receptionist.
Please meet me. Please.
Somebody please. Internet hello, help.
Hello. Please somebody help!
Hello? Anybody out there? Hello?
Please somebody?
Nobody? No?
We can't decide between
thin crust or stuffed crust.
That's the problem.
Why don't you try a pan pizza?
What would you like honey?
Don't call me honey!
Then gimme some money.
Actually you know what,
I'll just shoot him.
What am I thinking?
I should just do it. Yeah.
Don't.
Here's the money.
Just don't shoot anyone, please.
Two pan pizzas, please.
And two Mountain Dews.
And we're with Karan Saxena..
..who risked his life to try and
catch a dangerous criminal.
He shot at Harleen.. but I intervened.
But the bullet hit your leg.
It was a kung-fu style jump.
My flying kick is so fast,
I can kick a flying bird in the air.
What have you done that so
many people are gunning for your life?
Do I need to solve that to get an answer?
Nice.
What is it?
Don't you read the papers?
Please tell me this isn't something
that starts.. with the letter K.
Are you crazy?
That's the...
You're a thief!
I thought you were on a mission..
..to save the country. The world!
I can't believe I trusted you.
You still trust me.
Yeah, right.
That's why you haven't raised your voice yet.
You can expose me whenever you like.
But why did you steal the Kohinoor?
For Omar Zafar.
There are women and children around.
Let's talk peacefully..
Omar Zafar.
The No. 1 criminal on Interpol's most wanted list.
As soon as he put a reward on
the Kohinoor, Rajveer stole it.
The restaurant has been surrounded.
Escape is impossible.
So if you come with us quietly..
..it'll be good for everyone.
As far as I know, he isn't going to
come with us quietly.
So you decide.
Do you want to stay safe
with us or die for this thief?
Decide now.
ls it true?
You know, even after
everything that's happened..
..my heart was telling me
you're a good guy.
Crazy.. but not a criminal.
I was wrong.
I am leaving.
I'm sorry Harleen.
But I can't let you go.
Boys!
What a jump, Sir!
By the way, that's a one-way ticket to heaven.
He won't die so easily.
Someone is watching over him.
Don't worry Harleen.
We're safe.
Time to jump!
Trust me!
Conquer your fears!
Who are you?
Hey!
Good morning.
You shot me!
Ssshhhh!
Don't 'ssshhhh' me!
You shot me!
If I had shot you, I wouldn't need
to 'ssshhhh' you.
It was a dart. A dart.
A tranquilizer.
Whatever it was, why did you shoot me?!
Hey!
I'm talking to you!
It was a tranquilizer dart.
I could've died!
Ssshhhh!
- Ssshhhh!
What the hell do you think of yourself?
I'll show you Ssshhhh!
I sedated you for your own good.
If I hadn't saved you...
- They would've killed me.
Right?
Right.
By the way you're looking good
in these clothes I bought you.
Now go to the room and dry these clothes..
..because we don't have any more clothes.
My clothes?
Who changed my clothes?
Relax, I changed them myself.
You?
- I swear.
You changed my clothes.
Yes. Oh.. oh.
I see.
Come on Harleen.
If I can evade 50 guards,
100 security cameras..
..and steal the Kohinoor
from the Tower of London.
So, why can't I change your clothes
with my eyes closed?
I'm not admitting that my eyes were closed, but..
I deserved that.
Ok..
Wo...
Look Harleen. You're really good at martial arts..
..but save it for later.
I'm hungry right now.
Can we eat?
Let's eat.
Can you tell us where Harleen is?
We want to know where Harleen is.
I cannot answer any of your questions..
..without first consulting my lawyer.
Grandma, please stop watching American serials.
Hello!
Grandma!
- Who? Harleen!
Harleen.
Look, Harleen's on the line!
Hello?
Grandma! Grandma!
Sir, we've traced the location.
Have you finished sightseeing?
It's a pretty big island.
If you want to kill me,
then please kill me.
I don't want to kill you Harleen.
I just want to finish cooking dinner.
Come on.
You can cook too?
Cooking was my third subject in school.
Which school did you go to?
DPS.
Delhi Public School.
Dehradun Public School.
Who are you?
A thief.
So it is true.
You stole the Kohinoor for Omar Zafar.
Yes.
But did I ever say I'm giving it to him?
Then why did you steal it?
So that noone else steals it.
It's 'safe' with me.
Why don't you hand it over to the police..
..or the government?
You girls are so cute.
Why don't you hand it over to someone?
Harleen, Omar Zafar..
..has contacts within the
police and the government.
Noone can be trusted.
Right?
- Right.
Right.
Then what's the plan?
Plan?
There's no plan.
Right now everyone's
trying to figure out my plan.
And they must be trying
to make a counter-plan.
But, if I don't have a plan..
..how will they catch me?
That is the stupidest thing I ever heard.
Yeah!
So.. is this your hideout?
Yes. One of them.
How many more do you have?
12. No.. 11.
The one in Burma blew up last month.
You say a lot of bullshit!
Who are you? And what do you really do?
I'll never know.
There he is!
Harleen!
How's it possible?
Noone saw us coming here.
And I didn't make any calls.
And you..
I.. made a call..
..from your phone. Sorry.
- Oh Harleen!
Come on let's go!
Hands up!
What should I kill you for?
For trying to catch me, or..
..for bringing along only
four men to catch me?
I stole the Kohinoor dude!
Show me some respect.
Hand over the Kohinoor..
..or Zafar will not spare you.
And where do I find this Zafar?
I don't know.
Speak up!
Zafar never meets anyone.
Then who were you going to
hand over the Kohinoor to?
Huh?
Tell me!
Zafar won't care if you're dead.
Gul. Hamid Gul.
My job was to hand over
the Kohinoor to Hamid.
Wonderful.
And where can I find him?
Think about it.
Gul or.. death!
I'll tell you!
Bel Air.. Prague.
Bel Air.
He's there!
- Everybody move!
She's over there!
- Chase them!
Welcome to Prague.
We can't stay here too long.
So we should ahh...
You know, my life was really simple.
Just me and grandma.
Bank and home.
I never imagined life beyond that.
Since I've met you..
..life has turned into an action film.
God knows what will happen next.
But I'm not scared now.
I trust you.
You've made my dreams come true.
And you?
What is your dream?
We should go.
What's your 'one day'?
Home.
After it's all over..
..home sweet home.
One day...
Where are we going?
The desires of the heart were a little less.
All my prayers were also a little light.
But when you put your head on my shoulders..
..it was as if you tied the thread in the shrine.
Without asking, I've gotten everything.
God has showered his benevolence upon me.
Let me take your hands in mine..
..so that I can read my fate.
I look for the wishes, hiding in your eyes.
So that as you think of a wish, I'll fulfill it.
Just a while ago I was incomplete.
Now that I am in front of you I am complete.
I can't even see..
..where I end and where you begin.
When your eyes fall on me..
..then only am I able to sleep.
For a few days I've been feeling..
..you are my worship and you are my faith.
Without any reason, out of nowhere..
God has showered his benevolence upon me.
God has created everyone.
But who should go and tell God that..
..only while dying for you, I breathe.
The prayers that I make to God..
..all of them reach you now.
If you hear them, then God has heard them too.
The world doesn't know, even I don't know, where..
..both of us got united.
It's true that there's noone like you.
You are the destination to all my roads..
..in this life, and in every life.
Let's try and stop time now.
Let's teach it the meaning of love.
It'll surely stop being stubborn and agree to us.
God has showered his benevolence upon me.
Where are we going?
Not we, just me.
You stay here.
Order something from room service.
I believe the sushi's really good.
I'll be back soon, Ok?
- No.
You don't know this, but you need me.
We're a team now.
Harleen.
Take me along, or I'll follow you.
Get ready.
- Ok.
Police.
Don't try to kiss me.
It never crossed my mind.
Liar.
You did.
No.
Did you?
Have you ever kissed anyone?
Ofcourse I have.
Really?
When?
In school?
No.
After that.
Impossible.
See? I do know how to kiss.
You call that a kiss?
Yes.
Why?
This.. is a kiss.
What do we do now?
I need to find someone
to give the Kohinoor to.
Who?
Hamid Gul.
Excuse me.
- Yes ma'am.
I'm looking for Mr. Hamid Gul.
There he is ma'am.
See, there's Hamid Gul.
Hold on.
Please just.. leave this to me, Ok?
You're jealous.
You're jealous because
I'm better than you.
And you didn't want to bring me here.
Beginner's luck.
Now Agent 000.. let's try our luck.
14 Red.
Wow! That's a lot of money.
Changing 50,000.
Place your bets ladies and gentlemen.
I don't know how to play.
Bet everything on No. 31.
All of it?
All of it.
No more bets.
31 black. Congratulations!
We won!
Congratulations Sir.
Now?
Place your bets please.
26.
Ok.
The winner is 26 red.
We won again!
Ok.
- Can I just take this one?
Thankyou.
Here you go Sir, congratulations.
- Enough of this... - Thankyou.
Are people hot as this?! Come on, let's go.
Let's go. - 17.
No...
No. 17.
Are you sure?
Ok.
17.
No more bets.
The winner is 7 red.
Oh yeah!
No!
That confirms it.
17 means danger.
Then why did you say 17?
A minute ago I was rich.
A minute ago you didn't know
how to play roulette.
I should never have listened to you.
Ahaa...
Everything was fine when you were winning.
You were hugging and kissing me.
You girls are all the same.
How dare you?
Perfect.
- What?
Hit me.
- No.
Just hit me.
- I'm sorry.
I can't slap anyone without a reason.
You can't slap, you can't kiss,
what can you do?
Beg for romance over the internet?
Ooh, bank receptionist.
Good. Very good!
Good. Now go to the bathroom..
..and when he gets there..
..tell him you will meet him in 5 minutes.
Alone. Go, go, go.
Go to hell.
Excuse me. I'll be back.
Unfortunate are those people..
..who do not know the worth..
..of a diamond they own.
Not a diamond but the Kohinoor.
The Kohinoor!
The Kohinoor can't be stolen.
That depends on the thief.
Hamid Gul.
And the thief's intentions?
Stealing.
The Kohinoor's desire?
Some fresh air.
In 15 minutes, two glasses of champagne..
..and a thief will be waiting
for you on the terrace.
5 minutes.
Or someone may steal the Kohinoor.
Nice.
Well done!
Now go back to the hotel.
I'll meet you there.
And after this.. you.. me.
I mean.. we..
Y'know, you're completely crazy.
I'll be waiting.
Whiskey on the rock huh!
Greetings, Hamid Gul.
How did you find me?
I stole the Kohinoor dude,
show me some respect.
But if you really want to know..
..your man Robert gave me..
..your address.
Just the address.
But the modus operandi was all mine.
You're a thief..
but not a very smart thief.
You were never going to be paid anyway.
But now you'll lose the diamond and your life.
If it was about the money, why would I
sell the Kohinoor to you?
What do you really want?
Omar Zafar.
So why the Kohinoor?
Who are you?
Where is Zafar?
Tell me!
Hey!
Tell me where Zafar is.
Tell me!
You'll never find Zafar.
Hey you! Hey!
Look, Rajveer only wants
to keep the Kohinoor safe.
The Kohinoor was safe in London..
..until he stole it.
If he hadn't, someone else would have stolen it.
Oh really?
If it was that easy, then..
..why didn't anyone steal it for 150 years?
What else did he tell you..
..which could be true?
He said that you will kill me.
But you're still alive.
Where is he right now?
He's with someone called Hamid Gul.
Hamid Gul is dead.
He's dead.
Internal Secret Service Chief,
Mr. Narayanan.
Kohinoor's desire.
Open air.
In 15 minutes, two glasses of champagne..
..and a thief will be waiting
for you on the terrace.
5 minutes.
And we found his body
on that same terrace.
Do you know what this means?
Ms. Harleen, you're an international criminal now.
Killing you will be easy for us.
But we know the truth.
Ms. Harleen..
..you have an opportunity..
..to get your life back.
To go back to your grandma.
And that opportunity is
sealed in this transmitter.
'You're an international criminal now.'
'I trust you.'
'What else did he tell you which could be true?'
Come with me. We can't stay here now.
Let's go.
You left a long while ago from there.
Where were you?
Do you want the truth or
should I lie like you.
What did I lie about?
You lied about everything.
About you.
About us.
About Hamid Gul.
You killed him, didn't you?
Who told you that?
Zorawar.
So you still have the Kohinoor.
Why did you pretend to be Vickie that day?
You should have left me alone.
Why did you let me live out my dreams..
..and show me new ones?
I will fulfill all of them.
Trust me.
Enough.
I don't want to any more.
Then what are you waiting for?
Stay, don't move!
Your hands in the air..
..now!
Go go go go go!
Rajveer!
If the bullet doesn't kill him, he'll drown.
You've got your life back.
Go on.
Thank God, you're back
home safe and sound.
This house doesn't feel the same without you.
After it's all over, home sweet home.
Which school did you go to?
Dehradun Public School.
Hey!
What are you looking for?
Actually Sir, I.. - Pankaj, what?
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
She was snooping around like a thief..
..and you're questioning me?
No no Sir.. you ordered these books
on the internet.
I didn't order any books.
Oh Pankaj, you never remember anything.
Now put that stupid gun inside.
Come in my dear.
Come.
You have a lovely home.
How long have you been living here?
In this house?
Can't remember.
Pankaj, must be 40 years right?
Here. - Thankyou.
For as long as we've been married.
It's beautiful.
Everything seems so new.
Yes.. Pankaj won the Lottery for the second time.
You won the lottery twice?
Yeah he's really lucky.
Right Pankaj?
So lucky that...
Yes yes, I know.
He'll say he doesn't remember..
..when he bought a lottery ticket.
Like he doesn't remember..
..when he took part in the bank's lucky draw.
And, he also doesn't remember..
..when he ordered these books on the internet.
Let me get some tea.
Sir..
..this is Rajveer's hideout right?
Excuse me?
What do you mean?
What? What's going on?
Nothing. I was just..
I should be leaving.
Our sons.
Our brave sons.
This is Viren.
Died in the line of duty.
And him.. he's Jai.
He was in the army too.
Or maybe he's still in the army. I don't know.
He was posted in Kargil..
..when he heard about Viren.
And since then..
..they say that he was on a mission and..
..the lake was really deep and...
He's absolutely fine..
..no matter what people say.
He won this trophy in..
..the state swimming championship.
He was the only one..
..who could swim across the lake in one breath.
I refuse to believe he's dead.
Hello?
Hello!
Anybody there?
Harleen.
Excuse me. Who are you?
I'll ask the questions, not you.
Where is the Kohinoor?
I don't know, please let me go.
Zafar.
I am Omar Zafar.
How did you get this?
Not how, but why did I get this?
Why do I have it?
If you didn't want it,
why steal it in the first place?
Where's the real Kohinoor?
That was a fake?
The real one would've shattered the hammer.
She spent a lot of time with Rajveer.
Baktawar?
- Zorawar.
So she won't tell us so easily.
You're with him?
I gave him the Kohinoor I had.
I don't know where the real one is.
Quiet! Or else...
Get it?
Yes.
That's like a good girl.
Ow!
No more wisecracks from you.
Now you'll only speak the truth,
and nothing but the truth.
Tell me.
Tell you what? - The truth.
Honestly speaking Mr. Bhatnagar...
- Zorawar!
With that moustache..
..you look like a South-Indian hero.
What? - Yes.
And you know, my grandma's life..
..is more exciting than mine.
Quiet!
Just tell us where the Kohinoor is.
Kohinoor.
Rajveer has the Kohinoor.
But Rajveer is dead.
No.. he's alive!
He planned all of this.
He wants me to think that he's dead..
..so that you think he's not alive.
But he doesn't know that I know he's alive.
He thinks that I think he's dead.
Understand Mr. Zindagi Ek Safar?
If he's alive, I'll be absolutely fine.
You two are such fools.
That day on the bridge,
he pressed the transmitter himself.
He could've escaped.
But he intentionally gave me the fake Kohinoor..
..so that you would bring me here..
..and he could come after you.
Rajveer, Hi.
Not bad Harleen.
You turned out to be a lot
smarter than these fools.
I can't imagine the wit,
courage and obsession..
..one needs to get here.
Not as much as you think.
Luckily, neither you nor
your men are too smart.
Who's smart and who isn't
won't be decided so fast Rajveer.
That will be decided when one of us is dead..
..and the other one has the Kohinoor.
The question now is..
..how much pain can you endure..
..before handing over the Kohinoor.
Tell me.. where is the Kohinoor?
Otherwise, it'll be Harleen's
turn to endure the pain.
Tell me!
The Kohinoor is where it should be.
In London.
You're lying.
The Kohinoor's been stolen.
Everyone knows that.
Because we said it's been stolen.
What do you mean?
This was a joint operation..
..of the Indian Secret Service and London's MI6.
When you asked for the Kohinoor..
..we made our plan.
The Kohinoor is safe in its place, Zafar.
But unfortunately, you're not so safe.
You mean.. the Kohinoor was never stolen.
Brilliant, Rajveer!
Brilliant.
Not everyone is fortunate enough
to hear their eulogy before dying..
..but what's the point?
How will you save yourself now?
Because the countdown to your death
has already begun.
Those who serve their country..
..start the countdown to their
death from their very first breath, Zafar.
Take a good look in these eyes.
There's no grief..
..or fear of death.
There's only pride.
Soon.. you'll see your death in similar eyes.
Remember anything?
Colonel Nanda.
How are you related to him?
I am his brother.
The countdown to your death started that day,
Zafar.
And it ends.. today.
10!
9!
8!
Aye!! Go out and see what's happening!
7!
6!
5!
He's not alone.
Who else is with you?
4!
3!
You won't get out alive either.
2!
You'll die just like your brother.
1!
Bang-Bang!
They gave me an injection because of you!
That injection won't kill you.
You'll just speak the truth, that's all.
Ok? Let's go.
The truth is I wasted my entire life.
They're shooting, Harleen. Let's go!
All those boys..
..Dilip, Jaggi, Harbhajan.. all the same..
..boring, boring, boring.
Duck!
But not you.
You're very hot and exciting!
Jump!
You really excite me.
Good.
That's good. Shall we go now?
Your muscles are so strong.
I want to tear your clothes off.
But I can't..
..because I am not exciting enough.
Harleen! We have to go.
Do I look sexy to you?
A lot.
Then why didn't you do something?
What?
Why didn't you do something?
Thank God you won't remember anything.
I will remember everything.
The truth is, you don't love me.
You find me boring.
Rajveer.
Harleen get on the bike. Come on hurry up!
Soon we'll part ways.
You'll go on to live your exciting life..
..and me, my boring life.
Why would you be with a boring girl?
You're not boring Harleen.
Then what am I?
Tell me!
What am...
You're sexy, exciting, crazy, and right now.. alive.
Let's keep it that way, Ok!
Unzip me.
Now?
Hug me.
Did you find my guns?
You're very exciting Harleen.
Now take the guns out, and shoot!
Rajveer!
Enough! - Get up!
Rajveer. - Let's go.
Shoaib died because of him.
He killed Hamid Gul and took the Kohinoor.
Here's the Kohinoor.
If you can get to me, then..
..you can get the real Kohinoor as well.
When you have the real Kohinoor..
..you can come and exchange it for her.
I am sure you will find me.. again.
Goodbye.
Come on!
Take this.
- Rajveer!
Rajveer!
Help!
Somebody.
- Hey!
The next bullet will hit your face,
if you're not quiet.
Oh my God!
And listen, I want the Kohinoor at any cost.
The plane has been hit!
- David, check what's happening.
We have to land the plane!
Rajveer!
Well done.
Thankyou Sir.
Your parents have led a strange life.
One son sacrificed his life for his country..
..and the other is dead for them,
even though he's alive.
Harleen has been sent home.
And she has been instructed..
..not to see you again.
You know.. that Jai is 'dead'
for the sake of this mission.
Now you are Rajveer.
By joining the Internal Secret Services..
..you signed over your life to us.
Harleen can prove to be a threat for you.
She could be your weakness.
Anyway, you'll be transported
to a safe place tomorrow.
Till then, get some rest.
What did I just have?
Harleen?!
Stop! Stop the car!
...Hey!
Don't worry Rajveer. We're safe.
Good morning!
Where are we?
Who changed my clothes?
You ask too many questions.
I did.
And if I remember correctly, my eyes were closed.
Maybe.
What day is it today?
One day.
Jai!
Viren!
Come on, dinner is ready.
Jai, mom's calling us!
Viren! I am coming.
Jai.
So, what now?
There's just one thing left to do.
What?
Bang-Bang!
Our nights have taken some decisions.
And as we have met now..
..some magic is about to happen.
Talks have happened between our eyes.
And as we have met now..
..some magic is about to happen.
Whatever is about to happen will happen.
Something surely happens
when you meet someone.
This is surely about to happen.
I've felt this after meeting you.
Are you feeling it tonight?
I'm feeling it tonight.
Bang Bang. Talk to me the whole night.
Come and walk with me.
A spell has been cast on my heart,
I don't know why.
Bang Bang. Talk to me the whole night.
Come and walk with me.
A spell has been cast on my heart,
I don't know why.
Bang Bang, Bang Bang, Bang Bang.
Bang Bang.
Nowadays while roaming here and there..
..the eyes talk.
Today I'll get beguiled in the talks of the eyes.
Just do one thing..
..embrace me in your arms.
And all night long, this story of ours
will continue.
Yours and mine..
- Yours and mine..
The signs that our sights are giving.
Let's understand all of them.
As I'm about to lose my consciousness.
Whatever is about to happen will happen.
Something surely happens when you meet someone.
This is surely about to happen.
I've felt this after meeting you.
Are you feeling it tonight?
I'm feeling it tonight.
Bang Bang.
Talk to me the whole night.
Come and walk with me.
A spell has been cast on my heart,
I don't know why.
Bang Bang.
Talk to me the whole night.
Come and walk with me.
A spell has been cast on my heart,
I don't know why.
Talk to me...  (Bang Bang)
...the whole night.
I don't know why.
Bang Bang.
Bang Bang... Bang Bang... Bang Bang.
I don't know why.
Bang Bang, take a little chance chance.
Do a little dance dance.
Now get your body moving.
Bang Bang.
Talk to me the whole night.
Come and walk with me.
A spell has been cast on my heart,
I don't know why.
Bang Bang.
Talk to me the whole night.
Come and walk with me.
A spell has been cast on my heart,
I don't know why.
Bang-Bang!