This story happened before
insider trading was penalized.
Any resemblance to a bank or banker
is purely coincidental.
- Hello, Mr Julien.
- Hello.
Good morning, Mr Julien.
Good morning.
How's the new mum?
Much better.
Five kilos is quite a push!
Certainly is.
Five kilos!
BANK ERROR IN YOUR FAVOUR
Leg oflamb, pommes risolées.
Monday: lunch with Mr Gontran Gerbeau
de la Roche, director of EURoLEC.
Serve him separately, no salt.
Wednesday:
Mr Stuart Nelson, chairman of KKS.
Check we have enough
Château Angelus.
We need a new maid,
Caroline had words with Mr d'Espinasse.
I'll see to it.
Julien, my dear...
we're all going to miss you.
You're very kind, Madame Brière.
But it was inevitable.
The gentlemen prefer
eating out nowadays.
You're taking it philosophically.
But I'll bounce back.
It may be my chance
to attain my dream.
I'll tell you about it soon.
of course.
- Pommes rissolées...
- Yes?
... would be better with two Ss.
You want to snap up Blue Mineral?
The stocks dropped 2% again today.
Alban, we don't follow the trend,
we create it.
Blue Mineral is signing a billion euro
contract with Australia.
Highly confidential...
David, tell Madame de l'Epée
it's settled for her son.
His dispensation has been granted.
About Blue Mineral,
can you trust your source?
Sandrez told me himself.
It's good we put him on the board.
He's as crooked as they come.
That's why they took him on.
Blue Mineral should shoot up
25% - 30% today,
so we should make about 80 million.
Excellent! I'll tell my son to buy.
It'll pay for his divorce.
But using this information
is blatant insider trading.
The Market Authorities
will certainly...
He's a beginner.
- But sir...
- Alban.
Yes, sir.
You know the root
of the word "scruple"?
From the Latin scrupulus.
A little pebble...
... in a Roman soldier's sandal
that can hold up a whole army.
A silly little pebble.
How about Total Finances?
A loser! And a dead loss
in heavy going.
Black Money's the one to go for.
Black Money?
He should be turned out to grass!
Look at this.
Incredible!
Thermal shock.
Cold sauce, hot plate.
Taste it.
Fresh Noirmoutier soup,
with a whiff of citrus fruit,
cumin leaves...
And a flavour from my childhood.
- It's...
- Gingerbread.
And orange blossom water too.
You're an artist, Etienne.
The world will know it.
Hey, Harmony!
Rosemary on the strawberries?
At today's prices!
Tasted his marvel?
The potato soup? Do me a favour!
I've been scouring the chipmaker!
It's not worth it.
- He's pissing off!
- He'll be back in an hour.
Treat him properly. He's Picasso.
So what? I'm not an art dealer.
Well?
Have a look.
We start with 20 place settings,
then we expand in here...
You see?
And we move up a slot.
So you want to open
your own business?
No, our business.
It's now or never!
Don't be such an idiot.
Get yourself a good job first,
then we'll see.
Where? Today only the Rothschilds
can afford a Maître D.
Remember Maurice Barge?
- Your buddy from the Ritz?
- Right.
Know where he is now?
Buffalo Bill's, being hassled
by a manager his son's age.
No, I'm sorry.
Not after 20 years
serving the top drawer!
Well, I don't know
what the top drawer eat.
And I don't fancy serving fat cats.
You're wrong.
They'll love your cooking.
You could win
a Michelin star in 2 years time.
And the PAYE?
We can't handle that.
The accounts, all that stuff.
When I see poor old Georges,
I'd rather not be a boss.
How much will all this cost?
All in all, 250 000€
and it's ours.
You're nuts.
No bank will lend us that.
You have 20 000€.
I have 15 000
plus 30 000 severance pay.
Excuse me.
Yes, Mr d'Espinasse?
Absolutely, Mr d'Espinasse.
No problem, Mr d'Espinasse.
Goodbye, Mr d'Espinasse.
- It was Mr d'Espinasse.
- No kidding.
A lunch in his home...
He wants me to serve.
And who's lending us 200 000?
- D'Espinasse?
- Right.
I've spoken to him, he agrees.
For the Berthin-Schwartz Bank
200 000€ is peanuts.
Well?
Boss?
Chef. Not boss!
oK, chef.
Look!
Mao! Down, Mao!
Let him go!
You exaggerate! You know Julien!
You're a monster. A tyrant!
Not the tray!
Run along and play.
He's teasing, he's not nasty.
They broke in while we were asleep.
All the jewellery, the 2 Matisses,
the Vlaminck.
our Boulle furniture...
- There's nothing left.
- My God!
How ghastly!
You must be traumatized.
- It means more shopping.
- Yes.
- They're organizing another sale.
- You must come.
I don't need convincing.
Why have we got
to complain about, Henri?
You've been doubling
our turnover for 5 years.
This year will be even better.
We fired half the workforce,
the others will work double hard.
Remember "Work more to earn more"?
That was never intended
for the same people!
No.
Julien, there you are.
- It's Mao. I'm sorry.
- Again?
Something he ate.
Where?
How should I know? Heavens!
No, I mean where did he...
In the hall by the coats.
Hurry, or there'll be a disaster!
Full house!
Still playing poker?
He's exhausting!
Here, help me.
- Victoria!
- I'm coming!
Madame!
What's this?
Buzz off!
- Thank you, Julien.
- Thank you, sir.
Don't let Mao out of the garden
when you leave.
Mr d'Espinasse?
Have you considered my proposal?
What proposal?
The restaurant I want to open
with my chef friend.
Ah, yes.
But I won't have you
to do my dinners!
Don't worry,
I'll always be free for you, sir.
It's so hard to find good staff.
And you know the house.
- Thank you, Julien.
- It's nothing, sir.
France needs
more people like you.
The French grumble
about working too hard.
The problem isn't having
one job, but two.
Keep me informed.
I'll be your first customer.
- Mr d'Espinasse?
- Yes?
Excuse me...
would your bank agree
to give me a loan?
A loan?
How long have you been working
for us, Julien?
Almost 17 years, sir.
It's incredible.
After 17 years you still don't know
we never give personal loans?
No, but...
I thought there'd be
exceptions for staff...
- Personal staff.
- No, Julien!
That's the thin edge of the wedge.
Bring me a project
to rebuild Les Halles
and we can find a way.
But not a greasy spoon.
Your local bank will help you
at very acceptable interest rates.
But my length of service...
off already?
We've barely seen each other.
Let me see you out.
He took the piss out of you.
He kicked you out
and won't help you start again.
He didn't kick me out.
I have my severance pay.
Yeah, that gold mine.
How much?
30 000 for 17 years service?
Right, it's not peanuts.
It's peanut shells.
oK, back off.
It's d'Espinasse's cigar budget.
He's probably a millionaire.
So what?
We're not in the same line.
Sometimes you sound
like a communist.
Thirty euros isn't a fortune!
I'm expecting a money transfer.
You said that two days ago
but your account is still empty.
I'm sorry, I can't help.
Gentlemen, good morning!
Good morning, sir.
You're too old
to be turned down!
I'm sorry,
your loan has been refused.
Not enough guarantees.
Isn't a restaurant a guarantee?
Not if you go bankrupt.
I hope you don't, but it's a risk.
I based my calculations
on a turnover of... Shit!
What?
Sorry, our computers are down.
Third time this week.
Anyway we have nothing more to say.
Coming?
Wait, you haven't heard
the good news.
This capitol you need:
I can offer you a way
to constitute it.
We have a wide range of safe
high-return credit possibilities.
For instance: Multimoney.
It rose by 2.6% this year.
2.6%?
At a 4% inflation rate?
Very interesting.
We'll be able to open
in 40 years time.
Sounds good.
I'm talking about "safe" profit
but if you're not scared of risks
that changes everything.
Look.
our Asia Tech unit trust,
it's dynamic, it's Asian...
Blue Mineral should shoot up
25% - 30% today,
so we should make about 80 million.
Excellent!
I'll tell my son to buy.
It'll pay for his divorce.
Blue Mineral.
I want to buy Blue Mineral.
Pardon?
You know Blue Mineral,
the manganese?
It's out of the question,
we never intervene
on the Stock Exchange.
However with Multimoney...
Stuff your Multimoney.
I want to buy Blue Mineral.
- I'm sorry...
- No, we're sorry.
Come on, let's go.
We're too old too.
Leave the Stock Exchange
to the professionals.
Madame Morel,
what's happened?
Mum! What are you doing?
Stop it!
It's Mr FoucauIt's door.
Forgive her.
She's losing it.
Come on, mum.
Sorry.
Mr Foucault?
Gilbert Tomasini from the CPDF Bank,
Rue Legrand.
We have to talk.
Yes, sure.
Fine.
Blue Mineral and Canberra
go sky high. Up 29%.
I'm really sorry.
I made you lose money.
Bad for a bank manager.
29% in one day?
34% since this morning.
Just between us, how did you know?
No!
Don't tell me.
I'd rather not know.
However, if you have any more...
any more hunches.
I'd be honoured
to handle personally
all your transactions.
obviously...
this is just between us.
It's the moment to consolidate
our position.
We'll drop Chimicorp
and go up 10% on Ultramarine.
And Lynch Capital?
No change.
Saintonge says
they expect a bumper year.
Yes, David?
Here's the latest: ALCAo will announce
a rise in their profits.
ALCAo...
Alban, find something
in the Place Vendôme.
For Madame Saint André.
As usual, sir.
Two cancellations next week.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Two cancellations?
Unbelievable!
No, put half on Lynch Capital.
Right.
And 4000 on ALCo.
It'll shoot up.
Right away.
Fucking amazing!
What's going on?
Just putting a savings plan through.
That's the second this week.
Well done, Gilbert.
20 000€?
Are you putting me on?
No, it's crazy,
I can't get over it.
I'll have most of the money
before I leave.
I want a piece.
I am your partner.
- You can't.
- Why?
- You're a communist.
- Cut it out.
Don't be trapped
by capitalism, Etienne.
It's for a good cause.
I have 15 000€
in a savings account.
You shouldn't do that!
I'm happy to.
She's cute, huh?
Brains too. She works at Georges'
but she's a student.
What did you do to her?
Nothing.
I don't know what she sees in me.
She sees the man of her dreams.
Young, with a great job.
And a Led Zeppelin collection.
Piss off.
But she comes on to me,
it's embarrassing.
If I didn't hold back...
I'm not crazy, though.
The aging Romeo dating a young babe.
No way.
Well, well...
I'm off, Etienne.
Keep quiet about the Stock Exchange.
What do you take me for?
30 000€ in 2 weeks?
Not lrish, are you?
He's been in the business 15 years.
Serving Vivagel,
Philips, LVMH lunch every day!
The Stock Exchange is rigged.
Give me racing!
You're wrong.
They're both the same.
A simple punter
is screwed every time.
But if you have good tips
you clean up.
Yeah? And the crash?
- What crash?
- The Stock Market crash.
Wake up.
They're jumping
out of windows in New York!
So? You're on the ground floor.
A white Mercedes A-Class
with 78 plates?
That's me.
- Hurry, they're clamping it.
- No!
I'm on my way!
Hello, Mr Foucault.
A strong expresso?
- Later, I'm waiting for someone.
- I see.
No, it's professional.
The bank needs a new maid.
Then I won't dim the lights?
Hello.
You're late.
Yes, I'm sorry.
A glass of champagne.
No, a Bellini!
No, sorry, a kir royal
with blackberry, please.
How shall we do this?
Will you start?
or shall l?
First I need to clarify some points.
- Are you married?
- What?
No, I wouldn't be here if...
Single.
Any children?
No.
Good.
I have nothing against children,
of course,
but they complicate matters:
school, games, etc...
- You are strange.
- I beg your pardon?
Taking notes, asking questions,
like I'm taking an exam.
one strong coffee.
A champagne kir for Madame.
What about you...
What are you looking for
in a woman?
Someone available and motivated
who can buckle down to it.
I'm a stickler for tidiness
and cleanliness.
Pardon?
What else?
Not much ironing,
about half a day a week.
But the table linen
must be properly folded.
This isn't the 19th century.
We have the right to vote now.
I can't see the connection.
It's staggering!
This isn't the way to go about
looking for a soul mate.
A soul mate?
May l?
Aren't you Ulysses?
Ulysses?
No, I'm looking for a maid.
Are you Stéphanie?
Ulysses 45.
I was on time
but they were clamping my Mercedes.
I apologize. Please forgive me.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry.
Let's sit somewhere quieter?
Yes!
What's happened?
Big trouble.
Give me a lift?
Yes.
No, well...
Can't I help you fix it?
Forget it.
I'll do it tomorrow.
But maybe it's something minor...
You don't want to give me a lift!
No, it's not that...
No...
It's out of my way.
oh, yeah?
You know where I live?
No, you're right.
Where do you live?
Do you read Shakespeare?
He's my father's favourite writer.
There's a line of his I adore:
"Love looks not with the eyes
but with the mind."
Yeah. Beautiful.
Like some?
It's good stuff.
I don't believe it.
I don't believe it!
My favourite record!
"Physical Graffiti", Led Zeppelin.
I lent mine to a friend and lost it.
"Kashmir",
"Down by the Seaside",
"Houses of the Holy"...
Here.
Present for you.
You're mad. It's unobtainable.
Exactly.
Anyway no one listens to it.
oK, l...
I accept. Thank you.
I'm really touched.
Good stuff!
Mr Morel, hello.
- Have you seen my mother?
- No.
She's disappeared again.
I don't know what yours is like...
She's dead.
You're lucky.
I mean, some days
you wonder what's best.
Everyone knows her.
They'll bring her back.
But in what state?
Last time the kids painted her face
with magic markers.
They tagged her.
She didn't want me to wash it off.
She talks like them now.
A regular kid.
But my wife and l
have three children already.
Look, Mr Mo...
The solution is a nursing home.
Perfect for her.
We visited one with a lovely garden.
But very expensive.
over 20 000€ a year.
Goodness.
I have 4 000€.
But I can't get a bank loan on that.
There's the Stock Exchange,
of course.
But that's something...
you must know about.
Don't you agree?
otherwise it's very...
I won't bother you any longer.
If you see my mother
can you bring her back?
of course.
Mr Morel...
Can I have a word with you?
What?
Shh, Etienne!
oK.
oK. I don't have time now.
Me too, big hug.
My father.
He's cool but he's pressurizing me
over these exams.
He's scared I'll flunk the oral.
You're brilliant at the oral.
Very funny.
No, what kind of oral?
School leaving certificate.
That's why I'm quitting
my job next week.
School leaving certificate?
Aren't you very behind?
No, not very.
Not very? But...
How old are you?
You're not under age?
Seriously, you are over 18?
Sure I am.
I will be in october.
It's not true.
It is.
I can't register it officially,
they're not our clients.
Well then...
Put it on my account,
I'll share it out.
No more overdrafts.
All over!
Thank you.
Mr Martinez, our director.
- Mr Foucault.
- Delighted.
I'll leave you.
I'll deal with it.
May I open
a Multimoney security account for you?
Are you kidding?
It's worth peanuts.
I know! It's to reassure my boss.
He's seen you here a lot,
to allay his suspicions.
Don't worry, minimum 100€.
And the bank charges are for me.
Thank you.
That must be the client adviser!
Stop it. He's your son-in-law.
Holy shit!
He's bought the Volvo.
Be nice for once.
Smile!
Your husband is transformed.
He's scintillating. I'm worried.
So I see.
That's enough!
Wash your hands! Lunchtime!
And don't run.
Slowly.
You seem very edgy.
- You should be happy.
- Look...
We eat at the Tour d'Argent,
he gave me this ring,
and the car,
he wants us to visit Brazil
with the children.
You find that normal?
Last month
we couldn't pay the nanny.
Maybe he's been promoted.
It's great.
I hope he isn't being silly.
Come on!
Hey! You have a terrific car!
Have you robbed your bank
or something?
No, I have some clients,
personal clients,
I handle their portfolios...
Excuse me.
Mr Foucault! How are you?
No, nothing serious,
on the contrary.
Just to inform you
that EFELECT is up 21%!
21 points in a week.
Absolutely.
of course, don't hesitate,
Mr Foucault.
Goodbye.
Excuse me.
I'm very impressed, Gilbert my boy.
I try to be reactive.
The market
is fairly bullish right now,
it's tough, but I'm not complaining.
You know,
I have some money
sleeping in an account...
in Switzerland.
obviously
this money doesn't exist,
you understand?
We're used to that.
You too?
So if a good opportunity arises,
Iet me know, eh?
Making your money work
is better than working!
Lunchtime!
Finish dressing!
I'm ready. Let's go.
We're early. How about a coffee?
- In the bar.
- Sweetie?
Not saying goodbye?
Yes, of course.
Sorry, baby.
Harmony... Julien.
Hiya.
Mademoiselle.
Go back to bed.
I must run.
"Sweetie"?
I tried to resist, really I did.
But what can you do?
She doesn't like boys.
Boys her age.
She prefers boys your age?
I'm in love.
She makes me want to move on.
It hasn't happened for years.
You grab anything you can get.
As far as that's concerned
you've got it solved.
What do you mean?
C'mon, Julien!
Your last girl friend
was 18 months ago.
She lasted 2 weeks as she left
her toothbrush at your place.
It wasn't that!
I didn't have time for her
with my job.
With Mr d'Espinasse:
"Fine, Mr d'Espinasse..."
oh, back off!
What is your life today?
Your job, your TV, your apartment?
Lucky you're fucked by your boss!
If you'd like to sign
the sales agreement.
I must ask you
for a cheque for 15 782€.
The seller has refused
suspensive conditions.
If your loan is turned down,
your advance is non-returnable.
No problem.
Where does the 15 000€ go?
Invested at 2%.
What a waste! We have...
Where? Here?
Hello.
Remember me?
That vile man in the café?
Yes, of course.
Sorry...
Avoiding me?
Me? Not at all.
So you read Turkish?
I must have seemed
rather an oaf.
An oaf?
Do people still say that?
Macho then.
Heavy?
- Did you find your cleaning lady?
- Yes.
And your Ulysses 42?
45!
More like 54 frankly, but...
I shouldn't have gone
on that date...
A friend met the ideal man
on match.com.
She pushed me into it.
It's ridiculous.
He's no longer available.
Who?
The ideal man.
He's with your friend!
Well, goodbye.
You don't want it?
Mademoiselle...
I thought perhaps...
I could ask you out
so you'd forgive me.
You're forgiven.
I am?
But you can still ask me out.
Do you like banking, my boy?
Yes, very much.
It's most rewarding...
on a personal level, I mean.
Naturally. on a personal level.
BANK PARKlNG SPACE
I'm HUNGRY!
Lunchtime already?
Hello Stéphanie
Don't hang up on me
Stéphanie
Do you have time
To join me
For a glass of wine
Julien, serve us
a Château Smith Haut Laffite '82
and a Domaine de Chevalier
'96 or '95, I never remember.
- '95, sir.
- of course.
What would we do without you?
What guarantee do I have
that my company won't be carved up?
It's not in our interest, sir.
And it goes against our principles.
You'll keep the workforce on?
Never fear, Mr Lebrun.
Your team is as precious to us
as the spirit of your company.
You see, this company is my life.
I started off with one secondhand truck.
Now I have 800.
Just the two of us.
My wife handled accounts and clients,
I was on the road day and night,
summer and winter.
When Claudia was born
I had to borrow from the bank
to buy a pram!
How very touching.
But I have no heir.
I have my three girls
but trucks don't interest them.
And my son-in-law makes films.
With my money, of course.
He's been preparing his film
for 5 years.
Artists!
I have a son who wants to be a DJ!
Excellent.
Anyway I'm dealing with the top,
aren't l?
No question about it.
The affair is shaping up well.
And the planning permission?
They vote at the beginning of June.
our friends on the board
guarantee a yes.
The opposition will get a nibble.
And the redundancies?
1300 laid off.
The unions will give us hell.
Lebrun will take the rap.
They'll say he sold
without enough guarantees.
We're just doing our job.
But nothing must leak out
before he signs.
What's your impression?
He needs to sell.
Apparently his health problems
are worse than he says.
Yes?
It's Julien, Julien Foucault.
Just a minute.
I booked a table for 9 o'clock.
Collar's better open...
Hello!
Hey!
Can you come up?
There's a disaster,
it's my washing machine.
Do you mind?
No.
It's over here.
It's nothing, just a small leak.
I'll fix it.
Where's the stopcock?
The stopcock?
- To stop the water.
- oh, yes!
- Found it?
- Yes!
Good. Turn it off.
- What?
- The other way!
It's the wrong way!
- What?
- It's the wrong way!
That's it.
- It was the wrong way.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's nothing.
- I'm sorry.
It's my jacket, it's drenched.
So is your shirt.
That doesn't matter.
Do you have a hairdryer?
I'm so sorry!
You'll find me old fashioned,
but I don't see why
someone as attractive as you
needs to go on lnternet to...
Absolutely.
- What?
- You are old fashioned.
You want to know
why I go on lnternet?
Because your friend
found the ideal man that way.
I wouldn't like a computer
to find my ideal woman.
Why not?
People are incredibly fussy about...
choosing a new car,
the engine power,
the colour of the seats.
But they leave their love life
to fate.
Fate always brings me the same type.
What type?
The type who...
rather obsessive loners
who feel threatened
by a second toothbrush.
Here, let me.
- I've scared you off?
- Not at all.
I'll see if your suit is dry.
Sorry, I don't know
what came over me.
Was that all?
What do you mean, all?
Didn't you...
- Not even pissed?
- No!
I think he tried to kiss me
but I turned away.
Why did l?
You don't kiss on a first date.
It's normal, you're 36.
His eyes are very gentle, a bit sad.
He's gorgeous.
As gorgeous as an ltalian
Knowing he'll have love and wine
He only had wine.
Good. You took Auntie's advice,
I'm proud of you.
No, I said
I wanted to fall in love...
I was ready for something serious...
oh, right.
What? You think I freaked him out?
No, he's probably the type
who's not used to rejection.
He'll call you.
You think so?
Not a good idea.
She's sweet but...
she wants it all.
True love, commitment,
that's not for me.
Anyway,
I can't get involved right now.
No, you might be happy.
Stop doing those onions.
Hand me a truffle from the jar.
That fat truffle.
I'm not butting in?
We were just talking about you.
What's this:
"Filet of beef in fresh thyme
"on a bed of baby cardoons
"with bone marrow cromesqui
"en papillotte"?
The dish of the day.
My customers
have 45 minutes for lunch.
They may have time to read it
but not to eat.
Shit! First Picasso, now Proust!
I'm getting overcooked.
Drink my health.
- How kind. Thank you.
- My pleasure.
- I appreciate it.
- No, I do!
That tip-off
about the Bouygues deal!
No one saw it coming.
What Bouygues deal?
It was on the radio this morning.
We all cracked up
as Etienne had told us about it.
So what do we do?
Stay in the game
or pull out our winnings?
Brand new.
Straight from Geneva.
We can't stop grateful patients
thanking us!
Naturally!
- How much is there?
- 200 000.
I can have more.
No, no, that's fine.
To start with...
Antoine, I'm very touched
by your trust in me...
Doctor, you must come!
I'm in a meeting!
It's the trephination in room 108.
I'm coming.
Do your best.
You won't be disappointed.
- Where is he?
- Room 108!
Etienne sounds a bit dated, no?
Those old fashioned names
are trendy now.
What do his parents do?
You know Harmony,
the slightest question
and she treats us like torturers!
All I know is he dropped out of Uni
and wants to open a restaurant.
Perfect!
The year of her exams!
- Don't start.
- She's punishing us.
Chill out!
We've always encouraged trust.
And we've never regretted it.
I'd far rather Harmony told us
about her crushes.
Not like the time we found
some hash under her pillow.
Take the first exit
at the roundabout.
Hash!
Turn back...
Shit! Shit!
Yes?
Do come in.
- Good evening.
Something smells good!
- olivier. Harmony's father.
- Hello.
- My wife Marianne.
- Hello. Here.
Thank you. You shouldn't have.
- Can I take your coat?
- Thanks.
Harmony's popped out
to buy some bread.
Do sit down.
So your son is the next Ducasse?
My son?
Isn't he cooking tonight?
- No, I am.
- Runs in the family, eh!
Where is the wonder boy?
Here.
I mean...
I'm Etienne.
Your daughter's boyfriend.
It certainly does smell good!
A drink? A glass of white wine?
He's talking to you.
Call me Etienne.
What?
What will you have?
- Nothing.
- A glass of white wine?
I'll have a scotch.
Neat!
Hiya!
So you've all met?
- You could have warned us.
- Pardon?
Warned you about what?
Like a drink, baby?
No, I'll sip from your glass.
olivier, just a drop to toast with?
No, it's fine.
Health and happiness!
Excuse me, sir, but...
How old are you?
- Dad!
- It's fine, baby.
I know it's surprising,
I was surprised myself at first.
I'm forty five.
Well, forty eight to be exact.
only five years older than you,
not a lot.
What are you saying?
Boys my age
have never interested me.
Your mental age is what counts.
I can see there's no problem there.
That's vile,
you don't even know him.
If he was Pablo Casals or Picasso
I'd understand,
but a pizza cook...
How about some dinner?
- Already?
- Yes.
If you like.
What's that?
It's my record!
My Led Zepp!
He nicked my Led Zeppelin!
No, Harmony gave it to me.
Back off, you never listen to it!
Get your things, we're going.
What? No way!
Hurry or I'll smack you.
Violence is never a solution.
Fuck off! She's my daughter!
Have you gone insane?
Insane?
She's only doing it to upset us.
I see why your pupils hate you.
Do you now?
Right!
Come on, let's go.
Please, olivier, don't go.
Darling, please...
No. I'm out of the madhouse!
Marianne!
Well done, you won!
We've found something.
It's small but Maxime
will have his own room.
Wonderful!
This is for you.
For me?
It's fantastic! Very good.
Thank you.
Mr Foucault, do you mind
if I recuperate my money?
No problem.
I'll have it ready tomorrow.
Thank you, you've saved our lives.
- Have a nice day.
- Thank you.
Calf's sweetbreads, on the house.
- No, what for?
- It's normal.
LVMH was delicious.
My wife and I loved it.
I see. Thank you.
We thank you, Mr Foucault.
Apparently FED interest rates
have gone up.
- Is that good for us?
- I don't know.
I'd say LVMH in first place,
KKS second,
Bouygues in third.
Watch out for KKS.
The dollar's high.
What did Gaillard say about Vivagel?
Something about Areva,
I can't remember.
Me neither.
Stay on track, guys!
Bye.
Are you off, baby?
I'm studying at Quentin's.
I told you.
No, you didn't.
Is that him?
Why not my place?
It's too small. We'll disturb you
if you want to watch TV.
No, you won't. I'll cook for you,
gnoccchi in a lemon cream sauce.
Sure, sweetie,
but not tonight.
And you don't even have Wi-fi.
Right, as you like.
I didn't imagine him like that.
Trendy, huh?
Don't freak out.
- You know boys don't...
- He's no boy.
- He's 21.
- You see?
See you. Bye!
Don't wait up, we'll work late.
Sure.
He won't have to get up
to take her to school!
Japanese, what's more.
Hey, "Ratatouille",
bring us some pear tart
without the choucroute!
I quit.
You're kidding! It's a gold mine.
It's too risky.
The whole neighbourhood knows about it.
It's insider trading.
Insider trading?
It's what your bankers do!
Yes, but it's their job.
Don't worry, we've made enough
to pay the estate agent tomorrow.
And you know what that is?
Freedom, Etienne!
Freedom, yeah...
Freedom to work our asses off
till we drop.
I thought it was your life's dream?
We're not robbers.
We're making the money work for us.
Work for us!
You still believe that crap?
Money doesn't work!
Every banknote was sweated for!
By you or someone else.
It's not magic.
one last time.
You've changed.
All fine. No problem
with the planning permission.
And Lebrun?
He trusts us. But we can't act
before buying him out.
We have a signature date: the 18th.
Excellent.
There's an echo.
Yes, sir?
Bring us some brandy, Julien.
Very good, sir.
Two? That's ludicrous!
Yes, actually.
Absolutely, my dear fellow,
many thanks.
Big botch up at BMGM.
The supervisory board found
clumsily falsified minutes.
Gaspard's been caught
with his hand in the till.
Again?
For how much?
Two billion. For the moment.
Poor old Gaspard!
He doesn't care.
He'll return to the revenue court.
Anyway his wife has a fortune.
Alban, dispose of our holdings.
Discreetly.
We have 3 or 4 days
before this erupts.
What the hell's he up to?
Julien?
How do we stand with BMGM?
We don't have much,
but there'll be a huge scandal...
Damn fool Gaspard.
Nabbed like a greenhorn.
For how much this time?
You mean his fine?
No, his departure package, Alban!
His golden parachute.
More like a golden hot-air balloon!
"Morel: Blue Mineral + 14 000.
"EFELECT : Mr Denissovitch + 10 500.
"Etienne: + 30 000..."
If the flunkeys start
mopping up the sauce...
Who can one trust?
As he's leaving,
I suggest a farewell gift.
It's the last one,
I've made a note of it.
Wonderful how Julien makes a note
of everything.
It's still off the record,
but BMGM
is going to rocket sky high!
Shares will be snapped up.
We mustn't miss the bus.
BMGM double whammy!
They're beside themselves.
BMGM is massive.
Holy shit! We'll fuck 'em!
What?
Sorry, I was carried away.
I'll see to it right now.
Hello, Stéphanie?
It's Julien, Julien Foucault.
I say, Gilbert,
there must be a mistake.
I'm not on the new org chart.
Really? Let's see.
They've moved you.
Without asking me?
Where will they put me?
I don't know.
I can't see you anywhere.
What is this?
It's ridiculous.
I've been in this branch
for 25 years.
They can't treat people like that.
I'm fifty seven.
What will become of me?
Mr Martinez.
I'm terribly sorry.
Thank you, Gilbert.
I misjudged you.
You're a good man.
Excuse me, an emergency.
No! I expected your call.
Well?
I'm onto something big. It's huge.
Terrific!
Scalpel.
I suggest we mobilize our capital,
maybe half...
No, all the way!
- What are you doing?
- You said all the way.
I wasn't talking to you!
He'll sleep forever!
Don't just stand there.
Get on with it.
Sorry, Gilbert,
I'm single handed here.
I can invest half today
and wait for the market reaction?
I don't know. You hack it.
Not you, idiot!
What's wrong with you all?
Want to kill me?
Sorry, Gilbert,
there's a massacre going on.
Didn't you like it?
It was alright.
Alright? It's a masterpiece!
Don't exaggerate.
- It's a bit silly.
- Silly?
out of his mind!
It's a wonderful story.
He doesn't just say he loves her,
he proves it to her.
Is camping outside her house
for 3 days a proof of love?
I'd say it's a proof of weakness.
You're so prejudiced!
- I'm sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
Next time we'll see Predator 6.
And you say I'm prejudiced!
No, I'm kidding.
Well, I must be off.
- Have I upset you?
- Not at all.
But I get up early.
Kiss me.
Come on.
Harmony. Message.
First, why have a cell phone
if it's always switched off?
I called your friend Florence,
you must have got the days wrong.
She says
you're revising together tomorrow.
You can do what you like, of course,
but you could have let me know.
How old are you?
I mean...
To re-record your message, press 1.
Shit!
Hello?
Yes, I have 30 seconds.
You make me that offer
now I've bought my ticket?
In that case I prefer
the hydroplane, it's simpler.
Right, call me back, thank you.
- Hello, Monica.
- How are you?
- Is Antoine ready?
- I'll get him.
Sweet of you
to play squash with him.
My pleasure.
Don't wipe him out.
We can still use him!
Business News,
Stéphane Soulier.
BMGM in the news again,
a black morning for them.
As you know, the Fl have done
exceptionally well all year.
But they're under investigation
as a massive accounting fraud
has been uncovered.
Damages may be over 2 billion euros.
Shares dropped by half
on Wall Street last night.
Fuck!
We're in deep shit!
BMGM has collapsed!
No! They've never been wrong.
You better get me out of this.
I invested family money.
I could go to jail.
Right, call me back.
What the hell have you done?
Antoine! There you are!
You little shit!
I entrusted you with my fortune!
- Listen dad...
- Don't fucking "dad" me!
You tried to rip me off,
you little...
Antoine?
Monica!
What are you doing?
I have to go.
Really?
Are you oK? You look strange.
Do l?
Where did I put my...
Right.
Bye then.
Is tonight still on?
- For dinner?
- What dinner?
- Dinner with my friends?
- I'll call you.
Great.
Monsieur Foucault.
They want to see you.
"Mr Foucault"?
Tell us, Julien, my boy,
as you dabble on the Stock Exchange:
what did you think
of the BMGM collapse?
Appalling, no?
So you knew... and you...
Set you up?
But you set us up.
You betrayed our trust.
Did you think we were blind?
or should I say deaf?
It's not an excuse,
but I didn't harm anyone.
You're right, my boy.
It's not an excuse.
Do you have a passion in life?
Apart from the Stock Market.
Because from now on
you can devote yourself to it
full time.
Get out of here.
You're lucky we won't press charges.
- Press charges?
- We could easily.
- Spying.
- Spreading false information.
Illegal banking practices.
Insider trading?
Price rigging?
All the daily activities
that line your pockets?
Enough!
I don't want to see you again.
You sullied the bank's honour.
The bank's honour?
open the window, it stinks in here.
I thought I'd slipped up,
but they manipulated me.
I was set up.
What are you saying?
What is this crap?
- I'm saying we...
- No! Not "we".
"You". You fucked up!
I'm a chef, not a banker.
It's nothing to do with me.
What's happened to you?
I was cool working for Georges.
I've lost everything now.
You wanted to keep going.
I wanted to stop...
So I'm to blame?
I wouldn't have done it
if I'd known it was risky!
- So that's how you take it?
- How else?
I've scrimped and saved for years,
you've lost it all.
Expect me to hug you?
No.
Just to act like a friend.
Mr Foucault! Come in for a minute?
- Not now, Mr Morel.
- only a minute, it's important.
- You're pale. Are you alright?
- Look...
Mr Foucault!
Give it to Mr Foucault.
- For me?
- Yes.
It's from us all.
- No, I can't...
- Yes!
After all you've done for us.
You've changed our lives!
I'm taking the kids
to Corsica this summer.
our first holiday for 4 years!
Thank you!
For Mr Foucault:
Hip, hip...
My round! Let's drink to this!
Mr Foucault! Drink up!
Let's start, he may show up.
No, he's not coming.
You may be upsetting yourself
for nothing.
It's a shame. I really liked him.
Mr Foucault, what's the time?
Come over,
the decorating is nearly done.
Looks good!
Thank you.
Here.
Maybe you have it already?
A man called Jesus
No, I haven't read it.
It's a very good book.
Yes?
Thanks.
Mr Foucault,
about my money...
Mr Denissovitch,
there's a little problem...
Never mind.
It can wait till tomorrow.
- Come on. What do we say?
- Goodbye.
Is that your mother?
Yes.
Mum! Come here!
Now stop. Stop the ironing a bit.
She never stops.
Gaëtan, give granny a drink.
She's already had three, dad!
So?
She's been off the road for years!
I thought you'd put her
in a nursing home?
Yes, but the apartment
cost us a lot...
It wasn't that.
We didn't have the heart
to leave her there.
She's happy with her new TV.
Eh, mum?
The flat screen!
Shut your trap!
Can I come in?
I acted like a shit.
No, you're like everyone else.
I don't know what got into me.
I completely lost it.
Harmony had just dumped me.
Yes, I know,
it was on the cards but...
Shit!
I never thought
it would hurt so much.
Poor old Etienne.
Yes,
that sums it up.
They took me for a ride.
They found out and they set me up.
They're bastards.
And all those poor people
who think I'm their saviour.
The restaurant deal is tomorrow.
It was never meant for us.
Eternal losers, huh?
Is it the 17th today?
Yes.
So tomorrow is the 18th?
Yes. And the day after is the 19th.
We may have a card to play.
I'm listening.
Tomorrow morning,
Berthin-Schwartz Bank
are buying a truck company,
Lebrun Transports.
Big deal. So what?
We can stop them.
No kidding!
I don't give a shit.
My wife's leaving me,
her dad's had a heart attack,
the cops are onto me.
Your fucking bank
can buy the Eiffel Tower!
Now gentlemen, if you don't mind...
Hold it.
Go on.
To carry off the deal,
the bank needs 95% of the shares.
So they can eliminate
any tricky small shareholders.
But with under 95%,
they'll have to negotiate.
And we'll raise the stakes.
Get it?
Yes.
No.
Imagine this:
a property developer wants to buy
a group of plots to build on.
But he can't buy one tiny plot.
The owner raises the price.
What can he do?
It's a nightmare.
He has to buy it, at any price.
Right?
otherwise everything
he's bought is worthless.
I see. It's blackmail.
If you like.
But the bankers who do it
dine at the Grand Véfour.
You want to buy
5% of Lebrun Transports?
No, 5.1% to be exact.
5.1% by...
That's 40 800 shares at 75€.
It'll cost you 3 million euros.
Three million sixty thousand.
Three million euros?
Can I ask you something,
just curious?
Where will you find the money?
In your bank.
Sure.
Excuse me, I'm going to vomit.
Is that your plan?
We only need it for a few hours.
Who do you think I am?
Think I can just press a buzzer
and get you 3 million euros?
Not one buzzer.
Lots of buzzers.
Vincent Lambert. Borealis Life:
92 000, transferred.
Borealis Life: 92 000, transferred.
If we fuck up,
I can forget my pension.
If we pull it off
you can forget your pension too.
Savings account: 63 761...
63 000. Transferred.
Here's a big one!
Pierre Leyssieux.
Securities account: 175 253€.
The lot: savings plan,
current account, life insurance...
Pierre Leyssieux: 175 253,
175 000. Transferred.
Jim Jarvis...
2 900...
No, 29 000, sorry, transferred...
Right.
Xavier Navarre...
6 542...
6 000...
Transferred.
Shit!
What are you doing? Get up!
Am I late?
No, I'm very early.
Clients already?
Clients?
Yes! They're early
so we won't be disturbed.
Very important clients.
I understand.
By the way,
our computers are down.
Another virus.
It's not true!
I'll call maintenance.
No! Don't! I have already.
They're on their way.
- Mr Tomasini?
- Yes?
Your tie!
Did she swallow it?
We have such crap computers,
they crash all the time.
Not today, I hope.
Ready?
I hope you don't have weak hearts.
Nice one!
Now the stocks.
I wonder how Lebrun will take
the south zone development plan.
Is his area as big as that?
All those trucks need space.
Plus the warehouses,
the workshops...
It's a great opportunity.
A problem, sir.
Unexpected stock movement.
What did you say?
How much?
We're still calculating it:
about 6%.
For you, sir.
It seems important.
Move, Alban!
Find out about it.
Mr d'Espinasse?
Hold on.
It's out in the open.
We can meet if you like,
but I haven't much time.
Very well.
It's odd. I know that voice.
Well?
5.1% precisely, sir.
In 3 hours time
the alarm will warn head office,
maintenance will arrive,
I'll have 4000 Lebrun shares
and 150 clients demanding their money!
We only have till 13.00.
No, till 12.00. I need an hour
to repatriate the money.
And if they want a delay?
Why should they?
But...
What's the time?
10 o'clock.
No, 10.01.
Call me at 11.30, right?
Me? What shall I say?
Nothing. I'll do the talking.
oK?
Let's go!
Right. 11.30?
on the dot.
Him...
How did he raise all that money?
His racket may have gone on
for years.
Who knows how much he's made?
Then he must know everything
about our...
our activities.
Let him sweat it out.
We must look into this more closely.
Nice to see you, Mr Julien.
Thank you, Jérôme.
- Are you coming back?
- No.
I have other plans.
Has my money transfer come through?
I'm afraid I can't say,
our computers have crashed.
What am I going to do?
I need that money.
Come back later.
I'm very sorry.
Yes, Rue Legrand here.
Where are you?
We need you.
But we called you
as soon as we opened!
I'm telling you!
Hurry up! Get over here!
What a lazy lot!
Back amongst us?
Wasn't the last time enough for you?
My father always said:
after a fall get back in the saddle.
Who are you working for?
A private consortium,
that's all I can say.
What makes you think
we'll do business with you?
Scrupulus.
What?
You know, the tiny pebble
that can hold up a whole army.
You don't have the choice.
If you refuse
your property scam will collapse
like a house of cards.
Julien my boy, I underestimated you.
You're rather subtle...
for a flunkey.
You have half an hour.
Is this a joke?
I'll need a discharge
from my partners.
You'll have our answer in a week.
Impossible.
I have another offer.
May l?
Who?
An old victim of yours
happy to strike a deal.
It will cost you more with him,
of course. A lot more.
That takes the biscuit!
He must be getting impatient.
Etienne?
What are you doing here?
I'm signing on.
I passed my exam.
That's great!
With double As.
How about a kiss?
Yes, sure.
You look well.
You look a bit peaky.
oh yeah?
I'm just going to bed.
oK. Having a good time, eh?
No, it's not that at all...
You're even prettier than...
You look wonderful!
Fancy a coffee?
You're on!
It's lovely to see you.
I often thought about you.
- I was worried.
- Really?
- Yes.
- That's sweet.
Bravo, Julien. You learn fast.
I trained at the top.
17 years in the Holy of Holies.
17 years...
My family have been rich
for 200 years,
it gives me a bit of distance.
You know what differentiates us
from people like you?
What are "people like me"?
Moneygrubbers.
Who believe 100 million euros
will change their lives.
People like me know
it won't change a thing.
It will just help us make 200.
Interesting.
You have one minute left.
Here's what I think, Julien.
You're bluffing.
And you bluff badly.
You don't have another buyer
or a private consortium.
No backers would risk
buying your stock.
Unlike you, our rivals know
what they're up against with us.
Soon you'll beg us
to buy your stock.
You can go.
Very good.
As you like.
Hello?
It's me.
I was just talking about you.
Yes, my offer still stands.
What?
Let's say in half an hour?
Your office?
I'm on my way.
Asshole!
You know what you're into.
Mr Foucault!
You're in a hurry!
Could you spare us a minute?
Something tells me
you won't regret it.
That's tiresome, I've just...
Julien!
In memory of the good old days?
Two electronic transfers:
the stocks and the bonus.
Right!
I'll check immediately.
Hello?
Mr Lebrun, please.
I must go.
Shit! oh no...
What's wrong?
I have to make a call.
Keep in touch? Promise?
I promise.
Julien?
I'm sorry, I fucked up.
Mr Martinez?
All the accounts are down to zero.
Whatever's going on,
knowing you it must be lucrative.
It's not what you think.
I'll pay every penny back right now.
Don't imagine for a second
that I'll cover it.
No one will ever know,
please Mr Martinez...
Stop!
You haven't understood, Gilbert.
I'm not with the bank now.
All I care about
is...
how much will I get
out of your little scam?
18 million!
For that little fucker!
Yes?
Mr Lebrun is downstairs.
Send him up.
He'd rather you came down.
He insists.
Good God.
He better not drop dead
before we sign.
I have some good news.
one: I'm not selling.
What?
Impossible! It was agreed...
That you handle transport,
not real estate speculation.
Yes, d'Espinasse, walls have ears.
Don't look so glum.
You've just invested
in a solid company.
And two: my health is much better.
I'm delighted.
Let's go, Pierre.
What did he mean: walls have ears?
That the little waiter
fucked us over nicely.
Not too wet?
Sorry? Wet with what?
Bloody idiot!
76 000. Transferred.
Vincent Lambert.
Borealis Life: 92 000.
92 000. Transferred.
Shit!
Not them!
Did you call them?
I'll deal with it.
My friends.
Heard the news?
I've been fired.
- You too?
- No, not you!
Stuff their Multimoney.
I'm taking up fishing again.
I suggest Saint-Rémy-lès-Chevreuse.
Yes? I know it well.
But I may have an opening
in Polynesia.
Let's drink to it.
I insist!
Come on.
once it's been sorted, yes...
Gentlemen!
over to you.
Did you have enough time?
180 000€ is out there somewhere.
180 000?
That's 1% loss. Very reasonable.
What's in that suitcase?
I hope you won't be arrested.
Don't worry, darling.
It's your father's money.
I'm returning it. No more scams.
You're right.
Money doesn't mean happiness.
I'm as fit as a fiddle.
I'll play tennis again this autumn.
Remember what Dr Caumartin said.
Marguerite's right, honey.
You want to find yourself
a new partner!
Anyway, I have to say
that the money you gave me...
Enough! Say no more.
No, I insist.
I must give it back to you...
It's lost! Gone!
It's only money.
There's a positive side
to this heart attack:
it's shown me what really matters.
No, Antoine...
Time to go, darling.
We mustn't tire daddy out.
We should open for Sunday lunch.
I can do a family menu for locals.
What d'you think?
I think it's dead.
Why?
I've called her three times,
she doesn't answer.
You idiot. You had me worried.
Stéphanie? It's Julien.
Stéphanie?
often sleep under the stars?
It depends on the star.
Good news!
Your transfer has arrived.
I told you!
It's from my son.
You shouldn't let
such a large sum lie idle.
Transfer received
You've heard about Multimoney?
Madame?
Madame Laffont!
Are you alright?
Yes. I'm fine.
Subtitles: jahattt