Buster Keaton in "Battling Butler"
Directed by Buster Keaton
"Alfred, your father thinks
a hunting and fishing trip -
- in the mountains might
do you a lot of good."
"Yes - get a camping outfit -- go out
and rough it. Maybe it will make -
- a man out of you if you have to
take care of yourself for a while."
"Arrange it."
And so Alfred went out to rough it,
leaving the city behind -
- there was no other place to leave it.
"There doesn't seem to be
a thing here to shoot."
"Isn't she pretty?"
"This is my papa and brother."
"Have you any more brothers or fathers?"
CHAMPION BIG FAVORITE
OVER BATTLING BUTLER
ALFRED "BATTLING" BUTLER
New Arena Will Open Monday -
- Large Crowd Expected,
Every Ticket Has...
"Some prize fighter has
taken your name, sir."
"Arrange to stop it."
Advice to the Lovesick
by Beatrice Faircatch -
- H.H.R. - I have outlined the following
proposal, with the answers...
"I'd like to marry that
pretty little mountain girl."
"Shall I arrange it?"
"Mr. Butler would like to marry you."
"That jellyfish couldn't take care
of himself -- let alone a wife."
"We don't want any
weaklings in our family."
"Weakling!
You don't know who he is."
CHAMPION BIG FAVORITE
OVER BATTLING BUTLER
MR. ALFRED BUTLER
ALFRED "BATTLING" BUTLER
New Arena Will Open Monday...
"What's he doing here - training?"
Advice to the Lovesick
by Beatrice Faircatch -
- H.H.R. - I have outlined the following
proposal, with the answers you may expect:
He - "Do you think you could learn to love me?"
She- "Why - what do you mean?"
He - "I'm crazy about you."
She- "This is so sudden."
He - "You're the only girl I ever loved."
She- "Give me time to think."
He - "No, I must know now."
She- "Have you ever proposed to any other girl?"
He - "Don't you care for me just a little?"
She- "I don't know."
He - "It means everything to me."
She- "What will father say?"
He - "Will you marry me?"
She- "Do you really mean it?"
He - "Yes."   She- "Yes."
Then use your own Judgment.
"Do you think you could learn to love me?"
"I have."
"When are you going to fight again?"
"When I'm drafted."
"I mean, who do you fight next?"
"Yes."
"Sir, it's time to take your liniment."
"These people will never know
the difference - the champion -
- will win and no one will ever
hear of Battling Butler again."
"If you're going to fight tomorrow
you'll have to hurry to catch the train."
"Arrange the train."
"In this corner we have Battling Butler."
Butler's trainer and manager.
"- the Lightweight Champion."
"The Alabama Murderer
challenges the winner."
"I'm champion."
"That means you cannot go
back to the mountains, sir."
"You're wrong, I'm going back and tell her
the truth. I'd rather lose her that way."
WELCOME BATTLING BUTLER
World's Lightweight Champion
BATTLING BUTLER TO FIGHT ALABAMA MURDERER
New Champ to Defend Title Thanksgiving -
Starts Training at Silver Hot Springs tomorrow
"That means you have to leave right away."
"Arrange it."
"I'll hurry and pack my things."
"I'm sorry, but you can't go."
"I want you to know me as I
am -- not as the brutal, -
- blood-thirsty beast that
I am when fighting."
"Promise me you will never come near
the training camp or to see me fight."
"Where do we go from here?"
"We'd better go to Butler's
training camp, sir, -
- so that you can answer
her letters from there."
SILVER HOT SPRINGS
Hotel Register
Alfred Battling Butler & Wife.
NO ADMITTANCE
"Drive carefully. These country folks
may not be used to city speed."
Alfred Battling Butler & Wife.
Alfred Butler and Man.
NO ADMITTANCE
"How's your heel?"
"He's all right."
"Let's go out for a little road work."
Eight miles later.
"I'm glad you came to see me --
now you must go right back home."
"I won't go home! I'm going to stay
right here and help you train."
"Compliments of Mr. Butler."
"That woman says she's
married to you, too."
"-- so you see, sir, it would wreck
his home if she knew the truth. -
- Won't you be a good
fellow and fix it for him."
"My dear, we are not the only
Butlers here. This is -
- the Lightweight Champion, Mr.
Battling Butler, and his wife."
"Don't forget your date Thanksgiving."
"What date?"
"With the Alabama Murderer."
"If he wants to be Battling Butler
let him fight the Alabama Murderer, -
- and he'll never flirt
with anybody else's wife."
"I'm through - get him in
shape the best you can."
"Don't you think it advisable,
sir, to give this up?"
"No, Martin, I'd rather be killed by the
Alabama Murderer than have her know."
"Put up your hands."
By dinner time the only thing Alfred
had on his mind was his stomach.
And so for three weeks Alfred trained
and starved and suffered and ached -
- and bled and groaned and hoped and
prayed and - and then came the storm.
OLYMPIC Auditorium
THANKSGIVING NIGHT NOV. 26, 1925
CHAMPIONSHIP BOUT
BATTLING BUTLER vs. ALABAMA MURDERER
15 ROUNDS
"I persuaded her to stay at the hotel
- so she won't see you fight."
"I thought it best to prepare
for the worst, sir."
"See that she gets a good seat."
"I hope you win -- father and brother wrote
that they've bet all their money on you."
"Butler!"
"BUTLER!"
"That was Battling Butler - he fought!"
"You didn't think we'd throw away a
championship just to get even with you."
"Thanks - for saving me."
"I've been saving you for three weeks."
"That was Battling Butler."
"I lied to you -- I'm not even a fighter."
"I'm glad."
THE END
Subtitle by Reza Fa
V. 2