"THE BEAUTY AND THE BEAST"
- "Once upon a time there was a rich merchant,
"a kind and brave man,
"who, after the death of his beloved wife,
"lived only for the happiness of his six children.
"Three girls and three boys.
"They filled their home with their laughter and their bickering.
Oh, I think we have a guest.
- She also wants to listen to the story.
- We are going to make a wish, but it has to be in silence,
otherwise, it won’t come true.
Have you made your wish?
- Yes!
Then, one, two, three
Okay ! Do you want to listen to the rest
of the story?
Yes!
- "The merchant owned three ships, which
were the source of his fortune and pride.
"Their names were :
The Mermaid, The Triton,
"and the biggest one was The Leviathan.
"Their cargo was full of wonders as
they were coming back from their journey,
"when all of a sudden,
a storm broke out.
"The ships were swept
by huge waves,
"both the sails and the masts
were struck by lightning.
"On the surface, where the cold
and the silence reigned,
"the ocean sparkled
brilliantly.
"The armada and the treasures
sunk to the bottom of the sea,
"devoured, forever lost.
"Ruined in one month,
"The merchant and his children
decided to leave their house,
"their friends, their habits,
"everything that, until that moment,
made their happiness.
- I forbid you
to take that!
Go on, take it then!
The most precious things,
we will take with us.
Put that down immediately
or I will gouge your eyes out!
Daddy,
do something!
Evertyhing! Our jewels,
our beds. They have taken everything!
It’s the end, I want to die.
Clotilde, please,
don’t call me Daddy in front of these men.
And you, Anne,
stop talking about death.
Oh! Oh, my heart
is not beating anymore!
Are you happy now?
Bye!
Look Daddy, it’s a catastrophe!
What would become of us now?
Where is Belle?
Belle, Belle!
Everything is always about her.
- Wake up.
Maxime, come and help us.
There. What do you have in here?
All my books.
My notebooks, my sketchs,
I wasn’t just going to leave them here.
Tristan.
What is it?
Take good care of your father.
Don’t let Maxime waste
the little money you still have left.
Of course, don’t worry. I promise.
Everything is going to be fine.
Pay attention.
I want to punch
all those who laugh at us.
Ignore them!
So, tell me,
do you want to have some action
before we bury ourself in the countryside?
It’s not a bad idea for you to disappear
for a while, you know!
Don’t you think so?
Belle?
Here you have, mom.
It’s a new life
that is about to start.
I believe I am ready for it.
Do you think she would have loved
living in the countryside ?
She would have loved it.
- Me too, I’m going to love it.
I am sure of that.
It’s obvious! We are proud and
courageous in this family.
We are going to support each other
as we always have.
"They needed some time
"to get used to their new life.
"The first nights,
Belle stayed awake in her room
listening to the noises of the countryside”
"Then, aided by her brothers,
she decided to fix the garden.
She turned their home into a beautiful haven”
I have a fever.
I have a wrinkle!
And these bugs are pissing me off!
It’s been a month since we started
living in this hell.
We are going to die alone, wrinkled,
devoured by the beasts.
- Anne, Clotilde, come down.
Oh, not her!
Her happiness disgusts me.
I want to drown her in a well.
And me, I want to bury her alive in
her garden.
- What are you doing?
Clotilde is not feeling well so
we will have breakfast in bed.
You will certainly not!
And after breakfast,
we will all take care of the garden.
I would rather die instead.
Let’s go!
Everyone, downstairs now!
- "Defeated,
"pierced by arrows,
"the young man left
the battefield
"and took shelter in the forest."
Oh, oh!
Hou, hou!
Ah, we could say everyone at the Maritime Affairs
were happy to see me.
Dumont was charming.
It seems his eldest daughter
has married a count.
What?
Ah No!
But the biggest news
is that The Mermaid,
your mother’s favorite ship,
has been found.
They founf it drifting on the shoreline
and they brought it to the port.
And the merchandise?
Undamaged!
My children, I think we are saved.
Let’s get our suitcases ready.
Better not.
We will throw everything to the fire.
Blood is pumping through my body.
I come back to life, Daddy.
I have been reborn.
- We can’t go back
to the city in our present state.
Of course not, we need new dresees,
perfume, and … what else?
We will make a list
Ah yes. For our happiness in the city!
The city, the real one.
You will come with me to the city.
I think it’s time I introduce
my successor to Dumont.
I will not disappoint you, father.
Thank you!
- "And, after defeating
the last of his enemies,
"the young men returned
to his lands, triumphant,
"acclaimed by his people."
Period.
A new novel, brother?
- Even better.
This one will be a master piece.
What are you up to?
Are you sulking?
Obviously.
When a girl is sad,
people say she is sulking.
And when she is joyful,
people say she is crazy
How do you want us to understand you?
Everyone is happy but you.
I would have loved
to stay here longer.
That is all!
He is there.
We came to live here
to hide our misfourtune.
We don’t belong here.
You know, as well as I do,
what is going to happen.
Maxime will meet again with
those thugs he calls friends.
Anne and Clotilde will go out every afternoon
in hopes of finding a husband.
And you, you will always
be busy with work.
Belle, one day or another, we will
all follow different paths.
Even you, you will grow
and will want to leave.
But that doesn’t mean
we will stop loving each other;
it will just mean you’ve become a woman.
Above all, don’t forget anything.
Clotilde wouldn’t take it well.
And you, what should I bring you?
I would like just a rose.
I could never make them
grow here.
- They have taken everything from me!
They wouldn’t even allow me
to board my own ship.
You must have a reason to do so.
The Mermaid and its cargo
don’t belong to you anymore.
They treat me as if I were
less than nothing,
But without me, this place would
still be just another port of fishermen.
And you just let them do this to me?
You lacked common sense,
my poor friend.
You signed all the
debt letters,
when I had already warned you.
Do not look down on me, Dumont.
Without me, you wouldn’t
be sitting behind that desk.
Have you also lost your elegance,
alongside your fortune?
I’m going to crack you skull open!
Stop that inmediately!
Do you not understand?
You no longer have any power.
You pretend you are rich,
but you are a nobody now.
I pity you, father!
Maxime!
- I see a man.
You don’t have to let him get away.
He brings important news.
- News? Good and bad ones?
You know very well that it depends
on the other cards.
Are you not in the mood
of pleasing me, Astrid?
Predict something
exciting for me!
- I am like the cards, love,
I can’t lie to you.
Did I not warn you
about your scar?
A torrent of gold
under an emerald moon.
Fate smiles upon you.
Gold?
Emeralds?
Cheer up, my lousy friends!
Haven’t I told you
we were going to become rich?
Damn night.
I can feel the dust.
What will you drink?
I’m looking for my son.
I know he comes here often.
A regular customer of this slum?
Then I feel sorry for you.
What is your son’s name?
Maxime de Beauffremont.
You should have spoken lower.
I’m going to have to ask you to leave
through the backdoor.
I need to find my son.
Ah, you are not the only one!
Come behind the counter. Go!
Your scent,
your predictions,
you have too much power over me.
Monsieur de Beauffremont.
It’s been months since
I have been looking for Maxime.
And I ran into his old father.
I don’t know you.
You are...?
Perducas.
At your service.
Your son ows me
a large sum of money.
so, you and me, we are going
to settle this.
And everything will be forgiven.
My son doesn’t hang out with scoundrels.
Serve them a drink,
so that they leave me alone !
He thinks we are beggars.
- You can’t do this here, Perducas.
You know it.
Let the good man alone.
Okay.
Move back. And you,
come behind the counter now.
Come on, let’s go.
You should keep your courage,
because now he won’t let it go.
Go away. Now!
- "On his way back,
“the merchant fought against the wind,
the cold and the sadness.
"He had escaped the city without Maxime.
"He imagined him wandering
through the dregs of society or worst,
“dumped in an alley, lifeless.
“He pulled the reins of his horse,
“expecting to come back
home sonner,
"where his son would be waiting for him."
I don’t even have a weapon
to finish you off
Forgive me.
The house!
I found it!
No, this is not the house.
Is there somebody here?
I am lost.
And it was open.
Who is there?
I must be dreaming...
or I died and
I am in paradise.
No, I am certain I am alive.
And I am hungry.
I’m going to take some things
from the table.
Eh?
Scoundrel!
The dresses,
the shawls,
the make-up.
Incredible! Everything is here.
Well, almost everything.
But, who took care of your wound?
Aren’t my gifts enough for you?
You have to also steal that which is
most sacred for me?
I would not let anybody
treat me as a thief or a coward.
I am a righteous and virtuous man.
-For whom have you picked this rose?
It is for the youngest of my daughters.
She is my most precious
thing in the world.
Then, I give you one day
to say goodbye to those you love.
You will just have to whisper:
"More than anything in the world"
in the ear of your horse
so that he brings you to me.
I will not come back.
Oh yes, you will come back.
Otherwise, I will kill
all the members of your family
one after another
I will leave the youngest of your daughters
for last because she is your favorite
Remember,
a life
for a rose.
- There !
- Yeah, it’s him!
- There, I see him.
- Father!
Father!
This story about a beast and a rose
makes no sense.
-Then, how do you explain this?
You can see it is real.
"More than anything in the world."
And your horse is supposed to find the road
to this castle magically?
It’s our fault.
Everything is our fault.
It is not for you he picked up that flower.
It is not anyone’s fault!
Shut up!
I can not explain to you
who that beast is.
But, for having stolen this rose,
I must come back there
in a few hours.
What is he going to do to you?
- I don’t know, Tristan.
He said : "A life for a rose."
- And if you don’t do what he asks of you?
Then we will all die.
Don’t say anything.
I know what everyone thinks.
They all think mom died
giving birth to me.
I don’t know what you are
talking about.
I will not be responsible
for your death too.
- Belle! Belle!
Belle!
Don’t forget to love me!
- Belle! Belle! Belle!
Belle!
Belle.
No, father.
Guide me to the castle,
and take me to that beast.
“More than anything in the world”.
- A life for a rose.
- "Belle was already ready to die
"when the first bells rang.
"As she started discovering
the castle of the Beast,
"a noise, stronger,
headier than the bell,
"resonated in her whole being:
"her heartbeats."
My name is Belle.
I came here to exchange my life
for that of my father.
Sit down.
Eat.
When you have regained your strength,
you will be able to go for a walk
wherever you like in my properties.
But, at night,
I forbid you to leave the castle.
If I should die,
I prefer to die right now.
- You are more courageous than
your father.
Every evening,
at this same hour,
You must be here.
Do not think about running away.
The forest will close in on you.
Do you want me to stop?
- No, I want to hear the rest.
What makes me sad
is that she is all alone,
the poor little thing.
It’s true.
She felt really lonely.
“As she went up
the enormous staircase,
"Belle realized than no even once,
"in her entire life,
"had she spent one night
away from her loved ones.
"But, what she didn’t know
"was that in her room,
the Tadums were waiting for her,
"small creatures
that inhabited the castle,
"who would become
her best friends.”
- Sleep.
Dream.
Come.
Get me closer to the mirror where
nothing ever fades.
Come.
The source of memories.
Here they come ! They will shout, they will be dirty and
excited. They piss me off already!
The one who will conquer your heart
may be among them.
Then I will give him hell.
Here they are !
I always knew you were unfaithful to me.
Now, I’m going to eat you.
Get your dirty hands off her.
- Yes, my friend.
No doe, no reward.
You still haven’t given up?
For years it has eluded me,
but I will have it. I can feel it.
It will be my most beautiful trophy...
besides you of course.
Look what they gave to him.
All golden,
like the fur of that doe.
Let’s go!
I am thirsty.
We need to drink.
Come.
He could have stayed home with me.
I’ve had enough.
You stink of sweat.
My love,
I want to ask something of you.
Something of me?
I want you to give up on that doe!
But why?
I am tired of you leaving
for days and days to hunt it.
I feel terribly lonely in here
without you.
Okay.
But I have one condition.
Give me a son.
- "Belle hesitated for a long time before
deciding to leave her room,
"because she feared the Beast
will appear out of a dark corner.
"But her curiosity
was stronger than her fear.
"She wanted to explore the surroundings,
"to see the immensity of her prison.
The princess!
- "Then Belle understood
that years,
"or centuries ago,
another woman had lived,
"had known love and had died
"in that cursed castle.
"Why me?",
She sadly asked the statue.
"Why do you trouble my sleep at night?"
"Filled with melancholy,
"Belle ran to his room,
seeking sanctuary,
"waiting for the bells to announce
her daily meeting
"with her strange prison guard.”
You are late.
Do you like your new dress?
Don’t ever come to
my room again.
- Do I need to remind you
that I have every right to do so?
We will see about that.
Don’t look at me.
Eat.
Aren’t you going to eat too?
- No, not in front of you.
Can I talk or should I eat my dinner
in silence, like a child?
- Yet, that is what you are,
an arrogant child.
I like people to think I am
childish and futile…
And you talk too much!
I know you are pleased that
I furnish the emptiness of
this castle.
Who owns this castle?
- Everything here belongs to me.
You talk
like an ordinary man.
It’s very disappointing.
Do I really disappoint you that much?
Is there something else
about me that displeases you?
Why are you talking anymore?
Day and night, I wait for
you to decide my fate.
You play with me as if I were a mouse
between your paws.
If you accept to surrender yourself to me,
I could fulfill all your wishes.
Do you really think
a beast like you
could satisfy
a woman like me?
Lower your eyes.
Lower your eyes!
I know what I am.
Resist me all you want.
You will be mine.
"Eat, don’t look at me.
"Do this, don’t do that."
I will show that animal
some manners.
What is this?
Ah, but it’s me!
It’s the spitting image of me.
What a wonderful gift.
I wonder who could have
made this beautiful doll?
Where are you hiding?
Show yourself to me.
I’m not going to eat you.
I will leave it here.
Like this, il will always be close to me.
- Hapy days
that erase the past.
Dream.
Listen to our song
that leads to the mirror.
Look at the fiancé who became
an animal.
Dream, dream.
My friends,
today is a great day.
Our kingdom
Will finally have an heir.
What about you, my lady?
What would you say about
me making you a little heir?
- First, you would need
to have a kingdom.
Let’s pray to the heavens
that he wouldn’t get your brains.
What are you thinking about?
The first time I met you,
in the river.
You got close to the shoreline
and started undressing.
You were drowning.
I swin better than you.
What if we come back
to our bedroom?
And you, don’t you dare forget about your promise!
Which one?
The golden doe.
Let love blossom.
Dream, dream.
Dream.
We are the fireflies.
- "After waking up,
Belle went to explore the castle,
"determined to discover
the misteries of the Beast.
"She got lost in a laberynth
of corridors and run down footbridges.
"She always had the strange
feeling of being followed.
I ask you to forgive me
about last night.
You were right.
You fill an unbearable void.
Do you like my gifts?
Why don’t you answer?
I miss my family.
- Forget about them.
They no longer exist for you.
Maybe not thinking about the
past is easy for you.
But I haven’t given it up yet.
What do you know about me? Nothing!
Nothing.
You are right.
I propose a deal.
A few hours with my family...
- In exchange of what?
A dance.
In exchange,
you will let me see them.
You are giving me scraps of your attention.
- I will lead you
if this scares you that much.
Dancing with me doesn’t scare you?
Let yourself go.
Do you want to love me?
We had a deal.
Keep your promise.
It’s been a long time
since I promised anything to anyone.
You dress in the jewels of a prince.
You think you are a man.
But you are nothing
more than a cruel and lonely beast.
You can try it all: you can even blackmail me,
but I won’t stop being disgusted by you.
Now,
you know what I am.
Tell me again that
you are disgusted by me.
Say it to me.
I give you permission to see
your family one last time.
For real?
Are you sure you aren’t just saying
this to torture me?
I give you one day.
Nothing more than that.
You will leave at dawn.
Give me your hand.
Which one?
I don’t know.
It doesn’t matter, the left one.
Don’t tell me you’re you going give me a ring?
Just shut up.
Listen to me.
You know
the powers of this water.
If you ever hurt yourself...
if anything happens to you…
Nothing will happen to me.
I need to get ready.
Belle.
If you don’t come back...
I know, you will kill us all.
No.
I will die.
I will come back here,
at seven.
- Who is there?
I warn you, we are armed.
Belle.
Look at this mess.
What are you doing with these weapons?
Ask Maxime.
Shut up.
Go back to your position!
"Go back to your position?"
Yes.
You think you are a general? Idiot.
- Enough, enough.
Don’t start again.
Stop defending him.
Your drink wine all day, that scared are you?
Who is scared, ah?!
Enough, enough!
What is happening here?
Have you all gone crazy?
Come. Let’s go upstairs.
It’s going to be fine. Don’t worry.
Being sold as slaves to pay for Maxime’s
debts is out of the question.
They are going to get us on bord of a ship
full of sweaty sailors.
Oh! And will they force us
to clean the holds?
No.
We are going to tell them we suffer from seasickness
and we can’t do housework.
Oh yes.
- Anne?
Clotilde?
I have come back.
- Clotilde,
do you see what I see?
It’s Belle’s ghost
that has come back to haunt us,
all read and bloody.
You are not dreaming,
my beloved sisters.
It’s really me.
I have come to say
goodbye to you.
Even in death, she is prettier than us.
Look, that dress makes her look so elegant.
Know that I will always love you.
So will we, my little sister.
We think about you all the time.
But it was her who forced me
to take your bedroom.
I knew it!
I am going to take my revenge.
Where is dad?
He has been so depressed after you left,
that he doesn’t even want to get off the bed.
What was that dress?
- Dad?
It’s me,
Belle.
I am here.
Come back to life, beloved father.
Do it for me.
Dad!
Have you ever seen a jewel this big?
Do you remember the chest father brought from the castle?
Ah no, not that, I forbid it.
It’s our only chance, Tristan.
While I live,
you will not go through this door.
- Sleep.
Sleep.
Dream.
Mystery.
- Do you see me?
Come, come.
- Listen to me.
Look,
its flanks tremble,
its fur glows.
I can almost feel its scent.
Its time has arrived.
It belongs to me, understood?
Quiet.
I am the nymph of the forest.
I was granted the wish
to take human form.
I wanted to know
what men called love.
And then I met you,
my prince.
Forgive me,
father.
God of the forest.
Spare by beloved.
He filled your daughter
with eternal love.
Father.
Spare him.
- "A terrifying voice
resonated in the sky.
"For having killed my daughter,
I turn you into a beast.
"Only a woman
can save you,
"but what woman
would want to love you?
"I curse you for all eternity."
You are betraying Belle.
I am saving us.
She will understand.
You would have preferred
to have another brother, wouldn’t you?
What are you doing here,
my little rabbit?
Weren’t we going to meet in your shack?
Look!
My men got all dolled up
to meet your sister.
I want to propose you a deal.
I don’t want to have a deal with you.
I was very patient.
Look.
This comes from an abandoned castle.
If I take you there,
you can take the rest of the treasure
and then you can erase my debt.
And jewels like these,
How many of them are there?
There are chests full of them.
- Don’t let me down, my little rabit.
It’s your last chance.
You know it.
Tell your men to follow me.
Do as he says.
“More than anything in the world”
"As he rushed
through the magical road,
"Perducas started dreaming about
the treasure that awaited him.
"He cursed his men,
"because he thought of having
to share his spoils with them.
"He looked at Astrid and wondered
whether he preferred love or wealth.
"Sometimes,
the souls of men become troubled.
"All their beliefs disappear
"and they no longer have any doubts.
"Meanwhile,
"Belle relived the story
ff the prince who became a beast,
"until the moment when she felt
a heartbreaking complaint.
Dad.
My child.
I really missed you.
- Belle!
Father?
Oh, my God!
Anne! Clotilde!
Father is awake.
Anne, Clotilde, come quick!
I was so afraid.
- Come quick!
Something has changed in you.
Your eyes...
also your voice...
I must leave again, father.
I must return there.
Look at all the dead coming back to life!
It’s the most beautiful day of my life.
You are crushing me, silly.
Oh.
Do you feel something?
Danger.
I feel it, it’s everywhere.
All that we love, eh?
Let’s go.
You three, you will go west.
The rest, you go east.
And you, my little rabbits,
you will walk before me.
- Céleste Astrid.
Enough fear...
Enough blood...
with all your strength...
save your lover...
Save yourself.
You owe it to him.
So faithful.
Unless you want to suffer an eternal agony,
Take the gold in your hands, Astrid.
Take the gold, Astrid.
Save him if you can.
Take the gold in your hands.
Where are my brothers?
I must hurry.
Maxime also took your horse.
I tried to stop them, but…
Forgive me, Belle.
-	Quick, quick!
I don’t like it
when you are away from me.
Where were you?
If I tell you to leave right now,
would you follow me?
Is that gold?
- This arrows has a great power.
I feel we can have more
than than this treasure with it.
We will be respected.
We will be above everything.
Open your eyes.
We have finally found
that which we always looked for.
Stop.
Who assures me that you won’t
come back later to steal my treasure?
If you no longer believe in me,
at least listen to the prophecy of the cards.
What have you seen?
Death.
Yours?
Or mine?
What do you prefer?
None, my love.
And because you are not sure,
Let’s say it’s his.
There, let’s say
is that guy who will die tonight.
So?
That door will not open
by itself,
An abandoned castle?
Buck up, my rogues.
There are more floors to visit.
- YES!
We need to find a road.
I lost these bindings when I came here.
We are not far,
I am sure.
Belle, what are you doing?
Belle, stop. You will hurt yourself.
Come back.
Come back, Belle.
Belle, please, come back.
Belle!
God of the forest,
listen to me.
Let me come back to him.
It’s my only wish.
My only desire.
You were wrong.
No one was waiting for us.
Don’t spoil the fun.
Now, I am rich.
I can grant you all your wishes.
My wish of us dying together?
Your cards no longer call the shots.
It’s me.
Why does he squeal like that?
Where are my brothers?
There, they are with Perducas.
He is going to kill them!
Maxime!
Save yourself.
Ask Belle to forgive me.
No.
Quick, let’s go!
You will ask her yourself.
Stop!
You, my little one, you are going to help me.
Let her go.
What are you?
A lion?
A big cat?
Yes, and I will drain you of your blood.
You can purr
all you want,
but if you don’t want
me to crack your doll,
let me go.
I beg you!
Remember
you were once a man.
Spare this vermin
and let my brothers go.
The important thing is that I am here,
that I am with you.
Help me!
Quick! Quick!
- Don’t leave me!
My love,
you fate will be worst than mine.
Come and help me!
Hurry!
Into the pond, quick.
Go!
He is not breathing anymore.
Don’t worry about us.
Let’s go, my brothers!
We missed our dinner.
You say that
as if you regretted it.
Belle,
Do you think that with...
a little bit of patience,
or maybe by habit,
you would have come
to love me?
But I already love you.
-Okay, this story has ended.
It’s time to sleep.
Go, go.
And the brothers and sisters,
what happened to them?
- They left for the city.
The brothers opened a printery
to edit books.
And the sisters,
they married twins.
Even they are unable to tell them apart.
Like that,
they will always be together.
And the father?
He opened
a flower shop.
- Him too?
Yes, him too.
Sweet dreams.
Mom...
Sleep, my sweethearts!