Translated By
ll M7md 10 ll
- How's it going, man?
- How you doing, baby?
- What's up?!
- I really appreciate you doing this for me.
This is some serious proposal-ing wedding-type shit you're doing.
Oh, man, Phoebe is gonna love this.
- You're a sensitive nigger, bitch.
- Well, I love her.
- You gotta give it all when you love like that, you know what I mean?
- Want to drop some acid, go inside a titty bar?
No. It's 8:15 in the morning.
Cherry progressive, listen.
Man of red set is in motion.
Echo choir has been breached.
- Was that a lyric from something?
- Fuck.
Hey stop! Stop doing shit to my car!
I just killed two people!
- That's awesome!
- They had guns and knives and they were being like total dicks.
- You called the cops?!
- No, I didn't call the police
because I've got a lot of weed and, like, mushrooms in my car.
How the fuck did this happened?!
I don't know, but I'm like freaking out all over the place.
Babe, I have a lot of anxiety about this.
Oh, fuck!
- I'm sorry.
- Drop it!
Agent Hal has been activated. He killed two operatives with a spoon, sir.
A fucking spoon?!
- We're terminating asset Hal!
- Are you fucking insane?
Oh, language...
Something very weird is happening to me. I keep killing people.
- And there's a chance I may be a robot.
- You are not a robot.
You trying to get into our lives? Huh, huh, Mike, nuh-huh.
This guy is a trained killer!
We made him, he's a security risk.
So you're gonna blow up the town.
Catch!
No!
Help me!
I'm going to save my girlfriend.
Go! Go!
Well, the old frying pan bullet trick.
- We'll take my car and we'll get stoned.
- You want to get high right now?!
Okay.
No, no. I recognize that now is like a faux pas.