Subtitles by EvilAbbot
In Ancient China
China was divided into many small states
Each state invaded the other
Society was in chaos
There were 7 major warring nations vying for power -
Qing, Chu, Han, Zhao, Wei, Qi, and Yan
100 years later
A number of small states were annexed
Han and Zhao were the first and last
to be defeated by Qing respectively
In 227 BC
Troops from Wei marched against Liang
The battle took place at the Phoenix mountains
The 2 armies clashed fiercely
In total 3000 lives were lost
Both armies were annihilated
San Lang!
San Lang...
Guess you're not as lucky as I am
General!
Who are you?
I'm a Liang soldier!
On the great road to my home
at the foot of Mount Liang
5 acres of fertile land
It's rather good
5 acres of fields to farm
Let me tell you something
When I was a kid, I caught
a wild pig but my dad let it go
You know why?
Because the pig was pregnant
Are you pregnant?
You know, you're my slave now
You're not seriously injured
Hmm, you're bleeding a little too much
This medicine is a family recipe
we don't normally share it with outsiders
Does it hurt?
Well, it'll hurt a lot more now
Young man, don't get so worked up
You can't die on me
No cussing please
My father once told me
Scratch if you're itchy, and smile if you're unlucky
Good advice
General
Lieutenant Fu
Yes sir
Stand down
Why are you here?
To pursue and kill the Liang soldiers
How many have you killed?
Say something!
One
I expect my men to be aggressive in battle
Liang troops were aggressive, hard to defend against them
We must be prepared to die for the country at any time
I hope, General, that you remember that I rescued you
You know how we deal with deserters?
General, the army was destroyed last night
I'm still here! It's not destroyed!
We were ambushed last night
Maybe you're the spy?
You are ruthless!
He tried to rescue you, but you killed him!
What do you think you're doing?
He's right, you know
Your army is destroyed
Kill me then
I don't kill slaves
But, if you start begging now
I might even let you go
Kill me!
You really want to die?
Ok, I'll help you
Such a waste
I was not able to defeat the Liang army
You want to die?
I won't let you die even if you wanted to!
Master Wen, this time we've succeeded
He said if he will find peace in death on the battlefield
Your kind of soldiers are deserters
No, I'm the kind of soldier that feigns death
My father once told me that
there is no shame in fearing death
but to die a useless death is humiliating
I pity that soldier, San Lang
I told him to feign death, but he refused
How much am I worth?
There's no harm in telling you
A live enemy General is worth 5 acres
5 whole acres!
I have a piece of jade around my waist
How much is this broken piece of rock worth?
A lot
I accept our introduction gift, General
but I still do not believe you
He's one of ours, and he's still alive!
We were betrayed
Anyone home?
Anyone here?
Men! Bring on the food and drink!
Is that how you nobles say it?
How dare you! Execute him!
There's nothing to eat
General, spare me!
General, show mercy!
There were 2000 infantry and archers in the Liang army
They used 1000 infantry troops to ambush us
Both sides were destroyed
This is the sword I gave him
Where is he?
I believe we will find him
Wu..
If he is alive...
There's a war going on
Where can you take refuge in?
General, have you heard of the Magic Tree?
The Magic Tree at Mount Phoenix?
I hear they are very powerful
Is he your slave?
He is my good-luck charm
Just hold on, we'll be there soon
How many days more?
2 days
Peasant!
Don't force me
Don't force me!
Don't make me angry
Give me some wine
No
Wine!
Has the General fought many battles?
Many. I have survived over a hundred
Cut me loose
Then you must have killed a lot of people
Yes, that will be even more
In the battle yesterday with the Wei, I fought 8 men
Will you please bring me along with you?
I will be your slave too
Alright
I have studied music and I can sing
You drink, I will entertain you
If we find him alive, what then?
Just remember that he is dead
What was that for?
For killing a lot of people, General
I am not a General
My family was probably killed by you too
I was sold here as a singing prostitute
When we were entertaining you
I might even have served you before
Actually I didn't want you to drink
Hey, let's stop fighting
Open the door, I am a Liang soldier!
I've captured a General of the Wei army
Halt
Who is he?
A General of the Wei army
It is definitely him. I'm sure of it!
That head definitely belongs to a Wei General
Reward him!
Hold on
Who killed him?
Me
You're able to kill him?
He must be a deserter! He must have
cut the head off a dead soldier to deceive you!
Execute him!
I'm innocent!
Where's the horse?
Whether you want to kill me or release me
I will kill you at the first opportunity
Kill, kill, kill
I'm just a farmer
I won't kill, and I don't want to kill
If you make me angry
I still won't kill you
I can't believe I was tricked by a girl
I gave her food, and she poisoned me!
You tricked her, and she tricked you back. It's fair
She should have beaten you up!
Wearing this helmet is useless
What did she whisper to you last night?
Peasant!
Between me and him, who's the better fighter?
He is a talented General
Don't I even measure up to him?
You are soft-hearted, he's ruthless
To be King, you must know your enemy's strength
I will bring some men with me and search in
the direction of the Liang state. Will Master....
I will not go back without seeing him!
You know,
I have waited 20 years
Just to farm and not to fight anymore
The carriage is gone. This is cut
Don't feign death. I won't be fooled.
We're too prominent going on the main road
We should go by side roads
I haven't travelled on side roads before
But it's ok. I have my father's map
Liang wine is too strong
A small road also runs straight to my home
Men.... Men!
My father said stepping into bear droppings is good fortune
Ambush
Yeah ok
What's in the cart?
Nothing special
Rob!
I said, rob!
Hold on, who are you?
General
It's true!
Hit him
Hit him!
No!
Don't hit him anymore
Sorry
Please don't hit us anymore
You can take anything you want, just spare our lives
Eh? What do you have?
Only a broken down cart
For revenge!
Quiet!
How is he related to you?
Oh him?
He's my son
I am not his son!
You ungrateful thing!
He's crazy! He wants to go to war!
I tied him up so I can go back to my fields
You're a farmer? Our fields have been destroyed by your war
For revenge!
I will decide! Take the cart!
Unfilial child. Waste of time bringing him up
Are you crazy? What you want the sword for?
Plowing
Plowing? You have a field?
Let's go
They are a bunch of idiots
They don't know you are the most valuable thing here
I am your son!
I must be filial to you
Come, show me
Plowing fields!
Don't move. Don't even breathe...
You tried to strangle me!
If I had not rescued you....
Ungrateful!
I didn't poke yet
My father was right,stepping into
bear droppings brings good luck!
It's good
Please, have mercy on us!
Do not move
I can choose to let him live, or kill him
I have the power
One acre for growing beans, one acre for growing melons
Two acres for growing beans, and two more acres for growing paddy
No, three acres for growing beans
Ok, you tell me. I have 5 acres. What do I plant in them?
I can give you 1,000 acres
1,000 acres is too much
1 acre more, and I can't divide myself among them
Which do you think is better?
Growing paddy or beans?
Grow rice. I like eating rice
Idiot! Paddy is rice, rice is paddy!
Are you very tired?
Are you very comfortable?
Now I'm not tired anymore
5 acres of land.. I'll be so busy!
Right, must remember to buy a cow
Maybe buy 2 - one male, one female
The bull for plowing fields, and the cow for milk
I would like to see how you are
going to bring me into Liang state
Oh yes, I don't know how to milk a cow
I need to marry a wife that does
My eldest brother was very good at fighting
but he was killed in the war
My second brother was the most honest
he also died in the war
I'm the only one left in my family
General, do you have brothers?
As good as none
Hey, what are you doing?
I really cannot find him!
Mount Phoenix is so huge, where do I look?
He is tied up
His father tied him up, said he was crazy
but I think both of them are crazy
I'll be going now...
Avenge me....
I won't make it easy for you to be taken from me
In all the battles, in all the years
I have never seen such a fine arrow, have you?
Yes I have. It belongs to a rival family
All of you have brought it upon yourselves
Do you know why they want to rescue you? So that they can kill you
I captured you, but I want you alive
What your father said was right
A useless death is very humiliating
I will go with you willingly
Even the General is afraid of death
I just want to die with dignity and pride
Which way?
Actually when we arrive in Liang state, I can assist the Liang King
the only condition is to kill you first
Don't lie to me. No one can trick me
Except for that woman
You want a lot of women?
Let's talk about you. What kind of women do you like?
Pretty and sexy
Or intelligent?
I like honest ones
Intelligent ones will do too.
They can teach me how to read and write
You don't have a woman, do you?
So, what did that girl tell you?
I'll let you know when we reach Liang state
You, take a look down the moutainside
You, circle back and search again
Who's that?
Du Pham tribe, lawless and nomadic
Go over and say Hi
They won't understand me
They are fierce fighters
Don't provoke them
Hurry up. You're not tired, are you?
In strong winds, birds will not panic and will seek shelter
What are you talking about?
When the phoenix loses its feathers, it's uglier than wild chickens
Hey, you're pretty good at throwing stones
That's how we killed wild chickens when we were kids
How did you know the Wei army
will lay an ambush at Phoenix Mountain?
I didn't know
In any case, we've been ambushed for 2 days
So he's angry inside
If we weren't ambushed
With our training, we could each take on 10 enemy soldiers
Defeating the Liang troops would have been easy
Don't brag. Liang soldiers are no pushovers
In any case, soldiers like you disgrace the Liang state
Come, let's see how you take on 10 opponents
The General vs The Deserter?
Now it's Liang vs Wei, very fair
If you want to be fair, then don't attack my wounds
Ok, to even it up further...
You're already dead
You are also dead, so we both died together
Not counted!
The battle is over. Wei state wins
All these months, there's fighting everywhere
and people are drafted to be soldiers
He attacks him, he attacks him
What's there to see?
Liang state wins! Liang state wins!
So this is the fairness you spoke of?
There's no fairness in war
We'll have meat to eat in a while. Have a snack first
Fussy about dirty food?
As you wish
General, what do you eat when you're not at war?
Delicious meat from gorillas
Seafood from the Eastern sea
No wonder you wage war. You eat weird stuff
Aren't you illiterate?
My father taught me these 2 words. They are simpler to write
There's nothing simple about those 2 words
Why don't you come back with me to Wei state?
I can give you a post in the government
I forgot to tell you
The reward for capturing an enemy General alive is
wealth, lands, and lifetime exemption from the army!
A lifetime away from soldiers, just farming, no wars
Only when there is war, will there be a winner
And only when the winners rule, will there truly be peace
Then peasants like you can have an peaceful life
You know,
If it weren't for your damned war
I would be living that life right now!
You really don't want any food?
Honestly, I'm a little hungry
We have meat!
We have meat..
Hey, I'll help you start a fire!
You are pregnant, we can't eat you
Father told us before...
Hurry! Hurry!
There are people coming, let's go!
Why the panic? It's only one horse
Eh? One of our own?
Comrade...
Son of a bitch!
You, check those trees there!
A sword from Liang state
Kneel!
I am a Liang soldier. I only kneel to a Liang General
What's going on?
Are you a Liang scout?
Yes
What about you?
Me too
What's your mission?
I climbed up Phoenix Moutains
and discovered that both armies....
.. both armies destroyed each other, yes
Why travel by side roads?
Well you are on the main roads...
...side roads are easier to travel, and faster too
Really fast
I do not know him
What? He has a concussion
He has a concussion
I did not fall...
Whether I fell or not, I still don't know him
- What?
- What what?
We don't kill scouts!
Is this your sword?
Yes
How does a General's sword end up in your hands?
I found it
You're not a scout
I am not
Where's the Wei General?
I do not know
You dare to say you don't know?
Ok ok I know, I know!
I captured your General
You're pretty impressive
I'm not impressive
Where is he?
He escaped
Escaped? That means you're useless to us now
No no no, I had him hidden
Bring us to him
He really escaped
What you want me to do?
Stay back! Stay back all of you!
Stay back!
If I die, you won't get what you want
What do you want?
I want to be rewarded
I can reward you
You're a disgrace to the Liang army
Of the 2 of you, one is useless
So.. what now?
To the horses!
Sorry
Wu..
Stand down
Let them pass
He's alive, right?
Well then
He's only a General, nothing special
Who knows, I may capture a king next
Am I a disgrace to the Liang state?
Come on
Come get me!
You didn't expect that I still live?
Your evil plans
have killed 1,000 of our brave Wei soldiers
Their souls will never forgive you!
And you
you pitiful peasant
you cowardly deserter!
A big road runs straight to your house
And now you'll go home empty handed!
Where did you come from?
Where do you live?
Once I defeat Jiangshan
I'll start building that big ship
Yes, we'll set sail under the full moon
and travel the world
My father the King, said
we should paint 10,000 dragons on the boat for good luck
When Master becomes King, you can do anything
To become King, the old days are behind us
Get some rest, Master
My father told me that sparrows can become phoenixes
That's good
Why did you trick me?
I even beat you up
Kill me, General
I'm not a General. I'm only a foot soldier
There is no difference.
You still kill just the same
Hey, are you lost?
You really think you can get to
the Magic Tree and say a few prayers?
I'm only a peasant girl
I have a map here
It can help you find the Magic Tree
You should take the horse too. The road ahead is difficult
I'm returning this to you
You hungry? Me too
Have to find something to eat
5 acres of fertile land
at the foot of the mountains
5 acres of fields to plant some crops
You're wrong
No, you are wrong!
All of you, shut up! You are still lacking if you
want to be famous travellers and explorers
Lacking what?
Patience
Good point
Sir, how do I get to Wei state from here?
This way
No, that way
The way to Wei state is dangerous
Better to take your chances
with the Liang state instead
Let's see how you'll escape now
You'll be safe here
I'll be going home soon
Live long and prosper
That's good
A big road runs straight to my house
At the foot of Mount Liang
The land is fertile
That's good
Yeah
Relax, relax!
If I knew this was going to happen,
I would have strangled you back at the tavern
If not for the bear that day, you'd be dead now
Hey, ease up. Do you understand me?
They're taking us to be sacrificed
Sacrificed?
Definitely to be buried alive
Buried alive?
How far is it from here to Liang state?
If we take the road by the river, 1 day
Which village are you from?
3 Legged Hole village
You're still hoping
to bring me back for a reward?
Yes, you are my slave remember?
Hey! I am not your slave!
I am HIS slave!
Trade a horse for him
Be careful Master!
Halt!
How do we get out of these?
I was about to ask you the same thing!
Wu
I have an idea
What kind of ideas can you have?
Remember, we're in this together
Right, my father told me once
that whether it's eagles or chickens
in the pot, it's still called "meat"
Good point, a very good point
Help them!
This wasn't such a good idea
No, it's a good idea
Wu
Yes sir
So you finally face me with a real sword
You're no longer my Master, sorry
It's too bad. You were my best student
Come on, get on!
Hurry up, buffalo!
Run, Master!
This way
No, this way!
You know, I wasn't trying to rescue you
It was because the buffalo bumped around randomly
So, do you think the buffalo is strong
or were the walls too weak?
Regardless, thank you
It's all good
What do you have there around your waist?
It's a secret
Before we part ways, I'd like to tell you a secret too
You know why that bunch wants me?
I don't care
Anyway, the affairs of you nobles are too complicated
Eversince we met, it got even more complicated
Peasant!
You are still my slave
Let's see you try to escape now
You spoilt my big plans
Now you're the big plan
I am your fields!
Yes, 5 acres of field!
Not forgetting the monetary rewards!
Right, a lot of money
Wait wait!
Why?
I'm telling you to stop!
I'm not listening to you!
Why didn't you say so earlier?
The bush isn't strong enough
Don't grab me!
If not you, then what?
Let go first. I'll come for you later
You think I'll believe you?
I told you!!
Wu.. Wu!
Master!
Why?
He's still alive.
Is it pre-destined? Where is he?
Master, we should return to Wei
No! You don't know what I'm thinking
I truly admire you
Ok tie me up then
I'll go take look at where we are
I said, I'm going to take a look!
Where we are?
It's futile. We'll both die in here
A big road runs straight to my house
At the foot of Mount Liang
The lands are fertile
You're mad
It's ok. My father once said
be thankful to be alive
Why must I be King of Wei?
You'll be a good King for Wei
Are you saying that I should
harden my heart and kill him?
At this point in time, there is no other choice
Ok, how should he die
for us to be safe?
What are you thinking of?
Cauliflower
Yes, grow some cauliflowers
Why?
What do you mean, "why"?
Why am I here with you?
We could have conquered the world
And then lie in a grand tomb at the end
There will be countless people
buried with us, as packing material
No one will bury us if we die here
That's right! We'll save up and open a pharmacy!
Actually, your medicine's pretty good
I will appoint you as Chief Medical Officer
You know, we could be friends if it weren't for the war
Perhaps
If you can make it out alive
Promise to do something for me,
make it worth my while to save you
Tell me
Don't ever invade Liang state again
At least 10 years, let time heal old wounds
You sly fox! Ok, agreed!
Now you must promise me something
Ok, go on
If you make it out alive
You must tell your General
that I died on the battlefield
tell him I died on the sandy ground
that I didn't disgrace Wei
Even though the Wei army was
wiped out, the Wei flag still stood proud
Please don't lie to me
You peasant!
It's good to be a peasant
Wake up!
Dad! I'm alive!
Thanks be to the Heavenly God
Hey I just remembered...
You know, this place is 3 Legged Hole
There's a village nearby. I'll get a boat there!
It's just half a day by river
To where?
Where else? Liang state!
Don't try to escape!
You aren't going anywhere without me!
Hurry up!
Hide quickly!
Why hide?
Hide!
Help me up
Little brother
Little brother?
He is your little brother?
Hunting me down must be hard work
My Prince
Prince?
So who are you mourning?
Our father, the King
When I left, he was just ill!
It's fated. You are a great warrior,
and Father liked you because of it
If Father didn't get mad at me for
starting negotiations with Liang state
I would be Crown Prince
So, to ensure my demise, you set up the ambush!
Because of your feuding
the Liang state paid the price of 2000 men!
You are not fit to speak to me
It's you that is unfit to talk to me
He has nothing to do with this
But he is the enemy!
He wants me alive, you want me dead
Ok then. Kill me with the crossbow
I gave you. Return and be a good King
You've always had a soft spot
This is your sword. If you don't kill him, he'll kill you
Only one of you can become King
I don't understand why one of you must die
Stay out of this
You are making things complicated
I said, stay out of this!
Ah I see. It's that bald guy there stirring up trouble
Ok I'll keep quiet
Ok they are here. We can leave now
I've disappointed you
Do what you need to do, Master
Let's go hide
General!
Behind you!
I'm too nosey!
What a waste...
Where are all the stones?
Stay back!
I'll take out the other eye
Big brother!
Stop fighting!
I am the one you want
We are brothers
One of us must live
You don't understand what I am saying, right?
Do you understand now?
This is what I need to do
Little brother!
Big brother, did I die a good death?
That big boat of ours
We can't be on it together
Do me a favour
Please bury him
Hurry up. We still have half a day's journey by river, General
No, it should be "Prince"
The wine from Wei is too weak
I know what you're thinking
I also know what you're going to say
"It's good, we are still alive"
Honestly, after seeing you and your brother
It made me think of my own brothers
They must have been good soldiers
Actually, I want to be a good soldier too
At the time, all 3 of us were drafted
into the army at the same time
The first tour lasted 3 years
When we got back
our village had been burnt to the ground
Now I'm homeless
Before my father died, he said
We serve the country before we serve our home
But when will this war end?
He said, "Listen up, children"
"Of the 3 of you, 1 must live"
"to continue the family line"
Now I'm the only one left
Capturing you was my only good turn of luck
I guess my luck isn't that good
No need to ask me
That day, what she said to me was
"Retribution"
Peasant
PEACE
MOUNT LIANG
Liang state is just around this corner
Liang and Wei as allies. Perhaps my brother was right
If the King of Liang doesn't kill me
perhaps I can discuss national affairs with him
Perhaps.. perhaps
Perhaps it's too late
Perhaps
It's always bustling in Liang
Your secret
I underestimated you
I'd never expect you to capture
and bring me to Liang state
Am I your slave now, or your enemy?
Neither. You're free
Go, before I regret it
Why?
Of the 2 of you, 1 must live
Hey! Will you keep your promise?
What?
In 10 years
Of course I will
I forgot to tell you
That piece of jade you took from me is really valuable
You can exchange it for wealth and lands
Found it!
I may lose my life
I'm left with nothing again. It's fine
Leave quickly!
Run away!
Let him surrender
Liang state is destroyed. Kneel and surrender!
Liang state is gone?
How can Liang be destroyed?
Liang state refused to surrender, so Qing state annexed it
Your army is destroyed. Kneel or die!
The army is wiped out?
Liang state is gone
The army is destroyed
I have lost everything
Put the flag down
There's a big road..
Your army is wiped out
No, not wiped out yet
.. that leads to your house
Drop your weapons!
I'm still here. Come on!
My house is at the foot of Mount Liang
The land is fertile, 5 acres of it
5 acres of good fields, for planting crops
Dad, I can't continue the family line
A large river flows straight to my house
With a wife and kid, and spacious rooms
With fat chickens and geese
and strong cows and goats
Growing beans, rice and vegetables
I didn't disgrace Liang state
Liang state was annexed by Qing
The General went back to Wei and became King
He gave up wars
When Qing attacked, he ordered a quick surrender
so that the population can live in peace
Qing continued to conquer states for several more years
In 221 BC, the Qing unified China