Why in God's name...
would the Stantons
have their summer house...
out in the middle
of all this yuck?
I don't think they do.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means we're lost.
We're just gonna keep driving
until we hit someone's pig?
- Binky.
- How in God's name could you drag me down here...
to Yuckville, West Virginia,
when I'm 40 months pregnant?
Not that that was my idea.
Don't start that again.
You agreed.
Against my better judgment.
Well, you will have your own
personal beach house to console you.
Most husbands find it unnecessary
to bribe their wives to reproduce.
That's why I "dwuv doo."
God, haven't these people
ever heard of pavement?
Huntsy. Something happened.
What? What is it?
I think the kid wants out
at the next stop.
My wife is having a baby.
Where's the nearest hospital?
You might try down in Jane Lew.
How close are we?
I'd say about...
forty, forty-five miles.
- Is he crazy?
- There's no time!
Well...
the Hollowmade Hospital's
in Jupiter Hollow.
It's about three miles, but...
Hollowmade! Thank you!
How did you ever get me
out of Park Avenue?
You ain't gonna get in there.
Garth?
It's time again.
Where do you want me
to put this, doc?
Just put it right here,
Eufus, on your way out.
Check with me tomorrow,
and don't worry about it.
That's good cider, Nanny Lewis.
Could you take that
down to the lab?
Snack time!
There's the hospital, Harlan.
- Cross your legs.
- Hunt!
Tell them I want my own room.
My wife is having a baby.
Well! Jane Lew Hospital's
probably what you're lookin' for.
- This is a hospital?
- Yes.
But it's for employees
of Hollowmade only.
- Company policy.
- This is an emergency.
I'd love to help you out, but I can't do
anything without Mr. Stokes' authorization.
- He's a real stickler...
- Mr. Stokes?
He owns the Hollowmade factory.
Lives in the big, gray
house, right over there.
That's gratitude!
I shan't be a minute.
Hunt, where are you going?
Hunt? Hunt!
You all right back there, lona?
Don't you fret. I'm just fine.
- Howdy, lona.
- Mornin', Jake.
- Mr. Stokes!
- Doctor...
I'd like you to meet
Mr. and Mrs. Shelton.
They're the new owners
of Hollowmade Furniture.
Scrub up, Doc.
Your new boss is having a baby!
Look at this place. What a dump!
Hi, Doc.
Guess what?
I hate needles!
Now, hold on a second.
It'll just be a little prick.
Yeah, that's what got me
into this mess.
It-It's a girl.
Coming, lona.
There you are.
I like that lamp.
That new since last time?
Yeah. One more push.
It's a girl.
It's another girl!
Doctor! There's
something stuck in here!
Nanny, I think you'd
better get in here quick.
Nanny!
It's another girl!
Well, I hope you both
wanted twins...
'cause that's what you both got.
Girls!
- Wonderful!
- Damn.
That was the messiest,
ickiest...
most unbearably primitive
experience I've ever had.
If it's all right with you...
I-I'd like to name them
after my great aunts.
I shudder to ask.
Rose and Sadie.
You'll look so lovely
in that tiara.
Tsk. All right.
We'll name them Rose and Sadie.
What color are the stones?
You done real good.
Garth!
Why, that's your "purtiest" one.
Well, what should we call them?
It's just a duck.
You mean, the...
How about Rose and Sadie?
That's "purty"!
Sadie and Rose.
Good morning, Moramax.
- Good morning. Hi, there.
- Thanks very much.
Thank you. Miss Davis isn't in yet.
Would you take a seat
in the reception area?
- Yes?
- She's coming.
It's Sadie!
Good morning,
Moramax. Please hold.
Good morning, Moramax.
Please hold.
- Good morning, Miss Shel...
- Depreciation schedule, on my desk by 5:00.
Stuart. You know, when I ask for demographics,
I expect you to include all age groups.
- Children 7 to 13 don't purchase stock, Ms. Shelton.
- I did.
- Miss Shelton, the...
- Is this how we dress for the office?
- You look like a blood clot.
- Everything's ready for the board meeting.
Flow charts.
- Profit pyramid.
- I hope you'll be pleased. We were here until...
What's going on in research?
More money for more lab rats?
Some of our new products seem
to create, adverse reactions.
Get tougher rats.
- Where's my sister?
- Not in yet.
- Dieting again, are we?
- Shhh. Not here.
Good morning, Judy.
Come on, Duke.
- Hi, Rose.
- I know I'm late. It's just, I got to walking in the park...
and it was so beautiful, and I, I found
this cute little guy and he was lost.
- Rose.
- And I think I'm gonna call him Duke.
- Because I've always wanted to have a dog named Duke!
- Let go, Rose.
- God! Duke! What have I done?
- Push the button.
- Call someone. Do something. Duke.
- The down button, Rose.
- Help me! Call the security!
- It'll be all right.
- Duke!
- See? There he is.
Duke, you're okay. I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to do it.
It's all right. I deserve it.
Rose, why don't I take Duke
while you're in the meeting?
The meeting. I almost forgot.
I... I'm just not myself today.
Or any other day.
You're late. The meeting's
in two minutes.
I know, but, Sadie,
do I have to go?
I sit there, and everyone looks at me like
I... like I'm... because... especially today.
I'm just not grounded. I'm not centered in
the way I should be, because last night...
Dr.Jay and I,
we were having this...
This candlelight dinner
and, you know, too much wine.
I started opening up, and he started
closing up like he usually does.
But I started talking about
getting married and having kids...
and maybe a goat
and some ducks...
and a little garden
with fresh veggies.
- You know how I love to chop and...
- What happened?
- We broke up.
- Good riddance.
You are so completely out of sync.
You're dreaming about growing old in the
country while other women your age...
- Our age.
- Don't interrupt!
Are thinking about tummy tucks. I tell you,
it's not normal. Now, stop it. Stop it.
Do you want one of the board
members to see you?
They'll say you're a sniveling,
hysterical, pre-periodic twit!
I have a right to my own feelings,
Sadie, and I am not a twit.
I may be pre-periodic,
and I may be hysterical. So what?
So there are drugs for those things,
and we make most of them.
I could just kick myself
when I act this way.
Splash some water
on your face and maintain.
- Rose!
- Dr.Jay for Rose.
Put him on. Look, Jay...
- Rose, Rose, I'm so glad I reached you.
- I'm not...
I'm sorry, honey. It's not that I
haven't thought of the... the "M" word.
I have. I have.
No, I maybe, might.
It's just...
You know what it is?
Well, I'll be honest with you.
It's your goddamned family!
The idea of your blood-sucking
sister Sadie...
as a permanent
fixture in my life...
is so inexpressibly nauseating...
Well, take a purge.
I'm just gonna throw myself
into your work. Who was that?
A heavy breather
with intestinal woe.
- Dear. Paw prints.
- Look, I'm fed up with you.
You're a senior vice president...
and the window washer knows more
about this company than you do.
You're so wispy, wispy, wispy.
Why can't you focus?
- I'm going to.
- And these weird attacks of domesticity.
- Where do they come from?
- I don't know.
You're going to have to see Dr. Sullivan,
I insist. As soon as possible.
- He didn't stop you from getting married.
- That was a brief fiasco.
Well, this fiasco would like
to have a few words with you.
- I tried to tell him.
- Hi, Michael.
What are you doing here?
I'm going into a board meeting.
Well, that's certainly
more important than your son.
Yo, Ma. It's me, Sly.
It's your day with him. You're not dumping
him on me five minutes before a meeting.
I am not dumping him on you. I just
want to know the meaning of this.
- He said you gave it to him.
- I did.
- Do you mind telling me why?
- He earned it.
How?
A hundred dollars for every "C," two
hundred dollars for every "B"...
You pay our child to learn?
Why not?
Let's just call it a, a perk.
You're out of your mind! You're
raising a child, not a, not a C.E.O.
Well, perhaps I'll raise both.
I got you. I got you.
All right.
I'll take the money back...
if you'll just...
get him out of here.
Hey, that's my money! Mine!
Spoken like a true Shelton.
Jason!
Come along, Rose.
I-I don't even know
what's on the agenda.
There's a ridiculous little
company we've had forever.
- I'm going to ask the board to off-load it.
- What's it called?
Hollowmade.
Let's hear it for the Hollowmade
shop class and marching band!
Playing, well, frankly...
I didn't recognize
the tune, but...
Now, to head up this fight...
we think we got somebody who's
more than a match for Moramax.
Hollowmade's
own factory foreman...
Miss Guts and Gumption, Miss
No-Nonsense herself, Rose Ratliff!
- Come on up here, girl!
- Yee!
Come on, you spry chicken.
- Go get 'em, Rose!
- Think big, Rosie!
Thank you.
I appreciate that, Mayor.
I really do.
I don't know about you all,
but I'm mad as a wet wasp.
I've been doing some checking up
on these Moramax folks.
Last year, they put 300 Santa Clauses out
of work, and right before Christmas too.
And now, it's Hollowmade
they want.
No tellin' what they got
up their designer sleeves.
Could be condos, a ski resort.
Strip-mining's one
sure thing comes to mind.
Are we gonna let 'em swoop down on us like a
bunch of turkey buzzards in business suits?
- No!
- Pick our bones clean?
- Take our factory, our jobs, our way of life?
- - No!
Can we outsnake 'em? Hell, yeah!
Now, go on and get out there and buy
those canned peaches and ceramic items.
Mayor Finkar brought his two-headed
calf all the way up from Jane Lew.
And it's a beauty.
Twenty-five cents a look.
Come on, we got
to raise some money...
so I can go up north and raise some
hell and kick some snooty New York ass.
- Are you with me?
- Yeah!
'Cause right here, right now,
we've got the Swamp Mud Boys...
featurin' my sweet sister,
Miss Sadie Ratliff.
Hit it!
. Well, hello, Jupiter Hollow
I know you're doin' fine.
. Every day you work the factory
Every night, a jug of wine.
. But now them bums at Moramax.
. They're tryin' to milk us dry.
. But you all knows my sister Rose
will sound the battle cry.
Yee!
. Sister Rose is gonna kick 'em
in their little-lo-lay-hee-hoo.
Their little-lo-lay-hee-hoo
Their little-lo-lay-hee-hoo.
. Every cent's gonna help us kick
their little-lo-lay-hee-hoo.
. Hi-dee-olay-hee
Little-lo-lay-hee-hoo.
The most fiscally prudent action
at this point...
is to divest ourselves
of Hollowmade.
It's a little backwoods
furniture factory.
They actually still make
porch rockers.
Now, the opportunities
for expansion are virtually nil...
and the buyer has offered us
a most attractive price.
So you can see, gentlemen, that
were we to liquidate Hollowmade...
the return on our investment
would in fact be quadrupled.
But liquidate...
I mean, aren't there other considerations?
May I make a point?
I'm sitting listening here,
and I... what I...
I'm feeling, deeply inside...
I mean, what it is, is...
I mean, things are just not
computing exactly right.
I mean... Sorry.
Gentlemen,
help yourself to Danish.
God.
How many times have I told you you're not
to talk about things you don't understand?
- I know, but...
- Where do you get this bleeding heart from?
I can't help it. I think the way Daddy
bought the company is so sweet.
If Daddy were alive, he'd be the first to
agree with me. Sweetness wouldn't stop him...
from taking a huge profit out of some
toothpick mill in Hickville, West Virginia.
Now, eat the goddamn muffin. And for
God's sake, try to show some poise.
- Poise.
- Miss Shelton?
- Yes?
- We're for it.
But we don't want
any publicity about it...
People losing
their jobs and all that.
From a P.R. standpoint...
we might look rather heartless
if we shut down the mill.
Last year's hostile takeover of the
Santa City chain hurt us immeasurably.
Everyone's
forgotten all about that.
I know I have.
Three hundred angry Santas picketing our world
headquarters tend to be remembered vividly.
Yes, indeed they do.
Gentlemen, gentlemen. And Rose.
You have my full and complete
assurance that the buyer...
Mr. Fabio Alberici, will
continue running this factory...
in concert
with current management.
Therefore, I urge you to give your most
serious consideration to a "yes" vote...
to the Hollowmade sale initiative at
next Wednesday's stockholders' meeting.
So the people of Jupiter Hollow
are in support?
They are! I assure you.
Did you see that?
Sadie, you were so good.
You got 'em singin' and dancin'.
- That's gonna add plenty to the fund.
- The fund, the fund.
- You sung so good, Sadie. Didn't she, Rose?
- She did.
What's wrong with you? Don't you
want to save Jupiter Hollow?
I know it's small of me, but this doesn't strike
me as a way of life much worth preserving.
Hey, Sadie! I got this
thing all wrapped up.
I'm gonna get that little squealer
right there just for you.
- Great, Petey!
- Yeah? Wanna go get a grape soda?
Not with a man covered with pig poop.
No, sir, I don't.
I'm not good enough for you? You're gettin'
a little above your raisin', if you ask me.
She's just kiddin', Petey.
That's sure the truth.
You been above your raisin'
all your life.
- Mighty nice job, ladies.
- We're gonna win.
How can you say this is a way of
life not much worth preservin'?
Just look at this. How can you
not just love this place?
God, Rose, I wish I knew.
I, I feel like the real me is
all cooped up inside, you know?
And I want so many things.
I want designer clothes.
I want to see the world. I want a penthouse
in the sky and a maid to pick up after me.
I want to say things
like "keep the change."
God, sometimes I get so bored...
I find myself just prayin'
for a U.F.O. sightin'.
I'd stand here and I'd say, "Come and get me.
Come and get me."
Yeah, well, you're bored 'cause
you got no sense of purpose.
Why don't you help me
with this Moramax mess?
Over my dead...
What do you mean?
Leave town? Go to New York City?
- It's a dangerous, dirty, low-down place, Sadie.
- I know! I know!
My God! What'll I wear?
I gotta get my hair cut.
This is just
the sense of purpose I need.
I gotta get me some of those press-on nails.
Do those things stay on?
I wouldn't want 'em floppin' off
in any of those fancy nightclubs.
Listen. Nightclubs? This is business.
Now, you get a grip on yourself.
We're goin' to New York City!
What are you gonna tell Roone?
I don't know.
Just keep your eye on the ball.
Yeah! Hey, how's my baby?
If I can birdie the windmill hole this year,
I got a good chance of winnin' the Masters.
- Look at that!
- Hoo! You see that?
- Isn't that somethin'?
- When this tournament's over, I'm gonna take you away for a week.
I'm gonna take you up to the
tiptop of Blue Ridge Mountain.
- It might be more like the Empire State Building.
- What?
No, you're not gonna get me
in no New York City.
For a while there, I was worried they were gonna
send you to New York during the tournament.
- Listen.
- Hey, without my good luck charm, I'd be sunk.
Listen, Roone, I have
to tell you something.
Wait, wait. I got a
surprise for ya.
Goodness.
- What is this?
- It's a real golf ball, miniaturized down.
I saw it in Big Putts magazine.
And if I win this tournament...
I'm gonna replace it
with a real diamond.
- Well...
- Marry me, baby.
Roone...
God.
He just doesn't understand me.
So what happened?
What'd you say?
I told him I'd let him know.
- You didn't tell him you were gonna miss his tournament?
- No, I did not.
It's bad enough breaking his heart
without throwin' his game off.
- Mornin', Mayor.
- Mornin', ladies.
Come on, Duke. Get your tail out
of that truck, you big ol' baby!
Here, let me help you. Feels like
you packed your whole damn closet.
- How long you plannin' to stay for, anyway?
- For as long as I can.
- What do you mean by that?
- I mean I'm not comin' back.
Are you crazy? Does Hilda know?
Does Winona?
No, and don't you tell 'em, either, or I'll
tell Roone you're missin' his tournament.
You a heart the size
of an unsoaked pinto bean.
I oughta fit right in
in New York.
Mama and Papa would've
been so proud of you.-!
Don't carry all your money
in one place.
- Don't go into the subways.
- Don't talk to any strangers.
- No. No.
- Or eat clams.
Auntie Sadie, will you
bring me back a surprise?
Li'l Levon.
You know I wouldn't forget you.
Now, what's that all about?
We're gonna see you in two days.
- Come on, let's go. Bye, everyone.
- Okay, you go, you go.
- Get in the truck.
- Bye-bye!
- Good luck!
- Bye!
Take care! Hurry home!
Yee!
Well, first of all, I thought I'd
show you this year's annual report.
The photo of you two is great.
My God! How did I get so fat?
I look like a walleyed salmon!
What did he use,
a wide-angle lens?
No, he didn't. See, I look thin.
I-I mean I look thin. I mean, I
was sitting near the window.
- There was a lot of light.
- I know what you mean.
I don't understand how it is that you can
stuff your face and nothing happens...
and I subsist
on 60 calories a day...
or else blow up
like a Macy's Day float.
Do you mind?
Now we're not going
to Greenwich tonight.
The stockholders'
meeting is at the Plaza.
Get us our usual suite.
By the way, Rose...
Fabio Alberici
is flying in today.
Sadie, you know, I know that I'm
not that good at figures, but...
I mean, if we can't make a profit,
what makes him think he can?
That's his problem.
This deal is not closed yet, so I think we
should trot on out to the airport and greet him.
Italians love meaningless
gestures of respect.
- Makes them feel...
- virile.
What are you laughing at?
- This is another crank letter.
- From whom?
This R. Ratliff person
from Jupiter Hollow.
I've written him all sorts of soothing letters,
but he insists on coming up with his sister...
to, "raise some hell and kick some snooty
New York ass at the stockholders... ".
Why didn't you show me this?
What if he actually shows up?
I mean, this is just the kind of
hysterical intrusion I don't want.
A couple of moist-eyed
bumpkins...
making an impassioned
plea to save their...
Well, the board is suspicious
enough as it is. -Suspicious...
of what?
Nothing. I have a job for you.
A Harvard MBA for this? How are we
supposed to find these Ratliff people?
Who do I look like to you?
Nancy Drew? I mean, really!
Now, listen. These Ratliffs
are absolute hicks.
- There should be no problem in finding them at all.
- Taxi!
- Over here, taxi!
- Chuck? Chuck!
- Where did you go?
- I'm in the cab.
Harlan, stay to the right.
Who're you kiddin'? I haven't got lost
since the day the two of you were born.
- And that was at least...
- We know how many years ago that was, Harlan. Just drive.
Where do we find
the suitcases, Rose?
- Here. Look. Over here, Sadie. Over...
- Okay. All right.
Look at my glove.
- My God.
- Here, stick with me. Come on, now, stick with me.
- You're going the wrong way.
- What's the holdup here? I'm late for a flight.
- Rose! Rose!
- Stay with me.
- Wait here.
- Thank you, Harlan.
- Here you are, Mr. Alberici.
- Grazie.
Grazie, signore. Arrivederci
e buono giornata. Grazie.
Great. He's early.
Well, who looks Italian?
I don't know you foreigners.
I hope we didn't miss him.
- Bus number 79 to Roosevelt Parkway.
- Come on, Rose.
- 182 to Kew Gardens.
- The heck with that, Rose.
I'm in New York.
I wanna act like a New Yorker.
Sadie, hold on! Hold on, now.
Hold on!
- He al...
- My God!
- I don't know what I'm gonna do...
- Rose and Sadie?
At last we meet.
Do we know you?
I am Fabio Alberici.
Graham Sherbourne told me
to look for you.
But you are not easy to find.
They wouldn't let me park.
I had to keep circlin'and circlin'.
Did-Did you go and buy
yourselves brand-new outfits?
How'd you know?
Come over here a second.
- Wow, what's goin' on?
- That Graham Sherbourne who wrote us those shuck and jive letters.
I bet he sent this fella
over here to soft-soap us.
- But how'd they know when we were comin' in?
- Are you kiddin'?
Computer chips. They got their ways.
We better be on guard.
Sadie, don't you dare.
For once in my life, I'm gonna be Joan
Collins, and you're not gonna stop me.
Don't think we're always
gonna be this easy.
Perhaps we should
discuss business later.
Fine with me.
I just don't understand it.
I spoke to everyone
wearing an Armani suit.
That must be he.
- My!
- What the hell is Harlan doing?
Gee, these press-on nails. I guess
I should've pressed harder?
You want
the air conditioning on?
It's not n-necessary for me.
I don't know if...
- Don't touch.
- I just wanted to feel it.
- God, you are so bossy.
- Be quiet.
Will one of you
get the damn phone?
Hello?
Glad I got you.
Which would you prefer
in your room, roses or tulips?
- Roses.
- Rose is me!
Thank you.
It was one of those surveys.
Well, I'm utterly humiliated.
How could Harlan do this to us?
Look at this. Not enough
to get two blocks.
- Well, for God's sake, don't tell him that.
- He'll understand.
Driver, we're a little
short on cash, and I...
Hi.
What is this hideous compulsion
you have to be honest?
I-I don't know. I'm so sorry.
Now, we are going to walk
very casually, and yet very quickly.
Rose, it's just so cosmopolitan.
Isn't it excitin'?
Yeah.
The noise, the smog, the crowds...
the muggers, sex fiends, white
slavers, politicians... it's a pistol.
I got about as much use for it
as a toad has for spit curls.
You Americans are...
Are so funny.
Thank you.
P.U.!
What's goin' on?
What're we doin' here?
I don't know, but don't
take your eye off your suitcase.
Signorine?
Wine and cheese.
Good morning.
Welcome to the Plaza.
Right this way.
Come on, Sadie. Quit gawkin'.
I hope we will be seeing
each other soon.
Here we are.
It looks just like
the White House.
Yeah, and I bet the CIA's
in the basement too.
Look, let's level with each other.
Who's payin' for this room?
The arrangements were made
through Moramax.
Is everything all right?
- No, it's not all right, because...
- Rose..
But I guess it'll do.
We oughta cancel our
reservations at the "Y."
Testing, one, two, three.
Look, a sink in the livin' room.
That's what the French
call... a "bidet."
The French must be
taller than me.
It's me. Wasn't there supposed
to be a gift basket in this room?
- Will there be anything else, ma'am?
- That's not ours.
- It's not?
- Golly, no. I wish it was!
Wow, what a room!
What do you mean you've
given our suite to someone else?
I-I don't know if we did.
The key's not here.
I want to speak to the manager.
Rose, look at this!
Red wine and cheeses
of the world!
And look! Real wooden hangers.
But they don't come off.
"Here's to another great year
for you and Moramax. Graham."
- Who's Graham?
- Graham Sherbourne.
He's the pinstriped trouser
snake sent us those letters...
and that big car and this room
and now this basket of goodies.
He's just tryin' to buy us off.
Well, we are not impressed.
They got the cutest little
soaps in the shape of swans.
Could you die?
I want our room,
and I want it now!
Yes, ma'am, I can give you
the suite right next door.
It's identical. I'll have the bellboy
take up your luggage.
What luggage? It's evaporated!
No. There it is.
I feel like my stay here
is already ruined.
Enjoy your stay.
I just know we're gonna have
the most marvelous time.
Lunch.
Thank you. That was
the Hollowmade factory.
All I could find out is
that they've already left.
My God!
They may already be here.
I mean, what are we gonna do?
Call every hotel in New York?
I wish to God I'd never heard of Neptune
Gulch, wherever the hell it is.
Hi, everybody.
Chick Hearn here...
with ESPN's coverage of
the 26th annual Mini-Masters.
It's a gorgeous day
for professional putt-putt...
and we've got ourselves
a real barn burner.
Let's look at the leader board. In the first
round, our leader is Roone Dimmick...
who's heading for the 12th hole
with a two-shot lead...
six under par.
Now let's go to the 12th hole
and meet another member...
of our ESPN broadcast crew,
Ian Churchill.
Ian.
Mr. Dimmick here
is being most thoughtful...
at club selection
on his par-three tester.
The Windmill, or perhaps
the Hole of Lamentation to him...
has plagued Mr. Dimmick throughout
his otherwise stellar career.
He's now finished
studying the lie...
and positions himself
as a hush falls over the crowd.
Roone! Hi there, Roone!
We're rootin'for ya!
Hi, Winona! Hey, where's Rose?
Well, personally, I think
she should've told you herself.
Told me what?
Well, this morning, she and Sadie
just up and went to New York.
- Ladies and gentlemen, just a second.
- Roone, what're you doin'?
- It looks like Roone Dimmick is walking off the course.
- Roone, where are you going?
Lordy, it's high!
Well, Rose, I'm going
to get my legs waxed.
Are you coming? Or are you
just going to hole up here...
and pretend you're wafting
through a field of poppies?
You go ahead. I'm going to the library.
I have some reading to do.
Sadie. About that factory.
Rose, if you can't trust your
own sister, who can you trust?
Darling girl.
Rose, it is so gorgeous up here!
It makes me dizzy. Well, I am gonna
go find that Mr. Sherbourne.
I am gonna dip him in flour and
let him fry in his own grease.
- Are you comin'?
- No, I think I'll just go for a walk, if that's okay with you.
Well, here. Wait a minute.
Don't go off without
a "Save Jupiter Hollow" button.
All right, Rose. If you insist.
Hold the door.
Hold the door! Hold the door!
Moron.
Excuse me. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Is everything satisfactory now?
- My, yes!
That is some room! Have you
seen the view from up there?
- No. I've never been above the third floor.
- You haven't?
Well, you just gotta
come up there and see it.
- That's very nice of you.
- No.
It would be such a shame
not to share it.
And I bet it's just
so beautiful at night.
Well... bye.
I'll see you later.
Well, buongiorno.
Would you care
to join me for a drink?
That's not really my style.
You know, you are not
making this very easy for me.
Is there any reason on Earth
why I should?
I guess this is going to be
a difficult negotiation.
I cannot imagine what you think
we're negotiating for.
I thought it was understood.
Really?
Eurotrash.
I thought I'd just go
for a walk, if that's okay.
You, walk?!
Well, this I gotta see.
Hello.
Can you tell me what room
Fabio Alberici is in?
Yes, he's in room... 1402?
But if you're looking for him,
he's right over there.
My God.
He must think I'm insane.
By the way...
I thought the delay when we
first checked in was inexcusable.
What cute dogs!
Hello.
- No you don't.
- Well, it makes no difference to me.
I'm getting paid
whether you ride or not.
Suit yourself.
What the hell are they doin'?
Are they crazy?
I should've quit
this damn job years ago.
Harlan! Harlan! Harlan!
Harlan!
That happened to me once.
- Well, buongiorno.
- Buongiorno.
- You have changed your mind.
- I feel absolutely ridiculous.
Of course, I should've
known who you were.
You must meet a lot of people.
There was such a mix-up at the airport.
I still don't know what happened.
It's already forgotten.
Campari and soda.
Well, business.
My geologists have given me the plans for
the strip-mining of your Jupiter Hollow.
But first tell me,
would you have any objection...
to us making
our transaction in yen?
Laundering some lira, are we?
The Japanese are so discreet.
Well, tell me. Who buys
and sells money for you?
Jack Butler.
Jack? I went to Yale with Jack.
I did my first
hostile takeover with Jack.
No!
Hi, Rose. How's Duke doing?
Duke? My dog?
Boy, when you go snoopin'
into people's lives...
you don't miss a trick, do ya?
I'm sorry.
I'm here to see
Graham Sherbourne.
Okay. He should be
in his office.
And where is that?
Well, where it usually is, Rose.
You're a big help.
Hi, Rose.
Hi.
Hi. Hi, everyone.
Just fine. Had a good breakfast.
Oatmeal. But I guess
you know that.
Got on my Tuesday panties,
but I guess you know that too.
- My God, it's nearly time to go.
- There he is.
Well, I know, but we have to get over
to the Plaza, for heaven's sakes.
- You're right.
- Could I see your report tomorrow?
- Hi, gentlemen. Hi.
- Well, what are you doing here?
We were just on our way over to
the Plaza to see you and Sadie.
Is, everything okay?
No, everything is not okay.
We have to talk,
and we have to talk now.
All right. What's the problem?
What's the problem? Have you got your
brains and your balls in your briefcase?
Did she say "balls"?
- Wow.
- Let's just go in here and talk, quietly.
You want some reassurances that it will
be business as usual at Hollowmade...
after the sale?
- You know we can't do that.
- Well, you sure as hell better.
Or I'm gonna kick up a big ruckus
at the stockholders' meetin'.
And I've said my piece. Amen.
What are you talking about?
Does Sadie know how you feel?
- Of course.
- Does she agree?
Is a frog's ass watertight?
Do you suppose it's hormonal?
Who cares? We're off the hook.
How about some racquetball, and
where should we go for dinner?
Please, please. Let me just coast
for a few precious moments...
without having to make
any decisions.
I wanna go down to the South Street Seaport.
Do you go that way?
Step on it, please.
Guten Morgen.
- Out of the way, bitch!
- Wha... Wa... Wait!
I'd like a mint julep, please.
No you don't!
- Yo, Ma!
- Wha... What the heck did you do that for?
- I just wanted to go the distance.
- Go the distance? You...
- Get over here, you! Get over here!
- Hey!!
- What are you doing?
- I'm gettin' you out of harm's way.
- Get off.
- Relax, squirt. I've tied hogs slipperier than you.
I'm not a hog.
- Boy, you are hell on wheels!
- Well, what do you expect?
- Are you responsible for this?
- His mother spoils him rotten.
Well, she's a damn fool.
He's a disaster area.
- You don't really mean that?
- Yes I do.
I'm very sorry. But you know,
it's never too late.
Now, if you'll both excuse me...
I must be getting back
to the... Plaza Hotel.
Come back? Where you going?
- Wait! Your money.
- It's my money!
Ya-hoo!
That's Sadie Shelton.
How about an ice cream soda?
I'd rather have
the MP-60 rocket water gun.
- How about an ice cream soda?
- Messages?
And I get to keep the dollars
overseas, where they aren't taxable.
And invest them
in a villa in Italy.
But aren't Italian property values...
a little... soft right now?
No. Very hard.
Hold that thought.
Here's to our deliverance
from repugnant tasks.
Here's to the Ratliffs,
wherever they are.
What are the two of you doing
lazing around...
guzzling Dom Perignon
on my expense account?
This had better mean you found
those Ratliff people.
But I thought
you changed your mind.
What fantasy is this? Are we hearing
voices now, like Joan of Arc?
- But, Rose said...
- No matter what bleeding heart sentiment my sister expressed...
it has nothing to do
with what Moramax wants.
Now, I want those people
found tonight.
- Now?
- Now.
This is for you from... Sly.
Thank you.
You intimidate
your subordinates so well.
Don't I, though?
And what other
talents do you have?
Do you... dance, perhaps?
Don't think this is going to affect
my judgment in the slightest.
I'm planning to gouge you
on this sale.
And I... to impale you.
Thank you.
- Try the "Y." Hicks always stay at the "Y."
- I just did.
- And?
- They were going there, but they cancelled.
Are you ready for this?
They're here.
Where did you get it?
- It's from somebody named Sly.
- It's a bribe.
They want us
to keep our mouths shut.
- How come?
- They've got to be up to somethin' terrible.
- Wait until the stockholders hear about this.
- Do they have to?
What do you mean?
Well, just 'cause
we take a bribe...
doesn't mean we have to
do what they say.
Sadie Ratliff, sometimes I wonder
if we got the same blood.
My own sister. Damn.
I can't think how things
could get any worse.
They say the neon lights
are bright.
On Broadway.
They say there's always magic
in the air.
But when you're walkin'
down that street.
And you ain't had enough to eat.
The glitter rubs right off.
And you're nowhere.
They say the women
treat you fine.
. On Broadway.
But lookin'at them.
Just gives me the blues.
Doo.
- The Plaza.
- At the Plaza?
- Where's the Plaza?
- 59th and Fifth.
On Broadway..
As soon as I get my shoes on,
I'm gonna take this evidence...
and put it in the hotel safe.
Fine by me.
- Hello?
- Rose? Listen.
Did you say anything to Chuck and Graham
about calling off the Hollowmade sale?
- Of course not.
- Well, they are totally inept.
Look, I want you to go downstairs and
help them find these Ratliff people.
Sadie, why can't you do it?
Because Fabio has turned out
to be something of a... perk.
I had plans
for the evening, Sadie.
I know what your plans were. To hole up in
the room and make love to the pastry cart.
Now put down that eclair
and get downstairs.
Okay, Sadie.
I want to put this
in the hotel safe, please.
Rose Shelton, please.
Thank you. Never mind.
Excuse me. Rose!
- Yes?
- I've been doing a lot of thinking.
- We can fix this.
- What is this?
- Open it.
- You're Sly.
Sly... I don't know what you're talking
about. I couldn't be more sincere.
Please. Another bribe?
Bri... If you don't want this,
what do you want?
If you think you can
buy me off with this!
- Look, honey...
- Don't you touch me, and don't you call me honey...
you no-good, belly-scrapin'
pile of cow plop!
- Come along.
- What's a cow plop, Mommy?
Obviously, you're still upset.
You can't outsnake me.
Excuse me.
I-Is this the Plaza Hotel?
It's all yours.
Hey.
You stand here long enough,
you see yourself come out.
- What?
- Yeah.
There's two of everybody
in there.
The ones on the top, and one of those cocoa
truffles with the little swirl on it.
And...
I'll take two... no, give me three
of those pretty parfait nougats.
Surprise!
- Yes?
- I know I'm the last person you expected to see here...
and maybe you don't believe this,
but you're the gal for me...
and I'm the guy for you, and we're gonna get
married and there ain't two ways about it.
- Is this some kind of a joke?
- Is that all you can say?
I heard you were up here, I come up all
this way, and you think it's a joke?
You'll have to excuse me.
Can you believe he actually tried
to buy me off with a diamond ring?
I think I've earned a...
a few hours' sleep.
- Are you comin' to bed?
- 00.
Boy. I never thought I'd have
to wear this old thing again.
Sadie, that used to be
your favorite dress.
Yeah, well...
- Where are you goin'?
- I'm goin' downstairs.
I'm not gonna stick around here like a clove
on a baked ham. I'm gonna kick up my heels.
They got dinin',
they got dancin', food, beverages.
Shoot, I could stay right here
in this hotel the rest of my life...
and be happy as Beulah the cow.
I thought you was gonna help me.
Ratliff, Ratliff. A man
and his sister from Jupiter Hollow.
I'm telling you,
they're not here.
They must be registered
under an assumed name.
- Graham? Graham.
- Graham?
- Well, who's Graham?
- Rose?
- Hi, I'm Roone.
- I'm Graham.
- This is Chuck.
- Howdy. Y'all from Moramax?
- Hi. Yes, yes, we are.
- Well, I'm from Jupiter Hollow.
Jupiter Hollow?
I was born in Jupiter Hollow!
And you're proud of it.
Do you,
do you know the Ratliffs?
Well, you're standin'
right in front of one of'em.
Would you excuse us
for one minute?
Jus-Jus... Rose.
I've never seen
this person in my life.
He mu... He must have seen
my picture in the annual report.
- He calls himself "Roone"?
- He's "R. Ratliff."
He's the factory foreman from Hollowmade.
This must be his perverse idea of having fun.
Let's just humor him
until Sadie gets here.
Do I have to?
Roone...
would you like
to join us for dinner?
Well, that sounds
like a good idea.
Yeah, I could use
a tuna fish sandwich.
Hi, there.
- Hello.
- Gee, you're still workin'?
I bet you're lookin' forward
to gettin' off tonight?
- I was...
- I wanna have some fun tonight.
It's too early to go to bed.
You got any ideas?
Maybe.
Maybe I'll... see you around.
Okay. I'll keep my eye
out for ya. Bye.
So, you will not take back
any paper on the sale...
even if I kickback a percent
of the strip-mining profits.
Absolutely not.
I insist on total liquidation.
Well, this evening cannot end
until we conclude our negotiation.
Perhaps in my room?
Let me get my messages.
I'll meet you upstairs.
I, I want to change into
something less... al dente.
Do you have any messages for me?
One. I get off at 10:00, and I'd
love to see the view from your room.
Well, we certainly
can look forward to that.
Ma'am, could you put a little
more fire under this fish?
Will ya, hon? I, I think I just
heard it holler, "Help!"
Smooth. Very smooth.
Excuse me.
Well, what do y'all think
about Rose?
She's quite a little beauty, isn't she?
Don't you be gettin' any ideas now.
My God.
Excuse us.
I know.
I know it looks horrible.
But we've got the culprit right
here. He's a professional.
Fake name. Totally ingenious, totally
prepared. He actually knew Rose by sight.
Don't you let him out of your sight until
after tomorrow's stockholders' meeting.
Is that quite clear?
What are we supposed to do,
immobilize him with a death ray?
Let me think.
Stop.
I'm sorry. You know,
I know it seems strange...
my comin' up all this way
from Jupiter Hollow like this.
But, Rose, I love you.
Why are you doing this to me?
Well, from the first moment
I heard you were in New York...
all that mattered to me
was findin' you.
You can't be happy here.
I mean, the traffic alone.
I just can't see you up here
in all this traffic.
And the food. I mean, back home,
we'd use this stuff as bait.
Look, I'm doing
just fine, really.
I know. You'd do fine whatever
spot on earth they dropped you on.
It's just... Rose, I know you.
You don't belong
in New York City.
It's in your eyes.
It's all over your face.
You don't belong in that,
that suit.
I mean, all this Moramax stuff is
just bleedin' the heart right out of ya.
You know you want a whole other
kind of life than this.
I-I've never told
that to a living soul.
How did you know?
Well, I know you.
Tha-Tha-That's nothin' to cry about.
Here. Here.
Thank you.
Well, you're in America now.
Speak American.
Y-Yes, but,
you are dressed to go out.
Did you want to go out again,
or back upstairs?
I was going to go back upstairs.
Good.
- Shall we?
- No!
I can make it on my own.
You go right ahead.
Of course.
By the way, why don't you take
this, reading material now?
Last thing I planned
to do tonight was read.
Well.
- Hi.
- You.
You look almost...
almost wholesome.
- What are you doing here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
- Talk to me about what?
- About what you said aboutJason in F.A.O. Schwarz.
I was impressed and amazed. It reminded
me of a... of a girl I used to know.
Listen. I think we should
have lunch or something.
Y-You want me
to have lunch with you?
Well, I mean,
Jason too, if you want.
Well, 'long as you keep him
bound and gagged.
Well, we could talk more
easily if it's just the two of us.
Okay.
What about, here?
Tomorrow, 2:00.
Y-Yes. Ve-Very nice.
I'll see ya.
Friendly men in this town.
Have a good evening now.
Of course.
Hey, babe.
I used to be allergic to angora,
but I'm okay now.
I love to see a woman
with a good appetite.
You do?
I feel obliged to point out to you...
that this man is a con artist
of the first rank.
- Maybe he isn't. How do you know?
- I...
So where are you staying, Roone?
Well, I ain't exactly stayin' anywhere. I just
got off the bus and come lookin' for you.
Well, we have a whole suite.
Why doesn't Roone stay with us?
No. I couldn't crowd you guys.
We insist.
You know, this meal has not
satisfied my appetite one iota.
I got such a cravin' for some country
cookin', I'm gettin' downright homesick.
Shameless.
Hell, I only been out
of Jupiter Hollow one day...
but I sure do miss it.
What do you miss about it?
Well, my porch, for one thing.
Nothin' like rockin' on
your porch around twilight time.
Yeah, your bones
go as limp as a willow tree.
And the shadow from the mountain
makes its way up my steps like...
Well, like an old friend
comin' to visit.
And the stars!
I mean, that's about the only thing
crowded aboutJupiter Hollow.
Right now, the sky'd be
plumb full of stars.
You know. Kids playin'
in the schoolyard...
doors with no locks...
folks who look you straight
in the eye and smile.
Yeah, people are as close as corn
there in Jupiter Hollow.
You know, when Mother Nature
looks through her window...
Jupiter Hollow is the view
that she loves best.
The Colbyco board
has already approved the merger.
Adam, have a glass of water, please.
Give 'em hell, Alexis!
Golly, look at her go. She is just
runnin' that whole company.
Would you turn that damn thing
down? I'm tryin' to think.
You have seen that episode
a thousand times.
I just love it
when she fires everybody.
- I'm a very direct woman.
If I do not get your approval...
And please understand...
that I have controlling interest
in Denver-Carrington...
I shall fire you all
on the spot...
and replace you with a board
that will approve the merger.
- What's this?
- Somethin' that guy from the airport gave me.
My God.
- What's the matter?
- My God.
Just, just a minute.
- Roone.
- How could I go to sleep without kissin' you good night first?
Good night, darlin'.
No one's ever called me
"darlin" ' like that before.
Well, I should hope not.
Look. I want you to keep this.
- And...
- No, no.
- Please don't fuss.
- Roone, I...
I couldn't. I...
Well, I better go nows.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night.
Don't blame me. Don't blame me.
You're the one who lost him.
Well, he just bolted
for the elevator.
What was I supposed to do,
wrestle him to the ground?
Roone.
Sure is nice you boys
lettin' me bunk here.
Hey, that's classical music,
isn't it?
Yes. Yes, it is.
Yeah, I could tell. No lyrics.
So, what do you think
of my plans?
Fabio, you fiend!
.I'm in the mood for love.
- Simply because you're near me.
- My God!
He is not a Ratliff.
His name is Roone Dimmick.
He's traveling with $25,
no credit cards and a harmonica.
- Will you look at this quilt?
- .I'm in the mood for love.
- The workmanship!
- .Simply because.
. You're near me.
. An... Hey, I like your kimono.
Get that in 'Nam?
No, Fire Island.
Well, let's all
have a drinky, shall...
No, I think it's time
for beddy-bye.
Chuck.
Good night, Roone.
Don't tell me you two guys are
sleepin' in the same bed together.
- Yes.
- Gee, I feel awful about that.
Now if you want, one of you can take
the couch, and I'll share the bed.
That... That's very generous of
you, but, we wouldn't hear of it.
You guys are all right.
Wow.
How's the traffic out there
this morning, Joanna?
Well, we're starting out with the Long
Island Expressway bumper to bumper.
I am upset. There's only
an hour till the meeting...
and we don't have a chance
of finding these people!
- Keep your voice down.
- We are not going to find the Ratliffs.
Is that all that's botherin'
you, is findin'the Ratliffs?
Do you know where they are?
Sure. Just let me finish my Pop-Tarts
here, and I'll take you right to 'em.
- Mornin', Rose.
- Mornin', Sadie. You're late.
- I already ordered.
- Good. Grapefruit.
Can you believe these guys?
First they bribe us
to keep our mouths shut...
then they hand us
a complete copy of their plans...
and if that isn't bad enough, they
got the nerve to charge $12.50...
for four tiny little pancakes.
Come on, Rose.
Rose, come on now.
Look. You got your butter in the shape of a
goldfish, and you got your choice of syrups.
And I know how you like to mix and match those
syrups, and... Look, they got boysenberry.
Sadie. Damn, good bread.
Rose! Look!
All over my brand-new
polyester jacket.
Quick. Do something. Well,
go on and hurry and change.
I guess so. Okay.
Lord, my load is heavy.
Good. A grapefruit.
- Where did you get that?
- Milan.
Well, it's awful.
Excuse me? I'm being criticized
by a grown woman wearing a bib?
We've got to make a good impression
with the stockholders...
and you look like
you're runnin' a state prison.
Well, maybe
it's a trifle severe, but...
All right.
I'll change before the meeting.
Now... tell me more
about... Roone.
What are you botherin' me about Roone for?
You know I'm worried about the meetin'.
The "meetin"'? Why are you
worried about the "meetin"'?
- What's got into you?
- Well, what's got into you?
You know the stockholders
will do what we want.
- Can I get you ladies anything else?
- Do not even contemplate.
- Boy, you're bossy.
- Just the check, please.
Is that good enough for you?
Yeah, but it probably costs
$50 for each little bitty polka dot.
Listen. Meet me back here,
all right?
- Good morning.
- Hi.
I really must have that little
polka dot number in my size.
I'm a three.
A five.
Very well, give me a nine.
- Did you forget something?
- No, I don't think so.
Can you please tell me,
is my sister here?
Well, she was.
She left.
Well, then I guess I'll just have a
little bit of something myself. May I?
Excuse me.
I...
Let me guess. Pancakes.
Yes.
Madam.
You can give these...
to the maid.
So what do you think?
Sadie... I am so upset about this Hollowmade
sale, I don't know what to think.
What are you worried
about that for?
We're gonna march in there,
we're gonna set things right!
Set things... "right"?
Right! Come on. Let's go.
I knew I could c-count on you.
Keep the change.
Hell, if I know the girls, they
oughta be havin' breakfast about now.
- The girls?
- We should have been looking for two women. We are so stupid!
Rose, I have to visit
the toilet.
Well, we better hurry. The meeting. And
never say "toilet." Say "tee-tee."
Look.
Well, they're not in there.
- I have to go tee-tee.
- What are you talking about, go visit the toilet?
Hold on a second.
There they go.
Wait a minute! I'm in here!
Really?
Yoo-hoo.
What are we doing? I mean, look at us.
We are staking out a ladies' room.
Six more seconds,
and we've got them.
Can you contain yourself
for six more seconds?
You just get out of here!
They're clones.
What a cheap trick.
It's pod people!
I saw that movie!
- I was at the premier.
- Get back. Get back!
There is no such thing
as pod people, is there?
You're not my sister!
- And you're not my sister.
- Thank God!
Don't touch me!
Don't touch me, I say!
- Ghastly! Ghastly!
- Are they real?
They're robots. They wanna
kill us a-a-and take our places.
- You've seen too many movies.
- You get back.
- You just get back.
- We must be in some kind of parallel universe.
- That is the dumbest damn thing I've ever heard.
- You're such a hick!
- There's U.F.O. written all over this thing!
- They're probably relatives.
Relatives? How can they be?
Listen to them. They're imbeciles.
- Now listen.
- Now listen. I think what we ought to do...
Be quiet. We're going to go
clockwise, starting with me.
- Well, how come you?
- My God, it's me with a bad haircut.
Bad?
- I paid 12 bucks for this.
- I am going to kick your ass.
- I like it. I think if we could all...
- Stop it!
All right. Who are you, and where
the hell do you come from?
Rosie, Rosie. My sister Rosie.
- We gotta figure out who's who here.
- Rosie.
- I hope I'm still me.
- - Rose, there's a chance I could be her.
- Hardly.
- Isn't she divine?
I know for a fact.
I'm not me. Boo-hoo.
I just gotta be me.
Rosie, wait for me.
- How many? - Six brothers.
- And four sisters.
- Sadie, ten. You make eleven!
- You sure do.
- I can't believe it.
- Good morning. Good... morning.
- Morning.
Hold it. I know who it was.
It was that rickety old Nanny Lewis.
She couldn't see worth a darn. She spent
her last days puttin' diapers on chairs.
All my life I felt like I was out
of place, like I didn't belong.
And I didn't. I hate my job.
I hate shopping. I hate New York in June.
How about you?
I hate grits.
And I hate men who smell
like beer and bean dip.
And I hate makin' love in the
back of recreational vehicles!
Am I rich now?
- We're all rich.
- -To hell with that.
We got a meetin' to get to.
We're all on the same side,
now that we're sisters.
- Right.
- Right?
Of course.
The meeting's already started.
Now, we can't all of us go in...
because the spectacle of all
of this seems to upset people.
So, Rose, you take them sight-seeing.
I'll go in, call off the sale...
and then we'll all go
to Elaine's for lunch.
- Elaine's!
- Elaine who?
How do we know that you're gonna
call off that sale?
- No.
- Well, of course I will.
Are you sure that while we're out there
lookin' at the Statue of Liberty...
you won't be in there votin' so that Italian
fella can strip-mine Jupiter Hollow?
- Strip-mine?
- Yes.
- You lied to me.
- Would I strip-mine our birthplace?
No you don't. You're the only one's gonna get
strip-mined if you walk through that door.
You'd never miss
that little sinkhole.
- What did you say?
- I'll buy you a nice little condo on the East River.
- How dare you?
- Rosie! Rosie!
Help me
with this terrible vulgar woman!
- Rosie, don't you dare!
- I need your help!
Sadie, I just have to.
- I've got her!
- How could you do this to your own sister? Sadie!
Don't let them do this!
I'll share it all with you!
Join me in this, and I'll show you a
life that'll make your head spin!
I'll introduce you to the most
glamorous people in the world!
- Joan Collins?
- Yes.
No. Sadie, I know you're shallow,
but you're not heartless.
You don't want to help
do in Jupiter Hollow.
You're not one of them.
You're me! Look.
We even got the same taste
in clothes.
Yeah, and where in the hell did you
get the money to buy such a dress?
- Or do I need to ask?
- Come on, Sadie.
Who needs these dumb old
hayseeds anyway?
I do.
Grab her! Please!
In the closet!
You're a Ratliff deep down
inside. I knew you were.
- Don't push it.
- Quick, go get that chair.
Security! Help!
- I better stay with Sadie.
- Boy. I can't wait to loose my lip at those stockholders.
- Wait! You can't.
- Why not?
Because no one will believe you. The one
who always does the talking is Sa...
You fools. They'll never fall for that.
They'll see right through her!
By the liquidation
of the Hollowmade factory...
we'll double our corp...
Open up! Let me out!
- Just hold your horses.
- Let me out!
Good morning. Bill, Tom.
- Bill, Tom.
- Good morning.
Well, good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
Sorry if I'm a bit late. Well, let's get
right down to new business, shall we?
Hollowmade.
I have come to the conclusion...
that the sale of Hollowmade
to Fabio...
- Alberici.
- What's his face, is not in our best interest.
Excuse me, Miss Shelton...
but we were just reminding the stockholders
that you strongly advocate liquidation.
Rose, darling, may I have
a glass of water, please?
- Certainly.
- I'm a very direct woman.
If I don't get your approval
to cancel this sale...
please understand that I...
I have controlling interest in
Denver-Carrington... M-M-Moramax...
and I will not hesitate to fire
y'all right here on the spot...
and replace y'all with a board
that will go along.
Miss Shelton, this is outrageous.
We were told the sale
would make a huge profit.
Isn't that
what we're in business for?
What the hell's going on here?
What Sadie means...
What she's trying to tell you is...
I just want to say...
Gentlemen...
I have something to say.
This deal is a fraud.
Mr. Alberici...
plans to close down the factory
and to strip-mine Jupiter Hollow.
You're probably wondering how come all of a
sudden we care about this little Podunk town.
Well, it's, it's simply
because, because...
Because of the terrible image
problem we've been facing.
As you well know, Moramax
has the image problem of...
of a, of a...
- Pit bull!
- Yes! Look. Everyone hates us.
And now we're going to put 500 hard-working,
decent Americans out of work?
- They're not gonna take it lyin' down.
- They're not.
They're liable to be arriving here
any minute now... in pickup trucks.
- R.V.'s.
- Factory workers picketing Moramax...
with wives, kids, dogs.
- Pigs!
- All right! Get on with it.
Look. Ladies and gentlemen...
we're asking you
to please say no to this sale...
not just because it's gonna
spare 500 jobs...
not just because it's gonna save
10,000 acres...
of the most beautiful land
God ever put on this earth...
and certainly not just because
it's the right thing to do.
No. We appeal to you
as business people.
We appeal to your basic
business instinct.
Yes! To save your own asses!
Yes. How many of you are in
favor of saving Jupiter Hollow?
You were wonderful!
So eloquent. You nailed 'em!
- Rose?
- Sadie!
That's him. He's here.
Two Sadies.
You. Psst.
Aw!
No. It's me.
-
Think about it.
There must be higher love.
- Down in the heart.
- What next?
- Or hidden in the stars above.
- How about a nice long weekend on my yacht?
- Without it.
- We can describe the weekend...
- Life is a wasted time.
- As offshore drilling?
.Look inside your heart
I'll look inside mine.
Things look so bad everywhere.
.In this whole world what is fair.
I have been out of control
with that kid.
I mean, absolutely out of control with that kid.
- . We walk blind.
And we try to see.
- Falling behind in what could be.
- Yee!
Rose, Rose. Remember me and the
ring, the dirty names? I'm sorry.
- You know, I'm so glad to see you because...
- I wanna take you for coffee.
- You got quite a mouth, haven't you?
- I feel so good today!
I just saved Jupiter Hollow.
Bring me a higher love.
- Where's that higher love.
- Let's get one of these.
I keep thinking of.
- Worlds are turning and we're just hanging on.
- A nice front porch.
- With a rocker.
- There.
- Standing out there alone.
- Roone.
- Will I have a rocking chair too?
- Sure will.
- There must be someone who's feeling for me.
- Taxi.
Things look so bad everywhere.
In this whole world
what is fair.
We walk blind and we try to see.
Falling behind in what could be.
Bring me a higher love.
- Bring me a higher love.
- Excuse me.
- Good morning.
- We'd like a room.
- Please.
- .It's that higher love.
I keep thinking of.
Bring me a higher love.
I could rise above.
On a higher love.
I will wait for it.
I'm not too late for it.
Until then.
I'll sing my song.
To chant the night along.
Babe.
I could light the night up
with my soul on fire.
I could make the sun shine
from pure desire.
Let me feel that love
come over me.
Let me feel
how strong it could be.
Bring me a higher love.
It's that higher love
I keep thinking of.
Bring me a higher love.
- Bring me.
- .Bring me a higher love.
Bring me a higher love.-.
- Bring me a higher love.
- .Bring me a higher love.
- .Keep bringing.
.I said bring me.
Bring me a higher love.
Bring me a higher love.-.
- With a higher love.
- .Bring me a higher love.
.Bring me a higher love.
- Bring me a higher love.
- .Bring it on.
That love
Bring me a higher love.
It's that love,
- I said bring me, bring me.
- .Bring me a higher love.
- Yeah Bring me a higher love.
- .Bring me a higher love..