Sir.
Sir!
Open your eyes.
What happened here, sir?
Go start the car first.
- Hurry!
- Yes, sir.
Okay.
Sir!
Sir, wake up, please.
You have to hang in there.
You have to live.
You must live.
Since his stomach was pumped in time
- he will live.
- Okay.
Rather than focusing
on his physical status
he has to be mentally stable.
We understand.
- Thank you.
When he wakes up
we have to give him a hope to live.
In order to do that,
we have to find out the truth fast.
But we have no idea
where this victim is.
I agree.
- Manager Gu.
- Yes?
Contact the reporters now.
Pardon?
Tell them I will have an
interview at the company.
What kind of interview will  it be?
A can't miss opportunity.
You probably won't find him.
I'm certain that he was
cast by Kang Dong Suk.
As a representative of this company
I'll share our position on this matter.
As for the food poisoning case
it was staged.
Staged?
By someone who was trying
to harm our company and Soon Jin Dairy
it was his conspiracy.
Do you have any grounds
for this allegation?
If you say that without any evidence
it could create more problems.
I have something more
positive than evidence.
Right now
we have the person who collapsed
after drinking the rotten milk.
What is he saying?
He is under our care right now.
He also confessed that this case
was orchestrated by someone.
If that's true
where is that person now?
Due to his physical state
an interview seems unlikely.
But he will be out here tomorrow.
He will come out and
explain everything.
And the real conspirator
will be revealed!
We will see you again
at this hour tomorrow.
- Did you know about this?
- Not at all.
What is he going to do?
[Food poisoning case was staged.]
What is this?
How did this happen?
I made sure of it, but...
I'm sorry.
Did you confirm it yourself?
I didn't.
Did you try to get in touch with him?
He was homeless,
so he didn't have contact information.
Are you saying you didn't
confirm anything yet?
Why bother to confirm anything?
It's clear that you
were behind all this.
Kim Ji Hyuk.
You forced someone to drink
rotten milk, huh?
People wouldn't do that
even to a homeless mutt.
Is that something a person could do?
What are you talking about?
Are you that afraid of me?
You had to do all that
to crush me, huh?
I feel sorry for you.
You're out of your mind, aren't you?
Just wait, Kang Dong Suk.
By tomorrow, everybody will know
what kind of person you are.
Everybody will point
their fingers at you.
even your servant.
Look forward to tomorrow.
Go now to check on the homeless guy.
Yes, I will.
Go confirm it with your own eyes.
Yes, sir.
Yes, did you find his whereabout yet?
Where is he?
Got it.
What happened?
Did they really take him?
They couldn't have
found him that easily.
It's impossible.
Even an excellent cop would
have taken a day or two...
by any chance
would Kim Ji Hyuk?
No one is here.
I hope I'm wrong.
What do you think Kim Ji Hyuk did?
Cops often use that...
When there is no evidence or witness
they bluff.
- Bluff?
- Yes.
They say they have the witness
who will testify against you.
- They bluff like that.
- Then what?
Then the suspect gets nervous, so...
he tries to find the witness, right?
Then they follow him.
He's the one, right?
Yes, you're right.
Wait a second.
Damn it.
You suffered from food
poisoning, right?
Could you excuse us?
I have to talk to him privately.
Oh my.
You, seriously.
They made you drink the
rotten milk, didn't they?
Think carefully.
They didn't treat you
like a human being.
You were given money, right?
They think they can do
anything with money.
To you, I...
I will offer you something you
really need rather than money.
You're living apart from
your family, right?
I will help you reunite your family.
I will help you, so they will
never treat you like an animal again.
I promise you that.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Hold on. I will go to the pharmacy.
[We welcome you to Hyung Sung Distributions]
Yes, I received the money.
By the way
are the kids okay?
Sir, time is up.
The reporters are outside.
What do you want me to do?
Okay, I will make them leave.
Gosh, it will make the image
of our company even worse.
As for the reporters,
I will get back to you in a minute.
That's not what I'm here for.
What can I do for you?
By any chance, you...
Someone like me
can I be hired here?
Of course, you can.
You can work here.
with me, for the rest of your life.
Is it true what President
Kim said yesterday?
Yes.
It is true.
That day, someone came up to me.
He handed over the milk.
He told me to drink it and go...
He told me go buy one
more milk at the mart.
I took the money and...
did what he asked me to do.
I'm sorry.
I will go down to the police
station to report all this.
Hey!
Find the cop who will be
handling this case, and...
bribe him right away.
I heard that your son, Dong
Suk is getting married.
Is it true?
Yes.
Oh my, which family is she from?
I'm so curious.
Well, it's just that...
Tell us, please.
What powerful family is she from?
Later.
That's good.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
Who is she?
She is...
Ah, she works at our company.
Let's cheers.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
This tastes so good.
The future I dreamed of
was it becoming that woman?
Mi Ra.
Honey.
Honey, what's wrong?
Wake up.
Mi Ra, what are you doing?
Call the doctor now!
Honey.
Honey, what is it?
Honey, wake up.
Honey.
Excuse me.
Mi Ra.
Is that safe?
Did you find out who did it?
I know who.
The victim turned himself
in and confessed.
But the investigation
is going very slowly.
They probably had something
to do with it too.
They must have.
They have money and power.
I'm sorry.
You were only trying to help us.
But still it's been proven
that it was staged, so...
things will recover soon.
We will find a way too.
Okay.
It's this hard to live by my belief.
Cheer up.
And you have to survive till the end.
Someone who is following
in your footstep
will take your glory, so...
please keep close eyes on him.
I will.
I will also look forward to that day.
It appears that the artery
to the heart was blocked.
With surgery
the artery has been cleared.
Since it was a minor operation
if you rest for about a week
he will recover soon enough.
Okay.
I guess you got my heart after all.
Fortunately, the emergency
treatment was done properly.
That's why it was minor.
Please pay more attention from now on.
Who did the emergency treatment?
Why does that matter?
What matters is that you're safe now.
It was Mi Ra.
It was?
Mi Ra.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
It's okay.
I only did what I had to do.
Why does my father want you
to be the chief secretary?
After we get married
I was going to have you stay home.
Don't you think my
talent will be wasted?
Your talent?
You did a good job as
a nurse this time.
But it's different working
in the business world.
I want to do it.
It's important that we
get married, but...
I want to succeed in my career too.
Let me do it, please.
Just because I don't like it
can I make you do what I want?
It's an order from President Kang.
I can't just go against it.
I will do my best.
Thank you, anyway.
You're saving many of
my family members.
Earlier a customer
spilled coffee there.
Scrub there hard.
By the way, why do I have to work here?
Whose house do you live in now?
I'm on it.
Briefly I thought she was an angel...
People don't change, okay?
Hey.
I think this has been more
than enough for our rent.
- Money for food.
- Money for food?
You're unemployed now, aren't you?
Kim Ji Hyuk doesn't
have any money either.
Hey, you said you'd be nice
to me for the rest of your life.
Maybe I've been too nice to you.
You're being cheeky.
Hey.
You have to at least
feed us to make us work.
Wow, this was fast.
This will be added to our
breakfast menu, so...
it's important to make it fast.
It's nutritious and simple.
- What do you think?
- Why?
We're being your guinea pigs now?
Well, if this is the
guinea pig you need
we're always available.
I can't say much about you, but...
you sure know how to make a sandwich.
I was often home alone
when I was little.
It was too much to make
other stuff, so...
I always made sandwiches.
Why would you make it yourself?
You can have it made for you.
I'm not one of those princesses
who are given everything.
I'm an independent princess.
I'm a princess who has the looks and
the personality at the same time.
By the way, how did the
food poisoning case go?
It went okay.
But things are not the same as before.
Shall I help?
It's okay.
You can just make
sandwiches like this, okay?
When you try to help
you may make it worse.
You just don't know much about me yet.
I don't get involved because
I'm not interested, but...
When it comes to this
mine is much smarter than Dong Suk's.
You can eat this anywhere.
I'm at Hyun Sung Mart today.
I will have a sandwich again today.
With a sandwich, we can't
go without milk, right?
If so, I will eat it now.
You can eat this anywhere.
I'm at Hyun Sung Mart today.
I will have a sandwich again today.
With a sandwich, you
can't go without milk.
If so, I will drink it now.
Oh my.
It's good.
She's such a character.
She's cute and all, but...
she's a bit weird...
How do you like it?
This?
According to the comments uploaded
because of this segment
Soon Jin milk is getting good
reviews on the Internet.
- Is it?
- Yes.
Then, are our sales having the same...
Our sales are going up slowly.
Actually
once you leave a bad
image on the consumers
regardless whether it's true or not
it takes a long time
to recover from it.
I understand. Alright then.
Sir.
It was the Justice Department.
They want us to send our
revival plan again.
I have a feeling that it was
because of the recent case.
By when?
You're making sure the others
don't think otherwise, right?
Of course.
You have to do a good job.
If you do well, the
others will follow you.
Don't worry.
Even though we won't
be related as in-laws
I still think of you as my own brother.
not blood-related...
just like the way you treated
that scam artist as your own brother.
Ah, sorry. It was a joke.
But what do we do?
This time, between us...
there will be a cutthroat competition.
Are you talking about a bid over
petroleum public corporations?
Whoever gets it
the one who gets it will...
have their stocks go
up two or three times.
Alright.
I'll compete with you fair and square.
only with my skills.
Before the committee
reviews our revival plan
we have to make some
noticeable progress.
If we show up empty-handed
we will walk out of there
with their demands only.
So that means...
we have to make a progress...
to be able to reject their demands.
With our current products
from small companies
we can only do so much, right?
Well...
we are okay with groceries
and general goods.
The problem is...
the bulky items such
as home appliances.
It's s field that is dominated
by large companies.
Dong Suk is blocking our path...
There seems to be no
way to go about it.
Anyhow, we have to loosen the
chokehold from the big companies.
Other than that, there is no other way.
This is a copy of the bid document
that Dae Sam is preparing.
Good work.
Hand this over to the
Planning Department.
Based on this
tell them to prepare our bid document.
Who is stopping the supply
from large companies
it's the members of the Owners Club.
The leader is Kang Dong Suk, but...
the most influential person
to the members is...
the vice president, Moon
Myung Ho of Dae Sam.
Then what we need to do is have
Moon Myung Ho turn to our side, huh?
- Is it even possible?
- Well...
It's just that...
He was acting like a
bastard before, so...
I beat him up once before...
Don't worry.
When he thinks it's beneficial
he won't care about the past.
One second.
According to you
there is a possibility that we can
have Moon Myung Ho turn to our side?
Kang Dong Suk got a hold of a very
important bid document of Dae Sam.
If we can show him the document
there is a possibility that
he might switch his side.
When he was about to get screwed
it will look as though we helped him.
That's right.
By the way, Dong Suk...
isn't he close to Myung Ho?
Why did he sneak out the document?
In their world, a friend means...
just a closer enemy.
Actually, they are the same.
Based on the information
that he sneaked out
Hyun Sung will also
prepare a bid document.
If we get a hold of it and
hand it over to Moon Myung Ho
we'll stopped them from
getting screwed.
With that gesture
we can make a deal with Moon Myung Ho.
Are you still there to
help me out this way?
Don't put yourself in
danger unnecessarily.
If Dong Suk or Manager Do finds out
Just walk away.
We won't need your help.
You do need my help.
Only if I stay there
you can win.
If I have to use you,
it's not the victory I would want.
Yes, you have to win.
You must win, no matter what.
It's for my late father.
And...
And what?
Oh man...
I know that it's not the right
time to say this, but...
there was a time when I liked
someone very much in the past.
I'm telling you this
as a friend, but...
If you have feelings for
me right now by any chance...
You have a lot to do right now.
Focus on your work now.
Do I work every single moment?
Work will eventually end some day.
So, you also...
about me
if you give me a small hint...
What are you doing?
Are you cheating?
What do you mean I'm cheating?
You and I are living together.
If you see another woman other than
the woman you're living with
it mean you're cheating, no?
You moved yourself in.
Do I live with you because I want to?
I will get going now.
See you later.
Mi Ra!
You still have feelings for her?
Mi Ra will marry my brother.
- No.
- Yes.
Absolutely not.
Do you want to bet?
If she marries my brother
you will become mine, okay?
If she doesn't marry him
you're still mine.
What a psycho.
- I'm a psycho, so what?
- Hey.
- Seriously.
- You did wrong.
The bid document is prepared
at the headquarter.
Once it's complete
it gets handed over to the president.
The minute the document
is handed over to him
it gets stored in the company safe.
Then no one gets access
to that document.
Are you saying it's impossible
to get a hold of it?
No.
it's not completely impossible.
From the Planning Department
on the third floor
the document gets delivered to the
president's office on the 27th floor.
That's the window.
It's five minutes at most.
Is it even possible?
Not to be caught after
sneaking out the document
we will have to make a copy
and return it during that time.
No way. It's nonsense.
Isn't it?
If it's from the third
floor to the 27th floor...
they will use the elevator for sure.
This much will be alright, right?
It's good.
That amount will work.
Let's do it that way.
From now on
hand over all the documents
to me the Chief Secretary.
Do you have something to say?
Thank you.
Let's go.
I'm sorry.
Please hold the elevator for a bit.
I have things to load.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
You can't even lift that by yourself?
Come out.
- Can you move to the side, please?
- Sorry.
The director asked me to
move the stuff, so...
Get off.
What's gotten into you today?
Are you not feeling well today?
I might not be fully
recovered from last night.
- Lift it.
- I'm sorry.
Lift it.
What's going on?
What is it?
- Did you press something?
- No, I didn't.
Did I press something by accident?
- It's okay.
- That's right.
Your baby just had his
first birthday, right?
Yes.
Wow, it feels like it was only
yesterday that the baby was born.
- How time flies.
- Excuse me for a sec.
- Something is wrong?
- No.
- I didn't climb up there.
- I just need to check something.
Thank you.
Manager Do, you may go.
Yes, sir.
How does it look?
Me sitting up here?
You look good.
When my father isn't well
shall I ask him to hand
this position over to me?
It might be too soon.
Your father is still in good health.
And he doesn't seem to
want to step down yet.
Then I will make him step down.
What do you mean?
Mi Ra.
there are times I can't control myself.
It's probably because
of this lousy heart.
When my original heart was switched
I think the person who I am
might have been switched too.
I might have lost who I am
along with my heart.
By any chance
if I cross a line I'm
not supposed to cross
you should stop me.
It's only you who can stop
me when I'm like that.
Dong Suk.
you've gone too far for me to stop you.
What did you want to see me about?
Frankly
I don't have good feelings about you.
About the merchandise
from the big companies
let Hyun Sung Mart sell them again.
Why?
Why should I do that?
When you see this
you may change your attitude toward me.
What is this?
We snuck it out from Hyun Sung.
It's the bid document of Dae Sam.
With what evidence, can
you make such claims?
If you see the bid document
prepared by Hyun Sung
you will know for sure.
Based on your document
they offered a little
more on their terms.
You're trying to cause a dispute
between Hyun Sung and Dae Sam, huh?
You will make that decision.
If you don't want, don't check.
Any evidence this is
not a trick to get me?
If that confirms to be a lie
you can always stop the
merchandise again.
You are in a bind, aren't you?
Are you going to do it or not?
Okay.
By any chance
did you not think I might
go tell on Dong Suk?
That's not who you are.
Kang Dong Suk.
He's more than capable of doing it.
Yes, I understand.
Thank you.
Most big companies contacted
us to send the merchandise to us.
Okay!
We're almost there.
No, we still have a lot
of huddles to overcome.
First, we have to come up
with the revival plan.
- Let's gather around.
- Sure.
This is what I have so far, so...
this may not work.
Wait a sec.
Finally, it looks like
they are starting to work.
You gather all our resources and...
buy as much Hyun Sung stocks.
The price is at the bottom, so...
you should be able to buy them all.
Yes, sir.
Let's now hear people call me
the head of a company.
Weird.
Jin Ah left me because of you.
It was my first time to be
punched by anyone in my life.
There is something about
you that draws me.
Is this what they call
opposite attraction?
I'm not doing this for you.
The person, Kang Dong Suk who
even betrays a friend...
is what I wanted to show you.
Usually, enemy's enemies
become friends.
Are you feeling okay?
Yes, I'm all better.
I just took a few more
days off to just rest.
Please wait a little bit.
It's after rush hour, so...
you should be home soon.
- Mi Ra.
- Yes?
There is a place I want to stop by.
Where?
I want you to come with me too.
She hates me coming, so...
I will use you as an excuse.
Dong Suk will show up soon.
You stay with your heads
down, no matter what.
I will handle it, okay?
Besides, he's not himself right now.
As you already know it,
he's doing something unprofitable.
If he wants to go down,
he should go down by himself.
Why is he bringing us all to it?
Don't you think?
Mi Ra was asking about you, so...
she will be your sister-in-law.
I thought she should know
about your store at least.
Are you really going
to marry my brother?
Of course, our families have
already been introduced.
I was sad that you missed it.
Mi Ra, make sure you marry my brother.
Okay?
That's what I really want.
He needs someone like you.
Okay.
Jin Ah, can I have a sandwich you make?
I've only been having
hospital food lately.
Now I have a craving for it.
Hospital food?
Do you hate me that much?
Can you sit down, so I can see you?
What was wrong?
It wasn't serious.
I passed out for a
short period of time.
By the way
after I passed out
you were the one I
wanted to see the most.
What are you doing seriously?
I don't want to see you.
Do you like him that much?
so much that you would
leave your parents?
Yes.
Do you?
I might be being punished.
Honestly, I was trying to take
away something precious from him.
That's why he's taking away
something precious to me.
Who started it?
Dong Suk.
It should be enough.
Was it you?
I told them to stop.
What?
We were all fed up.
Business shouldn't be
run based on emotions.
I told you that I'd pay
for all your loss.
We agreed to do it not
for the money, but...
for you.
Dong Suk.
You're our leader.
You're a model that we learn from.
So you don't destroying that image...
this is where it ends.
Do you guys agree to this?
Alright then.
Thank you for your support.
We will stop right here then.
Obviously, you're our leader forever.
Mi Ra brought you home safe, right?
Yes.
Take a few more days to rest.
I will take care of the company.
How is it going with the bidding
for petroleum public corporation?
We received the document from
the Planning Department.
I looked through it and...
it looks like it will
come to us this time.
Since I collapsed
I will step down and appoint
you as the president soon.
If the bidding for petroleum public
corporation comes through
it will be a good excuse
to give you that position.
You will have to recover
from your mistakes too.
All the other bidders
are insignificant.
It comes down to a bidding
between us and Dae Sam.
Against Dae Sam
I'm positive I can win.
Don't underestimate them.
If you fail
not only your position at the company
but also Hyun Sung Energy
will be traumatized.
You know that our company isn't
at the top of our game now, right?
I'm saying that this bidding
will most definitely come to us.
Don't worry.
How is it going with Hyun Sung
Distribution that Ji Hyuk
is in charge of?
I'm paying attention.
I thought about it and...
what if we leave him alone?
Father.
If this deal comes through
it will take care of that as well.
Just let him live.
We will focus on Hyun Sung Energy.
We won't have to waste
our resources there.
I can never do that.
My pride won't allow it.
Your pride?
Apart from my pride
he's like a ticking bomb for us.
Once he gains power
we will explode.
Boom!
He and our family can
never coexist together.
Then what shall we do?
We have to crush him,
so he won't be able to get up again.
Don't you think so, father?
Good night.
When did this begin?
Why is it getting more twisted
as the time goes by?
Damn it.
Did you see your father?
Yes.
What is it? Is everything okay?
I may have underestimated Kim Ji Hyuk.
I've been treating him like
a little bug all this time.
Now I will admit that
he can be my match.
Dong Suk.
He's no match for you.
- Don't worry about him.
- No.
If emotions get in the way
I can't win the battle.
I forgot about that for a while.
Now that I admit that he's my match
I'll have to face him properly.
Not with my emotions,
but with my logic.
Hold on.
Sir.
Isn't this a bit too difficult?
What do you think?
In my opinion
conventional market idea
isn't making sense.
It's going to work.
Trust me.
- I understand.
- Let's go.
Hold on.
President Cho.
I've seen it once.
Because of the committee
of the creditors
I will finish up and
submit it right away.
Yes, sir.
What is it? Does he want
you to do something for him?
I've been going over his
financial management.
It's the least I can do for him.
Let's go.
See you later.
There is something I've been
curious about for some time.
He must hate my family.
How come he doesn't come
ready to fight like he used to?
To have his revenge
why is he focusing on getting
Hyun Sung Distribution back?
It might be because of the compensation
for the people at the market.
He takes Hyun Sung
Distribution back and...
he may try to compensate them.
Partly because he wanted to support the
employees who lost their jobs, right?
Yes, he's most likely to do so.
So when he's alone, he's a punk.
When he's with people
he becomes their leader.
His power comes from...
the people who are with him, huh?
Yes, it seems that way to me too.
The way we take away his power is...
we take his people
away one by one, huh?
His people...
That's all. You may leave.
Kim Ji Hyuk's people...
Excuse me.
Mi Ra.
I'm calling to tell you to be careful.
Kang Dong Suk may start to do
something to the people around you.
What do you mean?
He may use the people around you and...
harm you that way.
He might try to make
them betray you or...
Don't worry.
There are no such people around me.
I'm on my way to the committee now.
- Let's talk later.
- Okay.
With this much preparation
it should go smoothly
without a problem, right?
Well, big companies have started to
sell their merchandise to us, and...
we prepared the plan as
thoroughly as possible.
I'm not too happy about the
project proposal, but...
it shouldn't be a problem if
there isn't any variable.
If there is a problem
They will switch the legal
administrator or...
sell it to a different company.
The worst scenario would be...
disposing our assets
and then closing down.
If that's the case
what we've been doing
up to now will become all useless.
No, it shouldn't happen that way.
Let's go.
Hello.
It's been very hot lately, hasn't it?
Summer is already here, right?
- Hot, isn't it?
- It's cool in here.
Have a seat.
I'm the legal administrator
of Hyun Sung Distribution...
Kim Ji Hyuk.
Representing all the creditors
I'm Cho Young Ho, Director
of Myung Sung Bank.
The rest of us here...
they came representing
the major creditors.
Hello, all.
I'd appreciate your help.
You are...
Admit your fraud charge.
I will let you out on probation.
And they sent you money...
Go tell who sent you here.
I will come after them to finish them.
Hold still.
Even if my body gets all torn apart
I won't let go of my hold.
Why are you here?
You confirmed that Attorney Park
was included on the committee, right?
Yes, I did.
You pinpointed what gets
him all worked up, right?
Yes.
I explained about his personality.
I told him to hold on to his weakness.
Good job.
By the way, why is he so obsessed
with the people around him?
If he's nice to them
he's delusional that they
will become his people.
That may be the real delusion.
It's not fair that he's here.
He is here because Kang
Dong Suk paid him.
I can object here, right?
Objection.
Pull him out.
He's been already
approved by the court.
There is no flaw.
What kind of crap is this?
I'm sorry.
He is very quick-tempered,
so we apologize.
It's a small world, huh?
What did you say, you bastard?
Sir, let it go.
If you use your fist here
it will be over for us.
- Please.
- Relax.
Calm down.
We're now ready.
I'm sorry.
Please submit the revival plan first.
- Yes, sir.
- Manager Choi.
As for the repayment of the bonds
what are you planning on doing?
We've started to carry merchandise
from big companies now.
We are seeing the growth in
sales for the last few weeks.
If we have a surplus
we will start repaying our
creditors immediately.
When you have a surplus, immediately?
Then what are you going to do
with paychecks for the employees?
Excuse me.
We were in the middle of
talking about repayment.
Why are you bringing up
paychecks for the employees?
Here the information
on pay cuts is missing.
Same goes for reducing the staff.
Just because you have a surplus
it doesn't mean that you
can afford to repay.
In our position...
No matter how we look at it
Without pay cuts or
a personnel reduction
it's impossible to
stabilize the company.
We will repay even if we
have to make money elsewhere.
Why would you not tap into the area
with the most chance for cost cutting?
Hey, mister.
To be able to make money,
people have to stay on the job.
Before machines or systems
how can we make money
if we lose people?
Reduction personnel or cost cutting...
It all means getting
rid of people, right?
You don't know much
about business, do you?
Are you talking about this when you
haven't learned anything about management?
Hey, you punk.
I'm not educated, okay?
Even if I'm ignorant,
I know how to treat people.
Sir, do you know who he's working for?
To destroy us
they made a healthy man
drink rotten milk.
He was paid and sent from Hyun Sung.
He's just like their dog.
Please watch the language.
Without any confirmed proof
I advise you not to talk about it.
We apologize, sir.
Please calm down.
Please move onto the next agenda.
Sorry.
Honestly, what he said wasn't wrong.
Without a reduction of personnel
or a pay cut
it's rare for a company
to become stabilized.
You should come up with the
solution to that agenda.
I already told you.
- It's about...
- Excuse me!
Can we continue after we eat?
Let's eat.
Yes, as you mentioned
he's a moron with no
knowledge in economics.
It's so easy to handle such a person.
Don't worry.
- Hey punk!
- Please.
How much did you get this time, huh?
Sir.
When you are a lawyer
how can you like getting
a bribe like that?
What a greedy piece of crap!
- You seriously!
- Sir, please...
- Please calm down.
- Please.
How is it possible to have someone
like him to get on the committee?
This is how things are
in the real world.
Money can get you anywhere.
- Manager Gu.
- You came.
Sir, am I too late?
No, you're not.
What brings you here?
I contacted him.
I asked him to bring the agreement
on the pay cut by the employees.
Pardon?
What else can we do?
We have to fix this first.
I was in a hurry, so...
not everybody signed it yet.
But still if it's this
number of people...
Sir!
I won't allow this.
By having my employees
sacrifice themselves
I can't proceed like this.
Sir.
You're like our father to us.
When our family is
just about to go down
we can't just ask our father to
take the full responsibility.
Even if we skip a few meals
we all have to chip in together.
You're the only one we can rely on.
This is not a sacrifice.
We're helping each other as a family.
It looks like the problem
on the pay cut has been resolved.
Next...
in this proposal
there is one thing that
doesn't make sense.
As the major business plan...
introducing a conventional market feel?
Is this child's play or what?
By any chance
just because you grew
up in a marketplace
did you come up with
this childish plan?
Yes.
That's correct.
I grew up in a marketplace.
But now there is nothing I can
do about where I grew up.
Gentlemen.
by any chance
have you ever been to a
conventional market?
Isn't it a place with a
lot of human connection?
Everything is cheap and
full of life there.
If we introduce the idea of
a conventional market to our mart
I believe it will be a huge hit.
It's exciting too.
Lady, you choose and
grandma, you choose too.
It's two thousand won for eggs.
Excuse me.
This is not a place to make
a plea with your emotions.
I went a little too far, didn't I?
Well...
it was only the introduction
of my proposal.
The main point is...
About the system of a
conventional market
the part I propose as our
major business plan is...
theses reasons.
The foundation of a
market economics is...
the free economic system.
Mi Ra.
In our field of the distribution business
big markets and the
conventional markets are...
two main columns.
Take a look at this here.
As you can see it here
The system of a conventional market
is the first step to resolve
the issues of a big market.
Compared to big markets,
conventional markets...
they don't need big
facilities or investment.
The investment costs are
relatively low, and...
hold on, please.
They can have many variety of stores.
They can hold many merchants
in one area and...
The price competition
is already set up.
The merchandise is set accordingly.
They target the consumers with
middle income as the main consumers.
They directly deal with the suppliers.
They save the extra
cost in transportation.
All these made me think
of this conventional
market as our major
business plan.
If we work with these areas
unlike the way how other marts are run
I'm certain we can raise our sales.
It sounds doable.
It's a good plan.
How did you hear that he was
some sort of moron, huh?
What's the point of me objecting?
while all the other four
directors were agreeing.
Sir, was that really you?
Was that really you?
I thought it was somebody else.
I will go to pray in the
mornings from now on.
I witnessed a miracle today.
What really happened?
- Wait...
- What's wrong?
- I have to focus now.
- Yes?
It feels like there is an
earthquake in my head now.
Your brain is asleep now.
It wasn't used for a while.
Hold my head.
Let's go for some cold beer.
Did you see everybody's face?
Mother!
- Come here to have some.
- Please join us.
It's okay. I'm still open.
- Mother, come here to sit.
- What are you doing?
- What is it?
- Mother.
Do you know what today is?
I used my head for the
first time in my life...
I made something big happen.
Did you head-but someone again?
Mother, seriously...
Manager Gu, tell her.
Tell her what I said
today to shock people.
She might not believe me.
It's just that he did...
Mother, do you know the
foundation of market economics?
- Wow.
- There you go again.
What nonsense is that?
- Manager Choi.
- Yes?
Only this much.
- Manager Choi.
- Yes?
Tell her how fabulous I was today...
only that much.
If I have to tell you only that much
what a great job he did today...
Mother.
The effect on differentiated products
do you know what the merit
of one-stop shopping is?
Did he eat something bad today?
Mother.
I've been joking.
I realized something
after I did some studying.
Even if you use difficult words
and are proud of yourself
your fundamentals don't change.
I proudly grew up in a market.
The market raised me.
I'm a kid who grew up in a market.
I'm sorry.
Since I admitted that he was my match
I expected this much.
I let him fatten up himself.
It's time to hunt.
After we find out his vulnerable spot
we attack the areas around it.
We don't ever send him
away with one blow.
We make sure he suffers
slowly until he dies.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Why does he have my secret book?
Please forgive me once.
We will work under you like a dog.
They found out we took it.
So they took it back.
There is a big possibility that
So Mi Ra was in on it too.
We will go back to the
time when we were in love.
Don't go.
It's okay that you want
us to stay as friends.
Just let me stay near you.
I'm asking you.
You've been enough help.
Walk away now.
He took away all that was mine.
How can I possibly forgive him?