Subtitles by DramaFever
[Love 'til the End of Summer]
[Episode 45]
Congratulations on
the reopening of Island Studio.
I had thought...
this place would
continue to remain vacant.
Why would it?
Although so much has changed
there are still so many things
I want to say to Li Xia and Zhi Ang.
Yan Mo.
Can you help me take a picture?
Sure.
Look a little happier.
Mom, that hobo's eyes look so nice.
They're bright and large.
Don't say such things. Hurry along now.
Do I already...
look like a hobo?
There's not much to regret anymore.
Next, it's time to do what must be done.
Hurry! Ji Si has a new book out!
Yes, it's him!
["Angel"]
[Ji Si]
[This is Lu Zhi Ang.]
You... made a trip back.
- He's so dirty.
- A bum!
Hello.
Sorry.
How could you do that?
That boy taught me about maturity.
That girl taught me about love.
They once appeared in my life,
then disappeared without a trace.
However, I don't believe
they were angels.
They are the most ordinary
boy and girl on earth.
So, I will be waiting
under the camphor trees
because I believe
they will return one day.
They'll be back to find me
and teach me much more.
Contemplating the ten-plus years
of prison in store for me
filled me with fear for a very long time.
However, I am now no longer afraid.
I will never approve of
the things you've done, but...
I am sorry. I should bear
the consequences of my own actions.
Hello?
Yan Mo.
I plan on turning myself in.
Being on the run is really exhausting.
After I turn myself in,
I will at least sleep peacefully.
Lu Zhi Ang, you bastard!
Where are you right now?
I want to see you.
Of course I have to see you
before I turn myself in.
10 o'clock at
the police station entrance. Okay?
Yes, okay.
Wait for me. I'm coming to
see you right now.
Can we wait another 10 minutes?
Just 10 more minutes, please.
All right.
Lu Zhi Ang.
I don't know when it happened
but you became my weakness.
I'm always acting like a lunatic.
I'm not gentle or ladylike.
I don't fit the mold of your ideal girl.
I even shied away for no reason
such that it became too late for me
to tell you seriously
how much I like you.
I like you and am willing
to be sick in your place
to feel sad in your place
to face all the evil in this world
in your place.
Nobody but you.
It'll always be you.
Lu Zhi Ang, you have to wait for me!
That fool.
Still late.
Let's go.
Lu Zhi Ang!
I will wait for you!
This man of mine
isn't an undefeated hero
nor can he arrive atop
a rainbow-hued magic cloud to marry me.
But that doesn't stop me.
He is the love of my life.
There are a thousand different
types of waiting.
The best one is called
anticipation of days to come.
I'm willing to stand here and
begin at this very second
counting down the years
until our reunion.
Ding Yi Yang is waking up.
I saw his finger move.
Contact the family after
we conduct an examination.
That's how things stand.
There's not enough time now.
So, I ask that you understand.
It's possible you won't
be able to go on stage.
Mr. Ma, we've all prepared
for this for so long.
Our chance on stage
can't just be taken away.
That's right. It's not our fault
there isn't enough time.
It's too unfair that we have to
bear the responsibility.
I know you're all upset.
I'd like for you to perform too.
However, this is the dean's arrangement.
There's nothing I can do.
I have a suggestion.
All four of us can perform on stage at
the same time for the length of one song.
[Broadcasting Studio]
They say if we make a wish as we
release a sky lantern into the sky
then the wish will come true.
It works.
Here.
Zhi Ang.
Li Xia.
Xiao Si.
Let's write down our wishes.
On the lantern?
We'll stand together sooner or later.
I'm free!
Let's go!
[Qianchuan First High School]
- Let's go.
- Let's go!
So this is how I used to look.
Ding Yi Yang's stabbing,
which had caused quite a stir
has finally come to a close.
Suspect Lu has been sentenced to
three years in prison on assault charges.
I hope you all will be well.
Do you still have the "Angel" art book?
Sorry, we're all out.
That customer is holding the last one.
Excuse me, are you going to
buy this art book?
Thank you!
Hello, Yu Jian?
How is Lu Zhi Ang? Is he okay?
He is fine.
The court has given a ruling already.
All we can do now is wait.
What about you? How are you doing?
Me? There's nothing worth mentioning.
I'm just living life on my own.
I'm sorry, Yu Jian.
When you needed a friend the most
I wasn't by your side.
You've always been by my side.
But, as for Xiao Si...
He's been looking for you the whole time.
You don't plan on seeing him?
Li Xia, are you ready? The truck is here!
Okay, got it! I'll be right out!
Yu Jian, tell me when you
come back to Qianchuan.
I'll come to see you.
Bye now.
Mister.
Now that we're really leaving,
I feel a bit reluctant.
We've lived here for
so many years, after all.
Yes, I do feel a bit reluctant to leave.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
I hope you won't regret your decisions.
I have no regrets.
All right. It's time to part at last.
Let's go.
[Demolition notice]
Hello.
Watch your step.
- Right here?
- Yes.
Hi, I've been by to
view the house before.
I want to show the place
to my girlfriend this time.
- Go right ahead.
- Thank you.
- Straight ahead?
- Yes.
Go straight.
- We're not there yet?
- Soon. Don't rush.
Surprise!
Do you like it?
I like it. This place is beautiful
and it's huge.
We just arrived in Shanghai
and we don't have much in savings.
Your house is so well-decorated.
Is the price really that low?
- There's a piano over there.
- Go take a look.
This is great.
I'll be able to play the piano here.
Okay, all right.
If you like it, let's rent it.
You can do the things you love here.
Leave it to me to earn money.
- Thank you.
- No need to.
Is everything here available for use?
Yes.
You like music too?
I really hope I can
release my own album one day.
If you're interested,
I also have a guitar upstairs.
It's been with me for many years
but I have no use for it now.
I'll leave it for you too.
- Really? Thank you!
- Thank you.
I put a lot of thought into
decorating this house.
I don't want to see it go to waste.
If you like it here, you can move in
as soon as you want.
- All right, thank you.
- Thank you.
I hope your dreams come true.
[Duan Qiao and Yu Jian's Home]
You have so many things.
Will you be able to manage?
I used to roam the world
with one backpack.
Now, I'm no longer roaming.
I'm returning home.
I actually feel quite reluctant.
All right, don't walk me any further
or else I'd start crying.
Is this how we're parting ways?
I never imagined that in the end
it'd just be the three of us left.
Remember to contact us
after you're there.
Don't disappear on us.
I'm returning home.
We're not going our separate ways.
You won your countercharges
against Ding Yi Yang for libel.
Your new book, "Angel",
is also sold out everywhere.
You're a winner at life.
Stop looking so miserable.
Come on.
I'm leaving now.
Take care.
Thank you for taking care of me
all these years.
I mulled over this for a long time
and I think I should tell you.
Li Xia has been away for two months.
She's now back in Shi County.
Go find her.
Hey, little girl. Have you fallen?
Let's get you up.
Xuan Xuan!
Thank you, thank you.
Li Xia.
Am I destined to lose you?
You can put this plant in your study.
It can absorb the radiation
when you're on your computer.
How can I depend on this little plant
to absorb radiation?
At most, it's just for show.
So after we get married,
should we have a baby just for show?
Then we'll seem like a family.
What are you saying? You're terrible.
[Fu Xiao Si's works]
That's a pretty nice painting.
We can buy a few and
hang them in our house.
Let's go inside.
Do you like anything?
If you like them, I'll buy all of these.
Young man.
High school girls all like
these paintings.
You're quite up to date on the trends.
Thank you.
Enjoy your time here.
I also think this is
the best painting here.
I'll buy it then.
I'm sure it'll look wonderful
hanging in the living room.
[Ji Si]
Duan Qiao, three years after your passing
I'm now living a happy life.
But can days without you
be considered a happy life?
Time is like water.
It easily submerges our lives.
That story about angels
stands out the most in my memories.
I once told you Qing Tian is
the angel in my life.
He taught me maturity and love.
Yet, I never imagined
you were the angel in my life.
I can now finally calmly recall
memories of you.
I can also speak of you
without sounding brokenhearted.
I can even last a long time
without thinking of you.
It's only once in a while that
your mischievous smile
will float up from my memories.
Welcome.
It's much like how you liked to
sneak up behind me and hug me tightly.
When I sometimes see a young male
working at a convenience store
my mind would wander a little.
The sorrows I once thought
I would never forget...
and those wounds I thought
would never fade away...
will all be slowly soothed
in the hands of time.
I truly can let go now.
Qing Tian?
You didn't need to come pick me up.
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
Just pretend I am... a longtime friend.
Perhaps there will be someone
who is always in my heart
but I'd have no choice but to
bid farewell to him in my life.
Come, let's all drink.
Thank you, CEO Zheng.
- Thank you.
- Zheng Jr.
CEO Aron.
Your daughter is truly
both beautiful and talented.
Does she have a boyfriend?
- She--
- Yes.
What does he do?
He's in prison.
A civil servant, I presume?
Young and promising!
My son is no match.
Not at all, CEO Zheng.
Please don't say such a joke.
Your son is a fine-looking man.
- Here.
- Cheers.
Let's dig in.
- You--
- Eat.
Eat up.
Let's eat.
Handsome!
- Look, Xiao Si is so gorgeous.
- So handsome!
Being his girlfriend
would make one so happy.
Leave that in your dreams.
He is like a wall,
warding off any who come at him.
Do you still remember
that female colleague next door?
Her confession has failed
for the nth time.
She's so pretty.
Even she would be rejected?
"I suggest you focus on
your work at hand."
"Don't waste your time on me."
He's like a large iceberg.
He's so hard to approach and
rejects all who like him.
Do you think he's gay?
No way!
I think it's possible.
This is our last class.
Regardless of...
how many drawing techniques
I've taught you
you must rely on yourselves
to draw a perfect piece of art.
Sir, do you have any tips for this?
Follow your heart.
That's why...
You must find what
you believe to be most beautiful
and then use art to show everybody
the world you see through your eyes.
Sir, where does
your creative inspiration come from?
Subtitles by DramaFever