All right, everybody,
let's go ahead and start to shut up.
We're gonna jump right
in on the one subject
that brings me a little
bit of joy in Toledo
where I find myself currently trapped...
Taking down my rival Miles.
Now, I had a pretty good idea.
I was thinking maybe we
could hack into his Tesla.
How hard would that be?
I know it's possible.
You think you guys could do that,
or are you guys the kinda nerds
that are good at computers,
or are you the kinda nerds
that smell bad and wear capes?
Uh, you know what? Let's
go ahead a pin in that,
because a cute girl who
actually meets my standards
has swiped right on me.
I don't know if you guys
know what that means,
but basically, it just means
that it's... it's bang time.
Is it going to be happening
here in front of us?
No, Anthony, it's not gonna be happening
in front of you, you little freak!
No, we're gonna go get a drink.
Guys, gotta say...
I got a really good feeling about this one.
Can I get a "get some"?
Get some!
That's my girl! All right!
Um... see ya, dudes.
One, two, three, four!
Now boarding for New York city.
Whoo!
If it's on my license, you know,
they're not gonna want to save me.
- No.
- They're gonna wanna
- harvest my organs.
- Yes!
That's what they want, they want my organs.
Yes, exactly. And I am
not gonna die on the table
so some drunk slob can get my liver.
No, no, no. No, that's not fair.
- No!
- You should have your liver.
It's very good. It's pristine.
- Yeah, exactly.
- Nice...
So, you wanna... head up to your place?
I really like you, Jack.
I just... I just wanna get to
know you a little bit better.
Yeah, sure. More dates.
I'm around.
Cool. Good night.
Good night.
Wake up. We're in Toledo.
Time to go to work.
Now boarding for Cleveland...
Okeydokey, Principal Durbin.
Here are your daily announcements.
- Thank you, Helen.
- You're welcome.
Betty bought butter but the
butter was bitter, so Betty
bought better butter to make
the bitter butter better.
Ah.
The Magazine Drive ends Friday.
O... kay. Oh!
Oh! Text from Jack.
"Running late. Can you
cover for me, bud?"
Called me bud. Helen, you gotta
do the announcements
just this one time, okay?
Oh, no, I can't do that.
I get way too nervous.
I-I was in my cousin's wedding,
and if you've never fainted
mouth-first onto a candle...
it was a nightmare.
I-I actually ate fire.
No, I can't... I can't do that.
Just read off the paper.
It'll be fine, okay?
It'll be so easy.
Jack! You look really bad.
Yeah. Had a... bit of
a rough one last night.
- I had a date in New York.
- Again?
"Ooh, look at me. I'm Jack.
I'm too good for Toledo women."
Well I'm glad you understand.
Look, maybe taking a bus
to New York isn't ideal,
but it's worth it to date a woman
who doesn't believe in angels.
- They're watching over us.
- They help us.
- Don't hate on an...
- You know what?
Wouldn't it be easier
to just come to the bar
with us tonight?
Come on.
Yeah, sure, maybe I should just go ahead
and alienate all of my core principles
and date in Toledo. While I'm at it,
maybe I can eat pie on the toilet.
- I've done that.
- Okay, see,
- don't disrespect pie.
- That's disgusting!
Good morning, Whitlock High.
It's your daily announcements.
It's Meatloaf Day in the cafeteria.
There will be a vegetarian option.
Too bad there's not an edible option.
Oh. Thank you.
Creamed spinach will also be served.
And for dessert... Violent illness.
- Salmonella pie.
- Oh!
The green apple two-trot.
That's... funny. That... Okay.
And now, a special guest
to make your morning announcement.
This is Coach Novak.
There's gonna be
immediate suspension
if anybody's gawking at pornography.
Ha ha. She's really bustin' my chops.
Hey, guys, this was a real kick.
Don't tell anybody that I, you know,
went over my... Aah!
Oh!
Wow. I always thought announcements were...
a way to impart vital information,
but I guess what people like more
are dumb... stupid dumb jokes.
Okay, everybody, I'm here.
Thank you so much for covering.
I really appreciate it. You're the best.
Best? The best at what?
He is an odd little duck.
- So, did you get some?
- Did I get some?
Oh, my God, Heather, thank you for asking,
but, no, I did not get any.
I been commuting to
New York to go on dates,
which is a little bit
complicated, to say the least.
But now, for practical
reasons, I find myself
considering dating in Toledo.
Uh, at the risk of being contrary,
haven't you already dated in Toledo?
Doesn't your high school
ex-girlfriend live here?
Oh, look. It's you.
Wonderful. Good to see you, Marcus. Yes.
Meredith is the exception, you know.
But there's always gonna be an exception.
You see, sophisticated New York women,
they're really more my type.
You guys know what type is, right?
Victor, what's your type?
- Huh?
- Your type.
Who would you wanna get with?
Like... if I could marry anyone?
Yeah, sure, man. Whatever.
Just say who it is.
- I don't wanna say.
- Why not?
Oh... is it something
weird? Is it like somebody
- in your family?
- No!
Is it a big doll? You
could just say who it is,
or I could just keep guessing.
Is it your sister?
- It's her.
- Oh. Cool.
It's somebody who's... in the room.
That's great. We can follow up.
Grace, do you like Victor?
No! That's too bad.
But you know what, it's gotta feel good
to get that off your chest, clear that up.
All right, guys. Good job, everybody.
See ya tomorrow. Grace...
Good job today.
Success!
Oh, look who showed up.
Yeah, well, it was either this
or a 15-hour bus ride to Long Island,
so... it was a toss-up.
Mm-hmm. What the hell are you wearing?
I'm sorry... did you
just come back from court?
Yes. And the judge ruled I look awesome.
Ah!
Well, we're glad you came.
- What are you guys drinkin'?
- Oh, I'm not.
You don't wanna see me drink.
I get really emotional
and clean out my purse.
- It's nuts.
- Oh, well, that was
a long way around "no, thank you."
- Yeah, she does that.
- So, Jack,
here's what we're talking about.
Now, I'm looking to catch
a financially stable man
for a casual yet respectable situationship.
- Hmm.
- And Mary over here
is looking for a scuzzy little liar.
Oh, you always hated Mark.
Well, he stole your computer.
- He's fixing the viruses.
- No, he's not.
I'll tell you what kind of guy I like.
My husband Keith. He's so good to me.
He planted me a secret garden.
I don't know what's in
there. I think it's tomatoes!
- Ha ha ha ha.
- So what are you
- looking for, Jack?
- Well...
this one over by the bar
seems acceptable to me.
- Oh, she's acceptable.
- Oh, yes.
- She will serve my needs nicely.
- Her parents must be so proud.
Stop it, I mean, no, she's... she's cute.
That's our yoga teacher Vicky.
- Ah.
- Okay, we'll go grease
the runway, but you have to land the plane.
Uh... I think I got it.
Okay...
Yeah.
I, uh...
had sex with the Head of Women's Studies,
so I think I can handle Yoga Vicky, right?
Ah...
This is who we were talking about.
Jack is so smart
and has so many sweaters...
So, Jack, we're gonna
go grab another drink.
Will you keep our friend Vicky company?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay.
Hi, Jack. Nice to meet you.
Hi. It's nice to meet you too.
It's, uh... always nice to meet new people.
I just moved here from Cambridge.
That's where Harvard is.
I taught there. At Harvard.
I was a philosophy professor, so...
- Okay.
- At Harvard.
It's a prestigious
university in the Northeast.
I know.
Oh... I have a work emergency.
Oh, a yoga emergency?
Michelle told me where you work.
Well, then you know what this is.
Morning, boss!
Want a little touch-up before we...
Dennis, roll it.
I got a new take.
Okay...
Ahh. Yeah.
Good mornin', Whitlock High!
Here's the morning
announcements in your face!
Ooh!
Guess what's for lunch today. Pizza!
With a side order of hepatitis A.
Ha ha. Cafeteria food.
Sucks! Right?
You know who else has hepatitis A?
Jeremy Jones.
Jeremy will be spending
some time at Children's Hospital,
so everybody sign the big card.
We love you, Jeremy.
Oh! My God, a huge
celebrity just dropped by.
Yo, whazzup?
It's Snoop Da-zoggy Dogg!
Get your tickets
- to the Sadie Hawkins dance.
- What?
I think that's blackface.
Ah, l...
What ya thinkin', chief?
Uh, thanks for asking. I don't know.
I don't know. Last
night, I opened myself up
to dating Toledo women.
You clean up?
One would think.
Uh, no, you know what? I...
I came up empty all night.
You know, I have devoted my entire life
to studying logic and reason, but this...
this night made me
question everything. Truly.
I-I-I
just...
I don't know what... went wrong.
You probably talked about Harvard
- and philosophy too much.
- Sarika...
you may have stumbled onto something there.
Mm-hmm. You're saying that
it was too in their face
how much better I was than them.
That... wasn't really
- what I...
- A preemptive self-rejection.
An interesting concept,
and I think we should
get it on its feet. Victor.
Please, no more...
Is that why you've never confessed
your secret crush on Grace?
Because you're afraid that
she's going to reject you.
You think that you are beneath her.
Please wake up.
- Please wake up.
- Grace, do you think
you could ever be into Victor?
- What's wrong with him?
- I don't want to say.
Oh. You don't wanna say.
Maybe it's you that's into weird stuff.
- Maybe I should start guessing...
- I have a secret boyfriend.
- Is it me?
- It's not a secret
- to the boyfriend.
- Okay, this is good.
Yeah, no, okay, so, um,
Grace, who is the lucky guy?
It's Marcus.
My best friend?
Okay. Well, this has been a
surprisingly productive class.
Thank you, Grace. Thank you, Victor.
This has been very helpful for me.
Good work.
Did you make that at home?
- Yeah, girl.
- I might have to
- sneak in there.
- Hey, guys. Okay,
so I think you were right.
I misplayed it last night.
Oh... ya think?
I get it, I get it. I hashed
it out with my students,
and I realized with my Harvard pedigree,
I was like a Grace in
a bar full of Victors.
But I get it now. Let's get back in there
and let's get after it. I
need you guys to wing me.
- Let's go.
- You gonna take our advice?
Yes!
What was it again?
Just... be normal.
Right. Just... normal.
Why are you saying it weird?
Jack, it's "nermal." Oh, my God,
now I can't say it either.
Sorry, Jack, it's a no.
How 'bout this. I'll buy drinks all night.
- Good answer!
- Here we go.
- Good answer, good answer.
- Normal.
Thank God I got it back.
Whew!
Ooh. Now, there's a sturdy one,
looking like he could
mow his lawn in a tornado.
Well, you better give it up
for these pear-shaped men
- lookin' just like they mamas.
- Mmm...
Hey, hey. What do you guys think?
- Took your advice.
- You know,
mm-mm, I'm sorry, I forgot, ladies.
Was our advice to make him look like
a cell phone salesman from the mall kiosk?
Ha ha ha ha. No, no, no.
This is so the Toledo women
will not be intimidated by me.
Oh, so you think this
is what's normal here?
Yep. Tonight I'm just
normal old Toledo Jack.
Oh, waiter? Yeah. Can I
get a plate of cheese fries
and any kind of a beer
that's got a landscape on the can.
Let's do this!
All right, guys, ready to set me up?
Grease the runway?
No, no, no, no, no, Toledo Jack.
We wants no parts
- of whatever is happening here.
- Right.
But do leave your tab open... thank you.
Yeah, yeah. All right, here we go.
- Good luck.
- Watch him leave.
Look... Look at it. Look at his belt.
Ah... man. Feels good to sit down.
Can I buy you a drink?
Sure, I'll... I'll have another house wine.
Great. Another house wine, please.
Yeah, so...
Isis.
Don't those guys drive you nuts?
You know, for me,
it's like, ah, God, stop, you know?
You make me sick.
Yeah. Isis isn't great.
Yeah. No. It's like, you know...
Ahh... hey.
Are you, uh, an organ donor?
- Yeah, of course.
- Of course you are. Me too.
I would love to be able
to... you know, donate my...
I mean, I don't wanna die, but if I did,
I wanna give some kid the
gift of sight, you know?
Maybe I would get to see the world
through a child's eyes again.
Is that how it works? I don't know.
I'm just some normal
guy. I don't read much.
- ♪ I love gin juice ♪
- That is funny.
♪ Drivin' in my car ♪
♪ Gin juice ♪
Is there anything that
I can do before I go?
No, uh, Helen, I think you've done enough.
- Ralph, is there something...
- Could you close the door?
Can you do that, Helen?
Can you close the door?
Or is that too simple? Do you need to
put like a fun spin on it.
Or can I have. The door. Closed.
Which is... all I ever... wanted?
See how easy that was?
- Oh, no.
- Excellent.
I'm doing this!
- This place sucks.
- Please.
Did you think that wearing a golf shirt
and talking about organ donors would work?
You know what I think?
I think you're afraid
you'll meet someone and like Toledo.
Ooh! Michelle, comin'
through with the realness.
Yes, and you know what? And
while you're "slumming" it
- with the commoners...
- Here we go.
You're missing out on some fabulous women.
- Okay?
- Truth bomb.
All right, well, thank
you for the therapy, buds,
I appreciate it, but
I'm done with this place.
Oh, stay! We're gonna get some fire wings
and do pucker shots.
Plus, Michelle is drinking,
and so we might need a white
man to talk to the cops.
Well, this was fun, but I think I'm gonna
- close out my tab. Sorry, guys.
- Oh...
Hey, can I close out, please? Thanks.
Not a single imported beer.
God, I forgot I'm in Garbage City.
It's actually Glass City.
Yeah, no thanks.
I'm good. I don't need to
update my cell phone plan.
Oh, no, no, these clothes...
I'm doing a social experiment.
I'm actually just in
town for a brief stint.
I'm taking a break from Harvard.
- Oh.
- Yeah, you know what?
Forget that.
I-I'm Jack.
I take it you're not
from around here either?
Chloe. From Baltimore.
Yeah, I can see that you enjoy this city
about as much as I do.
- It's the worst.
- Yeah.
Oh, don't even try getting decent sushi.
- What?
- It's impossible.
You know what I worry about? I worry about
the doctors. I mean, if you're
actually good at surgery,
what are you doing
here? I mean, how did you
not move to Chicago?
Well, at least the people are amazing.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah, right? I mean
like that guy over there
with his gut hanging out?
He just invited me to his
summer home in Provence.
- Oh! You gonna go?
- Oh, I have to.
- I think you should.
- How do you turn that down?
Check this out. See da Vinci over there?
Yeah, he just invited me to check out
this crazy new invention
that he's never even tried called "a fork."
We shouldn't be too hard on this place.
- No.
- Right? I mean, after all,
there is a table of
scientists right over there.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Ugh! They're brilliant.
Booyah! These shots are
not gonna drink themselves.
Hey, you wanna get outta here
before the dumb rubs off on us?
Uh, uh...
I think they're just having fun.
And, uh, actually,
they're friends of mine.
Right! My friend is here too.
Right over there. She's the lady
that brought her newborn to the bar.
Busties!
Yeah, first of all, you really know
how to run a joke into the ground.
Secondly, I wasn't kidding.
They really are friends of mine.
You know what? No. I'm
gonna keep this open.
Can I get three blue pucker shots, please?
Uh, actually... make it four.
Also...
Baltimore... It's a third-rate city.
It sucks. And you have dead
women buried in your parks.
- Ladies, some shots.
- Hey!
It looks like you were making
it happen with that one.
What'd you mess up this time?
Who knows? But it looked like you guys
were having more fun over
here, so I figured I join you
- and stay.
- Okay!
- All right!
- Hey, hey!
- Mm.
- Yeah!
Tornado Dance!
- Yeah...
- Uh...
excuse you?
- Yeah?
- No, no, no, no, no.
Sorry. Sorry, that's on us.
It's not worth it, girl, it's not worth it.
Walk away.
Oops. It looks like there's
a little lighting issue.
There's a shadow. You want me to fix that?
Yeah, sure, Helen. Why don't you just
- take over the whole production?
- I can't take this anymore!
What is this about, Ralph?
Dennis, a moment.
You really don't know
what this is about, do you?
Morning announcements were my chance
to be the cool guy,
to connect with the students,
and you took them from me!
Oh, Ralph, why would I ever
do anything to hurt you?
You pulled me up from the gutter.
You're an amazing man.
I would never take the
announcements from you.
Well, it's too late.
I'm awake now, Helen.
I thought I had this game cornered,
then you came in and did it in a way
that I didn't know what possible!
- I'm a fraud.
- No.
- You should do them!
- Oh! I should do them.
Ha! You think that's
what people want?
Me runnin' around
like a big, dumb goof?
I do that crap for my
nephew, and he's five.
Forever, if you know what I mean.
Holy crap. Is that thing on?
Oh...
I don't understand what they see in you.
Well... this is fun!
Who, uh, who started all this?
- You!
- Me?
Well, this is already awesome.
- Explain.
- When you revealed
that Victor liked Grace, we also found out
she had a secret boyfriend, Marcus.
But she was actually protecting
her real secret boyfriend, Devin,
not realizing Marcus is
secretly dating Sarika,
who got super-jealous.
So Sarika decided to revenge-date Devin.
But Devin is fluid, so
he may actually like me.
And unrelatedly, Colin lost his retainer
and is afraid to tell his mom,
and no one is talking to
anyone, a-and we're drowning!
Colin, you need to just tell your mom.
Okay, hey, guys, guys, guys.
Wow! You are being far too dramatic.
I mean, don't you realize how meaningless
these little teenage crushes are?
Come on, only adult romances
actually mean anything.
Look, the point is, you should
all just be focused on your friendships.
Don't worry about all
this petty dating stuff.
Okay? You should all be
downing shots together
and doing dances based on
natural disasters, you know?
Leave all this other crap behind, you know?
Otherwise, you're just gonna be
stuck in Toledo goin' it alone.
Look, you're gonna have your whole lives
to worry about dating, 'kay?
Right now, honestly, you should probably
just be focused on masturbating.
You guys all masturbate, right?
Yeah?
Show of hands real quick.
Oh, no...
Yeah, that's tough. That's tough.
I noticed you weren't entangled
in any of the love triangles.
You prefer to stay above the fray.
I don't mess with this kid stuff.
I'm looking for a real woman.
Oh, [BLEEP].
Synced and corrected by louvette
www.addic7ed.com