[ Indistinct Whispering ]
Hmm?
[ Bleats ]
♫ Time of our lives, wonder of surprise
♫ The open blue skies
♫ Reflecting in our eyes
♫ In a perfect place, see the sunny days
♫ Coming into view
♫ 'Cause every day feels
like summer with you
♫ Everything feels right starting anew
♫ Every day feels like summer with you
♫ Oh
♫ Once you were here
my worries disappeared
♫ It all became clear
♫ Nothing left to fear
♫ Beyond any price, pure as paradise
♫ Coming into view
♫ 'Cause every day feels
like summer with you
♫ Everything feels right starting anew
♫ Every day feels like summer with you
♫ Oh ♫
[ Camera Shutter Clicks ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Clucking ]
[ Thuds ]
[ Crowing ]
[ Yawning ]
Mmm.
[ Alarm Ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Groans ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Mimicking Fonzie ] Aaay!
[ Squealing With Delight ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Blowing Whistle ]
[ Sheep Moaning ]
[ Whistle Blowing Shrilly ]
Baa!
[ Bleating ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Rooster Crowing ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Blows Whistle ]
Ugh!
[ Sheep Groaning ]
Ew!
[ Rooster Crowing ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Muffled Whistling ]
[ Panting ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Farting ]
[ Yawning ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Bones Cracking ]
[ Groaning ]
Ah.
[ Whirring ]
[ Bleating Fearfully ]
[ Farmer Grunting ]
Meeeh!
Oh!
[ Chuckles ]
[ Snorting Gleefully ]
[ Mutters ]
Meeeh!
[ Sighs ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Harumphs ]
[ Rooster Crowing ]
[ Feedback ]
[ Crunching ]
Ew.
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Groans ]
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
Mmm-hmm.
[ Bleating Rapidly ]
[ All Bleating ]
[ Quacks ]
[ Whistling Tune ]
[ Scoffs ]
[ Softly ] Baa!
[ Coos ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Blowing ]
Huh? [ Sniffs ]
[ Gasps ]
♫ You're mine
[ Slurping ]
♫ Oh, baby
[ Barks ]
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
[ Groans ]
[ Whistles ]
Ah! Hey!
[ Shouts and Mutters Indistinctly ]
Meeeh!
[ Flock Bleating ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Muttering Angrily ]
[ Whistles ]
[ Bleats ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Yawning ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Giggling ]
Shh!
[ All Shushing ]
[ Bitzer Barking ]
Hmm. Hmm.
A-ha!
[ Continues Snoring ]
[ Shaun Gasping ]
Phew!
[ All Cheering ]
[ Whooping ]
[ Bleats ]
Whoo-hoo!
[ Whistling ]
[ Crackling ]
[ Muffled Explosion ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Bleating Softly ]
[ Cowboy Music Playing ]
[ Sighs Happily ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Snoring Loudly ]
[ Growls ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Vehicle Creaking ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
[ All Gasping ]
[ Timmy Squealing Gleefully ]
[ Muttering Angrily ]
[ Spits ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Cawing ]
Meeeh!
[ Growling ]
Hmm?
Baa?
[ People Screaming ]
Huh?
[ Squawking ]
Ahhh!
[ Mooing ]
[ Car Alarm Blaring ]
[ Squeals ]
[ Scoffs ]
[ Humming ]
[ Crossing Signal Clanging ]
[ Train Horn Blowing ]
[ Yawning ]
Whoo!
[ Cockroaches Choking ]
Huh?
Oh! [ Laughs ] Hey!
[ Tyres Squealing ]
[ Bicycle Bell Rings ]
[ Man Screaming ]
Huh?
Ahhh!
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Horns Honking ]
Huh?
[ People Muttering ]
[ Whistles ]
[ Muttering In Confusion ]
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Siren Blaring ]
[ Bleats ]
[ Muffled Music Playing ]
[ Loud Rock Music Playing ]
♫ Get your rocks off,
get your rocks off, honey
♫ Shake it now now, get 'em off downtown
♫ Get your rocks off... ♫
[ Bleating ]
[ Moans ]
Hmm.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Engine Starting ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Crashing ]
Ooh!
Whoa!
[ Mooing ]
[ Crowing ]
[ Clucking ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Farmer ] Ooh. Hey. Oh!
[ Panting ]
Hey, hey! Hey, hey, hey.
Uh-uh.
[ Sighs ]
[ All Muttering ]
Hmm.
- What?
Oh!
[ Laughing ]
[ Muttering ]
Hmm. Yeah.
Yeah?
Nah.
[ Doctor ] Yeah? Yeah?
[ Farmer ] Uh...
[ Doctor Mutters Questioningly ]
[ Mutters Unsurely ]
Hmm.
Huh?
- No.
[ Whispering ]
[ Both Muttering ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Quacking ]
[ Chaotic Squawking and Squealing ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Flock Bleating ]
Hey!
[ All Bleating ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sighing ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Glass Shatters ]
[ All Bleating ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Sheep Cheering ]
[ ♫ Feels Like Summer by Tim Wheeler ]
[ Turns Music Off ]
[ Song Resumes Playing ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Indistinct Announcement Over PA ]
[ Calling Out ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ People Clapping ]
[ Man ] Whoo-hoo!
Oh! [ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
Hmm?
[ Barks ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Yelping ]
[ Bleats ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Radio ] ♫ You've got to search
for the hero inside yourself
♫ Search for the secrets you hide... ♫
[ Sniffing ]
[ Sheep Bleating ]
Huh?
[ Bleating ]
[ Humming ]
[ Sheep ] Shh.
[ Trumper Clears Throat ]
[ Gasps Softly ]
[ Gulps ]
Uh...
[ Clicks Tongue ]
[ Chuckles ]
Phew!
[ Chuckling ]
Shh!
- Shh!
[ All Shushing ]
Shh! Shh!
[ Whistling ]
Huh?
[ Sniffing ]
Ha!
Hmm?
[ Sighs ]
[ Door Banging ]
Huh?
[ Gasps ]
[ Lift Bell Dings ]
Phew!
[ Exclaims ]
[ Monitor Beeping ]
Um...
[ Nurse Mutters ]
Huh?
Shall we?
[ Retches ]
Uh...
Hmm.
Huh?
Huh? [ Gasps ]
[ Panicked Muttering ]
[ Gas Hissing ]
[ Inaudible ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Sighs ]
Hmm.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Inaudible ]
Huh?
[ Gasps ] Ah!
♫ You're mine
♫ Oh, baby
[ Slurping ]
♫ Yeah
[ Nurse Gasps ]
[ Surgical Staff ] Oh!
♫ Mine
♫ Yeah ♫
Eh?
[ Alarm Buzzing ]
Hmm?
[ Door Bangs ]
[ Humming ]
[ Panicked Muttering ]
Hmm.
♫ In a city this big
it's easy to not exist
♫ But that's a problem
you don't seem to get
♫ When you roll like this
♫ You left home a short time ago
but it seems so long
♫ We've only seen this in magazines
and it looked like fun
♫ Every doubletake, every false start,
every wrong move we make
♫ Start again, never at the end
It's a risk we take
♫ Scary things happen right here
all day and night
♫ But who cares when you look like us
you're gonna be all right
♫ We won't come this far
to get nothing back
♫ You can't stop us getting what we want
♫ We will find what we want in the city
♫ And we're really
fitting in around here
♫ We're feeling pretty hot in the city
♫ From the way we walk
the walk is pretty clear
♫ We're making it in the big city
♫ And you know
it's always gonna throw it down
♫ Down, down
So step aside, people, we're coming
♫ 'Cause we pretty much own this town
♫ This, this, this town
Yeah
♫ We're looking at you
but it's like you're with someone else
♫ In the heart of the city
we could easily lose ourselves
♫ In between making us sing,
we gotta see this through
♫ We can't stop to make it to the top,
got a job to do
♫ We won't come this far
to get nothing back
♫ You can't stop us getting what we want
♫ Ooh, yeah
♫ We're making it in the big city
♫ And we're really
fitting in around here ♫
[ Screaming ]
[ Yelling ]
Uh-oh!
[ Grunting ]
[ Both Grunting ]
♫ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♫
Phew.
[ Timmy Chuckling ]
[ Laughter and Lively Conversation ]
[ Sheep ] Ooh! Ooh!
[ Stomachs Rumbling ]
Hmm.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Playing Lively Tune ]
Ha!
Oh!
Hmm.
[ Tapping ]
Oh. Mmm-hmm.
Mmm!
[ Muttering ]
[ Both ] Mmm.
Mmm-mmm!
Psst. [ Muttering ]
Um...
A-ha!
Hmm.
[ Slurping ]
[ Water Splashing ]
[ Grunting Thoughtfully ]
[ Sheep Grunting Thoughtfully ]
Oh!
[ Cutlery Clattering ]
[ Groans ]
[ Burps Softly ]
[ Muttering ] No, no, no!
[ Sheep Burping Loudly ]
[ People Gasping ]
Shh!
[ Long Burp Continues ]
[ Woman Gasps ]
Shh!
[ Burps ]
[ Chuckles Awkwardly ]
[ Humming Nonchalantly ]
[ Hooves Pattering ]
Oh!
[ Gasps ]
[ Bleating ]
Hmm. [ Mutters ]
[ Bleating Frantically ]
Ooh! [ Giggles ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Timmy Hiccups ]
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Chuckles ]
Whoa! [ Giggles ]
[ Woman Gasps ]
[ Stops Playing Piano ]
[ Frantic Muttering ]
[ Man Laughing ]
[ Dialling ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Man ] Hey!
[ Glass Shattering ]
[ Playing Fast-Paced Chase Music ]
[ Shouting In Kitchen ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Yelps ]
[ Angry Muttering ]
Ow!
[ Gasps ]
[ People Screaming Inside ]
[ Laughing Wickedly ]
Hmm.
[ Scattered Applause ]
[ Chuckles ]
Oh.
[ Gasps ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Clicks Tongue ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Whistling ]
[ Engine Starting ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Bleating Frantically ]
[ Yells ]
[ Whimpering ]
Aw!
[ Gasps ]
Mmm-mmm.
- Oh!
[ Both Gasping ]
[ Both Muttering ]
Hmm.
Mmm.
Huh?
[ Scoffs ]
[ Muttering ]
No.
No!
[ Snaps Fingers ] Ahem!
Huh?
[ Screaming ]
[ Shrieking ]
Ahhh!
[ High-Pitched Scream ]
[ Gurgling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Farmer Grunting ]
Oh!
[ Muttering Angrily ]
Hey.
Hey!
[ Laughing ]
[ All Sighing In Relief ]
Oh!
Huh?
[ Giggles ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Giggling ]
Ooh!
- Ooh!
[ Muttering ]
Uh-uh-uh.
- Oh!
Oh-ho! [ Chuckling ]
Oh!
- Hmm. [ Giggling ]
[ Fans Squealing Excitedly ]
[ Shutter Clicks ]
[ Dogs Howling ]
[ Door Buzzes Open ]
[ Gulps ]
[ ♫ Jailhouse Blues Harmonica Playing ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Shudders ]
[ Growling ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Mimicking Hannibal Lecter ]
[ Trumper Muttering ]
[ Bleats ]
[ Growling ]
[ Growling Gets Louder ]
[ Yawns ]
[ Bleats ]
Huh? Ruff?
[ Dog Barking In Distance ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Growling In Frustration ]
[ Radio ] ♫ She could tell right away
that I was bad to the bone
♫ Bad to the bone
- Got you.
[ Chuckling ]
♫ B-b-b-b-bad
♫ Bad to the bone
[ Yelling ]
♫ I broke a thousand hearts
♫ Before I met you
♫ I'll break a thousand more, baby
- Hmm.
[ Yelling ]
♫ Before I am... ♫
[ Bleats ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts In Frustration ]
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Exaggerated Yawn ]
Hmm.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Woman ] Hmm.
[ Buzzer Sounding ]
[ Meows ]
Hmm.
- Hmm.
[ Man Chuckles ]
[ Sniffs ]
Mmm.
Hmm.
- Mmm-mmm.
[ Growling ]
[ Chuckling ]
Hmm.
- That one?
[ Both ] Ew!
[ Man ] Oh!
[ Gate Opening ]
Oh!
Aw.
[ Footsteps Receding ]
[ Blows Raspberry ]
[ Snarling ]
Hmm.
[ Croaks ]
[ Buzzer Sounding ]
[ Chuckles Softly ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Mobile Phone Chimes ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Phones Ringing ]
♫ I'm a wonderful thing, baby
♫ Such a, such a
♫ Wonderful
♫ I'm a wonderful thing, baby
♫ Such a, such a
[ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
♫ I'm a wonderful thing, baby ♫
[ Muttering ]
Oh!
[ Door Clanging ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Dog Howling ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Mockingly ] Baa!
Baa. [ Laughing ]
[ Snorting ]
[ Growling ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Trumper Chomping ]
[ Farts ]
[ Shaun Straining ]
[ Doorbell Ringing ]
Oh!
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Cat Meowing ]
[ Gasps ]
Hmm?
Oh! [ Mutters ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Growling ]
[ Timmy Chuckling ]
[ Groaning ]
Tsk!
[ Muttering ]
Shh.
Mmm!
[ Grunting ]
[ Rumbling ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Tinny Music In Headphones ]
[ Confused Bleating ]
[ Bleats ]
[ Alarm Ringing ]
[ Bleating Hysterically ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Sheep Bleating ]
[ Clangs ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Grunts ]
Hmm.
Hmm!
[ Door Opening ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Grunts ]
Huh?
[ Bleats ]
[ Roars ]
[ Both Howling ]
[ Howling ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Slip Whistles ]
Hmm?
[ Chuckles ]
[ Exclaims Happily ]
[ Growling ]
[ Yelling ]
Hmm?
[ Giggling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Barks ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Cheering ]
[ All Cheering ]
Hmm.
[ Barks ]
[ Bleats ]
[ All ] Whoo-hoo!
Ahhh!
[ Deep Bleating Echoes ]
[ Grunts ]
Hmm.
[ Trimmer Whirring ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Farmer Chuckling ]
Oh!
Baa?
Oh.
[ Stammering ] Shoo! Shoo!
[ Gasps ]
Oh!
[ Farmer ] Whoa!
[ Both Gasping ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Bleating ]
Shoo! Shoo!
[ Mutters ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Bleating ]
Shoo!
[ Manhole Cover Clangs ]
♫ Wish I were with you
♫ But I couldn't stay
[ Barking ]
♫ Every direction leads me away
♫ All I want
♫ Is to be home
♫ Stand in the mirror
♫ You look the same
♫ Just looking for shelter
♫ From the cold and the pain
♫ And all I want
♫ Is to be home ♫
[ Siren Wailing In Distance ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Gasps ]
Ahem.
[ Trumper Grunting ]
Argh!
[ Grunts ]
[ Powering Up ]
[ Both Gasping ]
[ Laughs Wickedly ]
Yeah.
[ Timmy Sobbing ]
♫ Every day feels like summer with you
[ Stops Sobbing ]
♫ Everything feels right starting anew
♫ Every day feels like summer with you ♫
[ Bleats Happily ]
[ Music Slows and Distorts ]
Hmm?
[ Whimpers ]
[ Timmy Sobbing ]
[ Whistling Feels Like Summer ]
[ Sighs Happily ]
[ Continues Whistling Song ]
[ Humming Along In Deep Voice ]
♫ Baa
[ All singing In Harmony ] ♫ Baa
[ All Humming Feels Like Summer ]
[ Whistling Along ]
[ Beatboxing ]
[ Singing Continues ]
Hmm?
[ Thuds ]
[ Lip-Syncing ]
[ Squeals Happily ]
Shh.
[ All ] Shh!
[ Door Opens ]
[ Woman ] Ooh!
Ahem.
[ Grunts ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ ♫ Mysterious Vocalising With Harp ]
[ ♫ Vocalising Continues ]
[ Music Stops ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Bitzer ] Hmm?
[ Gasps ]
[ Barks ]
[ Inaudible ]
[ Both Gasp ]
[ Sniffs ]
Ugh!
[ All Bleating ]
Baa!
- Mmm?
[ Exclaims In Disappointment ]
[ Bottle Clinking ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Neighs ]
[ All Bleating ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Yelling ]
Baa!
[ All Grunting ]
[ Rhythmic Thudding ]
Baa!
[ Grunting ]
[ Cloth Ripping ]
Huh?
Oh!
[ Bleating ]
[ Yawns ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Trumper Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Farmer Yawns ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Hooves Clopping ]
[ Farmer Snoring ]
[ Bleats ]
[ All Bleating ]
[ Clopping Resumes ]
Yeah.
[ Grunting ]
Huh?
[ Farmer Mutters ]
[ Snores ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Neighs ]
Oh!
[ Farmer Muttering ]
Hmm. [ Clears Throat ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Muttering ]
Hey!
Huh?
Whoa!
[ Yelps ]
Uh-oh.
[ Trumper Yelling ]
[ All Bleating ]
Hyah!
[ Trumper ] Ow!
Baa!
[ All Exclaiming ]
Oh.
[ Screaming ]
[ Car Honking ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Trumper Continues Screaming ]
Yeah!
Huh?
[ Clangs ]
Ow!
Ahhh!
[ Panting ]
[ Yelling ]
[ All Cheering ]
[ Tyres Screeching ]
[ Timmy Squeals ]
[ All Exclaiming ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Groans ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Trumper Groaning ]
[ Snarling ]
[ TV Playing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Farmer Groans ]
[ Both Squeal ]
[ Squeals ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Distant Yelling ]
[ Barks ]
[ Bleating In Fear ]
[ Shaun ] Shh!
Baa!
[ All Bleating ]
[ Shouting ]
Arf!
[ Fearful Bleating ]
Shh! Shh.
[ Snoring ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
Ahh!
[ Farmer Grunting ]
[ Engine Starting ]
[ All Bleating ]
[ Laughs Evilly ]
[ Yelling ]
Mmm.
Ooh!
[ Bleating ]
[ Groans ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Coughs ] Ugh!
Huh?
[ All ] Baa!
[ Yelling ]
[ Screaming ]
[ All ] Ahhh!
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunting ]
[ All Whimpering ]
[ Mutters ]
Aw!
Aw.
[ All Bleating ]
[ Muttering Angrily ]
[ Laughing Evilly ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Whistles ]
Whoa!
[ Farmer ] Ahh!
[ Gasps ]
[ Yells ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Whirring ]
[ Yells ]
Baa!
Whoo!
[ Cheering ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Shaun Yells ]
[ Laughs Evilly ]
[ Gasps ]
Ah! [ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles ]
Aw!
[ Bleating Happily ]
Oh.
[ Teeth Crunching ]
Hey!
[ Growling ]
Hey! Hey!
[ Yelling ]
[ Mumbling ]
[ Bull Snorting ]
[ Trumper ] Ahhh!
Ahhh!
[ Continues Screaming ]
[ Stops Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Muffled Grunting ]
[ All Laughing ]
Oh. Oh.
Oh.
Oh!
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Both Chuckling ]
[ Door Opens ]
Huh?
[ All Laughing ]
[ Clearing Throats ]
[ Both Muttering ]
[ Slip Barking Animatedly ]
Oh.
Mmm.
[ Crowing ]
Heeey!
[ Alarm Ringing ]
Ah!
[ Birds Twittering ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
Arf.
[ All Cheering ]
Oh. [ Laughs ]
[ Grunting ]
[ All ] Baa!
[ Chuckling ]
Oh.
[ Bitzer Growls ]
Oh!
[ Farmer Laughing ]
♫ 'Cause every day
♫ Feels like summer with you
♫ Everything feels right starting anew
♫ Every day feels like summer with you
♫ Oh
♫ Once you were here
♫ My worries disappeared
♫ It all became clear
♫ Nothing left to fear
♫ You have got my back
♫ Keeping me on track
♫ Like you always do
♫ 'Cause every day
♫ Feels like summer with you
♫ Everything feels right starting anew
♫ Every day feels like summer with you
♫ Oh
[ Laughing ]
[ TV News Report Playing ]
♫ Hey, yo, Shaun,
you ready to kick it with us, man?
[ Shaun ] Baa!
♫ That's what I thought
♫ Let's take this up another level
♫ Oh, yeah
♫ You ready?
[ Shaun ] Baa!
♫ All right, let's go Rizzle Kicks, yeah
♫ Yo! What you know
about Shaun the Sheep?
♫ Peeps hang on the words he Bleats
♫ Like, yo, best thing you heard
Best in the herd
♫ Count on him but don't fall asleep
♫ What you know about living in a barn?
♫ Shaun be the joker spinning that yarn
♫ Got them lyrics
Kicking them bars
♫ If you're with it, Shaun
♫ For Shaun the Sheep
♫ He's Shaun the Sheep
♫ He even mucks about
with those who cannot Bleat
♫ Keep it in mind, he's one of a kind
♫ Oh! Life's a treat
with Shaun the Sheep
♫ He's Shaun the Sheep
He's Shaun the Sheep
♫ He doesn't miss a trick
or ever lose a beat
♫ Perhaps one day, you'll find a way
♫ To come and meet with Shaun the Sheep
♫ Oh, yeah!
♫ Oozing with character
♫ His baa is hard to beat
What?
♫ From England to Africa
♫ You can't not love this sheep
What?
♫ Round the world, he travelled far
♫ And gee, he makes me proud
What?
♫ King amongst the herd
Oh, they should give him a crown
♫ [ Shaun ] Baa!
Who's that?
♫ He's Shaun the Sheep
♫ He's not afraid to make
the intellectual leap
♫ Oxford Uni
For brains and guile
♫ Oh, yeah?
With a wink and a smile
♫ You can't compete with Shaun the Sheep
Oh, no way
♫ La, la, la, la
La, la, la, la
Sheep
♫ La, la, la, la
♫ La, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la
Tell 'em.
Let's go!
♫ Oh, yeah!
♫ Whoo!
We rock, kid
♫ For Shaun the Sheep
La, la, la, la
♫ He even mucks about
with those who cannot Bleat
♫ La, la, la, la
♫ Keep it in mind
♫ He's one of a kind
♫ Oh! Life's a treat
with Shaun the Sheep
♫ Yeah!
♫ He's Shaun the Sheep
He's Shaun the Sheep
♫ He doesn't miss a trick
or ever lose a beat
♫ Perhaps one day you'll find a way
♫ To come and meet with Shaun the Sheep
♫ Oh! Come and Bleat
with Shaun the Sheep
♫ [ Shaun ] Baa!
Yo!
[ Digital Animal Game Bleeping ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Door Opens and Closes ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Inserts Plug and Clicks Switch ]
[ Hoover Whirring ]