Oh, God.
Well, what the hell happened?
- We're an old married couple.
- Mmm-hmm.
Was it the pot?
I don't think so, because we
brought it with us from New York.
- Yeah.
- It's the same.
What was that..
What was that old movie?
You know, Blame it on Rio.
It has to be that,
it has to be that.
You got to feel my heart.
Are you going to make
it till dinnertime?
After dinnertime.
Oh, God.
God, I'd love to live like this.
Yeah.
I'm willing, if you have enough money to
stay in Brazil for the rest of our lives.
I'll think about it.
Okay.
Do you think that's
it, being away?
- Yeah.
Hey, babe.
Where did you go?
Don't do this to yourself.
Everything is wonderful.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
I don't feel like such a fuck-up
when I'm here, that's all.
- Good luck.
- See you in a bit.
I love you.
Okay.
Don't touch anything. Don't
say anything. Back up.
Turn off the lights.
Turn them off.
Are you.. Don't even
think about the buzzer.
Get in the corner.
Is the cash in here? Open it up.
Open it up!
Quicker. Get over here. Get over here.
You want me to fucking shoot you?
Open it up. Open it up.
Get over in the corner. Get over
in the corner. Keep your hands down.
Keep your fucking hands down.
All right?
Come over here. Get over
here so I can see you.
Come over here. Stand at the corner.
Come over here.
Put your hands down.
Oh, shit! Is this all
you got in here?
I'm watching.. Stay away from
the fucking buzzer, all right.
Fucking shit, it's all she..
Get back in your corner.
Get back in your fucking..
Get back in your corner!
All right, keep your hands down by
your side, all right. I'm watching you.
I will shoot you, all right. I'll
fucking shoot you in a second.
This is all shit.
Diamonds.
Where's the fucking
keys for this case?
Where's the.. Where are
the keys for this case?
- In the drawer.
- Shut up, all right.
These are them? Don't
fucking move, all right.
Don't move.
What, are they all the same?
Are they?
Fucking stupid bitch.
I'm watching you.
Which fucking key.. Which fucking..
This is bullshit!
What the fuck is up..
What type of glass is this..
Fuck is up with this glass?
Fuck this..
Bullshit.
Fuck, no.
Fuck you, you motherfucking
stupid fuck.
Fuck.
My gun.
Fuck! Andy!
Hank, you're so stupid!
Fucking Andy!
Shit.
Hey, two for four.
You're batting.500.
No, Dad, the second
one was an air..
- No, no. It was a perfectly placed bunt.
- Good game, sweetheart.
- Good game.
- How many you got?
Yeah, who's going
to want seconds?
Uncle Andy, can I
have another hot dog?
Yeah, the way you played today,
I'll buy you the whole stand.
No, her mother doesn't want
her eating junk, all right?
That's not junk, that's all right.
That's a hot dog, right, honey?
What do I owe you?
Hey, Hank, your money
is no good here.
No, I got it, okay.
- I got it.
- You sure?
- That was a good game.
- Yeah.
Hey, give me a kiss.
Give me a kiss.
- All right. I'll see you next weekend?
- I love you.
All right, be good.
Here's your ball.
- You didn't feed her junk, did you?
- No, of course not.
I don't want her to develop
bad eating habits.
- She looks puffy.
- She doesn't look puffy, all right.
- You look puffy.
- Fuck you.
- She wore sun block?
- It was cloudy, Martha.
There are rays, Hank.
Hey, you got my money?
Oh, Christ, Martha. Do you have any
idea what that school is costing me?
You're the one who wanted
to send her there.
Yeah, because it is a damn good
school and she wanted to go there.
- You owe me three months.
- I don't owe you.
- I owe Danielle.
- Don't get semantic.
- Bye.
- April, May and June.
No, I promise, all right.
What's up, Hank?
Piece of shit!
Fuck you. All right. Can I
borrow your cell phone?
I don't have one.
- Just..
- It's brain cancer. There's a pay phone
- over there by the bathroom.
- No, it can wait.
What's happening with you?
I used to think you had
the world by the balls.
Now, I'm not sure if
you even got any.
I got them when I
need them, all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, smart and funny.
What I always admired
about you, your wit.
- You're a prick, Andy.
- I always was.
- So, let's see if there're any left.
- What?
Cojones.
Well, you need money. So do I.
Let's solve it.
- What are you talking about?
- Well, there's a place we can knock off.
Know it like the back of our hand.
Easiest money you'll ever get.
What are you saying?
It's worth about 600 grand.
And it's insured, so
it's a victimless crime.
I offer that in case your faggoty
little conscience bothers you.
I weigh it off on 20
cents on the dollar.
That's 60 grand each.
Give or take.
I can't believe this
is you that's talking.
Believe it.
So, it's safe, nobody gets hurt,
everybody wins. It's perfect.
Why?
What do..
- Do you need money?
- Of course, I need money. But this is..
This is serious crime, Andy. I'm not a
serious crime kind of a guy. I got a kid..
You've got shit.
You have a whole lot of shit.
You said so yourself.
All the time. Every day.
You know what? It's not as
serious as you might think.
You're my little brother.
Now, trust me.
God, Andy.
That's why you called me up?
That's why you wanted to
spend the night together,
- talk me into something crazy?
- That's why I called you up.
Talk you into something crazy.
Well, what's the place?
No, not another word
till you commit.
Fuck.
It's all right.
So, how's the wife?
Hey, Hank.
Hey, I got an appointment.
- I'll be back in a few, all right.
- Of course, you will. It's Thursday.
- You're early.
- Well..
You know my days are so busy.
Just tell me that
you'll think about it.
But I thought about it already.
And I came to the conclusion
that you're crazy.
I'm going to go where with you?
I mean, you've got
child support.
You've got Danielle's school,
you've got the rent..
- The mortgage..
- Come on.
- ..you're up to your ears in debt, Hank.
- I can solve all that. I know I can.
When are you going
to grow up, Hank?
We have a really
good thing going,
and you should just enjoy it.
We have a really good time in bed.
I don't ask for anything.
I love you. I want more.
So does Oliver Twist.
Can I help you to seconds?
Or do you really, really,
really have to get back?
Huh?
"The weight of this sad
time we must obey."
"Speak what we feel and not
what we ought to say."
"The oldest hath borne most."
"We that are young shall
never see so much,"
Bravo! Bravo!
You were great. I'm
so proud of you.
You were wonderful.
Grandpa and I thought
you were wonderful.
Excuse me, I'm sorry. It's just..
I have to have your autograph.
- Dad. No.
- What, you were incredible.
- No, stop it.
- What?
- I messed up some of my lines.
- No, you didn't. I didn't notice.
- Did you notice?
- I didn't notice at all.
Honey, you were great. What?
Mom, can I go see The
Lion King this weekend?
- There's a class trip, everyone's going.
- Did you ask your father?
- Can I, Dad?
- Yeah, sure. I got some money.
Well, it's $130.
But we're staying overnight and
that includes hotel and everything.
Okay, great. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Hey, man. Can I talk to you?
- Where are you?
- I'm down the hall, by the coffee.
- How about my office, 30 seconds?
- All right.
Hank, the super at 111 Riverside
says the boiler's really kaput.
He needs you to.. Hello?
So?
- That place that you were talking about.
- What place?
- The one that we were going to..
- To knock off?
Yeah.
To rob?
You say it.
Tell me about it.
I'm not going to tell you about
it until you say you're in
and once you say it,
there's no way out.
I'm in.
Let me see your hands.
- Just say it again,
- What're you talking about?
Just say it again,
I'm in.
What?
I just wanted to see if you were pulling
any of that chickenshit baby stuff
like when we were
kids, you know,
"It doesn't count. I had
my fingers crossed."
I'm in. What're we doing?
- And when?
- It's a jewelry store.
- Does this ring a bell?
- No.
What if I tell you it's got
a Foot Locker on one side and a
Claire's Accessories on the other.
Yeah, that's right. You got it.
Now, listen.
We don't want Tiffany's. We
want a Mom and Pop operation,
in a busy place,
on a Saturday when the
week's takes go in the safe.
We both worked there. We
know the safe combinations.
We know the burglar alarm signals.
We know where everything is.
I figure, between
the week's take,
the jewelry and the cases, the
vault, there's a $500,000 haul.
I figure probably six.
That old dumb old lady that works
there, she's alone till noon.
She's not going to be a problem.
Andy.
Yeah?
That's Mom and Dad's store.
That's what I said.
A Mom and Pop operation.
- You can't do that.
- Yeah, we can. Think about it.
It's perfect. It's perfect.
In and out in a minute.
Insurance takes care of Mom and
Dad, so they're not hurt. Right?
No one's going to give a shit.
After a week the cops
- will put it in the back of the filing cabinet.
- Jesus, Andy. I..
Why did you even
want me in on this?
Well, it'll solve
everything for both of us.
What has to be solved for you?
Same as you. I need money. I'm
going to start over again.
What do you mean?
What the fuck kind of..
It's none of your business.
I just want out. I just want to..
That's all.
I'm getting out, I want to
help my little brother.
Come on.
Yeah.
No, I don't think I can do this.
I don't think I can..
Yeah, you can. Yeah, you can.
I just..
That's $2,000.
It's an advance.
See what just that
much does for you.
And,
imagine the rest.
Five, six, seven, eight,
nine hundred dollars.
You still owe me May and June.
Yeah, Monday. All right.
Everything on Monday.
- That's what I said.
- Such a loser.
You're such a fucking loser.
I come over here with $900.
- Yeah, well, if it was for me, maybe.
- And I'm the fucking.. All right.
- May and June, asshole.
- Bye, bye, bye.
Danielle, dinner.
No, please don't put me on..
Jesus.
- Yo, Bobby.
- What's going on?
- Hey, here, let me buy you a drink.
- I'm working.
- I ain't loaning you no more money.
- No, come on, man. I'm flush.
- You don't exactly..
- Yeah, something like that.
Look, you just.. If you're
free tomorrow morning,
I got a proposition for you.
- Later.
- All right.
- What if there is a security guard?
- There isn't.
- Why?
- No, it's a Mom and Pop place.
Who ever heard of a Mom
and Pop jewelry store?
- What the fuck is that?
- It's in the suburbs, all right.
It's not in the city.
I don't know.
We drive out there, we check
it out, if anything looks off,
you know, we just drive away.
We say, we drive our
happy asses home
and I keep the money anyway.
Yeah, fine.
You keep the money anyway.
- Hanson?
- Yeah, that's me.
All right.
- Yeah.
- Bobby, for Christ's sakes,
- Bobby, we got to go.
- Just come on in.
I just got to throw on some clothes.
It'll only take a second.
We got to go.
- Just give me a second.
- God damn it.
Jesus Christ, Bobby,
it's so fucking early.
Boo wakes up, you fucking
sit up with him.
- I told you it was work.
- I don't give a fuck what it is.
Chris ain't used to
getting up this early.
Oh, Christ.
Come on, babe. Here.
- Thank you, baby.
- Yeah, just keep it down, okay?
You wake Boo up,
I'll kick your ass.
- All right.
- Yours, too.
All right.
Come on.
All right, let's do it.
- Are we there?
- No.
All right.
Who the fuck are you
supposed to be?
Look, I used to work there, all right.
I used to work there
and I can't take a chance on
being recognized. Don't.. Look..
- You ain't never done this before, huh?
- Yeah, so?
I got to tell you something, you
look like a fucking asshole.
- Yeah, all right, look..
- I'm going to do this on my own.
- Really?
- You do the driving, I do the thing, all right.
- What if you need help?
- I got all the help I need.
There's no shooting.
- I ain't looking for it.
- There's no shooting.
- You do the driving.
- Hey.
- I do the thing.
- No shooting.
You ain't got the balls to do the thing.
I got the balls
- and I got a gun. That's the deal.
- Listen, no shooting.
- Or else I'm leaving right now.
- Hey, no!
Just no shooting, okay?
Okay. Ten more minutes.
What the fuck is this?
You can listen to that faggoty
shit all the way home.
Right now, I got to
get into character.
- Right?
- Okay.
Okay.
This is it.
You ready?
Car out front. Door open.
I jump back in. You take off.
- Simple as a pimple, all right.
- Right.
- Right?
- Let's do it.
- All right.
Yes, hi, hello. Is Andrew
Hanson available, please?
Uh..
Mooney. Mooney. Okay, yeah,
tell him it's Mooney.
- Yeah.
- There's a Mr. Mooney on line two.
- He sounds like some nut case.
- Okay.
- But..
- All right, I'll take it.
It just came apart, Andy.
Oh, my God, Andy.
What the fuck am I gonna do?
No, honey, no, don't worry.
It's just some mistake.
It's either the bank's or mine.
Maybe I didn't put enough
money in the joint account.
Yeah. No. Listen, don't worry.
Of course, we have the cash. I'll
call, I'll take care of it. Okay?
Yes, okay?
- Andy?
- Yeah. Yeah.
We're waiting for you
in the conference room.
Okay, I'll be right in.
Jesus.
Okay, next.
The auditors.
Some of you guys might have heard,
we're getting hit with an IRS audit.
The auditors will
be here on Monday.
They'll spend a day or two
with each department.
On Monday, they'll start with
payroll, so you're up first, Andy.
Great. Great. No problem.
How are you doing today, sir?
Thanks a lot.
Hungry?
Have a drink.
Right, tonic water.
You know,
the thing about real estate
accounting is that you can,
you can head down the
page or across the page,
and everything works out. So,
every day, everything adds up.
Well, the total is always
the sum of its parts.
It's clean, it's
clear, neat, absolute.
But my life, it..
It doesn't add up. It's..
Nothing connects to anything else.
It's..
I'm not the sum of my parts.
All of my parts don't
add up to one..
To one me, I guess.
Get a shrink or a wife.
- I got a wife.
- Get a shrink.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Was it me, honey?
What difference does it make?
It's another strikeout.
I swear it would make
a lot of difference.
- You're all I want.
- Yeah, well..
I'm a lousy cook. The
house looks like shit.
I'm a lousy lay, I don't
know why you wanna keep me.
You weren't in Rio.
I wasn't what?
Lousy lay.
Well, like you said,
just blame it on Rio.
Suppose I could get
us back there.
What?
Rio.
- To live?
- Absolutely.
- You're just crazy. Crazy.
- No. It's not crazy.
The real estate market's booming in Rio.
There's a lot of new money.
And they're going to want the
same as Europeans, Arabs,
everybody wants real estate in New York,
in America and I know the market here.
You don't even speak
the language.
I'll fucking learn it.
Jesus Christ.
You know when..
When you met me, my biggest prospect
was inheriting a Mom & Pop jewelry store
in a fucking shopping
mall in Westchester.
Now, I know it's not
Trump Plaza, and..
But just take a look at
how we're living now.
Now, I took that
lousy job in that,
that real estate office, I was
practically a fucking gofer,
and I'm pulling down six figures now.
I'm smart.
I know the angles.
- Yeah.
I bet you do.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
Well, because there is
no extradition agreement
between Brazil and
the United States.
How the..
How the hell do you know that?
I saw it in a movie.
Yeah, I guess I saw
the same movie.
So, what are you thinking?
What are you thinking?
Don't ask, don't tell.
I just want us to
get back there.
I've seen Heaven, Gina,
it's a nice place to stay.
- Okay? All right?
- Uh-huh.
- What language do they speak there?
- Portuguese.
I speak a little Spanish.
That's.. I'm sorry, sweetheart,
that's not the same language.
- Yes, it is.
- I'm sorry, it's not.
- Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
- No.
- Yes, it is.
- Cómo se llama?
- Me llamo..
- Cómo? Me llamo..
Gina.
Why'd you come to me?
I know you from way back,
I know what you do.
You're a cop.
No, I'm not a cop, I just want to
make sure you're still around.
I'll bring you what I've got soon,
either you take it or you don't.
But I know you will.
You could work for the cops.
Check me out.
I'll be back.
That's $2,000.
It's an advance.
See what just that
much does for you,
and imagine the rest.
- Yeah, so how do we start? Oh, fuck.
- It's
not we, you.
Me?
What the hell do I know about
robbing a jewelry store?
You'll learn it there.
On-the-job training, you know.
Cut it out, man,
this is serious.
You know, I'm serious as a heart attack.
Listen, number one, I can't..
- I can't go up to the mall.
- Why not?
Oh God, three months ago,
I had to walk the whole goddamn area
with a Home Depot representative,
'cause they were thinking of
buying up a lot of space.
We own a lot of
land in the mall,
and I'm getting a lot of big handshakes.
"Andy, baby, how are you?"
"I haven't seen you in
so long since you left."
And telling me all that bullshit because
they figure I'm making a killing,
because a big chain
wants to buy them out.
I'm saying someone's going to
just recognize me too easy.
So we postpone, just..
Yeah, we could, you
know, wait a year.
I mean, I don't know about you,
my problems are pressing.
Jesus, Andy, I.. Andy!
- I wouldn't even know how to start, I mean.
- Well, you can stop being a baby.
- I'm not being a..
- Yeah, you're being a baby.
Get a gun. You get a toy
gun in a kid's store.
Right, that old lady that works
on Saturday, what's her name?
- Doris?
- Yeah, Doris, Mom's friend.
She's what, 60, 70?
She's blind as a bat?
Look at me. Blind as a bat.
All right, those toy guns, they look
so real, they fool cops all the time.
All right, you go in at 8:00
a.m., just as she opens up.
You put her old ass in the back
room, you empty the vault,
the cash, the trays and you
dump it in a fucking sack.
All right. You don't
gotta be neat about it.
Jesus, Andy, I don't know. I
don't know, I don't.. I..
I don't know.
Okay. Come on.
You can do it.
Anybody can.
- I just think..
- I know, I know. It's too late to think.
It's too late.
This is our future.
Okay.
- Yeah.
- There's a Mr. Mooney on line two.
He sounds like some nut case.
But..
Okay, I got it.
It just came apart, Andy.
Oh, my God, Andy.
What the fuck am I gonna do?
Could he be in a different wing?
If you just pipe down a second,
sir, I'm trying to help you.
- What are you doing here?
- Keep quiet one minute.
Dad called me, all right.
I just got here.
- This lady, she doesn't..
- Look, Miss, our father.. I got it.
- I got it. I know, but you might..
- I told him, we've got no Charles Hanson.
Wait a minute, I got
a Nanette Hanson.
- What?
- There's a Nanette Hanson.
- Brought in about three hours ago.
- What?
Gunshot wounds.
- Where is she?
- Emergency ICU.
Hey. Now. Hey, hold it. Wait,
are you related? Sir? Are you?
Dad?
She's unconscious.
And they..
She's..
They..
They say..
So, how are you feeling?
Yeah, I feel old.
I've been studying all week,
and I can't retain a thing.
Come on, you're going to pass
with flying colors, Dad.
That's how I'm going to spend my
birthday, taking that stupid test.
Have you spoken
to your brothers?
Few weeks ago.
Yeah? How are they?
Busy.
You know, Dad, Hank is
Hank and Andy's Andy.
No more cramming, birthday boy.
It's the moment of truth.
What time is Doris
coming to the store?
She said 12:00 at the latest.
She has to baby-sit
for her daughter.
I'll pick you up
right after my test.
Come on, come on.
All right, all right, all right.
- Perfect score, Mr. Hanson.
- Bingo!
Congratulations.
If you'll take this to Window C,
they'll give you the eye test.
I might not do so
well on that one.
- I've been studying hard, of course. Thanks.
- All right.
That's my store!
- What happened? What's happening?
- Let's go!
- Sir, sir, just stay behind the yellow line.
- What's happening?
- I want to know what's happening.
- Behind the yellow line.
- Where's my wife? Where's my wife?
- Calm down. Please calm down.
I love you.
There are more tests we can do, but from
what we've seen so far, it's very unlikely.
There's no brain activity.
And statistically speaking, there's
very little chance for recovery.
Why was Mom working?
I thought she didn't work at the store
anymore, that's what Katherine told me.
Doris had to baby-sit, I had to get
down to the DMV, get my eyes tested.
Today's my birthday.
Where's your brother?
He..
He says he can't take it.
To let him know if..
If he can help, but he just
can't see her like that.
He's 28 years old.
He's a goddamn punk
from Red Hook.
Red Hook. What was he doing up here?
What in the fucking world? What he..
I mean, did he put a map on
the wall and throw a dart?
It's so absurd. It's
so goddamn arbitrary.
Why me? Why her?
What was this goddamn kid doing?
You belong in hell.
Yeah. I understand. All right.
Thank you.
Look, it might be better if you
call, make an appointment?
Well, I'd rather wait.
Please. Steve..
Dad.
You have to make
a decision, Dad.
The gun was bought in Texas.
Stolen Texas driver's
license, his ID, fake,
the gun turns up in New
York, a year later.
- Mom needs you to make a decision, Dad.
- Andy, just leave him alone.
Well, something has to be done,
he has to make a decision.
Just leave him to his
grief for one minute.
- Mom is in the hands of Jesus.
- Now, will you cut it out with that crap?
You shouldn't push Dad to make a
decision he doesn't wanna make.
Well, he has to make a decision.
Hey, Patrick.
We know it's
difficult, Mr. Hanson.
Let her go.
"Almighty and ever living God."
"Remember the mercy with which you graced
your daughter, Nanette, in this life."
"Receive her, we pray, into
the mansions of the saints."
"As we make ready our
sister's resting place"
"Look also with favor
on those who mourn."
"And comfort them in their loss."
"Because God has chosen to
call Nanette from this life,"
"commit her body to the earth, for we
are dust and to dust we shall return."
I'm so sorry for your loss.
She was a wonderful person.
- She was a wonderful woman.
- Yes.
- I'm so sorry.
- You have my deepest condolences.
She was a dear friend.
So sorry for your loss, your
mother was a good person.
I'm so sorry.
God bless you.
There's no way I can
make this scene, Andy.
He was always such a baby.
Yeah.
I can't really talk right now.
I can't, I..
I have to go. Andy needs me.
22nd precinct.
Detective Barrett, please.
Just a moment, sir.
I'm sorry, he's
not in right now.
Is there anyone down there that knows
anything about the Nanette Hanson case?
- Who's speaking, please?
- Charles Hanson, yeah.
Just a moment, sir.
Sergeant Sullivan.
Yeah, good morning, Sergeant.
I've been trying to reach Detective
Barrett but he doesn't return my calls.
Would you like to
leave a message, sir?
No, I wouldn't like to
leave another message.
Doesn't anyone down
there give a damn?
Doesn't anyone down there
work for a living?
Would you like to
leave a message, sir?
Don't you know how
important this is to me?
I know, I just..
You know, I thought I was going
to be able to work it out, but..
But I couldn't get the
money together, you know.
All my friends think I'm going to be
there, what am I going to tell them?
You know, I mean, there's going
to be other field trips.
Not to The Lion
King, there won't.
Look, Dad, if you weren't going to pay
for it, you should have just said so
and saved me the humiliation of having to
tell all my friends that you're a loser.
Hey, this is Hank. I must be out,
so leave a message at the beep.
I know you're there.
Pick up the phone.
Pick up the fucking phone,
you fucking faggot.
- Andy, I'm here.
- Where have you been?
Here. I called in sick.
And what the fuck were you doing
with that fucking asshole?
- I was scared, all right? So I..
- I didn't say anything about
a fucking gun, God damn it.
But we got to talk.
Andy.
Meet me at Mooney's.
You still can't get by?
To see Mom?
- What am I going to say?
- Don't say anything. Fuck.
- Who else knows?
- Nobody.
- You didn't tell anyone?
- No.
- No one saw you talking with Bobby?
All right. Nobody saw you here?
No, come on, it was crowded,
it was busy. No, no.
- Did he rent the car with you?
- Did he what?
- Did he rent the fucking car with you?
- No, no, no.
All right, did you..
- You picked him up?
- Yeah.
- At his house.
- Did anyone see you there, at his house?
- Did anyone see you at his house?
- No, no.
- Nobody saw you at the house?
- No.
Did you clean the car? Did
you wipe the car down?
- Did you wipe the floor?
- Yeah, I totally.. Totally, totally.
- Did you leave anything in the car?
- No, of course not.
We're probably okay.
If they don't connect the car
to us, we're probably okay.
That's what I was thinking.
- Go back to work, totally normal.
- Okay.
I'm so sorry, Andy. I'm sorry.
I don't think I can
get through this.
Shut up.
- I loved her so much.
- Just shut the fuck up.
If he had to take somebody out,
why couldn't it have been him?
One new message.
This is Mike Steuben calling from
Auto Rent for Mr. Henry Hanson.
Mr. Hanson, you returned
a car the other day.
It seems you forgot some
personal items in it.
Please give me a call at 555-2649
and ask for Mike Steuben.
Again, that number is 555-2649.
Thank you.
End of messages.
Okay. God.
Okay.
Hello, you've reached Auto Rent.
Our office is currently closed.
- Our business hours..
- Fuck.
Fuck!
Okay. All right. It's
okay, it's okay.
Excuse me?
That's right, sir.
It's $255 plus tax.
But for an additional $17, I
could upgrade you to a luxury.
Or, for.. Yes.
No, that's right, the
mid-size is $255 plus tax.
Unless you'd like to upgrade to an
SUV, which I could offer you for 29..
Excuse me, is Mike Steuben here? No,
I know, I'm just looking for Mike.
So, would you like to
upgrade to the SUV?
No, no. No, mid-size
is fine, sir.
No.
Thank you for calling.
I'm sorry.
Good morning, how can
I help you, sir?
Yeah, I got a message
from Mike Steuben.
Apparently I left
something in a vehicle
that I returned last Saturday.
I think it was a CD.
Oh, well, you would talk to
Mr. Steuben, then. He's the manager.
Yeah, I know, so could
I speak with him?
I'm sorry, he's not here.
You'll have to come back.
- When will he be in?
- I don't..
He won't be in at all today.
Well then, maybe
you can help me.
Oh, no. Sorry, sir.
I'm sorry, excuse me.
- Do you think..
- I'm sorry.
- Will he be in tomorrow?
- Yes, Auto Rent.
No, I..
No, I didn't say that, sir.
That's not up to me.
No.
Excuse me, can I get a beer?
Thanks.
That's the guy, that's him.
Yo, buddy.
- This guy?
- Yeah.
You were with Bobby
Lasorda, Saturday?
- What?
- I asked you a fucking question.
What? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- What's your name?
- I'm Hank.
- Hank what?
- You know what?
Come. Why don't you.. Let's go.
Follow me, we can
talk over here.
- Come on. Have a seat.
- Is this all right?
Yeah, this is perfect.
So..
What's the deal, huh?
- My sister is quite all of a sudden a widow.
- Yeah.
She says you and
Bobby had some work.
Bobby said it was work.
Work that involved him
getting shot and killed,
but not you getting
shot and killed.
No, I just got him the car.
- I'm so sorry.
- What the fuck does that mean?
Well, Bobby said that he needed
to rent a car, but that he..
This was Friday night
and he didn't have a credit card, so I
told him that I would rent him a car.
And I owed him some money. You know.
That's it, I swear. It's..
I'm so sorry.
- So what? You're lying.
- No, I'm not.
Because if Bobby wanted a car, he
would have fucking stolen one.
Chris, go fucking wait outside.
Let me handle this.
You got a driver's license?
- A what?
- You know, the..
The driver's license you
show when you rent a car?
Yeah.
- Let me see it.
- Yeah.
All right, sure.
Here.
- Henry Hanson.
- Yeah.
This is your address, right?
Yeah, sure.
I'm going to be straight
with you, chico.
You mind if I call you chico?
People call me Hank.
Bobby was a piece of shit.
I know it, you know it.
That's not the point.
The point is that piece of shit was
the father of my sister's child.
And he was paying the bills.
And now he's dead.
And I'm thinking, who's going
to pay all these bills?
I'm so sorry.
Sorry ain't going to
pay the bills, chico.
I know, I know.
We need to negotiate a
settlement, so make me an offer.
Ten grand, done. It's 10 grand.
I consider us even.
If you don't like 10,
I can make it 15.
- No.
- My sister wants me to kill you.
Or I could call the cops.
But I don't like cops.
And the cops ain't going
to pay my sister's bills.
So, I think a settlement
is pretty fair all-around.
- Day after tomorrow, chico.
- Can I?
Here. 8:00.
You fucking crazy?
I was hoping that you had something
left over from the settlement.
Lend you money? You
owe me $2,000.
Shocked to shit you'd even ask.
Martha,
I'm in serious trouble.
I don't give a shit what
kind of trouble you're in.
The next time you show up
here, better be to pay me.
Listen, tell
Danielle I love her.
If you loved her, you'd pay
her fucking child support.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
She was a wonderful person.
Wonderful woman.
She was a wonderful woman.
God bless you.
There's no way I can
make this scene, Andy.
He was always such a baby.
Yeah.
- Hey, Gina.
- I can't really talk right now.
Andy needs me. I got to go.
Gina, Gina.
Excuse me, is Mike Steuben here?
- Not till noon, can I help you?
- Yeah, yeah.
I returned a car last Saturday
and I guess I forgot something.
Hanson?
That's right, Hanson. Yeah, and
I'm pretty sure it was a CD.
Hang on.
Here we go, Mr. Hanson.
- Great.
- I just need to see some ID.
Yeah, you know, I..
I lost my license.
You have a credit card, the one
you used to rent the car with?
Yeah.
- Yeah, this one.
- All right.
Okay, great.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
- Hello?
- It's me.
Andy, Jesus! Fuck,
man, we got problems.
Hi, Andy. This is
Jake at the office.
Really sorry to bother you, but
the auditors are coming tomorrow.
They've noticed a few problems.
It's pretty urgent, so give
a call when you get this.
You're going to have to
get some sleep tonight.
Have you given any
thought to the store?
I mean, you're going to have to give it
some consideration. It's just gonna..
I could open it up for you, you
know, while you're at the hospital.
A few hours a day.
So people know
you're still there.
I should burn the
goddamn place down.
Andy, this is Jake.
Now I hope you're checking your messages
because we have a real mess here.
The auditors say that there's
two terminated employees
from your department
still drawing checks.
And there's something
about unpaid OASDI taxes.
Look, you need to call us..
I got to go to the
office tomorrow.
There's a problem. I'll go in the morning.
I should be back later.
Okay?
His mother's dying, and
he's going back to work.
Yes!
Pick up the phone.
I know you're there, pick up
the phone, you fucking faggot.
Andy, I'm here.
What are you doing here? You
don't have an appointment.
- You know the deal, you can't just show up.
- I know, I'm sorry.
Come back in an
hour, tonic water.
My mom's dying.
Bummer.
Next time, make an appointment.
Stupid piece of shit.
Stop talking to me like that.
What the fuck?
Are you going to get tough?
Are you going to hurt me?
Why was there even a gun?
Why was there even
a fucking gun?
I gave you all the information you needed.
Why was Bobby Lasorda even there?
- Why the fuck?
- I didn't think I could do it alone.
I should fucking kill you.
How are we going to fix it so
your shit don't fall on my shoes?
So, think now, who else knows?
"Commit her body to the earth."
"For we are dust and to
dust we shall return."
"But the Lord Jesus will change our
mortal bodies to be like his in glory."
She hated it when I barbecued.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to
be what you wanted me to be.
I've never been very good
at talking about feelings
or showing you that kind
of affection or support.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't able to be the
father you wanted.
But I guess I wanted you
to be better than me.
And I thought that if I push..
It may not mean anything to
you, but I want you to know
that I really do love you.
And I'm.. I'm sorry.
I'm just so sorry.
I'm sorry I wasn't able
to be the son you wanted.
You did the best you could.
Still, yeah.
Manage to seem to
still like Hank.
He was a lot more of a
fuck-up than I was.
- He was the baby.
- Yeah.
- He needed us more.
- Yeah, he needed you more.
You sure it wasn't his cute
looks or his puppiness?
You were the first.
The first always has it rougher.
Yeah, so I'm told.
You know, the four of you, I never
felt like I was part of the club.
Beautiful birds of a feather.
You sure I'm your son?
Gina and I have got to
get back to the city.
Andy?
My dad.
Andy.
Okay.
Why don't we pull over?
My dad.
Oh, God.
It's not fair! It's not fair!
All my life I've been afraid of
becoming like him. All my life!
All my life with you,
and it's not fair.
He can't just say he's sorry
and make it all go away.
It's too late.
It's not that easy!
It's not fair! It's
not fucking fair!
No, Dad.
Oh, God!
He can't do that!
Andy.
- I'll be back in a bit.
- Where are you going?
I'll be back soon, I just got to..
I got to deal with some stuff.
What's going on?
What if you come home
and I'm not here?
You got some place
you got to be?
Your boss called and he wants
you to call him right away.
Are you in trouble?
They just miss me.
Where are you going?
Something has to change.
- What do you mean?
- I mean that this just isn't working.
- What's not working?
- The life that we have.
It was really bad before Rio
and now it's even worse.
You never tell me anything
that's going on anymore.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
What was that in
the car yesterday?
I could help.
I don't need any help.
Do you realize that I've
been having an affair?
What's that supposed to mean?
Means I've been
fucking another guy.
Every Thursday, me & your brother, Hank.
We get together and we fuck.
Not only that, he loves me.
And he still finds
me attractive.
All the time.
Not just on vacation.
Hank?
Yeah, Hank.
Aren't you gonna say anything?
Are you gonna get angry?
- Where are you gonna go?
- I was just gonna go to my mother's.
How're you gonna get there?
I was gonna take a cab.
I could really use
some, some money.
I'll go to the bank later.
Here.
Hi, you've reached Gina and Andy.
Leave a message.
Please hang up and
try your call..
Come on.
Last person I ever thought I'd
see again as long as I lived.
Charlie Hanson.
You're still a crook?
You come all this
way to insult me?
Did you hear anything about a holdup
at the Westchester Shopping Mall?
What would I know
about Westchester?
That's just for upstanding
citizens such as yourself.
Have you heard anything?
Why would I hear anything
about anything? I sell diamonds.
- And fence them.
- Never!
Did you hear of a young
guy called Bobby Lasorda?
Wrong tree, Charlie.
A couple of punks shot my
wife in a holdup. She's dead.
I'm sorry.
I don't give a shit about
your little side business,
I don't care about
anything anymore,
except finding the
guy who did this.
Do you know anything?
I remember when Charlie Hanson
started out on the streets.
Young and cocky, good cutter.
A long time ago, Charlie.
You always hated my guts,
you called me a crook,
but you didn't know shit
about how the world works,
or what some people
will do for money.
I guess,
now you know, Charlie.
The world is an evil
place, Charlie.
Some of us make money off of
that, and others get destroyed.
He walked in here,
he looks a little bit
like you, Charlie.
He walked in here and I almost
knew him, right off the bat.
Hello.
It's me.
Andy, Jesus, man,
we got problems.
What do you mean, problems?
Bobby's girlfriend's got
a fucking brother, okay.
And the guy is blackmailing
me, all right.
He said he's gonna go to the cops, all right,
or kill me if I don't pay him $10,000.
All right, all right.
Just stay there, I'll be right
over, I'll figure something out.
- Andy, this guy isn't fucking around.
- All right, I'll figure something out.
Andy, Jake needs to see you.
They're all in the conference
room with the IRS guys.
They're going all the way back
- through your accounts.
- Just fuck 'em, I got to go to my dad's.
I'm gonna have to tell
them you were here.
For God's sake, say something.
Okay.
We're in trouble.
The worst trouble imaginable.
You're aware of that, right?
So, why don't we try and fix it?
There's almost no choice, but you're
gonna have to follow my lead.
No questions, no hesitations.
I've done that before, all right, and
that's how come I'm standing here,
with my life going down
the fucking toilet.
Fuck you, fuck you,
I'll do it alone.
You can sit here and
wait till you go to jail
and take it up the ass for the
rest of your fucking life.
Let's do it already,
what's your idea?
Sorry, what's your idea?
What's Bobby's
girlfriend's name?
Chris. Yeah, Chris.
Chris.
Call Chris, tell her to get her
brother over to her apartment.
- What for?
- We'll meet him.
He figures we owe him $10,000,
we have to resolve it.
Resolve it how?
Play it by ear, see what
happens, maybe we pay him.
He's never gonna let
us off the hook.
All right, we're gonna be paying him
back for the rest of our lives.
Hey, you finally figured out
something for yourself.
Let's just get the
money, see what happens.
Where are we gonna get $10,000?
No, that might be easier.
Call Chris.
Taxi!
Andy, Jesus Christ!
You're gonna kill him.
Come on.
Shit.
Hold the bag. Hold
out the fucking bag!
Hold it open like this.
Hold it open like that!
I got it, I got it.
- Oh, shit, do you want these?
- Just put it in the bag!
Put it in the bag!
- Out.
- Got it.
Oh, my God, Andy.
- Did you touch anything?
- Did you go crazy?
- Are you fucking nuts?
- Did you touch anything?
- Wait, you didn't have to kill him, all right.
He's not gonna go to the cops. All right?
He's a drug dealer.
Yeah, I guess he'll just go to
some other dealers and suppliers
and that's all we need, is 10
South Americans chasing us
for the rest of our lives.
Did you touch anything?
I don't think so.
- You don't think so?
- I don't think so, no!
- No, I didn't touch anything!
- Think, God damn it, you think!
- I don't.. I don't like this, Andy!
- Did you touch anything?
- I don't like..
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Did you touch anything?
- No.
Are we good?
Let's go.
You got the money, chico?
I don't like wasted trips.
You don't look happy.
Mind if I call you groucho?
No, I don't mind.
- Like what you're seeing?
- Yeah, a lot.
- Stand up. Stand up!
- All right, all right.
- Turn around.
- All right, all right, all right.
So how we gonna do this?
Gladly pay you the
money, got plenty of it.
How do we know you're not gonna bleed
us for the next couple of months?
I just want enough to
take care of Chris.
That's nice, my brother wouldn't
take care of me like that.
Hey, what do you say, Chris,
should I trust this guy?
- Yes.
- Speak up. What?
Yes.
I don't think so.
No, Andy, don't, don't, don't..
- What did you say?
- No, you can't do that, I won't let you.
- You won't let me?
- No, no more,
you kill her, you're
gonna have to kill me.
Not such a bad idea.
You know, in fact, it's
a pretty good one.
You know I know.
What do you know?
I know.
I'm sorry.
I fucked it all up.
Just do it.
Do it.
Go ahead.
Come on.
You'd be doing me a favor.
Get the hell out of here.
Get the hell out of here! Go!
Go!
Hank! Hank!
Move out of the way,
move out of the way.
You'll have to move your vehicle.
Move out of the way.
Hi, Mr. Hanson.
Stick your head in.
If he's awake now,
you can spend a couple
of minutes with him.
Dad?
I never meant to hurt her.
I just needed money.
There wasn't supposed
to be any gun.
She wasn't supposed to be in the store.
Everything just went wrong.
It's okay, Andy.
It's okay.
Nurse, the heart monitor
cut out for a second.
It does that, don't worry. If it
happens again, just press reset.
Dad.
Nurse!
Emergency personnel, code blue.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326