Subs synced, cut and checked by ddeca
Join -= sTOs =- (sTerOids) now or not :)
- Paulie, how's it look?
- Snitch says the cop's body's...
about 300 yards down
in the abandoned tunnel.
- Howie?
- Right behind you, Captain.
Keep back till I process the scene.
Watch out below!
- So where the hell is the car?
- I don't know.
- That's the last time I take a red-eye.
- Maybe we can take a cab.
I'm gonna fire this son of a bitch.
He's always got an excuse.
Come on, we'll be home
before you know it, hmm?
Yeah.
Excuse me. Excuse me,
I think you’re going the wrong way.
Honey, honey, wake up. We're lost,
or he's taking us for a ride.
We're in the middle of nowhere.
Where the hell you going?
I said Fifth Avenue.
We're not tourists here, man.
Hey, where are you going?
Let us out.
Stop the car.
- Stop this car, man!
- Stop the car!
Shit.
- Oh, my God.
- Son of a bitch.
Stop the goddamn car!
- Stop it, please.
- Stop the car.
Stop this car, goddamn it!
Stop this car!
Good morning.
You look a little dehydrated.
- How about some juice?
- How about two fingers of vodka?
Isn't it a little early for vodka?
Time, as you well know,
is a relative consideration, Thelma.
-Juice.
- Vodka.
- Coming!
-Join me in a drink, Richard?
I'd love to, but a med tech with
liquor on his breath, I think not.
- Thanks.
- So, how are you?
I'm better than
your heart-pacing gear.
Every time I'm here, it's skewed further
out of spec. You need a new unit.
I really need a new body.
I'm afraid I can't help you
with that.
- I'll bring you a new unit tomorrow.
- Okay.
- This one'll be stable till then.
- Thank you, Richard.
- Take it easy.
- I'll take it anyway I can get it.
- How's he doing this morning?
- He asked for vodka again.
- Give him any?
- No!
- Good morning, Doctor.
- Hi, Richard.
Hey, would you look at this!
Peregrine falcon. Am I right?
Yep.
He likes cripples.
Yeah, there was a piece about them
in the Times the other day...
nesting all over the city.
Something to do with architecture
of all these old buildings.
I thought he liked my company.
They're a little shy.
Don't take it personally, Barry.
- Drink, Doc?
- No, thanks, Thelma, I'm fine.
Bed mode.
- Got vodka in there?
- No.
You ain't getting any either.
All right, I'll let you guys talk.
So, Linc, you can imagine how much
sleep I've gotten the past few days...
considering your request.
That's funny. Since I made my decision,
I've been sleeping like a baby.
After all you have survived,
beat all the odds...
you know as well as I do, there's work
on nerve regeneration every day.
One finger, two shoulders and a brain.
That's all I have, Barry.
These dysreflexia seizures
are occurring more frequently.
Build-up of fluid in my spine
is a degenerative condition.
We both know I'm waiting for the seizure
that's gonna make me a vegetable.
I don't wanna be a vegetable, Barry.
I wanna make the final transition
on my own terms.
I'll get it done
with or without you.
Oh, yeah,
I suppose you would.
So?
- Okay.
- Okay what?
Okay, I'll assist you...
in your final transition.
- What about today?
- Linc, preparations have to be made.
This is not a flu shot.
My business is in order.
My bags are packed.
Besides, I've got a medical conference
to go to. I've got a plane to catch.
You're lying.
When do you get back?
Sunday.
Okay. Sunday.
- I'll see you then.
- Get out before you change your mind.
Don't bother to get up.
I'll show myself out.
Yeah, I'll race you to the door.
You are...
a very good friend.
Amelia.
- Hey.
- Hey. Morning.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just couldn't sleep.
- What time is it?
- It's early.
I'm gonna be late for work.
I gotta shower.
- No, you don't. Stay here.
- I gotta go.
- Hey, I'll make breakfast?
- No, thanks, I'm gonna be late.
Another
slam-bam-thank-you-ma'am, huh?
Look--
My therapist tells me...
I might not be getting what I need
out of this relationship.
What are we doing here?
I think we make a great couple.
You know where I stand on this.
You know what I want.
Steve, we've been through this.
I care about you. You know that.
I can't make a commitment.
Go to work then.
Go ahead.
You're gonna be late.
So, Amelia, is it true
you're quitting the cops?
- No, transferring to Youth Services.
- You lucky fuck.
You must have one hell
of a rabbi downtown.
- We're gonna miss you here.
- Three-post-eleven here.
- Frightened child at Am trak site.
- I'm a block away. I'll take it.
Some kid found something
over at the tracks.
- Finish eating. I'll check it out.
- See you, kid.
Three-post-eleven,
anything further on that ten-ten?
Nothing yet.
Wait, I think I see him.
Are you the one
who called the police?
Wait there, okay?
- Are you out of your mind?
- Shut off the engine, all right?
There's been a homicide.
I can't let you through.
- My name is Amelia. What's yours?
- Chris.
Chris, hey. I got a job for you.
Here's some money.
I need you to buy me one of those
cheapo cardboard cameras...
the ones you can throw away.
Okay. Fast as you can.
Three-post-eleven to central.
Get Amtrak to send a bus over here.
Get these passengers out of here.
Captain Cheney, Detective Solomon.
- Anything else?
- First officer on the scene is there.
I found strange stuff near the body. I
collected it before it was washed away.
- I also took some pictures.
- Thanks.
- You the one who stopped the train?
- I thought it would disturb evidence.
So why not shut down Grand Central while
you're at it, hmm, Patrolman Donahue?
- Is that right?
- Donaghy.
- A rookie, I take it?
- No, sir.
Pretty dumb.
Captain, guess who
the vic turns out to be.
- Talk to me.
- Alan fucking Rubin.
Listen, I don't want anybody
in this area except for the crime unit.
- Okay?
- Okay, Detective.
Knight to H-6. Check.
- You got company. Cops.
- Tell 'em I'm busy.
- They said it was urgent.
- Tell 'em I'm out running.
She's too polite for that, Linc.
Hey, looky who's here.
- I got a serious situation.
- It's going around, Paulie.
Chief Murphy sent me.
The good chief.
Hear about the couple at the airport,
got in a taxi yesterday morning?
- Never made it home.
- We don't watch the news anymore.
He used to read four papers a day,
tape all the news shows.
Yeah, and now I just hit
the rewind button. A-3.
Things never change.
Yeah, well, that was Alan Rubin
and his wife in that taxi.
Found him dead, buried,
shot in the face...
hand sticking out of the ground with his
wife's wedding band on his finger...
which was skinned to the bone.
She's still missing.
Excuse me while you catch up, okay?
Don't go too far, Thelma. These nice
gentlemen are leaving in 30 seconds.
Sounds like you got yourself
an open-and-shut there, Paulie.
- I don't think so.
- Yeah?
A man worth millions found dead...
with his wife's wedding band
on his mutilated hand.
What does that tell you?
The doer is saying he's got her.
He's probably contacting the family
right now making a ransom demand.
- I would've been paged i fhe had.
- Check your batteries.
It's definitely a ransom.
Excuse me, Mr. Rhyme,
Kenneth Solomon.
I've read all your books--
Scene of the Crime...
at least a dozen times.
It's great to actually meet you.
- Where do you find these guys?
- They wanna work with the best.
I guess now you’re gonna ask me to
discuss the crime scene with you, huh?
In fact, we got a bunch
of physical evidence...
that doesn't exactly make sense.
Some seriously weird stuff.
It's in the report.
You okay?
- You okay?
- Out! Now!
- Anything we can do?
- Asses outta here now!
We're gonna get you some air.
Come on, breathe for me, Linc.
I said, out!
Come on, deep breaths.
Deep breaths, come on.
Deep breaths. I'm getting a B.P. on you.
Come on now, breathe.
Look at me. Breathe.
Look at me. Deep breaths.
Come on, come on.
You've got to take this oxygen.
Come on, Rhyme,
stay with me.
Come on, you can do it.
Don't go out on me now.
Come on, look at me.
You okay?
I would be okay if your powers
of resuscitation were less adept.
Not on my shift, all right.
If you have a problem with that,
you just fire my ass.
You know I provide generously for you
in my will. Keep that in mind.
Rhyme, I'm not interested
in having this conversation. Okay?
Okay.
Crime scene report Sellitto left--
would you load those photos
in the viewer for me?
View scan.
Okay, let's take a look
at what we got here.
Where it says location--
Now, what's that?
What's it say about that newspaper?
''Newspaper found beneath a coarse-thread
hex bolt with 4:00 p.m. circled on it.''
4:00 p.m.
Zoom.
What about the little piece of paper?
What's the number on it?
- Torn book page with 119 on it.
- 119, 4:00 p.m.
- What's today's date?
- Today's November 9.
Phone mode. Sellitto, Paulie.
Call.
What?
Sad fact is, a huge percentage
of inner-city kids...
are having their first drug experiences
at the fifth grade level.
Now, here are some of the drugs
they'll most likely be offered.
Marijuana.
Wouldn’t you like to get your hands
on that briefcase?
Barbiturates, amphetamines.
Cocaine.
Rock cocaine.
- What is this about?
- Do you know who Lincoln Rhyme is?
- Textbook guy?
- Yeah.
- What does that have to do with me?
- You'll find out.
Come on in.
They're right in there.
A patrol cop took these pictures?
Yeah, first one on the scene.
It started to rain.
Smart guy.
Also had the balls to stop an Amtrak
from running over the crime scene.
Here she is now.
Officer Donahoe...
meet Lincoln Rhyme.
Donaghy.
You took some terrific
photographs, Officer.
- You know who I am?
- I read your manual at the academy.
- What'd you think of it?
- I'm not a book critic, sir.
- But you found it useful?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Guess so? Sure, you did.
You stopped that train.
Photos you took.
I'd say you have a natural instinct
for forensics.
So what do we got, Paulie?
We have footprints, size ten,
thanks to Officer Donaghy...
using a dollar bill
to establish scale.
We have asbestos on the track bed
where there shouldn't be any...
and an iron bolt holding down
a piece of paper...
with a book page with 119
written on it.
Decaying oxidation on the bolt's head,
but not on the thread...
which says to me that someone
removed it from somewhere else...
and placed it there recently.
Wouldn’t you agree, Officer?
Paulie, I'm convinced
that this crime scene was staged.
- Perp's trying to tell us something.
- What the fuck you saying?
Book page 119.
11/9-- That's today date.
- Newspaper, 4:00 p.m. What time is it?
- 1 2:1 5.
She's alive.
- And he's gonna kill her at 4:00.
- P.m.
We have your interest yet, Officer?
- I want you to work the case with us.
- It's not my area.
Are you being modest...
or are you a little uneasy
about doing some real police work?
- Excuse me?
- What department you work in, Officer?
Youth Services Division.
I picked her up at orientation.
I see, youth services.
I waited over a year to get that
transfer. I'm not gonna jeopardize--
Jeopardize what? Cushy desk job?
- Forensics is not my area.
- I disagree with you.
You can't force me
to take this assignment.
I can.
- And if I refuse?
- You'd put your career at risk.
You think, because of your condition,
you can push people around?
I'm sorry.
That is truly pathetic.
- Truly?
- Yeah, damn right.
Well, forgive me, truly...
if I insist on having someone with
your brains and a fresh pair of eyes.
There's a life
at stake here, Officer.
We're gonna need some key people
and tech support.
- I know the guy.
- Okay.
What the hell are you smiling at?
Pull up a chair. Tell me everything
you know about the crime scene.
- You saw my report.
- I read your report.
I wanna know what you felt.
What you feel...
in the deepest recesses
of your senses.
You are in love with the sound
of your own voice, aren’t you?
It's your voice I yearn to hear.
Pull up a chair. I won't bite you.
The rifling on the .38 slug
they dug out of the victim...
is consistent with a Webley, a very
old, turn-of-the-century handgun.
Thank you, Kenny.
On the big board, please.
- What do you got on that bolt?
- Three initials on the head: N.S.G.
And the bolt's not steel,
it's iron.
Iron? Iron.
Making it old-- like the Webley.
Officer Donaghy,
what do you know about asbestos?
- It kills hard-working Americans daily.
- Very good.
- You computer literate?
- A little.
- Where's my Thelma?
- Guess.
Thelma, meet Amelia.
Amelia, Thelma.
Amelia hates my books and computers, but
she's got an A-plus nose for evidence...
so I want you to give her a crash course
in how to access D.E.P. files.
Check if there’s any large asbestos
cleanups going on in the city.
A.S.A.P.
- Where the hell is Eddie Ortiz?
- I'm right here!
How's the world's
crankiest crimina list doing?
Playing beat the clock.
Everybody's worst nightmare.
You get into a cab, and there's
a psycho from Jersey driving.
We don't know he's from Jersey.
Yeah, Bayonne. It's the toxins
in the water over there.
- What'd you do, bring the whole lab?
- Mama always said be prepared.
- Where do you want this?
-Just put it in the corner.
How is your mother?
She's 76, and she's schtupping some guy
named Morris. Can you believe it?
- God bless her.
- It's Morris I'm worried about.
He's 79, with a tricky ticker
and an active pecker.
Afternoon.
Captain Cheney.
What's your address?
There's about a dozen cleanups
scattered across the five boroughs.
Put it up on the viewer for me,
will you, please?
Narrow it down to the oldest location
as soon as you can.
- How you doing, Howard?
- Fine, thank you.
- How's it going?
- Middle of the middle, as you can see.
Hey, Linc, look what I found
on the threading of that iron bolt.
Look, I was hoping
to grab a minute with you.
- If you don't mind.
- Excuse me, Howard.
Sorry.
We got Officer Donaghy to thank here
for photographing the crucial evidence.
Crucial evidence?
We don't know that.
I just stopped by to make sure
you had all the support you need.
I'm putting the full resources
of my department here at your disposal.
And I appreciate it, Howie,
thank you.
But the thing is, Linc...
I've formalized department standard
procedure since you were in charge...
Eddie, could you put what you got
up on my screen, please?
so I'd appreciate it
if you kept me in the loop.
Absolutely.
At all times.
At all-- Eddie, what the hell
is that we're looking at?
Old paper.
Coarse grade.
I say, 80, 90 years old.
Turn of the century,
it looks like.
This perp likes old.
- I'll be in my office if you need me.
- Yeah, okay.
Good.
Old paper.
Old gun.
Buried his victim in a vintage
Civil War railroad bed.
Sand.
Eddie, what do you got
on the sand?
Doesn't really look like sand.
- I'm not sure.
- Can you individuate it?
- If I had E.D.X., I could do anything.
- We don't have that, Eddie.
Look who forgot their chill pill
this morning. Excuse me.
Come on, I'm all over
this thing now.
We're talking pearly looking.
Some kind of shellfish or something.
Oysters shells, maybe?
Could be.
Definitely. If I had to bet on it,
I'd say it was. Sure.
I got it. The oldest asbestos sites
are coming up now.
In 1 91 3, when the Woolworth Building
was being built...
workmen found the body of this rich
industrialist, Talbot Soames.
He'd been kidnapped the year before,
shot in the head and buried...
in what they thought was white sand
but turned out to be oyster shells.
Crushed oyster shells-- That's what they
used as landfill in lower Manhattan.
That's how Pearl Street got its name.
That's where Ms. Rubin is gonna be--
somewhere downtown.
She's gonna be underground.
She's gonna be in a basement...
near or in the Woolworth Building.
Paulie, call Emergency Services Unit
to meet us at the Woolworth Building.
Tell them to start their search.
Maybe we'll get lucky.
Okay? Eddie,
did you bring your van?
- It's downstairs.
- We're gonna need it.
Throw your keys to Amelia.
Paulie, you and Solomon go with her.
- Shouldn't I go too?
- You stay. We're gonna work that bolt.
- That's the missing piece.
- Should we keep Cheney in the loop?
Fuck him.
Just trust me.
Just follow those instincts
you were born with. I'll be with you...
every step of the way.
Jesus, 25 minutes left.
- How did Rhyme get to be that way?
- He was born brilliant. It happens.
I mean the physical part.
About four years ago, he was working
the body of a transit cop...
found shot in a subway tunnel.
Beam came down
and damn near cut him in half.
Jesus.
- Family?
- Married sister in Phoenix.
He never sees her.
Cut himself off.
Technically, he's still active duty
collecting full pay.
P.B.A. insurance picks up
round-the-clock care and the gadgets.
On weekends, always one or two cops
there, lending a hand.
- Tough deal winding up like that.
- You won't hear him complain about it.
He gets too much pleasure
pushing other people's buttons.
In your case,
I'd be complimented.
You gotta learn to relax
around a compliment...
especially one from Rhyme.
- You can be a little grating.
- Me?
Kiddo, if you were any more wound up,
you'd be a Timex.
He was a human dynamo. Writing books,
lecturing all over the world...
giving expert opinion in trials...
working half the crimes scenes
in the city.
- You know what he did on his downtime?
- I can't imagine.
He'd collect things--
dirt, metals, plastics...
hubcaps, plants, musical strings...
medical tools--
anything you could think of.
Obsessive.
He'd have it all analyzed
and catalogued for his database.
Jesus Christ! I'd like to get there
in one piece, if possible.
Yeah, find out about that.
That might be good. What else?
Nicholas Steven Gerard,
elevator construction.
- Gotta be underground.
- I got a subway builder here.
- Subway builder's out.
- N.S.G.-- Niagara Steam Generation.
Bought by Eastern Gas and Electric
in 1 928.
The six-inch iron bolt was used
mainly for steam pipe assemblies.
Forty-five, you got 11 minutes left.
Where the hell are you?
We just hit the financial district.
There's a steam junction
with big asbestos-coated pipes.
That's where our victim’s gonna be.
I bet my legs on it-- Wall and Nassau.
Has E.S.U. been notified?
Yeah, they're on their way.
E.S.U. says that steam is released
through that junction every day at 4:00.
Shit, what's this asshole up to?
I don't know, but it's gonna happen
in about ten minutes and 30 seconds.
All right, Linc, we're here.
We're going down there.
Yeah, I'm here.
It's their job to try
and save Mrs. Rubin's life.
It's your job to get ready
and work the crime scene if necessary.
There's some things you’re gonna need,
so look in the back of the truck.
You'll see an aluminum suitcase
and a radio headset.
- See it?
- Yeah, I see them.
There must be a way in.
- What's the problem here?
- Fucking valves freeze up easy.
Come on, guys, shut it off.
- You there?
- I'm here.
- I'm inside the pipe.
- One, two, three.
Go!
I think I hear something.
I hear something.
What is it? Someone's in there!
I can hear her crying.
Everyone, quiet now.
Mrs. Rubin?
She's in there.
Mrs. Rubin!
We're on our way in now.
Come on, guys.
Let's go.
Let's hurry the fuck up!
-Jesus Christ.
- Get a drill and a tap.
Somebody cut this thing
halfway through.
Let's dig!
Move back!
Linc, she's gone.
The whole place is scalded in steam.
Let's go. Move away.
Nothing to see here.
E.S.U. are gonna blow a hole in the
subbasement wall. No other way in.
I am working with Chief Murphy's
authorization on this, right?
- Yeah, that's right.
- I don't want E.S. U. guys...
rushing in there, trampling the evidence
before we get a chance to run the scene.
- What do you want?
- I want Donaghy to go in first.
Come on, Linc,
she's not trained for this.
We can get our asses in a sling.
My ass has been in a sling
for four years.
Tell Hanson and his beasts
that's what I want. Period.
All right, you got it.
Okay, let's move!
I'm doing this under protest.
The perp could still be in there.
Rhyme's in charge,
and they're his orders.
You can't handle it in there,
I want you to get your ass out.
- Amelia, you ready?
- Yeah.
You listen to me.
I'm with you every step of the way.
Go on.
Good luck.
- I'm in.
- Tell me what you see.
Everything's been boiled to hell.
Oh, God.
What is it?
It's an awful smell.
That means you're close.
- I can't believe I'm doing this.
- You're fine.
Just fine. You're doing great.
Just remember the academy.
When you walk,
move in a straight line.
We don't want to disturb
any footprints he might've left.
Yes, assuming he's gone.
There's no footprints.
There's nothing yet.
Oh, God.
What?
Talk tome.
I can see her.
The steam pipe was opened, and she's
tied down right in front of it.
Okay. There's nothing
you can do about that now.
Can't do anything but help her
by working the crime scene.
That's your job.
Open your suitcase,
get your camera.
I can't do this.
You can do it. Yes, you can.
Yesterday you stopped a train.
You can do anything you want
when you put your mind to it.
Don't work me, Rhyme.
- Just tell me what to do next.
- Very slowly, walk the grid...
one foot in front of the other.
I want you to look around you now.
Remember...
crime scenes are three-dimensional--
floors, walls and ceilings.
Yeah, I'm here.
There's something strange.
Things he left for us?
Yes.
- In a cluster again?
- There's a small piece of wood...
and it looks like some hair.
I'm gonna walk you through
collecting the evidence.
You do everything
exactly as I say.
- Oh,Jesus.
- Talk tome.
- It's a bloody bone.
- Where is it?
It's in my fucking hand.
Human?
I think so, yeah.
Photograph it...
bag it.
Okay, that's it.
I'm outta here.
One more thing.
We gotta process the body.
What? I'm no medical examiner.
I can't do that.
I'm not asking you to do an autopsy.
I just want you to--
Just describe the restraints.
They're strange-looking handcuffs.
They look more like
old shackles or something.
And there’s a chain
across her waist.
And her feet are...
bound with a rope.
Hands above her head?
Yeah.
There's also a large piece of flesh
missing from her right forearm.
It's right down to the bone,
like it was surgically removed.
This is what I want you to do.
We're gonna need those handcuffs.
It’s probably our best chance
for good prints.
The M.E. can remove them
when they get here.
The M.E. is all thumbs.
They'll mess up the prints.
Look in the suitcase.
There's a small saw.
Okay.
I want you to saw her hands off
at the wrist line.
We gotta have those cuffs
for prints.
I can't.
Cut her hands off.
We need the handcuffs.
I can't. No.
Saw off her hands,
take off the cuffs.
Listen to me. Saw off her h--
We need those cuffs.
I can't!
- Amelia, we need--
- No, fuck you!
If he wants that woman's hands cut off,
he can come down and do it himself.
Hello?
Who is it?
Jesus.
- Take it easy.
- Shit, what are you doing?
- You okay?
- Am I okay? What are you doing?
Rhyme has been trying
to call you for hours.
Your phone's down.
He was concerned.
My phone's fine.
I don't need his concern.
He needs you over
at his place right away.
I don't work for Lincoln Rhyme.
Rhyme thinks the evidence you collected
indicates there's an other vic in play.
And he's laying that at my feet?
Don't shoot the messenger.
- You just move in?
- Yeah, about a year ago.
Really?
- You were a model.
- Yeah, when I was a kid.
Kid model to street cop--
there's a leap.
For whatever it's worth...
I thought what you did today
was pretty damn terrific.