Episode 32
Dear reporters: As you all know,
my husband and I first met three years ago
without knowing each other's backgrounds.
Aside from my husband,
I have never been in a serious
relationship with anyone, and...
- What is that?- Oh?
Oh, wow! What is that?
I, Jin Hyeong Woo, take
Kang Il Joo as my wife.
For this long life, no
matter what storms may come,
I'll be a husband who
will take care of you.
I, Kang Il Joo, take Jin
Hyeong Woo as my husband.
For this long life; no matter how painful
and thorny the path may be to walk on,
I will be a wife that won't leave you.
Until death do us apart,
we will walk the same path.
Like today's oath, our love will
be constant and be eternal.
- What's going on?
- What kind of situation is this?
Assemblywoman? Ma'am?
The reporters will not be coming.
You're really disappointing me.
I didn't know you would
only amount to this much.
If I didn't do it this way, then you would
never have given me your permission.
Il Joo.
You know how determined I am, so
please return Hyeong Woo to me.
I've already set the date for your
marriage with Executive Director Kwon.
Do you want me to turn Korea's
strongest media outlet into my enemy?
It has always been your enemy.
That marriage goes against my wishes.
What I need is Hyeong Woo, not
a media publication company.
What you need is the media outlet.
You know what I'm trying to make of you.
To that end, I even threw
your brother away.
Even if that may be the
reason you abandoned my mom,
I'm different. I'm going to
have both power and Hyeong Woo.
In my 40 years in politics,
how many people do you think I've seen die?
Sometimes, politics can bring
slaughter to the innocent.
Assemblywoman. Would you mind explaining?
What is this video?
Where did Prime Minister Kang
Seok Hyeon take Jin Hyeong Woo?
Why did you abandon Jin Hyeong Woo
and choose your current husband?
Please clarify, you're the one who
called this press conference.
I'm finished for today.
- Assemblywoman!- Assemblywoman!
Assemblywoman!
Was someone filming at that time?
No, no one but the two people
was inside the church.
I think Jin Hyeong Woo had
installed a hidden camera.
Jin Hyeong Woo, you bastard...
Check with the broadcast station
to see if he was the one who gave them
the video or if it was someone else.
Yes, Sir.
You're Aide Jin Hyeong Woo, right?
- Did you happen to see our
broadcast today?- Yes.
What happened with
Assemblywoman Kang Il Joo?
You two were planning to marry but separated
due to Prime Minister Kang's objection, right?
Is that why you broke the
news of the slush fund?
No comment. That incident is already over.
Mr. Jin Hyeong Woo, for the courtesy
of informing the public, please...
- Jin Hyeong Woo!- Please say something!
My dear, are you okay?
Jin Hyeong Woo, that bastard
who is worse than a dog!
Call him and tell him to clarify.
Well, he was the one who
reported that video,
so there's no way he would take your side.
Why receive this type of treatment from
some trash that you know from the past?
Don't worry.
It's a relief that you know
his true character now.
I'll reattach your wings for you.
I'll punish that damned person
and allow you to fly higher.
It seems that Jin Hyeong Woo
deceived Assemblywoman Kang Il Joo and installed
a hidden camera due to his political ambition.
However, as his corrupt deeds
were discovered by Prime Minister
Kang and he was kicked out,
that's why he decided to
expose this story shamelessly.
To even exploit someone's love
story with a hidden camera...
This is tantamount to a "character
assassination or a [murder]."
You did well. With this, Jin Hyeong Woo won't
be able to hold his head up in front of people,
and my wife will receive sympathy votes.
Thank you.
Did you see the broadcast?
Turn JBS on right now, quickly.
Then are you saying you didn't
know about that video either?
That's right.
Since you saw the video, you may know
that I called a reporter to
publicize that marriage.
However, Prime Minister Kang
blocked that reporter from coming.
Then who could have recorded that video?
I don't know. I've tried to think who it
could be as well, but I just have no clue.
I want to ask JBS.
From whom did you obtain that video?
I'm not at liberty to
discuss that with you.
Just as it was shown on
the blank TV station,
does this breaking story have anything to do with
the Prime Minster's Kang's possible slush fund?
The tip-off about the slush fund has absolutely
nothing to do with Assemblywoman Kang.
As I managed the Eun
Gang Foundation's fund,
my conscience felt guilty.
Is ₩100 billion a small amount of money?
It's something he stole by using his
power to threaten innocent companies.
From what I know, they may be served with
a subpoena for a full investigation.
Because I believe that the law has to be
fair for everyone with justice for all.
Why indict someone without an arrest warrant? Under law, even
if charged, he has the right to contact his defense attorney.
Are you still going to indict a commoner (the general public)
without due process, if he illegally steals $100 million?
Let me ask you one last thing,
what do you think about
Assemblywoman Kang Il Joo?
She abandoned you and married the
son of a powerful media outlet.
I understand Assemblywoman Kang
and I was the one who
told her to marry him.
You did so yourself?
Yes.
In political and human terms, Assemblywoman
Kang is an outstanding individual.
She is not someone whom I can
dare to criticize or scrutinize.
She loved me wholeheartedly.
I'm terribly worried that Assemblywoman Kang's
political career will be hurt because of me.
Although I don't know who revealed this
personal incident at this time or why,
I'll make an earnest appeal to people
who are watching this broadcast.
Kang Il Joo is a more amazing
politician than anyone else I know.
She's someone who has love and a vision.
Please cherish her.
What sh♪t is he saying?
Why did you turn it off? It isn't over yet.
Do we really have to continue to
listen to such shameless words?
He was the one who did this!
I don't think so.
You're really an unpredictable character.
Whoever revealed that video, it becomes revenge
against Kang Seok Hyeon if you just leave it alone.
Why did you do such an interview?
I also eat under your roof.
I have no thought of creating
trouble for your daughter-in-law.
My grudge is against Kang
Seok Hyeon, not Kang Il Joo.
Do you really have such an innocent heart?
What else could it be?
There is so such thing as
"innocence" in this world,
especially for people like us.
I don't care what you do
as long as you place the Blue
Beauty fund in my hands.
I already told you I would do that.
Chairman, only money is your candid truth.
Jin Hyeong Woo, what are you planning?
You're not even a stalker, why
are you doing this again?
Don't deny it!
Did you think I wouldn't know you started
this and you're playing around with Il Joo?
Your life must be really difficult.
Suspecting people like that is a disease.
Your condition is quite serious,
you should go to a hospital.
Shut up and leave this house immediately!
Please leave my house. It's so
noisy whenever you come here.
Father!
Do you think that your media
subordinates are your possessions?
You spent that news prime
time to diss Aide Jin?
That's why our media outlet has
been ranked last in ethics!
What are you? Why are
you staring at Il Joo?
Aren't you going to move
your eyes somewhere else?
I don't want to.
This bastard...
Why are you acting so childish?
Are you taking that bastard's
side in front of me?
Please leave, you disgusting fellow.
Yes, Father.
Now?
You found out who circulated the video?
Ah, did you gather us
to reveal the culprit?
What kind of fearless bastard
did something like that?
It's not that he has the balls,
but rather is full of sh♪t!
It's none other than you.
It was you?
F-father, what are you talking about?
Why would I? I only found out afterward
that these two attempted to marry.
What nonsense...
Who the hell said I did it?
What bastard said that?
Secretary Kim was the one who handed the
USB file over to the broadcast station.
Where did you obtain that?
I heard it through the grapevine
at social drinking events.
Since, they're so big on keeping it
ultra-private, I'm not sure of the true identity.
In return, they said they would hand it
over as long as I matched their price.
You bastard! I bought it to protect Il Joo but you
betrayed me and handed it over to the broadcast station?
Just how much did you receive
from the broadcast station?!
Please forgive me.
However, this was due to my
loyalty to Vice President Kang.
Since you only politically
supported Assemblywoman Kang,
I didn't know what I was doing and...
Look, Father.
You don't honestly think I'm a narrow-minded
brother who'd rat out my younger sister, do you?
Still, it seems you've kept
someone quite nice under you.
Politically, he made a
decision that you needed.
Anyway, she's your political opponent so
you should at least wield that sword.
Father. Actually, I was the one
who ordered this incident.
I'm the brain behind this.
Oops.
I, too, can be quite politically savvy. It's
only because you always favor her over me.
Family should be strength to each other,
does it feel good for you to tear me down?
Did I lie?
Every citizen has a right
to know the truth.
Even when you drove my wife's
child to the brink of death,
I just took it because I
thought I was partly to blame.
That it is my karma.
However... if you cause a
disturbance in this house again,
you should be prepared to leave.
He calls whatever that wench Il
Joo does "political ability,"
but what? Everything I do lacks
ability, doesn't it? Damn it.
Stop drinking and go to bed.
If you cause a scene here, you'll
get marked by Father-in-Law again.
I'm going to drink in my own
house, so what's the problem?
This is Father-in-Law's house.
Hey! This house has been occupied
since my maternal grandfather.
This is clearly my mom's house,
and if we argue about this with blood, my father who doesn't share
a drop of blood with me has no right to live in this house.
Why did you do that?
What are you talking about?
Even if he is the eldest son,
this incident was a huge blow to Il Joo.
I find Il Joo so pitiful.
I know that as well.
However, Il Do is also
part of my bloodline.
I need to give him a last chance,
and this is also a test for Il Joo to
see how she overcomes this crisis.
You, the type of person you are...
You seem pretty logical, yet you want to grasp
both of your bloodlines (both his children).
Why? Do you not like it?
No.
No, Prime Minister. You're
always logical, Sir.
Thank you.
But why aren't you asking me
about when I met Jin Hyeong Woo
the last time I left this house?
I don't think it's my place to ask.
He came to see me twice.
The first time, he asked me to
start over at a restaurant,
and the second time,
he was beside me when I
fainted because of Mi Rae.
When I said I was going to go
to you, he told me not to.
But I still had to come here again.
Why did you do that?
You probably felt resentful towards me, but Hyeong Woo
is still young and has a bright future ahead of him.
Did you do that because you
were worried about Mi Rae?
Or did you do that because you
wanted revenge on Il Joo?
Both of the reasons are wrong.
I came because I realized I like you a lot.
Hate appears because of love.
I'm truly grateful that
you came to seek me,
and I...
really love you a lot.
I'm sorry,
and I'm thankful.
Assemblywoman Kang Il Joo
Why did you come here?
I was thinking that because of me,
you might lose the public's support.
I came because I was worried.
Still, you can't come here. What
will you do if someone sees?
That's why I came secretly at night.
I brought some files
that'll be of help to you.
Jongno District File
Please look over this very carefully.
Your district voters may be pleased.
Why are you doing this to me?
You have a grudge against my father,
so why do you keep helping me?
I already told you
that because I was deceived by
a woman named Shin Eun Soo,
I didn't know your worth.
You were the only one hurt because of me.
Still, don't be like this. There'll
be trouble if my father finds out.
I know. So...
if you want to earn more of the
Prime Minister's trust, attack me.
The envelope contains recent files
on me and President Kwon Soo Myeong.
Reveal this to the newspapers tomorrow.
Then the Prime Minister will trust you.
Timing and Subtitles brought to
you by The Glamorous Team @Viki
Is Chairman Kwon Soo Myeong Above the Law?
The Corrupt Family
Controversial Former Aide Jin Hyeong
Woo To Be Investigated by Prosecutors
On Suspicion of Illegally Receiving ₩5 Billion
in Stock From Chairman Kwon Soo Yeong.
Did you do this?
Yes.
You did well. Your support
has dropped significantly.
If you have a means to
retrieve it, bring it.
I am in the middle of planning.
You're okay, right? You can
overcome this well, right?
Of course. I'm my father's daughter.
Let's eat breakfast.
Director Han, your son is about to
be investigated by the prosecutors.
What, to receive only ₩5 billion of stock,
he stabbed my father in the back?
He's such a cheapskate.
Since he committed a crime, it's only
right that he should be punished.
I was shocked after seeing
Chairman Kwon's household.
The elder son and the younger son
were exempted from military service.
The granddaughter was accepted into an American college
with a special admission. The grandson was born overseas.
The mother and the daughter-in-law purchased
foreign real estate and evaded the tax.
You all are really quite the set.
I also heard from Ji Eun.
The reason for your military service exemption was "deficiency
in the ability to discriminate or to control his impulses."
If you have a weak mind, you don't
have to do military service?
Aunt, that is slightly related
to a person's mental state.
Oh my god! So in one word,
you're just a psycho.
You don't look like one. Are you okay? He
doesn't choke you at night or anything?
Father-in-Law, you really went too far.
Of course you should attack Jin Hyeong Woo,
but getting to the bottom of
my family and me was too much.
I did my best for Il Joo
by using the media.
Don't argue about this with me,
go and argue with your father.
The one who fired first was your father.
Oh my, this is an octopus side dish. Team
Leader Go, don't you have any octopus heads?
I want to nibble a full shiny
octopus head into pieces.
I'm sorry. Everything was
sliced before serving.
I said I want to eat it whole!
Oh, isn't this just so pretty?
You are really deficient in ability.
I'm not sure if I'll be able to see you
get your head straight before I die.
Nothing will happen to Hyeong Woo, right?
I heard he was going to the prosecutors.
By chance, did you show that
expression to Kang Seok Hyeon?
No. But, as a response to the ₩100 billion,
Prime Minister is so firmly determined to get back
at him that I am worried this case will get bigger.
It seems you forgot Kwon Soo
Myeong is behind Hyeong Woo.
He's holding onto him
because he has some use,
and since nothing good will come to him if he's in the
prosecutor's office for long, he'll take him out immediately.
Of course, Hyeong Woo was the one who
handed the files over to Il Joo.
He told her to attack him? Why?
You said yourself that Kang Seok
Hyeon gave Il Joo her final warning.
"I'll put the Blue Beauty on the line as the condition
to make you President, so just cut Hyeong Woo out."
To separate those two people,
Hyeong Woo is shaking Il Joo up right now.
Then, the clarification
interview the other day...
Is he saying he'll seduce her?
That's what you're doing right now.
Hyeong Woo, how did we end up like this?
Have you been well?
I called Hye Jeong and found out,
but your child...
She's undergoing treatment in
the hypothermia therapy unit.
Could you please give me some of your time?
I won't beat around the bush.
The Little Madam was poor but she seduced
Vice President Lee, replaced his wife,
and is now in that position.
Truthfully, you're in the same position,
even though the Prime Minister was
the one who held out his hand first.
Yes, I've also stood all
day working at a market
as my legs swelled.
I needed someone to save me
from that dreadful tunnel.
Please tell me the method too.
There's no reason I can't be
like the Little Madam too.
Well... the method?
Isn't sincerity the key to
all human relationships?
After seeing the news now, it seems Executive
Director Kwon will be having a difficult time.
On top of that, Il Joo isn't in a
relationship to console him or hug him.
At times like these, shouldn't you
become the warmest person to him?
Ah, right! If you want to create a chance for
conversation, having similar hobbies will be good.
You coming here for me, isn't it pointless?
Truthfully, you're not supposed
to eat things like this.
If you like it, then so do I.
However, is marketplace food that tasty?
Yes. Whenever I come to the
marketplace, I feel alive
and I get hungry. This place feels
like a place where people live.
Why do you look at me like that?
I'm really sorry towards you.
Sorry for what?
Those documents. That incident
happened because of me,
but I sided with Il Joo.
Your feelings must be badly hurt.
You should stop talking about that now.
I've also wronged Il Joo and you.
Even in marketplaces like this, I didn't
come often outside of election season.
When I was young, I was the same as you.
You really make me embarrassed.
Then we should come here often, and next
time we should also have a bottle of soju.
Nothing has been accomplished
without spilling blood.
Lotus flowers also bloom in the mud.
What you shouldn't forget is that you must make
flowers bloom, no matter how and what you go through.
Whatever you have done
to achieve your goal,
even if you have killed someone,
I'll forgive you.
I won't believe in whatever you say
because I know your true self.
It's really good.
Right?
You look like you came here
to buy a present for Madame.
Men are usually embarrassed to
come into shops like these.
You're quite thoughtful.
Il Joo doesn't like this type of style.
Oh my, why?
It's extravagant, sexy, and pretty.
She must not know that clothing
starts from the underwear.
Of course. Rather than the
clothes revealed on the outside,
clothing like this which
is hidden deep inside
is the consideration for
you the one you love.
Oh my, how can you think the same as me?
I'll have to leave now as
I've got other things to do.
Well, have fun shopping.
Later on, if you happen...
to get bored shopping by yourself
like this, give me a call.
It's so nice to have a friend to
talk to when you're shopping.
010-478-1379
Pawn (Subordinate)
Ta-da!
Your subordinate soldier was in danger where she
was almost jailed. How could you ignore that?
How can I just get in contact with you now?
Captain, I'm really disappointed.
Sorry, sorry. I was busy.
That's why I prepared
something as an apology.
Ta-da!
This is... a limited edition. Wow!
How did you get this? Where did you buy it?
Ah, right. More importantly than
this, put some money in my account.
Money? Where are you going to spend it?
It's kind of a good deed and
an investment for the future.
I'll report everything to you later. You'll
give it to me, right? Right? Right? Right?
Okay! Do you think this Captain can't even do
that much for his one and only footsoldier?
I'll deposit it right now!
As expected, you're the Captain! This has
returned our relationship back to normal.
It's recovered 100%.
Yay!
I said I'll repay it immediately!
Is there any way you can lend it?
I'm being like this because the house owner said she won't
ever extend the contract deadline for the security deposit.
Jeong Soon's mom? I
already gave her a call!
I got it, bye! I'm going crazy...
Mother! I'm coming in. Cold, cold.
What? Why are you here?
Hey! How can you wear your shoes inside?!
Oh, I'm sorry. I picked up the
habit from living in a hotel.
Beom Soo isn't here and
I'm busy with something
so whether you're Ah Reum or Da Reum,
leave if you're going to say nonsense.
Oh? I came to fulfill my
promise to you, Mother.
Here.
What is this?
Why?
No... you really didn't believe me?
I surely said I would lend you that money with three
nos: no interest, no collateral, and no guarantee.
But, Mother... Do you have
any ramyun in the house?
I couldn't eat lunch and I'm hungry.
You... Who are you?
What's your identity?
Aigoo, Chief Prosecutor. This time, you should
look forward to being the Attorney General.
Even if you release such a small
minnow, it won't affect any situation.
Did I say a word to you
when my son was demoted?
Jin Hyeong Woo is like a son to me.
Release him.
That's good.
It's been a while, we should go
fishing in the ocean sometime.
- What are you doing? - Do you know what type of
chance this is that you're releasing Jin Hyeong Woo?
Because you accepted that bastard, Father-in-Law
is digging through our household!
Do you think that your
father-in-law did that?
Of course. Jin Hyeong Woo, Jin Hyeong
Woo, it's all because of Jin Hyeong Woo!
Silly fool. It was the doing of your wife
that you cherish and treasure so much!
What?
You planned this with Jin Hyeong Woo, didn't you?
Since you knew that my father needed Jin Hyeong Woo,
you attacked my household knowing
that he would be released quickly.
It's been a while since I've
acted as a filial daughter.
When big-shot media outlet
kingpin Father-in-Law
tried to steal my father's ₩100
billion, he expected this much.
What?
How could you attack my household...
No, how could you attack me?
I stood on your side and worked so hard
to minimize your losses however I could!
Is that why you took out my documents?
Is that why you revealed the
documents in my bag to my father?
Don't do me any favors.
Timing and Subtitles brought to
you by The Glamorous Team @Viki
I went to the prosecutors. They
released you sooner than I expected.
You can't be discovered out here.
We can't waste my efforts.
I wanted to thank you for last time.
Then, would you be my drinking
buddy for the last time?
Are you okay? You didn't bring a
car, did you? I'll call a taxi.
Don't touch my body.
You're drunk. Listen to me.
What are you doing?
Then you should never have touched my body.
Don't think about shaking me up just
because you helped me with that.
I'll make it even with kissing
by getting slapped on the cheek.
Why the heck are you acting like this? You're
the one that left because you didn't like me.
You're the one who chose Eun Soo without even looking back when I
so desperately grabbed onto you, so why are you doing this now?
I know too!
My ankles were held so firmly by my first love that
I couldn't even properly look at you for years.
So what do you want me to do?
Just because you act like this...
I can't throw away my
dream now for you again.
This is my last chance!
Although I can't forgive myself for
not knowing your worth until now,
if your dream is shattered because of me,
I think it will be even
harder to forgive myself.
Because I couldn't protect you till now,
I want to protect your dream even now.
Hyeong Woo.
Hyung, you're here.
Here.
This is our next target.
B.B... are you talking about
women's makeup, BB cream?
Blue Beauty, the Blue Beauty fund.
It's the immense slush fund
that Kang Seok Hyeon has.
Kang Seok Hyeon
500,000,000,000
Credit Suisse Bank
500...
Suisse...
Yeah, Gi Hyeong. I need to ask a favor.
Could you check an account
at Credit Suisse?
Did you find out about it?
Yeah, that account number is definitely
Prime Minister Kang's account.
₩500 billion?
So, what is this? You're saying the
account he put out as bait to catch you
was the actual fund.
That's a piece of cake
to find out that fund.
That 500 billion has already been transferred to
a different bank, so it's not there any more.
Then that 500 billion is the
fund Blue Beauty manages.
I don't know if there'll
be more than that either.
However, Kang Il Joo's political
career has suffered because of this
and Kang Seok Hyeon will attempt to
bring that money into this country.
That's our target.
Mother-in-Law, please tell Father-in-Law
it was a misunderstanding.
I can really swear to this, this
incident wasn't my husband's doing.
What kind of strength do I have?
I can even be chased out of this house.
Mother-in-Law!
Here.
There'll be a terrible stench if the
milk is absorbed into the carpet.
I just soaked this in warm
water so it'll be okay soon.
You have to study hard, Mi Rae.
Otherwise, you'll have to do work like
what your mom is doing over there. Right?
What are you doing? If you don't hurry,
the carpet will absorb the smell.
Coffee stains don't erase easily.
Why aren't you cleaning it up?
Y-yes, yes, yes, yes.
What should I do about this?
That's enough! Will that get it out?
The Prime Minister bought me this clothing.
I don't think I can wear it now.
Was it ₩10 billion you embezzled from Eun Gang
Gallery by manipulating the account books?
If we compute compound interest,
and add all the interest,
is it ₩10 billion?
6 million 280 thousand and 74.
Oh! If that is tax-exempt, we have to
add another about 20 million, don't we?
Leave that account here and go.
What? Am I crazy?
Do you know how difficult it was for me to collect
that money? Why would I give it to you and leave?
I would rather reveal that to Father-in-Law and
tell him that you're trying to take that money!
You can do that. That money didn't
come into my hands, did it?
If that's revealed, you'll go
to the prosecutors immediately.
If you want to leave this house
and go to jail, go ahead.
Did you think you would be safe after
abandoning my daughter in storage?
It's your turn, Prime Minister.
Is something worrying you?
I need to bring in some
money from overseas,
but that's not very easy.
It's not something you should
concern yourself over.
Do you have a slush fund overseas as well?
You can just use the Eun Gang Gallery.
What are you saying?
Actually last time, about the review you told
me to do on Eun Gang Gallery's finances...
There were many problems.
Representative Lee personally took quite a
bit of money from selling the paintings.
I already presumed that.
She's treated harshly by Il Do
so she was bound to do that.
Didn't you also keep it a secret
because you felt sorry for her?
Yes, but that method...
She made a slush fund by
selling paintings overseas.
She did money-laundering in the middle too.
This isn't something that
can be solved so easily.
Although using the gallery
is a good method,
the process of laundering money
abroad is quite complicated.
Prime Minister, could I try
to manage Eun Gang Gallery?
I can't just let money continue
to leak out as it's doing now.
I want to be helpful to you.
I don't want to involve
you in illegal matters.
You're trying to bring in
money because of Il Joo.
I want to help too.
You know I worked in the
accounting department.
I can do well.
Please allow me to repay my
sorry feelings towards Il Joo.
If you win this round,
I'll put you in charge.
Great.
I shouldn't lose while I take
advantage of my nine-point lead.
Green Natural Ecological Park Development
plan at Mountain 221-8 Area, Jongno-Gu.
Green Natural Ecological Park?
If we change from the hillside
town to the Ecological Park,
90% of the town residents agree with the
idea according to the study results.
Please look at it.
What about the people living there?
They live in illegal residences anyway,
so we can move them to a different area.
How much do you think you'll need?
About ₩10 billion will be enough.
₩10 billion is moving? Are you sure?
I got it, Gi Hyeong. Continue watching it.
Why? Kang Seok Hyeon's
Swiss account is moving?
Yeah. Since he can't bring in a large
amount from overseas directly,
He will look for a money-laundering
company. We have to get that job.
By the way, why only ₩10 billion?
You said ₩500 billion
It's easy to be discovered if he brings
in a large amount from the start.
Also, I threw bait only worth ₩10 billion.
You made a very good stratagem,
to take the media background
away from Il Joo,
a plan to take her husband away from her.
How did you know that?
Look at what Hyeong Woo did
to help what you're doing.
It can't be only the woman who is
all hot and bothered by herself,
because it's the man who draws the sword.
It seems Hyeong Woo fanned the flames to
make Executive Director Kwon draw his sword.
Even though you've entered this house again,
those people won't trust you completely.
Buy their trust with this.
You're telling me to buy Il Joo's heart.
You can't see the shadow at noon, the
time when the sun is the hottest.
But as darkness approaches,
the shadow becomes longer.
Even if you walk through
that darkness alone,
don't be afraid.
I'll always be the shadow behind you.
On the way back from my walk,
I saw the maids bringing this in
saying it was mail for CEO Kang.
I took it to bring it to him but I was
bothered because there is no sender's name.
So I opened it.
Even though I clearly gave a warning,
you created a disturbance
in this house again.
Father, what about this? This is just
Brother-in-Law Kwon's affair with a maid.
Why is this my fault?
That's right. It's Miss Il Joo's fault for not
being able to control her husband properly.
Did you try to aim at Il Joo, again?
You even had someone follow Son-in-Law
Kwon to take pictures like this?
Father.
What are you talking about? Why
would I do something like this?
I have no intention of believing
what you say anymore.
Pack your things and get out
of this house immediately.
I really didn't do this,
why can't you believe me?
Has there ever been a time when
you properly told the truth?
- Didn't you hear me tell you to get out?
- Father!
Manager Jo and Team Leader Go,
call the maids and drag
him out immediately!
Ah, so refreshing.
- I'm sorry.- Oh no, it's fine.
You must crave alcohol on such a nice day like this.
Alcohol was the matchmaker between you and me.
Um, I'll use the restroom
and be right back.
Oh, okay. Hurry, hurry and go.
Oh, excuse me.
Please exchange this for
grape juice with a dose.
Grape juice with a dose?
Wine. Fill it with red wine, okay?
Didn't you say earlier you couldn't
drink because you're pregnant?
Pregnant? What pregnancy? In professional terms, they
call that a lie. Anyway, fill this up with red wine.
Yes.
Wait.
This isn't right. Don't
you know communication?
What needs to be said?
You said you weren't pregnant.
You just put on a show.
From the very beginning, did I
say that I was pregnant myself?
You! You were the one who
pushed me into pregnancy.
I was nauseous due to drinking too much
from the previous night so I gagged.
It's your fault for thinking of my
gagging as the gagging you wanted.
No, that... So, what I'm saying is...
Hey, go to the hospital.
Meet a proper doctor,
get diagnosed, and take
your medication on time.
Otherwise, it is hard to become a human.
What did you just say right now?
If you need a natural remedy, eat
mugwort and garlic for 100 days.
But you'll still be hopeless.
Hey, why are you being like this?
I also got goose bumps to
act pregnant at this age.
Do you know how many times I thought about jumping into the fire to
make myself a roast chicken because you're too cheesy and corny?
OK, that's enough.
I played well, octopus-head!
What's the matter?
How could something like that happen?
All right. I'll meet him.
What is going on?
It's nothing.
Thank you.
I don't really like this,
but a win is a win.
I lost with the difference of one house.
Welcome, Elder.
Chief Director.
Truthfully, I only decided
to manage Eun Gang Gallery.
I'm not confident to become
the Chief Director...
I'll help you beside you.
You can just do this with the spirit
you have when you play baduk.
You play in tactical moves
rather than in practical moves.
I will learn the practical moves as well.
I have a lot of greed.
What does "Brother-in-Law
left the house" mean?
Team Leader Go was talking about it.
My father didn't forget his attack on me.
Didn't he agree to forgive him for that?
On top of that, my sister-in-law was caught
for stealing money from the Eun Gang Gallery.
Eun Soo agreed to take over my brother
and my sister-in-law's position.
Have we made up now?
Just yesterday, we had a huge argument
because of Jin Hyeong Woo.
A married couple's fight is like
cutting water with a knife.
You're here, Executive Director Kwon.
How are you here?
I told her to come back
because I think I misunderstood last time.
I'm sorry for causing trouble for you two.
Give me the money first. Are you joking?
I have to confirm that you
really took the video.
Prime Minister.
If I die, Il Joo will
never move as you wish.
I'm fine if you abandon me. However, however, Prime
Minister, you can't throw away your dream as well...
That time,
I wondered what I should do if a murder
happened on my boat so I secretly recorded it
but the guy filmed in the video
appeared on TV yesterday.
I wondered who the Prime Minister was back then.
It's Prime Minister Kang Seok Hyeon, isn't it?
How much?
I got it. I reported the money laundering
companies that you mentioned to Interpol.
Kang Seok Hyeon's side would probably know those
companies were tailed when they entrust them with it.
We'll get an opportunity.
I even set up a company long
ago to prepare for this.
Is it a real company?
I just have the name.
It's a paper company.
There are quite a lot of
money-laundering showings too.
What's the name of the company?
Cukoo Corporation
These are the results after examining
the companies you mentioned.
There are some problems in
the companies we checked.
The only company left is called CK.
The fee is reasonable and their
accomplishments are also good.
Based in Hong Kong,
Cukoo Corporation?
Yes.
Let's start now.
Cukoo...
From Schweizer Bank to Stern Montrose Inc.
Frankfurt, Germany,
€7,660,000 is transferred for real estate.
That money is supposed
to come to our country.
From Stern Montrose Inc. to La Pluie-Frédéric
Import & Export Co., Paris, France,
€7,660,000 is transferred for merchandise.
From La Pluie-Frédéric Import & Export Co.,
Paris, France to Chaohu Co. in Hangzhou, China,
¥54,570,000 is deposited for antiques.
As you can see, it's doing
well in Hangzhou, China.
It seems to be going well.
Department Head, just a moment.
Why is it stopping in so many countries?
To avert the possible prosecutor's tracing,
the money is processed in
many different countries.
The money will probably go
to Eun Gang Gallery next.
You're selling paintings
to that Chinese company.
Prime Minister, something is strange.
What is it?
This Cukoo Corporation.
It is definitely based in Hong Kong,
but our employee tracked the
IP address and it's in Korea.
It could be a trap set
up by the prosecutors,
or it's also possible that
someone is targeting your money.
Jin Hyeong Woo.
It could be him.
Can you investigate if you
track the IP address?
Yes, we just need 10 minutes.
Please call me.
- Manager Jo, start the car.- Yes.
Is something going on?
It seems there's a problem.
Stay here.
Hyeong Woo, I think you've been caught.
Hurry and run away.
How long do you think it'll take to
move the money to Eun Gang Gallery?
Around two hours. It takes
some time in China.
I understand, I think I'll
arrive in 30 minutes.
Go to this address.
Understood.
Timing and Subtitles brought to
you by The Glamorous Team @Viki
You can't call me rashly. What if
you get caught by Kang Seok Hyeon?
Prime Minister Kang is going
over there right now!
Here? How did he know?
What is it?
The money came in.
What are you planning to do? The
money didn't come in from China yet.
I have ₩10 billion.
Doesn't Kang Seok Hyeon leave for the
prosecutors tomorrow? We have to imprison him.
What are you going to do? Can
you launch a frontal attack?
Yes, Mother. I'm sure I
can put him in prison.