"Save the Planet".
Whenever I've read that
bumper sticker, I had to lie.
Save The Planet... what for?
And from what?
From ourselves?
Life's simple, kill or be killed.
Don't get involved
and always finish the job.
A Survivor's code... my code.
It all sounds great...
'till the day you find yourself
confronted with a choice.
A choice to make a difference...
to help someone, or to walk away
and save yourself.
I learned something that day,
you can't always walk away.
Too bad it was the day I died.
Get up!
Move it.
Get back.
Remember me?
You sold me a gun that don't work,
you almost got me killed...
I paid you $20.00 for it,
I want my money back.
Give me that.
- How much?
- $15.00.
How much?
- Alright, $12.50.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Toorope?
I'll owe you.
- Toorope, are you leaving?
- I'll see you soon.
Okay, see you.
Hey, Toorope! Toorope, somebody
came by looking for you.
Real good.
... what a massacre!
...at the peak of the rush hour,
bombs were detonated in...
Let's go, Toorope!
Carl is that you?
I'm not gonna ask again!
Let's go!
I thought you were over
the Sudan killing babies.
- Shut up!
- Remember the last time we met...
I told you if you ever
point that gun at me again...
- I'd kill you.
- Let's go!
Who would hire a babykiller
to get me?
- Watch out!
- Who?
- Let's get him!
- Hold your fire.
No shit, Carl! If you wanted me dead
you would've blown up the building.
- Who?
- Gorsky
Karl, you're a disgrace
to the profession...
you're not a mercenary,
you're a terrorist.
You need two things to live
in this business...
your balls and your word...
you don't have either.
You know the difference
between you and me, Carl?
I still got both.
You killed him!
- What the hell's this?
- Take it easy.
What'd you do that for?
Why did you kill him?
Personal between him and me.
You are a hard man
to find, Toorope.
I'm not hiding...
You could have knocked.
I needed to be sure that you
are the same idealist...
who worked for me 10 years ago.
So you knew,
I was gonna kill Carl.
I don't like you, Gorsky...
you can't trust me
and I can't trust you.
Look at you...
still in this shit-hole...
surviving... no friends...
no family, no future.
We are the same...
You and me.
We're not the same.
What do you want?
I need a smuggler.
I don't do refugees anymore,
use your own cargo...
you own the borders anyway.
- Only on this side.
- This is an overseas delivery?
A girl, she needs to be
in America in 6 days.
Why're you playing with me?
You know I can't get back
to that country.
You know the U.N. Passports,
are impossible to fake.
This is not a fake.
Injected in your neck
when pass the official border.
This is your new life.
- I'll do it for half a mill.
- I can make you do it for free.
You can't make me do shit,
Gorski...
but you could pay me what I need,
so I can get the job done right.
A car will pick you up outside...
everything you need,
will be in the trunk.
Cross me and you'll have no
place to hide anymore.
Toorope.
That goes both ways...
Gorski.
Shit...
NOELITE CONVENT MONGOLIA
41*10'N. 74*46'E.
Good morning,
you must be Toorope.
I am sister Rebeka.
I just want to bring three
simple rules to your attention...
before we start our journey.
We?
I'm here to pick up one girl.
Wherever she goes, I go.
That is rule number one...
Rule number two:
The less contact she has with
the outside world, the better.
You're here to protect her
from outside influences,
That includes seeing,
hearing and feeling.
You know, it's a harsh world
out there, sister.
I know...
that is why we live in here.
Oh shit...
okay, what's the 3rd rule?
No foul language.
Do we have an agreement?
You listen
to my one and only rule.
Dont fuck with me...
or I leave you standing
in the middle of nowhere...
with nothing but your ass
to sell, to get back here...
your perfect world.
Do we have an agreement?
Obviously,
you're not a gentleman.
Obviously not.
Now, that we have
an understanding...
picks up the bag.
No.
YOU ARE HERE
TROISTK TRAINSTATION
BERING STRAIT
CANADA
MILITARY ZONE
What's your name?
My name?
You don't have to talk to him.
You didn't introduce yourself.
My name is Toorope.
- Are you taking as to New York?
- Yes...
Now, please get into the car.
Are you a killer, Mr. Toorope?
Look lady,
I'm just the delivery boy...
and to me,
you're just a package.
I'm not your friend, I'm not your
brother, I'm not your boyfriend...
in 6 days I'm gonna deliver
you and never see you again.
Sister Rebeka is right,
we shouldn't even talk.
Come on.
Comfy?
Your Highness,
the child has left the convent.
At last.
Six days until we reveal
our miracle to the world.
Your Highness, press conference
will begin shortly.
She's coming... let's pray.
TROITSK, KAZAKHSTÁN
RUSSIAN BORDER TOWN
Let's hurry up, the train's
gonna leave soon.
Take your bag.
Are you realy going
to need all that?
We never can have
enough fire power, sister.
In fact.
Never touched a gun in my life.
Now will be the perfect
moment to start.
No thank you,
I can defend myself.
Stay close, this is the real world,
there's no mercy for the weak.
Just because we are peaceful,
that doesn't mean we're weak.
It does here.
Not so fast,
let me see what you have!
- Change.
- What're you doing?
We located the target...
contact New York.
Patch me through Gorsky...
we found her.
Okay... be careful now.
The Neolite's
will be watching too.
My daughter must not be harmed.
Put this on.
Come on.
I'm scared...
can I hold your hand?
Hold mine.
Hang On.
Okay, give me three.
Where did he go?
What're you doing?
Come on.
Hey!
Hey, come here.
- She is on the run.
- Hey!
Aurora, stop!
- What're you doing?
- Stop! Nobody move!
- Don't go that way.
- She's not used to crowds.
- We have to go there, we have no time.
- We have to get away...
What is wrong with you?
Make her walk or I'll carry her.
- Don't have her...
- No, don't go that way...
- I'll do it now.
- Or we will die.
Come on.
We go to the train,
we need to catch it, come on.
Those tigers in the cage...
they weren't real, right?
Siberian tigers
went extinct in 2017.
The last one died
in the Moscow zoo.
What is you? A walking
wildlife encyclopedia?
They were clones?
Second generation clones,
not real tigers...
Copies of copies.
But they're living creatures.
Made by God.
No, they were organic machines
made by man.
God made man in his image,
so what man creates...
is also God's will.
Is this what you teach her
in the convent?
You wanna talk? Tell me what
happened at the market place.
How'd you know
about the explosion?
If I'm gonna protect you...
I need to know
whats wrong with you.
She was scared... her first
time out of the convent...
and you put us in that situation.
Your attention please, we're about
to pass through high radiations wall.
For your security, the shutters
will now be lowered.
First time
out of the convent, huh?
VLADIVOSTOK, RUSSIA
REFUGEE CAMP
43*05'N. 131*59'E.
744833 REFUGEES
Stop.
All your property goes there.
All of it.
Okay, we're done here,
let them go through.
Stay close.
- What are we doing here?
- Looking for a plane.
They must be somewhere
around here.
- I got them, they're right here.
- Better lay off...
be right there in a minute,
and you... dont talk to anybody.
They're splitting up,
what we do now?
Everybody maintain their position.
Get up! Dead man.
Hey! Toorope.
- How are you?
- How you doing?
What're you doing in this
beautiful part of Russia?
- Watch it.
- Working for who?
Hey! Hey! Two shots.
Gorsky.
He made me an offer
I couldn't refuse.
What can I do for you?
I need 3 passes on the boat...
and 2 snow-bikes
on the other side.
- You crossing?
- I'm delivering...
The girl.
Her?
Who is she?
Hell, I don't Know.
- Where you taking her?
- America.
What America? You're on
the terrorist list there.
Yeah.
You gonna need a passport,
a new identity, you shitting me?
- You got a passport?
- Yeah, and I'm not coming back.
That is a bold move.
I got 50 G's sayin'
you can help me out.
When?
Now.
You don't have to look.
Who is he?
He's a lost soul.
See you at the landing,
at 0:600 sharp.
You got it.
- Who was that?
- An old friend, a good smuggler.
- You trust him?
- I dont trust anybody, come on.
Sorry kids,
these girls are with me.
- Just let them go, Toorope.
- How do you know my name?
We know a lotta things
you dont know.
Yeah, like what?
Like, you don't know
what you're doing?
- I'm doing my job.
- Forget your job.
- What?
- One million, tax free.
Take the money and walk out
without a fight...
Make it easy on yourself,
Toorope.
After him!
Move.
Help!
No! No!
Aurora!
Hey!
- Aurora!
- Hey, man! Let the girl go.
Just let her go, let her go.
Another one is what we got,
another forfeit for Mc'Gilla.
Hey, man! Wait, I didn't say...
I'm gonna do this.
Get over there.
Wanna fight? Let's go.
Come on.
No, stop! Stop!
Stop, Toorope!
Stop it!
Stop!
Dont kill him.
He doesn't want to hurt me.
He wanted to protect me.
Your father sent us.
- My father?
- Yes, your father.
Get away from us.
Get away from us!
It's okay, come here.
I have to know.
No, Aurora...
Aurora.
Aurora! Aurora!
Wait!
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
Come on.
Let's go! Come on, let's go!
Move it!
Come on.
Go! Go!
Let her go!
The next one dies!
Come with us...
we're ready to die for you.
I don't want anyone
to die for me.
What the hell
you think you're doing?
What's wrong with you?
- You think this is a game?
- Why did you wanted to shoot them?
- You're trying to get us killed?
- They were gonna let me go.
- You don't know that.
- And what were you gonna do?
Shoot me in the head? Shoot them
'till you ran outta ammo?
Stop it.
I told you,
I take you to New York.
And I will.
You don't have to like me.
They said my father is alive.
No, baby girl, he isn't.
He died.
BERING STRAIT
INTERNATIONAL WATERS
This is way too many refugees, the
ice is getting thinner every year.
They're loosing cargo all the time.
They're not gonna all,
get on that boat.
Make sure we do.
This god-damn global warming
is bad for business.
What's happening?
Watch this.
Okay!
- There's not much time.
- Now boarding is less then...
They don't wanna be spotted
by satellites.
Hurry, come on!
Now boarding reached 4 minutes.
Now boarding reached 1 minute...
1 minute.
Move!
Come on.
No!
Get off!
You can't do this!
They die out there.
- No!
- Stop! Don't touch that!
Get away from there.
- What're you doing? Stop!
- No!
Stop it! Dont do that.
What's wrong?
It's this place.
Hey! Hey! Easy.
- Take it easy.
Go back up! Now!
- Okay, okay... relax.
- We go back up.
- Take it easy.
- Now.
No! They're gonna die!
You can't do that!
Let her go.
Don't let them die! No!
You just can't leave them there!
They die! They die! They die!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
What the hell was that?
When I was 17 years old,
living in San Francisco...
my life was a mess.
I met the wrong man,
I was lost in darkness.
But when the high priestess
of our church opened the doors...
that led me into the path of light.
I joined the No-lights...
and I ended up in the convent.
It was the heaven for women,
who needed to heal.
I worked in the orphanage...
she arrived.
A baby.
Her father was dead, nobody knew
anything about the mother.
I took her as my own...
I fed her, I thought her.
Everything was fine...
until 3 months ago.
The doctor came, gave her a pill,
he was with her for 10 minutes...
and that's when it started.
Change, huh?
Like schizophrenia...
Spasms.
But nothing, nothing makes
sense, is what you saw today.
But how could she know, how to
operate a 30 year old Russian sub?
She's always known things,
that she never experienced...
to walk and speak
when she was 2 years old.
I've never met a kid,
that could speak at 2 years old.
19 different languages.
- Who else knows about this?
- Nobody but the Doctor.
He told me to keep it
a secret to protect her.
He said... that we would get the
best medical help in the America...
She needs help.
Crew, get ready to surface...
Get her ready.
You know, two years ago...
it was in Pakistan, I saw
this viral bomb go off...
I saw it from the air, it was...
incredible, everybody died.
She's carrying, ain't she?
All the symptoms fit,
all that weird behaviour.
I tell you what she's carrying...
a weapon.
Do you have any idea,
how much money she's worth?
If she's carrying a virus...
I'll kill her myself
and burn the body.
BERING STRAIT
ALASKA
What happened to them?
Fire Drones, anything
that moves is shot on sight.
It's 10 miles to the D.M.Z.
Then, let's make it
10 fast miles.
Let's go.
Look out, they're coming...
Shit, we got spotted.
Hit it!
Break.
Quick, get close to me...
Hop on her bike.
I'll throw them off.
Where are you going?
Pick up on our way out.
We're only a mile
from the border.
- Toorope! We need help.
- Don't worry...
you're almost there.
- Toorope, we need help now.
- Hang on, I'm getting there...
Stop! We have to get Toorope.
Toorope!
He's not dead.
Ahh... shit!
Toorope, stay with me.
He's not reacting.
He's bleeding to death...
I need your help, okay?
We gotta get outta here, now.
It's a small piece of metal.
- I'm gonna take it out...
- What do you need?
Just hold him.
Look, we don't have time
for this, okay?
- They're gonna send more Drones.
- It's alright.
- Have you got it?
- I've got it.
- He's okay.
- There is no bandage.
We should never have come back.
He knows the rules.
I'll save that later.
Hey...
- now you and the passport are mine.
- What are you doing?
- You... I don't need.
- Careful...
Like I said, trust no one.
No Man.
It's good...
Where did you learn to cook?
Rule number one in the
mercenary handbook.
You never had a woman
take care of you?
Auh...
Sorry.
No, not in my line of work.
- Ahh...
- Finished.
- She get's pleasure out of it.
- Cry Baby.
Cry Baby?
What is that?
Pain Killer.
- No, thank you.
- Come on, live a little.
No.
Aurora, stop!
Spit it out.
Girls! We made it across
the border.
Here is to survival...
and thank you
for saving my life.
Maybe now you can trust somebody.
We protected each other...
Like family.
We're all going to die
in New York.
Good night.
She's just scared.
Yeah, right.
Go back to sleep.
We still have a long way
ahead of us.
What are you doing?
We go through customs tomorrow.
Can't take these.
You know, when sister Rebeka
first hugged me as a baby...
it was a night like this.
Aurora, that's where I got my name,
from the Chaos.
It suits you.
You're risking
your life for me, why?
I've done my time.
All this killing and pain and...
war, for what?
I'm tired.
Tired of it all.
You're my only chance
out of this now.
And go where?
27 Cedar Grove.
Near Canada, it's upstate New York.
Where my parents had a farm...
more like a cabin with a lotta land.
It's probably in ruins...
but I might be able
to fix it up.
There is no place like home.
You can't depend,
on used to be.
For reason to pause 1939.
That's right.
Toorope.
Are you really going to kill me
and burn my body?
I hope I won't have to.
KITIMAT, CANADA
10 miles from American border
30 minutes... Toorope,
the bus leaves in 30 minutes.
There's a plane to New York,
that flies in two hours.
Passengers, on flight 712
to New York...
please proceed to gate 211
for immdediate boarding.
You are now
leaving Canada.
We hope
you enjoyed your stay.
You walk through the
Main-gate to America.
Welcome to America.
Stop!
NEW YORK CITY
Population 22.7 M.
A miracle in the making.
Tomorrow is the dawn
of our New Age.
All them we've changed,
we've changed.
Right here, girls.
It's okay, it's safe here.
Here.
Can we turn it off?
Can't turn it off,
you change the channel.
Hey... there's no food.
Guess, we're not
gonna be here long.
What's wrong?
They're all dead.
Sources reported
destruction in Kurdistan...
of a 1000 year old convent.
One of the oldest continually
functioning convents...
in Central Asia.
Now occupied by the ascetic
branch of the Noelite.
The convent was strucked
by a missile late last night.
There were no survivors.
Here are initial reactions
from the Noelite.
It is a tragedy to think,
that even defenseless women...
who made the choice to withdraw from
society and lead a life of purity...
could suffer the attacks from
terrorists, who have absolutly...
no respect, for the lives
of decent, god-fearing people.
We shall mourn our sisters.
The Noelites have been
persecuted for too long.
Tomorrow will be the dawn
of a new age...
Congratulations, my friend.
- You made it safe and sound.
- Gorsky.
- Did you destroyed that convent?
- I'm not a terrorist, Toorope.
- I'm a mercenary like you.
- Bullshit.
What the hell...
is going on over here?
You've done your job,
when you turn over the girl...
I'll get paid
and you're home free.
And that tracking device in your
passport will be deactivated.
Deliver the package, my men will
be there to make sure you do.
They never hurt anybody.
- Maybe it was an accident.
- It was not an accident.
It was destroyed right after
we crossed the border.
Would you like to pray with me?
I don't feel
like prayinmg anymore.
Toorope said I'm just
a package to him.
Is that all I am to you?
Of course not, I love you.
How is she?
- Scared.
- Well, she should be.
Who are they?
To the left, the range rover guys,
work for your sect the Noelites.
To the right, the bikers
work for Gorsky.
They're all here
to make sure I deliver.
And if you don't?
It's gonna be a free fall.
Look sister.
We traveled
six thousand miles together.
The truth is, this has been a
suicide mission from the beginning.
They won't let either one of us
walk outta here alive.
That's the doctor, that came
to the convent 3 months ago.
Answer the door,
act like nothing is wrong.
Okay.
- Good evening, sister.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
- Where is she?
- In her room.
You're a bad man.
Thank you Aurora...
Thank you so much.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
- I have to run some more tests.
- More tests?
Hey! What is wrong her?
What's wrong her?
- I'm expecing a call from a client.
- What is wrong with her?
Toorope...
Toorope... let him go.
If you, Please.
Thank you, sister.
- Get over here.
- What's wrong with you?
I wanna know everything
that you know.
Don't you think that if I knew
anything, I will tell you?
No, I don't think.
You're a Noelite, you're
like him, you swore an oath.
Not to them, to God.
God has nothing
to do with it now.
You understand, if she carried a virus
that could annihilate half the city...
I'm not gonna have it
on my conscience.
I'm pregnant... twins.
It's not possible,
I watched over you all your life.
No one's ever touched you.
And nobody has.
It's a miracle.
Shit...
- Hello?
- Mr. Toorope?
- This is the high priestess, I am...
- I know who you are.
Thank you, for doing such
a good job, Mr. Toorope.
You're welcome.
Bring the girl to the
limousine and you'll be freed.
Toorope, if you deliver
me to them, I'll die.
One other the way out.
- We can't let her go, Toorope.
- Look around, do we have a choice?
She's your problem now.
Move!
- We're going on the subway.
- Thank you, Toorope.
What's wrong?
It's a missile
linked to my passport.
How can you stop it?
Only by death.
We're going on the subway.
Toorope!
Aurora?
It's you.
Protect them.
I need you to live.
Aurora was our miracle.
A true virgin birth.
It was to make ours...
the dominant religion on earth.
Now we don't know
what's happened to her.
In this mess,
there's no sign of Aurora.
We can't find her.
We were finally on the verge
of becoming a bonafide religion...
and your incompetence has thrown
20 years of careful planning...
down the tubes.
Who gave the order to
use guns to retrieve her?
You left Gorsky no choice...
What were you thinking?
- Your Highness.
- What?
The body stolen from
the morgue was Toorope.
The police found the van, that
transported him to New Jersey.
Who would want to abduct
the body of a dead man?
He's back on line.
- Where're you taking me?
- To Dr. Darquandier.
You should know, Mr. Toorope
is not a prisoner...
you can release him.
Good evening, Mr. Toorope.
I'm Dr. Darquandier,
Aurora's father.
- I thought you were dead.
- It's sometimes useful to be dead...
gives the last one
a second chance.
You'll see.
Oh yes, you were
clinically dead for 2 hours.
We lost quite a bit of time
getting you from the morgue.
And then you went
into a coma for 5 days.
I fixed you up as best I could.
Now, Mr. Toorope, I believe
I owe you some explanation.
You see, 20 years ago...
I was drummed out of
the medical profession...
for trying to implant
human babies...
with artificial intelligence.
Around that time, the Noelites
came to me to create smarter...
stronger, healthier human beings.
So I built a super computer to
be Aurora's artificail mother...
As a fetus Aurora learned
to process information...
just like a computer.
Until she was born, she became
much more than just an experiment...
you see, she became...
she became my daughter.
She was beautiful, she was unique,
and I couldn't bring myself...
to give her away, so...
that's when they hired Gorsky
to kill me and... well...
they almost suceeded.
He took my baby away and hid
her to the Noelites,
I searched for her for years,
but I couldn't find her.
I knew, that one day
the Noelites would have...
to present a miracle
to the rest of the world.
- What do you want from me?
- I want you to find my daughter.
We think she's alive...
and she left you a message,
you died with your eyes open...
but your brain recorded more
than you can actually remember...
we just need to rewind the tape.
You need to return
to the same condition...
you were when we found you.
Almost dead?
Quite.
What am I looking for?
What you missed the first time.
Will guide your memory
with our computer.
Are you ready, Mr. Toorope?
Stay with memory...
stay with the memory,
move forward a little bit.
Focus on the memories of Aurora.
You're beginning to see her...
excellent.
That's right, we're getting there...
We're getting there.
Now... good, focus on his gun.
Easy, easy, steady, steady.
He is way past
the danger threshold.
I know, but he'll be fine...
he'll be fine.
Okay, slow down!
Slow down now. Slow down!
It's the best way to with this...
I need you to live.
He's dead.
Wait...
don't bring him back yet,
he's almost there, he must be.
G O H O M E.
Alright, it's alright, thank god
you're back, you're safe...
- you're save.
- I know where she is.
Mr. Gorsky... I hoped,
I wouldn't have to see you again.
Where is my Money?
You still haven't paid me.
You have an odd way
of killing people.
What are you talking about?
I'm on my way to see our
old friend, Darquandier.
Impossible, I made his
car explode myself.
Mr. Gorsky, when I kill
I kill for good.
- Are you threatening me?
- Bless your soul.
You'll need a nuke to kill me.
Bitch.
How did you survived the blast?
It's the babies you see...
I gave them power...
they're the ones guiding her.
Their aptitude for survival,
is greater than...
anything you could
ever have imagined.
Professor...
your wife has found us...
she'll be here
in a few minutes.
Find a door open, she'll be the
only one who can take her now.
So, where we going?
North.
Hello my dear,
it's lovely to see you.
Where is my daughter?
I see you haven't found her.
And you never will...
you selfish bastard...
20 years ago I gave you the
opportunity you wanted.
Now it's my moment.
- Where is my daughter?
- She's not your daughter.
- She comes from me.
- I designed her.
For me, she's my miracle,
she belongs to my church.
Your church is a lie...
you play with miracles,
for your own profit.
- Are you willing to die for her?
- Yes.
Find Toorope...
He knows where she is.
Wait here.
- You're finally home
- What's left of it.
But I came back for you.
Have a little faith.
Toorope! They're coming.
Quick left.
Toorope, they need help.
No!
Take the wheel...
Toorope.
Thank you.
For protecting us.
You're their father now.
Aurora.
That's the first time,
you said my name.
You're gonna be okay.
Take care of them, Toorope.
Hey kids...
There is a storm coming,
we need to go.
- You ready?
- Okay, Dad.
THE END
Subtitles by: