Got a staring problem?
Fuckin' pervert.
You're right on time.
Yeah, well let's get this thing
over with it, huh?
What's your rush?
Have a drink.
Give me a scotch,
straight up.
Have a seat.
Cheers!
Where is it?
Where is what?
You wanna play fucking games
with me?
You have something for me.
I do.
I have a message...
from the Man.
Are you okay?
You look a little pale.
You son of a bitch.
Always watch your drink.
Break...
Frank.
Frankie.
Yeah... I'm here.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Fine.
Meet me at the bar...
in one hour.
- Okay?
- Okay.
What is your problem, man?
Let's make this easy.
Your wallet.
Just give him
what he wants, man.
You're early Frank.
And you're late
a fucking pile of shit.
This place is clear across town.
Why do we always have to meet here?
Because it's clear across town.
Another beer for you,
sweetheart?
Please, yeah.
And for you, darling?
- Cola.
- Cola?
Nothing a little more... stiff.
I like the service too.
May I ask you something?
Did you ever fuck a big fat girl
like that, with a big fat ass?
Look at the ass on her.
It's not really my type.
How about for 200 grand?
Fuck a big fat girl,
with a big fat ass...
200 K.
I guess, I don't know.
Look, so why am I here?
Uh...
You gotta see the Man.
What does that mean?
You know, your employer,
the Man...
got a job for you.
He wants to see you,
talk to you about it.
He never wanted to me
for any of the other jobs.
Well... this one's different.
It's kinda important, very serious.
And... he wants to tell you personally.
So, what about you,
you gonna be there?
No.
I'm the agent... I just... uh,
I get the phone call...
I supply the talent
and negotiate the deal,
I take my percentage,
that's it. Pfft, done.
Well, but what
if I don't wanna meet him?
There's nothing you can do about that,
it's already been arranged.
You're gonna meet his man,
at the entrance to the Tower club.
Tonight, at eleven.
A free one, for you.
Thank you.
And a cola, for you.
Look...
and here's your, um...
here's your new throw away.
This is a big one, Frank.
How big?
As big as her ass.
You alright, K.B?
20 percent for me.
So ... how much would it take
for you to fuck a girl like that?
Frankie... I've had bigger
and better than that...
and did it for nothing.
Follow me downstairs.
The Man is waiting for you.
He's waiting anxiously.
Thank you, Haiku.
His name is Haiku?
We call him that, because he speaks
in Haiku's exclusively.
That would be 5 syllables, followed by
7 syllables, followed by 5 syllables.
What about simple
yes and no answers.
- Haiku, are you queer?
- Homosexual?
That life-style does not appeal.
I do not like dick.
You see,
5-7-5 perfect every time.
Please sit.
Hey, sugar...
what can I get you?
Cola.
No alcohol, good.
Keeps you alert.
I wanted to meet you
for sometime.
I'm a big fan of your work, obviously,
there been no repeat business.
But I've respected
your position...
not... wanting to meet
face to face.
Then why am I here?
Job, just a job.
If it's just a job, it would've gone
through the proper channels.
It's delicate, Frank,
very delicate.
I apologise
for making you come here.
But I had to be absolutely certain you
understood just what this meant to me.
I'm dying.
I'm dying, and there's absolutely
nothing I can do about it.
Can you comprehend
what it means to a man like me.
Who's always been able to control
every single aspect of his life.
Suddenly, finds himself helpless.
So, you're the job.
You loose control, you do
what you have to do, to regain it.
How and when?
Slow down,
it's not that simple.
- There's someone else.
- What'd you mean?
Ooh, it's time, her set.
Watch, just... watch.
Isn't she exquisite.
That's my woman.
You know I been around too long
to deny what I have, Frank.
- What are you?
- Jealous, selfish.
She's only loved one man
before me, that I'm aware off.
And I know very little of him.
But I love her too much
to allow her...
go on and forget me
after I'm gone.
You see I've...
decided not to die alone.
You're the guy who eats alone?
Excuse me?
You're always here,
and you always eating alone.
- You're here alone.
- I'm waiting for my father.
Where is he?
I don't know,
I'm wondering the same thing.
He was suppose to meet me here,
after a meeting.
- The meeting probably ran late.
- Probably.
I've seen you before?
You always look like
you have a lot on your mind.
Maybe I do have a lot
on my mind.
What'd you do?
- About what?
- Your work.
- What'd you do?
- I'm a singer.
I'm trying to be a singer.
- Where'd you sing?
- I'm singing tonight at the Laba bar.
It's kinda my first show.
I'm a little nervous about it.
Can I get you a drink, sweetie?
Cola, straight.
Here to see the new talent, huh?
Did reserve you
that one over there.
Not that it matters
with this pair.
- How much?
- That one's on the house.
Thank you.
- Thank you for coming.
- You're welcome.
If you hadn't come in, I probably
would have faced an empty room.
- Gotta start somewhere.
- You're right.
- Your father never showed?
- No.
I'm really worried.
But I'm sure there's some
logical explanation.
You're really amazing.
So, what'd you do?
It's complicated.
You're not a drug dealer,
are you?
No.
You're just the guy
who eats alone.
Yeah.
But tonight I ate with you.
I'm glad
I could be there for you.
I'm glad I could be there
for you too tonight.
It's gonna happen
do her first.
And then I'll be certain
it's done.
Why don't you...
Why don't you just do it yourself?
Oh, I could never do it.
I love her to much
to do it myself.
I fuckin' quit.
Fuh'uh, fuck...
- What?
- Fuh'uh...
You can't help me.
He called me.
Let him through!
Let him through.
I'm not finished with you yet.
You're all done for now,
so piss off.
You have to excuse my friend, son.
He's a little hard of hearing.
Yeah, not only that,
but you can't understand
a fucking word he's saying.
That's enough,
both of you.
You call me down here?
I did, Frank.
Listen, I'm a little concerned
about this deal you're in, Frank.
- I just found out about it this morning.
- Do you know where I was last night?
Well yeah, I did, and I wonder,
you walk away from money.
But, it could end up messy.
Frank, you're a talented boy
and you're smart.
So, what I'm going to say,
won't come as any surprise.
You can't change the past.
Now everybody knows that.
But you can look into your future,
and weigh your options.
I was your associates associate,
for years.
He tells me, that there's
a woman involved in all of this.
There is...
a woman from my past.
Now you know as well as I do,
that's what really complicates things.
The two things people like us
should never get to intimate with...
are love and dead.
You know why?
No.
Because there's no clean break
from either one.
Now you finishing intimacy
with both.
But it's not to late,
to make a decision.
You know, if I was you
I'd listen to him.
That's why they call him
The Wise Man.
So you think
I should walk away.
I can't answer that,
you know what you have to do.
What about you? You're willing
to walk away from your cut?
Of course he is.
Of course.
Keep it neat, and don't get involved
beyond what you were hired to do.
The Man's waiting with half your money,
all you gotta do is go pick it up.
No clean break, Frank.
Don't ever forget it.
- Is the woman here?
- The woman is not.
He send her shopping today.
She shops quite often.
Home...
There he is.
I, uh...
trust everything is being...
planned accordingly.
Well yes, it is.
Wonderful.
Meet the lawyer.
This is the first half
of the payment.
The other half will be
deposited to your associate,
upon completion of your task.
I've arranged for the second half
to be paid for on completion.
She... uh, singing tonight,
for her final show.
It'll be
my last night with her...
before you carry out
your obligation tomorrow.
I need my final night
with her to... say my good-byes.
- Does she know?
- Of course she doesn't know.
I mean about you being sick.
Oh, no,
and I don't want her to.
It's better...
that way she won't have to...
worry and grief, when it's my time.
And I won't have to
pass on alone.
Perfect really.
There's two problems.
I don't like problems.
What is it?
There's a woman...
a young woman,
I think she's been following me.
I saw her last night
after our meeting.
I saw her again this morning,
outside my apartment.
- This woman, is she a Brunette?
- Yes.
She's nothing to be concerned with,
she is of no consequence to you.
You said there were
two problems.
I need a gun.
You're an Assassin,
and you don't have a gun?
I have guns,
this is a special one.
This is not the manner
in which we discuss.
this was to be carried out.
This gun is of no
consequence to you.
I would consider it a personal favor,
and I knock 10 thousand of my price.
Okay.
Haiku will direct you
to the Bishop.
He will procure
what ever you require.
Thank you.
One more thing.
No problems, huh?
Just solutions.
After all, you'll be
carrying out my dying wish.
He's been expecting you.
This way.
Welcome, my friend.
Good hands.
- What the hell?
- Don't mind him, that's just Rupert.
He gets excited when there're
new visitors. Rubert go!
Sit.
Stay.
You keep a very good poker-face,
but I can see your wheels turning.
I've seen a few things
in my life.
Well...
What can I get you?
- Woman?
- No.
Men?
No.
- Drugs?
- No, I'm fine.
Well then...
What's your pleasure?
I need a gun.
It seams odd to me, that a man
in your line of work...
needs to come to me
for a simple fire-arm.
It's not just any gun.
I need a small gun.
- The tiniest gun you have.
- A tiny gun?
- Big guns, not your thing?
- The smaller the better.
I think we can help you.
Sweetheart...
go find the gentlemen for me.
Would you like to feed Rubert?
No.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
You have no idea
how much better this is...
then the real thing.
Plus... he never shits
on the carpet.
- Small enough for you?
- It's perfect.
How much?
No charge.
So, what'd you want
in exchange?
- What would you like, sweetheart?
- I want to fuck him.
- Excuse me?
- She wants to fuck you.
And I want to watch.
How much, you freak?
You know...
money is no good here.
You... and her.
We watch.
Otherwise, buy your tiny gun
somewhere else.
You should
consider yourself lucky...
my last customer
had to fuck... Rubert.
What?
Jesus...
- Why you following me?
- What're you talking about?
- You're following me.
- No, I'm not.
I saw you outside
the Tower club last night...
and I saw you
at my apartment this morning.
You're following me...
I wanna know why.
The Man hired you for something,
I wanna know what.
- Are you a cop?
- No.
How do I know?
Because the only the only hand-cuffs
I own are made of leather.
You want the Man?
I want Haiku.
- His bodyguard?
- He's more then just a bodyguard.
- Well, what is he then?
- He does the Mans' dirty work.
- So do I.
- Please.
Don't go.
My husband did a deal with the Man
a few years back, that went bad.
Haiku was send
to deal with it.
I usually get that call.
I give you one change.
All you must do is beat me.
And freedom is yours.
Haiku showed no mercy.
Haiku just does
what he's told.
- Like you?
- Yeah... like me.
Well, normally.
The reason I followed you is because
no outsider has ever been allowed...
as close to the Man as you.
I figured you could help me
get close.
Look...
you want Haiku,
I won't stand in your way.
But, you're not gonna help me.
I gotta help
somebody else first.
Sorry.
What's he doing here?
That's him.
He's the one.
Well?
They are not deceased.
I find only him...
Both of them escaped.
Give me the Chinamen.
I kill you,
I kill you now.
Kill him! Kill him!
Kill him!
Ho... hold it...
Hold it right there!
The Man wants to talk,
he ask if you please join him.
I will escort you.
Fuck!
I don't wish to fight.
I will take you to the Man.
A job awaits you.
Who did you want
you tell me?
I work for the Man.
He'll pay you handsomely.
To kick a suckers ass.
Why didn't you say so.
I'll come with you.
I'll talk to you later.
Won't they find us here?
No.
Isn't this your place, though?
Trust me.
Frank...
I never knew
what happened that day.
I was wondering
if I ever see you again.
It's complicated, Frank.
I looked for you every time
I ate at that coffee shop.
Every night I think to myself.
Maybe tonight,
I won't have to eat alone.
But you were never there.
There's a lot you don't
know about that day, Frank.
My father...
he died that day.
That's why
he never made it to my show.
I'm so sorry.
- How did he die?
- I don't know.
They never told me.
He wasn't exactly healthy, but...
he wasn't that old either.
My father was a great man.
But, he did
some stupid things.
He owed the Man a lotta money.
When he died,
it was made clear to me, that...
I had to work off his depths.
So, I went to live with him.
Do you love him?
He puts me on that stage
and ask me to live my dream.
No, I'm not in love with him.
There's a lot you don't know
about the Man, he's dying.
- He's what?
- He's dying.
He's...
terminally ill.
He hired someone
to take him out.
What?
No, it doesn't make any sense,
if something was wrong
he would've told me.
- Trust me.
- Trust you?
How do you know all of this?
Because I'm the one he hired.
And he wanted me
to take you out with him.
I take it you are aware
of how jealous he is.
One of the guys don't want you to
ever move on after he's gone, so he...
made you part of the equation.
Lately he ask me
what I was thinking about?
I told him about you,
the short time we spend together.
How happy you made me,
and how alive you made me feel.
He didn't like it,
not one bid.
He promised me that one day
I feel the same way toward him...
I never did.
If you want me
to go with you, I will.
You can't cross the line
and get away clean.
It doesn't matter what we do,
they'll find us.
- There's only one thing that can help.
- What's that?
Carrying out
a dying mans last wish.
Only way.
Hey.
- Frankie.
- Yeah.
What the fuck did you do?
I did what I had to.
- Did you get the money?
- First half. 100 K.
But don't hold your breath
for the rest of it.
I figured that.
The Man is pissed, okay?
We gotta talk, you gonna get
your ass down the bar.
- Is it safe?
- What'd you mean is it fucking safe?
It's on the other side of town,
you think that's an accident?
I have to go meet someone.
You'll be safe here,
until I get back.
Just stay away from the windows,
and the door.
You fucked everything all up!
You fucked it all up!
No, I didn't,
they fucked it up.
If it was any other woman
any other woman in the world...
I be planning
a double-homicide right now.
I don't think
start it again.
I know exactly
where I started.
- Where is she?
- She's safe.
Safe where?
Clear across town safe.
The big Man's gonna start a war
over this whole fucking thing.
He's gonna start
a fucking war.
Well, let him.
I'm ready.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry, Frank.
So...
He send you after me?
Two ways to do this, Frank.
The easy way?
Or my way?
Choose one.
There's a reason the Man always
contracted me up till now.
Why is that?
Blijkbaar, I'm the best.
Shit joke, Frank,
I'm gonna take you down.
- How much is he paying you?
- Enough.
How much?
- Twenty-five.
- Pays me fifty.
- You... pour me drink.
- Wha... what would you like, sir?
- Tequila.
- What brand, sir?
Top shelf.
You're in trouble now,
mother-fucker.
Look, the Man
wants you alive.
The Man's gonna die alone.
- You want something, motherfucker?
- Something worth fighting for.
You gotta a death-wish.
Frank.
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
Let's get the hell
out of here.
Hey.
Teach me karate.
Who in the hell was that?
It's the Chinamen, one of the
deadliest Assassins in the world.
At least he was, until he
gave out to a drinking-problem.
Now he's just a loose cannon.
The Man contracted him,
he wanna take me out.
After what you took
the other night at the Tower club,
I'm not surprised.
You stole his woman.
He stole her from me first.
- Are you gonna run?
- No... no, we can't.
I have to finish this.
Great, then I'm coming with you.
No, you're not.
The way I figure it,
I just saved your ass.
You owe me one.
You didn't save me,
you helped me.
And it doesn't obligate me
to do favors for you.
You're going after the Man,
you don't think you gonna
have to go through Haiku first.
Let me rebate you
from that burden.
And how you gonna
take out Haiku?
Don't worry about that,
just get me to him.
I'm not gonna safe your ass,
if you do this.
You're not gonna have to.
What's wrong?
Frank!
Doesn't he understand
I don't love him.
It's only gonna make
things worse.
It's Frank that you love.
The Man can not stand
that truth.
Either way you loose.
It's him that will loose.
He could've just lost his life,
now he looses me too.
The Man sends his word.
You versus the Chinamen.
A fight to the dead.
Do I have a choice in that?
You got no choice,
mother-fucker.
And no bitch,
to safe you this time.
You cut my face,
now I'm gonna break you.
If I win?
Fuck that...
This is a great... Moment.
I can't believe you fucking
shot me, you bitch...
Fuck!
Stop fucking doing that.
Where did you manage
to hide that?
Use your imagination.
Hello Haiku.
I know your face well.
You've been after me a while.
poor, weak, helpless girl.
You killed my husband.
That's quite possible,
I killed many worthless men.
Yours was no different.
Your time has come Haiku,
me and you.
You are not kidding.
You really wanna fight me?
Bitch gonna get hurt.
- What you gonna do with them?
- I leave the Chinamen for you.
This one however,
I have plans for.
Now Haiku, in the end you didn't allow
my husband to make any decisions.
You are a cold-blooded bastard.
Unlike you however,
I do have a heart, and...
I will allow you to make...
some decisions here.
So...
in five syllables,
where would you like the first cut?
Oh... I'm in trouble,
let me help you.
How about...
- across the stomach.
- Ahh...
Now I need another 7 syllables,
for the next cut.
Hm... I've got it,
slice across the upper...
- groin.
- Ahh...
Please...
don't do it,
please stop.
Stop?
I can't stop.
There's another line in this, Haiku,
another 5 syllables.
Oh, you know what?
I got it.
Slash the fucking throat.
Haiku was a bad man,
he got what he deserved.
You did a good job.
Your turn.
The Man request your presents
on his Yacht.
What about you two?
I trust you two
handle the Man on my behalf.
I will.
So...
What life for you?
I'm... not sure,
I thought of nothing but today,
for someone.
I'm in need
of a new associate.
Something tells me our line of work
wouldn't be objectionable to you.
- I'll call you.
- Don't have phone.
- So, how do I get in touch?
- Don't worry, I'll find you.
Please...
sit with me.
If you defeated the Chinamen,
then you are the better killer.
I know I'm not a better killer
I just need to be sharp.
That's why
I never drink alcohol.
The Chinamen should've
followed my example.
What about Haiku?
That Brunette I told you about.
Apparently she was a great
consequence to Haiku.
Well done I suppose, now you wish to...
finish me as well, I guess?
Maybe so.
I like to let you live out...
the short time
you have left all alone.
I think it be
the worst possible ending.
But I don't think I can trust you
to stay out of our lives.
There is the wimp.
What about you, my dear?
You can honestly say
you feel nothing for me...
meaning
I sit here at your mercy.
I feel I've worked off
my debt to you.
And so much more.
In fact it's I
who's indebted to you.
For what?
For infallible meaning that...
pure blessing is "true love".
"True love"?
You call what we had true love?
- Sure was from my prospective.
- I felt like a prisoner.
And you gonna have me killed because
you couldn't bare the thought of me...
going on and being happy
when you're gone.
You sad, sad, old man.
You put me on that stage for your
own interest and to manipulate me.
I wouldn't be surprised if your
the one that killed my father.
No my dear, I'm not the man
who killed your father.
Everyone knows what you do to men
who don't pay their debts on time.
Not from me, the man
who killed your father is the...
gentlemen sitting
right next to you.
Me?
Well, what're you gonna say,
sweetheart?
Cat got your tongue?
Where's your undying love for him,
if you feel that way?
Did you?
- Where is he?
- I don't know,
I'm wondering the same thing.
He was suppose to meet me here
after the meeting.
You're right on time.
Yeah, well let's get this thing
over with, huh?
I had no idea who he was.
How could you?
I was hired...
- hired by him.
- Me?
I hired you?
When did you talk to me?
You talked
through an associate.
The one you just had killed.
All my jobs went through him.
All except the last one.
You have to believe me.
I had no idea.
The day we've meet
and fell in love...
you killed my father.
Break.
- I know now what he meant.
- What?
Your father... his final word
was... Break.
He's last thoughts were
listening to you sing.
Let's toast...
To life, with all of it's whoa's
and malice.
Some you see coming,
some you don't.
You're not drinking, Frank?
You think I'd poison you?
Give me some credit.
That's your specialty.
You won't interfere
with our lives.
in anyone’s life ever again.
What'd you do to me?
Your drink.
You should always
keep an eye on your drink.
You son of a bitch!
No...
You're the son of a bitch!
Because of you, she lost her father
and I nearly lost her.
Without me,
you'll never make it.
you got no career.
I was there that night,
at her show. her very first show.
That was enough for me to know,
that she had a career.
Your problem is...
you spend to much time looking
and not enough time listening.
Your question is,
you never really heard
the magic of her.
If you could go back and do it again,
would you still go through with it?
Yes.
The one thing my father wanted more
then anything, was for me to be happy.
You promised
to continue making me happy...
is what you can give
back to him.
Well, that's a promise
I can never break.
To never eating alone,
and singing to an almost empty Bar.
And to a promise,
that will never be broken.