What's your wish?
My wish is...
I want to take back...
what I said last night.
I don't want to be awkward with you.
Just forget about everything.
That's my wish.
You confessed last night and now you want me to forget it?
Why is she confusing me like this?
Okay?
It's my wish so you have to grant it.
I can stay with you longer...
only if you grant my wish.
Bong Pal.
Hyun Ji.
It feels so weird.
Bong Pal.
Hyun Ji.
Hyun Ji!
Where did she go?
Hyun Ji.
Bong Pal.
Don't disappear...
ever again.
(Bring it on, Ghost)
(Episode 9)
Goodnight.
You too.
Hyun Ji.
Yes?
It's hot these days.
You should sleep in my room from now on.
- Me?
-  Yes.
I can't stand the heat.
Goodnight.
Okay.
Don't disappear...
ever again.
His father passed away in an accident when he was young.
After that, he lived with his mother.
When he went to middle school, he lived in a dormitory.
Since then he lived alone.
I think he keeps in contact with his mother but he doesn't visit her.
- Is this it?
-  Yes.
There's nothing much to investigate about him.
He never received a bill in his life.
He pays his taxes well.
All there are his medical records.
- What is it?
-  It's not much.
He was very ill when little.
He has many medical records.
- What do the people say about him?
-  They all praise him.
"He's kind. He's trustworthy."
That's understandable. He volunteers at five different places.
He provides medical help to abandoned dogs without charge.
Nobody ever saw him lose his temper before.
My goodness.
Brains, looks and personality. He has it all.
You're right. He's perfect.
He's too perfect for a human.
Too perfect.
Shouldn't we change the direction of the investigation?
Have you found Noh Hyun Joo's cellphone?
No. I contacted the mobile carrier.
They told me that her phone was turned off in front of her house.
Check her cellphone call log and see...
- if you missed out anyone.
-  Okay.
Track the location of Mr Ju's cellphone from 1st to 2nd.
See his vehicle records and compare it with where the body was found.
All right.
(Ju Hye Sung)
Did you hear how Hyun Joo died?
Her neck was broken.
- Really?
-  Yes.
- My goodness.
-  Have they found the culprit?
Not yet.
Min Soo's here.
Who is he?
He asked Hyun Joo out last semester.
Professor. Hello.
You must have come to offer your condolences.
Yes.
- Professor.
-  Then see to your business.
- Are you up?
-  Yes.
You must be hungry. Wait a moment.
- Are you not eating?
-  What?
I will.
Why? Is it bad?
No, it's good.
Why are you picking at the food?
I'm not. This is how I eat.
The green light is on. Let's run.
What?
What is the title of the book?
It's "Principles of Economics".
"Principles of Economics"?
It must be around here.
I found it.
Excuse me.
I just remembered I forgot something.
See you later.
Hey, where are you...
Enjoy.
Thank you. Please take care.
In Rang, let's eat.
- Okay.
-  Let's eat.
Let me see.
One.
Two.
Three...
Why do we have so many?
I ordered one for Bong Pal as well.
We're including Bong Pal, but we have four.
Hey!
You...
You've changed.
Did making money change you?
Then...
All right.
This one.
This galbi lunch box.
It's my favourite.
I'll try it.
- It's for Hyun Ji.
-  What?
-  Hyun...
Hold on.
- You mean the angel?
-  Yes, the angel.
You lost your head over her. You're desperate to win her heart.
Giving shoes to her and all that.
Love makes you do crazy stuff.
Yes, you are crazy. You crazy fool.
Why don't you ask her out?
I'm too shy. Don't say that.
Gosh.
You've totally lost your mind.
You... You...
You're a human, and she's a ghost. You know what it is.
That means she's dead.
Look at him.
Why don't you marry her and have a child?
Gosh, you look so happy.
Ghosts and humans can never live together.
Can't you see that?
But it's too early to talk about marrying her.
You know where you should go?
Samil Mental Hospital. You need to be admitted.
Don't start eating first.
We'll eat together when Hyun Ji and Bong Pal come.
You're so rude. How can you dare to eat first...
when the angel hasn't gotten here yet?
Wait!
Stay still.
My heart almost burst.
I wish Kyung Ja were here to talk about Bong Pal.
Where is she, anyway?
She hasn't been around for a while.
She's not here either.
Did she go home?
Hello, Bong Pal.
Hello.
Hi, Hyun Ji.
Well, Hyun Ji isn't here.
Really? Where is she?
I think she went home.
Bong Pal, come take a seat.
You seem like you have a lot on your mind.
- It's about a girl...
-  A girl?
I want to do something for a girl,
and I have no idea what I should do.
- It's not about me.
-  Of course, it's not.
It's your friend's worry, right?
Yes, that's right.
Girls... Women...
Women, female, girls.
Should I give you a special lesson?
It's hard to grasp what women want and need.
You're talking nonsense.
Do you even know what love is?
Little brats like you know nothing about love. Shut it.
Before finding out what she wants,
you must know what kind of guys she finds attractive first, okay?
Assistant Kim. Look at him.
It's okay to be ugly.
Ghost Net.
Put your hand under your face and move your fingers.
It's okay to look foolish.
What women find attractive...
isn't something trivial like that.
Then, what kind of charms would women find fascinating?
Being "charming" in English.
In another word, a... at...
Let's say it's appealing points. Let's begin, then.
Step one!
Profile.
You must show her your masculine Adam's apple...
and your sharp nose that makes you look intellectual.
When women see such profile, they'll lose their heads...
They'll lose their heads over you.
Step two!
Eyes.
It's the eyes.
You need...
a wild look in your eyes that overwhelms women,
and a gentle gaze that's as deep as the sea.
If you look at women in such way,
their hearts will melt away,
just like glaciers melting under the hot sun.
Step three!
I'm fine. All right.
Don't cry, you fool
You must be able to make women laugh...
when they are depressed.
What kind of apple isn't an apple?
A pineapple.
Sense of humour.
I believe that sense of humour is one of the factors...
that make men attractive.
How is it?
Do you find it helpful?
It's all right.
There are still 8 more steps to go. There are 11 steps.
Step four!
That's more than enough. Thank you.
Hyun Ji.
Hyun Ji?
(Bong Pal and Hyun Ji)
Hyun Ji.
Yes, Bong Pal?
Where have you been?
I told you not to disappear. I looked for you everywhere.
I'm sorry.
- What were you doing here?
-  Nothing much.
Being "charming".
What makes men attractive?
Step one!
- Hyun Ji.
-  Yes?
- Bong Pal.
- Bong Pal?
-  Why?
What's the matter? Are you hurt?
It's nothing. My neck is a bit sniff.
It's not working.
Step two. Eyes.
My eyes? Okay.
- Hyun Ji.
-  Why?
What? Is this a staring contest?
No, my eyes are dry.
It's not working either.
Step three.
I believe that sense of humour is one of the factors...
that make men attractive.
Shall I tell you something funny?
- What is it?
-  How does a monkey ring a doorbell?
King Kong!
What do you call a belt made out of watches?
- I have no idea.
-  A waist of time.
How about this? What kind of apple isn't an apple?
A pineapple.
A pineapple. Pine...
What's wrong with you today?
- Are you okay?
-  I am.
- None of these work.
-  What do you mean?
No, it's nothing.
Let's eat.
Meat. Meat. I love meat.
It's all cooked now. Can I eat?
Sure. Here.
Which would taste better?
Meat works every time.
That star is the brightest.
Do you mean that star? It's called Altair.
Do you mean Altair and Vega?
Yes.
Can you see that star over there?
It's Vega.
Can you see the Milky Way across the sky?
I see. I didn't know that.
They are really far apart.
They must be so sad.
They can only meet once a year.
Wouldn't they be grateful for being able to meet?
Even if it's only one day.
You know a lot about constellations.
My father taught me when I was young.
- Do you want to hear more?
-  Yes.
Can you see those stars over there? They are the Eagle.
It's also called Aquila.
Bong Pal. Are you asleep?
Go to bed.
We'll go out tomorrow.
Really? Are we going out for a date?
Well, you can put it that way.
Okay. I'll get up early.
See you in my dreams.
What do you want to do today?
How about an ordinary date?
Eat food, drink tea, watch a movie, walk.
Okay. Let's do what others do.
Okay.
Hey.
No. Don't.
I'm sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
-  No, don't.
Stop it.
Excuse me.
What's taking her so long?
What should I wear for our first date?
Bong Pal.
Why did you want me out?
Just.
Let's go.
They are so pretty.
This doesn't look good.
It's similar to the dress you're wearing right now.
It's not bad, but..
Knock, knock.
What's on the menu?
We have makgeolli.
Really? Can I have a shot?
You shouldn't drink.
How do you like these?
You're so pretty.
This is nice, no?
Two seats for the 10 o'clock movie, please.
Would you like the couples seat?
The couples seat, please.
One moment.
Bong Pal. Can I have some?
Are you sure you can have it all?
Of course.
It feels like we're a real couple now.
Yes.
Here.
What would you like to eat?
What you want to eat.
Excuse me.
May I take your order?
I'll take Set Two.
I'm afraid that's for two people.
It's okay. I'll take it.
Also,
can you fill that glass?
Sure.
Didn't you spend too much today?
We went to a movie and had a course meal.
It's no big deal.
Still...
Fine. I'll work hard and earn you a lot of money.
Bring it on!
Sure.
It's raining.
Let's run.
Give me a second.
Shall we?
Bong Pal. You're getting all wet.
It's okay. Let's go.
Okay.
(Female Student Murder Case)
(Pictures from the Scene)
Are you going to interrogate the testifiers again?
I have to do something.
(Investigation Support Team)
It's from the analysis team.
Thank you.
What is it?
It's security camera footage from tollgates.
Wait.
You should see this.
It's his plate number, right?
Yes, it's Ju Hye Sung's plate number.
Before we start interrogating the testifiers, bring him here.
Arrest him if he resists.
Okay.
A fountain pen?
I gave it to the professor.
Where were you on the day of Noh Hyun Joo's murder?
I was at my clinic.
See you again.
Hyun Ji.
Is it a blackout?
Are you okay?
I'm scared.
Do you feel better now?
Yes, I'm okay now.
Bong Pal.
I've always wanted to ask you something.
What is it?
When did you start seeing ghosts?
Was I five years old?
I think it started then.
Were you that little?
How did it start?
Well...
Monk Myung Cheol says it's because I have evil spirits remaining in me.
Evil spirits?
What are they?
I don't know exactly.
I don't remember what happened...
before then.
You must have been scared.
Back then, yes.
Not any longer.
Thanks, Bong Pal.
For what?
For everything.
Everything feels okay when I'm with you.
When I woke up as a ghost with no memories left,
I was so scared and lonely.
But not any longer.
Even if my memories don't come back,
I'm happy now.
I'm so happy...
you can see me.
I'm happy...
I can see you, too.
He's here.
Hi.
(Ju Hye Sung's Personal Details)
This is a picture of your car...
taken on the night on the first.
Is this your plate number?
Yes.
It's my car.
I see.
You passed the tollgate at 11:28pm on the 1st.
You entered Inseong District at 1:38am on the 2nd.
You drove along Local Road 34...
to the entrance of Mount Woojeong.
You came back to Seoul that morning.
Do you remember that?
- Yes.
-  As you might or might not know,
Noh Hyun Joo's body...
was found near that mountain.
She was killed on the night of the first.
Presumably, she was buried on the morning of the second.
You apparently happened to be there at that time.
Is that a coincidence?
Why did you go to a mountain in the middle of the night?
Well...
It seems like I'm a suspect now.
Please answer.
I visited my mother.
My mother...
lives around there.
- Your mother?
-  You can check it if you want.
- You're lying your way out.
-  It's the truth.
Hello.
They need you.
Please excuse me.
What do you mean by that?
One of the testifiers in the Noh Hyun Joo case has died.
Which one?
It's Lee Min Soo. He goes to Myongsong University.
He talked to the victim on the phone for one minute,
so I put him on the testifers list.
He committed suicide by jumping off the building he lived in.
- He committed suicide?
-  Yes.
He left a message saying he killed the victim.
It's presumed that he died when he was back from the funeral.
Who are you?
I'm sorry.
I killed Hyun Joo.
I didn't mean to do it.
He sent a text message to his mother before he died.
He said that he had killed Noh Hyun Joo.
We found Noh Hyun Joo's mobile phone in his room.
I was told that he had chased her since last semester.
Chief said we should close this case...
and start investigating the Woohyeon-dong murder case.
What do we do?
Put the case file on my desk.
Okay.
Oh, my. You're still here.
Hi.
- Do you know that dog?
-  Yes.
He consoled me when you upset me.
When did I ever upset you?
Bong Pal.
That's the handsome professor.
Hello, Mr Ju.
What are you doing here?
I was looking at the dog.
You did? Why don't you come inside?
I'll make you some tea.
I want to go in there.
Come on in.
How adorable.
It looks as if you were looking at your girlfriend.
- Pardon?
-  Why are you so startled?
You were watching the dog with so much affection.
You must like dogs.
Oh, that. That dog is very cute.
The summer vacation is coming soon. Have you completed volunteer hours?
No, not yet.
How about you help me with the volunteer work I'm doing?
We're shorthanded lately.
You can complete your volunteer hours.
- What do you say?
-  It sounds great.
I was looking for volunteer work.
- That's great.
-  Oh, no.
Where are you going?
Puppy.
Where are you?
Where did it go?
There you are. Come here.
You're so adorable. Good dog.
Look at this.
Professor.
I'll get going now.
Oh, okay. Just a second.
Who told you you could come in here?
That's rude.
Go upstairs first.
Okay.
(Kim Hyun Ji)
(Veterinary Anatomical Terminology)
I'll get going.
Okay. See you later.
That's him.
Bong Pal. Bong Pal.
Monk Myung Cheol.
Who was the man you were with in front of the animal clinic?
You mean the professor?
- Professor?
-  Yes, he's my college professor.
Does he live in the same apartment as you?
No, I think he lives in his clinic.
In his clinic?
What's the matter?
What? It's nothing.
Let's go. You're heading home, right?
- Yes.
-  Let's go. It's hot.
Can I come in?
Bong Pal.
Are you preparing for the college exam? What are these photos?
I lack the basic knowledge.
What brought you here? You didn't tell me you were coming.
Have I ever called you in advance?
What is it?
Is there something in the veranda?
No, nothing.
Has anything happened to you recently?
No, nothing happened.
Why do you ask?
Never mind.
Let me see.
Can I come in?
He can hear ghosts sometimes.
Is his father's number saved on his phone?
He still hasn't saved his number.
Wait. I found it.
(Bong Pal, your middle school graduation...)
It was sent on May 13.
On May 13,
he was staying in the guest house.
"Your middle school graduation".
Bong Pal.
Bong Pal!
Yes?
When was your middle school graduation ceremony?
I think it was in February.
I guess it was. Why do you ask?
Nothing. Continue whatever you were doing.
Hello?
I'll be there soon.
I'll go somewhere and come back soon.
Okay.
The graduation ceremony...
What happened at the graduation ceremony?
Oh, right. He recorded the ceremony.
I saw him filming with a camera.
May...
It was after the anniversary of Yang Soon's death in February.
February 24...
(February 24, 2009)
I found it. February 24.
Well...
Today's client is a possessed man.
Hyun Ji, let Bong Pal deal with him.
- It's dangerous.
-  Okay.
You're lucky. He cares about you.
Are you jealous?
What did Hyun Ji say?
Are you okay?
Stay focused. Sit up straight.
Hyun Ji, are you all right?
(Doowon Middle School's 24th Graduation Ceremony)
The graduation ceremony will begin shortly.
All the students and families,
please come to the gym.
No!
No.
My brother used to be very sick.
After he was fully recovered,
he suddenly started having seizures.
Hey!
What happened?
What's the matter?
Wait!
Open the door!
Are you all right?
- Hey!
-  What happened?
- What happened?
-  I have the key.
- No!
-  Since then,
he's been staying in bed.
He starts screaming every time he wakes up.
Mum thinks he's possessed.
I'll take a look.
What happened?
No!
Please!
Please, no.
Hey.
- No!
-  Hey.
It's okay.
Bong Pal, look at that.
- It's okay.
-  She's...
the ghost we saw.
Was she choking my son?
Why is she torturing my son even after she died?
- My goodness.
-  Let's go in.
By the way, who is she?
She was my brother's girlfriend.
Then...
what should we do?
Once he falls asleep,
he doesn't wake up for a couple of days.
It'll be all right as long as he's sleeping.
We'll come back in a couple of days.
Give us a call if something happens.
I will.
Oh my.
Gosh.
Will I find anything in this video?
Bong Pal.
Bong Pal. Come here.
Smile.
What is he doing there?
Take care.
Bye.
- Hey.
-  Yes?
- Did you see that?
-  What do you mean?
Don't you feel anything after seeing him?
- No.
-  No?
You completely lost your mind.
Look.
That's what happens when you fall for a ghost.
The ghost will take away all your energy.
Do you want to look like a skeleton just like he does?
A human being and a ghost are not meant to be together.
Lower your voice. Hyun Ji will hear you.
Did she hear it?
Of course, she did. How could she not hear that?
I'm sorry.
(Doctor's Office)
Here.
Let's go home.
Bong Pal.
Will we be all right?
People will think...
our relationship is...
absurd.
I like you.
I don't care what others think.
You're the one I like.
(Bring it on, Ghost)
- You're so ugly.
-  Stop it.
Someday, we'll break up like everyone else, right?
Bong Pal, who are you talking to?
This time, it's a ghost that appears in a school.
Apparently, it has a very weird appearance.
It's from my middle school graduation ceremony.
Why was Monk Myung Cheol watching it?
Do you have Ju Hye Sung's mother's address?
What happened?
After killing his girlfriend, he killed himself out of guilt.
How can you love a ghost?
Bong Pal, I want you to be happy.
Hyun Ji!
Kim Hyun Ji!