[Drums: Rock Beat]
Like, wow. Like, crap.
Last year I was
a high school brat.
But now I'm here.
Hope I'm the one
you pick to cheer!
- Fantastic!
- I'm sorry. What?
Oh, nothing. Don't let me
slow you down. It's just...
Well, you're a surprise.
- How do you mean?
- You have great spirit.
But just a tad
more volume,
if you would.
- I apologize.
- Continue.
Like, whoo. Like, whee.
I'm at the university.
I'm psyched. I'm here.
Hope I'm the one
you choose to cheer.
I yell real loud and make
the Stingers super proud.!
Brilliant.!
My dear, you are wonderful...
cheer genius personified.
A real individual.
I'm joking, you spaz!
- Pardon me?
- That was a cheer?
That was the most boring,
unoriginal, biggest piece
of crap I've ever seen!
- You suck!
- [Gasps]
- [Cackling]
- [Whimpering]
[Cackling Continues]
[Screaming]
Mom, where are we?
Where are you, dear?
You finally made it.
You're in college.
[Chattering]
Oh, man!
[Techno, Hip-hop]
* C-Come on *
* The big game
is just about rockin' *
SubRip by divx.NeKryXe.com
[Chattering]
Hi. Can you guys tell me
how to get to Bancroft Hall?
Hi. Can you tell me
how to get to...
Hi, girls. Can you guys tell me
how to get to Bancroft...
Excuse me!
Hi. It's where some
of the cheerleaders are staying.
Um, I'm trying out
for the team.
You girls don't cheer,
do you?
First of all,
it's women, not girls.
Oh.
Second, um, we do
neo-modern ballet.
We don't wave pom-poms.
And third,
we can't direct you
to Bancroft Hall,
because Nathaniel Bancroft
was a slave owner
and an imperialist!
Okay. Thanks.
Appreciate it.
You're not giving
up already, are you?
Monica!
[Both Giggling]
First day of college,
I'm already saving my roommate.
You did not
have to save me.
I have been saving...
your butt ever since
cheerleader camp.
Have not!
Really?
I remember a time...
a spotter was out of position
and one of our cheerleaders...
was gonna do
a face-plant.
Who was that
cheerleader again?
Okay. Okay. I get it.
[Laughing]
I think the score
is Monica, two. Whittier, zero.
And... Bancroft Hall
is this way.
Did you know
that Nathaniel Bancroft
was a slave owner...
and an imperialist?
Our room has
a ceiling fan.
[Man]
As well as paint balloons,
panty trees,
super-gluing faculty doors,
releasing lab animals...
and most important,
I'd like to remind you...
that if you must...
urinate,
please...
do it in a toilet.
Do not... I repeat...
Do not urinate...
on an original manuscript
of The Canterbury Tales...
Iocated
in the school library.
You writing this down?
You'd think
I wouldn't have to say that.
The Nutcracker
is a patriarchal ballet.
Okay? The only good thing
in The Nutcracker are the rats,
and they die.
[Grunting]
Shakespeare. Hamlet?
[Chuckles Sarcastically]
"Euripidie..."
Euri... Eur...
Euripides.
Lastly,
we hope you take advantage of
the many extracurriculars...
here at the university.
Although I must report
we've had to cut funding...
to some of the more
non-essential programs...
on campus such as
the martial arts club,
- the ballet society...
- [Gasps]
Wha...
and the entire
musical theater department.
[Man]
That's a worthwhile program.!
Fortunately,
we haven't had to cut any money
from our two prized programs...
the football team...
That's right!
[Barking]
- Yeah!
- And... your seven-time...
defending collegiate champion
Stinger cheerleading squad!
- Yea!
- Let's hear it
for our heroes.!
[Cheering Continues]
[Students Chanting]
Tina.! Tina.! Tina.! Tina.!
Tina! Tina!
Tina! Tina! Tina! Tina!
Hey, everybody!
I'm Tina Hammersmith!
[Excited Squeal]
Y'all ready
to rock the body electric?
- Ahhh!
- Let's get this party started!
Five, six,
seven, eight!
[Techno Pop]
[Girl]
Whoo.!
Yeah.! Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo.!
You go, girl.!
[Cheerleaders]
Two, three, four...
Stingers in the house!
We're on the attack!
- That's right!
- Got no extra fat!
We don't eat Big Macs!
It's gross!
- Step to us.!
You might get smacked.!
- [Tina] Whacked.!
We got more game
than the man they call Shaq!
The moonwalk! The twist!
The shake and bake!
The what?
We can do it all
right here at State!
Strap yourself in
so your mind won't blow!
Sit back, relax
and enjoy the show!
What's wrong
with you people?
Stop it!
Yeah! Stingers!
This is terrible.
What do you mean
"terrible"?
- They're perfect.
- I know.
That's what's terrible.
They are perfect.
Speaking of perfect.
You ever checked out
your own ass?
Whoa!
Gross!
Just pay him no mind.
No. No. I think
we should pay him mind.
I mean, this...
this man has a lot to say.
I do.
- I have a lot to say.
- He's a unique individual.
- Very unique individual.
- With his own thoughts
and ideas.
My own thoughts.
My own ideas.
- Who would never
make a fool of himself.
- Never ever...
make a fool of myself.
Even if he was blindly
mimicking whatever I said.
Even if I was blindly...
[Laughs]
Hey, punk.
Be watchin' you.
Smart guy.
Thank you.
No problem.
Belly ring?
No belly ring?
It's a cheerleading tryout.
They're going to be looking
at your moves,
not your body jewelry.
Oh, I know.
But here's my theory:
If they concentrate on my belly,
they won't recognize
if I mess up on
my back handsprings.
Whit, you're not gonna mess up.
I've seen your cheer skills.
They're for real.
Maybe for high school,
but this is college.
And in college
you have to be the poo.
Well, that shaggy boy
at orientation sure thought
you were the poo.
[Giggles]
He was all on you
like ugly on an Osbourne.
Him?
You think?
He did smile at me.
Mm-hmm.
But I can't lose
my concentration. I've really
got to focus on tomorrow.
I got to work
on my cheer moves.
Hit it, girl.
[Rock]
[Giggling]
Before we begin,
I want you to know that
just by trying out today,
- you're already a winner.
- [Giggling]
Unless, of course,
you get cut. In which case,
technically
you're a loser.
[Clears Throat]
[Camera Whirs]
So, go for it.
Okay, I'll start
with a simple aerial.
No,
I was thinking more
of a front handspring,
back handspring,
front handspring,
back handspring...
Okay! Give me an "S- S."
Give me a "T-R." Err!
[Man Rapping, Indistinct]
[Rapping Continues]
That was awesome.
So, do you got
any good cheers?
- I got something for ya.
I got a little shout out.
- You got a what?
I got to give a shout out to
all my people, baby! Whoo!
I'm flossin'!
You can't see me. I got the ice.
It's just blindin' ya!
Peace, and I'm out!
Back handspring,
front handspring, cartwheel,
back handspring, cartwheel...
[Continues]
Give me an "S- S".
Give me a "T- R".
I just screwed up again!
Dang it! I can't believe it! No!
Just kill me right now!
Bam! Haha! Please?
Front handspring,
cartwheel, back handspring,
back handspring,
cartwheel...
Ooh.
Ohh, yeah!
Oh, my God.
Thanks for coming.
[Camera Whirs]
And lastly,
Smith, comma, Whittier.
- Okay. So...
- Wait.
- What is it?
- That thing.
That shiny offensive
thing... midsection.
- Oh, that's my belly ring.
- Lose it immediately.
- Okay. Sorry.
- [Scoffs]
[Ring Rattles,
Rolls Across Floor]
[Whittier]
Okay.
- Um.
- [Clattering]
- Okay. Are you ready?
- How about, are you ready?
I think so.
Here I go.! Hit it.!
[Up-tempo Scratch Mix]
[Panting]
- How's that?
- Thank you.
[Woman]
Sheila.
[Tina] Too fat.
Kenny.
Too dorky.
Brenda.
[Together]
Psycho!
Cindy.
Snaggletooth.
Carol-Ann.
It's called lotion.
Eczema.
Theo.
Too gay!
- Patrick?
- Not gay enough.
[Chuckles]
And finally, Whittier.
- She's okay.
- Okay? Marni, she's future
head cheerleader material.
Memo, pink ink,
we already have our future
head cheerleader. Hi.
[Chuckles]
The only difference being,
she's cute.
Yeah, she's cute the way
a smushed-up bug is cute.
Oh, and excuse me.
Did you see her blond hair?
- So fake!
- [Scoffs]
Well, if that's not the pot
calling the kettle blond.
Ohh! I was...
I was born with dark roots.
Mm-hmm.
Well, anyway,
I'd be all over her.
- You know,
if she had a schwinger.
- Maybe she does.
[Tina]
Enough.!
You two bitches can catfight
all night, but I'm the one
that makes the decisions.
Until I do...
you're dismissed.
Leave me.
Ow!
[Coughs]
- No time for rest, cherub.
- Dean Sebastian.
I didn't know
you were here.
I've been here six hours.
Saw every last peppy pigtail
that passed through this place.
Pretty ugly, huh?
[Chuckles]
Some were ugly.
Some were hideous.
While others were sublime.
I'm talking about
State's next head cheerleader.
Smith, comma, Whittier.
Whittier can't be head
cheerleader next year.
She's just a freshman.
She's just good
is what she is.
But the head cheerleader spot
is reserved for Marni.
Tina!
The State cheerleading
squad has won...
seven consecutive
national titles,
which over that time
has tripled alumni donations...
and allowed me the life
to which I am accustomed.
Just last year,
I upgraded...
from an '88 Jetta
to a 2003 Passat.
Wow.
I'm not about to throw
all that away...
over some brown-nosing
mediocrity named Marni.
Whittier might
have what it takes,
but she's awfully raw.
That, dear, is why
you must mold her.
Shape her. Twist her
like Silly Putty.
If you make her
half as great as you are,
the national title
will stay here
for years to come.
Remember
the school motto...
Whatever it takes.
I can't hear you.
[Stamps Floor]
Whatever it takes!
- Welcome to the team.
- [Whittier Squealing]
Welcome to the team.
[Girls Squealing]
Welcome to the...
Oh, uh, this is size four.
Is that gonna be
too small for you?
Kidding!
Get outta here.
Welcome to the team.
Wait!
This isn't a uniform.
These are towels.
You're very perceptive,
aren't you?
But aren't I on the team?
Of course you're on the team.
As a towel girl.
It's an honor.
How is it an honor?
[Incredulous Chuckle]
Say there is no towel girl.
Say Greg hoists
Tina up into a cupie,
and there is no one
to towel off his sweaty hands.
Tina slips.
Tina falls and-and lands
on her spinal cord,
and she spends the rest
of her life doing watercolors
with her teeth.
Do you want
that to happen?
I guess not.
Hmm.
I didn't think so.
[Chattering]
Man,
these colors are hype!
I am never taking this off.
Even after you're dead
in the ground?
Totally.
[Both Laughing]
[Locker Door Slams]
Congratulations,
my little pumpkins.
You have now joined
the best of the best
of the best.
Here's Marni
with some light reading.
Now, study
those rule books and wear
those uniforms with pride.
People
have given their ankles,
ligaments,
collarbones...
in service to those
very uniforms you have
on your taut little bodies.
'Cause from here on out
you must be
the "bomb diggity."
You must eat leaner,
train meaner, jump higher,
yell louder and out-pep
anyone who stands in your way.
You must brush better,
floss better, lather,
rinse and repeat better...
In other words, you must
be better in every
aspect of your life.
Are you ready for all that?
- Whittier?
- Uh. Uh. Uh...
[Up-tempo Pop Rock]
I'm gonna
catch you guys later.
All right.
Is...
[Clears Throat]
- Is everything okay up there?
- Again. Four, five, six,
seven, eight.
Is everything okay up there?
Hey, you're
the orientation guy!
Yeah, Orientation Guy
is my given name.
But, um, it's not my real name.
My friends call me Derek.
Well, hi, Derek.
I'm Whittier.
Whittier?
I like it.
- It's nice.
- Thank you.
- You want to do
something illegal?
- What?
Do you want
to do something illegal?
[Man] Shut up.!
Uhh. Okay.
Really?
What kind of girl are you?
[Laughs]
Stop!
Whoa!
[Grunts]
No way. No.
You're a cheerleader.
You get thrown three stories...
in the air every day.
Tina would kill me
if I sprained an ankle.
Who's Tina?
Our head cheerleader.
She's got rules
against this kind of thing.
It's all in the manual.
And you've
gotta follow the rules.
Well, do you see Tina
anywhere around here?
No.
- [Giggles]
- [Derek Groaning]
[Whittier]
Sorry. Are you okay?
Are we allowed
to be in here?
2:00 a.m.'s
the only good time to swim.
The rest of the time,
I'm working.
Where?
Well, I do work-study
in the cafeteria.
Part-time in an audio store.
Full-time as a student.
And the rest of the time
as a mix-master.
What's a mix-master?
It's a turn-tablist.
What's a turn-tablist?
It's a D.J.
I knew that.
[Both Laughing]
Oh, hey. I'm not into you
like that. L...
No, I didn't... l...
[Both Laughing]
Well, then I'm leaving.
I'm out.
Okay. Fine. Fine.
It's over.
Okay. Well, okay...
[Laughs]
Why do you work so much?
I work so much...
because my dad
wouldn't pay my tuition
unless I declared premed.
And you didn't want
to be a doctor, so...
So, I work.
Well, you know what they say
about men who work too hard.
They become
tired, boring...
and in the process they lose
all their spontaneity.
Derek, are you tired?
No. You're boring!
[Giggling]
You are boring.
Boring, my ass!
[Squeals]
Whoo!
[Laughs]
God, you look great
under water.
Well, did I tell you
I'm a cheerleader?
[Laughs] Yeah.
I think we covered that.
Did we talk about
your 10,000 part-time jobs?
Yeah.
I think a while back.
Oh.
Well, was there anything else
that we needed to cover?
Well, there was...
one thing I wanted to...
[Whimpers]
I gotta go.
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't you
want to stay and,
you know, swim
a little more?
I think my roommate might be
getting worried about me.
Why would she be worried?
Because,
you're turning me
into a criminal.
Whit... Whittier,
I could get hypothermia
without you here!
[Yells]
And five, six, seven, eight!
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight!
One!
Girls, put your hands
on your hips.
Suzy, how about
suckin' in the arm flab?
Thank you.
Claire, sweetie,
two eyebrows
are better than one.
Think I gave you the memo.
Oh, my God.! Monica.!
Time for some
damage control
on that ass!
For a minute there, I thought
I was looking at a Hefty Bag
full of chili dogs! Ha!
Greg.! How about
the happy cheer face now, huh?
This is my happy cheer face.
That's not
a happy smile!
That's a hate smile.
[Whispers]
Is it that obvious, bitch?
All right. Pop-off on two.
One, two and... down.
[Grunting]
[Snickering]
- [Drums: Rock Beat]
- [Tina]
Five, six, seven, eight.!
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, again.!
five, six, seven, again!
One, two, three, four...
You suck so much,
I can't stand you! Again!
Go.! Faster, faster,
faster, faster, faster.!
Come on, you Sasquatch.!
Let's go.!
Come on, Monica.!
Show me a herkie.! Let's see it.!
Let's see it.! What is that?
Push.
Push!
[Grunting]
[Straining]
This weight is a car,
and it is pressed
on top of your mother!
Lift it off your mom!
[Screaming]
Lift it off her!
Too late. She's dead.
[Whimpers]
[Tina]
What is this, a bowl ofJell-O
I'm looking at?
Whit, that water is not
from the French Alps!
Down for 10...
And six and seven
and eight!
[Grunting]
[Cries Out]
You guys are looking
so great today.
[Chuckles]
I'm just kidding.
You look like crap.
All right,
Monica and Whittier, get ready
for a pop-off on four.
Hey, you wanna do
a cradle off the back?
You want to?
Yeah.
Ready?
One, two, three, four.
- [Giggling]
- What the hell was that?
I asked for a simple pop-off!
Was that a simple pop-off?
I'm very curious
to know, Monica.
Was that or was that not
a pop-off?
Settle down, Tina.
We were giving the routine
a little flavor,
a little individuality.
A little flavor?
A little individuality?
[Laughs]
Missy, you are no longer
an individual.
All right?
You are a very small,
little minute part...
of a very big-ass machine!
And that machine
has my name on it.
You got it?
- We're sorry.
- Not good enough, Whittier.
Meet me
in my office... 0800.
Is that the address?
She's waiting for you.
Come on, this way.
Tina, I'm really sorry about
what happened in practice.
Shut the door.
Did you know that, um,
- George W. Bush was
a cheerleader in college?
- Actually, I did.
Ronald Reagan was
also a cheerleader.
So was Dwight D. Eisenhower.
The three greatest presidents
of the last 200 years...
- all cheerleaders.
- Was Ronald Reagan really
one of the top three?
Top 40.
My point is this.
From great cheerleaders
come even greater leaders.
You may be a great cheerleader,
Whittier, but you are not
a great leader.
I know,
and I'm really trying hard.
See these portraits
on the wall?
A 98-year tradition
of cheerleading excellence
at CSC.
Starting back with
the remarkable Margaret Whiting
in 1938.
What's she doing?
An arabesque.
You can't tell
under the hoopskirt.
All the way up to the fantastic
Hammersmith dynasty of today.
These are your sisters?
Yep.
They're all part
of a grand legacy
with no end in sight.
That last empty frame
right there is reserved...
for the head cheerleader
who will take our place...
our next leader.
Marni.
It could be Marni.
[Chuckles]
Or it could be Greg.
Whoo.
Or as I've been
thinking lately,
- it could be you.
- Yeah, right.
- I'm serious, Whittier.
- But I completely
messed up in practice.
I thought you called me in here
to kick me off the team.
Oh, I haven't
totally ruled that out yet.
I don't know.
I just expect more out of you
than the others.
Certainly more than
your friend, Monica.
Monica was just messing around.
Wait till game day.
She'll be perfect.
Oh, really? She's gonna
be great on game day?
Monica is a sinking ship!
To be a great cheerleader
you have to make sacrifices.
And I suggest
you start with her.
Do you mean
not being friends with her?
'Cause we're roommates.
Listen, sweetie.
Being head cheerleader...
is a privilege you should
very much want.
I mean,
[Chuckles]
Students have posters
of me on their walls.
They pay hundreds of dollars...
320 to be exact...
just to get my number.
They raffle off the right
to carry my books to class.
[Laughs]
[Chuckling]
It's so silly.
Foreign exchange students
literally...
beg to do my homework...
straight A's.
All this could be yours.
You could be the greatest thing
on this campus...
the next me.
[Chuckles]
- Whoa.
- But I don't know.
It's all a question
of how bad you really want it.
I mean, for starters,
you're gonna have to shine
at the home opener this weekend.
Literally millions
will be watching you.
But most importantly,
I will be watching you.
I'm tired now.
Handing out all those towels
has made my arms feel like
soggyJell-O.
I'm too tired to point out
how dumb that sounds.
Hey, guys.
[Gasps]
Hey, Britney Spaz.
[Giggles]
Why are you so happy?
Didn't Tina just rip you
a new... I can't say what.
Actually... and, ladies,
please keep this a secret,
Tina told me that
if I work really hard...
and I play my cards right,
I could become
head cheerleader.
- Congratulations, Whittier!
- Yeah, that's great!
You're not bummed are you?
No. I don't want
to be head cheerleader.
I'm just flossin' my moves
until I make it as a dancer
on J. Lo's next tour.
I've been meaning
to talk to you about that.
What?
Tina made a lot of sense
in practice the other day.
There is a big difference
between individual dance moves
and... Oh, my gosh!
What?
There's over 680 calories
in that. Not to mention
35 grams of saturated fat.
That must've been
a real special talk you had
with Tina back there.
Too bad yourJedi mind tricks
couldn't fend off the dark side
of the force.
Monica, if you want to be
the bomb diggity,
you have got to act
like the bomb diggity,
and Tina is the bomb diggity!
Did she just say,
"bomb diggity" three times
in one sentence?
[Crowd Cheering]
[P.A. Announcer]
Your halftime score is
Stingers, 17. Willowcrest, nine.
[Monica]
No, I'm serious. We're the ones
with all the pressure.
Pressure?
No, girly, you don't know
what real pressure is!
You see, I got to
go out there first. Just me.
Solo.
And if these 50,000 people don't
buy into the whole illusion...
of who I am
and what I represent,
you guys are toast!
Aren't you just a big bug?
Correction!
I am a hunting wasp...
of the order hymenoptera,
with a deadly venomous
ovipositor!
Do you know what that is?
Well, I'll tell ya!
It's a deadly
stinger, bitch!
Bug!
Stay in the zone, Sammy.
You stay in the zone.
Chest out!
Ponytail, no.
Up-do, yes.
Sweetie, no double earrings.
You're a State cheerleader,
not a State hooker.
[Mimicking Beatbox]
* Go, go, go, Stingers *
[Beatbox]
* Go-go, go-go-go
Uh-oh, the Stingers *
Remember, Whit.
Head cheerleader.
What do you mean
"head cheerleader"?
I'm the next
head cheerleader.
I am!
Focus on the performance.
I am not gonna focus
on the performance!
Focus!
No, I'm not gonna focus!
I won't!
I don't mean that.
Please don't hate me!
Tina, please don't hate me!
Hey, I don't
hate you, Marni.
Shut up!
[Beatbox]
* Sammy *
* Here comes Sammy *
[P.A. Announcer]
Ladies and gentlemen,
we ask you
to turn your attention
to the multi-champion...
Show time.
Stinger cheerleaders and their
"Stingtacular"halftime show.!
Yeah!
Come on! Let's go!
Let's get it on, Stingers!
Number one!
Number one! Yeah!
[P.A. Announcer]
Ladies and gentlemen,
say hello to Sammy Stinger...
and your Stinger cheerleaders.!
Let's go, Stingers!
Whoa!
[Man]
Hit it.!
[Techno Pop]
* Turn the beat back
Come on, turn the beat back *
* Turn the beat back *
* Come on
Turn the beat back *
* Come on, turn the beat back
Come on, turn the beat back
Turn the beat back *
* Free, free
Free-free-free *
Let's go, Stingers!
[Crowd Cheering]
- [All]
Stingers!
- [Cheering]
Let's go, Stingers!
- Let's go, Stingers!
- [All]
Ohh! Ho-ho!
Go back! Go back!
Let's see it again!
Go, Stingers!
- [Laughing]
- One more time.
One more time.
Tina, she's here.
Hey, baby.
[Crowd]
Way to go, Whittier.!
[Man Shouting]
Hey, Whittier.!
Hi.
Whittier, right?
Jackson. Senior,
with the Boxster
out front?
I was wondering if...
We just saw the video,
and we were like,
"That is the shizzle,"
and we...
Okay, okay, okay.
You two, hands off.
This is my party,
my cheerleader.
So, great facial
on TV today.
Sticking your tongue out on
camera, totally inspired.
You think?
O.M. G,
it was T.D.F., F.Y.I.
Whittier, this is Todd.
Starting wide receiver,
6'1 ",
3.2 G.P.A.,
runs a 4.6 forty.
4.5 forty.
[Both Laughing]
How ya doin'?
Uh, good.
[Gasps]
And it just doesn't happen.
He said he was a good listener.
Hi, Marni.
Would you like
an appetizer?
But he wasn't a good listener.
[Mouth Full, Indistinct]
Here.
How about a towel?
[Continues,
Indistinct]
[Grunts]
I'm sorry!
Sorry. Would you
like an appetizer?
This is why I go to
the trouble ofhosting
all these parties.
So guys like you
can mingle with girls
like you.
So mingle.
Blaine!
Eh, really nice
touchdown catch today.
Homeboy didn't want to play
the rest of the game.
Got taken off on a stretcher.
The quarterback's
all staring at me.
I'm like, "Oh, boy, I'm gonna
hit you so hard, your mama's
gonna feel it!" Right?
We broke from the huddle...
Hi, Whittier.
Would you like an appetizer?
I'm okay.
Thank you.
How about a towel?
Then they motioned into a slot.
That's when I knew
the running back...
was gonna do an up-and-under
pattern behind the linebacker.
And he's...
You know, that's...
great, really.
Do you mind
if for the next minute...
we talk about something
other than football?
Uh, I'm sorry.
It's my bad. I'm sorry.
Thanks.
So, Tina, um,
tells me you're a "C" cup.
[People Chattering]
Oh, dude, check out
the brunette. Sweet!
Yeah, she's hot.
She was not gonna be
head cheerleader. And...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Check out the blond
right over there.
Where? Where?
The dude right over there.
What do you mean,
"dude"?
Hey, you know what?
The one
with the great legs.!
I bet he could
leg-press a mule.
Oh, man!
What?
Oh, you...
You didn't know?
Listen.
I got nothin' against
your kind of people.
It's just football rules.
I gotta kick your ass now.
That sounds like a party.
You should know, though,
I bench-press 220.
Whatever, dude.
235.
Can we talk? Now?
Thank you.
Pardon us.
Yo! Dewey!
Okay, let's blow
this joint.
Mon, Mon, Mon.
Don't go yet.
Whit!
We cheered
on national television.
This is our coming-out party.
Blue!
Hey, excuse me.
Uh, I'm looking for a girl
named Whittier.
She's about yea tall.
She's blond, super-cute.
Well,
look who it is,
smart guy.
Why don't you say
something smart, smart guy?
Yeah, okay.
How about something foreign
and exotic like adios.
Hey, don't.
Chill, big guy.!
[Scoffs]
God!
Besides, there are some good
people here too, and they're
here to celebrate us!
Yeah, they want
to celebrate all over us.
[Gasps]
Derek!
Hey, Monica.
Hi, hottie.
I didn't think
you were gonna make it.
Yeah.
How'd you get past the goon squad?
Guile, cunning, cowardice.
[Chuckles, Coos]
You, scruffy boy.
Out.
This party is exclusivo.
No, it's okay.
- He's with me.
We're together.
- Who's he?
This is Derek.
He's a D.J.
[Laughs]
There are, like,
10,000 hot varsity
football players inside,
and you're snuggling up
to a D.J.?
- How edgy.
- What's wrong with a D.J.?
Honey, oh.
There's a logical order
to the college universe,
and the sooner
you learn it, the better.
See, way up here
at the top of the ladder
are football players.
Right.
They rule.
Just underneath them...
are basketball players...
smaller biceps
but still desirable.
Then, soccer hunks,
lacrosse studs,
fraternity presidents...
ohh... fraternity keg-masters,
guys with cars with parking
passes, guys with cars
without parking passes...
kind of a waste of time...
[Man]
Love your dress, Tina.!
Black Student Union
activists... Hey!...
Bruce Lee fan clubbers,
lit-mag squares,
pep-band dorks, um,
film society toads,
campus ministers,
school mascots...
and then, God,
all the way at the bottom...
are campus D.J.'s.
One spot above cafeteria workers.
Actually,
I work
at the cafeteria too.
Oh, do you?
Tsk.
That's hopeless.
Listen, Whit.
Remember our little "discush"
the other day?
You have to decide,
are you with us...
or are you with him?
I'm sorry.
Derek, l...
Oh, I get it.
Yeah.
- Oops.
- But... I'll call you.!
I can't believe
you just did that!
Oh, she did the right thing.
She stuck with the winners.
Excuse me? You think
you're a winner because
you got a bunch of idiots...
up your bomb diggity butt?
Excuse me?
Whittier!
- Are you coming?
- Yeah.
[Tina]
What are you looking at?
[Woman]
What's her problem?
[Man] Drama queen.
So Doc says if I sprain
my hip-flexor one more time,
I can kiss my herkie good-bye.
Hey,
you guys.
Hey.
- Greg, can you help me
stretch my hamstrings?
- Yeah.
[Snapping Fingers]
- Look, about the party...
- On your feet.
Practice
has started.
Today we're gonna
work on manners and respect.
Because some of you
don't know how to behave
at a team function.
Some of you
don't show proper manners
to a head cheerleader.
Some of you don't show respect
to the concept of team unity.
Come on.
Oh, good!
Monica.
We'll start with you.
[Woman]
Here we go.
What do you got?
Front handspring round-off,
back handspring toe touch.
[Synthesized Pop]
Stop the music!
[Stops]
Is that all you got?
- And again!
- [Resumes]
Round-off back handspring,
back tuck.
- Music stop!
- [Stops]
And again!
Herkie!
Herkie! Herkie! Herkie!
Herkie! Herkie! Herkie! Herkie!
- [Monica Groans]
- Herkie! Herkie! Herkie!
No one touch her!
[Stops]
I'm not done yet, Monica!
To be a real cheerleader...
- Tina, give it a rest.
- Not now, Greg!
I said give it a rest!
[Exhales]
Okay. All right.
[Sighs] You're right.
I should... I should...
I should give it a rest.
- Whittier,
call out the steps.
- What, me?
You heard me.
That's what leaders do.
- But Monica...
- Call out the steps.
- Call them out!
- No!
Listen, freshman. I put
you in that uniform, and I can
take you right out of it!
Call the steps,
or you're off the team.
Then I'm off the team.
Wh-What?
- [Nervous Giggle]
- You heard me. I quit!
I quit too.
That's right.
- Greg, you'll lose
your cheerleading scholarship.
- That's right! I'm stayin' here,
but under a cloud of shame.
Tina.
You can have this back
because it's supposed
to show team spirit.
It's supposed
to make us feel proud,
but I just feel
guilty and stupid!
So you can have your skirt
and your spankies and your top.
I'm out of here!
I need this to get home.
I'll bring it back
when it's dry-cleaned.
- [Mouths Words]
- Bye, Miss Bomb Diggity.
[Huffs]
She'll be back.
- She's not coming back!
- [Sighs]
It's only Whittier.
- Ice cream...
Super Fudge Chunk.
- No!
Ice cream!
All right!
Stupid.
[Spectators Yelling,
Cheering]
Hey.
[Woman]
Run.! Run.! All right, take home.!
Take home.!
[Groans]
- Our team sucks!
- Whittier, quit worrying
about the game...
and enjoy the sunshine.
- The sun sucks.
- Whittier, don't you know
that the sun...
is nature's Prozac?
Do you really think the sun
is gonna make me feel better...
about giving up
the most important thing
in my life?
No, but I'm out
of real Prozac, so you're
gonna have to deal.
I ruined my career
as a cheerleader.
I ruined
my relationship with Derek.
I could've had a boyfriend.
I ruined my entire life!
Yeah, I feel better.
- Anyone want
to hit the library?
- Ooh, I'll go with.
This place is starting
to weird me out anyway.
Women's softball...
I just don't get it.
[Chuckles]
Whittier...
- It'll be okay.
- I know. Thank you.
You'll be fine, girl!
- Trust me.
- [Woman] Come on.
Let's go, Stingers.
[Yelling, Cheering]
- [Grunts]
- [Woman] Nicejob.
Nice way to take the base.
[Woman]
Batter up.!
[Rhythmic Hissing]
[Bell Tolling In Distance]
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it!
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
- We got Stinger spirit.
- [Subdued Cheering]
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it!
We got Stinger spirit!
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it!
- What's going on?
- We got Stinger spirit!
- [Clapping]
- Come on, y'all. Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it!
[All]
We got Stinger spirit!
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit!
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.
Come on, y'all.
Let's hear it.
We got Stinger spirit.!
[Cheering]
[Woman]
Yeah.
- [Whistle Blows]
- Yes!
- Number one! Number one!
- [All Cheering]
Let's go, Stingers!
Let's go!
[Cheering Continues]
Those are my girls!
Go, Stingers!
[Man]
Whoa.! Whoa.!
Monica!
I got it!
You got...
You got what?
We're gonna start
our own squad.
Oh, shut up.
No, no. I'm serious.
Our own squad.
New and improved.
Shut up!
No. For real!
Come on! Let's go!
Are you sure you put
the audition time
on the flyer?
Yes.
Okay, because it was
an hour and a half ago.
I put the time on there.