Wow, the food is really good here!
It's got a nice vibe, too.
(December 24th, Christmas Eve)
You should get a girlfriend
and bring her here.
I'll give you my card if you do.
Dad!
I'll be a senior next year, busy
for college!
Hey! That doesn't mean you can't have
a dinner out with your girlfriend.
(Advert: Learn English Online!)
Is there someone you're waiting for?
Oh... So-woo.
I think he's having some issues lately.
So-woo?
Yes.
He hasn't been in school and I can't
get a hold of him.
I think he's starting to be depressed
again.
But I don't know how to help him.
Don't stress about it.
It happens pretty often, doesn't it?
He'll be fine soon.
It's a little different this time.
He keeps telling me things
I don't understand.
It's as if he's a completely
different person.
But Dad,
you seem very tired these days.
Maybe we can go on a trip
once my break starts.
Sounds good! Where?
When are you returning to school?
Ji-hoon is worried about you.
He said it seems like you're having
a hard time.
I wonder...
How you looked when you heard that.
I heard from Ji-hoon.
How his biological father killed his mom,
and how you touched his heart after.
How you accepted him as family,
and how you
looked after him.
You quit being a prosecutor
because you worried that Ji-hoon will
still remember that incident?
I was surprised.
I couldn’t believe there is such a great
person in the world.
A good will without any ulterior
motive exists!
But you...
I'm afraid that one day I'll grow up and be
an adult like you.
You don't have to worry about me.
Just worry about Ji-hoon.
What do you mean by that?
Does...
Ji-hoon know about this?
Why?
Are you ashamed?
I'm going to tell him.
He should know.
He should know what kind of a person
his father is.
He just got OK.
Don't make it hard for him.
I should keep my mouth shut because
it's an inconvenient truth?
That doesn't work on me anymore.
Ji-hoon is different from the kids
on the list.
- He's my friend.
- If he is...
You should protect him even more.
Why should Ji-hoon know about this?
Because it's sad.
Don't you feel sad for him?
He firmly believes that you are the savior
of his life.
He loves you and respects you the most!
It's sad to see.
The real you is far from it.
To be disappointed and hurt by you
is his burden to bear.
It's not my fault.
What I wanted to tell you
was that.
How dare you talk about Ji-hoon like that?
Jeong-guk Watchman.
Don't be mistaken about yourself, you were
just acting like a hero online.
No one will accept you in reality.
You can't get along with anyone, you're
always negative,
always complaining about the system,
spreading negativity like cancer!
Not just your school life, but
you'll live alone in your entire life
typing on your keyboard just like now,
and die alone!
But Ji-hoon
is not like you, you're not fit
for society.
Never show your face around Ji-hoon!
(Solomon's Perjury Episode 11)
It's been a while!
Hello.
You've grown up quite a bit
since the last time I saw you.
We've never met with just us two before,
without So-woo.
No.
It is a bit awkward.
Have you been well?
Just so so. How about you?
I shouldn't have asked.
I'm sure you're not fine.
No.
I'm OK.
You don't need to hide it from me.
Really...
Are you OK?
No.
Then why?
Why do you torture yourself that way?
I want to know.
There's an answer I have to find out.
From whom?
Ji-hoon.
When I heard about the trial...
I wasn't sure why you'd go that far.
People have the right to forget, too.
To talk about So-woo whom people had
already said good-bye's to...
And to discuss the incident in public,
all in detail,
it was uncomfortable.
I didn't think it was necessary.
But...
I kept hearing about how the trial was
going, and I realize what you're doing.
So,
I decided to go on the trial, too.
I'm a witness to the prosecutor.
You're gonna talk about the school?
Yes.
Choi Woo-hyuk's innocence is already
proven.
I think it's about time I should step in.
- I think that's a good idea.
- But...
How much should I say?
All of it.
All of it?
About you, too?
Yes.
Can you handle it?
I was already prepared before
the trial began.
I'm no longer the defense counsel
in the trial.
You can't call the judge into
the prosecutors' meeting!
Then what do I do? Soo-hee's not here
and I'm no help to Seo-yeon.
You're the one who came so quickly when
I asked you to come see me!
You didn't say anything about a meeting.
Then what, you thought I had something
to tell you alone?
Yes... No.
Hurry, I've pushed back my lesson for this.
Nothing extraordinary.
But I felt like I should let you know what
might be said in this session.
I already know about the call records.
I saw this video.
Lee Jung-woo? The teacher?
Yes.
He was our art teacher last year.
He was close to So-woo.
He's got something to say about the school.
Really?
That's surprising.
The vice principal again? Why?
Don't you remember how upset he was
last time?
I know.
But he's speaking from a different
position this time.
He said he'll give an honest testimony
this time.
He'll talk about why the school wanted
to hide the So-woo incident.
Then he's being a whistle-blower
after he's fired?
It's going to upset many people,
regardless.
I know. I'll be careful.
Who's the last witness?
I've never heard this name before.
That's to be told in court.
OK.
But you understand that your witnesses and
evidence are not so objective, right?
Your witnesses are former faculty members,
and your evidence is just assumptions about
that night.
There's no clear purpose the prosecutor has
in this trial session.
You only have three days before
you're expelled.
I can't set our objective to
just one thing.
I feel like I can find evidence as we go
through the testimony,
about the male student.
I think it'll be a psychological
examination.
I want to try it first.
When did you become so audacious?
This is just like Schrödinger's cat!
A paradox!
That's true.
What is this?
What are you guys talking about?
What is that?
Don't worry about it.
What happened?
Happy birthday to you
happy birthday to you!
What's this? We decided to skip
my birthday this year!
No matter how busy you are, you shouldn't
skip your birthday!
You probably only have about
80 birthdays left.
OK, again!
Happy birthday dear Seo-yeon...
Happy birthday to you!
Thanks! That made me feel so much better.
Hey, too early to feel that way.
You still have this!
Wait, stop!
I hate my sister! How come there's
no birthday party?
I waited for this day for so long!
I know, I know...
Let's go out to eat ourselves when Dad
gets home.
Not that!
I like the birthday atmosphere.
The party hats, the candles...
Grow up already!
You still like birthday parties
at this age?
Dad's home!
Hello, Dad!
What's wrong?
Seo-yeon banned her own birthday party.
She said she has to focus
on the trial.
You guys go ahead.
Go on and eat it.
You know anything about tomorrow's trial?
She hasn't been out of her room.
She just says, "I'm leaving for school,"
then, "I'm back from school."
That's all she says to me.
You didn't know?
Ji-hoon's father is the one who ordered
the club members to be expelled.
Do you think that was my only lie?
I am Han Kyung-hoon, the head of
the legal department.
(The day of the fourth trial)
(Notice: The participating trial club
members have been suspended for 5 days)
The defense counsel's space
has been closed off.
We can't use the main school building.
Ko Seo-yeon.
Tell me if you got something to say.
No need to avoid it.
I never did.
Isn't it because you're hiding something
that you feel that way?
This is the list of witnesses for
today's trial.
How about the defense counsel?
No witnesses.
No witnesses?
Why?
You said it yourself.
You asked me to pick apart your witnesses
and evidence, and assert for his suicide.
I'll do just that.
You haven’t heard?
They're threatened to be expelled,
counting the days until it happens.
Expelled?
Five points off just for watching it!
All the students are stuck in their
classrooms.
They're taking it too far!
The school's out of their mind.
What do you think? Don't you feel like
Ji-hoon's target it the school?
Hello.
We thank you very much for coming
this trial.
There is no defendant in this session.
We are here to find out the truth behind
Lee So-woo's death.
Please understand that there is no
defendant.
Please be seated.
We'll start the examinations.
You are Lee Jung-woo, the art teacher
in Jeong-guk High School until last year?
Yes, that's me.
You said you spoke with Lee So-woo
frequently.
Was it a personal relationship or just
between a teacher and a student?
I believe we were close friends, regardless
of age or being a teacher and a student.
We often met outside of school.
Was there a specific incident where you and
Lee So-woo became close?
He liked drawing.
We felt connected in a sense that both of
us are the outsiders of Jeong-guk school.
"The outsiders"?
Yes.
We'd joke about it together.
He was probably the only student who didn't
care much about his grades in school.
I was just an art teacher that's hired
on contract, no one cared about me.
We were the outsiders in that sense.
Do you mean that Lee So-woo felt like
no one cared about him?
But he didn't feel particularly lonely
or anything.
So-woo said he was much more comfortable
talking to people online.
So-woo communicated online?
Yes.
Jeong-guk Watchman.
What?
So-woo was the admin for
the Jeong-guk Watchman account.
So-woo was the Watchman.
So-woo was the Watchman!
Who was that?
Keep quiet during class!
Really?
Jeong-guk Watchman...
is still active.
So how can So-woo...
I believe a friend took over
that account.
Lee So-woo's friend?
From this school?
That...
I'm not sure.
Why...
Why did So-woo hide the fact that
he was the Watchman?
He didn't like getting attention.
He was also afraid that people might be
disappointed that it was him.
He said he'd rather remain
an imaginary friend.
Prosecutor.
Ko Seo-yeon!
I apologize.
Do you know how Lee So-woo started
to be active as Jeong-guk Watchman?
He...
Wanted to communicate with other students.
He was curious about what other students
were thinking.
He said they're not so honest in school,
always pretending to be someone else.
So...
He wanted to know what the students
were hiding in their hearts?
You make it sound like it was out of a
bad intention.
But it wasn't like that.
What So-woo wanted was more like
a release, an outlet,
for the students, so they can breathe.
Watchman! Tell me about Han Ji-hoon.
No girlfriend, went to Jeong-guk elementary
and middle school, living in
Monte Visa Penthouse.
Whoever took Lee Yoo-jin's wallet by
mistake, or found it, please message me.
I'll deliver it to the owner anonymously.
Jeong-guk Watchman!
Ahn Yoo-min in Class 2-1 is not
a teacher's pet who's reporting
everything to the teachers.
Please refrain from assumptions and
witch hunts.
Jeong-guk Watchman strikes again!
- What is it?
- Take a look!
Wow, how could he have thought of this?
It's such a relief!
- Did you see what he posted?
- He's so awesome!
I'm sure he's a tall and handsome guy!
As you all know, people liked him
very much online.
Many people went to him to be counseled,
many reported things to him and
exposed things, too.
Exposed things? What kind?
Were there things about the school?
I can't pinpoint it like that.
But So-woo took it as something that's
related with the school.
Can you show the picture that's on
the Watchman's profile page?
Yes.
Yes, this painting.
This was his favorite painting.
From So-woo's perspective, this is what
the school felt like.
Could you elaborate in more detail?
It's called "the Magpie on the Gallows" by
Bruegel.
It just looks like an ordinary landscape
painting of a farm.
But look at the middle.
There's a gallows, and a person seized by
people and being dragged to the gallows.
This was painted in the Netherlands in the
16th century.
Witch hunts and inquisitions were
popular then.
But their evidence against those charges
were completely absurd.
- Anonymous accusations.
- Yes.
Someone just had to say, "So-and-so
is a witch, a heretic."
Just with that, they could kill someone.
To today's standards, it seems like they
were such bad people.
But they had to do so to protect
themselves.
It was a way of life to them.
Then how did So-woo...
Relate this painting to Jeong-guk
High School?
There was once a bad rumor about a
particular student in school.
- It was a big issue.
- Ahn Yoo-mi?
Yes. That student.
She had told a teacher about another
student who broke a school rule,
and didn't get her own points deducted
because of it.
That other student started a bad rumor
about Yoo-mi.
So-woo calmed the students down a bit,
but Yoo-mi was very upset.
But wasn't that just between them?
Not to So-woo.
People don't change.
They make up systems and oppress,
or be oppressed.
And make scapegoats out of others so
out of their fear of being oppressed.
He wasn't sure why the world hasn't
changed, after all that time.
He had asked, "Isn't the school at fault
for creating a system that makes students
report on each other for
higher points?"
I couldn't answer his question.
You stated that So-woo was already
at odds with the school.
Was it because of his rebellious feelings
like this one?
It wasn't really about his rebellious
nature.
But I was told that he was asked to leave
the school for posting something
on the Watchman account.
The school had threatened to move
So-woo to a different school!
He was asked to leave?
Just what did he post online?
I don't know its content.
That's why he stopped coming to school?
It wasn't about the science lab fight?
It was long before the fight when he
mentioned that he was asked to leave.
There were a few months that Jeong-guk
Watchman didn't post anything.
Yes.
- That started around October.
- It was then.
That's when the school asked So-woo
to leave this school for a different one.
- Recess!
Time out!
Recess!
Adjourn the trial for a second!
Objection!
Objection... To Prosecutor?
You're in her team!
It's not that...
I request for a recess.
Yoo-jin!
I request a break for 30 minutes.
We'll be adjourned for 30 minutes.
Mr. Han.
It's brought up in the trial!
Lee Yoo-jin!
The students are asking for a recess?
Yes, they're going crazy saying that
they want to watch it.
Crazy, So-woo was the Watchman?
- I'm getting the chills!
- Why kick him out of school? For what?
- Hurry to the auditorium!
- For sure, we have to see this!
- Forget about the points deduction!
- Who can take my seat here?
Hey!
Hey, Joon-young!
So-woo was the Watchman?
- How about your class?
- That's not so important right now.
All the other kids are coming too!
What happened? Tell me the details!
We'll explain later, but have them sit
in the auditorium.
Hurry! Before we get in trouble!
Why me? I'm not even on the defense team
anymore.
Are you proud of that?
Just go.
Ko Seo-yeon.
Let me talk to you for a second.
Prosecutor. You get the feel for it?
I see what's happening.
We need to hear more details from
the next witness.
Are you sure about this?
You're just like them.
(Jeong-guk Watchman)
Did you watch the movie I recommended?
It was good!
What's your next recommendation?
Please be quiet.
We'll begin the examination.
What is your position as a witness
in this trial?
The former vice principal and interim
principal of Jeong-guk High School.
But you're not one currently?
No.
Did you quit your post on your own?
No way.
I am very attached to this school.
This is all from my effort to protect this
trial from the pressures from school.
Pressures from school?
Yes.
From Jeong-guk Foundation.
How were you pressured?
They told me to disband the trial club.
And if they don't listen...
They told me to expel the students involved
in it, so harsh!
The foundation?
You were fired because you didn't
listen tot hem?
Yes.
Like you, I was punished for doing
the right thing!
We're all in the same boat.
Just earlier,
Lee Jung-woo, who was once a faculty member
here, revealed that So-woo was
Jeong-guk Watchman.
Did you know this fact?
Yes.
He also testified that because of what
So-woo posted on the Watchman account,
So-woo was asked to leave the school.
Is that true?
Yes, it's true.
Do you know the content he wrote?
Yes.
It was about Jeong-guk's...
unfair admission documents, their pictures.
Unfair admission?
There are students admitted to Jeong-guk
High School unfairly?
Yes, there are several.
So you mean...
Lee So-woo posted documents proving
unfair admission practice of the school,
then he was asked to leave the school?
Technically, it wasn't the document itself,
but the cover of the document.
The school didn't ask him to leave, but the
foundation did.
- Where's that photo...
- It was immediately deleted.
I'm sure it was someone high up in the
foundation who pressured him.
Do you have any evidence to prove
your statement?
I don't.
Is there anyone who remembers seeing
the photo the Watchman posted?
I remember it.
The cover of the document said,
"VIP."
Yes, that's the one.
It's the list of students who were
admitted unfairly.
Witness.
Please tell us everything about this
unfair admission practice.
Because I was just the vice principal
then...
I was just told that there was a list.
The principal and people from the
foundation know more about it.
The School Violence Prevention Committee,
too, was not suggested by Choi Woo-hyuk's
parents.
While Lee So-woo was refusing to leave
the school,
he got in trouble by getting into a fight.
The foundation took it as an opportunity
for them.
That's why the Committee was called
so quickly,
and determined Lee So-woo as
the assailant.
It was already determined that
Lee So-woo...
will be expelled.
They are just too much!
I agree.
Who made that call?
Who pressured Lee So-woo
to move school?
And determined that he is to be expelled
through the Committee?
- That's my question.
- Do you really need me to spell it out?
It was Han Kyung-moon, the head of the
legal department of the foundation.
Defense Counsel, ask questions
after Prosecutor's examination.
No.
I'll finish my examination here.
You may cross-examine the witness.
You testified last time that the School
Violence Prevention Committee was called
according to school policy.
- Do you remember it?
- That was...
When I was still hired by the school.
Of course I couldn't speak the truth.
You committed perjury then?
I guess you can say that, technically.
But... I'm now here to correct it.
You knew that it was wrong then.
Yes.
But...
I was only following an order.
I wasn't the one who gave the order.
- I had no authority to do so!
- At that time, you were...
The committee chair of the School Violence
Prevention Committee.
Are you saying a harsh punishment like
expulsion was given without
the consent of the committee chair?
Isn't it that you also wanted to get rid
of So-woo from the school,
because he exposed the school's
corruption?
- I had no choice then!
- A great power called the foundation
drove an 18-year-old to
death.
You knew it was the wrong thing to do.
Yet you agreed to it and watched it happen.
Now you're saying, "I'm not responsible,"
"I had no choice."
Don't you think those words...
Are so cowardly?
Han Ji-hoon!
Do you have any right to say
those kinds of words to me?
- You are...
- Mr. Vice Principal!
Hey, Han Ji-hoon!
Illicit admission...
Isn't it a serious matter if it's true?
Of course!
Do you know how hard I studied
to enter this school?
How can someone just pay money
to get in?
They have no conscience!
If it is true, we have to find out
who were admitted unfairly and expel them.
I won't allow them to study in the same
classroom as me.
But where did Han Ji-hoon go?
- I thought he was here.
- He's been weird lately.
He hasn't met with the rest of the
defense counsel, and doesn't
check his messages.
It feels like... He's getting ready
to leave.
Just a hunch.
You didn't go to school today either?
Get out.
I'm going to sleep.
So-woo!
It's not that I'm not going to school.
It's the school...
That doesn't want me.
Where is it?
Hey there, I have a...
Wait.
You're the guy from...
Hello.
How...
Yes, sir.
I'm watching the trial.
It's pretty surreal what's happening here.
Unfair admission?
Who testified?
OK. I'll be right there.
We'll being the examination.
Please keep quiet.
Next is the third witness from
the prosecutor.
Please come in.
Ji-hoon.
Your honor!
I need a moment with the defense counsel.
Before the witness testimony.
- You...
- I know he's your father.
I met him a few days ago.
He asked why I wanted to continue with
the trial, and its direction.
And I asked him to come on the trial.
- What will you ask him?
- Why?
Is there something I shouldn't ask about?
Are you hiding something from us?
Something else?
I want to confirm if there truly are
students who were admitted illegally.
And if they really wanted to kick So-woo
out of school for knowing it.
And if he is...
The one who was behind all this.
Let me do it.
I ask you.
I want to examine my father.
No.
I don't trust you.
Witness.
You must swear an oath as written
on your table.
Do you agree to it?
Yes.
Please swear with your right hand raised.
I pledge an oath to testify to the
truth according to my conscience.
I will not hide anything nor add anything,
and only speak the truth.
Thank you.
Prosecutor may begin the examination.
Yes.
Are you Mr. Han Kyung-moon, the head of
the legal department of Jeong-guk
Foundation, to which Jeong-guk High School
belongs?
- Yes.
- The legal department...
What is your main responsibility there?
We make sure that there are no legal issues
that arise in our schools.
Then...
You have a say in the school's management.
I receive general reports.
What happens when you feel that there is
an issue based on the reports?
Do you give orders to resolve
those issues?
There hasn't been an issue that I had to
give an order.
Witness.
Did you know Lee So-woo?
- Yes.
- How?
He's the student that died last December,
in Class 2-1 of Jeong-guk High School.
I was briefed about him after
then incident.
Was that all? Being reported
after the incident?
There was a testimony that you had
pressured Lee So-woo to go to a
different school because of what was posted
in Jeong-guk Watchman account,
also that you wanted to expel him through
the School Violence Prevention Committee.
That statement...
Is not trustworthy.
What makes you say that?
The former vice principal has been let go
of his position due to violating
the committee's policies.
Thus, he has a motive to testify
against the school.
Another teacher, Lee Jung-woo, also
gave the same testimony.
He said that Lee So-woo was at odds
with the school because of the
Jeong-guk Watchman account.
All the same, he's no longer hired
by the school as his contract expired.
Did you know that Lee So-woo was
Jeong-guk Watchman?
Yes.
But Lee So-woo never revealed that he was
the Watchman to anyone.
Do you admit that you secretly investigated
to find out who he was?
It was to find out basic information
about the account.
You're saying that the school and Lee
So-woo did not have any issues...
Then why did the Foundation investigate to
find out about who's behind it?
Jeong-guk Watchman was an anonymous
online community.
It had the potential to cause legal issues
such as spreading false rumors or
harshly criticizing certain students.
The legal department had every reason
to watch the account.
If you have been watching it closely...
Then you must've seen the illicit admission
document that was posted.
This is the first time I've ever
heard about such a list.
Can you show it to me?
The picture of the list that So-woo
apparently posted...
Can you show it to me?
The picture has been since deleted but the
judge here also admitted that he saw it.
A cover that said, "VIP."
How can you prove that the letters, "VIP,"
refer to a list of students who were
unfairly admitted?
Witness!
The judge determines the credibility
of evidence.
Not you.
Your honor.
It's easy to be confused.
But admissibility and credibility are two
different things.
Even in real courtrooms, the judge is not
to determine the credibility of evidence
on his own.
Prosecutor has assumed that a document
showing students who were unfairly admitted
exists, as well as issues between Lee
So-woo and the school.
She's questioning me with these
assumptions.
Although it is a school trial
done by students,
shouldn't it be based on evidence
with credibility?
I'd like to confirm it before I go on
with my further statements.
Can you prove that such a list
exists?
The defense counsel can turn in
such evidence.
These are the photos of the document
Jeong-guk Watchman had posted.
Just as I said before...
And this!
Is the actual list of students who were
unfairly admitted to school.
The letters, "VIP,"
did refer to the list of unfairly admitted
students.
The existence of such a list is
also true.
Witness.
Please answer.
You are the head of the legal department
of Jeong-guk Foundation,
and you admitted that you've been closely
watching Jeong-guk Watchman.
Yet...
This is the first time you knew about
this list?
When Lee So-woo posted this picture...
You never gave any kind of order
because of it?
It's just a piece of paper with a list of
names, anyone can make it up.
This does not serve as the evidence to
prove that there were students
who were admitted unfairly.
Just as such, I never gave any kind of
orders based on this claim.
I never pressured anyone to move to
a different school, or frame someone
through the Committee.
Witness.
You just swore an oath.
You must follow your conscience,
not add or hide anything from the truth,
you swore it at your seat.
I'll ask again.
Are your words...
True?
They are.
That was enough examination.
We'll adjourn for 30 minutes.
They are extraordinary all around,
Ji-hoon who questioned his own father,
and Mr. Han who denied it
until the end.
You said Ji-hoon planned for the trial?
Yes.
Seo-yeon doesn't know this?
She did ask if I knew whom Jeong-guk
Watchman is.
I didn't tell her, it wasn't my place.
Good.
She'll find out eventually, she should
hear it from him.
We shouldn't get involved.
But illicit admission...
Should we investigate it since there are
witness testimonies and the pictures?
It wasn't reported to us directly.
The vice principal earlier...
I think he'll agree to report it
if we talked to him.
It's a very well-managed foundation.
It's hard to investigate, only a few
probably know about such a list.
If the vice principal had a conclusive
evidence,
they wouldn't have fired him.
Hello.
Hey there, nice to see you again!
You came for the trial?
Yes, after you guys came,
I've been curious about how it was going.
You must be disappointed.
We couldn't figure anything out.
But more than that...
Seo-yeon.
You know that male student I said
I saw in the phone booth?
Why is he here?
What?
Him, right there!
You must be mistaken.
No.
He saw me just now and
greeted me.
He thanked me for worrying about him then.
Is that really true?
Yes, it's true.
Hey there, are you OK?
Hey!
It was him alright.
The one you were looking for!
The one in the phone booth!
Seo-yeon, come! We need to discuss
what to do.
We've been waiting for you.
That was the last witness Prosecutor
submitted.
Now what do we do?
Well, we'll be expelled tomorrow.
- We better stop the trial.
- So just end it here?
Should I tell the jury to start
deliberation?
No.
I found him.
The male student from that night.
I'll put him on the stand.
I want to hear everything that was
hidden from us so far.
I have to know why.
He's our last witness.
One more day.
Just give me one more day.
So I can prepare for the next trial
session.
I just need one more day, today.
I feel so drained today.
The prosecutors seem down, too.
It'd be weird if you were actually
happy as usual.
Is that right?
Well, that's a good thing for me.
I'll get going first.
Do well tomorrow!
See ya.
Wait for me, we're on the same bus!
Bye!
Joon-young!
Thank you.
This is nothing, I'm your dad!
Joon-young.
Won't you come home now?
I...
- I'm still...
- It's OK.
Mom's not home.
We decided to spend some time
apart from each other.
We need to think about if we can continue
living this way.
She agreed to it, too.
After your brother died that way,
it was hard for me to see her
being sick, too.
I wasn't living each day, I was just
persevering.
It's not that it justifies my leaving
you alone that way.
I'm really sorry.
I didn't know you were having that hard
of a time, to think such thoughts.
I'm sorry.
But for me...
I want to start up our family
all over again.
I want to go back to the time
that we were all OK, just as your
brother remembered.
Can we try it?
Dad...
Did you know Lee So-woo?
No.
Prosecutor is imagining things.
Someone had called So-woo from
pay phones.
- Five times.
- So?
Did you find out?
Yes?
What's happened? Is something wrong?
Yoo-jin.
Unfair admission...
It's true.
My dad and the principal are friends.
They paid money so I can be in this school.
Lee Yoo-jin, why are you telling us this?
I saw the list earlier, your birthday was
there!
I was going to just forget it,
why did you bring it up?
Soo-hee...
Just forget it.
This never happened.
Let's just say that you got lucky in
the admission exam,
and you're just not so good in school.
I don't know any of this, and you
don't know either.
How can we pretend not to know?
It hurt other students.
Someone must've not made the cutoff
because of me.
A student who deserved to be admitted.
I pushed that person aside and I got myself
in, though I'm wasn't qualified.
I'm stupid!
And I don't even put in the effort!
But I'm the same Jeong-guk student as you
are, because my family is rich!
I feel so ashamed and I feel so bad
for them.
How can I just ignored it?
You're such a fool!
Did you ask to come to this school?
Your parents did that behind your back!
How can that be your fault?
Why should you feel bad and ashamed?
I'll go and testify tomorrow.
I'll admit that it's true.
I'll testify that I was admitted that way.
I'll say it all.
Yoo-jin.
No one can deny it if I admit it.
It needs to be exposed so a case like mine
can never happen again.
That's how people who were responsible
will no longer be there.
Isn't that right?
I'm sorry I'm late.
I needed some time to think.
I...
Was even more late than you.
Seo-yeon!
Seo-yeon, you'll be home all day
from starting tomorrow?
You're lucky!
I want to be expelled, too!
She's about to be expelled,
not quite yet!
If you're jealous, then you should
just get in trouble, too!
Mom! They should be in trouble!
They're speaking nonsense!
Hey guys!
You all need to wash up!
Otherwise we have to go to the dentist
again!
Make sure you're completely clean!
I'll see you.
You'll do great!
(The last day of trial)
(Notice: The students involved in the
trial club are suspended for 6 days)
Hello.
I am Kim Min-seok, and I'll be the
presiding judge of this trial.
Thank you for attending this school trial.
Please be seated.
Today's the last day of this trial.
After the last witness testimony, each side
will give their final argument.
And when the jury goes into deliberation,
there will be no more school trial.
We'll begin the examination.
- Witness...
- But first!
I have something to tell you.
The person I am about to examine is
not a witness.
He is the new defendant of this trial.
The defendant is a party directly involved
in this case, though he has been in hiding.
But he mustered up a great amount
of courage to be here today.
Until the defendant is done
with the examination process,
I ask that you'd watch in silence without
any remarks.
Defense Counsel, Han Ji-hoon.
Please sit in the defendant's seat.
- Ji-hoon!
- Seo-yeon! What are you doing?
Why does he need to sit there?
I'll ask you directly.
On the night that Lee So-woo died...
Where were you and what were you doing?
I was with So-woo on top of the school
building.
What should you be charged with?
The murder of Lee So-woo.
(Solomon's Perjury)
(Strong Woman, Doh Bong-soon,
Coming February 24th)