LordSadler
lordsadler2012@gmail.com
[ Car Horn Honking]
[TV: Static,
Indians Whooping]
[ Water Bottle
Bounces On Ground]
[Whooping
Continues]
[Gunshots, Ricochets]
[Door Creaking]
[ Door Creaks, Closes ]
[ Dog Growls,
Barks ]
[Growling Continues]
[Quietly] Candy? [Sniffing]
Shit.
There goes
my goddamn dinner.
You couldn't pull that job off last night;
how you gonna do this one in broad daylight?
Last night they had a clog. Today I
got you. What is wrong with you?
I don't want to do this.
There's a cop over there.
- That ark? 1:' no cop!
- How do you know?
He don't piss like no cop. What
are you worried about, man?
Just keep your nerve,
that's all you gotta do.
Trust me,
and you won't go wrong.
Come on. Come on back.
Come on, come on, come on.
To your lefi' a little bit.
Come on back.
ldon 't think I can do it. Man,
don't tell me that stuff now, man.
-just hang in there. Don't lose your
cool, okay? - Come on back. Come on. Ho!
[Crash]
How's that?
Don't worry about nothin'.
I got the tape readouts.
We got it made. just put
on the cap and thejacket.
[Mumbles] Come on, man,
they're getting suspicious.
Slide over here.
Come on, hurry up!
This guy's a real meatball, man.
Hurry up, man.
I'm talkin' about El Tubbo. You
know what I mean? Okay, hurry up.
What's the matter?
Keep your cool.
Hey, 2O bucks tip if you get me out
of here in 3O minutes, all right?
Hey! What's happenin', brother?
Hey. I ain't your brother.
Right.
You ain't my brother.
What is you, my mother?
[ Laughs]
East, uh, Philly store.
All right, come on.
...requested for
next year's program.
The spokesman went on to say that
aspects of last year's program...
are still under
investigation.
And on the subject
of funding,
we now go to our reporter
Inez Pedroza in the field...
where she has this rather shocking story
about a children's home about to close.
The Claremont Children's Home
on South Street...
was closed today after 38 years
of continuous operation...
because of drastic budgetary cuts
in the city's welfare department.
Now, so far all of the
children have been relocated,
with the exception of eight in the
home's special education unit.
Watch howl handle this.
Hey, blood, what's happenin'?
My man!
Outta sight. Good to see you, man.
How's it goin', man?
Lookin' good. Good. Hey,
East Philly store, huh?
Yep. Check it out.
75 Hitachis?
Man, that's more than we did all last
quarter. We're kickin' ass, man.
I'll bet you are. Want
me to run that through?
Uh, no, I'll handle my main man right here.
Thank you, I appreciate that.
Everybody wants something
Japanese nowadays, man.
Cars, radios, they're even
eatin' Japanese food.
You know, raw fish, shit like that.
Tastes worse than chitlins.
Uh, this number doesn't compute.
Doesn't compute?
- [Bangs On Monitor] Try it now.
- I Typing]
- Now itsjammed. jammed? Damn. It's
gonna take them a week to fix this.
I mean, a black man can't stand a week off.
You know what I mean?
You gotta help me out. I
don't wanna hold you up.
Luke, give him
whatever he needs.
Whool You 're all right, brother.
I mean that You got soul.
Outta sight.
All right, soul man.
Here, have a cigar.
Thanks, man.
- Nice man. I'd like to introduce you
to my sister. - Love to meet her.
- You disco?
- You kiddin'?
Get down! All right.
She'd love that. Later.
What kind of problems
are we talking about?
The children in the special
unit have very unique problems.
There's blindness, lameness,
pyromania,
learning disabilities.
One of them--
One of them was even forced
into prostitution in Vietnam...
at the age of nine.
Fifteen minutes! Big tip! All
right, come on. Get 'em on.
Know your job!
You got to know your job!
[ Laughs]
Marvin! What the hell
are you doin', man?
Let'; get the hel/ outta here!
Take it easy, man. Be cool.
This is a score of a lifetime! We gonna
get five, ten thousand apiece, baby!
You mean five to ten
in the pen. Let's go!
just take it easy. You know
how to move and haul, right?
Well,just get ready to move and
haul our asses outta here.
Here you go, my man.
[Chuckling]
No hard feelings,
right?
Right.
All right, let's move it!
Load that big-screen TV!
[Exhales]
Now this bimbo wants the ?oor demo
out there. So what's the problem?
Give him whatever the East Philly
store needs. just mark it down.
- At least check the registration to that
truck out there. - Truck registration?
Wait a minute! Do I have to take this
kind of abuse, man, because I'm black?
'Cause I bet you don't torture the
white people that come in here!
Hey! I'll bet he don't torture the white
people that come in here. Do you? No!
We don't see te/e vision anymore!
O-O-Okay,just calm down.
We're having a sale down at the East
Philly store-- a “Before The Riot“ sale.
Black people gettin C2 chance to buya
television for the first time since the '60s,
and this guy
wanna mess it up!
Well, I'm movin' this! If you wanna
help me, you help me! [Manager] Okay--
Get outta my way, man! I'm mad!
See what you r1701 man?
Now give me a hand with this. You've embarrassed
me enough. Are you gonna fall for that?
[Truck Engine Starts]
- [Tires Screech]
- [Glass Shatters]
Marvin', no!
What are you- Shit!
Jesus! lvl__
What? What-- What you
gonna-- Wha-- Wha--
Huh? Wha- Whafre you--
Huh? What? What it is!
What it looks like! No, no, no, baby!
What you gonna do?
- I'm gonna knock you out! - Well,
shoot your best shot, baby!
[ Door Buzzer]
Hey, ifit isn't
Miss TV Personality of 1981.
Bad choice.
Come on, let's go. I'm not going with you
this evening; I'm staying with the children.
Vivian, don't you think you're carrying
this thing just a little too far?
What are you gonna do
with eight kids?
Well, I am planning to
take them to my aunt's farm...
just outside of Seattle for
starters; that'll give them a home.
Do you really thinkyou're going to get
permission to take these kids out of state?
Come on, Donald, nobody cares about those
children. They won't even know they're gone.
Besides, uh, I--
I already have permission.
Why don't you give this up? I thought you would
be willing to help me with these children.
How am I gonna help you get eight
children 3,000 miles across the country?
No.
Charter a jet?
But you can get me a driver to drive
that old bus we have in the back.
Th-That wreck?
Well, yeah.
Vivian, get serious.
Sweetheart. Oh, Donald.
I've never been more serious
in my life.
I need your support more than ever before,
darling. Please, you've got to help me.
Mr. Braxton,
in my 30 years on the bench,
I have never seen a criminal record
equal in intensity, length...
and downright antisocial
uselessness as your own.
“The sale of counterfeit
bus passes at the age of five;
“conspiracy to impersonate
a truant officer;
Oh, thatihar-
“a dishonorable discharge...
“from the Army motor pool;
'profitee?ng on Christmas
Seals-- Can I see that?
Defrauding
a chicken franchise“?
Oh, I can explain that--
Braxton,
you have already spent three years
in a home forjuvenile offenders,
six years in state prison,
and four years on probation under the
guidance of that... gentleman over there.
Now, before f pass sentence,
do you have anything
to say for yourself?
Uh-- [Clears Throat] [
Feedback, Thumping]
-;;[Whistles]
- It's on, it's on!
Your Honor, I'd like
to make a confession.
- I did it on purpose! I wanted to
go back to prison. - You-- You what?
I mean,
doesn't it make sense?
Anybody that'd hold up a store in
broad daylight, stay 45 minutes,
- must wanna go back to prison. - Braxton,
you are talking about five to ten years.
I know that, Your Honor, but I
want you to give me 2O years!
I gotta have 2O years! I cant go
back on parole, not with that man!
The man's a racist!
He's an animal, Your Honor.
I mean, he looks black, right, but he ain't
black. He's as white as you are! No offense.
I'm telling you, he treats
black people like dog poo!
Yeah! Fouryears I've been
on parole in his hell!
It's worse than being in the Ku
Klux Klan, being under that man!
Your Honor, you gotta help me!
You can't allow me--
The prisoner will come to order!
Please send me back to prison!
Three meals a day! And let me sleep
and rest and get my hair done!
Let go of me! What do
you mean, “let go“?
Ten years probation! Case closed!
No! Not probation!
Oh, no! [Whimpering] Get that
man out of my courtroom!
- I'll get you for this, you dirty rat!
- Get him out of my courtroom!
I'll get you for this!
[Sobbing]
Please!
Viva America! [judge]
Get that man!
God bless the queen!
Get hr??? out!
No--
Whew! Great show, Braxton.
[Grunts, Panting] One
hell of a performance.
Well, you know,
Yeah.
Us actors must do what we do.
You can pull that stuff
on Runzuli,
but it don't go down
too well with me.
So, I will see to it that
you do that five-to-ten...
unless you do a little acting for me.
What are you talkin' about?
You understand?
Yeah, yeah. What--
Okay, now, you listen carefully and I'll explain
to you exactly the role you're going to play.
[Laughing]
Well,
is it gonna make it?
[jog Groaning] 0h, G00'!
Well,joe, how's it look?
It's a piece of shit!
[Laughing]
Everything's rotted away, man; it ain't
gonna make it out of the garage.
Unless you know somebody from
Mario Andretti's pit crew.
We can get it
to thejunkyard.
We have until Friday.
[Chuckles]
Didn't you hear what I said? Yes, I heard,
but everything has been arranged for Friday.
I have money set aside in case you need
anything, and I'll give you my business--
Something wrong, Mr. Braxton?
No. I thought you said--
Hey!
Uh-- Yeah.
Uh, sweetheart, th-this
man is an expert.
Now, if he says it's not possible,
it's just not possible.
Donald, I thought you were going to get
me someone to drive us to Washington.
I 0ok, sweetheart-- Don't tell me whats
possible and whats not possible.
Vivian,just-- Get your
expert to fix the bus!
Vivian, let me explain to you what?
going on! I'm serious, Donald.
He )4 /00/<, f got a job x}? tervfew
to go to, I am serious, Donald!
and I know this is personal-- Y'all look
real nice together-- but I gotta split.
- Hey, Braxton, you trying to make me
look bad? - I ain't tryin' to do nothin'.
I told you to tell her-- You told
me to tell her the bus don't work!
Donald!
What's going on here?
Askyour old man.
You know something, Braxton?
Uh-uh.
I'm gonna burn your butt.
You are?
You're gonna burn that checkup on me, 'cause I
ain't going back to the joint for you or nobody.
I took care of that, man. You
take care of your business.
I'll see you Friday.
Fix your hanky there.
Miss Lady, nice meeting you.
Braxton. Braxton!
Donald! Let me just try to
explain to you what's going on.
Oh, never mind! Look, I'm
trying my best to help you!
This scheme is impossible! it's not
gonna work! There's just no way!
[ Typewriters Clacking]
Hey, man, I wanna
talk to you later.
Hold it,joe. You know darn well you
don't have an appointment for today.
Who needs an appointment?
Goddamn! Whoo!
I'm not going through that. Go
through that one time with me.
You disrupted the place last time; you're
not going to put me through that today.
Baby, you do it! jump back!
Oww! Mr. Kinsey.
James Brown! Get down, boogie!
Joe Braxton is here again.
[On Intercom] Well, send him fight in,
Miss Thomas. I've been expecting him.
James Brown! Oww! Oww!
Go on in now.
Shit! Boy, if I had
some gravy, I'd sop you!
Goddamn!
[ Knocking]
- Hey, come on. You ain't mad, are
ya, brother? - [ Both Laughing]
Ain't no hard feelings
on my part, you know.
[Laughing
Continues]
Did I get you good, or did
I get you good? Whoa.
You're funny, man. I never knew you
had a sense of humor, you know that?
Miss Thomas, would you get
me the 35thjudicial Court.
Judge Antonio...
- Runzuli? - Donald, what the fuck
you cloin'? That man don't play.
I didn't like that little game you played
on me, and this is the paybaclgjoe.
Hey, man, I was havin' fun
with you. I thought you--
It was fun. Ha ha!
You know, like, a joke!
Hey, look,
I'll tel! you what.
I mean, I'll, uh, wash your car
and, you know, clean your house.
I don't give a fuck--
pet your cat.
But you can't ask me to fix a bus and go
to Washington with a bunch of funky kids!
Look, let's
turn it aroundJoe.
Let's look at it from the other direction;
now, what would you do in my position?
If I was in your position, man, I'd
give me a break! Give you a break.
[ Chuckling]
Yeah.
Tell you what I'm gonna do-- As a matter of
fact, I'll tell you what you're gonna do.
- Okay.
- You're gonna fix that bus,
Yeah. you're going to take Miss Perry and
those kids all the way to Washington,
- and you're gonna be on your best behavior.
You got that? - All the way. I got it, man.
And if you
screw this one up,
it's your ass.
Okay. I know--
I know what you want.
I'm gonna take care of it.
[Backfiring,
Gears Grinding]
[ Backfiring Continues]
All right, children, here's our bus.
[L oud Backfire]
Look at that! Yuck! lfit makes
it outta Philly, I'll faint.
Where's the observation deck?
I'm takin' my tape deck.
What a crate!
[Kids Chattering]
Remember
our point system now.
I want you to get 39's and 40's
all the way to Washington.
[Kids Together]
Yes, Miss Perry!
This is Mr. Braxton, and I want
you all to get in a line...
and introduce yourselves
as you board the bus, quietly.
[Door Buzzer]
Samantha, I want you to be
in charge for the moment.
Lead them all on the bus
for me, please. Excuse me.
[Boy] Is he the driver or the porter?
I oaks like the janitor to me.
Definite schizoid personality
with homosexual tendencies.
Get on the bus.
You didn't tell me you were gonna come
see me off. I don't tell you everything.
Miss Linda. I'm the lady on this trip,
and I'm gonna be a great actress.
Get on the bus! My daddy
used to have a bus!
I don't care what your daddy does!
ldon 't wanna hear it!
Get on the bus. [Linda] We went all
around the world. You shut up!
Hey, brother! What the hell's
the matter with you, man?
[ Boy] He's blind, stupid!
Help him on!
Why don't you zip his
pants up if he's blind?
Get outta my seat! I can drive!
Tell him, everybody!
Harold loves to drive! He's always driving!
I don 't care!
Drive your ass to the back of the bus.
Do that! Hey!
You leave Harold alone!
He's our pal!
How come you ain't takin' me fishing?
What? Take you where?
You promised
to take me fishing!
[Boy] Before this trip is over,
I'm gonna ha ve to kick your ass!
You couldn't kickyour-
[Muf?ed] grandma's--
I can kickyours right now! Get on the bus.
On the bus, please.
Get on the bus,
and watch your language!
Hey.
Hell of a group, man.
Here's
your travel permit...
and your return bus ticket back to Philly.
Bus ticket? Thanks so much.
Behave yourselves.
Fifteen days, Braxton.
You got that?
Yes, sir. You got fifteen
days to get back here.
And Miss Perry
is a lady.
[Spits] Anybody can
see that, boss.
[Girl] You still got
lastyeark dirt wrinkles on.
Did your mother ever tell you
to take a shower? [Squirts]
Hi, sailor. My name's Annie.
What's yours?
My name's j oe. Excuse me.
Up the stairs.
Let's get in.
Come on.
[ Vivian] Aii right, children--
[ Continues, indistinct]
Fifteen days.
[Hits Bus] You're
all heart, Chief.
Hey, mama, grab hold of this. Make
yourself useful. [Vivian Coughing]
There'll be no smoking on this bus, Mr.
Braxton.
Hey, no, no. No good.
Wait a minute.
You don't
throw out my cigars.
I drive the bus and work on the bus, but
I smoke when I want to. Understand?
I don't feel like smokin' right now.
[Grinds Butt Out]
Take care of yourself,
homes.
You all right.
Bus. Fifteen days.
Miss Perry?
Yes. What?
Oh, Donald.
Thank you.
[ Engine Cranks,
Starts]
[Engine Backfires]
[ Loud Backfire]
[Screams]
[ Backfires]
[Girl Screams]
[ Kids Arguing]
Get off of me!
Make me.
Get 026'? Martin! Martin!
Stop that, please!
Go sit in the back.
Ernesto, move over there.
Quickly!
Now, listen, children, this is going to be
an extremely difficult trip for all of us,
and it is not an excuse to get
out of doing your schoolwork.
Get your workbooks out,
please.
Miss Perry,
mine fell out the window.
So did mine, Miss Perry.
Hey, let me drive. Get your hand off
the wheel beforel tell Miss Perry!
I can drive!
You can't do nothin'!
This is a hijack!
What?
Hijack, bro. I don't give a
damn what it is. Hijack off!
I can drive! I'm serious!
Back of the bus!
Where you keep
your money, chump?
Yeah! I keep my m--
Damn,you thief.
Convict.
Yeah?
You the bad one in the group, huh?
Yeah, that's right.
I can kick ass
when I have to,
and I can see now you and me is
gonna get it on yet! Mm-hmm.
I can kick ass too. You know what
I was in prison for? [All ] What?
Murder.
Get your ass to the
back, You're crazy!
Or I'll stickyou
in your ass!
Stole my wallet.
Martin, you'll share a room
with Ernesto and Tony.
Annie-- I wanna room withjoe.
Annie, you and the girls
will room with me.
All right, uh,
Harold and, uh,julio--
I ain't staying in a room with julio;
he always makes me bump into furniture!
If you could see, you wouldn't
bump into any furniture!
I can see! I just can't see furniture!
I don'! wanna sleep with Linda,
'cause she snores and keeps
me and Dakota awake!
At least I don't
talk in my sleep!
Hey! Uh, I'd like-- Ho! My
key, please, Miss Perry!
I'd like to go to my room. I'd like to--
You know what I mean? [Kids Laughing]
That's enough.
I want you all to go to the
bus and get your things.
And I want you all
to behave like young adults.
You behave any differently, I'll
be very disappointed in you.
[ Cheering, Screaming ]
Uh, Miss Perry, what time are
we leaving in the morning?
Can I have the key
to my room, please?
There are no more rooms available
in the motel, Mr. Braxton.
You'll have to sleep
in the back of the bus.
Wait a minute.
You gotta bejoking.
I'm sure you'll be
quite comfortable.
But there's no shower; there's no
bed; there's no TV on the bus.
Mr. Braxton, I think it would be marvelous
if you read a book for a change.
“Marvelous,“ my ass. I ain't
sleeping on no goddamn bus!
- What did you say? - I am
not sleepin' on no goddamn--
bus.
I'm not sleepin'
on no bus!
F am not sleepin'
[Snoring]
[ Banging On Bus]
[ Vivian] Mr. Braxton!
[ Banging Continues]
Mr. Braxton, wake up!
Mr. Braxton'.
[ Snoring Continues]
[Grunts]
Mr. Braxton!
[Fabric Tearing]
[Head Bangs On Wall]
Holy-- Mr. Braxton, why are
you sleeping on the ?oor?
[ Muttering] I put it over the pillow...
Isn't the back seat big enough?
And I couldn't-- Listen, never mind.
Listen, we're in trouble.
Three of the boys havejust run off!
Great!
Maybe the rest of them will run away!
No, you don't understand.
I need you to get up and come look for
them for me. I ain't no truant officer!
I ain't goin' chasin' no damn kids!
I drive the bus! What did you say?
I said, lam no truant
officer, I drive the bus!
You wouldn't do a damn thing to help those
children, would you? You're swearing!
Never mind! Nobody! Nobody but your
little old, pathetic, selfish self!
My little old, pathetic, selfish self
deserves three hours' sleep tonight,
and, damn it, I'm gonna get it!
All right, I'll go look for them.
Good idea. But may
I impose on you...
tojust keep an eye on those children in
number five while I look for these boys?
No, no, no, no. I'm no baby-sitter.
I drive the bus.
Would you like me to call Mr.
Kinsey, Mr. Braxton?
What room are they in?
Number five!
Number five. Right.
Number five.
Mr. Braxton. Yes, ma'am.
Now. Number five.
Number five.
[ Banging On Bus]
Ohh!
Linda's got the bathroom locked,
and Dakota has to go pee!
Yeah. Right.
Mr. Braxton, wake up!
Take her to the bathroom
in the woods!
Bears pee in the woods.
I ain't gain' in the woods!
There's snakes in the woods!
Good.
That's wonderful.
[Banging Continues]
What?
Dakota has to go pee!
Let the bear pee in your pocket!
Leave me alone!
[ Banging]
Okay. okay!
You, me and Dakota,
we go pee.
G," [ Rhythm And Blues]
Hurry up'.!
Don't wake me up no more. You understand?
[Kids Yelling]
What the hell's
goin' on?
[ Yelling Continues] Stop!
Stop it, Linda!
- No! No! No! -You've got to let
her in that bathroom sometime!
- Well, I'm not gonna--
- Hey, fool!
What's the matter
with you, man? Hey!
He loves to play with matches! He burned
his house, his mother and the family car!
- No, I didn't!
- Yes,you did!
Sit down, man!
[Screams]
[ Electricity Crackles] Hey! What the
hell's the matter with you guys?
You tryin' to kill yourself?
Get back! Pull that out!
You guys
want something to do?
Okay, I got something
for you to do.
[ Girls Together]
Wow!
[Samantha] Where 'd
you learn to do that?
Huh?
Now we gonna play
a grown-up game.
- Can I light it?
- No, you cannot light it.
We're gonna play
strip poker.
I'm not. What? Hey,
that's my favorite.
- Mine too. - We get to
keep the clothes, right?
Oh, yes. Winners keepers, losers weepers.
A/lr/ghzfi/
- This is serious business. We
gonna get down, jack! - Uh-oh.
Straight. Straight!
To the left. To the left!
Now spin it to the right!
Al! right, stop. Straight.
To the left! To the left! Stop! Stop!
Stop! I'm a mean driver!
J.“ I P0P]
[ Boys Continue Yelling]
Spin it to the right! All
right, stop it! Straight!
You got it! Stop-- All right.
Let's go. I can
drive, Miss Perry!
I said, let's go, Harold! Really!
Watch! I'm winning!
What is the big idea?
[joe ] Gimme m y pants! You don't
gimme m y pants, I'm killing Dakota!
Children, gimme-- [Kids
Yelling, Mufiled]
- Mr. Braxton!
- Aah!
What do you thinkyou're doing? Where are
the children? What's going on here?
They were--
There they are.
Why are they in the closet?
Wejust-
- And why are you half-dressed in here?
- It's, uh, Halloween?
[Yelling, Laughing]
Let's have some french fries.
French fries? I love them!
I know! They're greasy, just like
meatballs! [Yelling, Laughing Continue]
[ Vivian ]
Donald. No--
No. I am not
coming back, Donald.
I don't care if you call
out the SWAT team--
Operator, yes, just a moment, please.
just a moment.
Fifty-- There.
Yes, hello?
Hello, Donald?
I'm not being unreasonable.
Donald, I have made a commitment to
these children which I intend to keep.
He's lying!
Donald,
he is lying! He--
He's a liar! Go away, please.
Please, go away.
He's a liar! He's a
self-righteous, pompous liar!
G-Go.
I don'! care what he does.
Miss- Miss Perry.
- Go away, please.
- The kid? ha viz? 2a barbecue.
Miss Perry! Miss Perry! Uh--
Ohh!
Anthony, what the hell's wrong?
What are you, damn crazy?
- Jesus Christlje-
- No! No!
- [jog Anthony Yelling]
- [joe ] Get away from here! Get away!
- Don't hurt him! Anthony!
- No! No! No! Help!
' Oh! A
" No! nthonhf!
' Sto -
“ Ne? It! Stop it!
[Screaming Continues]
Don't anybody move.
- What the helVs goin' on? - [ Vivian] It's
onlya child that's a little disturbed.
It's only a child. He's a little disturbed.
[ Screaming Continues]
Anthony! It's all right.
It's all right!
It'; all right. It'; all right.
[ Anthony Screaming, Crying]
ifs all right. Calm down.
Who's gonna pay for this?
[ Vivian] Please calm down.
Everything's fine.
Miss Perry! [ Vivian
Continues, lnziistinct]
Here's $20.
That'll cover any damage.
That's about a dollar's worth of hay.
Please gimme a break, will ya?
She's burning! No, no, Anthony.
Listen.
She's burning! You mustn't
think that-- She's all right.
She's burning. She's all right.
Please believe me.
She was on fire. No, she wasn't.
She wasn't.
She--
Um, I, uh,
I paid this guy.
I don't know what's happenin'.
I didn't mean to--
I didn't hurt him. I just
threw him back, ma'am.
I'm sorry. I don't know
what's goin' on, okay?
It's a fire. He's a-- He's-- I never
seen that. [ Anthony Meaning]
She burned up! It's all right, Anthony.
Come on.
She's all right.
She's burned up!
Shit.
She's all right.
Joe.
What?
Stop the bus. Dakota has
to go to the bathroom.
Dakota don't need to go to no bathroom.
Don't you like her?
I don't like Dakota or her mama.
She likes you.
She does?
Stop the bus!
I don't wanna stop the bus!
I want you to stop the bus!
Shut up! Oh, gee, why don't you
stop the bus? Stop the bus!
Damn! There's two bathrooms.
You're gonna stand in line?
Why don't you use the other bathroom?
Somethin' wrong with you?
[Kids Talking, Laughing]
[Joe Mumbling]
[Annie] Miss Perry, what's
the farm gonna be like?
Well, I haven't been there
in a long time, Annie,
but I'll tell you, I spent the
best days of my life there.
Is there fish in the lakes? Well,
there were a lot offish then.
I don't know if there are anymore, but my
dad and I used to go fishing all the time,
and I didn't catch one fish;
he caught all the fish.
I never been fishing in my
life; Joe's gonna take me.
Can Dakota climb trees?
Come on.
Samantha, did you ever
climb a tree? No.
You never climbed a tree? I used to climb
a tree a lot. I was a little tomboy.
- I fell out once. Look what
happened to me. Ohh, boy. - Ooooh!
I cried like a baby. I'll tell you
one thing, my mother surprised me.
Instead of a beating, she ga
ve me a big hug and a kiss...
and a huge slice of blackberry pie.
[Laughs]
That took care
of the crying.
Do I cry.
[ Thunderclap]
[Kids Together] It was a
dark and storm y night.
Two men
were sitting in a graveyard.
- One wanted to--
- [Samantha] No! No! Giants!
Two giants were walking--
Ho, ho, ho!
[Banging On Bus Floor]
Shit! Damn kids!
[ Banging Continues]
[ Thunderclap] [ Harold]
I at'; do it again!
[Kids Together] It was a
dark and storm y night.
Two men were sitting
in a gra veyara'.
One wanted to tell a story,
and this is the story he told.
[ Banging, Screaming]
[Banging,
Screaming Continue]
- Hold it!
- [Whistle Blows]
[Screaming Dies Down]
Listen to me.
I'm gonna take that whistle
and stick it up your ass...
if you don't shut up
when I turn around!
I mean it! I'm finished!
I gotta drive this bus!
Now, shut up!
[ Engine Starts,
Gears Grind]
[ Engine Revs]
[ Gears Grinding]
[Kids Yelling]
We're stuck!
[Yelling Continues]
[ Vivian]
Stop it! Calm down!
We're stuck and we're in trouble.
We have to try to help Mr. Braxton.
What can I do? I'm going
to, um, go out...
and, um, I want you
to sit here,
and when I say “Kick it
over,“ you turn it on...
and put it in gear, and I'm gonna try
to put something under the tire...
and we'll get it to movin'.
Okay? All right.
And we'll be out of here
in no time.
[Chuckles]
No problem.
Move your foot
out of the way.
Get 'em out of the way! [ Vivian] Children,
let'; try to keep ourselves together.
I'm not playin'!
[Kids Giggling, Laughing]
Shut up!
[Laughing Continues]
Jesus!
- [ Grunting]
- Look atjoe! Look at that!
[Laughing Continues]
I'm gonna kill 'em.
[Engine Starts]
He]!
Stop!
[ Samantha]
He looks like Godzilla!
The Creature 290m the Black Lagoon!
[ Laughing Continues]
[ Engine Re wing]
[ Gears Grinding]
I'm sorry, Mr.-
Ahh.
It's okay. I'm awfully sorry.
I tried to--
to get the--
the bus going.
What did you--
]ust-- Well, here.
I mean, I really-- No, listen to me.
Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho.
Is it out of gear?
Is the bus outta--
Yes, I think it is.
Uh, I saw a farm
back there.
You 're a mess! I'm sorry--
Can I ask you a question?
just try to clean yourself up a bit,
will you? Oh, I certainly will.
If I see a toilet, I could use it.
Here.
No, no, no, no.
Oh, more. Thank you.
Uh, don't shift nothing.
Don't do anything.
Just leave it like it is, because
it's straight now, Yes, I will. Yes.
And we... wanna keep it... that way.
Okay? Right. Right.
Please hurry back,
Mr. Braxton.
[ Thunderclap]
Get back, children.
Get back inside.
Joe Braxton's my name,
and woodsman's my game.
Fuck with me.
The bitch send me to get a
motherfuckin' piece of push!
Well, I don't take
no shit from nobody!
I'm Mrs. Braxton's
favorite son!joe, baby!
Joe-Motherfucki W-Braxton.
Try me one time, you understand.
Get me workin' on the motherf-
Bitch gonna
have to be saved.
Shit.
“And so Sir Gawaine
and the Green Knight...
“crossed the mountains at night,
torches lighting theirway,
“paying no heed
to Lancelot's warning...
that the forests were filled
with frightening white ghosts.“
Miss Perry!
- [ju/io] What'; that?
- Fire.
- Who are they? - Miss Perry, take it easy.
It's all right.
Everything's all right!
Take it easy! Please be--
[ Tony]
Fire!
Well, you weren't lying, were you, boy?
You got a bunch of kids here.
- What are we gonna do with you, boy?
- Is that you,joe?
- What are you doing? - He's blind!
He's blind! All the kids are blind!
All of them! I'm taking
them to the hospital.
I'm just tryin' to take them to the
hospital. They need an operation.
I Joe 1 Look, can I talk to you?
They're very sensitive.
Listen,
they're all blind.
You're kiddin'. No, all of them.
All of them.
Oh, that's terrible.
Except for her.
We're going to the Ray Charles Institute for the
Blind; they're gonna have miracle operations.
You saw it on Oral Roberts. They
probably ran it here. It was on TV.
Get up behind the wheel. We'll help push
you out. You're a wonderful human being.
Ohh.
And a great American.
[Groans]
[Klan L eader] You guys,
get behind the bus!
- Let's go, boys!
- [ Engine Starts]
Come on, let'; go! Boys, come on,
let'; get these people out of here.
All right.
hit it up there!
There's children in that bus,
boys! Let's go!
- [ Grunting, Shouting]
- [ Engine Re wing]
- Heave!
-[Gears Grind]
Heave! Heave!
[Grunting, Yelling]
[ Laughing, Yelling ]
[Laughing,
Yelling Continues]
[Klansmen Shouting]
[Kids Laughing, Yelling]
Shee-it!
Boys,
I don't think we should...
tell anybody about this.
G; [ Slow-Tempo Pop]
,' just when I needed you,'
g You had your arms g
g Around my life g
# You understood;
g Said you could g
# I never dreamed #
# You would #
,' Be there when I needed you,'
; You were the only
land in sight g
# You seemed to be #
# All I need #
g Somebody sent me you g
I' And I #?
g Somebody somewhere g
g Heard me cry,“
g Somebody gave me you g
LordSadler
lordsadler2012@gmail.com
Hey, look at that!
Fishing!
- [Kids Chatter/mg]
- Hey,joe, you promised to take me fishing!
No, I didn't.
Yes,you did!
No, I didn't! I wish
you'd stop lyin', man!
Okay, I'm gonna
take you fishin'.
Really? Yeah! We goin' fishin'!
Hey! [Kids Yelling, Applauding]
- All right! - You cant do that;
we don't ha ve fishing equipment.
You're looking at a man who can
catch a whale with a toothpick.
You kiddin' me?
We're goin' fishin'.
[Samantha]
Ooh!
This is one of God's creatures, baby.
Nothin' to worry about.
They calledjoe “The Old Man and
the Sea“ back in Philly...
'cause I can handle it.
There.
[ Laughs]
Now I'm gonna show you suckers
what fishing's all about.
Yeah.
Don'! put your shadow
on the water there, son.
Now, I gotta bite.
Shh. Gonna see it!
Oh, shit! Damn. I saw it!
I saw it!
[Joe] I had a fish, now.
Come on.
It was right in there.
##C Humming jaws Theme]
Mr: Braxton!
Yeah.
[Kids Cheering]
[Joe Hooting]
Whoo! Look at that!
[Girls]
EWW!
I Joe 1
Samantha!
[Kids Screaming]
[Vivian] Get her!
Grab onto him!
Grab onto his shoulder!
Put your hand around her neck!
[ Kids] Come on!
[indistinct Screaming]
[ Screaming Continues]
[oe/joe/ I can't-- I can't swim!
Miss Perry! Miss Perry!
MY. Bvaxton'.!
Mr. Braxton, don't drown!
[Kids Yelling]
[ Yelling Continues] I can't swim!
I can't swim either!
- [Screaming]
- [ Gasping]
Wait.
Waita minute.
Stand up!
Stand up.
Ifs only four feet
of water.
You knew it all the time,
didn'tyou?
You'.
[ Kids Laughing]
- [ Laughing]
- You knew it, didn't you?
- [Joe Laughing]
- [ Kids Laughing]
You knew it was only four foot!
You wanted me to get in there!
[All Kids Laughing]
It's not funny!
[Laughing]
- [ Laughing]
yvbe/ieve,'
g Somebody sent me you g
I' And I #?
g Somebody somewhere g
g Heard me cry,“
g Somebody gave me you g
-“ When I;
g I needed you g
# Ohhh #
g Somebody sent me you g
,' You ,'
g Somebody somewhere g
g Sent me you g
g Say yeah g
g Somebody gave me you g
# Gave me what I needed #
g I needed you S.“
This is the way it's supposed to
be if you're trying to fix it.
See? Look. See, the hood's down.
It's gotta be like this.
This is prettier than that one. You've got to
put that one down so it looks a little better.
How am I gonna put it down if
I'm fixing the spark plugs?
Why don't you-- Take a hike!
You have to put it down.
I don't think he likes
your picture or you.
Joe?
What do you want now?
Whatever you want. joe
don't want nothin', okay?
Come on, I'm pretty.
Don't you like me,joe?
I like you a whole bunch. You're
real pretty. Now, leave me alone.
Then, you could take me
to your room and--
Don't do that. What the
hell's wrong with you, man?
You think you can say
anything to anybody? Nothing!
Don't you like me? Yeah, but don't
mean I want to go to bed with you!
Why not? You think everybody who
likes you goes to bed with you?
Yeah, they do. Well, that's sick!
Jesus Christ!
Most men always-- I don't
care about “most men“!
I'm not “most men“! You can like
people-- Don't have to make love to 'em!
Don'! you care nothin' about
yourself' I just thought that--
I don't care
what you thought!
But every other time...
when I ask somebody...
they all-- But--
Well, they're wrong!
It's wrong!
God.
[Crying]
Please-- Please don't tell
Miss Perry. She'll--
I'm not gonna tell nobody!
lust don't do it no more!
You 're a kia? man. Do
some thing with your life.
Look, you're an artist.
Do some art or something.
[Crying]
You're really good.
Y-Y-You could--
lfitwere smaller,
I'd put it in the bus
on the dashboard.
W-Would you really?
I really would.
I think
it's beautiful.
And I think you're beautiful.
[Sobbing]
Okay,
I'll make you one then.
Okay?
Okay
Ciao, Annie.
Ciao.
Oh,Jesus.
Joe, I--
I'm not a social worker.
I'm not!
I only wanted--
I just drive the bus!
[TV] Henderson to Bird. He shoots a
15-footjumper. [joe] F/y on, Biro'!
Don't stall! Pass it underneath, stupid!
A short rebound to Pa?sh.
Ah, shit! That ain't real. What wild
basketball' Rebounded to Maxwell.
He puts up a four-footer and scores against
the Lakers. Get down, come on, bro!
[joe Heating] Man, somebody
guard the white boy.
[ TV Continues]
Hey! Hold it!
Who is it?
It's Vivian.
Who?
Miss PerryJoe.
Lust a minute, please.
Let me fix it up
a little bit.
Hey, listen. I-l just stopped
by because I saw the light--
It's all right.
Don't worry.
L/kte/Ljoa it'; al/right. I'll talk to
you in the morning. N o, it's fi ne.
l__
[Clears Throat]
Hey, come on in.
[Coughs] Excuse me.
How ya doin'?
How areyou?
I'm good.
Yeah. You weren't at dinner.
I didn't expect you either.
Uh-- OW! Shit! What?
Uh-- Uh-- What are you-- Oh.
Hey.
[Chuckles] Don't set yourself
on fire, for God's sake.
No, ma'am, I'm sorry. I didn't want
to disrespect you with a cigar.
Oh. Thank you. Come on, sit down, please.
I was watchin' the game.
Who's winning? Uh, the
Celtics are kickin' ass.
Is that your team?
No, 76ers my team.
What's up?
L, uh--
I wanted you to know how much I appreciate
what you did this afternoon with Annie.
I really do. Oh, hey.
you know I wasn't--
Listen, it could have gone either way.
But I acted like an ass.
You handled it beautifully.
The kids love you and
you're doing a terrificjob.
I want you to know that.
Yeah, uh--
Thank you.
I ha ve to get back. Got a lot
of paperwork to do tonight.
Can I help?
Well,you might.
Hey, you wanna watch the game or somethin'?
I really can't,joe.
I've gotta get this
paper-- [Knocking]
Donald!
What are you doing here?
I'll be damned. [ Donald] 0/1, that?
good.
That's real good.
What are you doin' here?
What the hell's
goin' on, Braxton?
It ain't what you think
it is, man. We was--
I really don't appreciate your
asking that question, Donald.
- Vivian. - What are you doin', man?
The lady loves you, man.
Donald, man, come on. Come on.
Come on, Donald! Vivian!
Listen.
Jesus Christ.
Come on.
Hey, man, come on.
Hey!
Look,just go away.
Listen to me, okay?
Look, Braxton, you are
hangin' on by a thread!
[ Knocking,
Door Opens, Slams]
[ Donald] It is highly illegal.
It is against the law.
[ Vivian ] Don't tell me
about the law, Donald!
Falsifying records. Blackmailing an ex-con.
The issue is not arguable!
[ Snoring ]
[Knocking]
[ Vivian Whispering]
loe?
[ Knocking Continues]
[ Knocking]
K
H m m P neck/Hg]
[ G roa n s ]
[ Knocking Continues]
[ G roa n s ] Okay.
/oe. It'; Vivian.
Okay. Okay.
Joe, I'm sorry. Please, get
dressed quickly. [ Mumbling]
The children are already on the bus.
We're leaving now.
Please hurry. Put your
clothes on quickly!
Okay. Yes, ma'am.
Miss Perry?
Where are my clothes now?
[ Muttering]
Okay.
I'm gonna lose my job over this,
that's what's gonna happen.
I'm gonna lose
my goddamnjob.
[oe/ Kinsey'; on your tail'
Come on! Hurry up!
- Come on,joe! You can take him!
Come on,joe! - He's comin'!
You can take him! Oh, Miss Perry!
Harold. Harold.
He can take him! It's not a race.
It's not a game we're playing.
Mr. Braxton, please, pull over to the side.
He can take him.
[Door Buzzer]
Donald. Now, look, I have really had it.
I have really had it.
Donald! I want you and
these brats and Braxton...
to get back on that bus, turn this thing
around and let's go! You have got to stop--
Come on! I don't want to hear it!
lam not going back!
Miss Perry! Miss Perry!
Look, we're rolling!
[ Vivian, Donald Continue Arguing]
Miss Periy, the bus is moving!
Oh. my God!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop the bus!
[Vivian, Kids Screaming]
[Tires Screeching,
Joe Screaming]
Hurry UP!
[kidjHe/p us! [Joe]
Stop the bus!
[ Donald] One of the kids
driving that bus. Harold!
Harold? Which one is Harold?
Harold is the blind one.
- Holy shit! - I ain't goin'
back to Philly! I ain't goin'!
Reel me in!
Turn!
[joe Babbling, Screaming]
- [ Mumbling]
- Help me!
Come on!
-[Car Horn Blaring]
- [ Kids Chattering]
[ Tires Screeching]
[ Samantha Screaming]
We're gonna crash!
[Joe]
Oh, shit!
[Gasps]
[ Samantha]
Miss Perry, Miss Perry!
Miss Per/y 070' you see that?
Wait! Stop!
[Harold] I ain't goin'
back to Philly!
You don't own me!
I ain't goin'!
Please!
Please, don't!
[Vivian] It's all right.
It's all right.
Donald, please.
I'll handle him.
It's all right. He told
us he's gonna take us.
Harold, we'll work out something.
He told us!
I know he's gonna take us back!
Listen, Harold. Listen to me!
It'll be all right. We'll work
out something. No, it won't!
We'll work out something.
Please, calm down. He always--
Why do we gotta go back to Philadelphia?
'Cause we don't wanna go back.
They'll send us to Coolidge!
All the teachers there are mean.
No one likes us! We don't want to go back!
We don't want to.
Please, sir, don't let them
take me back to that place.
All right, children,
get on the bus.
No, Vivian.
No!
Don'! make me
do this.
No, Braxton.
Braxton, you get
the hell out here!
Damn it!
[Door Buzzer]
[Engine Starts]
Where your wallet at, man?
Wait a minute. Look, look, look.
Listen to this.
I tookyour wallet,
and I put it in Donald's pocket.
Now I've got his wallet, and I'm
giving it to you, man. Jesus Christ!
Look, if you get caught on the
highway, you'll be all right.
Hands on the car. Let me explain
it's not mine, will ya?
We've got a live one. Will ya
give me a chance to explain?
Says he's
a parole officer.
Hey, call in. Have 'em check
out ajoe Braxton, 456321.
Just stay right there.
You got it.
Yeah.
You got it
all byyourself.
[ Harold]
Told ya I could drive.
Truck coming at us!
Watch out! [ Laughing]
# Open your eyes
to your feelings #
-,'5h0wme that you care,'
- This is it, children!
gjust like the stars in
the heavens ,' Home'.!
[ Kids Cheering]
g Love is everywhere g
Look at that house! Oh!
I had forgotten how big it is!
[ Indistinct Chattering]
Oh, Miss Perry!
I seen that!
[Kids Hooting]
[ Indistinct Chattering]
# Open your eyes
to your feelings #
; Your heart
will let you see g
; And let me say
that I love you g
g God bless you and me g
- [ Laughing]
- [ Piglet Grunting]
[ Laughing, Chattering]
[Grunting]
Hey'.!
[Quacking, Crowing]
[Chick Peeping]
[ Mooing]
[Neighing]
[Giggling]
Is he getting on?
[Clucking]
[Speaking Gibberish]
[Striking Match]
[Match Ignites]
What are ya doin'?
Oh...
playin' war.
[Clears Throat]
Why are you tryin'
to set it on fire?
I guess it got blown up.
Hey, man, I know what happened
to your parents was an accident.
I know you didn't mean
to do that, Anthony.
It wasn't my fault.
[Sighs]
I was standin'...
near the curtains...
and I was playin'
with the match...
and... they caught...
and... I tried
to wake up my parents,
but...
they wouldn't wake up.
And then the fire
started spreading...
and I just couldn't--
[Crying]
OhJoe!
I didn't mean it.
I know you didn't mean it.
It was an accident.
You understand?
An accident.
Nobody means to do
stuff like that.
But you gotta throw it away
now, leave it in the past.
It's gone.
Your parents would
want that, Anthony.
You gotta try now.
You gotta leave
that stuff alone.
[Snif?ing]
I love ya, Anthony.
[Sobbing]
I love you.
Hi.
Hey.
You've been walking.
Man, I was down there
by the creek.
I went over there. I was over
there fishin' withjulio, right?
Yeah? And then I went down this way.
There was a creek down there.
Mmm.
That's for you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Big old trout in there
like that!
What'd you do with it? I didn't do nothin'.
I didn't have my pole then.
We was over there fishin'
in a river that had salmon,
but they wouldn't bite now
because they're spawnin'. Yeah.
Lotta memories
in this place for me.
It's a beautiful place.
Yeah.
See that tree there?
I fell outta that tree. Remember
I talked about this scar I had?
What you doin' in an ugly tree like that?
My cat! My cat!
It got stuck up in the tree.
I went up to get--
That is a rock egg.
And that's for you.
It's magic.
It's laid by the rock bird.
You mean I can rub on it
and make three wishes?
You can make as many wishes
as you wish.
[ Horn Honks]
[ Horn Honk/mg]
What is Miss Perry doing?
She's robbin' the bank. I'm gonna
drive the getaway car. [All Laughing]
Perhaps your bank in Philadelphia
could be more helpful, Miss Perry.
Good day, Mr. Schuyler.
And thank you for nothing!
'*§
There she is.
Hey, look at that car!
Yeah!
What kind is it? I don't
know, but it's bad!
Honey, you forgot your lunch.
0/1!
Thank you, dear.
All right.
What's wrong with Miss Perry?
I don't know.
Get in.
Vivian?
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
I have a problem
that I want to work out,
and I need to do it
by myself.
I Joe 1 You can't work
problems out by yourself
Maybe I could help.
I want to help you!
just tell me the problem. lfl can't
help you, I'll say, “I can't help.“
But what's the matter?
I didn't get the money.
What money?
I didn't get the money. I'm gonna
lose the land, the house. I'm--
This is your house.
What are you talkin' 'bout?
I needed $15,000 to pay
the taxes, the mortgages.
They're gonna
sell the place!
I don't qualify. I don't have a job.
I cannot get the money.
Everything I...
dreamed is... gone.
What do you mean, gone?
I lost the dreamJoe. What you
talkin' 'bout, you lost?
What are we, losers?
I ain't no goddamn loser!
Well, do you have it?
Can you give it to me?
Do you have $15,000? No, I don't have it!
If I had it, you'd have it!
I don't have shit, but me! But I ain't
no loser, and don't you tell me I am!
And they ain't
losers either!
I drove that goddamn bus all the way
from Philly... with baling wire!
And I fixed it and we're here!
So don't tell me I'm a loser!
I did something
once in my life!
I'm somebody, and you ain't
gonna take that away from me!
Hey, guys, come over here.
I gotta tell you something.
Miss Perry couldn't pay the bank,
and we're going back to Philly!
[Kids Groaning,
Chattering] Aw, man!
[ Chattering Continues]
[Boy] A w, it'; not even ?air!
We don't wanna go back!
Shut up!
Go take a hike!
Up-
You guys
are somebody, man.
And you stop this shit!
The woman put her ass
on the line for you!
And you don't think nothin'
'bout yourselves!
We're not losers!
Hey.
What?
We're not losers.
She tried.
[Bus Engine Re wing]
“Dare to be rich.”
[Snickers]
“The Trapezoid Approach...
To Personal
Economic Security."
This sounds very familiar.
I know this.
[Crowd Laughing, Applauding]
In what way does your trapezoid
differ from the pyramid schemes...
that we've been reading about in the
papers? I'm glad you've asked that.
I'll bet you are.
Now, the pyramid is based on the
triangle, which has three sides.
But the trapezoid
has four sides!
And it is that fourth side
which guarantees,
geometrically and mathematically,
the enrichment...
of all those
who participate in it.
- [Crowd Murmuring]
- Does that answer your question, sir?
Yeah, thank you.
Now...
are there
any other questions?
I have a gentleman
in the back row.
Uh, Mr. Professor Renfrew?
Sir.
My name is Millard Gregg,
and I'm from Texarkana.
I have a few questions about
that tra-- tripi-- trapezoid?
Now, you say if I give you
a thousand dollars,
by this afternoon
my money will double?
Maybe even triple? Triple?
[Chuckling]
Oh, my God, sir. Why, some people-- Mr.
Munjak here--
have seen their bank
accounts grow twenty-fold...
in under a week through
the trapezoidal method!
Twentyic?d? Yes, let's
hear it for the gentleman!
[App/aud/ng]
And he don't pay no taxes?
- That is right! - Hot damn!
I don't wanna miss this!
Now, I'm gonna give you
my thousand dollars...
'cause you're at the top of the trapezoid.
That's right.
And then I'll sell my share
to two other people,
and they give you half,
and give me half.
That's right. And then this
thing doubles and then splits.
And then you get money from that side and
that side and that side. That's right!
My God. my wife and I this
morning said a prayer... to God.
I was hopin' somethin' like
this-- I just can't believe it.
I really can't. I mean,
this is on the up-and-up?
That's right. Then you won't
mind if I collect the money?
I'm one of these people.
You people don't mind, do you?
Uh, Dwayne, would you let the
gentleman take your chair...
momentarily? [Joe] Well,
thank you, Dwayne.
Don't mention it, brother.
You know, my God, look at this!
Thousand-dollar bills!
You know, you can live a lifetime and
never see a thousand-dollar bill.
I haven't seen one of them
since-- Well, hell.
Mmm, my, my.
Look at that.
Ain't that nice!
This is gonna be real fun here.
I can tell we gonna have a real good
time, all the way, me and you, huh?
You wanna get started?
Samantha, pass me a piece of corn.
Ernesto, you want this?
[Boy] Come on, pass me the com
bread Can I have some greens?
[ Si g h s ] [Girl]
Pass me some greens.
Aunt Beedee, I'd like to borrow
the truck for a little bit.
I want to run into town and see if
I can find out what's goin' on.
[indistinct Shouting]
[ Shouting Continues]
Thank you. Thank you.
Dare to be rich, sir.
- Dare to be rich, sir. - Everybody's
doin' what they gotta do.
Yes, sir.
Yes! Dare to be rich!
Now, who next
will dare to be--
The gentleman
in the cowboy hat!
Yes, you, sir.
Uh, Mr. Munjak!
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
[ Mumbling] Yes, indeed.
Everybody dare to be rich.
Assist our new associate.
[Joe] Dare to be rich.
- You bet. - Everybody's supposed to
dare to be rich one time in life.
You get two people,
and they get two people...
and you split up like that
and just dare to be rich!
Having fun, turkey? Oh,yeah.
lam, I am.
Dare to be rich! You better dare to
haul ass when we get you outside.
[Renfie w] And now, who's next?
Who will dare to be rich?
Martin, isn't that the car
we saw at the bank?
[ Harold] What car?
The Rolls -Royce.
Yeah, let's trash it!
No, let's steal it.
Wait!
I've got a better idea. What?
[ Renfie w] As you know, we will
not be returning to this area...
forat least three weeks. 50, laziies
and gentlemen, while Miss Peas/ey...
pins these two remaining names, I would ask
those of you who ha ve not yet joined us...
in the trapezoid, to consider seriously
the thought of coming along with us.
[Joe] That's right, 'cause the
professor would never lie to you!
'Cause easy come, easygo. Round
and round she goes. Joe!
Where she stops, nobody knows. I'm telling
you, Missjohnson, you did a wonderful thing!
She's in the trapezoid!
Let's hear it for Missjohnson!
Yes, sir. Why don't you
take care of that, Dwayne?
And look it here! Here's another lady
who wants to join the trapezoid!
What are you doing? There she
is, ladies and gentlemen!
You got a thousand dollars?
How many shares you want?
What? Now, don't ask me. I sold
the bus and bought this outfit,
and I'm trying to make us money.
Yes, ma'am, $300!
You sold the bus? Here's $15,000
for the kids. Take it home!
Don't worry about a thing Next
time we come to town, we gonna/am.
You sold the bus? Everybody
wants to be in the trapezoid!
Yes, I sold the bus. You remember
high finance! You gonna die poor!
Dwayne, would you go, please?
I wanna ask you- Did you say
someth-- Don't ask me nothin'.
The lady thinks the pentagon's
better than a trapezoid.
Oh, my God! [Renfie w] Ladies
and gentlemen, just keep calm!
You sold the bus?
Yes!
Everybody keep calm! My associates
had a slight altercation,
but, uh--
Now, wait. Don't crowd!
What are we runnin' for?
They got guns!
[ Tires Squealing]
[Joe indistinct]
Halt! I warn you, sir,
I'm trained in kung fu!
[Screams]
What have you done?
[Guns/vats]
[ Screams ]
[Vivian Screams]
- [Vivian Screams]
- [ Gunshots]
- [ Gulps ]
- A// right, wxke guy.
Where's the money?
I don't have the money.
All right--
[ Munjak Groaning]
- [ Groaning, Gun Fires]
- You check that out.
I'll guard the door.
[Screaming]
[ Gunshots]
I'll fix this young lady's wagon!
Waita minute!
Are you gonna hit me with
a plunger? Are you crazy?
[Groans]
Sheesh.
[Grunting]
- [ Mockjapanese]
- [ indistinct Yelling]
[Joe Muttering]
- Just put it down!
- [ S word S wooshing ]
You thinkyou're bad, don't you?
You're messin' withjoe Braxton, baby!
Joe B__
Oh, shit.
Kill him.
[Joe Screaming]
[ Raft in?ating]
Money!
Leave him alone!
You want the money? I got the money!
Come and get it!
Get the money!
Come and get the money!
Frank, we need water!
Get up, please! Let's go! Tell
Samantha Dakota can go pee now.
Come on! [ Vivian ] I
et's get outta here!
They're gonna kill us!
Come on!
Where's the money? Never mind that.
Let's just get outta here!
Wait a minute! You burned the money?
They're gonna kill you!
just get the truck!
Meet me out front!
[Screaming]
Yeah!
You stinking bastards!
[Groaning]
Jump in! Hurry up! They're catching us!
[Yelling]
They're catching us! jump in!
Slow down!
Jump in! I gotta turn the corner!
Don't turn!
I have to turn! jump in! No!
Come on, th-they're coming! Get up!
Get up. They're coming.
#76.' GE!' up]
H“? up, get m!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
Thanks for what?
Thanks for the help.
It was real nice of you to throw the
money away. Well, you're welcome.
You're welcome, Mr. Braxton.
You're a fuck-up!
I have asked you not to use that
kind of language to me! Bullshit!
Did you want me to sit there
and watch you get killed?
That's real nice. Fifteen thousand dollars!
He had a gun!
He would have killed you for$15,000!
Killed shit!
That ain't nothin'
but a meatball!
Do you think I could sit there and let
'em blow your life away for nothing?
It ain't for nothing! I'm tryin' to help!
It is worth more!
Your life,joe, is worth more
to me than $15,000,you fool!
[Crying]
Here. The money.
Here, take what's left of it!
Here! Take it!
Take it! There it is! I don't want it!
Vivian--
You can have it! Here, take it!
Listen, Vivian.
Leave me alone! Vivian,
I don't want the money.
I don't want the money. [Crying]
I don't want
the money.
I didn't do it for me.
Goddamn, I didn't--
Vivian.
I 0e.
Ain't nobody ever told me
I was worth no $15,000.
My daddy used to say, “Boy, you ain't
worth a quarter for two ofya.“
You say that to me...
you set me on fire.
Shit.
[Rooster Cm wing]
What the hell is that?
Where'd you get it from?
I don't know.
It's not mine.
Well, then,
whose, whose car--
[Schuyler] Good-bye: children.
Good-bye: Linda.
I hope you feel better.
Good-bye.
You must be Miss Perry
and Mr. Braxton.
Uh, what's wrong?
What are you doing here?
I'm Gladys Schuyler, and this is my
husband Alfred, whom I believe you met.
Yes, but...
what's going on?
Well, these children have told us
about all the wonderful things...
that you did for them.
Hitchhiking 300 miles in a snowstorm
when your bus broke down.
And sitting up all night for a week with
little Linda when she had the fever.
Helping Harold learn Italian in Braille.
Malta grazie.
[Sti?ed Laughter] [Gladys]
You people are terrific.
You know, these are
really wonderful children,
and they deserve e very chance
they can get. [ Siren Approaching]
[Siren Blaring]
All right, Braxton,
this is it.
Officer, this man is in violation of
his parole. I'm his parole officer.
I'm taking him, this woman and
these brats back to Philadelphia.
- What's going on here? - You heard me. I'm
taking these people back to Philadelphia.
Do you have a warrant
for my arrest?
Well?
No.
- I'm not going back.
- She's staying.
Who the hell are you? That's Mr.
Schuyler, our town mayor.
All right, now, look, this woman has
violated at least 2O federal statutes.
Number one: kidnapping. [Alfred]
You want a legal battle?
All right, I'm gonna get on the phone.
I'm gonna get a warrant for his arrest,
for her arrest-- [Alfred]
Hold on a minute, friend.
Before you get off the phone, all these
children will be registered in the state.
And I'm having the farm transferred
back to Miss Perry in her name...
with a big enough loan so she can
operate it properly [Kids Cheering]
But this man is still under myjurisdiction.
[joe] Dona/d...
take it easy, man.
I'll go back with you.
[ Kids, Vivian Protesting]
I gotta go back. I did something. Don't
worry. Please don't go, we need you!
We have a reason
for you to stay.
“Dear Mr. Braxton, we,
the children of this house,
“pardon you for the crimes
you have done...
“because we know...
“you is sorry...
you did them.“
You have to read it.
"We wish that when we grow up we
're fine people just like you.
“From this day on,
you are off parole...
and nobody can
stop you no more."
[Joe]
This is real special.
I just-- I did something
wrong, you know,
and I made a deal
with the government...
to let me off,
to stay on parole.
That's my parole officer,
and I gotta go back.
[Linda Crying]
Don't go back.
Shh, don't cry.
All right, Braxton,
let's go.
I'll give you a minute
to say good-bye.
Hey, stop it. Don't try
to drive no buses.
[Harold]
Yeah.
Hey, big mama, come here.
Come here.
Hey, man, you're
gonna make me cry.
[Kids Laughing]
No more swearing.
[Laughing]
I love you.
Thanks.
I ain't no loser. I'm
a tough Puerto Rican.
[Laughing]
You better
believe it, man.
[Engine Starts]
What happened?
Get out.
Go on back home.
[Laughs]
Joe's back!
[Kids Cheering]
- # Open your eyes to
your feelings ; - we'.!
g Show me that you care g
gjust like the stars
in the heavens #
g Love is everywhere g
# Open your eyes
to your feelings #
[Kids Cheering] ,' Yourhean'
will let you see,'
; And let me say
that I love you g
g God bless you and me g
# Open your eyes
to your feelings #
; Your heart
will let you see g
; And let me say
that I love you g
g God bless you and me g,"
LordSadler
lordsadler2012@gmail.com