Did you know where the
spirits go after people die?
Many believe that the spirits...
will remain close to us in a parallel world.
And sometimes they may even try
to talk to us to tell us something.
"Possessed"
Three. Two. One.
Action!
Hi, I'm Pent. I'm the director
of a short film called...
To eternal lovee until death do us part
and I will never break your heart.
Is that a poem or a moveie
title? You sure about that?
I'm inspired by a true story
that once happened here.
It was a story about a blind rich girl...
who fell in lovee with a deaf poor man.
This is where they met.
Naturally, the girl's parents intervened...
and forced her to marry some rich guy.
As soon as the man found out...
he decided to kill himself
and gave her his eyes.
So when the girl...who could now
see learned about the sacrifice...
she killed herself too. Right here.
Bullshit!
I was told that someone actually
hung herself right in that pavilion.
well, then use that to promote the film.
Tell people this is based on true story.
If they don't buy it, well...screw 'em.
Japan, why don't you go
check on the camera?
Go on. Get your ass moveing.
what are you up to, Mr. Zenjen?
I'm hearing veoices?/ whose veoices?
Shhh...
I heard something. what is it?
Shit!/ That's funny.
This tomboy is a cameragirl.
Her name is Ying.
what are you filming this for?
what you see is not always what you get.
This macho-looking guy is a She-Man
Hey! what the hell? Asshole!
This young lady is a general assistant.
Ji, can you look at the camera?
I'm doing the behind-the-scene
thing for YouTube.
It's gonna be a blockbuster. Trust me.
Ji. Ji.
There's a ghost behind you./ what
the hell? what's wrong with you?
It's way past 9 a.m. and we
haven't even started yet.
Quit screwing around./ what
do you want me to do?
There's no one around. But
I just saw our leading man.
Go fetch him./ All right. I'll go get him.
Not me.
what?/ what on earth are
you doing back here?
I'vee been looking all oveer for you.
I'm just trying to memorize the script.
Memorize the script? / That's right.
You're playing a dumb
guy...you know...can't talk.
There's nothing to memorize.
Listen! Even though I can't talk...
"l still have to work on my
feelings... expressions...
gestures...tones...you
know...the whole shebang.
An amateur like you wouldn't understand.
Are you guys ready to rock and roll?
I was ready since yesterday.
That's why I'm here.
May your spirit be reincarnated.
Please leave me alone.
I'll make merit and dedicate it to you.
Hey! what's wrong?
A ghost./ Ghost?
where is it?/ It was right here.
I don't see any.
You can't... cause you
don't have a sixth sense.
This man is a cemetery guard.
Listen! I'm really sorry about this.
How long will you guys be
here for?/ Just one day.
well, try not to stay up too late
then. You might irk the others.
who are the others? It's just us oveer here.
I'm talking about those
lying under the ground.
That'd be great.
Our film will be much more
realistic if they could join us.
Beware of what you wish for./ Are they real?
Hurry up! we don't have all day.
what's with all the light checking?
It changes anyway./ I don't like it this way.
Knock it off, will you?
what the hell is wrong with you guys?
when're we gonna start shooting?
Need I yell every single
take? My throat's killing me.
water?
Thanks!
How're you doing?
You ok?
I'm fine./ Good.
Go get some lunch for the crew.
Go get some food. Please.
I don't know how to drivee.
Come on. All right!
what're you doing?/ Buckle it up for you.
what do you think?
Are you upset?/ what for?
You seem quiet./ There's
nothing to talk about.
So... what brought you here?
Aof asked me to come./
He's your boyfriend?
Are you crazy? He's my cousin
I see. That's why you look
just like him./ Really?
Not really.
Hi, Chompoo. where're you
at now?/ I'm in Bangkok.
Bangkok? why are you still there?
You're already several hours late.
I'm really sorry.
Right now I'm painting my nails,
but I can leave in about two hours.
what do you mean?
It won't open.
The handle broke. Gotta
open from the outside.
Be my guest.
Pent!
It's all because of you.
You wanted to hire a superstar
and she stood us up.
Now what?
Japan, who else can fill in this role?
Do you feel lonely?
what's taking her so long?
A cameragirl as a leading
lady? I can't believe it.
Givee me a break. we have no other choice.
I think she's good for the role.
Are you an amateur?
Making a tomboy a leading lady.
I'm ready.
Look at those shoes./ Don't
you have other pairs?
You'll just have to deal with it.
Action!
Honey... do you realize
you're the lovee of my life?
Cut! Cut!
what is that?/ why did you cut that?
I saw something in the
camera./ I didn't see any.
That's impossible.
I tagged along...hoping to see a ghost.
I always wanted to see one.
Grisly ghost! Grisly ghost!
Grisly ghost my ass.
Come on.
I saw something flashing by just now.
where?
Ok... on the count of three...
If it doesn't show up... we'll leave./ Deal.
One.
Two.
Three.
Let's go.
I'm so disappointed...
I didn't get to see one. Maybe
I needed to count longer.
Yeah, right.
Don't be naughty. I'll come back in a bit.
who're you talking to?
A baby ghost./ Baby ghost?
You think I'm crazy, don't you?/ Not at all.
I hope all crazy people are as pretty as you.
That is so corny.
Here you go./ No, thanks.
How do you raise the baby ghost?
It's not that hard. Just feed him every day.
wanna raise one too?/ Not really.
I don't want to talk to myself.
But I really do see him.
Scene 2, Cut 1... 52nd take already.
Haste makes waste...haven't you heard?
Action!
Are we doing this forever?
I'm freezing to death.
Cut! Let's take a break.
Japan, coveer for me please.
You look really sexy soaking wet like this.
Pervert!
You should go pay respect to
the guardian spirit after this.
I'm veery busy.
But my assistant is probably available.
No way. I hate the burning incense.
Son of a bitch!
Here's your lunchbox.
Thanks!
wow! You look fantastic.
Had I known you'd turn
out to be pretty like this.
I would'vee asked you out when we first met.
For the record... the feeling is not mutual.
That's harsh
Hi, dad.
Are you gonna come home
for the ancestor veeneration?
I can't. I need to finish this film.
But you'vee been missing it for many years.
I'm really busy, pop. Besides grandpa
must'vee been reincarnated by now.
You're an ingrate. That's
why you're still a nobody.
I'm done talking to you. That's it.
I'm so sick of it.
It's always worshipping this and
that it's a waste of time and money.
Your grandpa must be so proud of you.
Ji is a poor girl.
Her dad is a runaway felon...
for selling fake amulets.
Her mom is really into spiritual beings...
and her friends think she's
the witch's daughter.
I don't realize her life is so eventful.
That's why she's a recluse...
Locks herself up in a room after school...
Doesn't talk to anybody much...
I'm afraid she'll go nuts.
So I take her here... hoping
to brighten things up for her.
Are you gonna cry?/ Nope.
This is too spicy for me.
Sorry.
Are you lonely?
wanna go home?
we'll be home real soon.
Pent... do you have it in another color?
This is like a see-through dress.
People can see the outline of my underwear.
This is the funeral. You
want an orange dress?
If you got one... sure./ I think
you look really sexy in that.
I can barely see your pantie./ Barely?
Hey, babe. Hit me baby
one more time./ Babe?
Cut it out.
He's a creep.
Let's get back to work.
You pervert./ That's enough.
Get back to work, Ying./
what're you staring at?
what's wrong with these two?
Hey, Book. why don't you
movee the offerings out?
It looks better that way./ Are you sure?
Just movee them out. I'm about to start now.
All right / Hurry up!
Hold on, guys.
I think you should ask for
permission before moveing them.
That won't be necessary.
You worry too much. I'm
sure the dead won't mind.
That's right. we're just
shooting a short film.
Take them out, Book.
Don't worry about it.
I'll start from the end to the beginning.
It's Hollywood's latest trend./
whatever floats your boat
Gosh!
Hey, Book. where is the
coffin I asked you to bring?
Look, Pent./ what?
You gave me only a few bucks.
How am I supposed to
get a coffin with that?
what do you think?
You're asking me? That's
all the money we got.
That's plenty, I think
Anyway you're the Art Director
it's your job to figure it out.
So what?
what? / what? You want me to dig one out?
They shouldn't have any
problem./ That's not a bad idea.
we can save money. That
might work./ what a moron!
Knock it off. Stop it!
why don't you go look around?
See if we can borrow a spare one.
Go on.
Get out of here. what an attitude! You idiot.
You think this is a Hollywood
film? It's just a senior project.
Uncle./ what is it, boy?
Do you have a spare coffin I can borrow?
who's dead?/ No one.
It's for a prop in our film.
No problem. Just a second.
Ok, let's go.
Look at all these graves, boy.
They're coveered with oveergrown grass.
Nobody cares about them anymore.
The children have forgotten that...
they have today because
their dead ancestors...
had worked so hard to raise them.
Maybe they don't have
time. It's pretty far out.
They always have time to
go somewhere, don't they?
Even oveerseas.
what about your own
children?/ I'vee got three.
Haven't seen any lately
though./ And your wife?
She's here./ Here?
How come I'vee never seen her?
That's because she's six feet under.
Japan./ what?
why don't you find something
to coveer the picture of the dead?
I think it's better off without
that./ Do it yourself.
what're you scared of? All right. I'll do it.
Always an excuse. Every single one of you.
Book is one./ So are you.
will this work?
I think so.
It's just what we need.
Today is the Chinese's Ghost Day.
That's why I haven't buried this one.
You mean there's a body in there?
Sure. You wanna take a look?
I can show you. You can
ask him to be in your film.
Thanks, but no thanks.
I just want an empty coffin.
well, I don't have any.
This is the only one left.
Do you still want it?
Hmm, how about this?
I'll take the body out first
and bring just the coffin.
when I'm done I'll put
the body back in there.
No way. That's strictly forbidden.
Once the body's in, you can't take it out.
The spirit will be lost can't find its way back.
And one more thing.
If someone smells or hears
something... don't say a word.
when you movee the coffin
always go forward. Never back.
Also, don't make a noise...
and don't ever let the
coffin touch the ground.
Always find something to cushion.
Can you remember all these?
I believe so.
Hey, Japan. Focus the camera on me.
I want to make sure people see me.
Can we change this portrait? I don't like it.
It's too late now./ Take a good look at this.
we're running out of daylight.
Take it easy.
Cut it out, you guys./ wait a minute.
This is the best we'vee got./ Damn it!
You never listen to me./
No, you listen to me.
Shit! It's hot./ You deserve it, asshole.
Now, listen to me./ what?
I'm doing this for free.../ l
could'vee made 20 bucks a day.
You know how much that is?
It's getting heavy.
It's heavy./ I know.
Shut up. I'm trying to concentrate.
where is this smell coming from?
Shit! It really stinks.
All right. Let's get ready./ Ok.
Action!/ wait a minute.
what is it again?/ My portrait.
It needs some cleaning up.
All done. Ready to roll.
Movee it. You're blocking the camera.
Ok. Ready?
Action!
I can handle it myself.
Slow down a bit./ Yeah. Slow down a bit.
Slower./ Slower.
A little slower./ A little slower.
Damn!
Can't you movee in unison?/
Yeah. Movee in unison.
That's it./ That's it.
Step further back./ That's
right. Step further back.
I can't focus the camera./ He can't focus.
Stop repeating after me./ Holy shit!
Hey, Japan. Concentrate, will you?
I'm sweating like I'm in a sauna.
Ready?/ Yes.
Take two. Action!
Cut! Cut!/ what again?
Zenjen. what now?
I'm hearing something in my headphone.
That's impossible. There's no one around.
Are you sure?
I'm positivee. I definitely heard something.
Maybe it's from some people
nearby./ Yeah. Maybe.
Dear grandpas and grandmas. May
I please continue my shooting?
Please let us finish our job.
It's gone. we're ready to go.
Hey, Book. why is the
coffin so damn heavy?
why not? There's a body inside.
why do you stop moveing?
Ji. Ji.
She's going into shock.
This will require a mouth-to-mouth.
Ji. Ji./ Let him go.
Are you ok?
why did you hit me,
bitch?/ You insulted me.
Insulted you? Are you kidding me?
Ji, what's wrong?
Can any of you help?
what just happened?/ You pretentious slut.
Are you sure you didn't know anything?
Ji, what happened?
Look...there is an old
man... sitting on the coffin.
You guys find someone else.
I'm out of here.
Hey, Japan.
I'm also out.
This is so spooky./ Ying. Ying.
wait up! / Hey, Zenjen.
we're out as well.
This is not what we signed
up for. Let's get the hell out.
It's all because of you, Book.
why did you bring a real coffin?/
Now the shit is all on me?
You suck. You can't handle your job.
You suck more. I gotta go through shit.
I can't work with you anymore.
Fine. Go do something else. I don't care.
You can count me out. I'm out of here.
Fine. Get out!
well, everyone's out
now. So what do we do?
Pack our shit. Get out of here.
Here we are. The gas station.
Pull oveer.
Hurry!
You're not using the bathroom?/ I'm fine.
want me to get something for you?
I'm coming with you.
Can you go in with me?/
You want me that bad?
Don't flatter yourself... I'm just scared.
Hey, Ying./ wait right
here. And... no peeking.
Ok. Hurry up!
Hey, Ying.
will you take it easy? I can almost picture it.
Shut up!
I'vee got something to tell you./ what?
I think I'm in lovee with
you. will you be my girl?
You idiot.
This is your idea of romance?
I'm so not into it right now.
what's the matter?
I think you're really pretty when you smile.
How can I smile when...
when what?
when I'm...
Nothing.
So...what are you going to do next?
I'll probably shoot the film myself.
I'm going to direct it this time.
Let me know if there's
anything I can do./ Really?
The coffee is kind of bitter, don't you think?
It could...use some sweetener.
Just kidding.
You son of a bitch. what is wrong with you?
Scared the shit out of me.
You know in a horror film...
A ghost always appears in
the mirror. Just like this.
You idiot! what're you trying to pull?
I almost shit in my pants.
Because you saw yourself in the mirror?
Right...you look just like
Robert Pattinson yourself.
Thanks for the compliment.
who could be calling now?
Hello./ what's up, Dave?
Is my car key with you?
Yep. I'll mail it to you tomorrow.
Tomorrow my ass! You
have to bring it here now.
I was going to.../ No, you listen to me.
I can't leave my car here. It's a classic.
You dig? It'll be stolen.
All right. I'll bring it back to you
then./ Now! Right this second!
Guys, I'll have to bring the key back to Dave.
Stop howling... you stupid dogs.
Can't you stop more gently?
It's ABS technology.
where is he? I can't see him.
I'm sorry...the number you'vee reached...
Damn! His phone's dead.
Let's go and find him./ we're not going.
You go ahead, Aof.
Thanks so much... for your kind support.
Come on. Go.
You idiot.
where can he be?
God damn it. You scared me, man.
I thought you weren't coming.
I think we should go back
now. Just leave the key here.
He'll be back soon./ I can't just leave.
He'll kill me if something
happens to his car.
This car?
Look at this. I don't even know
how it still runs. It's ancient.
Givee him a break.
Let's go look in the pavilion.
He might be in there.
why couldn't you just wait at the car?
It would save me a lot of trouble.
Actually this place is not that scary.
You could'vee come out here by yourself.
Yeah, right.
It's actually kinda nice here.
And l...will always lovee
you./ Shut the hell up.
why? I'vee got good veoice./
This is not the time.
Let's go inside.
Quit acting like a child./
That was a classic gag.
Let's get in.
This door could definitely use some lube.
Is that Dave?
I think so. Let's check it out.
Aof, I think he's dead.
we need to get out of here./ Hold on.
He might still be alivee. I gotta help him.
An asshole like him deserves to die anyway.
what's all the commotion about?
Dave / Yep!
I thought you were dead.
Dead? I just asked him to rub my neck.
You want some?/ No, thanks.
I thought you killed him.
You son of a bitch!
You pee in your pants?
Stop jumping around. You're spilling it.
My shoes.
Put that away. It's embarrassing.
See you later, losers.
Pent. Next film... it's 20 bucks per day.
That's a lot of money.
And if the afterlife is real
hope we'll never meet again.
Are you sure he's normal?
Good luck and godspeed.
Let's go home. I'm exhausted.
You guys can't go just yet./ why's that?
You have to take the coffin back first.
Otherwise...you know...
you may not be able to get out of here
wait a minute. where're you going?
I'm going back to get some sleep.
Stay with us, uncle.
Tonight is the 7th lunar month./ Oh, is it?
You wanna take us to the full moon party?
what are you kids talking about?
It's the Chinese's Ghost Day.
Tonight, hell's gate opens up...
and the spirits will come
out to take the offerings.
That sounds more like an urban legend.
You don't have to believe
me. I'm just warning you.
All right, I'm leaving now.
And don't forget to bring the coffin back.
Ok. Let's do it so we can all go home.
It's not my job.
Maybe we can do it tomorrow.
Are you sure?/ Absolutely!
Fine.
Ji & Book...a match made in heaven.
I'll do it tomorrow. Don't
worry. Let's go home now.
Book, this doesn't look familiar at all.
Are you sure this is the way
out?/ He knows what he's doing.
I recognize this red pavilion.
why do you stop?
Someone just cut in front of our vean.
Did we hit him?/ I don't
care. Let's get out of here.
I don't think it's human./
That's right. Let's get going.
Come on, Book.
But I think you should go check it out.
Shit!
Book.
I don't see anything at all.
why don't you take a look underneath?
He might be down there.
That's scary.
There's nothing down there, is there?
Nope.
See... I was right.
Guess not.
This is too close for
comfort. This is not nice.
Open the door... I can't stay
here anymore./ wait up!
I can't open it.
Ji, recite your incantation./ That's right.
I don't know how.
well... ask your baby ghost to help
then./ Yeah, ask your baby ghost
I can't. It's all bogus.
what about you being
possessed?/ That was a fake too.
You bitch. You'vee been
fooling us all this time?
Can you spare some change?
Damn! I thought you were
a ghost. Just a beggar.
why did you do it?
I wanted you guys to believe it
so you wouldn't insult the dead.
That's why you did it?
I'm so sorry.
Don't be. I'm not buying
it. You're such a liar.
what more do you want?
She said she's sorry.
Let's get out of here.
Ji...Ji...
Something's wrong with her.
You're faking it again,
bitch?/ Take it easy, Ying.
Allow me...
what was that for?
You haven't learned, have you?
A Chinese ghost, huh?
I know Chinese.
Let me demonstrate my kung-fu movees.
Ying.
I think it's real this time.
Look at the blood.
If you really wanna know
if she's possessed...
you have to see through your legs.
Really? / Really.
wow! Your ass is huge.
Stop kidding around. I'm serious.
what did you see?
A ghost.
who is it?
Maybe it's your grandpa.
How do you know?
He's probably upset that you
didn't go pay him respect today.
I'm so sorry, grandpa. Please forgivee me.
what did he say?
He said you're an asshole.
Asshole? Are you sure?
Do you really know how to speak Chinese?
I took some lessons. I'm pretty sure.
Or is it the one you
spray-painted on his picture?
Please accept my apology. I didn't mean to.
I'm really sorry.
what did he say?
He said that's not his picture.
why did he hit me then?
well?/ His friend asked him to.
Oh, I think I know.
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean
to pee on your grave.
I was wrong. I deserve to die.
what did he say?/ That's
not his grave either.
That's a relief. Thanks so much.
what's that for?
well?/ You're getting on his nerves.
Getting on his nerves? Now we're even.
I know... Must be the one in
the coffin we used in our film.
How do you know that?
That's easy. Most ghost films are like that.
Some ghosts come back for revenge.
Some for belongings, and some for lovee.
This one is probably upset that
no one knows where his body is...
or something like that.
See? He said I'm right./
That's not what he said.
He said... he's going to kill us.
Can you ask him what he wants from us?
what do you want? You damn ghost!
Hey, be nice to him.
we just want to know what he wants.
Translate that.
He wants us to bring him back to his grave.
well, it's your grave...
we're not coming with you.
All right. Let's do it.
So... nobody's coming with me?
what are you guys waiting for? Come on.
Ying./ what?
You stay back here and watch her.
You want me to stay here with her?/ Yes.
I don't think so.
You're the best person.
You're the only one who can speak Chinese.
I'll stay with you./ I'd rather stay with him.
Come on. Let's get moveing.
what do you think you're doing, Book?
He probably needs some air.
You're so considerate.
Shall we?
Aof, wait up.
what's wrong with you?/ I'm scared.
No need to be...oops.
what's wrong with you two?
Keep it down.
Not my turf.
It's spooky.
Shit!
why is the lid open?
where's the surprise?
In a typical ghost film, this
is the "surprise" moment.
Lizard. Lizard!
Do you believe in Ghost Day?
why are you asking me this?
I just wanted to know... when
the ghosts will come out.
why don't you givee your grandpa a call?
Did you see that?/ what is it?
I wouldn't ask if I knew.
would you stop bombarding
me with questions?
I'm terrified now.
why did he honk?
Help! Help!
Let go of her.
Help me!
Stop yelling.
Slow down.
I told you two to stay and
watch Ji. why are you here?
well, she almost killed us both.
Her face's turned into an
old man. It's frightening.
I'm going back there./ wait for me, Book.
I'm with you.
Hurry!/ Hey, come back.
I'm not going back there. Are you? No.
Hi, how're you?
Hello. Excuse me.
Do you happen to know the way
out? It's quite confusing in here.
Keep going straight.
Take a right when you see a big oak tree...
then take a left at the anthill...
and take one more left turn when
you get out of the cemetery.
That's it? Thanks! But it
sounds really complicated.
I got bad memory... you know?
So if you're not busy, why don't
you come along for the ride?
we'll split up at the gate.
I'm waiting for my boyfriend.
well, do let me know when
your boyfriend's away then.
Must'vee never been out in
the sun... so damn pale.
See you later, beautiful.
Remember, when your
boyfriend's away, let me know.
Pervert!
Damn! where's she?
That's good.
I'll go find her.
This is a cemetery.
Not a city center that you can
roam around anytime you want.
Are you crazy?
Hey, wait up./ Easy.
why didn't you ask me to come?
You were too full of yourself.
Hey, guys.
where do you think the body went?
well, it's possible that the
coffin was empty at first.
Yeah.
A twist ending that fools us all...
but if it ends like this the veiewers will kill us.
will you stop thinking we're in a moveie?
The atmosphere is so right.
what are you gonna do if
something grabs your leg?
Shut up already. I nearly pissed my pants.
Don't worry.
Usually it's the one at the
back who gets the action first.
Guys. Help me please. I fell into a hole.
Pent.
Hey./ what?
Come on. Help me out.
Stop pointing the flashlight at me.
This is great.
The other hand.
Can't find a better way out, can you?
Are you all right?
Hey!/ what?
Is that a hand on your leg?
what is that?
Are you laughing at me?
You laughing at me?
I'm gonna kick your ass.
what the hell?
She was here a second ago.
where the hell is she?
Maybe she ran off.
You'd better not let me catch you
or I'll beat the crap out of you.
who is it? Aof, go take a look./ wait up.
Don't you recognize me?/ It's Dave.
I thought you were long gone./ I was lost.
I drovee around and my car fell into a mire.
what are you guys doing
here?/ we're looking for Ji
Ji? where did she go?
She was possessed by a spirit
and now she's disappeared.
Possessed?/ Yes.
If I know which one of them did that...
I'm gonna beat the crap out
of it./ No need for veiolence.
She's right behind me?
This can't be her.
Doesn't look anything like
her at all./ Yes, this is her.
But she didn't look this old then
Step back./ Hurry!
No doubt.
She looks much older.
what's going on here?
what did she say?/ Tell me.
wait. wait.
She mumbled something about helping her.
It has something to do with crying... I think.
You'd better shut your mouth.
Ying. what did she say?
She said her body is in the swamp.
If that's so we'll need to
call the police for help.
Take it easy./ Call the police.
More... she wants something more?
Shut up!
what does it mean?
She wants us to get her body
out of the swamp right now.
Really? Is she nuts? who's gonna do it?
I won't. My pretty face might get infection.
I can't swim... swear to God.
I'm a girl. I'm not going in.
Me too. I'm chicken. I'm a wimp.
That was well synchronized... you bitches.
who's gonna do it then?
I will.
wow! Dave. I'm impressed.
what I just said, I take it back.
Auntie, I'll take care of it for you.
Dave.
Shit! I'm sinking.
what's all these? It really stinks.
Unbelievable. It's gotta be around here.
Damn smell.
Hey... I found it. I found it./ Bring it out.
The stench's getting stronger.
Lizards. Lizards! Get
me out of here. Lizards.
Stay away from me. Help. Help. Help me.
The lizards are all oveer the
place. They're everywhere.
I think he's being eaten
alivee./ what do we do?
Let's help him.
what is that for?/ Come on. Let's do it.
Let's go.
How's it going?
why're you still here?/ I can't... I can't swim.
I see...
Can't swim, huh?
Dave. Dave.
Lizards. Get away from me.
Are you in a veibration
mode like a cell phone?
Get the body out./ I got it.
what's wrong with her?
I don't know. She was
trembling all of a sudden.
Maybe she's dead.
Don't leave me.
I don't need this. wait up please.
Stop chasing me around.
Hurry up!
I can't shut the door.
The lizards are trying to
break in. Lizards. Lizards.
It's me! Dave. It's Dave.
I'm sorry. I thought you were a lizard.
Sorry.
Come on. Quick. Movee oveer.
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean to. Are you hurt?
I think I know... who the
corpse in the coffin is.
who?
There he is.
No doubt about it. The
exact same gold teeth.
I knew it. This is the twist
ending... of a ghost film.
what's wrong with you guys?
Looks like you just saw a ghost.
He must not realize that he's already dead.
Leave us alone, will you?
Stay in your own world./
Go to hell... or heaven.
Are you guys crazy?
I'm still alivee. why do you wish me death?
You are dead. Let's face it.
Everybody dies... it's inevitable.
That's right.
watch out!
Here... feel my heart. Is it still beating?
How can I be dead then?
why do you have gold teeth...
just like those in the corpse?
well, that's what wealthy people
do. They put gold in their teeth.
A twist ending, right?
Eat crow... you idiot.
This is not a moveie. This is reality.
Try to be optimistic about it.
So why are you here then?
I heard some noise so I thought
there was a thief in here.
That's him. He freaked out
and screamed like a girl.
That's not true.
And why are you up this late?
Shouldn't you be home already?
How could we?
The lizards dragged the
corpse into the swamp...
so the spirit took oveer Ji's body
and asked us to help bring it back.
See what I mean?
I told you.
Never insult these things
even if you don't believe it.
Come on.
Easy. Easy.
That's enough.
Thanks, you guys.
You're not gonna go pay
respect to the corpse?
No, thanks. I'm actually in a hurry.
Some modeling work... you know?
Good luck, you guys.
Drivee carefully.
Bye.
what about you guys? You're not coming?
Yes, we are.
You lead the way.
May your spirit and other spiritual
beings in this place rest in peace.
If we did something offensivee to you...
be it veerbally, physically, or mentally
consciously or unconsciously.
May you please forgivee
us all for our mistakes.
Again?
Please leave her alone.
My sister is not a conveenience store...
that anyone can veisit anytime of day.
Hey, she said she's forgiveen us all.
Nice!
Thank you so much.
The belief in the afterlife can
neither be explained logically...
nor proveen scientifically.
But for us...
we believe wholeheartedly... that it's real.
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
Unleaded gasoline... 20 bucks
please./ Just 20 bucks?
Open the lid.
what is this?/ It's a gas tank lid
opener. Do you know how to use it?
You think she's gonna
break my car?/ Possibly.
Are you tired?
You can take a nap. I'll wake
you up when we get there.
It's ok. I'm fine.
It's for you.
You don't want it anymore.
It's ok. I'vee got a few more back home.
Stay with him. Be a good boy.
Please don't cry.
I promise. I'll take you to veisit her often.
Smile.
Hi, dad. It's me. I'm coming home.
Hey, can you prepare the offerings for me?
It's too late now. Are you out of your mind?
Nope. I just miss grandpa. That's all.
Ok, then./ Ok.
I lovee you.
But I lovee you more.
Here.
Back to where I was again.
will I ever get home tonight?
where are you going?
I'vee already told you that
when your boyfriend's away...
it's gonna be my day.
Come to papa.
where're you going?