Dre, you ready?
- Ya, one second.
Oh Dre, I am so excited.
It's like we're brave pioneers on a quest to
start a new life in a magical new land.
You could say that.
Okay! Alright, let's go.
And don't forget these backpacks.
Amm.. okay.
I'll see you later uncle Charlie.
- Oh! C'mon Charlie! Can't miss the flight!
Bye guys!.
- I'm gonna miss you.
No man it's yours.
- C'mon Dre, just stay here.
Thanks man.
Okay Dre c'mon we gotta go.
Okay bye guys! We'll call as soon as we land!
PA: Chinese: Ladies and Gentlemen, welcome to CA flight 982.
Towards Beijing, China.
Got it?
Yeah
Oh Dre look! We're already on lesson 10.
How are you?
Chinese -  The name of this guy.
Do you remember what that one is?
No.
Dre you're killing me.
Mom! Look! In China... everythings is old.
Old houses... old parks... old people!
Look!
This guy is at least 400 years old.
Dre, please focus. Okay!
What is your name?
What's your name?
You need to practice.
Yeah you need to try it.
- No mom!
Yes! Dre.
- Mom.
Dre.
Ask him. Go ahead.
Ask him. What's your name?
And how are you? Do
it NOW.
Arr......
How are you? Cat!
Books... first...
Dude! I'm from Detroit.
Oh!
Aa...
What's up?
PA: Our flight time will be 3 hours and 30 minutes.
It says to meet by No: 5.
Mrs Perker!
Hi!
Oh... It's Parker.
Oh! Apologies Mrs Parker.
Welcome to Beijing.
Woah... Okay
You're electricity card.
Look! There's the Olympic Village.
Isn't it beautiful?
Yes!
Guess that's nothing old in China.
Huh, Dre?
Look at that Dre.
Beverly Hills!
We've always talked about living there.
Huh?
But I think we were talking about the
other one. Mom.
I've got a good feeling about this.
Oh yeah! You must - you must be
the new dude in 305. Hi, I'm Harry.
Hi, What's up. I'm Dre.
Here, let me help you.
Thanks man.
Welcome to the building, Dre.
Thanks.
Can you please... explain this
electricity card? Because...
we don't have these in America.
Shifu (Master) How are you?
- Fine! And you?
Know any Chinese?
Mmm... Na!
This is China. Might not
be a bad idea.
Oh that's our park.
You should come!
Look at you. Making friends already.
Hi.
- Hi.
I'm Dre's mother.
- Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too. You
can call me Miss Sherry.
I'm Harry.
- Hi, Harry.
So I guess I see you later then.
Maybe!
Okay cool. See ya!
So the rent lady is Mrs. Huang.
Her english is not good.
But if somethings go wrong. You
go to Mr. Han.
His english is very good.
- Okay.
Okay, so welcome to Beijing Mrs Parker.
Amm... so I'll see you tomorrow.
- Okay sure!
Thank you. Oh wait wait.
This is perfect! Dre...
Everything we need is at walking distance.
Oh you know what...
we could have lunch together everyday,
at your school if you want to.
Negative.
Not a chance.
Dre, we are NOT doing this in Beijing!
Dre! Pick up your jacket!
Mom, I'm tired.
Okay. I have airplane lag.
Airplane...
It's jetlag.
I know baby. I got it too.
Can't go to sleep!
But then you'll be up at 2 am.
You have school tomorrow.
Dre! Can you PLEASE go find the
Maintenance man!
I need to take a shower and
the hot water's broken.
Yes!
Excuse me!
Amm..
The maintenance man?
Mr. Han?
Oh old Han.
Exit the building walk to the left.
Then left again.
Thanks!
Mr. Han
Me and my mom! We
just moved in.
305.
The hot water's not working.
Mr. Han?
Okay.
Or I can just come back. Another time.
Or... you can just show me how to do it. So!
that I can get outta your hair.
Hmm...
I can always come back. If this
is a bad time.
Mr. HAN... Mr HAN!
Why's the toilet's plumbing
system always out of order!
Quickly... get this fixed right away!
It's always the same problem!
Hey man! You made it!
Thanks!
You play right?
- Yeah!
C'mon.
Let's play hoops together.
You four guys make a team.
Us three against them four.
Okay.
- alright.
Great!
Good job , good shot.
Pass!
Stop! Stop!
My shooting hands has got jetlag! So!
You know just...
You want this?
You want me to play?
You know? I have no problem beating old people.
Background I come from they
call me Ping Pong Dre. Alright...
I'm gonna take it easy on you.
Hey... c'mon man I'm, I'm twelve.
Ouch!
He's really good. I've never seen him
lose to anybody.
Yeah...
Dude!
You go talk to her? Or what?
To who?
To her.
The girl you've been staring at.
I wasn't staring at her.
Yeah, you were.
Just go talk to her.
So, so scared?
- I'm not scared
of anything.
Then do it! Go!
C'mon.
Cool.
- Right now.
Hey!
What's up?
I've got...
No english... Amm...
How are you? Cat!.
Books...
What language was that?
You speak english?
Me too!
So... What you listening to?
Bach.
Bach! I listen to them all the time.
They are tight.
Have you heard of this?
Oh yeah... You like them huh?
Waay cool... while I'm here.
Wait, wait...
It's coming back.
May I touch your hair?
You wanna touch my hair?
Amm...
Sure!
Chung : Your father wanted you to practise violin
PROPERLY.
Meiying: I'll practise now.
Chung : Why didn't you practise just now!
Meiying: What are you doing!
Leave it!
Meiying: Shouldn't you mind your own business?
Chung: If your dad finds out... He will get
very angry.
Meiying: What's wrong with you?
Meiying: You aren't my father!
C'mon dude!
Boy: Get your things and go home!
I said leave it!
Meiying: Why don't you mind your own business!
Meiying: I will tell your dad!
Meiying: Let go of me!
Harry: The American is new here. He's didn't
know who you are.
Harry: Please don't hurt him.
Chung : Leave!
Meiying: Don't hurt him (Dre).
Meiying: Enough! Don't hurt him!
Meiying: He didn't do anything!
You want to fight!
Boy in crowd: He's giving you a chance to fight him.
Meiying: Let me go! That's enough!
Meiying: That's enough beating!
Are you okay?
Let me...
- Just leave me alone.
Just... I'm fine!
Great!
- Dude!
Dre!
Are you ready?
We gotta be there like twenty minutes.
I know mom!
And you have your uniform on! Right!
Yes mom!
Don't wanna break any
rules on the first day.
Okay... c'mon! Waiting for you.
Hey, you don't have to come in.
I mean... I can handle it.
Dre! Don't be silly.
it's your first day! Plus we both
have to meet your assistant principal...
Mrs. Peng.
I can find her.
And you need to get to work.
Right?
Are you trying to get rid of me?
No mom.
Mrs. Peng?
Hi! Mrs. Peng.
Ms. Parker...
Lovely meeting.
I am so sorry we're late.
This is my son Dre.
Hello!
Hi...
We only wear uniforms on uniform's day.
Oh! That's my fault.
I didn't have a chance to read the school packages...
We'll be better tomorrow.
And hats are not permitted.
Aa... I should have read up on the
dresscode.
Dre, is that makeup?
Ouch...
What is that!
Mom, I ran into a pole.
No you have a black eye.
You got into as fight?
Fighting is not tolerated here.
You heard him. He ran into a pole!
Come here Dre.
Mom, don't start.
Who did it?
Nobody mom.
I ran into a pole.
I didn't tell you cos I'd knew you're act
like this.
Dre you know I don't play...
If somebody hit my baby,
I would tear...
I know mom!
That's why I don't tell you stuff.
Just relax! I just ran into a ...
Yeah, yeah, yeah you RAN into a pole!
Alright Dre. Alright, Alright!
Look! Go to class
Go to class. But we will talk about
this later.
Okay! already go.
I love you!
Mom!
I'd say I love you.
Okay I love you too.
Okay! Have a good day!
Hi!
Hey!
You know. We only wear our
uniforms on uniform's day.
Oh yeah... I so got that one.
Thanks.
I'm Meiying.
I'm Dre.
I'm sorry about Chung.
So that's his name.
Is he your boyfriend?
No!
Our parents are very close.
Well, he definitely likes you.
I have to go practise.
Wait!
You eat and practise at the same time.
Yes.
But my mom says...
If you eat standing up...
gives you gas.
You're funny.
Come to fix hot water.
It's in there.
Kid!
Did you just hit me?
In the neck with a toothpaste cap?
Hot water fine.
Flip switch.
Wait half hour.
Take shower.
Flip switch off.
Why don't you just leave it on?
You leave on in America?
Don't have switch in America.
Get switch.
Save planet.
What happen to eye?
I ran into a pole.
Interesting pole.
Dre!
That's my mom.
And the door handle's messed up.
Are you ready for school?
Yeah!
Here! let me help you.
They have your favourite cereal here.
Found it!
Dre.
For the 100th time.
Can you please pick up your jacket?
One second mom.
No!
No in one second! Now!
This programs gonna be over.
Give me two minutes.
- Dre, I don't care!
Come pick it up now!
God! How many times do I have to ask you?
Once.
That's right!
Make it happen!
I'm sorry what was that!
- Nothing.
Okay that's what I thought.
Nothing!
Thank you!
Okay. That's not play.
You're rushing it.
You must play the pauses.
You know how important this is for your family?
What it will mean for your life?
We have to work with regent.
I'm calling your father.
Continue.
What is your name?
How's that sound?
Almost like the chinese.
Yeah! I'm fluent.
And I don't know what
that guy was talking about?
I thought you sounded great!
Thank you.
So are you practising for anything?
Like a show.
Yes!
I have an audition next month.
For the Beijing Academy of Music.
Beijing Academy of Music.
Sounds important.
You know!
Their initials spell: BAM!
What?
Oh... gotta go.
Hey!
Can I touch you here?
Gonna do something?
Just stay away from us!
All of us.
Dre!
Dre? Are you sleeping?
Hey! Can you sign this?
Forbidden City!
I think it's funny to give my permission to go
to the Forbidden City.
Cool! In Beijing.
Not funny mom.
Oh, cut it out grumpy.
I'm serious Dre...
this ice cream I don't know what they do to it.
But it's more favouristic.
What?
Mom.
This is you...
Oh goodness this ice cream here is so good...
and everything in China is just so much...
better than everything else...
Ouch! Mom!
C'mon!
First of all, I don't sound like that.
I don't move all like that.
I'm sure this ice cream is really good.
Mom, mom c'mon.
Dre.
Wait!
Boy you won't a ... running from me.
Wow...
Kungfu.
What did you all learn?
Never Fail,
Never Falter,
Never Backdown!
Salute!
Mom! C'mon let's go.
What!
Dre, we just got here.
- C'mon mom!
Dre! What's going on?
Nothing!
Dre, what happened?
Nothing happened.
What is it? You don't want to
take that class?
Whatever Dre. What happened?
We moved to China!
That's what happened!
Okay Stop!
Don't be like that Dre.
What do you want me to do?
We've been here less than a week...
And I feel...
- I feel like it's a year!
I hate it here!
Dre, please let me help you.
I can't hope to if you don't
tell me what's wrong.
Please.
- You don't care what's wrong!
All you care is...
how happy I am...
and how great the ice cream is!
Well, I'm not happy!
I hate it HERE!
I want to go HOME!
Dre, we can't go home...
Okay!
There is nothing left for us in Detroit.
This is what we got!
This IS home.
Okay...
Gather round here!
Welcome to one of the most...
popular landmarks in all over China.
It's visited by millions of people...
every year.
The Forbidden City!
... for good luck.
I wish someone would just...
- yeah.
Me too.
Just tell someone.
Yeah! I got it.
Thanks a lot.
The floors of the palace was reinforced with bricks.
15 layers deep...
To prevent anyone from climbing in.
Mr. Parker.
Oh yes...
Is everything okay?
Er... yes, Yes.
Thank you.
Chung: Let's go.
Man:  Go away, go away...
Man: Go away, quickly go away.
- We were just playing.
Chung: Who done it!
Halt!
Over here.
Chung: Halt!
Man: Hey! That's my roof!
Get him!
Halt! right there!
Don't let him run away!
He's lock the door!
Chung: Hurry! Open the door!
He's (Dre) beyond the door.
Halt!
Stop right there!
Still wanna run!
Now you're done!
You're fast.
Not fast enough.
That's enough Chung.
Chung: Don't you guys wanna
use what you learned?
I'm serious! That's enough beating!
Chung: Don't stop me!
Go home.
C'mon!
C'mon.
What's up with the light bulb Mr. Han?
I thought you were just the
maintenance man.
You think only with your eyes.
So you are easy to fool.
It doesn't hurt.
Ancient chinese healing.
How do you do that out there?
You like... didn't even punch them.
They... beat each other up.
When beating angry blind men,
Best to just...
stay outta the way.
So... where did you learn kungfu?
From father.
Have you ever taught anybody?
No.
Would you?
Depends.
On what?
Reason.
What about to kick somebodies ass?
Best fights... are the ones we avoid.
How about avoid getting my ass kicked?
Stop saying ass.
Sorry.
Kungfu...
if for knowledge... defense.
Not to make war.
To create peace.
That's definitely not what they are taught.
Not such things as bad students.
Only bad teacher.
Erm... That's great!
I guess we just...
stroll into their school and talk to their teacher.
Good idea.
No!
Bad idea!
If I go in there! I'll get my ass kicked.
I'll get beat up.
You got beat up anyway.
would you go with me?
No! Sorry.
but you said it was a good idea.
For you! Bad idea for me.
C'mon it's not like you are busy or anything.
And...
I don't even speak chinese.
Very sorry.
Right.
Alright whatever.
Hey!
What's wrong?
Why didn't you finish him?
DO IT!
Okay Mr. Han. Let's get outta here.
Return to position!
Never show mercy even if the opponent is down.
Don't hesitate.
Keep attacking.
Until you obliterate the opponent.
What are you looking at?
Chung: It's that man that beat me.
We'll here for an apology.
Let him fight his own battles.
If it was a even fight.
But he was outnumbered.
It was unfair.
I understand.
Prepare for a duel!
Woah...
Mr. Han did he want us to fight?
We're not here for a fight.
You beat up my student.
You ask for a duel.
Now you wanna walk away?
Not without a fight.
Master Li.
Why don't you fight in his (Dre) place.
One of you have to fight.
Then we fight in the tournament.
Fine.
I accept.
From now til the tournament.
Leave my student (Dre) alone.
Listen UP!
Until the tournament.
Do not harass Mr. Han's student (Dre).
UNDERSTAND!
UNDERSTOOD!
Hey!
If the boy fails to appear,
then you are a dishonoured!
So!
That go pretty much you planned it?
There's good news and bad news.
Good news is. They promised
to leave you alone.
Really?
While you prepare.
Prepare for what?
Tournament.
You'll fight them all, one to one.
Huh?
So the bad news is,
Now they get to beat me up in public!
Yes.
Great!
Thanks!
Thanks a lot!
They're gonna kill me.
You saw they're kungfu.
That's not kungfu!
That does not represent China!
Well, that bad man teaching,
very bad things hurt!
A lot!
More good news
I will teach you real kungfu.
Yes!
See you later mom!
Hey wait! This is early for you for a Saturday.
Mr. Han is teaching me kungfu.
The maintenance man?
It's China mom! Everybody knows kungfu.
Dre, you know how I feel about you fighting.
Kungfu is not about fighting mom,
It's about making peace with your enemy.
Be careful Dre!
Okay!
Mr. Han!
Mr Han!...
Back here!
You know you have a car in your living room.
Mr Han.
Okay.
I was thinking about it yesterday.
I know I was kindna freaking out
about the tournament.
But I realised something last night.
I'm an athlete!
My number one asset!
Is I'm fast okay.
I'm quick.
Quick...
Speed...
Catch me...
I'm quick... yeah.
I used to take gymnastics at P.A.L!
That's the Police Athleteic League! So
check it right...
Boom! You see that!
Boom. You see that!
Yeah!
My uncle Raymi used to date
this brazilian girl.
And he learnt Jujitsu...
and he taught some of it to me.
Its like locks and holds and stuff...
Okay.
Attack me.
See that?
Feel that?
I could break it.
I'm choosing not to.
It's a pressure lock.
Dangerous.
Oh he also taught me Caporeira.
Can't touch me.
Can't...
That antique?
Pickup your jacket.
Oh...
So basically Mr. Han...
I'm trying to say is.
I've got a good foundation here.
Know... like I say just I'm just...
Might not be as hard as you
teach other people you know.
Hang it up.
Okay.
Happy now?
Take it down.
But I just...
Put it on.
Take it off.
I'd already did all these.
- TAKE IT off.
Can you tell me why I'm doing this.
Take it OFF.
Hang it up.
Take it down.
Put it on the ground.
Pick it up.
Hang up.
Take it down.
Put it on!
Take it off.
Put on the ground.
Pick it up.
Hang it up.
Take it down.
Put it on.
Take it off.
Mr. Han.
Why do you have a car in your living room?
No street parking.
Hey!
So how did it go?
What'd you learn?
Nothing.
Uniform on uniform day.
You're fighting the tournament.
Yeah.
How did you hear?
Everybody knows.
I hope you have a good teacher.
Yeah... me too.
He's a maintenance man.
Can I ask you a question?
Yes.
Well, now that you're practising and,
I think I'm practising.
I mean I don't know...
what I'm doing.
Meiying we'll wait for you over there.
But.
We're both tons of practising
you know and...
Are you going to Chi Sze Festival?
Yeah I mean...
I haven't miss the shedi festival fits a bill in China.
We're going.
Meiying: Okay.
Go to the Shadow Theatre.
Okay.
What, I mean to meet you?
Oh, oh so.
Like... Shadow Theatre. Okay.
Itshe Fishe Festival,
Shadow Theatre okay.
Cool
Okay
When it is again?
- Tomorrow.
Show starts at seven.
Okay, so tomorrow.
Shadow Theatre, sheshe Festival.
At seven.
See you tomorrow.
Sheshe Festival.
Festival.
Okay
- kay.
Mr. Han!
May I come in?
You may come in.
Where's your jacket?
I was warming up without it.
Go get it.
You want me to go all the way back just to get it?
Yes, all the way back where you hide it.
It's not right.
What?
I'm doing it.
No.
Something's missing.
Nothing's missing.
Ah...!
You forgot.
This.
Attitude.
Check it off.
Yes! That's it.
Yes, Mr. Han I get it.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't treat my mom like that.
You were right.
Put on the ground.
Hello!
Oh... Hey mom!
Amm... did you get the tickets?
Yes! I got the tickets.
And... I got an extra one for
Mr. Han!
But I didn't say...
Dre, stop it!
Mr. Han would you like to go
with us to the Shi Sze Festival?
No thank you.
Too many people.
Yeah mom way too many people.
But I already bought the tickets.
I don't go
- Mr. Han I won't take a no for an answer!
You have fun, you need to get
out of the house okay!
Here's your clothes Dre.
C'mon hurry up and change.
Dre?
PICK UP YOUR JACKET!
You were right Mr. Han. There
are a lot of people here.
Chinese Valentine's Day.
This is beautiful.
Yeah mom.
Yeah?
I'm gonna go get something to eat.
And then I'm going to the bathroom.
Be back.
Right here. In twenty minutes.
Okay.
Okay. I love you.
Love you too. Be careful.
Twenty minutes!
Twenty!
- Okay.
So what is the origins of this festival again?
I know everything you do here have a meaning.
'Shadow Theatre'
Hi.
Shadow master: You two come over and help.
Hi...
Hey...
Well, I got this and this
for you.
I got one of this and...
cos she have this really cool violin stuff.
And...
I thought maybe you could play along
and...
Its not like Bach and them but...
So I thought maybe you like it.
And...
Thank you.
So amm...
Do you have any kids?
No.
So how's Dre doing?
Aaa...
Xiao (Chinese:Young/ little) Dre making a progress.
Xiao Dre?
Yeah Aa... Chinese for little.
Oh!
So Amm...
How many students do you have?
Including xiao Dre?
Yeah.
One.
So hmm... What's this show about?
Aa...
It's the story of the Goddess...
And the boy she loves...
I love this story.
Her mother does not approve of him.
So, she cast a wide river in the sky.
To separate them forever.
But, once a year.
All the birds in the sky...
feel sad for them.
And they form a bridge.
So the two of them,
maybe together for a single night.
I'll be there at the audition.
If you come to my tournament.
Okay. I'll be there.
Pinky swear?
See. You wrap your hands like this.
I swear...
I'll be there at your audition.
No matter what happens.
And I promise,
to cheer bigger than anyone else...
when you win.
Wha UP! Mr. Han!
Did I say come in?
I think you did I mean...
Mr. Han Can I please come in?
Yes.
So what are we doing today?
Same!
Woah Mr. Han!
I told you!
I get it! Okay!
Be respectful!
I got it!
I put on my jacket a thousand times!
I took it off a thousand TIMES!
Okay!
This is stupid!
I'm done!
They can beat me up if they want to!
And do you know why you only have one student?
Cos you don't know kungfu!
Xiao Dre!
What!
Come here!
Jacket on.
Mr. Han I'd already...
JACKET ON!
Jacket on.
I don't have a jacket ...
JACKET ON!
Be strong.
Jacket on.
Firm.
Jacket off.
Remember.
Always strong.
Jacket off.
Strong!
Left back!
Right feet back!
Left feet back!
Hang up your jacket!
Wow...!
Focus!
- Okay!
Always concentrate.
Left back!
Right foot back!
Pick up your jacket!
Stay!
Pick up your jacket.
Ouch!
Strong.
Hang it up.
Hang it up!
Hang up!
Attitude!
Strike!
Hang up! And Attitude!
Harder!
HARDER!
Good.
But no face.
AGAIN!
Kungfu lives.
Everything we do. Xiao Dre!
It lives in...
how we put on a jacket.
How we take off the jacket.
It lives in how we treat people.
Everything...
is kungfu.
So why didn't we take the Ceroco?
I don't drive the Ceroco.
Do you have a licence?
Yes
So you have a licence...
and a car.
And we're on a train.
Please be quiet.
I'm just saying.
Seems like we could save a lot of money.
Don't you think?
You always ask this many questions?
It's alright.
So what are we learning today?
Chi.
Internal energy.
'The essense of life'.
It moves inside of us.
Flows through our bodies'.
Gives us power from within.
I get it.
Like 'The Force' in Star Wars.
You're Yoda and I'm like...
I'm like a 'Jedi'.
Hey! Trishaw!
Driver: Thank you!
Is this where you learned kungfu?
Yes.
Everything good about me was born here.
Xiao Dre,
you can leave your backpack
and skateboard here.
So where we're going?
We journey to the top of the mountain.
Drink from the Dragon Well.
'Dragon Well'.
It's probably closer than it is,
looking at it.
Right?
Are we there yet?
Soon.
Oh...
How do you say water in Chinese?
Shui (water).
I need some shui.
I'm really...
thirsty.
I'm thirsty Mr. Han.
Water on top of mountain.
Xiao Dre.
The journey is complete.
Is this the 'Dragon Well' ?
Yes.
I stood here...
with my father.
When I was your age.
He told me its...
'Magic kungfu water'.
You drink and nothing can defeat you.
It's the best water that I ever tasted.
Did you see the lady with the snake?
Yes.
She was doing the cobra thing.
She was like...
copying the snake and it was like...
right here and she was like...
You did not watch closely enough.
Xiao Dre.
The snake was copying the woman.
But.
Don't get it.
Look.
What do you see?
Me
My own reflection.
Yes.
Now what do you see?
It's blurry.
Yes.
Women...
like still water.
Quiet.
Calm.
In here.
And in here.
So.
The snake.
Reflects her action.
Like still water.
Like a mirror.
Yes.
So...
she controlled a snake by doing nothing?
Be still and doing nothing.
Are two very different things.
She used her chi essense didn't she?
Very good.
You gotta teach me that like...
how to control people.
There's only one person you
need to learn how to control.
Who?
Empty your mind!
Flow with my movement.
Connect through the energy.
Around you.
I kinda just want to learn the cobra thing.
Cobra.
Takes a lifetime.
Requires great focus.
But how great focus?
Woah...!
Oh my god.
Mr. Han?
Your focus.
Needs more focus.
Mr. Han?
Thank you Mr. Han.
There's no such thing as fortune cookies in China.
Dre, please be careful crossing the street.
You just scared the life outta me the other day.
Have the right of way.
And the symbols.
I can't get the symbols right on the bathrooms.
And I stay.
Walking into the men's restroom.
The other day I walked in...
There was a ninety year old chinese man.
He thought he was going to get a little treat.
Dre, please stop that!
You look crazy.
Here! Eat your noodles!
Ouch!
Uggh!
Up.
Mr. Han what's going on?
Ooh!
Wow!
Anticipation.
I can't see that...
Don't see it. Feel it.
Dammit Mr. Han!
I felt that one!
Mr. Han!
What?
Concentrate.
Okay.
Okay, do I get the stick now?
Woah!
Ouch!
Dre! You okay?
I'm okay.
So Mr. Han what time we training tomorrow?
Xiao Dre, we're not training tomorrow.
Why not?
Wu Ji Bi Fan (Haste makes waste).
Means too much something is not good.
You train a lot.
You need rest.
A day off!
Yes! Mr. Han.
Yes!
Xiao Dre need to REST!
Yes, Mr. Han.
You rest too.
Love you Mr. Han.
Peace!
Hey!
Are you okay?
My audition is tomorrow on the sixth.
But isn't that what you've been auditioning for?
Yes, of course.
Don't worry. You got it.
What if they don't pick me?
Meiying wait!
Okay.
First of all.
I'm gonna be there with you.
And B...
All you have to do is do
what your teacher says.
Play the pauses.
It's easy watch!
See?
I have to practise.
Wait!
Would you be fun!
What?
I'm sorry. I think you don't
speak chinese.
Would you be fun!
Too much good stuff fits bad stuff.
Oh!
Wu Ji Bi Fan (Haste makes waste).
Yeah!
Would you be fun!
C'mon!
Where are we going?
Darn! Have you been to the gym?
No!
- C'mon we're gonna have some fun!
Dre!
C'mon! I know you wanna go have so fun.
Don't do it.
What do you see?
Me.
Now! what do you see?
You go c'mon!
C'mon!
You know you can dance.
Go ahead!
Hooof...
That's like...
Amm... American dancing like.
You should have a group.
No!
With like other people in it.
And they're dancing behind you.
Doing the same stuff.
Hello?
I'm sorry.
I understand.
The Audition...
It was changed to two today.
But they said it was tomorrow.
- How could it happen.
It's in twenty minutes.
My father is coming to get me.
Meiying's mother: What were you thinking?
Where did you go?
Excuse me, Sir!
Excuse me, coming through!
They're here.
C'mon, c'mon...
Excuse me!
Hey! She's like...
totally gonna get it right?
Because that was just...
Great!
Hey!
That was ...
Fantastic!
That was... You just...
You played so beautifully and...
We can no longer be friends.
You are bad for my life.
See you at the tournament.
Don't be late for that!
Mr... Mr. Han!
Mr. HAN!
We'll not train today.
What are you doing?
It's July 8th.
Why'd you break the car?
His name was Gang Gang.
Xiao Dre, how old are you?
Twelve.
He was ten.
He was so beautiful.
Her name was Zhang.
She was a singer.
Not professional.
She sing only for me.
What happened?
It was a steep hill.
Lots of rain.
The car just...
I was driving.
We argued about something.
I was so angry...
I lost control.
I try to remember...
I try to remember what we were arguing about...
I hope it was something important.
Every year...
I fix a car...
still fix nothing.
Punch!
Good.
Mr. Han!
Down!
One more.
Hurry!
Win or lose!
Doesn't matter.
Fight hard.
Earn respect.
Boys will leave you alone.
Have present for you.
Mr. Han!
Man!
It's the one Bruce Lee had!
Great!
Thank you.
You have taught me a very important lesson.
Xiao Dre.
Life.
Will knock us down.
But we can choose...
whether or not...
to get back up.
You're the best friend I ever had.
Mr. Han.
Okay.
Wait! Aa...
Can you help me with something?
Dre...
Is your dad home?
Meiying's father...
My name is Dre Parker...
My feelings towards your daughter...
are respectful and honourable.
Meiying was once...
a very good friend of mine.
She has taught me,
what true friendship means.
I would like to be given another chance.
I would accept any punishment.
If I am unable to honour our friendship.
I hereby would like to ask for your permission
and would like the opportunity,
to prove myself and to your family.
That's it.
Meiying have told me that she have promised
to be there when you compete.
Our family have never gone back on our promises.
My daughter told me,
that she made a promise to be at your tournament.
In our family,
we do not break our promises.
Thank you.
Rock and roll.
Announcer: Everyone in the crowd!
Welcome to the Junior Wushu tournament!
Let the tournament begin!
Stop!
First fight.
Proceed to platform '5'.
Thank you.
You're up.
What's that?
Rulebook.
You don't know the rules?
Yes, of course I know the rules!
Simple.
You hit him.
Don't let him hit you.
What?
Mr.
They're gonna kill me.
Ah...
two points to win.
Go!
Aim two times.
Referee: Come here.
Salute!
Get ready!
Begin!
Wait!
If you exit again!  Points will be deducted.
That's a warning.
You cannot run outta the mat.
Next time you lose a point.
Go!
Be strong!
C'mon Dre!
Begin!
Stop!
Out of area!
Penalty!
Blue, one point!
Red, one point!
Good job.
Next time no face!
I'm sorry I can't help it.
Okay, okay...
Next point winner.
C'mon baby!
Begin!
Red! Winner!
Red, one point!
Winner!
The fight's over!
Go.
Begin!
Red!
Announcer: Dre Parker has entered the semi finals!
From now on...
Semi final matches.
Three points to win.
Be kinda high if I won this thing.
Right? Mr. Han.
Be kinda high,
if you focus.
Yeah well... after that!
Alright stairs here.
Now's the time
for the first match for the semi finals!
Now we have Chung from the Long Cheng Martial Arts School!
Against Wu Pi of Xi Xing Martial Arts School!
Begin!
Halt!
Red, one point!
Master Han would you get ready?
Halt!
Halt!, Halt!
Winner! Chung!
Announcer: Next up is Lai Zi How from
Long Cheng Martial Arts School!
And he's challenger is Dre Parker!
Empty your mind.
Focus!
To your position!
Get ready!
Begin!
Improper conduct! Disqualified!
Be still!
Xiao Dre!
You okay?
Don't move, don't move.
Doctor!
Is it serious?
He cannot compete.
You did well. Young warrior.
You did your family proud.
Doctor says,
you did great.
Thank you.
You okay, baby?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Announcer: If challenger Dre is unable to
participate within the next two minutes.
We would unfortuately have to
disqualify him from the compeition.
Long Cheng Martial Arts School will
be announced winner by default!
Wow! We have seen many puglists
representing different schools...
Can you guys give us a second?
Yeah okay...
Sure...
Baby whatever you need.
Do you think I could have won?
Win or lose, doesn't matter Xiao Dre.
You know that's not what I mean.
Yes...
I think you have a good chance.
So let's do the firery cup thing!
You don't need to fight anymore...
You have proven everything,
you need to prove.
What!
That I can get beat up easy and then...
Quit!
It's not balance...
it's not real kungfu.
You said!
That when life knock's you down.
You can choose whether or
not to get back up!
Well, I'm trying to get back up.
And why won't you help me?
Because...
I cannot watch you get hurt anymore.
Please Mr. Han.
PLEASE.
Just tell me Xiao Dre...
Why?
Why you need to go back out there so badly?
Because I'm still scared.
No matter what happens.
Tonight when I leave...
I don't want to be scared anymore.
Announcer: Due to injuries, Dre Parker
will no longer be competing.
Hold on...
Dre Parker will still be able to compete.
Wait!
Announcer: And the champion is...
Judge: Dre Parker will still be competing.
Announcer: So Dre is still in...
Dre Parker will still be competing!
Crowd: Dre! Dre! Dre!...
Referee: Back up!
Begin!
Red, one point!
Xiao Dre!
C'mon Dre!
You can do this Dre!
Begin!
Halt!
Pause!
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Master Li: Go for his weakness.
Get ready!
Salute!
Begin!
Now we are neck and neck!
Another point and we will have our champion!
Begin!
Blue, one point!
And the winner is...
Teacher, please let me present.
Dre!... he's my hero...
I love you...
so much.
Shifu! (Master).