DISC JOCKEY:
Hey, hey, L.A., L.A.,
it's a brand new day.
What you say, babe?
If you wanna get down,
you got to get up
and I'm your
wake up man, baby.
The J.B. is here
rappin' in your ear.
The J.B.'s not on your radio,
your radio's not really on.
Too hot for you?
Then you stay cool with
the baddest sound in town!
This is KGYS,
where the music's
always the best.
News and weather at 8:00
and don't be late,
'cause you ain't got
the news till you get it
straight from KGYS.
It's Friday. T.G.I.F.
and there's smog
in the basin,
traffic on the freeway,
crime on the streets,
music all day long at KGYS.
It's 7:47 baby,
that's a good time to fly.
Can you dig it?
Hey, get right tonight.
Tonight's the night.
J.B.'s Disco Dance
and Show, live at
Howard's Grand Casino
Music Hall and Rib Shack
and you can be there!
Or be square!
Now, there are only
three pair of tickets left
and I got 'em right here
in my hot little hand
and I'm gonna
give 'em away today!
'Cause they ain't
no good tomorrow,
so when you
hear this sound...
MAN:  Disco dance!
DISC JOCKEY:
Get on the phone and call
J.B. at 5-5-5 KGYS.
And if you name the tune,
two of those tickets
can be yours.
Remember now,
that's 5-5-5 KGYS.
The eagle flies
today, payday! Ooh!
Listen to that eagle scream.
Don't fold it,
I wanna hold it.
Money don't buy
no love, honey,
but it gets you the best
low calorie substitute.
We'll be right back
with you after this
station identification.
Hey, peace, Lonnie.
How you be, man?
All right.
I heard that.
(CHUCKLES)
(OVER RADIO)  Good morning.
This is Billy Bass
and this is the news.
In Washington a new scandal
as Congressional investigators
probed into the rumors
of male Congressional Aides
being hired by male
Congressmen in exchange
for sexual favors.
This will never do, honey.
Here in Los Angeles,
Gay Activist spokesman,
Harry Twig,
issued
a statement applauding
the alleged violation
of the ethics
committee rules,
after an extended filibuster
in a special caucus.
A Southern Senior
Committee Member
replied that
he had no objection
to homosexuals
as long as they
stayed in their place.
(WHOOPING)
Move, will you?
Get outta the way!
(CONTINUOUS HONKING)
Hey, hey!
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Listen, you don't...
You don't know what you
have to do with Lonnie.
Girl, you're crazy!
You're very confused.
Just shut up!
Don't tell me to shut up!
Just shut up, okay?
You shut up!
Hey, Otis,
is, uh, Mona here?
She's late again
as usual, T.C.
All right,
all right, all right.
Huh? What?
Today we got
the Big Three.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Uh, the baseball pool,
the fight and the jai alai.
All right.
Jai alai?
Yeah. They're playing
jai alai in Tijuana.
I thought that was a dance.
A dance?
Hey, I'm gonna bet
two dollars on the fight.
On the fight?
Yes, sir.
All right.
Up tight! Outta sight!
Stand and deliver, honey.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Sweet sexy thing!
Watch it,
here comes Ann Margaret.
Keep an eye on your zippers.
(LAUGHING)
One thing you can be
sure of, Hippo,
is when I'm around
your body is safe.
(ALL WHOOPING)
Hey, Lindy,
where's my money?
Slide, you know I ain't got
no sweet potatoes today.
Hi, I'm Floyd!
And I'm Lloyd!
(ALL CHEERING)
Oh, Hollywood, Hollywood!
Hi, I'm Floyd!
Ho! And I'm Lloyd!
And we're the 'Futuristies'!
¶ Sittin' by my telephone
¶ Waitin' for my woman
to call
(VOCALIZING)
¶ I don't know
what I did wrong
¶ I just wish that she
would come back home ¶
(VOCALIZING)
Go! Uh, do it!
Do it!
Oh, do it, aha.
Uh, do it. Uh, do it,
do it, do it!
All right.
We got an audition
for an agent today.
How'd you like
our new opening?
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Lonnie, what'd you
think about it?
Well, it's improving.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, hey.
LLOYD: I said, no! No!
That's all right.
They're fools.
They don't know!
(ALL WHISTLING)
Well, kiss my grits!
Aw, try it for the night.
What's the matter, man,
you goin' to a funeral?
Carry on, honey.
Ritzy Titsie!
You know, somebody
around here gotta
have a little class.
BOTH: Ooh,
little is right!
(GUFFAWING)
MAN: (ON RADIO)
...In our policy
after victory
in the war resistance
against Japan...
Will you just put
that stuff away, Irwin?
August 15, 1945
from the selective...
I heard you! I heard you!
I heard you already, damn it!
Good morning, Mr. B.
Morning, Snapper.
Good morning, Mr. B.,
how are you?
Lonnie! Irwin!
Come on, Irwin! Irwin!
Hey, Irwin.
Hey, Lonnie.
How you doin'?
SNAPPER: Irwin,
how you doin', Irwin?
Hey, baby,
what's happening?
Aw, man.
I don't think
I know that one.
Hey, lay back, baby.
I catch you later.
CHUCO: Hey, T.C.,
I ain't heard nothin' about
the Fly in a long time, man.
Way it is
with the Fly, brother.
He just lays back, man,
and he just
checks the buzz...
(WHOOPING)
Hear the cry.
Whoo! Is it a bird?
Is it a plane?
No, dude,
it's the Fly!
All right. Man.
All right.
Check this out!
You ain't seen nothin' yet.
Whoa!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Put your heart
in my hands, honey.
Look out, Mr. Clean!
Now, hear this!
I believe it is exactly
two minutes eleven seconds
to opening.
(ALL CACKLING)
Thank you.
Keep the change.
You probably noticed
I ain't got nothin'
against you people.
against any people.
That's what I think
we need is more love
in the world.
I don't know about marriage
and I don't know if
I'd go that far
but, uh, I believe in
the lunch counter thing.
I think, if a guy
wants to be able
to get somethin' to eat,
he oughta be able to
get somethin' to eat,
you know.
Come on,
let's move it up there!
(HONKING)
What is this?
A Mobil Gas Economy Run?
Come on,
what's goin' on out there?
Bunch of bastards!
(CONTINUOUS HONKING)
Move it!
Yeah, you're probably
wonderin' why I even
picked you up
in the first place, huh?
Lotta guys are scared.
Ah, they're scared of
gettin' ripped off,
they're scared they're
gonna get beat outta
their fares.
MAN: (ON RADIO)
A KGYS public health
service announcement.
Hi, Leon.
Remember,
cancer cures smoking.
Watch it, Marsha.
My son's here today.
Oh, okay.
I used to drive
a gypsy cab in New York.
Know what
a gypsy cab is?
Gypsy cab will go to Harlem.
Gypsy cab will go to
Puerto Rican neighborhood.
That's what it is.
We used to have a slogan
on the side of the gypsy cab.
Kinda funny
now that I'm workin'
with the Yellow Cabs.
And the slogan used to be,
"We will go anywhere
we are not yellow!"
(CHUCKLES) Get it?
We are not yellow!
That's no kind of
slur on the Chinese
or anything like that.
But I ain't afraid,
uh, because
I trust people.
I trust people because
I like 'em, you know?
Come on, you bastards!
(HONKING)
Come on! I could
tell from a block away
that you was honest.
I could tell
by your eyes.
Well, not the eyes, actually,
from a block away,
but I go by body length.
Just your body length.
You got a real honest body.
You bastard!
WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
Philadelphia Flyers record run
in the women's 100 yard dash
was point five seconds
better than Wilma Rudolph's
Olympic record
set a decade ago.
And in baseball,
another record was set
when Reggie Jackson hit two
consecutive Grand Slam
home runs in one inning
to aid in the 16 to one
undeniable slaughter
of his former teammates.
Now that's what I call
swingin' a big bat!
The weather for
Los Angeles and vicinity
continued clear and warm,
with light smog
in the basin.
79 at the airport,
83 downtown
and in KGYS land,
watch out Los Angeles,
89 degrees.
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, come on.
How about that
Reggie Jackson?
Reggie who?
He's a great
baseball player.
Honey, baseball
is not my game.
Well, do you know
about this...
MAN: (ON RADIO)
...Soul support in
greater Los Angeles.
Remember now,
we're gonna be
givin' away tickets
to J.B.'s big
Disco Dance
and show tonight.
Now, here's a smooth one
called, Water.  Take a sip.
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
Good morning, Abdullah!
Where were you
yesterday, Duane?
And you're late today, Duane.
You better get off
of my case, Earl.
And my name is
Abdullah Mohammed Akbar,
all right?
Mohammed Akbar.
(LAUGHING)
Hey, man, you all right?
Hey, Abullah!
No, man!
You got a problem?
I mean, you need somethin'?
No.
Just wondered if
you was all right.
I'm okay, man.
Go to work,
I'll be there
in a second, okay?
See you outside.
Yeah, uh, excuse me,
I realize you don't get to
look up very often,
but, uh, did you
happen to see a big,
tall, black blonde chick?
Uh, big, big, black,
blonde chick?
Red boots.
Long, big, black...
Yeah, black blonde!
No.
Scruggy!
What's the matter, man?
You should be feelin' great!
Oh, look,
I'm worried about Charlene.
I mean, maybe I should
call her or somethin'.
You know, I am...
Ain't never stayed out
all night before.
It's not cool to
let a woman take
you for granted, man.
Besides, you was
terrific last night, huh?
Yeah, well,
that's another thing.
I got a burn
down there now.
I mean, suppose
I caught somethin'.
Suppose I got the...
Hey, this ain't funny.
Suppose I got the clap,
how am I gonna explain that?
Hey, man,
you ain't caught nothin'
but a case of the guilts.
Will guilt burn?
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(ON RADIO)  All right,
this is J.B. back on the case
with a change of pace
with another better
than the other.
All right, come on, go man.
Hey, come on, fellas.
Hey, come on,
what are you doin'?
Hey, come on!
This is KGYS, Los Angeles,
the Hip Trip.
Guaranteed to put
more dip in your hip,
more glide in your stride.
Now, on the flip side,
here's the hottest
sound in town.
The coldest sound around.
J.B. the round man
of sound, live and in
full livin' color.
More pleasure
per pound, get down.
¶ You might not ever get rich
¶ But let me tell ya
it's better than
diggin' a ditch.
¶ There ain't no tellin'
who ya might meet
¶ A movie star or maybe
even an Indian Chief
¶ Working at the car wash
¶ Workin' at
the car wash, yeah
¶ Come on and sing it
with me car wash
¶ Get with the feelin'
y'all car wash, yeah
¶ Come summer
the work gets kinda hard
¶ This ain't no place to be
if ya planned on being a star
¶ Let me tell you
it's always cool
¶ And the boss don't mind
sometimes if you act the fool
¶ At the car wash
¶ Talkin' about
the car wash, yeah
¶ Come on, y'all, and sing it
for me car wash
¶ Car wash, yeah
¶ Work and work
¶ Well, those cars
never seem to stop comin'
¶ Work and work
¶ Keep those rags
and machines hummin'
¶ Work and work
¶ My fingers to the bone
¶ At five I can't wait
'til it's time to go home
¶ Hey, get your
car washed today
¶ Fill up and you
don't have to pay
¶ Come on and give us a play
¶ Get a wash right away
¶ Car wash
Talkin' about the car wash
¶ Car wash, yeah
¶ Come on, y'all, and sing it
with me car wash
¶ Sing it with feeling y'all
¶ Car wash, yeah
¶ Car wash
¶ Those cars never
seem to stop comin'
¶ Well, I say
keep those rags
and machines hummin'
¶ Car wash
¶ Let me tell you
it's always cool
¶ And the boss don't mind
sometimes if ya act a fool
¶ At the... ¶
Say, Mona!
Hey, baby, it's me!
T.C., mama. Hey!
You'll like it there, baby,
MAN: (ON RADIO)  All right.
That is so bad,
super smash number three
with a bullet
to slow the pace to taste.
Here's a bit of mellow funk.
Lonnie, how are you?
How you doin', Mr. B.?
How's the family?
Everybody is all right!
Kids okay?
Yeah.
Charlie?
Fine!
Hey, Duane?
Duane, I wanna
talk to you, Duane.
I don't know how many times
I gotta tell you this,
my name is Abdullah.
Abdullah!
Where was Abdullah yesterday?
Somethin' came up.
Something always comes up!
Something came up
three times for...
Yeah, you want these cars
washed or don't you?
Here you go!
Looks good!
Good morning!
I don't want you
to leave here without
realizing what
I can do for your car.
Like what?
Take over the payments
for me?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
And there ain't no
black Superman, man.
Dig it, man. I would be
the first, Lloyd.
I wouldn't be like Superman,
that square sucker, jack man.
I'd be sharp,
sharp, sharp, man.
Yeah.
Oh, wow, man I'd have me
a bad black cape, man,
a helmet,
look like two big eyes,
you know, and a brim, man.
You're full of shit!
Oh, come on, Lloyd,
like, well, man,
like I just be able to walk
up buildings, brother, man!
Hey, and nobody
would mess with me, man.
Nobody, man,
'cause like I would be
the Fly!
(MIMICS BUZZING)
But you still
full of shit, though!
You wouldn't
talk to me like that
if I was the Fly!
Oh, yes I would!
Because then,
you'd be full of
fly shit!
You know what else, man?
There ain't nothin'
lower than fly shit!
Not kangaroo shit,
elephant shit
or chicken shit!
Ain't nothin'
lower than fly shit!
(MIMICS BUZZING)
You crazy man,
I swear to God,
I'll kill you, man,
you ever do that again!
You ever touch
my shirt again,
I'll kill you!
EARL: It's only four hours,
give you the best shine
you ever had.
All right, do it!
Look, uh, you didn't,
by any chance,
happen to see a, uh,
tall, blonde, black girl,
did you, around here?
No. No.
Okay, yeah,
go ahead, get in!
I'm on my way
to see Slide,
play a number. Earl?
Never sucker me
with that lame game.
Go lose your money, fool!
Fool?
Who you callin' fool?
Say, what makes you
think you're so special?
'Cause I'm the nigger
who doesn't get wet
around here.
I'm the star.
Just like me, shine, shine.
Only you stoop a lot lower.
MR. B: (OVER LOUDSPEAKER)
Irwin, report to the office.
A lot lower.
Irwin, wherever you are,
report to the office.
Did you hear
your father, Irwin?
Report to the front office.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Dee-Luxe Car Wash!
Hold on, please.
Leon, it's your wife.
Myrna? Uh, yes.
Uh, uh, sure we can talk.
Why not? Uh...
Yes.
Uh, yes.
Don't do that!
Now, don't do that!
Put that down!
Nothing! Nothing!
Myrna, is that all, Myrna?
Myrna, I'm busy, Myrna!
The new drapes
aren't long enough
in the living room.
What does she care
how much it costs me?
Oh, poor Leon!
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Watch it! Watch it!
My son! My son!
Uh, Irwin, uh, would you
come to the office?
I wanna talk to you.
(CHUCKLES)
Irwin, uh, I hate to
interrupt your
summer vacation,
but maybe
you can look over
last week's receipts,
give us the benefit
uh, of what you're learning
in Business Management, huh?
Double check
my figures, why don't ya?
I wanna work
with the men, Dad.
What?
I wanna work with the men!
Listen, Pop, I wanna be
one of the working class,
like Mao says,
"Workers of the World, unite."
I'm hearing this
from a college man?
$20,000 worth
of education,
you wanna wash cars?
Listen, Pop.
"All work done
for the masses..."
And that book again.
I don't want to see
that book again!
All right, Pop,
hang loose!
(SIGHS)
Go ahead! Go ahead!
Wash cars! Wash cars!
All right!
J.B.:  So, hang in there,
'cause we're
makin' it all happen.
J.B. here on KGYS.
Keep that glide
in your stride.
It's 10:18 in the A.M.
the midmorning hour.
It's 75 out at the ocean,
and the surf
reported good from Malibu
to Newport Beach,
so this next tune is for
all you surfers out there.
Hang Ten!
You all right, Calvin?
Huh? You all right?
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Didn't I tell you
not to skate through here?
Now, go on, get outta here.
Calvin, not...
Watch out!
FLOYD: Oh,
are you here again?
Yeah, that's right!
Ah, go play
in the street, Calvin.
Your mama!
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Here's somethin' for you!
Go skate under a truck!
Listen, I'd like to
talk to someone
and get some information
about a social disease.
Well, I can't right now,
I'm working.
Uh-huh.
No.
Not yet.
Well...
Well, it's just
kinda hangin' there,
lookin' sick, you know?
MAN: (ON RADIO)  I know
you're diggin' it 'cause
I dig playin' it, babe.
Hey, Irwin, you cool?
I'm cool!
Hey, what's happening?
And then after,
and then after we...
Looks like the
Car Wash heir wants
to play in the water.
Mmm! Look at that child!
Hey, brothers,
I'm here to unite with you.
Ooh!
Stoned to the tits, honey!
Say, uh, Irwin,
Irwin why don't you
go 'round there
with Lloyd and Floyd,
and work with the steam, huh?
Right!
Go ahead!
(LAUGHING)
I think I better go
work with the dryers.
Mmm-hmm.
(GUFFAWING)
(EXCLAIMING)
You got a problem
there, boys?
Ooh, man! Far out!
You okay, kid?
Oh, wow! What a trip!
Hey, hey, stop...
Stop that horsing around!
All right, stop that
foolin' around, Irwin! Irwin!
You better go put on
somethin' dry!
MR. B: Wash cars!
Come on, wash cars!
Wow, look at that! I'm
the first human being to
go through the car wash!
Number one! Number one!
Hey, Mr. B.!
Uh, hey, kid,
this is no playground, huh?
How come all the other
car washes got fancy brushes
and you still
wash cars by hand?
That's the feature
of this car wash,
we do it all by hand.
The personal touch!
Can't you read the sign?
I think you're
just too cheap
to put in machines.
Uh, come on,
get outta here, huh?
Beat it! Beat it!
(BLOWING RASPBERRIES)
(OVER RADIO)
Radio, radio, radio, radio.
WOMAN:  Because you
wanna keep yourself
fresh and feminine
you'll wanna use
Wild Flower
for personal hygiene.
because it's made for you.
MAN: (LAUGHS)
I drink it every day.
Can you dig it?
And, when I do,
it makes me go...
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Sorry!
Hey, that's okay, baby!
You're my kind of woman!
Disco dance!
First person to call me
at KGYS at 5-5-5, KGYS
and name this song gets to win
the first pair of tickets
to J.B.'s
Disco Dance and Show,
don't you know.
Drop a dime, get on the line.
That's 5-5-5, KGYS.
All right!
Oh! Gimme, gimme,
I ain't got no change.
Call me now.
(LAUGHING UNCONTROLLABLY)
What's that cat
lookin' for, man?
You mean I ain't got a dime?
JUSTIN: You're kiddin'!
He's funny.
We have a winner
in Compton.
How 'bout that?
He's out of his mind.
Man, I knew the song,
didn't have no change. Man.
Quick as a flash,
no cash, T.C.!
The next song, T.C.
is Swanee River.
Yeah, I never liked you
anyway, Slide.
Hey, T.C.,
you need a dime?
Yeah, thank you, man.
I mean, it's on me.
WOMAN: Of course it's busy,
it's a beauty salon.
Just break in.
Rickie, darling,
hold it in for Mommy.
Come on,
you can do it.
Now, now if you
have to throw up,
do it out the window.
Away from the car.
(RETCHING)
Operator, this is urgent!
Please, uh, look, if you...
If they do come through,
will you please
phone me at this number?
It's absolutely urgent
that I talk to them.
No, away! Away from the car!
Hippo, you got yourself
a customer, honey!
Oh, my God!
It's gonna
eat the paint out!
I told you...
I told you, for Mommy, to
throw up away from the car.
Can you get it off?
Can you get it off in a hurry,
before it wrecks the finish?
You better get outta there!
Come outta there!
I'm very late!
Do you think it's gonna
eat through the paint?
Look at you! You're just...
Uh, can you tell me
where the, uh...
Over there.
Thank you very much.
You will hurry with this
because the paint...
The finish is gonna be...
Oh, if  Monsieur Mark calls...
If he calls would you ask
him to take me a half
an hour later, please?
Sure.
Thank you.
Hello,
is somebody in there?
Is somebody in there?
This is an emergency!
I have an emergency!
I think someone's
in there, ma'am.
What?
Oh, I... Someone's...
Please! Open up!
(RETCHING)
Oh, please!
Uh, Miss Thing
wants it clean, honey.
Uh, Charlie,
come take over for me
for a minute, all right?
What is going on in there?
Why don't you open this door?
Oh, God, please.
Please, God,
open this door!
Oh, my God,
it stinks in here!
It's supposed to, lady,
it's the toilet.
I'm not gonna go in there.
It's the ladies' room,
WOMAN: (OVER WALKIE-TALKIE)
Six-A-eleven. Six-A-eleven
ambulance injury...
MAN: (ON RADIO)
Beautiful, beautiful!
Stay with me,
'cause we'll be givin' away
tickets all day,
so we can boogie all night.
Get down, baby!
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
MAN: You wanna
get that, Mona?
Hello, Five Spot!
¶ Mona Lisa, Mona Lisa
¶ Men have named you... ¶
Mona? Mona?
(BLOWING RASPBERRIES)
Oh, my God!
I'm sorry.
I know you didn't do it!
It's all right.
It's all right!
Is it clean yet?
Sir? Is it?
Oh, yes, ma'am.
Thank you very much.
Rickie, get into the car.
God, I see a speck.
Oh, it's in the paint.
No, that is
not in the paint!
Do it again, please!
Lady, believe me,
it's in the paint!
I do not believe you!
Please, try that again!
Lady, I'm telling you,
it's in the paint!
Look for yourself!
I am looking for myself!
I brought this car in.
You are refusing to do
your job, I am refusing
to tip you!
Just shows you what happens
when you go out of
Beverly Hills for any service!
Mom!
Not now, Rickie!
Adios, Miz Beverly Hills!
(GASPS)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
MAN: (ON RADIO)
I know you gonna dig this.
Guaranteed to ease
your pain and take the chain
off your brain.
It's long and low
and dedicated
to what makes
the world go 'round.
Hey, guys, look who's here!
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Whose car is that?
That belongs to
the supreme black man,
that's who!
Yeah, man,
that's Daddy's car, man.
Daddy Rich!
You never watch him on TV?
T.C.: That's the man
with the answers
to all my questions.
SLIDE: Go on
with your bad self!
Praise the Lord,
praise the Lord!
ALL: Amen! Amen!
Praise the Lord!
Well,
praise this car, honey.
Thank you, Miss.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah, Daddy.
Daddy Rich,
what's your secret, brother?
Your secret, please!
DADDY RICH:
Thank you, brother.
Good to see you!
The secret?
There are no secrets.
Uh-huh.
Believe that.
I believe that.
Except believe in the Lord!
Right!
Whoo!
And believe in yourself!
Yeah, that's right.
I believe it.
And most of all...
Uh-huh.
Believe in that
Federal green.
ALL: (CHEERING) Yeah!
'Cause money walks
and bullshit talks!
How you doin', brother?
Daddy Rich,
I been followin' you
for over five years.
Well, bless you,
brother, bless you.
Would you allow me
the privilege of
shinin' your shoes?
Please.
Well, you know
what they say,
"I take what is
given unto me."
(ALL CHEERING)
Daddy Rich's special polish.
Special polish.
Ooh! That's a real one.
What's it feel like
in there, Lindy?
Like being in church
with Burt Reynolds, honey!
Brother, I'd like you
to drink with me,
'cause my cup runneth over.
All right.
Blessed be the Tithe.
All right!
ALL: Yeah!
From the body
to the heavens!
And a little bit
for the earth!
(ALL CHEERING)
Amen, brothers.
ALL: Amen!
It's good, too.
Don't even look dirty.
You gonna wash this car
because of a little
pigeon shit on the trunk?
No, not the car,
just the spot.
Don't let the water
be hotter than 66.4.
Water?
You better speak to
this gentleman.
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Daddy Rich, ever since
I've been followin' you,
I got a new house
and a color TV.
All right.
Praise the Lord!
Why don't you
tell everybody how you
got so rich, Daddy Rich?
This is one nigger
you ain't foolin, brother.
I mean, I'm hip to this game,
you runnin' down
these people here!
What can I do
for you, brother?
Oh, the same thing
you doin' for everybody else!
Nothin'!
I guess you don't believe
in my church.
The Church of Divine
Economic Spirituality!
That's right.
I don't believe in it.
Then you don't believe in God?
Not your God.
My God's doin'
all right by me.
He sure is.
He's doin' all right
by me, too.
Why don't you climb
on board, brother?
And believe in me?
And for a small fee,
I'll set you free,
'nearer Thy God to thee.
ALL: Amen!
Praise you, honey,
praise you!
'Cause it's
better to have money
and not to need it,
than to need it
and not to have it!
Yeah! Amen!
And there's a good place
in this world for money!
Yes, siree,
and I know where it is.
It's right here in my pocket.
Right! Okay!
You talkin'
just like a pimp!
(ALL JEERING)
SNAPPER: Answer him!
Answer him, Lord!
I don't get mad
at people like that.
You know why?
Because he's a revolutionary!
Yeah!
That's right, brother!
You must be leadin'
a bunch of fools!
Disrespect one that
he don't even know.
Wilson Sisters some of
the finest women
you ever wanna meet!
He don't know
nothin' about 'em!
Don't talk about 'em!
Yeah.
That's right!
If I wasn't a Christian man,
I'd probably be
kickin' in your ass!
(ALL CHEERING)
Drop on down, brother.
Drop on down, little brother!
I'm gonna drop on down
with a bit of light!
Make him apologize, Sister.
All right, you got it!
I shall not be moved!
Like a tree planted
by the water.
I shall not be moved!
¶ Rattatat Boom
¶ Make the sound
of a Jet Plane zoom
¶ Ooh rattatat boom
¶ Make the sound of a bomb
¶ You got to believe
in somethin'
¶ Why not believe in me?
¶ You got to believe
in somethin'
¶ Why not believe in me?
¶ Tell me brother,
what have I,
I done to you?
¶ To make you mean
and treat me the way you do
¶ Go on and wave
your flag, brother
¶ Start your revolution
¶ I'm willin' to
let you do your thing
¶ Tell me why
are you blind when it
comes to mine
¶ Oh, you gotta believe
in somethin'
¶ Why not believe in me?
¶ Me, me, me, me, me
¶ You gotta believe
in something
¶ Why not believe in me?
¶ Why don't you let
the Wilson Sisters
set you free?
¶ Take the
chain off your brain,
Lord and believe in me
¶ Lord, I said that!
¶ Take the chain
off your brain
¶ Listen, brother
¶ You always talkin' 'bout
the world needs changin'
¶ You better stop!
Take a look at yourself
¶ Stop ridiculin'
everybody else
¶ You gotta believe
in somethin'
¶ Why not believe in me?
¶ Why don't you let
the Wilson Sisters
set you free?
¶ You got to believe
in somethin'
¶ Yeah you got to believe,
believe, believe
Why not believe in me?
¶ The world don't need
to be no colder
¶ Get the chip
off your shoulder ¶
Uh, maybe this will
help you find Joe.
Seek and you shall find.
MAN: All right, Daddy Rich!
Bye, bye, Daddy.
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Can't understand?
You got it
in you, too, brother.
You got it in you!
MAN: (ON RADIO)
Here's the big one
back at you.
Hot lines have been ringin'
off all day for this one.
The chart climber
of the week!
(LAUGHING)
Take it on outta here, honey.
Okay, Lindy!
Ciao.
(BARKING)
You gonna drive that car.
You are driving
and cleaning that car!
Listen, it's okay.
He won't hurt you.
(GIGGLES)
Hey!
(SCREAMS)
He's a puppy dog!
Yeah, but just drive
your puppy dog
on around there
and get him in
the shower.
Trash!
Yeah, scum, scum!
Look, I'm gonna try to get
away after dinner,
you gonna be home?
I don't know. Maybe!
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, we got work to do!
We got work to do!
You cats have no maturity!
Hey, man,
there's a dog in the car.
(BARKING)
Sparky! Sparky!
Back dog!
Hey, man, open the door.
Go, go, git! Git him,
git him, he's out!
Sparky, come 'ere!
Catch him! Hold him!
Get him! Get him!
Hold him! Sparky!
Sparky!
Thank you.
All right, Sparky!
Let's go. Sparky!
Give me a break, will you,
Sparky, not here?
Ooh!
Yuk! Sparky! Ugh!
Ooh! Yuk!
Dog catcher!
Yeah.
Gets points with people.
Geronimo?
Hey!
I got a customer.
What's that for?
To clean up the dog shit!
(LAUGHS)
Hey! We don't
clean up no shit!
Uh-uh!
Don't gimme no lip,
clean up the shit!
Hey, you clean
it up, Earlie!
That's right,
you clean it up!
I don't get wet and I don't
clean up no dog shit!
But I do kick ass!
I love him!
Clean it up, Goody!
MAN: (ON RADIO)  It's five
minutes before the hour.
I promised you
more about
the Pop Bottle Bomber.
KGYS is first
with the flash
live from Parker
Center's soul sister
reporter LaVonne Styles.
Come on in!
Hi,
this is LaVonne Styles...
Oh, no, thank you!
And I'm here in
Parker Center talking to
Police Chief Dave Evis.
Chief Evis, have you
been able to identify
the Mad Bomber?
Hi, Sam.
EVIS:  He's a short,
nervous, straggly
haired individual.
How you doin', Marsha?
Okay.
And from recovered
fragments and eyewitness
descriptions
his principle weapon
seems to be
a common pop bottle
that's filled with,
oh, you know,
high explosives
and capped
with silver foil
containing a fuse device.
From Parker Center,
this is LaVonne Styles
for KGYS News.
Hi! Finite, honey.
Oh, thank you.
Lindy, you
lightened your hair.
I love it.
What color is it?
It's supposed to be
mango, honey,
but it's not right yet.
But wait till I get
to the school tonight.
Listen, Lindy,
I finally figured out
how I wanna have my nose done.
I was thinking
of doing Elizabeth Taylor
from here to here
and Olivia Newton-John
on the bottom.
What do you think, huh?
Flawless, honey!
Crimes, who is Earl
to tell me
to clean up that shit?
And then Geronimo run off
and leave me standin' there.
What? Who do they think...
Hey, Tall Chief.
Lend me your ears.
Yeah, uh, run that
by me again?
Lend me your ears.
Uh, lend me your lips.
Aw, come on, man,
I ain't askin' to
sleep with your mama.
Have you ever seen me
give up my ears?
No, man, but...
Well, then,
what possessed you
to even think
to ask to borrow my ears?
This chick wants to take
my picture, man.
Just for a minute.
You gotta do
better than that.
And just for a minute
ain't gonna get it
either, man!
You gotta
tell me somethin'!
Make me understand...
Well, you know,
it ain't every day
you can do somethin'
for a fellow American.
MAN: (ON RADIO)  Hey,
it's noon on the moon...
Hey, and don't
get it all dirty.
...midday in L.A.,
and time for Rod McGrew
to do it to you.
Yeah! Thank you, J.B.
This is your brother
Rod McGrew
and don't forget
to stick around
because later on
we've got two free tickets
to J.B.'s Disco Dance and Show
live at Howard's
Grand Casino Music Hall
and Rib Shack.
It happens tonight.
We want you to be
there for the funkiest
sounds in town like this.
(SNORTING)
(SCREAMING)
Hey, Tall Chief,
thanks a lot for the ears.
Any time, my friend.
Hey, uh, the Five Spot
got ribs today.
I'm gonna get me
some ribs.
Ooh, yeah.
How about y'all, man?
Uh, how about you, Abdullah?
You want some ribs?
Man, I told you,
I don't eat meat!
I'm off the pig!
I eat natural foods!
Not slave food!
Is that all right with you?
Uh, excuse me, brother,
but is ribs pig?
(LAUGHING)
(YELLING)
What did I do?
Shit, man, what did I do?
She's crazy,
she's got her brains
in her lungs!
Then the bitch
must be a genius!
(LAUGHING)
Hey, Marsha,
what'd you do to my lunch?
What'd you do
with my ears, man?
Nothin', man!
Yes, you did!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Looks like a nice lunch
you got there.
Hey, Geronimo.
Yeah, what do you want?
I was just thinkin'
maybe I oughta call Charlene?
Just to let her know
I'm all right?
Hey, Scruggy, man,
what'd I tell you
this morning?
It ain't cool for
your old lady to know
where you are
every minute
of every day, man.
You know what I mean?
Now tonight when you get home,
she's gonna be waitin' there
at the door
with your pipe
and your slippers
and that little negligee
you told me about.
You know, it ain't good
for her to know that
she can boss you around!
Well, I don't smoke a pipe
and I don't wear no slippers.
It's the decent thing...
Scruggy, I'm
the expert, right, huh?
Take it from me, man,
I've been married
three and a half times.
I should know.
Who should know
if I should know, huh?
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, hey
what the hell
is goin' on around here? Huh?
Hey,
this is no playground!
Wash cars, huh?
We're on our lunch hour!
Well then, eat your lunch.
Now, go ahead,
you heard me!
You heard Mr. B.!
That's right, Chuco,
I'm gonna get you!
In your dreams, Pocahontas.
Hey, come on!
MAN ON RADIO:
The station that brings you
(CHORAL)  Soul music!
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Get you some coffee?
Anybody want
a little more coffee?
¶ Oh, baby,
see things my way
¶ You don't even look my way
¶ I wanna get next to you ¶
Okay, what'll you have?
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
Hey, boy, you better
stay away from that hooker.
Hey, Goody, Goody,
watch! Watch!
Uh, let me have the special.
Two more specials.
You look
really pretty this mornin'.
What'll it be?
You and me.
Listen, T.C.,
I got no time...
Okay.
What's the special today?
Ribs and wings.
What kinda wings?
Chicken wings!
I've always been a
breast and thigh man myself.
Hey, Mona,
why you so cold to me?
I went out
with you once, didn't I?
Yeah, but what's that got...
Get your hand off o' me.
What about tonight?
T.C., it's just
not in the cards
for you and me.
Why?
Because you got no money,
no future, and no class,
and I'm not
going out with niggers
with no class anymore.
COOK: Pick up two.
Well, what about Chinese?
We got class?
(LAUGHS) Uh-oh.
(MAKING BUZZING SOUNDS)
Wanna get
outta the car, Harold?
(MURMURING)
Okay, okay.
May I?
(MURMURING)
MAN ON RADIO:  It's a mellow
afternoon, and I know
you're out there groovin',
you're funin' and sunin'
with your brother Rod McGrew
on the big KGYS,
playin' the sounds
that you want to hear
on your Soul Support Station
in greater Los Angeles.
Dad, let's rap.
It's very important
that you and I rap.
Ray Hoenig almost choked
to death the other day.
He was eating
a chicken sandwich
when his son decided,
at that moment, to tell him
he's a homosexual.
Got a piece of chicken
caught right here.
So, please talk later.
That's cool.
Irwin, Irwin?
(CLEARS THROAT) You're not
a homosexual, are you?
Not yet.
(COUGHING)
Can I help you, honey?
Uh, yeah.
You haven't by any
chance seen a small,
blonde, black chick
around here, have you?
No.
Buck, look at that.
Oh, shit.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
Get goin',
get goin', get goin'.
You think it's
the Invisible Man? (LAUGHS)
Come on, man...
...don't make me crack up.
Look, look, look!
(LAUGHS)
Hey, baby, how you doing?
(MUTTERS)
Good,
I'm glad to hear that.
What happened to you, man?
(MUTTERS)
Yeah?
That's some tough shit, man.
Oh, my God,
I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do.
CHUCO:
Hey, watch out, Goody!
(MUTTERING)
T.C.: Hey, man!
Look here,
I don't know what,
I don't know what you all...
(BABBLING)
Say, Goody,
you know you almost
got my hair wet, man.
My stuff ain't straight
like yours, it takes time!
(MAKING BUZZING SOUNDS)
Come on.
No, man.
That brother
don't know who he's
messin' with, man!
Come on, now, forget it.
He didn't mean nothin'.
No, that cat's lucky, Jack.
He don't know how close
he was.
I am the Fly!
Let me go! Hey!
(MAKES BUZZING SOUNDS)
T.C.: Cat got that
straight hair. Shoot,
my hair takes time
to get together, you know?
You know what
I'm talkin' about? Shoot!
What'd Chuco
do to that cat,
anyway?
JUSTIN: I don't know,
you know, he did somethin'
with Goody's ears, uh...
(T.C. LAUGHS)
MAN ON RADIO:
Yeah, that was nice,
and really, really smokin'.
Here's a new tune
called, Zigzag.
Let's see if this goody
is hot enough for you.
(MUTTERING)
You hungry, Harold?
(MUTTERS)
You want Chinese or Italian?
Italian.
Hey, peace treaty, man.
Yeah.
All right?
Hey, man, I didn't know that
Marsha was gonna do that.
Oh, I'm sorry, man.
I understand.
You know, just like
the other time
with that wet towel?
Yeah.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Hey, man,
loan me some soda.
Hey, that's the truth,
that little ol' man.
Oh, hey, all right.
What was that in that car?
That, that funny looking...
Hey, what?
(YELLING)
(LAUGHING)
Hello, Lonnie.
Hey, man, what the hell
are you doin' here?
Oh, it's
part of our policy,
from time to time,
to visit our men at
their place of employment.
Man, I report every month
just like I'm supposed to.
You ain't got to
keep checkin' on me.
It's just part o' my job.
What's the matter,
you think I'm lyin' to you?
Oh, no, Lonnie...
You think I ain't
workin' here no more?
You think...
Now, Lonnie, please.
I ain't embarrassed.
I served my time.
I check in every month,
I keep my job,
washin' the god damn cars,
now, how the hell come
you can't leave me alone?
Like I said,
I'm just doin' my job.
Well, I'm just doin' mine,
and I can't afford to lose it,
so don't you come
around here no more,
you understand? Huh?
(PLAYING)
ANNOUNCER:  It's time for...
VOICE:  Disco Dance.
Ooh!
ANNOUNCER:  Your lucky number
is 5-5-5 KGYS.
T.C.: Oh, no, no, no, no!
Tell me the name
of the tune and you got it.
T.C.: Not now, please, lady.
This is an emergency!
Please, lady, excuse me!
I... I have to get in.
This is an emergency! Please!
Hey, lady, I don't have...
My family is dyin',
they're all chokin',
and I'm the only one
who can help them!
I'm the only... Lady...
Come on, lady.
Lady, listen to me.
Don't ignore me!
Hey, listen to me,
I gotta make this call.
Lady, please,
I'm just beggin'!
Just one minute, please.
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYING)
¶ I'm goin' down
¶ 'Cause you ain't
around, Baby
¶ My whole world stopped ¶
Hello, uh, is Joe there?
Joe.
You ain't got no Joe?
Is this 555-5330?
Well, this is
the number he gave me.
No.
Okay. Bye.
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(MR. B. HUMMING)
Don't they ever get
sick of it? You'd think
just once, just, just once,
they'd wanna hear
a Frank Sinatra,
Perry Como, huh?
Well, it's your place,
play what you want.
You think so, huh?
Just watch this, huh?
(SWITCHES RADIO STATION)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL YELLING)
That's funny, huh? Huh?
Very funny. Very funny.
Well, just forget it,
I'm not goin' back to school.
Justin, would you
please listen...
Now, whatcha mean,
"Justin, please?"
I done listened
to you and my folks
long enough now.
What do I have
to show for it? Nothin'.
I'm gonna
get me a real job,
makin' me some real money,
you know?
Like the job that
was offered to me? Huh?
Hey, listen, we can,
we can get married,
do you know?
We can do all the things
that we wanted to do,
you know?
We... We don't have to
do no more waitin'.
That's all I'm sayin'.
I understand
what you're sayin', but...
CHUCO: Hey, Justin!
Hey, Justin!
That's it! I am not
goin' back to school!
Then we're not
gettin' married.
Say what?
I said, no college,
no marriage.
Hey, now,
you talkin' crazy, Loretta.
No, I'm not talkin' crazy,
you are talkin' crazy!
(CHUCO WHISTLES)
Hey, I gotta go back to work.
We'll just talk about this
later, okay?
No, you forget
about talkin' to me,
sweetheart, ever!
Goodbye, Justin!
What did you mean,
"Goodbye, Justin"?
You heard me. Goodbye!
ON RADIO: (CHORAL)  ¶ KGYS
¶ Radio, radio,
radio, radio ¶
MAN: Will you
close the door, Hippo?
Oh, okay.
Hey, Irwin,
come here for a minute, man.
Look here, I got a real
bad stomach ache.
Man, why don't you
take my place for a while
while I go
to the bathroom, huh?
Oh.
I appreciate it, Jack.
Yeah, sure.
FIRST VOICE:  Talk is cheap.
SECOND VOICE:
That's right, honey.
That is what is meant by,
"A fall into the pit
"is a gain in your wit."
Irwin, who did you say
said all that?
Mao, man. Mao Tse Tung.
He's the head dude
o' all the Red Chinese.
Is he anything
like Bruce Lee?
Bru...
It's real hot, ain't it?
Uh-huh.
(SIGHS)
Oh, hot.
Ooh, hot.
If you wanna feel
somethin' hot,
you oughta put your hand
on this beer.
Hmm.
Marsha!
Will you please stop?
I mean, this is
a place of business, huh?
I dropped my contact lens
in the cold cream.
My brother told me
not to go into this business.
Parking lots, he says.
I told him he was crazy!
Now he can buy and sell me.
Enough!
Geronimo, man, I gotta
win that radio contest.
I get them tickets, boy,
I take Mona out tonight.
Boy, I'll be over, you know?
Wooo, she's so fine. Mmm!
Man, I got down on her,
can you believe that?
Can you believe that, man,
I ever tell you?
Every day.
And to overthrow
the reactionary
ruling classes...
And therefore,
impossible for the people
to win power.
That's from Hibbett, page 150.
Hibbett?
Heavy rhetoric, little boss.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Duane? I mean...
I mean, Abdullah.
You know what
I'm talkin' about, right?
I mean, you know
where I'm comin' from.
Revolution is the anti...
You wanna
pick my brain, right?
Right.
I'm gonna let you.
You know, that Revolution
you keep talkin' about
all the time?
Uh, when it happens,
and it's gonna happen,
then you're gonna be
workin' here for real,
and not just playing around,
splashin' in the water.
Do you understand?
We get a chance
to run your white ass,
and you all get a chance
to sing  We Shall Overcome
in Chinese.
GROUP: Hey, hey, man!
That's not what I meant.
I'm so tired of you
runnin' off at your mouth,
it's gettin' me down, honey.
Why don't you just leave?
And be an assassin.
'Cause the only thing
you're good at shootin' off
is your big mouth!
Would you please
get outta my face,
you sorry lookin' faggot?
(GROUP LAUGHING)
Who you callin' sorry lookin'?
(LAUGHING)
Can't you all see
that she ain't funny?
She's just another
poor example of how
the System has
of destroyin' our men.
Honey, I am more man
than you'll ever be,
and more woman than
you'll ever get.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN ON RADIO:
KGYS news update.
Here in Los Angeles,
the mysterious
pop bottle bomber
is still at large
after exploding
his latest bomb in Anaheim.
Take over for me.
A psychological profile
released by the police
department
pictures the bomber
as a short, eccentric,
middle European man
with an unhappy childhood.
More on this
fast breaking story later
on KGYS News.
Hi, there, sir.
Good morning.
Look, can I interest you
in a hot wax for your car?
We shampoo rugs.
We even got regular wax!
Yes, yes, anything!
Are you quite through
with this, sir? Oh, yeah.
Look, here, here,
take care of the car.
Boy, there's been some
weird people in here today!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, uh, pardon me, lady.
Pardon me.
You didn't by any chance
see a tall, blonde,
black girl, did you?
T.C., T.C.! Come 'ere!
I'm serious, man!
T.C.!
What is it, Hippo?
T.C., come 'ere!
See that cat down there?
Yeah?
Do you know
what he got in that bag?
Naw, I don't know. Uh...
A pop bottle.
You call me over here
to tell me dat cat's
got a pop bottle?
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
A pop bottle with
silver foil on the top.
So what?
So? So what? Look,
just take a look at this!
Look at that!
(MAKING BUZZING SOUNDS)
Just be cool, Hippo.
Follow me, follow me!
You think he ain't gonna
see you finger up against
the wall like that man?
Come on, come on.
Uh, how you doin'?
I like your hair, man.
It's bad, it's bad!
It's him, Hippo!
He's got the bomb!
We the next victim!
He gonna blow us up!
T.C., what are we
gonna do, man?
What are we gonna do?
Quiet! This is a job
for the Fly, Hippo!
(MAKING BUZZING SOUNDS)
You're worthless, man,
I swear!
Two and a half gallons of gas.
This a charge?
Yeah.
The, uh, the blue, uh...
Stop, thief!
(SHRIEKS)
MAN: They took my bag!
(MUMBLING)
MAN 1: Hey, T.C.,
what's goin' on, man?
MAN: Get him! Get him!
It's a bomb! It's a bomb!
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Catch him!
My bag!
Oh, my bag!
Piss?
ALL: Piss?
It's, it's piss.
Piss?
He broke my bag.
ALL: Piss?
I was just takin' that
sample to the doctor.
It took me two days to go.
You see, I had this
operation, and the doctor...
I'll handle this.
I'll handle it.
I was just takin' that
sample to the doctor.
It took me two days to go.
You see, I had this operation!
I'm terribly sorry, sir.
But I... I'd like
to replace it.
I mean, I can't replace it,
but here, here's a little
something to take care
of everything, and...
And the car wash,
the car wash is on me.
How about my pants?
It'll all... It'll all
be taken care of.
(MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
We'll find it. We'll find it.
Why, why, why don't ya
fix the wheel?
Listen, Earl, Earl,
see that, that stuff
is cleaned up.
Hey, fellas, hey, fellas,
wash the cars, wash the ca...
Look, come with me, huh?
Come with me?
You know who that was?
The pee bottle bomber.
I just don't understand
white folks.
Hey, man, ain't that
Sonny Fredricks over there?
Yeah. We got
a little deal workin'.
Workin'?
Thought you wasn't hangin' out
with him no more.
What's the matter, Lonnie,
he ain't good enough for you?
I mean, he ain't good enough
because he's an ex-con?
You forgettin' somethin',
ain't ya?
I ain't forgettin' nothin'!
Well then, you just lay off me
and my friends.
I mean, at least
he didn't bust no head open
on no gas station attendant!
Hey, don't push it, Abdullah!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Whatta you doin', Marsha?
What?
Why, why are you
closin' the door?
It's so noisy out here, Leon.
I thought it might
disturb you.
Hey, hey, you're
a sweet girl, Marsha.
With the gas,
that's five-fifty.
What's your name?
Marsha.
Hi, I'm Kenny.
Hi.
Here's your change.
And here's your rain check.
You get a free car wash
if it rains.
Well, what if it rains today?
Then come back tomorrow.
Well, what if I can't wait
until tomorrow?
Let's say I come back
tonight around 6:00?
Oh, well, it would
be too late...
You couldn't get
your car washed then.
Yeah, but let's say
I was to come back
at six, anyway?
Hey, come on, will you?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hi, Mr. B.
Hey!
Hi, Abdullah!
Hey, little Lonnie,
how you doin'?
Sister, hi!
Hi, Dad.
Hey, how you doin'?
Hi, Daddy.
Hey, baby,
how's my girl?
Say, how's Mama?
Okay.
Yeah?
Dad, can I play the pinball?
Hey, how much homework
you got today?
Not that much.
Aah, not that much.
You ain't even got no business
over here this afternoon,
huh, have you?
Daddy, look what I got.
Now, let's see. Hey!
Yeah, that's beautiful, baby.
Here's the car wash,
and there's you.
That's really nice, baby.
I drew it for you.
For me? Aaah, thank you, baby.
That's my girl.
BOY: Come on, Dad,
let me go play pinball!
(HESITATING)
Now, you got
more responsibilities
than playin' pinball, Son.
You just take
your sister home and get your
homework done, okay?
Okay.
Do it. I'll be home later.
Oh, and, uh,
watch out for the traffic
at the corners.
Bye.
See you later.
Bye, Dad.
Thank you for
the drawing, baby. 'Bye.
Do you own a Cadillac
with the license plate
YNL 877?
I sure do.
You're under arrest.
Turn around, please.
For what, man?
You have over
37 parking violations
you haven't paid.
Oh, man, I gave
my sister-in-law the money
this morning to pay it all.
Is there any other way
we can straighten this out,
Officer?
Look, man, I gave
a certified check, man.
I would'a brought it myself,
but I hadda go to work, man!
Tell it to the judge.
Look, wait a minute, man,
I would'a brought
the check myself, man,
but I hadda go to work.
Hey, Slide, you going
to the slammer?
Hey, hey, look,
call my sister at
the May Company.
Better not look
in his locker...
See you on
visitin' day, Slide!
Hey, call my sister
at the May Company.
Hey, Slide, guess this means
all debts are canceled.
No, it don't!
Get back to work.
Come on, wash cars!
Wa... Wash the cars.
Call 'er!
Wash the cars, huh.
(STUTTERING) What's the number
of the May Company, huh?
Which one?
Look, I don't know.
Any one.
Calvin, will you come on?
I gotta go home now, turkey.
See you tomorrow.
Don't do us no favors, honey.
Go to the Bluebird Car Wash
and give 'em your business.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Calvin!
Hey, Calvin, Calvin!
You okay?
Yeah! I made you look!
I made you look!
(BLOWING RASPBERRIES)
MAN: You little creep!
Boy, why don't you look
where you're goin'?
Owww!
(LAUGHING)
MAN: Do it!
MAN 2: Pipsqueak
got it that time.
He needed it, too.
MAN 3: Oh, it's a pain
in the ass!
Oh, Mr. B., I forgot my money.
What money!
Hey, you firin' me?
How much you get?
Uh, let's go inside.
We'll talk inside.
I don't need
your stinkin' office!
Now, you fire me right here!
Look, I warned you.
Y... You were out
yesterday, twice last week.
Look, I need someone relia...
Now, I'm warnin' you,
you understand me?
I'm gonna burn
this place to the...
You think I need your
stinkin' slave job?
You think you gonna be
the boss?
You ain't! And I'm gonna
get you for this!
Now, I'm warnin' you!
You understand me?
Now, look, look,
everybody, back to work.
I'm gonna get you!
Look, I'm sorry, Duane.
My name is Abdullah, you...
GROUP:
All right, all right!
Hey, come on, man.
Come on, now.
Hey, don't grab a brother.
Sorry.
What the hell
you sorry about?
Come on, now!
It's all right.
Come on.
Watch your... You watch
your ass, nigger.
You... You watch yourself.
Understand me?
Come on.
GERONIMO: Take it easy, man.
You watch yourself!
It's all right.
Come on, man.
Where's the aspirin, Marsha?
It's in your drawer.
Mr. B., about Abdullah.
I mean, I'm sorry
about Abdullah. I mean, he's
really wired up, you know?
Wish you'd
think about givin'
him another chance.
I've given him
a thousand chances.
Oh, but, Mr. B.,
the man is just
confused, you know?
He really, uh...
Lonnie, now is not
the time, huh? Please?
Mr. B., every week I keep
trying to talk to you.
And every week,
you keep tellin' me,
"Now is not the time."
I've been workin' for you
for over a year now,
when is it
gonna be time?
Uh, I don't wanna talk
to you about Duane, huh?
All right, let's don't
talk about Duane,
let's talk about me.
I got to have
more money, Mr. B.
I can't make it
on what you payin' me.
I got two children.
Look, Lonnie, that,
that Bluebird Car Wash,
they're driving me
outta business.
Mr. B., I keep tryin'
to tell you, you got
a big lot here.
If you organize this thing
right, you can be makin'
twice as much.
Lonnie, uh, look,
I know you got ideas.
You... You got ideas.
Look, don't I always
pay you extra
for opening and closing, huh?
Damn.
ANNOUNCER:
All right, out there,
it's time
to get back
in the music groove.
But first...
VOICE:  Disco Dance.
Ooh!
ANNOUNCER:  You heard it.
It's the Disco Dance
at Five-five-five KGYS.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Ooh!
ANNOUNCER:
You'll get those last two free
tickets to J.B.'s Disco Dance.
Come on, man.
Please, answer it,
answer it.
Answer, brother, come on.
Born to Love You.
The answer is
Ooh! Ooh! Yeah!
Oh, oh, hey, uh, uh,
my name is Theodore Chauncey
Elcott, man.
I work at
the Dee-Luxe Car Wash.
Now, dig it, man.
I'm gonna be there after work.
I get off at six to pick up
the tickets, is that cool?
Oh, all right,
beautiful, beautiful, man.
Yeah. Ooh!
Woo! Woo!
Woo, woo!
ANNOUNCER:
We got a winner at
the Dee-Luxe Car Wash
(CHEERING)
at Sixth and Rampart
in greater Los Angeles.
His name is Theodore
Chauncey Elcott...
ALL: Theodore Chauncey Elcott!
...and he's gonna
get down tonight.
T.C. gotta stand
for somethin', don't it?
Well, I always thought
T.C. stood for Tough Chit!
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm gonna try
to get away later.
Uh, you gonna be home?
Uh, no, Leon.
I'm going to visit
my sister tonight.
Well, maybe
tomorrow night, huh?
Yeah, maybe.
Watch it, Marsha!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, you guys.
Uh...
I just wanna say
it's been really far out
hangin' out with you guys.
I mean...
Hey, it's been nice hangin'
out with you, too, man.
You know?
Good luck, man.
Yeah, come back some time.
Good luck!
Oh, Lonnie. (SIGHS)
Lonnie, I didn't know
where you were.
Uh, Lonnie, uh,
we'll talk about
all that stuff tomorrow.
Lonnie, tomorrow we sit down,
we talk about all the things
on your mind.
You got my word.
(SIGHS)
I promise.
Hey, Scruggy,
you gotta help me
pick the ninth race, huh?
Charlene!
Hey, I told you, man!
I told you!
I was just gonna call you!
Charlene...
What's this?
Hey, Charlene, what's the...
Charlene, whatta you doin'?
Charlene!
Later, brother.
Listen, I was gonna call you!
I didn't mean
to stay out last night!
Yes, you worked late!
Charlene! Hey, Charlene!
ANNOUNCER:
It's one minute before
the hour of 6:00 P.M.
News and weather,
and then weekend music,
stay with us.
(CHORAL)  ¶ KGYS
¶ Radio, radio,
radio, radio... ¶
Loretta gonna come
pick you up?
Did you get
everything straight?
Yeah, everything's straight.
She's coming.
Hey, you all,
it's quittin' time!
Naw, naw, naw, naw.
I'm the boss around here.
ALL:
I get to say
when it's quittin' time!
Well?
GOODY, GERONIMO AND CHUCO:
It's quittin' time!
(CHEERING)
(ALL TALKING)
Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Now for our next
impression, we'd like to do...
James Brown!
Brothers! I'm tired!
But I be clean!
(LAUGHING)
Put some here!
Hey, damn it, who's got
my Swahili Sheen?
Nigger, you know you got
my Swahili Sheen.
No, no, no, I don't!
I don't have...
Man, why you always hassle me?
You know I got a date!
Oh, come on, man,
don't I always come to see
your raggedy act, man?
Come on!
Come on, brother!
Aha! The Fly flies again!
Yeah, uh, triumphant
after the Pop Bottle Bomber.
It's a bomb,
it's a bomb, it's a bomb,
it's a bomb,
it's a bomb, it's a bomb!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
You cats are just jealous
'cause I got the tickets
to the concert tonight.
Yeah, well, uh, too bad
you're goin' alone, though.
(FLOYD AND LLOYD LAUGHING)
Here, honey...
Okay.
...I'll show you how.
Woo! (LAUGHING)
We see who you
takin' out tonight.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hey, brother,
where's your radio, man?
I ain't never seen you
without your box!
I, uh, broke it.
(CHUCKLES) What'd you do,
sit on it?
(LAUGHS) Sit on it, yeah!
MAN: Hey, come on, Charlie,
let's hurry it up, man!
Hey, Lonnie, you want a ride?
Ah, no, thanks, Charlie.
I... I gotta close up.
We'll wait for you.
Naw, that's all right, thanks.
Try not to leave
the locker room too messy.
Aw, will you listen to this?
GROUP: Yeah, yeah!
FLOYD AND LLOYD:
¶ Ding dong, fool is gone
ding dong, the fool is gone ¶
Aha, 'spect to see
you people on the Soul Train!
GOODY: Good luck.
CHARLIE: Good luck.
FLOYD: Thank you, Charlie.
Thank you.
Hey, man, come on.
(EXCITEDLY) I got a date!
Uh, you go ahead.
I'll check out
the register.
Oh, Lonnie, thank you.
Oh, thank you.
(HORN HONKING)
Bye.
ON RADIO:  ¶ Bye, bye... ¶
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
You clean it up.
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Hey, hey!
Don't I get
any congratulations, girl?
I'm the big winner!
And the whole city knows it.
Can you get to that, my love?
I won the tickets
to the concert tonight,
I'm gonna go pick 'em up
in a few minutes.
Look, T.C., I'm tired,
and I'm busy!
And I've had a date...
Now, you listen to me.
You wait for some high class
prince to come in here
and sweep you off your feet,
that's not gonna happen.
I am your prince.
Don't no one dig
you as much as I do.
You know that.
But if you don't
get yourself together and
start treatin' me different,
I'm not comin'
around here anymore.
And if you don't wanna
go out with me tonight,
I'll just get me
somebody who will.
T.C.?
What?
I'm gonna be
through in an hour.
Come back then?
All right. That's what
the kid wanted to hear, baby.
The Fly...
Flies again!
Bye.
Here's the bus.
(CAR HONKING)
Loretta...
Listen, I've been thinking...
JUSTIN: Mmm...
Let's not even
talk about it. Okay?
We'll just sit down calmly
next week, and discuss it.
No, 'cause I mean,
I want you...
Next week!
A deal?
A deal.
Hey, move over, I'm drivin'
All right!
(JUSTIN LAUGHS)
JUSTIN: All right!
Hey, is somebody out there?
Oh, say, Abdullah,
whatcha doin' here?
Hey, man, I'm glad
you come back, though.
Look here, I'm gonna
have a talk with Mr. B.
in the mornin',
straighten out
that whole mess.
I didn't come here
to talk, Lonnie.
I came for the money.
Abdullah, you'll have to
use that piece.
I am, huh?
I forgot you was
a house nigger for Mr. B
protectin' him this afternoon,
and now you're
protectin' his money!
Come on, man, I don't give
a shit about Mr. B.'s money,
I'm protectin' you!
That's chump change, man!
Whatcha gonna do with it?
You gonna buy you
a revolution?
You gonna solve
all your problems?
Will you just
give me the money, man?
You and I both know
that the jails are full
o' thousands of young men
just like you.
Is that what you really want?
Come on, man, gimme the gun.
I don't wanna
kill you, Lonnie.
Abdullah, you don't have to...
Gimme the gun, man.
Come on.
Come on, man.
Huh?
Man, don't make me.
Gimme the gun.
Abdullah.
Aw, shit.
Come on.
It's all fallin' apart, man.
Hey, come on.
It's all fallin' apart.
Yeah, it's all right.
I know.
It's all fallin' apart.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know
just how you feel, man.
I don't know, man.
I don't know.
I know I'm not crazy.
But every day,
I have to come here,
watch this clown show, man.
Sometimes...
(INHALING DEEPLY)
I just can't take it.
I know.
(SNIFFS)
Hey, look, hey,
it's gonna be all right.
Okay?
We'll work it out...
Together.
Huh?
(SNIFFS)
ANNOUNCER:  All right!
This is J.J. Jackson,
the prince of darkness,
coming to you in the
night time, 'cause you know
it's the right time.
Starting with the best,
the number one sound
in the West.
Car Wash.
Dig the players
on this session.
Blowin' on steam guns,
Floyd and Lloyd.
Darrow Igus...
And De Wayne Jessie.
Suckin' it up
on the vacuum, Hippo!
James Spinks.
Lindy, Antonio Fargas.
Dig the Pointer Sisters
and Daddy Rich,
Mister Richard Pryor.
The taxi driver
is George Carlin.
On the shoes,
Clarence Muse.
T.C. is Franklyn Ajaye.
And Mona's somethin' else.
She's Tracy Reed.
(MAKES BUZZING SOUND)
Duane, uh, I, I mean,
Abdullah, is Bill Duke.
Lonnie, Ivan Dixon.
On the bottle, Henry Kingi.
On burrito, Pepe Serna.
Geronimo is Ray Vitte.
Scruggs, Jack Kehoe.
The man with the mummy,
that's Garrett Morris.
Justin and Loretta,
Leon Pickney and Ren Woods.
On the outside,
Miz Beverly Hills,
Lorraine Gary.
On the inside,
Lauren Jones.
From left to right,
Leonard Jackson,
Sully Boyar,
and Professor Irwin Corey.
The head on the head,
Richard Brestoff.
On make-up, Melanie Mayron.
Arthur French is Charlie.
And on skateboard,
Michael Fennell.
MAN:  All right, get down!
¶ Car wash
Talkin' 'bout the car wash
¶ Car wash, yeah
¶ Come on, y'all,
and sing it with me
¶ Car wash
¶ Sing it with feelin', y'all
¶ Car wash, yeah
¶ Ooo, ooo, ooo, oooh
Car wash
¶ Those cars never seem
to stop comin'
¶ Well, I say
keep those rags
and machines hummin'
¶ Car wash
Let me tell you
it's always cool
¶ And the boss
don't mind sometimes
¶ If you act the fool
at the Car wash
¶ Working at the car wash,
yeah
¶ Yeah yeah yeah
Car wash
¶ Car wash, yeah
¶ Car wash ¶