J_Carmen_Comes_Home_(1951)_Karumen_kokyo_ni_kaeru ,BR_MKV_H264(ShochikuCo,Jpn,Sub) 988x720
Father! Father!
Okin's letter!
I don't want to see it!
It's a nice letter.
A waste to send candy!
It's not that! She's coming home!
I'll read it.
"It's growing cooler.
Me and everybody well?"
A bit funny...
"Please don't worry about me.
I am lost in my art."
"Next month... in October,
our theater's closing for repairs."
"We get 6 days off, and I'd like to
go home in all my glory."
"You tell Father for me."
See, Father?
"I'm bringing a friend along."
"Please tell him not to be mad..."
"Forgive me for running away."
"Goodbye, Sister. From Lily Carmen."
Please be nice to her.
She's famous... a lot of presents.
Fool! No Jiji Carmen's my daughter!
It's not Jiji Carmen! It's Lily Carmen!
Father, Mother's coming.
What shall we answer?
It's not for me to say.
Don't be that way!
She sent that necktie!
You ate most of the candy, too!
Let's ask the principal to help us.
Father won't refuse, then.
Yes, that's a good idea!
She's a great artist...
and was born here.
It's the principal's duty to talk to Father.
Let's go.
What did you come for?
Let's go home.
Mr. Tagushi!
Wait! Wait!
Please stay.
Thanks.
The athletic meeting's soon.
Were you practicing for it?
Will you play something for us?
I can't. I don't have a harmonium
any more.
Why?
It's sad to be poor. Maruju took it.
That's downright cruel of him!
It can't be helped.
Please use ours.
I like your songs very much.
Thank you.
I'm a friend to art.
Have to protect art.
Japan's culture.
Goodbye.
How do you do?
I'll play my newest one.
The name's "My Sweet Home".
At the foot of Mt Asama,
is a quite little village.
And it is home to me.
The flowers, trees and birds...
Everything is full of light.
I don't wonder you want to cry.
Your husband came home blind.
So you do all the work.
I don't mind that.
But we had to give up his harmonium.
I intended to sell this horse.
But I can't work without it.
He said so, too.
Yes, you've got to eat.
Can't with just a harmonium.
Maruju's a bad fellow.
We shouldn't have borrowed
money to buy the harmonium.
I meant to pay it back.
It was cheap, so I wanted to
make him happy.
Work hard and
get the harmonium back.
You've a good work horse.
I thought it was sick.
It's fine.
Thank you.
Sho!
Yuki went and told him!
How are you?
What's up?
I hear Okin's returning.
It's not my concern!
People say you're lucky
to have a good girl.
She even sends you pocket money.
I don't ask her to... a waste to
throw it away, though.
Let her come if she wants to.
And she's a famous dancer in Tokyo,
after all.
What does Jiji Carmen mean?
Carmen's a famous foreign name.
An interesting novel.
Anyways, it's art.
Japan is cultural.
Then Okin's a culture?
Well, she represents it.
Even Mt. Asama's proud to
have her become great.
Look at that splendid sight.
Everyone must return home
with honors.
Be generous and welcome her
with a smile.
Mt Asama's beautiful,
no matter when we see it.
Oh, youthful love,
nurtured by Mt Asama.
All too soon it seems,
the autumn flowers bloom.
MARUJU EXPRESS COMPANY
The scenery here's nice after Tokyo.
Yes, it's beautiful.
It moves like the wind.
If you built a hotel here,
you'd be the village pioneer.
Reads and posters after that.
You'll get rich by lending money, too.
I'm not doing it for that!
No, your soul is like that cloud!
It's a big, floating and up high!
Yes, I guess that's about it.
Coming!
The principal.
No village headman?
Mr. Aoyama.
Where...?
Oh, my, Okin!
Hello, Sister!
Oh, my I'm so glad to be back!
When was I here last?
She's Okin?
How do you do?
Welcome back.
My friend Maja Akemi.
Hello
I'm her sister.
I'm Ichiro.
Okin, you've become beautiful!
Why, Maruju, it's been quite some time.
I'm Lily Carmen.
In place of my card.
Want it signed?
Your things?
Bring it.
Truck?
A wagon's better.
Get Omitsu.
Right away.
Mr. Principle
The bus will now pass the most
beautiful scenic spot in Japan.
In the distance is the Japan Alps...
Enough!
I liked being a bus girl.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
remember this lovely scenery.
And put it away in the memory
book of your mind...
Thank you very much.
My regards to Haruo.
Tell him to come and see me.
Here.
It's...
But Maruju...
Don't tell him.
500 yen, please. I must pay Maruju
a percentage.
I thought it was free.
It's high. Here.
Thanks.
Grandfather!
How nice! It's beautiful here!
Yes, poetic and dreamy!
Hurry and call Grandfather.
I want to run!
How wonderful! The air's sweet!
So beautiful! It's sad!
It's Father!
Father!
I'm back, Father!
You've come back?
I brought a present and some money.
Thanks.
I'm glad you're well.
So am I.
Yes, mountain air's good for us.
Let's have some tea.
I brought whisky. Let's drink it.
It's wonderful!
Let me have it!
Lily Carmen's an eyeful!
A nice belly?
No scars like yours!
She's famous in Tokyo.
I'll run away, too.
You couldn't be even a streetwalker!
Here they come!
Hello.
A beautiful sky.
A nice backdrop. Let me take you.
Sit down.
Look to one side.
Okin!
Hello.
Ah, lovely! Very lovely!
You stingy man, you!
Charging 500 yen! I thought it was free!
What are you laughing for!
What cute flowers!
Who are they?
Listen, it's boring here.
We only got here yesterday.
It's no fun.
Your father's not very sociable.
Country people can't talk easily.
Maybe I'll go home.
Idiot!
You were heart-broken!
That's why I brought you!
I want to see him again.
Hmph! What's good about him?
A real artists tries to get away
from men like him!
I'm all confused lately.
What?
About art.
You're hopeless! I'm even willing
to die for art!
So am I.
I guess I'm in the dumps. It tortures me.
Cheer up!
If you could only see me!
I've changed completely.
My wife says you're beautiful.
She did? The people all stars,
so it's very trying.
I can't blame them...
it's so in Tokyo, too.
The price of fame.
Nice to be so popular.
It's a nuisance, signing and
giving out pictures.
Not easy to be a dancer.
I'm not in a genius!
Art's very difficult. I suffer.
You haven't changed.
You may be right.
I always want to feel nice inside.
I loved you.
But I was afraid to send
a love letter to a teacher.
You're lucky you didn't marry me.
I'm sorry. I sympathize with you.
It's hard for my wife.
Pulling a horse like that.
It made me cry.
She's nice. Too good for me.
You're a lucky man!
Yes, I take blindness and poverty
in my stride.
I'm unlucky compared to you.
I may be popular,
but my art won't let me marry.
No boy friend?
There are a lot of men,
but they don't understand art.
You're lucky.
I guess so.
I've carved out my career.
I'll sacrifice myself to it.
I'm going.
I'm disappointed.
Come and see me. I've no one
to talk to except you!
I'm honored.
Want help?
No thanks.
You don't look like you're single. Am I?
Go ahead. Be frank.
I guess you are.
Teachers are naive. You're blushing.
You embarrass me.
I don't care!
Worried because of the kids!
Like playing at night, don't you?
I'm single. I'm really a bachelor girl.
But no one believes it.
Liar!
You wanted to see him!
It's not so! She's lying!
Let's go!
I'll come tomorrow!
What'd you talk about?
She was bullying me.
What's the matter?
A big headache.
A fever?
It's not that.
Tell them not to wear dresses like that.
Why, Father?
When I think they're walking around
showing their legs...
I feel ashamed!
You don't know, Father.
They're fancy clothes in Tokyo.
Maybe so, but exposing themselves...
Livestock can go around naked.
But what about her picture?
It embarrasses me, but it's for her art.
If that's art, I'd rather look at
horses and pigs!
That tree makes me remember...
when Okin was kicked by a cow.
I remember.
She was knocked over
and frothing when I came.
Seems it made her head funny.
You may be right.
Father, we're back!
I'm going!
Back, are you?
ATHLETIC MEETING
Don't lose!
Behave today.
You behave. Before Mr. Ogawa, anyway.
You're vulgar.
My skirt keeps falling down.
Isn't it nice?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
He understands music, too.
Let's go over.
My sister's here!
She's lovely.
Okin came!
The artiste?
You're so right, she's Carmen!
See her dress.
Very good.
Please relax and listen.
Stop, stop! No. 2!
Staring at me.
Take a bow.
But...
You owe it to them.
That's enough.
That's enough!
I see.
Next on the program is
a special number by Mr. Taguchi.
The principal would like to
say a few words.
We would like you to listen to
Mr. Taguchi's new composition.
The song will move you.
It is a marvelous piece of art.
I am very happy that a man
from our village composed it.
I'm sure we'll all be proud of it.
On this beautiful autumn day...
I'd like to listen to this work of art
with you.
And I'd like to listen to it, too.
It's not only a great pleasure to me...
I am sure that Mt Asama's
very proud of him, too!
That's my harmonium.
It's a very fine one.
Please begin.
It's the harmonium we had.
What is it?
He grabbed my hand!
You're wrong!
Let's go!
But, we...
Please wait!
I'm going!
They didn't laugh at you!
Please be quiet, everyone!
Quiet, please!
I'm sorry about this! I apologize!
I apologize, so please play again!
I ask you to.
Don't be offended and play again.
I ask you to leave.
We're not to blame!
Anyway, go home!
All right, we'll go!
I'm awfully sorry!
Idiot! Idiot!
What's funny?
I'm sorry, but I can't play today.
I'm going.
No wonder. Art's a delicate feeling.
It's not that.
Come again when you feel better.
I'm sorry I bothered you.
You've no luck with that harmonium.
Let's go back to Tokyo.
Mr. Ogawa?
I'll give him up.
You don't care?
I'm not going yet.
But we can't even run around here.
And your father's got a fever.
That's why I can't go!
I don't run after an insult!
I came to be honored!
Can't even wear my borrowed dresses!
Maruju's bad.
He just held your hand!
I like Mr. Ogawa, so I don't want
others to touch me!
Acting so pure!
Wish I could see him.
No school today... what's he doing?
Go and see him!
Don't!
I've got a plan!
Let's do a show! That'll surprises them!
It sure will.
We'll show them our art and...
make up for yesterday!
It's popular in Tokyo,
so it'll wow them!
Costume...?
A handkerchief's enough.
What'll Mr. Ogawa say?
He'll be glad. All men like it.
Will he understand it?
What?
A country teacher's...
I'll guarantee it.
He's a bachelor! He'll love it!
Hook him then.
Let's, then!
All right! Settled!
Let's go!
You can draw below!
My son saw them!
Without a stitch on.
It was something to see!
Let's go.
It's too late!
Like to see it.
Art's terrific. You know,
those sculptures? It's like that.
I'm going to Tokyo.
I'll dance for you!
I'd like to see it!
See a good show at the farm?
I'm telling them.
A sensation.
I'd like to see it.
It may mean more money than a hotel.
We'll have them dance.
You go and ask!
You bet! A fortune in show business!
You'll get rich.
No, it's to introduce art. Go on!
Sure, by horse!
But the old man's got a fever even now.
Why can't we? I'll give him the money!
I'm a good girl!
Certainly.
He gets mad even if
we stretch our legs.
He's too old.
Certainly.
Art's misunderstood.
I'll fight.
Have to for art.
Yes, yes.
You're right.
You understand? It's hard to.
A little.
It has to be tomorrow.
Very well, we'll play it up.
We'll go later.
We'll be waiting.
Find some curtains for costumes.
Okin's dancing tonight.
You can go if you want to.
It's a nude show.
That's what they were excited about?
How'll her father feel
if he sees the posters?
She's not bright, she'll do anything.
I wonder. She likes you.
She used to wait for me after school.
Wasn't it pleasant?
A pleasant memory now.
I've fewer memories than others.
And the fewest of me.
Married a year, then the war.
I haven't seen since.
But that one year has remained
in my mind.
Your songs show it.
The blind can see well.
If I were a composer,
I'd compose a lot.
You are.
No harmonium but you're an artist.
Okin's artist enough.
It's the principal.
How do you do?
Together?
We'd like to borrow your harmonium.
I see. I'm going to the farm.
See the poster?
Okin's dance poster?
It's the limit! It'll poison the villagers!
It's the limit!
A big rock in the middle of the road!
Poison for people who see.
They like it.
Father!
I'm afraid I made a big mistake.
I must apologize.
Why? I haven't done anything that great.
I'm ashamed of myself.
Okin shouldn't have come.
What'd she do now?
I'm an educator.
I can't keep quiet this time.
He just got up today.
Go on. She's my responsibility.
I'm responsible, too.
It was a mistake to be glad
without knowing.
Not here?
At the water trough.
I see. I'll go and see her.
Principal, did she steal or something?
Of course not.
Then tell me. I'm beyond surprise.
Okin's dancing tonight.
A nude show.
Father!
It's sensational.
The admission's 100 yen.
Probably Maruju's idea.
It's not only bad for the young men
but for the children, too!
I'm determined to stop it.
I'll see her.
I will, too!
They're practicing.
No wonder our bucket's gone!
It's crazy!
Please wait!
I don't want to see her shameful act!
Don't you, either!
I'll tell you the truth!
I love her the best!
She ran away to Tokyo,
but she's weak in the head.
So she can't get along decently.
I don't know what's she's doing...
but it's not respectable work.
It may be art or culture.
But how can I be happy
when she's not even married?
I love and hate her and,
at the same time, she worries me sick.
It's been a long time,
so I wanted to see her.
Still I was afraid of what she'd done.
But she's back now!
Let's let her dance if she wants to!
Let's her be laughed at!
I'm unlucky to be her father.
She was unlucky to be kicked by a cow.
Let them laughed at me, too!
Let them all laugh!
If her dances are bad,
let the government put a stop to them!
If it's all right in Tokyo, it's all right here!
It must be art!
You win today!
I don't know what to say!
She has the right to dance
if she wants to!
Even cycle races are authorized!
Maruju chose the lesser of the two evils.
No, I've got something to say to him!
I'll go and see him!
Don't tell Okin.
I'm going, too!
Don't waste money! It's only tonight!
The front row for reserved seats.
It'll be worth paying for them.
Sure.
Well, well!
A lot of time yet.
A fine way to make money.
I'm doing it for our villages.
For its culture, you might say.
No progress if we're insensible to art.
"Keep up with the times" is my motto.
Stop your smooth talk!
I'm her father, so I know!
At the tail end of her class,
runny nose till 18!
How could she know art?
You just want fun at her expense!
You're wrong. She's Lily Carmen.
You really think so?
Sure I do.
I hate liars!
You talk of culture and the village...
but you're after money!
Acting like a Diet member!
Shut up!
There's more!
I've been wanting to say so, too!
But it seemed rather childish!
Still, if a good man like him is angry,
it's time I am, too!
You took away a blind man's
only pleasure!
So how can you now about culture
or helping others!
Poor boy, he takes his father to...
play the harmonium!
I thought you a devil to do that.
Only a devil could!
What happened?
I heard you were here. I was worried.
Look at him! And at me!
A principal using violence!
But I'm not sorry! Mt Asama knows!
I'm sorry, but I don't want to see Okin.
She's leaving tomorrow
but I won't see her.
May I stay the night?
Of course. I don't feel
any too good either.
Come along and drink with us.
Listen to my Asama song.
Father!
Look here, Naokichi, get off!
Say, hurry up and open the curtains!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
The show's about to begin.
You will be treated to a great art
of sublime beauty...
The dances of Lily Carmen
and Maja Akemi!
Hurry up!
Maruju has brought the band
all the way from Karuizawa.
The Cupid Band will delight you
with their playing.
The show will now begin.
We will first play a number from
the great Schubert!
Principal, when I think she's naked
there before the others...
I'm more ashamed than
if I'd danced naked.
I know, I know.
Only human beings know shame.
It's a noble feeling.
Please pour me some more.
Drink a lot and pass out!
Keep bringing the sake!
She went to buy something.
I see.
Drink up, Sho.
The moon seems to be out.
Mt Asama must be beautiful.
I don't think Father will take that money.
He will. Everyone likes money.
I don't, of course.
You take it if he won't.
Really?
Yes, but send me half, then.
I will.
Should've brought half.
Father may take it.
He might.
I'm so glad!
He's giving Father the money by now.
I hope he refuses.
Father's funny.
He didn't even see me off.
I wanted to see Mr. Ogawa, too.
My regards to him.
Say I was sad.
Yes, tactfully.
Hello, there... thanks for last night.
Very popular.
Did they understand?
Yes, all of it.
I made a lot of money.
I got treated to a drink.
It'll help my cultural work.
You listen, too. Oyuki.
It had slipped my mind...
Take the harmonium.
My kids are tired of it.
That harmonium?
You'll need it for the new hotel!
That's so...
Never mind, though. I'm generous.
Take it with you.
You mean it?
I hate lies!
Tell your father so.
Say I returned it.
Made money, that's why.
I can't rob a blind man!
His debt can wait.
You tell the principal!
Say I returned it to make up
for the athletic meet!
For free!
How very generous.
Hurry before he changes his mind!
He's like that cloud!
Hurry!
It may be dirty money,
but my girl earned it.
If you use it, her dancing
will be of some use.
Please take it.
I see. I gladly accept it.
We'll make good use of it.
And try to give everyone
an artist education.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Taguchi of this village, too.
People like him would make Japan
very beautiful.
Let's use some of this to pay his debts.
That's fine.
He's coming to teach a song,
this morning.
I'm relieved.
She's a fool, but she did
some good here.
Come again, Okin!
The idiots!
There go the nudes!
You were nice last night! Come again!
I'm glad I came!
The people are cute.
I want to eat noodles!