1
00:00:42,566 --> 00:00:46,934
<b><i>Colombia is the world's second-</i></b>
<b><i>largest recipient of U.S. military aid...</i></b>

2
00:00:47,103 --> 00:00:51,767
<b><i>...receiving $ 1 billion a year for training</i></b>
<b><i>and equipping Columbian armed forces.</i></b>

3
00:00:53,476 --> 00:00:56,001
<b><i>The revolutionary armed forces</i></b>
<b><i>of Colombia...</i></b>

4
00:00:56,179 --> 00:01:01,116
<b><i>...are Latin America's oldest, largest</i></b>
<b><i>and best-equipped guerilla insurgency.</i></b>

5
00:01:01,284 --> 00:01:03,252
<b><i>Known by their Spanish acronym,</i></b>
<b><i>FARC...</i></b>

6
00:01:03,419 --> 00:01:06,717
<b><i>...they have waged a cruel,</i></b>
<b><i>50-year campaign of terror...</i></b>

7
00:01:06,889 --> 00:01:09,790
<b><i>...against the government</i></b>
<b><i>and the people of Colombia.</i></b>

8
00:01:10,259 --> 00:01:14,127
<b><i>Their tactics include bombings,</i></b>
<b><i>murder, mortar attacks...</i></b>

9
00:01:14,296 --> 00:01:17,993
<b><i>...kidnapping, extortion and hijacking.</i></b>

10
00:01:22,738 --> 00:01:26,969
<b><i>American soldiers are frequently deployed</i></b>
<b><i>to assist in anti-narcotics...</i></b>

11
00:01:27,141 --> 00:01:29,268
<b><i>...and anti-guerilla operations.</i></b>

12
00:01:29,443 --> 00:01:32,640
<b><i>And the American government</i></b>
<b><i>has posted over $ 70 million...</i></b>

13
00:01:32,814 --> 00:01:39,219
<b><i>...of reward money for any information</i></b>
<b><i>leading to the capture of FARC leadership.</i></b>

14
00:01:45,258 --> 00:01:47,886
<b><i>The Colombian people</i></b>
<b><i>frequently take to the streets...</i></b>

15
00:01:48,061 --> 00:01:50,552
<b><i>...to protest the FARC's brutal methods...</i></b>

16
00:01:50,730 --> 00:01:56,168
<b><i>...and to call for the end to the violence</i></b>
<b><i>and for the release of hundreds of hostages.</i></b>

17
00:02:01,575 --> 00:02:04,100
<b><i>Although with its massive</i></b>
<b><i>cocaine revenue...</i></b>

18
00:02:04,276 --> 00:02:06,540
<b><i>...the FARC has been able</i></b>
<b><i>to equip its army...</i></b>

19
00:02:06,712 --> 00:02:11,342
<b><i>...with the most modern weapons</i></b>
<b><i>of any terrorist organization in the world.</i></b>

20
00:02:36,241 --> 00:02:38,402
<b>We got movement on Lago.</b>

21
00:02:50,721 --> 00:02:52,086
<b><i>Principal acquired.</i></b>

22
00:02:53,323 --> 00:02:55,757
<b>Flashpoint Bravo, what is your count?</b>

23
00:02:56,593 --> 00:02:59,585
<b>We are minus two,</b>
<b>three minutes to full count.</b>

24
00:03:18,180 --> 00:03:20,307
<b>Flashpoint Charlie, slow him down.</b>

25
00:03:20,483 --> 00:03:23,974
<b>l got him but if l engage now,</b>
<b>this thing blows wide open.</b>

26
00:03:24,152 --> 00:03:28,111
<b>-No choice, Charlie. Move for intercept.</b>
<b>-Copy that, Alpha.</b>

27
00:03:33,695 --> 00:03:35,458
<b>Abort, Charlie, abort.</b>

28
00:03:39,834 --> 00:03:43,132
<b>First rule of engagement:</b>
<b>Always know your target.</b>

29
00:03:43,304 --> 00:03:44,828
<b>That's gonna take him five.</b>

30
00:03:45,005 --> 00:03:47,030
<b>Proceed to jump point.</b>

31
00:04:09,696 --> 00:04:11,357
<b>Surprise!</b>

32
00:04:13,232 --> 00:04:14,665
<b>Hey.</b>

33
00:04:14,834 --> 00:04:16,062
<b>What's up, dude?</b>

34
00:04:18,638 --> 00:04:19,730
<b>Hey.</b>

35
00:04:19,906 --> 00:04:22,533
<b>Got a special delivery</b>
<b>for that old bastard.</b>

36
00:04:23,842 --> 00:04:25,742
<b>We got you something else too.</b>

37
00:04:25,911 --> 00:04:27,503
<b>Where is it?</b>

38
00:04:42,360 --> 00:04:44,828
<b>God bless America.</b>

39
00:05:04,414 --> 00:05:06,712
<b>All right, Marcy, go.</b>

40
00:05:11,221 --> 00:05:13,951
<b>-Come on. There you are, baby, bring it on.</b>
<b>-Yeah.</b>

41
00:05:14,457 --> 00:05:16,049
<b>Baby.</b>

42
00:05:20,963 --> 00:05:22,555
<b>Come on. Right this way.</b>

43
00:05:28,303 --> 00:05:29,895
<b>Oh, yeah, baby.</b>

44
00:05:31,340 --> 00:05:33,740
<b>Sweet cream on an ice cream sandwich.</b>

45
00:05:34,777 --> 00:05:36,870
<b>Very nice, very nice.</b>
<b>Let me tell you something.</b>

46
00:05:37,046 --> 00:05:39,412
<b>-Listen.</b>
<b>-Here. Great.</b>

47
00:05:58,499 --> 00:06:00,159
<b>What--?</b>

48
00:06:03,036 --> 00:06:06,267
<b>-That wasn't supposed to happen.</b>
<b>-What the hell's wrong with you?</b>

49
00:06:06,440 --> 00:06:09,432
<b>-Don't get hot about it, all right?</b>
<b>-At least the brew's cold.</b>

50
00:06:11,678 --> 00:06:14,476
<b>-Yes.</b>
<b>-That's so--</b>

51
00:06:14,648 --> 00:06:17,776
<b>One more thing. ln order to maintain</b>
<b>the element of surprise...</b>

52
00:06:17,951 --> 00:06:19,815
<b>...when surveilling from a structure...</b>

53
00:06:19,985 --> 00:06:24,752
<b>...make sure to watch your shadow throw</b>
<b>so as not to reveal your position.</b>

54
00:07:00,424 --> 00:07:02,585
<b>-How much?</b>
<b>-900 pesos.</b>

55
00:07:03,961 --> 00:07:06,191
<b>Look, honey. Like this.</b>

56
00:07:17,940 --> 00:07:21,341
<b>Maybe he'll be in the orchestra</b>
<b>like my grandfather.</b>

57
00:07:21,511 --> 00:07:25,641
<b>No way. He's going to be the soccer</b>
<b>champion of the World Cup.</b>

58
00:07:26,015 --> 00:07:28,142
<b>That's your dream, my love.</b>

59
00:07:28,351 --> 00:07:30,148
<b>But of course, l'm his father.</b>

60
00:07:30,319 --> 00:07:32,116
<b>Who brought him his first soccer ball?</b>

61
00:07:32,288 --> 00:07:33,550
<b>Me.</b>

62
00:07:34,757 --> 00:07:36,782
<b>Mazorcas. l love them.</b>

63
00:07:36,959 --> 00:07:37,982
<b>One, please?</b>

64
00:07:46,935 --> 00:07:48,163
<b>Thomas.</b>

65
00:07:48,336 --> 00:07:50,361
<b>Relax, my love. Let him be.</b>

66
00:08:16,696 --> 00:08:17,788
<b>Maria!</b>

67
00:09:02,340 --> 00:09:03,398
<b>My condolences.</b>

68
00:09:06,010 --> 00:09:07,568
<b>l am sorry for your loss.</b>

69
00:09:08,613 --> 00:09:10,376
<b>Those FARC sons of bitches...</b>

70
00:09:10,781 --> 00:09:12,248
<b>...l will make them pay.</b>

71
00:09:12,950 --> 00:09:14,474
<b>Whatever you need.</b>

72
00:09:15,052 --> 00:09:17,349
<b>Understand? Whatever you need.</b>

73
00:10:05,233 --> 00:10:07,326
<b>-Morning, sir.</b>
<b>-Morning.</b>

74
00:10:08,403 --> 00:10:10,200
<b>Still got you at the desk, commander?</b>

75
00:10:10,371 --> 00:10:13,306
<b>Fastest way to kill a SEAL</b>
<b>is to give him some pencils to push.</b>

76
00:10:13,474 --> 00:10:17,307
<b>l'd rather be pinned down in a firefight</b>
<b>any day. Some of us are just born to it.</b>

77
00:10:17,778 --> 00:10:19,370
<b>Let's get out of this prison cell.</b>

78
00:10:22,049 --> 00:10:24,711
<b>What do you know about Colombia,</b>
<b>specifically, the FARC?</b>

79
00:10:24,885 --> 00:10:26,910
<b>Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia.</b>

80
00:10:27,087 --> 00:10:30,523
<b>The most powerful, most dangerous</b>
<b>communist guerilla force on the planet.</b>

81
00:10:30,691 --> 00:10:33,091
<b>They have territorial control</b>
<b>of half the country...</b>

82
00:10:33,260 --> 00:10:36,228
<b>...and have been at war</b>
<b>with the government for 40 years.</b>

83
00:10:36,395 --> 00:10:39,193
<b>NSA intel has the FARC</b>
<b>responsible for this.</b>

84
00:10:39,365 --> 00:10:42,027
<b>They kill about 3000 Colombians a year.</b>

85
00:10:42,201 --> 00:10:45,136
<b>They stay funded by protecting</b>
<b>the cartel drug operations.</b>

86
00:10:45,304 --> 00:10:49,001
<b>People up here buy drugs, that money keeps</b>
<b>these guys in bullets and body bags.</b>

87
00:10:49,175 --> 00:10:51,109
<b>-Exactly.</b>
<b>-So, what's the op?</b>

88
00:10:51,277 --> 00:10:53,335
<b>Operation Ghost Watch.</b>

89
00:10:53,511 --> 00:10:55,376
<b>Strictly recon.</b>

90
00:10:55,547 --> 00:10:59,608
<b>NSA Keyhole picked this up</b>
<b>in the deep jungle outside of Puerto Limon.</b>

91
00:10:59,784 --> 00:11:02,344
<b>lt's about 150 klicks south of Bogotá.</b>

92
00:11:02,520 --> 00:11:04,215
<b>Now this...</b>

93
00:11:05,590 --> 00:11:07,251
<b>...one month ago.</b>

94
00:11:08,059 --> 00:11:10,425
<b>This yesterday.</b>

95
00:11:11,796 --> 00:11:13,922
<b>Roughly triple the under-roof capacity.</b>

96
00:11:14,098 --> 00:11:16,692
<b>So they are either storing up coca</b>
<b>for a long winter...</b>

97
00:11:16,867 --> 00:11:19,301
<b>...or prepping for a serious rumble</b>
<b>in the jungle.</b>

98
00:11:19,470 --> 00:11:22,462
<b>Exactly. Our job is to find out which.</b>

99
00:11:23,207 --> 00:11:26,472
<b>We've got it on good intel</b>
<b>something major's going down tomorrow.</b>

100
00:11:26,643 --> 00:11:28,577
<b>We're gonna ghost in, see what's what.</b>

101
00:11:28,746 --> 00:11:31,180
<b>Go in with cameras rolling,</b>
<b>get it all on tape.</b>

102
00:11:31,348 --> 00:11:34,316
<b>-Wait, wait. You say tomorrow morning?</b>
<b>-Yeah, that's right.</b>

103
00:11:34,484 --> 00:11:36,247
<b>We're running this op in the daylight.</b>

104
00:11:36,986 --> 00:11:40,717
<b>We're all for catching some rays, LT,</b>
<b>but that's coloring way outside the lines.</b>

105
00:11:41,357 --> 00:11:46,090
<b>Got no choice. They want eyes</b>
<b>on the action. Not before, not after.</b>

106
00:11:47,830 --> 00:11:49,229
<b>-Questions?</b>
<b>-Yeah.</b>

107
00:11:50,233 --> 00:11:53,599
<b>What about the Colombians?</b>
<b>We're not jointing with them?</b>

108
00:11:53,769 --> 00:11:57,364
<b>Negative. FARC's got too many hooks</b>
<b>in with the national army.</b>

109
00:11:57,539 --> 00:12:00,508
<b>Been a lot of ops already,</b>
<b>been blown because of tip-offs.</b>

110
00:12:00,675 --> 00:12:05,635
<b>Which is why we mission plan in the air.</b>
<b>We're gonna HALO into the Rio Ariari.</b>

111
00:12:05,814 --> 00:12:09,511
<b>Should be fun. Wheels up 1700 hours.</b>

112
00:12:12,453 --> 00:12:13,681
<b>-Yeah?</b>
<b>-Yes.</b>

113
00:12:13,854 --> 00:12:17,585
<b>Sir, given the extreme sensitivity</b>
<b>of this mission, l believe it's my duty...</b>

114
00:12:17,758 --> 00:12:22,923
<b>...to respectfully inform you that</b>
<b>you are now much too ancient...</b>

115
00:12:23,097 --> 00:12:25,964
<b>...to effectively lead this team</b>
<b>behind enemy lines.</b>

116
00:12:28,736 --> 00:12:31,000
<b>My ancient memory recalls...</b>

117
00:12:31,805 --> 00:12:33,295
<b>...something about...</b>

118
00:12:33,473 --> 00:12:36,601
<b>...me almost tackling you</b>
<b>to get you from ringing that bell...</b>

119
00:12:36,776 --> 00:12:38,243
<b>...at the end of BUD/S training.</b>

120
00:12:38,411 --> 00:12:40,641
<b>Who's dragged you</b>
<b>out of half a dozen bar fights?</b>

121
00:12:41,681 --> 00:12:42,705
<b>That would be you.</b>

122
00:12:43,450 --> 00:12:45,179
<b>Who's got your back 24/7, huh?</b>

123
00:12:45,652 --> 00:12:48,519
<b>Who makes sure that you come home alive</b>
<b>all the time?</b>

124
00:12:48,688 --> 00:12:49,712
<b>That would be you.</b>

125
00:12:49,889 --> 00:12:51,515
<b>You're damn skippy.</b>

126
00:12:53,225 --> 00:12:54,692
<b>See you guys on the tarmac.</b>

127
00:12:55,427 --> 00:12:57,327
<b>Copy that, LT.</b>

128
00:13:08,507 --> 00:13:13,205
<b>New intel says that it might be a meet</b>
<b>between FARC and Colombian sympathizers.</b>

129
00:13:13,377 --> 00:13:15,743
<b>Now, you have evac here, 20 klicks east.</b>

130
00:13:16,180 --> 00:13:18,580
<b>Safe location and DEA contact here,</b>
<b>if you need it.</b>

131
00:13:18,749 --> 00:13:22,549
<b>Now, keep in mind, FARC's not just</b>
<b>some rebel insurgency. They don't play.</b>

132
00:13:22,720 --> 00:13:25,917
<b>Every year, we pump half a billion bucks</b>
<b>of aid into the region.</b>

133
00:13:26,090 --> 00:13:28,718
<b>The guerillas are coming.</b>
<b>They're armed, well-trained.</b>

134
00:13:28,893 --> 00:13:32,191
<b>And we're playing in their sandbox.</b>
<b>Stay frosty. Get ready.</b>

135
00:13:36,600 --> 00:13:38,033
<b><i>We are entering drop zone.</i></b>

136
00:13:40,036 --> 00:13:41,401
<b>Word is:</b>

137
00:13:41,571 --> 00:13:43,596
<b>Ghost Watch is a go.</b>

138
00:13:43,773 --> 00:13:47,174
<b>Stay on your triggers</b>
<b>and watch your back.</b>

139
00:13:47,344 --> 00:13:48,606
<b>l'll see you at happy hour.</b>

140
00:13:49,479 --> 00:13:52,845
<b>-The only easy day....</b>
<b>-Was yesterday.</b>

141
00:14:04,360 --> 00:14:06,055
<b><i>-Green light.</i></b>
<b>-Game time.</b>

142
00:14:37,291 --> 00:14:39,225
<b>Prepare to release.</b>

143
00:14:40,327 --> 00:14:41,624
<b>Now!</b>

144
00:14:57,777 --> 00:15:00,837
<b>Stingray Alpha, rally point bravo.</b>

145
00:15:14,993 --> 00:15:17,962
<b>Careful with these vid packs.</b>
<b>l had to sign for these babies.</b>

146
00:15:22,567 --> 00:15:24,091
<b>Vid on.</b>

147
00:15:25,971 --> 00:15:28,666
<b>Good. Weapon's hot.</b>

148
00:15:50,360 --> 00:15:53,227
<b>Commander. Stingray insertion is green.</b>
<b>En route to target.</b>

149
00:15:53,396 --> 00:15:55,956
<b>-Let me know when we have visual.</b>
<b>-Yes, sir.</b>

150
00:15:58,501 --> 00:16:00,059
<b>Hi, commander.</b>

151
00:16:00,236 --> 00:16:03,137
<b>Like what we did with the place?</b>
<b>lt used to be a radio station.</b>

152
00:16:03,306 --> 00:16:04,330
<b>Works for me.</b>

153
00:16:04,907 --> 00:16:08,273
<b>Nicole Jennings, U.S. Embassy liaison.</b>

154
00:16:09,878 --> 00:16:11,209
<b>Visual's coming up now, sir.</b>

155
00:16:13,148 --> 00:16:14,809
<b>Your boys better stay invisible.</b>

156
00:16:14,983 --> 00:16:16,644
<b>Colombian government</b>
<b>catches wind...</b>

157
00:16:16,818 --> 00:16:19,218
<b>...of this unauthorized operation</b>
<b>on their soil...</b>

158
00:16:19,388 --> 00:16:21,720
<b>...and you would devastate</b>
<b>our anti-drug relations.</b>

159
00:16:21,890 --> 00:16:25,189
<b>ClA pulled up a name, Carlos Rivera.</b>

160
00:16:25,661 --> 00:16:28,151
<b>But they think he's been bought</b>
<b>by the FARC.</b>

161
00:16:28,329 --> 00:16:31,093
<b>He set up the factory bombings</b>
<b>in Bogotá.</b>

162
00:16:31,265 --> 00:16:32,698
<b>He's got a handler...</b>

163
00:16:32,867 --> 00:16:35,665
<b>...codename Apotequil.</b>

164
00:17:26,451 --> 00:17:28,510
<b>Nothing glowing.</b>

165
00:17:29,087 --> 00:17:30,145
<b>Switching to Specter.</b>

166
00:17:45,402 --> 00:17:47,063
<b>Got something.</b>

167
00:17:53,543 --> 00:17:56,103
<b>About 10 meters out, 1 o'clock.</b>

168
00:18:14,597 --> 00:18:17,498
<b>lt looks like they're paranoid.</b>
<b>Stay alert.</b>

169
00:18:52,666 --> 00:18:55,362
<b>Magnetic AT12 mine, Cuban-made.</b>

170
00:19:01,575 --> 00:19:03,201
<b>lt's old.</b>

171
00:19:05,044 --> 00:19:06,568
<b>Do the job.</b>

172
00:19:09,182 --> 00:19:11,343
<b>These guys are not messing around.</b>

173
00:19:22,395 --> 00:19:26,057
<b>Rendered it inop. Repeat. Repeat.</b>

174
00:19:26,498 --> 00:19:27,965
<b>lt's inop.</b>

175
00:19:39,911 --> 00:19:42,674
<b>Stingray's in the objective perimeter, sir.</b>

176
00:19:45,983 --> 00:19:48,543
<b>Looks like we're losing the satellite, sir.</b>

177
00:19:48,719 --> 00:19:50,846
<b>-Get it back.</b>
<b>-Working on it, sir.</b>

178
00:19:51,021 --> 00:19:53,546
<b>-Trying to get another bird.</b>
<b>-Find another SAT.</b>

179
00:19:59,830 --> 00:20:01,229
<b>Turn starboard.</b>

180
00:20:22,584 --> 00:20:24,211
<b>We're ghosts here, boys.</b>

181
00:20:24,386 --> 00:20:26,752
<b>Spirits of this jungle. You copy?</b>

182
00:21:04,457 --> 00:21:05,515
<b>This is it.</b>

183
00:21:06,092 --> 00:21:08,117
<b>l want overwatch in five.</b>

184
00:21:08,295 --> 00:21:09,626
<b>l'm on it.</b>

185
00:22:04,414 --> 00:22:07,212
<b>Specter is on and recording.</b>

186
00:22:11,722 --> 00:22:14,885
<b>All right, we eyeball</b>
<b>what they got in their cookie jar...</b>

187
00:22:15,058 --> 00:22:18,550
<b>...catch them on tape, make it back in time</b>
<b>for 2-for-1 beers on me.</b>

188
00:22:19,061 --> 00:22:21,825
<b>Stingray Delta, ready to move.</b>
<b>How's the neighborhood?</b>

189
00:22:21,998 --> 00:22:23,898
<b>Quiet streets.</b>

190
00:22:24,066 --> 00:22:27,365
<b>Good schools, no nosy neighbors.</b>

191
00:22:28,270 --> 00:22:29,669
<b>Switching to EM.</b>

192
00:22:30,206 --> 00:22:31,764
<b>Clear on cams.</b>

193
00:22:31,941 --> 00:22:33,670
<b>No infrared trip lines.</b>

194
00:22:33,843 --> 00:22:35,504
<b><i>No motion sensors.</i></b>

195
00:22:36,012 --> 00:22:38,037
<b>Going to thermal.</b>

196
00:22:38,214 --> 00:22:41,705
<b>We've got 25 sparks inside.</b>
<b>Fairly clustered.</b>

197
00:22:43,685 --> 00:22:45,516
<b>All the guards have two-ways.</b>

198
00:22:45,687 --> 00:22:48,281
<b>-RF short-range.</b>
<b>-Copy that.</b>

199
00:22:50,191 --> 00:22:52,125
<b>-Door's open.</b>
<b>-Alpha advancing.</b>

200
00:22:52,293 --> 00:22:54,557
<b>See you around the punchbowl, boys.</b>

201
00:23:20,987 --> 00:23:23,956
<b><i>Stingray Echo, hold your positions.</i></b>
<b><i>Bogie in truck.</i></b>

202
00:23:27,593 --> 00:23:32,087
<b>Stingray Echo, watch your 6,</b>
<b>you don't wanna get splashed.</b>

203
00:23:52,317 --> 00:23:54,182
<b>He's wearing Colombian army fatigues.</b>

204
00:23:54,352 --> 00:23:57,115
<b>Colombians are compromised. Let's go.</b>

205
00:24:24,114 --> 00:24:28,676
<b>Tango Niner, l'm looking at MRE's.</b>
<b>Great for waging war on your stomach.</b>

206
00:24:29,085 --> 00:24:30,143
<b><i>Nothing suspicious.</i></b>

207
00:24:39,495 --> 00:24:41,725
<b>Affirm. FARC soldiers at Tango 1.</b>

208
00:24:42,164 --> 00:24:43,893
<b>Something feels off about all this.</b>

209
00:24:44,066 --> 00:24:46,057
<b>Delta, what's the count?</b>

210
00:24:46,401 --> 00:24:49,234
<b>You got 25 spark hits. Fairly clustered.</b>

211
00:24:49,404 --> 00:24:50,837
<b>Taking a look. Wait one sec.</b>

212
00:24:55,344 --> 00:24:58,540
<b>The time has come</b>
<b>to end the violence...</b>

213
00:25:00,314 --> 00:25:02,145
<b>...end the killing.</b>

214
00:25:02,316 --> 00:25:04,409
<b><i>Looks like we got big fish.</i></b>

215
00:25:04,585 --> 00:25:08,077
<b>Some kind of peace conference</b>
<b>between FARC and the Colombian army.</b>

216
00:25:08,256 --> 00:25:14,718
<b>Let's not let this historical</b>
<b>moment pass.</b>

217
00:25:14,896 --> 00:25:18,092
<b>Looks like we just walked</b>
<b>into the history books, boys.</b>

218
00:25:26,373 --> 00:25:30,571
<b>How can we hear each other</b>
<b>over the din of gunfire?</b>

219
00:25:31,611 --> 00:25:32,703
<b>Tango 6.</b>

220
00:25:32,879 --> 00:25:36,678
<b>Fuel depot, diesel. Maybe 1500 gallons.</b>

221
00:25:36,849 --> 00:25:38,510
<b><i>No munitions. No nothing.</i></b>

222
00:25:38,684 --> 00:25:41,244
<b>On both sides there are those...</b>

223
00:25:42,855 --> 00:25:48,691
<b>...who would fight</b>
<b>until Judgment Day.</b>

224
00:25:53,732 --> 00:25:57,497
<b>The mission of peace!</b>

225
00:26:09,113 --> 00:26:10,876
<b>Thermals moving in from the jungle.</b>

226
00:26:11,049 --> 00:26:13,483
<b>Twenty more, carrying heavy.</b>
<b>Get out of there!</b>

227
00:26:15,586 --> 00:26:17,816
<b>Bravo!</b>

228
00:26:23,260 --> 00:26:24,784
<b>Back to insert, move.</b>

229
00:26:26,129 --> 00:26:27,892
<b>No! No!</b>

230
00:27:08,770 --> 00:27:10,965
<b>Capture and kill the Americans.</b>

231
00:27:11,139 --> 00:27:13,003
<b>Secure the perimeter.</b>

232
00:27:13,340 --> 00:27:16,002
<b>-Get up!</b>
<b>-Cover me!</b>

233
00:27:31,659 --> 00:27:33,489
<b><i>LT, on your right.</i></b>

234
00:27:33,660 --> 00:27:35,992
<b><i>Delta. Delta. Left. Left.</i></b>

235
00:27:39,832 --> 00:27:41,026
<b><i>Cover me, I'm moving.</i></b>

236
00:27:42,335 --> 00:27:43,859
<b>Road's clear. Wait!</b>

237
00:27:51,311 --> 00:27:53,005
<b><i>Kevin, watch your back.</i></b>

238
00:27:58,583 --> 00:28:01,143
<b>Carter! Diversion!</b>

239
00:28:02,054 --> 00:28:03,578
<b>Grenade!</b>

240
00:28:31,448 --> 00:28:33,882
<b>Overwatch taking fire.</b>
<b>Overwatch taking fire.</b>

241
00:28:49,032 --> 00:28:50,761
<b>Hit the ground! On wheels!</b>

242
00:29:01,377 --> 00:29:04,471
<b>Moving to the fence. Watch my six.</b>

243
00:29:09,651 --> 00:29:11,345
<b>l'm hit!</b>

244
00:29:13,388 --> 00:29:14,616
<b>Give him some cover.</b>

245
00:29:31,371 --> 00:29:33,339
<b>Let's go!</b>

246
00:29:40,680 --> 00:29:41,738
<b>Move out! Come on!</b>

247
00:29:47,187 --> 00:29:48,916
<b>Carter! Give me a hand!</b>

248
00:29:50,189 --> 00:29:52,089
<b>Guys, fall back!</b>

249
00:30:00,132 --> 00:30:01,531
<b>Fall back. Fall back.</b>

250
00:30:08,808 --> 00:30:10,570
<b>Go, go, go!</b>

251
00:30:12,544 --> 00:30:14,307
<b>Come on, get him to the boat.</b>

252
00:30:15,213 --> 00:30:16,339
<b>He's not breathing.</b>

253
00:30:20,618 --> 00:30:22,483
<b>Move, move, move.</b>

254
00:30:24,656 --> 00:30:28,057
<b>-Who are these assholes?</b>
<b>-Must have been here the whole time.</b>

255
00:30:28,226 --> 00:30:30,693
<b>Knew exactly how far to lay back</b>
<b>and not be detected.</b>

256
00:30:30,861 --> 00:30:32,590
<b>Overwatch. Overwatch, come in.</b>

257
00:30:32,763 --> 00:30:35,027
<b>Greg, do you copy? What was his last?</b>

258
00:30:35,199 --> 00:30:37,190
<b>-Taking fire.</b>
<b>-FUBAR, man.</b>

259
00:30:37,367 --> 00:30:39,801
<b>That was some really great intel</b>
<b>on this shitstorm.</b>

260
00:30:39,970 --> 00:30:42,063
<b>lf they got Greg,</b>
<b>they knew we were coming.</b>

261
00:30:43,407 --> 00:30:45,568
<b>lt's time to leave. Now!</b>

262
00:31:02,792 --> 00:31:04,555
<b>Ambush! Ambush! Take cover!</b>

263
00:31:05,661 --> 00:31:07,185
<b>Take cover!</b>

264
00:31:19,407 --> 00:31:22,274
<b>We're naked out here!</b>
<b>Take it back to the jungle!</b>

265
00:31:28,582 --> 00:31:31,210
<b>Carter! Go!</b>

266
00:31:31,719 --> 00:31:34,415
<b>No! l'm covering!</b>

267
00:31:46,467 --> 00:31:48,525
<b>-Man down!</b>
<b>-lt's no good! lt's no good!</b>

268
00:31:48,701 --> 00:31:50,362
<b>-We're not leaving him.</b>
<b>-We have to.</b>

269
00:32:12,925 --> 00:32:14,984
<b>He's alive.</b>
<b>Take him and any gear you find.</b>

270
00:32:15,160 --> 00:32:17,185
<b>Secure the prisoners.</b>

271
00:32:17,396 --> 00:32:19,489
<b>The rest of you, after them!</b>

272
00:32:30,942 --> 00:32:33,240
<b>Goddamn setup.</b>
<b>We walked right into an ambush.</b>

273
00:32:33,411 --> 00:32:36,039
<b>-Those guys got skills.</b>
<b>-l'm thinking AFEUR.</b>

274
00:32:36,213 --> 00:32:37,908
<b>Colombian Special Forces.</b>

275
00:32:38,082 --> 00:32:40,550
<b>Our own Green Berets</b>
<b>trained those sons of bitches.</b>

276
00:32:40,718 --> 00:32:45,781
<b>-Something didn't feel right.</b>
<b>-Bro, look at me. What's our next play?</b>

277
00:33:39,440 --> 00:33:41,237
<b>We got com.</b>

278
00:33:55,322 --> 00:33:57,415
<b>One of ours is still breathing.</b>

279
00:33:57,591 --> 00:33:59,957
<b>They're moving him to Villavicencio.</b>

280
00:34:00,127 --> 00:34:02,652
<b>-What are you thinking?</b>
<b>-l think we get our boy.</b>

281
00:34:02,829 --> 00:34:04,194
<b>Get some payback.</b>

282
00:34:04,363 --> 00:34:07,821
<b>That's definitely not</b>
<b>standard operating procedure, LT.</b>

283
00:34:26,217 --> 00:34:28,742
<b>Check out the footage</b>
<b>from their camera.</b>

284
00:34:32,357 --> 00:34:35,019
<b>Excellent. Exactly what l want.</b>

285
00:34:45,335 --> 00:34:48,566
<b>These SEALS were better</b>
<b>than l gave them credit.</b>

286
00:34:49,973 --> 00:34:51,201
<b>Find the other gringos.</b>

287
00:34:59,550 --> 00:35:01,381
<b>We've got two jeeps, one truck.</b>

288
00:35:02,152 --> 00:35:04,051
<b>King Shit sitting up front in the Hummer.</b>

289
00:35:04,220 --> 00:35:06,484
<b>Say the word.</b>
<b>l'll put one through his right eye.</b>

290
00:35:06,656 --> 00:35:07,987
<b>l've got an idea.</b>

291
00:35:30,746 --> 00:35:32,213
<b>Go.</b>

292
00:35:54,869 --> 00:35:56,496
<b>We need a phone.</b>

293
00:36:00,141 --> 00:36:02,199
<b>All right, this village here.</b>

294
00:36:02,375 --> 00:36:04,366
<b>Should make it in a day if we haul ass.</b>

295
00:36:04,544 --> 00:36:06,774
<b>-We need to stay close to Kevin.</b>
<b>-Yep.</b>

296
00:36:06,946 --> 00:36:09,141
<b>-They'll have teams out tracking us.</b>
<b>-Well...</b>

297
00:36:09,315 --> 00:36:11,909
<b>...we'd be out of work</b>
<b>if this shit was easy.</b>

298
00:36:12,752 --> 00:36:13,776
<b>Let's move.</b>

299
00:36:22,928 --> 00:36:25,726
<b>-Anything?</b>
<b>-They've missed two com checks now.</b>

300
00:36:25,898 --> 00:36:29,834
<b>Did you ping their SAT phone?</b>
<b>Monitor their ground coms? Something?</b>

301
00:36:30,002 --> 00:36:34,336
<b>Sorry, sir. No bounce-back. All commo's</b>
<b>been down now for eight hours.</b>

302
00:36:34,506 --> 00:36:36,997
<b>Call NSA, DEA,</b>
<b>anyone who's got a SAT overhead.</b>

303
00:36:37,176 --> 00:36:38,734
<b>l wanna know what's going on.</b>

304
00:36:38,911 --> 00:36:41,037
<b>l got off the phone</b>
<b>with our embassy in Bogotá.</b>

305
00:36:41,212 --> 00:36:44,670
<b>-There's word of an incident.</b>
<b>-What are you talking about?</b>

306
00:36:47,718 --> 00:36:52,018
<b><i>Sources are calling it an unauthorized</i></b>
<b><i>incursion of U.S. military forces.</i></b>

307
00:36:52,190 --> 00:36:54,988
<b><i>The story is still developing</i></b>
<b><i>but there is a claim...</i></b>

308
00:36:55,159 --> 00:36:58,720
<b><i>...that the incident involves</i></b>
<b><i>the assassination of high-level officials...</i></b>

309
00:36:58,896 --> 00:37:01,193
<b><i>...of both the FARC</i></b>
<b><i>and the Colombian army.</i></b>

310
00:37:01,631 --> 00:37:03,064
<b>Holy shit.</b>

311
00:37:16,580 --> 00:37:18,673
<b>There's a phone line.</b>

312
00:37:21,250 --> 00:37:23,411
<b>Runs right through the center of town.</b>

313
00:37:25,921 --> 00:37:30,085
<b>-Hold down the fort.</b>
<b>-l gotcha. Reach out and touch someone.</b>

314
00:37:46,074 --> 00:37:49,703
<b>LT, take cover. Bogie at 2 o'clock.</b>

315
00:37:55,817 --> 00:37:57,478
<b>Spotted it.</b>

316
00:38:01,688 --> 00:38:05,283
<b>Stay down. Stay down, please.</b>

317
00:38:07,895 --> 00:38:09,294
<b>Go, go, go.</b>

318
00:38:19,572 --> 00:38:20,596
<b>Shit.</b>

319
00:38:20,773 --> 00:38:24,004
<b>Hey, we got wheels at 12 o'clock.</b>
<b>Let's go.</b>

320
00:38:38,990 --> 00:38:42,118
<b>And apparently that was rush hour.</b>

321
00:38:55,373 --> 00:38:58,535
<b>-Sir, you've got a call here. lt's collect.</b>
<b>-What?</b>

322
00:38:59,443 --> 00:39:01,877
<b>-Hello?</b>
<b><i>-Deep Blue, authenticate.</i></b>

323
00:39:02,046 --> 00:39:07,484
<b>Sierra Niner Foxtrot Romeo 1-4-7.</b>

324
00:39:07,651 --> 00:39:11,610
<b>Alpha Stingray, this is Deep Blue</b>
<b>authenticating. Counter-sign...</b>

325
00:39:11,789 --> 00:39:13,484
<b><i>...Lima 3 Whiskey 1-7.</i></b>

326
00:39:13,657 --> 00:39:15,625
<b>Stingray? Sit-rep.</b>

327
00:39:15,793 --> 00:39:18,488
<b>We were engaged.</b>
<b>Say again, we were engaged.</b>

328
00:39:18,661 --> 00:39:21,824
<b>They were waiting for us.</b>
<b>Guerrillas took out secret peace talk...</b>

329
00:39:21,998 --> 00:39:24,330
<b><i>...between FARC</i></b>
<b><i>and the Colombian army.</i></b>

330
00:39:24,500 --> 00:39:28,027
<b>-l need a secure line to the ambassador.</b>
<b>-Yes, ma'am.</b>

331
00:39:30,340 --> 00:39:32,035
<b>Take me off speaker. Now.</b>

332
00:39:33,176 --> 00:39:35,041
<b>Stingray, what's your count?</b>

333
00:39:36,145 --> 00:39:39,136
<b>Minus two. One capture.</b>
<b>Sir, these were AFEUR...</b>

334
00:39:39,314 --> 00:39:41,248
<b><i>...Colombian Special Forces.</i></b>

335
00:39:41,416 --> 00:39:42,883
<b>Stingray, confirm your last.</b>

336
00:39:43,418 --> 00:39:44,908
<b><i>Minus two. One POW.</i></b>

337
00:39:45,087 --> 00:39:46,577
<b>Affirm.</b>

338
00:39:46,755 --> 00:39:48,848
<b>Proceed to LZ for emergency exfil.</b>

339
00:39:49,024 --> 00:39:51,857
<b>Negative, we have a location</b>
<b>on our captured asset.</b>

340
00:39:52,027 --> 00:39:54,996
<b>Not gonna happen.</b>
<b>We reassess and mission-plan a rescue.</b>

341
00:39:55,163 --> 00:39:56,425
<b>l'm not leaving him behind.</b>

342
00:39:56,598 --> 00:39:59,327
<b>Make sure your ass is on that chopper.</b>
<b>We'll get our boy.</b>

343
00:39:59,500 --> 00:40:02,196
<b><i>-But we'll do it the right way.</i></b>
<b>-l lost two men.</b>

344
00:40:02,370 --> 00:40:03,769
<b>We lost two men.</b>

345
00:40:03,938 --> 00:40:06,099
<b>And l'm not gonna lose two more.</b>
<b>You hear me?</b>

346
00:40:09,577 --> 00:40:10,669
<b>Yes, sir.</b>

347
00:40:11,512 --> 00:40:13,912
<b>Proceed to emergency evac coordinates.</b>

348
00:40:14,081 --> 00:40:15,742
<b><i>Rendezvous at 1300.</i></b>

349
00:40:16,883 --> 00:40:20,375
<b>This is Deep Blue, out. Son of a bitch.</b>

350
00:40:25,025 --> 00:40:28,756
<b>Get me General Burlings. Son of a bitch.</b>

351
00:40:30,563 --> 00:40:31,723
<b>Your call, LT.</b>

352
00:40:32,332 --> 00:40:33,629
<b>We follow orders.</b>

353
00:40:34,234 --> 00:40:35,963
<b>l knew you were gonna say that.</b>

354
00:40:42,141 --> 00:40:43,472
<b>Let's do it.</b>

355
00:41:32,823 --> 00:41:36,417
<b>Don't tie him like that, you idiot!</b>
<b>Tie him from behind so he can't get loose.</b>

356
00:41:37,393 --> 00:41:38,826
<b>Take him up to the room.</b>

357
00:41:57,645 --> 00:41:59,203
<b>What's going on?</b>

358
00:42:00,849 --> 00:42:02,441
<b>Making you a star.</b>

359
00:42:05,887 --> 00:42:07,684
<b>Smile for the camera.</b>

360
00:42:10,425 --> 00:42:12,552
<b>You and your friends made quite a mess.</b>

361
00:42:14,795 --> 00:42:15,955
<b>So who sent you here?</b>

362
00:42:18,332 --> 00:42:22,564
<b>l'm looking for Colombian chicks.</b>

363
00:42:49,462 --> 00:42:52,625
<b>-Commander, we've tasked a SAT.</b>
<b>-Good.</b>

364
00:42:54,766 --> 00:42:56,859
<b>Bring up the evac LZ.</b>

365
00:43:02,407 --> 00:43:03,931
<b>Go thermal.</b>

366
00:43:06,411 --> 00:43:07,605
<b>Move your asses.</b>

367
00:43:09,681 --> 00:43:13,047
<b>-Where's Swordfish?</b>
<b>-Swordfish, time to contact?</b>

368
00:43:13,484 --> 00:43:17,614
<b>This is Swordfish. Roger that.</b>
<b>Ninety seconds inbound.</b>

369
00:43:52,621 --> 00:43:55,488
<b>Here. Come on.</b>

370
00:43:58,427 --> 00:43:59,758
<b>We got them. We got them.</b>

371
00:44:04,299 --> 00:44:05,926
<b>-We have a problem.</b>
<b>-Not now.</b>

372
00:44:07,903 --> 00:44:09,837
<b>Daisy Forge, say again your last. Over.</b>

373
00:44:10,472 --> 00:44:14,168
<b><i>You are ordered out of Colombian airspace</i></b>
<b><i>immediately, without pickup.</i></b>

374
00:44:14,342 --> 00:44:17,436
<b>-What? We have them on sight, right here.</b>
<b><i>-Abort. Do not land.</i></b>

375
00:44:17,612 --> 00:44:20,012
<b><i>-Return to base.</i></b>
<b>-What are they waiting for?</b>

376
00:44:20,815 --> 00:44:23,579
<b><i>I repeat, abort. Do not land.</i></b>
<b><i>Return to base.</i></b>

377
00:44:23,751 --> 00:44:25,810
<b>-Goddamn it.</b>
<b>-Come on.</b>

378
00:44:30,558 --> 00:44:34,015
<b>-What's going on? Why aren't they landing?</b>
<b>-They've been ordered not to.</b>

379
00:44:34,194 --> 00:44:36,162
<b>-From who?</b>
<b>-The Colombian army.</b>

380
00:44:36,329 --> 00:44:38,695
<b>Commander, we've got vehicles</b>
<b>moving into the area.</b>

381
00:44:46,773 --> 00:44:47,967
<b>LT, we got company.</b>

382
00:45:36,019 --> 00:45:37,247
<b>Turn left! Turn left!</b>

383
00:45:45,062 --> 00:45:46,222
<b>That was close.</b>

384
00:45:48,532 --> 00:45:50,499
<b>Pedal to the metal, Carter.</b>

385
00:45:55,137 --> 00:45:57,002
<b>You best talk fast.</b>

386
00:45:57,173 --> 00:45:59,539
<b>Your men have been declared</b>
<b>war criminals.</b>

387
00:45:59,709 --> 00:46:02,735
<b>When the hell did Colombians</b>
<b>get into our chain of command?</b>

388
00:46:02,912 --> 00:46:05,210
<b>-Who ordered the exfil abort? What?</b>
<b>-Washington.</b>

389
00:46:05,381 --> 00:46:08,214
<b>They want this handled</b>
<b>through diplomatic channels.</b>

390
00:46:08,384 --> 00:46:11,875
<b>We can't start swapping bullets</b>
<b>with an ally of the U.S.</b>

391
00:46:13,021 --> 00:46:16,252
<b><i>FARC leaders have vowed</i></b>
<b><i>to increase their terror campaign...</i></b>

392
00:46:16,424 --> 00:46:19,882
<b><i>...against the U.S.-controlled</i></b>
<b><i>puppet government of Colombia.</i></b>

393
00:46:20,061 --> 00:46:23,553
<b>This is insane.</b>
<b>This footage is from our own vid packs.</b>

394
00:46:23,732 --> 00:46:26,098
<b><i>The Colombian government</i></b>
<b><i>has issued a statement...</i></b>

395
00:46:26,267 --> 00:46:28,633
<b><i>...condemning the actions</i></b>
<b><i>of the U.S. Military...</i></b>

396
00:46:28,802 --> 00:46:33,432
<b><i>...and is calling for an immediate withdrawal</i></b>
<b><i>of all U.S. armed forces of the region.</i></b>

397
00:46:33,607 --> 00:46:37,475
<b><i>They've also released this video</i></b>
<b><i>of a captured American serviceman.</i></b>

398
00:46:37,644 --> 00:46:42,104
<b><i>It seems talk of peace regarding</i></b>
<b><i>Colombia's 40 years of internal strife...</i></b>

399
00:46:42,282 --> 00:46:43,772
<b><i>...is now all but history.</i></b>

400
00:46:43,951 --> 00:46:46,112
<b>Holy God, this is going tits-up.</b>

401
00:46:46,286 --> 00:46:50,016
<b>Commander,</b>
<b>your men have lost control.</b>

402
00:46:50,189 --> 00:46:53,989
<b>No, l know my men.</b>
<b>This is wrong. This is not right.</b>

403
00:46:54,160 --> 00:46:56,628
<b>-They've been set up.</b>
<b>-l wanna talk to this commander.</b>

404
00:47:00,066 --> 00:47:01,727
<b>Carl Dobb, ClA.</b>

405
00:47:01,901 --> 00:47:04,893
<b>Commander, you are ordered</b>
<b>to stand down immediately.</b>

406
00:47:05,071 --> 00:47:08,767
<b>-l still have men in the field.</b>
<b>-This is no longer a military operation.</b>

407
00:47:08,940 --> 00:47:10,271
<b>Listen up, people.</b>

408
00:47:10,442 --> 00:47:15,641
<b>This is a high-priority situation.</b>
<b>l have full NSA authority.</b>

409
00:47:15,814 --> 00:47:17,441
<b>Are there any questions?</b>

410
00:47:47,524 --> 00:47:49,355
<b>l'm sorry.</b>

411
00:47:50,694 --> 00:47:52,161
<b>l can't untie you.</b>

412
00:47:52,796 --> 00:47:55,196
<b>You Navy SEALs don't know</b>
<b>when to give up.</b>

413
00:47:56,066 --> 00:47:59,661
<b>-Who are you? FARC?</b>
<b>-No.</b>

414
00:47:59,837 --> 00:48:04,001
<b>-Colombian army?</b>
<b>-The FARC killed my wife and my son.</b>

415
00:48:04,475 --> 00:48:07,204
<b>The Colombian army</b>
<b>was also at that meet.</b>

416
00:48:07,377 --> 00:48:09,242
<b>You murdered your own countrymen.</b>

417
00:48:09,412 --> 00:48:13,007
<b>Anyone who wishes</b>
<b>to make peace with those monsters...</b>

418
00:48:13,182 --> 00:48:16,549
<b>...are no countrymen of mine.</b>

419
00:48:17,153 --> 00:48:18,484
<b>They're traitors.</b>

420
00:49:01,929 --> 00:49:05,262
<b>l think it's empty. Let's secure the site.</b>

421
00:49:11,938 --> 00:49:13,963
<b>Everyone went home for the night.</b>

422
00:49:14,140 --> 00:49:17,132
<b>This is awesome.</b>
<b>lt's like junior high all over again.</b>

423
00:49:19,913 --> 00:49:22,438
<b>So why didn't they pick us up?</b>

424
00:49:27,219 --> 00:49:28,743
<b>That's the Colombian president.</b>

425
00:49:30,222 --> 00:49:31,780
<b>Oh, he looks pissed.</b>

426
00:49:38,430 --> 00:49:40,455
<b>He's calling us assassins.</b>

427
00:49:40,632 --> 00:49:43,430
<b>American military hit squad</b>
<b>sent to derail the peace talks...</b>

428
00:49:43,602 --> 00:49:47,002
<b>-...between FARC and the government.</b>
<b>-Assassins?</b>

429
00:49:48,906 --> 00:49:51,306
<b>That's not even off our vid packs.</b>

430
00:49:51,476 --> 00:49:54,912
<b>Somebody wanted that summit stopped.</b>
<b>They wanted us to take the blame.</b>

431
00:49:59,450 --> 00:50:02,510
<b>Now he's saying we did it</b>
<b>because the U.S. believes...</b>

432
00:50:02,687 --> 00:50:04,847
<b>...that as long as FARC is a problem...</b>

433
00:50:05,355 --> 00:50:08,188
<b>...Colombians will be dependent</b>
<b>upon us for aid...</b>

434
00:50:08,358 --> 00:50:10,849
<b>...and therefore,</b>
<b>will remain America's puppet.</b>

435
00:50:11,027 --> 00:50:14,326
<b>No, no, no.</b>
<b>We saw the guys that ambushed us.</b>

436
00:50:14,498 --> 00:50:17,126
<b>The Colombian army</b>
<b>hit its own peace talks. Why?</b>

437
00:50:23,273 --> 00:50:24,432
<b>First, we get Kevin.</b>

438
00:50:25,207 --> 00:50:27,107
<b>-l agree.</b>
<b>-They're gonna keep him alive...</b>

439
00:50:27,276 --> 00:50:29,244
<b>...for a few more photo ops.</b>

440
00:50:30,713 --> 00:50:33,079
<b>-Check the radio.</b>
<b>-l'm on it.</b>

441
00:50:38,788 --> 00:50:43,122
<b>-l got static. We're too far out of range.</b>
<b>-We're gonna need a trace and wheels.</b>

442
00:50:44,826 --> 00:50:47,556
<b>Maserati? Ferrari? What do you want?</b>

443
00:50:48,563 --> 00:50:51,293
<b>Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait. This guy.</b>

444
00:50:54,903 --> 00:50:58,464
<b>He's the one l saw doing most</b>
<b>of the talking before bullets started flying.</b>

445
00:50:58,640 --> 00:51:00,039
<b>Okay. Who is he?</b>

446
00:51:01,009 --> 00:51:02,533
<b>He's a witness.</b>

447
00:51:08,081 --> 00:51:11,175
<b><i>Protesters have been throwing firebombs</i></b>
<b><i>at the American Embassy...</i></b>

448
00:51:11,351 --> 00:51:14,047
<b><i>...shouting ''U.S. out of Colombia. ''</i></b>

449
00:51:15,122 --> 00:51:16,521
<b>Look.</b>

450
00:51:17,958 --> 00:51:19,949
<b>l'm sorry about your men.</b>

451
00:51:20,127 --> 00:51:23,254
<b>l need the ClA intel on Rivera,</b>
<b>and this Apotequil character.</b>

452
00:51:23,429 --> 00:51:25,693
<b>l wanna know who sent my men</b>
<b>into a meat grinder.</b>

453
00:51:25,865 --> 00:51:27,526
<b>l don't know if l can do that.</b>

454
00:51:28,734 --> 00:51:31,862
<b>You and l both know that if the Colombians</b>
<b>get ahold of my men...</b>

455
00:51:32,038 --> 00:51:34,097
<b>...there will be no diplomatic channels.</b>

456
00:51:34,273 --> 00:51:37,538
<b>-The Colombians are an ally of the U.S.</b>
<b>-They'll say my men resisted.</b>

457
00:51:37,877 --> 00:51:41,540
<b>They'll say there was a firefight.</b>
<b>lt'll be an execution.</b>

458
00:51:47,285 --> 00:51:50,118
<b>Okay. Okay.</b>

459
00:51:55,227 --> 00:51:58,788
<b>-Boytano.</b>
<b><i>-I had to call your wife to get your number.</i></b>

460
00:51:59,798 --> 00:52:02,459
<b>You okay? What's your status?</b>

461
00:52:02,633 --> 00:52:05,568
<b>Well, we've got everybody</b>
<b>in Colombia on our ass.</b>

462
00:52:05,736 --> 00:52:08,705
<b>-You know we didn't do this.</b>
<b><i>-You're being hung out to dry.</i></b>

463
00:52:08,873 --> 00:52:11,899
<b>The company's calling the shots.</b>
<b>Trying to save face.</b>

464
00:52:13,143 --> 00:52:16,943
<b>You know, there's a general. He survived.</b>
<b>He can confirm we're not the shooters.</b>

465
00:52:17,114 --> 00:52:19,378
<b>Yeah, well, he's not talking.</b>

466
00:52:19,917 --> 00:52:21,907
<b><i>The Colombians</i></b>
<b><i>are calling it an act of war.</i></b>

467
00:52:22,452 --> 00:52:26,388
<b>The FARC has gone apeshit.</b>
<b>They're burning down entire villages.</b>

468
00:52:27,190 --> 00:52:29,283
<b>Yeah, great job on the extraction,</b>
<b>by the way.</b>

469
00:52:30,226 --> 00:52:31,818
<b>Washington.</b>

470
00:52:33,630 --> 00:52:35,598
<b><i>Washington wants to talk this out.</i></b>

471
00:52:35,765 --> 00:52:37,460
<b>They want you to surrender.</b>

472
00:52:37,634 --> 00:52:38,896
<b>ls that what you want?</b>

473
00:52:41,937 --> 00:52:42,961
<b>What do you need?</b>

474
00:52:43,138 --> 00:52:46,005
<b>l need a trace on a radio frequency</b>
<b>in Villavicencio.</b>

475
00:52:48,710 --> 00:52:50,109
<b>What are the numbers?</b>

476
00:53:28,715 --> 00:53:30,649
<b>-Go ahead.</b>
<b><i>-Major.</i></b>

477
00:53:30,817 --> 00:53:34,309
<b>We searched the entire area</b>
<b>where the jeep was found.</b>

478
00:53:34,487 --> 00:53:37,820
<b><i>No sign of the gringos.</i></b>

479
00:54:04,148 --> 00:54:06,878
<b>See if this works.</b>

480
00:54:34,244 --> 00:54:35,506
<b>Cluster of radio signals.</b>

481
00:54:35,679 --> 00:54:39,876
<b>One-eighteen degrees, four minutes,</b>
<b>six seconds east.</b>

482
00:54:40,082 --> 00:54:42,380
<b>Twenty-four, 26, 46 north.</b>

483
00:54:43,786 --> 00:54:46,016
<b><i>Traded my last favor for that.</i></b>

484
00:54:46,188 --> 00:54:47,382
<b><i>Get our man out alive.</i></b>

485
00:54:49,492 --> 00:54:51,221
<b>This building's poured concrete.</b>

486
00:54:51,394 --> 00:54:53,259
<b>l can't get any heat signatures.</b>

487
00:54:53,429 --> 00:54:56,330
<b>We're gonna have to go in blind.</b>
<b>This is a tactical nightmare.</b>

488
00:54:56,499 --> 00:55:00,264
<b>Hostile count,</b>
<b>principal's location unknown.</b>

489
00:55:01,403 --> 00:55:02,427
<b>Trident.</b>

490
00:55:04,706 --> 00:55:08,039
<b>Yeah, it's our boy. All right, l got this.</b>
<b>Two guards on the roof.</b>

491
00:55:09,044 --> 00:55:11,638
<b>-And two on the ground.</b>
<b>-l'm gonna need a big show.</b>

492
00:55:11,813 --> 00:55:14,611
<b>-Give me two minutes.</b>
<b>-l can do that for you.</b>

493
00:55:22,823 --> 00:55:24,916
<b>Amigo?</b>

494
00:55:25,426 --> 00:55:28,520
<b>Amigo. Amigo?</b>

495
00:55:30,798 --> 00:55:32,595
<b>Hey, amigo--</b>

496
00:55:42,408 --> 00:55:43,466
<b>Where's my gear?</b>

497
00:56:11,803 --> 00:56:12,792
<b>What was that blast?</b>

498
00:56:13,839 --> 00:56:15,170
<b>The boys are back.</b>

499
00:56:15,340 --> 00:56:19,139
<b>-A car bombing, sir.</b>
<b>-lt's the gringos. Alert everyone.</b>

500
00:57:17,999 --> 00:57:19,227
<b>Get down.</b>

501
00:57:22,737 --> 00:57:24,534
<b>Goddamn, am l happy to see you.</b>

502
00:57:24,705 --> 00:57:27,105
<b>l'm only here</b>
<b>because you owe Carter 10 bucks.</b>

503
00:57:27,275 --> 00:57:29,971
<b>-l'll stop at the ATM on the way out.</b>
<b>-Let's go.</b>

504
00:57:33,347 --> 00:57:34,575
<b>Damn, it's locked.</b>

505
00:57:45,992 --> 00:57:47,016
<b>Now.</b>

506
00:58:10,482 --> 00:58:11,949
<b>Grenade! Get out of here!</b>

507
00:58:22,994 --> 00:58:24,825
<b>Meter's running, boys.</b>

508
00:58:25,797 --> 00:58:27,162
<b>Move. Go.</b>

509
00:58:29,834 --> 00:58:31,631
<b>What took you guys so long?</b>

510
00:58:43,080 --> 00:58:44,809
<b>This thing got seatbelts?</b>

511
00:59:06,869 --> 00:59:09,804
<b>-Sure you're all right?</b>
<b>-Bastards made me eat McDonald's.</b>

512
00:59:09,972 --> 00:59:12,600
<b>-What are you still doing here?</b>
<b>-Carter will fill you in.</b>

513
00:59:12,775 --> 00:59:15,368
<b>-We need fresh wheels.</b>
<b>-Where you going?</b>

514
00:59:15,644 --> 00:59:17,544
<b>To see a sick friend.</b>

515
01:00:11,230 --> 01:00:13,493
<b>-Carlos?</b>
<b>-Shut your mouth.</b>

516
01:00:14,900 --> 01:00:17,198
<b>You and me,</b>
<b>we're gonna have a little talk.</b>

517
01:00:17,369 --> 01:00:19,599
<b>Okay. Okay, okay.</b>

518
01:00:20,505 --> 01:00:21,563
<b>Okay.</b>

519
01:00:25,377 --> 01:00:28,938
<b>-What do you want?</b>
<b>-l was there. l saw what happened.</b>

520
01:00:29,114 --> 01:00:31,547
<b>And l know that you know</b>
<b>we weren't the shooters.</b>

521
01:00:31,716 --> 01:00:34,947
<b>-You understand me?</b>
<b>-Understand. l understand.</b>

522
01:00:36,454 --> 01:00:39,150
<b>l'm sorry about what happened</b>
<b>to your people.</b>

523
01:00:40,858 --> 01:00:44,123
<b>But your government's blaming us.</b>
<b>They're calling us assassins.</b>

524
01:00:44,295 --> 01:00:46,525
<b>Yeah, well?</b>

525
01:00:46,697 --> 01:00:48,790
<b>-l cannot contradict them.</b>
<b>-Why not?</b>

526
01:00:48,966 --> 01:00:52,025
<b>Americans are not very popular</b>
<b>in Latin America.</b>

527
01:00:52,202 --> 01:00:53,965
<b>There are people in my government...</b>

528
01:00:54,738 --> 01:00:59,198
<b>...who want to see the U.S. out.</b>
<b>Completely out of South America.</b>

529
01:00:59,376 --> 01:01:02,607
<b>Well then, we need to do something</b>
<b>about that. Who were the shooters?</b>

530
01:01:04,047 --> 01:01:05,378
<b>The uniforms had no markings.</b>

531
01:01:05,548 --> 01:01:08,312
<b>-l didn't recognize anyone.</b>
<b>-You know they weren't American.</b>

532
01:01:09,586 --> 01:01:12,611
<b>We were set up.</b>
<b>And you have to tell the media that.</b>

533
01:01:12,788 --> 01:01:16,224
<b>l saw the news report.</b>
<b>They say you were the only survivor.</b>

534
01:01:16,392 --> 01:01:19,020
<b>-You're a national hero to them.</b>
<b>-No.</b>

535
01:01:19,194 --> 01:01:22,061
<b>The government will discredit me</b>
<b>and call me a liar.</b>

536
01:01:22,231 --> 01:01:25,394
<b>Then they'll shoot me for treason. No.</b>

537
01:01:25,901 --> 01:01:27,960
<b>No. lt's too late.</b>

538
01:01:33,841 --> 01:01:35,365
<b>Wait.</b>

539
01:01:38,379 --> 01:01:39,937
<b>Wait.</b>

540
01:01:41,916 --> 01:01:44,180
<b>Unless you have proof.</b>

541
01:01:47,855 --> 01:01:49,254
<b>l'm gonna give you a number.</b>

542
01:01:50,957 --> 01:01:56,623
<b>You find anything, you call me.</b>
<b>lt's the only thing that can stop this.</b>

543
01:02:22,988 --> 01:02:25,456
<b>Oh, God.</b>
<b>This car smells like boiled ass.</b>

544
01:02:25,624 --> 01:02:29,423
<b>Sorry. lt was the only thing l could find</b>
<b>that didn't have goats, chickens...</b>

545
01:02:29,594 --> 01:02:31,721
<b>...or people sleeping in the back, okay?</b>

546
01:02:31,896 --> 01:02:34,763
<b>So did you and the general</b>
<b>solve our little problem there, LT?</b>

547
01:02:34,933 --> 01:02:37,367
<b>His hands are tied</b>
<b>unless we can get him solid proof.</b>

548
01:02:38,136 --> 01:02:41,469
<b>Kevin? Tell him what you told me.</b>

549
01:02:41,639 --> 01:02:47,202
<b>The guy in charge is Alvaro, real intense.</b>
<b>Said his family was killed by the rebels.</b>

550
01:02:47,378 --> 01:02:51,143
<b>There's not a chance in hell</b>
<b>this guy wants to make peace with FARC.</b>

551
01:02:51,315 --> 01:02:53,146
<b>Anything else?</b>

552
01:02:53,317 --> 01:02:57,845
<b>Got a guard to spit out the location</b>
<b>of our gear. Along with a few of his teeth.</b>

553
01:02:58,021 --> 01:03:00,683
<b>Was gonna grab the SAT phone</b>
<b>soon as l blew up that joint.</b>

554
01:03:00,858 --> 01:03:04,259
<b>That'd be a great idea,</b>
<b>except the bastards fragged our phone.</b>

555
01:03:05,195 --> 01:03:06,526
<b>Right.</b>

556
01:03:07,631 --> 01:03:09,427
<b>Our vid packs.</b>

557
01:03:10,266 --> 01:03:12,700
<b>Yeah. Yeah, the vid packs.</b>

558
01:03:12,869 --> 01:03:16,669
<b>Maybe we've got</b>
<b>these assholes on tape. Proof.</b>

559
01:03:17,507 --> 01:03:20,635
<b>-Let's get our gear.</b>
<b>-10-4.</b>

560
01:03:26,582 --> 01:03:29,049
<b>This is a major shitstorm.</b>

561
01:03:29,217 --> 01:03:34,382
<b>Colombia's ordered our military</b>
<b>and diplomatic personnel out of the country.</b>

562
01:03:34,923 --> 01:03:37,153
<b>My priority is my men.</b>

563
01:03:38,793 --> 01:03:40,226
<b>The intel about the base...</b>

564
01:03:40,829 --> 01:03:45,630
<b>...was leaked through the ClA to Rivera.</b>
<b>He was the only source.</b>

565
01:03:45,800 --> 01:03:47,858
<b>Son of a bitch.</b>

566
01:03:50,604 --> 01:03:52,231
<b>Dobb.</b>

567
01:03:54,542 --> 01:03:57,306
<b>You and your Langley gang</b>
<b>got played by your source.</b>

568
01:03:57,478 --> 01:04:02,074
<b>-We need to stop this madness right now.</b>
<b>-We're putting together a scenario...</b>

569
01:04:02,249 --> 01:04:05,912
<b>...linking your men to a rogue arm</b>
<b>of the Ruiz-Mendoza Cartel.</b>

570
01:04:06,086 --> 01:04:07,382
<b>-What?</b>
<b>-You can't do that.</b>

571
01:04:07,554 --> 01:04:10,079
<b>This puts their actions</b>
<b>outside of any political agenda.</b>

572
01:04:10,256 --> 01:04:12,781
<b>Operating on their own,</b>
<b>paid for with drug money.</b>

573
01:04:12,959 --> 01:04:14,927
<b>You're not gonna burn SEALs reputations.</b>

574
01:04:15,428 --> 01:04:17,419
<b>Those men have families.</b>
<b>They died for us.</b>

575
01:04:17,597 --> 01:04:21,158
<b>Their sacrifices will not go unnoticed,</b>
<b>just unsaid.</b>

576
01:04:21,334 --> 01:04:22,733
<b>Not by me.</b>

577
01:04:22,902 --> 01:04:25,962
<b>Your lousy intel put my men</b>
<b>in this FUBAR situation.</b>

578
01:04:26,139 --> 01:04:27,230
<b>l'm gonna get them out.</b>

579
01:04:27,406 --> 01:04:29,738
<b>You will do exactly</b>
<b>what you are told, soldier.</b>

580
01:04:29,908 --> 01:04:32,934
<b>Unless you wanna be reassigned</b>
<b>to a cell in Leavenworth.</b>

581
01:04:34,112 --> 01:04:38,481
<b>lt's commander.</b>
<b>And l'd advise you to back off.</b>

582
01:05:01,806 --> 01:05:06,174
<b>So, Kevin, let me ask you,</b>
<b>that fence is wired and hot.</b>

583
01:05:06,343 --> 01:05:09,870
<b>-You were gonna break in there?</b>
<b>-When the guy said ''barn,'' l thought barn.</b>

584
01:05:10,046 --> 01:05:12,071
<b>Cows, chickens.</b>

585
01:05:12,916 --> 01:05:16,943
<b>Open space. Cheap, easy to secure.</b>

586
01:05:18,688 --> 01:05:22,055
<b>The buildings look old but they've had</b>
<b>some high security retrofitting.</b>

587
01:05:22,225 --> 01:05:24,489
<b>-Can you get us through the doors?</b>
<b>-No problem.</b>

588
01:05:24,661 --> 01:05:27,151
<b>They got all our security tech</b>
<b>and protocols from us.</b>

589
01:05:29,331 --> 01:05:31,231
<b>Wait a minute.</b>

590
01:05:33,335 --> 01:05:36,133
<b>-The well.</b>
<b>-Yeah? What about it?</b>

591
01:05:36,305 --> 01:05:39,741
<b>This water tower. That well.</b>
<b>Gotta be connected, right?</b>

592
01:05:42,278 --> 01:05:44,303
<b>Some kind of pipe.</b>

593
01:05:44,779 --> 01:05:46,974
<b>Would be hell of a thing.</b>

594
01:05:48,383 --> 01:05:50,214
<b>No way.</b>

595
01:05:51,886 --> 01:05:53,615
<b>No way.</b>

596
01:06:00,695 --> 01:06:03,163
<b>-All the air we got.</b>
<b>-He doesn't have enough air.</b>

597
01:06:03,331 --> 01:06:05,594
<b>Hypothermia will get him</b>
<b>before his air runs out.</b>

598
01:06:05,766 --> 01:06:08,234
<b>lf he doesn't get strangled</b>
<b>by the root of a tree.</b>

599
01:06:08,402 --> 01:06:10,267
<b>You know,</b>
<b>you guys suck as cheerleaders.</b>

600
01:06:10,437 --> 01:06:15,397
<b>You're right. Blast our way in,</b>
<b>fight a battalion. lt could work.</b>

601
01:06:15,909 --> 01:06:18,810
<b>-The only easy day....</b>
<b>-Was yesterday.</b>

602
01:06:45,470 --> 01:06:48,405
<b>Push the car, don't start it.</b>
<b>l'll go this way.</b>

603
01:07:31,714 --> 01:07:33,682
<b>Come on. Come on. Come on.</b>

604
01:08:01,842 --> 01:08:02,866
<b>Got anything?</b>

605
01:08:16,557 --> 01:08:18,957
<b>l hate to say this, amigo.</b>

606
01:08:19,493 --> 01:08:21,393
<b>We need to start thinking Plan B.</b>

607
01:08:27,367 --> 01:08:29,198
<b>He's still kicking, l know it.</b>

608
01:08:42,514 --> 01:08:43,879
<b>Come on. Come on. Come on.</b>

609
01:08:51,824 --> 01:08:54,258
<b>Son of a bitch.</b>

610
01:08:54,426 --> 01:08:56,860
<b>He made it. He made it.</b>

611
01:09:10,975 --> 01:09:12,533
<b>Get ready.</b>

612
01:09:45,574 --> 01:09:47,371
<b><i>What's happened over there?</i></b>

613
01:09:47,543 --> 01:09:49,602
<b>This diesel is so dirty...</b>

614
01:09:49,778 --> 01:09:51,609
<b><i>...it cooked the filter.</i></b>

615
01:10:35,822 --> 01:10:39,120
<b>You don't think they'll mind</b>
<b>if we crash the party, do you?</b>

616
01:11:00,345 --> 01:11:04,406
<b>-Good to see you.</b>
<b>-Got this from the security guard.</b>

617
01:11:04,583 --> 01:11:07,313
<b>-Good to see you, LT.</b>
<b>-Yeah. Let's do this.</b>

618
01:11:15,560 --> 01:11:18,153
<b>They didn't even bother to change</b>
<b>the factory pass code.</b>

619
01:11:28,305 --> 01:11:30,136
<b>Here's our gear.</b>

620
01:11:31,842 --> 01:11:34,174
<b>Triggered the alarm.</b>
<b>Carter, you got security.</b>

621
01:11:34,345 --> 01:11:35,903
<b>Watch that door. Kill that alarm.</b>

622
01:11:41,918 --> 01:11:44,648
<b>-All right, find those vid packs.</b>
<b>-Got them.</b>

623
01:11:44,821 --> 01:11:46,516
<b>Good. Check them.</b>

624
01:11:49,492 --> 01:11:50,652
<b>-Nothing here.</b>
<b>-What?</b>

625
01:11:50,827 --> 01:11:54,524
<b>-Nothing. Must have wiped them off.</b>
<b>-We got nothing?</b>

626
01:11:54,697 --> 01:11:56,392
<b>-Nothing.</b>
<b>-Damn it.</b>

627
01:12:00,669 --> 01:12:04,161
<b>Boys, we got company.</b>
<b>l got the door.</b>

628
01:12:04,506 --> 01:12:06,531
<b>Carter, smoke. Ammo.</b>

629
01:12:06,942 --> 01:12:08,000
<b>Got it.</b>

630
01:12:15,417 --> 01:12:16,849
<b>Open the gate!</b>

631
01:12:19,553 --> 01:12:20,577
<b>Take cover.</b>

632
01:12:23,024 --> 01:12:24,616
<b>Ramirez!</b>

633
01:12:28,029 --> 01:12:29,053
<b>Damn it.</b>

634
01:12:32,600 --> 01:12:33,589
<b>Get that sniper.</b>

635
01:12:50,450 --> 01:12:53,647
<b>-Let's rock and roll.</b>
<b>-All good. l'm right behind you.</b>

636
01:13:15,339 --> 01:13:16,897
<b>Now. Go.</b>

637
01:13:17,842 --> 01:13:19,742
<b>Fall back to the car!</b>

638
01:13:35,926 --> 01:13:36,950
<b>Here they come.</b>

639
01:13:40,030 --> 01:13:41,497
<b>Pop the smoke.</b>

640
01:13:44,601 --> 01:13:47,434
<b>-We're in some real pretty shit now.</b>
<b>-They got here fast.</b>

641
01:13:47,604 --> 01:13:49,629
<b>-Hoof it or drive?</b>
<b>-We'll never lose them.</b>

642
01:13:49,806 --> 01:13:51,933
<b>Probably got a helo on the way.</b>

643
01:13:52,676 --> 01:13:54,700
<b>Holy shit. You're right.</b>

644
01:13:56,145 --> 01:13:58,238
<b>-Hey, how much smoke we got left?</b>
<b>-l got four.</b>

645
01:13:58,414 --> 01:14:01,281
<b>-l got two.</b>
<b>-That'll do.</b>

646
01:14:04,653 --> 01:14:06,621
<b>-l'm gonna need some cover.</b>
<b>-We got you.</b>

647
01:14:56,903 --> 01:14:58,803
<b>Rock and roll!</b>

648
01:15:34,371 --> 01:15:36,305
<b>-That shit worked.</b>
<b>-Go.</b>

649
01:16:01,130 --> 01:16:02,154
<b><i>Yeah?</i></b>

650
01:16:02,332 --> 01:16:05,893
<b>We took our shot, tried recovering</b>
<b>the vid packs. We came up empty.</b>

651
01:16:06,069 --> 01:16:09,334
<b><i>-What's your play, lieutenant?</i></b>
<b>-Play? Can't come home.</b>

652
01:16:09,505 --> 01:16:12,598
<b>How about we go downrange</b>
<b>and get ours before they get us?</b>

653
01:16:12,774 --> 01:16:14,071
<b><i>How about that?</i></b>

654
01:16:14,243 --> 01:16:16,939
<b><i>-That an idea?</i></b>
<b>-That's a one-way mission and you know it.</b>

655
01:16:18,513 --> 01:16:22,711
<b>-What's your situation like there?</b>
<b>-FARC has started their attacks.</b>

656
01:16:22,885 --> 01:16:26,252
<b>They bombed a school bus.</b>
<b>Killed 12 kids.</b>

657
01:16:26,421 --> 01:16:28,946
<b>The Pentagon's projecting</b>
<b>civilian casualties...</b>

658
01:16:29,124 --> 01:16:31,819
<b>...to be a quarter million in three months.</b>

659
01:16:31,993 --> 01:16:33,893
<b>Maybe it's time</b>
<b>we get our pound of flesh.</b>

660
01:16:34,061 --> 01:16:37,792
<b>We still have time to make this right.</b>
<b>Go back over the mission in your head.</b>

661
01:16:37,965 --> 01:16:39,956
<b>Everything you heard.</b>
<b>Everything you saw.</b>

662
01:16:40,134 --> 01:16:41,965
<b>Every branch snap. Every bullet hit.</b>

663
01:16:42,136 --> 01:16:45,367
<b><i>-Why? What's the point?</i></b>
<b>-Because l trained you, Sean.</b>

664
01:16:45,539 --> 01:16:47,666
<b>And l sure as hell</b>
<b>didn't train you to give up.</b>

665
01:16:49,810 --> 01:16:51,868
<b>The bogus intel</b>
<b>on the Venezuelan Alliance...</b>

666
01:16:52,045 --> 01:16:54,980
<b>...came from Carlos Rivera.</b>
<b>Colombian national.</b>

667
01:16:55,148 --> 01:16:57,139
<b><i>And a handler, codename Apotequil.</i></b>

668
01:16:57,317 --> 01:17:00,286
<b>Rivera was responsible</b>
<b>for the bombings in Bogotá.</b>

669
01:17:00,453 --> 01:17:01,920
<b>-l don't know how...</b>
<b>-Commander?</b>

670
01:17:02,088 --> 01:17:03,953
<b>...but they're tied into all of this.</b>

671
01:17:04,491 --> 01:17:06,686
<b>Do what you can, but do it smart.</b>

672
01:17:09,329 --> 01:17:10,693
<b>May l see your phone?</b>

673
01:17:12,498 --> 01:17:14,489
<b>l could give it to you.</b>

674
01:17:15,567 --> 01:17:19,128
<b>But you'd need a proctologist</b>
<b>to read my text messages.</b>

675
01:17:20,472 --> 01:17:22,372
<b>Consider yourself relieved of duty.</b>

676
01:17:22,541 --> 01:17:25,009
<b>You don't have the authority</b>
<b>to relieve me.</b>

677
01:17:26,345 --> 01:17:28,336
<b>Actually, commander...</b>

678
01:17:28,514 --> 01:17:29,538
<b>...l do.</b>

679
01:17:38,823 --> 01:17:40,222
<b>What now?</b>

680
01:17:40,391 --> 01:17:43,121
<b>l've still got a few cards to play.</b>

681
01:17:47,699 --> 01:17:49,189
<b>Thanks.</b>

682
01:17:53,804 --> 01:17:56,637
<b>All right. Shut it down.</b>

683
01:18:07,117 --> 01:18:09,108
<b>All right, mission walk-through.</b>

684
01:18:09,285 --> 01:18:11,310
<b>We split up in the jungle.</b>

685
01:18:12,321 --> 01:18:13,720
<b>Greg had the overwatch.</b>

686
01:18:17,026 --> 01:18:19,290
<b><i>Greg radioed in guard positions.</i></b>

687
01:18:21,364 --> 01:18:24,094
<b>-Right.</b>
<b>-Greg saw the black hats coming.</b>

688
01:18:24,367 --> 01:18:26,892
<b><i>Greg was watching the base</i></b>
<b><i>through the Specter.</i></b>

689
01:18:27,069 --> 01:18:29,127
<b>-Yeah?</b>
<b>-lt wasn't with our gear in the barn.</b>

690
01:18:29,604 --> 01:18:31,401
<b>No. lt wasn't.</b>

691
01:18:31,973 --> 01:18:34,407
<b>Oh, God. Could still be out there.</b>

692
01:18:34,576 --> 01:18:37,739
<b>lt would have caught everything.</b>
<b>Our position, the bad guys.</b>

693
01:18:37,912 --> 01:18:39,743
<b>-Yeah?</b>
<b>-Gear up.</b>

694
01:18:54,294 --> 01:18:55,625
<b>l have proof.</b>

695
01:18:57,898 --> 01:18:59,490
<b>Are you absolutely sure?</b>

696
01:18:59,967 --> 01:19:02,663
<b>Everything the world needs to know</b>
<b>to know we didn't do it.</b>

697
01:19:02,836 --> 01:19:05,634
<b>Okay. Excellent.</b>
<b>Where can we meet?</b>

698
01:19:06,073 --> 01:19:08,233
<b>Puerto Limon, 1700 hours.</b>

699
01:19:08,408 --> 01:19:10,535
<b>Okay, l will be there.</b>

700
01:19:10,710 --> 01:19:12,905
<b>And l pray that what you say</b>
<b>is correct.</b>

701
01:19:13,312 --> 01:19:14,939
<b><i>For if not...</i></b>

702
01:19:15,481 --> 01:19:18,609
<b>...tomorrow will be the bloodiest day</b>
<b>in the history of my country.</b>

703
01:19:20,119 --> 01:19:22,451
<b>Lucky for us, we still have today.</b>

704
01:19:48,913 --> 01:19:52,007
<b>Keep looking. lt's gotta be here.</b>

705
01:20:14,204 --> 01:20:15,228
<b>Gotcha.</b>

706
01:20:16,339 --> 01:20:17,465
<b>Thattagirl.</b>

707
01:20:22,078 --> 01:20:23,545
<b>Yes.</b>

708
01:20:23,713 --> 01:20:27,204
<b>-This clears us.</b>
<b>-When's the general due?</b>

709
01:20:27,382 --> 01:20:28,940
<b>One hour.</b>

710
01:20:29,118 --> 01:20:31,052
<b>Oh, shit. Wait a minute, guys.</b>

711
01:20:33,655 --> 01:20:35,020
<b>-What?</b>
<b>-Down there.</b>

712
01:20:38,760 --> 01:20:41,752
<b>Son of a bitch.</b>
<b>How'd these bastards find us?</b>

713
01:20:41,930 --> 01:20:45,764
<b>LT? We're against the mountain here.</b>
<b>The only way out of here is through them.</b>

714
01:20:47,168 --> 01:20:50,103
<b>l'm getting too old for this shit.</b>

715
01:20:51,139 --> 01:20:54,199
<b>This guy starts a war, don't lose it.</b>

716
01:20:54,742 --> 01:20:57,540
<b>-Great. No pressure.</b>
<b>-Options?</b>

717
01:20:58,479 --> 01:20:59,503
<b>Thin the herd.</b>

718
01:21:00,381 --> 01:21:02,440
<b>Quiet. No guns.</b>

719
01:21:03,851 --> 01:21:06,045
<b>How did l know</b>
<b>you were gonna say that?</b>

720
01:21:06,219 --> 01:21:07,516
<b>This is who we are, brother.</b>

721
01:21:10,524 --> 01:21:12,617
<b>For Greg and Steve.</b>

722
01:22:09,413 --> 01:22:11,938
<b>All you Americans</b>
<b>think you are Rambo.</b>

723
01:22:15,586 --> 01:22:18,578
<b>l prefer John McClane.</b>

724
01:22:21,491 --> 01:22:23,652
<b>Rafael, Dario.</b>

725
01:22:27,096 --> 01:22:28,893
<b>Dario. Rafael.</b>

726
01:22:51,186 --> 01:22:53,780
<b>Alvaro! Stop!</b>

727
01:24:14,131 --> 01:24:15,598
<b>Do it.</b>

728
01:24:16,200 --> 01:24:17,224
<b>Go on.</b>

729
01:24:17,902 --> 01:24:19,563
<b>Tell your people the truth.</b>

730
01:24:21,272 --> 01:24:24,399
<b>What about your wife? Your son?</b>

731
01:24:24,574 --> 01:24:26,906
<b>ls this what they would have wanted?</b>

732
01:24:27,077 --> 01:24:28,806
<b>Help me to end this.</b>

733
01:24:29,546 --> 01:24:31,480
<b>Death is all l have left.</b>

734
01:24:35,552 --> 01:24:36,883
<b>Kill me.</b>

735
01:24:37,053 --> 01:24:38,645
<b>Or l will kill you.</b>

736
01:24:39,522 --> 01:24:42,012
<b>Stand down, soldier.</b>

737
01:24:43,592 --> 01:24:44,616
<b>General Velez.</b>

738
01:24:45,794 --> 01:24:48,991
<b>-Carter?</b>
<b>-We've secured your man.</b>

739
01:24:49,164 --> 01:24:50,631
<b>Where's your proof?</b>

740
01:24:52,901 --> 01:24:54,596
<b>This man's a traitor.</b>

741
01:24:55,137 --> 01:24:57,367
<b>Give him the vid pack.</b>

742
01:24:58,574 --> 01:25:01,974
<b>We have footage of him</b>
<b>killing your soldiers on there.</b>

743
01:25:08,616 --> 01:25:09,742
<b>Alvaro.</b>

744
01:25:13,888 --> 01:25:14,980
<b>You're working with him?</b>

745
01:25:16,524 --> 01:25:17,786
<b>He works for me.</b>

746
01:25:18,292 --> 01:25:21,089
<b>-l'm his commanding officer.</b>
<b>-What?</b>

747
01:25:22,696 --> 01:25:24,027
<b>When l was a little boy...</b>

748
01:25:25,265 --> 01:25:27,825
<b>...the guerrillas cut my father's throat.</b>

749
01:25:28,001 --> 01:25:31,266
<b>They made me watch,</b>
<b>that's why l became a soldier.</b>

750
01:25:31,438 --> 01:25:33,497
<b>To hunt them down.</b>

751
01:25:34,441 --> 01:25:36,033
<b>What about your talk of peace?</b>

752
01:25:36,476 --> 01:25:39,809
<b>Those innocent men you killed?</b>
<b>They were your allies.</b>

753
01:25:40,379 --> 01:25:43,439
<b>They sacrifice for Colombia.</b>
<b>They're heroes.</b>

754
01:25:44,250 --> 01:25:46,343
<b>The bogus intel and the peace talks.</b>

755
01:25:46,519 --> 01:25:50,819
<b>-And my men. You set us up!</b>
<b>-Alvaro, kill him.</b>

756
01:25:52,324 --> 01:25:56,124
<b>Rivera, videotape the bodies. Make it look</b>
<b>like they tried to bomb the base.</b>

757
01:25:57,163 --> 01:25:58,562
<b>Rivera, Carlos Rivera.</b>

758
01:25:58,731 --> 01:26:02,496
<b>The factory bombings in Bogotá?</b>
<b>lt wasn't FARC.</b>

759
01:26:02,667 --> 01:26:05,830
<b>-lt was you.</b>
<b>-That is a lie. Kill him, Alvaro.</b>

760
01:26:06,004 --> 01:26:09,963
<b>No. No. Rivera has a handler.</b>
<b>His codename was Apotequil.</b>

761
01:26:15,580 --> 01:26:17,343
<b>Apotequil?</b>

762
01:26:18,616 --> 01:26:19,673
<b>You?</b>

763
01:26:20,751 --> 01:26:22,480
<b>My wife?</b>

764
01:26:23,854 --> 01:26:25,481
<b>My son?</b>

765
01:26:27,858 --> 01:26:30,326
<b>They died heroes for Colombia.</b>

766
01:26:30,494 --> 01:26:33,327
<b>Their sacrifice brought us together.</b>

767
01:26:33,831 --> 01:26:36,391
<b>-You killed them?</b>
<b>-No.</b>

768
01:26:36,567 --> 01:26:40,332
<b>America killed them.</b>
<b>The guerillas killed them.</b>

769
01:26:40,503 --> 01:26:42,835
<b>But now, we will win.</b>

770
01:26:43,005 --> 01:26:44,700
<b>We will crush the guerillas.</b>

771
01:26:44,874 --> 01:26:48,537
<b>We will kick the Americans out.</b>
<b>And Colombia will belong to us again.</b>

772
01:26:48,711 --> 01:26:51,942
<b>Alvaro, l will lead us into a new era.</b>

773
01:26:52,114 --> 01:26:53,809
<b>Two lives?</b>

774
01:26:53,983 --> 01:26:56,747
<b>What is that compared</b>
<b>to the destiny of our country?</b>

775
01:27:19,039 --> 01:27:20,939
<b>You're no soldier.</b>

776
01:27:21,108 --> 01:27:23,633
<b>You die a traitor to Colombia.</b>

777
01:27:28,349 --> 01:27:30,613
<b>He betrayed our country.</b>

778
01:27:32,119 --> 01:27:34,383
<b>He betrayed us all.</b>

779
01:27:40,627 --> 01:27:42,788
<b>This is so wrong.</b>

780
01:27:43,329 --> 01:27:45,320
<b>Then make it right.</b>

781
01:28:54,764 --> 01:28:56,993
<b><i>There is a special breed of warrior...</i></b>

782
01:28:57,166 --> 01:29:00,033
<b><i>...ready to answer our nation's call.</i></b>

783
01:29:00,202 --> 01:29:03,603
<b><i>A common man</i></b>
<b><i>with uncommon desire to succeed.</i></b>

784
01:29:03,772 --> 01:29:05,672
<b><i>Forged by adversity...</i></b>

785
01:29:05,841 --> 01:29:10,278
<b><i>...he stands along America's finest,</i></b>
<b><i>Special Operations Forces...</i></b>

786
01:29:10,446 --> 01:29:13,540
<b><i>...to serve his country,</i></b>
<b><i>the American people...</i></b>

787
01:29:13,716 --> 01:29:16,309
<b><i>...and protect their way of life.</i></b>

788
01:29:18,319 --> 01:29:20,480
<b><i>I am that man.</i></b>

789
01:29:20,922 --> 01:29:22,981
<b><i>SEAL creed.</i></b>

790
01:33:27,022 --> 01:33:29,013
<b>[ENGLlSH]</b>