Episode 13
Ahh...
Why are you hitting me?
Park Tae-In?
It's me! Who do you think it is?
Oh...
I thought you were a thief!
What did you say?
Why are you here?
How come you're not answering your phone?
You came here just to ask that?
I'm not here just to ask about that. I was worried about you.
But why are you dressed up like a thief?
Why do you still come when you're not feeling well?
Who asked you not to answer your phone?
I didn't bring it with me that's why I couldn't answer.
Really forgetful.
Go back and rest after taking your medicine. You're already sick. What if it gets worse?
- Hey!
- Why?
It can't be like that...
What is it?
I'm sick and I'm feeling hungry. Besides... the weather is cold.
What?
I'm hungry...
Come in.
Do you have to come here only when we're out of rice? I feel sorry to be cooking only ramen for you.
- Can I sleep here tonight?
- What?
I don't want to stay home alone. Now that I'm sick... It's harder to stay home alone.
Yesterday I dreamt about Ji Hyun-Woo.
Was it a nightmare?
My heart almost fell.
- Cold?
- Yes.
I've put the hot blanket on top of the bed. Go inside and sleep after you finish eating.
Don't ride on the motorcycle anymore. It's dangerous and easy to fall sick.
* noona = older sister
- Noona...
- Yes... Why?
That... Noona...?
Why?  Say it...
Noona, the reason you were against Bo-Ri...
Why do you always talk about Teacher Na Bo-Ri?
Was it because of the school?
Is it because I can't manage the school after marrying Bo-Ri?
You want to give our school to someone else?
Other than us, who would want take over the school?
I'm older than you, you should know how to weigh this.
At least, your wife has to know how to manage.
- Pass it to me.
- What?
I will take over the school. Just agree to my marriage with Bo-Ri.
What?
You're a person who really knows how to joke.
You know how to manage the school?
If you had known how to manage the school in the beginning... I wouldn't have had to take over.
A person who only knows how to paint, how can he manage a school?
Just learn it!
Bo-Ri and I will study overseas... We'll come back after 3 years.
For the time being, you will have to manage the school.
I will take over the school when I come back with Bo-Ri.
Eun-Seong is not our family member...
There's no need for Eun-Seong to manage it. I'll do it myself.
You... Do you really think that you can marry Teacher Na Bo-Ri?
How ever it is, I will not allow you two to get married.
- Why?
- Why don't you like Eun-Seong?
You used to like her so much. Why all of a sudden don't you like her anymore?
Even if you don't like Eun-Seong, how come you like Na Bo-Ri?
She didn't even finish her studies and her parents left them and went to a temple.
You want to marry someone like that?
You want to have a monk as a father-in-law?
You're not a foolish person.
Why are you so into starting a relationship with this kind of woman?
I... seriously don't know why and don't understand.
Seriously can't understand.
- Yes...?
- Ah... Teacher.
No... not asleep yet.
What are you doing?
I cooked ramen for Tae-In. Then I went to prepare a bed for Tae-In because he wanted to stay over tonight.
Tae-In... Is at your place?
Yes.
- Sleeping at your place?
- Yes.
Why?
He barged in my house requesting for food then doesn't want to sleep alone in an empty room.
Even so... he cannot sleep over at your house. He's a grown man.
He's just a kid to us. Sleep is the best thing for him right now.
- Bo-Ri...
- Yes?
- Yes...?
- Bo-Ri...
- What?
I'm sorry.
Yes?... Hello?
I love you.
Teacher's becoming like Tae-In.
So pretty...
I'm leaving... Can't sleep because it's too comfortable.
See you later at the school.
Where did Tae-In go? ...leaving only his bag at the desk.
We said that we would go to school together...
How come you're here first?
It shouldn't be this way.
Are you well already?
You're well, that's why you can play basketball?
Park Tae-In... I'm getting angry.
In a school, there's never a student that likes a teacher.
If there is, it's just for a short period. It'll be forgotten after a while. You misunderstood.
Still not able to let go?
Feeling disturbed?
You think you can't forget Biscuit? That's why you're like that?
How much does a cell phone cost now?
Teacher Na.
You have to be in the office if you're working in the school. Where did you disappear to?
I'm sorry. I didn't know there was a meeting.
So I've been weeding outside.
If you repeat this often, you'll be fired.
- What?
- Finally, they'll be conducting the teacher evaluation.
Teacher Na falls under most of the checklist for resignation candidate.
By following this, most of teachers have to be resigned.
Maybe... Seong-Il Financial Group is trying to take over our school
- What?
- What do you mean by that?
Think about it... Why do they try to replace teachers? Why do they change school regulation?
Even from the beginning, I felt that she was weird and very suspicious.
It's a ghost.
You don't have any work to do.
And the person you like is no longer here.
But you are still trying to be here.
This is what you call the Ghost of the School?
After reading the new rules, you are still the same?
You know you'll be fired... so you don't care?
Go on your way... You like to talk to the ghost a lot?
This is the latest... It has good sales now.
- How much?
- 550,000 won
Buy 2, for 1.1 million won?
Why so expensive?... 1.1 million won.
If I asked for 1.1 Million won from Father, he'd beat me to death.
* ajeosshi = mister, sir
Ajeosshi... My uncle bought me this for 15 million.
How can it be less 2 million? No way...
- There are some scratches. Surely you've been in a couple of accidents.
- Once only.
Ajeosshi, please give me a higher price... There's not much left after buying the cell phone with this money.
Ok. I'll add 100,000 won more.
Not selling!
- Then don't, and return the money...
- Ah... Ajeosshi... please add another 300,000 won
- Cannot. 200...
- 250.
- 230!
- 240! I can't lower it anymore.
Don't say anything else. 240! Cannot...! Cannot...! 240! Must be 240!
What am I supposed to do?
Hello?
You haven't finished work yet?
Wait a while. I'll come pick you up.
No. I want to go back now.
Need to buy a cell phone immediately.
Don't want to always look at people's reaction. And I can't text message you. So disturbed...
Your sister won't lend her cell phone to you?
She complained about the expensive phone bill because I always talked to you. So she took it back.
Don't stay there too long.
The Ghost will appear if you stay alone too long in the school.
I'm also a ghost... so it's ok.
- What?
- Nothing... Go home then.
Be careful on the road.
Ok...
Hello?
It's for Teacher...
Tae-In?
It's your wedding gift.
Where are you now? In the school?
If not in school, then why?
Where are you?
Back home.
I didn't get the money from Father or steal it.
So don't feel burdened.
Understand?
- Yes...
- Thank you.
- Hang up then...
- Ok.
Wishing you peace and goodnight...
I can't say I love you...
I can't say that now but to only wish you... Goodnight...
What?
What is this?
It can't be...
How come the school's changed into a college?
A sudden change. Besides,
she is a person who studied overseas. How can she be like that?
Ah... Really an immature person.
Where did the Director go?
She will only be satisfied if she sees the school being destroyed?
Say something. Why aren't you talking?
You wanted to see my face, was that why you called me out?
Yes.
What?
I wanted to see which part of you is prettier that mine.
Nothing of yours is comparable to mine.
Maybe Hyun-Woo likes the looks better...
I wanted to see that.
Hyun-Woo...
We lived in France together before. Did you know?
That...
You are taller than me... prettier than me... much more glamorous than me...
Like you said, I have nothing better than you.
But after being dumped by a man,
You came looking for his lover like this... Doesn't this hurt your pride?
You broke-up with him so long ago.
Why are you still acting like that? You make me feel awkward.
Don't talk to me like you know everything.
Aren't you younger than me?
Don't you know how to be respectful?
I met him when I was 20 years old.
And I didn't see anyone else for 10 years.
If I were to marry him, one of us has to take over the school.
That was why I started studying and let him continue painting.
You understand?
Because of him, I had let go of my dreams.
But I was suddenly dumped.
Then I became a total mess.
So seeing you like this
doesn't hurt my pride a bit.
I can get down on my knees and beg you.
I can make myself cry
till you give Hyun-Woo back to me.
To ask you to give him up
and return him to me.
That's why I came here to ask you.
You're still young.
You can still love someone else...
But I cannot.
Without him... I don't know how to live.
Can you help me?
Are you thinking of me?
Why are you not saying anything?
Bo-Ri...
I want to know one thing...
- Chae Eun-Seong... Why did you break up with her?
- What?
She sacrificed her life because of you.
You broke up with her because you didn't like her anymore?
What do you mean? Why do you suddenly bring up Eun-Seong?
- Bo-Ri...
- It's nothing...
Sheep 172, Sheep 173, Sheep 174...
Sheep 175
Why can't I sleep?
Because of him... I had let go of my dreams.
But I was dumped suddenly. Then I became a total mess
I can get down on my knees and beg you. I can make myself cry till you give Hyun-Woo back to me.
Without him... I don't know how to live...
Can you help me?
Goodnight...
What's the occasion?
You came to see me first.
- Seeing your expression, I already know.
- What?
In these days, you cannot sleep nor eat... As if you were going to die.  Right?
How do you know?
Only now you know. How my heart aches because I like you.
What you are going through now, it's nothing. For me, I had wanted to commit suicide.
- What?
- I was just thinking about it...
I'm not crazy. If I die, I will never see you again.
Do you like me that much?
Hold the kettle properly.
The water is spilling.
- Hey...
- The things that you want to do with me...
Things that you always want to do together...
From now onwards, let's do it together.
Together, we shall go to the lake... Watch movies together.
When your mother comes back to Korea, we'll have meals together.
A person must go through a lost of love, then he'll become human.
Good... Good... You have now became a human, Park Tae-In.
Have you forgotten all about Biscuit yet?
Not yet.
It's not easy.
Even if it's not easy, you still have to clean it up properly.
Wait...
If you still miss another woman, how can you hold my hand?
What?
Don't fool around.
What did you say?
The school... might be taken over by Seong-Il Financial Group.
I told you before...
If I can't have you, at least I'll have this school.
Eun-Seong.
Why?
Why...
can't you forget about me?
We were separated for so long.
Why are you acting like this?
You aren't that kind of person.
You're strong and smart.
You don't rely on anyone else.
You do well without anyone's help.
That was me when we were together.
But why do you like Na Bo-Ri?
You dumped me... who was with you for 10 years.
And liked someone whom you only knew for a few days?
You are that person. That person who dumped me for Na Bo-RI.
Miss Na Bo-Ri,
she didn't tell you that she met up with me?
I wanted her to let go...
and give you back to me.
Marry or separate...
I want her to leave you.
What?
I want her to do that.
Chae Eun-Seong...
She seems to understand...
If she doesn't let you go...
I will still let go.
Because I wouldn't want a person who liked a woman like her before.
Hello.
Where are you?
What?
Where!
I'm watering the plants.
Why didn't you tell me that you met up with Eun-Seong?
Why didn't you?
Do I have to report to you on whoever I meet?
Not everyone but because it was Eun-Seong.
Yesterday was because of this?
You suddenly asked about why I left Eun-Seong...
Because you just met Eun-Seong?
Your heart was moved?
Eun-Seong is very good at that.
That is the strategy that she used to separate us.
Don't misunderstand.
There is no one that will destroy themselves to hurt others.
Forget about Eun-Seong.
Don't see her anymore...
Even if you see her in school, pretend you don't know her.
I broke up with her and what are you still thinking about it?
If it goes on, it will affect our relationship.
I'm a woman with lots of imperfections.
I don't have any confidence to continue to be with you.
Waking up every morning... being scolded by you every time...
Having to live with that everyday...
Do you know how worried I am?
I don't know when you will stop loving me...
and break up with me.
It's like I'm seeing you in a danger zone.
I'm sorry...
Why don't you trust me...
Why don't you trust me?
Why feel lost and unsure?
I wasn't going to come here again.
You never listen my prayer.
Last one...
I will not come anymore.
The person I love...
Don't allow her to love someone else
You have to agree.
Other than this, I have nothing else to ask.
I beg you...
Beg you...
Hello?
Yes...
I am Director Lee.
Summons?
What summons?
No...
I have been managing the school very well for 25 years.
Why have I received a summons out of the blue?
Chae Eun-Seong is the Head but I'm the person in charge.
And... we merged with the Seong-Il Financial Group.
What do you mean?
You want us to hand the school over to the Seong-Il Finance Group?
What's the matter?
No...
You want me to go to a summons because of this?
Why do I have to accept this and hand over the school to the Seong-Il Finance Group?
I understand...
I will come now...
I know... I'll hang up first.
What's going on?
I don't know.
No...
I really don't understand why...
oh... oh... Dear...
Eun-Seong... I don't think that something has happened.
No... Don't tell me there's something going on...
I have something to show you.
What are you doing here?
Teacher...
Don't think of unnecessary things... go to school.
What are you doing?
Bo-Ri...
Take a look.
When did you take all these pictures?
I didn't want you to know.
I didn't want others to know too...
That's why I took it secretly.
This is when I was washing the toilet.
If a cigarette was given to you...
you'd surely smoke it immediately.
This is when,
I was punished in-front of the Teacher's room.
Why did you take only this kind of pictures?
It's because this section only has pictures of you being punished. There're many others in these albums.
This is when you were drawing.
And... All these are you.
Everything is you...
The storage is full of big drawings of you. Wanna go see them?
Don't worry too much.
Since I met you,
I only draw you alone.
That is why you have to trust me.
Don't be confused after you hear what people say.
Are you a fool?
Why did you bring this when you even don't have a motorcycle?
I'm an idiot.
What's happening?
Why are we supposed to hand over the school to your Finance Group?
Sit down...
Eun-Seong!
Please sit down first.
I will explain to you.
This school... is managed by me right now.
So?
The term was...
I will manage it if I were to marry Hyun-Woo.
Then?
Then...
Hyun-Woo dislikes me
- and I'm not able to marry Hyun-Woo,
- So...
Since you can't marry Hyun-Woo...
You want to take the school?
No...
That might happen...
so you have to help me get married to Hyun-Woo.
It is not I, who is getting married.
I've been helping so much.
You can't expect me to pull him into the church.
Just pull him.
What?
I told him before...
If he is not going to marry me, I will take the school.
Hyun-Woo...
didn't care what I said.
I studied painting with Hyun-Woo.
One of us has to take over the school...
and so he continued painting...
I stopped.
Without Hyun-Woo,
I have nowhere to go.
In the end...
I don't care about this school...
Whether I bring it under our Financial Group... or close the school.
Is erasing the board,
one of the things that you want to do together with me?
Not just erasing the board... Not just this.
The other students helped me erase the board...
Water the plants...
They helped me with my work, but you don't.
The other day, I was burning the trash and I was so dirty...
You didn't care at all.
If I were to do it together with you this week, you'll still feel bad.
Biscuit...
Have you forgotten about it?
Ermm...
Yeah.
How do you feel when you have to forget about the person you love?
Not good.
That's right. Why do you love someone you can't have?
The person that you can get is beside you.
But... I feel very tired.
I'll wait for you even if I'm tired. Don't worry.
But then, why did you fall in love with a teacher?
As if you are Romeo and Juliet.
Wanted to fall in love with someone you shouldn't?
I hate you a lot.
Hey!
Hey! You did something that deserves a beating...
Don't!
- Hey!
- Don't!
What are you doing in the class?
If you want to kiss, go outside.
Continue on like this, you'll be married right after you graduate high school.
They already have. You already have a new plan? Keep it up.
Hey... hey...
Brats!
You want me to finish up this painting?
Yes.
What is this?
What should I paint?
Anything.
Anything? On this?
But this is your piece of painting...
I'm afraid of ruining it.
That's fine.
It's dirty. What should we do?
It's ok.
Just paint whatever you want.
It's really dirty now...
Oh gosh... Teacher.
No... It's ok.
Oh gosh...
Oh... what to do, Teacher?
Did you do that on purpose?
Are you ok?
It's ok.
You really... Come here...
- Wait a minute...
- Come here...
- You drew on me a lot...
- You drew on me even more...
No... Don't draw on me... Wait...
Noona...
How's the school?
- Hello.
- You...
You... You better go talk to Eun-Seong.
What's the matter? Why?
You want to give up the school?
You...
Go and apologise to Eun-Seong now.
Understand? I will choose a wedding date for you.
On that day, you two should just get married.
You don't need to care about other things.
And you, Teacher Na... Resign and leave Hyun-Woo immediately.
Noona!
A person should know what shame is.
Even if you're not intelligent, you should know what to do at this point.
- Noona!
- Shut up!
Why are you being so hard headed? You think I'm kidding?
Is Grandfather's and Father's school going to be sold to someone else?
How can this be?
And...
Why must Teacher Na Bo-Ri marry Hyun-Woo?
Noona, go outside. I'll talk to you outside.
Liking and marrying...
They are two different issues.
Do you think you're suitable together?
Teacher, you think you're able to get Hyun-Woo?
Enough! What else do you want to say?
Don't blame me... I too...
I've been very patient.
You... Must not forget...
The name that established this school is Ji Jeong-Su.
As long as I am Ji Hyun-Ae and you are Ji Hyun-Woo. You cannot run away from the school.
Until you are dead, you have to marry Eun-Seong.
It's better for us not to meet again, Teacher.
I want to clean up. I should get going.
Some say that if you change suddenly, it'll lead to death.
You have to finish doing all the things that you want to do with me.
You... You are looking for sympathy.
That is why you are doing this. You want to use me to forget about Biscuit.
If it is reason no. 1, you are going to die today.
If it's reason no.2... I can let you go.
Which one?
Second one.
Really?
Really.
You have to eat and sleep at the right time.
You are very weak at this point in time.
The loser has to buy pizza.
No... chicken ginseng soup.
- What?
- You are really weak right now.
3...
2...
1...
0...
The person I love...
Don't let her love someone else.
Tae-In.
Tae-In...
Hey...
Tae-In
Are you awake?
Hey... Are you awake?
Are you ok?
I'll buy chicken ginseng soup.
You scared me.
I told you I will take over the school.
That's nonsense.
How are you going to manage it?
I was going to manage it anyway.
Our grandfather started it...
Our Father took over it and now it is my turn.
Why do you have to jump in, Noona?
Bro-In-law, you have to speak nicely.
Yes... I jumped in.
Your father didn't believe in you at that point in time.
Because you only liked to paint and drink. I didn't want you to suffer and that was why I took over the school.
Why do you have to marry her?
You think I married your Bro-In-law because I liked him?
If there had been any one of our family who could have taken over the hospital,
I wouldn't have married your brother-in-law.
When I was 25 years old,
I had to cause a married man with a child to get a divorce. Then I got married
to your Bro-In-law. I let him manage the whole hospital.
Only now am I able to come out of the school.
I'm 44 years old now. I started managing the school at a young age.
My life had changed because of that.
Do you see it?
Don't you feel it for your Noona's life?
Don't continue to be like this.
For the sake of your happiness, you have to make this decision.
Why don't you know how to appreciate this...
You are only being hard headed.
Tae-In.
Why so late?
What's the matter?
Came out for jogging...
Why jogging so late at night?
You ran here?
Yes.
You're so weird.
Go in. I'm leaving.
Tae-In.
Do you want me to make ramen for you?
I will cook a more delicious one the next time.
Right now I don't have the strength to do it.
Be careful. It's hot.
Why are you jogging at this hour?
Eat slowly.
I always play during school. That is why I can't sleep.
After sweating, maybe I can sleep.
But do you have to come this far?
Don't talk to me when I'm eating.
Sorry... Eat.
Why do you not have strength?
This morning you were laughing together with him.
I'll get some rice for you.
Could you sleep here tonight?
Why?
I've been only living with my younger sister for more than 10 years.
When you slept here the other day, it felt like we had one more family member. So, I was happy.
Teacher.
Why are you crying? Did you have a bad dream?
What's wrong?
This is my prayer.
I wish this woman whom I love,
does not fall in love with another person.
If I'm with this woman,
I have the courage to go through any ordeal.
But if this woman loves someone else,
I don't have a reason to live.
So, God, if you exist, please listen my prayer.
I wish this woman whom I love,
does not fall in love with another person.
This is a FREE fansub. Get it for free @ d-addicts.com
Translator : PsychoWabbit
Timer : Aplepy
editor: ray of light
QC: Aplepy, h@lfb0y
Brought to you by S.O.S Fansubs
Save Our Soul - Subtitles to Survive
Thank you for watching with us.