Hellbooy20 Presents
Champagne Shower by REDFOO!!
We're gonna get you wet
We're gonna make you sweat
A night you won't forget
Are you ready for it?
Champagne showers
Pop it in the club
We light it up 80 hour
I said
Champagne showers
Pop pop pop pop it in the club
We light it up 80 hour, 80 hour
Let the party rock!
Put your hands up
Everybody just dance up
We came to party rock
Flash your titties like Mardi Gras
They call me Redfoo
I walk in the club with a bottle or two
Shake it, spray it on a body or two
And walk out the party with a hottie or two
I'm gonna get you wet
I'm gonna make you sweat
A night you won't forget (won't forget - no)
We're gonna get you wet
We're gonna make you sweat
A night you won't forget
Are you ready for it?
Champagne showers
Pop it in the club
We light it up 80 hour
I said
Champagne showers
Pop pop pop pop it in the club
We light it up every hour, 80 hour
Let the party rock!
Boom!
Guess who stepped in the room
SkyBlu, Redfoo and Goon
He's a party rocker from night 'til noon
And it's about to be a champagne monsoon
Baby girl, you look legit
Come to my table and take a sit
Open wide 'cause we're spraying it
Fifty six bottles ain't paid for shit
I'm gonna get you wet
I'm gonna make you sweat
A night you won't forget (won't forget - no)
We're gonna get you wet
We're gonna make you sweat
A night you won't forget
Are you ready for
Champagne showers
Pop it in the club
We light it up 80 hour
I said
Champagne showers
Pop pop pop pop it in the club
We light it up 80 hour, 80 hour
Party people
Now I want you to grab your bottles
Put them up in the air
Now shake, shake, shake that bottle and make it [pop]
We're gonna get you wet
We're gonna make you sweat
A night you won't forget
Are you ready for it?