What's the matter? You're quiet.
Can't we decline this assignment?
Why?
He's a serial killer. He won't hesitate to kill.
He is the one, who planned this strike.
That's a guarantee of safety.
And l'm sure he knows about us, too.
Huh? About what?
l'm going, Raye.
Hey, Naomi.
l'll be all right, Raye.
Do you know ''takami no kenbutsu''?
''Takami no kenbutsu.''
Watch an event unfold as a spectator.
My intention is to fight along with them.
Following the B.B. case,
this is the 2nd time you're assigning Naomi.
You must really trust Naomi.
She plans to quit the F.B.l. to get married.
At such a time,
she can prove to be most effective.
Just like this.
Do you think of quitting, too?
Me? Quit?
For me...this is everything.
Watari, l'll be happy as long as you're with me.
lsn't Miss Naomi in danger?
12 sec. earlier than l planned. She's very good.
You're very good, too.
Thank you very much.
Make arrangements to go to Japan.
To Japan?
With 97% probability,
Kira is in Japan.
l may not be able to come back here.
''The person whose name
is written in the notebook... will die.''
''Time of death, controlled by Death Note,
is 23 days.''
120 DAYS LATER
BANGNUM VlLLAGE, THAlLAND
You, over there.
Yes, Sir!
Take care of that.
We're finished here.
BOY!
We've got to get out of here!
This village is over.
Come on. Let's go.
This mission is accomplished.
Look, sir! They're here!
Wrap it up.
Come on! Move out!
Sir! There is a truck moving north.
We don't need any witnesses or survivors.
Yes, Sir!
We're being followed.
Drop you off.
Find a phone and call 0105928147218.
Shit! You need to write it down, don't you.
0105928147218
Well done. Listen!
Call that number, and say F1225, OK?
This is very important.
You must call that number.
Watari will protect you.
Good luck! BOY!
Light Yagami...
''F dead. Biomonitor's not responding''
Bad news?
F died in Thailand.
lt was in the line of duty,
so it couldn't be helped but...
That's Misa's notebook, isn't it?
Whose name did you write in? Light Yagami's?
This is the last name to be written...
in the Death Note.
''L. Lawliet - Will quietly die...
of heart attack 23 days later.''
L...
Light Yagami will attempt to kill me
with the Death Note.
Determine my own fate.
lt's the one and only way to outwit Death.
To stop the enormous evil called Kira,
it's a small sacrifice.
So, it's 23 days later.
Bring Misa Amane here.
Kira and l have a score to settle.
lNFECTlOUS DlSEASE CENTER OF ASlA
This should do it.
Do you check your temperature?
Of course. Every 4 hours.
You told me to, dad.
Prof. Nikaido.
- Kujo here.
- Come in.
- Dr. Kujo.
- Maki.
l want to take you somewhere
on your next day off.
No day off for a while, l guess.
''WHAT COMES WlTH 'HOPE'
lN THE CHART BELOW?''
Maki, Dr. Kujo has work to do.
Yes, dad.
BlO-lNFECTlON DEFENSE WARD
lt's finished.
Thanks. Good work.
Dr. Kujo.
Virus weapon sent from Thailand.
Virus weapon...
Washington wants us to examine this.
l examined it,
and discovered 2 types of virus are its roots.
Highly infectious influenza virus
was crossed with the deadly Ebola genes.
lt is Death itself.
lnfection rate is 100 times that of Ebola.
Who in the world made this?
Many countries are secretly undertaking
the development of virus weapons.
Some countries succeeded.
No, this one is a failure.
What?
Virus weapon is a success,
only if it comes with an antidote.
Otherwise, the user will also be infected.
l'm sure there was antidote,
but it's of no use now.
What do you mean?
This virus has mutated in the past 20 hours.
Mr. Watari, are you Mr. Ryuzaki's father?
No, l'm...
The Death Note.
Checkmate.
Wait a minute.
Burning that won't change your lifespan.
l know. l have 20 days.
C'mon...Wait.
Light said he could be
the god of a new world with that.
Doesn't that interest you?
The way Light died...
Was it godly?
K...
ENVlRONMENTAL GROUP - BLUE SHlP
Water temperature 24, Ph 6.2.
Sorry l kept you waiting, Prof. Kagami.
Though we act like the ruler of Earth,
mankind cannot even imitate the basics of nature.
10 years ago,
the planet's self-recuperative power
would have been effective.
But now it is no longer...
Yes, Earth is coming to its end.
All the more,
l looked forward to cleansing Earth, that is...
by reducing humans with the virus.
l'm aware of that.
lf you are, Matoba,
why seek a buyer for that virus?
Pardon?
Union of European companies,
the American establishment,
and Russia.
You're weighing their bids.
ls it money you want?
Such greed for personal gain...
has contaminated the wealth of Earth's nature.
Don't you understand that?
Get out of here.
There is no place here for the likes of you.
There's no place for you here.
Prof. Kagami.
Are you really trying to sell the virus?
You heard the originator of this plan.
The virus must be scattered
simultaneously in various areas.
To enable that...
we need to become partners with a group
which has a global network.
We don't need any people hesitant
of our Earth Cleansing Plan.
Are we clear on this?
We're all gonna die anyway.
19 DAYS LEFT
See the man the camera captured.
He's the serial killer, murdering the clergymen.
This man?
Yes.
The probability rate is 86%.
lf he's the culprit,
he hides souvenirs in the crypt under the church.
Yes, sir.
Concerning Princess Joanne's death...
l have evidence that it was not accident
but assassination.
l see. Please send the data right away.
l will.
The leader of the arms syndicate, Rod Ross.
He deals with the mafia
at the Far East underground market once a month.
Most of the arms go to the Middle East.
Fifty AK47s. When is the next trade?
Next Saturday.
14 DAYS LEFT
You can't make a call unless you put in money.
Phone call from Chaiang Mai. lt's for Watari.
l, L will take that call.
F1225... F1225...
A gift from F.
l'll accept the gift.
12 DAYS LEFT
Although he's scared, he's physically sound.
Why was he the only one not infected?
l don't know.
Unless we find a countermeasure,
the virus will be used again.
And in the near future.
10 DAYS LEFT
8 DAYS LEFT
This Room...
is only for Watari and l.
May l take a look?
My first babysitting experience...
doesn't seem to work out.
Maki, welcome home. Did you have a good day?
Mom.
Maki.
l need a favor.
What?
Please deliver this to him.
The address is in here.
Him? Who is it?
He's the answer to this.
Homework was well done.
Naturally.
And...This is your new homework.
Again?
l'm well aware.
that ''if it's difficult,
it's worth the challenge.''
Now, off with you.
Dr. Kujo.
Yes?
Can you stay? l'd like to talk to you.
Fine with me. What is it?
Meet me in P-4.
Yes, l will.
Mr. Matoba, please.
Watari.
While l was working undercover
on the bio-terrorism attack in the village.
l met a boy who doesn't seem to be affected
by the virus.
The virus is devastating this village.
lt is extremely dangerous and fatal.
l am going to give the boy the contact information
for Wammy's headquarters.
The attack is connected
with the global terrorist network.
This Japanese man ''Matoba'' is a key person
to this investigation.
VlRl AND BACTERlA lNFECTlONS
May l help you?
Sorry to bother you at this hour, but we're...
such people.
Why are you here?
Dr. Kujo.
How can l help you?
Oh, it's you.
Examined the culture fluid of that virus.
The ingredients matched those l mixed.
ln other words,
that virus was created in this lab.
What is this? Who are you? Why're you doing this?
We are people who grieve the future of Earth.
Earth's ecosystem will be destroyed.
The human specie has increased excessively.
Don't you understand?
lf there are too many,
all we do is decreasing that number.
Virus weapon for that? That is so foolish!
Dr. Kujo, don't tell me you agree with him.
You're intelligent and decent.
l am...the originator of this plan.
By the excessive increase of humans,
earth is now at peril.
l will eliminate useless human beings
to create a new world and its ecosystem.
How could you...?
Prof., l didn't intend to tell you so soon.
l wanted you to concentrate on developing
the antidote for that virus.
What's the matter?
l knew it.
You've succeeded.
This is the only antidote.
l've deleted all the data.
l'm going to incinerate this, too.
Professor.
Without this, you can't spread the virus.
Prof. Nikaido.
Hand it over.
No.
Prof., don't do it.
Bring the professor's daughter.
Why my daughter?
Which is more precious?
Your daughter or antidote data?
Go.
Wait!
l guess there's no alternative.
Why that virus?
Professor!
Dr. Kujo.
You have overcome the weakness
of the virus weapon.
Virus will not onset immediately.
Because of this,
it was said that virus cannot be a weapon.
But you have...
The new world needs people like you, professor.
Need?
l do not want to be chosen by people like you.
Have P-4...
incinerated in the plasma furnace.
This virus...
eats through the epidemic prevention filter.
Thank you!
- Hey, what's up?
- Please. Drive.
Where to?
Go to all these addresses.
You said the antidote data is here.
Please look for it.
l am. ln my head.
''WHAT COMES WlTH 'HOPE'
lN THE CHART BELOW?''
What?
''HOPE''
W... A...
T... A...
R... l...
l found it.
Maki, welcome home. Did you have a good day?
Maki, welcome home.
Clear these.
- Mustn't communicate now.
- Get back.
l'm K. How do you do? You're L?
Yes, you're right.
l'm L. How do you do?
Thank you for letting me know about Watari.
You surprised me.
ls anything wrong?
l'm working on infectious disease.
Something happened, and l need your help.
My help? Why?
A new, devastating virus was discovered.
But my partner who developed
the antidote was murdered.
The data is missing, and l want you to find it.
Mankind must be saved.
l see. You must provide me with the details.
Please come over at noon tomorrow?
Yes, l will. Tell me where to go.
l'll send you a map.
See you then.
l'm working on infectious disease.
Who was that?
A formidable foe.
Maki took the data with her.
The data will come here.
6 DAYS LEFT
Ah...Excuse me.
Can l help you?
l was told to show you this.
l have no idea what that is.
So this isn't it, either. Darn.
What's the matter?
l've been driving all night from yesterday.
l've really had it.
Only talks to her bear. l give up.
Bear?
A teddy bear. The passenger is a girl.
She's looking for a man named Watari.
l guess this isn't it, either.
Thank you for your time.
Would you please let that girl in?
What is that?
Some medicine?
No, this is a virus.
A virus?
Yes.
At all costs, no one must possess the antidote.
One who possesses
it will be invincible to the virus weapon.
That's why Prof. Nikaido
entrusted Watari with this virus
and destroyed the only antidote he developed
along with himself.
Have a bite.
What time is it?
lt's 8:00.
My dad's orders.
lt's unlocked.
Good.
Maki!
What your dad confided in you...
was the wrong item.
He needs that badly. Can you give it back?
So, that's it.
K...
Or shall l call you Dr. Kimiko Kujo.
The appointed time is noon.
You seem to have found out my name.
Then, l want you to show your face.
Watari was very proud of you.
l'm sure he still feels that way.
Don't think he can save you.
He has his weak points, too.
Some things can't be solved up here.
Let me go.
Maki.
What the hell...
Murderer!
l saw it all.
You should bleed and die like my dad.
lndeed, that is my weak point.
Let me go. You'll be infected.
Let me go.
l'll kill her. l'll kill her with the virus.
F.B.l, Suruga.
After Watari's death, we'll protect you.
That's encouraging.
- This way.
- No!
The Countermeasure Transfer Room is in here.
What in the world is this?
Crepe...
Please drive.
Didn't the girl have the virus?
What happened to the antidote data?
Don't tell me it doesn't exist.
What's our next move?
You're the developer. We can make the virus.
But it's useless without the antidote.
You're right.
He's ahead of us.
Shut down all L's access from the outside.
Yes, ma'am.
l can kill anyone l want now...
Do you think your dad sent you
to Watari for that purpose?
Dad is...dad is dead.
You know this Watari person, don't you?
Yes. l am L.
L...
They call themselves ''Blue Ship''...
an environmental group.
That man with a scar is an extremist
using that as his cover.
But K is not a group member.
- Mr. Suruga.
- What?
Turn left 30m ahead. We're getting out.
- 30m...
- Over here.
Here?
Let's go.
Let's meet here 2 hours later.
Drive on as fast as you like.
That means...
Am l a decoy?
Damn! They're persistent.
What the hell are you doing?
This is a one-way street. Stop.
What're you doing?
l told you to stop, you bastard.
l said it's a one-way street. Stop.
Let me through. F.B.l. business.
So what? Get out. You're Japanese, aren't you?
Look. F.B.l.
You're Japanese. You can't fool me.
Welcome, master.
Sorry l kept you waiting.
Please enjoy, master.
He's strange.
Easy to call him that.
They're Fibonacci Numbers.
He's a mathematical genius.
He's F's...
A gift Watari left me.
By the way, the virus you had seems to be...
a fake.
That's impossible.
Your dad was infected right after contact.
Your body temperature shows no change.
Body temperature?
That might be the reason.
Maki received an injection every 10 days.
Dad didn't tell me what the injection was.
l see. You're saying the virus is restrained
because of the injection.
lt can't be anything else.
Does it mean Maki's body has both...
the virus and the hint to restrain the virus?
All the more, we must get her.
- You go, too.
- Wait.
Let's change our plan.
We don't have much time.
lt seems we don't have much time.
Don't worry about it.
l, too, need to settle this in 6 days.
Did she inject the virus by herself?
Yes, she did.
Don't worry. ln the dormant stage,
no virus will be a threat.
l see...
But before the virus takes effect,
we need to travel a bit far.
With her?
lf the virus awakens, we'll be infected first.
We probably will.
''L. Lawliet - Will quietly die...''
''of heart attack 23 days later.''
Perhaps it won't be as ''quietly'' as l hope to.
Leave the rest to the F.B.l.
Thank you. ln that case, Mr. Suruga,
l need a favor.
Anything for you.
Damn.
Made me a decoy again.
Where're we going?
To a man named Koichi Matsudo.
Prof. Matsudo?
l've met him before. But why do you know him?
When l looked at the book on
lnfectious Disease Center, his name and...
your dad's were there as co-writers.
''KOlCHl MATSUDO'' ''KlMlHlKO NlKAlDO''
We interrupt this program for emergency news.
A girl infected by a dangerous virus.
has escaped from a hospital.
We have Dr. Kujo of the
lnfectious Disease Center here.
Dr. Kujo, what kind of a virus is this?
This virus is extremely infectious and...
there is no effective vaccine yet.
lf symptoms appear, recovery is impossible.
l can say the virus is lethal.
This is Maki Nikaido, who is currently missing.
She is 12 years old
and goes to a school in Saitama.
Body height 150cm.
lmpossible.
She was last seen wearing
a navy blue school uniform.
Let's get off.
Can't use public transport anymore.
A girl infected by a lethal virus
got off the train at this station.
The virus could be airborne.
We are undertaking an infection test.
Please cooperate to prevent the virus
from spreading.
Please. We need your cooperation.
We are looking for this girl.
Witness reports on the girl
infected by the virus.
Approximately 30,000.
We need some time to verify them.
L...
l'm really tired, L.
lt's ok. l knew this would happen
Suruga, haven't you recovered Death Note yet?
L and l are moving separately now.
Separately? What do you mean?
To gain L's trust.
Why moving separately for that?
But l promise to accomplish my mission.
5 DAYS LEFT
You bastard.
Move around with a virus infected person?
lt's common sense to avoid
densely populated areas.
lf the symptoms appeared?
Not just Maki,
but everybody around her will be involved.
Are you listening?
Absolutely irresponsible.
What is it?
Quarantine me.
Have the symptoms...?
You're all right.
You must've run through the woods.
lt's a tick bite.
Come with me.
What d'you plan to do?
Maki is fighting that horror.
That's why we need someone
who can make the antidote.
l can't.
Prof. Nikaido could, though.
l'm...
l'm scared.
The vaccine l developed killed people.
So, l'm scared.
There are lives l have sacrificed, too.
But now,
l can't abandon the life before me.
Hi, Mr. Noda.
Oh, hi, Prof. Matsudo.
l'll be using the lab again.
l hope you have permission from the professor?
4 DAYS LEFT
3 DAYS LEFT
Find out anything?
lt's energy source is sugar.
lt likes sugar, but not fruit sugar.
Sugar?
Maki basically has low blood sugar.
The virus probably wasn't active inside her
because of that.
Not because of her dad's injection?
The injection was probably for her
low blood sugar.
Does determining the energy source
help in developing the antidote?
No.
Destroying the sugar in the body
will kill the virus,
but that would stop the body activity.
13:11
What?
Please be quiet for a while.
What is that?
M... K
So, what is it?
lt's a code.
But where did you see this?
That's the homework my dad gave me.
lt's a message from Prof. Nikaido.
What could MK mean?
Prof. Matsudo. Tell me if any word
draws your attention.
... Midkine
That's it.
Midkine may be able to suppress the virus.
So that's what it is.
lt's a protein, which creates and breeds cells.
Restores broken cells
and stops cancer from progressing.
Restores nerve cells,
so it may be a wonder drug for Alzheimer.
ls it possible to artificially synthesize Midkine?
Yes, with 10 billion yen research fee and 5 years.
5 years...
But l'll think of some ways to do that.
For example,
Midkine is abundant in a fetus.
lt has to be a fetus.
He's a survivor of the village
destroyed by that virus.
He was examined,
but not for MK proteins.
Let me take some of your blood.
Ah, that feels good.
There will be a series of tests from tomorrow.
l know that.
C'mon. Let's eat.
Wait.
Let's eat.
Why do you only eat sweets?
Sugar is an essential energy source
of the brain and...
Over eating is bad.
You'll die.
You may be right.
You should...
straighten your back, too.
l'm going to the bathroom.
Maki.
Thanks for the call.
l'll kill you.
Can't kill you when the antidote is made.
l'll kill you before that.
Sorry. l broke the promise to come alone.
You coward!
They are searching for the reason
why symptoms don't appear on Maki
to develop the antidote.
No, Dr. Kujo's aware...
Maki's symptoms can appear any time.
Then, why take Maki?
Maki is a perfect vessel
for secretly carrying the virus.
Please continue to work on the antidote.
We'll need a lot of it.
You know what to do?
Wait a minute.
ls it finished?
Hasn't been tested yet.
You're incredible.
l'll get to work.
and make as much as l can.
Please do so.
l didn't expect a child
to stake her life for revenge.
Her dad was killed before her eyes.
Can't blame her.
You may be right.
lf Kujo is escaping from Japan,
does that mean they've developed the antidote?
No. By taking Maki,
she deceives the Blue Ship members
that the antidote is completed.
How does Kujo intend to scatter the virus?
They could disguise as a emergency patient
and medical staff.
lt has less procedure to clear the
boarding procedure. They can easily board a plane.
Then, hijack the plane.
- To where?
- Probably to the U.S.
To the U.S.?
Matoba may have chosen the destination.
As you said,
Matoba uses the ecology group as his front.
Matoba has no principles, just greed.
People with greed will head
for the most profitable country.
2 DAYS LEFT
Please.
JNA flight 204, right?
Attending personnel are Dr. Kimiko Kujo...
And myself, Daisuke Matoba.
Let me see the papers.
ls she Mayumi Honda?
Yes.
l wish for a successful operation.
Good morning.
Thank you for boarding JNA flight 204.
l burned Death Note. l no longer have it.
l'm sorry l couldn't help your mission.
l see...
But l...
L
l want to help you.
Good morning, passengers.
This is your captain, Saito.
A message from Control Room.
We are ready to take off,
but have just received...
a report from the control tower.
A suspicious vehicle is in the runway.
We have been requested to be on standby
at this location.
We will inform you of any further development.
We appreciate your patience.
Thank you for your cooperation.
- What're you doing?
- Make way.
Make way.
Anything wrong?
Don't move.
What's going on?
We only take action above the U.S.
Don't be so rigid.
Change in schedule.
We'll be safe, right?
You'll soon find out.
What d'you mean?
Didn't we have an injection?
l didn't make any antidote.
You tricked us?
A buyer's paying $10 million
for the virus and the antidote.
Your true aim.
Wait a minute. We'll all die.
lf you're gonna die, die alone.
We'll all die.
l don't wanna die. Help me.
Dr. Kujo, help me. Help me.
Captain.
Oh, no. The girl on TV is on this plane.
What's wrong?
All right?
Be quiet.
Earth is finished anyway.
Take off.
Finished...Damn.
So, we're finished.
Don't move.
Stop it.
lt's moving.
Hey, hang on.
Don't mind them.
lt's merely a minor sacrifice for a big purpose.
Whatever...
the reason may be, murder is always a bad thing.
Too bad. lt's too late now.
lt's not too late.
The antidote.
We've succeeded.
We can save them all.
lnject this to everyone.
You've done enough damage.
We don't need that.
This girl and everyone else here can die.
Like she said, we'll all die.
Mankind, which destroys environment
and wages war, should die.
Correct ecosystem will save the world.
ls this what Watari hoped for?
He said: ''Make the world better.''
So, destroy mankind. You must take over this plan.
l decline.
Mankind must have the power to change its future.
lt's too late.
The plane will fly. Everybody dies,
and the virus will scatter.
No.
The magnetic wave of
this is enough to crash the plane.
The virus will fall into the sea
and become harmless.
lt's checkmate.
lf you're alive, you can start over.
No one has the right to take that away.
Start over...
By my contract with Death, l'll die 2 days later.
Death...
You must live on.
lt's Watari's wish.
lnject these to everyone.
OK.
All right?
Enough antidote for everyone.
OK.
Hurry. Take these.
What will you do?
l'm okay.
l'm okay now.
You're a good girl. l believed in you.
l am honored to work under
the command of the legendary L.
l was not in command.
Mr. Suruga, l'm glad l trusted you.
Thank you very much.
l still have 2 more days.
This is from L.
Maki, welcome home.
Did you have a good day?
Yes.
The 5 days were good.
Maki, welcome home.
Make tomorrow a good day, too.
Same to you.
L...
1 DAY LEFT
ls this him?
Yes.
There is one thing l want you to remember.
No matter how gifted,
you alone cannot change the world.
But that's the wonderful thing about this world.
l will give a name to this boy.
Watari would've wanted you to do so.
''Near'' is a good name.
You will always be near when someone is saved.
Find happiness, ''Near''.
Watari.
l want to live
a little bit more in this world.
''RESTS lN PEACE''