TRANSLATED BY:
||killer_sub||
I need to know everything you know
about the Winter Hill Gang
and specifically what you know about
your former boss, and now fugitive
James "Whitey" Bulger.
Well let's start.
In the beginning...
Jim was a small town player.
He's a very smart
disciplined man.
Take your shot.
But make it your best,
cause I get up, I eatcha.
Then the next thing you know he's a damn kingpin!
You know why?
Because the FBI let it happen.
I grew up with Jimmy
and his brother Billy, the senator.
And that is a bond that doesn't get broken.
Your brother is wading into some very dark waters...
Jimmy's business, is Jimmy's business.
We all need friends.
Even Jimmy.
Even you.
I can help you.
Jimmy, and you can help me.
It's an alliance.
We'll get the FBI to fight our wars.
And we do whatever we wanna do!
To success.
Just gettin' started.
Boom!
Bulger's playing us.
Makin' a fool of the bureau...
We're in too deep!
And he knows it!
God help us.
How come no one has nailed Whitey Bulger?
He seems to be involved in every crime in the city
and yet the Bureau keeps sayin' he's clean.
Well, what's Bulger DONE?
What's he done?
Everything!
You cannot say that to me!
You're changin', John.
If he gives me his word?
He will keep it.