- So, why do it?
- 'Cause it's dangerous.
Like you can sprain
a tit or something.
This is the most dangerous sport
in American high school, bitch.
More dangerous than football?
More catastrophic
injuries per student.
- How do I look?
- Dangerous.
Duh.
Take me through a typical Thursday.
Well, first I get up at
the ass crack for my run.
I mean, obviously staying in
shape is a part of the gig.
It's called cheerleading. You
know, I have to be a leader.
Oh, Marvin.
And diplomatic.
Proactive.
Seriously, hon.
Come to the realm, boys!
My bitches do not disappoint.
So why do you call
yourselves bitches?
Blackfoot Bloodhounds, yo.
Boys be dogs, girls
be bitches. Gangster.
Not now, Leena.
Maddy!
After that, I track
down Terry and, um...
Blue up his balls.
God, Terry charges
my bones. For real.
Next year, he's captain of
the football team and...
I'm captain of the squad, so it's pretty
much gonna be the best year ever.
MMS class.
I avoid taking honors classes,
so I can maintain all A's.
Overheard that from a senior
bitch, freshmen year.
Take basic classes, show up on time
and always look hot!
And he's married!
Hey, Trace. K-Mads is making me
the star of her little class video.
Please, call me Maddy. Not K-Mads.
Hey! Each day this week, I'm
filming a different student.
Getting school from their
perspective. So...
Well, oh! Hi!
Easy to judge everyone else
from behind this thing, huh?
Yeah, can I?
Thank you!
Do you wanna show
me some action now?
Bitch, I thought you
would never ask.
- Where's Hanna?
- Here!
- Sorry, Lexi, the head got stuck and...
- Put it on.
- Well?
- Magical.
All right, smart ass.
Check this shit out.
Oh, my God!
Get up, Alexis!
Alexis!
Bomb Vik. Get that arm warm, cuz.
Oh, poor Hanna. Still a
prisoner to child lock.
Thank you, Manny.
Hanna!
Seriously?
Not in front of my little sister.
Okay.
Yeah.
- Cheetos.
- Goddamn, dude.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
I would've eaten those.
Nah, it taste like shit.
Listen up, chiquitas.
I got one spot open.
But, I don't have
to take any of you.
I'd rather be one bitch
short, than have a weakling.
When I say your name,
line up in front of me.
And girls...
Don't waste my time.
Corra.
Jen.
Bonnie.
Megan.
Vanessa.
What the f?
Maddy?
Dang, man. Who is that?
Maddy.
Goddamn, somebody gave
that bitch a credit card.
What do you think you're doing?
Uh, there's a spot
open and I want it.
This isn't easy for
us, okay, Maddy?
We put it off as long as possible,
out of respect to Lexi.
God rest her soul.
Yeah, well, Alexis
was my friend, too.
Did you guys know that we did
gymnastics together, 7th grade?
I guess, she went one way
and I went another and...
I don't know, I guess
with everything...
Look, I uh, I just know that she was
happier than me and I wanna find out why.
I'm not asking for any favors.
You won't get any.
Keep it up. Let's go, let's go.
Hey, why don't you kiss George.
Come on, take what you
want like a goddamn pro.
Come on!
Ow!
Welcome to the squad, bitch.
Check this shit out.
Oh, my God!
Oh, shit.
- Oh, my God!
- Alexis!
So, uh, here is the new wardrobe.
Ta da!
You cannot believe the kind of money
these chicks drop on clothes.
Physical stuff, I can handle.
The hard part is going to be, pretending
that I actually like those dumb bitches.
Like that dipshit, Tracy.
Acts like she's all sad
but then, jumps on Terry's jock
before Alexis is
even in the ground.
That's classy.
And Terry...
Mr. big bad wolf himself.
I'm gonna ruin your perfect
little senior year, dog.
Jesus Christ!
Leena, what do you want?
Wow, you look, uh...
Uh...
You... you have a lot of makeup on.
- So?
- Can we talk?
No.
Uh, please?
Look, I'm sorry things
got so intense.
And I'm trying to respect that you
want to be alone and everything,
- but, we really need to talk.
- About what?
About you and... and...
Well, Little Madeline here.
Oh, hell no, you did not
name the kitten after me.
- Oh, fuck, Leena.
- I know it's pathetic and...
I was lonely and it
doesn't matter, okay?
She was in perfect health when I got
her and then, I gave her your name
and she got sick, just
like that out of nowhere.
And I suppose, you want me to think
it's one of your signs, am I right?
Well, yeah. I mean...
Look at yourself.
You're like a different person.
Something is going on, right?
Can you just listen?
She didn't just get sick, okay?
- She died.
- Leena!
It's over.
What's up, bitch?
Sick threads. Make 'em yourself?
Yeah.
Did Mads tell you the
news? It's official.
She's a cheer... leader.
Later.
Blackfoot Bloodhounds, bitches.
Ow!
I'm sorry, sis.
Hey, this really
brings out your face.
- Really?
- You look so beautiful, yeah.
- Totally.
You okay?
Do you think Lexi
would be mad at me?
Why?
- 'Cause of me and Terry.
- Oh.
- I'm rotten.
- No, you're not rotten.
- Tracy, you're just... You're living.
- Hmm.
Did you like him before?
Uh, before Alexis died, I mean.
I wasn't going to do
anything about it.
I mean, Lexi and I always liked the same
things that's why we were best friends.
Mmm.
Well, don't look at me like that.
- I didn't do anything wrong.
- No, I'm...
Damn it, seriously, okay?
Dogs are coming over.
You know the rules.
It's bitches only, tonight. Okay?
So, run along.
And Mr. Man. Yeah, don't even
think about calling me tonight.
Martha, my dear?
We would never consider
breaking Blackfoot tradition.
Which is why,
we are on our way to break into the
school for our annual pool party.
Dogs, only.
I just came to drop
something off for my gal.
Oh, man, I wanted to
piss in their pool.
Bye, Martha!
We were just talking about you.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mmm-hmm.
Here.
I found it. It's broken. But,
it's still kinda cool, right?
Aw! You're so sweet.
It's just a broken clasp,
I can make it work.
Where'd you find it?
Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God!
- Oh!
Look!
Look, so sweet!
Yeah, it is.
What's wrong?
I don't know, I...
I feel like I should
tell you something
but, you just seem so happy.
Jesus. Okay, now you
have to tell me.
Okay, will you...
You said that you and
Terry got together
on the last day of school, right?
Yeah, why?
It's just...
I saw him and Cassie
Decker together...
At the lake, fourth
of July weekend.
Cassie Decker?
What's wrong with her? Can't she
just find some college guys.
Tracy, there's only one
person to blame for this.
- I just think that...
- No buts.
He cheated on you. He's an asshole!
- Give it to me, please.
- Well, say it. No!
Say it!
Terry's an asshole!
Yeah.
- He's gonna freak.
- Fuck him.
- Tracy, stop!
- No.
It's okay.
Look at you.
- Maddy?
- Hmm?
Is the rumor about you
and Leena Miller true?
What's the rumor?
- You okay?
- Hmm.
Hmm.
Was that weird?
Was what weird?
Oh, wait. Here.
Take my car, pick me up
tomorrow before practice.
No, it's fine, I'm gonna walk.
We're practically neighbors.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Thanks, Mads.
No problem.
Get some sleep. You wanna look
hot for the rally, tomorrow.
That's right, bitch.
What do you think my chances
are tonight with Martha?
The chances of you striking
out? Pretty goddamn good.
Come on, man. It's rally night.
- Something could happen.
- She even let you smell it?
Hey, guys.
I snagged a couple of bottles of kank
out of my dad's garage last night.
- Shit, you guys smoke?
- Enough to kill a horse, yo.
Do we keep this party
exclusive enough?
Yo, if we ain't hung the fuck
over for the first day tomorrow.
We just ain't dogs. Woof!
Terry?
Hey, man.
You mind not slamming every
single weight down like that?
It's a weight room. Get over it.
Whatever, dude.
So, you really think
I did good tonight?
Are you kidding?
You are a natural, okay?
It's a rush, huh? Getting the
whole school fired up like that?
It's real fun.
Need another brew, Manny?
- Oh!
- What's that, it sprayed in my mouth.
Hi.
- How are you doing?
- Good.
I got a...
Ooh!
Don't mention it.
Hey, Tracy. Do you
know where Terry is?
He wasn't at the rally and
he's not answering me.
Probably eating dick somewhere.
Wait, what? What's going on?
I'm gonna go get a drink. That's
what's going on. Want one?
Yeah.
So, uh, do you know what's up?
Well, that's between
Terry and Tracy.
You sure?
What do you mean?
Oh, I don't know. Nothing.
But, I'm glad you're hanging
out with us, tonight. It's cool.
What are those?
- You'll just make fun of me.
- No, I wouldn't.
These stones put out special energy,
all I'm doing is focusing it.
On what?
- Protecting someone.
- Who?
Oh.
Look, Hanna. I'm kinda
doing my own thing here.
Okay, sorry.
Hanna?
Come on, I'll show you.
Okay.
This is you.
This is somebody close to you.
This is somebody close to them.
Does this sound right to you?
What do I do now?
Uh...
Clear your mind and
focus on what you want.
Anything I want?
As long as you're prepared to
deal with the consequences.
Consequences like what?
Okay. Say um, the mother
of a soldier makes a wish
that she wants her son
back from the war.
And she gets her wish.
But, her son comes
back in a body bag.
Consequences.
Exactly, so...
- You think I should text Terry?
- No.
It's not like him to bail on a
rally, he lives for this shit.
- Cassie Decker.
- Fucker.
Gee.
Oh, my God!
- Come here.
- What?
Just, come here.
- Why are you so nice to me?
Uh...
It's kinda new to me.
Is it okay?
- What's wrong?
- Fuck off.
Leena!
Manny! Come here! I need
to talk to you for a second.
Yeah.
Threesome, bro.
- She's really, really pissed of...
- What's up, brother?
- What's left to drink.
- Uh, we've still got a few beers left.
- Do I look like I want a beer?
- No, man.
Oh, there he is, yo. I haven't
seen you in forever, dog. Oh, yo.
Give the man a swig, yo.
Hey, you want some smoke?
- Oh, okay.
- No, no, no. Not you, man.
Give me a smoke.
No, you can't have any, dude.
Goddamn, Manny.
Give me a fucking hit.
You good, man?
You want to waste your senior
year chasing a Jesus freak
who's never gonna put out?
That's fine with me, cuz.
What?
But, if that's how it's
going to be, Manchester,
your ass is going to be
warming the bench all season.
Mmm. My dogs!
I've been thinking. If we're
gonna go all the way, this year.
We gotta shake things up. So, I'm
instituting a new team rule.
No fraternizing with cheerleaders.
Effective immediately.
It's good enough for the NFL. It's good
enough for Blackfoot fucking high.
Come on, fellas.
Sack up.
You're gonna realize,
I'm doing you a favor.
There's a whole world
of pussy out there.
Drama chicks.
- Stoners.
- Mmm.
Goths, smart bitches.
Hell, even fat bitches got
their charms, brothers.
And tomorrow, first
day of school...
You're eyes are gonna be
open to a fucking gold mine.
Just waiting there.
Freshmen.
You ain't gonna remember that cunt's
name when your balls deep in a puppy
that was blowing bubbles in
the eighth grade, last spring.
Fucking A, boss. That's
what I'm talking about.
- All right, girls, we're leaving.
- Hell, yeah.
Grab me that smoke.
You're gonna let him talk to
your bitches like that, Tracy.
This will stop, right
fucking now. Go!
- Go.
- You know...
Tracy.
I'm not gonna say you
have a small dick, Terry.
'Cause that would
just be predictable.
I mean, it's not big,
and that's fine.
But for the sake of the puppies,
I just wanna make sure
you know how to use it.
Three people in my 17
years have made me come.
Myself, of course.
This really sweet boy at summer camp
the summer after freshmen year.
Lovely fingers on that boy.
And then, not 10 minutes ago,
I got my freaking socks
rocked off by Maddy.
But, never... by you, Terry.
So, you don't wanna hang
with us, this year?
Well, freaking fine with me.
No, no, no, no. You
can have the puppies.
We'll find us some college dogs.
- Get her out of here.
- Fuck you.
Is a big tough guy like you scared
of a sweet little thing like me.
What do you think, Maddy?
Do you think I hurt Mr. Tiny
Peepee's little feelings?
Oh, are you gonna cry, Terry?
Huh? Are you gonna cry?
Oh, my goodness! Tracy! Are you okay?
You can kiss your precious
football season, goodbye, Terry.
Which one of you is
gonna kick his ass?
You fucking pussies!
He punched Tracy.
He hit a fucking girl.
Manny?
Manny, do something! You asshole!
Do something!
Oh, my God. I'm calling the cops.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Give it back! Give it back!
Hey! Hey, Terry, Terry!
Are you fucking stupid?
We should go.
You fuck!
What are you doing?
What the fuck are we doing, huh?
- You gotta stop.
- You worry too much, Vik.
Come on, you're kidding me.
Go!
What the fuck are you doing?
Oh, my God!
Martha, you need to slow down.
Fuck.
There.
Oh!
Come on, come on.
We gotta get them out.
Come on, come on!
We gotta get 'em out.
Oh, God! What are you doing, man?
- You can't pull them out.
- We gotta get 'em out.
They're gonna drown.
Let go of me!
Let's get in the car. Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Maddy!
God!
Maddy! Maddy!
Maddy!
No!
Don't die!
Come back to me, please.
Maddy!
What are you doing?
Oh, shit!
What happened last night?
The girls, they're okay?
Jesus!
You don't feel anything about this?
Is it our fault, chicks
can't drive for shit?
Fuck, Tracy.
Oh, crazy fucking dream.
Well, you killed Madeline.
Who's Madeline?
Ugh, what are we doing here?
No way!
Oh, dude, your cheek.
No, other cheek.
Ah, don't touch it.
Wait, did I break up with Terry?
He punched you in the face.
Oh, no, no, no.
Tracy?
Oh, gross!
Martha?
- Martha?
- What?
Uh, she's...
I'm with...
We've kinda...
What is, uh, happening?
Where's my phone? Where's my phone?
Hanna, if you could just shut
the fuck up for 2 seconds.
I'm not Hanna.
Think. Gotta wake up. Okay.
I just gotta...
Eat.
Friggin' goat milk.
Buenos dias.
Um, hello?
I'm Larry.
God, I'm freaking starving, Larry.
- Uh...
- What's for breakfast?
So you told me to focus on
what I wanted, and I did.
I couldn't get you to stop
panicking behind the wheel.
It was Manny.
- I remember that and then...
- So, now...
Now I can be with Manny.
And the car was full of water
and everything is upside down.
I mean, I'm sure the stones are
just trying to get us back,
- right?
- I'm trying to get us out, but I can't
- Right?
- because of the fucking child locks.
It was my fault.
I crashed us and now,
God is punishing me.
Martha was driving.
- I was.
- She was.
Oh, my God. I swear to God,
I'm gonna kill somebody.
I'm the only one you could
kill at this point, Maddy.
Because you died last night.
All 4 of you died.
Uh...
Real milk.
The bitches think I'm crazy, but,
I drink like half a gallon a day.
I've kept my mouth shut about you
and your mom's crazy wicca bullshit
for as long as I
possibly can, Leena.
- What's a wicca?
- No, it's not exactly as wicca.
- Leena's a witch.
- That's not nice, Maddy.
- You shouldn't call people names.
- No, she's right.
- I am a witch.
- At least she thinks she is.
Are you okay?
- I feel good.
- Maybe, maybe...
You should go lay down.
At your own house. I mean, you
should lay down at your own house.
My head's hot.
It is hot.
The rest of you is cold.
And then you start stalking me?
When you have no idea
the shit that I'm up to.
No idea what I'm going through.
You think everything is about you.
That is your problem, Leena. You
think everything I do is about...
What are you doing?
You feel mine, right?
Oh, what? Your broken
heart? Give me a break.
What do you feel now?
We can hear the sound
of your heart.
You can...
What?
What did you do?
I saved you.
Wait a minute.
Leena!
I'm sorry, Larry.
I think, my friends are hungry.
What?
Are you kidding me?
This is... This is, uh...
I feel freaking fantastic.
Do you, um...
All feel better?
Stronger?
Yes! Oh, my God! Yes!
It worked!
What works, this?
My crazy wicca bullshit, it works!
These work.
Then why am I in my
sister's body, Leena?
Why would you do that to me?
I don't know, I wasn't
trying to, Martha.
You can change us back, right?
I don't know.
Chop, chop, girls. School's, like, in
a half hour, we totally got to go.
Who's driving?
My car broke down last
night, we walked here.
Shit! I can't be seen walking
to school on the first day.
Fuck school. Look at what we
just did to Leena's neighbor.
Whatever. We can sit
around and sing Kumbaya
if it's gonna make you
feel better, but...
- Tracy, shut the fuck up.
- Sure, I'll shut the fuck up
as soon as someone tells me
who's driving me to school.
Uh, what about his car?
You weren't wrong about the hot
young tail up in this bitch, huh?
Ladies...
Let me the first to welcome
you to Blackfoot High.
I'm Terry.
- We know who you are.
- Yeah, we do.
This here is the star
quarterback, Mr. Vik De Palma.
Go ahead. Feel the arm,
girls. Don't be shy.
There's more than
enough to go around.
It's so hard.
Can you give some
love to my boy, Manny
And Ben.
Hi, guys!
Hey.
Give them some love.
My dogs bleed on the field
every day for this school.
Wow.
- Do you have Facebook?
- So, how's the...
Fuck!
I like your shirt.
So, let's talk soon.
Hi, Vik!
Are you okay?
No.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Yeah, of course. Come on.
Clear the road, puppies.
Bloodhound bitches
in the house, ya'll.
Vik?
Look at her in that suit,
she looks like such a slut.
Mmm-hmm.
Psst! Yo, bitch!
Cell phones off, people.
What are the odds, Ben.
We're table mates.
It sounded like...
You're speaking my language.
You guys are okay?
Sure.
We tried to help you guys,
we just... We... You know,
- we couldn't get down there...
- Hey, hey, hey.
No harm, no foul, right?
Get me high after class,
we'll call it even.
Oh, shave my ball sack.
- Leena. Leena Miller.
- Who?
Leena Miller. I'm not
fucking with you, dude.
She was making these little
stones float in the air.
- It was fucking magic, dude.
- Oh, it's fucking magic, dude.
You know what? Fuck you.
Fuck you. Fuck you.
What's up, Terry?
Wow, Hanna. Didn't
know you had tits.
If she's a dog.
She must have 6 more
hidden somewhere, dude.
So, there's two things you
gotta know about George's van.
1, there's always a weed stash.
And 2, it's never locked.
And 3, it smells like dick.
Hi, guys! Terry, how's your hand?
Punched his girlfriend in the
face. I mean, you know.
That shit can hurt the puncher
as much as the punchee, so...
Maddy and I had a little
fling over the summer.
I guess she's still
a bit sore from it.
All right, we're gonna go.
We'll see you guys later.
Remember the buddy system, girls.
There's only one outcome when
people play games with me, Maddy.
- They lose.
- Playtime's over, Terry.
What happened last night?
You know, before last night,
I was just gonna ruin
your senior year.
But now... I'm gonna
have to kill you.
Just watch your mouth, dyke.
Oh!
Ah!
Let's go, man.
Let's go!
Uh, what the fuck is going on?
Somebody got fucked, somebody
got killed and I'm going to PE.
Come on.
Martha! I'm so, so
happy you're okay.
I was drunk and I was stoned,
I didn't know what to...
For real?
- Right.
- Mmm-hmm.
Whoa!
Wow!
Oh, my goodness.
What?
Jesus Christ, Martha.
Shit, I didn't mean
to say his name.
I know you hate that.
Oh, God. I'm sorry.
Did I do it again?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Wanna see something?
Yeah.
You sure you want our
first time to be here?
- In the handicap bathroom?
- Mmm-hmm
- Yeah.
- I love you, Martha.
- I want you to call me Hanna.
- What?
Check this out.
Oh, shit!
Tracy, that...
Fucking disgusting.
Please, just call me Hanna.
Okay. Hanna.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Oh, I love you Hanna!
Oh.
Uh, are you okay?
- Yeah!
- Oh, it's cold.
Ugh!
It's cold.
Oh, it's cold.
Oh, help me, Jesus.
- There you go.
- Yeah, you can do it. It's nice.
- So, how are you feeling? It's all right.
- Feeling good?
Oh, shit.
Uh, what the fuck is going on?
Somebody got fucked, somebody
got killed and I'm going to PE.
We should never have
come to school.
Hey, bitches!
- Who was it?
- What do you mean?
Ben.
At least it's not more
innocent blood on our hands.
No more feeding at school.
Don't do that.
Anyone else seen this?
No.
Let's keep it that way.
- Sorry, Nicholas.
- Asshole!
I've been waiting for
this for so long.
- Vik. Dude, it happened.
- What's up?
- What happened?
- Dude, me, Martha, the handicap bathroom.
Dude, I was all up in that
sweet, sweet freezer.
What freezer? What are
you talking about?
- Hey, I didn't even know.
- Know what?
That it's cold in there.
Uh... I don't even...
It's supposed to be
cold in there, right?
Manny...
Oh, hey, Hanna.
Come with me.
No, I got trig. I gotta go.
But, Martha asked me
to bring you to her.
- Where is she?
- The sticks.
- Said she wanted to see you in private.
- Really?
But I'll just tell her
you've got trigonometry.
What? No. Are you serious?
Uh.
Martha?
How could you do it?
How could you have sex...
With my sister.
She's my girlfriend.
No, I'm your girlfriend.
Um, I can't miss class for
whatever this is, Hanna,
- so why don't you...
- No, you stop right there, Mr. Man.
Hanna, you're a...
You're a sweet kid. But, you don't
need to be like your sister.
I love her, but everybody hates it
when she pulls that
prissy, bossy bullshit.
Ahhh!
Close your eyes.
Fuck!
Shit, Maddy, my stones are gone.
Somebody stole them.
Do you think it was Terry?
Well, who else?
- You okay?
- No. I'm sluggish.
- And that sucks.
- It's okay, you just need blood.
Leena.
Here, drink from me.
Come on. Let's find the
others and get out of here.
- Practice time, bitches.
- What?
We're not slacking on my
watch, big game Friday night.
Okay, did you feed again?
No, you said not to.
I'm a team player.
Somebody did and...
- Terry stole my stones.
- Okay, enough already.
Bitches and I got work to do.
Come on, Mads.
- You've seen Vik?
- No.
- What about Manny?
- No, not since lunch.
- You thinking what I'm thinking, boss?
- What are you thinking, Shank?
That voodoo dyke and her bitches
are picking us dogs off.
One by one.
Bitches glowing like Lite-Brites
and shit. You saw it.
Look, I've been thinking a lot.
- About borrowing your sister's clothes?
- Don't be an asshole, Vik.
- No, fuck you guys.
- You're being a pussy.
- Find yourself a new quarterback.
- Fuck you.
- Pussy.
You think I'm gonna let you quit?
Hey, Dad. Me and the
bitches, the girls,
um, we are going to be staying
at Maddy's house tonight,
because we have a
whole lot of cheers
that we have to go over and
practice and everything.
So, I guess we'll be
seeing you tomorrow.
Uh, don't work too hard. We
love you. Okay, bye, Dad. Bye.
So, I just have to do
this all the time now.
- Where did you get that?
- None of your beeswax.
Can I use it a minute?
I'm just gonna keep
killing innocent people.
Am I the only one that
gives a shit about that.
Come on, Martha,
- I need to check Facebook.
- No.
You don't have to kill,
we can do it this way.
- Martha!
- Leave me alone!
Martha, chill!
Tracy, you can use my computer.
Hanna, Leena, look after these
bitches. I gotta go take a shower.
We're family now. Like it
or not, families fight.
Yeah, well, I don't really
need a family, so...
Well, what if we need you, Maddy?
Goddamn, boss.
Taking it to the next level.
Let's get Vik.
Why do you have Manny's phone?
Because Manny was a jerk.
You should see what these
texts say about me.
Okay, what do you
mean he was a jerk?
What do you think I mean?
You shouldn't have
done that, Martha.
Shut up, Leena. You
don't even know me.
Oh!
Hanna, no. Wait. You need
blood, you're weak right now.
Okay, Hanna is a little weakling.
- No, I wasn't saying that.
- Fuck off, witch.
God!
Sorry, Leena. I just
need to be alone, okay?
- I have to go.
- Hanna!
Bonus, K-Mads keeps a video diary.
Vik's gone, his bike's gone.
I told you he'd queef and run.
The hard part is going to be, pretending
that I actually like those dumb bitches.
Like that dipshit, Tracy.
Acts like she's all sad but
then, jumps on Terry's jock
before Alexis is even in
the ground. That's classy.
And Terry.
Mr. big bad wolf himself.
I'm gonna ruin your perfect
little senior year, dog.
But, right now. I have to go and
paint my face up like those whores.
So, uh... Maddy Killian, out!
Tracy.
Tracy, that was like a week
ago. I didn't know you then.
I'm taking Larry's car.
No, we have to stay together.
I'm not asking.
Give me a ride.
You don't let me borrow your phone but,
you expect me to give your ass a ride?
- No, no. You have to listen.
- Cassie Decker.
Is that true?
- Wait.
- No!
I thought you were being nice
to me because you liked me.
This is all your fault.
Tracy, wait. You can use my phone.
What did he do to you?
Tracy!
After Lexi died...
I felt like I needed to do
something nice for her.
So, I started to make
her a tribute video.
I wanted to interview
all of her friends.
Terry always seemed
kind of pompous, but...
All of a sudden, he was
just a regular guy.
I felt sorry for him.
That's why I didn't think twice
about going to his place to talk.
Martha?
Just kinda laughed it off at first.
I said no thanks.
Then his eyes changed.
How could someone like me
turn him down.
Grab her! Grab her! The other side!
Punched me in the stomach.
And then he...
I think you need to say it.
He raped me.
Hanna!
She's got me, boss. She's got me.
You killed Hanna!
- Just forget about them.
- Leena, they're our friends.
Martha! Tracy!
You need blood, you're not
strong enough for this.
- Maddy, are you okay?
- What did you guys do?
What are you talking about?
I didn't do anything. I'm not
with Terry, I came here for you.
I don't need you to rescue me, Vik.
Maddy! No, no!
Let her go.
Whoo!
I can't move.
I never understood why you
had the hots for her, Viky.
Till I fucked her, this summer.
She puts up a good fight.
Who are you, man?
I'm your best friend, bud.
I broke her in for
you and everything.
Vik?
Hey, Vik, I need your help.
Yeah.
Oh, you are such a
little bitch, Vik.
I owe it to you, too, cuz.
You want her? Come and get her.
You girls got your seatbelts on?
Oh!
Whoa!
Tastes like jellybeans.
I'm like the Cookie
Monster up in this bitch.
Oh, I hope that shit
was gluten free.
Come on, bitches.
- Terry!
- Maddy!
I don't know but I've been told
Killing pussies, going home
Mad, we have to do this together!
Whoa!
Maddy! Maddy!
Maddy!
No!
Oh, my God!
Terry!
No, no, no, no.
Maddy!
Come on, Leena. We gotta talk.
You're gonna tell me
how to use these.
She just died, didn't she?
Again.
Trap must've ripped that
stone right out of her.
And you feel it.
Is that it?
But I feel fucking great.
Why is that?
Because you're an interloper.
- Like a free agent?
- More like a leech.
I'm so sorry.
What can I do with these?
You wanna show me?
Or...
I can see what happens...
When I carve that one
out of your throat.
No.
- It's your call.
- No, you...
Holy shit!
I've never done that before.
Ah!
This is a new and improved Terry.
Oh, it's gonna be a hell
of a season thanks to you.
You know, I never did get
a straight answer on that.
Girlfriend?
Ex-girlfriend?
Girlfriend, bitch!
No!
Ah, no!
Maddy!
No, no!
No! No!
No! You're not leaving me.
I won't let you go.
Crazy wicca bullshit.
Leena!
Oh, shit!