China in the mid-19th century...
the suffering of its people under
the corrupt rule of the Qing dynasty
set the stage for the Taiping Rebellion.
During the chaos of
the 14 years long civil war,
70 million people died
in battle or from starvation...
The casualties equaled
the recorded death toll from WWll.
He said...
the day he crawled out
from the pile of corpses...
he was a dead man
He also said...
it was an age when death came easy...
but living was hard
All my men died
I alone survived
You were lucky
I played dead
My brothers... more than 1600 men...
fought for three days and nights...
They all died...
The Kui army were inhuman
They only stood behind us and watched
My brothers were
slaughtered one after another
No one survived
He met a woman that day
They spent the night in a deserted house
He didn't know if it was
the woman or the soup...
that brought him back to life
Where can I find food?
Try the main street
He said...
the first time he met me...
the sky was overcast, like his mood
But I remember clearly...
that it was a glaringly sunny day
Eat your food and let's get going!
Eat and get to work!
Dig in!
You sure know how to fight
I should introduce you to my big brother!
Where are we going?
To rob!
from the rebel army!
He later told me he was outraged...
that bandits like us dared steal from troops
What did we care? Famine is everywhere
We either robbed or died
Ride out!
Kill them!
Seize their leader, hurry!
He saved my life that day...
and taught me a lesson
Strike the head... and the body will fall
Brother Jiang...
Look!
That man gave them to you
They're for generals
Brother Jiang has become a general!
What are you thinking about?
My home
They've returned!
Come with me! We've got food!
I have good news, tonight we feast!
Why are you alone?
I ran away from home
Is that a Yangzhou accent?
You noticed?
How could you tell?
Have you ever heard of Yangzhou Ponies?
You mean pretty young girls
who are trained as courtesans...
and sold to rich men?
Yes
But when I turned 15...
and was about to be sold...
a man came and stole me away
He was my childhood playmate
He killed a few people
We went into hiding and he became a bandit
He thought he saved you,
but you were no longer the same peasant girl
He's a good man
Go in peace!
Big brother laid down the rule...
to save seats and wine...
for the brothers who died
Were you a general in the army?
Not anymore
Why did you desert?
Drink up!
My troops and the Kui troops
planned to join forces against the enemy
But they betrayed us
We were outnumbered...
and all my brothers were killed!
There's nothing more important
than the love between brothers
That I agree
These days, without brothers...
you can't survive
Wu-Yang, dinner's here
Are the new recruits staying?
No one wants to leave when there's food
Except for Pang, he 's not our kind
I don't know if he's staying or not
Pretty, isn't it?
I snatched it from a dead man
Do you know what this is?
No
It protects you
Did that night really happen?
I waited there for you...
wondering if it was all a dream
If you ran away, why did you come back?
I ran away many times,
had it all thought out
But I always ended up back here
Why did you come back?
You should decide for your own life
Stay here!
"Kui"
Why are you robbing our food?
I dare you to hit me?
Go ahead!
Stop fighting!
I'm old enough to be your grandmother!
Stand back or I'll shoot!
I dare you!
I swear I'll shoot...
Go ahead! Kill me too!
You!
Nobody moves!
Look at me when I speak
You think you can keep the food you robbed?
Consider this as a pay back to your country
Let's go!
If only we had guns... we could fight them!
That's suicide!
I'd rather die than live like this!
Thieves are always on the run
Why not join the army?
Once you're in the army...
you'll receive wages to feed your families
You'll get guns so...
that no one will bully you
This village will finally have peace
We're bandits, will the army take us?
The Kui army is grandiose and powerful
They couldn't care less about us
But Lord Chen's army is desperate for men
He wants to increase his power...
to rival the Kui army
He should welcome us with open arms
Er-Hu, seize this opportunity
Then today's event...
will never happen again
Alright!
As bandits...
We have to be the biggest!
You deserted the Ching army,
now you want us to join them?
You're a two-faced man
Why shall we trust you?
Take the blood oath!
To be blood brothers, we kill an outsider...
to show our loyalty to the brotherhood
Only the lives of our brothers count
The rest are expendable
I asked him that day
There's no turning back
Are you certain?
He said nothing
Let me...
Masters, what is it?!
What are you bastards doing?!
We were only passing through!
Mercy me... please...
Remember my face...
and take revenge in your next life!
We, Pang Qing-Yun
Zhao Er-Hu
and Jiang Wu-Yang...
join the brotherhood today
We take the blood oath
We pledge our lives
Those who bring us harm...
must die
A brother who harms another brother...
Heaven and earth bear witness...
and strike dead any man who breaks his oath
We share one heart...
He told me later that...
he didn't believe in the pledge
I asked him what he believed in
He said Er-Hu...
and me
Wait! Take these shoes with you
Take care!
Mother may never see you again
Good-bye, ma
Er Hu!
Shi and his men are leaving!
He said that he'd rather die...
than serve the Qing army!
Your entire battalion perished...
in the battle against
the Taiping rebels in Hechuan...
and you disappeared for 2 months!
How dare you return now?
My Lord Chan
Lord Jiang sent the Kui army...
to aid us in the battle at the Hechuan
But they left us to fend for ourselves
My men were slaughtered on the battlefield
All your men died...
but you alone survived?
I stayed alive...
just to see you again...
Lord Jiang
How many men do you have?
Give me another 800...
and I will capture Shu City within 15 days
Don't jest with me!
10!
I will capture Shu City in 10 days!
Well...
then...
I'll give you 1,500 fine soldiers...
but no wages
We don't need wages;
we get half the spoils
once we capture Shu City
Pang Qing-Yun
Name your army "Shan"
Thank you, my lords
You're gambling...
with 800 lives
War is a gamble
I won't gamble
My 1500 men are the last of Lord Chen's army
If we lose them...
my lord will be powerless
at the imperial court
Make me an offer!
My army...
will only give you a semblance of multitude
This is your only chance for victory
Otherwise...
you'll forever be
at the mercy of the Kui army!
Big brother!
They're all useless
We'll be facing 200 rifles
The odds are against us
To win, we need to attack
Break through their firing line...
Engage them in hand to hand combat
Brothers!
Tell him who's the toughest?
We are!
The enemy will be 300 paces away
Rifles have a range of 200 paces...
arrows have only 100
We'll need a vanguard of 200 men...
to run straight at the firing range
They must not dodge the bullets...
but must use their bodies as shields...
so that our archers...
who run behind them can get within range
Many brothers will die in the process
I'm in!
Who's with me?
Die and your family will
receive double your wages!
Live and you receive triple!
Don't you want to be rich?
Where are the real men?!
Come on!
Damn it, count me in!
Me too, I'm in...
Count me in...
me too...
I'm in...
Take Shu City!
Take their money, their food, their women!
You're vastly outnumbered...
victory is already ours
Surrender and your life will be spared
Kill them!!!
Fire!
They're dying out there! Let's go!
Shut up and listen!
There's only one commander in a battle!
Kill them!!!
Shoot!
Brother!
Prepare!
Blinders on!
He's using himself to goad me into combat
Go!
Big brother!
Brother...
No! Don't pull that out!
Hold steady!
We're really going to die this time
We're blood brothers!
We die as one!
That's right!
We might as well take a few with us...
as we go down!
Let's go...
Kill them!
It's madness!
800 men manage to upset an army of 5000...
We can win!
We really need a victory badly!
Follow me!
Wu-Yang!
Lord Di...
Pang Qing-Yun must be blessed
Pang...
Fate has brought us together again
How fortunate of you to capture Shu City...
you have made a name for yourself
Pang...
how does 5 more battalions sound?
On top of that...
- Lu Da-Shan...
- Sir
will be under your command
Thank you, My Lord
Pang Qing-Yun
Your old friend from the
Kui army is waiting for you
He Kui
Sir
Greetings, my lords
It's been a long time, General Pang
lt'll be a reunion of old allies...
with you leading the attack...
and him bringing up the rear
How do we divide the spoils?
Lord Di and...
Lord Chen...
no objections I trust?
I'm afraid he won't be able to keep up!
We'll take Suzhou, and then Nanking!
What are they laughing at?
Nanking is the enemy's capital
To topple Nanking, we must first take Suzhou
Since they have nothing to
gain when the war is over...
they won't let us take Suzhou
If we attack, they can't stop us
The Kui army was precisely sent...
to keep an eye on us
They've returned!
Xiao-Wu
Xiao-Wu, Xiao-Wu...
Xiao-Wu's shoes...
Xiao-Wu...
Xiao-Qi?!
Xiao-Qi... my boys...
We were no longer bandits
He said a bandit kills for his own interests
But a hero sacrifices for others
I wanted to be a hero
You've lost weight
Big brother says,
we'll only be away for 3 years
I know you've never liked it here
When the war is over...
I'll find us a better place to settle down
Where's Brother Pang?
He's staying outside the village tonight
We'll leave tomorrow morning
Remember...
Winning is all that matters!
Begin!
Kill them!
We're here to take over
Give the men 3 days leave to pillage!
Let them take their money,
their food, their women!
You can come out now, the war is over
Come
Come, don't be afraid
Have you eaten?
You hungry?
Let go!
What are you doing?!
Don't just stay there! Give me a hand!
No!
Don't touch me!
Gouzi, I'm leaving!
Let me go...
Brother Pang
- Move!
- What is it?
Why am I being arrested?
- Go!
- What is it?!
Gather the people for a public execution!
Brother Zhao!
Brother, what's this about?
They raped 2 women
They were given three days of pillage,
this was bound to happen!
From this day on, I will not tolerate
such conduct under my command!
It's what we've always done
We're soldiers now, not bandits
We must better ourselves or
we won't achieve anything!
If we allow this to happen...
we're no better than those Kui bastards!
Today is the day we start
setting down some rules!
We've just killed their families!
Now you want to protect them?
By killing our own?
No one will risk their lives
fighting for you after this!
Brother...
Listen to me, look at them!
They've learned their lesson
There's no need to kill them, right?
Don't just kneel there!
Say you're sorry!
Big brother, we were wrong, we're so sorry...
Gouzi!
Say it again!
Gouzi, say you're sorry!
Say it!
Come on, Gouzi...
Big brother, we're sorry!
Big brother, they know they're wrong
Have mercy
When I was still a civil servant...
I saw a soldier...
beating a peasant on the street...
...until the man was
covered with his own blood
There was no reason for it...
except that the man was poor
But the poor man never retaliated
He accepted it as part of his lot in life
I promised myself that day...
I would never allow...
something like that to happen again!
You joined the army...
because you don't want to be bullied
Let me tell you
not only you but everyone...
men and women alike should
be free from oppression!
That's what we're fighting for!
That day...
he finally revealed his dream
for the future
He said...
he waited because he was afraid
we wouldn't understand
But I did
Stop!
Don't you touch my men!
Back off!
Brother...
Please...
Who do you owe your lives to?
Who?!
Big brother!
What will you tell my mother?
Closes your eyes
I'll be quick
Brother Jiang... What will you tell my mother?
Don't tell my mother!
How I wish I could sacrifice my life...
for this future of his
I used to think...
we only kill to survive
Now I see that...
we must also kill in order to do good
We must end this war in 3 months
We must take Suzhou!
Look! The abandoned!
You're behaving like Pang -
too ambitious
Thinks he can take Suzhou
with a few thousand men?
I'm worried for you, Lord Chen
With no supplies or reinforcements...
He's dead for sure!
There's a fine line between winning
and losing
If I add the right piece... here
Pang might just climb to the top...
and then...
Do you think I'd let Pang
return to the fold?
Leaving him stranded...
benefits everyone
"Suzhou City, One Year Later"
I saved you once in Ji-An...
you ungrateful bastard!
What's keeping all of you?!
Suzhou is at an impasse;
both sides will starve to death
The Kui army are waiting
to swoop like vultures!
How much longer can you afford to gamble?
Butcher...
sing me a song
I heard that...
there is a man named Jesus
Each day at noon...
He gives the Taiping general Huang
in Suzhou...
5 loaves of bread and 2 fat pigs
He would then divide the food casually...
and somehow he feeds all 5000 people...
Everyone is fed
Their bread never runs out
And new piglets are being born everyday
Sit down!
I'll steal into the city and kill Huang
Those who tried never came back
I won't put more lives at risk
I'll go ask Lord Di...
for food and weapons
But we've defied their
orders by attacking Suzhou
I'm still of some use to them
Please leave now
Give me provisions and I'll seize Suzhou!
My men may die in battles but not from hunger!
Please, I beg you!
My lord says he didn't know Suzhou was at war
To the Kui army!
We can't go begging to them!
Then I will go alone!
Let's go!
Quick!
Hurry...
Take my hand!
They tried to steal into the city;
they all said there was food inside
I must go in for myself
Give me provisions and weapons...
I'll make you a deal
I don't need that
Suzhou is already mine
I'm talking about...
Nanking
My men do the fighting and the dying!
All you have to do is stand behind us
We divide Nanking between us;
we enter the city together...
unless you want to be under
the power of those three old men forever
We must capture Nanking...
before the Kui army arrives to take credit
But we only have 10 days' supplies
We act quickly
We capture Suzhou within 2 days!
The heavens are good to me...
sending you to me tonight
It can protect you
If you don't see a red flare
by dawn from inside the city...
my men will take you to safety
Tell big brother and Wu-Yang that...
Er-Hu wanted to be a hero
General Pang is back!
Sir, the provisions have arrived!
General Zhao has entered the city
He said if we see a red flare by dawn...
it means he has succeeded
My friend, did you bring the goods?
They say we have food in the city
But we may start eating each other soon
I promised they would be clothed and fed...
and could go home within 3 years
It's been 5 years now...
We attack at dawn
Lian
I like to study different faces...
but I haven't seen a new face...
since Suzhou came under siege a year ago
I hear the opium dealer is a new face
but I don't use opium anymore
it only eases the pain
My wife's grave is just
outside the city in the woods
I long to see her...
but can't
Do you know what it's like to be a prisoner?
Suzhou has become one big prison...
I can't get out...
you can't get in either...
unless...
I let you in
Remember Shi?
You joined the Qing army, he followed me
Hurry!
Sir... it's past dawn
Prepare the horses
Escort Lady Zhao away
Er-hu said that...
he wanted to be a hero
If I survive, I will...
marry you
4,000 soldiers are outside crazed with starvation
If you kill me...
you will all die in a blood bath
I too have 4,000 men
They'll defend every inch of the city...
to their last drop of blood
Stand down
Lay down your arms
Please surrender!
11 years ago...
I closed my business and sold everything...
to join the Taiping rebellion
From that day on...
the word "surrender"...
no longer existed for me!
As long as I live...
the people of Suzhou City...
will never be free
Spare my soldiers... let them go home
Don't make the civilians suffer
May you...
go in peace!
Get ready!
Er-Hu... Er-Hu...!
Zhao Er-Hu!
I want to see Zhao Er-Hu!
We want bread! Bread!
Are we going to conscript them?
They will never agree
There are 4,000 captives
How much of our food will you give them?
Brother...
They surrendered only because...
I promised to let them live
The city's granaries are empty, and...
we have only a 10-day supply of food
We must save it for Nanking
Nanking?
Are we attacking Nanking?
The Kui army decamped yesterday;
they will attack Nanking at any moment
I can't read!
Just tell me where the supplies are from?
Where?!
The Kui army
How could you make a deal with He Kui?!
These solders will never join our army
If we attack Nanking...
Suzhou will be defenseless
Can you leave the city in their hands?
Listen to me!
No, you listen!
These soldiers are our enemies!
We want bread! Bread!
Open the stores!
Give me what I need
No!
Pang Qing-Yun!
I knew you were a liar!
This bread...
was meant for our brothers
But you want to give half to the captives...
and then the other half to the civilians
Our brothers have fought for 9 months...
and starved for 9 months!
You tell me...
Who should get this bread, them or us?
I don't care!
Give them food!
Now!!!
Let them eat
It's their last meal
But I promised to spare their lives!
Winning is all that matters in war!
A man who breaks his word is an animal!
Brother...
He's right
Move!
Get out of the way!
He's right
Let me go!
Let me go! I promised to spare their lives!
Archers!
Quiet!
Don't kill them!
Again!
Don't kill them! Don't kill them!
From that day on...
Er-Hu never said another word to me
It hurts, but...
big brother was right
Let's go home!
Who's with me?
Er-Hu, you can't go
We still have to take Nanking
What for? To kill more defenseless people?
They were soldiers
They surrendered!
They were still soldiers!
Do you remember what you said to us?
You said everyone deserves...
to be free even the poor!
What have you done now?
You have ordered right here...
the massacre of 4,000 poor people?!
You know that?!
Only the poor are willing to go to war!
Which one of us weren't poor!
Those men were soldiers
Soldiers are prepared to die
But the millions in Nanking are civilians
If He Kui reaches them first, they're dead!
I need your help to take Nanking
Please don't go
If you go, it will be mutiny
The Shan brothers will turn on each other!
Think about the consequences!
Don't force my hand!
I'll kill anyone who touches Er-Hu!
Brother, you must not leave
If you leave now...
ours pledge will be broken
Er-Hu!
The Kui army has already left
We must leave now or we'll be too late!
I promise you...
after Nanking...
there'll be peace
One day you'll see that...
my decisions today were right
Fine
I'll be watching you in Nanking
If you're right, I'll kneel before you
But if you're wrong, I'll kill you
Let's go!
We...
- Zhao Er-Hu...
- Pang Qing-Yun...
- Jiang Wu-Yang...
- three brothers as one...
Attack!
Victory is ours, Nanking is ours!
Long live the Empress Dowager!
One month after the capture of Nanking
Go in peace
We swore an oath...
to remain loyal to the Shan regiment
As long as there is hunger, oppression...
and injustice...
the Shan regiment will fight!
Dole out the wages!
Zhang Wen-Fang, 5 taels
Wang Xiao-San...
Er-Hu, what are you doing?!
The money belongs to the imperial coffers!
We agreed to take Nanking and
give half of the spoils to our men
If you won't do it! I will!
Remember!
The Shan regiment has only one leader!
And that's General Pang!
Show him your gratitude!
Thank you General!
Again!
Thank you General!!!
Back to the wages...
Wang Xiao-San, 3 taels 4 mace
Wang Long, 4 taels
My lord
He needed your help to take Nanking
Now you're at his mercy
I will kill him eventually!
You're always a step behind
The Empress is making
him Governor of Jiangsu
So what?
He Kiu, even I can't help you this time
We just need to get Zhao Er-Hu on our side...
and Pang's downfall is ensured!
- Zhao Er-Hu... - Pang Qing-Yun...
- Jiang Wu-Yang...
three brothers as one...
Drink up!
Heaven and earth be our witnesses
We take a blood oath, pledge our lives
We were born apart but die as one
Loyalty through good times...
and bad
General Zhao, you did the fighting
but he took the credit
How can you live with that?
So what?
This opera is about brotherhood
He's your brother, yet he had you in chains?
He forced you to break your
word and made a fool out of you
Make him pay
If we join forces and Nanking can be ours
Give it some thought
General He is only thinking of your future
Come over here!
Revenge is sweet!
Shallow wounds heal...
but deep wounds fester
General Zhao, take your time to think it over
General He
You must be wondering...
how long it takes to get from the gates to here?
I had the same thought the first time...
I stood outside the palace gates
By the time I reached this far...
my hair had already turned gray
it took me 30 years
Now I'm too old to walk
Li Lianying
The Empress said your youth is an asset;
you will serve us for a long time
The Empress also said
Pang should be commended
for the capture of Nanking
He will receive the Golden Robes
and appointed Governor of Jiangsu!
Show your gratitude!
Your servant Pang requests that...
the people of Jiangsu be
exempt from 3 years of taxes
to recover from the war
Request granted!
Thank you your Highness
You're responsible for the Suzhou massacre...
yet you saved the people of Nanking
Lord Pang, you're surely adaptable
The Empress favors Lord Pang because
he does not belong to any fractions
Nanking may be yours
But you've offended Lord Jiang
and He Kui along the way
Now, without allies...
how long do you think you'll last?
Lord Pang, I checked the lunar calendar
The 8th day of the 4th month...
will be the most auspicious
time for your inauguration
...and for all
Before you can do good...
Lord Pang, you must look after yourself!
You must look after yourself
I must leave now, My lords
The unrest has subsided,
but the local militias wield too much power
Lord Pang, the Empress is concerned
The Shan regiment will be the first to disband
Good!
Once you sever your old ties...
you can devote yourself
to your duties as governor
Your brother Zhao Er-Hu
threatened to desert the army in Suzhou
He almost created...
a mutiny there
In Nanking, he doled out funds
meant for the royal coffers
Does he own your regiment?!
Be careful, my lord!
I've walked on thin ice my whole life
Do you think I can safely cross over?
You're awake
Yes, I am
Perhaps they're right
Nanking...
doesn't need someone like me
I want to go home
Will you come with me?
I don't need this anymore
What is it?
Bad news, my lord!
He Kui plans to assassinate Lord Pang!
It's nothing
General Zhao
Big brother!
Where's he?
Lord Pang has not returned
from the imperial court
Decided?
Then I'm off
General Jiang
Who are they?
Guards sent by the imperial court
Cover that table with the red cloth
Move these vases as well
Hurry!
- Brother Wu Yang
- You have guests coming?
General Pang has invited General Zhao to dine
They've reconciled!
Is big brother home?
He should return by the afternoon...
why have they replaced all the guards?
General Zhao, wait!
Sir...
We received news that...
He Kui plans to assassinate Lord Pang
He must not return to the city now
he asked you to meet him at Jianpu
Tell Wu-Yang to bring
the others and meet us there
Wu-Yang
Where's Er-Hu?
He...
went to see Brother Pang
You're up to something!
What's with all those new guards?
You're going to kill Er-Hu...
all because of Lian?!
Have you forgotten our pledge?!
When will Er-Hu arrive?
Tell me when!
Nightfall...
He'll be here by nightfall
Wait for me!
You scared me
Lian, I'm here to say goodbye
Are you leaving?
No, you are
But where to?
I'm waiting for Er-Hu...
I've just prepared dinner
Big brother is going to kill Er-Hu over you
No, it can't be!
Come down here
No
I have to finish draping this frame
Have you ever seen such beautiful fabric?
I haven't seen one in years
I saw the red one in a shop yesterday...
but I also wanted the green one
I asked Er-Hu what to do
He said...
green for this year and red for the next
I'll be 29 next year
I lived through 14 years of war...
didn't starve to death or get killed
I've been lucky!
I still have to hang the red curtain next year
Come down!
You wouldn't kill me... I won't let you!
It wasn't easy for me to survive!
Why must you kill me?
If I don't kill you... how will I save Er-Hu?
Can you really save him by killing me?
I don't know...
but it's all I can do
I watched you grow up
You wouldn't do it... You won't!
I know you can't kill me...
You wouldn't do it...
Anyone who harms our brothers...
You can't kill me!
must be...
killed!
5 years ago...
108 men left their village to join the army...
risking their lives for a little food
They were the first to join the Shan army
The three of us were their leaders
Today, I found a good place to free you
I told you...
there will come a day when
you'll see that I was right
Each year at this time, I'll drink with you
I'll tell you what I've done in the past year
I just returned from the palace
The people of Jiangsu have been...
spared from taxes for 3 years
Next year, I promise...
no one will go hungry
You'll understand eventually
that Xiao-Qi and Gouzi...
didn't die in vain...
and the massacre of the 4000 captives...
was necessary
And you...
You...
You will not die in vain
You defied my orders in Suzhou
I could have killed you then,
but I couldn't do it
But now it's the imperial court...
that wants you dead
What choice do I have?
My brother...
go in peace
Brother...
Big brother, you don't need to kill Er-Hu!
Brother!
you don't need to kill Er-Hu!
Lian is dead!
You don't have to kill Er-Hu!
Lian is already dead...
no reason to kill Er-Hu now!
Brother!
Lian is dead!
The gods bless this day
Joining the ranks of those that went before...
a great servant to the empire
To lead by example and serve his people
The inauguration of Pang Qing-Yun
as Governor of Jiangsu will take place...
at noon on this day, the 8th of the 4th month
A fence needs three pillars
It's not the same without Lord Jiang here
A quarter to 12
Stand down!
A brother who harms another brother...
must die!
A brother who harms another brother must die
It's time
Don't push me!
A brother who harms another brother...
must die!
Wu-Yang!
I beg you stop!
A brother who harms another brother must die
Pang Qing-Yun!
Pang has talent
but doesn't know how things work
Nanking is of vital importance
to the peace of the country
The Empress would never entrust it
to an outsider
Pity... such is life
Noon is here! Salute cannons, fire!
Honor our pledge...
now!
I, Jiang Wu-Yang, killed Pang Qing-Yun!
At that moment...
My mind went back to
the day we took the blood oath
We are born apart but we shall die as one
Our origins are different...
but our hearts act as one
In good times and bad, in life and in death
We honor our pledge
Governor of Jiangsu, Pang Qing-Yun...
was assassinated on the 26th of July, 1870.
His assassin Jiang Wu-Yang
was executed 2 months later.