(female voice): Today
is a very special day.
It is your first step
on the road to serenity.
You are not alone.
You are doing great.
One step at a time.
Lesson one.
In this first lesson,
you'll have to visualize
different landscapes.
First landscape.
A beach.
Picture that beach.
Then, picture yourself
on the beach.
Close your eyes,
relax...
and open your mind.
You are calm.
- OK.
Come on.
Picture on the beach.
The beach...
(waves washing ashore)
Ah...
(female voice): Now
picture yourself on the beach.
- Now...
Yourself on the beach...
- Isn't this a beautiful day?
Isn't this gonna be a beautiful day?
- Picture yourself on the beach.
(seagulls cawing)
Yourself on the beach...
Picture...
Picture yourself...
... yourself on the beach.
Picture...
"Be sure to complete lesson one
before attempting lesson two."
(female voice): You are calm.
You've made one step
toward serenity.
- Fuck!
Smile: Now. Ask your doctor.
- I call at 9, the agency's closed.
That's not OK, Max.
Especially not today.
Inexperience is no excuse,
it's been two weeks.
I've had it.
Do you want the job or not?
I'll be there in ten.
Fuck.
(seagulls cawing)
Picture yourself...
... on the beach.
Yourself on the beach...
Picture yourself...
- I'd prefer you waited till I left.
I can't stand smoke.
Sorry, it makes me sick.
- No problem.
Anyway, the agency was right.
You have a beautiful energy.
- You enjoyed it?
- A lot.
- Picture yourself on the beach.
... the beach.
Picture...
yourself on the beach.
(smoke alarm beeping)
(footsteps)
- Picture yourself--
(female voice): We've completed--
- Fuck you, ostie.
- Are you sure we've never met?
- Positive.
- Jennifer...
That your real name?
- Why wouldn't it be?
Do I ask your real name?
- No.
- Alright.
- Max?
Max, you there?
Goddamn!
Fuck.
(phone ringing)
- Not answering?
- No, I'm running late.
- Want me to?
- No, don't bother.
- I'll leave too.
- No, stay. Go back to sleep.
(phone ringing)
- You think?
- Got the key?
- Yes.
- Stay long as you want.
- I dunno.
- I'd be glad if you did.
- Thanks.
- You can sleep in my bed.
- This is comfortable.
- I'll call.
- OK.
(phone ringing)
- You can unplug it.
(meowing)
I made coffee.
You alright?
- Yeah.
- Will today be a good or bad day?
- Today?
- Yeah.
- A good day.
Better than yesterday.
I think.
- Are you sure?
- No.
Did me good to sleep here.
- See you later.
- Yeah.
- I'm off.
- You were watching me sleep.
- What?
- You slept next to me, on the floor.
- See you later, Stéphanie.
- What's the idea?
Just another whim of yours?
You've changed ten times.
- I have not!
- Now it's Jenny, before it was Cindy.
Before that Candy.
There was Claudia--
I was never Claudia.
I was Julia, but never Claudia.
So many names
and what's it got you?
The guy at the motel this morning...
It's Jennifer
he wants in his bed. Period.
- Jennifer?
- Yup.
- You want to change to Jennifer?
- Yes.
- Jennifer...
- It's the same damn thing!
The same name!
- Jenny and Jennifer?
- It's the same name.
- I'm not going to negotiate, Ron.
Jenny's cheap. I don't like it.
- What happened here?
- Where were you?
I tried your cell, at home...
- They took the book.
- The book?
- The girls' pictures.
- Who'd want it?
- Tell me you have a copy.
- Not me.
- Christ!
- But...
Ron has a hunch.
- He does?
- Yes.
- Who?
- Cheech.
- Cheech?
- Never heard of Cheech?
- Should I have?
- Nah.
- Nah?
- Clean up, I'll be back in an hour.
Jenny, we'll talk.
- My name is Jennifer.
- Jesus!
I'm so sorry, Gaétan.
I had car trouble.
- We said 10.
I had breakfast, three coffees...
- My treat.
Sit down, have a seat.
So, how's it going, Gaétan?
- Want conference gigs?
- Do I want conference gigs?
- Because if you want conference gigs,
that's fine, but...
you have to learn the ropes.
- Come on, Gaétan.
- I need to work with professionals.
Anyone can do one-ons.
A four-year-old could do it.
But conferences
require organization,
professionalism.
Do you mind?
I've no time to waste.
- Neither do l, Gaétan.
- I called the guys.
- From Wisconsin?
- We're looking at 10 girls.
- Right.
- Very discreet.
- Wasn't it a dozen?
- What?
- Nothing, forget it.
- Vaginal, anal...
- Of course, of course.
- And they want to see the book first.
- Sure.
- They wonder why
you don't have a website.
If you ask me,
it makes you look like an amateur.
Do you have it?
- What?
- Your book.
Ron?
- Look, Gaétan.
Come to think,
don't take it wrong,
but I'd like to meet them myself.
- What?
- The guys from Wisconsin.
I mean,
I could go there with you.
We'd be a team.
It's at 8, right?
- What do you mean?
- I'd like to present the product,
since it's my first time.
I'd be super presentable.
In terms of dress code, 4 stars,
like the hotel.
- Did I wait half an hour
like a turkey for nothing?
- I'll be happy to pay
for your breakfast.
So, 8 o'clock?
- I want my commission tonight.
- Tonight? We said--
- That was then.
This is now.
I want my cut tonight.
- What if they don't pay me?
- There's other agencies.
Want me to call the Regency?
They never give me problems.
- See you tonight.
- My treat.
- Does that answer your question?
- Is that Cheech's agency?
- Yes.
- Wow.
- Why the castle?
- Well, Regency...
- So, like kings?
That's so random.
- Only because
you don't know the Regency.
- 150 girls.
- Professionalism.
- Discretion.
- Courtesy.
- Quality.
- Competitive rates.
- Loyalty points.
- Total satisfaction.
- Like a mega-mart, but X-rated.
- Really?
- On his desk, a gold plaque.
A motto:
"We fuck for less."
- But underneath, in smaller letters,
the motto continues...
"So don't fuck with us."
- Don't fuck with us...
- Ron wants to do conference gigs.
And at the Grand Hotel, too.
That's great. Fine.
Good luck.
When you elbow aside the big boys,
there's a good chance
they won't like it.
- I won't be intimidated!
- Been there long?
- We redo the book.
- What?
- I'm not letting this chance slip by.
Let's call the girls.
Where you going?
- I have a date.
- Cancel it.
- There's no time.
- To hell with you.
We take new pictures,
only dirtier.
- How, dirtier?
- Real dirty.
We won't be intimidated.
- Yes, hello.
Is this 1-800-555-0147?
(camera shutter clicking)
I got your number...
A friend warmly recommended
your service.
Yes, hello.
Is this 1-800-555-0147?
(whip lashing)
Yes, hello. I'd like
to engage your services.
Well, in fact,
I'm calling for someone else.
Since he feels
a bit awkward about this,
I'm helping him out,
since he's a good friend.
A very good friend.
(camera shutter clicking)
(whip lashing)
(alarm beeping)
- Come on, fuck!
- What's up?
- Gimme a minute, OK?
Take a break.
(women grumbling)
- Taping yourself?
- I won't be long, so just...
- Sure.
- "Spirit moment.
Press record."
- In English?
- Max, Christ!
Please, Max! OK?
- Sorry.
- It's alright.
It's alright.
- Is it for your depression?
- What?
- This. Is it to help you?
- I dunno anymore.
I dunno what to do. I'm trying.
I'm trying stuff.
I dunno what to try.
- You can speak French.
- Two minutes, OK?
Two minutes.
- Cool.
- "Spirit moment.
"Press record and think
of ten positive things
"so far in the day.
"Express without judging.
"I'm thankful for...
OK.
Record.
Spirit... moment.
Ten positive things.
Number one...
The sun.
(phone ringing)
Jesus Christ!
- I can answer!
- Yes. Yes, that's right.
Just a second, please.
They took the pad!
- The pad...?
- The reservation pad.
Why would anyone steal
a fucking reservation pad?
Hello, yes...
Yes, I'm sorry.
Is it for today? OK.
What's the address?
Your name?
Give me his name then.
You can give me a borrowed name,
for discretion.
I don't know.
Let's say... Robert?
- Mike.
- There's Mike too.
Mike or Robert.
They're fine names.
Great, Mike. He'll be thrilled.
What does Mike like?
We have a special this month,
for the holidays.
We call it "the kit."
The girl has a kit of accessories
and different outfits.
There are over 50 possible combinations,
so you can personalize your product.
Interested?
OK, perfect. I have--
- Not Stef!
- The charming Stéphanie.
- Stef's not--
- The charming Stéphanie
is very well liked.
What time?
- I'll be back.
- Have you ever cancelled?
- Come in.
- Have you ever called back
to cancel?
- I don't understand.
- A girl's coming at 1.
I swear.
- You did it?
- Yes.
Well, no.
I thought I'd made up my mind,
but I'm not sure.
- Second thoughts?
- Yes.
Thinking it over, I'm not...
I wanted to...
I wanted to ask you...
y'know, what exactly happens?
What happened the times you called?
- What?
- The times you called?
- I've never called.
- You never called?
- No. You thought I had?
- You asked me the number.
- Yes, but...
- You asked me.
several times.
You said,
"Call them, it'll do you good."
You said, "It's a sign,
follow the sign."
The flyer I found under the sofa
was a sign.
- Yeah, so?
- Why didn't you tell me?
- You never asked.
To me it was clear.
I don't sleep with prostitutes.
- Who's she?
- She's a girl I met.
- Really?
- Mélanie.
- I didn't know.
Bravo.
- Thanks.
- You should introduce us.
- Yeah.
- We could all go out.
Us two and you two.
Sophie'd like that.
- Of course.
- Or are you still at the stage
when you like to be alone?
- Yes. I'm expecting her.
- Now?
- Tonight.
- We could drop by.
After our cocktail party.
It'd be fun. Around 9.
- Yes.
- What do you think?
- If you want.
- A quick visit.
- Perfect.
- You OK?
- What about the escort?
- I don't know.
- Stéphanie?
Stef?
Shit!
What's going on?
- Did you find my letter?
- What?
- I'm going.
- Where were you?
I called here, your cell.
- I didn't answer, sorry.
- Where you going?
- Home.
I'm working this afternoon.
- Ron called?
- Yeah.
- You answer for him, but not me?
- Please stop asking
so many questions.
- You shouldn't go to work today.
- None of your business.
- The agency's a mess.
- It's OK.
- You told me about a black hole.
- Stop it, Max. Stop it.
- You said yourself,
it could come back.
- Go away.
I don't know what you want.
I want you to leave me alone.
- I want to help you.
- Stop it!
- I think you're someone...
someone...
... who needs help.
- Screw you!
(singing softly in Chinese)
(singing)
- Hello. I'm a bit late.
I'm expected.
- The reservation's in what name?
- Goodness, I'm not sure.
Anything for Regency?
The Regency Agency?
- They haven't arrived yet.
(knocking)
- Hello.
Stéphanie?
- Yes.
- Stéphanie.
- Mike?
- Pardon?
- Are you Mike?
- No, Olivier.
- OK.
Is Mike here?
- No.
I mean, I'm Mike.
Actually, Mike doesn't exist.
It was me who called.
- OK. You're Mike.
- No. Well, yes, I guess, in a way.
- I understand.
- Are you OK? I mean, come in.
Sit down. It's alright, your being late.
What's an hour?
Here's your money.
I was told I should pay first.
Give me your coat.
- I'll go to the john.
- Sure.
If you could... It's down there.
If you could take off...
Your boots, maybe.
- How's it going?
- Fine.
It's just,
Marie brought along this oil.
They all want to put some on,
so it might stain the sofa a bit.
Careful with that.
- Call Stef.
I told her about the client,
but not the book.
So tell her to come by after.
I'm going home to get my suit.
I'll be back soon.
- OK.
Alright, girls, shall we start?
- Is everything OK, Stéphanie?
Can I get you
a glass of white wine?
- That's it...
I've been with my boyfriend 5 years.
I have a stable employment,
a normal job.
I don't know if it's you I told,
but I only work part-time.
I work in travel.
It was as a tourist guide
that I got into this line,
if you follow.
- Yes, it's me you spoke to.
- Yes, I remember your voice
very well.
I hesitated before calling you, but...
... finally I told myself
it was time to change.
- To get serious.
- Absolutely, yes.
To get serious.
- Mm...
- And I assume that...
... what I told you
about my current employer
was useful to you.
From what I saw earlier...
... it was useful, right?
- Yes, absolutely.
- About his address...
... his home address.
I hope you won't need to use it.
Do you think you'll need to use it?
- I wouldn't think so.
(door unlocking)
- I'll take that wine.
- Yes, sure, it's on the counter.
Excuse me. I thought
since it was taking so long,
I thought you were getting ready.
See, I asked for the kit.
They offered it to me.
I said yes. I thought
you were putting on
the kit in question.
So I thought that meant
I should go ahead
and get into my kit too, but...
Sorry, I'm not an expert
on prostitution.
- Prostitution?
- It's not a bad little wine.
Not bad at all.
- I don't do the kit.
- You don't?
- No.
- Plus I'm very versatile.
I do a bit of everything.
I have no taboos.
- Excellent.
That's really excellent.
- Do we wait for Cheech?
- Cheech?
No, Cheech isn't coming.
- He's not?
I thought the point was to meet me,
like an audition.
- The audition will be tonight.
- I see.
- Does the Grand suit you?
- The hotel?
- Mm-hmm.
We're regulars there.
The suite's already reserved.
You'll see,
it's discreet, private,
and comfortable.
- With Sophie,
it's not that I don't try.
I do try, but...
Desire is so mysterious.
It's a mystery.
Not so long ago, I was happy
just being with her.
Just that.
She says work drains her sexually,
but I don't buy it.
Like that négligé I told you about.
In the display it was
the most erotic thing I'd ever seen.
The salesgirl wrapping up
the bit of fabric...
Wow.
How could something so exciting
become so banal
once she put it on? It's a mystery.
The same sexy outfit!
A hot outfit should be even sexier
on a girl, no?
Shouldn't it?
- I'm not an expert on sexiness.
- You're not?
- No.
Maybe we should start.
- God, yes,
we'll even have to hurry up.
- I have to pee.
- Again?
Sure, fine.
Go ahead, no problem.
- You can undress.
- Fine. Thanks. But...
Thanks.
- You'll thank me after.
- No, thanks for just now.
It was nice that you--
- I wasn't listening.
Being here isn't listening.
And listening isn't being here.
I was thinking I can't wait to leave.
- I'm going to make it
through the day!
(female voice):
Ride with the Whale, Volume l.
It is time for a very special journey.
Take a deep breath.
Relax... join the sea.
And ride with the whale.
- Ride with the whale.
(whale song)
Ride with the whale.
- Are you OK, Stéphanie?
Anyway, I'm ready now.
Ready as I'll ever be.
(water running)
I'm not so sure about a bath...
I'm not sure we even have time.
Sophie's coming to get me at 4.
We have a South American
cocktail party tonight.
So that doesn't leave
a whole lot of time.
Not much time at all.
In fact...
What the fuck?
- I won't be long.
- Oh... OK.
(water running)
Stéphanie!
Turn off the tap, it's flooding!
Stéphanie, open the door!
Open the door!
Open the door now!
I want you to leave!
Open the door!
I want you to leave! Open up!
- It's alright.
I think it's alright.
It's alright.
- Get out!
- Let's go, I'm ready now.
- I don't do the kit.
Can I have some more wine?
- You're bleeding!
- Think I'll sit down.
- No, don't sit down!
Don't! Not on the sofa!
- I'll sit down.
- Don't sit down. Just go.
Come on, it's time for you to go.
- Do you have a towel?
- I have Scott Towels,
but you have to go. Here...
Take these.
You can have these.
I'll give them to you.
Now leave.
Here, take your money too.
In an envelope, it won't get bloody.
Let's go. I added a good tip.
It was great.
(phone ringing)
Wipe yourself off.
That's Sophie, she's downstairs!
- Not answering?
- No, no, no!
Don't touch that! Leave it alone!
Come on, get your clothes
from the bathroom.
- I'll take your wine.
I don't do the kit.
I'm gonna sit down.
- Shit, my sofa!
Get up!
- Let's go, I'm ready.
(phone ringing)
I want you out of here
in two minutes, OK?!
Two minutes.
I'm counting on you.
Get dressed and leave!
OK?
I'm counting on you.
Get dressed and leave!
Sorry. Excuse me, sir.
- No problem.
- Sorry.
- I've been running all day
and I'm on time!
You lay around and you're late!
Can you explain the logic of that?!
- No.
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
- You're out of breath.
- Me? No.
- You're pale.
- No.
- Got your swimsuit?
- You don't swim, you don't dance.
What do you do?
- I need a drugstore.
- I dunno, it might be bad.
- My shoes!
- Pardon?
- I forgot to bring my shoes,
my dress shoes.
I'll have to go back for them, shit!
- I see.
- Mmm...
Delicious!
You understand...
... I hate doing this
to good customers.
- I understand.
- But it is my third visit.
- And today I need funds
to pay a colleague, so...
- Of course.
- Got any money?
- No.
- You sure?
- I can check.
- Yes, if you don't mind,
please check.
- You know,
I convinced a friend to call you.
- Very kind.
- It was good publicity.
- Thanks.
- That's all I have just now.
- One of my girls
said you were depressed.
- Pardon?
- If you like,
I can recommend a good book.
"Learn how to smile again."
It's one of the steps.
A key step.
- "Learn how..."
- "Learn how to smile again."
Learn how to smile again.
- That's all I have right now.
- When's the last time you smiled?
- The last time I smiled?
I dunno.
- Try to remember.
- I can't say.
- Would you be able
to smile right now?
- Now?
- Would you be able to smile?
- Right now?
- Would you?
- I dunno.
- Try.
Go on, try.
Not easy, huh?
- My jaw hurts.
- It's not easy.
It's not easy to smile.
"Learn how to smile again."
A key step.
The rest in a week.
Don't make me come back.
Max, it's me.
You were leaving?
Listen to me. Go to my desk.
Listen, in my desk, second drawer.
The cashbox, there's a gun inside.
Get it.
16 - 12 - 69.
- 16 - 12 - 69, OK!
(female voice): Relax.
Ride with the whale.
Are you enjoying your ride?
Are you relaxed by now?
- I am very relaxed.
- That a prescription?
- It's not for me.
- Is this the line?
- Uh, yes.
- I didn't see the photo counter.
- It must be up front.
- I didn't see it.
- I don't know.
- It's not for you?
- Pardon?
- The prescription?
- No.
- Someone you know?
- Yes.
Xanadril. Heard of it?
- No. Xana--
- Xanadril. It's a...
tricyclic antidepressant.
- Tricyclic?
- Yes.
- For depression?
- Does it work?
- I guess.
- Is the person better?
- Much better.
A letter?
- Yeah.
- Sir?
- Good news, I hope.
- Do you offer
one-hour film development?
Takes an hour?
- It's not here, it's in front.
- It is?
- Yes.
- Sir?
- I also need...
you know, something tricyclic.
I don't know the exact name.
It's called tricyclic.
The man ahead of me had a paper.
- A prescription?
- That's it, a prescription.
- May I see your prescription?
- Pardon?
- Your prescription?
- I don't have one.
The other man did.
- Then I can't help you, sir.
- You can't?
- No.
Photos are in front.
- But it's very important.
- In front.
Would you let the lady by?
I understand what you said.
- Look, I'll take them over.
But you need--
- I have a letter.
Not a prescription, but...
it's on paper
and it means something.
I mean, I know you need
a prescription. I understand.
But any doctor who saw this letter
would say it's like a prescription.
- Sir, other people are waiting.
- Maybe you should
expand your definition
of a prescription.
- Sir...
- "I'm not leaving now,
I left long ago."
- Sir, please.
- Look, I have no choice.
I'm not a bad person.
But I need you to give me
those tricyclics.
Give me all the tricyclics you have.
- What?
- Tricylics.
- I don't understand.
- We're here too.
- I won't be long, madame.
I don't know the name.
- It's my first day.
- What?
- Please go away.
- Is anything wrong, Colette?
- No, everything's fine.
- Are you satisfied, sir?
- Yes, absolutely.
- Alright.
- It's very good.
The service is very courteous.
- Do you have his prescription?
- Yes, sure.
- May I see it?
- No--
- Here.
- Is this a joke?
Is this some kind of joke?
- It's no joke.
- No, it's not a joke!
(gunshot)
- Whoa! Whoa!
Stay calm, please! Stay calm!
(female voice): You are calm.
You've made one step
toward serenity.
(alarm beeping)
- Don't tell me, shit!
Spirit moment.
I'm learning to be grateful...
... for all life's gifts.
The air that...
The air we breathe.
We forget it too often.
(phone ringing)
Goddammit!
Hello.
- Ron, have you heard from Stéphanie?!
You have to find her!
Stéphanie's very tired!
What?
The photos?
Yeah, I went.
Yeah, fine. Just fine.
There's just a hitch.
A mini-hitch.
I don't think I can get them.
The photos.
I'm not sure
they'll give them to me.
The mini-hitch is... Cheech!
- Cheech?!
- Yeah, Cheech.
- Fuck!
- Two of his guys.
I dunno, guys who work for him.
They said they'd whack me
if I picked up the photos!
They said, "We'll whack you.
"Conferences are our turf."
- I don't care
about your silly worries.
Too late.
The shit's hit the fan!
I need the photos at 7!
We fuck for less, we fuck for less!
Really!
Don't discretion and class
count anymore?
Work well done, personalized service,
who cares?
78% repeat call rate! 78%!
Nobody gives a damn. So what?
I won't be intimidated, dammit!
Fuck!!
- What the fuck?!
- I do what I can in life.
I get up, I go to work.
I deserve it.
I think I deserve the good things...
... in life.
I cry.
I get up in the morning
and cry like a baby.
"Stop, why are you crying?"
I can't say, but I cry.
If I listened to myself...
... I'd kill myself.
But I have no time...
... to kill myself.
(lively Latin music)
- You stay till the end.
- I don't know anyone.
- Exactly, you need to get out more.
Olivier, it's a party, smile.
- I feel like it's forced.
I'll stay for your category,
and then we'll see.
- Hello!
How's it going?
You're not dancing?
- We just got here.
- Give me your coats.
- Thank you!
- Olivier, give me your coat.
- No, no, no.
- Olivier?
- I'll hold on to it for now.
- What's with you?
- I'll hold on to my coat for now.
Excuse me, miss.
Could I have a glass of water?
- Can I borrow him?
- He's all yours.
(music slowing)
- Hello?
Are you home?
(knocking)
Hello?
- The winner of tonight's
first Tropical Sun award is...
... Sophie Bilodeau!
- Bravo!
- Thanks!
Thanks a lot!
It's always great to receive
a trophy like this.
Especially since
I've worked very hard this year
to satisfy my clients.
I think that...
the key to success,
the only key, is hard work.
You have to work,
put in the time, keep at it.
If you think you can make do
with three or four Scott Towels...
(laughter)
- I'm thrilled for her!
- I'd also like to thank Suzanne
and her amazing team in Personnel
for tonight's wonderful party.
The decorations,
the Jacuzzi,
the water overflowing, you fuck!
It's great.
We can't wait till next year!
Before I go,
I'd like...
I'd like to thank Olivier...
my partner,
who's here tonight.
Olivier...
if she dies it's your fault!
Thank you!
(silence)
(knocking)
- Not bad, huh?
- You're not dancing?
- No.
- Me neither.
- Olivier, will you please--
- Well, well!
I don't believe it!
(laughing)
We met this morning.
- You did?
- Of course. You...
You were...
Fort Lauderdale, right?
- Right, absolutely.
Thanks for the excellent service.
Do you know her?
- Barely.
- Courteous, attentive...
Enterprising too, right?
As for trophies,
I'd have given you one too!
A woman of hidden talents.
- I'll go lie on a deck chair.
- Tell me something, Miss Jennifer...
... in Fort Lauderdale,
is sodomy de rigueur?
Jennifer?
Jennifer? Jennifer?
Hey, hey.
I didn't plan to come.
A colleague of my wife invited me.
Are you OK?
- Just fine.
- Great party, huh?
Your real name's Sophie, right?
Hey, hey.
What's wrong?
Where are you running to, doll?
Why are you leaving like this?
Do you want to...
go to Fort Lauderdale with me?
How bout a little Fort Lauderdale
in the snow?
- Ahhhhh!
(groaning)
- It's twenty to eight!
- Sorry.
- Go on, you drive.
- What?
Want me to come?
- Hurry up!
Move it!
- What?
- Get going!
Floor it, fuck!
And the pictures?
The pictures, Max!
- They're great.
- Good.
Those guys cause problems?
- Those guys?
- Cheech's guys.
- I didn't see them.
- They didn't show?
- No.
- What were they like?
- Cheech's guys?
I didn't see them.
- When you saw them before.
- I didn't see them.
- Not when you got the film,
when you left it!
You called me.
- Right, I saw them!
- Was one guy fat?
- I think so.
The other was skinnier,
with a moustache, I think.
Did Stéphanie call?
- No.
- I dropped by her place,
she isn't answering her cell.
I'm really worried.
- Hold these a sec.
OK.
Give it to me.
The photos?
- I have them.
Well, give 'em to me!
- Here.
- Perfect.
Good.
- I'll make it through the day.
I'll make it through the day.
(sniffling)
I'll make it... through the day.
- Stop here.
We'll act real calm and cool,
like professionals.
Are we professionals or not?
- We're professionals.
- If you see Cheech's guys, tell me.
- Here?
- What do you think?
The shit hit the fan.
- Your briefcase...
- What?
- Want me to carry it?
I'm your assistant.
It looks more professional.
- Alright.
Good thinking.
What are you doing?
- Huh?
What are you up to?
I'll take it.
Keep your eyes peeled.
I want you to put on your best smile
and shut up.
Here we go.
If you recognize anyone, tell me.
- Like Cheech's guys?
Ron?
Is that Gaétan?
Wanna go?
Ron...
- Wait here a sec.
- What are we doing?
- You can close the door.
- Alright.
I'm a bit early, I think.
- No problem.
Cheech is here.
- He is?
- In the next room.
He's real eager to meet you.
- Glad to hear it.
Could you...
Could you give me just two minutes?
To freshen up.
The day has been...
- Trying?
- Quite.
- No problem,
take all the time in the world.
- Thank you.
- I don't get it.
- Neither do l.
Knock, see who answers.
Tell me if you recognize anyone.
- I don't get it.
- Just do it.
- I'm ready.
Ready and waiting.
Cheech isn't here?
- Cheech?
- Yes.
- In half an hour.
He'll be out in half an hour.
Long enough...
- Long enough for what?
- To test your skills.
- Could I speak to him, please?
- You want to speak to Cheech?
- Yes, please.
- After. You can speak to him after.
- I'd like to speak to him now.
- I don't think that'll be possible.
You have to be patient,
sweetheart.
He's not here?
Cheech isn't here?
I see.
He's gone.
Cheech is gone.
- Where is he?
Where is he?!
- Jenny?
Hello.
- By what right...?
Beat it. It's none of your business.
I'm with a client. He's a client.
- Raymond Palucci.
You may not know me,
but I know you.
- I know you very well.
- He's dead.
Cheech is dead.
It's so sad.
Prostate cancer.
Four of us at the funeral.
The agency closed three weeks ago.
$187,000 in the hole.
We've got an office suite
if you're interested.
Not marble, but a good imitation.
- It's not what you think.
- That depends.
What do you think I think?
- I just wanted to meet him.
Cheech.
I didn't know.
I didn't know anything.
Did you trash his office?
- No.
But we'd have loved to.
- The Regency's closed?
- 27 years of loyal service
down the drain.
- I'm sorry.
What's wrong?
Want me to go tell Gaétan?
He's waiting.
- One's fat,
one has a moustache.
- What?
- Cheech's men. One's fat,
one has a moustache?
- Did I say that?
- Don't you remember?
- No.
- They knew about the book.
- I said...
- What?
- Yeah, the guys knew.
They said, "The conference is ours."
You said that.
- I don't remember.
- You said Cheech's guys--
- I thought that--
- OK.
I want you to explain something.
How can two guys work for a dead man?
How can two guys
speak for a dead man?
How can a dead man steal a book?!
- You told me it was Cheech!
I don't know Cheech!
All I heard was Cheech, Cheech, Cheech.
So I thought...
Maybe they weren't Cheech's men.
- Not his men?
- Maybe not.
- Why'd you lie?
- I didn't lie.
- Stop. You should ask Jenny that!
- Why'd you lie?!
- Your staff seems to be
giving you trouble.
(chuckling)
- Max...
I want an answer.
I want the truth.
Did you steal the book?
- So you think I did it?
I refuse. I refuse to answer, Ron.
- Answer me!
- Stop it, I have a gun too.
- You stole the book!
- I have a gun.
- You stole my book!
- Ron...
I'll just go, OK?
- I'm gonna shoot.
I swear I'm gonna shoot.
- I just want to leave.
- Maxime...
Maxime...
I'm so unhappy.
(alarm beeping)
- Fuck.
- Ron?
- I'm still going to sleep
with you, right?
- Could you read me my book, please?
The book in my briefcase.
Please.
- Shall I start now?
"Lesson one."
"ln this first lesson,
"you will have to visualize
different landscapes.
"First landscape: a beach.
"Picture that beach,
"then picture yourself on the beach.
"Close your eyes,
relax and open..."
Are you listening?
Can you hear me?
Hello?
- Hello?
Are you alright?
- Not at all.
- If it's 4, it's on the 4th floor, huh?
- Yes.
- Thanks.
- Excuse me.
- Can I help you?
- No, I'm sorry.
Stef?
- Max?
I killed myself.
But I think I slept.
I fell asleep.
But I'm not home,
I think I'm somewhere else.
I'm sorry.
Look,
I think I stopped bleeding.
The Scott Towels are crusted on.
I can't get them off.
The guy told me to leave
but I couldn't.
Can we go now?
- I'm sorry about before.
I could've given you
more Scott Towels.
- Jenny?
- Sophie?
Why're you here?
I can explain.
- What happened, Stéphanie?
- You know her?
- You live here, Jenny?
- It's...
It's Jennifer now, I think.
(answering machine beeping)
- Hello, Ron?
It's Mom.
Well...
... we waited for you.
But we got fed up.
We'd hired someone
to make it special.
So we left it all there.
It's a professional decorating job.
Where are you?
Anyway, I'm calling
to wish you happy birthday.
So...
... happy birthday.
OK?
Bye.
- Hi.
Isn't Sophie with you?
You said she'd come.
Too bad, you missed Mélanie.
We had a lovely evening.
She said to say hi.
You get my messages?
It leaked a bit,
but not that much.
Was there much damage?
- Lots.
Smile: Now. Ask your doctor.