For a year Tahrir Square has been
at the heart of a tumultuous
struggle for freedom.
Last February, people from all over
Egypt united in their desire
to bring down a dictator
and build a new country.
This World has followed
three young revolutionaries.
Ahmed's came from Cairo's
backstreets to fight for an Egypt
where he can find work.
For Gigi, it is a battle
for freedom.
While Tahir wants to build
an Islamic state.
GUN SHOTS
Some dreams have been crushed.
Others have come closer.
It was a year which has
divided families.
And a year that risked
dividing the nation.
Once just another roundabout
in Cairo,
Tahrir Square became
the crucible of the Arab Spring.
Could Egypt become the model
for an Islamic democracy
in the Middle East?
Or would the dreams evaporate
into intolerance
and another dictatorship?
The battle begins on Police Day,
25th January, 2011.
Inspired by the successful
uprising in Tunisia,
unofficial opposition groups
called for a demonstration
against corruption
and police brutality.
The 25th January, I remember that
the first thing I did that day,
I went to get another battery
for my BlackBerry.
At 24, student, Gigi Ibrahim,
is a veteran of illegal protest.
Going into residential areas
for people to join us.
We started being tens, then grew into
hundreds and grew into thousands.
But I didn't realize the impact
until I reached Tahrir.
CHANTING
I was so happy.
I have this clip on video,
the exact moment
I knew this was a revolution.
We were in Tahrir and a huge wave
of central security officers
started to run.
The people first ran
as the normal reaction.
But then they stopped,
some people started attacking.
And then a wave of protestors
ran after the officers.
And the officers actually ran away.
SHE SCREAMS
I'm like, "Let's go! We've waited
30 years for this!"
This is the moment I physically saw
people not being afraid and running
after officers.
SHE SHOUTS
That night the thousands become
tens of thousands who begin
to camp out in the square.
Ahmed Hassan joins
the demonstration,
angry after years of suffering
every day humiliations
at the hands of the state.
Over the next 17 days,
as the confrontation escalates,
hundreds are killed.
Instead of leaving, the crowd grows.
Ahmed is still there on February
10th and watches on
an improvised screen
as President Mubarak appears on TV
to calm his people.
The vast crowd, now made up of
every strand of Egyptian society,
are united in their response,
waving their shoes,
the ultimate sign of disrespect
in the Arab world.
That night, the army, for years
a mainstay of the Mubarak regime,
takes control.
At 6pm, a general arrives
at the state TV building
with a recorded message
from the vice president.
He orders it to be broadcast
immediately.
THEY ALL SHOUT OUT
SHE LAUGHS WITH JOY
THEY CHANT: Finish, Mubarak.
Finish, Mubarak. Finish, Mubarak!
Finish, Mubarak!
The army joins the protesters
on the square,
promising to oversee a transition
to a democratic Egypt.
The morning after, Gigi and fellow
revolutionaries celebrate
by clearing up their mess.
There is a sense
that a new era has begun.
My dad, my dad. Hello.
He's asking about what happens next.
He's asking me!
My dad asking me. That never happens!
Life has to go back to normal.
Like, people have got
to go back to work.
Now, we fight,
we fight legitimately
for free and fair elections
where the people are going
to choose democratically
for the first time ever.
Now, the real hard work starts.
Really. It begins now.
Across Cairo,
Ahmed returns home
to the slum of Shubra,
where unemployment runs at over 30%.
He lives with his widowed mother,
Awatef, and younger brother, Amrr.
They are glued to
the new debate shows on TV.
Ahmed is convinced that
his life has changed for the better.
TRANSLATION: God willing
I will find work.
Now, after an employer finds out
that I was part of the revolution,
he will never treat me badly
like before. Impossible.
At his barber shop,
Ahmed is the local hero.
They are conscious
the world has been watching.
Every day at dawn,
Ahmed's mother Awatef gets up
to purchase the vegetables
for her market stall.
Not everyone supports
the revolution.
Under Mubarak, the police
were seen as a constant menace.
Harassment of a market trader had
sparked the revolution in Tunisia.
TRANSLATION: That boy set fire
to himself. You'd never catch me
doing that. Poor kid!
Government trucks would clear
the street by force.
My friend, the baker,
suffered more than any of us.
Since the day he moved in
by my stall,
he's been dragged
to and from police station.
They wouldn't let him go
till they took a £100 bribe.
No-one dared to speak,
or they'd get beaten and get taken
to the police station too.
That's how we used to live.
This is the Nile River. Smelly.
SHE LAUGHS
I wish I had more time to come here
more often.
My dad is here every single week.
Gigi inhabits a different world.
She is the American-educated
daughter of a wealthy industrialist.
My dad is a business man, you know.
He has benefited but, at the same
time, in the past few years
he really has suffered also
from the regime.
SHE LAUGHS
AND GREETS HER FAMILY
She let me feel I am a failure.
GIGI: No!
Honest, true. After this revolution,
how come we stand?
I'm 55, 56 years old now.
I stay with the Mubarak regime
for 30 years
and I didn't even think,
think even to change.
How many generations were useless
not to stand and say no?
This is what I feel. I feel bad.
Not everyone buys into the euphoria.
Gigi's aunt and sister are worried.
THEY ARGUE
Before the revolution, religious
groups were ruthlessly suppressed.
The only real opposition to Mubarak
was the illegal Muslim Brotherhood.
Now they are in the open,
along with other Islamic groups
such as the ultra-conservative
Salafis.
24-year-old Tahir Yasin is a Salafi.
HE SINGS TO HIMSELF
He has been in prison seven times
from the age of 16
for organising Qu'ran classes.
For the first time in his life,
he is free to preach as he wishes.
Tahir was held here, in
the state security prison at Giza.
He claims that, like thousands of
others, he was routinely tortured.
Tahir comes from a religious family
of teachers and scholars, Salafis,
inspired by the Saudi Arabian model
of Islam.
For Tahir, his family and friends,
the Mubarak regime had sold out
to the west.
They were all imprisoned
for their beliefs.
The fall of Mubarak after 30 years
has unsettled the whole country.
The head of the new military
council, General Tantawi,
appeals for order.
Gigi's father owns a clothing
factory on the outskirts of Cairo.
Since the revolution, his workers,
like many all over Egypt,
are demanding more rights
and better pay.
He can't even visit his own factory.
I don't go to the factory
because, if I go,
maybe 80%, 70% will strike.
If the workers stop working,
it's a disaster.
Everyone thinks the new revolution,
that means, I'm getting a salary now
1,000, I'll get 5,000.
This is what you call freedom!
Gigi went to my factory and
she turned the people against me.
My workers, turning against me
because of Gigi. They tell me,
"Ask your daughter!"
I think she's a Communist.
Gigi and her comrades
are using social networking
to agitate across the country
and organise strikes.
This is how exactly I would have
expected our revolution to go.
There is a striking school
at least in every governance,
doctors are also striking.
The fall of Mubarak
is just the beginning.
Gigi wants to destroy the old system
that made her father.
This is the disagreement
that I've had with my dad.
It's like, he wanted to engage
in the corrupted system
to make his life and his family's
life better.
Why am I OK with this?
The revolution has done nothing
to help Ahmed.
Even though he has a diploma
in telecommunications,
he is still looking for work.
TRANSLATION: When I go for jobs
that suit my qualifications,
they only take people who bribe them
or who have contacts.
I think it's high time for me
to repay my mother for everything.
As a widow, Awatef put her sons
through college herself.
TRANSLATION: So many times I haven't
eaten so I can feed my kids.
I lay on the bed all night
with a stomach ache so painful
I couldn't sleep.
Mubarak did nothing for his people.
He never felt anything
for the suffering of the people.
There are so many
much poorer than me.
Despite his diploma,
the only work Ahmed has been offered
is in a clothing factory.
TRANSLATION: He's scared of me
because I was part of the revolution
that toppled the Mubarak regime.
The revolutionaries are
the bravest men in Egypt.
Ahmed decides to rejoin the
revolutionaries on Tahrir Square.
MAN SPEAKS THROUGH MEGAPHONE
For so long driven underground,
politics is now on the streets
all over the country.
Tahir has joined the new
Party of Light, born out of
his conservative Salafi movement.
Under Mubarak the Salafis
operated as a secret charity.
Now they work from district
to district,
openly using donations to win over
possible supporters.
Accompanied by one of his
party leaders, the purpose is
to get noticed.
Tahir relishes the competition
with more established groups
like the Muslim Brotherhood.
MAN LEADS CHANTING WITH LOUDSPEAKER
On the weekend of July 28th,
the Salafis and the
Muslim Brotherhood come together
to put on a show of force
and claim the revolution for Islam.
Ahmed is concerned that
the Islamists have a different
agenda from the revolutionaries.
By chance, he runs into Tahir.
MAN LEADS CROWD
IN SHOUTS OF "ALLAHU AKBAR"
Speakers call on the military to
fulfil their promise of elections
and to try Mubarak.
The next day, Ahmed's mother,
Awatef, sets out to fight.
The Islamists have taken over
the square.
She discovers that women no longer
have a place there.
As she tries to make her way
through, the men object.
Finally she has to meet Ahmed
on the edge of the square,
but her problems are not over.
SHE SPEAKS ARABIC
TRANSLATION: "Why are you sitting on
the ground? You look like beggars."
I was upset when he humiliated me.
They were like Iranians,
not Egyptians.
To be honest, I don't know anything
about Iran, but I hear they're evil.
They don't act like normal people.
I don't like it.
MUEZZIN CALLS
If they come to power, will they let
women work?
Will they give me handouts
so I can sit at home,
or are they going to
make mincemeat of me for working?
Within days of the demonstration,
the military high command
fulfil one promise.
They deliver Hosni Mubarak,
their former commander in chief,
for trial -
the man who for 30 years had
been seen as crucial for maintaining
peace in the Middle East.
He is accused of ordering
the killing of the protesters
in January.
THEY CHANT
Tahir watches the trial
with his mother and brother-in-law,
along with the whole nation.
Watching this makes me remember
all the chants, all the chants.
"We will put you in the cage
when the revolution will come."
It's like all of our hard work
are finally paying off.
SHE SPEAKS ARABIC
It's good.
No, this is too fattening.
Back at her sister's,
Gigi finds that even her aunt
has changed her tune.
Success!
At the same as putting Mubarak
on trial, the military
clear Tahrir Square of protesters
and clamp down
on any form of dissent.
Over 12,000 civilians have been
tried in military courts.
Gigi has been briefly detained
by the military for filming
at a strike.
As soon as she's released,
she's back in front of
the military courts,
tweeting to her
30,000 followers.
He was yelling and he was just like,
"I'm gonna kill you," and I'm
like... I'm looking at him
and I'm just like, "I wanna know
why am I arrested, I need
a lawyer, don't touch my stuff."
If you show them that you are weak
or afraid, they really crack on you,
so I knew that I have
to hold it together.
Filming on her phone, she and
a friend confront an army officer.
Back home, Gigi's father is worried
for his daughter.
Here is a good one.
You don't know the bad side
of the country.
You don't know the ugly face
of the army... Luckily... ..and
the ugly face of the government.
She want it...quick.
This is the youth people.
The youth, they are always...hurry.
They are always... They want it fast.
This democratic, it take time.
You have to teach the people
how to think.
He now wants the army
to remain in power.
Something is going on,
we don't understand it really.
It's not clear yet to everybody.
But... It's the army trying to stay
in power. Well...and the army
HAVE to stay in power.
Because we don't know the democracy.
This is the first to time
to feel free, to feel this...
SHE SPEAKS ARABIC
"Freedom"!
Politically we just...arghh!..
completely disagree on everything.
I mean, you've heard... It's...
It's very difficult to talk about
it with him,
cos it's very personal to me,
and it's my dad...
'If I look at him in a political way
it will be very, very conflicting,
'to the point that I would
have to choose,
'and I never want to put myself
in this position.
'If at some point I have to
choose...like...I might just not
choose my dad.'
On September 26th,
the military council
finally announce parliamentary
elections for the end of the year.
All the polls point to a win
for the Muslim Brotherhood, who have
a presence all over the country.
For Tahir's Salafi party, the
campaign is an opportunity to spread
their more conservative message.
He is proud of their new
election posters.
The Salafi election advert confronts
popular fears of their extremism.
The message has a strong appeal
in the conservative countryside.
Tahir travels out of Cairo
to secure the support of
an old friend and village mayor,
Muhammed Abdul Sumed.
Tahir invites his friend to
his wedding at the end of the year.
I wait number four!
Muhammed has been in power
for as long as Mubarak.
This, to Tahir, is Salafi Egypt.
October 6th is Army Day,
Egypt's annual holiday,
which this year would dissolve
into violence that threatened
to derail the elections.
As usual, the holiday
begins with celebrations
of the army's victory
over Israel in 1973.
TRANSLATION: I pray that I can
join the army.
Maybe there are people
waiting for someone to say no,
and we can all say no together.
# Get in, just get in
# Check out the trouble
we're in... #
HARD ROCK PLAYS
The holiday gives Gigi the chance
of a weekend on the Red Sea.
Ohhh! Look at that!
Oh, it's so beautiful.
Maybe, maybe, maybe, off record, the
Salafi guys and all his family won't
be happy seeing this part of Gigi!
That's never gonna happen,
they're never gonna ban the bikini.
This is like...suppression of...
you know...freedom of expression!
INTERVIEWER:
If the Salafis get power,
would you regret the revolution?
It's not going to happen.
I really, really, really believe
that it will never happen in Egypt.
We will never be another Iran, where
there is an Islamic government,
or the Salafis would get in power
or the Muslim Brotherhood
would get in power,
because...
it just does not work in Egypt.
Back in Cairo, a protest by
the Christian minority
against discrimination
is broken up by soldiers
guarding the state TV station.
It turns into the most
serious violence
since the January revolution.
The authorities clamp down
on reporting.
Independent TV stations are
broadcasting live clashes between
the demonstrators and the army
when soldiers appear in the studio
to take them off air.
State television appeals
to the Muslim majority,
accusing the Christians of setting
out to destabilise the country.
Friends call Ahmed to come down
to the demonstration.
Using his own camera, he decides
to take on the role of reporter.
Gigi is stranded at the beach.
She is told the army
and Islamic groups are forming
an alliance to crush protest.
Something seems to happen and people
are chanting, "Islam and the army
are one hand."
From Democracy Now -
"Egyptian state TV is completely
distorting tonight's events,
"airing interviews of soldiers
saying the Christians began
by beating and shooting them."
27 protesters die.
The authorities accuse
"invisible hands" for the deaths -
until footage appears online
showing army vehicles
running over protestors.
The dead are brought to the morgue
of the local hospital.
Among them is one of
Ahmed's fellow fighters
from the January revolution.
Another of his friends is injured.
They both feel the army
has betrayed them.
CROWD CHANTS
The military continue to blame the
protesters for the violence that is
putting the elections at risk.
BOY RECITES VERSES
At his weekly Qu'ran class,
Tahir is clear who is at fault.
The demonstrators are now
labelled as enemies.
When Ahmed returns to the barbers,
his friend Imad from the Muslim
Brotherhood openly challenges him.
ALL: Salaam.
Find people, prepare the place,
get the car,
get my suit, get her dress,
get the...
Tahir has both an election
and a wedding to organise.
Where are you?
So many ambulances are going to
just pick up the injured...
injures from Tahrir Square.
God be with us.
SIREN IN DISTANCE
OK. Who else? Ah, Wael,
my cousin Wael.
For Tahir, the violence is now a
conspiracy to subvert the elections.
With a week to the elections,
downtown Cairo is a battleground.
The revolutionaries, who had
inspired the January uprising,
now see the military council
as a brutal continuation
of the Mubarak regime.
They want justice for those killed.
Just a few streets away,
campaigning continues -
the Muslim Brotherhood
and the Salafis are determined
that the elections go ahead.
So is the military council.
On 28th November, Egypt's first
ever democratic elections are held.
CAMPAIGN SLOGANS THROUGH SPEAKER
For so many, this is the triumph
of the revolution.
Just a year ago, Tahir was living
under constant threat
of imprisonment
for his religious activities.
He voted!
Now he is confident that the
elections will bring real change.
You are not going to get down to
the street and find alcohol market.
You are not going to find that,
in Sha'allah.
The government is not
going to support that any more.
Gigi spends the day filming and
tweeting as an unofficial monitor.
She refuses to vote,
because of the violence
and the continued detention
of her fellow protesters.
Of course what we are
living under right now
is much worse than Mubarak days,
but that doesn't mean that we want
Mubarak days to be back.
No, this means that we're
that much closer to freedom.
If Egypt become a Muslim state,
Gigi might leave or she will fight
and she will go to jail.
She doesn't understand yet.
She still thinks she can change,
she can do more.
Even if she lose her life.
This is... For a father,
this is very scary for me.
This is the revolution.
Freedom doesn't come easily.
We have to pay in sacrifices
of blood, arrest, injures
for us to win this battle
and at the end win this war.
Ahmed is back on the square,
with no intention of voting.
When the election results
are announced,
as expected the Muslim Brotherhood
end up as the biggest party.
Tahir's wedding turns into
a double celebration.
His Salafi party have taken
almost a quarter of the vote.
I feel like I am flying in the sky.
His father wants an end to chaos.
Tahir's plans for an Islamic Egypt
are a step closer
and if the military attempt
to stand in the way
the Salafis
and the Muslim Brotherhood now have
the strength to challenge them.
WOMEN ULULATE
For the Islamic parties, Egypt's
revolution has for the first time
brought the chance of real power.
But for many of those who went
to Tahrir Square last January
to overthrow a dictatorship,
the new Egypt has yet to be born.
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
E-mail subtitling@bbc.co.uk