Who's that?
I'm not expecting visitors.
It's the sad clown!
I painted his face!
- Damn them.
- Not again!
- What do we do?
- The dress routine, okay?
Hey, blue face!
- Okay, show's over!
- If you can carry a weapon,
get into the trucks!
You've been recruited
into the 11th Division
of the Republican Army commanded
by Col. Enrique Lister!
Hey, can't you see we're working here?
The place is full of children.
Goddammit!
- Take it easy.
- Easy?
When he just barges in here
as if he runs the place?
Actually,
I do run this place.
And you, clown,
are coming with us.
If you're not with us,
you're with the rebels!
Are you
with the rebels, clown?
I'm not with anyone.
I'm working.
Listen to him. Always joking!
Tell him you're joking.
Joking? I tell you, this fucking war's
a joke! A bad one!
- Jesus, Manuel! Apologize.
Why should
I apologize to anyone?
Especially this ridiculous asshole,
hiding behind his gun...
I like your friend.
He's got balls.
But balls alone
don't win wars!
You need discipline,
dammit!
Right, then.
To hell with it.
If you're up for it, follow me.
Let's get going!
- What about the animals?
I want to go
with you!
Wait for me
at Aunt Angeline's house.
Soldier:
Hurry, hurry!
THE LAST CIRCUS
Open Up!
Jesus wept!
Hats off!
Oh, God.
- What's this?
- Can't you see it's a woman?
- But, the beard...
Christ!
On your way, lady.
- Right...
- Here they come!
- Hurry up, they're here!
- Okay, damn it!
Right.
Here's the plan.
We open that door and kill the people
on the other side.
Otherwise, they'll kill us.
Simple as that.
- With this?
- What?
Think it's a toy,
do you?
No, but...
You, clown,
give him your rifle.
When those fascist bastards
are eating your guts,
you'll be eating your words,
you useless prick!
Hand-to-hand combat
is the key to survival.
- Any objections, clown?
- No.
Okay, good man.
- I like you.
- Just one question.
- What?
- Can I change clothes?
No.
A clown
with a machete...
You'll scare
the shit out of them.
Let's go! Show 'em what
you're made of!
Bastards!
Let's get 'em!
Holy shit!
C'mon, clown!
Motherfuckers!
I can't see anything.
Am I wounded?
Man:
Attention!
Salute!
Man:
At ease!
Stop.
Leave him.
So this is what wiped out
my whole regiment?
Very funny.
Now the real fun begins.
Ready!
Load!
Aim!
- - Fire!
Off limits, kid.
Go back to your parents.
I can't find my dad.
Listen, kid...
You'd best go home.
I want to see my dad.
How do you know
he's a prisoner?
He didn't do anything.
He worked in the circus.
- You're the clown's kid?
- Will he be shot?
Long live
the Republic!
the circus!
Dad!
I told you to go
to Aunt Angeline's house.
I want to be with you.
Listen.
There's nothing
to worry about.
I doubt they'll kill me.
We're being kept prisoner.
Honest?
They need labor.
Workers.
It's okay.
A month from now,
we'll be together,
eating a nice
Sunday roast.
- You'll see.
Come on, time's up.
THE WAR IS OVER!
LONG LIVE SPAIN!
Dad.
You look awful.
That's funny.
They treat us like royalty
Don't say that.
My poor son.
Life's been cruel
to you.
You never knew
your mother,
your dad's going
to die in jail.
One day you'll be free.
You're here for a reason, you said.
So they say.
We're going to build a cross.
A huge cross.
It can't be worse
than this.
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
Why do you ask?
A clown?
Of course. Like you,
Granddad, everyone.
A funny clown?
Yeah.
To make kids laugh.
No.
You should be
a sad clown.
Why?
Because you've
suffered too much.
Son, you'll never be funny.
You were never a kid.
Since childhood,
you've faced death.
Your lot is
to be the sad clown,
with bushy eyebrows
and a little saxophone.
The funny clown's sidekick,
who laughs at his jokes.
If I can't make people laugh,
no one will ever love me.
Don't say that.
Wait.
There's a way
to be happy,
to thwart your fate.
How? What can I do?
Revenge.
Ease your pain
with revenge.
Revenge!
Man:
Come on, dammit!
What are you doing?
Watch out!
Man:
Run for it!
- Run!
Dad!
You little son
of a bitch!
- Colonel, your eye...
Shut up.
INAUGURATION OF
THE VALLEY OF THE FALLEN
Man: Franco inaugurates the temple
on the 20th anniversary of the victory...
25 YEARS OF PEA CE
Man #2:
Our fellow countryman, Angel Cristo,
is regarded as one of the best
lion tamers in the world.
Have you seen them?
Pompoff
and Teddy's cousins.
They're great.
And no make-up.
Each to his own style.
Pass me a hairpin.
Look.
One, two, three.
Slick, eh?
Been in the job long?
No. My dad
and granddad were clowns,
- but it's my first time.
- Got to start somewhere.
- Do you make kids laugh?
- No.
No?
No.
Too bad.
Well, not every gag
has to be a side-splitter.
- Maybe your humor's more intellectual.
- No, it's not that.
I'm a sad clown.
I'm not funny.
You're right.
- Then you're doing just fine.
- You think so?
Sad? You couldn't
look any sadder.
- David, the trapeze artist.
- Hi.
- Manolo, the strong man.
- Welcome.
- Our zebra. Well, painted donkey...
Tightrope walkers
and my animals.
The circus boys. We can have a drink
here later... when we get paid.
- Man: Ramiro!
-
How do I look?
Fantastic!
The Ghost Biker.
They changed his bike.
You sure?
It's not too flashy?
Ghosts are supposed to be flashy.
Have you tried the turbo?
It needs adjusting.
Is that the new guy?
Hi! Javier.
What do you do?
Sad clown!
See? He gets
a snazzy outfit.
Why won't they
let me wear sequins?
Because you're a tough guy!
You're the Ghost Biker!
You wear leather!
Like Marlon Brando
and Charlton Heston!
- Charlton Heston wore leather?
- Woman: Puri, come here!
- Have you fed them?
- They're your dogs.
- Mine?
- I wanted a seal.
- We can't afford seals.
- One would have been enough.
Ignore him,
he's a pain.
- A seal and a ball.
- You haven't got any balls either.
Don't mind him.
- Always barking.
- Who, me?
No, the dogs.
And they sleep with us.
Do you have to tell him
our life story?
It's true.
They sleep in our bed.
That's not normal.
- Come here.
- Let's go.
The turbo,
it needs adjusting!
Have you met
my elephant?
I haven't had time,
I was getting ready...
This is Princess.
She's a sweetie.
She gets jealous
if she sees me with women.
And your outfit...
She must have thought...
Beautiful,
isn't she?
Hey... Careful,
she belongs to someone else.
Your boss,
no less.
Man: Damn, I'm sick
of fucking midgets!
Their bowed legs,
oversized heads, Jesus!
- Every circus has midgets.
- Mine doesn't.
Man #2:
This isn't your circus. It's mine.
Are you sure?
Sergio... You've no right
to talk to me like this.
Fire me.
What are you waiting for?
We'll talk later.
Whenever.
And then we'll settle things
I've told him
a million times.
This circus
doesn't need midgets.
He never listens.
What do you want?
I'd like you
to meet Javier.
He's our new sad clown,
starts tomorrow.
- You into kids?
- Excuse me?
I don't mean
kiddie porn.
Do you like working
with them?
Are you patient, kind?
- I'll do what you tell me.
- Not good enough!
Kids need care
and understanding.
You have to
become one.
He's like
a little boy.
Aren't you? Look at him.
With his chubby cheeks.
So, tell me.
Why do you want
to be a clown?
Think.
Spit it out!
What did I ask you?
Why do you want to be a clown?
You must have
a reason.
People don't just
become clowns.
Let's see.
Because life scares you?
Your parents were clowns?
You like being humiliated?
What about you?
Because if I weren't a clown,
I'd be a murderer.
Me too.
You're all we've got.
You start tomorrow.
- Welcome to the circus, kid.
You invited him?
Yeah, he doesn't
know anyone...
- The dogs love him.
- They want to hump him.
Reminds me of the joke about the father
in the maternity ward.
- Heard it?
- No.
- It's hilarious.
- Shut it.
The father goes in,
there are babies everywhere,
he's looking for his.
The nurse points to one.
He starts crying with joy.
"My baby..."
The nurse wraps it up in a
little sheet
and shows it to him.
"Oh, my baby, he's so cute..."
And the nurse goes...
Right in the dad's face.
"Oh my God!
What have you done?
You killed my baby!
You killed him!"
And the nurse says,
"No, I didn't.
It was born dead."
"it was born dead!"
Hilarious!
Sergio:
Good one, eh?
"It was born dead!"
So who gives a shit?
- Don't you think it's funny?
I don't get it.
Where was the mother?
What mother?
The mother.
Who said
there's a mother?
Shouldn't there be
a mother?
The father's
there but...
He spoiled
my appetite, dammit.
Don't bring assholes
to dinner.
They eat
on their own.
- Don't get upset.
- I will if I want.
- You've had a lot to drink...
- I'll drink what the fuck I want!
- Ramiro: Sergio...
- Shut up!
- Sweetie, don't start...
- Don't start?
I'll start if I want.
- It was a sick joke!
- Really?
-- Think so? Sick? You didn't like it?
- Well I think it's funny!
And I decide what's funny
around here. I'm the clown!
The kids come
to see me!
I'm your meal ticket,
assholes! Me!
I decide
what's funny around here!
- Goddammit!
Fuck!
We were having
a nice time.
Right, Andrés?
Ramiro?
We were talking.
Right, Sonsoles?
In harmony,
relaxed...
Having a conversation...
And it all gets fucked up
because some idiot
doesn't get the joke.
There's no mother,
you got that?
Anyone for dessert,
or straight to coffee?
- What's for dessert?
- Fruit salad,
rice pudding,
homemade flan
- ...and whisky ice cream.
- Rice pudding.
- Black coffee.
- Coffee with milk,
- not too strong.
- Coffee with milk.
I'd like your special homemade flan
with whipped cream
and a coffee
with milk,
not too strong,
with sweetener.
And you?
Coffee with milk, please.
Hey, Ramiro...
What does a pessimist do
when opportunity knocks?
- I have no idea.
- Complain about the noise.
- Complain about the noise!
Hey, I've got
a great one.
An Englishman, a Frenchman
and a Spaniard...
That's ancient.
This one is
different.
Natalia,
are you okay?
I'm fine. Don't worry.
- Is he always like that?
- Only when he drinks.
Is that often?
Every night.
sol"'Y-
I gotta go
or he'll be really mad.
Who are you?
The sad clown.
I start tomorrow.
- What's your name?
- Javier.
You're in for it.
You think so?
Know what happened
to the last sad clown?
No.
You don't want to.
- Natalia, what are you doing?
- I'm cleaning up!
Always keeping me
waiting...
Can you forgive me?
I'm sorry, my love.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry.
You like that, eh?
Want me to screw you
senseless, eh? Do you?
Ah!
Stop hitting her...
Don't hurt her...
- Boss, listen...
- What's your problem?
We haven't rehearsed.
- No rehearsal, no jump.
- Don't exaggerate.
The new turbo isn't adjusted
for my weight.
- And the ramp...
- Come on, come on.
You'll be great!
How's the new guy?
So far, so good. The kids laugh
when he gets hit with the piano.
Success!
A bit green,
but he'll do.
He looks serious, scared of me.
I like that.
The kids laugh.
A hit!
A real hit!
Congratulations. Keep it up
and I'll pay you double.
Time to announce
this guy.
- I'm not going on.
- Owner: Shut up and get in there.
- How was I?
- Spectacular.
The way you stared him down
while he threw pies at you.
And as you talked to the kids
and he set fire to your butt...
You didn't even flinch.
That studied passivity
reminds me
of Buster Keaton! Really!
- Was Natalia watching?
- Of course.
You were wonderful.
Take me to dinner in Madrid later
and we can talk.
- About what?
- Just to get to know each other.
Sounds nice, but maybe
it's not a good idea...
- He'll be there. Eight o'clock?
- Perfect. Eight o'clock.
Eight o'clock,
don't forget.
-
House of Horror
Look, what did
I tell you?
- What a place!
Look at their faces.
- Javier: This is Blue Beard.
- His beard isn't blue.
You're right, his beard...
isn't blue.
Natalia, you have
to leave him.
- You know the story?
- What story?
Blue Beard had
many wives.
He gave them each
a bunch of keys
and told them,
"Go wherever you like,
but this little key
opens a door
that I don't want you
to open."
Right.
So you're saying...
...you opened the door.
Yes.
And I love
what's inside.
- You're not like other men I know.
- No?
You don't want
to take advantage of me.
Of course not.
You're too scared
to even touch me!
It's late.
We'd better get going.
- Come on.
We shouldn't be seen
arriving together.
I was about to say the same thing.
For your sake...
Anyway...
ciao.
See you.
- Sergio: She's cheating on me.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- What? You think I'm making it up?
I'll look for her.
If she's not home, I'll kill her.
Sergio, wait until morning.
She's probably asleep.
You know something.
- Something's going on.
- I don't know anything.
If you hold out on me,
I'll cut your balls off.
Don't, Sergio.
We've had too much to drink.
Call her in the morning
with a clear head.
- What are you doing?
- Shh!
What's going on?
This is wrong.
- Are you scared?
- Yes.
Fear spices things up.
You're like a kid.
I was never a kid.
I don't understand.
Who's Blue Beard?
- That's not the point.
- But you were in her trailer?
- Yeah, well...
- So what's the problem?
She's toying with me.
She just wants to be friends.
Wake up, sunshine.
If a woman invites you to be her friend,
you'll never screw her.
Sure, like you're
an expert.
I was married, Javier.
- She left you?
- No.
Princess killed her.
She sat on her,
and crushed her to death.
Right.
I told you she hates seeing me
with other women.
Listen, kid.
Let me tell you:
you're doing great.
- You think?
- Yeah, you're very good.
You can tell
it's in your blood.
- Fixed the turbo?
- Yeah, don't be a pain.
- You sure? If it happens again...
- Come on.
- My father...
- I met him once when I was a kid.
- He was great.
- Yeah.
- Remember the door routine?
- Of course.
Were you with my girl
last night?
What?
When I got home,
she wasn't in bed.
I heard you went out with her.
Maybe you know where she was.
I didn't see her.
No. I didn't see her.
I don't know
where she was.
I was doing things...
I might have run into her,
I don't remember...
Javier.
That's your name, right?
- Yeah.
- Look.
Natalia means
everything to me.
I'd do anything for her.
Anything, Javier.
Javier.
- Listen.
Sometimes I drink too much
and lose control.
But I'm not
a bad person, Javier.
I love Natalia deeply.
True love.
- True love.
- True love, Javier.
You're on.
Let's go.
What a team!
Now it's elephant time.
What do elephants do?
He's different
when things are going well.
You mean
he beats you less.
Don't say that.
I love him
too much sometimes.
You can
say that again.
Any other girl
would run away from that.
Look, Natalia.
It's not normal.
Have you never
felt trapped by a love
you know might kill you,
but you still
can't help yourself?
Yes, every day.
This circus will be
the end of me.
See?
We're two of a kind.
If I hadn't met him...
- If he disappeared...
Don't even joke about that.
We'd be sunk without him.
He's the best clown
I've had in years.
Look at him.
The kids adore him.
Sergio:
Who wants to ride with me?
We're a hit!
We'll be in the paper!
We're staying an extra week.
Good work!
- Can he have a ride?
- Of course, ma'am.
And now the sad clown will
hop on with this baby
for a ride on the elephant!
Let's hear it for the sad clown!
- Hurry up, asshole.
- It's too far.
A big hand
for the sad clown!
Pass him over.
- It's too far.
- Come on.
The sad clown's got cold feet!
Pass me the kid.
The elephant's moved away.
The sad clown is scared!
- Javier: I can't reach.
- Sergio: Come on!
I can't reach.
She needs to come closer.
Do it, asshole!
- Throw me that kid!
I'm really sorry, ma'am.
I'm sorry, love.
If a child gets hurt, I'll kill you.
You got that?
Children are
our livelihood.
You Okay?
Better.
Panic's over.
- Will you take me to the fun fair?
- Where?
Ferris wheel, carousel,
cotton candy...
Paris...
We can dine out, have fun,
like the other day.
Are you crazy?
What about Sergio?
Sergio got drunk, went to bed at five.
He won't be up until morning.
- You sure?
- Not entirely.
He could wake up,
come looking for us,
find us...
and kill us both!
- You have to take risks in life.
- Yeah, but...
There are risks
and there are risks...
My baby's scared!
Why are you doing this?
Why me?
Am I a joke to you?
No.
$0?
I don't know.
With you it's different.
I feel safe.
Javier: Thanks.
- Hey, listen...
- What?
I know for you this is like a day out
with your nephew,
but I want you to know
these things really affect me.
What do you mean?
That I could end up
loving you.
Loving me?
How much?
A lot.
More than a lot.
Don't! I'd rather never see you again
than be treated like this.
Don't you see?
You're the only one
who stood up to him.
You didn't laugh
at his jokes.
That's what
I call a real man.
-Oh!
Cock of the roost, eh?
Full of yourself.
Sergio, it's my fault.
I made him come...
- No, Sergio!
No, Sergio!
Let her go!
Don't worry.
Be patient. I'll be back for you
when I've left her in the car.
I won't
let you take her.
Man, this is good.
We can use it in our act.
You stand up to me
and I beat the shit out of you.
You say you love her,
but one day you'll kill her.
What do you know
about love?
Lie there.
I want a prize.
Man:
Stop it!
My Prize!
Stop! You'll kill him!
You'll kill him!
- I want my prize!
- Stop! Police!
Let me go!
The bell rang!
I want my prize!
I want
my teddy bear!
I want my prize!
Let me go! The bell rang!
Man over TV:
Yesterday, in the High Court,
the hearing began in the case against
Eleuterio "El Lute " Sanchez Rodriguez...
- ...and his brothers Manuel and Raimundo,
alias "Lolo" and "Toto",
charged with breaking parole,
robbery, assault,
homicide, fraud,
illegal arms possession,
kidnapping and terrorism.
The prosecution is asking
for a sentence totaling 3,291 years.
Are you related
to Javier Granados?
His girlfriend?
- No, co-worker.
- We've stabilized him.
He has internal bleeding
and several broken ribs.
- He's just come 'round.
- Can I see him?
- Just for five minutes. He's very weak.
- Man: Don't go, gorgeous.
- Nurse: Be quiet.
Dad?
No. It's Natalia.
- The circus acrobat.
- Natalia.
I was dreaming
about my father.
He wanted to tell me something.
But I can't remember.
I'm sorry, Javier.
I shouldn't have gone out with you,
or even spoken to you.
When he gets back,
I have to be there to calm him down.
Calm him down?
You're going back to him?
Javier, I'm scared.
If I'm not there
and he finds you...
So it's for my sake?
Get some rest.
Answer me, Natalia!
Are you doing it
for my sake?
The doctor said
you're weak.
I'll kill him!
Really?
For my sake or yours?
Are you crazy?
He almost killed you,
don't you see?
It's over, Javier.
We can't see
each other again.
The police have
released him by now.
He's not like you.
He's an animal.
An animal...
Remember
your father, son!
- Man: Where are you going?
I can see your ass!
Andrés:
What are you doing here?
Are you crazy?
Where are you going?
- Sonsoles: He lives here.
- Andrés: You don't understand.
Look at him,
for God's sake.
Where is she?
She's here with him!
Andrés:
You need to get as far away as you can.
We'll pay
your bus fare. Whatever.
Sonsoles: Leave him alone.
He knows what he's doing.
- Really?
- You're a coward.
Me, a coward?
Bullshit!
Javier, don't do it.
- Get off!
- Forget her! You can't stop it!
- Out of my way!
Don't worry
about him any more.
What's wrong?
You're free.
I freed you from the monster.
- Where are you going?
- What have you done?
- Goddammit!
We have to call
the police.
He's alive.
But not for long.
Stop! Police!
- What's this?
- Ramiro: He's badly hurt.
Who? Do you know
what time it is?!
It's those circus people.
I only treat dogs
and farm animals.
I know nothing
about elephants.
What?! For God's sake!
Don't you see?
We must act fast
or he'll die.
My God!
What happened?
Was he mauled
by a tiger?
Woman:
His face is badly disfigured!
The man needs
a hospital!
There's no time.
He's losing too much blood.
Don't get involved.
It could ruin you.
Do what you can.
I'm begging you.
What if he doesn't make it?
What if he dies here?
Vet:
I could...
stitch and cauterize his wounds,
but I can't make any promises.
- I don't have the right equipment here.
- Woman: This is madness.
We shouldn't attend to people at night,
or even open the door!
I'm telling you,
send them away!
I have a nose
for these things!
Shut up, woman!
Let me think.
I don't know, really...
I don't want to be
held liable for this.
Natalia.
It's up to you.
Is he your husband?
No... I'm... I'm...
- Do you assume liability?
- Yes.
Do what you can.
Whatever it takes.
Boil some water, bring me the chloroform
and get everything ready.
Get what ready?
We're only equipped
for delivering piglets!
What are you doing?
Tuck the teeth inside...
- This is madness!
- Shut up!
You're crazy.
You'll go to hell, all of you!
And you...
You'll be the first.
This is all your fault!
You don't fool me, cutie.
- Believe me.
- It's not done like this.
Pull it tighter...
- Shut up, dammit!
- Natalia!
Natalia!
Where are you going?
Monster! Monster!
Monster!
That can't be me.
It can't be!
Once again, Eleuterio Sanchez,
Spain's most wanted criminal,
has given the police the slip.
After his arrest in Seville,
"el Lute " was taken to
the prison hospital in Madrid
where he was treated
for multiple injuries.
It's over.
No news from Javier.
Nothing from Sergio.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
The tour's been canceled.
I can't pay the bills.
I have to close down.
Waiter!
An espresso, please.
- Waiter: Hot milk or cold?
- Owner: Warm.
We'll just have to do
something else.
Any ideas?
No.
Why don't you sell
the animals?
They're not mine.
I've got nothing.
Just debts.
Then... we'll just have
to make beds or scrub floors.
Don't worry, woman.
I'm sure we'll come up
with something better.
I don't believe it!
He looks like an animal.
Eh, Colonel?
Put him
in the Land Rover.
In you go!
Come on, move it!
We got lucky today,
Anselmo.
We bagged
a unique specimen.
The biggest boar
in the whole area, Colonel.
Take them
to the stables.
- Both of them, Colonel?
- Both of them.
Hello?
Enrique!
How are you?
No, impossible.
You can't come.
Tomorrow's the hunt.
I've a lot to prepare.
I got a call from Franco's residence.
He wants to be alone, to relax.
Bye, Enrique.
Colonel, what do
I do with that man?
Leave him for now.
Put him to work tomorrow.
He's weird.
He doesn't speak.
Maybe he doesn't
know how.
He knows all right.
Off you go.
General.
My dear Salcedo,
so good to see you again!
Everything is
ready for the hunt.
The sooner I smell
gunpowder, the better.
After you, General.
- Come on!
Get to work,
like everyone else!
Get a move on, dammit!
What did I tell you?
What did
I tell you, eh?
The bird
in your mouth!
- Come on!
Good boy.
What on earth
are you doing?
What's the poor man done
to be treated that way?
A long time ago,
he made a fool out of me.
He likes to joke around.
It runs in his family.
Nobody deserves that.
It's not Christian, Salcedo.
We've been friends for years,
but there are things about you I don't like.
-- Right...
Seems I hit
the mark this time!
Don't tolerate this, lad.
You shouldn't put up
with such humiliation.
Get up now.
Call a doctor!
Take him away!
You're the best thing
in my life
Even if I never tell you
If you're away, I'm sad
I miss you at night,
I miss you during the day
My heart is happy
And full of joy
Ever since
you entered my world
And I thank life
And pray to God
you'll always be with me
I want you to know
I never loved like this
That my life began
- When I met you...
Come on. Move it!
I was wondering...
- Get inside!
You bit Franco.
I could get
to like you after all.
Shame you're
to be shot.
Get some rest.
Salcedo wants to do it himself.
You lucky devil!
The Day of Wrath is here.
You will be my Angel of Death.
Save me from Evil and fulfill
your destiny, my beloved.
A gunshot wound.
It was an accident.
We can't say
a lunatic bit him.
Like any other vermin,
he'll be put down.
And that's that.
- Not until the Generalissimo
has left the castle.
Now's a bad time, Salcedo.
And you know it.
Sodium hydroxide
Anselmo:
Weirdo! Weirdo! Weirdo!
Hey, weirdo, it's time.
What are you dressed up as?
A priest or a lady?
If the colonel sees you
dressed like that, he'll have a fit.
I don't know where you came from,
but, I must admit, I didn't expect this.
You're off your fuckin' rocker!
What did you do to your face?
- Ciao.
- Adios.
Man:
Hey, blondie, where's the fire?
Stay with us,
gorgeous.
Sergio:
Who are you running from?
- I'll never forgive myself.
- Man: Alright...
- But the press mustn't get hold of this.
I thought
we controlled the press.
We're losing
international support,
the opposition is
getting organized.
Our contact in the north
has warned us
of a plot to assassinate
Admiral Carrero Blanco.
We know there's
a terrorist cell in Madrid.
Don't believe
everything you hear.
What the hell is that?
Damned bastard!
You haven't got the balls!
Shoot me,
son of a bitch!
- Life goes on, like the song says?
- Where's your boyfriend?
- I don't know what you're saying.
A better lay than me, is he?
Hung like a horse?
- Leave me alone!
- Of course! Sorry.
How vulgar of me!
You two don't fuck.
You read books.
Does he read you
bedtime stories?
Natalia, help me.
It hurts, Natalia.
Please, help me.
Help me, Natalia!
Five omelet sandwiches,
two Cokes
and three orange Fantas.
I want lemon!
Two Cokes, two orange Fantas
and a lemon Fanta.
I don't want omelet,
I want chorizo!
One chorizo,
four omelet,
two orange Fantas
and a lemon Fanta.
What about the Cokes?
Don't order me anything.
Just a glass of water.
- Didn't you say you were hungry?
- Not any more.
- I need to pee.
- Then go pee!
A friend in need, is a friend indeed
Ballad of the sad trumpet
For a past that died...
Ow!
- Who's Raphael?
- A great singer and a great person.
Boy:
Daddy, he looks like a woman.
He's not a woman,
he's a clown.
Clowns make
children laugh.
That's what you want,
isn't it? To make us laugh?
You don't scare me.
- We forgot Miki!
All the weeping
of the trumpet
Filled my heart
with despair
- What are you doing?
- Escaping. He's after me.
You have work here.
We need to call the police.
And get him arrested,
like Javier?
Make up your mind.
You say he wants to kill you.
- Why are you bringing up Javier?
- He did all this to save me.
- Are you in love with him too?
- He was nice to her.
Who asked your opinion?
I need someone who makes me laugh,
who protects me...
And who fucks you senseless,
makes you come, talks dirty?
You can't have
your cake and eat it too.
What shall I do
with the animals?
Find an open space
and release them.
You're right.
Give them some fresh air.
- Sorry, I've had enough.
- Natalia, wait!
- Where are you going?
- I can't let her go alone!
- Let's call the cops first.
- Andrés!
Damn!
( Gasps )
- Fuck!
- Where is she?
She just left.
The back way.
Sonsoles: Quiet!
Don't tell him anything.
Javier, please,
don't do anything crazy!
- It's me! Take it easy!
What? Don't you
fancy me now?
Jesus!
Get a load of you!
Natalia!
Get out of there!
Where are you off to,
dressed like that?
Look at his face.
Competing with me, eh?
Step away so I can
kill him, Natalia.
Do it.
Go with him.
Natalia, it's me.
What's wrong?
So...
Do you get it now?
It's me she prefers.
No, Natalia, tell me
that's not true, please.
You said
you felt safe with me.
You asked me to save you,
to be your Angel of Death.
You're making
a fool of yourself.
- Idiot, an utter fool.
You're just a crybaby.
A blubbering clown.
POLICE
- Stop!
- Sonsoles: Show some pity.
He's sick. He doesn't know
what he's doing.
Oh, God. Please!
Don't move!
Let him go!
Run, Javier, run!
She loves you, I know it!
She loves you!
Where are you going?
Fucking COPS!
Suck my cock!
But one by one.
Now you can beat the shit
out of me, if you want.
Sonsoles: No, please,
for God's sake, let him go!
No, please,
let him go!
Let my man go.
NIGHTLY NEWS
In the wake
of the "el Lute" affair,
a madman in a clown suit now
has the nation on tenterhooks.
Javier Granados, dubbed by the media
as "The Sad Clown ",
escaped, aided
by fellow circus workers.
He is wanted
for at least three murders
and police are looking for him
all over Madrid.
Until yesterday
I was just a bum
- Today I'm guarding your dreams of love
I love her to death...
You two!
You're to blame!
Why?
Why did she go
with him? Why?
She raises a tower
from here to the sky
She puts wings on me
and helps me climb it
In a hurry, in a hurry
I love her to death
Ballad of the sad trumpet
For a past that died
And weeps
And moans
How it weeps...
Javier, listen.
That slut's not for you.
Forget her.
You're a good man.
Give yourself up.
You can't go around
shooting people.
Don't listen
to him, son.
Go after her and kill that bastard.
He doesn't deserve her.
She doesn't love me.
I'm not funny.
Humor is
for the weak.
If they don't laugh,
scare them shitless!
You'll see it works.
How dare you talk
like that to your own son?
- Kindly get out of my movie.
- Hands off!
Who's this creep, son?
What's he doing in your head?
I like the way
he sings.
Remember who your father is.
Remember your destiny.
There's only one way
to be happy.
Excuse me.
We can't see.
Could you sit down?
- What's with him?
- Never mind. We'll move.
Why should we?
He can sit down like everyone else.
Look at the state of him.
He's not all there.
- So what?
- Be careful!
Hey, I asked you
nicely, okay?
I just want to watch the film
with my girlfriend in peace...
- Sergio: How is everybody?
- Kids: Greeeatl!
I'm told there's a ghost
who's chasing me
but I don't know
where he is.
- On your back!
- Sergio: Where? Where?
On your back!
- Where?
- Behind you!
Where? Where?
- Where's...?
For God's sake!
- Look at his face!
- Get away from my son, you hear?
- Get away!
- Sergio: We're leaving, okay?
Is this the guy
the police are after?
- No, it's not me.
- Call security!
That's someone else,
not me.
Natalia, tell them.
Tell them
it's not me.
Kids don't
love me any more!
Is that all
that bothers you?
It bothers me
that you clammed up!
Why didn't you tell
the truth?
That you all
did this to me.
Forget it, Sergio.
Forget it?
That's enough!
Your clown days are over!
No.
Not that.
It's all I know, Natalia.
Natalia, my love.
I don't know how to do anything else.
Please, Natalia!
ICE CREAM
Who are you?
You don't have
the balls.
What circus
are you from?
DEATH OF CARRERO BLANCO
Man on TV:
A huge crater in the road
and serious damage
to nearby buildings
were the result
of the powerful terrorist bomb
which killed President
Carrero Blanco in Madrid.
Reporter: Let's try to speak
to some of the eyewitnesses.
- Good morning.
- Man #2: I only heard it.
- Reporter: You what?
- Man #2: I just heard it.
- Reporter: Where were you?
- Man #2: In bed.
- Reporter: What did you hear?
- Man #2: A terrible explosion.
Reporter:
What did you think?
Man #2:
That it was a car exhaust
or a welder's gas cylinder...
But from the balcony I saw
people running, a taxi driver...
Look, I'm still in my pajamas.
Reporter:
Where were you?
Man #3: I was on an errand
when I saw an ice-cream van, just there,
driven by a clown
or a priest...
- Reporter: Amazing.
- Man #3: Imagine, a clown right there.
He hopped in the van
and sped off.
OFFICIAL BULLETIN
As Spain mourns the loss
of one of her most loyal
and faithful servants,
I wish to address the nation.
Where are
you going, shorty?
The garage. I'm having the turbo
changed on my bike.
Right, the show
must go on, eh?
Well, yeah.
But most of all, I miss it.
You like flying
on a motorbike, eh?
I don't have a bike,
but the flying
can be arranged.
- I don't know anything!
- Yes, you do.
- It's Ramiro who talks to him!
- So you do know something.
Jesus! Let me go!
I'd rather fall
than see your face.
Yeah, you'd get off on that.
Where did Ramiro take
the animals?
I don't know.
I'm not telling you anything.
He talked to Javier
and they took them to a hideout, right?
Where? An abandoned
warehouse, a basement...?
A cave?
- Who told you?
- You did, just now.
So, a cave, big enough
to house them all, right?
- Tell me!
- I didn't say that.
- It's not a cave.
- Alright, it's not a cave.
But similar,
dug out of stone?
- A cave.
- I didn't say anything.
- Is it a church?
- No, it's not a church!
A church
like a cave...
Dug out of the rock!
Javier:
You're in for a surprise.
Look what
I've got for you!
Get a load
of this! Look!
Shall we dance?
- Where are you going? Come here!
Come here!
Fuck... They left your face
looking like a battlefield.
What's up?
Cat got your tongue?
If this is a hoax,
you'll answer to the authorities.
He's here.
I know it.
- Cops.
- And more cops.
All this ruckus means
Andrés was right.
Puzzles me how the police found out
Javier was hiding here.
- The damn police know everything.
- I just want my motorbike back.
- You and that fucking bike!
- That stupid bike!
Don't you ever think of anyone
but yourself? Bike, bike, bike!
Can't you see those two are going
to kill each other and Natalia's in danger?
It's hard to dance
in these clown shoes.
I'm sorry about all this, Natalia,
but it's not my fault.
I was told to do it.
- By who?
- Well...
He asked me, Raphael,
the singer. Look.
He told me.
Him and my dad.
- I know you don't love me.
- Who told you that? Raphael?
Maybe in time
I'll learn to pretend to be like Sergio.
You're well on your way.
I'm scared of you too now!
Come back!
AMBULANCE
Over here!
We found them.
There are tunnels under the church.
Come on, let's go!
Move it!
Move it! Move it!
What the fuck
is this? A joke?
You're as mad
as the other guy!
Like all of you who just
dick around for a living!
Doing an honest day's work would
stop your bullshit. No messing around!
Lazy fucking bastard!
The Valley
of the Fallen.
Ever been here?
There are 15 caves here,
full of bodies.
One of these has
to be my father.
Some fascists,
others reds.
But they all
ended up here together.
Death unites people.
Javier, stop this.
I'll do whatever you want.
Just one thing. Desire me,
for my body, like you desire him.
Well, well.
- I made her laugh.
- No, Javier.
- I didn't mean to. I'm sorry...
- No!
Don't you dare
do that again!
Don't you dare feel
sorry for me! Never!
I'd rather
you hated me.
I'd like to hate you,
but I can't.
I don't love
Sergio any more.
I was wrong.
I thought I could live
with you, but not like this...
Like what? Crazy?
You drove me crazy,
Natalia!
You're crazy for me?
Is this
a declaration of love?
Yes. Yes, it is.
Yes, it is.
Because I love you, Natalia!
I'm mad about you!
Sergio:
How sweet!
Can I be the best man?
Run for it!
Head for the cross!
Look!
They'll be killed!
- Andrés: It's hopeless.
- Owner: There's nothing we can do.
We'd have to cross
the police cordon.
I can.
I can fly.
Isn't there a single one of us
who isn't completely nuts?
He did have
his turbo replaced.
Six cans
of pure gas oil,
three parts hydrogen
and one part helium.
Like a 747 jet engine.
I can break
the sound barrier!
-( bullets ricocheting )
- What are you doing?
It's the only way
to escape.
Let me.
It's my job, remember?
We're escaping together?
Yes, sweetie.
We're escaping together.
- Man: Follow me, let's go!
- Man #2: Come on! Come on!
Sonsoles:
Get down! Get down!
- Relax. It's a piece of cake.
- This is too much.
It's not us, it's this country
that's gone to the dogs.
It's like a kick in the balls
losing your girl...
Isn't it?
It'll hurt even more
when you hit the ground.
Jump.
- Jump.-
Jump, bastard.
Jump!
I can do it!
Let me get it right
for once,
for fuck's sake!
I can fly, damn it!
I can fly!
- Come down, kid!-
Look! I said look!
Otherwise it isn't funny!
See? In the end, I'm the smart one
and you're the dummy.
Who cares if you're funny
when it's time to die?
You think death
is a joke?
-- Come on, clown! Make me laugh!
Prove you've got
a sense of humor!
I don't want you to be like him.
You have to believe me.
Nobody wants you
to be funny.
You have to
believe me.
I love you,
sad clown.
You, come here.
So what now, eh?
Are you happy?
What should I do to you?
This makes you horny, eh?
This is what
you wanted, right?
Tell me! Tell me!
They're in here!
Pull him up!
- Man: You too.
- Man #2: Take them away.
Come here.
Man: We still don't know
the motive of this murder.
Police have arrested
two suspects.
There are two bodies...
THE LAST CIRCUS