OK. It's Monday morning.
Your name is M.L. Pogue.
Maurice Leonard.
Pogue is fine.
You live in Venice.
That's Venice, California.
You have an office
just off the boardwalk.
You're a small -time gumshoe--
credit reports, insurance scams,
that kind of stuff.
Nothing you'd call...
adventurous.
Right now, you're
on vacation temporarily.
You're unable to take any cases
due to illness.
You have a dog.
He has
a depth perception problem.
But don't worry about the dog.
He can take care of himself.
It's you
that's got the problem, pal--
a problem called
Korsakoff's syndrome.
OK. Are you ready for this?
Whenever you go to sleep,
you lose your memory.
What?
Whenever you go to sleep,
you Lose your memory.
-Shit.
-Now, don't get upset.
You're bound to feel a little
disorientated at first...
but, really, don't panic.
You've got a system.
As long as you talk into
this recorder every night...
everything's going to be fine.
OK. Here's what happened.
Two months ago, you were
injured working on a case.
-There was an explosion.
-Are you my dog?
That's what's causing
this amnesia every night...
so be careful.
There may be complications.
Wait. It gets worse.
You can't tell anyone
about the amnesia.
You're the key witness against
the guy who set the explosion.
If anyone finds out
your memory's gone...
the whole case could collapse.
The best thing you can do
is stay in your apartment.
Don't show your face
around town...
don't talk to strangers...
and above all
don't answer the door.
I repeat--don't talk to anyone.
Just stay in bed.
Shh! They're following me.
They want to kill me.
Who's trying to kill you?
Cornell. The FBI.
I don't know.
What--what are you doing?
I'm calling the police,
as soon as I find the phone.
-No. You can't.
-Why?
-I don't trust them.
-Who?
-I need you.
-I'm not taking any cases.
Thank you.
Well, I can listen.
-You're mad at me.
-No, I'm not.
-You are.
-Really, no.
-You can't lie to me.
-AII right, I'm a Little mad.
Pogue, you've got to believe
I missed you.
I didn't want you to suffer.
Oh, do you believe me?
Yes, I believe you.
Did you think I was dead?
Should I have?
Yes, I--I did think
you were dead.
Will you kiss me?
AII right.
Down!
You want
to run that by me again?
I'm being blackmailed.
-Uh, by who?
-I honesty don't know.
I got a note
telling me to come to L.A.
If I didn't,
they'd tell Cornell where I was.
I'm supposed to phone them
in two days, set up a meeting.
Uh, who, uh, followed you...
-B-Beth?
-You can use my real name.
Good, yeah. I will.
I don't know. I didn't get
a good look at him.
-He was big.
-Big?
By the way, how's Dolby doing?
Dolby?
Oh, he's, uh, great.
Really?
I heard he was shot.
Uh, except for that. Yeah.
And he was dying.
Yeah, yeah, but, uh,
he looks great now...
and he's jogging and
playing tennis. He's good.
So he's out of the wheelchair?
-But?
-It's, uh...
-But then, what--
-It's a new wheelchair.
They just invented it.
It's water-powered.
Really?
Look, could we not
talk about this right now...
because, like,
it's really sad for me, OK?
-Who's that?
-It's the police, Mr. Pogue.
It's the police.
Don't tell them I'm here.
Don't.
I need you, Pogue.
Mr. Pogue?
Would you step outside,
What is it?
Turn around, please, Mr. Pogue.
Get your hands behind your back,
Mr. Pogue.
Let's go.
Come on.
What do you think?
What's it going to be?
The Mona Lisa.
How's it going, Pogue?
Just great.
-You want the joke of the day?
-Sure.
Why don't blind people
sky-dive?
Why?
It scares the shit
out their dogs.
That's funny.
Mr. Pogue!
Mr. Pogue, the rent!
The rent, Mr. Pogue!
If it's not too much to ask,
what'd I do?
-Stay here.
-Right here.
Surprise!
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Pogue
I told you I'd get you.
Happy birthday to you
Make a wish.
Speech!
I, uh...
I just want to thank everyone
for their effort here.
Thank you.
-More!
-No!
Come on!
Seeing all your...
faces here today...
brings back such...
memories.
It's hard to know
where to begin.
Start with the girls!
Jealous, Bob?
You old dog, Bob!
Sure, I could talk about Bob...
John and Susan and Mary...
Mary and--and Fred and Ethel
and Little Ricky...
and all the others...
whose friendship
means so much to me...
but that wouldn’t be fair.
I'm reminded of a story.
A story about....
about guts...
and blood.
Blood and guts and patriotism.
And love.
Let's not forget Love.
That-a-way!
I think we all know
who I'm talking about.
I'm not going to embarrass them
by mentioning their name...
but what sacrifice, huh?
When they went into the...
the thing with the...
the guy in the--
you know, the flames...
and the running the back
with the thing and the...
Next thing, they're getting up
in the middle of the night.
Who knew?
There's an old joke
that goes...
why don't blind people
sky-dive?
Is it irrelevant?
I don't think so.
Call me old-fashioned,
call me irresistible...
call me late for lunch...
but I think
grabbing the initiative...
overcoming handicaps, and, yes,
even skydiving blind...
are the true virtues, hmm?
I'm sure you have
your own stories.
Raise your hand
if you have your own story.
Come on, put 'em up.
Yeah, a lot of stories...
a Lot of hands...
which is to say...
I have a rare group of friends.
Thank you.
-Guess who!
-I'm not real good at this.
-Come on, guess.
-Let the man go, Judy.
-Judy.
-No fair, Dolby, no fair.
11:30.
How's it going, Pogue?
Uh, pretty good.
I ran into a friend of ours
this morning.
-Who's that?
-Sarah Novak.
What? Sarah Novak. What?
Come over here.
Listen, Pogue, I've seen
a Lot of innocent people...
killed in my time, and
I'm haunted by them constantly.
But Sarah is dead, Pogue.
You're alive.
Stop torturing yourself with it.
Stop talking to Sarah.
Concentrate on putting that
bastard Cornell in jail, OK?
You nervous about Thursday?
Thursday?
Remember, be yourself
on cross-examination.
Tell it Like you know.
Like I know.
-Right, counselor?
-That's right.
Nobody's gotten that close to
Cornell before--not till now.
Either wind up dead or bought
or in a wheelchair.
But not you, Pogue.
Too Late to rent a hall.
Listen, I need to ask a favor
as a friend.
Sure.
I think my fiancée’s
cheating on me.
I know what you're thinking,
''Rosenheim, you're paranoid.''
But that's not it.
I want to hire you.
I need to hire you.
I'm not taking any cases
right now.
-I'm desperate.
-I'm real busy.
-Listen, she's making me crazy.
-I'm on vacation.
Just find out who she's
sleeping with. That's all I ask.
May I borrow the birthday boy
for a sec?
Actually, we were talking.
Come on, come on, come on.
You're supposed to be resting.
Open your mouth.
I told you I would keep
your amnesia confidential...
but if you're gonna be
running around...
making an ass of yourself...
Turn your head.
You need some stability.
You need settle down.
You need to relax.
Find a woman, somebody to
help you get through this thing.
Look up. If you keep up
this life of high adventure...
this amnesia's
going to be permanent.
Look down. The best place
for you right now is home--
familiar surroundings,
people you know.
I'm surrounded by people I know.
That's my problem.
Now, who are they?
Hey...who are you?
-I'm your doctor.
-You are?
Anthony Doover.
We're friends.
We play tennis on Saturdays.
Doover, Doover. And the guy
you were just talking to?
Rosenheim. Donald Rosenheim.
He's the assistant D.A.
You worked together
on the force.
Rosenheim, assistant D.A.
And the guy in the wheelchair?
John Dolby. He's the D.A.
Dolby. D.A.
Sarah Novak?
Don't think about her, Pogue.
You're feeling guilty.
About what? What?
Listen, you're never gonna
get over this amnesia...
until you come to grips
with what happened.
Would you just
tell me what happened?
Go home. Go to bed.
Don't move.
AII right. Zip up.
Why, thank you.
We haven't met formally,
have we, Mr. Pogue?
Philip Cornell.
You've got no thumb,
Mr. Cornell.
My dad loved art, Mr. Pogue.
He Loved art so much...
that when I was kidnapped
as a Little boy of 8...
the kidnappers
threatened to kill me...
unless my father surrendered
his Rubens--
Descent from the Cross--
a surpassing work, by the way.
Dad called their bluff.
The kidnappers sent my thumb
back to him in a box.
What'd your dad do
with the thumb?
Does he still have it?
The kidnappers were captured.
The Rubens was undamaged.
Did he freeze the thumb?
They can do--
Could they stop doing that?
Your testimony on Thursday--
I shall be most grateful if you
could see your way clear...
to have a convenient
loss of memory.
This is a statement
explaining you were mistaken.
You never saw me
at the crime scene.
In turn,
we could offer you this.
Is that a comma?
Can I think about this?
Of course.
Till tomorrow morning.
Give us time
to make other plans.
This is bad.
I've gotten involved
with a Sarah Novak.
She's either in trouble
and needs your help...
or she's dead...
and in a remarkable state
of preservation.
OK, According to the file
in your office...
Sarah Novak
was Philip Cornell's lover.
They were apparently
inseparable for five years...
till she left him.
Sarah was afraid that
Cornell intended to kill her...
for what she knew
about his illegal activities.
She decided to testify
against him.
She hired a private detective
to protect herself.
Yours truly.
The day after the indictment
was brought against Cornell...
Sarah was killed.
A car bomb.
You were blown clear.
The only witness.
Oh, good. Let's see.
So, all of this leaves you
with an interesting dilemma.
That is bizarre.
Maybe, maybe.
Ow! Ow! Shit.
Dead woman
walks into your Life...
and now we have a date
to meet her at a fashion show.
AII right, two questions.
One--why isn't she dead?
And two--
what am I going to wear
tonight?
There's only one way you can
get your questions answered...
and only one place
you can find her.
Excuse me.
Sorry, sorry.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
He's watching me.
So what did the police want?
Um...it's my birthday.
I know. Psst.
-Happy birthday.
-Thanks.
These are nice.
Put them on.
Come here.
They seem very you.
You think so?
-Mm-hmm.
-How's that?
Black and white.
Like your anklet?
Yes, Like my ank--
You're a very good detective.
-How do you tell time?
-With difficulty.
-It's broken.
-Why don't you get it fixed?
My grandmother
engraved on the back of it...
''Vivi ogni momento
al suo massimo.''
Ah, yes. Romanian.
-No, It's Italian.
-I knew that.
That was my second choice.
So, what's it mean?
''Live every second
to its fullest.''
I'm doing my part.
Clasp.
Um, do you mind
if I ask you a question?
Sure.
Why aren't you dead?
-It wasn't me. It was a double.
-Why?
-Can we handle this later?
-No. Tell me now.
The FBI knew
Cornell was gonna hit me...
so they put an agent in
just in case.
They didn't expect...
ba-boom.
Why would someone
want to kill you?
You're on, Beth.
I became Beth Holly
of San Francisco, a model.
What do I call you now,
Sarah or Beth?
Sarah.
Someone is threatening to tell
Cornell I'm still alive...
unless I give them something.
What? Give them what?
You're on.
On display at the end
of the hall of archeology...
you'll find the oldest coin
we now know to exist--
the Coin of Royal Power.
Dating from the year 650 b.c...
the coin is customarily held...
under the tightest security
in China's forbidden city...
but was loaned
to the county museum...
in a rare cultural exchange
Last year.
-He stole it.
-Cornell.
He was obsessed with it.
You know, he has every
valuable coin in the world.
He had to have this one, too.
That's why you went to the FBI.
I took it from him.
It is named
the Coin of Royal Power...
due to the symbols of royalty--
the lion and the bull.
Its estimated value
is seven million dollars.
I was angry, I wanted
to hurt him, so I took it.
He came after me,
so I went to the FBI.
I promised to testify
about Cornell’s business...
if they protected me.
And now the blackmailers
want the coin?
-Give it to them.
-I don't have it.
-Who does?
-You do.
This whole thing
is about a $7-miIIion coin...
that Cornell
stole from this museum...
and you stole from Cornell?
The morning
before the explosion...
I gave you something to hide,
remember?
I didn't tell you what it was.
I couldn’t.
I just asked you to hide it...
and you said you had
the perfect place for it.
Remember?
-Pogue.
-Right.
You said one word--''baby.''
-Baby.
-Uh-huh.
You wouldn’t tell me
what it meant.
This way.
No. Left.
-That's who's following you?
-That's him.
His name is Hendrix. He's FBI.
Be careful. I need you.
This isn't the way out?
I told Novak I'd kill her
if she went to the police.
I'm not the police.
That's why
I'm going to kill you instead.
Who did that?
He made it after all.
Welcome. Welcome.
December 18, 1988--
a date Like any other...
or was it?
This is the path we took.
It was a good path, a red path,
a path of many moods.
Thank you.
We...
we started here.
Then we went here, here,
down here...
over here, here,
and ended up here.
Many people thought
we wouldn’t make it.
This was one of the people
who laughed at us.
We called him...Steve.
Later he died of dysentery.
We buried him here.
This, I think,
is self-explanatory.
These dates are important
to remember, obviously.
They reflect
a different time and--
a different place.
Exotic? Yes...and no.
Who's to say who's the savage?
Not me. Not you.
There's an old joke that goes,
why don't blind people...
But I--I think it was
my illustrious colleague...
Dr. Howard from
the University of Geneva...
who said it best.
I think I should let the doctor
tell it himself...
shouldn’t I?
Doctor.
Come on up, doctor.
Come on up.
Where you going, doctor?
Don't be shy.
Oh, yes. The doctor's
going to lead us...
on a walking tour
of the neolithic exhibits.
Please, everybody.
Don't Let the doctor get away.
He's on a tight schedule.
-Doctor!
OK, things have gotten
a bit more complicated.
Now, Sarah gave you
something to hide.
You hid it either
with someone called ''Baby''...
or in a place that has
something to do with babies.
It's a coin
about the size of a penny.
It's worth
seven million dollars.
Maybe ''Baby'' is something
to do with your past...
maybe when you were a cop.
Or maybe not.
Maybe it's something
more recent...
something
just before your amnesia.
''Testimony.''
I'II check that out Later.
You were a private eye.
Maybe that's a clue.
''Two-way radio
and survellance glasses.''
Someone's wiling to kill Sarah
to get at the coin.
She needs your protection.
She needs your help.
Maybe it's time
to do a little legwork.
''Baby.''
Oh, damn. Oh, damn it.
Where--where are the bullets?
Oh, so it was you.
-Guess who.
-Judy.
Surprise.
-What are you doing here?
-11:30 on the dot.
Ready?
I...
For what?
I hope you don't mind.
I borrowed a shirt.
Th-this is not a good idea,
Judy.
Oh. That's not what
you said Last night.
Don't I Look as good tonight?
That's not the point.
Well, what is the point?
Hey, I--I think the point is--
-Say it. Say it, Pogue.
-What?
-Like Last night.
Like Last night. Right.
Let's pretend
there was no Last night.
Oh, you animal.
Baby! Baby!
What did you say?
Skip it.
What?
You know what to do.
Then do it.
What are you doing?
Judy, wait a second.
Next time, try not to confuse me
with your other girlfriends.
Pogue, do you ever Listen
to your messages?
It's Paula.
I'II be home tonight.
I have the baby.
Let's talk this out, OK?
Hey, stranger. You drop off
the face of the earth or what?
Give me a call.
Hi, Pogue. It's me.
Call me sometime.
I'm at the new number.
Pogue,
it's curia you call me today.
I'm at the office.
Pogue, do you ever Listen
to your messages?
It's Paula.
I'II be home tonight.
I have the baby.
Let's talk this out, OK?
OK, your name is M.L. Pogue,
and you got a problem--
whenever you go to sleep,
you Lose your memory.
Shit.
Whatever you do,
don't talk to anyone.
Just stay in bed.
Pogue? It's me, Sarah.
Did you get rid of him
Last night?
Was there any problem?
Could you hold on one second?
You've become involved
with a Sarah Novak.
Afraid that Philip Cornell
intended to kill her...
for what she knew
about his operation...
Sarah hired you to protect her.
Sarah, are you safe?
Does Cornell know where you are?
Pogue, Cornell thinks I'm dead.
Oh...right.
One second.
But Sarah made a deal
with the FBI...
and they made it Look Like
she was dead...
after a failed bomb attack...
so she could testify
against Cornell.
But now an FBI man named
Hendrix is blackmailing her...
threatening to tell Cornell
she's still alive...
unless she gives him
a valuable coin...
that Cornell stole from
the Natural History Museum...
and Sarah stole from him
and gave to you to hide.
But you hid it with
either someone called ''Baby''...
or a place that has
something to do with babies.
-Sarah, can I get back to you?
-Pogue, are you all right?
I'm fine. I'II get back to you.
I'II meet you on the beach
at 6:00.
-I want my money, Mr. Pogue.
-Who is this?
Your landIord. Don't tell me
you've forgotten again.
-How much is it?
-Eight hundred.
AII right.
I'm sending you a check.
No.
I'm coming over this second.
Good, good.
My apologies
for the early hour, Mr. Pogue.
Have you decided to cooperate?
Here it is.
Thank you.
Sorry about the lateness.
Don't be sorry, Mr. Pogue.
The important thing is
you signed it.
Yeah, I signed it.
I'm in your debt, Mr. Pogue.
Remember, anything you need,
just Let me know.
Um, this door,
it seems to stick a bit.
It probably needs
a Little oil on the hinge.
So, just so I'II know,
it's the first of the month?
No. It's the 8th.
Oh.
So it's always the 8th?
Today is the 8th.
Tomorrow is the 9th.
OK. Good. Good.
AII right. Bye.
What's up?
Sorry about that, boy.
Here's fresh air.
I'II be right back.
May I help you?
Oh, Maurice. Oh, go on in.
What room number is it again?
Naughty.
You've been away too Long.
Number thirty-two.
Up the stairs, at the end.
Thank you.
Problem?
Whose room is that?
Mrs. Pogue's?
Right.
Mom?
Son?
Mom.
Oh, I made some brownies.
Thank you.
They Look delicious.
Mom?
Son?
Don't just stand there.
Come and kiss your mother.
Seven pounds, nine ounces.
-Hmm. That's me?
-Mm-hmm.
The nurse said you were...
the prettiest thing
she ever saw.
Oh, Look,
there's your first Christmas.
Oh, and that pretty tree.
That was our prettiest.
-You remember that house?
-Mom?
Mom, when I was a Little baby,
was there someplace I'd go?
In your diapers.
No. Some kind of hiding place.
Even as a baby,
you had the straightest teeth.
Oh, there you are.
Mom, where's the rest
of this picture?
''Maurice, Paula, and Baby.''
Where's the rest?
Nap time, Shirley.
Now, don't worry about it.
-Come on.
-Mom.
Visiting hours are over.
I promised I would never say
anything bad about her.
About who, Paula?
Come on.
What are you doing here, Pogue?
Nostalgic for the old academy?
Good to see you, John. How's
the district attorney's office?
Fine. Rosenheim wanted to
get in a Little target practice.
Oh, you mean my good friend
Donald the assistant D.A.
That's right.
I'm looking for Paula, John.
Do you know
where I might find her?
Sure you want to see her?
It's none of my business,
but watch out for Willis.
He's never forgiven you,
slugger.
Paula’s on lane eight.
Slugger?
You been seeing
any more of Sarah?
Sarah Novak? No.
-Good.
-But she's coming by tonight.
Pogue, sit down.
You need to get some help.
I wish I could.
You can't fight this
on your own.
Sarah's afraid
of bringing anyone else in.
Pogue, Listen to me.
Sarah is gone.
-Just till tonight.
-No! She's not coming back.
-How do you know?
-It's a fact of Life.
Good, John. Thanks a Lot.
Not now, Pogue.
-You two going to fight?
-Shut up, Donald.
Just great to see you
back together.
We're not together.
I was just visiting Shirley.
Yeah? She still mad at me?
N-no. She said to say hi.
I'm trying to shoot here, Pogue.
It sounds Like fighting.
I do hear fighting.
You two should have
never got married.
Ya-ya.
He Looks just Like his daddy.
-You think?
-Oh, yeah. Spitting image.
What do you think, Maurice?
I always thought he looked more
Like me, but, yeah, I see it.
-Thirty seconds.
Can you watch him for a second?
Maurice, just take him
for a walk or something.
Sarah gave you
the coin to hide...
and you hid it either
with someone called ''Baby''...
or in a place that has
something to do with babies.
Can I have teddy?
Teddy? Yeah.
Do the happy face.
Get away from him!
Don't push your luck, Pogue.
It was a sucker punch.
-Willis.
-You stay away from him.
-It's not what you think, OK?
-Yeah, right.
Just walk away! Just walk away!
-Knock it off.
-Would you leave him alone?
Let go of the damn thing!
I don't want you near my wife...
and I sure as hell
don't want you near my son.
I'II kill you
if I see you near them again.
Pogue, I got a clue about
who's sleeping with my fiancée.
She comes home Last night
wearing this.
It's a man's, not mine.
And check out these initials--
M.P.
Someone with the initials M.P.
What do you think?
Maybe it's somebody called M.P.
Uh, not--not necessarily.
I just came by to check
the roll call, you know?
Let's see. There's, uh,
Mike and Manuel...
-Maurice!
-Mattie, Mickey...
-One second!
How about Last names?
Last names.
-Maurice Pogue!
-I'm coming!
Well, your car payments
haven't been.
I'm not a suspicious type
by nature. You know that.
It's just the idea of Judith
sleeping with someone else--
I could kill, you understand?
-Well, I'II check into it.
-Will you?
You're a buddy. Thanks.
Listen,
the suspenders Look great...
but I'd Lose the teddy bear.
What do you think?
-Looks great.
-Yeah? Aw, thanks.
So, what's it going to be?
Very you.
Thanks...
I think.
You Look happy.
You had a good day?
Have we ever...
I mean, we...
Did, uh...
How serious are we?
I guess that depends.
I get serious very quickly.
I think you do, too.
I do?
Don't you?
I mean, but...
wh-what do you really
know about me?
I know enough.
There's something else.
I hit a snag with the coin.
-I don't want to talk about it.
-It's not as simple as...
Kiss me.
There was an explosion,
and my memory...
''Kiss me''?
What is with this ''Kiss me''?
Ouch.
What is this? What is this?
Oh, that's where those were.
Thank you.
Like it's the first time.
Just one second.
-What?
-It's all right.
Wait.
Right back.
When you hear this,
it'll be Wednesday morning.
The woman sleeping next to you,
her name is Sarah Novak.
Don't be silly. I want you.
I got to go.
Where are you--
Don't Let her down because...
What are you--
Shit.
Because I think
you're in Love with her.
Come here.
My watch is in your hair.
I'm sorry.
-My bra.
-Oh, your bra, yes.
I'm real good at this.
Man.
The woman
sleeping next to you...
her name is Sarah Novak.
Don't Let her down because
I think you're in Love with her.
Of course it's a good sign.
I go to sleep, I wake up...
I remember everything
from the day before.
I'm not saying
it's a bad sign, Pogue...
but we can't tell anything
from that. Cough.
Why not?
You still can't
remember anything...
from the day before yesterday
or the day before that, right?
What I'm saying is,
you need a breakthrough...
a memory of something
before your amnesia.
-What's that?
-What's what?
Scrambled or poached?
-Scrambled.
-Scrambled?
-What's scrambled?
-The eggs.
Well, whoever she is, Pogue,
she's exactly what you need--
someone to help you
get on with your Life.
Got to go.
''Baby.''
Baby Ruth. Baby Ruth.
Baby powder.
Baby grand.
Baby face.
Baby blue.
Crybaby.
Sugar baby.
Baby.
Fido. Here, Fido.
Here, Spot. Here, Spot. Spot.
Rusty!
Pete? Here, Pete.
Hi, boy. Hi, Baby. Hi. Yeah.
Have you got something?
It's incredible.
You're incredible.
Oh, no. Well, all right.
A Little bit.
-Yes. Look at it.
-Gorgeous, gorgeous, gorgeous.
So, what time's
he supposed to call?
2:00.
I may have to meet him alone.
-AII right.
-Ouch.
-What are you doing?
-What is this?
What are you doing down there?
What is this?
That's a two-way surveillance
glasses and radio.
Wear them when he phones.
-Over there.
-AII right.
Santa Monica Pier
in half an hour.
No one else. Just me.
He says if he sees you
within a mile, he won't show.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
You’ll need the coin.
Thanks.
Anytime.
Stay, boy.
You're Late.
How Long does it take
to drive a block, you idiot?
I don't want to hear it.
-Did you get it from him?
-No problem.
Well, where is it?
-I've got it.
-Well, let's see it.
Not here. The big guy's
gonna want to see it. Come on.
The big guy can wait.
What about Pogue?
He didn't catch on?
-Do not underestimate him.
-You should talk.
Any more questions,
or can we go now?
Let's go.
Hold on, boy!
May I help you, sir?
Yes, you may. You may.
The gentleman on court six.
I believe he's a friend of mine,
but I'm not quite certain.
Well, I'II call down.
Oh, I want to surprise him.
Certainly.
Court six.
That's Doover.
Dr. Anthony Doover.
Is he your friend, sir?
Dr. Doover?
My mistake.
Give me a high five.
Well, smile, Beth.
You pulled it off.
-She's got a guilty conscience.
-Shut up.
What, about Pogue?
Looks to me
Like you've been doing...
a few Little favors for him
on your own.
Stop it.
You're a character, Beth.
Well, let's see it.
Let me see the coin.
Come on.
What?
OK, this is Pogue's doing.
He saw through
our Little charade.
So you go back, you get
the tape before he wakes up...
and we'll begin again
from the beginning.
I beg your pardon?
It's over.
I'm not doing it anymore.
I'm not.
May I remind you this Little
item is worth $7 million?
Seven million.
Are you telling me you're going
to turn your back on that?
I don't think so.
Watch me.
Does it Look Like it now?
Like what?
Pogue,
you want the joke of the day?
How do you find a blind man
in a nudist colony?
How?
It ain't hard.
You ain't much
in a laughing mood today, Pogue.
Neither were your friends.
What friends?
The guys in your apartment.
Hey, where you been all day?
Uh, out.
Yeah, well, I been calling.
Somebody kept hanging up.
Come here.
I've got another clue.
Nobody at the LAPD
has the initials M.P.
Are you sure?
Check this out.
I caught Judy
tearing up a letter, OK?
I got this out just before
she flushed it down the toilet.
Check it out.
Look at the numbers--
''1-1-9--''
What's that other number?
5? Maybe a 3?
Could it be a license plate,
maybe a phone number?
Uh, probably a phone number.
Maybe an address?
Oh, I-I'II Look into it.
OK. Well, we've got to go over
your Cornell testimony.
How about tomorrow night?
Tomorrow night. That's good.
The testimony's tomorrow
at 2:00, so you know...
That makes sense.
That wouldn’t be--
You're...
-Excuse me.
-You're coming through.
There you are.
You all right? There you go.
Pogue, the testimony.
Tomorrow morning at 9:00.
Judge BIock's upset because
we missed the Last court date.
He said if you're not
on the stand tomorrow...
he's throwing out
the whole case.
I'II be there.
What do you think
of the tie now?
Have you thought about
a clip-on or--
That's enough.
Oh, you're in trouble now.
Where's the coin, Maurice?
See that?
You got to watch out...
when he starts calling you
by your first name.
I wouldn’t do that
if I were you.
There's some guys in there
with guns.
-Open it.
-I really wouldn’t advise it.
My landlord?
Sir?
Seen a pickup truck
speeding by here?
Just out for a walk?
Oh, I hate to iron.
When do they empty the meters?
Tomorrow. Why?
I--I just saw some kids
messin' around with them.
-W-what time?
-3:30.
Don't worry, sir.
We’ll be here all night.
Great.
-He paid me to scare Pogue.
-Shut up.
To shoot up his apartment,
make him turn over the coin.
What coin?
Royal...something.
It's supposed to be worth a Lot.
How do you know Mr. Pogue
has this coin?
Well, when they brought Pogue
into the hospital...
he was babbling on
about the coin being with Baby.
Will you shut up?
Baby? What's baby mean?
I don't know.
Anything else you can tell us?
No, except I think
I deserve something.
I mean, for my trouble.
Oh, yes, you most certainly do.
Not on the rug.
Pogue, I'm sorry.
I'm not Sarah Novak.
I'm really Beth Holly...
a washed-up actress
trying to become a model.
I Looked Like Sarah.
That's why Doover hired me.
OK, it's Thursday morning.
Your name is M.L. Pogue.
You're a private investigator.
When you're slapped,
you’ll take it and Like it.
You're a, uh,
you're a tough guy...
a dangerous customer.
Women, they flock to you.
You use them and drop them
Like yesterday's laundry.
Or they use you.
OK, your name is M.L. Pogue,
and you got a problem.
Whenever you go to sleep,
you Lose your memory.
''Half a league, half a League,
half a League onward...
''all in the valley of death
rode the six hundred.
''Forward the light brigade.
Charge for the guns, he said.
''Into the valley of death
rode the six hundred!''
''Aardvark--an animal
resembling the anteater...
''found in parts of Africa...''
Whenever you go to sleep,
you Lose your memory.
You can't go to sleep,
or you’ll Lose your memory.
''Push this button.''
Good morning, Mr. Pogue.
Good morning.
I'm disappointed with you.
Eight hundred dollars
for a bribe?
I thought I meant more to you
than that.
Now I hear
you've been holding out on me.
The Coin of Royal Power--
we know you have it.
Are you sure you've got
the right person here or...
Where we going?
What happened to your thumb?
Nothin'.
Anything?
He's good.
If you don't tell me
where that coin is...
I will have to kill you.
But first I will kill her.
I have a court date to keep.
You have two hours...
to sweat it out, as it were.
Oh, Pogue, I'm so sorry.
I was wrong.
When Doover came to me,
I had no money, nothing.
But I didn't mean
to get you into this.
Can you forgive me?
Sure.
Who are you?
AII rise and face the flag.
What is going on,
Mr. Rosenheim?
We've hit a snag, your honor.
Our witness is missing.
AII right.
Both of you, up here.
OK, Let me get this straight.
I'm a detective with amnesia...
caused by an explosion
set by Cornell...
the guy I'm supposed
to be testifying against...
in a court of law
on a murder charge.
You are an actress
who pretended to be...
a victim
killed in the explosion...
in order to get
a valuable coin...
that she gave to me
before my amnesia...
and I hid in my dog's collar.
But now you say you're sorry...
and you want to help me get
to court and find the coin.
If we could just have
another day...
to locate our witness,
sir, I'm sure--
You've got until 3:00,
Mr. Rosenheim.
Listen, you're a detective.
You've been in tough spots
Like this before.
I can't remember.
Listen, that doesn't matter.
You are who you are.
Think. Give me that.
-Careful. Careful.
-That's cold.
Here, take this.
You get the guy in here...
and then I'II--Poof!
Bam, bam, bam.
You just sit right back down
there and get comfortable.
That's right.
-Now what?
-I have no idea.
-Pogue.
-What?
You're a baseball pitcher.
You are. I'm telling you.
That's about the distance
to home plate.
Hit him with a pitch.
I thought you said
I was a detective.
You were in a baseball League
at night.
-How Long ago?
-A few years--Last year.
I think you pitched
three no-hitters...
struck out twenty-five batters.
-Left hand or right hand?
-Right.
-You think I'm making this up?
-How many batters?
Twenty...ten in one game.
You said twenty-five
a second ago. I heard you.
What is this, a sports quiz?
You're a champion. Let's go.
AII right, I'II do it one time.
-Let's go.
-One time.
Right now.
Just take it and do it.
Now. Now.
-What are you doing?
-I got to be a pitcher.
Now, now, now.
Loose. OK.
See? I suck.
I'm horrible.
Listen, you always lean high
on your first pitch.
-I can't.
-Just do another one for me.
One more.
OK, for you, I'II do it
one more time, and that's it.
You're a champion.
Now.
Just do it now.
Did you see that?
You did it.
You forgive me,
don't you, Pogue?
That's kind of hard for me
to answer...
-Beth.
I don't know anything about you.
You know enough.
Come on.
First pitch.
That was the first pitch.
Now, where am I going?
Make a right to the courthouse.
We're going to smarten you up.
Here. Wear these.
-Those are nice.
-Thanks.
Pogue, you have to memorize
your testimony.
The only way to keep Cornell
off our backs...
is to put him in jail.
What testimony? What do I say?
Here. Listen to this.
-Comb.
-''Testimony.''
It doesn't work.
-It works.
-Try it.
Give it to me.
Damn it! It's batteries.
The batteries.
Do you have batteries?
Uh, glove compartment?
No, no, no.
Batteries. Batteries.
-The glasses. Put those on.
-I don't need glasses.
Don't worry.
Listen, just Listen.
I can see fine.
That's you. I hear you.
That's it.
God damn it, Pogue!
Where the hell have you been?
Keep the glasses on.
I'II go and get batteries.
Listen, Pogue,
just stay calm, all right?
I don't want you to be too
detailed in your descriptions.
I'd rather Let the jury's
imagination run wild...
than have them question
specifics.
The glasses are a nice touch,
by the way.
They make you Look
very, very respectable.
Thank you.
I got another clue
about the LAPD T-shirt...
the one with ''M.P.''
on the collar?
They haven't made that shirt
for two years.
Let us through, please.
You have to Let us through.
Do your job there,
will you, fellas?
Oh, kiss me!
No time for family reunions.
I'm sorry.
I still don't have a check.
Did you talk to Sarah Novak
today?
No. She's dead.
So happy you could join us,
Mr. Pogue.
I'm happy, too.
-Excuse me. I need to buy--
-Just a sec.
Nice lady's buying a postcard.
-OK, but--
-Patience.
Stand, sir.
Raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear to tell
the truth, the whole truth...
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
I do.
State your name and spell it
for the record, please.
Maurice Pogue.
P...o...g...
-U-e!
Mr. Pogue, I'd Like to begin...
with a few simple
background questions.
You're a private investigator,
is that correct?
And where is
your place of business?
For the record.
-Stall!
Excuse me?
No. You stall.
I mean...stall.
S'tall possible to turn up
the air conditioning here?
Answer the question, Mr. Pogue.
My address.
You want my address.
P-o, P-o, P-o.
Before I give my address...
I'd Like to state
one thing for the record.
That's a fabulous pin.
Oh, thank you. It was a gift.
Really?
Have you seen this, judge?
Objection, your honor!
Nonresponsive.
He's such a well-mannered boy.
Pogue! 1195 Speedway!
-Mr. Pogue.
-1195 Speedway.
-Beautiful postcard.
-Can I have some batteries?
Just one moment.
And your change.
Batteries!
Mr. Pogue, is it also true
that you used to work...
as a police officer?
-What size?
-''C.''
Amigo.
And that you retired from
the police force two years ago?
AII right, Mr. Pogue,
I have a few more questions...
before we move on.
Mr. Rosenheim,
do you have a question?
Yes, your honor,
I do have a few more questions.
Back stock.
It's in front of you,
in front of you. No, no, no!
Mr. Pogue...
you're a bachelor,
isn't that correct?
Do you Live alone?
Would you say that you Live
a promiscuous lifestyIe?
Objection, your honor.
What's the relevance?
For background, your honor.
Rather pertinent background.
Well, I'II allow
a Little leeway.
Thank you, your honor.
Again, Mr. Pogue.
Would you say you Live
a promiscuous lifestyle?
I--I wouldn’t say promiscuous.
Let me rephrase.
You are attracted to women,
aren't you?
And not being married
hasn't kept you...
from being sexually active?
A simple yes or no will do,
Mr. Pogue.
-No.
-Thank you.
Mr. Pogue, what is
the seventh commandment?
The seventh commandment?
Yes, yes,
that one in particular.
The right to bear arms?
A Little difficulty
with that one, Mr. Pogue?
Like some help with this, hmm?
Shall I help you out
with the seventh commandment?
Thou shall not commit adultery!
Your honor! Your honor!
Your honor!
AII right.
Withdrawn. Withdrawn.
Mr. Pogue, where were you
on the night of April 7th?
I don't remember.
Come, come, Mr. Pogue.
It was three nights ago.
Would you have this court
believe you don't remember...
who you were with
three nights ago?
Yes. Let me refresh
your memory a Little bit.
I have evidence here that
suggests you were with a woman!
Background is fine,
Mr. Rosenheim...
but let's get back
to the crime, please.
Mr. Pogue, you've testified...
that the defendant
was responsible...
for the death of Sarah Novak,
is that correct?
I got it! Your testimony.
I'm sorry, Pogue,
I'm not Sarah Novak.
Oh, my God.
Pogue, I taped over it.
What?
A simple question, Mr. Pogue.
You testified in the past...
that Mr. Cornell
murdered Sarah Novak.
Is that correct?
Now, to the best
of your recollection...
and perhaps drawing upon
your extensive expertise...
in this particular area...
do you think
that Mr. Cornell has ever...
boffed his best friend's
fiancée?
Objection!
That's enough, Mr. Rosenheim.
Where is this leading?
I'II tell you where
it's leading, your honor.
-To his fucking grave!
-Objection, your honor!
Tell the court
you were with her!
-You're in contempt!
-You were with that slut!
You want to talk about sluts?
-Let's talk about Cynthia!
-Leave her out of this!
You slut!
As far as I'm concerned,
we're even!
Even? He did boff her!
We need help in courtroom five.
Damn it! What's going on here?
I'm sorry, Pogue.
I'm not Sarah Novak.
I should’ve told you sooner...
but I started to Like
being Sarah...
and I started to Like
being with you.
I've lied to you throughout,
Pogue, I know...
but there is one thing
that's not a Lie.
I Love you. I Love you.
I'm not Sarah, but I Love you.
Rosenheim, what are you doing?
I can't reach his throat.
Order in my courtroom!
I gotcha!
Order in the court!
I'II have order
in the courtroom!
Leave him alone!
Leave my baby alone!
That's it! That's it!
That's enough!
Come on, back off.
Back off. Back off.
You touch her again,
I'II kill you!
You son of a bitch!
Not me, her!
The coin, it's in the alley
behind my apartment.
The Last parking meter.
Your memory's back!
I'm on my way.
I'II kill him!
Give me two seconds!
Get your hands off of me!
What are you doing?
I'm the bailiff, damn it!
I'II have your badges for this.
Move it on out.
Mr. Pogue,
what do you remember...
of the night of February 8th,
the death of Sarah Novak...
its aftermath,
and the person responsible?
I remember...
everything.
Miss, there are some kids
breaking into a parking meter.
-What? Not on my beat!
-Around the corner.
Thank you!
Why did you change your plea,
Mr. Cornell?
The fact that we made a deal
has no bearing...
on Mr. Cornell’s
guilt or innocence.
But it's kind of a thumbs-down
for his credibility, isn't it?
Thumbs-down? Thumbs-down?
What do you mean, thumbs-down?
We will ask that Mr. Cornell
receive the maximum sentence--
Life imprisonment.
I want to add one more thing.
This successful prosecution
could not have happened...
without the assistance
of one very special person.
Oh, thank you.
Even as a baby, I always knew...
that Maurice
was a very special person.
Hey, boy.
Good to see you.
Here we go.
Remember me?
Humphrey Bogart?
I can give you a hint.
Mmm, it's coming back.
You know what?
It's almost there.
I'm cured.
How much do you remember,
anyway?
Well, let's see.
How about, uh...
Viva suo massimo momento...
No. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Yeah, but what did you do
with the coin?