== sync & corrections by Alice ==
== www.Addic7ed.Com ==
[Chicago's "25 or 6 to 4" playing]
["25 or 6 to 4"
continuing over car stereo]
[Singing along with song]
[Humming along with song]
[Siren wailing]
Oh. Fuck.
Sir, you were driving
erratically back there.
I'm gonna be honest
with you, ok.
I kind of got swept up
in the music and...
You know, I got swept up.
I was swept. I got swept up.
Sir, step out of the car.
Have you ever performed
a field sobriety test?
What?
Just put one foot
in front of the other.
- Yeah.
- Heel-to-toe, for nine steps.
One foot and extend
your arms to the side.
Can you do that?
I'm sober!
I can't do it!
No shaking.
Look, this is not easy.
You can do it
'cause you've practiced.
- Come with me.
- What?
Sir, you are clearly
intoxicated.
I'm not! I wasn't drinking.
I was just happy.
Is that the penalty
for being happy?
Oh, the head, the head,
the precious head.
Don't hurt the head.
- Hey, Nathan.
- Hey, Ben.
How are you, man?
What a fucked up morning I had.
- Today? This morning?
- Yeah, this morning.
Unbelievable.
Hey, did you hear haney's
gonna use one of my ideas
in the big presentation today.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, how about that, huh?
- Congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
Your mother must be
so proud of you.
- Well...
- "Ben got something in the presentation."
- "We're so proud of him."
- It's... yeah.
- "Did you hear?"
- I hope haney likes it.
Did you see? His son
is in the office today.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, Howard.
He named his son
after Howard roark
from ayn rand's the fountainhead.
- Howard roark.
- Oh, I never read it.
As far as I'm concerned,
he's the biggest asshole
in the history of literature,
and then you name your kid...
- Why would you do that?
- Oh Jesus.
- Are you all right down there?
- This just drives me crazy.
What?
I'm sick of these outlets
always on the floor.
Every time I try
and plug something in,
I have to move furniture,
and I strain my back.
Why can't outlets be up here?
- At eye level.
- Eye level?
What are they, like genitals?
We have to hide them?
Why are we hiding outlets?
- Think about it.
- Yeah. It's a...
- Oh. See you later.
- Ok.
Good to see you, boss.
Good luck today.
Hey. Ben, how are you?
Where you been?
[Chuckles] I had a little
problem this morning.
- It's... crazy.
- Big day today.
Sorry. Sorry I'm late.
Ok.
Is that new?
No. I've had it
for a while.
That's a plepler,
he paints shopping carts.
As a kid, I was fascinated
by shopping carts
because you get to drive
them in the supermarket.
It's quite beautiful.
I can't believe I never
noticed that before.
Something about the shopping
cart I find mesmerizing.
Hey, look who's here!
Hi, buddy. How ya doing?
How are you doing?
You wanna meet Mr. flomm?
- Hello. Hi.
- Hi.
Nathan, this is my son, Howard.
- Hello.
- This is our nanny, marina.
Marina, this is Nathan flomm.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
I like that, that swirl
you got on your hair there.
Thank you.
It takes a few hours.
Huh? It takes
a few hours.
What do you do
about the shampooing?
[Sighs] Once a week.
- You shampoo once a week.
- Once a week when I do it.
You may wanna consider
going twice, you know.
That's a long time
to go without shampooing.
But this takes two hours.
Try a second shampoo.
Take a little tip, little tip.
He's a full-time job.
She's a very valuable member
of our family.
Wonderful caregiver.
Will you do me a favor
and take Howard out
to the front desk
and wait for me there.
You need to get in there.
I wanna say good-bye
before he goes to school.
I'm... every day.
Ok, buddy. Will you wait
for me out there?
- Ok.
- All right.
Bye. Nice to meet you.
Love you.
Isn't he cute?
She's shampooing once a week,
are you kidding me.
- [Applause]
- Congratulations to Andy matsin.
Good job. Also to mark
and his aerodynamics team
for perfecting the
exterior profile of the car
and reducing
the drag coefficient
to a very slippery 0.23.
- [Applause]
- Very good job, mark.
So I've answered all the
tough questions about the car.
Is it safer?
Is it more efficient?
Can it travel further
on a single charge
than any other production
electric vehicle out there?
Yes, yes, and yes.
So there's probably
one more question
that you all have.
What's the name?
What are we gonna call
this bold new vision?
It's a name that instantly
defines our product.
Ladies and gentlemen...
The Howard.
- [Applause]
- Brilliant.
- Are you kidding?
- Thank you very much.
The Howard? Honestly?
That's what we're calling this?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I got a real problem
with this name, man.
- Oh God, Nathan.
- Howard? You can't...
You can't call a car Howard.
Come on. Seriously.
I tell you what. Everybody,
let's reconvene in 15.
Nathan and I are gonna
have a quick discussion
about the marketing of this.
Let's move forward.
- Nathan:  Do you like this name?
- Man:  It's a great name.
Grab that door
on your way out. Hey.
All right.
Let me just say this, ok.
You brought me
into this company
for my marketing
expertise, correct?
- Yes.
- Ok.
I hate to toot my own horn,
but you know I was the brains
behind the edible arrangements,
1,030 percent growth
in three fiscal quarters.
- I'm aware.
- I'm not making that up.
Call Patrick lyons,
he'll tell you...
Nathan, I'm aware
of your success.
It's why we hired you.
Ok. You're making
it impossible
for me to market this car.
I can't do it.
Nobody's gonna buy a car
named Howard.
It's like naming
a restaurant hepatitis.
- It's a name.
- It's not a good name.
Call it a Dewey.
That's a good name.
- A Duncan. Call it Duncan.
- Nathan,
your job is to come up
with the marketing.
Marketers market.
Inventors invent.
It's a slam-dunk.
By the way, what happened
to the pee flap?
The pee flap...
Nathan, are you still
on this horrible idea,
the pee flap?
- I thought you were into it?
- It's an insane idea.
Everybody wants to pee
in their car.
Nobody wants to pee
I wanna pee in my car.
You'd get pee
all over yourself.
No, the tube comes up
high enough
that it will catch everything.
Nathan, everybody's different.
How big is the tube?
You put your balls
and your penis in the tube
and that's that.
And you have
different size pee tubes
if you happen to have
big genitals.
What about the liability?
What happens if you hit a bump
with your dick
and balls in a tube
and you...
It chops it off?
So people sign a little waiver
or something. Big deal.
Nathan, it's a...
What do women do?
Half of our market?
All right. So women
don't have to use it.
You can't turn the interior
of a car into a urinal.
Bad idea.
The car is perfect.
I'm sure I could've worked
something out for women.
Nathan, your job is to sell it,
and if you can't do that job,
we're gonna find
somebody else that can.
You are invested
in this company.
You have ten percent
of this company.
You wanna walk away from that?
Are you offering me
my ten percent back?
I will happily give
you your ten percent back.
You have a deal.
You're making a huge mistake.
I think you're
making a mistake.
It's the worst decision
you've ever made in your life.
You made the worst
decision:  Howard.
How beautiful is this?
I don't think that salmon
was wild, by the way.
- Did you see this?
- Oh my God, that's beautiful.
We have a rosewater-infused,
white chocolate souffle,
with an almond chutney.
And here we have the raspberry
and chocolate mousse
with a kola nut
and coco mousse in the center.
- Kola nut?
- Yes, kola nut. Enjoy.
I was... I was walking
down Castro street,
and this fat woman
is coming toward me
and she bumps me
with her stomach
and knocks me off the curb.
It was hilarious.
What is...
What did you do to her?
Are you ok?
Yeah, of course, I'm ok.
It was funny.
There was a cop, saw the whole
thing, he was laughing.
This city, what's happening
is disgusting.
These homeless people, the
hospitals are releasing them...
- It's so sad.
- They're in Mountain view now.
It's not sad.
It's a funny story.
- I just don't understand...
- You don't think that's funny?
A fat woman just hits
me off the road...
If you say fat again...
Nathan:
Oh, you can't say fat.
You can't say fat.
What is going on
with electron motors?
I'm very excited about
the electric car coming out.
Oh, my gosh.
You have no idea.
They doubled that battery life.
Did you know that?
- They have doubled that battery life.
- What?
- You're sitting on a fortune.
- That thing is gonna be huge.
- I'm so excited.
- Yeah, well, there's a problem.
Woman:
With the car?
- I'm out of the company.
- What?
Yeah. There was a presentation
today and he revealed
that the name
of the car is Howard,
and I had
a big problem with that.
And he said,
"if you don't like it,
"you can sell back
your shares," and I did.
No, you didn't.
Please tell me you're joking.
No. I'm not joking.
Because he named his car
Howard? This is a joke?
You can't name a car Howard.
It's just not a name of a car.
Honey, enough about the name.
Let's get back to the shares.
You have to go back
and get your shares back.
I actually love
the name Howard.
I do. I was thinking
about the name last night.
Howard's a solid name.
Howard's a good guy.
There's a lot of good
Howards. They're average.
They're an average guy
doing average things.
And this is the campaign:
Solid, dependable, trustworthy,
that's our Howard.
The name that yesterday
you had nothing
but disparaging comments about.
I'm really sorry.
I am. I'm sorry.
Yeah. Sounds to me like
you're sorry you fucked up,
but not, you know,
not for what's underneath it.
I apologized.
That's what's important.
It doesn't matter if you
apologize if it's not sincere.
Apologies don't have
to be sincere.
It's just the act
of the apology itself.
It's only... all that matters
is if you're acting sincere.
That is literally
the only thing
an apology has to be,
is sincere.
Oh God, will, I completely...
- Otherwise, it's just words.
- I'm acting sincere.
Of course, I don't believe it.
Here at this company,
we believe in sincerity.
You had the opportunity
to meet my son yesterday,
the one thing in the world
that I happen to care about
more than this company.
What did you do?
Do you remember?
You talked about
his nanny's hair
and how much it might stink.
Nope. Never said
the nanny's hair stunk.
I never said that.
I never said it stunk.
You know what you didn't say?
- What?
- "Cute kid."
- I was gonna get to that.
- "What a nice son."
What a great job
you did raising your son
as a single parent.
"What a nice job,
seems like a good kid."
You know what,
you don't get to that.
You lead with it.
How could you lead with it
if somebody's shampooing
once a week.
Janine has your severance
package at the front desk.
Your things
have been packed up.
You can tell the delivery
company to take them
wherever you need them to be.
I'm sorry
it had to be like this.
Are you sorry?
Are you really sorry?
- No.
- You see?
You did the exact
same thing I did.
You apologized,
but you didn't mean it.
Janine has your things.
The delivery guys
need an address.
You know, I was an early
investor in this company.
I believe in this car.
I thought we were good friends.
Will, this isn't fair.
It's not fair.
The Howard is
the model t of it's day.
It's literally
a billion-dollar idea.
Will haney with the Howard
has built a better mousetrap
and changed American
culture forever.
And in the process
he and those smart enough
to have partnered with him
have become very, very wealthy.
Thanks for coming in, Nathan.
I know how
to get a hold of you.
Yeah. If anything
comes up...
Yeah.
Sure. Thank you.
Hey, did you see my plepler?
Who took my plepler?
[Door slams]
Kashman?
Anchorman:  Electron
motors' stock continued
it's meteoric rise.
That's good news
for everyone except this man,
Nathan flomm,
who sources say...
- That's you on the TV.
- Hey, that is you.
- Nathan? Nathan?
- No, no, that's not me.
- I have your drink.
- Shit, man, you lost
all that money.
What happened?
- That is huge.
- Like you never made a mistake.
Oh, come on.
Nate, come back.
Hey, don't you want
your coffee?
So what else is in the news?
Hey, have you guys heard
of Nathan flomm?
Yeah. Of course you have.
Like you never made a mistake.
Conan:  You think
you had a bad day?
This guy lost
a billion dollars.
He lost a billion, but
don't worry about him.
What little money he had left,
he invested it in enron.
[Audience laughs]
Thank you, rolly.
And I got you a little pickle.
Hmm, a pickle.
Half sweet, half sour.
Just like you.
I don't eat pickles.
You've been working
for me nine years.
You should know that, rolly.
You drive me crazy.
I just wanna eat in peace.
What do you think
you're doing to me?
Here. You don't want the pickle?
- I'll take the pickle. Ok?
- Please.
Yeah, get it out of my sight.
And don't eat it
in front of me.
- Oh, my God.
- It makes me sick.
I'm gonna tell you something,
it's fantastic.
I hope you choke on it.
♪ Happy Birthday to you ♪
♪ blah, blah, blah, blah
blah, blah ♪
- No. Oh dear...
- ♪ Bah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah ♪
- ♪ blah, blah, blah... ♪
- Oh, gee. Oh.
- Just for you.
- Oh, gosh.
That was quite awful.
It's your birthday.
I'm really looking forward
to getting wasted
with somebody who's turning 90.
That's gonna be a first for me.
Wow, that's
really sweet of you.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna watch cocoon?
- Ok. That's good. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Yeah.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Nathan flomm, marketing.
- What?
- Who's that?
- Oh, yeah, a guy.
The old owner must have left it
in the closet or something.
I don't know. What's the plan?
North oak tavern?
That's the plan.
Beer's on me.
What do you think?
- A Howard?
- Yup.
Half the people on
the island drive this.
Why should I be the only
asshole paying for gas.
[Chuckles]
Let's take my car.
Why would we take your car?
I got a brand-new car.
I wanna drive you
in it tonight. Come on.
I'd really rather
we take my car.
Come on. Get in. We're going.
I'm gonna show it to you.
Do you see
how the doors open up?
I know how they open up,
it was my idea.
What do you mean
it was your idea?
Well, I mean, you know,
I had that idea
a long time ago.
Well, then you should
sue the company.
- Watch this.
- Computerized voice:  Hi, Frank.
I'm ready, ready for
a nice big meal on you.
- Oh, on me?
- Absolutely.
I said one drink, I didn't say
drinking for the whole night.
What? Are you kidding?
It's my birthday.
You have to pay
for my... come on.
Surprise!
Fuck! My fucking nose!
- I'm so sorry.
- Oh, rolly...
Who is this guy?
- Look, you know...
- Uh-huh. You got me.
I'm really sorry.
Honestly, I just got
frightened, I guess.
I saw a face and I lashed out.
You're frightened
of a black man. Just say...
- [Speaking gibberish]
- I don't think so.
I don't think I was frightened
of the black man. No.
It could've been any black
person standing there.
It could've been
a black old lady
saying, "hey, surprise."
Are you gonna punch her
in the fucking nose?
- I don't...
- A little kid?
A dwarf, a black dwarf? Have
you ever seen a black dwarf?
Yeah. I would've punched a white
dwarf, too, and a white old lady.
You wouldn't have punched
a white dwarf.
No one punches white dwarfs.
They play around.
They pick them up. You never
punch a white dwarf in the face.
What, I have dwarf racism?
Of course, there's
always dwarf racism.
So you mean the white dwarf
is cuddly and cute...
White people are afraid
of black dwarfs.
I would find a black dwarf
just as cuddly as a white dwarf.
You're way off base there.
You'd pick them up and
punch them in the fuckin' face.
I'm really sorry,
and I beg your forgiveness.
We're good?
Very nice.
Honestly, you guys are great.
- Happy Birthday, rolly!
- To my boy rolly.
Ok. All right. Ok.
- Pretty good party.
- Rolly deserves it.
You know a lot of people
come into my diner,
I gotta tell you,
that rolly davore
is the nicest guy I know.
Yeah. [Laughs]
Happy Birthday.
- Thank you.
- Here, it's for you.
Oh. Wendy.
You know, that's one of
the benefits of breaking up,
I didn't have to spend
as much this year.
Looks like
you didn't spend anything.
I didn't. Yeah, I just was
cleaning out my drawer at home.
[Both chuckle]
How's the job hunt, anything?
[Sighs] Still looking.
There's nothing.
I gotta get out of that diner.
I smell like fried clams.
I can't take it.
- Well, I'll keep my ears open.
- Thanks, thanks.
Cake, there's gonna
be cake, right?
- I guess.
- Ok. Dancing?
- No.
- Yeah, come on.
Pussy.
You can't sleep
in the same bed with a woman?
No. I mean,
I enjoy the sex part,
but the sleeping part,
I'm not good at.
I need the space in the bed,
and I feel like
the air is contaminated
from the breathing.
They're shedding skin cells.
Skin cells? What are you,
a fucking microscope?
I just wanna close
my eyes and go to bed.
What else is there to do?
Happy Birthday, rolly.
[Laughs]
It's Jennifer.
Are you kidding me?
No, I'm not kidding you.
I lost a lot of weight.
I just can't get over
what I'm seeing.
It's me, it's just
a lot less of me.
That is incredible.
It is incredible.
It changed my life, rolly.
Everything good.
I got a new job.
I got... I'm engaged
to be married.
Really?
I'm engaged to be
married, yeah.
I'm surprised.
Why?
You know, you could have
a lot of suitors now.
Go off and get engaged
to the first guy you meet?
You're in demand.
Did he like you
when you were fat?
He never talked to me
when I was fat.
Ok, there you go. See, he's
superficial, just like me.
I wouldn't have dated you
when you were fat either.
- I'm sorry to say.
- What a terrible thing to say.
Yeah, I know, it's terrible
but it's true, it's true.
Huh...
Who is he?
His name is jaspar.
He's the guy you...
In the face when you walked in.
He's the guy over there.
[Laughing]
- Hey. Rolly, how are you?
- Hey. Hi, Carl.
Did you get that birthday
e-mail I sent you?
Oh, well, you know Carl,
generally, I gotta tell you,
I don't reply
to birthday e-mails.
You know, "thank you very much."
So kind of you.
Oh, you remembered."
It turns the birthday
into a job.
Yeah.
The birthday
shouldn't be a job.
We should be celebrating
a birthday.
We shouldn't be going,
"oh, it's my birthday,
- "I have to go to work."
- Yeah, you're right.
[Indistinct chatter]
- Hey, rolly.
- Hey.
- Oh, hey, Wendy.
- Great party.
- Thank you for the shoelaces.
Oh, you're very welcome.
She got me shoelaces
for my birthday.
Man:  Big fucking cocksucker.
Let me ask you somethin'!
What the fuck is that thing
you're building over there?
You wanna have a cup
of coffee, sober up?
That was my daddy's place, Mac.
Yeah, well, it's not his now.
"Well, it's not his now."
Not his now
'cause of guys like you.
You're fucking up
the whole island.
I was just hired to build
a house, that's all.
- Mcmansion, Mr. mcmansion.
- Come on, we gotta go, brother.
Blue heron's fucked!
The whole fucking
island's... fucked!
Please, honey...
I'm begging you.
Man:  You're
a mcfucking prick!
Waitress:
Stumpo, come on.
Well, there's
my favorite birthday boy.
I had such a great time
at your party last night.
It was a hell of a party.
Well, you deserve it.
You're the best guy.
Thank you, Gladys.
That's sweet.
All right. Let me know
if you need anything.
There's one little thing
that's kind of been on my mind
and I've been meaning
to tell you about it.
What?
I noticed that you put
the silverware on the table.
That's where you put
silverware.
It doesn't seem quite
sanitary to me.
It's clean. I cleaned it
right before you came in.
The last people left, I...
And how did you wash
the table, Gladys?
I have these cloths
that are like...
These rags?
- See what I mean?
- My rags aren't dirty.
Oh, Gladys, rags
by their very nature are dirty.
The rag is a filthy animal.
So what are you saying?
Why not put
the silverware on a napkin?
Terrific idea.
I'll get back to you, ok?
[Whistling melody]
Jaspar:
What the fuck, man?
You're telling Jennifer
she should date other people?
You don't want her dating a black
man, that's what it is, right?
No, no, no. Of course not.
And I said that to her before I
knew who she was going out with.
You're fucking me all up.
First you punched me and shit.
Now, you're telling
fucking Jennifer
that she should
date other people.
Who the fuck does that shit,
but a jealous, racist
motherfucker?
Oh, no, no, no.
You don't want her dating
a black man, that's what it is.
- No. That's ridiculous.
- It's gotta be.
I don't care who she dates.
You know how hard it is
to find a Cuban woman?
That shit ain't easy, man.
Three or four of them escape
Cuba every fucking day.
That's a low ratio.
They come over here on fucking
rafts and holding on wood
and floating their
ass over here.
Sometimes they float on other
fucking Cubans, sometimes.
They gotta use
a Cuban to float on.
Leave her the fuck alone,
man. Stay out of my shit.
Sorry.
Something about you.
I haven't put my finger
on that shit yet,
but there's something
about you, man.
You're fucking familiar to me.
You haven't seen me anywhere.
Maybe on TV.
I'll figure this shit out.
It will come to me.
Get the fuck out of here
with that wagoneer.
That's a white man's
fucking car.
Who the fuck rides
around with wood
on the side
of their fucking car?
Nobody does that shit.
Too much to the right.
Go to the left, rolly.
Come on, dig in.
That's a boy.
I... you know...
Who are you, captain bligh?
You can stop shouting
out instructions to me.
- I know what I'm doing.
- [Laughs]
[Airplane propellers buzzing]
Ooh, look at that.
Those must be the people
who bought Blue heron.
That's a shame.
That used to be a beautiful
piece of property
with a beautiful home on it.
It doesn't have the charm
that it used to
when the stumpos owned it.
I don't know
what they were thinking of.
[Voice fading]
Must have enough money...
[Indistinct chattering]
All right, looking good.
All this stuff is
going to the kids' gym.
We'll get it all unpacked
and everything...
Oh, hey, uh, great...
I wanted to tell him,
but I didn't have a chance.
A lot of these boxes in here,
the flat stuff, are mirrors,
so just be extra careful
with those.
Obviously,
no one wants bad luck.
I'm in your way.
[Laughs]
I'm so sorry.
You have a job to do.
Uh, I will let you
get on with it.
Thank you.
Back up, back up.
Just back up.
- Me?
- Yeah, back...
Right over here, there's
a place. Right over there.
- Are you kidding?
- No, come on.
You have a clearance
right around the bend there.
- I can't back...
- Of course, you can.
I'm way back there,
you should be backing up.
- Back up.
- Damn it.
- You're supposed to back up.
- Fuck you. Let's just go.
Asshole.
My clearance is
like 80 yards behind me.
He's got... just right around
a little bend, it's nothing.
- Right.
- And he won't back up.
I'll tell you this,
if that's happen to me again,
no way I'm backing up.
I don't give a shit who it is.
- Stand your ground.
- But it happens all the time.
Last time that happened to me,
I just pulled up, I wouldn't
move, he wouldn't move.
I get out of the car
and I started walking away.
The guy goes, "where are you
going?" I said, "I'm leaving.
You happy now, asshole?
You win."
And I walked
and I left the truck
and I went
to bridget tobert's house
and I just smoked a joint
and came out an hour later.
Truck's there,
he's gone, I win!
You guys ready to play
cards or what?
Yeah. What are we playing?
Chicago, highest spade
in the hole, splits the pot.
Speaking of Chicago,
anyone going to the concert?
- What concert?
- The Chicago concert.
They're coming back
to the island.
They haven't been here
for 20 years.
Wendy should be happy
about that.
- [Laughing]
- What does that mean?
Why should Wendy
be happy about it?
Last time they were here,
she blew the lot of them.
- [Laughing]
- Is that supposed to be a joke?
No! They came here
20 years ago,
she went to the concert
and she ended up
blowing the band.
- Allegedly.
- It's a rumor.
- Wendy blew Chicago.
- Wendy the waitress,
who I lived with
for three years, that's...?
- No, not the whole band.
- How many did she blow?
- What's the difference?
- There's a big difference.
If you blow one guy,
ok, I get it,
people blow people, it happens.
But what? We're not talking
about Simon & Garfunkel here.
This is Chicago.
That's a big band.
[Laughing]
Was it one? How many was it?
I know she blew Robert lamm
and James pankow.
- No way.
- Yeah.
Lee loughnane was
in on that, I will bet on it.
I don't wanna get you upset,
but as a friend,
I heard it was three.
But you don't wanna
get me upset?
- No, no.
- No.
You don't wanna get me upset,
but you heard it was three.
You're my friend,
I don't wanna get you upset.
Oh, no, I really
appreciate that!
"Your ex-girlfriend blew
three guys from Chicago."
You're not gonna get me upset.
You're all wrong.
[Whispers] It was four.
Fuck you, dottie.
Ok? If anybody was blowing
Chicago that night, it was you.
- [Laughing]
- I wish.
I'm gonna find out
about this, by the way.
I'll get you a picture
from when she was in high school
and you show it to the band
and see who remembers her.
- Ok. Yeah.
- They'll remember.
One thing I don't understand,
why do you care?
Everybody seems to know about it
except me and it pisses me off.
If I were you,
this whole Chicago thing,
I'd let it go.
Eh... we'll see.
- [Knocking on door]
- Who's this?
- I'll find out.
- Rolly, two to you.
Hey, everybody, this is my friend will.
I met him at the barge.
I wanted to show him
some island hospitality.
- Will, this is dottie.
- Hi, will, how are you?
Mike, Rick, rolly,
and that's Frank
- and that's molgy.
- For all your insurance needs?
Thank you very much.
Hey, I don't wanna
kiss your ass,
but I'm the proud
new owner of a Howard.
Thank you. It's been very
successful, been very good.
Who do I give money to?
- Oh, you brought your money, good.
- I did indeed.
We love new card players.
You're in.
Do we know one another?
I feel like...
I feel like we've met.
You thought I was a mover
a couple days ago.
You thought he was a mover?
Him? He's like
90 years old.
- No, I did not.
- [Indistinct chattering]
Starving seniors? It must've
been the shoulders.
I feel terrible.
I hope I tipped you.
[Laughing]
Dottie:  Hey, will,
is it true you have
an actual
bowling alley in there?
- We do.
- And a tennis court?
We don't have the tennis court.
Oh, just thought
I'd bring that up.
The basketball court
can be multipurpose,
so we can, uh,
we can work it out.
You guys ready to play
cards here or...?
Was there a guy,
like a few years ago,
is this true or is this myth,
about the guy who was like
your partner or something
when you started the company,
but he got out early
and then...
He would've ended up making
like a million dollars?
Yes. He was one
of our marketing guys
back when we were
just a little start-up,
and we were just about ready
to take the car public.
Had he kept that investment
stake in the company,
it would've been worth somewhere
in the area of a billion dollars?
- Oh!
- That's just his?
- Yeah.
- What an idiot!
[Laughter]
He must regret
every day of his life.
- Maybe he's happy.
- [Laughing]
- That's what I like to think.
- He's a broke idiot!
Maybe he has his integrity.
- I'd rather have 12 bathrooms.
- That's right.
You don't know
what he was thinking.
Maybe he wanted to get
away from the company.
Maybe he was an idiot.
Maybe he doesn't give
a fuck about money!
What do you know
about this guy?!
- I don't know shit about him!
- I know you don't.
Because he's a moron!
I wouldn't be associated
with somebody that stupid.
- Come on. Who's in?
- [Poker chips clack]
Here, you know what?
I'm gonna take off.
- Aw, come on, rolly.
- Come on, rolly.
Uh... we'll do it next week.
- All right, rolly.
- Nice to meet you.
- Ok, see you.
- See you next week, rolly.
- [Door opens, closes]
- What's eating him?
Everything ok?
His ex-girlfriend blew Chicago.
Yo, rolly.
What's going on?
Come take a walk.
Jesus, I just can't
even imagine this.
You never told anyone
about any of this?
No, I never told anyone
except your father.
He's the only one who knew.
Yeah.
I don't understand how
haney couldn't recognize you.
I mean, I would
recognize you if that...
No, I look
completely different.
How different could you look?
I mean, really.
All right.
How about that?
Holy shit.
You look like the guy who
kidnapped Elizabeth smart.
Yeah. That's me.
So, um...
I'm leaving the island.
Yeah. I can't stay
with this guy here.
Oh, come on,
your whole life is here.
Forget it. The guy's
at my poker game now?
I got to hear about his
garish monstrosity of a house
with bowling allies,
a gymnasium. Come on.
And I can't stay here
with him, on the island.
I just can't. I can't be here.
I can't be here. I'm leaving.
I wish there was something
I could do that, you know...
There's nothing anybody can do.
- I'll... yeah.
- We'll be able to hang out...?
[Line ringing]
Hi, it's Wendy.
Leave me a message.
- [Answering machine beeps]
- Hey, Wendy, it's me again.
So, you know, I spoke
to tibby and I told her
you'd make a fine replacement,
and she wants you
to call her tomorrow.
So, you don't have to smell
like clams anymore.
All right, see you.
[TV playing indistinctly]
TV announcer:
That's it for us.
Have a great night
and stay tuned
for the midnight matinee.
[Dramatic music plays on TV]
Man:  I couldn't help it,
Howard.
They started making changes
without any reason.
Everybody had authority
and nobody.
I tried to fight, they pushed
me from office to office.
Howard, what are
you going to do?
You have to leave
that up to me now.
[Loud explosions]
[Dramatic music continuing]
- [Dramatic music fades]
- Hey.
- Yo, what's happening?
- I gotta talk to you.
All right.
Step into my office.
You're nuts.
This is fucking madness.
You can't blow up
someone's home.
It's not allowed on the island.
It's not allowed
fucking anywhere.
You wouldn't hold up
well in prison.
You think leaving the island
is gonna be any better for me?
Is that supposed
to be a good life for me?
I don't know anybody anywhere.
All my friends are here,
my whole life is here.
My house is here.
He's already
ruined my life once,
is he's gonna ruin it again?
So you're just gonna
gonna end up in jail,
and get turned out
by some fucking Aryan dude
and become his boyfriend.
That's a better outcome to you?
Nobody's gonna rape me.
I'm an old, ugly man.
[Laughs] There might be
someone who would rape you.
I think they can do
better than that.
Well, there's probably
a dude in there
who has a fetish
for an old bald guy.
- A bald fetish...
- It could fucking happen.
I haven't seen
any women with one!
[Sighs] Where would you even
have gotten an idea like this?
The fountainhead.
Howard roark,
he blows up this building
at the end of the movie.
[Sighs]
Well, it is a pretty ugly house.
Nobody on the island likes it.
You'd probably be
considered a fucking hero.
Listen, nobody would get hurt,
nobody's gonna be
in the house when this blows up.
I'm just wondering,
how do I do it?
The only guy that I know
that could handle
something like this,
would be Joe stumpo.
Joe stumpo.
[Loud explosions]
Get the fuck out of here!
Hey, stumpo, it's me, Frank.
I don't give a shit,
get out of here.
Hey, Joe, can I talk
to you for a minute?
What do you want?
I know that your family
owned Blue heron
for a long time.
Three generations.
And I've seen what this
multi-billionaire has done
to your old property
and to the island.
He's destroying the island.
I wanna blow it up.
Why do you wanna blow it up?
I want him off the island.
- Is he fucking with me?
- He is not fucking with you.
You think you wanna blow it up?
I've thought about it
every fucking day
for 18 months.
Every time I drive
by the place I think about it.
I see it, I smell it at night.
I can smell the gunpowder.
You can't do it.
Access my friend, you need
access and I don't have it.
What do you mean access?
Access, you gotta get in
or have an inside man.
If I had a guy inside,
if I knew one of the workers,
but those pricks
don't even talk to me.
Inside guy, working
there, that could work.
Otherwise, get it out
of your head. Let it go.
Let it go,
get the fuck out of here.
Hey...
I know McKenzie.
Yeah, that's right.
You're gonna like this, stumpo.
He owes me a big favor.
- Really?
- I can go talk to him.
Maybe I can get a job there.
Rags!
Rags! Cocksucker,
come out here!
Who's this guy?
[Indistinct conversation]
[Sighs]
- It's a deal.
- There you go.
Nice job, Frankie.
Actually, I'm not involved
in this deal.
I was just here
to introduce you guys.
- Yeah, he's not involved.
- I'm not here.
When do we start?
How about tomorrow?
Who's this guy?
That's, uh, my associate,
he works for me.
Well, did... rags!
He's involved in this?
Yeah... trust me, he's fine.
You'll see him
and he'll be all right.
Uh, rags, this is, uh...?
- Rolly.
- Rolly. You know Frank.
You guys should know something
about me... full disclosure.
I, uh, on occasion...
Will talk in my sleep.
And I have a girlfriend
who, on occasion...
Sleeps over.
And, uh, she's got a big mouth.
All right.
Looking forward to it, man.
Button up, my friend.
Button up.
- Hey, McKenzie.
- Hey, rolly.
Can I have a word?
Yeah, sure, sit down.
Thank you.
What's up?
Well... [sighs]
Here's the situation.
You know I work for tibby
and, uh, lately, she's been
sexually harassing me,
putting her hand on my leg,
dressing suggestively,
things of that nature.
The point is,
I gotta get out of there.
I was hoping maybe I could,
uh, get something with you.
You're working on
Blue heron, right?
Nah, I don't think so. No.
I got a bunch of guys
I hire from a pool,
guys I worked with before.
[Scoffs] You know, I hate
to bring this up, McKenzie.
But, uh, I'm sure you'll
recall that a few years ago,
I found your dog,
in the woods, behind my house
and at the risk of my own
personal safety,
I brought it back.
I fed it and gave him
the rest of my meatloaf.
And he had a baked potato.
I didn't know dogs
ate baked potatoes.
And then we sat down and we watched
an episode of law & order.
And I fell asleep with
that poor dog in my arms.
And he must've had
some dog dream
because I woke up and he was
twitching and going like that.
And then, I woke up in the
morning and I called you.
You're saying I should give you
a job because you found my dog?
I got lyme disease
from that night.
I never told you about that.
Ok. I'll tell you what...
Only because I do appreciate
you saving lucky...
- ...we'll try it out.
- I appreciate it.
I won't let you down.
I'll work for you.
I'll do a good job for you.
Monday morning, eight o'clock.
See you then.
Eight o'clock.
Uh, rolly,
what are you doing?
So, um...
I couldn't help but notice
that my suggestion
has gone unheeded.
I heard you,
and, uh, I just decided
that I have
pretty good system here.
Well, you just saw
what I have to do.
I have to clean it in the water.
Now I need more water.
We're in a vicious cycle here,
of silverware into water,
into more water, on napkins.
The whole thing can be avoided.
It's disappointing.
I gotta get going
because I've got other people
I have to care of.
- You look real good.
- Thank you.
Sorry you had to wait.
It's still hot.
So, who are you having
lunch with there?
[Conversation
continues indistinctly]
[Wendy laughs]
[Chicago's "Saturday in
the park" plays over jukebox]
[Song continuing]
- [Song fades]
- Rolly.
- Hey.
- I got the job.
- Good going. Yeah!
- Thanks.
- I'm gonna start Monday.
- Wow. That's fantastic.
Thanks for the recommendation.
That was really nice of you.
My pleasure. I told you
I was gonna keep my ears open.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
- Good song.
- Awesome song.
- You like this band?
- I love these guys.
- Really?
- They're amazing.
How much do you love them?
I have four of the albums.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Huh. You go to the concert
here 20 years ago?
- I did.
- Yeah.
Me and my cousin Pam went.
And how was it, you had fun?
Oh, it was a great show.
They put on a great show.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And did you, by any chance,
blow them afterwards?
["Saturday in the park"
continues playing]
[Song fades]
McKenzie:  Yeah, let's really
get cracking on this wall, guys.
I wanna see you fitting,
and I wanna see you chipping,
I wanna see you on the machine.
I wanna see some real work
done on that wall today...
So, so sorry. Gentlemen,
so sorry I'm late.
Trying to take a shower,
hot water didn't come on.
Waiting, waiting.
You know what
I'm talking about?
Feeling, testing,
feeling, testing.
The hot water,
it takes a year to get hot.
I think you better put this on
while you're out here, ok?
- Ok, you guys, let's go.
- Really? Look at this. Huh?
- Ok, guys, let's get to work.
- Come on, get to work.
Take a walk with me, will you?
Remember Lee j. Cobb,
on the waterfront?
"Get to work!
You get to work!"
Never saw it.
Look, I think I got
a job for you.
- Yeah.
- It's not easy.
I want you to finish assembling
this swing set, all right?
First thing you do, dig some
holes, put concrete in there,
then put your
four-by-four in there.
Nothing to it.
Add water to that...
[Muttering] That...?
Yeah, yeah. And then
just put it in the hole, ok?
- [Speaks gibberish]
- Ok.
I'll check in on you later.
- No need.
- No, no.
- No need, I'm good.
- No. I'll check back.
Don't come back!
- [Tool sputters]
- Aah!
Hey!
McKenzie!
Wee!
[Grunts] Aw, fuck!
Excuse me.
Where's the bathroom?
Mr. cesspool.
[Toilet flushing]
Excuse me. Sorry.
Are you the heating guy?
I'm not the heating guy
per se, but I do heat.
So you can look at my system.
- Sure. Yeah.
- Great.
Thank you so much.
I've been having
real issues with it...
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Watch the cord here
because I can't
seem to get behind the couch
for the outlet.
You got an outlet
behind the couch?
They're always
behind the furniture.
- Not in my house.
- Really?
In my house,
my outlets are eye level.
There's no bending down.
There's no moving furniture.
There's no injuring backs.
Ok. That's a great idea.
I'm gonna talk
to McKenzie about that.
You don't... you don't
need to talk to him.
Yeah, no, I think I should.
- I'll mention to him.
- Ok, great.
- Yeah, don't talk to him...
- Ok, please do.
So listen, this is
what happens here.
Yeah.
See that, that's the temperature
it stays at all the time,
so whether it's cool
or whether it's hot.
- Uh-huh.
- So it just stays there.
It doesn't matter
if it's on 68 or 78,
it just is always
that temperature.
And I have no idea why...
There's an asterisk,
the asterisk,
it's a sort of a warning.
It's saying, "we're coming on."
Get ready,
we're gonna be warm soon."
Or "we're gonna be cooler,"
you know.
Can we just fix it?
I'm on it. On it.
- Will:  Rhonda!
- Yeah?
- I'm sorry. Hold on.
- Rhonda!
Hey, have you seen
my gray jacket,
the new one that I just got
with a black liner?
No. But why don't
you put on the seersucker.
I got it for your birthday,
it looks so...
I would put
the seersucker jacket on,
but my barbershop quartet
license just expired.
Well, you don't need to take
that kind of attitude.
- Rhonda!
- You know I don't like that.
I don't like it either. I've
had it with this whole thing.
Rhonda:
Don't you talk like that...
- We're done!
- [Door slams closed]
- Will, open the door.
- No, no!
Will, you've got
to stop doing this.
[Arguing continues indistinctly]
Rolly:  I was coming
out of the bathroom
and she asked me
if I was the heating guy
and now I'm in the house.
- That's great.
- Well done, newcomer.
Thank you, stumpo.
- I'm proud of you.
- Stumpo's proud of me.
He's never proud of people.
He doesn't dole out complements.
I don't like anybody. Go ahead
with your story, though.
It's not really a story.
I'm just saying
I'm in the house.
- Yeah.
- That's the end of the story.
It's not a story.
I didn't say it was a story.
- It's kind of a story.
- It's a nice story.
Joe:
Anyway, this is perfect.
She's complained
about the heating system.
We'll make it look
like a gas explosion.
We already have an alibi.
Hey, by the way, did you ever
hear a rumor about Wendy
blowing Chicago 20 years ago
when they were here?
Oh, yeah, she did.
Yep. That's a fact.
How do you know this?
My sister was there, saw it
happen. She blew them too.
How is Roberta doing?
- She's doing good.
- That's great.
Yeah. Now, you're
gonna need a detonator.
- I have to get the detonator?
- You gotta get a detonator.
- I'm not involved in this.
- Yeah.
I made the introductions,
but I was under the impression
that you guys were taking care
of all that kind of shit.
Well, you're
under the wrong impression.
How much is a detonator?
Not much. [Sniffs]
What's not much?
I don't know,
just not a lot of money.
What's not a lot of money?
I don't know.
What do you think?
What's a detonator gonna run?
- Not much.
- Yeah.
Ok. So you guys don't know
what a detonator cost, do you?
- No, no...
- You have no idea.
- We know what a detonator cost.
- You have no idea...
[Both muttering]
We've been around detonators,
trust us, we know.
We know exactly how much
it cost, it cost nothing.
It's not very important.
You're fixated on this.
Don't worry, it's nothing.
Where is he supposed
to get a detonator?
I know a guy.
Oh, that haney's such a jerk.
You should see
how he treats his wife.
Does he ever see you
around the house?
Yeah. Yeah. He thinks
I'm the heating guy.
He doesn't have any idea
who you are?
Oh, wait.
- Is this him?
- There he is.
My God, he's got a Howard?
Oh, he went with
the orange one.
Should I get out?
I'm rolly.
[With accent] I'm tibor.
Nice to meet you.
You want detonator?
What's that accent?
I'm from chechnya.
- Ah, chechnya.
- You have been to chechnya?
Tibor, I haven't been
to chechnya,
and may I be perfectly honest,
I mean no disrespect,
I never had any desire to go.
- You bring money?
- How much is a detonator?
One thousand dollars.
Really? Hmm,
$1,000 seems a tad pricey.
Oh, you have bought
detonator before?
- No.
- So how do you know price of detonator?
It's like if you go on
the price is right
and they bring out
a television.
You have to guess
what this thing cost.
Some people are off
by thousands of dollars.
You guess 1,000 and it's 6,000.
If I'm on the price is right,
and they bring out
the detonator, I'm saying $600,
- $500...
- Shut the fuck up!
All right. Ok.
You know, when you get older,
it's not so easy
to go through the bills anymore.
That's why you see old people,
you know,
they always go like this.
I'm starting to go
like this now.
This all the time,
you know, like fagin.
I'm doing this.
There you go.
This is detonator.
- Ok, this is it, huh?
- Good luck.
Computerized voice:
Hi, tibor.
- Oh, shit.
- What the fuck?
What the fuck?
You waved me to go
and then you hit me.
No. No, I didn't wave you to go.
I waved good-bye.
That's good-bye.
It was not good-bye.
It was not this.
It was like this,
like go. You said go.
- No, I didn't say go.
- I went and you hit me.
No, tibor, I did not say go!
I said good-bye.
Go, if I said go,
I would have gone go, go, go.
This is good-bye.
How do you misinterpret that?
Why would you wave
good-bye to me?
I don't fucking know you.
What do you mean
why would I wave good-bye?
It's polite. We had
an encounter, we talked.
I will get estimate,
ok, for Howard.
I will find you
and you will pay.
Hey, rolly.
Hey. You wanted to see me?
Um, yeah.
Uh, it was a little
chilly last night
and I just wanted to know
how it's going.
Well, first of all,
I'm really sorry about that,
but I gotta tell you something.
I'm working overtime
on this thing.
I'm sure.
The problem is the, um,
ecto-plexmatic tubes are
not connected, uh, properly.
[Children scream]
[Children shrieking, sobbing]
- You know what?
- Hmm?
Come with me because it's...
I left my hammer in the gym,
and I'll explain
the whole thing to you.
But you've got
a hammer on your belt.
Rolly:
No, my lucky hammer.
Can I ask you a question?
Do you know anything
about this fair on Saturday?
Oh. [Scoffs]
Are you kidding?
- The fair, of course.
- Yeah?
They have it once a year,
and everybody
on the island goes.
It's fun.
You know, there's rides
and there's a dunking booth,
you ever see one of those?
I love the dunking booth.
The dunking booth,
and they got like, best pig.
- Ok.
- And best Danish.
[Laughs]
[Sighs] Oh God,
it feels so good to laugh.
[Sighs] You know what?
My husband's leaving
this weekend.
I think that's
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna go to the fair
on Saturday. I'm gonna do it.
You know what,
you're a real vineyarder now.
- Mrs. haney?
- Uh-huh.
There's a package here
you need to sign for.
Ok, great. Um...
- See ya.
- Bye, rolly.
[Door closes]
- [Phone ringing]
- Yeah.
- Rolly:  Hey, stumpo.
- Hey.
Ok, get this.
Haney is gonna be
out of town this weekend.
His wife is gonna be
at the fair all day Saturday.
The house is gonna be empty.
You can do your recon,
take pictures, scope it out.
Beautiful. Ok, we'll case
the place on Saturday night.
Ok, see you.
I'm gonna follow
her from the gate...
- Right.
- ...Over to the fair.
If I see that she's heading
back, I'm gonna text you.
That should give you
plenty of time to get out.
All right.
Well, I gotta pee.
[Sighs]
See, they should have
pee flaps in cars.
Pee flaps... a little
flap, a cylindrical tube,
you pee right into the tube.
Wouldn't that be a great idea?
- Where does it go?
- Yeah, where would it go?
- Can't just let it out.
- Yeah. The same set-up as an airplane.
I don't think
you thought this through.
I'm just gonna be
honest with you.
There'll be piss
all over the roads?
Just use a bottle
like everybody else.
No. That one astronaut tried
to kill that other astronaut
- and she drove cross-country in a diaper.
- Oh, yeah.
That's a good idea,
a car diaper.
You do a car diaper, that makes
more sense than a pee flap.
A car diaper? That's
the worst idea ever.
You sell them at gas stations...
Hey, hey, hey.
There she is.
Get out, get out, get out.
I'll text you.
Well, well, well.
What a surprise, rolly.
Hey. Fancy meeting
you here.
- Meeting you, yeah.
- Yeah.
You know that swing set
I asked you to put together?
- Yeah.
- It collapsed.
I know.
I know all about that.
Yeah. Did you know there
were a lot of kids on it?
Did you know two of them are
in the hospital right now?
I followed
all the instructions.
You're fired.
- What?
- That's right, you're fired.
Turn in your helmet.
If anybody is getting fired,
McKenzie, it's gonna be you.
Rolly here has fixed
my exo-plasmatic tube
and done wonders
on your shoddy work.
"Ecto" what?
I'm sorry...
The flagellator... we can't
even find the flagellator.
- The "flaga" what?
- And the exo-plagmatic tube.
The heat has not been working
since I arrived
in this house, McKenzie.
I will take care of it.
If you're gonna fire anybody,
you're gonna come to me first
and you're gonna ask me.
- I'll take care of everything.
- Well, you better get on it.
- That's why I hired you.
- Nice to see you, Mrs. haney.
Yeah, nice to see you too.
Enjoy the fair.
I'm so sorry about that, rolly.
Blaming me for the swings?
Those poor kids.
I felt so horrible.
I feel so much
guilt about that.
I'm gonna visit those kids
in the hospital tomorrow.
- You are?
- I am.
- That's so sweet.
- Yeah.
By the way,
this is very fortuitous...
This is.
I must say,
bumping into you like this.
Excellent.
We should take in
the fair together.
- Let's do it.
- Oh, great.
Hey! Look at that!
- Right for the one I aimed...
- That was unbelievable!
What's over there?
[Laughs] That's all you got?
Come on. You can throw
better than that one.
Come on! [Laughs]
Hey, Mrs. Lee,
I want my nails do.
Oh, look who's here.
I wanna talk... ooh!
[Indistinct conversation]
Oh, it's disgusting.
No, I'm literally
gonna throw up.
How could you drag me here?
I'm sorry.
Here's the itinerary, ok?
Ok.
Ferris wheel next,
then we go
right to the big tent.
Oh, that's cute.
- Oh. Oh, yeah...
- Who's Bartholomew gosnold?
Rolly:  He's the founder
of the vineyard, and Martha is
his grandmother,
maybe his daughter.
I don't know.
- Martha's vineyard.
- Yes, yes.
Ah, of course.
Rolly:  Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Let's do it.
Let's be pilgrims.
- Pilgrims?
- Yes.
- Really looking forward...
- I got it. I'm gonna get it.
- Come on.
- Let me get it.
- No!
- I'm doing it.
Hi, um...
Yeah, look at you over there.
Taking pictures. [Chuckles]
Must be nice, huh?
Come around here,
pretend to be
somebody else, huh?
You just jump in another
motherfucker's body, huh?
[Laughs]
Oh, look at this on my phone!
Motherfucker named Nathan.
I knew your ass looked
familiar to me.
- How you doing, Nathan?
- Shh! Quiet.
No, you be quiet.
You know what
Jennifer told me now?
That she wants her space.
You put that shit in her head.
"Space" means "I wanna be
with somebody different."
No, no. She's saying
she wants her space.
It's like space.
You're alone in space,
the planets aren't
near each other.
It's the black void of being
alone in a black void.
So no one wants to be
near a black void?
- I'm a black-ass void now?
- No, you're not a black void.
You're talking about me. I'm
the blackest motherfucker here.
- You're not a black void!
- Man, I'm about to smash
the rest of that fucking hair
out your goddamn head.
I can read between
the lines and shit.
Oh, no. That's crazy.
You fuck my life up, I will
fuck your life up, Nathan.
Tit for tat.
Tit for tat? There's no tat,
there was no tit.
If I see Jennifer
with another man,
going fucking crabbing,
antiquing, getting
pushed on a swing,
this whole charade you're
doing right now, it's over.
I'm telling everybody, Nathan.
[Woman laughing]
[Lively chattering]
Ok. Oh, that's funny.
That's a funny story.
- Ha ha.
- What a funny story.
- This is my friend, rolly.
- See you later. Take care.
Ok. You're
gonna friend me, ok.
Get lost.
Don't forget.
I'm gonna Facebook you for sure.
Ok. Take care.
What's going on here?
- Oh, having fun.
- You're having fun?
Meeting people, thanks to you.
What about jaspar?
I don't wanna have
just one man.
It's the time
to have fun for me.
Thanks to what you told me,
you made, like,
a light go off in my head.
Ok. It was
a stupid thing to say.
Jaspar's nice
for somebody else.
I wanna, you know,
I wanna see what's outside.
I got some news
for you, baby. Ok?
You're gonna gain
the weight back.
Then there's not gonna be any
jaspar, then you're gonna be alone.
You're gonna gain
the weight back.
What is that...
Why do you gotta say that?
What do you mean? You're going
to, that's what happens.
Nature abhors a vacuum.
- It wants to fill up...
- It wants to pour the vacuum.
No? [Laughs]
Doesn't a vacuum suck
something up,
like when you vacuum?
You're gonna get fat again.
Well, you know what?
I changed my lifestyle,
I'm not gonna gain
the weight back. Ok?
You wanna make a little bet?
- I'll make a big bet. - Yeah, how much?
- Not a little one, let's make a big one.
I'll make a big one.
Fifty bucks.
- Fantastic. That's it?
- Yeah, that's it.
- I'll do more.
- Fifty bucks.
Just do me one favor.
Before you start dating
other men,
will you just think about it?
Give it a little time.
You claim to want your space.
Well, now give it some time.
Time and space, they work
together. They're partners.
How much time do I need to?
A long time.
- A long time?
- Yes.
Take my time.
Be by myself.
- Yeah.
- I'll think about it.
- Ok. Come on.
- Let me give you a call.
- You deserve a free coffee.
- Give me a hug. Ok.
- Ok. This is fantastic.
- Ok.
You're gonna think about it.
What kind of coffee you want?
- A vanilla latte.
- I'll make it myself.
- Ok.
Vanilla latte!
What are you doing here?
I have estimate for you.
What is this? Have
you been following me?
This is not important to you.
What is important to you is
I am here
and I have estimate for you.
- Ok.
How much is the estimate?
Thirteen-hundred dollars.
Really?
Thirteen-hundred dollars?
- This is what it costs.
- Where'd you get this estimate?
I got it from vlad's body shop.
- Vlad is a chechen.
- What's the problem?
You're in chechen cahoots.
- No, it's chechen coincidence.
- Oh, that's a coincidence?
- I want to ask you something.
- Yeah.
You have problem
with chechen people?
Me? Are you kidding?
I adore the chechen people.
You're one of my top
five ethnic groups.
- Really? Listen to me.
- Yeah.
I don't have time to fucking
talk with you all day.
No, of course not.
You pay the money
or you have big fucking problem.
One vanilla latte.
Hey, thank you.
- It's on the house.
- You're sweet. Thank you.
Enjoy the fair, rolly.
So what is this Cuban coffee?
Rolly:  Oh, look at this.
Rhonda:
It's funny, isn't it?
What a great picture.
Um...
So I'm gonna head home.
What? No.
You can't do that.
- Really?
- May I ask a question?
Sure, rolly.
When was the last time
you were on a Ferris wheel?
- Really?
- Yes. Here.
- All right. All right.
- Come on.
Ferris wheel and there's
piglets to see too.
- There are piglets?
- There's little piglets.
Ok. [Chuckles]
Let's do it.
Joe:  Give me a measurement,
right here, of the duct.
Here, hold on.
It's from rolly.
"I can't hold her much longer."
All right. Come on.
Let's hustle it up.
- Yes!
- Huh?
Huh? What did I tell you?
- That was so much fun.
- That was excellent.
I haven't done that in so long.
Rolly:  What?
Because of the silverware?
- No. That is not...
- But it's neon, it's cute.
It's not you. You know, you're
lighting up, "I'm an asshole."
White's a good color.
I like white.
A little fur
with those little tie things.
I don't know...
Hey, you know what?
Let's get outta here.
Wait, wait.
I wanna get a hat.
- I don't think so.
- No? Nothing?
- No.
- Ok. Well...
I'm not a hat person?
He doesn't like me in hats.
Well, if she really
wanted to buy it,
she would have bought it.
She's blaming it on me.
I had nothing to do with this.
You know, except for the rides
and then the food, it was
actually pretty good.
- I can't believe the junk you ate.
- Made me so happy.
It's unbelievable.
How are my teeth?
Good?
I think you're ok?
Let me see your teeth,
let me see.
- Hmm. You're good.
- Yeah?
You have a... hold on...
A little smudge.
There.
[Sighs] All right.
This was the best day,
excellent.
So, good night.
I'll see you at the house.
- Ok.
New plan.
Instead of blowing up
the house,
I'm gonna steal haney's wife,
marry her and take
half his money.
Oh, you gotta be...
- What? Is this a joke?
- It's not a joke. No.
It's not a joke?
It's stupid.
You think she's gonna leave
her young, handsome,
- billionaire husband...
- Oh, yes.
For a broke, bald old dude?
I know when I have a connection
with somebody, ok?
This woman likes me.
Really?
Oh, it's there. It's there.
I love you so much.
I have to tell you something.
I spoke to the doctor...
And I've decided to stop
the treatments.
[Crying] Oh, no.
No, no, no.
No! No!
I took her to the fair
yesterday.
She asked me for a tooth check.
A tooth check, come on.
- It means nothing.
- Who the fuck cares? That's means nothing.
Rags will give me a tooth check.
All the time.
- Right...
- You guys do tooth checks?
- Sure.
- Constantly.
I might have kale
in there or something.
She wiped
some smudge off my cheek
when I said good-bye to her.
It was probably annoying her.
Rolly:  No!
Yeah. She's like,
"get that shit off your face."
What about our plan?
What about me?
Where does that leave me?
Where does that leave
the fellas?
That's a very legitimate
question, stumpo.
Once I marry her
and get half her money,
it's gonna leave you with
a million fucking dollars
for each of you!
- [Shouting, laughter]
- And after I move in,
we invite everybody
on the island
to come watch us
blow up the house.
- We blow up the house?
- We blow up the house!
And it's all legal.
I own it.
[Laughing]
How's my plan now?
You're so brave.
Will:  I'm just hope
the house is ready in time
for the first busload of kids
that are going through. [Sighs]
- This is for them.
- Yeah.
They should have
a beautiful place to come
with their family to fight off
this... terrible disease.
[Sighs] I love you so much.
I love you.
Good morning.
- Rolly.
- Hey, Rhonda!
Good morning, ray.
- How you doing?
- Rhonda:  Good morning.
Got a little surprise for you.
They call it vanilla latte.
Aw, you're the best.
I observed you the other day,
I saw what you ordered.
I took a little note, you know.
And you in the seersucker.
- Mm? What do you think?
- Wow.
I mean, it takes a lot
to pull that off.
[Scoffs] What? Are you kidding?
I was raised on seersucker.
Got bar mitzvahed
in seersucker.
I got a closet full of these.
- Well...
- It's all I wear.
- You wanna come inside?
- Love to.
- Hey, asshole.
- Man:  What?
What the hell
are you looking at?
- Get the fuck over here.
- Yes, sir.
Throw those bags in...
God damn it!
You know what? That lid, that
sippy lid with the hole in it.
- Yeah?
- I invented that.
Really? You know
what else you invented?
- What?
- Ah. [Chuckles]
- Oh, my God.
- They look so great. I really love them.
I hope it really catches on.
I gotta tell you something.
Because I would love to be
remembered
as the guy who invented
the eye-level outlet.
What a legacy that would be.
Yeah. It would be amazing.
And then you could get into
designing the plates...
- Hey.
- Rolly:  Hey.
You have coffee.
You need coffee?
Oh, no thanks.
Yeah. Rolly got me
a vanilla latte.
Rolly:
She likes lattes.
Look at the jacket.
- Yeah, it's seersucker.
- Yeah. Sharp.
I never could get my head
around seersucker.
Really?
It's a nice look.
Hey, guys.
Look at the skiers.
Will:  Oh, wow.
Look at that. What a day.
Let's go water-skiing.
We gotta take out the new boat.
I know, but I cannot
do it. It's a...
Hey, you know what?
I'm happy to take
you water-skiing.
You want me to...?
My friend Frank
can drive the boat.
Take it out.
It's there to be enjoyed.
- I love it.
- Sure.
- You should enjoy it.
- Yeah.
- Those guys are good.
- She wants to go. That's fine.
- I'd love it. Let's do it.
- No, it looks great.
- Dad. What's going on?
- Hey, there he is.
How are you?
- Howard, this is rolly.
- Rolly.
He's helping us out around
the house a little bit.
- Hello, Howard.
- Run upstairs, grab a shower,
- we'll go get something to eat.
- All right. Sounds good.
- Ok. See you, bud.
- All right. Hey, rolly.
- Yeah?
- It's good to meet you.
Yeah. Nice to meet you, Howard.
- Will:  See you, bud.
- Howard:  See you.
Oh, my God.
What a kid.
Man, oh, man.
What charisma.
He lights up a room, this kid.
- Rhonda:  He does.
- He lights it up.
- Can I say something crazy?
- Yeah.
I think this kid
could be president.
I'm not kidding.
He's got that aura.
Or at least a senator.
- The girls are all over him.
- A councilman, a city council.
- A councilman?
- That kid could be in the city council.
You're very sweet,
thank you so much.
At the very least a dentist.
Frank:  I fucking doubted you,
but you were right.
She fucking loves you.
- Did I tell you?
- You told me.
- Was I right?
- You were right.
- Am I crazy?
- You're not crazy.
And how dumb is
the fucking husband?
Oh, my God.
Moron!
He let you take
her water-skiing?
- Water-skiing, take her!
- Unbelievable.
I wonder where we should live?
I know I made fun
of the bowling alley.
To tell you the truth, between
you and me, I love to bowl.
Oh.
- We'll get a league going.
- Let's start a league.
- We'll start a league in the house.
- We'll bowl in the house.
[Laughs]
I wonder if she'll let me
date other people.
Rolly:  Hey.
Oh, my God.
You were incredible.
- That was pretty impressive.
- Oh, thanks.
- That was awesome.
- Oh, boy.
- Congratulations.
- Whoo-hoo.
- That felt so good.
- Here you go.
All right. I've been
hogging all the time.
It's your turn, rolly.
You wanted to get out there.
- Yeah. I know, but...
- Here's the wetsuit.
I've checked every
database available to me.
I've checked with my friends
around the country
in law enforcement.
I even checked morgues
and hospitals.
This guy, Nathan flomm,
it's like he's fallen
off the face of the earth.
I need to find this man
and repay him what I owe him.
He's gotta be
out there somewhere.
- Rolly:  Stop!
- I don't understand.
Rolly:  Stop the boat. Stop!
Will:  I've been looking
for him for ten years.
- Rolly:  What are you doing?
- I need to right this wrong.
Hurry!
We must find him.
- Rolly:  I'm drowning!
- We must.
Throw the fucking thing!
Throw it!
[Tinkling]
[Knocking on door]
I told you I would find you.
Well, what a pleasant surprise.
Look at this, it's tibor.
Where is the money for the car?
I don't quite have it
on me, but I'm...
- You don't have it on you, eh?
- I will definitely...
I will tell you
something now, ok?
If you don't
give me this money...
Yeah.
I will have to take
something from you.
- Yeah. Mm-hmm.
- Ok?
I will take something
from you very, very important.
You will take something
important, ok.
Perhaps I will take a ball.
Ok. You'll take a ball.
Yes, a ball.
I see. Very nice of you
not to take two.
You could be taking two.
This is a testament
to your character, tibor.
You could be taking two balls,
you're only taking one.
I think that's very nice.
I want for you now
to stop all talking.
- Ok.
- And to give me the fucking money, ok?
I promise you, I'll be giving
you that money within two days.
That's a scout's honor promise.
[Silently] Sorry.
Rolly:  Oh, no.
Hey, tibor.
Can I talk to you
for one second?
Hey, uh...
You and Jennifer, huh?
What is it to you?
Well, I was just curious.
You're dating?
She's nice girl.
Oh, lovely, lovely girl.
But there's something
I need to tell you.
What do you need to tell me?
She blew Chicago.
The city?
The band.
"25 or 6 to 4" Chicago?
- Yes. Yes.
- How do you know this?
It's common knowledge.
Everybody on the island
knows this.
She blew Chicago?
It's not such a big deal.
You blow people.
People blow people, it happens.
Eh... it's not so bad.
[Chicago's "Saturday
in the park" playing]
- Tibor:  Good song.
- Awesome song.
- You like this band?
- I love these guys.
You love them, huh?
How much do you love them?
Oh, I have, like,
four of their albums.
Tell me. You go to concert
here maybe 20 years ago?
- I had a blast.
- Oh, you had a blast, huh?
Let me ask you
one more question.
Did you perhaps go
backstage after show?
Jennifer!
["Saturday in the park"
continuing]
Jennifer!
What the fuck?
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Look at this.
- So funny.
How about that, huh?
Crazy.
That's funny.
All right.
No, no. You back up
'cause you've got, your
clearance is much closer.
Your clearance isn't far back.
It's right around the corner.
Your clearance is
right around the corner.
My clearance is a little bit
further than around the corner.
- Rhonda...
- It just is.
I know where
the clearances are.
Rolly, I've been driving
this road every day.
Rhonda, I've been
here ten years.
I know every clearance
on the island.
You need to back up.
Why should I back up?
You got a little tiny car.
I'm sorry. I can't even believe
we're having this conversation!
I don't believe it either!
Your clearance is
right behind you.
You want to bet
some money on that?
Yeah, I wanna bet
a lot of money on that!
Oh, and you have
the money to put on it!
- Move your car. Rolly!
- What?
- Back up your car.
- No, back up your car.
Oh, my God.
Are you out of your mind?
- I'm out of my mind? What?
- Are you kidding me?
It's not that hard!
[Loud arguing]
Vineyard etiquette dictates
that the person closest
to the clearance...
- Vineyard etiquette?
- ...Moves back.
- No, you back up your car.
- What, you have a Howard,
you're entitled to do
anything you want, is that it?
I didn't say
that my Howard entitled me
to not move backwards.
- Back up your car.
- No, you back up your car.
- No, you back up.
[Grunting]
[Spits, sputters]
[Sputters]
Are you crazy?
Are you out
of your fucking mind?
No good?
Crazy old man!
I love my husband.
"No good," rolly.
I thought there was a little...
Yeah. Get in your car
and back the fuck up! Back up!
[Muttering] The smudge...
You gave me a smudge thing.
A smudge?
Yeah. A tooth check. [Mutters]
- Get in your car!
- I'll get in the car.
- A smudge?
- Sorry.
What are you,
in fucking middle school?
A misunderstanding.
I don't know what I was
thinking. I don't know.
No, you placed too much emphasis
on a tooth check
I don't know what I was
I can tell you that right now.
Tooth checks don't mean
what they used to be, you know.
Rags:  So what now,
what do we do now?
Back to plan a.
This is exactly what we should
have done in the first place.
Now we're right back,
full circle, it's on.
Am I right? Come on. Let's go
blow that fucking house up.
Am I right?
Ok.
Good news. Hot dog!
What's the plan?
Well, next week's
the Chicago concert.
I know that haneys are going,
nobody's gonna be home.
All right. The day of the
Chicago concert, that's it.
This is great. This is great.
Do me a favor, will you?
Sure.
There's a painting
of mine in that house.
- Ok.
- It's a plepler.
He stole it from me.
It's a painting
of a shopping cart.
- It's a painting of a shopping cart...
- Shopping cart.
Is a plepler is a type of shopping
cart or is that who painted it?
[Whispers] What does
it matter to you?
We're in. The day
of the Chicago concert,
all hands in.
Hands in.
I'm not involved,
I'm just a liaison.
Come on, fellas. Put our
hands in. Go on in there.
Put your hand in there.
Nice work.
I'm gonna fix
that bald-headed motherfucker.
- [Door opens]
- Wait until you hear this bullshit.
Hey, you better
hold on to these.
I plan on getting fucked up.
All right. I'm gonna meet you
in the lobby in a few minutes.
- I gotta do something.
- Whoo! Fucking Chicago!
- Do you have a pass?
- No.
I can't let you in
without a pass, my man.
I'm gonna level with you, ok?
- Ok, level with me.
- Here's what happened.
My ex-girlfriend, who I lived
with for three years,
I found out now that
it's possible that she had
some kind of oral activity
with them 20 years ago
after they played here.
So it's kind of...
It's bugging me
and I need... I just want
to find out if it's true.
I understand
you might wanna know,
but I just can't let
you back here without a pass.
Ok. Yeah, you did a good job.
- You're doing your job.
- That's what it is.
Where do they want us for this photo shoot?
Excuse me...
I'm not a nut. I just
have one quick question.
- I'm sorry. One question.
- Yeah. Sure.
When you guys were here,
um, 20 years ago,
do you remember getting blown
by a woman named Wendy?
- [Laughter]
- What?
- You're serious?
- Sorry to be so blunt.
Twenty years ago?
Rolly:  And this is
what she looked like.
- That's a long time.
- Yeah. I do remember her.
- I don't know.
- You do? Really?
- Yes.
- I don't know.
Oh, yeah that was me.
Yes. I remember her.
She was a lot of fun,
wasn't she?
- Yeah, she was.
- I think that was you.
- You and you?
- Both:  Yeah.
- Two?
- Definitely. Yeah.
Wendy.
Hmm. Ok.
I was with another chick.
Roberta stumpo?
- Yeah.
- Roberta St...
Thanks for clearing that up.
Appreciate it.
- Whatever.
- Roberta stumpo...
Can't believe
how good that show was.
Hey, that's Nathan flomm!
That's the guy that
lost a billion dollars.
That's him.
Hey, rolly, what's the deal?
Are all these rumors true?
Are you Nathan flomm?
Just be honest.
- Everybody knows.
- Yeah. I know. Jaspar.
- I think I'm gonna go home.
- Go home?
I can't stay here,
this is horrible.
No, it's...
It's embarrassing.
I don't wanna be here.
Who cares if it's embarrassing?
This is your alibi, remember?
Right.
[Loudly] How dare you,
Nathan flomm,
come to the Chicago concert!
That's good.
How dare you! Get the fuck
out of here, Nathan flomm!
- Man:  That's him, flomm.
- Jerk.
Man:  That
billion-dollar guy?
I would like to speak
with please, um,
Mr. Robert lamm
or members of Chicago band.
Do you have a pass?
I have problem.
My friend, uh,
they say she has had, um,
oral intimacies
with the... with the band.
And I want to know
for me is this true.
Is her name Wendy?
- No.
- Roberta?
No. Her name is Jennifer.
Jennifer? All right.
I'll be right back.
[Chattering]
You got a tissue?
Why would I carry
a tissue around?
Why wouldn't you have a tissue?
It's not inconceivable.
I would leave my house
and take tissues
before I leave,
just put them in my pocket?
I take tissues sometimes.
"Rolly," my ass.
You let me read
about that in the newspaper?
Big whoop, I blew the lead
singer from Chicago.
That's not nearly half as bad
as what you did.
First of all, it wasn't
one guy from Chicago.
I spoke to them,
I went backstage.
You blew two Chicago-ans! Two!
You know what's worse?
Blowing an impostor.
That's worse.
[Scoffs] Rolly.
Tibby, what are you doing
at the Chicago concert?
Hey!
[Laughs]
I can't believe it's you!
It's really you!
Honey, rolly...
Rolly is, is, is Nathan.
You should have seen
this guy ten years ago,
with the beard and the hair.
My God. It was...
It was crazy.
I mean, one of the best
marketing guys in the world.
What are you doing?
Why didn't you...
Why didn't you tell me
you were you?
Things ended
so badly between us,
and I needed the work...
The work? You must've seen
the painting, in my house?
- Yeah, I did.
- The shopping cart.
Yes. I wondered what
it was doing there.
I kept it all these years,
three houses, remember?
Yeah.
And I kept it to remind me
that I did not treat you right.
I've been looking
for you for ten years
to try to repay you
your share of this company,
from the beginning,
your original stake,
your ten percent share.
I'm prepared to make
that good. [Chuckles]
Are you kidding me?
You're gonna do that for me?
- You're doing that?
- I need to.
Rags:  Your hands shaking?
Did you have a drink today?
No, I didn't.
I thought I'd try something new.
Today of all days,
you didn't have a drink?
Nope, I didn't have a drink.
I got myself a smoothie.
[Shouts]
[Phone dialing]
- Come on, stumpo!
- Ah, yes. It's Joe stumpo.
If it's business related,
leave a message. [Beeps]
Pick up, stumpo!
Announcer:
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome,
to Martha's vineyard,
- Chicago!
- [Concert crowd cheering]
Rig.
Pick up!
Come on, stumpo.
Stumpo!
[Woman] There's a car coming!
A car coming. Stop! Stop!
Please, please, stop!
Help us, please!
- Oh. Rolly?
- [Woman moaning]
Oh, thank...
It's rolly, Joyce.
It's all right, Joyce.
It's all right.
Rolly, thank God!
[Crying] We had
a horrible accident.
You have to take us
to the hospital.
Rolly, I think I broke my arm.
Rolly, help me get her
into the car.
You know what?
It's not a good time.
- I'm sorry.
- What?
I absolutely, I have
to get going. I'm sorry.
You're not gonna help us?
I thought you were nice.
- I am nice!
- You're gonna leave us here?
What can I do? I have to go?
You rude prick!
I sent you a birthday e-mail
and you never even answered it.
No. No. I don't respond
to birthday e-mails.
I never have.
It's just that I get so many.
You are such an asshole.
You are not nice!
No. I'm nice. I'm very nice.
I'm a living doll.
- You're not nice.
- I'm nice. I'm nice.
- You're a dirty bastard.
- I'm really nice. I'm sorry.
- You're a fucking asshole.
- I hope your dick falls off!
You're a motherfucking asshole!
[Beeps]
- [Beeping]
- What's that? Beeping?
What's beeping?
No, no, no, no, no!
Damn it! No!
[Slurred computer voice]
Good-bye, Frank.
Howard! You fuck!
[Yells]
You piece of shit!
Fuck!
[Children singing]
Rolly:
Stop it!
Call it off!
- I changed my mind!
- Get back! Get back!
[Children singing]
- I changed my mind!
- Get back!
[Cheers, laughs]
Yeah! Come on!
We're gonna get out of here.
Hey, we got you your painting.
This is a car!
I said a shopping cart!
- You said car.
- I said cart!
- [Honks horn]
- We gotta go.
We'll take you in the car!
Come on! Come on!
[Distant sirens wail]
Come on!
Where are you going?
[Sirens approaching]
[Chicago's
"if you leave me now" playing]
Are you excited? You ready
to get back into things?
Back into what?
Future's wide-open now.
Really?
What am I gonna do?
I don't know.
Maybe you could, uh,
become a wizard,
find the hobbits
and help them destroy the ring.
You don't like my look?
If you do decide
to change your name again,
Gandalf could be
a good way to go.
How's Wendy doing?
She's actually
doing pretty good.
You know, when tibby passed,
she left her
everything she had.
And it turns out
the old broad had millions.
Beautiful out here.
[Chicago's "colour my world" playing]
How you doing?
Heineken.
- No.
- Oh, my God.
- [Chuckles]
- Holy Christ.
Mm-hmm.
What are you gonna do?
Yeah. What are you gonna do?
- The whole scandal. My God.
- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Everybody knew about it.
And you went to jail.
- Oh, my God.
- Jail. Yeah.
You survived. You look good.
Did you got raped?
- No. No.
- No. Oh, good.
- Who's gonna rape me?
- Oh, my God. Good. Thank God.
- I raped a few people there.
- No. No. No. You're kidding.
- [Laughs]
- No. Please say you're kidding.
- Yes. I'm kidding.
- Thank God. Oh, my God.
But, hey, I'm really
happy to see you. Wow.
And I'm happy to see you.
But, uh, it's
a different you, isn't it?
No. It's the same me.
You owe me 50 bucks.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm so sorry.
[Chuckles] You certainly do.
- No. I think it was a miscommunication.
- I don't think so.
- I think it was a miscommunication...
- I know it wasn't.
But I tell you what,
you can take me out to dinner.
Like as a way to pay you back?
Absolutely.
Like a date?
Like a date.
Fantastic. When?
Tomorrow.
On one condition.
You take a shave.
- You got a deal.
- Got a deal?
- For you.
- [Slurps]
I can't wait.
Me either.
- [Loud laughter]
- Unbelievable!
Is your cousin stinky
still working on cars?
- Nah, he sucks.
- Oh, man.
[Indistinct chatter]
All right. Come on,
let's play some cards.
[Cheers, lively chatter]
- Wow!
- All right.
- This is awesome, man.
- Good to see you, brother.
- Good to see you.
- Pull up a chair.
Oh, look.
I got my old spot back.
You got all cleaned up.
I was prepping these dudes
for the homeless wizard look.
Yeah. I got a little
shave and a haircut.
I didn't want to scare
anybody, you know.
Hey, what do we call you?
Rolly? Nathan? What...?
Rolly.
- Rolly it is.
- Yeah. Rolly.
- Welcome home.
- Thank you very much.
So, rolly, am I the first
woman you've seen
since you've been out?
Dottie, you're the first.
You and me, come on,
let's go. Let's do it.
You're the first, dottie.
- [Laughing]
- Rolly:  What's the game?
Five-card draw. I think
that's your favorite, isn't it?
Same shit-game that he always
plays, nothing's changed.
[Laughing]
Ante up, you guys.
Well, whether you
know it or not, rolly,
you have become a bit
of a hero in these parts.
A lot of people
were happy to see
that monstrosity of a house
hit the dust.
- Local hero.
- You're the guy.
Ballsy move.
Your three years in prison was
worth getting rid of that house.
- Absolutely.
- Hey, what happened to money bags?
They got him on some treatment.
He's in remission.
- They went back to California.
- No kidding?
Are they ever coming back
to the island?
I don't think they should,
knowing that rolly's
back in town.
Oh, yeah.
What am I thinking?
[Lively chatter]
All right, ante in.
My only regret, rolly,
is that you missed
the Chicago concert that night.
My God! Best show
I've ever seen.
The entire island was there.
- They were great.
- Yeah. All three encores.
Everybody had a great time,
especially the band.
Rolly:
Why is that?
Jennifer blew them
in the parking lot.
- I forgot about that.
- Jennifer? The whole band?
- Lee loughnane, for sure.
- Definitely Jimmy pankow.
No. No. Not pankow. It was
loughnane and Robert lamm.
Dottie:  No.
It was all three.
[Laughing]
[Chicago's "does anybody really
know what time it is?" Playing]
== sync & corrections by Alice ==
== www.Addic7ed.Com ==