Hi, Leonard!
How are you doing?
Heh heh heh heh!
Ha ha!
Ricardo, I see you're feeling
better. Good for you.
(Children laughing)
Hey, father cliff.
Hello, Victor, boys.
What's the story on Roger?
Is he getting
booted out of here?
I hope not.
But he's a bad kid.
You weren't exactly
a Saint when you first
got here, were you?
Lest we forget.
(Laughs)
Got me there.
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Good-bye, boys.
¶ ...was a little,
little man
¶ and a little, little man
was he
¶ he climbed up
to a sycamore... ¶
uh!
Who's...
I say, who's throwing...
Ow!
Father Clifford.
What are you doing, Roger?
Are you running away?
Who, me?
No, no.
What would make
you think that?
I just,
uh... I lost
my balance
while cleaning
my outside
windows.
Cleaning your windows
with a suitcase, were you?
Oh, Roger!
Oh!
Roger!
My heart...
It hurts.
Whoa...
(Thud)
Oh, no!
Oh, look who's recovered!
Let go of me!
Now, now, now, what
seems to be the problem?
(Crying) Oh...
Now, now, now, now, now...
(Roger) Whenever there's
something I
really, really want,
there's always some adult
who comes along
and says, "no,"
like Mr. byrne.
First he said I could be
on the basketball team,
then he said I couldn't.
You thought
blowing up
the gymnasium
was an appropriate response?
Yes.
But your parents
told Mr. byrne
they didn't want
you playing any
contact sports.
My parents say no
to everything I want.
The other boys
are very angry
at you, Roger.
I don't care what they think.
Then why are you running away?
What's your IQ, son?
185.
Ah! My, you're
a real genius.
Mine's 190.
Oh, wait. I forgot.
Mine is 195.
Oh, wait.
I forgot.
Mine is almost 200,
but that's
not really
the point.
The point
is that people
like you and I,
when we get very frustrated,
can cause a lot of damage.
You're not like me.
Why? Because I'm
all grown-up?
That's true.
I've changed,
but when I was your age...
Ooh! I...
Let me tell you
a story about when
I was your age.
I was traveling
with my parents
to the island of Hawaii.
Weather conditions seem
vastly improved, steffen.
I think now
we can safely proceed
with the scheduled lift-off.
Splashdown!
Would you please
stop hitting
my chair?
I am trying to sleep.
I'm sorry,
miss nice-older-person,
but I don't know
what you're talking about.
Perhaps you were
just having a nightmare
about your early days
in the circus.
One more word,
I'll call the flight
attendant.
It wasn't very nice
of the mean old lady
to smash your collar-bone,
was it, steffen?
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be passing
over Los Angeles
in about 10 minutes.
The skies are crystal clear.
It should be smooth sailing
all the way to Honolulu.
(Yells)
Damn it! Clifford,
why did you wake me?
I didn't.
Steffen did.
Why wouldn't you let him sleep?
Now that
you are awake,
my papa,
when we land in Los Angeles,
can we then
immediately go
to dinosaur world?
I've told you,
the plane doesn't
go to Los Angeles.
It goes directly to Honolulu.
How can that be?
What?
That on my birthday,
I can be so close
to dinosaur world
and yet so far away?
Your birthday
was six months ago.
Clifford,
daddy is on a business...
A business trip,
and this is not a vacation.
Drop this
dinosaur world thing
for five seconds.
Would you do that for me?
You're driving me crazy!
Looks like daddy
is going to have
a big stroke,
and then he'll be
talking like this.
I swear to God...
Clifford!
Would you just stop?
Whatever you say,
sweet one
who birthed me.
May I visit the captain?
I imagine
he would be very
brave and wise,
possibly with
a cleft in his chin.
All right.
Just be back
for dinner.
Whatever you say, my papa.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Oh, God! Ow!
Captain, we have
a young man here
who has a request.
Hi. What's
your name, son?
Clifford.
I think you're
the bestest captain in
the whole wide world,
thank... you, Clifford.
I was wondering
if we could land
in Los Angeles
so I could go
to dinosaur world.
The only way
we could land
in Los Angeles
would be for an emergency.
Whatever you say, my captain.
Jeez, it's awful quiet in here.
Where's Clifford?
He shut the engines down.
I don't know why
steffen did that.
Are you out of your tree, sir?
(All) Aah!
Steffen, hang in!
I've regained control
of number four, Los Angeles.
Request permission for
emergency landing procedures.
Roger, flight 43.
This is l.A.X.
You're cleared for immediate
landing on runway 23.
(Roger)
Hee hee!
What an amazing story.
You liked that, did you?
You got them to land the plane.
You got what you wanted.
But I risked the lives
of a couple of hundred people.
But no one got hurt.
But they could have.
But they didn't.
That was a truly
wonderful story,
father,
but I have to get going now.
Fine.
Bye-bye.
(Swish)
Oh!
Son, that's not
the whole story.
It's just the beginning.
Oh, sorry, father.
That's all right.
Sit down and get comfortable.
Would you like a mint?
No, thank you.
Mmm...
I guess we have to
begin the story
earlier that day.
You see...
(Choking)
Yes. I'll save this
for later.
You see,
I had an Uncle
named Martin
who was a famous architect,
and he had two dreams.
One was to build a great
mass transit system
for what was known at that time
as the city of Los Angeles,
and his other dream
was to marry Sarah,
the love of his life.
Sarah was a teacher
who operated a daycare center
where he worked.
She loved him very much.
In fact, they were engaged
to be married.
Hi.
You look so handsome.
I'm in a very good mood.
How come?
I'll tell you later.
Tell me now, right now.
(Martin) You will love this.
It will literally be
the biggest surprise
of your life.
We're here?
We're here!
I'm excited!
Don't peek!
I'm not!
Are you excited?
Yeah.
I'm so excited.
Wait.
O.K.
Please don't peek.
I'm not.
O.K.
All right.
O.K., look!
Are you stunned?
What am I looking at?
The house!
I bought it!
It's on a cliff?
That's what
you want...
A cliff.
It's incredible, isn't it?
Uh-huh.
It's very minimalist,
but it's got
a quiet intensity,
doesn't it, honey?
Doesn't it?
It's very warm.
(Clifford) There was, however,
one slight problem.
Sarah wanted children
very much,
but Martin, it seemed,
was in no hurry.
Martin...
How many bedrooms
in this house?
One, honey.
One bedroom, honey.
But look
at this view.
Look at this!
The ocean!
You can see catalina out there.
Whoa! It is quite a drop!
(Door closes)
Honey?
I can't believe
I let this happen again.
Honey, what's wrong?
I can't marry you.
You're just like
my first husband.
He didn't want kids either.
When did I say
I didn't
want kids?
It's so obvious.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about
this bachelor pad
with one bedroom.
Where's a kid
supposed to sleep?
Have you ever
heard the word
sofa-bed?
Have you ever heard
the word stupid?
Stupid?
Stupid!
Are you saying
this house couldn't
work for kids?
Oh, no, it's just perfect.
"Where are the kids, honey?"
"Oh, the kids
are just out back
playing on the cliff."
I love kids.
No, you don't. I saw you
at the daycare today.
You should see me
with a kid I know...
My nephew.
You never mentioned
you had a nephew.
I love my nephew.
What's his name?
I want to say Mason.
Uh... Clifford.
Little Clifford.
How old is he?
I haven't
seen him since
the christening.
He'd be older now...
Like, 10.
My brother julien
and I don't speak
as much as we'd like to.
I have heard
that Clifford is
a very special boy.
Where is that little monster?
Julien, please!
Ooh!
You did it, didn't you?
You did it again, didn't you?
You're banned from
the flight.
No.
They won't allow you
back on the plane.
I'll miss
the convention
tomorrow
and lose
thousands of dollars
in speaker's fees.
Do you understand me?
Where did you get that walkman?
Did you steal it?
No.
Is there no end
to your madness?
A kindly
old priest
gave it to me.
You're lying.
No.
You're lying
to your own
father's face.
I should leave you here,
you little animal.
What a terrible thing to say
to such a sweet child.
I'm sorry,
Mrs. extra-wide-load.
What are you packing in,
two dozen doughnuts a day?
Huh?
Julien, calm down!
Your heart...
Daddy, it's coming...
Oh, God!
Oh, theodora,
what am I
going to do?
I... I got to
be on that plane.
Pappy, pappy, pappy.
What?
Doesn't Uncle Martin
live in Los Angeles?
Maybe I can go to his house,
and then you could
go to Hawaii,
and I could go
to dinosaur world.
(Telephone rings)
Wait. Sarah?
(Julien) Martin?
Yes?
Martin, it's julien,
your brother.
Your brother
julien.
Yes?
I haven't made
much of an attempt
to keep in touch.
I wouldn't blame you
if you hung up on me,
but don't hang up, o.K.?
I'm in a terrible dilemma.
I have a tremendous
favor to ask you.
Ha ha ha!
I can't believe it.
He went for it.
I'm going to dinosaur world!
I told him I had
this speaking engagement
and that Clifford gets airsick.
Dinosaur world I'm going to!
He almost seemed
excited about it.
Ha ha ha!
I'm Martin Daniels.
I'm here to pick up
my nephew Clifford.
Do you have any identification?
Yeah.
All right.
He's in the back room
resting. Come with me.
Thank you.
Clifford.
This is so cute.
Come here.
Look.
¶ LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA
¶ LA LA ¶
mmm... mmm...
¶ LA LA LA
¶ LA LA... ¶
Clifford.
Don't reject me!
¶ LA LA LA LA LA... ¶
Uncle Martin?
Yes.
¶ LA... ¶
I'm going to go big.
Oh!
¶ LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA ¶
dearest Uncle Martin,
can we go
to dinosaur world now?
Dinosaur world?
It's closed.
It's 10:30,
Clifford.
I'll let you in on
a little secret.
I've got
a lifetime pass
to dinosaur world
because I designed
Larry the scary...
Scary Rex? You designed
Larry the scary Rex?
¶ I'm Larry the scary Rex ¶
¶ I'm a scary dinosaur
¶ but don't be scared
of my sharp, sharp teeth
¶ and my mighty, mighty roar ¶
oh, boy, you're
some sort of hero.
Let's go get your bags.
Yes.
Somebody stole my dog sneakers.
Calm down!
Have you unloaded
everything off
flight 791 yet?
Oh, yeah.
So far I'm missing
a Mountain bike,
a stereo, a surfboard,
and a big brown dog.
You brought a lot of stuff.
Dad's scared of burglars.
He makes us
take everything
when we travel.
And your dog.
I couldn't leave
my sneakers at home.
Of course you couldn't.
Sarah will be so excited.
I told her
how special
you are to me.
We've never met before.
I was with you
at the christening.
I spent the better
part of a day
in your company.
I have the utmost
admiration for you.
Oh, Uncle Martin!
Oh!
O.K.,
you can let go now.
Okey-dokey.
Okey-dokey. O.K.
(Arf)
Oh, Sarah loves dogs.
Come on, sneakers.
Come on.
(Meow)
(Martin) Come on, boy.
Come on, sneakers.
Please, boy.
Get out of
the car. Oh!
(Meow)
Whoa!
(Sarah) Just face it, Sarah.
You'll be alone
the rest of your life,
just like that maid
on the Brady bunch,
faking enthusiasm
for other people's happiness.
And there's, of course,
the pity of others
to look forward to.
"Isn't that Sarah Davis?
"My! She's aged.
"She drove off
every man she ever had,
"and then she just withered up
like an old prune
who couldn't..."
Aah!
Sarah?
Don't judge me.
It was steffen's
fault.
Shame on you.
Shame on your eyes.
What? Sarah!
Martin?
Are you o.K.?
That was
a lousy trick
to play.
What trick?
Your stupid dinosaur
in the shower.
Oh, no, no.
That was Clifford.
Who is Clifford?
My nephew. Remember?
I was telling you about him.
Your nephew's here?
My brother julien called.
He was flying to Hawaii.
Julien said would I
look after him
for a week.
I said, "of course."
He's a wonderful kid.
Come on, meet him.
O.K.
Hi.
Uncle, Martin, I hope
your friend doesn't mind
that I helped myself
to a snack.
That's o.K.
Martin.
Oh, Clifford,
this is Sarah Davis.
¶ LA LA
¶ LA ¶
hello.
Hello, miss Sarah Davis.
Whew! That's
a lovely bathrobe
you're wearing.
I'm sure on anyone else
it wouldn't look
half as lovely.
(Sighs)
Thank you.
What a sweet thing to say.
Isn't he
everything
I said he was?
I love you, Uncle Martin.
And I you, Clinton.
Clifford.
Isn't there
an incredible
family resemblance?
Well, I guess so.
Yes.
I'd like to see more
of you, Clifford.
Perhaps you can
convince your Uncle
to make sure of that.
Absolutely!
But right now,
sleepyhead,
we got to
get you to
Uncle Martin's.
Normally I would despise
when someone ruffles
my hair like that,
but not when you do it.
Isn't he something?
Yes.
He certainly is.
O.K., honey,
let's go.
Good night, darling.
Good night.
O.K., Clifford,
come on.
Good night.
Good night to you.
Good night, sweet Sarah.
May all
your dreams be
pleasant ones.
May the rainbow arches...
Come on, sweetie.
Time for bed.
(Door closes)
Like other native peoples,
the lake girls
copy the movement of animals.
Since the beginning of...
(Slurp)
Allow them to enter
the prayer land.
There has been mutual respect.
This dance, called the...
Time to turn off the videos.
Is an expression
of their culture.
O.K. Time to go
to sleep.
Steffen felt that was a very
cruel action, Uncle Martin.
Oh, well, you tell steffen...
That it's 2:00
in the morning
and we have to
get up very early
because tomorrow
we're going
to dinosaur world.
Oh, you're the bestest Uncle
in the whole wide world!
Thanks.
Good night, Clifford.
Good night, Uncle Martin.
You wouldn't lie to me,
would you, Uncle Martin?
If you lied to me,
I'd be so angry,
I don't know what I'd do.
No, I wouldn't lie to you.
Get in the bed.
Cozy, cozy.
Uncle Martin,
whose ring is this?
Where did you get that?
On the dresser.
Give me that.
No.
That's
my grandmother's
wedding ring.
Then wouldn't she be
my great-grandmother?
Yes.
Then wouldn't it be
just as much mine as yours?
What's your point?
I want to marry Sarah
and give her this ring.
That's very sweet,
but it's, it's, it's
very unrealistic.
I still want the ring.
You can't have it.
I, I... give it...
But it sparkles.
I like sparkle as well.
I will give Sarah
this ring someday.
How exciting!
Ring bearer?
We'll see.
(Sarah) This is smiling,
isn't it?
(Knock on door)
Hi, Martin.
Hi, Clifford.
Hello, miss Sarah Davis.
I didn't know
you were a teacher.
Had I known,
I would have brought
you an apple.
What a charming
thing to say.
How very thoughtful.
I'm taking Clifford
to dinosaur world.
Then I've got
a meeting with Ellis.
This deadline is really
closing in on me.
It'll be o.K.
Your ideas are great.
It's a little odd
that this daycare center has
been here for over six months,
and Mr. Ellis hasn't
even dropped in once.
I'm sure he hates kids.
What makes me nervous
is that if I
don't talk fast enough
he snaps his fingers at me.
I hear he's a womanizer
and he's obsessed
with himself
and that's supposed to be
a wig that he's wearing.
Ellis wears a rug?
Oh!
Mr. Ellis,
how are you?
Thanks for coming in.
I don't believe we've met.
This is miss Sarah...
Sarah Davis, of course.
I want to thank you
for the wonderful
job you've done.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, isn't that impressive?
You know, I don't think
there's anything
more meaningful
to me
than the welfare
of our employees'...
(All laugh)
This is my nephew Clifford.
Say hello
to my boss Mr. Ellis.
Isn't he a cute little fella?
Hi, Sonny.
My! That's the bestest-looking
wig I've ever seen!
Oh, no, no, no.
That's, that's not a wig.
You said it was a wig.
You called it a rug, too.
You misunderstood me.
I never said that, sir.
Good.
What are you looking at?
It's not a wig.
It's not a rug either.
(All laugh)
Just don't worry about that.
Right. Don't worry
about that.
I guess we have work to do.
I was wondering one thing.
Later on,
could I give
you a call?
Me?
No. Her.
There's something I would love
to talk to you about.
Oh, well...
That'd be f... fine.
Su... o.K.
Well, good-bye, sir.
Charming.
(Martin) You want me
to redesign
the entire model
in two days?
The bottom line is,
you've got to move
the train line.
What?
Yeah. 2 Miles.
That's impossible!
That'll put the train line
right through
the sepulveda dam.
Hmm.
That's not good.
Well.
You'll come up with something.
You'll hole up for a few days
and drink a lot of coffee.
You being
the professional
I know you are,
I know you'll hit
another home run for us.
You all right?
No.
Good man.
If you're a visitor,
would you do me a favor?
Enter your visitor card number.
(Martin) Clifford!
Hello, Uncle Martin.
Are we ready to go
to dinosaur world?
Uh, Clifford, uh...
I've got some bad news.
I can't take you right now!
The freeway
to dinosaur world
is back there.
You're going to make us crash!
(Tires squealing)
Steffen,
make it all better
somehow.
Get ahold of yourself!
You're out of control!
(Hyperventilating)
What? What?
A whole gang of chocolate,
I need it badly.
(Hyperventilating)
Jesus!
(Horn honking)
(Hyperventilating)
O.K. All right. O.K.
Wait one minute.
I'll be right back.
Don't... don't
breathe so much.
O.K. Excuse me.
O.K., kids,
next stop... dinosaur world!
Who's excited?
(Kids cheering)
I have to go to the bathroom.
You're out of chocolate?
How can that be?
Everybody wants chocolate.
I need chocolate!
I might have
an easter bunny
left over.
Get me the bunny!
Thanks for making
us wait, you dork.
Clifford?
Well, where
did you get
those clothes?
This kid bought
my dinosaur costume.
What's the matter with you?
Are you crazy?
I'm terribly sorry.
Where's my son?
He was counting the money
he was given in the men's room.
You pervert!
Ahh!
Ah!
Ow! My ear!
You hit my ear!
Tell me where he is!
Mom, I'm over here!
Oh, Kevin!
You're all right!
What in the world is...
So...
Any luck with that chocolate?
"Any luck with that chocolate?
Any luck with
that chocolate?"
Bad boy, Clifford!
Bad boy!
I don't know
what to say to you.
You could have
given those parents
a heart attack.
If they press charges,
you could end up in prison.
And the wasted time!
I happen to be
very busy, young man.
The city of Los Angeles
is relying on me
for public transit.
My boss is breathing
down my neck.
That was so embarrassing
with Mr. Ellis.
Don't tell someone
they have a nice wig.
I said,
"the bestest-looking wig."
It was a compliment.
(Sighs) He says he
doesn't wear a wig.
People don't take it
as a compliment
if you say,
"nice wig."
I didn't say,
I said,
"bestest-looking wig."
There is a difference.
Why are you such
an authority on wigs?
My teacher
Mr. Cavanaugh wears one.
He lets us play with it.
He lets you play with it?
Frisbee.
(Whistles)
Miss gathecold,
the art teacher,
borrows it as well.
That would be
for different reasons.
Let's just forget
about the wig.
I've got to punish you,
and that means
dinosaur world is out.
I don't understand.
I've got a bombshell for you.
I'm the boss in this house.
You cannot fight city hall.
Surely someone as wise as you
would realize that breaking
a little boy's promise
and punishing him for it
would be a terrible thing.
That little boy
wouldn't be responsible
for what he was
going to do next.
I don't like threats.
You're going to spend
the day in your room.
Now you march, young man!
March!
It's not fair, steffen.
He was the one
who broke his promise,
and now I'm the one
who's being punished.
It isn't fair.
They're never fair.
I am going to go
to dinosaur world.
I don't care what he says.
(Ring)
Hello.
Hi, it's me.
How was dinosaur world?
I postponed it.
Ellis hit me
with a hundred changes
to make on the model.
(Gasps)
Oh, you poor thing.
How's Clifford?
He must be heartbroken.
No, he's fine.
We're in the kitchen
making popcorn.
Use a potholder, cliffie!
I was calling about tonight.
Tonight?
My parents' anniversary.
Why?
Did you forget?
No! Are you kidding?
I can't miss your
parents' anniversary party!
It's 7:00.
I can't wait
for my folks
to meet Clifford.
See you then.
Bye.
(Line disconnects)
Isn't that something, steffen?
Too busy for a boy's dream,
but not too busy
to go out to dinner.
(Martin) Punish you,
and that means
dinosaur world is out.
I've got a bombshell for you.
I'm the boss in this house.
You cannot fight city hall.
(Tape rewinding)
Steffen, do you
like Uncle Martin?
So do I.
This is Martin Daniels.
I've got a bomb.
(Clifford) Wow! Is this house
ever huge!
Uncle Martin,
do they live in a hotel?
You're not still mad at me
for grounding you,
are you, Clifford?
Of course not.
Whatever would make
you think that?
There they are.
Now, daddy, be nice
to Martin for me.
If I have to, honey.
I don't understand
a man at his age
and still not married.
Hi, honey.
Hi. Daddy, look.
It's Martin.
Hi.
Congratulations, sir.
Happy anniversary.
I hope you have
many, many more.
Daddy, this is
Martin's nephew
Clifford.
Well, now, look
at this big fella.
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
A dinosaur.
Ha ha ha!
Do you like
dinosaurs,
miss Sarah?
I adore dinosaurs.
Would you like some punch?
I would like that very much.
Martin, bloody Mary?
Thank you.
You have a most
exceptional
daughter.
Thank you for letting me know.
You must be having
the time of your life.
Why do you say that,
miss Sarah?
Getting to spend time
with your Uncle finally
and everything.
Oh.
Uncle Martin.
Yeah.
Scary Uncle Martin.
Sarah!
Hello, darling!
Oh, how fabulous you look!
I always loved you
in that dress.
It's new, Julia.
Oh, yes.
Of course it is.
Oh, come and meet raweejni.
I'll be back soon.
Okey-dokey.
Hi, Clifford.
Have you seen Sarah?
She was taken
by a lady who
looks like this...
What makes her face
look like that?
They call that
a face-lift.
What's a face-lift?
Let's not shout so much.
Oh, sorry.
I believe your drink
is right there.
Oh, thanks.
Martin!
Oh, Mrs. Davis.
Oh, I knew you'd come.
Parker said you'd try
to weasel out of it.
I knew better.
Oh, not to come
to your 35th anniversary,
that would be unthinkable.
(Both laugh)
Ha ha ha!
Is this Clifford?
Yes, I believe it is me.
I'm Sarah's mother.
I'm Annabelle.
If you're miss Sarah's mother,
you must
be the most
wonderful person
in the whole wide world!
What a gorgeous,
gorgeous child!
Oh!
Wait.
Wait. No.
(Yells) Wait!
I believe Uncle Martin
would like
to offer
you a toast.
Oh, how sweet.
Parker. Sarah.
Everybody, come on.
Gather around.
Sarah's Martin is toasting.
Come on. Quickly.
Here we go.
A toast.
We raise our glasses
first to Parker Davis,
the patriarch
of the Davis family,
for 35 years, a devoted husband
and a loving, loving father.
We love you very much, sir.
Hear. Hear.
Next...
Aren't you going to
say something about
Sarah's mother?
(Parker)
Goddamn it, Daniels!
Get on with it!
Are you feeling o.K.?
(Glass shatters)
Ahh!
Ah!
Excuse us.
I would like a word
with my nephew.
The paprika sauce
was the talk
of the party.
You're trying to punish me
because I haven't taken
you to dinosaur world.
You put something in my drink.
In your drink?
In my drink!
My mouth was going to burn off!
You think it's funny?
No.
It was funny, Uncle Martin,
because you made a toast,
"here's to Parker Davis.
We love you, sir."
And then you
held up the drink...
(Gagging)
Everyone was
staring and saying,
"what a goof!"
You ran to the punch bowl.
Argh!
(Yells)
Oh! Oh! Oh!
See, when
you are looking
at the baseball,
look at it.
Oh, I see now.
Keep your eye on the ball.
Tricky to remember,
Uncle. Thanks.
Well, so...
O.K.?
Yes.
They're starting
to serve dinner now.
Dinner is served.
Oh! Hungry boy
am I.
(Sarah)
Clifford, maybe you'd
like to wash your hands.
Oh.
Yes.
Bye, captain.
You'd tell me
if you were having
a nervous breakdown,
wouldn't you?
(Both laugh)
Nervous breakdown.
He wants me to fly
to San Francisco
with him tomorrow
to open a daycare center.
What did you say?
I said yes.
It's only for one night.
You're spending the night
in San Francisco with Ellis?
He is my boss.
Was I supposed
to say no?
What's wrong with you tonight?
Clifford, what are you doing?
I just wanted to borrow
your lip-thingy
stuff.
My lips are somewhat parched.
You can't put your hand
into somebody's pocket.
No. You cannot borrow it.
It's not sanitary.
Whatever you say, Uncle Martin.
Here are your pickles, sir.
Oh, thank you
ever so kindly, sir.
What a nice, polite
young man you are.
He said even though
you're a worrywart,
he has confidence
you'll come
through in the end.
Then maybe he'll take
me to San Francisco.
Because
I'm in a good mood
and you're not,
you just can't stand it.
I can stand it.
Just forget it.
Hi.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
Oh, Martin,
you are hysterical!
(Guests laughing)
Wha...
Go like this...
Martin, go to the bathroom
and wipe it off.
(Guests laughing)
There's a bathroom
on the second floor,
madam.
Are you Martin Daniels?
Yes.
May I sleep at your house?
Oh...
Madam, come quickly, please.
You're making
a terrible mistake.
Stop this.
I'm the fiance of...
ugh!
I'm miss Davis' fiance!
Martin!
Sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
We are police officers.
Don't be alarmed.
This gentleman
is suspected of planting
an explosive device.
What? No!
I'm with the city!
I'm designing
a public transit system
for the entire city
of Los Angeles.
Honestly, this is insane!
You've made some
sort of mistake.
We don't think so.
It's not as if
I didn't warn her.
Oh, wait.
Uncle Martin!
No!
In the name of all that's holy,
somebody help my Uncle!
He's an innocent man,
I tell you!
An innocent...
Man.
Mission accomplished, friend.
Why don't you tell us
where the bomb is hidden?
What are you talking about?
Do I look like someone
that would
put a bomb
under city hall?
You're trying to get
a confession from me
by grilling me
under hot lights.
Sorry.
Well, you know,
now I can't see
anything.
That's... No.
Is that better?
I don't want
to make this
about lighting.
Let's move on.
You wanted
to get caught.
You called us.
What?
Yeah.
Hi. This is
Martin Daniels.
I've got a bomb
under city hall.
Talk to you later.
This is part
of my answering
machine message!
This is a prank!
You don't have to believe me!
Call my home!
Here.
Speaker's on.
(Ring)
Hi. This is Clifford.
I can't tell you where
my Uncle Martin is,
but I'll give you
a hint... kaboom!
Clifford?
Ah!
I didn't mean to scare you.
Morning, miss Sarah.
You're all dressed up
to go dreaming.
Don't say I'm wrong.
Oh, thank you.
I didn't hear you get up.
I've been up since 5:00.
I don't sleep as much
as one might assume.
Well, I see you
found something to eat.
(Knock on door)
Hi.
It's the jailbird.
Oh, Martin,
I've been
so worried!
You've been worried.
There he is.
Hi, Clifford. You o.K.?
Hi, Uncle Martin.
How was your stay
in penitentiary?
Did you meet any
interesting hoodlums?
Ha ha ha!
Ah!
Are you really in trouble?
I've told you about
Larry gould, right?
No.
You know,
Mr. practical jokes?
The whole thing was a setup.
Oh, no!
I don't believe
what I'm hearing!
I don't either.
Honey, be careful
how you eat your cereal.
This boy and his cereal.
Ha ha ha!
Explain to me what happened.
Larry tapes my
answering-machine message
and my phone conversation.
He edits them together.
The police play it for me,
and I think I'm going insane.
That's sick!
It gets better.
The two cops who arrested me?
Larry's cousins.
No! I don't think
that's funny at all!
I didn't either,
and then I started
thinking about it,
and I got to laughing.
Ah.
It is funny.
Those guys are certifiable.
Tell me about it.
I'm so relieved.
Oh, now, Clifford, see?
Didn't I tell you
that everything
would be just fine?
Yes, you did,
but I don't like those men.
They're liars.
Everybody knows that liars
eventually get caught.
That's right...
You little pecker-head.
O.K., I'll see
you tomorrow.
Try to get some sleep.
I got a lot of work
to catch up on.
I'm sorry I was a jerk
about your trip with Ellis.
I know, sweetheart.
I know.
I'm staying at
the wemberton hotel.
You can phone my suite.
You have a suite?
Yes.
Bye, Clifford.
Make sure
by the time
I get back
your Uncle's
not working on
a chain gang.
That's very good.
O.K. Bye.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
Bye!
Get in the car.
I am now out on bail.
Are you listening to me?
Are you?
Yes, I am.
I have a criminal record,
but you know what
you're going to have?
A one-way ticket
back to your parents.
No! They hate me!
Not as much as I do!
(Crying)
Stop with the fake tears!
I'm not faking!
I'll admit anything!
Just don't send me
back to my parents.
I'll tell miss Sarah
I put the lipstick
in your pocket,
which I didn't.
Her father did it!
He wanted to embarrass you.
He said you were
a simple-minded moron.
He called me a moron?
A simple-minded moron.
And Sarah's father
put the lipstick
in my pocket?
Yes.
Why would he do that?
Because he hates you!
I don't know why.
I certainly think
you're a nice enough sort.
I suppose that Sarah's father
also put the hot sauce
in my drink.
That I don't know.
You don't?
No.
You have no idea who did that?
I would suspect
the bartender.
Theory.
Well, you know, I would
suspect someone else.
Now, who could that be?
If you're about
to say what I think,
then I don't want to hear it,
because Sarah Davis loves you.
She wouldn't do that.
She has problems with you,
but every relationship
goes through that.
Oh.
Oh, you...
you don't think it was me?
Uncle Martin!
Stop!
I had to be made
naked in the jail!
I was strip searched!
I was humiliated!
I know.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I made the tape.
Oh, God, it was wrong!
Why did I do it?
I think I know why.
Because
I was angry at you
for having promised
that you would take me
to dinosaur world
and then breaking that promise!
What is it with you
and dinosaur world?
It's sick!
You're obsessed with
this dinosaur world!
I believe dinosaur world
is the only place
where a boy like me
can be happy.
(Sobbing)
Oh.
Listen to me.
Shut up a minute!
Will you listen to me?
I'm listening.
Don't put the dinosaur
on me like that.
Just leave the dinosaur
over there like that.
I'm trying to
tell you something.
When I...
when I was a little boy...
you touch the dinosaur,
I'll kill you.
Steffen wanted to stand here.
Give it to me!
I'll rip its head off!
God almighty, boy!
Listen.
I'm trying to tell you
something to help you.
Clifford, I'm trying
to tell you something
about when I was
a little boy in Chicago.
All right?
Yes.
There was a great
amusement park
called riverview.
Did your father mention it?
Yes.
I thought that was
the only place
I could be happy,
but my father never took me.
And then one day...
They tore it down,
before I ever got to go there.
I understand how you feel.
You do?
Yes.
Does it ever get easier,
my Uncle Martin?
Not really.
Now listen to me.
Here's the deal...
you go to your room,
write a confession that
I'll take to the police,
and I won't send you
back to your parents.
You tell Sarah
that you and I
are best friends.
We are,
aren't we?
Shut up.
But if you even
look at me funny,
if you do one thing
I find weird,
which is, like,
your middle name...
You're doing it now.
Can you act like
a human boy
for one minute?
Look at me like a person.
You can't do it.
Look at me like a human boy!
Don't mess around with me,
or you'll be back
on that plane.
You understand me?
I understand that I love you.
All right. All right.
Let it go. Let it go.
Steffen walked back.
Give me that!
Give me that, Clifford!
Please don't hurt him.
He's the only one
left in his family.
Take the dinosaur
and go to your room.
You take the dinosaur.
Write your confession.
Yes.
Pretty soon, there won't be
anyone left in his family!
O.K., I've got 20 hours.
I can do it if I don't panic.
Clifford, come on down
and get some lunch.
Clifford?
(Clifford)
My dearest Uncle Martin,
I've failed you many ways.
I have taken
the 1:45 train
to San Francisco
to find Sarah Davis.
With all the love
in my little heart,
Clifford.
Oh, my God.
What have I done?
Clifford!
Have you seen this boy?
No, sir.
(Train starts)
Have you seen this boy?
No.
No, I haven't.
¶ San Francisco,
¶ open your golden gate
¶ you'll let nobody wait
¶ outside your door
¶ San Francisco,
¶ here is your wandering one
¶ saying I'll wander no more
¶ other places only
make me love you best
¶ tell me you're the one
in all the golden west
¶ aaaahhh! ¶
would you like a hunk?
(Loud music playing
on headphones)
(Porter) San Francisco.
(Telephone rings)
Hello?
Who's this?
This is Brian.
Whose house is this?
Um, it's the kid
who's throwing
the party.
I think his name is Clifford.
Is Clifford there?
I saw him in the back
bashing the shit
out of a pinata.
He said we could party
if we took him
to dinosaur world.
Should I get him?
I'll get him later.
Where you going?
Uh, the airport.
Swing by the wemberton hotel.
(Thunder cracking)
Driver, let's just
forget about the hotel.
Let's go to the airport.
What am I doing?
Wait a minute!
Stop the car!
Hey, buddy.
I'll get out here.
You'll get hit.
(Horn honks)
This is not just from me.
This is from us at the company.
Here,
let me help you
with it here.
I saw you eyeing it.
There you go.
Little tight.
You like it?
I don't know what to say.
It's very beautiful,
but I... ahh!
What?
What's the matter?
Nothing, uh...
It's I'm so excited.
Ahh!
Excited.
I thought you would be.
I'd like to go
see how it looks on me.
O.K.
I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
What are you doing
spying on me?
What am I doing?
What are you doing?
What's with the necklace?
The company gave this to me.
I have no intention
of keeping it.
You are such a baby.
Clifford should be
baby-sitting you.
I prefer baby-sitters
who aren't affiliated
with the manson family.
What are you talking about?
Where is Clifford?
Don't worry about Clifford.
He's happy with
a ton of sugar
and a book about Hitler.
What's that supposed to mean?
I mean Clifford
tricked me into coming
to San Francisco.
Why would he do that?
Why? Because he wanted
to throw a party.
You don't know anything
about Hitler... Clifford.
He's a lying, conniving,
evil little monster.
You see, Martin,
that is the reason
you and I can
never get married.
If Clifford were your own,
you'd be talking the same way.
It was all
a big act,
wasn't it?
The special
relationship
with Clifford.
The loving Uncle.
Well, let me
tell you something.
You're a phony.
Believe me, I can spot a phony.
Excuse me.
Have you seen a collie?
No, ma'am, I haven't.
That's why I feel sorry
for you, Martin,
because you're going to
end up one lonely old man.
Well, I feel sorry for you.
Don't think you won't age.
Don't call me
a lonely old man
and a phony.
¶ I like the way you move, yeah
¶ I like the way you move ¶
ohh, no!
You creep!
Oh!
I think you broke a rib.
I'll break more than that
if you try that again.
(Chuckling)
As for this stupid thing,
which I had no
intention of keeping...
no?
No.
Don't think
I don't know
what you're doing
with your
romantic little dinners
and showering me with gifts.
What is this thing,
soldered on?
Ha ha.
Shut up!
I'll help.
No!
Ooh, ooh.
Oh! Thanks
but no thanks!
Hmm.
Aw, honey.
If you think this
frightened little
high school virgin act
is turning me off...
You're wrong.
Ooh, God!
Oh, my God!
It's true!
Ha ha.
Put that back.
No.
Put that back on my head.
No, no...
No, you don't!
(Muttering)
Clifford!
Uncle Martin!
Uncle Martin,
I'm so glad
you're here!
I got on a train,
but a person
tried to touch
my no-no place!
There were bikers here,
and they tied me up,
Uncle Martin!
And then they told me stories.
Some were fun,
but some were scary!
(Phone ringing)
Hi.
This is Clifford.
I can't tell you
where Uncle Martin
is right now...
Hello?
Clifford?
Miss Sarah Davis?
How are you?
Not very good.
Why?
Uncle Martin is becoming nuts.
He went away
for the longest time.
He came back crazy.
I know, Clifford,
but I think
he's just overworked.
I'll get the first plane
home in the morning.
I love you, miss Sarah Davis.
I love you, too, Clifford.
(Panting)
Sometimes I scare myself.
(Boards rattling)
Ohh.
Aren't you a sight
for sore eyes.
Ohh.
Miss Sarah Davis,
my little mouth is parched
from my long night of bondage.
You poor, dear darling.
Are you o.K.?
What has he done
to you?
Ask him how he got tied up.
Tell about the bikers
and your damn no-no place.
You stay away from him.
Larry gould didn't make
the bomb threat, he did.
I don't know what he's saying.
Why is his face twisted so?
You need help.
He needs help.
Good. Take him away.
But don't blame
me when his head
starts spinning around.
Watch out for the green vomit!
(Beep)
Oh, God!
The cassette.
My model cassette.
Where is it?
How did it get out?
Ahh.
Gee, I don't like him.
We live in an age of gridlock.
Our projections
for the year 2000
indicate that
the average speed...
Where have you been?
You should
have been here
an hour ago.
I've been listening
to this idiot...
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
Good.
Did you make the changes?
Yes.
Yeah, but you didn't shave.
The press is here.
You look like shit.
I look like shit?
You look like Willie Nelson.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to introduce
the man who was
the chief designer
of this entire
mag-trans project.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Martin Daniels.
Marty, come on up,
you son of a gun.
Come on.
They love you.
Hey, go get them.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
I just want
to say that...
(screaming)
Fire extinguisher!
Look out!
Congratulations, Clifford.
Brilliant.
Who the hell
is responsible for this?
I am.
Then you're fired.
Of course I am.
And by the way,
I love Willie Nelson.
This is his...
I underestimated the evil one.
Oh, Clifford, what shall we do?
Whatever shall we do now?
(Recorder playing)
¶ I'm Larry the scary Rex
¶ I'm a scary dinosaur, but...
¶ Don't be scared
of my sharp, sharp teeth
¶ or my mighty, mighty roar
¶ I love kids,
and kids love me, even... ¶
shut up!
Well, there it is, Clifford.
Dinosaur world.
Are you happy?
I'd say I'm the happiest boy
in the whole world,
Uncle mental case.
I'm the mental case?
You're in the strait jacket.
I imagine when they
put you in yours,
they'll need
a much larger one, sir.
That's cute.
(Beep beep) Hi, Mitchell.
Hi, Mr. Daniels.
He's crazy about dinosaurs.
I'd like to take him on a tour.
I'll take full responsibility.
Yes, sir.
And throw some light
on the Rex, would you?
Okey-dokey.
Climb aboard, Clifford.
Are you excited, Clifford?
Yes, 'cause this has
always been my dream,
Uncle Martin.
The same way as building
a transit system
was always my dream.
Was? Has something
happened to it?
"Has something
happened to it?"
We'll see how you feel
about your dream
after being
on the ride
for 10 hours.
I'd like it even more!
Then we'll see
how you feel
after 100 hours.
Wow! Ah!
Oh! Ah!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ah! Ha!
(Squawk)
Hello. I'm Terry
the pterodactyl.
I'd turn back if I were you.
Larry is in a horrid mood.
Things haven't
been going well
around here.
(Rumble)
Oh, dear!
An earthquake!
Ah! Ah!
Aah!
Whoa! Ah!
Ha ha!
Heh heh heh!
Oh!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
(Squawk)
You'd better
get out before
it's too late.
Save yourself.
No one has ever
wandered into
Larry's lair
and lived to tell the tale.
Aah!
(Grrr)
Oh, boy.
You're big.
(Grrr)
(Terry) Use your laser.
It's the only chance
of surviving.
Lady luck, you owe me.
(Grr)
Steffen, we did it!
We killed that big lug.
(Terry) Bravo!
And don't forget
our new frozen-yogurt bar.
¶ Larry the scary Rex
¶ he's a scary dinosaur
¶ but don't be scared
of his sharp, sharp teeth
¶ or his mighty, mighty roar
¶ he loves kids,
and kids love him
¶ even though his... ¶
was that scary?
That was fun!
How many years
will you get
for kidnapping me,
Uncle 10-most-wanted?
Life. Let's go
a little faster,
shall we?
Yes!
Ah!
Aah!
Was that scary?
Not at all.
Ah, a thought occurred to me.
Do you think
that miss Sarah
and Mr. Ellis
perhaps would name
their first child
Martin?
That is so cute.
You know, Clifford,
I really shouldn't
put this in hyperdrive,
but I just can't seem
to help myself.
Oh, well...
Ah!
Ha ha!
Aah!
Oh, boy!
Hee hee!
Hee hee hee!
Hello. I'm Terry
the pterodactyl.
I'd turn back if I were you.
(Grrr)
Ah!
Someone help!
Uncle Martin, save me!
Uncle Martin?
I'm thinking it over.
Please. I'm scared.
I'm scared of
what might happen
if I save you.
Maybe I should do mankind
a tremendous favor...
let that dinosaur eat you.
What horrors you might unleash!
What if you
got your hands
on some plutonium?
"I just made
the bestest
nuclear bomb
in the whole wide world."
Aah!
Ah!
Uncle Martin!
Aah!
Take my hand.
Come on!
(Grrr)
Help me, please.
Uh! Ah! Come on!
(Grrr)
I'm sorry.
No, Clifford, don't!
I don't want to hug you.
I can't imagine
anyone ever
wanting to hug you.
But I really am sorry.
You really are sorry?
You know, sorrow
is a human emotion.
As we know, you're
not a human boy.
You're just
this, this
destructive thing.
Eventually,
everyone just
gets to hate you.
Let's go.
If that's how you feel,
why should I go
with you, then?
Then don't go with me.
It's your choice.
(Clifford)
For the first
time in my life,
I felt very confused.
I had thought
that I didn't care
how Uncle Martin felt about me,
but I was wrong,
and his words
had devastated me.
And I thought
I was so clever...
And yet I hadn't figured out
until that moment...
That if you destroy everyone
who stands in the way
of your dreams...
Then you end up alone...
With no dreams at all.
Is that what will happen to me?
You?
No. You're much
too intelligent
for that.
Did your Uncle
ever forgive you?
I begged him to.
I sent him
over 287 letters
of apology,
all of them returned unopened.
You're improving, lofty.
Ha ha ha!
Whatever became
of his girl friend?
Miss Sarah Davis.
Well, one day, out of the blue,
which is an expression
we used to use back then,
I received
a phone call
from her...
With the bestest
request in the whole
wide world.
Uncle Martin had forgiven me,
and that single
act of kindness
changed my life.
Thank you, father.
You're welcome, Roger.
Hey, father.
You were some kid.
I'd really have
to go a long way
to match you,
but I won't.
Why is that?
I want people to like me.
How will you do that, Roger?
I'm going to write
287 letters of apology.
Ah...
See you next week, father.
Bye-bye.
Mission accomplished,
old friend.
¶ LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA
¶ LA LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA
¶ LA LA LA ¶