can I help you?
hi
I think I'm supposed to work here today
sit here until someone comes here and tell you what to do
and read this while you're waiting
ah, my feet are killing me
who's the new girl?
she must be felling in for someone
I can't believe you've been waiting for 2 hours
why didn't you say something
well, eh,
they told me to wait here
well, I hope you can type, follow me
okay
type the information from this list
onto the invoice form and then when you done
you will make 3 copies of each
and the copy room is down the hall
um
try not to make too many mistake these forms are very expensive
[coughs]
[giggles]
hi, uh, you know what
this machine is not really working very well
you gotta use that one
damn, you know, I think
somebody put a curse on it 'cus it's jamming
alright
excuse me
you know, if you hit it evenly and put the
pressure down, is like, that smears that way works better
if you, when you're done, would you close it because it'll dry up so fast
[sniffs]
I like your shoes
I once read that there are two kinds of time
mechanical and human
You could say my story began at 8:59 the day I started that job
and ended months later, when I left it
But I'd tell you it began in the past
with my old self
and ended in the future
with the new one
[phone ringing]
hello
eh
I'm not sure, I'm just a
temp, could you please hold on? please
uh, he's kinda busy right now may I take message?
auh
yeah
um
I saw in the bathroom
you must be the new girl
I'm just temporary
figures, that's why they sent me over
they don't like our kind mingling with the permanents
there's phone call for Mr. Wheeler
oh, just leave him on hold, he just get tired and hang up
that's lessen number one
people in siting in those glassrooms don't answer phone before 10
maybe I should take message
uh
whoops
[laughs]
oh don't worry, if it's important they'll call back
so, see they stuck you at Louise's desk
might as well get comfortable,
she's gonna be out for awhile if you know what I mean
claimed she was a motorcycle accident
she's probably faking it
I'll get it
oh that pen doesn't work
alright, just swipe off, I know the desk, thanks
good morning, global credit
I'm sorry he's in a meeting
pig__ starkwell__
tax payer
says he needs an answer right away
it's not 10 o'clock yet
hey
yeah I talked to him
he said go ahead and sell
no thank you
and you have good day now, bye
it's everything about temping, give advice
yeah by the times anyone finds out
you'll be long gone
just be sure you cover your tracks
um
the only real challenge of this job is
trying to look busy when there's nothing to do
they'll keep you here, that's how it works
you're part of the corporate hierarchy
it's gonna be button every seat of entire infrastructure crumbles
you drink coffee?
sometimes
soon or later someone's gonna ask you to fetch it for them
I'll show you the kitchen
this way please
I'm gonna be your tour guy today
welcome to wonderful world of credit
how bad is this music
some dodo burning charis study
that increase worker efficiency
scary, isn't
sooner or later you'll learn to tune it out
this where Arth sits
oh that's nice
smaller the man bigger desk, I always say
see that ribber band pa?
it's his price possession, stay away from it
who's Arth again?
he's the credit of gaurd of supplies
he does nothing counts paper clips, check mileage on copy machine
they are tax deduction , speak of devil
why aren't at your desk Arth?
I needed pencil holding__
oh really we wore working here
I'm working too
well act like it
I am acting like it
well lets see sitting at that chair the, okay
clock is ticking, we're at work
I need to talk about __feet
he's got a thing about him
I was in at 8:30
oh god
see that guy, it's Mr killmer, cheer__me__
hoping to give me recommendation when i need__ this__ price
good mornig, Mr killmer, hi
I'm nit gonna be a tad much longer
I get ___ tu___
hello excuse me person in the purple dress
what you name
margart
-I know I did that mass mailing for you last night
-you did that?
3000 letters yeah
-really?
you know we've got a couple 'em back
I think that was a
insufficient zip-code
anyway, listen, can you get me the __coplian file
I need some pencils I need a cup of coffee
what I really need? is I need an assistant because you know
an executive need an assistant
an assistant, uh
it's a filing room
obviously
oh my god
jeez
this place is booby traped
I swear
this sould be it
look at this
you know, got files within files
they wanna something disappear, just file it
be gone forever like magic
oh hi
-coffee's fresh just made it
-we're just looking, okay
remember to leave a donation
-okay
come here, watch this
Mitt laskies__ 's cup
one of these day the entire cup is gonna disappear, just like that little bikini
you never know
okay
let's deliver this, I'll show you the rest of building
and we will get to the other 50 percent of job
what's that
-watch
see the girl in blue, that's our spot
jane, paula this is Iris
-don't panic she's the one of us
-hi
I'll get you a chair
-it's okay
I'll just grab one from ____ pool
have you been temping for very long?
no, uh, just another job
at bank
oh bank, alright, any cute guys?
I spend most of my time in a basement
god they took the other furniture now too
there you go
you know what it is they're just jealous, uh?
right? you know
you know I got sent to a bank once
it was a nightmare and set the alarm
off and ...
cops came
ooh, i love the police, uh
how you do it?
there was this button on the desk an I kept looking at everyday
for a month and finnaly I just
I push it
really why?
what
how I supposed to know? you know how it goes
they never really explain to you anything you're temp, they figure you're not gonna be around long enough
try to take with their job or something
bad chance of that, uh?
I've got bigger plans
I'm a performer
yeah , drama's in my blood
you know there's no outlet
for it here
god, here he comes
eddiepo__ works in mail room
the_ reject of capitalism
hi ladies
who's your friend?
her name's Iris
-she's not interested
so, Jane
you think we can get together from these__drinks this week
oh, gush, you know, Eddie
Derick and I gonna go pick out our china patters
for wedding
oh
-maybe some other time then
-bye
I gotta go
I'm working on a job from Mr. kilmer
-ooh
god
he had a such crush on Jane
he didn't even figure it out with that diamond ring and all
Jane honey, show her that necklace Derick gave you
do you like it?
he felt bad that for not picking up the other day so he gave this
I can't wait for you guys to meet him, he's gonna come to the happy hour
really
-alright
you wanna come? we go every Wednesday
great, you buy one drink, other free snacks you can eat
you should come, ___
oh you should come, it's fun
it'll be good time
I don't know
good
hey you guys
let's go to the 35er this time I heat a lot single men go up there
no I have to mail something for Mr. Anderson first
alright of course you do
-what was, what she said?
said of course she does
I never been to the 35er
what I hear it's really great
uh, she's doing it again, I'm gonna go get her
oh god
Jane got this cheeking thing going
she's perfectionist, it's a bit much
where's the waitress? I need a drink
she's flirting with the entire restaurant
on lades night shame on her
I'm gonna get me these
cute I gotta remember shot glass on my bridal list
what?
give me your purse
why?
just give it me
there, save you the trip, best wishes, Jane
somebody could've seen that Margaret
if anyone saw us we'd be drinking by now
-yeah, fine
-can I get your number too
I don't like her
let's hit the buffet, come on
get me some nachos I gotta make phone call
watch out
'cus it's spicy
ooh, you're right, it burns
aw, uh
excuse me
now I haven't ever seen you here before
oh yeah
you work around here?
well I tell you I am freelance
oh , what line of work
um, the credit business
for the honeymoon___
credit
did a book report once for extra credit
oh [chukles]
that's what you do, I'm sure
-no it isn't
can I give you on of these?
-okay
ooh
great, Derick's gonna come up pick me up later
he has to work late
did you see that guy? did you see him
he gave me his card
and a pen, Jack Shoberg COU, cute
what is COU stand for?
I'd tell I don't know but
he's probably an executive of some kind
that name doesn't famlier to me and I don't know
I think I need to get more __these
oh here I finished you can take mine
well, I think I wanna strech my legs
get it?
[fake laugh]
no, Jack Shoberg, I know his name
the ladies room
his card on the floor of my stall
awh, he's passing his business cards like
it's candy that's gross
god they're laughing at her
jerks
hey Jack
okay, let's get out of here, time to go
come on Paula let's get out of here
what?
let's go
what about that guy I just met
you can do better
hi ___cumu
hi, hi
I think you can choose someone else
auh
oh I forgot just one thing
oh, let's go in
I don't really __ that crap
you know some people can see into the future, it's a fact
you __this
-yeah
I read about a horse that he has esp
he could type out messages on a typewriter with his
um nose
he predict it ___ world war II
and he helped find the body a boy who be missing for 2 years
he could type
stupid
I'm just kidding
hey
anyone of you want a reading
I could give discount
alright
__ said__ magic discount
I see changes ahead
something to do with work
my dad wants me get real job, could that be it
depends, is that what you want?
[sighs]
no
I don't wanna do sales
do you think I able to stay where I am
do you want to change your destiny?
you tip toe through life
don't be afraid to make your mark
what she say to you?
oh crap, ___ on fortune cookie
you know what stand out gets pounded down__
fraud
Derick's here
do i smell like booze?
oh you shouldn't care
c'mon hurry up
see you tomorrow, good night girls
good night, okay, night
hi Derick
did you see him, damn he's gorgeous
what's his deal though you know anything about him?
I don't know not much about it except we've been going out forever
and he buys her a lot of gifts, what you need to know?
I'm tired I'm going home, how do you go home?
I take the Broadstreet bus
so do I
I'll walk you guys
come on
we should ride together
right
-oh, okay
[whispering] don't tip toe through life
you have to make your mark
hi there
hello
hi, would you mind typing this letter for me?
okay
thank you I'd appreciate it
come in
that was quick
could you make me 40 copies of this? please
-yes, sir
-thank you
by the way, what's your name?
Iris
Iris, thank you Iris
I'm so so sorry
these are excellent
did you make 'em from scratch?
uh
where's yours?
I did ate it already
yeah
I fit right in
I liked it there
we're becoming good friends
ooh oh, excuse me, sorry
I'm so bad
okay
watch this
[laughs]
happy
uh
oaky
sad
uh
-angry
-uh
correct
okay
I give up
it's fear
yeah
I got my stage name all figure out too
Camille LaPlante
oh
you look beautiful
thanks
oh, Camille LaPlante, that's perfect
auh, yeah
I'm gonna change it legally too
as soon as I can afford it, you know
oh, I tell you, ever since I was little, I just
I know I was meant for somthing big
you know, I was just like
meant to be somebody
just a matter of time before I get discovered
oh look, here's one
low __wages in the office of supplies that you can steal
[chuckles]
oh, forget it, you have to type
I thought you're a good typer
no I cheat it on that test
oh, I just want a desk by a window and a decent
chair
but this place is so cheap
they don't wanna pay benefits, that's why they hired transients
they make you (__ ign) bond (in__) hiring too
I should introduce myself and
sure I'll be showing her what really upset__ her
her loss, uh
I don't know it's good to
care, you'd look like __ cares
oh, Eddie let me have Kilmer's mail, I'll deliver this for you
-no,
I have to get it to his assistant
-his what?
the new girl, Cleo, over there
Jane, I was at lunch and I didn't see down there
oh, I'm on diet
you don't need a diet
excuse me
I thought she was just a temp, just look at her
oh, no no, she's Kilmer's new assistant
and she's permanent
how she get that job? I check the bulletin wi____ tab__ post it
can I have those back?
yeah, here
she's the president's ___ ma'am
would you look at that?
a new desk
damn this place
and everyone in it
you look busy
I think you won't come until Friday
well, I thought I swing by
before I take crack at those stores in berwesburg__
so, what you've been up to?
well, my job's going very well
my boss really likes me
there you go
haven't I just told you
just hang in, be your sweet self
and good things bound to happen
I made good friends too, we went out to dinner and everything
oh, they have good taste
I hope you gonna stay in touch with them
what do you mean?
I mean after you move on
to the big job with international __food
you know I have a feeling this is it, this is the one
yeah, I don't do so well with interviews
don't be silly of course you do
you're just gotta get in there and promote yourself
you know what they say
a good salesman's born, not made
you just happen to be born Bud Chapman daughter
you're not a nobody
listen, you won't be call Ed __claiber_ and
see I can speed up the process
-oh no no, that's okay
I actually spoke to him today
and said had to go out of town for awhile but he got my letter
and he's gonna give a call when he gets back and
setup an interview
great, you're off to a good start
you know with your education and personality
__while you can take over a company
you just have to get on door
most people spend their life dreaming about future
everyday
events are taking place around us while we wait for them
unaware
little things
quiet things
you hardly even notice
[in french accent] zthat is a
french tip
maybe only you pay attention when
something announces itself with a shout
that's how it went in that office
we're all just killing time
waiting for something to happen
anything
and then one day
something did
thief, thief
the money from coffee can, it's missing
shouting in the office
harder__ than work with
-can you believe this
it's stupid
____
they wouldn't do that, I don't think so
so no
-they done stupider things, my dear
____
a handful of change
it seems small enough
but, did know what it meant at the time
didn't change our routine
still
maybe there was some thing in the air
like a spell I've been cast over the office
I wonder if there was anything to that fortune teller said
my ban___ though
was here before, wasn't I check that at lunch, didn't I?
I don't know honey, but I gotta go, okay
copy guys are here too
you know what, here
just take new one, blank one
here you go, watch out for me
people clung to the adventure
they look for ways to __draw it out
some folks create their own traumas and practice their roles
and art
hey art
he kept an even tighter watch over the supplies
hey Margaret
can I have some staples?
how many?
how should I know? just give me some
thank you
I have a confession to make
Art
I've been ___hawking wide out
and pencils on the corner
just trying to make ens meet, you know
is that okay with you?
yeah
you'll keep it a secret
o'kay
there's mr do__ today
it's I don't know
excuse me this is personal
yeah it just keeps jamming, I don't know
so how did you get be with him__
you go to special school or
or work
um the machine is being repaired right now, you're gonna have to come back
Iris, wanna play hide and seek
did you see my coffee mug?
oh that really nice one with a naked lady on it
yeah, have you seen it?
no I haven't
are you sure you didn't move it
-I'm sure yeah
cus it had three pencils on it, it was on my desk
I tell you what, I look for it
it's very important
okay
thank you
hi
move out
conference room everybody in the conference room
chop, chop, let's go
what's this all about?
staff meeting
we're not on the staff
it's for everyone
all the department heads gonna be there
I mean I have to ask you to sit in that chair
because you're sitting in my seat, thank you
I wanna sit in this seat
it is my seat you know
thank you
I've called this meeting today because of serious problem
it's been brought to my attention
this morning
Tom Briggs an accounting
noticed
her crystal paperweight in missing
number of you also reported
my coffee mug is also missing
actually was stolen, it wasn't missing if it stolen
from my office
recently
[stifled laugh]
number of you have also reported
crystal items missing
Mr Dolton's gold cigarette lighter
a framed photograph and dictionary
from Fred's desk I believe
and some spoons from the kitchen
yes Diane
I keep a pair of shoes in my desk
and now one of them is missing
what
if anyone here
has a problem
financial or otherwise
come forward to say something
[clears throat]
I'd like to think of us as a family here
it's difficult for me to believe
someone in this room
could be capable of stealing
um
[clears throat]
who do you think is doing it
use your head it's that new girl
you mean clio__
yeah, I do
on that missing _jock non of it missing until she showed up
how could be so sure it's her
oh c'mon she's Kimer's assistant
she got free access to anyone office that she pleases
uhh
but why she steals?
why, why not? what difference does it make?
look I'll know is everything was fine until she showed up
um
-um
this is not for me, you know who would look great with this
Iris
oh, no I don't wear much lipstick
why not you got such beautiful mouth
you got lips that say hi, I'm here
I wanna be heard
would you look at that
excuse me
hi
yeah do you have any free samples of this?
no, we certainly oh that's
50 dollars an___ ems
oh great I have very expensive taste
-yeah
oh god I'm out my hand__ tonight
oh that's pretty you should get that
-I don't need anything
-it look good on you
maybe it's part of sales
you know, I watch)__ that sign over there
oh no, I don't wanna bother her
excuse me is this part of sale?
excuse me is miss
excuse me
it's not in sale
it should be, I could tell you that much
it's okay, I pay whatever it ....
let's go like this if she looks our way
we're going to discount
that night I thought about missing items at work
how every objects has it's own story
like a seashell
or notebook
what's seems ordinary to one person is another's treasure
well I'll love that __ensemble
look
matching umbrella
morning
good morning
oh mamacita, what's the big occasion
copy guy, today's the day I make my move
oh, he smells nice
thank you
hi Barbara
morning Barbara
good morning
um
I understand that the four of you left early yesterday
I hope you remembered to adjust your time cards
we will oh yeah we will
also it has come to my attention that some of you are making personal phone calls
that is against company policy
wow, you know what? I love your scarf
oh these colors really compliment your skin toes
oh Barbara listen
the copy machine's not working again
do you want me to call the repair guy? cus I will
no, that won't be necessary I have chleo take look at it
she is very good with office equipment
okay, great okay
shit shit
shit I just got this new outfit and everything
I can't believe that skinny bitch knows how to
fix a copy machine
she was hanging around my desk other day when I was on the phone
I wonder she was the one ratted on me for making personal phone calls
I wonder she saw us leave early yesterday
I'm not afraid of her,I mean cus she's got a job
she's in__ nothing
she's wearing your sweater
yeah
it's weird
I like your blouse
[phone ringing]
yeah
that new girl. she kept to __ourselves
that made her specious I guess
it somehow just by being there
she seem to bring us close together
hey, guess ho I saw last night
Jack showbert
__clu
-uh
oh she looks so cute
my presentation gone, in fact somebody stolen my presentation
okay
-I don't have a copy, my presentation is in 30 minutes
so could we do something about this? please, my presentation's gone
in 30 minutes a client is coming
-okay
I can't find it, I don't have backup file, and I think in fact ...
-[whistles]
somebody stolen my presentation
-okay
we're on it
did you guys see Jane?
-I need help
-it's taken care of
be busy, you know, help, I like help
okay, my presentation gone
_(deal__theorize) numbers, when you get to the numbers just follow the numbers
don't care about the colors, okay?
they happend to to be defferent colors, get it ____
-he wants to talk to __bob
I don't care who it is
you can't talk to _mark you'll find answer because he has neighbors
just bought this blouse, just gonna wear it for audition
I told you to wear a _beav
oh god let me go help her
Mr. Lasky, we got it all taken care of
you can take this call in to the ...
-okay
honey I'll call back, bye bye sweetie
-to your office
do we do spell check?
of course
you sure
-ahm
do you wanna check?
-auh
thank god, one of us can type, uh
got it
Jesus
check out the new look
wider rims__
why she look at and why you're setp_ down
because she spying on us
notice that cleo didn't gets her hands dirty
who do you think took those damn documents anyway
she was watching us the whole time
I'm getting little sick of it
I don't know about you girls but we're doing all the shit work and still even notices
hey I'm not laughing
Jane will you get me tissue will you
give me a whole roll cus I'm low at home
this cause for action
I think we should go and strike
just not show up one day
can you imagine? they'd be totally lost it
and completely scrambled
specially between 9 and 10
my god the phones
with all this out they definitely see how much they need us
I think we should do it
hah, count me in, I'm looking forward to it
yeah so am I
oh me to , my god
wow it's really coming down
even though the lady__ ____arowing, jezz
you coming or what?
criminal secretly wanna get caught
I read that once , they have a
- guilty conscious
-oh, yeah
she'll trip Barb, nothing last for ever
Iris isn't that Jane's boyfriend?
that chick better be his cousin
oh man
son of a bitch
2 weeks before her shower
he's gonna have to buy her something really big with this one
sorry about the mess my roommate's outta town
just make yourself comfortable
take your coat off
Oh' kay
so what you roommate like?
you know what I don't know
and we never see each other
she's flight attendant
we communicate through notes on the fridge
oh just like the one's at work
yeah
can I fix you a drink
yeah sure
- why don't you sit down I'll be your hostess
I got that form a hotel I was stayed at
a souvenir you know
it's cute
-yeah
you know what I like out apartment
really
-yeah
um
you know this is a closest I've come to live by myself
where I was growing up I had to share everything with my sisters
perfect sisters, uh
who would have thought getting a crummy job would be so hard?
[cough]
itll__ last place I was at there for 3 years
place was so big there was temps filling for temps
I don't think anyone even knew I was there really
why did you leave?
I didn't leave I got canned
yeah, I was fired
hired some relative over me
permanent
I am actually sit there doing nothing as good as somebody's nephew
you know 3 years zip nothing no even a recommendation
I think Mr. elaski really starting to depend on you
I think if you asked give you a recommendation
I need that recommendation
to the recommendation
-um
-to the recommendation
I can't believe you got one of these, wasn't expensive?
oh yeah, please don't make fun of me today my parents ____
good morning how are you today
- hi
you look great
my mom and dad are in town
oh look at you?
- how's the audition
oh it went okay
I got a small part
can't wait to see you act professionally
it's too bad that last year fell through
who's this one coming up?
um, I'm not sure but when I know I let you know okay
you know what gotta get in
-alright
hi
leastki need it by 5 but he's checking on it every 30 frigging seconds
look it finished
I can't deal with this now, I'm incredibly late
so if my wife calls would you tell her I left 14 minutes ago, but __ alot of traffic, alaen
ellen
you hair is so beautiful
I mean it looks great with that
you think you could find out what kind of perfume she wears
would that be passible
so if her birthday coming up
no machine can replace __ one that drinks
want some?
um
it can __ start tonight
my mom and dad taking me out to dinner
to hear big loser speech while you___ free tommy
you're not a loser
[sigh]
___you're just my dad now
why can't be more like your sisters?
is that hard to find permanents?
yeah it is
you can tell him how hard you've been working here, that's something
yeah you're right that's good idea
think they'll understand, gonna go smoke
so will you be taking this bus to rehearsals too?
I guess so
you know when they start I mean, right
I'd tell you that Jack guy better call me soon
left him 2 messages
suppose he thinks I'm just gonna sit and wait
tell you I've got better things to do with my time
yeah, dont' worry
I'm not worried
Iris
oh my dad's here
hey do you wanna come meet him?
he could give you a ride
I'd tell you the bus will be here soon , I'll wait
yeah I'm fine go ahead
okay go then bye
hi
wow, small world, uh?
yeah
I had to pick up some thing from the mall
so I thought I swing by here, see if I can catch you
yeah thanks
looking at backseat?
I had it on layaway
dad it's looks expensive
I don't realy need ___ at this job
oh don't be silly
you need it alright for that big interview
it's known as power suit
I'm sure you really hear something really soon
yeah I guess
I mean they had your letter for while now
good morning, Iris
hi
oh my got it's so bright in here
I feel like I'm inside of xerox machine
I was_ so wasted last night I told my dad I've got a real job here
executive assistant
[chuckles]
please
she needs a briefcase
you in __ you out the other lady
__ sadas___ sudden disappearance
____
what's going on
__  laski 's dead
he had a heart attack last night
you lucky you latch on __ he really appreciates you
not to mention he's alive
try getting a recommendation outta dead guy
can I have one of those?
see that old lay over there, __it's been couples years
feel like ___ heer
you're floating
you're not connected to anything or anybody
yeah sometimes
I feel like I could vanish and no one would even notice.
Not for weeks
where's jane?
she's still getting ready
hope you'all ready to play some games
tina Jane's sister is an actor too just like you
what? really?
-um
is she been anything?
oh I don't know, I think she takes classes
oh she does take class, I think she's pretty
nah, what she is, she's Jane's sister
but what's up with these games she want us to play,I mean, stand up and give advice to __brag
i don't what you mean, like in front of any one like speech
what are you gonna say?
she don't wanna hear my advice, believe me
you don't have to leave soon before it's starts
I'm gonna buy__with__ exactly
suppose you have something against Derck
what was that?
Margaret what is going on?
what is it babe? you looking at each other
I just think she's too good for him
that's your big secret
that's it?
okay? okay?
wanna know why i __loathe__ him???
it got nothing to do with Derck, it's Jane
have you noticed? she's a freak
have you seen her? have you look at her in office?
she's like this fluffy stuffed animal
big dead eyes__ she's going through emostions, you know
that's what's she's been doing with this wedding
she's getting married just to get married
if that's your only option
like that's what she supposed to do
yeah
-allright
first of all margaret
that is what most people do do
okay, our Jane has found a fellow who gives her things
and he's got good taste too
he gives her pandi__ and flowers and jewelry
that's hell of alot
right after he's blowing her off
Derseck forget to pick me up today, bing
she gets a necklace
cheap necklace
you know what, you have to lighten up because we're at the party
here, honey
just when I was hoping things settle down loise shows up
ih
it was a permanent , so I moved
items began to vanish again
there are new rules putting to effect
routine socializing was frown upon
locks appeared on kitchen cupboards
we did our best to pretend we're busy
we played our parts
and we wander what lay ahead
just around the corner, waiting for us
so creepy here now, you know
I feel like I'm up to something, right
thinking about asking the agency for transfer
yeah, even only 2 months I don't care
don't bother I did already tried
cus my rehearsal schedule, you know
anyway the agency says there's no work right now, it's just really slow
i gotta keep on working
thoufhdfg ___ i don't __have money __yet
if you leave now they never know how thing turn out with all stealing
don't you wanna know how it ends
if you leave now i bet that sneaky little bitch would stop her thievery
and what's that gonna look like
I feel gulity
it's fine
I'm not leaving
not without a recommendation, I was here at first, I'm staying right where I am
Iris, I just figured something out
I think I know what the next move gonna be
I was thinking to myself what would I do if I were stealing
like I 'd say something of mine is missing
to defect attention, like I was a victim
I am not a phony fortune teller but I can tell you one thing
whoever trying to stealing
is gonna say something of theirs disappeared
there's gonna be sure sign ___killed
what are you looking at?
-nothing
attention, no unauthorized personnel allowed in this floor after 5
see  I'm __ ,didn't I tell you? guilty
guilty as charged
my scarf is missing
you know the one you're all admiring
so if any of you happen to see it
let me know
why would she looking at us like that?
she think it's one us
I never said anything about her stupid scarf
hey doesn't matter to her we're interchange__
she always sees us together, she doesn't know who's who
why would she thinks it's one us
cus we're temps
and you heard what kimer said at that meeting
that crap  about _ it's all about being family
guess what we're not part of thier office
family and I don't wanna be anyway
we're all temps are like, corporate orphans, we're like corporate call girls
we don't belong here, that's what's make us suspects
those are our desks
huh
what a coincidence
there are only temps on this floor
shove us together where they keep their eyes on us
stare at us all day
glass wall ___ sick amusement
we're in goddamn fishbowl
staples are horizontal__
let's try to keep it neat
these are going to important clients
paula
do you have pen __ just right now
cut it out, will you?
some one see us talking
[phones rings]
credit
could you hand me a pen please
you know what I'm all out, mines keeps disappearing
I can't even find my Jack__Solbert
here you can take mine, it's not very sharp but you can have it
no that's alright Iris you need it
just take a look at desk in front of you Paula
I'm not about to picking through somebody else's desk, eheh
no one is sitting there
somebody might see me
you're the one who always wanted an audience
you know what?
because you're loud doesn't mean people have to listen
what's that supposed to mean?
nothing, nothing, it's just that
I'm not one who's trying to stir things up around here okay I've done anything right
oh really, I've two words for you
copy machine
will you be quiet?
right?
you're getting us a lot of trouble
I wouldn't point fingers if I were you
you're the one who's always making personal calls
you're just saying that because you guys don't like Derck
what __ took my chair
can I have something to write with?
I gave you number2__ pencils yesterday
Art, please
I'm in no mood, okay
oh come on 5 or 6, I'm on big project
[tods]
damn this music
trying to mess with our heads
I'm going to launch
you say you won't coming?
I'm on a diet
guess I cancel our reservation for four
down to cafeteria Paula
__ stay with derck
bye
___ we lunchtime __ wanna smoke some pot
[door closes]
[food steps approaching]
are you allright?
no
I'm pregnant, I think
have you been to a doctor you should see a doctor
yeah, i have an appointment tomorrow
I cleared it with BArbara
believe me this is the last thing I can afford right know
well if you need money I have some saved
um, I got it covered, thanks
uh, you know what just forget I even said anything
probably shouldn't told anybody
Paula
kilmer's wallet was stolen, he noticed last night
there's a lot of money in it too
you see those guards in there
they are starting interview people
they took a statement form me
they want us to rat on each other
get us ol' divide and conquer
trying to split us apart
where's Paula? she get her stupid transfer
maybe she has a rehearsal
Iris
there's no rehearsal, don't you get it?
it's all sad ___ aniv___
yo seidny try to go the __show
and mysteriously disappeared just like us
I know what else _camile__ lying about
oh shit
Paula
hey did you get my messages other night?
yeah oh thank you
my whole life is here
why don't you call
I was worried and then you didn't show up yesterday
I just got a lot going in on right now, remember
rehearsals and ...
everything
you want some?
oh no thanks
why looking at me funny
no I'm not
I get it
my mother know someone in cosmetics
sometimes she give me free samples
it's it's
fucking perfume, anyway, right?
oh, nice flowers
what are you depressed about
you have a boyfriend, you're getting married
at least you have a way out of this place
Iris, I'm scared
I think I was here like the night the wallet was stolen, I don't know
I can remeber
maybe I placuk__ out or something but
I think I''m the guilty one and I did it _____
I looking for wallet calling over the police, you know I can't find anywhere
oh god I don't know anything anymore
__glad_ I didn't know something
god , __ we don know anything for sure
I don't know
It's funny how doubt hides itself
It follows behind you
It waits in every corner
You never see it coming
But you feel it, on the inside
Maybe it was just that office
or maybe it was bigger than that
it was all around. A million eyes
Watching
Judging
The whole wide world even
You feel so small
could you come with me please
we have a certain standard grooming we expect our employees to adhere to, and
your shirt ham is hanging
I hope this isn't going to be a problem
I really hate to have to replace people
excuse me
Iris
what did she tell you?
you don't tell me
you should write that in your little notebook of yours
it's fine
do you know anybody might have financial needs?
no
how about a grievance
you hearing any complaint about working environment or other personnel
anybody that's unhappy?
let me ask you this
how well do you know your co-workers
because situation like this
your perpetrator could be anybody
could be somebody
you know very little about
or that might be somebody
you think you know
very well
um a problem I told you about before, was a flasw alarm
I thought you show know
[sigh]
no
I forgot something
excuse me you can't go up there
I leave my notebook up there
it's after 5 o'clock ma'am, you'll have to come back in the morning
floor's closed
it oughta worth another meeting
what the hell?
did you see a notebook in there
if you like report missing, we can add it to list
excuse me sir those are some of personal belongings
what are you doing?
-routine desk search lady
-oh, routine my butt
yeah why did you pick these desk to search
why not that one over there?
Cleo's desk, Cleo with C, a big gold C
why is __she all suspicious___
and you know what they're doing
trying feel us guilty, so they can control us
just want us to feel crappy about ourself
man __ that everything we do
that's it I'm sick of it, I'm sick of being treated like a criminal
remember that plan we had I think it's time follow through with it
let's not show up tomorrow, see what's happens then
is everyone in?
-yeah sure
oh, look, my finger puppet ___ incriminating evidence
you're like held one
__twice
as a group you can really make big statement
it's a risk, but gotta take a risk, if you noticed
they can treat us this way
and they can't crush us in the silence
tomorrow
you strike
I eh, got scared, never missed a day before
I changed my mind
I don't know about you guy but I need this job
you know, it's a little I've got
besides you know what was I just thinking?
maybe it's not her maybe that's just somebody want us think
you konw what that cop told me?
he said the guilty one is the first one who point fingers
maybe people stoped looking at me all the time
where's the other one?
um I don't know
it's not very professional she knows company policy
must have call in if you're absent or late
I think she's done this before
I wish I could tell you I never doubt a friend
I wish could say that place hadn't gotten better of us
but that's not the way it happened
Sometimes it hits you how quickly the present fades into the past
and you question everything around you
you wonder if anything you'd ever do would matter
or if you could just disappear
without a trace
hey, I thought of this crazy place all day
yesterday I can wait hear what happened , they have to noticed right
I noticed
did you checking in and out, or some thing?
Paula, what happened?
if i were you I would keep my voice down okay, cus you're in a shitload of trouble
what happened?
I guess
I'm just
not like you
yah know it's sad, isn't it, how people always end up betraying each other?
And for what?
can you read this while you're waiting
excuse me
you're in my seat
there's a vacancy over there though
we won't be needing you here anymore
I was really sick yesterday Barbara
okay let's have scene
you aren't need it
you firing me
how can you fire me, you don't even know my NAME
why not, listen to lady say take your stuff and leave
oh I get it
Oh. You think I'm your little office thief
oh, you got me
You finally got me
-come on
yeah
-you've got 15 seconds, lets go
stop it can you just let go, can you see I'm trying to get my stuff
can I get my stuff?
thank you
I had things you know
is anyone gonna say anything?
you know I'm not a thief
is anyone gotta stick out for me
is anyone gonna speak?
I have a name you know
it's Margaret
Margaret with M, take a memo Barbara
I often wished I had that moment to live over
I wished I'd said something
Soon afterward Jane left
the wedding was beautiful
I read about it in the newspaper
Paula got transferred to the accounting department
Once in a while they let her out to photocopy
I like to imagine she kept up her singing
I had to change desks a few more times
It was easier to forget where I was that way
And there was something else
the stealing stopped
I was almost beginning to think none of it had happened
Sometimes I thought about what Margaret said
About how a person can just drift through life
like they're not connected to anyone
or anything
You look around
all those characters trying to kill time
Going around in circles
Even if a person wanted to break free
they could find out they've got nowhere else to go
listen I'm gonna be in the meeting shortly when I'm done just pop in the office, thanks
we never talked about it
we didn't have to
there was nothing to say
what she took from us
is more than she can put in her pocket
it was like she owed me something
can you make 10 copies of this please
thanks
that girl Cleo, she wasn't so different than rest us
she just wanted to be noticed
she wanted to be somebody
you have to make your mark
excuse me
This is my last day here and I was wondering if you could give me a recommendation
I'd be glad to
Well, actually, I've already written something if you could just sign it
Well you've certainly been a big help here
Good luck to you, Margaret
Everything is temporary
Everything begins and ends
and sometimes begins again
When I look ahead
I imagine infinite possible futures
repeated like countless photocopies
a thousand blank pages
and in each one I see myself
never hiding
never sitting silently
and never just waiting
and waiting
and watching the world go by
the end