Buster Keaton in College
Directed by : James W. Horne
On the sunkist slopes of the Pacific,
where land and water meet - -
California.
High School Graduation Day, where the next
step is either go to college or go to work.
A few drops of rain
couldn't dampen a mother's -
- enthusiasm on her
son's Graduation Day.
MAIN STREET DEPT. STORE
$15
Mary Haynes - winner of
every popularity contest -
- in which the boys
were allowed to vote.
89 CENTS
Jeff Brown -
Star athlete, who believed so much -
- in exercise that he made
many a girl walk home.
"I didn't think you would call for me in
the rain. I'm sorry you are all wet."
"Young man, it's time you graduated.
You've been here seven years."
"I know you are going to be as popular
at Clayton College as you were here."
"It is my pleasure to present this
diploma to our most brilliant scholar."
"- and your scholastic record
richly merits this honor medal."
"Ronald will now speak on
the 'Curse of Athletics'."
"The secret of getting a medal like
mine is - - books not sports."
"The student who wastes
his time on athletics -
- rather than study shows
only ignorance."
"Future generations depend
upon brains and not -
- upon jumping the discus
or hurdling the javelin."
"What have Ty Ruth or Babe
Dempsey done for Science?"
"Where would I be without my books?"
"Your speech was ridiculous.
Anyone prefers -
- an athlete to a weak-knee'd,
teachers' pet."
"When you change your mind about athletics,
then I'll change my mind about you."
"Mary is going to enter Clayton ...
I wish I could go."
"I'm afraid we can't afford it, dear."
"I can work my way through. Other boys do."
So the following term, Ronald arrived
at Clayton, and was met by ...
Clayton
BOY WANTED
"I need another clerk as good as he is."
"You can commence tomorrow."
"Well, if it isn't the student prince."
Slow
Narrow Bridge
DON'T SMOKE
DON'T SPIT
How to play Baseball
How to play Football
How to Sprint
"I am Dean Edwards. Your principal writes
me what an excellent student you are."
"A boy like you can make
this athlete-infested college -
- a seat of learning once more."
"You boys will do well to follow the
example of this young scholar."
Sunday found Ronald taking
"fizzical" exercise.
BOY WANTED
"You play third base for the second team."
"You forced two men out
and you're out too."
WANTED
Colored Waiter
"Bring me something you
can't stick your thumb in."
Clayton's wonder track team training
for the intercollegiate meet.
"I admire his spirit.
At least, he's trying."
"Don't get too interested
in that campus clown. -
- You're supposed
to be going with me."
"You take an awful lot for granted."
"Attaboy, you made a hole in one."
A call to the Dean's office
meant only one thing -
GRIEF
"You have been a miserable failure in all
your studies and I know the reason why."
"I took up athletics because the
girl I love thinks I'm a weakling."
"I love her and would do
anything to please her."
"I understand, my boy. The
same thing happened to me, -
- but I was stubborn.
That's why I'm a bachelor."
"Here's a list of the men
eligible for the rowing crew."
"Coach, I'd like to have you make
this young man coxswain of the crew."
"His size and weight are
perfect and he has brains."
"My request is final."
"Clayton can't lose the boat race now.
I've just been appointed the 'Coaxer'."
"Boys, get out the smelling salts - -
- Little Lord Fauntleroy is
your new coxswain."
"It's the Dean's orders. He'll
be in that race unless -"
"- unless something
happens to the poor boy."
The day of the race.
"Hey, coach - nothing has
happened to Mama's boy!"
"Don't worry - you're coxswain.
Give him this and -
- he'll wake up just in time
for the football season."
"Please leave! If you were seen in my
room it would mean expulsion for me!"
"That's just what I want. I
was expelled this morning -
- and thought I would like
to take you with me."
"I'm going to stay here
until we are discovered - -
- then you might change your
mind about marrying me."
"Boys, we've got to win!
If we don't, rowing -
- will be a thing of the
past at Clayton!"
"Is Ronald our coxswain to-day?"
"Certainly not. I've taken care
of that pest in a big way."
The rival crew, ready for their
most important race of the year.
THE BULLET
"Go on, they are waiting for you.
They've just been kidding me."
"Maybe it's halitosis -
Four out of five have it."
OFFICIAL
DAMFINO
"Go get a boat with a strong bottom."
OLD IRON BOTTOM
"Ready all!"
"Hurry - Jeff has me locked
here in my room, and he -"
"Young lady, do you know what this means?"
"Yes - it means we are
going to be married."
THE END
Subtitle By Reza Fa