- Night, Michelle.
Bob saget.
America's funniest home videos.
[Upbeat funky music]
[Woman moans]
Oh, my God.
Male announcer: This is
the comedy central roast
of Bob saget
with your roastmaster
John stamos
and roasters susie essman,
Jeff garlin,
Greg giraldo,
Gilbert gottfried,
cloris leachman,
jon lovitz,
norm MacDonald,
Jim Norton,
Brian posehn,
and Jeffrey Ross
with special appearances
by Lewis black,
Sarah silverman,
and don rickles.
The comedy central
roast of Bob saget.
And now please welcome
your roastmaster, John stamos.
[Cheers and applause]
- Thank you.
Tonight we're here
to pay tribute to an actor,
an author, director,
humanitarian,
and incomparable showbiz whore.
I'm talking, of course,
about Bob saget.
[Cheers and applause]
Now, if you younger viewers
are tuning in
to watch Uncle Jesse
help Danny Tanner
find a tender way to solve
one of Michelle's problems,
go fuck yourself.
So the good news is,
we're here
to bust saget's balls.
The bad news is,
it's yet another show
starring Bob saget,
which means it won't be funny,
and it'll go on
for fucking ever.
Now, let's take a look back
at what Bob thought
made people laugh.
- You're now about to witness
the strength of Bob saget.
Bob saget.
- Bob the comic, ladies!
Let's bring him back out!
- ♪ Bob saget, bitch,
you better ask someone ♪
- ♪ who you rolling with?
- ♪ Bob, Bob saget
♪ numero uno
♪ nobody does it better
- ♪ who you rolling with?
- Hey.
- Hey, Bob saget.
- Hey-oh!
- Oh, your dick is so big!
- ♪ I got a cock like a donkey,
hard as a rock ♪
♪ and a trigger finger
itchier than chicken pox ♪
- Come on, grandpa.
We want to watch
Terrance and Phillip.
- No, we're gonna watch
the Bob saget show.
- Hello and welcome to America's
funniest home videos.
Gee, my name is granny,
and I'm falling on my Fanny.
- [Laughs]
- This guy sucks!
- Yeah, he's almost as bad
as that guy on full house.
- You are full house daddy-dad?
- I was the full house
daddy-dad.
The girls just mean
so much to me.
- It's cool, cool, cool.
- And now we're gonna do
what daddy always does.
Suck dick for coke.
- I seen him!
- Little bitch Kimmy gibbler.
I feel bad I banged her.
- You know how that feels,
Mr. t.
- So they're all
fucking each other, right?
All of a sudden,
the kid can't take it.
Diarrhea starts squirting
out of his ass.
It's like a hemorrhaging
shit ass.
- You know what an ass shot
of America's favorite dad
is going for these days?
What the fuck happened
to Mr. Tanner?
What the fuck?
- ♪ 'Cause I'm a pimp,
they see me rolling through ♪
- Oh my God.
- Hot 19-year-olds
or 20-year-olds
are attracted to you.
- Why don't you show me
your room, baby?
- Did you just get cock blocked
by Bob saget?
- You don't exploit that,
obviously,
in your personal life.
- I have met--
- [laughs]
- ♪ Bob saget
- thanks a lot.
Good night, boys.
Excuse me.
I've got to go
to my nuclear physics class.
Oh, you know what?
I got to go on.
I'm sorry.
I got people to entertain.
- Who the fuck was that guy?
- ♪ The illest motherfucker
in a cardigan sweater ♪
- Night, Michelle.
[Cheers and applause]
- Please welcome
our guest of honor,
the luckiest man
and the worst entertainer
in the history of show business,
he's a huge asshole
and one of my best friends,
Bob saget!
[Cheers and applause]
[Goat bleats]
- Hey, call me.
- Bob, I was with you
for 192 episodes of full house,
and I can honestly say
you don't have a funny bone
in your body,
unless, of course,
you count the one time
you sat on Dave coulier's cock.
And by "sat on,"
I mean hungrily backed into.
And by "one time,"
I mean eight seasons.
You know, the whole time
Bob and I were doing full house,
he was also hosting
America's funniest home videos.
He did that show for so long,
he can't get a boner
unless a six-year-old boy
whacks his balls
with a wiffle bat.
What a tough gig
that must've been, huh?
His entire job
consisted of saying,
"take a look at this,"
which is what he used to say
to Mary-Kate Olsen
in her dressing room.
Bob's last hbo special
was called that ain't right.
Should have been called
that ain't watchable.
That was the most pathetic
piece of shit I ever seen.
And need I remind you, I did
eight seasons of full house.
Bob, you're
an undeniable success,
deserving of the millions
of dollars
you lost in the divorce.
Bob, you are a class act.
And you've been there for me
through the good times and bad,
and I'm so flattered
that you asked me
to be the roastmaster
this evening.
I think this is gonna be
a great night for you.
I hope you have the time
of your life, buddy.
- Thank you.
[Cheers and applause]
- Enough of this sappy shit.
Let's get on this
with this train wreck, shall we?
He's back again
making his annual disappearance.
Please welcome
the unknown comic,
one of my favorites,
Greg giraldo.
[Cheers and applause]
- Thank you.
Thank you, everybody.
John stamos.
Isn't he/she great?
John played the bongos
in a beach boys video
wearing a pink tank top.
That couldn't have been
any gayer
if George Michael
was on your lap
stuffing crystal meth
up your ass
with Rupert Everett's fist.
You're on er now, John.
Congratulations.
You're like
susie essman's vagina.
You're almost useless,
but somehow you keep working.
John was married
to my favorite supermodel,
Rebecca romijn O'Connell.
Jesus.
Holy.
John, you--
John, you lost your wife
to the fat kid
from stand by me.
Holy shit.
Look at you,
you greasy Greek bastard.
I look at you and I wonder,
how can there be
an energy crisis?
We shouldn't be drilling
in Alaska.
We should be wringing out
your family's pillowcases.
Norm MacDonald is here,
one of the funniest people ever.
Norm's got
a giant gambling problem.
He's dropped more coin
in a casino
than Michael j. Fox
at a parking meter.
It's a fucking roast.
Groany-groan-groan.
Brian posehn, look at him,
that giant fucking ghoul.
We've all seen you shirtless
on the Sarah silverman show.
It's hard to believe
you could be so out of shape
considering how often
the townspeople
must chase you around
with torches.
The great cloris leachman,
of course, is here.
Cloris leachman, yup.
[Cheers and applause]
Cloris is so old
she lost her virginity
to a druid.
What are you doing here, cloris?
You're the only person
with any talent.
You won an Oscar and nine emmys.
When it comes to winning awards,
you've been more voracious
than jon lovitz
at an all the dick
you can eat buffet.
Jon lovitz,
you fucking gay weeble.
Come on, jon, there hasn't been
a more effeminate Jew
in the closet
since Anne Frank.
Susie essman, look at you.
You're a mess.
You're like screech with tits.
I guess cloris leachman is here
to make you seem fuckable.
Gilbert gottfried's here.
Gilbert recently had a baby.
Who would fuck you?
You have the sex appeal
of a school bus fire.
Which brings me
to the man of the hour,
Bob saget, everybody, huh?
Bob saget.
[Cheers and applause]
Bob--
Bob, you are a genital wart
on the cock of American culture.
Seriously, who gives a shit
about Bob saget?
With your long neck,
pointy beak, and granny glasses,
you're like
the vlasic pickle stork.
Except instead
of delivering babies,
you're not funny.
You're like
my seven-year-old son.
You think cursing is hilarious,
and you're not surprised
your dick
is the same size it was
in the first grade.
And where the hell
are the Olsen twins?
The olsens
are like tom green's testicles.
They look the same, but one
is fake and empty inside,
and the other one's been licked
by heath ledger.
He'd be cool with it, fuckers.
I read an interview
where you referred to yourself
as an artist.
Are you fucking kidding me?
As an artist?
You used the phrase,
"as an artist"?
You are a vortex
of artistic compromise.
Charlie sheen watches you
and feels good about himself.
You--
you are an artist
in the same way
cloris leachman is moist.
[No audible dialogue]
You're not an artist, Bob,
and stop enjoying
your ironic hipness
that's going on
with you these days.
You're not cool.
Stop trying to be hip.
At one point in your act,
you actually say,
"who's your daddy?
Say my name.
Look me in the eye.
True that."
Holy fuck.
I couldn't cringe any harder
if I watched my mom
in a bukakke video.
I'm done being mean, Bob.
I've met you a bunch of times.
You've always been hilarious
and super cool,
and everybody that knows you
loves and respects you.
Nobody ever has a bad thing
to say about you,
and that's
particularly surprising,
because you're Jewish,
and you're obnoxious people.
Thanks a lot
for letting me do this.
Thank you.
[Cheers and applause]
- Greg giraldo.
Our next roaster
brought Saturday night live
to a whole new level of funny
by leaving the show.
Tonight he's debuting a
character he's been working on:
Sweaty guy with no jokes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please tolerate jon lovitz.
[Cheers and applause]
- Thank you.
Say, how funny was the new guy,
Geraldo Rivera?
Yes.
I tell you, that's
the first time I've been roasted
by an illegal alien.
You know, Bob's
a good friend of mine.
He's probably one
of my best friends,
and there's been a rumor
going around Los Angeles
for the last 50 years
that Bob is gay.
And he's not gay.
You know, he's got
a beautiful wife,
beautiful girlfriend.
So I'd like to sing
some songs now
to kill the rumor
that he's gay.
And this first song is called
Bob saget isn't gay
and hopefully
will kill the rumors that he is,
which he is not.
[Clears throat]
♪ Bob saget isn't gay ♪
♪ the sky isn't blue ♪
♪ grass isn't green,
and I'm not a Jew ♪
No, I'm kidding.
Of course he's not gay.
But did you know that Bob's
a gourmet chef,
and he's always in his kitchen
cooking up something,
so I wrote a song about it.
It's called Bob saget
likes it in his kitchen.
♪ Oh, Mr. Bob saget
likes it in his kitchen ♪
♪ likes it in his kitchen,
♪ Mr. Bob saget
likes it in his kitchen ♪
♪ kitchen, of course
♪ is code for butt
hey, it's Bob's code.
I just cracked it.
Now, on a serious note,
I knew Bob's father.
He's a wonderful man
named Ben saget.
Ben saget was so proud
of his son's success,
he wrote a book about it.
The book is a loving tribute
from a father to his son.
It's called, my son the the fag
by Ben saget.
"I knew Bob was gay
when he was five.
"We were Jewish,
but Bob was so gay
"he used to run away to church.
"He'd beg the priest, 'let me
stay, and I'll do anything.'
"and then he'd say,
'can you blow out the candles?'
"and Bob would say,
'I don't know.
"Can you light your dick
on fire?'
"Bob's so gay, his asshole
is no longer a hole
but a smile."
- Oh, man.
- "Bob's so gay,
when he plays cards,
"a full house
is two dicks in the mouth
"and three in the butt.
"My son Bob is so gay,
"he wanted to rename his show,
1 vs. 100
"to stick it in my jellyfish ass
till it bleeds,
"catch the drippings in a cup,
"pour them back
into me intravenously
vs. 100."
I'd read you more,
but it starts to get gross.
Good-bye, everybody!
Good-bye!
[Cheers and applause]
- For your safety,
please avert your eyes
and welcome
the pork roastmaster general
Jeffrey Ross.
[Cheers and applause]
Wow, give it up for chachi.
Ladies, I spoke to flavor flav.
He said you can be on the show.
They're still here
from last year's roast.
Wow.
I know this is a big night,
because cloris leachman
put her teeth in.
Wow, what a legend.
Shakespeare did her in the park.
You look great, babe,
not a day over dead.
She come her in a limo
or a time machine?
Wow, doesn't Lisa lampanelli
look fant--
oh, that's Jeff garlin.
Sorry.
Norm MacDonald's so stoned
he thinks he's at a roast
for Bob seger.
I love you, norm.
Wow, you never come out, norm.
You're like the j.D. Salinger
of dick jokes.
Ugh.
Of course, Bob saget directed
norm MacDonald's movie,
dirty work.
Yeah.
A move that transformed
norm MacDonald into a star...
Bucks employee.
- Did you say something
after "star"?
- What's the over-under tonight?
What's gonna happen, norm?
- No, I wanted
to read something funny,
so I'm reading marmaduke.
- [Laughs]
Oh, my God.
This is what happens when
you book a dais off craigslist.
Jon lovitz, great job tonight.
Jon lovitz is single out there,
ladies, if you're single.
Yeah.
Jon lovitz went on match.Com.
They paired him up with a couch
and a bottle of hand lotion.
Yeah.
That's a three-way for him.
[Laughs]
And Dave coulier,
in case you think
we forgot about you, we did.
Oh.
But, ladies and gentlemen,
I'm here today
because I only roast
the ones I love,
and I love Bob saget.
I love him--
I love him
like a perverted Uncle
who pays for lunch
and then follows me
into the men's room.
Bob saget is a sick bastard.
He has two daughters in college
and three girlfriends
in high school.
Bob saget's girlfriend
is so young,
r. Kelly wouldn't pee on her.
Most comics dream
of performing
in Las Vegas, Nevada.
Bob saget dreams of performing
in Hannah Montana.
Full house should've
been called Blackjack,
'cause he hit on the olsens
when they were eight.
He didn't stop
till they were 21.
Is it true you used to give
Mary-Kate acting lessons?
He'd tell her,
"act like this never happened."
She'd be like,
"you got it, dude."
Actually, Mary-Kate and Ashley
were supposed
to be here tonight,
but they heard
there was gonna be food.
And although Bob saget
is not an insult comic,
I am insulted
when people call him a comic.
But if some of us
use dirty words as a crutch,
then Bob saget
must be a quadriplegic.
- [Laughs]
- But here's one
four-letter word
I know he's never heard:
Haha.
Bob, in case you haven't
figured it out yet,
this isn't a roast.
It's an intervention.
You can keep doing drugs,
but please stop doing comedy.
Please.
The people have spoken.
And, Bob, you may have noticed
I didn't use
any curse words tonight,
'cause I didn't want
to compete with the master.
Out of all the comics I know,
you have the filthiest mouth
and the kindest heart,
and I knew there was no way
I could top you.
But in honor of the late,
great George carlin,
I would like to leave you
all with another seven words
you can never hear
on television:
And the emmy goes
to Bob saget.
[Cheers and applause]
That's all I got to say,
'cause that's the punch line.
Bob saget.
[Laughs]
It doesn't even need a setup.
Bob, did you really need
a roast?
Your career
wasn't enough of one?
Full house.
Are you kidding me?
What the fuck was that about?
I think it's based
on what passes through the brain
of a comatose child molester.
It was like watching a stroke
in slow motion.
America's funniest home videos.
Were they, Bob?
Were they really the funniest?
How'd you do it, Bob?
How the fuck did you do it?
Why did you do it?
To make me feel better
about my career,
which at that point
was in the dumpsters--
I played pisshole clubs
across the country--
so I can feel better
about myself,
so I could think, "well,
things are shitty,
"but at least I'm not saget.
"I'm just a stripper.
At least I'm not a whore."
Well, I got to go.
All the best, Bob.
And, stamos,
you are so gay.
I tried to get
our next roaster's autograph.
Then I realized
she wasn't gene Simmons.
Please welcome
the least attractive cast member
on curb your enthusiasm,
susie essman.
[Cheers and applause]
- Thank you, pretty boy.
I had no idea, John,
you had such a sharp tongue.
That must really hurt
saget's ass.
You know, Bob, I was talking
about your career the other day,
and out of nowhere,
a fat lady started singing.
It was so weird.
Most of you don't know that Bob
is the complete opposite
of his image.
His image, by the way, is funny.
Jeff, my darling husband--
not in real life.
But you know,
you know I love you.
People are always
fascinated by Jeff,
and they're always asking me,
"is Jeff really fat?"
No, the camera adds 465 pounds.
Doesn't matter.
You're funny.
Doesn't matter
if you're a fat fuck,
'cause you're funny, right?
That's all that really matters.
Lot of funny here.
This dais is graced
with many, many fine comedians
and Bob saget.
- [Laughs]
- What do you get
when you cross Gilbert gottfried
with Jim Norton?
I don't know, but you wouldn't
want to fuck it.
Greg giraldo: The reason
vaginal dryness was invented.
Stamos, you're doable,
but I wouldn't,
because you're one of those
narcissistic good-looking boys,
like the kind of guy
who calls out his own name
when he's cumming.
Let's face it.
The only one
who's getting screwed tonight
is Bob saget.
Bob is one of those people who
every time you see him on TV,
you think, "whose dick
did he suck to get that gig?"
You know?
Bob spends more times
on his knees
after a big audition
than Mary-Kate does
after a big meal.
Bob will do anything for money.
That's why he's always
getting into cars
on Santa Monica boulevard.
And for years, I thought
he just needed a ride.
You know, I'm such an innocent.
You know,
and I met your girlfriend.
She's lovely.
And one good thing we know
is at least she's not
a star fucker.
The reason I'm here
is because
it was a challenge to me.
I love to putter in the kitchen,
and this was an opportunity
I couldn't pass up,
because I've baked a cake,
I've fried a chicken,
and this is the first time
I had a chance
to roast an asshole.
So I figured
I would just show up and do it.
And you know, I just got
a text message
from my self-respect,
and it said I have to leave.
So good night, everybody.
Thank you.
[Cheers and applause]
- We're lucky to have
our next comic, Brian.
After the roast,
he's got to get back
to the cabin in the woods
to skin some teenagers.
To avoid startling the creature,
please no flash photography
for Brian posehn.
[Cheers and applause]
- Keep it going for John stamos.
Wow, John.
If you and I were at a party,
our cocks would have nothing
to talk about.
[Chuckles]
Your dick has
a more impressive resume
than you do.
You know what?
I don't even know Bob saget.
I've met him twice.
I'm only here
because Lisa lampanelli
finally got murdered
by one of her black boyfriends.
That's right.
Norm MacDonald is here.
He does an amazing
Burt Reynolds impression.
And by that, I mean he's not
in movies anymore either.
Jodie sweetin's in the crowd.
Remember her?
Yeah.
[Cheers and applause]
I can't point her out,
but she's the full house girl
that isn't a crazy Christian
or a vagina on a stick.
So, uh--
Jodie sweetin, by the way,
hosted this terrible cable show
called pants-off dance-off.
Yeah.
Which is how I
used to watch full house.
That's right.
Yeah, how about Jeffrey Ross,
my buddy?
Yeah, yeah.
[Cheers and applause]
Jeff wants to be
an old comic so bad
that he's having
his balls lowered.
Cloris leachman, look at you.
You're older than the dirt
you sleep in.
Ah, that's so mean.
Susie, I know what it's like
to be called ugly like you.
I do.
I--my whole life.
Don't take it
personally, though,
'cause if you were a chick,
I would totally fuck you.
Seriously, I came here
to honor Bob saget.
Yeah.
[Cheers and applause]
That's right.
Bob has done a lot
for this country.
For eight seasons,
half an hour a week,
full house kept pedophiles
off the street.
In fact, three of them
were on the show.
Bob, I love
how you reinvented yourself
as this dirty comic,
you know?
But it worked a few times,
and now no one cares.
You're like the boy
who cried, "cunt."
- [Laughs]
- But, Bob, you've been
a big influence on me, man.
When Sarah silverman asked me
to play a gay guy on TV,
I didn't want to.
But then I thought, "hey, if
saget can do it..."
Bob, in all seriousness,
and I mean this deeply,
I hope horrible things
happen to you
tonight and for the rest
of your pitiful life.
I'm kidding, buddy.
Congratulations,
and have a good night.
Thanks, you guys.
[Cheers and applause]
- Our next roaster
has never been to a roast,
but in 1620, she was almost
burned as a witch.
Her first std was the plague.
Please welcome cloris leachman!
[Cheers and applause]
- I am not here
to roast Bob saget.
I'm here to fuck John stamos.
Stamos, you shouldn't
talk so much.
Your mouth is canceling out
all the hard work
your ass is doing.
If you play your cards right,
I'll do something
no woman has ever done to you:
Put you in the movies.
Does any one of you
actually know who I am?
I was on
the Mary Tyler Moore show.
[Cheers and applause]
Total slut, by the way.
She taught me everything I know.
Here's something
you don't know about Mary.
When she had an orgasm,
she threw her hat in the air.
I don't know
who any of you people is.
Maybe that's 'cause I watch TV
and go to the movies
and read the trades.
I have vibrators older
than most of you.
The difference is,
my vibrators still work.
They do.
You, the fat one.
Not you, the ugly fat one.
Yeah, your name is Jeff Ross?
- Yeah.
- I just want to thank you
for doing the jokes
my father used to tell me
when I was seven.
I'm sure this is the first time
you've ever made a woman happy.
None of this dirty joke stuff
is shocking to me.
I mean, during the golden era
of comedy,
I broke my ankle
when I tripped over
Milton berle's cock.
Which one of you fellas
is susie essman?
Normie MacDonald.
I've never met you before,
but I want you to know
I'm carrying mace.
Norm can't stay much longer.
He has to get his suit back
to his father's coffin.
I'm an academy award winner.
For the love of God,
will someone please
punch me in the face
so I can see some stars?
I can't believe
I shaved for this.
I mean, what am I even
doing here?
Who cares about Bob saget?
I was giving reach arounds
to Jack Benny
before you were born.
And that man had timing.
I was actually offered a role
on full house.
I turned it down,
'cause I wanted
to focus on comedy.
I'm glad I got out of sitcoms
before you killed them.
You didn't just kill sitcoms.
You raped them and left them
for dead in a ditch...
Just like I did
with Gavin macleod in 1975.
And then again in 1978,
that bald bitch.
Bob, dearest,
I've seen some of your work.
And you're not an actor.
Not one of you is.
I was classically trained
in live theater.
I improvised.
No script, no director.
Just me and the donkey.
Five sold out shows a night
for six years
till the donkey died
of exhaustion.
Then I was finally ready
for Hollywood.
What have you nothings done?
"My YouTube video
has 400 hits."
Fuck a donkey,
then talk to me.
Now, get up here, stamos.
Let's see what you got.
[Cheers and applause]
You're very funny.
- You.
Our next roaster used to be
on Saturday night live.
Now he just watches it,
well, up until last week
when a hooker stole his TV.
Please welcome
the incoherent norm MacDonald.
[Cheers and applause]
- Yeah, I want to start
with John stamos,
our esteemed roastmaster.
John--well, John
has a reputation
for being a bit of a swinger.
Did you know instead
of an umbilical cord,
John was born
with a bungee cord?
And cloris leachman is here.
Cloris?
[Cheers and applause]
Cloris, if people say
you're over the hill,
don't believe them.
Why, you'll never be
over the hill,
not in the car you drive.
Greg giraldo is here.
He has the grace of a swan,
the wisdom of an owl,
and the eye of an eagle.
Ladies and gentleman,
this man is for the birds.
Susie essman, of course,
is famous
for being a vegetarian.
Hey, she may be a vegetarian,
but she's still full of bologna
in my book.
I--
Gilbert gottfried,
one of my best friends.
I love Gilbert.
When you go
to the men's room later,
you'll see a sign
that says, "gentlemen,"
pay no heed.
Go right in.
There's no room
that says "scoundrel" on it.
But now we come to Bob saget,
and that's why we're all here.
Bob.
[Cheers and applause]
Bob, you have a lot
of well wishers here tonight,
and a lot of them would like
to throw you down one--
a well.
They want to murder you
in a well.
Seems a little harsh, but--
apparently, they want
to murder you in a well,
it says here on this card.
No, but Bob has
a beautiful face
like a flower--
yeah, a cauliflower.
No offense, but your face
looks
like a cauliflower.
Now, I heard you have hair
on your chest, Bob.
And, well, let me
tell you something.
That isn't your only resemblance
to rin tin tin.
- [Laughs]
- You're a fucking dogface.
How can you not get that?
No, there are times when Bob
has something on his mind:
When he wears a hat.
But no thoughts at all.
Just a hat.
And Bob isn't
the biggest sports fan.
I don't think I'm telling
any tales out of school.
I took him to a--
I took him
to a ball game,
and he came toting
a double-barreled shotgun.
Do you remember that?
I said, "what the 'h'
is that for?"
Bob said, "I heard the lions
were playing the tigers."
Do you remember that?
- Yeah.
- No, he's a good guy.
He's a good guy.
He's never bought
Christmas seals.
He told me he wouldn't know
what to feed them.
This concludes the joke--
[cheers and applause]
In all seriousness,
Bob was the first comedian
that I ever saw perform
when I was a boy live,
and I loved him.
But one thing
that bonds us as comedians is,
we're bitter and jealous,
and we hate everyone else
that has any success.
But Bob honestly has never
had an unkind word for anybody,
and I love him,
and I hope everybody else does,
so I just wanted to say that.
Thank you.
[Cheers and applause]
- Norm MacDonald.
We're very lucky
to have our next roaster.
He's a legend.
The executive
who bought full house
to network television:
Sol Schwartz.
[Cheers and applause]
- I remember the day
that they came to me
with the full house pitch.
It was the last day
my assistant jaclyn blew me.
I remember it clearly.
And in walked in
the full house people.
And they pitched
their little show,
their dream show,
their classic.
And I said, "it's a yes,
"but I want it to star
three schmucks
"I've never heard of.
'Cause I want to prove
that time slot is everything."
Let me tell you something,
John stamos.
You are the most talented actor
that I have ever come across.
You are wonderful.
You're delightful.
You're a dream!
You're fantastic.
No one has ever touched
your talent.
It is remarkable.
You are the best performer
I have ever seen.
No one in the world
has ever come close
to the magic that you bring
to the stage, to the screen.
My balls are clapping.
You are truly God's
favorite actor, John stamos.
Oh, by the way, I've already
read tomorrow's variety.
I get it early.
You've been replaced on er
by Jerry O'Connell.
It's true.
Let's talk about a true mensch,
my pride and joy,
who I discovered 25 years ago,
Bob saget.
I'm not--
[Cheers and applause]
Yes.
I think you're more
than just the sitcom dad
or the guy who hosts
that video show.
You're really one
of the shittiest comics
I've ever seen.
The other day, I--
after all these years,
I'd never met the Olsen twins.
He introduced me to them.
I said to him,
"how do I tell them apart?"
He says, "Ashley swallows."
What's my character's name
again?
Saul Schwartz.
Bob--he called him sol.
John stamos is so not Jewish.
"Please welcome sol Schwartz."
[Laughs]
The truth is, Bob,
we've worked together
for many, many years,
and I'm starting to think
I have Alzheimer's,
because I can't remember
a single funny thing
you ever said.
All right,
I'm not fucking around.
I said to them before the show--
I said, "I want to say
something nice about him now,"
and I swear, on the screen,
it says, "sincere moment."
[Laughs]
What a sincere moment.
No, what I want to say
to you is,
we never hang out.
I'd like to.
We see each other.
We're always happy
to see each other.
I've always liked you.
And I remember
when we first met,
you asked me
if I knew how dry
my grandma's vagina was.
Those were the first thing--
- really?
- I was opening for you
in the '80s,
and that's the first thing
you said to me,
and I knew that I liked you
from that moment on.
Isn't that a fantastic--
you ever met somebody--
"hey, do you know how dry
your grandma's vagina is?"
That's fucking great!
You know he's a great person.
But I think the world of you.
And for me, it was an honor
to be here tonight.
Thanks.
[Cheers and applause]
- We're roasting Bob saget?
I heard that Bob saget
calls his balls
the Olsen twins.
And that's actually--
I know for a fact
that's not true, because
he calls them Michelle.
Greg giraldo,
it's like I don't--
I think he's hispanic.
He's, like,
nine different things.
nine different nationalities.
Or maybe eight.
I don't know.
Is gay a nationality?
Norm, Jim Norton,
Greg giraldo--
why don't they just--
they should've done the roast
at the racetrack,
you know, where norm works.
Oh, who's the, like,
really pretty little girl
from full house?
Oh, um,
John stamos.
He's hosting it.
That should be good.
I wish so much that I could be
at the roast in person,
but I, um--
just after everything
I've been through lately,
I really need
to be around people
that can make me laugh.
I got Bob's mother
to tape something.
And I just got it,
so let's look at it.
- Bobby, what a son.
[Laughs]
I was proud of you
when you were bar mitzvahed,
and when you got married
and had
those wonderful children.
And all those millions
you made on full house
and America's home videos.
And oh, if I had
to do it over again,
I'd probably get an abortion.
- [Sighs]
God, I know that's Bob's mother,
and it was so sweet of her
to do that,
but I just hate that.
I hate when people
use words like "abortion"
just for a laugh.
You know what I mean?
It's cheap.
It's like--it's lazy comics
just getting a laugh
with shock value,
especially when it
comes to susie essman's cunt.
[Cheers and applause]
- Many comics on this dais
have worked holes in the wall.
Our next roaster
just sucked a cock through one.
You can see him
on the Internet sensation,
one guy, two cups, and a baby.
From meganslaw.Com...
It's the Uncle fester
of unfunny, Jim Norton.
[Cheers and applause]
- Oh, thank you.
How about a nice hand
for John stamos?
Isn't he terrific?
This is, honest to God,
the biggest collection
of non-celebrities
I've ever seen in an audience.
You know you have a shit crowd
when Alonzo bodden
is "the big get."
Winner of last comic standing
season three
25 minutes before they did
last comic standing
season four.
Your head looks like one
of Shaq's balls.
And Sarah silverman
was terrific.
I know she's having a hard time,
but don't feel bad.
Sarah's fucked
so many comedians,
she has a little light
over her bed
so they know when
they have two minutes left.
And Brian posehn,
I'm so happy you're here.
Your face always looks
like you just saw
the ark of the covenant.
Bob, how many people
turned down comedy central
before they finally
settled on you?
I mean, not to be a dick,
but like, you know,
on the fucking
comic scale of importance,
you're two notches below
Blair's cousin geri
on the facts of life.
Jeff garlin, how fat a man
do you intend on being?
Fuck enthusiasm.
Curb your appetite.
Norm MacDonald, God bless you.
Watching your set
was like watching Henry Fonda
pick blueberries.
- Is that--
now, wait a minute.
- What's that?
Oh, he wants to say something.
- No, I just think
it would be--
why, I don't think
there's a person in here
that would not love
to watch Henry Fonda
pick blueberries.
- [Laughs]
You raise a good point, norm.
Jon lovitz,
it's gotten to a point
where I almost feel like success
has a restraining order on you.
God bless cloris leachman.
You were terrific tonight.
[Cheers and applause]
Terrific.
She costarred
in young Frankenstein.
Wonderful.
Although back then,
she worked
under a different name:
Peter boyle.
I don't mean
to be a little blue here,
but cloris leachman's pussy
is so dry,
that when I tickled the lips,
it coughed on me.
Life sucks.
Pryor's dead.
Carlin's dead.
Saget?
Healthy as a mule.
Bob, you're a great guy,
and I'm honored
to have been here with you,
and you're a friend,
and I thank you so much.
And it really is it out of love
that we shit on each other.
Thank you guys so much.
The great Bob saget.
[Cheers and applause]
We all know that,
but once in a while
you got to kiss up to him,
because he plays
the guitar well.
And in case you have
a bar mitzvah
or a private party,
you need somebody in the garden
to stroll along
with the dirty words
and his little guitar pick.
I'm not gonna lie to you, Bob.
You have no talent.
Get a harmonica,
put it on your ass,
and try to come up
with a tune.
John stamos, I can't believe it.
You are the mc
of a guy that's going nowhere.
And John, I'm a friend.
Your case comes up Friday.
She was only 11,
11 years old.
You kept pulling on the dress.
You don't need that, John.
Get yourself a day job
in Greece.
Live there.
Clean apples.
Do something.
Run around looking for zorba.
Bob, do yourself a favor.
Go to Israel,
and get picked off.
Get the Hamas to knock you off.
It's all over.
In the meantime,
I'm going back to my estate,
and we need a guy
to clean the lawn.
So I'll give you a buzz, okay?
Take care of yourself.
Our next roaster
never opens his eyes,
because he can't bear
to watch the audience walk out.
Here to scream obscenities
in a screeching voice
that never gets old,
Gilbert gottfried.
[Cheers and applause]
- Thank you, John.
Boy, is he funny or what?
How can you follow John stamos?
And they say greeks
aren't funny.
And they say greeks smell bad.
And they say their women
are fat and hairy.
But enough about John
and his sisters.
Now, a lot of you are saying,
"why did we pick Bob saget?
"Why should we pick Bob saget,
"who raped and killed a girl
in 1990?
"Should we even waste
two seconds on Bob saget,
who raped and killed a girl
in 1990?"
Well, first of all,
it's not true.
It's not true that Bob saget
raped and killed a girl in 1990.
So if you have any proof
that Bob saget
raped and killed a girl in 1990,
stop gossiping,
and go right
to the police with it.
Jim Norton is a pervert.
He's a necrophiliac.
Last night, he fucked
norm MacDonald and his career.
- [Laughs]
- And cloris leachman.
Cloris leachman is so old
that her tits are labeled,
"whites only"
and "colored."
Her tits are a shameful time
in this country's history.
When I saw a great man
like nipsey Russell
pushed away
from one of her tits,
it was wrong.
Now, I watched Bob saget's
hbo special in high-def,
because in order to enjoy it,
you have to be
either high or deaf.
But his career's
totally insignificant.
I googled "Bob saget,"
and it came back, "why?"
Now I'd like to do
an old joke.
John stamos walks into a bar.
The bartender says,
"we have a drink
named after you."
John stamos says,
"you have a drink
named secret fag?"
Mary-Kate and Ashley Olsen
walk into a bar.
They say to the bartender,
"give us two ass hurts."
The bartender says,
"how do you make an ass hurt?"
The Olsen twins say,
"well, Bob saget
"hands you a chocolate milk
that he just made,
"and you wake up
three hours later
lying on your stomach."
And lastly,
Bob saget walks into a bar,
and he says to the bartender,
"give me the Bob saget."
The bartender says,
"what's a Bob saget?"
And he says,
"you give me one shot,
"I suck it for eight years,
then you give me
$100 million."
God bless you all.
Don't use drugs.
[Cheers and applause]
- Well, it's been
a great night of comedy.
But all good things
must come to an end,
which means it's time
for our guest of honor.
I can't believe that
after spending so many years
begging him to shut up,
I'm now gonna ask him to speak.
It takes a big man
to sit up here
and take all this.
And I'll tell you two guys
that are laughing
the hardest tonight:
Our fathers.
Please welcome
the great Bob saget.
[Cheers and applause]
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
What a night.
Thank you, John.
This is the longest
John stamos has gone
without putting his cock
in a desperate actress.
Yeah.
You know, they say
the measure of a man
is judged
by the company he keeps.
I'm fucked.
Greg giraldo,
you should be a bigger star.
You should be much bigger.
You have more talent
in your little finger--
oh, sorry.
That's your dick.
Jeff garlin
is a very funny fuck.
I'm sorry.
Last minute changes.
I apologize.
Jeff garlin is a very fat fuck.
Jeff's so fat...
[Chuckles]
His last comedy special
was shot in imax.
Norm MacDonald, norm,
you're the funniest man I know,
because these are
the other people that I know.
Norm is such a horrible gambler,
he bet that jon lovitz
would be funny tonight.
Okay, now I'd like
to say a few words
about susie's vagina.
I don't want to say
that her vagina is foul,
but it has a beak and feathers.
In fact, her vagina
got a job last year
as the monster in cloverfield.
Jeff Ross,
Jeff, we're buddies...
- Yeah!
- But I've always wanted
to tell you this.
You look like they took
the friars club
and beat you
in the face with it.
If you looked
any more like a horse,
norm MacDonald
would lose ten grand on you.
[Sighs]
Brian posehn.
Am I saying it right?
Is it bri-an?
Look at that face.
Did any other lesbians
survive the fire?
Which brings us to jon lovitz.
Jon, your act
is like masturbation.
You're the only one
who enjoys it,
and you should be arrested
for doing it in public.
But I love you, John
stamos.
Cloris leachman, it's truly
an honor to have you here.
[Cheers and applause]
Cloris was very hard
to get for this roast,
because she communicates
by telegraph.
Gilbert gottfried.
Gilbert.
Why are you always squinting?
Seriously, it's like
you're staring at an eclipse.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's your career.
Look at you.
That's the face
of a pedophile.
What better way
to lure a kid into a van
than to use the parrot voice
from Aladdin?
Jim Norton,
you look like something
that just got burned
off stamos's cock.
You are the most
repugnant creature
I have ever seen.
You look like a mongoloid
fucked an iguana.
And then there's my good friend
John stamos.
[Cheers and applause]
He's so handsome.
Even his dick
has a great hairline.
During full house,
John's dick had a mullet.
In the '80s,
there were two things
every actress wanted to be on:
The love boat
and John stamos's cock.
Neither help your career,
but at least the love boat
didn't try
to fuck you in the ass.
That would have been
exciting and new.
I love you, Jesse.
This, honestly,
has been quite a night.
I was concerned,
because it's hard
to make fun of my friends
and the people I love,
but luckily,
none of them are here.
And it's really--truly,
it's really great to be honored
and to be part
of a hit show,
and I know this
is gonna be a hit show,
because I'm on it,
and we're gonna edit out
jon lovitz.
'Cause that's what I do.
I star in monster TV shows,
and I cut out the lame parts,
you talentless,
white motherfuckers.
So in summation,
and I mean this to all of you
from the bottom of my heart,
fuck you all,
and suck my $100 million cock.
[Cheers and applause]
Good night, and thank you.