[Memory lane prepared
for the participants]
[Precious moments where they
cried and laughed together]
[Season 2 members walk
down memory lane]
[Valuable connections made dreaming
the same dream on the same stage]
[Suddenly becomes emotional]
[We'll see them
in a moment!]
Seasons 1 and 2's members will have a
collaborative battle on the dream stage.
The union of Park Ji-min and
Akdong Musician is fantastic.
If they win here too...
[Shin Ji-hoon and Baek A-yeon]
[Bang Ye-dam and Lee Seung-hoon]
[Yoon Hyun-sang and Andrew Choi]
[Park Je-hyung and Raccoon Boys]
I think we'll be the
best of the best.
Yeah!
It could be more fun than
KPOP STAR Season 2.
It's Season 2!
It's the main cast
of Season 2!
Ye-dam!
[And then]
It's Season 1!
It's seniors and juniors.
Hello.
[The driving force of K-pop's
future all in one place!]
All the members of Seasons
1 and 2 have gathered.
Didn't Hi perform at the
final stage together?
Looking at Season 2's
members, how is it?
Felt like I was a
part of Season 2.
- In feeling?
- Yes.
Even Season 1 feels
like yesterday.
I know.
Seung-hoon looks cool.
He shaved the sides.
Anyone can see that's
YG's style, right?
You just met the
members of Season 1.
Was there anyone you wanted
to meet? Shin Ji-hoon?
A-yeon!
[Baek A-yeon
JYP artist]
I was moved when I
heard her songs.
I see.
That's good. The members of
Seasons 1 and 2 are here.
As MC, I thought a collaboration between
Seasons 1 and 2 would be great.
And my wish will come true
today on this stage.
That's right. Seasons
1 and 2 are here.
Seasons 1 and 2 will have a collaborative
battle today on KPOP STAR's dream stage.
It's another battle!
You thought it was
over? It's not.
We have 100 people on the spot that
will rate the best stage via votes.
Since this is a combo battle, you'll
be a unified champion if you win.
- That's right.
- Since that's the title.
[KPOP STAR's best
will be born!]
First is Season 1's singer-
songwriter, Yoon Hyun-sang...
And Season 2's professional
composer, Andrew Choi.
- Looking forward to it.
- It's a ballad showdown.
Season 1's Baek A-yeon and
Season 2's Shin Ji-hoon!
It's a great team.
[Receives the song list]
This is a stage
for women.
If you're not moved,
you're not a woman.
[What song will sway
women's hearts?]
["Because I Love You"
Yoo Jae-ha]
[Singer-songwriter and
professional composer!]
It's a perfect match,
even the tone of voice.
He sings and plays
the piano well.
I think it'll
be awesome.
I thought we wouldn't
match but we did.
I think it'll be a good stage
since he was considerate.
They're sentimental
and sing well.
I also want to be moved
as I watch the broadcast.
If they put on a perfect
stage by being in step...
They can melt the hearts
of their female fans.
They're likely winners.
[They try to relax by
shaking their bodies]
[Will they win in
this ballad match?]
[Because I Love You - Yoo Jae-ha
Yoon Hyun-sang & Andrew Choi]
[Yoon Hyun-sang was praised
for singing as if speaking]
[Andrew Choi sings in a
sweet R&B soul style]
[How will they harmonize?]
[Starts off slowly
as if speaking]
[As if feeling Season
1's impression again]
[Andrew Choi newly interprets
it in his unique R&B feel]
[Hears Yoon Hyun-sang
up close for the first time]
[Women's hearts sway]
[Even men's hearts sway]
[Even the competitor is
struck with that voice!]
[Different styles evoke a profound
and mysterious harmony]
[Collaborative stage produces
twice the impression!]
- That was great!
- Go, Andrew Choi!
Please return here.
Another round of
applause for them!
You did great!
- It was a warm stage.
- Harmony was great.
It's my first time hearing
Andrew Choi in person.
When he sang a downward
ad-lib during the interlude...
I thought he sings very well
and didn't just become TOP3.
I'm also TOP3.
Actually, Baek A-yeon is
the queen of ballads.
But she was envious
of Andrew Choi.
The first stage was by
Hyun-sang and Andrew.
Was it good? Press
the buttons!
[How will the 100
people rate them?]
[Experts from the 3 agencies, including the
competitors and the MCs, form the 100 people]
[How many will they
receive from the 100?]
The two best romantic
guys sang on this stage.
- The score's going up.
- It's going up.
It's 82!
- It's 82!
- 82 people pressed it.
They're clapping but we don't
know if this is high or not.
- They're currently 1st with 82!
- As of now, they are.
Please return
to your seats.
Baek A-yeon and Shin Ji-hoon's
strengths are very similar.
They move the emotions deep
inside of us with their voice.
Since Baek A-yeon is
Shin Ji-hoon's senior...
If she leads her well
and prepares this well...
They could draw out twice or thrice
the impression with this song.
[These two have heavenly voices.
What will they be singing?]
[I Dreamed a Dream
Les Miserables OST]
[A sad ballad sung by
the tragic heroine]
She was kind and
helped me out.
I was able to do
it comfortably.
It was great that we found
a song that suits us.
Our voices went together
well than I thought.
I hope you can close your
eyes and just appreciate.
[Ji-hoon loosens up
like a figure skater]
[I'm nervous]
[Silently holds her hand
like a reliable sister]
[Can she overcome the tension
and do well without mistakes?]
[I Dreamed a Dream - Les Miserables OST
Baek A-yeon & Shin Ji-hoon]
[It's about the tragic life of a heroine
forsaken by the world and love]
[The scene where Anne Hathaway sings
while sobbing is one of the best scenes]
[Forgets the tension and
completely immerses]
[Park Je-hyung admires
Ji-hoon's voice]
[Making eye contact]
[Making eye contact
create a soft harmony]
[Their voices go together
exquisitely on every note]
[The sad lyrics and melody
are conveyed to our hearts]
[Completely immersed]
[Glistening with tears]
Thank you.
[The impression lingers]
[Awesome!]
A perfect stage by
two goddesses!
Please come over here.
[Still impressed]
I can't continue right now.
- What's wrong, Yoon Do-hyun?
- Since I'm so absorbed...
I'm speechless.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- Even they were mesmerized.
- I think they have a lot to say.
- Especially, Lee Hi.
- Lee Hi!
I was watching her and her
expression never changed.
Lee Hi!
This was her expression
as she watched them.
She was like this.
It never changed.
Her mouth opens slightly
when she's focused.
- She was focused.
- How was it?
Their voices go well
with each other.
I was immersed since
they were focused.
That's why I was
mesmerized...
Your mouth was
open really wide.
Ji-min should've
closed it for her.
- I was into it too.
- You too?
It's been a while since we heard
Baek A-yeon. She really sings well.
What do you think
the score is?
- 85?
- 85.
That means you won.
You're sorry to say
it out loud so...
Is it okay, Hyun-sang?
I think they're
looking down on us.
No, we're not.
I told Andrew, "Let's be
first," and we are first.
- They're champions!
- For now that is.
We feel bitter because
they are too good.
Will they lose first
place already?
Or will they maintain it?
Please get ready to vote.
Press the buttons!
[What is their choice?]
[They would like to
give more votes]
[Even the MCs rate them]
[Will Yoon and Choi
maintain first?]
[Will Baek and Shin
move up to first?]
Is it stopping?
It's going up...
It's 91! They are
first for now!
- They are now first.
- Yoon and Choi are 2nd!
But you're 2nd.
Just keep on going down.
3rd, 4th, 5th, and 6th.
[Baek A-yeon and Shin Ji-hoon
Current first place]
Next stage is by Season 1's
artist, Lee Seung-hoon and...
Season 2's runner-up,
Bang Ye-dam.
[We expect a completely different
performance from this strong team]
Look at him warming up.
He's determined to get to the
point and show their stage.
Ye-dam, you're close to
the guys from Season 2.
How did you feel when you
met Season 1's Seung-hoon?
It was awkward at first.
It still is awkward.
How did you feel,
Seung-hoon?
I once prepared with
Rae-sung in Season 1.
[He worked on the same team as
dance prodigy Choi Rae-sung]
[No one expected rapping and
performance from Choi Rae-sung]
[Lee Seung-hoon's
leadership and creativity]
[Left the judges in awe]
He's like Rae-sung. He's
young and uncontrollable.
- Uncontrollable?
- He's like...
Both of you have to work
together on stage...
I'm worried that the worst
teamwork might come out.
You saw the high score.
Right now, it's 91.
What's your plan?
Since Ye-dam was preparing
for the final round...
We only practiced once yesterday
and couldn't meet before that.
If you listen to him,
it's all Ye-dam's fault.
Uncontrollable
and no practice.
He has a lot
of worries.
- Alright. Let's go.
- Let's do it.
Off to the dream stage.
He's carrying him.
- Their start is different.
- It's a performance.
They look like
Jeju mandarins.
They are the akdongs
(mischievous)!
I don't even need to see it.
They'll be jumping around.
Lee Seung-hoon has a
unique ability in staging.
When Ye-dam's performance
is combined with it...
They will release their
potential with various ideas.
I think it will be
the most fun stage.
If Lee Seung-hoon
ruins this stage...
It will pose a threat to his
position as a YG trainee.
I want him to do well
and be adored at YG.
Nice to meet you,
Ye-dam.
He's a kid.
You're busy with the finals so
I thought about some things.
There are two singers around
your age that dance well.
[Ryang-hyun Ryang-ha's
"I Didn't Go to School"]
- Lyrics are simple, right?
- What do you think?
... good.
Does he always
say it's good?
Do you like flashy things?
Like everything?
I'll just do it.
I'll dress you
up nicely.
Here, we dance some
and do a cute dance.
[Already finished
with Ye-dam's rap!]
- What do you think?
- It's great.
Am I a genius or...
[Ye-dam is busy?]
[D-2 - after finals
are over]
[Congratulating him
on being runner-up]
Did you listen to
what I sent?
It was good.
Two days left - today and tomorrow.
The recording is on Tuesday.
We're cramming today and
tomorrow with intense training.
Please do well,
Mr. runner-up.
[D-1 - recording room]
We couldn't prepare much
because of the time.
[They have to start
with the steps!]
[Teaches the moves
step by step]
It's tomorrow, but we can't practice
late. We need to be in top condition.
He followed well
than I expected.
He's not a genius
for no reason.
[Practicing alone]
Doing good, Ye-dam!
We didn't have much time,
but we practiced hard.
Won't you be first?
Ye-dam can do it!
Go, go, go!
Me too!
[Sitting at the desks
and waiting]
[What stage did
they prepare?]
[I Didn't Go to School - Ryang-hyun Ryang-ha
Lee Seung-hoon & Bang Ye-dam]
[Starts off with a
cute performance]
[Secret weapon
dance break]
[Cheers]
[Tooth brushing
into a dance!]
[This is what's called
Seung-hoon style]
[Two akdongs running
all over the stage]
[In perfect step]
Lee Seung-hoon and
Bang Ye-dam as expected.
That was great!
High five!
That was good.
- Great performance.
- It was the best.
First time seeing a
gargle performance.
- A gargle performance!
- I can gargle without water.
- You can do that?
- Of course, with sound.
That was fun.
You did all this
in one day?
It would've been hard just
memorizing the lyrics.
It's 91 right now. Think
you can beat that?
I think we can
beat Hyun-sang.
So that means 2nd.
He's being put
down completely.
I thought his rhyme and
flow was unnatural.
[Taking revenge
with criticism]
The dance had no air.
Alright then...
Press the buttons!
Please press.
Bang Ye-dam and Lee Seung-hoon
put on the best performance.
Will they get
more than 91?
Or will they beat
Yoon and Choi?
91 is first as of now.
They're all having a
fierce war of nerves.
The results are out.
The production crew
are laughing.
We're curious of
the results.
100 is perfect.
It's going up.
Lee and Bang... 78!
They're 3rd! It's
okay Ye-dam.
Ye-dam, it's okay.
They got 78.
Wait, wait. Ye-dam
took off his jacket.
- Right now...
- Put it on.
I don't know if I should say this, but
we score them for fun during rehearsal.
It was lower than that.
Ye-dam is taking
off his bracelet.
- He doesn't need it.
- He never did this on stage.
- Are you fine?
- Yes.
YG could be watching this.
Please say something.
I'm deeply ashamed.
I'll do well with
the other trainees.
Please give him a hand.
Next, we have the LA Boys
from Seasons 1 and 2.
It's Park Je-hyung
and Raccoon Boys!
It'll be a global stage.
Oh! I love this!
This is great!
They're my sons.
If Raccoon Boys came out on Season 1,
I would've teamed them with Je-hyung.
They could look like a team since
they grew up in a similar environment.
That's how much they
share in feeling.
[First day of practice]
[Greets naturally
in American style]
[Kim Min-seok enters last]
- How old are you?
- I'm 23.
Oh! You're older
than me!
I talked down on you.
[Another young one]
Really?
I'm curious.
Play it.
[A similar feel
to Je-hyung]
He's better than me.
It's our first time, but I
think we're in perfect step.
I think we can do well.
We're an acoustic style
different from the others.
So we're confident.
They chose well to sing
Britney Spear's "Toxic".
Je-hyung improved a
lot in the past year.
Raccoon Boys showed their amazing
ability in musical reinterpretation.
A good combination of that
will make a great stage.
Je-hyung's high notes, Raccoon Boys'
harmony, and Min-seok's rapping...
It'll be like watching an
existing singer's stage.
[They're a bit nervous]
[How will they
reinterpret it?]
[Toxic - Britney Spears
Park Je-hyun & Raccoon Boys]
[Gets our ears
from the start]
[It's acoustic with
a strong rhythm]
[Wow]
[His voice is more relaxed]
[A perfect harmony
only by Raccoon Boys]
[Je-hyung's sweet voice
makes it sound fuller]
[Kim Min-seok's unique rapping
is catchy and pleasant to hear]
[The mood is building
up with the harmony]
[Perfectly in step as
if they are a team]
[Four men showing
great harmony]
[We could feel their
8-month growth]
[They look relaxed
and natural on stage]
[Female listeners cheer wildly]
[How did Park Je-hyung
and Raccoon Boys rank?]
- That was a hot stage!
- It was really hot.
[MCs felt hot because
of the special effects]
- Lee Seung-hoon!
- Yes?
Do you think you won't
be last anymore?
I think it's possible since
Je-hyung was blinking.
He was blinking a lot.
That means he's nervous.
What did the 100
people think?
Press the buttons!
They pressed it.
Will the order change?
I think you're more nervous
than at the live broadcast.
I can feel the tension.
Park Je-hyung!
You're staring at
the screen.
- I'm really nervous.
- Look at them.
I'm sorry.
What score will they get?
Show us the results!
[Voting results]
[Lee and Bang have 78.
Will they still be last?]
[Are they?]
It's 90! You got 90.
That's a high score.
- How do you feel?
- Really good.
[He's afraid to see YG]
As you all know, the judges
make the call on KPOP STAR.
Their opinions are
very important.
But they're not
here today.
- Not here.
- Nope.
That's why...
They'll be in our shoes
and we will rank them!
[How will they
rank the judges?]
I'm worried for
one of them.
I don't think
I'm in danger.
I'm not worried.
I'm going to be last.
[Why do you think so?]
I said a lot of things
they don't want to hear.
JYP's strength is that it
takes a lot to hurt him.
Giving him sharp criticisms for
fun and for the broadcast...
As a viewer, I think
it's going to be fun.
Ranking will be based on
who was the scariest.
- The scariest judge...
- Actually, it's not good.
- Think about it. Who was scary?
- Who was the scariest?
Hold them up! JYP!
BoA! JYP! YG!
We can see the
winner is JYP.
JYP is first.
First place
goes to JYP!
JYP, congratulations!
Soo-hyun, is there a
reason why he's scary?
His looks are scary, and you can
see what he likes and dislikes.
When we sang "Ugly" and "One of a Kind",
we saw him and thought, "This is bad."
JYP is pure. He can't
hide his looks so...
Since I sing and he raps...
"Hyo-bin, don't sing!"
"Il-do, don't rap!"
- What do you do then?
- We had a hard time.
You heard you were old-fashioned.
You heard that the most, right?
- If I use a comparison...
- Go on, we like that.
He's like a professional boxer.
He keeps punching the same spot.
We block, but he still
gets a punch in.
That hurts!
In the final stage, we didn't block
and lost for getting KO'd.
Since we miss JYP's expressions,
we prepared 7 different looks.
First is the expression where he's
not sure and wants to point out later.
- Do you know that?
- Yes, we do.
It's this expression!
[Sea of laughter]
Everyone agrees.
This expression always shows
up in the middle of the song.
It's this.
[I saw that a lot]
That's when he's
really angry.
Akdong Musician are
covering their eyes.
- They can't bear to watch.
- They don't want to watch.
They're horrified.
He had that expression when
we sang "One Million Roses".
[An expression that'll
get you eliminated]
We'll show that
as a video clip.
It's the first stanza.
Second stanza...
then third stanza.
He's getting emotional.
It's the fourth stanza.
Next stage is 2,000 won!
What is this?
2,000 won wanted to
see this expression.
He should've shown this.
[To all the contestants]
You might think someone scary on
broadcast will also be scary in real life.
But it could be the opposite.
YG judges with care, but will
he still be like that later on?
We're wrapping this up. Chan-hyuk
said JYP was a great help to him.
Like in the photos, he's really honest.
You can see that written on his face.
He will point things out,
and I actually needed that.
Since I write songs, I needed an honest
ear and professional commentary.
He's very passionate.
We met every day and...
He'll listen to our
corrected version...
- You met every day?
- Yes, we did.
I see.
We have info that
you are in love.
- Right?
- Me?
Yes!
- You even wrote a song...
- What's going on?
I didn't write one.
I was just humming.
- That means you wrote it.
- Oh, really?
Who did you
write it for?
Well, I...
- As a fan...
- It's Suzy. Suzy, Suzy, Suzy.
- Huh?
- It's Suzy.
Oh! Suzy!
[Chan-hyuk's woman
miss A's Suzy]
[Met Suzy during
the live broadcast]
[Your smile was dazzling...]
- I even registered on her fan site.
- On Suzy's fan site?
When I met her, she has
a good personality...
Of course. She's very kind.
It still lingers...
She could be watching this.
As a fan... what's the title?
- "A Lucky Day".
- I see.
Alright. "A Lucky Day".
This will be an impromptu.
Okay, it's an impromptu.
Su... su... su...
"It's a lucky day."
Alright!
This is...
"A day where I look
only at you."
A lucky day where I
look only at you.
"The moon is getting bigger."
[Admiration]
It's good. Can we
get one more?
When you fall in love,
the moon can look bigger.
After the moon...
"My flesh trembles
when I see you."
Trembling flesh!
[Acknowledged as
genius composer!]
- It's coming out!
- Great! It's good!
But that's not the ending.
He has to complete it.
Right.
"Slowly."
Slowly.
[Akdong Musician are witty]
Great, really great.
He has to end it here.
What can we do?
This isn't about me.
But I think everyone
knows, right?
Is it Ye-dam?
Bang Ye-dam?
Who?
- Ye-dam...
- Ye-dam?
Ye-dam's surprised.
The youngest, Ye-dam.
He comes to me one day
and hugs me, and says...
"I think I'm in love."
- Wait, we'll give you time to speak.
- You will have enough time.
Who was it?
It's okay.
[Tell us]
Who was it?
- Girl group YouU's...
- Who in YouU?
- Min-joo.
- Min-joo?
He gets nervous
when he sees her.
We return to our rooms when it's over
and he turns on the television.
- He watches it again.
- He watches again...
- He doesn't look at his...
- He looks at YouU's part.
Only YouU's part?
- He kneels down and watches.
- He stops at YouU's part.
[Getting jittery]
He says that she's pretty.
I never did that, honest!
Then why did you
watch it again?
I was monitoring...
You monitor your
part, not YouU's.
He monitors only
YouU's part.
Ye-dam, we prepared something
special without you knowing it.
We knew in advance that
you liked her, and...
We have her on the phone.
Why don't you say hello?
- Really?
- Yes.
- Call her.
- Hello?
- Louder.
A little louder.
Hello!
Yes, that was
Ye-dam's "hello".
He was eagerly waiting for
her. "Min-joo, hello?"
We could test him to see
how much he likes her.
Didn't you hear
his voice crack?
No, no! I...
We all heard him eagerly
calling out to her.
Now it's my turn!
Alright. Let it out.
- He's breaking out.
- He's laughing by himself.
Who is it?
Soo-hyun and?
And who?
- Who is it?
- Soo-hyun and...
- Why are you looking at me?
- Soo-hyun and McKay?
McKay?
Soo-hyun and McKay?
No, it's not...
- Then you hate her?
- No, he said it.
Soo-hyun's cute, but...
I just wanted to look after
her like a little sister.
[No one believes it]
That's not it at all.
This is the truth.
Our practice room is here and
Raccoon Boys are right next to us.
We have to practice but they're
sending melodies back and forth.
A piano melody.
- Room to room?
- Yes.
When a melody comes from
that side, she listens.
- Then she plays along.
- Oh my!
Then he hits the wall,
"Why are you following me?"
Chan-hyuk couldn't bear to
watch. "What are they doing?"
- I wanted to practice...
- That's not it.
They're so innocent. I want
to make this into a movie.
[They're ashamed and
don't know what to do]
Isn't Bang Ye-dam funny?
He reveals it and is smiling
like it's a good thing.
This is KPOP STAR's
dream stage.
Baek and Shin are
still first place.
Next is Lee Hi
and 2,000 won!
[No need for words for
these likely winners]
- Lee Hi! Lee Hi! Lee Hi!
- Don't go out yet.
It's unpredictable since Lee Hi and
2,000 won are an unexpected combo.
It's our first time
meeting her.
We were worried because we thought
she would be reserved and chic.
But it was the opposite.
She led us well.
She's younger than us in age,
but gave us advice as a senior.
- Really?
- Yes.
Hyo-bin's her fan and asked for
her autograph as soon as we met.
He asked for his friend
and not for himself.
- She asked for the name.
- I wanted to write the name.
I kept on asking him for the
name because I wanted to write it.
He says, "My friend wouldn't
care if you don't write it."
Really? I have to write it.
Then he said, "Uh... Hyo-bin."
He was ashamed to get an autograph
and lied it was for his friend?
- I couldn't so...
- What a loser!
[The day she gave
an autograph]
To Hyo-bin please...
- Can you give that to me?
- Alright! Thank you.
Thank you.
Can we cross our arms?
[What stage will this
unbalanced team show?]
It'll be fun.
2,000 won's voice and rap
plus a female voice...
It'll be a stage
everyone would like.
[D-7 - meeting to
choose a song]
[2,000 won's shy greeting]
- Hi, I'm your fan.
- Thank you.
Since I'm younger,
should I call you...
You can call us little brothers
or talk down to us...
No, I can't.
"Why do you sing like
this?" You can hit us.
No, no, no.
- What song should we do?
- I wanted to do your song.
- There's one arranged.
- Really?
- Raccoon Boys did it.
- Oh, I see.
We can just ask them.
You potential will be released
if you work with us.
Our potential has to be
released and not others.
Only your potential
need to be released.
Is there a song
you have in mind?
It's a pop song.
Rihanna and...
- Eminem?
- Yes.
"Love the Way You Lie"?
I really love this song.
It was a collaboration between
Rihanna and Eminem, right?
Then Il-do's Eminem?
We looked for a song where Lee Hi's
and Hyo-bin's voice went along.
We sang this and
it suited us.
I'll sing until the
note over here.
[She was a high schooler a year
ago. Now she's a senior artist]
Her musical interpretation
is remarkable for her age.
That mature sensibilty is what's
going to polish this song.
And it will go along with
2,000 won's sensibility.
We'll show a great stage.
Cheer us so that
we can be first.
Please watch.
[Both Akdong Musician and
Baek A-yeon are nervous]
[It's been a while since we
saw those eyes on Lee Hi]
[Love the Way You Lie - Rihanna
Lee Hi & 2,000 won]
[Her soulful voice
became fuller]
[First time for Ji-hoon
hearing Lee Hi's voice]
[Hyo-bin's mournful falsetto
filled with a lonely feeling]
[An ardent harmony
piercing the heart]
[They're absorbed
as if possessed]
[As if watching a
scene from a movie]
[This stage conveyed
some deep sentiments]
That was great!
[They're really good]
"Love the Way You Lie"
by Lee Hi and 2,000 won.
- Who chose this song?
- Lee Hi did.
The harmony and rap in the
middle... whose idea was it?
It was Lee Hi.
- Lee Hi's idea?
- She did everything.
2,000 won left everything to
her who is six years younger.
Well, she's Lee Hi.
Shin Ji-hoon was in
awe. How was it?
I had the chills when I heard
Hyo-bin and Hi's voices.
- The chills?
- Yes.
- I thought we lost.
- Since they sing well...
What will be the results?
The 100 people will
press the buttons!
[They're busier than ever]
[Will they be the
new first place?]
Will Baek and Shin lose their
place? Let's see the results!
The score's going up.
It's going up, up...
[Will they?]
[Everyone watches
with bated breath]
It's going up, up...
It's 92!
[They turned the tables]
[A pity]
They took first! Another
round of applause.
Because we were with her, our
shrunken heart opened up.
We're not afraid
with her.
I was more nervous than receiving
good commentaries on the show.
- This is more nerve-racking.
- My mouth went dry.
I'm very happy.
It's such an honor.
- You did it like Miss Korea.
- It's an honor. I mean...
Anyways, first is 2,000 won and Lee Hi!
Another round of applause for them!
[One team is left!]
This is our last stage.
Winners of Seasons 1 and 2
make up this team.
Park Ji-min and Akdong Musician
will be preparing next.
KPOP STAR's winner
is Park Ji-min!
Congratulations!
Season 2's winner is
Akdong Musician!
The winners of
Seasons 1 and 2.
I can't imagine Park Ji-min
singing "Don't Cross Your Legs".
But I can't imagine Lee Soo-hyun
singing "Rolling in the Deep".
The two songs are different. How will
they mix it? I'm looking forward to it.
[Right after the finals]
[Park Ji-min came to congratulate
Akdong Musician for winning]
The winners of Seasons
1 and 2 are here.
He have to win that
stage too, right?
- Really...
- We have to win, right?
[Starts singing
on the spot]
[Something's not right]
- What do I do?
- This is bad.
[Struggling with
high notes]
We have to meet
up tomorrow.
[A day before
the recording]
[Only one day to practice
because of the finals!]
[They practice seriously]
[But it's soon midnight]
[I'm sleepy]
[Strength depleted]
[I'm hungry]
"I want fishcakes and
spicy rice cakes."
"Soondae, soondae."
"Spicy rice cakes, pizza."
This isn't it.
"Pizza, pasta, pasta, buffet."
[Their "snack song"]
[They feel great after playing
around and singing]
High notes with a belt.
[High notes know-how
A belt treatment?]
[It's working!]
[They get back up
and practice!]
Let's get 1st. Go Park Ji-min
and Akdong Musician!
[With what bright spark will
they sing these two songs?]
[Don't Cross Your Legs + Rolling in the Deep
Park Ji-min & Akdong Musician]
[Starts off with acting]
[They are in perfect step while
satisfying this witty, lively stage]
[Connects to Soo-hyun's solo
of "Rolling in the Deep"]
[Park Ji-min sings
solo next]
[Ji-min and Soo-hyun's
exquisite harmony]
[Soo-hyun's voice
gradually explodes]
[They give and take as they
create harmony on stage]
[The chorus and mood feels
completely different]
["Don't Cross Your Legs" peeps
out from "Rolling in the Deep"]
[The arrangement of the two songs
go together remarkably well]
These legs. Your legs.
[Two different songs became
one in this arrangement]
These two were the representing
songs from both seasons.
You mixed "Don't Cross Your Legs"
and "Rolling in the Deep".
Chan-hyuk...
You set it off
at the end.
- Lee Hi, how was it?
- I have mixed feelings.
Felt that your place
was threatened?
I was hesitant to press the
button, but it was great.
- I pressed for you.
- Me too.
I should avoid them.
2,000 won, how was it?
We never won before.
Why always sad stories?
The stage by the two
winners was awesome.
Will you rely on them
or on Lee Hi?
We only have Lee Hi.
[Thank you]
I see you're a big fan.
We love you,
Lee Hi!
Alright.
What are the results?
Will they become first or will
Lee Hi and 2,000 won keep it?
The 100 people...
Press the buttons!
Will today's winner be
Lee Hi and 2,000 won...
Or Akdong Musician and Park Ji-min
that challenged them right now?
The recording for KPOP STAR's
dream stage took 6 hours.
We are now waiting
for the results!
Which team will be first?
Lee Hi and 2,000 won
have 92 right now.
If they get more than 92, a
unified champion is born.
We now reveal the score the
100 people gave this team!
It's going up!
What's the score?
[Season 1's top rivals
Park Ji-min vs Lee Hi]
[Season 2's best duo
Akdong Musician vs 2,000 won]
[Who's the ultimate victor?]
It's 91!
2,000 won became first
relying on Lee Hi!
We won! Yeah!
I had a fun time.
Seems like KPOP STAR
is finally over.
I return to school
tomorrow.
I return to my place and will
try harder to show a better self.
You didn't forget us,
right? Don't forget us.
Thank you for these
unforgettable memories.
Yeah!