Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Marvelous Rivals @ Viki
♫ Pressed the alarm clock!Every morning has the same routine ♫
♫ Unending dreams.Dreams are at war with reality ♫
♫ Who to listen to?Just ask the one deep within your heart ♫
♫ Thousands of attempts to fly.Flap your wings and wait for the wind ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ All my partners are accompanying me ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ All my partners are accompanying me ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ La La La La La La La ♫
Refresh Man
It's an emergency situation, this will determine MUSE Cosmetic's future.
Everyone needs to listen to my instructions.
Today, we must make sure that MUSE Cosmetics and Xinwen Cosmetics'
contract signing is a success.
Ji Wen Kai!
Duck Egg King, long time no see!
What are you doing here?
Let's welcome our new CEO, Ji Wen Kai.
Do you remember what you used to say in high school?
Zhong Yu Tang is the king while you're a pawn. A pawn should listen to his king.
Right now you're a pawn, so you must listen to me.
We worked all night.
No matter what, I am your personal secretary. You should've called me,
because these things are within the realm of my work. You guys shouldn't have left me out of it.
We did call you.
But we never got your call.
After that your cell phone was off.
From now on
I hereby announce that
the head secretary position will be handled by Miao Ai Sha.
- You will be in Sales Team 3.- Sales Team 3?!
The cemetery of the talented and the incinerator of MUSE?
Starting from now, I will...
specially monitor this section.
It can't be. Are the superiors serious?
Strange.
I've been in MUSE Cosmetics for 30 years.
From the time the company started 'til now,
the number of CEO's that have come and gone
is more than the number of shoes I've thrown out.
But there were never a CEO who focused on us Sales Team 3.
Such a big movement today... could it be...
could it be someone has offended the new CEO?
Me?
How could it be me?
It can't be. I don't even know him so why would he give Sales Team 3 a hard time just because of me.
Although I'm a newbie in sales,
I'm full of energy and passion.
I believe that as long as we work hard, there's nothing that we can't do!
Let's all strive together!
Make our Sales Team 3 the grand prize winner for this year! Everyone say,
okay!
It's 12 o'clock sharp. Let's all eat outside.
- Okay, I'm so hungry.- Otherwise, the supervisor will come looking for trouble again later.
We are not ordering take out?
Hui Xin, are you going with us or not?
- Right. I still have to call my nanny.- Let's go...
Okay... you guys go first. I'll go the lavatory first for a while.
Let's do our best.
Zhong Yu Tang
cannot be defeated.
You should never become like them who only work to wait for death,
a useless talent with a brain that only thinks about lunch and dinner.
Even you don't listen to me..?
Sigh. Always have to think hard of what to eat everyday...
Should we go to the Shabu-Shabu on the left side or the Roasted Chicken on the right side? Please decide, Team Leader.
Shabu-shabu! Go as a group of four and you get one share for free!
Meng He, 50 years old, the team leader of Sales Team 3.
She's one of MUSE Cosmetics' start up employees.
She likes to use her free time to secretly go the the market to buy ingredients.
- $20 NTD- How can that be?
Owner, this is not 3 kg of spring onions.
Okay, okay.
Regarding the likes of housewives
and what's popular among the commoners, she knows them very well.
She's MUSE Cosmetics moving information bank.
Her brain automatically stores the previous years' amount of items sold and its sales numbers.
She's the only employee who owns 20% of the company's stocks that is not also a company executive.
Meng He... better at gossip than sales...
Auntie Type of Refresh Man
Okay. It's agreed.
Eh, wait!
Let me think about whether I have any allergies towards tomatoes or not...
Huang Jia Ying, 30 years old.
"One who treats her child as her sky" type of single mother.
Then have to trouble you for now. Here, this is for you.
She used to hold the title of MUSE Cosmetics Fashion Apparel's
best sales person of the year, a super employee.
And even was the top person of the year in a career magazine.
But after giving birth to her child...
Little baby, I'll fetch you later after I get off from work. You have to be good.
- I'll leave this here.  - Okay.
Then I'll go to work now. Bye-bye.
Huang Jia Ying, from a super employee
demoted to a Check-In Card-Swiping type of Refresh Man.
Let me check it first!
Don't think about your child all the time.
Hey, Hui Xin is not here yet.
Zhu Liang Yu, twenty six years old.
A typical book-geek who will never stand if he can sit.
His text analysis is very good. He is a creative genius and an expert in making reports and contracts.
- New books... I've already finished all of them.  -Mhm.
Then do you want to take a look at my romance novel
and give me some critiques?
He's very lazy in making sales.
He just wants to be the next Chiung Yao, a famous romantic-fiction writer.
Please, just take a look.
Zhu Liang Yu is the standard culture youth "after rookie."
Hui Xin is not here yet?
Sorry!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Jiang Hui Xin, twenty one years old.
Took a five-year course in a senior vocational school and almost didn't graduate.
She entered MUSE as a cashier.
She thinks business is too complicated and busy and that she doesn't have the capabilities,
so she asked to be transferred.
Jiang Hui Xin checks-in then sleeps.
It's lunch time! What are we eating, what are we eating?
She only revives during lunch break.
After work she becomes a super model.
She has no passion for working.
But after work, she has more passion than anyone.  " The later it gets the more beautiful I am" type of Refresh man.
No matter how skilled you are,
if you don't have passion then it won't work.
Zhong Yu Tang,
you think that I sent you to Sales Team 3 because you think I'm picking on you.
No. You are destined to stand on top of this scattered desert.
But I'm very curious
how long you can keep it up.
If there's no problems, then you have strong abilities,
but if there are problems...
Kevin, the meeting with W Group's Director Zheng will begin shortly.
I know. Let's go.
A bouquet of fresh flowers can cause lazy people
to change beyond recognition.
I must allow myself to be like
flowers in full bloom when reporting on my first day of work.
So foolish! Why cause yourself to be so tired?
The semi annual reporting with W Corporation.
Director Zheng likes to drink English milk tea with double cream and sugar.
This Elsa would most likely not know.
Section Chief!
I ask to be excuse for 10 mins and go back to the secretary department to take care of some turnover work.
Perfect example of being subjugated by one authority but remaining loyal to another.
This little girl completely doesn't understand the situation.
This can only lead to a cold rebuke despite having shown warm feelings.
Right. She's only begging to be rebuffed. She's so idle.
If I had known earlier, I would have asked her to stand in line for me to buy a limited edition bag.
Tada!
The scent of the glue will cause the baby to have an allergic reaction.
Sorry.
Be careful!
This is the English mlik tea with double cream and sugar that Director Zheng likes to drink.
Every time he comes, he always instructs me to make this.
Don't make a fuss, Director Zheng will be upset.
That's right. I'm sorry.
What are you doing here?
Open the door for me now. I want to bring this in.
Ai Sha.
Director Zheng likes to drink English milk tea the most.
I have especially added double the amount of cream and sugar.
Thank you for your advice.
But this month's Korea magazine just interviewed Director Zheng.
Director Zhong mentioned that his mother passed away after being diagnosed with diabetes,
because of that, he is considered to be at high risk for diabetes.
He isn't able to drink English milk tea with double cream and sugar.
And that is why I changed it to Jingdong matcha.
Director Zheng, you won't blame me for asserting my own assumptions, right?
This cup of Jingdong matcha,
is made using hundred year-old green tea, carefully and thoroughly.
Bittersweet and wonderfully scented.
It is good for diabetes and good for your health.
Okay.
It's really good.
Your new secretary is excellent.
She is very attentive.
Director Zheng, you're overpraising.
By the way, why are you still here?
Weren't you already transferred to Sales Team 3? There's nothing for you to do here. Please leave.
Sorry, excuse me. I will leave now.
- Sorry, we'll continue.  - Okay.
I always thought Yu Tang was going to safely get MUSE's top secretary position.
Who knew that after Ai Sha came,
I'd realize the true abilities of a head secretary? Perfection!
Yes.
Hey, to drop from our secretary division
to that garbage-like Sales Team 3...
It's literally like dropping from heaven to hell!
Yu Tang fell hard this time.
You feel sympathetic towards her?
I feel like she brought this upon herself.
Did you see her bring the milk tea in earlier?
- She looked so proud of herself - Yeah.
She doesn't even know what she is capable of.
No wonder she lost to Ai Sha.
This level of skill is far too great.
That's right.
You two...
Do you want me to move your offices here? It's very convenient to talk here.
Go now.
- Yes.- Yes.
So the person who really didn't understand reality...
was me.
Chief...
the main brand Mei Mei that Sales Team 3 is responsible for...
why can't I find the newest business for this year?
It smells so good. I like this fragrance.
Wash using Mei Mei, and you'll become "Mei Mei."  (Mei Mei=beautiful)
Yu Tang likes Mei Mei that much?
Then you should go to Mei Mei to work when you grow up.
Okay, Mom. It's agreed then. Let's make a promise.
Mom, I'm really working in the sales department of Mei Mei now,
but I didn't imagine that
it would be under such a harsh environment.
Wait.
- What's wrong? - Your jacket.
Thanks.
Oh right, did you get William's favorite 91 Burgundy Red Wine for me?
Without this bottle, I couldn't even get in the front door.
No wonder Director Zheng praised you.
Let's go.
That is already not a level I can climb to.
Sorry, it's all been sold out.
What? It's sold out?
Why do you look so tired? Have you eaten yet?
I haven't eaten yet.
I'm starving to death!
Here, two eggs and two pieces of cheese.
Eh, pretending to cry? I'm not giving this to you.
Give it to me!
Was today's business that good? Everything is already sold out.
Do you think that's possible?
Dad didn't go to the market today, so there aren't any ingredients to make three servings of food for us.
I know, my omurice isn't as good as your mom's.
I don't know what it's missing so business can't improve.
No way. I think it tastes really good.
It's my favorite.
I find that his is okay.
Why don't you let me drink it instead of throwing it away? Such a waste!
I'm going after the world's highest-level first-place coffee-latte art title.
You can't drink it if it's not done well.
Oh, that's right, Sis. Shouldn't you treat Dad and me to a big meal?
What big meal?
You really love to act.
How long have you waited for that position?
Son, just stay here at home, it's a lot easier.
Dad, if we don't go to a restaurant, it's not considered a celebration.
Sis, you're now an executive secretary.
The restaurant is going to be more classy, right?
Yes. I'm now...
My position has changed.
Sis, there's this amazing top notch restaurant.
What about this? Let's set it at tomorrow. I'll make the reservations, I'll make the reservations.
Okay, okay, fine.
How can I tell them that I didn't just not get a promotion
but I also got degraded?
This wont' do. I can't be brought down by Ji Wen Kai.
That type of person doesn't deserve my anger.
At least I have a day off. I don't need to work.
I don't have to see that petty person's face!
And I get to sleep until I naturally wake up.
Everyone listen carefully. Aunties and uncles, grandmas and grandpas,
I have a very important thing to announce!
- Zhong Yu Tang!- Ji Wen Kai is
going to confess to the girl he likes!
The recorded love confession will be broadcasted live later!
It'll be live! Everyone please give Ji Wen Kai lots of support and encouragement!
You called me up this early just to bring this thing over?
Why are you wearing sunglasses? Is the sun even out?
I look handsome.
What else then? What are friends for?
Friends are of use on social networking sites. So please...
don't bother me with such small things, okay?
I'm going to sleep.
Hey.
Trust me, friends are for bothering.
Let's go.
All the locals, neighbors, aunties, uncles, grandpas, grandmas. Everyone good morning.
Today the chief of the office has something very important to announce.
Zhong Yu Tang, who was top in her class since childhood,
has been transferred from MUSE's secretarial office to the sales team. I repeat, from the secretarial office to the sales team.
Zhong Yu Tang has gone from executive secretary to office clerk.
So, I'm asking people to give support to this Refresh Man.
Zhong Yu Tang, wake up!
What's going on?
Make me breakfast quickly. Wake up, wake up!
I'm not dreaming!
Make breakfast for me now.
Zhong Yu Tang. Hey! Are you home?
Zhong Yu Tang, hi.
Ji Wen Kai, what are you trying to do?
Can't you leave me alone? I have the day off today!
Hey, hurry up and come down. It's time to eat breakfast.
Remember to brush your teeth and wash your face. All the locals good morning!
I have a very important thing to announce.
This person, who's living at number fi—
You! Shut up!
Hi.
- Who are you?- My friend.
You want me to shut up? Catch me if you can.
Ji Wen Kai!
Everyone, uncles and aunts, brothers and sisters, fathers and mothers,
I want to announce something to everyone.
- Ji Wen Kai!-Miss Zhong Yu Tang has transferred from the position of MUSE's
executive secretary to office clerk.
Don't let me catch you!
Stop it right now!
She is so cute. Don't you feel bad about it?
I don't.
Zhong Yu Tang! Run faster with those little legs. Don't you want me to shut up?
Listen carefully everyone. The girl who would score number one since childhood—
- What's wrong with this car?- I forgot to tell you,
rhis car isn't reliable. Its engine is thirty years old, practically the same age as us.
What, what, what? You just asked me for a car, you didn't say you were gonna drive it.
What would you use a car for if not to drive?!
Ji Wen Kai!
Hey, hurry, she's catching up! Hit the gas pedal all the way!
I've already pressed it down all the way!
Everyone, don't forget, when it's breakfast time—
there is something to announce to everyone. It's very important and everyone must hear it.
You must let her know of your support for her transfer!
Okay. Bye-bye.
I'm not playing anymore.
- Are you going back?- Yeah I'm going back to sleep.
- Bye. - Bye-bye.
Want some shaved ice?
Wait for me!
Uncle Wang!
Long time no see.
It's Ji Wen Kai.
Uncle Wang.
Hey, Yu Tang?
I didn't imagine that your relationship is that good.
You're even eating shaved ice together?
Hey, not bad.
That year, you would never pass your tests. I was scared you wouldn't graduate.
Look at you now! Who would have thought?
Uncle, we'll have the usual.
Okay, the usual order.
The better person can pay.
Ji Wen Kai, what exactly are you doing?
Ji Wen Kai!
I heard my dad talking out here and I couldn't believe it.
You've become so handsome!
Wang Hai Di, don't go crazy for the flowers!
Hi, Hai Di.
You still remember me?
You're right.
Back in those days I was also a class flower (the prettiest girls in a class).
You remember?
Although at that time, I didn't pay close attention...
This place is still the same as ten years ago.
Are you trying to say that
I haven't changed at all?
That's what you said.
Hey. I say, Zhong Yu Tang,
I swear, the way you talk is so inaccurate.
The Ji Wen Kai now,
isn't like the guy you said he was before.
How can you say that!? Be quiet!
What else did she say?
She said you were super naive and careful.
And mischievous... it was so funny!
I'm coming! A double egg-yolk shaved ice coming up!
Here, eat.
Wasn't this your favorite?
You haven't eaten this for ten years. You must have missed it.
What's wrong? Want me to share some with you?
No, thanks.
You never heard that when women past the age of 25,
their metabolism will slow down?
Aren't you afraid your cholesterol levels will be high and you'll have a stroke?
It was out of the kindness of my heart to share some with you.
No need.
I am a very important CEO.
My health is very important.
Hai Di, take this.
Thanks.
Uncle Wang.
Give me a bowl of plain ice.
Okay. Eh, I almost forgot.
Old rules, if you want to eat shaved ice, please take out your report cards.
First?
Excellent.
What about yours?
It's still the same with so many red marks?
Hey, Ji Wen Kai, this seems to be the
fifty-eighth time I've beaten you.
Sorry. You will have pick up the tab again today.
Thank you.
This is the taste of victory!
When it's free, it tastes especially good.
Add some fighting spirt, huh?
You need to win and get your pride back.
Uncle Wang will treat you to a huge bowl of shaved snow.
CEO? Hmm, that's pretty impressive.
Eh? What is this?
Dad! This is a black platinum credit card.
There's no limit, you can swipe as much as you want.
This card can not only buy this entire store,
but also this entire street!
Wow, that impressive? Hey, let's return this to him.
Eh, Yu Tang, what about you?
Today I left the door too quickly,
so I didn't get the chance to take anything.
Here is Yu Tang's report card.
Dad... without comparing you should know, so it's uncomfortable to say...
I see.
It's very rare for Wen Kai to win over Yu Tang.
Yu Tang will buy today's shaved ice.
- Why do I have to buy?  - Ehhh!
This is my store. We play by my rules.
Kiddo, you've won 58 times already,
just giving in once isn't too bad.
Good kid, I'll get a large order of shaved ice for you!
Okay!
How can there be a man as selfish as you?
I think you're just getting me back for every single thing I did.
Oh, what a coincidence. We come for shaved ice and you've brought my business card.
What else then? You think I've just been sleeping these past ten years?
If you're not satisfied, then turn your life around as a sales clerk.
- I—- I'm afraid,
you're so used to your secretarial position,
that you can't take off your high heels and go down to sales.
Wow! How great is it to be a CEO!
If you dare to provoke me, Zhong Yu Tang. Be prepared to lose everything, you loser!
It's been ten years, and your body lines are starting to sag.
I hope it's not just your voice that you can raise.
You—! I will definitely win and show you!
Hai Di! Let's go.
You need to pay!
Don't you have a platinum card?!
Where are you going?!
- Wen Kai.  - Yes?  - Once you irritate a woman,
you'll be pursued for your whole life.
Really? Perfect.
In the past, I pursued her. Now it's her pursuing me.
You're shaved ice is almost ready.
What are you doing? Why am I coming in here?
Tang, why did you bring me here?
You're wearing your pajamas! Why are we shopping?
Who said I'm here to shop? I'm here to wear my armour.
The battle of me as a Refresh Man...
it starts from now on!
Battle?
Here.
Here, take this.
Take this.
Hai Di, foot the bill.
Me!?
Does it look like I've brought my wallet?
No way!
You are still shopping?
I'm home.
Daughter, we are ready.
Why are you both dressed like this?
We are going to a high class restaurant.
Don't tell me you forgot! You're lacking sincerity.
I almost forgot.
How about I quickly use the restroom and change my clothes, so that we can go?
I totally forgot.
Which one of you locked the door again? I'm in a rush.
♫ The first person I think of is you ♫
♫ There is no reason ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ All my partners are accompanying me ♫
Which one of you locked the door again? I'm in a rush.
What are you doing here?
Daughter, this is...
Xiao Kai said that he wants to eat with us. (Xiao Kai is a nickname; "xiao" means "little")
I invited him and he accepted.
That's right. I haven't seen Daddy Zhong and Yu Han in such a long time.
We should get together and have a meal once in a while.
Hurry up.
Am I the goddess of unluckiness? Why won't he leave me alone?
If he comes along to eat with us,
then the fact that I didn't get the promotion will come to light!
Da Antonio Italian Restaurant
That's right, Kai Ge. What have you been up to these last few years?
These few years I've been working abroad.
For real?
Working and studying abroad. So cool!
If you knew what work I was doing, you wouldn't find it so cool.
Why is all the food on the menu so expensive?
Should we go to another restaurant?
Dad, it's so embarrassing to leave without even ordering.
Kai Ge, what do you want to eat? Sis is going to pay.
She's going to pay?
Oh, then I won't be so courteous then. Waiter!
Order as you wish.
I want...
I want this set at NT$5,280.
Make it four servings.
Before we eat, let's raise our glasses.
Okay.
Let's congratulate Zhong Yu Tang for becoming more and more...
Hey! Ji Wen Kai.
Have you lost weight recently?
So pitiful. You must be working too hard.
It's better that you eat more meat
and talk less.
Understand?
It's fine!
I will eat to my fill later.
What's more important now is that we still need to congratulate Yu Tang.
I need to fix my makeup.
Daughter, we're congratulating you on successfully changing your profession.
Let's raise our glasses.
Being a secretary is a dead end, where you earn dead money.
Now in sales, you can earn living money.
The possibilities are endless!
That's right.
Your sister is making big bucks now. Congratulations!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
How did you guy know about this?
The people fixing the screen doors and windows announced it so loudly this morning.
Everyone knows.
Oh right, Xiao Kai. How did you know about her change in profession?
Oh... Yu Tang and I are working in the same company now.
Oh! You're working in security? That fits you well.
Sis originally wanted me to apply for a job there, but I'm a coffee connoisseur.
Siblings think alike, huh?
Dad, Yu Han,
let me make the introductions.
This is our company's new CEO.
He is more senior than the director.
He's a famous person now!
Xiao Kai, after our meal,
come to our store and autograph our wall.
Having the support of a famous person like you will boost our business!
- Yes, yes, yes!- Mr. Kai, you're a CEO now.
Then you must know latte master, Terry Yang. Please, I want to be his apprentice!
You two! Don't you think treating someone who use to work for us
like this... is a little embarrassing?
Not at all.
Daughter, Xiao Kai is our family member.
Being proud of our family member is normal!
We are proud of Brother Kai.
Kai Ge, cheers.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Marvelous Rivals @ Viki
Ji Wen Kai, you wait and see.
I will definitely impress you.
And revert the hierarchical statuses between us back to how they were ten years ago.
Please, Director.
Aiyo, aren't you making it hard for me?
The clients for Sales Team #3 are all long-term and loyal clients. How could I give the client list to you?
You want to develop a business? Then you must do it yourself, right?
Hello? Sister Jia Yin isn't here yet.
I can take a message for you.
Di Shi Kang? Yes, I know you are a pharmacy store that sells our "Mei Mei" products.
An emergency that requires she go over there immediately? Yes, I got it.
Yes, I'll pass on the message for you. Thank you.
Sister Jia Yin, Di Shi Kang just called and said—
I heard.
Oh no, I can't go over there today.
Last night, when I was changing my son's diaper,
I found a red spot on his butt!
I suspect the nanny is abusing him, so I must monitor the video feed all day.
But... but they said it was an emergency.
No one gets to bully my son!
Jia Yin, since you don't have time right now,
why not leave Di Shi Kang to Yu Tang?
Zhong Yu Tang, not in office
This is my first time going on a trip as a business person.
Dad said that working outside the office tests your strength and endurance.
There are more opportunities here than there are staying in the office all day.
Excuse me, where are the Mei Mei products?
They should be over there.
Excuse me miss, do you know where the Mei Mei products are?
- Over there. - Okay, thank you.
- Excuse me, do you know where the Mei Mei products are?
They're right there.
[Mei Mei]
Mei Mei should be put at this height.
That way, it can be at the most customers' eye level,
and make them want to make a purchase.
It's almost time for the meeting.
Excuse me. May I ask where the manager's office is?
- Third floor.  - Alright...
Thank you!
She's crazy.
Now I have to move it all back.
What?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I probably didn't listen clearly just now.
You said...?
You didn't hear incorrectly.
Next week, Di Shi Kang is going to remove all of Mei Mei's products from the shelves.
♫ The first person I think of is you ♫
♫ There is no reason ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ All my partners are accompanying me ♫
Sorry, I didn't hear clearly just now.
Are you saying that...?
You didn't hear wrongly.
Next week, Di Shi Kang is going to remove all of Mei Mei's products from the shelves.
What?
This is the contract for removing the products off the shelves. Please take it with you.
Why are we suddenly terminating the contract?
Mei Mei is a 30 year established product brand.
It's a classic within the classics!
Not to mention we have partnered with Di Shi Kang for so many years.
Why is this so sudden?
Sorry, I have a meeting to attend. Please go back first.
But—
But I—!
How could this happened?
The first client that I worked so hard to get
wants to terminate the contract?
If you're not satisfied,
change your lifestyle as a Refresh Man.
Give it to me.
I heard about the products going off the shelves situation. Is it serious?
This was my first client.
Business hasn't even been expanded yet
and now it is coming off the shelves.
And I even bought clothes for the job.
Are you happy now?
You can laugh if you want.
If you're here to look for sympathy,
I've already done what you asked for.
Hurry and go back.
♫ My uncertain footsteps are slow, ♫
♫ although I’m nervous. ♫
I'm here to advise you.
In twenty minutes, I will hold the Sales Team 3 meeting.
Do what you have to.
Are you not going to give me a ride since you're heading back?
What are the feet of a businessperson for?
It's almost time.
Twenty minutes?
Would you like coffee?
That person is about to come report for duty.
Okay... when it's time, let the east wind enter  (let that person come in to help).
These are the decisions from the board of directors.
The big cases that have to be fulfilled this year.
Two-thousand YOURS Retail chain-stores' collaboration cases.
It'll be given to Sales Team 1 to handle.
Sales Team 1... is the elite among the elite,
the people on the top of the pyramid.
Letting them negotiate high-end merchandise is no problem of course.
But...?
But... it's different this time.
The flagship of YOURS is regardless of class and borders.
Using the method of penetrating into family households for sales.
This time MUSE must
think of a way
to get into each level of dressing tables and sinks.
Only this type of sales method
can make the upcoming case a success.
Bring the YOURS proposal and follow me.
A coffee a day
makes happiness seem everlasting! Anyone want coffee?
Ah, I forgot! I have to...
Everyone stop what you're doing.
I have something to announce.
Come to the front.
Is there a problem today?
What I'm holding in my hand,
present in two thousand places across the country,
is the very powerful YOURS chain-store project.
I want each one of you,
within three months,
to settle the YOURS shelve-stocking distribution agreement.
Note that
it includes each— one— of— you.
You're so funny! How can it be only three months?
I probably can... you guys...
Even my grandma doesn't use this type of cellphone.
Do you think this is my first day on the job?
I don't recall MUSE's
cooperation with this company.
How much longer do you need?
Half a month.
- Clear it all right now!  - Yes! CEO, I've done wrong.
I don't want to see
you guys messing things up.
I'm telling you guys...
If you don't reach my requirements within three months,
the notice of dismissal
will be the
last document that will have your personal signature.
Also...
if there are any clients
who want to terminate their contract,
I want you to put your life on the line to get it back!
There are a lot of people who can order lunch here at MUSE.
I don't need to spend money to support this department.
Refresh Man fact #2
Don't worry when the sky is falling down
since there is definitely someone who will have to hold up.
But if you're the unlucky one who
has to face the consequences...
don't get flustered as well because...
there is bound to be more unfortunate things to come.
Okay.
One last thing I have to announce.
Come in!
Hello!
This is
your new colleague, Chen You Rui.
Everyone, I'm Chen You Rui.
Not bad. You guys have quite the spirit.
Zhong Yu Tang?
You could even recognize me this way?
What are you doing here?
You both know each other?
She is my girlfriend.
♫ The first person I think of is you ♫
♫ There is no reason ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ All my partners are accompanying me ♫
What are you doing here?
You both know each other?
She is my girlfriend.
That was two years ago.
Oh!
Romeo, are you done talking?
Remember this, it's three months. Did you hear me?
Yes, sir.
Zhou Yu Tang, why don't you pick up my phone calls?
I've spent so much time trying to find you.
Everyone gather together.
We need to discuss how that YOURS case is going to move forward.
Jia Yin, get the sales reports to me tomorrow morning.
And then tomorrow afternoon, Hui Xin and Liang Yu will come with me to observe the stores.
- We need to see where our clients are spending their money.  - Let's go.
Then Yu Tang and her ex-boyfriend should stay and watch over the office.
My, that scared me!
What a huge contrast.
Come out with me!
Woah! Gentler! Hey!
Hey!
That new CEO that just came doesn't have problems in his head, right?
Why is he handing such a huge project to us?
A meat pie which fell from the heavens is a trap.("Meat pie" and "trap" sound similar in Chinese)
He obviously wants us to die.
Jia Wen Qing, who cares if he is a meat pie or a trap?
If he is a meat pie, then eat him.
If he is a trap...
we can just push those two Refresh Men!
No matter how big the earth and sky are, we just need to fill our bellies.
Hey, it's almost lunchtime.
- What should we eat? - What should we eat?
- Fish soup? Helps increase lactation.
No. How about pizza delivery?
After all that, I've lost all creativity.
Do you want low fat food?
Sure, let me know once you've decided.
Have some creativity.
Even though Chen You Rui is reputed to be the Casanova of MUSE Cosmetics,
I never thought that Yu Tang was also one of his former girlfriends.
What is so surprising about that?
Haven't you heard of the best match for a turtle is a green bean,
and the best match for a flea is a bed bug?
Everyone has their place in life. (T/N: Literally translates to one hole for one radish.)
What kind of place is this?
I'll just wait and see when you guys clean this place up.
I have not been kabe-don before.
Can you be a little gentle?
I'm warning you.
Don't you dare even bring up the words "ex-boyfriend" in front of anyone.
Otherwise...
But we've held hands...!
A relationship so touching.. you wouldn't have—
Hey! I was crossing the road and almost fell, and you just happened to lend me a hand. That's it, okay?
The next day I saw you flirting with someone else and blacklisted your number.
- What relationship?-But...
I've already given my true heart.
Can't you tell?
Forget it.
If you can even resist this trick of mine which no one could.
Looks like I should tidy up.
Very good.
I'm making this clear to you.
We have only a working relationship and nothing else. Understand?
Okay, I get it.
Peace and love, right?
Peace and love.
There is only peace. No love.
Don't worry.
Anyways, I need to stay here for a month.
Next month is our anniversary sale.
MUSE Cosmetics can't be without this sales god, Chen You Rui.
Or else the stock drops ten percent.
To put it frankly, everyone, I'm here to save you.
- Yes. - Yes.
Good! You've got it.
Zhong Yu Tang, calm down. Everything will be peaceful.
Peace.
Since you're the savior of Sales Team #3,
I'll give the biggest case to you.
No problem!
Chen You Rui, Chen You Rui.
Chen You Rui, sales god, Chen You Rui.
Good! Yeah! Yes!
Wait a minute.
Didn't the Director say that this case needs to be handled by each and every one of us?
You're giving it to this flower boy? I don't think that's very safe.
I say, young lady, you...
Why do you care about how the boss assigned this?
Once the boss is gone, we can reassign it ourselves.
Wait a minute.
Why don't you two ex-lovers take care of this case together?
That's fine with me, I don't find it awkward.
That's a plan!
I'm already being pushed the edge with the Di Shi Kang products being taken off the shelves.
How can I take on another big case?
Director, it's fine.
I think you should just assign it.
Okay, it's agreed.
Xia Zhi Hui?
God really does have a good eye.
Their big manager is a woman!
Everyone, leave this up to me.
I'll get it done within a week.
Hey, handsome boy. Their small manager is a man.
A man?
My colleagues at the counters told me that though Shen You Rui is really good with women.
But whenever he meets a man (a hard task), he'll immediately... [chokes] become mute.
And can't get a word out.
No, not... Listen to me, guys.
Actually...
Back down.
Everyone has their own field of speciality.
Must you be so heartless?
Hello, I'm sales assistant, Jiang Hui Xing.
Hui Xin, is there anything you need my help for?
Ah Jiao Bento Store, five signature-
Sorry. Originally this task was meant for Yu Tang.
But, you came after her. So now it's yours.
- I—  - Oh right!
Extra spicy carrots and pickled vegetables. Thank you!
Hey! Have you ever seen someone like me buy lunch—?
Yu Tang, what is this?
Hey! You—
Guys, I don't know how to get lunch. Guys?
Hello?
Hello, CEO.
I don't understand.
Shen You Rui's performance is considered really good.
Why did you move the prince of VIP to Sales Team #3?
He wasn't a player in my original game of chess.
He burst in unexpectedly.
It might be a good thing.
After all the saying goes, "It's better for things to come at the right time than early."
At least there are more players.
Putting qualified personnel in Sales Team #3... wouldn't they turn out bad too?
All these Refresh Men who have different symptoms, if up until this point,
still do not know to save themselves.
Then I have to come out myself,
to get them up to standard before they all rot.
Isn't it just about buying bentos?
Why do we have to go get diapers and storybooks as well?
I actually think it's interesting.
Why do you have to drag me into buying lunches with you?
Before in sales, I would be eating French cuisine with VIP customers.
Even if there isn't, female colleagues would willingly bring me a Japanese bento.
How would I know how to get to the bento shop?
For goodness sake!
Stop recalling your amazing accomplishments from the past, okay?
Don't you know that the company has already dealt with you like waste?
Waste?
I'm outstanding achiever Shen You Rui.
It's weird. What exactly did I do wrong?
It probably would have something to with your luck in love.
Peach blossom... oh, I knew it!
Right, I wanted to use this chance to be in love. And wrap up my virg—
virgin adolescence... and become an adult officially.
When can I actually end my virgin life?
I—
Yu Tang, I'll just suffer a bit.
If it's you, I can.
I can't!
There is nothing going on between us!
No... eh, there's a lot!
♫ The first person I think of is you ♫
♫ There is no reason ♫
♫ Lead me on! Let me be on my own ♫
♫ Dreams are currently flowing free with the wind ♫
♫ Say La La La La La La La ♫
♫ There will be sadness! There will be happiness ♫
♫ Good and bad will naturally divided ♫
♫ All my partners are accompanying me ♫
There is nothing going on between us.
No... eh, there's a lot!
Zhong Yu Tang!
What time is it now?
You can still fool around with your ex-boyfriend here... buying bentos?
You're very inactive.
You didn't forget the Di Shi Kang matter right?
You're just a Refresh Man who only knows how to escape from problems.
- What are you— - Ai Sha.
Have the punishments for the departments who fail to get the desired results been announced yet?
Let's go.
This CEO seems to know you very well.
What is the relationship between you two?
It can't be the same holding-hands relationship as me right?
Hold hands, hold hands!
Hey, what are you looking at?
My son's appetite hasn't been too good these past 2 days.
So I want to look on the Internet for baby food that can help nourish him.
You're exaggerating!
I'm just taking a long break before the year-end sale.
I'll make a comeback soon.
It's you who should take care of yourself well.
Don't make me worry, okay?
Please, Chief.
Jia Yin, why don't you pass Di Shi Kang to Yu Tang?
Next week, Di Shi Kang is going to remove all of Mei Mei's products from the shelves.
- Huh? - This is the contract for removing the products off the shelves.
Please take it with you.
This is the first case I've tried to get on my own initiative since becoming a salesperson.
But it has unexpectedly caused Sales Team 3 to lose its biggest client.
How can I admit such a big mistake?
Chief Meng He, I...
Thanks.
Is there anything else?
Everything's good. There isn't really anything.
Sister Jia Yin has always been in charge of Di Shi Kang.
I'll just tell her first.
- Sister Jia Yin, may I ask you a question?  - I'm sorry...
Every time I think about my son, all my maternal love comes bursting out at once.
I'm going to go squeeze some milk out.
But I wanted to discuss with you about Di Shi Kang... there's...!
My dear colleagues, there are thirty seconds remaining until we get off work and go back to our warm homes.
Time to get off work.
Get off work... pick up my son!
That... that...
Urgent announcement!
Di Shi Kang wants to terminate their contract with us and take Mei Mei off the shelves.
Why this all of a sudden? Jia Yin?
What do we do?
Wasn't it still fine before? Why would it be like this?
Yu Tang, wait a second.
I'm going to call the nanny to see if she can take care of my son for a bit longer.
What's going on?
Why is she not answering now?
Jia Yin, there shouldn't be any problems right?
If Di Shi Kang really removes Mei Mei off the shelves,
our whole sales performance will be cut to less than half!
Then the whole Sales Team 3 will be cut by our CEO!
That's great! I didn't think I would be able to return to the VIP station this soon.
Anyone want to catch a ride with me?
Yu Tang?
Then...I'll be leaving first.
Let's leave first then.
What?
Yu Tang, I still can't get in touch with the nanny.
I am really worried about my son.
Let's talk about Di Shi Kang's situation tomorrow. Okay?
Tomorrow? It will be too late by tomorrow.
-Yu Tang.-What's the matter, Chief?
Remember to switch off the lights.
Chief!
Something so big happened
so aren't we supposed to have an urgent meeting to discuss countermeasures?
Young lady... because such a big thing happened, it therefore has nothing to do with us.
If the sky falls down, there is someone who will have to hold it up.
I'm telling you...
for those of us who get paid a low wage, it's considered passing if you just complete your duties.
Don't stick your nose into other things, okay? That's it.
Bye.
But...!
Hey!
- Sister Jia YIn! Sister Jia Yin!  - Oh... Yu Tang,
I've called my nanny more than thirty times and still can't get in contact with her.
I'm really worried right now.
Let's talk about the Di Shi Kang's situation tomorrow. Okay?
Why don't you teach me then?
Just give me ten minutes.
Teach me how to do it. I'll deal with it. No problem.
I'm really worried about my son now.
I promise you that as soon as I reach the company tomorrow, I'll discuss it with you.
Sorry.
Huang Jia Yin!
You have always been in charge of Di Shi Kang's business.
After you had your child, it seems that you haven't even stepped through Di Shi Kang's doors.
The CEO said before that if the sales performance drops, the whole team will be cut.
Others may be able to go find free time, do nothing, and wait for the worst to come,
but what about you?
Do you have this choice?
Or do you want to go set up a stall at the night market while carrying your child?
Hello?
My son is in the emergency room?
Which hospital is he at?
Okay, I'm going over now.
The nanny just called and said that my son is having a high fever.
He was brought to the emergency room.
I'm sorry, I really need to go now. I'm sorry.
I will go with you.
Let's go.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Marvelous Rivals @ Viki
If you want me to save MEI MEI, then you must accept my training.
Sell everything within thirty minutes.
What?
"The First Person I Think of is You" by Weibird Wei
♫ I’m always telling myself not to be too addicted ♫
♫ And ignore the scenery in front of me ♫
♫ You're too smart, too mysterious, too beautiful ♫
♫ How can I be ruthless to you ♫
♫ and miss out on this gap? ♫
I like you.
♫ The first person I think of is you ♫
♫ There is no reason ♫
♫ In a lonely night, ♫
♫ hold your coat tightly ♫
♫ You are the brightest star in the darkness ♫
♫ The first person I think of is you ♫
♫ The first thing after I wake up ♫
♫ Is a message with no reply ♫
♫ And a queued answer ♫
♫ Every moment is a reminder to me ♫
♫ I can't do without you ♫