w
ww
www
www.
www.d
www.da
www.dap
www.dapa
www.dapat
www.dapatf
www.dapatfi
www.dapatfil
www.dapatfilm
www.dapatfilmg
www.dapatfilmgr
www.dapatfilmgra
www.dapatfilmgrat
www.dapatfilmgrati
www.dapatfilmgratis
www.dapatfilmgratis.
www.dapatfilmgratis.b
www.dapatfilmgratis.bl
www.dapatfilmgratis.blo
www.dapatfilmgratis.blog
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogs
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogsp
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogspo
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogspot
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.c
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.co
www.dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.com
Silahkan Kunjungi
http://dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.com
Upload from IDWS
By Jahust Jarzani
Are you gambling tonight?
Damn! Why you always come to me
only before you go gambling?
What, you think I am
some kind of tranquilizer?
Okay, I won't come next time.
Can't you be sweet to me?
Be sweet? Cheating is my job.
You have to pay me
to be sweet to you.
I've never seen you carrying a knife.
Is there going to be danger tonight?
Are you scared?
I have two knives.
But I think you will never
get to see the second one.
I'll call you, bye.
Do remember it.
Let me tell you,
don't ever use this color
of lipstick again, okay?
Why are you so picky
when it comes to color?
Think about it,
if I can't tell the difference
between a red heart and a black spade.
What good does it do to me?
Bye.
Why are you here?
You are really here!
Is that you wife?
Yes.
You are really good,
you can find your way here.
I'm sorry.
I am in hurry.
If you want to fight,
wait until I get home.
I don't want to fight,
I just want an answer from you.
I just put on my pants
five minutes ago.
Do you get it now?
I was going to tell you something,
but I guess that
is not necessary now.
Bye.
I think you should go talk to her.
If woman wants to fight,
she just needs a good kick.
But she is quiet,
you should go check on her!
Look at what you are wearing,
go back inside.
King.
Did you wife find out?
It's time, drive.
Chung, Fanny in these days...
There is nothing.
King, listen to me, this couple
of days when you were not home,
your wife vomited many times.
I think she is pregnant.
Anyway, is everything in place?
Jack's already worked in Bad Temper's
restaurant for three month.
He works hard
and gets everything done.
Everyone trust him.
Now he is able
to set up the VIP room.
Everything is in place.
How is Bad Temper's card skill?
So so.
Eighty points?
Yes. But his name
tells the whole story.
We are going to win no matter what.
King, be honest with you,
your wife is a good woman.
If you like, you can have her.
Really? Stupid.
We, as a sharper,
we can't get distracted.
If we are going to cheat,
we have to do it right.
Just like Macau Mon.
Your idol?
My target.
I have to beat him.
I want to be like him,
get rich from gambling.
But I heard others say...
anyone offends Mon
will regret at last.
There are always exceptions.
Maybe I will be the first one.
Spades 2, heart 2,
four of a kind, king.
Three tens, no club ten.
Three, four, five and six,
one of each.
You have been
coughing the whole night.
I am allergic to cigar.
Nowadays, if you don't like cigar,
then you are not a man.
A pair of jack.
Three aces.
Stop me now, this is my warning.
Straight flush.
Are you really this good?
If you can't beat it then pass.
Pass.
Three threes.
Is this for reals?
Bad Temper, behave yourself
or no one will play with you again.
I just fell kind of weird.
It is like he can
see through my cards.
Want to cut?
Sure!
Sorry!
Sorry, one second.
What is it?
King, it's over.
It's that all?
One more thing I want to tell you.
Because I think
you have the right to know.
I am having your baby.
But I will not let you see him.
Do you still want to play? Hurry up.
Don't get so mad.
Watch your stupid mouth?
Or I will make you give
all my brothers outside a blow job.
Sorry! Begin.
Wait.
I want to trade cards,
I want to have your cards.
Bad Temper, there are no such rules.
This is my place,
what are you going to do?
Trade!
A pair of six.
A pair of seven.
A pair of jacks.
A pair of twos.
Do you have to use
the biggest pair this early?
What do you think?
Three aces.
How come your cards
are so good tonight?
I don't know.
I was letting you
hit me at a pair of sixes.
But I didn't know
you are this bad luck.
Cards please.
No more! This is like a magic show.
Calm down!
I think you should
go have some sex tonight.
What? Not you.
Look into the mirror!
You face looks like a pile of shit.
Hey, give me some respect,
I am a human being too.
To hell with you!
Who do you think you are?
You crazy!
Take her to the bathroom
and tell Hindu guards to rape her.
Sorry, this is it for today.
I lost four hundred cards,
this is yours.
Yeah!
Cut of his hand.
Jack!
Leave...
Close the door!
Jack...
What did you give me?
What did you inject in me?
How come I can't see any color?
Your have seriously
damaged your head.
No!
You do have rights to remain silent,
but anything you say
can be used against you in court.
We are charging you with murder.
Is Bad Temper dead?
What about my brother Jack?
Sorry! He lost too much blood,
we can't save him.
What about my wife? Where is she?
There were no injured female
presented at the scene.
No! My wife was there.
My wife was there!
My wife was there! Please,
I want to see her!
Calm down... calm down.
I will call her for you.
I couldn't reach Fanny.
From that night on,
Fanny seems to have disappeared.
None of her relatives
knew where she went.
I was found guilty of murder and
was sentenced to five years in jail.
During the time,
Chung came visit me twice.
He also said that
he didn't know where Fanny was.
I became a color-blind person.
Everything I see is all in one color.
I understand that
if I don't learn something in jail,
I will not be able to catch up
to the society when I come out.
So I decided to learn something.
I learned how to use a computer
to store all horse racing records.
I also learned to use a formula
to predict some gambling results.
Granny, what's taking so long?
What horse should I bet on tonight?
Got it! The first race,
number 4,5 and 7.
And the second one,
horse number 2, 8, and 12.
At last! I realized
something very important,
that is, out of ten gambling places,
nine of them are cheaters.
In this world, if you don't cheat,
you are never guaranteed to win.
Open.
Five years later
It's good! I lost everything!
I am no Dragon!
You got the wrong man.
Damn you! You are Dragon,
I know you well, let's go!
Eastwood... please don't get
any closer, you are about to kiss me.
Anything's going on?
Nope!
Recently I got the arthritis
so I wasn't about to get any news.
Really? Nothing?
I heard that Uncle Liang's fellows
are always gathering.
Are they making a big deal?
Eastwood, I am only a gambler,
I am not gangster.
I can tell you tips
on Saturday's race.
The 9th race, brother Tat said
the number 8 will win for sure.
Who is Tat?
Ng Man Tat.
Dick head!
Nonsense!
Let me tell you,
when I call you,
you have to answer at once.
Or you will get it.
Yes... yes! If you have time
go to Peter's place for a massage,
just tell him you are my friend
and you don't have to pay.
You dickhead!
I can't stand you anymore.
- Get down.
- Why?
Get down!
Eastwood, I won't do that?
What are you thinking about?
Let me tell you,
I haven't dealed with you
for using fake money.
Do you want me to kill you?
Of course not!
Let's do this!
Rabbit jump all the way
to the end of the street.
Eastwood, this is a crowded place.
Why don't we find a more quiet place
and I'll jump for you then?
Now!
Son of a bitch!
If I become rich someday,
you will really get it!
Dragon.
Uncle Liang, what's up?
What are you doing here?
Nothing! My legs are hurting,
I think it's the weather.
I just want to do some exercise.
In a crowded place like this?
Boss, you know, I like to act.
What's up, boss?
Your hero is getting
out of jail tomorrow!
My hero?
The big sharper King.
He is coming out of jail tomorrow.
He is a famous Sharper...
in our field!
The man you ever dream for so long!
Right...! So?
He is my brother.
Tomorrow I'll going to Shenzhen,
go pick him up for me.
Okay...
- Take him for a shower
- Of course...
- A good meal.
- Yes...
- Then take him to a night club.
- Okay...
- Get him a girl.
- Yeah...
Hold this.
Three hundred dollars?
Is not enough?
I call on you
there must be some difficulty.
You are a smart man,
you can take care of it.
$300?
Do I have to take him
to Grant Hyatt hotel too?
Hello, King.
Did you call me?
You are brother King?
Call me Dragon!
Uncle Liang asked me to pick you up.
How long have you been here?
One hour or so.
Did you see a woman with a kid?
It's windy,
I don't think any kids'll come
even his dad is out of jail.
How can there be
a woman carrying a kid?
Brother King...
Brother King, are you ready?
It's cold!
Brother King, are you done?
So, did you find them?
It's been so long,
the numbers have been changed.
Who are you looking for?
My wife.
Now you are out of jail.
With your look,
you can get lots of woman.
Come, let me take you for a shower
and wash away all the bad luck!
Good luck to you! Bad luck's gone!
All the bad lucks leave at once,
and all the good lucks come now.
Done!
Brother King,
how come you don't have any tattoo?
I am not a gangster, I am a sharper.
All the gangster
want everyone to recognize them.
As a sharper,
you want no one to recognize you.
Right!
I thought all the gamblers
are dressed nicely
and with their hair jelled.
Don't you think acting like that
can win you millions?
That is only for movies.
Right... only for movies.
Brother King, I heard that you are
good at winning lots of money.
I am a good sharper.
Can you take me as a trainee?
If I teach you,
then you will
become one more enemy for me.
Then can I be your assistant?
If you can keep your month shut,
I might consider it.
Okay!
Brother King,
you are really something!
Brother King...
What?
Where are you going?
Massage!
Forget it! Those massage girls
will only massage for couple minutes,
then they will give you blow jobs.
And they will charge you for it too.
- Let's go eat, okay?
- Okay.
Uncle Liang asked me
to treat you to a great meal.
We have fish and meat here,
I've tried my very best.
Come on, eat.
What is it? Do you think I'm cool?
Brother King, come on, smile.
Lots of my friends
have been into jails before.
But the strongest always survive.
You are educated.
I always watch
those charity show on TV,
I copied their lines.
You really want to help me?
Starting tomorrow,
we will make money together.
Yeah! Brother King, that's great.
Are you done!
After this I will take you
to have fun in a karaoke.
Be happy!
You sing... quite good.
It's okay, I can't catch up
to some of the beats.
You know,
I always wish to be a good singer.
Everyone in my family
has some singing potential.
Like my sister,
her voice can alone attract many men.
Your sister works here?
Yes! She is a PR girl here.
But she's a fool!
She gives her hard earned money
to a dump ass for tuition in America.
She is a good girl.
I think she is stupid.
Only women spend men's money,
how can there be an opposite?
I need to go to the bathroom.
I didn't ask for girl.
Where is Dragon?
He went to the bathroom.
You tell him,
I am not going to pay his bill.
Are you his sister?
Sit.
No, thanks.
I haven't seen you before.
Your brother just took me in.
You seem like a nice man, but don't
mess around with my brother,
because he will bring you down.
- Don't smoke too much.
- You are not young, man.
No... Rocky baby, be careful.
No... stop.
I don't want to do like this.
Neck bridge.
No... Rocky baby.
No... please stop!
Come on, Kimmy, come down.
Rocky baby,
you don't have to treat
my sisters like this.
I only care about you.
I am not interested in sex.
You will only be disappointed.
I don't mind,
let me have the disappointment.
You are always like this.
How dare you hit me? Bitch!
Rocky baby, you want to have fun,
I will get you the right girl.
Ching Ching cries easily,
she can't handle it.
Shut your hole and
get out of my face! Now!
Get her out of here.
Out!
Then... Ching Ching,
don't make Rocky baby mad again.
Let's play the guessing game.
Okay, I will play with you.
Fine! If you lose,
you have to go with me.
But if you lose you have to leave.
Okay, fine.
What is wrong with you,
why the rush?
Dragon, your sister is in trouble!
Are you sure? Who?
It's Rocky!
This guy is an animal.
He wants to screw
your sister tonight,
what are we going to do?
Let's call the cops.
Is this a good idea?
Cops?
Who is calling the police?
Did someone get hit by a car?
No! My sister is in deep trouble.
Really?
That jerk is a well-known gangster.
He has hundreds of fellows.
He fights like a hero.
Woman touches his pillow
will end up a sorrow...
Are you a poet now?
Stop messing around,
what are we going to do now?
Open the door!
Slut, you lost? Open the door.
Hey man,
the stick is for pool,
not for you to bang at the door.
Who the hell are you?
Who are you?
Oh is Dragon,
what are you trying to do?
She is a PR girl and she is supposed
to sleep with customers.
In my eyes,
I can sleep with
all the girls in this world.
You are night,
all the girls in this world
can have sex with,
but is either with you or me!
White head, what is your problems?
Do you want to get your ass kicked?
Someone told me before that
you are good at pool,
why don't we play a game?
Do you know that I always play...
with Hong Kong's Pool King before?
Me too! But how come
I've never seen you before?
Let's play a game,
if I win I will take Ching Ching.
But if I lose you get to have here.
And an extra
thirty thousand dollars bet.
Really?
Okay! Don't move!
We don't have
thirty thousand dollars!
I really don't have
Don't mess with him then.
I am a little scared too,
let's go then.
I don't care, you have to continue.
I break!
You don't have to yell!
Be careful!
It went in! You're a pain in my ass.
Damn I am lucky!
Yes!
Pay up.
Bastard! Act all stupid,
watch your back.
Thanks.
No more pool from now on, let's go!
Bye.
Come on out, sister,
I am your brother!
You don't have to peep, it's me.
Thanks.
Give it to me,
I will keep it for you.
I need to find somewhere to stay.
I have an extra room in my house.
What, thirty thousand dollars
for a room?
It's a long rent payment.
I was going to put
this room up for rent,
but my boyfriend
doesn't like the idea,
so it became a store room.
Sister, I am interested
in this room too.
Get out?
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
I want to get something straight.
Okay.
I have a fiance, his name is Raymond.
He is studying in America.
I only have him in my heart.
I rather be a PR girl
so I can help him finish his study.
I let you stay here
is because of your money.
So please don't have
any idea that included me in it.
Besides, we have
a huge age difference.
Let me tell you something.
I have a wife before I went to jail,
her name is Fanny, she's very nice.
She gave birth to my kid.
I regret so much that I didn't took
care of her when I have the chance.
After I got out of jail
I totally lost contact with her.
I haven't even looked at
my kid's face one time.
But my point is that
I only have them in my heart.
So relax,
I will not have any fantasy
that includes you in it.
That settles it.
Why don't you
let your brother stay here?
I will take care of him.
In Hong Kong, people bet most of
money on football and horse races
- Let me teach you bet on horses.
- Alright.
Master, the 9th race
is about to start now.
The last two horses
are about to enter the barrier.
One left now, hurry.
Which one should we bet on?
Hung's Restaurant? 2 Won Ton noodles
and a plate of vegetable.
4/F, number 34 and room A, thanks.
I thought you were
going to bet, didn't you?
We wasted so much time
and you didn't bet a penny, why?
I don't have the confidence
so why should I bet?
The trainer bet
less than ten races a season.
If you bet on every race, you'll be
broke even if you are Bill Gates.
This is boring.
You want to be a happy loser
or a boring winner?
You are the master,
I will listen to you.
We will do it again next week.
Record all the race results
and we will study that later.
Master, we are gambling,
not going to school.
Nothing comes easily!
I don't think
Won Ton noodle will do it,
let's go out and eat, okay?
Okay, I will take you
to a place which is free.
Let's go!
I thought it will be a good meal!
This is not good enough?
We will have shark fins later,
now we will have crab meat noodle.
Waiter, bring me
another glass of orange juice.
Do you know that fellow?
No really. But I am
very good friend with his wife.
Did you give them a red pocket?
Of course,
I put a deck of newspaper
in the red envelope.
What if they find out?
It's in the red envelope!
Who will know who did it?
Sir, your check is
one hundred and forty dollars.
What? I am a guest.
The order is that...
juice and noodles
will be paid by the guests.
I will kick your ass.
Stop!
- Let me kick his ass!
- Pay.
I won't teach you anything
if you won't pay the bill.
Pay... Hurry.
Sorry... Sorry.
- Kick you ass!
- Thanks... Thanks.
Let me tell you, you asked for it.
Sit.
No, I want to make some money.
Don't do it here,
there are lots of
sharpers making money here.
Eat. Come on.
Brother King.
You are a sharper too,
why are you acting like a gentleman?
There are eight
different kinds of sharpers.
Master, provider, beauty, liar, informer,
warrior, negotiator and gossipmonger.
Total 8 kinds of sharpers.
I am the master
and I do it for a living.
What about the other seven kinds?
Provider's job is to set up the trap.
Beauty's job is to
use beauty to trick a man.
Liar's job is to disappear
after his job is done.
Informer's job
is to gather information.
Warrior's job is to
take care of the dirty works.
Negotiator's job is to negotiate.
Gossipmonger...
to produce rumors so
somebody will be easily cheated.
You make it sounds...
like mission impossible.
Right.
Eat.
What are they playing?
Shoot the gap.
You will get two cards at first.
Say you get an ace and a ten.
If the third card you get is between
ace and a ten then you win.
But if you get J, Q, K then you lose.
But if the third card
is an ace or a ten,
that is called hitting the post.
You will lost double.
Are you done?
Let's go then!
I don't want people to find out your
red envelope when we are still here.
Bet big and you can will big...
there are lots of money on the table.
Dragon, come on,
play couple of hands.
Come on.
Let's win back
the one hundred and forty dollars.
I called you many times!
There are over $20,000 on the table.
Deal it.
Okay.
You want to donate money to me?
How come you have so much money?
My personal saving.
I will bet five thousand dollars.
No more bets.
Here comes...
You hit the post!
You lose double, give me $5,000 more.
Have you learned
your lesson yet? Let's go.
Brother, you look good today!
Play a hand.
No... Sorry.
You can always win the money.
There are something wrong
with all 52 cards,
you can't win!
What do you mean?
He marked all the cards.
Look at him, his whole head
is loaded with hair jell.
He put some of that on the cards,
and he will know what the cards
are by its reflections.
How does he know?
Normally, all sharpers
mark their cards with 40 squares.
4 rows across for the shapes
and 10 rows down for aces to 10.
If two sides of rows have reflections
then it's a J, the short rows are Q.
No reflection means K.
Also, he is always
dealing from the second card.
He deals every hand
from the second card.
He puts the ace on top for emergency.
That son of a bitch!
I stupidly lost ten thousand dollars.
So what? That was your choice.
You want to win it back?
Let's go.
But he is a cop!
So? Give me the money.
One thousand dollars!
That is all I have... I only have
two thousand dollars left.
If we lost it
we will have no money for bus...
Can you make it?
Go take the bus then.
Okay... Okay! Give it a chance...
- I want to play a hand.
- Okay.
Here!
Yeah!
The second card!
4 and a 9? If I have a 5, 6, 7 and 8,
then I will win, right?
Whatever, dump ass!
I want to bet
all the money on the table.
There are thirty thousand dollars!
Okay... that's good.
I really want to bet
all the money on the table.
You sure?
Deal it.
I bet so big,
can I pick my own card?
Okay.
Yeah!
Pay up!
- Dick head, what are you doing?
- What's the matter?
Let me tell you, next time
when you cheat, do it better.
Don't let others catch your mistakes.
There are lots of people here.
You win.
Let him go.
Read carefully the man's face.
The one who comes with Dragon.
After the dinner is over,
go catch him.
Let me cut off
every fingers on his hands.
I want to go to the bathroom.
I will go alone...
It's very fat.
Really? You like it fat?
Then I will let you taste it!
You like it fat, right?
Why do you think it's fat?
It should be called "Dynamic".
Who uses newspaper as a handsel?
Damn it! Who did this?
You really received newspaper?
How did you know?
A cop in the toilet was saying that
he used newspaper as a handsel.
What a bastard!
If I were you I would kick his ass.
- Kick his ass!
- Who is a cop here?
- I am.
Help... you are assaulting a cop!
Let me tell you,
don't let me see them again.
I will kill them, let's go!
Are you crazy?
How can you afford these many girls?
We won lots of money
at the wedding feast.
So we decided
to come here for a little fun.
I am really going to pay today.
Right! Thanks.
No way! I called on you for so long
and you finally show up now.
I was taking care of
some important customers.
A man from Macau was treating
a group of friends from Taiwan.
They just left.
What man from Macau?
Mamasan said that he is
very powerful, his name is Macau Mon.
Stop acting! Pay up.
http://dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.com
Just give tonight's check to me.
Come back again.
Is Macau Mon.
You know him?
Who doesn't know him?
He is the true sharper.
He controls Hong Kong, Macau
with all the horse racing
and soccer matches betting,
and the underground Index market too!
He has a nickname, "Shenzhen Soros".
He will beat you no matter what.
I wanted to challenge him
five years ago,
but he was always in Macau.
Now he mainly lives in Hong Kong.
And his fellows
work everything in Shenzhen.
After the World Cup,
he'd win more than
one thousand millions.
- One thousand millions?
- Right.
If I have that much,
I will trade it
for my son and my wife.
You're still thinking of
your wife, aren't you?
This place is as big as a town,
how can we find him?
Are you sure is here?
Who put your brother
Jack's remains here?
One of my brothers,
his name is Chung.
At the beginning of my jail time,
he did come visit me.
But now he disappeared also.
He told me it's around here.
Is that it?
Looks like someone
has been here a while ago?
- What?
- I will be back.
What is it, master?
Did you see your wife?
Maybe!
She was carrying a kid
and I think that is my son.
Calm down, master!
I spend your money with you
and I will find your kid for you.
What are you talking about?
Maybe I am mistaken of someone else.
A woman with a kid
can't walk this fast.
But someone has been here.
Maybe someone who is kind.
Forget it, I want to look around.
Okay! Go look around.
Master,
I just saw a woman
with a kid up there.
- Really?
- Wait.
Does your wife
have a breast this big?
No! I don't think
that is the one then.
But you have to go take a look! Her
breasts are too big to be true.
You are very nasty!
King, 2 minutes left, but
the spread's still changing big time.
Big bets on number five,
you can see it's raising rapidly.
The dividend is from
ninety down to seventy.
Right! We have been sitting here for
three days and we haven't bet a dime.
Account 1123794, code 217377.
Second race, two thousand dollars
on number five as winner.
$2,000 on quinella, number five
with number seven, eight and twelve.
At the finish, first place number 5,
second place number 8,
third place number 7...
We won!
The winner is horse number five.
Winner pays $935.5,
place pays
one hundred forty six dollars.
The second one is
horse number eight, the place pays...
Master, we won
seven hundred thousand dollars!
What's wrong, aren't you happy?
It's only
seven hundred thousand dollars.
If you win seventy million dollars,
what are you going to do?
We won so much money,
what should we do tonight?
What do you think?
Let's have a good meal?
We will pay for this meal, okay?
Hello.
Brother King,
this is my brotherfriend Raymond.
Hello, brother King.
This is my brother Dragon,
remember him?
Yes.
You guys are betting on horse racing?
Sorry to bother you.
Don't worry! You already did!
- Sit.
- Thanks.
Raymond is on summer vacation.
Which college are you studying?
Princeton University.
I am also going to college too,
Fu Kin University!
Fukin U! How do you do?
Behave.
Excuse me, I am going to
exercise my stomach.
To dump all the waste and
other unnecessary items in my body.
What do you mean?
To take a shit! College student!
Don't mind him! He is weird.
Don't worry!
He is just joking around.
- Raymond, right?
- Yes.
How much longer before you graduate?
April next year.
Then I will get to see
Ching everyday.
We don't have to
write letters anymore.
You can use e-mail.
No! She hates computer.
Yes! I am not very good at computer.
I taught your brother already,
he can help you.
My brother?
How about this, I will help you.
Write your e-mail address
on this paper.
Maybe later.
I think there is
something wrong with that guy.
That slut face?
I am going to beat him up someday.
I don't know why
my sister likes him so much.
I don't think
he is a college student.
Are you sure?
My sister sends him
money every month for tuition.
Is there any proof?
No!
I think he is using your sister.
Are you sure?
Really! I tested him earlier,
I asked him
does he have an e-mail account,
and I can tell by his expression
that he has no clue about e-mail.
The students in America
is not like that.
Really?
What is his full name?
Raymond Chou,
I am going to call
Princeton University
and check it out.
Okay! I will pay for the phone bill.
If he lies to my sister,
he will get it.
Angela.
Hello! I miss you very much.
Nice car! Let me drive it, okay?
Where are we going?
Up to you. Let's go.
You little son of a bitch!
My lord! How can he
go out with an old slut?
I feel sorry for my sister...
Shit.
Son of a bitch!
What an old sluts gigolo!
Watch you back!
- Bye.
Bye.
Sorry!
Watch it buddy!
Hey man! You want my ass to?
Go get yourself some drugs.
Get the hell out of my face!
Leave!
Not a bad gigolo!
Does he have time
to go to the bathroom?
Look like it's not bad
to be a gigolo.
What's wrong?
You don't seem happy today.
I can't see you for six months
after I go back to America,
how can I be happy?
You can call me.
No! The telephone is too expensive.
But I am planning to
open a comic book store in America.
I just want to make some money.
But everyone has to put in
twenty thousand US dollars.
Then it will be one hundred
fifty thousand HK dollars?
Don't worry!
I will take care of that.
Ching, I owe you too much.
I didn't say you have to pay me back.
Tell them you are in,
I will take care of the rest.
Ching, you treat me too good.
I feel that I owe you a lot!
Ching, you have a new boyfriend?
What are you talking about?
Where is the pool player boyfriend?
Rocky baby, stop fooling around.
Why?
Tell this slut face
to go kick his ass, go!
Ching, who is he?
- Let's go.
- Okay.
Are you leaving, Raymond?
Hello.
You told me to come.
I told you to come?
I am her fiance,
call me Ching, you are...
I don't care you go out with little
girls, but why call me to come?
Who are you?
He is my little gigolo.
Is this true?
Oh, no! Volcano is erupting!
Raymond,
you better explain this to me.
The reason I asked you to come...
so you can see me
telling her the truth.
Ching, I can't stay with you anymore.
I love Angela.
Raymond, what are you talking about?
He's just told you that
he's never been to America.
The letters he sent you...
were first sent to
America to his friends,
and then his friends
posted them back to you.
White head is here, get to work.
Is this truth?
So what?
And earlier you told me to give you
twenty thousand US dollars.
- Raymond, let's go.
- Okay.
Let me do this.
You bitch, go to hell!
How dare you trick my sister?
Stop...
Don't trust those people again.
No more... I won't trust him anymore.
Good.
Brother King, don't die! I am sorry.
That's enough! Stop vomiting.
The blood is sweet, swallow it.
Why didn't you tell me
a car is added?
You almost scared me to death.
Enough!
Can't you tell her the truth later?
Why can't you let
an old people rest a little more?
Don't go out with
that slut face anymore.
I won't!
I don't think
you can see him anymore.
With this situation,
he is on his way back to China.
How come he is in it too?
You didn't know brother King
took me in as a student?
- He teaches me to play pool.
- That's nothing.
I am about to become
third best in Hong Kong.
Is he really scared?
I don't think he's gone to far.
Skinny Dragon...
The slut face hid in China
and had plastic surgery.
Now when the wind blows,
his face will come apart,
I think this isn't enough.
I printed a fake paper
about King's death.
It scared the shit
out of him and he fled to Cambodia.
Where is brother King?
Master? He is in
deep thoughts right now.
- Brother King.
- Master.
- He is looking for you.
- What's up.
Sit, brother King.
I went to the gambling boat yesterday
and lost couple hundred thousands.
You are ill-fated.
I guess that ship is haunted,
I have lots 3 consecutive times.
I lost almost
over two million dollars.
Let me look at your palm.
It's all messed up! Take a rest.
No way? Brother King,
I want you to help me.
No.
Master, go win some money.
Then we can hire ten private eyes
to look for your wife.
We can go gamble for you!
But we'll get half the gains and
you'll handle all the loses.
Agree?
Forget it then, master, let's go.
Okay! No problem!
Sure?
I'll take control on the ship
and keep your voice down, understand?
Of course!
There's over 10 gambling ships
between Hong Kong Singapore.
That involve big money.
I love gambling ships
because it's safe.
How?
The owner is Macau Mon.
Everyone knows him
is a straight forward person.
Thanks.
Macau Mon?
Yes! Also, his left hand Handsome...
is always there.
Brother Handsome.
Welcome...
We meet again. I will pay.
- Brother Handsome.
- Hello, Good luck...
Handsome.
What's it, Rocky?
Haven't you
lost enough money already?
I want to win it back.
Good!
Mon left me with couple millions
and told me to pass it out.
I don't know how I should do that.
Just take the money away,
if you can.
Handsome, you're funny guy!
Let me introduce to you my brothers.
King, Skinny Dragon.
- King?
- Yes.
Your name is very familiar.
I am Rocky's fellow.
Rocky,
how come all your fellows
are taller than you? Why?
Have you heard of
the name Bad Temper?
No... no.
I am Handsome,
I am Bad Temper's little brother.
Isn't this like soap opera?
Help yourselves.
He is so high.
Forget him! Let's go gamble.
Bigger... bigger.
Damn it!
Eight, dealer wins.
What?
He bets on player,
I have to bet on dealer
so as to read the cards.
You'd win,
but no just to look at the cards.
If you want to look at cards,
I will go buy you
two deck of cards, okay?
Okay?
Fine!
Sorry.
Nine, player wins.
Yeah... we win again.
You, let brother King play.
Why do we need to look at the cards?
So what if we can't look at them.
I will let you peek at it okay?
Okay.
This is a little machine.
It can read...
your heart beat
if you put your finger in it.
Really?
Bet this much!
Picture!
Bigger...
Yes!
Come on...
Eight, player wins.
You gamble at least twice a week,
everytime you play at least
one to two hundred games.
Even the machine can't stand it,
can your heart stand it?
Who cares, you will play
for me from now on!
You want me to die?
Thanks, smart ass.
Brother King, I got leads,
but why are we betting this much?
What leads?
Leads to bet on player, isn't it?
You can't trust any leads!
All the leads are created by sharper
in order to trick you.
You can only trust your confidence.
- We will wait.
- Okay.
Nine, player wins.
Eight, player wins.
Master, it's been a long time,
should we still bet on player?
Look at the chart,
the player wins less than five times.
- Eight, player wins.
- It's really player.
Do you believe it now?
I'll take the dividend this time.
It's a joke.
What should we bet on?
You go ahead.
Thanks.
Four million dollars,
finally I win something.
Half goes to brother King.
Don't worry!
I only worry he won't take it.
Who said not to bet on player?
The player won 14 straight.
At those kind of situation,
you have to be equally.
Keep betting on player
until the dealer wins.
But don't gamble too long.
Where should we go now?
Let's go to karaoke,
I'll sing for you.
I just love going
to karaoke with chicks.
Handsome.
OK, I'll sing on stage, you can play
with your dick under the table.
I am not going... you go first,
I have to use the bathroom.
We will wait for you at the karaoke.
I'm sorry.
Stop running?
- Stop it...
- Why you have to run?
Tell me.
Sorry brother King.
Why?
I can't take care of Fanny.
How is she?
How is she...?
When she found out
that you went to jail,
she swallowed many pills on night,
and jumped to death.
Where is my kid?
Dead too!
I am sorry, brother King.
Don't worry... it's not your fault.
Forgive me!
You work here?
Give me your telephone number,
I will call you.
I am right! He sings well.
Brother King.
Where did you go?
I saw an old friend.
I think I know who that is.
So what?
Don't worry!
I didn't like my brother anyway.
But I want to talk business with you.
What business?
If I tell you, you can't back out.
Then save your breath.
Okay! We will
talk again someday, bye!
Have fun. He should be a singer.
I am back.
Drink some water,
it's almost lunch time.
Wash your face first.
I saw King yesterday.
I lied to him and said you died.
I don't know if he will believe me.
It doesn't matter to us anymore,
right?
Very cosy.
I thought you were dead.
You asshole stole his wife?
- What are you doing?
- Stop!
http://dapatfilmgratis.blogspot.com
By Jahust Jarzani
This is your family business, I...
I don't know why I should trust you.
When I was in jail,
I wrote many letters to Fanny.
When you came visit me,
I told you to take care of her.
And you did a great job.
No matter what I say,
I am still wrong,
but sorry!
Why say sorry to him?
Without his help,
me and my son would have
starved to death.
To wait for you?
If we waited for you,
I would have been a hooker.
Sorry!
Use the other leg.
Smoke?
Try it, it's good.
Let's go.
Brother King,
this kid is pretty cute.
Too bad he is cripple.
Tell him your name.
I am Little King, diamond King.
I am having your kid,
but I won't let you see him.
If I have 1 billion dollars,
I'd trade it for my wife and kid.
What happened to you?
I don't know!
Ask my mother and father.
Can I...
take him out to play sometimes?
Thanks.
In the past five years,
I have never been so happy.
Today with Little King besides me,
my world's become a colorful one.
Everything in front of me
has become very pretty.
Look at them, they are so happy,
and you are so bad.
If you like it,
get yourself one baby.
Your are very annoying.
Stop thinking about that slut face.
Forget him.
Think about how good
your life is without him.
You are single and happy now.
Let's see when master
will start to like you,
and when you
will give birth to his baby.
When you will have his last name
and live happily ever after.
Stupid.
He will be yours someday.
Brother King.
Come, sit a while.
Why does she seem so sad?
You know what happened.
Play with him for a while, okay.
Take care of him,
I will go check on her.
Do you want to try
something very exciting?
What's wrong?
Are you still thinking about Raymond?
No...
There is still this feeling...
I don't know!
Let's do this, make yourself a goal.
Like where you want to go.
Europe.
Ask your brother to take you then.
If he goes with me
I'd rather stay here alone.
If you don't mind...
an old man coming along,
I will go with your then?
I mean it!
Brother King, what a surprise!
Your girlfriend?
I am not as good as you.
I have something that need your help.
I know you killed my brother.
He is an asshole, serve him right.
If you didn't kill him,
someone would do it.
If you help me make some money,
I can call you my brother.
Go.
It's Macau Mon!
I want to gamble with
Macau Mon on Big two.
In Hong Kong, people make a big bet
on Big Two and Baccarat.
Baccarat is too easy.
Macau Mon calls himself
the king of big two.
I want you to go challenge him.
You rich people play around
$3,000 dollars a card,
even you win,
you can only get millions,
you don't care about that.
You are really a wise guy.
But I have a bigger plan.
You want to kill him?
As you said.
He didn't hurt me in any way,
I don't have to help you.
Really?
You know what,
I hate traitor like you.
He is your boss
and you want to kill him.
How can I trust you?
You have to.
Look at this!
What an interesting tape!
King.
So?
You are worse than your brother.
Will you work with me?
No way!
Are you scared?
Little King, run!
Run... little King.
Run, little King.
This kid is cute. He can run
so fast even he is crippled.
Go to hell.
Little King... Little King.
Tell your boss to work with me,
or else... he's shit!
Take this home and enjoy it.
Let's go.
King.
Do you think I am useless?
No! You are brave
and you win everytime your gamble.
Even my dump brother,
you made him a better man.
I think that you are a great man.
I used to think this way.
Everytime after I gambled,
I always felt that I am a winner.
But this time,
I feel like I am the loser.
I lost my family, time and happiness.
I even lost my confidence.
So what if I am a good sharper?
At the end Handsome will use us
to cheat and lie for him.
You can beat him.
How?
My son is in the hospital.
Chung and Fanny are being locked up.
Even if I win
I might not be able to save them.
But they are not
the only ones you have left.
You still have my brother, yourself...
and me.
Are you crazy or silly?
After Raymond left,
don't you know what I am thinking?
Let me tell you,
sometimes I really envy your wife.
Are you crazy?
We have a huge age difference...
I thought I told her to talk to him.
Did I tell her to sleep with him?
Oh well, who cares?
I guess my sister needs lots of love.
Quiet.
- You are going to help Handsome?
- Quiet.
You are really
going to help Handsome?
I have no choice.
Macau Mon is cold blooded and smart.
No matter you win or lose,
you might not able
to save your wife and Chung.
I am going
to take it one step at a time.
You are really
going to help Handsome?
Quiet.
- You are really going.
- Quiet!
If I don't know your plan,
I won't help you.
Macau Mon is the biggest dealer...
in Asia.
He won a lot of money
from betting on World Cup.
Two nights from now will be the World
Cup final between France and Brazil.
The whole world feels
that Brazil will win.
So what?
I know that the European mobsters
are already doing something.
If Brazil loses,
the whole world's dealers
will win big.
Macau Mon should know about this.
Of course he knows! He is
a very good friend with the Mafis.
He knows Brazil is going to lose.
So he calmly accept
the betting of Brazil's winning.
If Brazil wins, he will be broke.
That night, we'll play big two on
the ship, each card worth's $10,000.
I want you to make Brazil win.
Make Brazil win?
Do you think I am GOD?
You can do it.
It's on TV.
You'll bet
ten million dollars on Brazil.
I'll take half.
It's not this simple.
By the way, recently I'm told that
Macau Mon has
a serious heart problem.
You want him to die of
a heart attack that night, right?
Smart people's lives
are always short.
I am not very smart.
Can you tell me one thing,
how can we make him
have a heart attack?
You must have an idea.
TG7, a poison
that dissolves in water.
If he drinks it,
it will create heart failure.
Even the coroner can't detect it.
You want Chung
and fanny to take one too?
You try it.
Okay!
Don't act all cool.
Get out of the car.
Stop at the side.
I can't believe he knows our plan.
So what?
Did you get your men ready yet?
Yes! After this incident,
even if he hides at the earth's
corner, I will have him killed.
I will pay you when I see the body.
That is director Squirrel
and he is good.
He is specially good
at conducting live show.
He is over there.
Curly!
Dragon.
This is my master, brother King.
Brother King.
Is there any problem
with the things I told you to do?
No problem.
I want it seems like a live show.
We want commercials too.
No problem.
I want the famous commentator
Lin Sheung-yee.
No problem.
What?
You have to win tonight.
I won't lose.
You spend a night...
at your cousin's home.
Meet us at the train station
at nine tomorrow morning.
We will go to Mainland China,
then we will go to Europe.
I will wait for you.
If you don't see us
after nine thirty,
then you have to go first.
I won't leave without you two.
Listen to me, leave after nine thirty.
And that is a must.
Go.
How long have you been standing here?
Yes!
- You heard it all?
- Yes.
Let me tell you, we are
going to face the pros tonight.
If we win tonight,
you can be God of Gamblers.
You don't have to be God of singer.
Okay.
Brother King,
let me ask you a question.
- How is my voice?
- Very bad.
You don't have to tell the truth.
Let me ask you a question.
What.
Is your first name really Skinny?
No way! Have you ever known
someone named Skinny?
What is your real surname?
Don't worry,
just call me Skinny Dragon.
Tell me.
- No...
- Tell me...
What?
- Louder?
- I can't hear you.
Stupid Dragon!
Stop laughing!
Look at you, I fed you so well.
And you won't say 'be careful' to me.
Be careful.
Okay. Bye.
Brother Mon is waiting for you
in the VIP room.
Tonight's final
is between France and Brazil.
We can play big two and
gamble on the game, what a night!
I want to see Chung and Fanny first.
Look, they are still alive! Relax!
Okay!
Brother King,
let me introduce to you.
This is my boss Mon,
everyone calls him Macau Mon.
My brother Dragon,
nicknamed Skinny Dragon.
It doesn't matter who he is,
who cares?
Right! Just save
your energy for the game.
You brought so much money
onto this ship,
I wouldn't let you walk away
with it so easily.
Here is a $50 million dollars
bank check.
We will be on the game first.
Okay! If you bet on Brazil,
we have a special offer for you,
here is our package,
if Brazil wins, you'll gain 10%% % less.
Which means if Brazil wins by a goal,
I win $25,000,000.
If Brazil wins by two,
I win $45,000,000.
Brother, money doesn't
come this easily.
No pain, no gain.
Okay! We will play big two
and bet on the game then.
$10,000 a card.
Eight cards double, ten cards triple,
thirteen cards quadruple.
I came with cash and a check
and I expect
to walk home with it too.
Of course! I, Macau Mon,
always pay up when I lose.
If you want to bet on fingers
then I will pay you with my fingers.
Are you scared?
Who is the other player?
It's me!
Winner Gary, why are you so late?
I've been on the ship long time ago,
but I took a nice sauna bath
that is why I am late.
Brother Mon, I've never seen
this white head before.
Where did you find this loser?
Hey, you look
more like a loser to me.
What's wrong with you?
Who let you speak here?
Go out and take a walk.
I follow the fat boy's direction,
why isn't it working?
I've got something.
Damn! How come it's ATV?
Got it.
Diamond three first.
Pass.
What's wrong? Why the rush?
- Pass.
Good.
Diamond two.
Pass.
Three threes.
You are good,
you can break up four threes.
I just hoped it would work.
Luckily it worked and
now you lost four times more.
Very good!
I haven't faced
such a good player for a long time.
Thank you.
Master, did you win?
A little.
He just got luck.
I am the king of big two.
You'd play at least 200 rounds with
me before knowing who the winner's.
How dare you look down on my master?
How dare you hit me?
Dragon.
Dickhead! Go to hell.
Brother King,
what should I do with your man?
There are rules,
this is your place, you take charge.
Take him away.
Get up!
Continue.
Yet another one.
Dickhead! You are still alive?
Where is your boss?
He is in the VIP room.
So what? You are going
to leave him there?
Look after the three of them.
Dickhead! I told you
that you will get it someday.
So what if you are
with that white head?
You can't hide?
Act tough?
Why are you acting like a woman?
Use some strength!
You dickhead!
How dare you pretend to be tough!
Fight back...
Damn!
Damn! How dare you?
Damn! You want to pretend dying?
Get in there.
What's wrong with you?
Do you want me to rape you again?
How dare you bang on me!
I just want your wife.
You want me to screw you?
We are so happy with now.
Let's have more fun.
Come on, let's play.
What a gathering!
Why don't we play
the game of banging?
Yes!
Luckily I have you guys to play with.
You bastard!
Dickhead! I can't stand you anymore.
You treated me like a piece of shit.
And you wanted me to rabbit jump
in front of so many people.
You nasty scum!
You cheated me money.
You want me to look at
a piece of shit in front of you.
I didn't!
You did.
I didn't ask you to look at
a piece of shit in front of me.
But I just want
to frame you, so what?
- Okay!
- That's good.
You jerk!
I will kick your ass today.
Damn, it couldn't
be more righteous of me!
Fanny!
Are your tits okay?
How is King?
He is fine!
He planned everything already.
Let's go.
Is King really okay?
Can't you be quiet?
Hey man, where are you going?
Philippines.
Damn you! Go to Saikung.
What's wrong with Ronaldo today?
It must be the French girls,
they distracted Ronaldo.
Or maybe he just had
too much sex last night.
27 minutes passed,
but there is still no score at all.
Zidane's got it by a header...
France scored first.
There is another half to be played.
We got to go to work now!
Quickly, film extras get ready,
it's one to nothing.
France scored first?
Go change! Stupid!
Hey... aren't you the
famous commentator Lin Sheung-yee?
I am his older brother,
I am Lin Sheung-wai.
Stop eating and get to work.
Or I will take
$50 off your pay check.
Who do you think you are?
I'm your boss!
Hurry.
Get to work...
Skinny Dragon, hurry.
I am here.
Ready...
Action.
Well, the other commentator Chan's
just gone to the bathroom,
I, Lin Sheung-wai... No,
Lin Sheung-yee'll commentate alone.
Everyone just saw France score first
on a header by Zidane.
And they have taken
a one to nothing lead.
I think everyone is
surprised by this result.
Hope Brazil will play better...
in the second half.
Let us go to commercial break first.
Ericsson's brought you
the best game...
It's your time. Go...
There are lots of people
like to drink soy sauce.
Some people like it sweet,
salty, not too salty, and...
fatter, whiter...
Are you for real?
I will pick Beer soy sauce.
There is only one reason.
That is...
So exciting!
I mean Beer soy sauce!
Who do you think I am?
5, 4, 3, 2, 1, kick off.
Before the match,
everyone thinks Brazil should win.
But their performance in the
first half was very disappointing.
Brazil now change their plan...
Ronaldo and a French player crushed
into the French goal keeper.
Both men are down.
Oh no!
Brazil can get a penalty shoot.
Yes, the referee awards
Brazil a penalty shoot.
Let's see what really happened.
Ronaldo was pushed into the goalie.
Barthez held Ronaldo
down on the floor.
Will Ronaldo get up with this?
Brazil got a penalty,
and their fans are going wild.
Ronaldo is fine!
He is carefully
putting the ball in place.
He is going to take the shoot.
He shot, he scored!
We are tied at one goal piece.
Ronaldo is celebrating
with his teammates after the score...
What happened to Ronaldo's face?
You dropped a card.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Oh no! Skinny Dragon,
cover your head.
Ronaldo is happy, he is celebrating
with his jersey over his head.
Go back to live.
France got a corner kick
and Djorkaeff is going to take it.
What is wrong with
Brazil's goal keeper?
Zidane scored again with a header.
Zidane scored twice
and the France leads two nothing...
No, is two to one.
Looks like Brazil must try harder.
Skinny Dragon passed out.
No way?
Go to commercial.
One day on a beautiful island,
a high tech specialist Leung Jing...
is on his way to have dinner
with his mother-in-law.
He suddenly detected a strange storm.
The storm destroyed many countries.
No one was able to stop it.
The storm was about to reach
the island within thirty minutes.
But Jing seemed like he had
confidence to defeat this storm.
He ordered a warning on one hand.
On the other hand,
he is racing with the storm.
Jing was lucky to escape from death,
he decided to save the kids on the dam.
He risked his life
and rolled down the hill.
Jing finally had the whole
situation under controlled.
But someone was here
long before Jing's arrival.
Who is this secret Lemon?
The girl is very pretty.
Do you still want to play?
Play!
You haven't even put down a card.
Oh! I forgot.
No need! Four aces.
Pass.
- Do you have it?
- Pass.
Straight!
Quaduple again?
What?
France scored again.
Why didn't you wake me up earlier?
Come on, let's back to work.
I am your boss!
Brazil's Cafu is attacking
and is about to pass the ball...
Desailly was there in time
to kick the ball out of play.
Desailly seems to be hurt.
Bebeto is ready to take the corner.
Ready...
Action.
Ronaldo takes the pass
and he shoots...
Even Barthez can't save this one.
Ronaldo is awesome.
We are tied again.
The score is two to two.
The match is getting more exciting.
Without any doubt,
Ronaldo is this match's hero.
Look at him, he is celebrating
with his jersey over his head again.
You should be happy...
Brother Mon, are you okay?
I am fine.
You, bring us a glass of water.
No thanks.
Brother King,
it's only me and you now.
This is the last game.
I am still twenty cards ahead of you.
If you don't beat me
more than ten cards,
you can't beat me.
It's not bad
if I win the bet on the match.
Now is two to two,
you are still losing.
Unless it's three to two.
Sometimes when you think...
you are going to win,
you are going to lose.
Sometimes when you think
you are going to lose, you might win.
I can't see myself winning the game.
Of course! You are losing
more than one thousand cards.
You better pay up
or we will charge you with interest.
I think I can put on card down.
Oh no!
You don't mind
losing another game, do you?
I can afford it, so what?
This match is awesome, fantastic!
France is on the attack again.
Plan A.
Piette is in the
penalty zone and he shoots...
Oh no! He hit the pose.
It's useless holding your head Piette,
who told you to hit the pose.
If the shot went in then
your team is going to win.
If there is not more goals,
then we will have to go to overtime.
No overtime!
The real match is three to nothing.
We don't have any live scene,
you moron!
Really?
Diamond A.
Aces of spade.
Diamond two.
Why the rush?
Pass.
Who has the big two?
Better use it now.
The white head is very lucky today.
You can really hold it.
Pass.
What is going on? Four Js.
I am going to lose again.
Pass.
Straight!
Sorry! You lose triple.
Triple?
How come no one used
the big two? Who has it?
Brazil's Edmundo passes
the ball to Carlos.
Carlos passes the ball
back to Edmundo...
and he puts the ball
in the penalty zone,
Denilson gets the pass
and he shoots...
but it hits the pose.
But Ronaldo is there
and he puts the ball into the net.
Three to two, Brazil is leading now.
Yeah! They have a winning heart!
The score is three to two.
Not much time left,
looks like Brazil is going to win.
- The game is over!
- Bravo!
The game is over now.
Show the celebration tape
four years ago.
Brother Mon...
Brother Mon, are you okay?
Brother Mon.
Let's go to some commercials first.
Don't drink it! There are germs.
Of course! It's good for you!
The commercial nowadays
are very funny.
But you can't see it, dead man!
I already bet on
hundred million dollars on France.
Now this ship and
the casino are all mine.
Leave the money here,
and the check...
and yourself too!
You put poison in the water.
I didn't!
Although he beats me, but...
Don't move!
You killed my boss, I will kill you.
Macau Mon is dead, I am the boss now.
Brother Mon...
it's not my fault, it's him.
It's not your fault?
King save me.
How? How he did that?
Remember the last game?
How come no one used the big two?
Because I had it.
The water is poisoned.
Do you understand it now?
No... don't kill me!
Brother Mon, no.
Damn you! You betray me?
- Brother Mon, no...
- Dickhead!
- No... don't kill me!
- Traitor.
Who is looking for King?
I am Ching,
tell him I am waiting for him.
Is this King?
What...
You got the wrong number!
King!
Stop it... King...
King, get up.
King... get up! Are you okay?
Are you okay?
I am okay... lt's only an accident...
No, it's not!
They hit you on purpose.
Why can't they let you go?
- It's an accident...
- It's not!
- Believe me.
- No!
It's the truth!
Believe me... look who is the driver.
Skinny Dragon,
what is wrong with you?
Sorry, brother King, I thought
you were going to leave me here,
so I drove a little faster.
How are you?
You want some medicine?
Put some of this into the nose
and it can stop the bleeding.
You stupid!
It will work! Trust me.
Stupid! Who told you to come here?
I should have left long ago.
It is going to work.
King...
You bastard!
Are you guys going to kiss?
None of your business...
Stop it! Stop the bleeding first...
Upload From IDWS
By Jahust Jarzani