It's obviously a major malfunction.
...their President is a crook.
Well, I'm not a crook.
Robert Kennedy was shot
in that ballroom.
Thank God Almighty,
we are free at last!
A sniper has fired
at President Kennedy.
Or have you ever been
a member of the Communist party?
Hi-yo, Silver!
... 194 1...
...a date which will live in infamy.
We bring you the final edition of
our Maxwell House Good News of 1939.
Good evening, Mr. and Mrs. North
America, and all the ships at sea.
The only thing we have to fear
is fear itself.
CQ...
...this is W-9 GFO.
CQ, this is W-9 GFO here.
Come back?
CQ...
...this is W-9 GFO here.
Come back?
CQ, this is W-9 GFO.
Is anybody out there?
Not getting anything.
Small moves, Ellie.
Small moves.
CQ, this is W-9 GFO here.
Come back?
Copy, W-9 GFO.
K-4 WLD here.
What do I say?
Just be yourself.
Where are you, K-4 WLD?
Come back?
Pensacola.
Over.
Pensacola, where's Pensacola?
I'll give you a hint.
Orange juice.
Copy that, K-4 WLD. How's the
weather down there in Florida?
Pensacola, Florida.
I have to tell you, Sparks.
1,116 miles.
Pretty good.
That's the farthest yet.
Can we hear all the way to New York?
Sure.
Can we hear all the way
to California?
I don't see why not.
Can we hear all the way to Alaska?
On a really clear day.
Can we hear all the way to China?
On a really, really clear day.
Could we talk to the moon?
If it's a big enough radio,
I don't see why not.
Could we talk to Jupiter?
Or what's the one after that?
Don't tell me.
I'll give you a hint.
Hula-Hoops.
Saturn!
Could we talk to Saturn?
Dad, could we talk to Mom?
I don't think even the biggest radio
could reach that far.
All right, no more stalling.
Pensacola!
That's a beauty.
Now get some sleep.
Hey, Dad?
Do you think there's people
on other planets?
I don't know, Sparks.
But I guess I'd say...
...if it is just us...
...it seems like
an awful waste of space.
CQ, this is W-9 GFO.
Repeat. This is W-9 GFO.
Come back?
I'm going to need a bigger antenna.
What do you think, Doc Arroway?
Isn't she a beauty?
It'll do.
The village is five miles away.
There's a general store
in the cantina.
They can order anything
from San Juan.
When can I get dish time?
Dr. Clark said you couldn't wait.
Your first shift is tonight.
Go back.
Try back a little bit.
You had something there.
There!
-Right there?
-You hear it? Right there, that's it.
All right, 1221 .46.
That's well within the L-band.
Check off-axis.
On it.
It's not in the neighborhood.
Here it is.
J-1741 ...
... + 2748.
Catalogued November 4, 1982.
Pulsar.
Must've been the glitch
in the timing that threw me.
Must've been a starquake.
I think it's great that you listen.
Most don't do that anymore.
It's just an old habit.
It makes it feel more real.
Ellie.
Kent Clark.
They said you'd been...
...up at Owen's Valley
working under Drumlin.
How'd you like him?
That much? About what I'd expect
after what he had to say about you.
And what was that?
That you are brilliant...
...driven...
...a major pain in the ass...
...and obsessed with a field
of study he considers tantamount...
...to professional suicide.
Anything else?
Those were the highlights.
David, Dr. Vernon.
Dr. Arroway.
Believe you've already met our tireless
research assistant, Mr. Fisher...
...as well as his cologne.
Brook's looking at the black hole
in M-87.
Ellie's studying Markarian 541,
a major gamma ray source.
Dr. Arroway will be spending her
precious telescope time listening for...
...listening for...
Little green men.
One down...
...a couple billion to go.
Arecibo, right?
Does it show?
Cracker Jack?
No, thanks.
Mind if I sit down?
I hear the locals,
they call it "El Radar."
Convinced it has some
dark military purpose.
I think we're harmless.
Palmer Joss.
-Ellie Arroway.
-Nice to meet you, Ellie.
What are you studying up there?
The usual.
Nebulae, quasars, pulsars,
stuff like that.
What are you writing?
The usual.
Nouns, adverbs...
...adjective here and there.
I work on a project, SETI.
Search for
Extraterrestrial Intelligence?
That is out there!
Are you a student or something?
I'm a writer.
I'm writing a book.
I'm here doing research...
...about how technology affects
Third World cultures.
I'm also looking for this guy,
David Drumlin.
He's head of the National Science
Foundation. I want an interview.
I take it you know him?
You could say that.
SETI.
That's fringe!
I've crossed paths with him. Something
like that must really chap his ass.
Compass.
That's for you.
You better keep this.
Might save your life someday.
Have dinner with me tonight?
I don't make a good
research subject. I'm not quotable.
No quotes.
Scout's honor.
Good meal, good company.
I've got to go.
Drumlin's coming in Tuesday.
Now I remember
why I took that desk job.
Dr. Drumlin, how are you?
Glad you could make it.
If I'd known it took 3 planes,
I might've reconsidered.
How is that new office?
Still settling in. They already want to
give half my budget to the Pentagon.
Still waiting for E.T. to call?
Good to see you too!
Asshole!
Looks like it's
going to be a long night.
Science must be accountable to the
people paying for it, the taxpayers.
We must stop wasting money
on pie-in-the-sky abstractions...
...and spend it on practical,
measurable ways...
...to improve the lives
of the people who are paying.
Not unlike my L-band,
globular clusters work.
You want to do away
with all pure research now?
What's wrong with science
being practical? Even profitable?
Nothing, as long as your motive...
...is the search for truth. Which is
what the pursuit of science is.
That's an interesting position
from a man...
...on a crusade against
the evils of technology...
...Father Joss.
I'm not against technology, Doctor.
I'm against...
...the men who deify it
at the expense of human truth.
Kent, I need to have
a word with you. Over here, please.
You think that hurt my chances
with that interview?
You're a priest?
Not really.
I got my Masters in Divinity...
...then left the seminary to do
secular humanitarian work...
...coordinating
Third World churches.
I couldn't live
with the celibacy thing.
You could call me
a man of the cloth...
...without the cloth.
You want to get out of here?
You see that large W-shaped
constellation there? That's Cassiopeia.
And Cassiopeia A gives off
a whole lot of radio signals.
I listen to them a lot.
It's a remnant of a supernova.
When did you know
you wanted to be an astronomer?
When I was about eight years old...
...watching the sunset...
...I asked Dad, "What's that bright
star over there?"
He said that it wasn't a star.
It was...
...a whole planet called Venus...
...which should be over there soon.
He said,
"You know why they called it Venus?
Because they thought
it was so beautiful and glowing.
But they didn't know...
...that it's filled with...
...deadly gases
and sulfuric acid rain."
Wow, I thought,
"This is it! I'm hooked!"
There are four hundred billion
stars out there...
...just in our galaxy alone.
If only one out of a million
of those had planets...
...if just one out of a million
of those had life...
...and if just one out of a million
of those had intelligent life...
...there would be literally millions
of civilizations out there.
If there wasn't...
...it'd be an awful waste of space.
Amen.
So I was lying there,
just looking at the sky.
And then I felt something.
I don't know.
All I know is that I wasn't alone.
For the first time in my life
I wasn't scared of nothing...
...not even dying.
It was God.
And there's no chance that...
...you had this experience because
some part of you needed to have it?
I'm a reasonably intelligent guy,
but this...
My intellect
couldn't even touch this.
No.
I've been to Sunday school
a few times.
And?
I kept asking all these
really annoying questions like...
..."Where did Mrs. Cain come from?"
And pretty soon they asked my dad...
...if he wouldn't mind
keeping me home from now on.
Your dad...
Is it this guy?
Yeah.
You're close to him, aren't you?
I was. He died
when I was nine years old.
I never got to know my mother.
I'm sorry.
That's got to be tough.
Being alone.
What do you say...
...we pack a picnic tomorrow
and hike up to Mount Arecibo?
I don't think I can.
I've got to work.
How about dinner tomorrow night?
I know a great dive.
No, I don't think so.
Ellie, did I miss something?
No.
Shit, I'm late!
I told Kent
that I'd be there at 10:30.
I'm not trying to push you.
I've wanted to look at
this sector for weeks.
Just hang out...
...and sleep in.
There's food in the fridge.
How can I reach you?
Just leave your number.
I'll call you.
Dad!
It's starting,
you're going to miss it!
Dad, there's another one!
Hurry up!
In a minute, Sparks!
I'm almost done.
There's another one.
Come on, hurry up, Dad!
I'll get the medicine.
I know it's hard
to understand this now...
...but we aren't always meant to know
why things happen the way they do.
Sometimes,
we just have to accept it...
...as God's will.
I should have kept medicine
in the downstairs bathroom.
Then I could've gotten to it sooner.
CQ...
...this is W-9 GFO.
Do you copy?
Dad, this is Ellie.
Come back.
This is Eleanor Arroway...
...transmitting on 14.2 megahertz.
Are you there?
Come back.
Dad, this is Ellie.
Hi, Kent.
What are you doing up so early?
I was thinking...
...we'd make a pretty good team.
We could put together
an ad hoc SETI program.
You know the Very Large Array
in New Mexico?
It's a dynamite place
to do SETI work...
What are you talking about?
Drumlin pulled the plug.
We're homeless.
It's true, you pulled the plug?
You can't see it now,
but I'm doing you a favor.
You're too promising a scientist to
waste your gifts on this nonsense.
I don't consider what could be...
...the most important
human discovery nonsense!
400 billion stars...
And two probabilities.
One, there's intelligent life...
...but too far away
to contact in your lifetime.
-And two!
-You're making a decision...
There's nothing but gases
and carbon compounds...
...and you're wasting your time!
In the meantime,
you won't be taken seriously.
Your career will be over!
So what?
It's my life!
Hey, Kent.
You were right.
Screw Drumlin. We'll raise the money
ourselves. We'll go to New Mexico.
Chicago's set.
Let me know how it goes.
I've got more corporate stops
on the East Coast for you.
Did that investor from Houston
ever get back to us?
I'll hit him up on my way to L.A.
Beg for some of that
Hollywood money!
They've been making
money off aliens for years.
-Begging is good for the soul.
-We'll see.
Just do me a favor.
Try not to be too...confrontational.
Confrontational? Me?
What do you mean?
I'll see if I left anything.
It's a unique time in our history,
in the history of any civilization.
It's the moment
of the acquisition of technology.
That's the moment
where contact becomes possible.
The Very Large Array
in New Mexico...
...is the key to our chances
for success.
With its 27
linked radio telescopes...
...we can search more accurately
than at any other facility.
We've gotten approval to buy the
telescope time from the government.
Now all we really need is the money.
A nice presentation, Doctor.
But while our foundation arm
has a mandate to support...
...experimental programs,
your proposal...
...seems less like science,
and more like science fiction.
Science fiction.
You're right.
It's crazy.
In fact, it's even worse
than that: nuts!
Want to hear something nutty?
Two guys wanted to build
a thing called an airplane.
People go in it and fly like birds.
Ridiculous, right?
What about breaking
the sound barrier...
...or rockets to the moon, or atomic
energy or a mission to Mars?
Science fiction, right?
All I'm asking is for you to
just have the tiniest bit of vision.
To step back
and look at the big picture.
Take a chance on something which could
end up the most impactful moment...
...for humanity, for the history...
...of history.
I'm sorry.
I just spent 13 months...
...coming into rooms
and talking to people like you.
You're my last chance.
Sorry I wasted your time.
Doctor.
Yes, sir.
You have your money.
Thank you.
Perfect cast!
Come on, fishy!
Frank, look at the size...
...of that son of a bitch!
Welcome back, Dr. C.
How'd it go?
How was the trip?
I've had better.
Drumlin!
Is this a personal vendetta now?
There's been enormous pressure
from other scientists as well.
It doesn't matter. Hadden's funding
us for 2 more years.
The government doesn't want their
telescopes used by the high priestess...
...of the desert anymore.
What?
Staring at TV static for hours,
listening to washing machines.
These stories get out!
I was seeking patterns in the chaos!
It doesn't matter,
we're a joke to them.
They want us out!
We've got 3 months
till the paperwork goes through.
I'll start looking for
other funding.
Could you face reality?
Just this once? We lost.
It's over.
Fine.
I'm not stopping.
If I have to, I'll go it alone.
I've done it before.
My guest tonight is author
and theologian Palmer Joss.
He's become a spiritual counselor...
...and a recent fixture
at the White House.
"God's Diplomat, "
according to The New York Times.
His latest book, "Losing Faith, "
is currently number one...
...on that publication's
bestseller list.
Thanks for being here.
You've had quite a ride...
...the last few years.
Yeah, I sure have, Larry.
Fish, I was thinking.
Who would make the best astronomers?
Think about it.
Who has the perfect synthesis
of career and lifestyle?
I give.
Vampires!
Are you anti-technology
and anti-science?
No, not at all.
The question that
I'm asking is this:
Are we happier...
...as a human race? Is the world
fundamentally a better place...
...because of science
and technology?
We shop at home,
we surf the Web...
...but at the same time
we feel emptier...
...and more
cut off from each other...
...than at any other time
in human history.
We're becoming
a synthesized society...
...in a hurry to get to the...
We're looking for the meaning.
What is the meaning?
We have mindless jobs,
take frantic vacations.
Deficit finance trips
to the mall to buy things...
...that we think will fill
these holes in our lives.
Any wonder we've lost
our sense of direction?
Holy shit!
Right ascension...
...18 hours, 36 minutes,
56.2 seconds!
Declination...
... + 36 degrees, 46 minutes...
...56.2 seconds!
Confirm!
Right ascension,
18 hours, 36 minutes...
...56.2 seconds!
Is anybody awake in there?
I'm moving the array!
Confirm!
Boss has a bogey!
Right ascension, 18 hours...
We're on it!
36 hours...
...47 minutes and 1 second!
Strong possible...
...pulse chain on sub-array four!
I'm moving the rest.
Confirm coordinates!
Check the status of the array.
She's doing all the dishes.
Systems nominal.
Hello.
Full systems check!
Coordinates confirmed.
Willie's checking the system.
Stay on top of
the systems diagnostics!
Check reference point offsets.
And I want you off-axis
on 27 the second we get there!
And tell Willie
to break out the big boy!
Copy that.
Yeah! Go, Ellie!
I hear it on the headphones.
We got to be sure about this.
Give me another array status.
Her four are online,
the rest are tracking in.
But there's a bad drive on 16.
The four are online,
the rest are tracking in.
There's a bad drive on 16.
Copy that?
What shall I do
about the source queue?
Forget it and hold the queue.
Get ready to set the target frequency
to manual the second we're aligned.
Do you copy? I want you to go
off-axis on 27 the second we're there!
And leave the LO frequency
where it is!
Don't let it get away!
If you lose it, scan the band!
Run every frequency
you can think of.
How you doing?
Talk to me, guys.
Partially polarized moving pulses,
amplitude modulated.
We're locked. Systems are fine.
What's the frequency?
4.46...
...23 gigahertz.
Hydrogen times pi.
Told you!
Strong sucker too!
I got it!
I'm patched in!
Let me hear.
Listen to that.
Make me a liar, Fish.
It could be AWACS
out of Kirkland jamming us.
But I doubt it.
See if F.U.D.D.'s reading it too.
Patch it back
and give me the off-axis.
-We recording?
-Never stopped.
Thank you, Elmer!
AWACS status is negative.
White Sands?
On this frequency? No.
I'll punch up the darks.
How's spying tonight?
Come on!
NORAD's not tracking
any snoops in this vector.
Shuttle's in sleep mode.
Okay, point source confirmed.
Whatever it is, it ain't local.
Position?
I checked interferometry.
Somewhere in Lyra.
-Vega?
-Can't be!
It's only 26 light years away.
-Peak intensity?
-Coming up!
Vega.
Vega. I scanned it a bunch of times
at Arecibo. It was always negative.
Got it!
Reading over 100 janskys.
Jesus! I can pick it up on my...
No!
Come on!
It's restarting.
Wait a minute.
Those are numbers.
That was 3, before it was 2.
Base 10 numbers.
Count and see how far we get.
One.
Seven.
Those are primes.
2, 3, 5, 7 are all prime numbers.
No way that's a natural phenomenon!
Let's just calm down
and pull up the star file on Vega.
It doesn't make any sense.
The system is too young.
It can't have a planetary system...
...let alone life
or a technological civilization.
Maybe they're not from there,
they're visiting.
Spacecraft? This system's full
of debris. It'd get clobbered.
Not if they used their
laser blasters and photon torpedoes.
-That's not funny.
-How else can we explain it!
He's right. If we go public
with this and we're wrong...
...it's over. We're cooked.
I wish Kent was here.
Whatever it is, let's do something.
Vega will set.
Position confirmed. We've got 4.4623
gigahertz, confirmed.
We've got 112 janskys.
Do you have a source location yet?
We put it right smack in the middle.
Vega.
Thanks. Keep tracking
and we'll get back to you.
Right-o.
101 . The pulse sequenced...
...through every prime number
between 2 and 101 .
Who do we call now?
Everybody.
The rumors are flying,
the implications extraordinary.
Detection of an unidentified...
...radio source from space
can neither be confirmed nor denied.
But the military arriving...
Sources close to the VLA
report they have been contacted...
...by some form
of intelligent being...
...living outside our solar system.
Again, there is no confirmation.
I want all of these people
out of here.
Where's the girl?
22 stations worldwide...
...now confirm the signal.
Vega's now below our horizon.
You're hearing the signal
from the Russian...
Get decryption people here.
Lunacharsky's visiting at Cal Tech.
Explain this to me.
If the source of the signal is so
sophisticated...why the remedial math?
Why not just speak English?
Maybe because 70%%% of the planet
speaks other languages.
Mathematics is the
only truly universal language.
It's no coincidence
that they're using primes.
I don't get it.
Prime numbers.
Integers only divisible
by themselves and 1 .
We think this may be a beacon,
an announcement...
...to get our attention.
If it's attention you want,
you got that. One thing: Vega.
People have looked at Vega
for years, with no results.
Yesterday they start
broadcasting primes. Why?
It's hardly yesterday.
The signal's been transmitting
for 26 years.
Excuse me, who are you?
Michael Kitz,
National Security Advisor.
Your reputation...
First, ask the gentlemen
with the guns to wait outside.
This is a civilian facility.
With all due respect...
Excuse me.
Hi! I'm so glad you're back!
Come hear this.
Is this great?
-Who are all these people?
-I have no idea.
Sit down. We need help
with the spectrum analysis.
-I'll get on it.
-Headsets.
I'll just come right to the point.
Announcing this all over the world may
well be a breach of national security.
It's not a person-to-person call.
You think a civilization sending this
message intends it just for Americans?
You might have consulted us.
-The contents could be very sensitive.
-You want to classify prime numbers?
Due to earth's rotation, we're
in line with Vega only hours a day.
The only way to monitor the signal
is to cooperate with other stations.
If Dr. Arroway hadn't acted quickly,
we'd have lost key elements.
Fine, they've got the primes.
But if a more significant
transmission is to come...
We need help to receive and decode.
You understand
that my job is to protect...
-Listen.
-I hear it.
Hear what?
Harmonic.
Bingo! I had Willie ask Rattan
to retune to 8.9247 gigahertz.
There's a lot more here.
-Get on the negative sideband.
-I'm already on it.
What is it?
Another signal!
A second signal at double
the frequency. Looks like...
Get a TV monitor!
Patch it into the image processor.
Want the new data?
Yeah, the new one we just recorded.
David, explain this to me, please.
There's another signal.
Looks like a TV transmission.
We're hot.
Go get the blinds.
There is a lot of glare.
You're patched in.
It's definitely an image.
Let's try and stabilize it.
What do you make of that?
It's two different
interlaced frames. I'm framing one.
-lt's just noise.
-Trying frame two.
I've got an offset carrier.
I think it's audio.
Plug it in!
Center that segment.
Centering.
Can you clean it up?
I'm working on it.
What the hell...?
Try zooming out.
Freeze!
Reverse values.
Try zooming out again.
Rotate 90 degrees counterclock...
My God!
What's going on?
You're not going to believe this.
Does anybody speak German?
"I declare the Games in Berlin...
...at the celebration...
...of the first Olympics
of the New Era...
...as opened."
Get me the White House.
20 million people died
defeating the bastard...
...and he's our first ambassador
to outer space?
The broadcast of the '36 Olympics
was the first TV transmission...
...that went into space.
Sending it back is a way of saying,
"Hello, we heard you."
Or, "Sieg Heil,
you're our kind of people."
Hitler's politics
have nothing to do with this.
It's unlikely they understood it.
People must understand...
The people are
in very good hands, Doctor.
We'll take it from here.
Smile, folks. We're on.
A message of unknown origin
from deep space...
... was received by American
scientists. Now to the White House.
We're told the President
will have only a few remarks...
...about today's
extraordinary events...
...and that he won't be taking
any questions from the press.
Good afternoon.
I'm glad to be joined by my...
...Science and Technology Advisor.
This is the product
of years of exploration...
...by some of the world's
most distinguished scientists.
Like all discoveries...
...this one will continue
to be reviewed...
...examined...
...and scrutinized.
It must be confirmed
by other scientists.
But clearly...
...the fact that this is being
explored is a vindication...
Fish, what is the story over here?
I thought Ellie was supposed to be on.
I don't know.
Guys?
Those interlaced frames
we thought were noise?
This has structure.
I'm hearing structure.
If this discovery is confirmed...
...it will be one of the most stunning
insights into our universe...
...that science has ever uncovered.
Its implications
are as far-reaching...
...and awe-inspiring
as can be imagined.
Even as it promises answers
to some of our oldest questions...
...it poses still others...
...even more fundamental.
We will continue
to listen closely...
...to what it has to say...
...as we continue
the search for answers...
...and for knowledge...
...that is as old
as humanity itself...
...but essential
to our people's future.
Thank you.
Is there a renewed assessment
of security threat?
I'll answer your questions
after a few corrections.
The message was received Friday...
...at 6:31 a.m.
Mountain Standard Time.
It was largely mathematical...
...and in spite of reports
to the contrary...
...appears to be
completely benign in nature.
Let me say that again.
The message is completely benign.
The President has contacted
the world's heads of state...
...and every security measure
is being taken.
To better explain the events
of the last 48 hours...
...is the leader of the scientific team
that made this remarkable discovery...
...Dr. David Drumlin, special
Science Advisor to the President.
Thank you, Rachel.
Hello.
In 1936,
a very faint television signal...
...transmitted the opening ceremonies
of the Olympic Games as a show...
...of German superior technology.
That signal left Earth at the speed
of light and 26 years later...
...arrived in the vicinity
of the star we call Vega.
That signal has been sent back to us
hugely amplified...
...an unmistakable
sign of intelligence.
Kent, go ahead.
The Adolf transmission used 25 frames
per second but we're receiving 50.
So we put the other 25
through search algorithms.
We found a series of markers
on the top of each frame.
-Are you ready?
-Yeah, go ahead!
Send it, Willie.
Here it comes.
It's digital...
...massive amounts of data which
extend right to the higher harmonics.
Jackpot!
All right, as you'll see...
...interlaced with the frames
of the original Hitler image...
...we found these sections.
We thought they were noise,
but they're actually data...
...huge amounts of it.
When we combine this with the data
from the original signal...
...we get
these encrypted pages of text.
No two are alike and
we've uncovered over 10,000 already.
What does it mean, Doctor?
We have no idea.
It could be anything.
Volume 1 of an
Encyclopedia Galactica.
Instructions for us
on their colonization procedures.
Moses with a few billion
new commandments.
How long will it take to decode it?
It could take forever.
We really need a primer...
We need to get
the best decryption people we have.
I intend to use the VLA
as my command post.
In the meantime, my office
has made out a preliminary budget.
Wait a minute.
This is a privately-funded
operation.
We lease dish time
from the government...
This is a clear-cut case of eminent
domain.
I'm recommending to the President
we militarize this project.
What?! This is my project!
Nobody knows more about this
than I do. David, tell them...
Excuse me!
Could we calm down here?
I'm going to recommend that...
...Dr. Drumlin coordinate
the decryption effort.
But in light of Dr. Arroway's
long experience in these matters...
...for the time being, she will
direct operations at the VLA...
...understanding that future discoveries
will be kept in strict confidence...
...until such time
as the President...
...can decide the most suitable
course of action. Understood?
Yes.
This is CNN Breaking News.
The President
called the message from Vega...
... "a stunning insight
into our universe..."
...as police clashed
with neo-Nazi protesters.
So, there's life on other planets.
Boy, this will really change
the Miss Universe contest.
Health officials worldwide are concerned
that the message from Vega...
...might trigger
a rash of mass suicides...
...not unlike recent cult deaths
near San Diego...
Even a scientist must admit...
...there are some pretty serious
religious overtones to all this.
Here's someone whose organization...
...is accused of conducting
its own inquisition:
Richard Rank,
head of the Conservative Coalition.
Thank you.
This is yet another example of science
intruding into matters of faith.
This means they
have been reacting to TV signals...
...from the 1930s.
They're just getting them.
Imagine how disappointed
they'll be if they're Cubs fans.
We now go to Jeremy Roth,
who is reporting...
...from the Very Large Array
near Socorro, New Mexico.
Like a bolt from the blue it came.
"The Message from Vega"
has caused...
...thousands of believers
and non-believers...
...to descend upon the VLA facility
here in the desert of New Mexico.
Many have come to protest,
many to pray...
...but most have come to participate in
what's become the best show in town.
Well, I saw the thing
coming out of the sky
It had one long horn
and one big eye.
I commenced to shaking
and said, "Oo-ee!"
"Looks like
a Purple People Eater to me"
Hail to Vega
But they have failed!
It's the same people who,
again and again...
...have brought us
to the brink of destruction!
Who've polluted our air,
who've poisoned our water!
Now these scientists...
...have had their chance.
Are these the kind of people...
...that you want
talking to your God for you?
Efforts continue around the clock.
But for now, almost 2 full weeks
after the message's arrival...
...scientists here at the VLA
still have no answers...
...only more questions.
Jeremy Roth, CNN,
Socorro, New Mexico.
More on the quest for the message's
meaning, after this.
They have to line up somehow.
This one doesn't fit, either.
We've tried over
a million permutations.
Always, I can only get
three corners to fit.
I don't understand
their significance.
Somebody broke in...
Hello?
Whoever you are,
you broke into the database...
What? Now?
Where?
I'll be there.
You should feel fortunate.
He hardly lands for anyone.
Dr. Arroway.
I presume?
Mr. Hadden.
I've had my eye on you
a long time, Doctor.
I consider you one of my
most valuable long-term investments.
And when it comes
to my investments...
...I always do my homework.
Eleanor Ann Arroway...
...born 25th August, 1964...
...De Pere, Wisconsin.
Mother, Joanna, died from
complications during childbirth.
Early testing indicated
high predisposition...
...towards science and mathematics.
Father, Theodore...
...advised to provide enrichment
activities in these areas...
...did so conscientiously
until his death...
...from myocardial infarction,
November 10, 1974.
You graduated from high school
in 1979...
...almost two full years early.
Awarded full scholarship, M.I.T...
...graduated magna cum laude.
Doctoral work, Cal Tech...
...where you worked
on the lanthanide-doped ruby maser...
...dramatically increasing
the sensitivity of radio telescopes.
Subsequently offered a teaching
position at Harvard University...
...which you turned down
to pursue SETI work...
...at the Arecibo Observatory
in Puerto Rico.
Changes in N.S.F. policy...
...gave rise to certain
funding problems...
...at which point...
...you came to my attention.
You compromised our security codes.
Once upon a time...
...I was a hell of an engineer.
Please, sit, Doctor.
I have guests so rarely...
...it's important
they feel welcome in my home.
You live here?
I find it convenient
to keep my interests...
...mobile.
Anyway, I've had my fill
of life on the ground.
I guess I should...
I guess I should thank you for
having bailed me out all that time.
I know a good bet when I see one.
Earl Grey.
No sugar, no milk, I believe.
What am I doing here?
The powers that be
have been very busy lately...
...positioning themselves...
...for the game of the millennium.
Maybe I can help deal you back in.
I didn't realize that I was out.
No. Maybe not out...
...but certainly
being handed your hat.
I've had a long time
to make enemies, Doctor.
There are many governments...
...business interests...
...even religious leaders that would
like to see me depart this earth.
And I'll grant them their wish
soon enough.
But before I do,
I wish to make a small contribution.
A final gesture of goodwill to the
people of this planet who have given...
...from whom I have taken so much.
You found the primer.
Clever girl!
Lights.
Pages and pages of data.
Over 63,000 in all.
And on the perimeter of each...
Alignment symbols, registration
marks, but they don't line up.
They do...
...if you think like a Vegan.
An alien intelligence
has got be more advanced...
...and that means efficiency
functioning on multiple levels...
...and in multiple...
...dimensions.
Yes, of course!
Where's the primer?
You'll see.
Every three-dimensional page
contains a piece of the primer.
There it was all the time,
staring you in the face.
Buried within the message itself
is the key to decoding it.
Within the layering of the matrix,
we have these basic equations:
So with this very elementary foundation,
they have given us a kind of...
...general scientific vocabulary.
We now have the symbols
for true and false...
This was the key...
...that allowed us to decipher
their language...
...for physics, geometry, chemistry.
Next frame, Ellie.
Yes, and when we apply this
to the rest of the message...
...we find this.
Those look like engineering
schematics, almost like blueprints.
Yes.
It is our belief that
the message contains instructions...
...for building something,
some kind of machine.
A machine?
That does what, Doctor?
We don't know.
It might be some type...
...of advanced communication device,
or a teaching machine of some kind.
Or it might be...
...some kind of a transport.
-Transport?
-There's no proof of that.
The fact is you don't know
what it does. It could be anything.
A Trojan Horse. We build it
and out pours the entire Vegan army.
Why risk the personnel?
It could be a weapon.
Right.
Some kind of a Doomsday Machine.
Every time they detect
a new civilization...
...they fax
construction plans from space.
We poor saps build this thing
and blow ourselves to kingdom come.
There's no reason to believe
their intentions are hostile.
Why is it the egghead position
that aliens are always benign?
We pose no threat to them.
It'd be like us
going out of our way...
...to destroy microbes
on an anthill.
Interesting analogy.
How guilty would we feel...
...if we destroyed a few microbes
on an anthill?
I hope you're right.
I really do.
But my job is to protect American
lives from any threat...
...so I am obligated
to assume the worst.
Yes, and I am forced
to agree with you.
My problem is this:
The content of that message
is morally ambiguous at best.
Our internal numbers show
support for this is incredibly soft.
If the President
stays this course...
...his numbers will be going
south like ducks in winter.
This is nuts!
Excuse me...
...Miss.
We know nothing
of these creatures' values.
We don't even know
whether they believe in God.
This doesn't make any sense. If...
Excuse me, Dr. Arroway.
We won't be suppressing
any opinions here today.
No, of course not.
I understand.
What I meant to say...
...is the message was written
in the language of science.
If it was religious in nature,
it should have taken the form...
...of a burning bush
or a voice from the sky.
But a voice from the sky...
...is exactly what you found,
Doctor Arroway.
I'm sorry I'm late, ma'am.
I agree with Mr. Rank
that there are unavoidable...
...religious implications at stake.
But that doesn't justify
being an alarmist.
I hope that we can find
a common ground...
...break through obstacles
that may have kept us apart.
Listen, I need to make
one thing very clear.
Our organization will not be placated
with flowery New Age rhetoric...
Mr. President!
The President
met with top advisors...
...regarding the latest efforts
to decode the message.
While there has been some progress,
the official line remains cautious.
If you're asking
when we'll find out...
... what the purpose
of that Machine is...
...maybe tomorrow,
maybe next year, maybe never.
There he is. The man with his finger
on the nation's spiritual pulse.
It's so good to see you.
You too.
Your discovery, all of this.
It must be a real vindication.
I'm really happy for you.
Are you?
Mr. Joss, the President's waiting.
The President's waiting.
See you at the reception?
Yeah, I wouldn't miss it.
Miss Constantine,
may I speak to you?
Certainly.
I have a big problem.
Do you know where I can find
a really great dress?
God created man in the form of
Himself, not in the form of monkeys!
Get a job!
Don't waste my tax dollars!
You look beautiful, Ellie.
-So do you.
-You really do.
I read your book.
Here we go.
You want me to quote you?
"Ironically...
...the thing people are
most hungry for...
...meaning...
...is the one thing science
hasn't been able to give them."
Yeah.
It's like you're saying that...
...science killed God.
What if science simply revealed...
...that He never existed
in the first place?
I think we need to get some air.
And a few more of these.
Thank you.
A little chilly out here.
Yeah, this is nice.
I got one for you.
Occam's Razor. Ever heard of it?
Hoccam's Razor.
Sounds like some slasher movie.
No, Occam's Razor is a basic
scientific principle which says:
Things being equal, the simplest
explanation tends to be right.
Makes sense to me.
So what's more likely?
Thank you.
An all-powerful God
created the universe...
...then decided not to give
any proof of His existence?
Or...
...that He doesn't exist at all
and that we created Him...
...so we wouldn't feel
so small and alone.
I don't know.
I couldn't imagine living in a world
where God didn't exist.
I wouldn't want to.
How do you know
you're not deluding yourself?
I mean, for me...
...l'd need proof.
Proof?
Did you love your father?
Your dad, did you love him?
Yes. Very much.
Prove it.
Kent.
The White House.
No excuses. Whoever's responsible,
I want their head on a platter.
What happened?
You were right all along.
The team at the VLA
has worked around the clock...
...and the hard work
has finally paid off.
This key section uncovered tonight,
and obtained exclusively by CNN...
...shows an illustration
of a human figure...
...inside a geometric structure
of some kind.
This and other contextual clues...
...now lead scientists to believe
the message is, in fact...
President called
an emergency meeting.
I imagined he would.
...designed to take a single human
occupant into space...
...presumably to the star Vega.
Tell me.
They will build it.
Who goes?
The President's gone international
to spread the risk and cost...
Who goes?
Well, it's complicated.
They have formed
a group of international candidates.
Now, it's your discovery.
They understand that. You're
at the top of a very short list.
But they're also forming
a selection committee.
It's made of scholars, theologians,
scientists, philosophers...
You're on it.
I've been asked, yes.
I guess that means...
...that you're a selector,
I'm a selectee and we can't...
Yeah.
What you don't understand,
Ellie, is...
I understand.
I want you to know, whatever
happens, as far as I'm concerned...
Good luck.
Whatever you do, make sure
he doesn't monopolize the committee.
He is not on the committee, Ellie.
He just resigned.
He wants to be the one to go.
The President is already feeling
the financial pinch.
Sources say the cost of the project
is spiraling...
...to more than a third
of a trillion dollars...
...making this perhaps
the most expensive single project...
...in all of human history.
Months of debate finally reached...
...a conclusion last week as 10
candidates were selected by the I.M.C...
...representing a cross section
of political and religious views.
Many are the same experts
who have consulted...
...on the Machine's design
and function.
They will actively participate on-site,
during the construction process.
The choice of these 10 candidates
has been controversial.
One-third of the candidates
are American.
And many
international observers ask why.
The U.S. is shouldering
a large part of the cost...
Isn't it true that contractors,
like Hadden Industries...
...are making contributions
in exchange for technology rights?
Different nations are being
compensated in different ways.
Japan made headlines by opting
to forego candidate representation...
...in exchange for the
systems integration subcontract.
On what basis do you choose...
...a human being
to represent humanity?
Good question, Larry.
If nothing else...
...it should be somebody fluent in the
language the message was given in.
Science, in this case.
Despite your obvious enthusiasm...
...there's been
a lot of criticism...
...that this endeavor
is simply too dangerous.
Some of that criticism
from scientists.
One Nobel Prize winner noted,
his words:
"There is every indication...
...that this is beyond our capabilities,
that this endeavor will fail...
...and that the Machine's occupant
will pay for it with his life. "
How do you respond?
This message is from a civilization
that may be anywhere...
...from hundreds to millions
and millions of years ahead of us.
I have to believe that
an intelligence that advanced...
...knows what they're doing.
Now all it requires
on our part is...
Faith?
I was going to say,
a sense of adventure.
And in breaking news...
...astronaut John Russell...
...considered to be the leading American
candidate for the Machine seat...
...has dropped out of the running.
Russell met with reporters today
at his Houston home.
I told my dad I didn't want him...
...to go.
Daddy, don't go.
Nothing would give me more pride...
...than to...
...represent my country.
But what can I say to this?
Consortium officials had no comment,
but inside sources...
...have disclosed
that Dr. Arroway...
...appears to now be the
front-runner for the Machine seat.
"Meet me at noon.
Must talk."
I didn't expect a message
like this from you.
Thanks for coming.
Is this kosher?
Fraternizing with the enemy?
Selectors and selectees
mingling around?
Can we talk about Einstein?
Yeah, sure.
Special relativity.
This Machine...
...if it works, and you travel
to Vega at the speed of light...
-...when you come back...
-lf you come back.
If you come back...
...you'll be 4 years older, but over 50
years will have passed here on Earth.
Basically.
And everybody that you care about...
...will be gone, dead and buried.
If you came back,
if you survived at all...
Look, Palmer, nobody's saying
this isn't dangerous.
The rest of the candidates and myself
understand the risks we're taking.
Why?
It's a historic opportunity.
The world needs...
You, Ellie. You!
You personally.
By doing this,
you're willing to give your life.
You're willing to die for it.
Why?
From as long as I can remember,
I've been searching for...
...something...
...some reason why we're here.
What are we doing here? Who are we?
If this is a chance to find out
even a part of that answer...
I don't know,
I think it's worth a human life.
Don't you?
You're an incredibly brave woman,
Ellie.
Or incredibly nuts.
I'm really confused.
So am I.
I think I speak for us all
when I thank you for your patience.
Myself, I have one
final question, Dr. Arroway.
If you should meet these Vegans...
...and were permitted only
one question to ask of them...
...what would it be?
I suppose it would be:
"How did you do it?
How did you evolve? How did you
survive technological adolescence...
...without destroying yourself?"
That more than any other question is
one I personally would like answered.
Not too bad, Mike.
I join Dr. Bergeron...
...in expressing thanks for
your patience, Dr. Arroway.
We're all impressed
with your candor...
...and your stamina.
I think we're ready to move on
to your final statement.
I have one more question.
Yes, Mr. Joss.
Would you consider yourself...
...a spiritual person?
I don't understand
the point of the question.
I consider myself a moral person.
We're sure that's the case, but what
Mr. Joss is in fact asking...
Do you believe in God?
As a scientist...
...I rely on empirical evidence,
and in this matter...
...I don't believe
that there's data either way.
So your answer would in fact be
that you don't believe in God.
I don't understand the relevance
of the question.
95%%% of the world's population...
...believes in a Supreme Being
in one form or another.
I believe that makes the question
more than relevant.
I believe...
I believe I've already
answered that question.
I'm proud of what
we've achieved as a species...
...and as a civilization.
I would hate to see
everything we stand for...
...all that we have fought for
for a thousand generations...
...all that God
has blessed us with...
...betrayed...
...in the final hour because we sent a
representative who did not put our...
...most cherished beliefs first.
Thank you.
Why'd you do it?
Our job was to select someone
to speak for everybody.
I couldn't in good conscience
vote for a person...
...who doesn't believe in God.
Someone who...
...honestly thinks
the other 95%%% of us...
...suffer from some form
of mass delusion.
I told the truth up there.
Drumlin told you exactly
what you wanted to hear.
With full humility
and utmost gratitude...
...I accept this great honor...
...and I promise I will do my best
to represent my nation...
...my planet and my God
on this historic...
...journey.
I thank you
from the bottom of my heart.
There's a carnival atmosphere
at Cape Canaveral...
...as the International
Machine Consortium...
...hosts as much a media event
as a systems test.
David Drumlin is supervising
the on-site portion of the test.
We spoke with him earlier today.
We'll be able to monitor
the stresses and effects...
...using the robot passenger...
... who we lovingly call Elmer.
The press wants to
ask you a few questions...
...as soon as they're done
with Dr. Drumlin.
When we release the pod...
...a substantial amount of energy
will be generated.
We'll be able to monitor
the stresses and effects...
...using our robot passenger,
who we...
...lovingly call Elmer.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
They're ready for you
out at the site.
Yeah, just a minute.
-Congratulations.
-Glad you could come.
Didn't expect to see you here.
Well, I'm still...
...Crew Ops at the Control Center.
I suppose the fact that I discovered
the message means I have PR value.
Of course.
I know you must think
this is all very unfair.
And maybe that's an understatement.
What you don't know is, I agree.
I wish the world was a place
where fair was the bottom line...
...where the idealism you showed
at the hearing was rewarded...
...not taken advantage of.
Unfortunately,
we don't live in that world.
Funny...
...I always believed the world
is what we make of it.
Excuse me!
Good luck on the test.
Thank you.
Test director...
...everything looks good.
Ready to go.
I want things double
and triple-checked here.
We only get one shot at this.
Let's get it right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are ready for start-up.
All controllers, I need a go-no-go
for test initiation.
-Mechanical?
-Go.
Electrical?
Dynamics?
Communications?
Pod systems?
Safety?
Crew Ops, verify all pre-test
procedures are complete.
Yes, verified.
I'm go.
Pad Leader,
is everything okay with you?
Roger. The pad is a go.
Test initiation, on my mark.
5...
...4...
...3...
...2...
...1 .
Mark.
-Test start.
-Rings are unlocked.
Power levels show a good start.
We've begun the test of...
...earth's first system built by sharing
knowledge with a neighbor in space.
All power sources
on core induction bus.
IPV power transfer.
Ring motion detect.
Alpha, Bravo, Charlie.
-Gerry, how are we looking?
-Looks good. We're underway.
Looks like a normal start-up.
Roger, David.
It's looking good here.
We are moments away from
the initiation of the drop sequence.
All systems are go.
-Mechanical, you still happy?
-Roger.
It's very exciting...
...from up here.
We've got 4%.
Frequency 9.85.
Harmonics in the green.
G-level 1. 1.
-5%.
-Confirmed. We are at 5%.
David, how's it looking to you?
Okay. I'm going to take a look
and show you what we got.
Instrumentation looks good.
We have a good picture
from Dr. Drumlin's PRD.
Hope you guys are seeing
what I'm seeing.
All systems are go.
This is really something!
For purposes of this test...
...Dr. Drumlin will be on top of the
Gantry crane that's over the Machine.
We've got some video animation...
...to show just how this Machine...
it is thought... will work.
The passenger pod will release.
It will come down
through the center of the rings...
...and into the Machine's core.
The question everyone
here is asking is...
... what happens then?
Some believe the rings function...
...as some sort of an accelerator
or something...
...sending its energy
into the pod...
...making it rocket away
at near light speed.
Others believe it might open up
a doorway to some other dimension.
Who's right?
That's what
today's test is all about.
-35%%%.
-Subsystems ready?
40%%% normal acceleration.
Controllers stand by
to initiate drop sequence...
...on my mark.
All systems ready for drop sequence.
45%%%.
Verify closure.
46.
All controllers stand by to initiate
IPV drop sequence. On my mark.
48%%%.
I'm feeling
a very strange vibration.
-Are you feeling it down there?
-Gerry, can you confirm?
Everything looks good.
Crew Ops?
Nothing wrong.
We see nothing abnormal here.
No good. Hold sequence.
I'll take a direct reading.
What's he talking about?
Can anyone say grandstanding?
He sure knows he's on TV!
Back home that's what we call
an overcooked ham.
I'm reading 10 kilohertz!
What do you read on the first
and second order G-levels?
G-levels are right on!
We confirm Drumlin's readings.
All normal. We're go.
I think we're okay,
but we'll let him finish.
-Mechanical, you still okay?
-Roger. Right on the money.
Security problem!
Ellie, are you sure?
He shouldn't be there.
I know him.
Gerry, execute the
rapid shutdown sequence.
Security, move emergency
response team into position.
Get Drumlin on a secure loop.
You got him.
-Can you hear me?
-Yes, I hear.
We've got a security breach here.
Behind you.
The tall guy.
The technician.
See him?
He shouldn't be there.
Something's in his hand!
Him! Take him!
Security breach!
A bomb!
I want that emergency response team
up on the gantry. Now!
Stage One Alert!
Move all fire and rescue personnel
into position one.
All right, back to your stations.
I need you to be professional.
Settle down!
Pad Leader, do you copy?
The scene earlier today,
when David Drumlin...
...advisor to two Presidents...
...and winner of the National Academy
of Sciences lifetime award...
... was laid to rest
at Arlington National Cemetery.
In a related story...
Can I help you?
I've got some mail for you.
...the apparent suicide note of the
terrorist now believed responsible...
...for the explosion
in Florida this week.
What we do...
... we do for the goodness
of all mankind.
This won't be understood,
not now...
...but the Apocalypse to come...
... will vindicate our faith.
Welcome home.
Comrade Arroway...
... we have been expecting your call.
One moment, please.
Mr. Hadden?
Doctor!
How kind of you to call.
Mr. Hadden, where are you?
The Russian government...
... was kind enough
to give me accommodations on Mir.
You're living on a space station?
It's quite simple, really.
The low oxygen,
zero gravity environment...
...is the only thing keeping
the cancer from eating me alive.
Actually, I quite like it up here.
My little room
has one hell of a view.
I want to show you something.
Hokkaido Island.
The systems integration site.
Look closer.
First rule in government spending:
Why build one when you can have
two at twice the price?
Only, this one can be kept secret.
Controlled by Americans...
...built by Japanese
subcontractors...
... who also happen to be...
...recently acquired...
... wholly-owned subsidiaries...
...of Hadden Industries.
They still want
an American to go, Doctor.
Want to take a ride?
Augmenting our restraint and...
...communications console
subsystem...
...is your personal recording unit.
Normal,
infrared and ultraviolet lenses.
Digital microchip good for
thousands of hours of recording.
Okay, look, I understand...
...the reason for recording
and documenting the mission.
But I just want to go on record
one more time.
The transmitted specs never said
anything about any chair...
...or a restraining harness...
...or survival gear.
Why can't we just trust
the original...
Doctor, both the IMC Board and
the SI team reviewed the matter...
...and concluded that the design
impact is negligible.
Bottom line is...
...we're not putting anyone
aboard this Machine...
...unless there is
some sort of minimal protection.
End of story.
We've given these to the astronauts
since the start of the space program.
It's never been made public,
of course.
It's fast and it's painless.
I'm going to travel 26 light years
to commit suicide?
Something may go wrong.
There may be
an unforeseen mechanical failure.
You could be marooned,
unable to return.
There are 1,000 reasons
we can think of to have this...
...but mostly it's for the reasons
we can't think of.
Come in.
Dr. Arroway, time to get ready.
Thank you.
I know there's not much time.
As soon as I found out about it,
I called the President.
I came with Kitz.
I had to see you one more time.
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
No, I'm glad you came.
There's something
I got to say to you.
The reason I didn't vote for you was
a good one, but not the real one.
I didn't vote for you to go...
...because I don't want to lose you.
Now you find your way home,
all right?
23 hours ago, the world...
... was stunned by the announcement
of the existence of another Machine...
...and its passenger,
Eleanor Ann Arroway.
Now...
...the question
that's on everyone's mind:
Will history repeat itself?
With a piece of engineering
this complex...
... with so many unknowns,
could the unthinkable occur?
The security in Hokkaido
has been incredibly tight.
No reporters whatsoever
have been allowed near the site.
Restraint secure.
Life support functions normal.
Roger.
This is Control.
Do you copy?
Reading you five-by-five.
Give me Ellie's PRD.
Video unit recording
and transmitting.
-Are you reading me?
-That's affirmative.
Video looks good.
Copy, Control.
Ellie, we're going to proceed
to button you up.
I'm ready.
Confirming walkway retraction.
-Communications?
-Go.
-Life support?
We are go for closure.
I'm go here.
Mechanical, initiate
IPV closure sequence.
Let me get you a chair.
-lt's nice to smell you again, Mr. Kitz.
-You too.
Wouldn't peg him as a Polo man.
I got a visual on the door.
The door is looking good.
Door alignment looks good.
We're green across the board.
Copy that, Control.
IPV is secure.
Copy that, 30%.
How you doing in there?
Kent?
Is that you?
That's a big affirmative.
Who let you in there?
A higher power intervened.
I'm glad you came.
35%.
Copy that, 35%.
-Mechanical?
-We're good.
40%.
I'm picking up a moderate vibration.
Dynamics, can you confirm vibration?
It looks good here.
She's feeling the same thing
they felt at the Cape.
Vibration's normal.
Copy that, 50%.
Vibration's a little stronger now.
We're picking up
some low frequency noise.
Mechanical, confirm?
It looks fine to me.
Roger.
Jerry, what do you think?
I'm still go.
People, we are still go.
Something's happening.
You see that light?
I'm seeing...
I can't tell if it's daylight.
There it is again.
It's coming from the bottom.
Let me show you.
See that?
Negative.
You're breaking up.
-Can we boost signal?
-lt's at maximum.
65%%%.
The material is changing.
It's bordering on translucence.
The system's intact.
It has to be...
...some kind of
electromagnetic field.
Do you read this?
We see only interference.
It's becoming translucent.
I can't describe it.
I can't even explain it!
70%%%.
We have intermittent comm,
but we are go!
Initiate secondary drive systems.
Initiating
auxiliary booster sequence.
We're go for ignition.
We have auxiliary ignition.
Life support, how is she?
Heart and respiration are high
but within limits.
Ellie, do you copy?
If you hear...
...I am okay to go.
80%.
All vibration and G-levels
are in the green.
Control, if you're reading me...
...I am okay to go!
Okay to go!
85%%%.
All tips are on the profile.
90%%%. We're detecting
some structural instability.
-ls she holding?
-We're within limits, barely.
I'm okay to go!
My God!
Okay to go!
I'm okay!
100%%% target velocity.
Tremendous EMI levels around Machine!
Field measurements are off-scale.
We're approaching our abort limits.
Okay to go.
I hear her!
I hear her.
Barely, but she's there.
Okay to go.
Says she's okay to go.
Steve, we're real close.
-Your core reading?
-lnternal environment looks normal.
Inside the core,
the weather's beautiful.
I'm okay to go.
Initiate drop sequence.
On my mark.
10...
...9...
...8...
... 7...
...6...
...5...
...4...
...3...
...2...
I'm okay to go.
Oh, God!
Ellie to Control.
Ellie to Control,
do you read me!
I'll try...
...to keep recording!
I'm going through...
...some kind of a tunnel!
There's a light source ahead!
Brilliant...
...blue-white.
Residual radiation?
It's a star.
I must have...
...gone through a wormhole.
It's Vega!
I'm in another wormhole now!
I had no idea!
A series of them!
They're alive.
It's like...
...some kind of a transit system.
A subway!
Oh, God!
I have to keep talking.
It's a triple...
...no, a quadruple system.
Beautiful!
They're alive!
Another wormhole!
This one's much more violent!
Some...
...celestial event...
No!
No words!
No words...
...to describe it!
Poetry!
They should have sent...
...a poet.
It's so beautiful!
Beautiful!
So beautiful.
I had no idea.
Hi, Sparks.
Dad?
I missed you.
Aren't you...?
I'm sorry I couldn't
be there for you, sweetheart.
You're not real.
None of this is real!
That's my scientist.
When I was unconscious, you
downloaded my thoughts, my memories.
Pensacola!
We thought it might
make things easier for you.
Why did you contact us?
You contacted us.
We were just listening.
There are others?
Many others.
They all...
...travel here through
that transit system you built?
We didn't build it.
We don't know who did.
They were gone
long before we ever got here.
Maybe someday they'll come back.
All the civilizations
you find come here?
Not all.
-ls this some test?
-No, no test.
You have your mother's hands.
You're an interesting species...
...an interesting mix.
You're capable
of such beautiful dreams...
...and such horrible nightmares.
You feel so lost...
...so cut off, so alone.
Only you're not.
In all our searching...
...all we've found
that makes the emptiness bearable...
...is each other.
What happens now?
Now?
You go home.
Home?
But...
...I have so many questions.
Do we get to come back?
This was just a first step.
In time, you'll take another.
But other people need to see
what I've seen...
This is the way it's been done
for billions of years.
Small moves, Ellie.
Small moves.
We've got video on Ellie!
She's through!
She is in the net.
She's alive.
Get the President on the phone!
What's going on?
How is she?
Ellie, this is Control.
You copy?
-What's going on?
-I don't know.
-She's alive.
-Put her on P.A.
Ellie, hold on tight.
We're still trying to determine
the nature of the malfunction...
...but the important thing
is you're okay.
What?
It's all right.
The important thing is you're safe.
What malfunction?
What happened?
What day is this?
I'm sorry.
Did you say what day?
How long was I gone?
The IPV dropped
straight through the Machine.
You didn't go anywhere.
But I did.
I did go.
That's what I've tried
to tell everyone.
But the headset
didn't record a single image?
Just this.
Static.
Thank you.
Let me show you what we saw.
43 separate remote cameras
show exactly the same event.
The IPV dropped straight through.
Everyone saw exactly...
...the same thing.
Nothing happened.
How do you explain this, Doctor?
I can't.
I'd encourage you...
...not to inflame this situation...
...beyond the facts.
Let us deal with this on the facts.
We are monitoring
what has actually happened.
We are taking
what we believe are factually...
...appropriate steps.
Amid a flurry of accusations
and counter-accusations...
...by the nations representing
the Machine Consortium...
...the President has ordered
a special inquiry.
But the appointment
to the committee of Michael Kitz...
... who has resigned
as National Security Advisor...
...has raised eyebrows
on Capitol Hill.
I have made no decision to run for
Congress, announced no candidacy.
I resigned as
National Security Advisor...
...in order to devote
all of my energy to this inquiry.
The people of the world have a right
to know what really happened.
Yet every scientific
instrument confirms...
...the IPV was out of contact
for only a fraction of a second.
Isn't that correct, Doctor?
A fraction of a second Earth time,
yes.
Earth time?
Senator, I believe that the Machine
opened up a wormhole...
...a tunnel through space-time, also
known as an Einstein-Rossen Bridge.
Due to the effect of general relativity,
what I experienced as 18 hours...
...passed instantaneously on Earth.
Isn't it true these wormholes
are merely theoretical predictions?
There is no evidence
they actually exist?
There is no direct evidence, no.
Tell me...
...why would these aliens
go to all this trouble?
Bring you thousands of light years,
then send you home without proof?
They said it's how it's been done
for billions of years.
You have no proof because
they didn't want you to have any.
A phenomenon known
in psychiatric circles...
...as a self-reinforcing delusion.
You think I was delusional?
I do think you may have suffered
some kind of an episode. Yes, I do.
I'd like to propose
an alternate hypothesis...
...and I'd like you to bring your
scientific expertise to bear on it.
To fake a signal from Vega...
...what would you need?
You'd need a satellite to transmit
it, but it would be impossible to...
You'd need a satellite
and launch capabilities to orbit it.
And the message itself. To put
something like this together...
...so complex,
drawing on many disciplines...
Would be impossible.
Impossible?
Is there anyone who might
have been up to the challenge?
Someone with extraordinary
technical expertise...
...enormous financial resources...
...someone perverse enough, eccentric
enough to come up with the idea?
Hadden?
S. R. Hadden.
You're implying that this was...
...some kind of a hoax?
That he engineered this?
S. R. Hadden...
...a legendary power broker in
perhaps his final bid for immortality.
Maybe he wanted to
exploit new technologies...
...having world governments
pick up the tab.
Perhaps this was his
final altruistic gesture...
...to unite the world in some
common goal. Maybe all of the above.
S. R. Hadden, a brilliant...
...and complicated man.
Doctor, are you familiar
with the scientific precept...
...known as Occam's Razor?
Yes.
It means the simplest explanation
generally tends to be the right one.
Exactly.
You tell me.
What is more likely here?
A message from aliens
results in a magical machine...
...that whisks you
to the center of the galaxy...
...to windsurf with Dad
and a split second later...
...returns you home
without a single shred of proof?
Or that your experience
is the result of being...
...the unwitting star in the
farewell performance of one...
...S.R. Hadden?
A man with the means and motive
to play you and all of us...
...as pawns in the most elaborate,
most expensive hoax of all time?
You come to us with no evidence,
no records...
...no artifacts...
...only a story that, to put it
mildly, strains credibility.
Over half a trillion dollars
were spent.
Dozens of lives were lost.
Are you going to sit there and tell
us we should just take this all...
...on faith?
Please answer the question, Doctor.
Is it possible
that it didn't happen?
Yes.
As a scientist I must concede that.
I must volunteer that.
Let me get this straight.
You admit you have no physical
evidence to back up your story?
Yes.
You admit you may have
hallucinated this whole thing?
You admit if you were
in our position...
...you would be as incredulous
and skeptical as we?
Then why don't you simply withdraw
your testimony and concede...
...that this journey to the center
of the galaxy never took place?
Because I can't.
I had an experience.
I can't prove it.
I can't even explain it.
But everything I know as
a human being, everything I am...
...tells me it was real.
I was given something wonderful,
something that changed me forever.
A vision...
...of the universe...
...that tells us undeniably...
...how tiny and insignificant...
...and how rare and precious
we all are.
A vision that tells us
that we belong to something...
...that is greater than ourselves,
that none of us are alone.
I wish I could share that.
I wish...
...that everyone, if even for one...
...moment...
...could feel...
...that awe and humility and hope.
That continues to be my wish.
Dr. Arroway,
can I get a picture, please.
Reverend Joss!
What do you believe?!
As a person of faith, I'm bound by a
different covenant than Dr. Arroway.
But our goal is one and the same.
The pursuit of truth.
l, for one, believe her.
So what happens now?
We give her a medal?
I'd say at least a healthy grant.
You read the confidential report
from the investigating committee?
I flipped through it.
I was very interested in the section
on Arroway's video unit.
The one that recorded the static.
Continue.
The fact that it recorded static
isn't what interests me.
Continue.
What interests me...
...is that it recorded
approximately 18 hours of it.
That is interesting, isn't it?
And you can see over there,
we're building 45 brand new dishes.
That means when you put them together
with all the radio telescopes...
...all over the world...
...we'll hear farther into space
than anyone has ever heard before.
Are there other people
out there in the universe?
That's a good question.
What do you think?
I don't know.
That's a good answer.
Skeptic, huh?
The important thing is that you all
keep searching for your own answers.
One thing about the universe,
though.
The universe...
...is a pretty big place.
It's bigger than anything...
...anyone has ever
dreamed of before.
So if it's just us...
...it seems like
an awful waste of space.
Right?