:Joseph M. Schenck Presents
"Buster" Keaton
in
Convict 13 [1920]
Written and directed by
"BUSTER" KEATON
and
EDDIE CLINE
Golf - the game that brings
out the beast in men.
Written Subtitle by:
Jaffar AlBori
"Fore!"
GUARD
WARDEN
"She loves me, she loves me not..."
"You shouldn't have gone to
all the trouble just for me."
"I want you to meet my father."
"You are to be hanged today."
"This is the guy we're
hanging today."
"Don't worry. it'll work just fine."
CHAMPION
HEAVY WEIGHT
HANGMAN
1916-17-20
"Sorry. boys. We'll fix it and
tomorrow we'll hang two of
to make up for this."
"Nice day we're having. eh?"
"If you want to see who's boss,
just try me!"
ASSISTANT
WARDEN
"The riot starts at three o'clock"
THE END