[Woman] WHEN I WAS A CHILD, I WOULD
COME TO THIS PARK AND PLAY.
MY GRANDMOTHER TOLD ME WHY
THE BAMBOO IS HERE.
SHE SAID, "IT IS WAITING
FOR THE WIND TO TOUCH IT.
"IT IS FILLED WITH EMOTION.
LISTEN TO THE SOUND
AND YOU CAN FEEL THAT."
[Chanting In Chinese]
[Horns Honking]
[Horn Honking]
[Man #1]
THE GUY WITH
THE CIGARETTE'S THE MAN.
LIU IS HIS NAME.
HE DECIDES WHAT TO BUY.
[Man #2]
SO HOW'RE WE DOING ?
[Man #1]  THEY'VE GOT PROBLEMS
WITH THE TV PACKAGE.
THAT'S WHY WE FLEW YOU IN.
[Man #2]  THEY SEEM
TO BE ENJOYING THEMSELVES.
WHO'S THE COMPETITION ?
- [Man #2] GERMANS ALREADY BEEN HERE ?
- HOFFMANN CAME IN YESTERDAY.
AH !
RIGHT ON TIME.
SHOW TIME.
THE DIRECTOR
HAS CONCERNS ABOUT
YOUR PROGRAMMING PACKAGE.
HE SAYS YOUR PROGRAMS
ARE PORNOGRAPHIC, VIOLENT
AND SUPERSTITIOUS.
AS, OF COURSE,
THEY ARE.
HAVE YOU LOST
YOUR MIND ?
WE'VE MADE
A RECOMMENDATION, AND
WOULD LIKE YOU TO COMMENT.
YOUR GREAT CHAIRMAN MAO
ONCE SAID--
YOU'LL HAVE TO EXCUSE
THIS PRONUNCIATION.
I'M SORRY.
- [Speaks In Chinese]
- [Interpreter Repeats
In Chinese]
USE THE WEST
FOR CHINESE PURPOSES.
IS THAT TRUE,
OR AM I MISTAKEN ?
IF OUR PROGRAMMING
TEACHES YOUR PEOPLE...
THAT AMERICA IS IMPERFECT,
OFTEN VIOLENT AND PRURIENT,
WOULDN'T THAT TEND TO DISCOURAGE
THE PURSUIT OF WESTERN VALUES ?
[Chinese]
[Interpreter]
WITH SOME DELETIONS, PERHAPS
WE CAN COME TO AN UNDERSTANDING.
LET US TALK
AMONG OURSELVES.
XIE XIE.
DAVID.
NICE WORK, JACK.
NICE.
IT LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE BUYING
THE PACKAGE OUTRIGHT.
GREAT.
MINUS
"THE BRADY BUNCH."
WHICH DEVIATES
FROM PARTY MANDATE,
"ONE CHILD PER FAMILY."
MR. McANDREWS, WELCOME.
DAN.
HELLO, JACK.
HI.
MY FATHER OFFERS
A THOUSAND APOLOGIES
IF HE KEPT YOU WAITING.
PLEASE.
DAVID McANDREWS
WELCOME.
MR. JACK MOORE.
MR. LIN.
MR. MOORE.
[Chinese]
PLEASE COME IN.
THANK YOU.  XIE XIE.
DAVID IS AN OLD FRIEND.
HE IS THE FIRST WESTERN
BUSINESSMAN I MET...
AFTER MY APPOINTMENT
TO THE MINISTRY OF RADIO,
FILM AND TELEVISION.
IN FACT, HE WAS THE ONE
WHO CONVINCED ME THAT
NOT ALL FOREIGNERS HAVE HORNS.
ONLY SOME.  I RAN INTO
GERHARDT HOFFMANN...
IN BEIJING TODAY.
YES.  MR. HOFFMANN.
HOFFCO TELEKOMM.
HE GIVES THE APPEARANCE
OF, UH, TREMENDOUS ENTHUSIASM.
MY SON TOLD ME
HOW SKILLFULLY...
YOU SOFTENED
OUR VERY STUBBORN CENSOR.
[Sighs]
YES, WE REACHED
A MEETING OF MINDS.
THERE ARE THOSE
IN MY GOVERNMENT...
WHO WISH TO SEVERELY
LIMIT THE FLOW...
OF WESTERN ENTERTAINMENT.
AND THERE ARE THOSE
WHO ARE IMPATIENT,
WHO WISH THE FLOODGATES
RELEASED.
LIKE MY SON.
BUT THERE MUST BE
A HAPPY MEDIUM.
WE MUST PROCEED
WITH BALANCE.
YOUNG MAN
THERE'S NO NEED TO FEEL DOWN
I SAID, YOUNG MAN
LIFT YOURSELF OFF THE GROUND
'CAUSE YOU'RE IN A NEW TOWN
IS THIS HOW YOU
IMAGINED CHINA, JACK ?
YOUNG MAN
THERE'S A PLACE YOU CAN GO
I SAID, YOUNG MAN
[Chuckles]
WHEN YOU'RE SHORT
ON YOUR DOUGH
YOU CAN STAY THERE
AND I'M SURE YOU WILL FIND
MANY WAYS TO HAVE
A GOOD TIME
IT'S FUN TO STAY
AT THE Y.M.C.A.
- [Shouts In Chinese]
- [Crowd Shouts]
- [Shouting Continues]
[Shouts]
[Crowd Shouts]
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING ?
"IS IT GOOD ?  IS IT GREAT ?
LET'S DO IT
ONE MORE TIME, BABY !"
[Shouting Continues]
[Applause]
[Chinese]
IS THIS WHAT YOUR FATHER
WOULD CONSTRUE AS
"PROCEEDING WITH BALANCE" ?
MY FATHER HAS THE POWER
TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
BUT HE RARELY USES IT.
BUT HE'S GOING TO BE USING IT
ON BEHALF OF McANDREWS.
I LIKE YOUR STYLE, JACK.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU CUT TO THE CHASE.
YOU DO
YOUR HOMEWORK.
WHY DO YOU NEED THIS DEAL
TO HAPPEN SO MUCH ?
I WANT MY SON TO GROW UP
IN A DIFFERENT CHINA
THAN THE ONE THAT EXISTS TODAY.
WE COULD BE
AN UNBEATABLE PARTNERSHIP.
YOU AND I.
ESPECIALLY WITH MY BACKERS
OVER THERE.
YEAH.
WE CAN TALK ABOUT THAT
AFTER THE DEAL GOES THROUGH.
OF COURSE.
[Dan]  WE CAN DISCUSS THIS
FURTHER TOMORROW.
TONIGHT WE CELEBRATE...
THE FIRST CHINESE-AMERICAN
SATELLITE JOINT VENTURE.
[Resounds]
[Chattering, Laughing]
HOW MUCH ?
[Chinese]
HMM ?
[Jack]
OH, DAN PAID FOR IT.
[Camera Shutter
Popping]
[Camera Shutter Popping]
- MINE ?
- DA BI ZI.
[Chuckling]
THIS IS WHAT YOU CALL AMERICANS.
YOU CALL THEM "BIG NOSES,"
DON'T YOU ?
HMM ?
DA BI ZI.
THESE ARE GREAT.
THESE ARE REALLY GREAT.
[Chinese]
DO YOU MIND ?
WHAT HAVE WE GOT HERE ?
MAILLOL.
AND A HENRY MOORE.
RODIN.
CORRECT ?
YES, CORRECT.
I SHOULD BE
GETTING YOU HOME.
I BET YOU'RE WONDERING
HOW I KNEW
[Chinese]
'BOUT YOUR PLANS
TO MAKE ME BLUE
WITH SOME OTHER GUY
YOU KNEW BEFORE
BETWEEN THE TWO OF US GUYS
YOU KNOW I LOVE YOU MORE
IT TOOK ME BY SURPRISE
I MUST SAY
WHEN I FOUND OUT
YESTERDAY
DON'T YOU KNOW THAT I HEARD IT
THROUGH THE GRAPEVINE
NOT MUCH LONGER
WOULD YOU BE MINE
OH, I HEARD IT
THROUGH THE GRAPEVINE
OH, I'M JUST ABOUT
TO LOSE MY MIND
[Chinese]
HONEY, HONEY
YEAH
LIPS.
HEARD IT THROUGH THE GRAPEVINE
NOT MUCH LONGER
WOULD YOU BE MINE, BABY
I KNOW A MAN
AIN'T SUPPOSED TO CRY
SHETOU.
BUT THESE TEARS
I CAN'T HOLD INSIDE
TONGUE.
LOSIN' YOU WOULD MEAN
MY LIFE, YOU SEE
'CAUSE YOU MEAN
THAT MUCH TO ME
BREAST.
[Chinese]
[Elevator Bell Rings]
[Laughing]
[Chinese]
[Continues
In Chinese]
WHAT IS IT ?
WHO WERE YOU TALKING TO ?
MEISHI.
MEISHI.  MEISHI.
I KNOW MEISHI.
MEISHI MEANS
"IT DOESN'T MATTER."
MEISHI.  MEISHI.
MEISHI.
THAT'S PRETTY.
[Chinese]
SHOU.
HAND.
MMM.
"I WANNA HOLD
YOUR HAND."
[Laughing]
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
I WANNA HOLD
YOUR HAND
HAND
I WANT TO HOLD
YOUR HAND
I WANT TO HOLD YOUR HAND
[Chinese]
WHOA.  WAIT, WAIT--
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE ?
[Chinese]
NO !  NO !
[Shouting
In Chinese]
OH, MY GOD !
[Jack]
HELP ME.  WHAT IS--
PLEASE !  WAIT.
GET A DOCTOR.
WAIT.
[Grunting]
[Chinese]
DO YOU SPEAK ENGLISH ?
DO YOU SPEAK--
I'M AMERICAN.
SPRECHEN SIE DEUTSCH ?
[Siren Wailing]
AAH !
WAIT.
[Coughs]
HEY !
[Jack Grunts]
LET ME GO !  LET ME GO.
[Rifle Shots]
[Rifle Shots Continue]
I'M AN AMERICAN CITIZEN.
[Door Opens]
FINALLY.
HELLO.
[Chinese]
JACK PETER MOORE.
YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
ENGLISH NO GOOD.
SO... [Chinese]
[Interpreter]  YOU HAVE
REFUSED TO ANSWER QUESTIONS.
NO ONE HAS ASKED ANYTHING.
[Jack]
NO ONE ASKED ANY QUESTIONS.
[Chinese]
[Interpreter]  DID YOU
RAPE AND MURDER HONG LING ?
YOU'VE MADE A BIG MISTAKE.
- [Chinese]
[Interpreter]
THERE IS NO MISTAKE.
I HAVE THE RIGHT
TO CONTACT MY EMBASSY.
[Chinese]
[Interpreter]
YOU HAVE NO RIGHTS.
I HAVE
A RIGHT TO CONTACT THE EMBASSY.
I WOULD LIKE TO TALK
TO MY EMBASSY.
[Chinese]
YOU WILL BE TRIED
ACCORDING TO THE LAWS OF
THE PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC OF CHINA.
I WOULD LIKE TO TALK
TO THE AMERICAN EMBASSY.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME ?
[Chinese]
[Interpreter]
FIRST THE INVESTIGATION.
- [Chinese]
- DID YOU RAPE HONG LING BEFORE
OR AFTER YOU MURDERED HER ?
- I WANT TO TALK TO MY EMBASSY.
- [Chinese]
PLEASE TRANSLATE THIS.
I WOULD LIKE TO SEE
AN ATTORNEY.
[Chinese]
[Continues
In Chinese]
[Interpreter]  THE SIGN SAYS,
"LENIENCY FOR THOSE WHO CONFESS.
SEVERITY FOR THOSE WHO RESIST."
I'M NOT RESISTING, AND--
IT CAN BE MORE EASY...
IF YOU CONFESS YOUR CRIME.
[Window Bars Slide Open]
HEY.  HEY !
YOU OKAY ?
YEAH.
I BROUGHT ALONG
ED PRATT, MR. MOORE.
WE'RE ONLY ALLOWED
FIVE MINUTES,
SO LET ME MAKE IT CRISP.
AS SENIOR CONSULAR OFFICER
AT THE EMBASSY...
I NEED SOME INFORMATION
ABOUT THE NIGHT IN QUESTION.
- YOU BRING ME
THE SENIOR CONSULAR ?
- HEAR HIM OUT, JACK.
MR. MOORE, THE EMBASSY IS TRYING
TO TRACK THROUGH WHAT HAPPENED.
CAN YOU GIVE ME SOME DETAILS ?
I MET HER.
WE WENT BACK TO THE HOTEL.
[Phone Disconnects]
HELLO ?  HELLO ?
I CAN'T HEAR ANY--
HEY !
I CAN'T--
IT'S OFF !
I CAN'T HEAR ANYTHING.
THIS DOESN'T WORK.
[Jack]
HEY.  HELLO ?
THE PHONE
DOESN'T WORK.
YES.  HELLO ?
MR. MOORE, THE GENTLEMAN SAYS
WE CAN'T TALK ABOUT THE DETAILS
OF THE INVESTIGATION.
- WHAT CAN WE TALK ABOUT ?
- YOU'RE ON CHINESE SOIL.
YOU'RE SUBJECT TO CHINESE LAW.
THIS IS HOW THEY DO IT.
YOU CAN DISCUSS
THE INVESTIGATION
ONLY WITH YOUR LAWYER.
GET ME A LAWYER.
CALL JOE SHAPIRO
IN WASHINGTON.
ASK HIM WHO'S
PLUGGED IN HERE.
THAT'S A NON-STARTER.
NON-CHINESE LAWYERS
AREN'T ALLOWED TO PRACTICE HERE.
THERE ARE THREE OR FOUR
CHINESE CRIMINAL LAWYERS...
WHO COULD HANDLE
A CASE OF THIS MAGNITUDE,
BUT NONE OF THEM WILL TOUCH IT.
THE PROCURACY WILL APPOINT
A DEFENSE ADVOCATE
FOR YOUR CASE.
WE'LL GET YOU BAIL,
JACK.
[Pratt]
THERE AGAIN, I SHOULD WARN YOU,
IT'S VERY RARE.
IT'S CALLED A GUARANTEE.
AND IT ALMOST NEVER HAPPENS.
ED, I'M SURE
IT'S VERY RARE.
-I WOULD ASSUME THE AMBASSADOR--
-AMBASSADOR REED IS IN SHANGHAI.
I ASSUME THAT HE COULD,
EVEN POSSIBLY FROM SHANGHAI,
MAKE A FEW PHONE CALLS.
USE HIS INFLUENCE.
ABSOLUTELY.
[Pratt]
HE'LL DO EVERYTHING
HE CAN FOR YOU.
NATURALLY, AS AMBASSADOR,
YOU JUGGLE YOUR CRISES
IN THE INTERESTS...
OF PUSHING OUT THE ENVELOPE
FOR MANY PARTIES.
GUESS WHAT.
WE'RE REALLY GOING TO BE
PUSHING THAT ENVELOPE NOW.
YOU'RE GONNA GET ME A COPY
OF THE CRIMINAL CODE...
IN ENGLISH.
-I CAN CERTAINLY TRY, MR. MOORE.
-THANKS, ED.
[Prisoner Coughing,
Gagging]
[Cell Door Opens]
FINALLY.
[Chinese]
[Continues
In Chinese]
WHAT'S HE SAYING ?
WHO IS HE ?
[Chinese]
[Continues
In Chinese]
THIS IS GENERAL HONG.
YOU KILLED HONG LING,
HIS DAUGHTER.
YOU TELL HIM
THAT I DID NOT KILL HER.
GO ON, TELL HIM.
- [Chinese]
- I UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR GRIEF.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR PAIN
THAT COMES FROM LOSING
A CHILD.
BUT I DID NOT KILL HER !
[Interpreter
In Chinese]
[Chinese]
WHAT DID HE SAY ?
HE SAID
HE WILL SEE YOU DEAD.
I SAY IT AGAIN.
IT CAN BE MORE EASY
IF YOU CONFESS YOUR CRIME.
[Siren Wailing]
[Woman In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter
On Headset]  JACK PETER MOORE,
YOU ARE CHARGED...
WITH INTENTIONAL HOMICIDE
AND RAPE WITH
AGGRAVATING CIRCUMSTANCES.
DOES ANY PARTICIPANT
IN THESE PROCEEDINGS CHALLENGE
THE COMPOSITION OF THE COURT ?
-[Interpreter] PROCURATOR MA ?
-[Male Interpreter]  NO
CHALLENGE, PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
[Female Interpreter]
DOES THE DEFENSE AIDE CHALLENGE
THE COMPOSITION...
OF THE COURT ?
HUH ?
[Female Interpreter]
DOES THE DEFENSE AIDE
CHALLENGE--
[Male Interpreter]
I'M SORRY.
CAN YOU PLEASE SPEAK LOUDER ?
[Female Interpreter]
DO YOU CHALLENGE THE COMPOSITION
OF THIS COURT, SIR ?
- AH-- [Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]  NO
CHALLENGE, PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
[Female Interpreter]
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN.
MADAME.
PLEASE EXCUSE ME.  I WAS WITH
CHIEF LI AT THE MINISTRY OF
JUSTICE PREPARING FOR THIS CASE.
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
YOU'RE EXCUSED, ADVOCATE.
[Chairman Xu In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
ACCUSED MOORE, DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THE CHARGES AGAINST YOU ?
WHAT I UNDERSTAND
IS I HAVE NEVER MET
MY ATTORNEY BEFORE.
[Female Interpreter]
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN, HAVE YOU
NOT MET WITH THE ACCUSED ?
UM--
[Female Interpreter]
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN--
[Static From Headset]
WAIT A MINUTE.
I'VE LOST THE SOUND.
I CAN'T HEAR ANYTHING.
WHAT IS SHE SAYING ?
[Mouthing Words]
WAIT, WAIT.
I DON'T HEAR.
I'VE LOST THE SOUND.
I CAN'T HEAR ANYTHING.
WHAT ?  I CAN'T--
THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT--
CAN YOU HEAR ME NOW,
ACCUSED MOORE ?
[Female Interpreter]
CAN YOU HEAR ME ?
CAN YOU HEAR ME NOW ?
YES, I HEAR.
I WOULD LIKE MY ATTORNEY
I HAVE NEVER MET...
TO REPEAT
WHAT SHE HAS SAID.
[Male Interpreter In Chinese]
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
I TOLD CHAIRMAN XU I WAS
ASSIGNED THIS CASE ONLY TODAY,
BUT I'M FAMILIAR WITH THE FACTS
OF THIS INVESTIGATION.
HOW COULD YOU--
YOU NEVER SPOKE
WITH YOUR CLIENT !
[Chairman Xu]
YOU MUST ADDRESS THE COURT
IN THE PROPER MANNER.
I'M SORRY.
W-WHAT IS THE PROPER MANNER,
YOUR HONOR ?
ACCUSED MOORE,
PLEASE BE SEATED NOW.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
[Female Interpreter]
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN,
WHAT DOES THE ACCUSED PLEAD...
TO THESE CHARGES ?
UM--
[Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]
THE ACCUSED PLEADS GUILTY.
- THE HELL I DO !
I DON'T THINK
YOU GET THE PICTURE.
THE DEFENSE ATTORNEY
IS SUPPOSED TO REPRESENT
THE ACCUSED, NOT THE STATE !
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ?
DO YOU SPEAK ENGLISH ?
[Chinese]
YES.
OKAY.
I AM NOT PLEADING GUILTY.
YOU WILL CHANGE THE PLEA.
NO.
FINE.
I WANT ANOTHER LAWYER.
THERE IS NO OTHER LAWYER
WHO WILL AGREE TO DEFEND YOU.
ONLY BECAUSE
THE MINISTRY OF JUSTICE
REQUESTED MY SERVICE...
HAVE I ASSUMED THIS ROLE.
ASSUMING THE ROLE REQUIRES
LISTENING TO THE FACTS,
WHICH YOU SEEM
UNWILLING TO DO !
LET ME SHARE WITH YOU
THE FACTS.
A FOREIGNER COMES TO
MY COUNTRY, TAKES A GIRL TO BED
AFTER KNOWING HER A FEW HOURS,
AND CONSUMING
MUCH LIQUOR.
NEXT MORNING
SHE IS DEAD.
THE FOREIGNER SAYS
HE IS INNOCENT.
I AM.
HIS HANDS ARE COVERED
WITH HER BLOOD,
AND HIS FINGERPRINTS...
ARE ALL OVER
THE MURDER WEAPON.
WITH A GUILTY PLEA, THE COURT
MAY BE PERSUADED BY MY ARGUMENTS
OF EXTENUATING CIRCUMSTANCES:
ALCOHOL, PERHAPS
MOMENTARY INSANITY,
TO BE LENIENT IN SENTENCING.
I WAS NOT INSANE.
I'M NOT PLEADING GUILTY.
IF YOU PLEAD NOT GUILTY,
THE JUDGE...
AND THE TWO MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC SITTING NEXT TO HER,
CALLED "PEOPLE'S ASSESSORS,"
WILL BE OFFENDED BY
YOUR UNREPENTANT ATTITUDES.
THEIR MAJORITY VOTE
WILL DETERMINE YOUR FATE.
IN OUR COUNTRY,
MORAL EDUCATION OF CRIMINALS
IS OF GREAT IMPORTANCE.
LENIENCY IS GRANTED
TO THOSE WHO CONFESS.
SEVERITY IS REQUIRED...
YES, I KNOW THAT.
FOR THOSE WHO STUBBORNLY INSIST
ON THEIR INNOCENCE.
THEREFORE,
IT WOULD BE WISE OF YOU...
TO TREAT OUR LEGAL SYSTEM
WITH RESPECT.
SPARE ME THE LECTURE
ON THE MORALITY
OF YOUR JUDICIAL SYSTEM.
IF YOU PLEAD NOT GUILTY,
YOU WILL BE SENTENCED TO DEATH.
AND, UNLIKE IN
YOUR COUNTRY, MR. MOORE,
SENTENCES ARE CARRIED OUT
WITHIN A WEEK.
YOU WILL BE SHOT,
AND THE COST OF THE BULLET
WILL BE BILLED TO YOUR FAMILY.
I'M INNOCENT !
- YOU TRULY BELIEVE
YOU ARE INNOCENT ?
- YES, I KNOW I AM !
HOW DO YOU KNOW ?
HOW CAN YOU BE CERTAIN ?
YOU WERE UNCONSCIOUS WHEN
THE POLICE CAME TO YOUR ROOM.
I WAS ASLEEP.
YOU HAD CONSUMED
AN EXCESS OF ALCOHOL.
IT WASN'T THAT.
AN ENORMOUS AMOUNT WAS CONSUMED
BY ANYBODY'S STANDARDS !
I KNOW WHAT I DID
AND DID NOT DO !
HOW CAN YOU BE SURE
WHILE UNDER THE INFLUENCE...
OF SO MUCH ALCOHOL ?
HOW CAN YOU
EVER BE CERTAIN ?
IN CHINA, WE HOLD
THE WELFARE OF THE STATE...
ABOVE THAT
OF THE INDIVIDUAL.
WE HAVE SIX TIMES
THE POPULATION OF YOUR COUNTRY,
MR. MOORE.
AND ONE-TENTH
THE CRIME RATE.
TELL ME,
WHO IS RIGHT ?
YOUR PLEA IS GUILTY.
[Camera Shutter
Popping]
- [Disc Jockey Shouting
In Chinese]
- [Shouting]
[Chinese]
WHAT ?
WHAT'S HAPPENING ?
COURTESY OF YOUR EMBASSY,
THE CHINESE CRIMINAL LAW
TRANSLATED...
INTO ENGLISH.
GREAT.  THANKS.
JACK, YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT YOUR ADVOCATE
IS ONE OF OUR BEST.
SHE GOT PERMISSION FOR
MY VISIT.  VERY UNUSUAL.
WHERE'S GHERY ?
HE'S GIVING
HIS DEPOSITION.
ABOUT WHAT ?
HIS KNOWLEDGE
OF THE CASE.
XIE XIE.
HE HAS NO FIRSTHAND KNOWLEDGE,
BUT I'M SURE HE'LL GIVE YOU A
CRACKERJACK CHARACTER REFERENCE.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME HERE.
WHAT KIND OF COVERAGE
ARE WE GETTING ON THIS ?
THE EMBASSY SEEMS CONVINCED
IT'S WISER TO KEEP A LID
ON THIS.
[Dan]  IT'S GOOD STRATEGY.
THERE ARE QUESTIONS
OF FACE INVOLVED.
AND GEOPOLITICALLY, THERE ARE
TRADE ISSUES PENDING...
WHICH ENSURE YOU OF
A FAIRER SHOT THAN USUAL.
[Sighs]
IS McANDREWS
STILL IN TOKYO ?
IT'S AGREED THAT A VISIT
FROM McANDREWS WOULD BE...
IMPRUDENT.
YEAH.
YEAH, RIGHT.
[Dan]  JACK, AS YOU KNOW,
THIS IS A DANGEROUS TIME.
THERE ARE POWERFUL FORCES
FOR CHANGE,
AND THERE ARE POWERFUL FORCES
OF RESISTANCE.
THE OLD GUARD
SEE THE MURDER OF HONG LING
AS JUSTIFICATION...
FOR THEIR CAMPAIGN
AGAINST SPIRITUAL POLLUTION.
[Chinese]
SORRY.
NO POLITICS.
HOUSE RULES.
EXCUSE ME.
[Chinese]
[Dan]  YOU LIKE
STAR TREK, JACK ?
WHAT ?
STAR TREK.
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
THE ORIGINAL.
I HAVE ALL 79 SEGMENTS
ON TAPE.
OKAY.
PROGRAMMING NOW
JUST DOESN'T COMPARE.
[Dan]
IT OFFERS ONLY VIOLENCE.
[Chinese]
WOULDN'T YOU AGREE ?
I'M VERY SORRY.
I'M GOING TO DO EVERYTHING
IN MY POWER TO HELP YOU.
[Voice Of Shou]
THERE ARE THOSE
IN MY GOVERNMENT...
WHO WISH TO SEVERELY
LIMIT THE FLOW...
OF WESTERN
ENTERTAINMENT.
AND THERE ARE
THOSE WHO WISH
THE FLOODGATES RELEASED.
[Pratt]
IS THERE ANYONE
YOU WANT US TO NOTIFY ?
ANY FAMILY ?
SO THEY KNOW WHERE TO SEND
THE BILL FOR THE BULLET ?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
[Prisoner Coughing]
[Rumbling Sounds]
[Rumbling Sounds Continue]
[Chinese]
HELLO ?
[Window Bars Slide Open]
[Chinese]
HELLO ?
[Cell Door Opens]
[Cell Door Closes]
[Yuelin's Voice]
TELL ME OF YOUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH HONG LING.
[Jack's Voice]
WE LAUGHED.  WE HAD FUN.
NO EXPECTATIONS.
JUST A TERRIFIC NIGHT.
ONE NIGHT.  IS THIS
THE TYPICAL DURATION OF YOUR
RELATIONSHIP WITH WOMEN ?
I DIDN'T CHOOSE
THE DURATION.
NEXT TIME...
YOU PICK YOUR SEXUAL PARTNERS,
YOU MIGHT WISH TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT THEM.
YOU WILL MAKE MY JOB
A LOT EASIER.
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
DID YOU HAVE THE KNIFE TESTED
FOR BLOOD ?
YES.
THE BLOOD ON THE KNIFE
IS THAT OF THE VICTIM.
[Female Interpreter]  WHEN YOU
SAW THE ACCUSED, WHAT WAS YOUR
ASSESSMENT OF HIS CONDITION ?
[Male Interpreter]
A STRONG SMELL OF ALCOHOL
WAS COMING FROM HIM.
HE WAS UNSTEADY,
CONFUSED.
HE SEEMED SURPRISED
BY IT ALL.
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
DID YOU FIND ALCOHOL
IN THE ROOM ?
[Male Interpreter]
TWO EMPTY BOTTLES OF CHAMPAGNE,
AND TWO EMPTY BOTTLES OF SCOTCH.
I HAVE NO FURTHER QUESTIONS
FOR THIS WITNESS.
[Female Interpreter]
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN.
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
WHAT TIME DID YOU RECEIVE
THE CALL ABOUT SCREAMS...
COMING FROM THE ACCUSED'S ROOM ?
[Male Interpreter]
APPROXIMATELY 5:45.
[Female Interpreter]
AND ENTERED
THE ACCUSED'S ROOM WHEN ?
[Male Interpreter]
6:04 A.M.
[Female Interpreter]
CAPTAIN, HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE
THE ACCUSED'S STATE OF MIND ?
[Male Interpreter]
SURPRISED.
[Female Interpreter]
IN THE SITUATION, WOULD YOU
DESCRIBE "SURPRISED"...
AS A RATIONAL RESPONSE ?
[Male Interpreter]
NO.
[Female Interpreter]
WOULD YOU DESCRIBE "SURPRISED"
AS A SANE RESPONSE ?
WHAT WAS HE WAITING FOR,
HIS OWN ARREST ?
OBJECTION !
I'D LIKE TO CONFER
WITH MY ADVOCATE, YOUR HONOR.
I AM NOT INSANE.
I WAS NOT DRUNK.
I AM NOT GOING TO PLEAD
DIMINISHED CAPACITY.
I AM OBLIGED TO DO
WHAT IS REQUIRED...
TO AVOID
YOUR EXECUTION.
[Female Interpreter]
ADVOCATE, DOES THE DEFENSE
HAVE FURTHER QUESTIONS...
FOR THIS WITNESS ?
YES, I HAVE QUESTIONS.
I AM NOT FINISHED.
ACCORDING TO ARTICLE 26
OF THE PROCEDURE LAW...
OR ARTICLE 32 OF
THE AMENDED VERSION OF THE SAME,
I HAVE THE RIGHT
TO DEFEND MYSELF...
TO COMMENT ON AND ASK QUESTIONS
OF WITNESSES...
EVEN IF MY ADVOCATE
HAS ALREADY QUESTIONED THEM.
ACCUSED MOORE, THIS RIGHT
IS RARELY EXERCISED.
I KNOW, BUT I DO HAVE
THE RIGHT TO EXERCISE IT,
YOUR HONOR.
THE APPROPRIATE FORM OF ADDRESS
IS PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
YOU MAY PROCEED.
ASK YOUR QUESTION.
THANK YOU,
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
CAPTAIN,
YOU TESTIFIED THAT
YOU ENTERED MY ROOM AT 6:04.
WHEN YOU ENTERED MY ROOM,
THE BLOOD YOU FOUND ON MY HANDS
AND SHIRT,
WAS IT WET OR DRY ?
[Male Interpreter]
DRY.
DRY.  THE SCREAMS
WERE HEARD AT 5:45.
WOULDN'T IT HAVE TAKEN
MORE THAT 19 MINUTES
FOR SO MUCH BLOOD TO DRY ?
[Male Interpreter]
USUALLY, YES.
SO THE MURDER MUST'VE
TAKEN PLACE BEFORE 5:45 A.M.
[Male Interpreter]
PERHAPS.
[Jack]
IF THE MURDER TOOK PLACE
BEFORE 5:45,
WHO WAS THERE TO SCREAM
AT 5:45 ?
[Male Interpreter]
PERHAPS YOU.
PERHAPS ME ?  WHY WOULD I
HAVE BEEN SCREAMING ?
YOU WERE DRUNK.
[Male Interpreter]
TWO BOTTLES OF SCOTCH...
HAD BEEN EMPTIED.
NO, NOT TWO BOTTLES.
ONLY ONE.  ONE BOTTLE.
I ORDERED ONE BOTTLE.
YOU CAN VERIFY THAT
FROM ROOM SERVICE RECORDS.
MR. MOORE.
[Male Interpreter]
YOUR FINGERPRINTS WERE FOUND
ON BOTH BOTTLES.
AND THE HOTEL RECORDS SHOW
THAT TWO BOTTLES WERE ORDERED.
[Chairman Xu]
ACCUSED MOORE,
ARE YOU FINISHED ?
ARE YOU QUITE FINISHED ?
JUST ONE MORE QUESTION,
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
CAPTAIN, DID YOU FIND
A GOLD LOCKET...
ON OR ABOUT THE PERSON
OF THE VICTIM, HONG LING ?
[Male Interpreter]
I HAVE NO INFORMATION
ABOUT A LOCKET.
THERE WAS A LOCKET THERE.
I'M SURE THERE WAS.
WHERE IS IT NOW ?
[Ma In Chinese]
[Laughing]
WHAT--  I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T GET A TRANSLATION.
WHY ARE THEY LAUGHING ?
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
HOW CAN I BE EXPECTED
TO MOUNT A DEFENSE...
IF I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
THE PROCURATOR ?
THE PEOPLE'S ASSESSOR
MAY NOT BE INTERESTED
IN LISTENING, BUT I AM !
[Chairman Xu
In Chinese]
ACCUSED MOORE,
WHAT THE PROCURATOR SAID THAT
BROUGHT LEVITY TO THIS COURT...
WAS PERHAPS THE VICTIM
HAD A MAGIC WAND,
AND TURNED THE LOCKET
INTO A SECOND BOTTLE OF SCOTCH.
ARE YOU FINISHED NOW,
ACCUSED MOORE ?
YES, I AM FINISHED.
[Female Interpreter]
THE COURT IS DISMISSED.
IN OUR COUNTRY, IT IS WISE
NOT TO RAISE QUESTIONS...
TO WHICH YOU DO NOT KNOW
THE ANSWER.
MY COUNTRY TOO.
IF YOU WISHED TO HAVE LAW BOOKS,
YOU SHOULD HAVE REQUESTED THEM
FROM ME.
I HEAR YOU'VE
BEEN QUESTIONED.
THEN YOU APPRECIATE
THE SITUATION I'M IN.
YOU SHOULD GO HOME.
WHAT SHOULD I TELL DAVID
ABOUT HOFFMANN ?
UH, TELL DAVID...
[Sighs]
TO LET HOFFCO
HAVE THE SATELLITE.
[Jack]
CONCENTRATE ON AMERICAN
CONTENT PRODUCTION.
MAKE HOFFMANN PAY
THROUGH THE NOSE.
YOU THINK THE WORLD'S WAITING
FOR PROGRAMMING FROM BONN ?
[Chuckles]
I DOUBT IT.
[Ghery]
YEAH.  I MEAN,
IF A CHINESE GUY WOKE UP
AT THE PLAZA HOTEL...
WITH A DEAD
AMERICAN GIRL...
IN HIS SUITE, AND
THE CHINESE GOVERNMENT TRIED
TO MUSCLE IN ON HIS TRIAL,
I KINDA SEE THEIR POINT.
YOUR LAWYER'S VERY GOOD.
SHE EVEN GOT A FEW
DISSIDENTS OFF.
GO ON.
[Jack]
GIVE MY BEST
TO JANIE AND THE KIDS.
I WILL.
GET OUT OF HERE.
THANKS, JACK.
I'LL BE BACK.
MR. MOORE ?
I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS...
TO ASK YOU.
BUT, UH...
IF YOU STILL PREFER
THAT I RESIGN,
I WILL DO AS YOU WISH.
NO, I DO NOT PREFER.
[Bicycle Bell Rings]
[Yuelin]
ROLL IT, PLEASE.
WHAT IS MY COUNTRY GIRL
WITH A CITY MOUTH
LOOKING FOR ?
THE TRUTH
ABOUT MY CLIENT.
WAIT.  FREEZE IT.
HIT "PLAY."
I HAVE A CERTAIN SYMPATHY
FOR YOUR AMERICAN.
ONE MAN
AGAINST EVERYONE.
VERY COOL.
PENG, BACK IT UP.
[Yuelin]
STOP.
[Bicycle Bell Rings]
[Chinese]
WHAT ?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
NO, NO.
NO !  YOU CANNOT HAVE
THIS BOOK !  NO !
NO !  NO !
[Buzzing]
NO, YOU CAN'T HAVE--
NO !
[Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
I WISH TO SPEAK
OF THE LOCKET YOU SAID
HONG LING WAS WEARING.
SHE WAS WEARING A LOCKET.
I KNOW.  I HAVE CONFIRMATION
THAT SHE WAS.
CONFIRMATION ?
YOU DIDN'T BELIEVE ME ?
THE LOCKET WAS A GIFT
FROM HER FATHER.
HE ASKED
FOR ITS RETURN.
WHERE IS IT ?
IT HAS NOT BEEN FOUND.
YOU FIND THAT INSIGNIFICANT ?
XIE XIE.
[Equipment Beeping]
[Beeping]
[Door Lock Clicks]
OPEN THIS.
I HAVE ALREADY
EXAMINED THIS.
SMELL IT.
WHAT DO YOU SMELL ?
[Sniffs]
- SOMETHING STRANGE.
- EXACTLY.
[Female Interpreter]
DR. TAO, DO YOU DETECT
A CHEMICAL ODOR ON THIS SHIRT ?
A FAMILIAR CHEMICAL ODOR ?
[Male Interpreter]
THESE QUESTIONS
SERVE NO PURPOSE.
- [Chairman Xu In Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]
WE WILL SEE.  CONTINUE.
[Female Interpreter]
GIVE US YOUR EXPERT OPINION TO
WHAT YOU BELIEVE THE ODOR TO BE.
[Male Interpreter]
MAYBE CHLOROFORM
OR AN ETHER DERIVATIVE.
[Female Interpreter]  COULD
CHLOROFORM OR ETHER BE USED
TO RENDER SOMEONE UNCONSCIOUS ?
[Male Interpreter]
YES, IT COULD.  THESE QUESTIONS
WASTE THE COURT'S TIME.
[Female Interpreter]
I WILL MAKE THAT DECISION.
CONTINUE.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
THE ACCUSED HAD NEITHER
CHLOROFORM NOR ETHER...
IN HIS POSSESSION
AT THE TIME
HE ENTERED THE COUNTRY.
AND NO AUTHORIZATION
WAS ISSUED FOR HIM
TO PURCHASE EITHER CHEMICAL.
NEITHER CHEMICAL
WAS FOUND...
IN HIS HOTEL ROOM.
THEREFORE, THESE CHEMICALS
MUST'VE BEEN BROUGHT TO
THE CRIME SCENE BY SOMEONE ELSE.
BY THE SOMEONE ELSE WHO RENDERED
MR. MOORE UNCONSCIOUS.
BY THE SOMEONE ELSE
WHO MURDERED HONG LING.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
THE ACCUSED WISHES
TO CHANGE HIS PLEA
TO "NOT GUILTY."
- [Chairman Xu In Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]
THE COURT IS DISMISSED.
[Woman Over Loudspeaker
In Chinese]
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
AGH !
[Grunting]
[Chinese]
[Groaning]
[Shouting In Chinese]
[Telephone Ringing]
[Ringing]
[Chinese]
[Vendor Shouting
In Chinese]
[Crowd Chattering]
IN ADDITION, I WANT TO SEE
ANY OF HONG LING'S EFFECTS
GATHERED AT THE SCENE.
WHY DO YOU PUT YOURSELF
AT RISK FOR THIS FOREIGNER ?
- THIS FOREIGNER
WAS ATTACKED LAST NIGHT.
- BECAUSE HE IS A FOREIGNER.
I MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO PROTECT YOU THIS TIME.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR CONCERN,
DIVISION CHIEF LI.
[Shouts In Chinese]
[People Chattering,
Baby Crying]
[Knocks At Door]
GOOD MORNING,
MR. MOORE.
I WAS INFORMED
THAT YOU WERE ATTACKED
LAST NIGHT.
ARE YOU OKAY ?
YEAH,
I'M ALL RIGHT.
WHAT AM I DOING HERE ?
IT IS A PROVISIONAL
GUARANTEE.
THE COURT WILL
NOT MEET TODAY SO THAT WE
MAY PREPARE YOUR DEFENSE.
RIGHT.
EMBASSY FINALLY
GOT OFF ITS ASS.
YOU MUST RETURN
TO CONFINEMENT...
AT NIGHTFALL.
WOULD YOU LIKE TEA,
MR. MOORE ?
YES, TEA...
PLEASE.
OKAY.
[Sighs]
[Trills Piano Keys]
[Piano Continues]
YOU PLAY THE PIANO ?
I AM TEACHING MYSELF.
MY PROGRESS IS SLOW.
WHEN I WAS YOUNGER,
I PLAYED THE CHINESE INSTRUMENT,
THE PIBA.
THE WHAT ?
PIBA.
[Clears Throat]
WHAT DOES IT
SOUND LIKE ?
WE HAVE MUCH TO DO.
NO, PLEASE.
PLAY FOR ME.
[Sighs]
I'D LIKE TO HEAR
SOME MUSIC AGAIN.
[Strums Piba]
YOU HAVE BEAUTIFUL HANDS.
WHY DID YOU STOP ?
WE HAVE LITTLE TIME
AND MUCH TO DO.
[Chinese]
MY GRANDMOTHER.
- [Chinese]
[Laughs]
IT'S A GREAT HONOR
TO MEET YOU.
UH...
[Chinese]
[Laughs,
Chinese]
[Chinese]
SO, YOUR PARENTS
ARE DECEASED ?
YEAH.
AND BROTHERS
AND SISTERS ?
NO.
AND A WIFE ?
NO WIFE.
FOR US, TO BE WITHOUT A FAMILY
IS A TERRIBLE THING.
BUT YOU'VE NEVER MARRIED.
I HAVE BEEN UNABLE TO FIND A MAN
WHO'S NOT THREATENED
BY A WOMAN'S INTELLIGENCE.
[Laughs]
WITH HALF A BILLION MEN IN THIS
COUNTRY, IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE.
YES, ISN'T IT ?
YOU HAD A PRESTIGIOUS...
AND EXPENSIVE EDUCATION
AT HARVARD AND
STANFORD LAW SCHOOL.
I HAD SCHOLARSHIPS.
I SERVED DRINKS
AT RICH PEOPLE'S PARTIES.
YOU PURSUED LAW...
BECAUSE YOU WANTED TO BE
ONE OF THE RICH PEOPLE
YOU SERVED ?
NO.  I WANTED
TO BE IN CONTROL.
AND WERE YOU ?
I THOUGHT I WAS.
UNTIL NOW.
[Sighs]
[Clears Throat]
YOU ASKED ME IF I HAD A WIFE.
I SAID NO.
I DON'T,
BUT I DID.
WE HAD A DAUGHTER
SEVEN YEARS OLD.
THEY WERE IN A TAXI
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THERE WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I AM SORRY.
ANYTHING ELSE
YOU WANT TO KNOW ?
UM...
WHAT WAS YOUR FIRST CONTACT
WITH HONG LING ?
DO YOU THINK
I KILLED HER ?
MY JOB IS TO FIND THE TRUTH,
TO HANDLE THIS CASE...
ACCORDING TO LAW.
DO YOU BELIEVE ME
OR NOT ?
I HAVE GROWING QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED THAT NIGHT.
NOW, PLEASE TELL ME
OF YOUR FIRST CONTACT
WITH HONG LING.
[Yuelin]
DID YOU APPROACH HER ?
NO, SHE WAS--
SHE WAS MODELING.
SOME KIND OF FASHION SHOW.
YOU SIMPLY SAW HER ?
WE SAW EACH OTHER.
YOUR EYES MET ?
I GUESS SO.
ARE YOU SURE ?
YES, I'M SURE.
SO YOU WERE
ATTRACTED TO HER ?
YEAH.  YES,
I WAS ATTRACTED.
BECAUSE SHE
WAS BEAUTIFUL ?
[Sighs]
I GUESS SO.
YOU APPROACHED HER LATER
WHEN YOU SAW HER AT THE TABLE ?
I WAS OVER THERE.
SHE WAS OVER HERE.
SHE WAS LOOKING AT ME
AND DRAWING SOMETHING.
SO YOU WERE CURIOUS,
THEN YOU APPROACHED HER ?
WHAT WAS SHE DRAWING ?
MY NOSE.
SHE SAID, "DA BI ZI."
[Laughs]
"DA BI ZI."
IT MEANS... BIG NOSE.
BIG NOSE, YEAH.
THANKS.
[Laughs]
WE WERE SITTING THERE
AND TALKING...
AND LOOKING
AT HER DRAWINGS...
AND LAUGHING.
WE JUST CLICKED.
"CLICKED."
YOU MEAN CHEMISTRY.
IS THAT THE RIGHT WORD ?
MM-HMM.
CHEMISTRY.  CLICKED.
SO...
YOU ARE A ROMANTIC.
YOU WERE DRAWN
TO EACH OTHER.
DID YOU KISS ?
NOT HERE, NO.
TO RETURN HERE
IS DIFFICULT FOR YOU.
DO YOU REMEMBER ANYTHING
UNUSUAL HAPPENING ?
THINK BACK.
IS THAT THE PROPER WAY
TO SAY IT ?
THAT'S FINE.
SHE GOT A PHONE CALL.
IT UPSET HER.
- [Yuelin]
ON THE HOTEL PHONE ?
- NO, IT WAS ON HER CELLULAR.
SHE, UH--
SHE SAID IT WAS NOTHING.
PERIOD.  MEISHI.
- MEISHI.
- MEISHI !  MEISHI !
[Chuckles]
ANYTHING ELSE ?
SHE SAID--
[Chinese]
DOES THAT MEAN ANYTHING ?
NO.  YOU DID NOT
HEAR HER SCREAM ?
NO, NO.
BUT SOMEONE MADE
AN ANONYMOUS CALL
TO THE POLICE...
CLAIMING TO HEAR SCREAMS
COMING FROM THIS SUITE.
THIS IS AN OLD HOTEL,
ISN'T IT ?
LET ME SEE.
IT'S VERY SOLIDLY CONSTRUCTED.
OUTER DOOR
AND AN INNER DOOR.
[Screams]
[Chinese]
NO, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
MEISHI, MEISHI.
YOU HEAR ANYTHING ?
NO.  COME.
THESE ARE OBJECTS
HONG LING HAD WITH HER
IN THIS ROOM.
THE POLICE DEVELOPED
THE PICTURES.
THE LAST CALL SHE MADE
ON THIS PHONE WAS 5-1-7-8-5-7.
IT HAS BEEN DISCONNECTED.
- [Chinese]
- THERE MUST BE A CENTRAL
TELEPHONE EXCHANGE.
THAT'S WHERE
THE BILLING RECORDS ARE KEPT.
WE ARE GOING THERE NOW.
WHY ARE YOU SMILING ?
I'M USUALLY THE ONE WHO
FIGURES OUT THE NEXT STEP.
OH.
THIS MUST BE EXTREMELY DIFFICULT
TO RELY ON A STRANGER, A WOMAN,
A FOREIGN WOMAN,
IN SUCH A SERIOUS MATTER.
THAT'S WHY I SMILED.
YOU WILL WAIT HERE,
PLEASE.
[Chinese]
[TV Announcer
In Chinese]
[Chinese]
[TV: Chinese]
[German]
[Male Interpreter]
...HAS SELECTED
HOFFCO TELEKOMM...
AS CHINA'S PARTNER
IN THIS MULTIBILLION DOLLAR
SATELLITE UNDERTAKING.
[Chinese]
[Jack]
WHAT'S WRONG ?
THE RECORDS
CANNOT BE ACCESSED.
THEY HAVE BEEN DELETED.
BY WHOM ?
DO NOT TALK
ABOUT THIS HERE.
WHO DELETED THE RECORDS ?
WHO HAS THE POWER
TO DELETE TELEPHONE RECORDS ?
COULD YOU DELETE YOUR RECORDS ?
YOU COULDN'T, COULD YOU ?
'CAUSE YOU'RE NOT
A GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL.
ONLY A GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL
COULD AUTHORIZE THE DELETION
OF THESE RECORDS.
IS THAT IT ?
IS THAT TRUE ?
WHOEVER LING CALLED THAT NIGHT--
MIGHT KNOW SOMETHING ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED.  DO NOT SAY MORE.
WE MUST LEAVE NOW.
IF THAT PERSON IS A GOVERNMENT
OFFICIAL OF A GOVERNMENT
I'M NEGOTIATING WITH--
IF I COULD BE EMBARRASSED
OR DISCREDITED IN SOME WAY,
MAYBE HE GETS A BETTER DEAL
WITH MY COMPETITOR.
SWEET SYSTEM
YOU'VE GOT HERE.
THE RECORDS WERE NOT DELETED
BY THE SYSTEM.  THEY WERE
DELETED BY AN INDIVIDUAL.
INDIVIDUAL.  OKAY.
I'LL GO WITH THAT.
WHO DO WE HAVE ?
WE HAVE MINISTER LIN SHOU
AND HERR HOFFMANN.
NO.
WHAT ABOUT GENERAL HONG ?
IT IS NOT GENERAL HONG.
WHY NOT ?  HE'S GOT INFLUENCE
WITH THE P.S.B., WITH EVERYBODY.
GENERAL HONG IS NOT CORRUPT.
HE ONLY WANTS THE KILLER
OF HIS DAUGHTER PUNISHED.
HE'S OLD GUARD !
HE'S LOSING CONTROL.
YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
NO, YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND !
THIS IS A SATELLITE
COMMUNICATIONS DEAL.
AND FOR BETTER OR FOR WORSE,
THE EFFECT
OF THE McANDREWS DEAL...
WOULD HAVE BEEN TO OPEN
A TOTALLY CLOSED SYSTEM.
WHO ARE YOU TO CRITICIZE ?
ONCE THAT SYSTEM OPENS UP,
THERE'S NO GOING BACK.
YOU COME FROM A COUNTRY
WHERE THE INFANT MORTALITY
RATE IS HIGHER THAN OURS.
THE REASON YOU KNOW THAT
IS WE DON'T DELETE THE RECORDS.
- WHERE PEOPLE ARE PUNISHED
FOR THE COLOR OF THEIR SKIN.
- HAVE YOU EVER BEEN THERE ?
YOU FIND IT EASY TO ASSUME
THAT A CHINESE FATHER
WOULD KILL HIS DAUGHTER...
TO STOP YOUR PRECIOUS
BUSINESS DEAL !
I DO NOT FIND THAT EASY
TO ASSUME.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
ARE KILLED EACH WEEK
IN YOUR PEACEFUL COUNTRY ?
I DON'T FIND THAT EASY
TO ASSUME.
HOW MANY, MR. MOORE ?
TOO MANY.
[Horn Honking]
[Shouting]
[Horns Honking]
[Honking]
[Gunshot]
[Gunshots]
[Groans]
[Gunshot]
JACK !
- [Jack]  I GOTTA GO !
- JACK, DON'T !
JACK !
[Shouting]
[P.S.B. Officer]
STOP !
[Woman Shouts]
SORRY !
[Shouting]
GET OUTTA MY WAY !
[Horns Honking]
[Shouts]
LOOK OUT !
[Shouting,
Excited Chatting]
LOOK OUT !  LOOK OUT !
[Chinese]
SHIT !
[Shouting]
[Chinese]
[Babbles]
[Quacking]
SHH.  SHH.
[Chinese]
[Shouting
In Chinese]
[Motorcycle Engine
Revving]
[Revving Continues]
[Officer Yelling
In Chinese]
[Chinese]
- [Old Woman Shouting]
- [P.S.B. Officers
In Chinese]
[Gunfire]
[Chinese]
[Camera Shutter Clicking]
[Girls Scream]
[Chinese]
[Siren Wailing]
[Wailing Continues]
OPEN UP !
I'M AN AMERICAN CITIZEN
SEEKING ASYLUM !
- [Siren Wailing]
- OPEN UP !
MAY I SEE YOUR PASSPORT, SIR ?
IF I HAD A PASSPORT,
I WOULDN'T NEED ASYLUM !
PLEASE,
YOU'VE GOTTA LET ME IN.
LET ME MAKE A PHONE CALL.
[Siren Wailing]
OH, MAN.
PRATT,
I'M REQUESTING ASYLUM.
THIS IS A CONFIDENTIAL MATTER.
THIS IS NOT THE PLACE FOR US
TO HOLD THIS DISCUSSION.
WE GOTTA
HOLD IT SOMEWHERE.
VERY GOOD ACOUSTICS.
THIS USED TO BE THE PAKISTANI
EMBASSY.  BEFORE THAT, IT WAS
WIRED TO THE HILT BY THE P.R.C.
FOLLOW ME.
[Pratt]
THIS, HOWEVER,
IS ENTIRELY BUG FREE.
MR. MOORE.
PEYTON REED.
JACK.
THE AMBASSADOR HAS ALREADY
BEEN SUMMONED TO SEE THE
MINISTER OF EXTERNAL AFFAIRS.
THIS HAS THE MAKINGS
OF A FULL-SCALE INCIDENT.
FULL-SCALE INCIDENT !
[Laughing]
SORRY I DIDN'T CALL
FOR AN APPOINTMENT.
DO THE TWO OF YOU
HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT I'VE BEEN THROUGH ?
- NO.  I AM NOT LEAVING HERE.
- NO ONE SAID YOU SHOULD LEAVE.
I'M NOT GOING.
[Pratt]
OF COURSE NOT.
NO, YOU'RE IN... BUT
GETTING OUT IS ANOTHER STORY.
YOU'VE GOTTEN OTHER PEOPLE OUT.
YOU CAN GET ME OUT.
IT TOOK US A YEAR TO GET
THOSE CHINESE PHYSICISTS OUT,
FANG LIZHI AND HIS WIFE.
AND THE CHINESE ARMY THREATENED
TO STORM THE EMBASSY.
THAT WAS A SIMPLE ASYLUM CASE.
YOU'RE CHARGED
WITH A CAPITAL CRIME.
THIS BECOMES AN INTERNATIONAL
DICK-MEASURING CONTEST,
THEY MIGHT NEVER LET YOU LEAVE.
WHAT ?
WHAT IS IT ?
YOUR ATTORNEY SHEN YUELIN
IS AT THE GUARD STATION.
SHE WISHES TO SEE YOU.
I WOULD ADVISE
NO CONTACT.
[Pratt]  IT WILL ONLY
MAKE THINGS HARDER FOR HER.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ?
- YUELIN PUT UP YOUR GUARANTEE.
I THOUGHT THE EMBASSY
PUT IT UP.
NO.
IN CHINA, BAIL HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH MONEY.
IT'S REPUTATION.
[Reed]  TO HAVE YOU
RELEASED TODAY SO THAT
SHE COULD PREPARE A DEFENSE,
SHEN YUELIN PUT UP
HER CAREER, HER FUTURE.
IT WAS REALLY
QUITE UNIQUE.
[Sirens Wailing]
YUELIN ?
YOUR SHOULDER !
OH, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
- IF I'D KNOWN WHAT YOU DID
FOR ME, I WOULDN'T HAVE LEFT.
- I'M GLAD YOU LEFT.
GLAD ?
YES.
BECAUSE I'M NOT SURE
I COULD HAVE SAVED YOU FROM
THE DECISION OF THE COURT.
AND I... I COULD NOT
HAVE LIVED WITH THAT.
WHY DID YOU RISK
YOUR LIFE FOR ME
IF YOU DIDN'T BELIEVE ME ?
I ALWAYS ASSUMED THE WORST
ABOUT YOU.
I HAVE NEVER QUESTIONED.
I HAVE ALWAYS
ACCEPTED THINGS.
IT IS THE SAME
AS WHEN I WAS A CHILD.
WHY ?
I WAS BLIND.
I WAS MUTE.
WHEN YOU WERE A CHILD,
IT WAS DURING
THE CULTURAL REVOLUTION,
WASN'T IT ?
YES.
WHAT IS IT ?
I WENT TO SCHOOL
UNTIL THEY CLOSED DOWN
AND EVERYTHING WENT MAD.
I DO NOT KNOW IF YOU COULD
UNDERSTAND THIS, JACK MOORE.
TRY ME.
I... I WATCHED--
I WATCHED MY FATHER
BE HUMILIATED,
AND I SAID NOTHING.
I WATCHED MY FATHER
BE SPAT ON.
I DID NOTHING.
I EVEN WATCHED
MY CLASSMATES POUR BLACK INK
OVER HIS HEAD...
ONE AFTER ANOTHER
AND AFTER ANOTHER.
WHAT DID I DO ?
I HID MY HEAD IN SHAME
WHILE HE WAS DRAGGED AWAY.
I NEVER QUESTIONED.
I WAS BLIND.
I'M VERY SORRY
THAT I DID NOT BELIEVE
YOUR INNOCENCE.
BUT NOW, I DO.
I DO.
SOMEBODY ALERTED THE PRESS.
LET'S GET YOU OUT OF HERE...
BEFORE YOUR FACE IS ON THE COVER
OF TIME AND NEWSWEEK.
[Excited Chatting]
[Whispering]
WO MEN.
[Chinese]
WO MEN GUANXI--
[Phone Dialing]
[Gasps]
A CERTAIN GENERAL
HAS A PERSONAL INTEREST...
IN SEEING THAT SOME
OF THIS EVIDENCE IS RETURNED.
IF, BY CHANCE, ANY ONE
OF THE ARRESTING OFFICERS...
POCKETED THIS EVIDENCE
AND IT IS NOT RETURNED,
THEN EVEN AN ATTORNEY
AS GOOD AS I AM
CANNOT ENSURE YOUR WELL-BEING.
I SUGGEST
THAT YOU SEARCH AGAIN.
ANYTHING YOU MIGHT TURN UP CAN
BE GIVEN TO MY AIDE AND BROUGHT
TO THE COURT FOR SAFEKEEPING.
[Rifle Shots]
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
I NEED YOUR COUNSEL.
I WANT YOU TO WALK AWAY
FROM THIS.
I'M TRYING TO GET ACCESS
TO EVIDENCE WHICH WOULD HELP
TO PROVE YOUR INNOCENCE.
NO.  I WANT YOU
TO WALK AWAY NOW.
WHY DID YOU NOT ?
THE SMART THING
WOULD HAVE BEEN
TO STAY AT THE EMBASSY.
YEAH.  AND MOVE PAST IT.
YES, I DO THAT REALLY WELL.
WHY DID YOU NOT ?
DID YOU EVER SEE LITTLE GIRLS
PLAY SOCCER ?
LITTLE... SILLY BUNDLES
OF ENERGY...
SWARMING ALL OVER EACH OTHER,
TRIPPING ON EACH OTHER.
HAIR RIBBONS
LEFT ON THE GROUND
WHEN THEY'RE THROUGH.
YOUR DAUGHTER ?
YEAH.  THEY WERE--
THEY WERE DRIVING BACK
FROM A GAME WHEN IT HAPPENED,
THE ACCIDENT.
AND YOU WERE ?
I WAS IN TOKYO.
I WAS--
I WAS CLOSING A DEAL.
I COULD HAVE FINISHED IT
THE DAY BEFORE
IF I'D WANTED TO.
YOU CANNOT BLAME YOURSELF.
NO, I DIDN'T.
I SET IT ASIDE.
I JUST MOVED PAST IT.
BUILT A WALL AROUND IT.
I HIRED SOMEBODY TO CLOSE UP
THE HOUSE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
I GOT ON A PLANE,
WENT SOMEWHERE
TO DO SOMETHING.
AND I DID IT AGAIN
AND AGAIN,
AND I ENDED UP HERE.
BUT WHAT YOU LEAVE BEHIND
CATCHES UP WITH YOU.
TOOK ME A LONG TIME
TO LEARN THAT.
IF I HAD STAYED IN THE EMBASSY,
YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN IN DANGER.
I AM NOT MOVING PAST THIS.
JACK.
YOU ONCE OFFERED TO RESIGN.
I WANT YOU TO DO THAT.
I WANT YOU TO DO THAT NOW.
MY DUTY IS TO PROVE
YOUR INNOCENCE.
IT IS ALSO--
IT IS ALSO MY WISH.
COURAGE.  YONG QI.
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
[Sighs]
YUELIN ?
WHY DID YOU COME HERE ?
I AM HERO !
A RECORD OF CALLS MADE TO
AND FROM HER CELL PHONE...
AND A PRINTOUT AT HOME.
PENG !
WHERE DID YOU GET THIS ?
MY FRIEND MAI.
SHE SAY I AM
THE WORLD'S GREATEST LOVER.
AND NOW I AM HERO TOO.
PENG, HOW DID YOU
TALK YOUR WAY PAST
THE SECURITY MAN OUTSIDE ?
I DID NOT HAVE TO.
THERE WAS NOBODY THERE.
COME, PENG,
YOU LEAVE NOW.
GO ON, LEAVE.
[Gasps]
[Groaning]
- [Screams]
- YUELIN ?
[Gasping]
[Coughing]
[Pratt]  IT DOESN'T BRIGHTEN
THE SITUATION THAT YOUR ATTORNEY
GOT ROUGHED UP LAST NIGHT.
MY ATTORNEY GOT WHAT ?
SHE WAS A TRACE ROUGHED UP
LAST NIGHT.
A LITTLE BRUISED
IS ALL.
BRUISED ?  WHAT--
BY WHO ?
SHE DIDN'T KNOW WHO.
SHE WAS IN THE HOTEL SUITE WHERE
THE VICTIM EXPIRED.  SHE'S MORE
SHOOK UP THAN ANYTHING.
STOP.  GO BACK.
NO, I'M AFRAID
THERE'S NO STOPPING IT NOW.
THE INSTANT YOU LEFT SANCTUARY,
YOU WAY OVERSHOT ANY POINT
OF POSSIBLE RETURN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING !
YOU LEFT
THE EMBASSY OUT ON A LIMB.
- WE'VE GOT ZERO OPTIONS.
- THE EMBASSY OUT ON A LIMB ?
WHAT ABOUT HER ?
-YOU DIDN'T MAKE OUR JOB EASIER.
-ALL RIGHT !  MEISHI !
WHAT ABOUT HER ?
- I TOLD YOU NOT TO TALK TO HER.
- HOW ?  SHE'S THE ONE PUTTING
HERSELF ON THE LINE FOR ME !
SHE'S NOT OUR JOB.
SHE'S OUT THERE ALL ALONE,
ISN'T SHE ?
YES.
WHAT HAPPENED ?
I HAVE THE
TELEPHONE RECORDS.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
WHATEVER GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL
CALLED HONG LING THAT NIGHT...
ALSO HAD CONVERSATIONS
WITH A P.S.B. OFFICER
NAMED HUAN MINGLU.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I DON'T WANT YOU HURT.
I HAVE REQUESTED
HIS PRESENCE IN COURT TODAY.
IT DOES MATTER.
IT WILL MATTER.
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS ?
YOU COULD BE TAKEN...
FROM YOUR HOUSE,
FROM YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
YOU COULD BE SENT AWAY
OR PUT HERE... OR WORSE.
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING IT ?
I'M DOING THIS
BECAUSE...
I DO NOT WISH
TO BE SILENT ANYMORE.
SUPERVISING JUDGES.
THEY ARE HERE TO MONITOR.
IT MEANS
TODAY IS THE DAY.
PROCURATOR GENERAL YANG
NEXT TO GENERAL HONG.
AND MANY OF
THE PARTY ELDERS.
[Chairman Xu
In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
THIS FINAL SESSION
OF OUR PEOPLE'S COURT...
HEARING CRIMINAL CASE 4-1-1-6
IS NOW OPEN.
COURT IS IN SESSION.
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
I WISH TO SUMMON HUAN MINGLU
TO THE WITNESS STAND.
[Male Interpreter]
HUAN MINGLU HAS NOT BEEN
INTRODUCED AS A WITNESS.
THIS MAN MAY KNOW THE TRUTH
OF WHAT HAPPENED TO HONG LING.
[Female Interpreter]  ADVOCATE
SHEN YUELIN, THIS APPEARS
TO BE A DIVERSIONARY TACTIC.
[Male Interpreter]
THIS IS PURE MANIPULATION
OF THE FACTS.
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]  ADVOCATE
SHEN YUELIN, REQUEST DENIED.
I CAN OFFER EVIDENCE
THAT HUAN MINGLU ATTACKED
THE ACCUSED AND ME IN DAZHALAN.
[Female Interpreter]
SUCH EVIDENCE IS OUTSIDE
THE SCOPE OF THIS PROCEEDING.
AND ATTEMPTED TO MURDER
THE ACCUSED IN BEIJING
NUMBER ONE DETENTION CENTER.
[Male Interpreter]
I MUST PROTEST
ONCE MORE AGAIN.
THIS IS CRUCIAL EVIDENCE
THAT SUGGESTS
THE ACCUSED IS INNOCENT.
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN,
THERE'S A PROCEDURE FOR BRINGING
UNRELATED CHARGES.
WHEN WILL THAT BE ?
AFTER MY CLIENT IS SENTENCED
OR AFTER HE IS EXECUTED ?
ANSWER ME, PLEASE.
[Female Interpreter]
ENOUGH !
WE MUST CALL AN END TO TESTIMONY
ONLY INDIRECTLY RELATED.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN--
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
WILL YOU PLEASE SIT DOWN ?
NO, PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
- [Chairman Xu In Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]
WHAT DID YOU SAY ?
A MAN'S LIFE IS AT STAKE.
NOT AN AMERICAN LIFE,
NOT A CHINESE LIFE.
A MAN'S LIFE.
IN SUCH CIRCUMSTANCES...
WHAT I AM ASKING IS NOT
AN UNREASONABLE REQUEST.
[Chairman Xu
In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
I WILL DECIDE WHAT IS REASONABLE
AND UNREASONABLE.
[Chairman Xu In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
NOW SIT DOWN.
- [Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]
I SAID, SIT DOWN.
THE MATTER IS DECIDED.
THE COURT IS NOT INTERESTED IN
THE TESTIMONY OF SUCH WITNESSES.
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
- I AM.
- YOU ARE WHAT ?
I AM INTERESTED IN HEARING.
WHAT ABOUT YOU ?
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
I HAVE ALREADY RULED.
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
WHY NOT ?
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN, THE VOTE
ON THIS MATTER IS TWO TO ONE.
WITH THE APPROVAL OF THE COURT,
I SUMMON HUAN MINGLU
AS A WITNESS.
[Man]
HUAN MINGLU ?
[Whispering]
WHAT'S HAPPENING ?
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
[Li Cheng]
YUELIN.
[Whispering]
YOU CUT THE SOUND.
I'VE LOST THE SOUND AGAIN !
IT'S OKAY.
THE PROCURATOR GENERAL
WISHES TO SEE ME.
WHY DO THEY WANT YOU ?
TRUST ME.
EVERYTHING WILL BE OKAY.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[Chairman Xu In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
BE SEATED.
[Chairman Xu
In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
I DECLARE THE PEOPLE'S BEIJING
INTERMEDIATE COURT...
HEARING CRIMINAL CASE 4-1-1-6
ONCE AGAIN OPEN.
DEFENSE ADVOCATE
IS NOT PRESENT.
[Jack]  NOR IS HER AIDE.
[Female Interpreter]  THEN
THE WITNESS SHOULD STEP DOWN.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN--
NO, WAIT A MINUTE.
TING, TING, TING.
[Chairman Xu]  YES ?
I'M ENTITLED TO QUESTION
THIS WITNESS.
YOUR RIGHT TO QUESTION
HAS BEEN PREVIOUSLY
ESTABLISHED.
YOU MAY DO SO,
BRIEFLY, AND TO THE POINT.
I CANNOT SIGN IT.
HUAN MINGLU, AT APPROXIMATELY
2:00 A.M. ON THE MORNING
OF THE MURDER...
RECORDS INDICATE
THAT YOU RECEIVED A CALL
FROM AN UNLISTED CELL PHONE.
YOU REMEMBER WHO MADE
THAT CALL ?
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
IRRELEVANT !  THIS IS A WASTE
OF THE COURT'S TIME.
[Chairman Xu]
YOU MAY PROCEED, ACCUSED MOORE.
PLEASE BE DIRECT...
BEFORE EVEN YOUR FRIENDS,
THE PEOPLE'S ASSESSORS,
MAY LOSE THEIR PATIENCE.
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHO CALLED YOU ?
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
IT WAS THE WRONG NUMBER.
WRONG NUMBER ?  THEN WHY DID
THE CALL LAST FIVE MINUTES ?
[Minglu In Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
MAYBE IT WAS SOMEONE
TALKATIVE LIKE THE ACCUSED.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN, WOULD YOU
INSTRUCT THE WITNESS TO WIPE
THE SMIRK OFF HIS FACE ?
I CANNOT SIGN IT.
THEN YOU'LL BE DISMISSED
OF YOUR DUTIES AND DISCIPLINED.
ACCUSED MOORE,
I AM LOSING MY PATIENCE.
GET TO THE POINT BEFORE
I DISMISS THE WITNESS.
HAVE YOU EVER SERVED AS A GUARD
FOR ANY GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL ?
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
YES.
- HAVE YOU EVER MET
MINISTER LIN SHOU ?
- [Chairman Xu]  IRRELEVANT.
HAVE YOU EVER MET GENERAL HONG
OR HIS DAUGHTER HONG LING ?
[Chinese]
[Chairman Xu]
IRRELEVANT.
I HAVE ALREADY RULED AGAINST
THIS LINE OF QUESTIONING.
ALL RIGHT.
HUAN MINGLU,
AS AN OFFICER IN THE P.S.B.,
DID YOU EVER WORK IN A PRISON--
[Male Interpreter]
BEYOND THE SCOPE
OF THIS HEARING.
[Chairman Xu]  SUSTAINED.
ARE YOU FINISHED ?
NO, I AM NOT !
ON THE EVENING OF APRIL 10,
DID NOT YOU AND TWO
ACCOMPLICES ROUGH ME UP...
IN DETENTION CENTER
NUMBER ONE ?
[Male Interpreter]
BEYOND THE SCOPE
OF THIS HEARING.
SUSTAINED.
ON APRIL 11,
WHILE I WAS SITTING IN A
P.S.B. CAR IN DAZHALAN, DID YOU
NOT ATTACK ME AND MY ATTORNEY ?
[Male Interpreter]
- NO.
- IRRELEVANT.
I HAVE NOT FINISHED
THIS LINE OF QUESTIONING.
- I HAVE LOST MY PATIENCE.
- WHY--
WHY WILL YOU NOT
LET THIS WITNESS
ANSWER MY QUESTIONS ?
HE JUST SITS THERE,
LAUGHING AT ME !
LAUGHING AND LYING !
WHERE'S MY ATTORNEY ?
CAUSING TOO MUCH TROUBLE ?
THAT WHY YOU DRAGGED HER OUT ?
- YOU ARE IN CONTEMPT.
- IF THAT'S THE CASE--
WHY DON'T YOU LET HER GO
AND STAY WITH ME ?  YOU'VE
ALREADY MEASURED MY COFFIN !
I SAID YOU ARE IN CONTEMPT !
YOU THINK I GIVE A SHIT ?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO,
SHOOT ME TWICE ?
LET MY ATTORNEY GO
AND TAKE ME.
I DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY,
BUT I'VE GOT SOME SHOES.
THEY'LL PAY FOR THE BULLET.
ALL RIGHT ?  PUT A NICE
DROP CLOTH DOWN.
YOU CAN PUT A BULLET
RIGHT IN THE BACK OF MY HEAD.
DO IT RIGHT HERE.  BANG !
BULLET IN THE BACK
OF MY HEAD.
BAM !  BAM !  BAM !
DO IT RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T WANT TO WAIT.
[Chairman Xu
In Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
WE WILL NOW PROCEED
TO FINAL ARGUMENTS...
IF PROCURATOR MA IS PREPARED.
[Male Interpreter]
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN--
[Whispering]
FOR YOU.
YOUR LAWYER
IS VERY PERSUASIVE.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN, I WISH
TO CALL AN ADDITIONAL WITNESS.
[Male Interpreter]
THIS HAS NO PRECEDENT.
- [Chinese]
- [Female Interpreter]
I HAVE ALREADY RULED.
[Hoffmann Speaking
In German]
[Hoffmann]
MULTIBILLION DOLLAR
SATELLITE UNDERTAKING.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
I APOLOGIZE TO THE COURT.
I REQUEST THE COURT'S
PERMISSION TO CALL
AN ADDITIONAL WITNESS.
I HAVE ALREADY RULED.
[Male Interpreter]
THE FOREIGNER IS MAKING
A MOCKERY OF THE PEOPLE'S COURT.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
I IMPLORE YOU !
I RECOGNIZE
THAT I HAVE TRIED
THE COURT'S PATIENCE.
I PROMISE YOU
IT WILL NOT HAPPEN AGAIN.
THIS WITNESS
IS IN A POSITION TO HAVE
UNIQUE KNOWLEDGE...
OF THE PROCEEDINGS
OF THIS CASE.
NOT TO CALL HIM WOULD CALL
INTO QUESTION THE PROCEEDINGS
OF THIS CASE ALTOGETHER.
PLEASE !
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
PLEASE, JUST ONE MORE WITNESS.
- REQUEST DENIED.
- PRESIDING CHAIRMAN.
THE PROCURATOR GENERAL
HAS GIVEN HIS PERMISSION
TO CALL ANOTHER WITNESS.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
I WOULD LIKE TO CALL
MINISTER--
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
I WOULD LIKE
TO CALL LIN DAN.
[Male Interpreter]
THERE IS NO FOUNDATION
FOR THIS WITNESS.
[Female Interpreter]
LIN DAN, PLEASE TAKE
THE WITNESS STAND.
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
YOU MADE USE OF
THE CRIMINAL CODE I GAVE YOU.
SPEAK ENGLISH.
I KNOW YOU CAN.
CONGRATULATIONS
ON YOUR RECENT APPOINTMENT,
THE PRINCIPAL CHINESE
PROGRAMMING PARTNER...
FOR HOFFCO TELEKOMM'S
JOINT VENTURE
WITH THE CHINESE GOVERNMENT.
THANK YOU.
WONDERFUL OPPORTUNITY.
YES.
WOULD IT BE ACCURATE TO SAY
THAT MY OWN COMPANY,
McANDREWS COMMUNICATIONS,
WAS HOFFCO TELEKOMM'S
PRINCIPAL COMPETITOR...
FOR THAT RECENTLY AWARDED
CONTRACT ?
I SUPPOSE SO.
YOU SUPPOSE SO.  OKAY.
WOULD IT ALSO BE ACCURATE
TO SAY...
THAT YOU HAD NO GUARANTEE
OF AN EQUIVALENT PAYOFF
FROM McANDREWS ?
[Male Interpreter]
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN, "PAYOFF"
HAS NEGATIVE CONNOTATION.
LET ME REPHRASE.
LIN DAN,
McANDREWS COMMUNICATIONS
DID NOT OFFER YOU
AN EQUIVALENT POSITION.
THAT HAD NOT BEEN DISCUSSED.
THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH HONG LING'S MURDER.
IT HAS EVERYTHING TO DO
WOULD YOU SAY MY INDICTMENT...
WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR McANDREWS COMMUNICATIONS
LOSING THAT DEAL ?
[Chinese]
[Male Interpreter]
WHY DOES THE COURT PERMIT THIS ?
YOU USED HER, DIDN'T YOU ?
YOU USED HER
AND YOU SACRIFICED HER--
TO SABOTAGE THE DEAL
YOUR FATHER WAS COMPLETING
WITH McANDREWS.
WITH WHOM HE HAD A LONG
PERSONAL RELATIONSHIP.  IT
COULD'VE LEFT YOU IN THE COLD.
THESE ARE NOT QUESTIONS.
BUT THIS IS.
WHAT WAS THE NATURE OF YOUR
RELATIONSHIP WITH HONG LING ?
I HAD NO RELATIONSHIP
WITH HONG LING.
NONE AT ALL ?
WOULD YOU LIKE TO RECONSIDER
THAT STATEMENT ?
I KNEW HER, KNEW OF HER FAMILY.
BUT THERE WAS NO RELATIONSHIP.
NO RELATIONSHIP.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS ?
THIS IS HONG LING'S LOCKET.
SHE WORE IT
THE NIGHT OF THE MURDER.
JUST TURNED UP.
INSIDE IS A PICTURE
OF GENERAL HONG.
INSIDE OF THAT,
IS A CHARMING PHOTOGRAPH...
OF HONG LING...
AND...
YOU.
[Chairman Xu]
ACCUSED MOORE,
LET ME SEE THIS EVIDENCE.
[Jack]
PLEASE SHARE THAT WITH
THE PEOPLE'S ASSESSORS.
THEY SEEM
A LITTLE MORE INTERESTED NOW.
ALSO, PROCURATOR MA,
YOU'RE NOT SMILING
SO MUCH.
WHY WOULD THERE BE
A PHOTOGRAPH OF YOU AND
HONG LING INSIDE HER LOCKET ?
THERE WAS NO RELATIONSHIP.
I KNEW HER THE WAY
MANY MEN KNEW HER.
THE WAY YOU KNEW HER.
[Yuelin]
BUT YOU DID KNOW HER ?
ANSWER ME.
[Li Dan]
I KNEW HER A LONG TIME AGO.
I HAD NOT TALKED TO--
I HAD NOT TALKED TO HER
SINCE I CAN'T REMEMBER WHEN.
[Jack]  CAN'T REMEMBER WHEN ?
ADVOCATE SHEN YUELIN,
WILL YOU ENTER
THE PHONE RECORDS...
INTO EVIDENCE, PLEASE ?
ON THE NIGHT HONG LING
WAS KILLED,
THREE CALLS WERE MADE
FROM THIS NUMBER.
- TWO CALLS WERE RECEIVED.
- [Male Interpreter]
OBJECTION !
THE FIRST CALL RECEIVED
WAS FROM HONG LING
EARLY THAT NIGHT.
THEN LATER,
AROUND 2:00 A.M.,
A CALL WAS MADE
FOR A NUMBER REGISTERED
TO HUAN MINGLU.
AT 3:10 A.M., THE SECOND
CALL MADE WAS TO A NUMBER
REGISTERED TO HONG LING.
[Male Interpreter]
WHAT DO THESE
TELEPHONE NUMBERS--
AT 5:41 A.M., A CALL
WAS APPARENTLY RECEIVED
FROM HUAN MINGLU.
AT 5:46 A.M.,
A TWO-MINUTE CALL
WAS MADE FROM THIS NUMBER
TO POLICE HEADQUARTERS.
[Interpreters]
- THIS IS CHAOS
- I WILL HAVE YOU REMOVED.
- LIN DAN, DO YOU OWN
A CELLULAR TELEPHONE ?
- YES OR NO ?
I DO.
CAN YOU GIVE THE COURT
THE NUMBER OF THAT PHONE ?
I AM NOT A SECRETARY,
AND I RARELY CALL MYSELF,
SO I WOULD NEED TO CHECK IT.
IS THE NUMBER OF YOUR
CELL PHONE 5-1-7-8-5-7 ?
NO, IT IS NOT.
YOU'RE QUITE SURE ?
EVEN THOUGH YOU RARELY
CALL YOURSELF ?
YES, I AM QUITE SURE.
[Jack]  WHO DO YOU THINK
HAS THAT NUMBER ?
5-1-7-8-5-7.
IS THE TELEPHONE NUMBER YOURS,
MINISTER LIN SHOU ?
IT IS MY NUMBER.
[Male Interpreter]
DON'T, FATHER.
DON'T WHAT ?
I'M NOT AFRAID.
WHY ARE YOU AFRAID ?
YOU USED YOUR FATHER'S PHONE
'CAUSE YOU KNEW THE RECORDS
OF AN OFFICIAL CAN BE WITHHELD.
HONG LING WAS SUPPOSED
TO SET ME UP IN SOME WAY,
WASN'T SHE ?
WHATEVER IT WAS,
SHE CHANGED HER MIND.
THEN SOMEONE GOT IN,
DRUGGED ME WITH CHLOROFORM.
ISN'T THAT WHAT HAPPENED ?
WAS IT--
WAS IT HUAN MINGLU ?
[Chairman Xu]
SUCH SPECULATION
IS OUT OF ORDER.
SHE RESISTED !
AND SHE ENDED UP DEAD !
HE KILLED HER, DIDN'T HE ?
SHE GOT KILLED
AND I GOT SET UP !
I WASN'T THERE.
ASK HIM.
DA GUAR.
WHAT DID HE JUST SAY ?
WHAT ?  DA GUAR ?  THAT'S WHAT
HONG LING SAID THAT NIGHT.
SHE SAID IT OVER AND OVER.
- DA GUAR.
- DA GUAR, DA GUAR.
WO MEN DE--
[Chinese]
HE IS SAYING DA GUAR.
HONG LING SAID "DA GUAR,
WO MEN DE GUANXI WAN LA."
IT MEANS "BIG SHOT."
LIKE A MINISTER OR AN
IMPORTANT BUSINESS PERSON.
"BIG SHOT,
OUR DEAL IS OFF."
OR MAYBE...
"OUR RELATIONSHIP
IS OVER."
[Yuelin]
LIN DAN,
ARE YOU KNOWN TO YOUR FRIENDS
AS DA GUAR ?
ARE YOU KNOWN
TO YOUR FRIENDS
AS DA GUAR LIN DAN ?
[Chinese]
[Female Interpreter]
THE COURT IS DISMISSED.
- I REQUEST--
- WHAT'S HAPPENING ?
I REQUEST THE SESSION
TO BE REOPENED
AND MY CLIENT BE RELEASED !
DA GUAR.
[Chinese]
HE SAID IT AGAIN !
YOU CAN'T LET THEM TAKE YOU
OUT OF THIS ROOM.
[Chinese]
WHAT'S HE SAYING ?
HE'S SAYING "HUAN MINGLU'S
THE KILLER.  ARREST HIM."
- DID HE CONFESS ?
- PRESIDING CHAIRMAN, HE SAID
IT WAS LIN DAN'S IDEA !
[Chinese]
HONG LING WAS SUPPOSED
TO DRUG YOU.
THEN HE WOULD PHOTOGRAPH YOU
WITH A YOUNG GIRL.
EMBARRASS YOU.
PRESIDING CHAIRMAN,
YOU MUST RECONVENE THE COURT
AND ALLOW MY CLIENT TO BE FREE !
ARREST LIN DAN INSTEAD !
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I JUST SAID ?
ARREST LIN DAN !
[Crying]
[Chinese]
HE SAID HE'S SORRY
HE CAUSED YOU
SO MUCH TROUBLE.
[Chairman Xu]
IN KEEPING WITH THE LAWS OF THE
PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC OF CHINA...
THE GUILTY PARTIES
HAVE NOW CONFESSED
TO THE CRIME...
OF CONSPIRACY AND MURDER,
NAMELY, THE DEATH OF HONG LING.
THE COURT WOULD PARTICULARLY
LIKE TO THANK...
ALL LEVELS OF PARTY
AND GOVERNMENT LEADERSHIP
INVOLVED IN THIS CASE...
FOR THEIR DILIGENCE
AND PROFESSIONALISM.
THE JUSTICE ACCORDED
WILL BE SWIFT...
AS IT WILL BE FAIR...
AND IMPARTIAL.
HER TRAGIC MURDER
WOULD NOT HAVE BEEN SOLVED
HAD IT NOT BEEN--
[Pratt]
MR. MOORE.
WE NEVER HAD ANY DOUBT.
WE WERE ALWAYS THERE FOR YOU
BEHIND THE SCENES.
YOU REALLY BELIEVE
THIS SHIT, DON'T YOU ?
WHAT DID YOU SAY ?
I SAID, GO TO HELL.
[Yuelin]
I HAVE TO TAKE MY GRANDMOTHER
TO THE COUNTRY.
YOU SHOULD SEE ME.
I LOVE TO BE THERE.
I'LL MISS YOU.
THERE ARE SO MANY BEAUTIFUL
AND REMARKABLE THINGS HERE.
YES.  I KNOW.
WHEN I WAS A CHILD,
I WOULD COME TO THIS PARK
AND PLAY.
DO YOU KNOW WHY
THE BAMBOO IS HERE ?
IT IS WAITING FOR THE WIND
TO TOUCH IT.
IT IS FILLED WITH EMOTIONS.
LISTEN TO THE SOUNDS
AND YOU CAN FEEL THEM.
[Chanting In Chinese]
[Wind Rustling
In The Leaves]
COME WITH ME.
YOU KNOW I CANNOT.
CHANGE YOUR MIND.
I KNOW YOU CAN.
I'VE SEEN IT.
FOR NOW, ESPECIALLY NOW,
I MUST STAY HERE.
I AM NEEDED
TO MAKE IT BETTER.
YOU UNDERSTAND.
SO...
DO WE JUST
SAY GOOD-BYE NOW...
LIKE NOTHING
HAS HAPPENED ?
NO.
SOMETHING DID HAPPEN.
MY LIFE HAS CHANGED.
YOU HAVE OPENED ME UP.
YOU ARE A PART OF
MY LIFE NOW, JACK MOORE.
AND I'LL NEVER BE
THE SAME.
NEITHER WILL I.
BECAUSE I HOPE I'M A PART
OF YOUR LIFE NOW.
[Whispering]
WHEREVER WE ARE.
ZAI JIAN.
YOU SHOULD GO.
YEAH.
REMEMBER, EVERYTHING
IS DIFFERENT NOW.
NOW YOU HAVE SOMEONE
ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE WORLD...
WHO IS FAMILY.
YOU WILL ALWAYS HAVE
A FAMILY.
CLOSED-CAPTIONED BY
CAPTIONS, INC.  LOS ANGELES