We will win!
Fight! We will win!
Getting ready for the party!
I take my daughter with me
Since going to the ball, you gotta dance like a princess.
1, 2, 3 ...
You'll dress how?
- I'll get dressed ...
- With...
A bucket on his head?
Dress like a barrel.
And mops to toe.
Good afternoon.
Hello, are you?
Want to eat?
I'm not hungry.
Ok
Franklin?
It's me. I wanted
you leave a message.
It might be to talk? Without children.
I would really like to ensure.
I miss you.
Eva Khatchadourian?
You've done a ton of stuff.
Listen, Eva, no matter who you are
and where you come from. If you can type and rank, I urge you.
It's wonderful.
Thank you.I'm sorry
I will not disappoint you. Promised.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
At Monday.
Great, thank you.
Looks like all is well with you.
Are you satisfied?
Excuse me
I hope you burn in hell, bitch!
- What happened?
- It's nothing.
- I call for help.
- It's my fault.
- It hit you!
Are you OK?
Eva, when you come home?
I miss you.
I love you.
Promise me you will not go over.
I will not leave ... more
never.
- You promise? - Yes!
Promise me you will not go over.
It is safe?
- No, the contrary.
We did! Homer took him.
Are you sure?
I can not believe it!
I feel it move.
We managed.
We must classify it today.
I'm not working this afternoon.
I told you so.
Shit, it's true.
You will do when you can.
- Hello, Eva.
.
Let me go! Leave me alone!
"Do not stop!
Lady, help me! I have done nothing, damn!
Help me! Pity!
Let me go! Do not touch me!
Do not contract.
Do not hold back, Eva.
It's time to get up.
It's late.
The day is almost over.
Good afternoon.
Do not get me, please. He has just fallen asleep.
Cuckoo!
Want to play?
Everything is fine.
You just rock him a little.
You think I dramatizing?
The rocking a little.
My little boy!
The cow! The twelve?
- I take them anyway.
- But they are all broken.
You will be a handsome young man.
The girls will crack.
Do not wake up.
You can say "mama"?
Ma .. man.
Kevin?
You say "ball"?
Not? OK.
I'll run it and you send him back to mom.
Returns it to me.
You kick it back?
Baby, he cried constantly, it may have damaged his hearing.
He hears very well.
He should talk. Not?
I read somewhere that does not speak
was a sign of autism.
No symptoms suggest.
Do not worry.
It is not very reactive.
But he's fine.
Returns it to mom.
I am sending. It was very good.
"E" is not very big small elephant
Not really great small as a mouse
You can say "elephant"?
Elephant.
You can say "mama"?
Mom.
Say "mama".
Trick or candy!
We know you are there!
We want candy!
Madam, we want candy!
Candy!
I do not like. I want it.
I want more. I love it!
Mom was happy
before Kevin arrived. You know?
Candy!
Now, mom wakes up every morning
regretting not be very far!
This elevator is too dangerous.
It needs a garden to play ball, a swimming pool.
But I love New York.
Stop
Sounds like a slogan for the city!
There are priorities. He must take his childhood.
Looking for houses if you want.
I will not leave New York.
Kevin, that's enough. Mom and Dad talking.
Stop
There is a huge living room.
The parents room has two huge walk-in closets.
The bathroom is great.
Here we are.
Our little castle!
I'll get to eat.
You want something?
Wait ... Ms. K?
"It's me,
Soweto.
Good afternoon.
How do you go?
I'm well, thank you.
You look like.
The doctors say I remarcherai.
It's great.
Take care of yourself.
You too.
Die!
How do you do to jump?
Go on!
Die!
Kev, big boy!
Come here.
You see, Dad peed in the toilet.
You can do it, too.
You want to go there.
You see? You click on the link and it opens by itself.
And if it does not open,
you go again.
You must click on the left. You try?
No, right click. That way, it's good.
So, it opens.
super gasoline
Thank you. I understood.
Thank you for your help.
I pooped.
What?
You pooped?
I come right away.
Go to your room, I'm coming.
We let mom sleep.
Go ahead, my great.
All these pieces of paper scrawled, this is stupid.
Everyone must have his play.
You have your room and that's mine.
I can help you to make you an original room.
How is that possible?"
A room that reflects your personality.
What personality?
You know what I mean.
This is stupid.
It's great.
You do not want me to do?
And type ...
If you take care of everything ...
I could.
We did! Homer took him.
That sounds perfect.
See you later. Goodbye.
He is really sorry.
He wanted to make you an original piece.
You remember how you got that?
This is the only sincere thing you've ever done.
How we teach cats to relieve themselves?
They put their noses in their shit.
They like it.
Then they go in their litter.
Figures are reviewed.
- What is it after 3?
9.
- After 7?
- 71.
Got it? We stop?
Here
Add me that since you are so smart.
You did not do that!
It amuses you?
I can see the doctor alone.
I have something to say.
You have a very brave son.
What Mom did, it was very bad,
and she regrets it very much.
Wait!
Hi, Kev.
What happened?
I have broken my arm.
How ?
I pooped in my bed
Mom went to get the wipes.
I fell off the changing table in my garbage truck.
Mom took me to the doctor Goldbutt.
That's my fault.
Do not talk nonsense.
You can not watch him constantly.
Crazy!
How you managed?
Anyway, it worked.
Expect.
Are you OK?
I love you.
I do not like this music. Turn off.
Honey, you can stop at the supermarket?
I want to go.
I must buy ...
We're going home.
Good evening.
Best wishes!
You took some great photos?
Eva is a child.
A nice little boy.
Like all others.
Mom is big.
Counted when you tell me?
Soon. Now.
You took the decision without me.
I'm supposed to say what, now?
Daddy Bear puts small seed
the mama bear, it becomes an egg.
That's right, kiss?
Do you know what that means?
The boy puts his penis in the girl's pussy.
You never wanted to have someone to play with?
That you might like.
And if I like it not?
Then you'll get used.
It can be used to something without necessarily loving.
You're used to me.
In a few months
you get used to someone new.
She is beautiful!
Come see your little sister.
This is your big brother.
Kevin.
Your big brother.
This is Kevin.
Do not do that.
It's not nice.
We go down and buy food. Come.
Ecuador? For 2 months? Them send someone else!
I would really like to ensure.
He cries too, and after he said nothing.
He invents his own language and it bothers you.
It has layers, it is not abnormal.
This is not good for him.
Unhook the fuck!
Wins!
Getting ready for the party!
Please!
Give me to drink.
I beg you.
Please do.
My heart!
Sorry, Mom.
Do not worry, darling.
It was not your fault.
"By my soul!" exclaimed Gilbert.
"Are not you the Devil whether to aim well?"
"No," said Robin, laughing.
"I'm not as bad as that."
And there went out another arrow.
That's okay, darling?
He took out another arrow and adjusted it on the rope.
He drew back and threw the arrow next to the center of the target.
The third time he bent the bow and sent the arrow
right next to the other two in the middle.
The feathers of three arrows
were gathered as a large bouquet.
A long murmur ran through the crowd.
Hello, my grandfather.
What's up?
Go away. I'm tired.
Okay. Sleep well.
Continues to read, Mom.
He threw 280 arrows
with such speed and accuracy
once planted,
targets resembled the back of a hedgehog
returned from a hunting dog.
Hello Madam,
I hope it does not bother you.
In fact, if.
We had some questions.
About what?
Where will you go when you die?
I know very well.
I'll live in hell.
Eternal damnation.
Thank you for your question.
I'll help.
I know how to dress himself. You can go out?
Yes.
Glad you are better. You want soup for lunch?
I do not care.
- A pop tart?
- I do not care a lot.
Thank you, Dad. This is too cool.
You're welcome.
Seeks the middle.
Almost.
Bravo, Kevin.
It is innate within you.
It was perfect.
Thank you, Dad.
That's how ...
You wake
and we watch TV.
It gets into his car and listening to the radio.
It goes quietly to his job or his school,
but that, we do not hear about the news of 18h.
Why?
Because nothing happens.
It comes home and puts it on TV.
Or if it's a fantastic evening,
we go out and goes to cinema.
It sucks so much that very often people on TV,
those that one is watching, watching TV.
And what do they look?
People like me.
You, for example, what do you do?
You look at me.
They had already changed string if I was a model student.
With Kevin, we play with Christmas kidnapping.
You are my friend.
Stops, Celia.
Give me a soda.
No one, moron.
A Root Beer.
What?
Thank you, Celia. I was thirsty.
I tell you a secret?
Approach
Who else is thirsty?
You know?
The monster vacuum cleaner.
Stop
Hello.
Look what I brought!
- You just help me?
- I arrive.
You dance?
No thank you, Colin.
Ok, a little dance.
I love to dance.
What excites you, kind of pretentious bitch?
What want you crazy?
Remains. Another glass timber.
Are you happy?
It will leave a carrot for the reindeer?
I saw you at the bookstore today.
No !
Funny, I could have sworn ...
In fact, you do something on Friday?
Why?
It could be something
of fun.
Like that?
Go to a restaurant?
Make a mini-golf course?
You did not take a jacket?
You always do everything possible not to be comfortable.
Uncomfortable?
With my mother?
Large are always eating.
This is not because of a slow metabolism or crap like that.
This is the food.
They eat anything.
They eat too much and all the time.
You can be very hard sometimes.
You look great thing to say.
Exactly!
I wonder who I am.
You won.
And now, Mamounette?
We go back, you put clothes more appropriate and we will dine.
super gasoline
Go to the restaurant.
I was hungry.
I'm growing.
I will
a salad of calamari,
a steak and a bottle to the point of merlot.
Immediately.
It's going to school?
I am Okay.
Want my schedule?
And your teachers?
- There you ...
- I listen to anything, like music?
Ask me if there is a hottie also interests me.
This will bring you
to say that it looks at me, but before the fuck,
I must be sure you are ready.
For dessert, you aborderas the subject of drugs.
Gently, without scare me,
by lying to me.
You tell me your own experience.
And when you whistled your bottle,
you will give me the soft eyes and said, "It's good, you two!"
You get closer you and me enlaceras
shaking my little one.
YOU HAVE LOST
Your computer is broken?
Yes.
All of the office too.
I earned it.
Why did you do this stuff?
I collect them.
Bizarre, as a collection.
I do not like stamps.
What is the advantage?
there aren't two,
That's the interest.
It was easy to organize.
Everyone brings a dish.
They arrive. I leave you.
Have a nice day.
Goodbye, Mom.
Merry Christmas!
To you, Kevin.
Guess what it is.
This is an arc of seven series.
The seller told me it was the best.
Daddy!
Thank you very much!
It's great.
What you eat in the morning?
I don't actually know...
You heard the impact?
My dear, it's time to sleep.
I thought I had closed the door.
Kevin says I'm stupid, he's right.
You're not stupid.
Do not worry, we will find him.
Put yourself to bed.
You are well?
Snuffles?
Admit it.
Mr. Snuffles went into the great pet in heaven.
Do not say that.
This is the truth.
"My dear friends,
"We are here to pray for Mr. Snuffles ...
"... Who died in a tragic way ..."
Mom and Dad have searched all night,
and we did not find,
because he went to live in the garden.
He lives in the garden with all its new animal friends.
Give your spoon.
They make a big party tonight.
With rodents,
squirrels
and raccoons.
They eat nuts and berries ...
And they'll do
high ...
Why you left out the Destop?
I have not left.
- I had stored.
- How is it released?
Kevin.
This is Kevin.
You should go see a shrink.
Your mother has something to tell you.
I wanted ...
thank you for calling the ambulance.
and
I fear that you feel
Editor:
Why?
Because you had the monitor!
You have nothing to reproach yourself.
Are you OK?
I blame myself for anything.
She'll have a glass eye.
We would like you to be nice to her.
You do not insults.
Do not you remember you were a kid, too?
Celia is going to cash it.
You do not like lychees.
Say I ...
I appreciate now.
Pardon me, my angel.
Thank you, Mom.
You go back training?
You know me!
Celia, you just pick up the arrows?
What do you do?
We will finish the school year
and arrange this summer.
Child care, at least it's done.
We did! Homer took him.
You decided.
there is nothing to see here.
This is obvious.
I want a glass of water.
My great,
we must put things in context.
I know the background.
It's me, the context.
We will appeal.
You lose your job, your house ...
I always hated that house.
A package for Kevin Khatcha ... Durian?
- Warning, it's heavy.
We did! Homer took him.
Best wishes!
- You too.
You're going to do what? You do not bike.
I bought cheap on the Internet.
I will be selling them wheat.
You think you're Donald Trump?
Come with me.
I'm back on my ship.
Ready for the reverse?
Pleased to meet you.
I am ready!
- You ate your cereal? - Yes.
And your bread?
You're a little feverish.
You feel good?
Better than ever.
In three days you shall have 16 years.
We should celebrate that. Sunday?
I don't actually know...
I may be taken elsewhere.
The heading and we dress.
I want to go to school.
I know, but I'll take my shower and after we go.
Say goodbye.
It might be to talk? Without children.
I would really like to ensure.
Kevin Gladstone goes to school?
Unhook the fuck!
Have you seen Kevin?
You did not look happy.
I've had look happy?
I'm almost 18 years.
What's wrong?
Go into the big leagues, it makes you afraid?
Fear?
You're already gone to such places?
You did very well out.
You were when you were considered minor
for a moment of madness because of Prozac.
You will be released within two years.
You know what day it is? Why I am on a Monday?
Obviously.
This is the anniversary date.
Two years!
It gives you time to think.
I want you to tell me
Why?
Before, I thought I knew ...
But I do not know.
It's time.
Adaptation: Isabelle Juhasz
Subtitling TVS - TITRA FILM
Translated To English - Produksiz