Subtitle By Udin Ahmad
-=www.forumsatelit.com=-
A great man.
He was loved by few others.
Although he leaves behind
no family...
...he had an army of friends.
Be not sad for Dominic...
...no, for he has entered
a better world...
...a reward for a life
of selfless deeds...
...a pillar of the community.
Testing, testing.
That one.
That's it, fellas.
Smile for the camera.
Microphone's all set, sir.
Oh, good.
Take over the camera.
Okay.
Uh, sir, uh...
I've been doing
some thinking, and...
Yeah?
Well, since nobody knew what
Godfather Dominic looked like...
...how can we confirm that he died?
You see that funeral?
That's your confirmation.
Now, shut up, Jack.
I'm trying to gather
some evidence here.
Where's my pad?
I don't know.
This is gonna be bad.
Jack!
I'm sorry, sir.
It's my allergies.
This is a sad day, Georgie.
Your boss...
what can I say?
He was a credit
to organized crime.
Jack, now get control
of yourself.
You're gonna give us away.
Great.
Jack, you're suspended.
As family consigliere,
tell me...
who takes over now as Godfather?
Ah...
Shh!
Don't worry, Sal.
We got somebody.
You got somebody?
Okay.
This ain't over.
Come on.
Let's go.
Hear that?
Yeah.
They probably got themselves
the toughest...
...meanest criminal
they could find.
Out went the confined corsets
with their impractical material...
...and in swept
a design revolution:
A modern dress with a cleaner,
straighter silhouette...
...leading us today,
100 years later...
...to the widely popular
belly shirt.
Miss, uh... Taylor.
Ow!
What?
Professor Kingfield, hi.
Yes, you with
the wrinkled sweatshirt.
Please stand
when answering a question.
Sorry.
I hope you all find
your final grades as amusing.
Miss Taylor,
I bought this suit in 1985
...off the rack at Bloomingdale's.
The label reads"Pierre Cardin."
Please explain and define
the historical.
...and sociological significance
of my purchase.
Okay.
Louder, please.
I can't hear you.
Pierre Cardin
was the first couture house.
...to offer prêt-à-porter
or luxury-wear clothing...
which is a staple
for fashion buying today.
That's why you could buy
that suit off the rack.
...at Bloomingdale's.
And the year Cardin
started it?
1959.
Well done, Miss Taylor.
Thank you.
Perhaps if you put as much
thought into your wardrobe.
...as you do into your homework.
Come ready tomorrow
to discuss.
...the political ramifications of
the culotte.
I'll make designers
out of you yet.
You know,
it's really not fair.
I spend every waking moment.
...designing clothes
for other people.
when I'm not working
on five different committees.
...or my part-time job.
And they expect me
to wear heels after that?
You're right.
That isn't fair.
I mean, who really has time
for their own appearance?
She does.
Her own design
every single day.
It's like she's
a walking billboard.
I don't know
how she does it.
I heard she doesn't.
They say she's been secretly
getting outside help.
What?
It's the hottest rumor.
Três scandalous!
It's official.
I truly hate her.
I do not believe that.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Brooke.
Um, listen, don't worry
about what Professor Kingfield.
...said in class today.
Maybe one day,
plain and ugly will be in style.
Hey, back off, Candace.
Yeah, you're just jealous.
Here's a news flash, ladies.
The meek and the dorky
don't inherit the arth.
The bold and the trendy do.
That's why my label CandaceWear.
will one day be America's
top-selling brand...
...and you three
will be designing.
...boys' underwear
for a children's catalog.
Okay, now I hate her.
Yeah.
Welcome to Fashion University,
where being the best means...
Brooke, the words
are all smeared.
How am I supposed to read that?
Maybe if you learned
your lines.
Let's go again.
Action!
Welcome to Fashion University...
where being the best means
looking your best.
Our motto is...
"Veni, suei, vici:
I came, I sewed, I conquered."
Where all the biggest names
in fashion.
...first learned to make
the world a prettier...
...more color-coordinated place
to live.
Cut!
You're welcome.
We have only one philosophy
here at Fashion University:
You are what you wear.
But don't worry.
After four years...
...you can count on it
being fabulous.
I designed this myself,
and you can too.
Cut, cut.
Sorry, sorry.
All right,
let's wrap this up, people.
Yeah, I hate her.
Oh, man, I'm late
for my wedding dress class.
Ugh, I'll see you guys later.
All right, bye.
Hey!
Hey, hey!
Do I throw trash in your house?
Ugh.
Freshman, I swear...
Hi, can I help you?
Get in the car.
Xcuse me, sir.
I took self-defense classes
in high school.
I know three ways to disarm
an attacker.
None of which apply right now.
Where are you taking me?
You will not be harmed.
Who are you?
I'm gonna be very late
for class.
Get in the car, please.
This is really gonna ruin
my perfect attendance.
Seriously,
where are you taking me?
Relax, Miss Taylor.
Buckle up.
It'll all be explained.
I promise.
You're part of the family now,
just like cousin Frankie.
Family.
Family?
You live here?
It was your grandfather
Dominic's.
Grandfather?
Wait, wait.
I don't have a grandfather.
I had a grandfather.
This is me.
I don't understand.
How did he die?
You might say heartache
over the loss of his family.
You mean my parents?
He wasn't the same
after the car accident.
Ate him up inside.
Why didn't he try
and contact me?
It was complicated.
It's complicated?
Sounds pretty simple to me.
He didn't care.
That isn't true.
He abandoned me
at foster care.
while livin' it up
in this mansion.
What else is there to know?
He checked up on you.
He sent you toys and cards...
I was five.
I was shuffled
from one stranger to another.
I didn't want cards or candy.
I wanted a family.
I wanted a real family.
Wait, listen to me...
Why should I listen to you?
You're probably in
on this whole thing too.
This whole time,
I think I'm alone in the world...
...and then I find out
I had a grandfather...
...someone that I could have
gone to when I needed help.
And now he's gone.
Brooke...
I will never forgive him
for that.
Never.
Oh, what's that?
More bad news?
His will.
Keep it.
I don't care
about anything of his.
It was his last request...
...his dream that you take over
the family business.
Me run a business?
Are you serious?
Two seconds ago,
I find out I have a grandfather...
...and now I'm supposed
to take over his job?
What was he, anyways,
a rich stockbroker?
Lawyer?
Ooh!
It's not a toy.
Come on.
Into the kitchen.
Mob boss?
I was kidding.
It's not what you think.
I can't be a mob boss.
I'm an honest person.
I've never cheated on anything
in my entire life.
We've got plenty
of legal businesses too.
Oh, so that makes it okay?
Look, look,
I am a fashion student.
I design pretty clothes
that don't include gun holsters.
Your grandfather
wanted to go straight...
...but he ran out of time.
That's why we found you.
He wants you to finish
what he started.
Forget it.
You're the only one left.
We need you.
I have to get back to school.
I have a test to study for.
Brooke.
Your grandfather loved you.
That kind of love
I can live without.
Why can't my family
just be normal.
...like the Osbournes?
I had a nightmare
like this once.
You!
What are you doing here?
I'm not used to people
saying no.
In fact,
you might be the first.
Well, get used to it.
'cause I'm gonna say it
again right now.
No, no, no, N-O.
No, no, no, no, no.
Hey, Brooke, who, uh...
who's your little friend here?
Fashion cop come to arrest you
for this tired design?
He's my...
Sewing counselor.
Makin' sure
she doesn't drop a stitch.
He is very thorough.
You got nothin' to do?
Well, I'll leave you two
to work out your issues.
Obviously, there's plenty.
You shouldn't let her
talk to you like that.
Oh, whatever.
You want me
to take care of her?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
It's fine.
You should...
you should get out of here.
You're the boss.
I'm not the boss.
Stop saying that.
Go. Shoo.
Bye.
If you ask me,
it'd look better as a strapless.
It does look better
as a strapless.
I hate him.
You'd think
a classy place like this.
would have a dress code.
...or a limit on the number
of nose rings you can wear.
You don't give up, do you?
Now you're catchin' up.
You hungry?
Okay, why did you come.
...all the way to Staten Island
for lunch?
I've been comin' here
for over 40 years.
Best gnocchi around.
Look, George,
you don't want me, okay?
I know nothing
about what you do.
That doesn't matter.
Family don't turn their back
on each other.
Tell that to my grandfather.
You can hate him,
but the fact is...
...he was protecting you.
He was keeping you
away from danger.
Great.
And what about now?
We're so close to being legit.
We need someone to take us
the rest of the way.
Someone like me?
Honest.
Smart.
Better.
Stop it.
Stop.
I'm very susceptible
to compliments right now.
Look, don't throw away.
...everything that
your grandfather worked for.
You can turn his legacy
into something good...
...something you can be proud of.
My school
means everything to me.
I won't leave.
I can't leave.
You don't have to.
And nobody finds out,
nobody.
Believe me,
I ain't no squealer.
Oh, I hope you're happy...
'cause you've given me quite the
headache.
Is that a yes?
Yes, it's a yes.
Shh!
I'm done talking about this.
You're the boss.
Oh, yeah, yeah, I'm the boss.
I can't even run my own life...
...and now I'm supposed
to run your family's.
It's just perfect.
Jack!
Sir.
You wanted to see me, sir?
I've decided to take you
off suspension, Jack.
Okay!
Wow.
Thank you, sir.
I've got
new allergy medication...
...so there won't be
any more problems with the...
...the nose and the sneezing
and the...
...oh, I'm fine, I promise you.
We just received a tip
on the Sarto family.
Looks like they found themselves
a new don.
Oh, uh, wow.
Okay, uh, great.
L... I don't understand, sir.
A fashion student?
I want you to go
inside her school...
...find out what this...
this Brooke Taylor is up to...
...and then bring her down.
You mean enroll
in dressmaking classes, sir?
Sure, a young man
like yourself.
...must know a lot about fashion.
Besides, a big bust like this.
...could really boost
your career, Jack.
Absolutely, sir...
...but isn't there a better way?
You know, phone taps
or internet surveillance...
...something
that doesn't involve sewing?
If you can't do it,
I'll get Carter.
He's a real sharp dresser...
...and he's been bugging me awhile
for a big case like this.
Sir, I can handle this, okay?
I will be the...
...most fashionable fashion student
on campus, sir.
Would you mind clipping me?
Don't screw up, Jack.
Hey, workin' on somethin' new?
Uh, no, it's nothing.
So you ready to go?
I don't want to be late
for the fashion quiz.
They might deduct a point
from me or something.
Then I'd have no chance to win.
You know,
maybe I should stay home.
We're a bit nervous.
Hey, you studied very hard
for this.
It's the fashion finals.
You're going.
You'll be fine.
Just don't look
into the audience.
with all those eyes
just watching and judging you.
Whew!
Talk about scary.
Why'd you have to say
a thing like that?
What?
I'm just trying to help you.
You guys.
Now, next question:
Love beads.
That is correct!
Now, next question.
What was unfavorably worn
by little old ladies.
...in Florida in the summer
of 1982?
Testing.
This is Agent Jack Lawton.
...on case number 479358:
The takedown of mob boss
Brooke Taylor.
Bring it, bring it,
bring it, bring it!
Hoy!
Uhh!
Next question.
What item...
Oh, my God, he's so gorgeous.
Too bad he doesn't know my name.
So go introduce yourself.
Ask him out.
Me ask him out?
No way.
Why not?
Because, Page,
girls don't ask guys out.
It's weird and desperate.
What if he says no?
What if he says yes?
B, if you want something
bad enough, you go get it.
I've spotted the subject
with a female accomplice.
If you can't, you can't.
Okay, fine.
I'll do it.
Something is definitely
going down.
They are on the move,
and, sir, I am on the...
Here we go.
Hey, Marcus.
You know, you're the one
who should be up there.
I mean, you're so brilliant
and smart and everything.
Come on.
He's not worth it.
Our next category...
Hey, Dee,
there's always next year.
Can I ask you guys something
about family?
Of course, anything.
What do you do when
they're not exactly like you?
I know a lot about that one.
And how do you deal with it?
Any way you can, 'cause,
girl, you stuck with 'em.
That's what I thought.
But still,
no matter how freaky.
...or weird they are...
...it's nice to have them around,
like Dee.
So what's up, B?
Why you askin' about family?
It's nothing.
Never mind.
Movies.
Believe me, nothin' like that.
Oh.
Well, except maybe Sal Hugo.
Who's Sal Hugo?
Old-school mob boss.
He's gonna want your territory.
At some point,
you got to meet him.
Me?
You gotta sell him
on our new direction...
...gain some respect...
...or he'll walk all over us
and ruin our plans.
But how?
I'm not convincing.
Nobody listens to anything
that I say.
That's okay.
I'll teach you.
Ready?
Ready.
You see?
You gotta own the room...
...make everyone notice you.
Oh, I don't want anyone
to notice me.
Come on.
Try it.
Ready?
Ready.
One more time.
You're still not owning.
You're returning
a late library book.
Oh, that reminds me.
Where you going?
Come back!
We're not done yet.
Watch me.
I can't tell
what you're thinking.
Xactly.
In meetings,
you don't reveal anything.
You let them reveal.
Then you'll have the advantage.
Try again.
You look like you just got
a C on a test.
Hey!
I'm sorry.
You're right.
That would never happen.
George, I can't do this.
I'm an emotional person.
Hello, college girl.
We'll try again later.
Fine.
So what about this Sal guy?
I sent a man over
to buy us some time...
...see what kind of a mood
he's in.
I had plans!
I waited a long time for this.
I am not gonna let
this new boss, Brooke... Brooke?
What kind of a name is Brooke?
Mr. Hugo, you want me to run
this Sarto guy through again?
Huh?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Run him through again.
This time, put him through
the rinse cycle, will you?
He's makin' a mess
out of my floors here.
These people, you know...
...they gotta learn
a little respect.
I made a joke!
That's a good one, boss.
Come on.
Hey, you got any quarters?
Do you have me now, sir?
Yes... No, I plan on
making contact today, sir.
Yes.
No, nothing yet.
I will fill you in
as soon as I know, sir.
Yes.
Believe me,
I am trying my hardest, sir.
Oh, yes.
Hi.
They're, uh...
they're tricky little guys.
They're impossible to sew with.
That's because
it's a seam ripper.
Right, yeah.
Just... Just kidding.
Do I know you?
You look really familiar.
Me?
No, I don't think so.
Last semester,
floral print design?
Scarves and handbags?
Oh, ladies' undergarments.
Actually, I just
transferred here from...
Shh.
Designer State.
Fashion U of the West Coast.
That's a great school.
Yeah, my name's Jack.
I'm Brooke.
Okay, people!
Now it is your turn!
So find a partner
and practice marking them.
...for a fitting.
Let's go!
A fitting?
Yeah.
Uh, it's been a while
since I've marked anything...
...so maybe you could,
you know, help me.
Be my partner,
my little honeysuckle.
...of the garden of love.
Okay, comin' along.
Uh-huh.
Watch it with the pins
when you get to the inseam.
Mm-hmm.
Keep at the chalk.
With the chalk, come on.
Lovely, fine.
Mm.
All right, then.
It's funny, really.
Actually, this whole time...
I never even thought
you knew my name.
I don't.
Oh, right.
Of course.
It's Brooke.
It's Brooke,
in case you're wondering.
And you're Marcus,
which, you already know that.
I'm gonna just keep measuring,
and I'll just shut up.
Don't mind me.
Okay, now I have to measure
your inseam.
32.
I say it's 32.
Can I ask you something?
Yeah, sure.
Anything.
I mean, how does
my butt look in these?
I feel so naked
without a mirror in here.
Oh.
Fine, fine.
Only fine?
No, really good.
You really fill
these pants out nicely.
I mean, they're...
the lines are perfect.
Really good.
Yeah, well,
I do a lot of squats.
Ah, yeah.
Check this out.
Ooh!
I mean, that is tight, huh?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, it's really tight.
Yeah, my girlfriend
thinks so too.
Right.
Yes.
See me after class.
Okay.
They're... They're...
they're caprey...
...or capri shorts.
Oh!
Come on, Jack.
You can hit a fleeing suspect
from 50 yards away.
I think you can do this.
Come on.
Yeah!
Okay, you thought
I couldn't thread you...
...but I threaded you.
How does it feel
to be threaded?
Aah!
Is this what you want?
Wait, let me get this right.
You had your hand on his butt?
You're missing
the important part of the story.
What, that it was nice?
No, that he has a girlfriend.
Like I have any chance, anyway.
Don't say that.
Of course you do.
Well, did you at least
give it a squeeze?
Oh.
Dare to dream, girls.
If the board of trustees
thinks I'm gonna live.
with outdated furniture
in the dean's mansion...
...they got another thing coming.
The mansion reflects
on the school...
...and I refuse that reflection.
...to be anything short
of recherchê.
No, that means refined,
you idiot.
Ladies.
Dean Faber, how's it going?
If you girls only knew
what I did around here.
Oh, we do!
And we appreciate everything.
You missed a spot.
Yes, hello.
Is that...
Oh, it's a table,
not a trough.
So this is everyone, huh?
Kind of scruffy,
don't you think?
Scruffy?
Yeah, with
some definite hygiene issues.
Not very polite, either.
Believe me...
...that'll come in handy
in their line of work.
Come on, say something.
What? Me?
No, no, no.
No, I didn't prepare
anything to say, no.
These guys don't care.
Half of them are deaf
from all the gunfire.
No, George,
you don't understand.
I am very bad
at public speaking.
Introduce yourself.
Let 'em know
you mean business.
Okay.
Hello... Everyone.
Guys?
Listen up.
Hello, everyone.
How are you?
I intend to learn
all of your names...
'cause, you know,
that's what a good leader does.
She gets to know
and gets along with everyone.
I heard a famous designer
say that once, yeah.
So I have no experience.
...in what you guys do...
whatever it is that you do...
...but I intend to work very hard.
People at my school
can vouch for that.
Let me tell you...
I mean, the people that know me.
Not a lot of people know me.
I'm kind of, you know...
I'm not very popular
at my school.
They have these, you know,
these cliques.
You guys...
you know, cliques.
They just get together,
and I'm telling you...
I just wish we could just.
...put all of that aside
and come together.
...so we can make beautiful,
yet affordable clothes as one.
So are there, like,
any questions?
They hate me!
They hate everyone.
Well, this time,
it was pointed at me...
...and it's more than
a little scary, okay?
They need to work on that.
It's not healthy.
Boss, these guys
may be rough around the edges...
Dges?
All they have are edges.
But they know
how to follow orders.
So you're saying they have to
listen to everything that I say?
Mm-hmm.
Verything that I say?
Are you sure about this?
Oh, yeah.
You don't like this one?
Talk about extreme makeover.
Whoa!
Hey!
Too much?
Nah, they'll clean up fine.
Good.
Hey, watch out for the heat!
Okay, now,
try to avoid it if you can...
...but if there is an accident...
...gunpowder can be removed
with a 15-minute soak.
...in lukewarm water
with a teaspoon of ammonia.
Okay?
Yeah... No!
Oh, this is way too many carbs
for the new look.
Here.
Try a Slim-Fast bar, okay?
It's way better for you.
Now, let's talk
general fabric here.
I could totally
get used to this.
It's like Simon Says,
but with grown-ups.
By the way,
you look very handsome.
I forgot how this feels.
It's me.
You're having fun?
I love being the boss.
Yeow!
Oh, wow.
You've been busy.
Good.
Let's keep it that way.
Yes, Miss Candace.
Cheer up.
I can't get you into Fashion U
unless I have more of these.
And remember, a happy designer
is a productive designer.
And next time, no names.
I'll make sure
you get your credit.
Trust me.
You all look fashion-tabulous.
Hmm.
Forget about it.
Like, totally forget about it.
Brooke.
What's going on?
You talkin' to me?
So yeah, I'm a mob boss.
Look, you guys,
I wanted to tell you sooner.
I was just afraid
of how you would react.
You were right.
Whoa, our shy little girl
has become Vito Corleone?
Shh.
Nobody can know.
Imagine the reaction.
Trust me; that's the least
of your worries.
Look, it's very safe.
George is protecting me, okay?
It's just a part-time thing.
It's like an after-school job.
Couldn't you just work
at the mall like everyone else?
Look, you guys,
my grandfather spent years.
...trying to make
this family legitimate.
I just want to be the one
to finish the job.
I need my best friends
behind me on this, please.
I can't do this alone.
I'm sorry, B.
I can't.
I just can't.
Hey, don't look at me.
I gave up everything I have
to come here.
I can't risk that.
Brooke?
Running the mob?
Yes, it explains everything.
Such as her high grades
or her lack of a social life.
...or even the way she dresses?
Yes, that and... And more.
I haven't got time
for this nonsense, Candace.
I'm in the middle
of a fund-raising campaign.
Have you ever tried
to get money out of alumni?
Marge?
Yes?
Has Tommy Hilfiger
called back?
No, sir, he hasn't.
You see?
This is what I'm up against.
Shouldn't you at least
look into it?
I mean, the school's reputation
is at risk.
Dean Faber?
Yes?
Is it Vera Wang?
Your decorator's
on line three.
He's asking why you've ordered
three of the same armoire.
Unless you have proof...
I don't want to hear
another word.
Fine.
I'll get you proof.
Remember, when you meet Sal...
...you pause,
quick nod of the head...
...then you reach out to shake.
Not too soft.
Okay, not too hard, either.
That's fine.
And finally,
you lean in to Sal for the kiss.
W!
Why do I have to kiss him?
A small peck on each cheek.
It's a sign of respect.
I'll just send him
a fruit basket.
Please, Brooke,
you gotta convince Sal.
...that you're in command
or we can't go legit.
Our family depends on...
This is gonna make
a great pair of socks.
Freak.
How was that?
Too much?
No.
It was different.
Oh, wait, let me get that.
We can't have a tough guy
like you George.
with lipstick
on your face, right?
So we'll continue
with the lessons later then?
Okay.
I got that as a kid.
It's actually what first got me
interested in fashion.
See?
We used to have this guy
come to the foster home.
His name was Donny.
He was an ex-orphan
or something.
Anyway, he gave
all the kids presents...
...but he called me
his special angel.
And then one year,
he gave me this for my birthday.
That's nice.
I know.
It still works too.
Work?
I got to go to work.
Will you give me a ride?
Hey.
It's... it's you.
Look out, man!
That's tulle from Paris.
Very floaty and feminine.
Oh, yeah.
I was just...
I was just looking.
Can I help you
with something?
Brooke Taylor works here,
doesn't she?
Well, why don't you ask her
yourself?
What?
Jack, hey.
Hey.
Uh, George,
thank you for the ride.
I'll talk to you later.
You kids have fun.
He's just a friend.
So were you asking about me?
No.
L... I mean...
I'd heard that you worked here,
and so I, uh...
You wanted a deal
on material.
Right, yeah.
Yeah, that's it.
Anything for a classmate.
Come with me.
Oh, okay.
Hello?
Yeah, could I speak
to a reporter, please?
An investigative reporter...
...preferably one with a Pulitzer.
I'll hold.
We've got some great fabric
back here.
Let me show you one I think
you're really gonna like.
It's got amazing texture
and balance, don't you think?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
Actually,
it's my own creation.
Really?
Yeah, when it's slow
around here...
I like to play around with the
fabric.
See, with this one,
I just steamed it.
...and then sewed ruffles
across the grain.
See?
Wow.
You... You really know a lot
about this stuff, huh?
Yeah, I should.
It's only my life.
Yeah.
Okay.
So what can I get for you?
Right.
I don't know.
How about...
how about this one?
It's... it's pretty.
Yeah, okay.
So I really like
this new look of yours.
Oh, thanks.
It's more you,
except that tie.
What?
Yeah, here.
That was a gift.
A little kitschy-retro,
don't you think?
Uh, yeah.
That's what I was going for.
I think a bit less dorky
is better.
Oh.
Here, let me.
There.
Okay, I'll see you in class.
Bye.
Okay.
This is gonna make
a great suit.
Yeah.
You know, Dee, we
should have helped Brooke out.
What kind of friends are we?
I miss her.
You know, I was just about
to say that.
You always do that.
What?
Take what I have to say
and make it about yourself.
Mm-hmm.
Sounds like someone's jealous.
Ow, ah, ah!
Jack?
Hey, Brooke.
These cups, you know?
There ought to be a law.
Two times in two days.
I swear you were following me.
Following you?
Why... why would I be
following you?
Um, no reason, I guess.
But now that I've found you,
maybe I can...
I can walk you to class?
Okay.
So you were
a problem child, huh?
Oh, yeah, the worst.
Like getting arrested
and stuff like that?
No!
Nothing that bad.
No, I... I just had this notion.
...that my real family
would come looking for me.
So I never let myself
get too close to anyone.
You know,
I acted like a real brat...
...but my family never showed.
Well, until...
Until?
Until I came here.
This place, it's like my home.
Ah.
You've become emotionally
involved with this Brooke.
No, sir, believe me,
there's been a mistake.
She's not what we think she is.
Is that right?
Absolutely, sir.
She's not a mob boss.
There's no way.
Then how do you explain that?
What do you got to say
for yourself, Jack?
What... Do you...
do you have a quarter?
We should probably get one.
What's this?
Did Donatella Versace
show up again?
There she is.
Donna! Donna!
Are you selling
your movie rights?
Um, what... what's going on?
Is this you?
Oh, my...
That is a horrible picture!
Hey!
Hey, get away from her!
I think we lost them.
You guys totally
saved me back there.
Friends stick together
no matter what.
And so do family...
'cause that's what
the three of us are.
Oh, we are.
Oh, God,
this can't be happening.
I'm gonna be the most
hated person on campus.
Well, at least
they'll be too scared of you.
...to do anything about it.
Oh, no, wait.
What?
This means everyone's
gonna know who I am.
Oh, you're right.
That's worse.
I've gone from a nobody
to a somebody.
...in a single morning.
I can't breathe!
Girl, snap out of it!
Oh!
Ow.
What?
I saw Cher do it in a movie.
That's for hysteria,
not an anxiety attack.
Ooh, yo, sorry, B.
I have to quit.
I have to tell George
to find another boss fast.
Can you do that?
I mean, is it that easy?
I'm just gonna lay low
for a while.
I'm gonna stay away from crowds,
blend in.
So much for blending in.
Sit down, everybody, please.
Hi, Jack.
Verybody, sit down now.
Come on, children.
Thank you, children.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'd like to open by saying.
...that I have been tough
on you all semester...
...but that's only because
I care as much about your minds.
...as I do about your future.
And, Miss Taylor, I'd especially
like to apologize to you.
...for anything that I might
have said about your wardrobe.
It has been most unfair
and cruel of me...
...and I promise you
it will never happen again.
So, uh...
why don't we just forget
today's pop quiz, eh?
Maybe this boss thing
isn't so bad.
You got to tell her
the truth.
I can't.
She hates me.
...for what I did
by abandoning her like that.
She'll forgive you.
when she finds out
you're her grandfather.
No, we stick to the plan.
It's working.
Once she learns the ropes,
takes us legit...
I disappear forever
and remain dead and buried.
Trust me.
It's better that way.
Okay, I don't think
Sal's gonna buy it.
Hey, boss, I can have
one of the boys do that.
No, no, no, no.
No, it helps me relax.
When I was a kid working here,
I could do 40 shirts an hour.
Perfect creases,
not a wrinkle in sight.
Is that funny?
Did I say something funny?
So what do we do
about this Brooke?
You set up the meeting.
I want to know who I'm dealing
with before I make my move.
Hey, put your hand in here.
Go ahead.
Put your hand in.
Put it in.
Funny?
Is that funny?
That's funny, isn't it?
Get out of here.
Hey, George.
What's up?
It's time.
Can you come back later?
You really think
I'm ready for this?
Listen, Brooke, don't forget
what I've taught you:
Control the room,
shake Sal's hand firmly...
...and then the two kisses
of respect.
Now, remember...
Sal does this thing
where he's staring at you.
where he's looking
for weakness.
Just stay calm and show him
that you can handle yourself.
But weakness
is my strongest quality.
Come on, boss.
You're one of the toughest
people I know.
Tough?
Oh, you are so off base
on this one.
I'm not even close to being...
...you really think I'm tough?
You order me around
pretty good.
Well, you make it
really easy and fun.
I grew up
without a family too...
...so I know.
You made yourself
into this amazing person.
with nobody
handing you anything.
That's tough.
Uh-huh.
I hope I don't lose any points
for this one.
Nah, but I might.
You're not coming in?
I'll be out here waiting.
Just be yourself.
You'll do fine.
Here.
Make sure it don't drip
on the rug.
Right, boss.
What is this?
It's, um...
...it's very nice to meet you.
Sit down!
You know, they mentioned
that you was a chick...
...but nobody said nothin'
about you bein' a skirt.
Oh, I'm neither, actually,
Mr. Hugo, sir.
Come again?
I'm a girl.
I object to being labeled
as a chick or a skirt.
It's, like, totally sexist.
You object?
You got moxie.
I'll give you that.
But you don't look like
you could run a sewing circle...
...much less a family.
Oh, no, I assure you I can.
I can fax you my rêsumê.
I have excellent references.
Top of my school,
grades, everything.
Yeah.
Or not.
Listen.
Now that Dominic is gone,
God rest his soul...
I figure everything that's yours
is now mine.
Oh, well, I'm sure
we can work out an agreement.
...that is beneficial
to both of us.
Oh, I'm sure that we can.
The agreement is that you give
all your businesses to me...
...and I'll let you
continue to live.
...so that you could do your
fashion school thing, you know.
I assume from that weird
expression and the silence.
...that that is a yes,
which is good.
Now, get out of here.
I'm busy.
Is... is that
an Italian wool suit?
Custom made, the best.
May I?
Hmm.
What I thought.
What?
It's a mid-weight.
It's too heavy for you.
Makes you sweat a lot, right?
You could say that.
Um, a lighter wool,
say a 110...
would be softer
and breathe better.
Probably make you
sleep easier at night.
You know, I get two hours now,
I'm lucky.
Clothes not only make the man,
they shape the man.
Now, have you ever given any
thought to your color palette?
I have some swatches
in my purse.
Well, you know, I always
thought of myself as an autumn.
Mm, okay, well...
I have this lovely
brown one...
...and it goes with your...
your manliness...
...and still a touch
of your feminine side.
My what?
I did it.
I think I turned him around.
I knew you would.
It was easier than I thought.
I mean, it was scary,
but it was still easy.
You're the boss.
That's right.
Let's go.
Round up the guys.
This is gonna be easier
than I thought.
You guys remember that girl
that hates me for no reason?
The one that spilled
butterscotch pudding.
...on you at dinner?
Mm-hmm.
Well, today she held
the door open for me.
I'm serious.
I was ten feet away,
and she waited.
And it wasn't like there was
anyone else around either.
Just me: Liza!
Did you guys ever think
we would become this popular?
Hey, boss girl.
See you brought a couple
of your goons to the party.
You're only, like, the fifth
Stella McCartney here tonight.
And I don't wanna guess
who you're supposed to be.
What about you, Candace?
What great designer did you
choose to wear tonight?
Me, of course.
Who else?
Come on, ladies.
Heat's all over me
on this one, Jack...
...so I'm here to make sure
you do your job.
Well, I am trying to, sir...
...but I just think I need
a little bit more...
No, no, no.
You're not digging hard enough.
Now, I want you to stay on her
and stay on her close.
...until we can get some evidence
that we can use.
Now, look
at this beautiful baby.
What's that?
New surveillance bug.
Got a camera and microphone
built right in.
That's a... An earring, sir?
It's not...
not really my style.
Would you rather wear
these camera glasses?
I'll take the earring.
Smart choice.
Sir, this is...
this is not a clip-on.
I'd have to get my ears pierced
to wear this, so...
Time to take one
for the bureau, son.
No.
Sir, you can't.
What are you doing?
Sir, n... Aah!
Ow!
Ah.
Ah!
You look nice, Brooke.
Hey, look at you.
You've got an earring.
Yeah, yeah.
It still hurts.
Just when I think I know you.
Yeah, well, I guess
you can't really know anyone.
We all have our secrets.
Whoa, lighten up, Jack.
It's a party.
I'm sorry.
I'm having a really bad day.
Do you want to talk about it?
Yeah.
Yeah, that'd be good.
Do you mind if we go
somewhere else?
The sound is really loud
in here.
Yes, that's my boy!
Way to bring it around, Jack.
Okay.
Hey, Brooke.
Want to dance?
You want me
to dance with you?
Come on.
I paid the DJ to play
a slow song next.
Don't let that pretty boy
take the girl!
So you, uh, notice anything?
Uh, just that my heart
is beating very fast.
Um, I'm wearing the pants
you made in class.
Oh.
So does my butt
still look good?
You might want to ask
your girlfriend that.
Girlfriend?
Pffff.
We broke up days ago.
No, I'm a... Free man.
What happened?
Why'd you leave?
Well, she's with
the male model.
Nothing was gonna happen
tonight, anyway.
Oh, Jack,
can't you do anything right?
Lt... it's pitiful
the way you let that guy.
...take your girl like that.
Oh, man.
Ah.
You wimp.
So look, I was wondering...
would you like to go
on a date with me?
Oh, I love dates!
I love raisins.
I love all that stuff.
They get the worst rap,
but, mmm, they're delicious.
No, go on a date.
What?
I said go on a date with me!
Okay, I'll go on a date
with you.
I don't like this guy.
George...
I've tried to tell her.
He's into you
for the wrong reasons.
I can tell.
Stop trying to act
like my parent.
Sweetie, why don't you wear
the silk blouse you designed?
No, I can't.
I messed the stitching up
on it.
Besides, it's way too amateur.
What are you talking about?
It's beautiful.
She always does this.
George, look at these.
Do these look amateur to you?
They're exquisite.
See?
No offense, George...
...but you know nothing
about fashion.
Hello?
Okay.
He's here.
Gosh, I'm so nervous.
Tell me I look okay.
You look beautiful.
You look great.
Okay, let's go.
Okay, let him pay for dinner,
and laugh at all his jokes.
Okay.
Specially the dumb ones.
All right, got it.
Good night, George.
Bye.
Yeah!
Yes.
I still don't like this guy.
Are you sure you wanted
to come here?
Oh, yeah.
I've read about this place.
Yes?
May I help you?
Table for two.
Sarto.
Welcome.
Welcome!
Hi.
It is my family's
deepest honor.
...having you here tonight.
Please, come with me.
I have the most perfect table
for you.
One moment while we clear
the table for you, huh?
Let me offer you something
while you're waiting.
Thank you.
Whoa!
Would you... would you like
some water, Don...
Miss Don... Miss Donna?
Don's daughter?
It's all set.
This way, please.
The head chef himself
will be out shortly.
...to explain the specials.
...and to make
some lovely recommendations.
Please, order anything you like,
anything at all.
It's on the house.
Your money is no good here.
Yours we'll take.
Njoy.
Must be ladies' night.
Maybe it's because
you're a lady and it's night.
Yeah, there's just so many
talented people on campus.
Sometimes when I think about it...
...it's a little intimidating,
you know?
Yeah.
But I'm not gonna
let that stop me.
No way.
Is that Joey Blow Pops
over there?
Oh, I don't really know.
He likes to chew gum
when he's bumpin' people off.
Always goes with peppermint.
So, Marcus, what about you?
Is modeling something
you want to do long-term...
...or is there...
No, I don't know.
Maybe, I guess.
So look, when people
don't pay you back...
...do you really break their legs?
Huh, send them down the river,
canary in the mouth...
...horse's head in the bed?
Do you believe this guy?
He's using her.
A beautiful girl like that...
...and all he cares about
is gangsters?
Jack, let's stay
professional.
Well, Marcus,
I don't know what you've heard...
...but we don't do that.
Oh, come on.
I'm not scared.
I want to know
all the gory details, really.
Is this why
you asked me out on a date?
Well, yeah.
I mean, dating a Godfather...
...how cool is that?
Verybody's talkin'.
Ugh!
This guy is too much.
You're not even
that good-looking, pal!
Oh, that's real professional.
That's Kneecaps Swanney.
Oh, and he's coming this way.
Yo, Kneecaps,
can I get a picture?
I'm just a big fan, man.
I know all your hits.
Say,"bullets."
Lt'd be hilarious.
Bullets.
Did you take it?
I didn't see a flash.
You know what?
Next time you want to spend
an evening with a mobster...
...rent a movie.
Um, signorina,
is there something wrong?
Yes, tell my date
never to talk to me again.
My pleasure.
All right, let's go.
Come with us.
What?
Can I get my camera?
Girl, what did you think
you guys did...
...steal Girl Scout cookies?
I don't know.
I tried not to.
Well, maybe you should.
The Mafia does
a lot of bad things.
Not us.
Oh, you're the friendly
and nice mobsters.
You know,
you guys really aren't helping.
Look, all we're trying
to say is...
...how much do you really know
about your grandfather.
...and the businesses he ran?
He was dragged into it
by his father...
...never given a choice.
Believe me,
your grandfather was no killer.
He was a good man
doing his best to survive.
...and provide for his family.
And my parents,
were they involved?
No, he kept them out.
...like he kept you out
'cause he loved you.
He wanted you to have
a chance at a normal life...
...and you can still have that.
How?
Right there in the books.
Yeah, but waste management,
concrete, scrap metal.
What do I know
about that stuff?
Dress factory?
What's that?
I'll show you.
We run a sweatshop?
These are skilled workers.
...making a decent wage
with insurance.
Hey, what are these?
Those are mine.
I did them on my break.
They're beautiful.
You have
a very distinctive style.
Thank you.
Oh, the mother lode!
Check it out.
Oh, my gosh.
We got Prada and Fendi
and Gucci.
Oh, my!
Don't tell her,
but they're fake.
I think
I got designer brain freeze.
Okay, I'm fine.
You're trying to tell me
we sell knockoffs?
'Cause that's all we know
how to do.
Why didn't you tell me
about this before?
Look at this, girl!
Girl, look at this.
This is beautiful.
Oh, my gosh!
Oh, my goodness!
This was
your grandfather's office.
He made clothes?
First job he ever had...
...helping the wiseguys
in the neighborhood look sharp.
I have fashion in my blood.
You have designer genes.
I knew it.
Sarto means"tailor"
in Italian.
That's how you got
your last name.
Here you are, sir.
Oh, great.
Thanks, Rosa.
What's that?
Present.
Oh, sorry.
I don't wear fake clothes.
It's not fake.
It's a genuine Brooke Taylor.
My dress!
You asked how you can help us
become legit?
That's how.
Oh, my God!
I'm so good!
I knew it all along.
No, really.
I'm, like, really good.
Right.
You see that?
What?
Veryone's looking at you.
Pretty cool, isn't it?
It's the office again.
Should I be worried?
Yeah, I got the same call.
Dean Faber must be needing money
all of a sudden.
I heard him say
he was raising tuition.
Oh, well.
I'll see you guys later.
All: Bye!
Jack?
Jack!
Hi!
Oh, hey, Brooke.
Wow, look at you.
I know.
It's a little dressy
for class but...
No, you look incredible.
You look like you just
stepped out of a French issue.
...of Vogue magazine.
That is the sweetest thing
anyone's ever said to me.
Jack!
Get out of here!
Are you a janitor here?
Jack!
I think that is so great,
working your way through school.
Yeah, right, work.
Jack!
I'll be with you
in a second!
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Yeah, okay.
Okay.
So tomorrow in the quad,
there's this sewing rally thing.
Yes, last team rally
before the sew-off.
I never miss it.
Right, and I was thinking,
you know...
...since you're going,
which you are...
...and if I'm going,
which I am...
...then maybe we could, uh,
you know...
You're gonna make me
finish this, aren't you?
Go together.
You mean like a date?
Well, it sounds kind of corny
when you say it like that.
Oh, sorry.
It'd be better
if you just sort of said...
"Yeah, I'd love to go."
I mean, if that's
how you're feeling.
Then, yeah, I'd love to.
Great.
So it's a date.
I can't wait.
I'll see you tomorrow.
So how did it go?
Sir, for the record,
I do not think this is right.
What are you talking about?
It's working.
She said yes.
Yes, I know, but...
Do I have to remind you
about your job, Jack?
And that your career
is on the line with this case?
No, but, sir...
She is the linchpin we need
to bring down.
...all organized crime
in this city.
You want that, don't ya?
Of course.
Well, then keep putting
on that charm, boy...
'cause all that romantic
sweet talk's gonna help us.
...bag that fashion crime queen.
I'm sorry.
This ain't right.
She doesn't need me
anymore, Frank.
That ain't true.
I want you to keep
an eye on her.
Make sure she gets
anything she needs.
Okay?
Anything.
George!
You're never gonna believe
what happened today.
What's this?
You going on vacation?
Brooke, I wanted to talk
to you about it.
I got a date tomorrow.
I'm sorry, I couldn't wait.
It's with Jack.
That's great.
I'm happy for you.
I know; I wanted to go get
coffee and talk about it.
I'm so excited.
I don't know
if I'm gonna sleep tonight.
But if you're going somewhere...
...you needed
to tell me something?
I, uh...
I was going to throw away
these suitcases.
...and wanted to know
if you needed 'em.
Oh, okay.
Well, can we do it later?
I'm just so glad you're home.
It's so great to know
I can come here any time...
...and you'll always be here, isn't
it?
Yeah, it is.
If you got
any more together, Brooke...
I'd have to start hating you.
That is so sweet.
So does this Jack know
about what you're doing?
No, we haven't really
talked about that.
He must.
It's all over the school.
You don't think
he's like Marcus, do you?
No, you would've caught on
by now.
But you need to talk about it,
explain it to him.
Otherwise all he's got
to go on is vicious rumors.
Ladies.
And speaking of vicious.
Great news.
You're being expelled?
I got straight As on all
of my latest dresses here.
Check 'em out.
Beauty and brains.
I am indeed the full package
come to life.
I swear, one day,
she is gonna get hers.
She cheated.
What?
She didn't design
those dresses.
I knew it!
She's a big phony.
Wait.
Then who did?
It wasn't my fault.
I swear.
Oh, no, Rosa.
We know it's not your fault.
Just... why don't you tell us
what happened?
My mother works
for her family...
...cleaning and taking care of the
house.
That's how I met Candace.
When she saw my drawings...
...she said she'd help me
get into the university.
But instead
she's been ripping you off?
I can't say anything...
...or maybe my mom,
she loses her job.
Well, we got to tell
the dean.
Yeah, we'll tell him
Monday morning.
We just need to gather
all the evidence.
We're gonna need
all your drawings, okay?
Don't worry, Rosa.
Candace
won't get away with this.
No, sir.
I'm sure we mailed it.
Foreclosure?
Now, why do you have to go
and use a word like that?
Hello, Dean.
Let me call you back.
What's the matter?
You havin' a little trouble
with the bank there, huh?
Sal, what are you doing here?
You've been
a bad boy again, huh?
Stealing money
from the school, right?
I told you, it's not for me.
It's for refurbishing
the dean's mansion.
I can see.
You got very expensive taste
in furniture.
Too expensive.
Sal, we had a deal.
As soon as the alumni
come through...
I'll pay you back.
What deal?
There is no deal.
I want my money now.
Now!
But I owe other people too.
Yeah, but with them,
you just get a nasty phone call.
With me, you get Bruno.
Oh, hi, Bruno.
What's the matter?
You look
a little hot there, Dean.
No wonder.
This is so heavy.
You ever think about goin'
with somethin'
...a little bit lighter,
say, a 110?
So much softer, you know?
Breathes better, you know?
It's done wonders for me.
Look at this.
Oh, yeah.
See that?
Yeah.
I sleep like a baby now.
Well, thank you.
II'll give it some thought.
Terrific.
Now, I want to discuss a little
business proposition with you.
Well, it's not exactly
a proposition.
It's more like a...
what do you call it?
Hostile takeover, boss.
Hostile takeover.
HH-hostile takeover?
As in,
I take over the school.
This is a prime piece
of real estate you got here.
I can turn a pretty penny.
But it's been in my family
for generations.
Aw, we're gonna have to put up
a plaque or somethin', you know.
Hey, we can put it
right in the new parking lot...
which is going to be very soon.
...right here where your office
is right now.
A parking lot?
What is this?
That's French, boss.
French?
Ming.
Ming?
I don't care
for the Ming thing.
Ooh, look at those sparkles.
That's good crystal.
It's leaded.
Yeah, excellent quality.
I like that chair.
You got it, Mr. Hugo.
No, no.
Oh, my God.
You call that a pleat?
Drop stitch, and give me 20.
Wow, Ms. Sandusky
is really on the ball this year.
I've lost it, guys,
completely.
It's gone.
What are you talking about?
Very instinct I used to have,
good-bye.
I totally suck at fashion.
You do not suck at fashion.
Page, help me.
Not totally.
What am I even doing?
I don't belong here.
I'm completely fooling myself.
Hey, there's Jack.
I'll be right back.
Be nice to her.
Hey, at least your fingers
look thinner.
Here we go.
Come on, girls, let's do it!
Real loud, y'all!
So they actually give out
awards for this stuff, huh?
They sure do.
Last year, I won the gold
in welt pocket.
...and buttonhole stitch.
Oh, nice.
I think the only time
I've ever won gold.
...is for a star in attendance.
Me too.
And I bet you were punctual
as well.
Never late,
grades 2 through 12.
What about first?
Ah, it was an accident.
Were you okay?
Yeah, it was with my jeans.
We had to go home and change.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I have this bad habit
of confessing.
...the weirdest things
about myself.
Um, actually,
I'm glad you said that.
I have a confession myself.
All right, Jack, this is it.
Don't blow it.
I'm sure you've heard some
rumors around campus about me.
Are they true?
Yes and no.
See, the thing is...
Actually,
you know what, Brooke?
It doesn't matter.
What?
Forget about it.
It's not important.
What?
No, no, no,
I need to tell you...
We... we all have our faults.
I mean, I once...
I stole a candy bar
from a market.
I mean, it was an accident.
...because a friend of mine
put it in my pocket...
...but the fact is,
I broke the law.
Okay, but for me...
What is really important
is what's in your heart...
...and I can tell
that you have a good one.
Jack, listen.
I have been working for the...
Hey!
Can I have your attention,
please?
Wait, what was that?
I have an important
announcement to make.
I'll be right back.
Brooke, wait.
You idiot!
That's it, Jack.
That's it.
Oh!
Can I have
your attention, please?
I have a very important
announcement to make.
Hello, people, people,
please gather around.
Gather around, everybody.
I have a very important
announcement to make.
...to you all today.
Tomorrow's sew-off
is cancelled.
Aw, come on.
That's ridiculous!
In fact, tragically...
we're closing down
the entire school.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing I can do.
It's out of my hands.
Less competition for me.
Dean, you can't do this.
You mobsters,
always ordering people around.
What?
What are you talking about?
Sal Hugo runs things now.
This was his decision,
not mine.
I need to go home
and be with my furniture.
It might be my last chance.
Miss Taylor?
Or should I say Miss Sarto?
We need to talk.
Jack?
I'm sorry, Brooke.
Miss Sarto, you might want
to call a lawyer about now.
I don't need a lawyer.
I haven't done anything wrong.
We'll let the federal
prosecutor decide that.
I'm changing them,
Mr. Tiernan.
I'm making
the family legitimate.
Our contacts confirm it, sir.
Well, if that's true...
...perhaps you can help us
with Sal Hugo.
It would go a long way
in clearing your name.
No way, sir.
That is way too dangerous.
We have other options.
Thank you, Jack,
if that's your real name...
...but I don't need
your phony concern.
My feelings were not phony.
Jack, let me handle this,
please?
No, I understand that, sir,
but I have a...
Hey!
I have my own issues
with Sal Hugo.
He's trying
to take over my school.
Then maybe
we can help each other.
That's
a really good idea, sir.
That was my idea.
No, I know, but I'm just
suggesting that I could help...
We don't need your help.
But it's not...
I don't want your help.
You should seek help.
I really should have changed
my hair for this picture.
George, you've got to help us.
I can't pull together
that kind of cash...
...not so fast.
Well, then, we'll raise it.
The school is not closing.
But what can we do?
What we do best.
We'll put on a fashion show.
Yes, that's perfect.
We'll sell
all the clothes afterwards.
...and squeeze every penny
we can get.
Well, we got a lot
to squeeze, though.
Gonna take
a lot of planning.
Can I be in charge of it?
I can do it.
Please.
Okay.
Hope I did the right thing.
You're the boss.
Yeah.
We will save the school!
Now come on back and sign up.
Hey!
Love has gotten me nowhere.
That's right, dear.
You let it out.
You'll feel better.
I'm always falling
for the wrong guy, always.
It's like my keen senses
only apply to fashion.
You aren't the only one.
Okay, yes, I lied too.
But I thought
we really had something.
It turns out I'm just a way
to advance his career.
Didn't work.
I've been suspended.
You, uh, mind if I join you?
You see, when I was a kid...
...my grandparents' shop
was burned to the ground.
...by Sal Hugo.
That's why
I initially joined the FBI...
...to take people like him down.
So now you want me
to help you?
No, I just want you to
understand why I did what I did.
Okay, look, it's knit one.
Purl two.
See?
This isn't more
undercover work, is it?
I mean, you're not wired
or anything, are you?
No.
The only thing undercover
was my job.
My feelings have been out
in the open the entire time.
I have to go.
Wait.
What are you gonna do
about Sal?
Make him an offer
he can't refuse.
Well, be careful.
Now, let me get this straight.
You're gonna get me my money...
...and you want to give me
all of your businesses?
Xcept for the dress factory.
That's nonnegotiable.
Keep it.
All those salaries
with the dental insurance.
...and the 401 this and that.
Who wants it?
I do.
And all I gotta do.
...is to let you keep
the fashion school open?
That's the deal, Sal.
I don't know.
Anything looks this perfect,
usually there's something wrong.
Our families fight,
and nobody wins.
In the end...
...maybe you'll be the one
giving me your businesses.
You really think you could
pull off something like that?
I do.
Okay.
Let's talk dollar amounts.
Cigar?
Okay, think, Dee.
What do we do?
George!
What's wrong?
Some of the models
aren't here...
...and the show's about to start!
Dee, what is the holdup?
Some of the models
aren't here...
...and the show's about to start!
What?
Hey, what's going on?
You're late,
and I'm tired of explaining it.
You know, somebody
must have given the models.
...the wrong address.
Now, who would do that?
I've had about enough
from her!
George, don't waste your time.
Okay, look, let's not panic.
We will be the models.
Xcuse me?
Okay, Page and I
will be the models.
But the sizes
will be all wrong.
Please, girl,
I can fit into anything.
Come on.
Come on, now.
Yeah!
See?
It's perfect.
Yeah, it's good.
Just mix and match
some outfits.
...and make
some alterations, please?
I think I'd rather model.
It's gonna be fine.
George, help her.
What are you waiting for?
For you to do everything.
You got the ability.
I know you do.
You just need to trust
yourself.
Okay.
Well, let's go!
Let's do it!
Okay.
Mix those outfits.
Brooke Sarto
and Fashion University.
welcomes you
to the first annual.
Save The School Fashion Show.
One minute, ladies!
One minute!
Don't just sit there,
George.
Find me some pinking shears.
Move!
Thank you.
And once again,
ladies and gentlemen...
...a sneak peek at the hottest
new look of tomorrow.
Looks are from signature series
appropriately labeled.
Crimes of Fashion.
Now let's give it up
for your host...
...the boldest newcomer
to the fashion world...
Brooke Sarto!
Your designs are stunning,
my dear, absolutely stunning.
You are definitely
going places.
But you still got
the afternoon shift Friday.
Don't forget, 3:00 to 6:00.
Don't be late.
Brooke!
Neiman Marcus is downstairs
and wants to talk to you.
What?
There is a buyer here
from Bloomingdale's.
Can you believe it?
Bloomies!
But how?
I called in a few favors,
bent a few arms.
Bent, not broke.
You did it.
You saved the school.
You're a real
honest-to-God designer now.
Oh, I don't know.
Do you really think
I'm ready for that?
Yes!
This is just the beginning.
It's everything you worked for.
Okay, there's just
one more thing I have to do.
Okay, so we're square
then, right?
I hand over all
the illegal operations to you...
...and you let me keep the school.
I don't think so.
Wait.
What?
We had a deal.
Yeah, and I just broke it,
'cause this way, I get it all.
See, I like parking lots...
...and your school
has a lot of potential.
You can't do this.
What, are you kiddin'?
This is what I do best.
I lie.
I extort, except on my taxes...
'cause I don't even pay taxes.
See, I do bad things
to good people.
And I enjoy it.
And the best part is
that nobody can stop me.
Nobody.
That's a nice earring
you got there.
Don't pay your taxes, huh?
That's not good, Sal.
Smile.
You're on Government Sting TV.
Nobody move!
That was a joke.
It's all over, Sal.
Keep your hands up, sir.
Hey, careful.
This is 110.
It's very delicate.
Tell it to a judge.
Take him away, guys.
Bye.
Nice work, Jack.
Gonna get a commendation
for this one.
Nice work.
Thanks.
So I guess you're all done
with the case now.
Guess so.
That's what I thought.
But a complicated case
like this...
...there's probably
a lot of cleaning up to do.
Oh, yes, a lot.
Yeah, it could take weeks,
even... Even months.
Well, you could start
by interviewing me...
...you know, one-on-one.
Well, you are
the star witness.
It was a joke.
I was kidding.
Hey, Sal.
I told you we got somebody.
You...
Brooke, they arrested the dean
for embezzling school funds.
Great.
Who's gonna be the dean now?
Xpelled?
But how will this look
on my rêsumê?
You cheated.
You stole someone else's designs
and claimed them as your own.
Put that on your rêsumê.
Well, what about Brooke?
I mean, she's a mob boss.
Nothing in the rules
against that.
Besides,
I just don't like you.
Hi.
What's she doing here?
She is getting
what she deserves.
I enrolled Rosa this morning.
Full scholarship.
Yours actually.
Works out very nicely.
Thank you so much.
It's been my dream
to come here.
Can I go tell my mom?
Sure, go ahead.
Remember, though,
class starts at 9:00.
Good work, dean.
You can still call me George.
This place is gonna look great
when you add your touch...
...you know, get rid of the gold.
Hey, that's me
with my asy-Sew...
...standing next to you.
I don't...
You were the ex-orphan.
You were Donny.
Yes, my special angel.
It was me.
I can't believe it.
Did my grandfather send you?
Brooke...
I am your grandfather.
What?
You're not my grandfather.
Come on.
That's...
Oh, my God.
You are my grandfather.
Why didn't you tell me?
You were so angry,
I couldn't.
And when my cousin died,
I faked my own death...
...and I was planning
to disappear.
...once you took over the family
and made it legit...
...but I couldn't.
Why?
Why couldn't you?
You opened a piece of my heart
that had been shut long ago.
So I couldn't leave you again.
Not ever.
Anyway, I know you
can't forgive me for all this...
...but I...
I did it for you.
I love you, Grandpa.
I love you too, sweetie.
# Step up #
# There's no reason
to hesitate #
# We're primed,
and we're restless #
# So we better start moving #
# Come on #
# All this waiting,
all this wonder #
# Now our time has come #
# We're making history #
# very second adds up
to what we'll be... #
Miss Taylor, come out
with your hands in the air!
Oh, my God!
Oh, it's so beautiful.
Thank you.
# It's not just victory #
# We're standing in the presence
of royalty... #