Filmed in Grand Scope
SHOCHIKU
presents
HUMAN CONDITION
Part 1
Enterprise
Bungei Production Ninjin Club
Based on the novel by Junpei Gomikawa
Written by Zenzo Matsuyama, Masaki Kobayashi
Photography: Yoshio Miyajima
Art Direction: Kazue Hirataka
Sound Recording: Hideo Nishizaki
Music: Chuji Kinoshita
Directed by Masaki Kobayashi
It's not like you.
Why?
You're running away!
Don't you want me?
Of course I do!
And I want you!
Yet we can't marry!
How many times do I have to tell you!
Because you may be called up
at any moment?
I don't care if you're called up
the day after we're married.
I'll cry no doubt.
But happiness comes
only through marriage.
Then will you come to my dormitory?
Will you spend the night with me?
You'll come?
I'll come.
As I thought...
Go back to your own dormitory.
I couldn't do that to you.
You... were just trying to test me!
Weakling... coward! I've had enough.
SOUTH MANCHURIA STEEL CO.
Research Section
Hi! A rare meeting.
I just dropped by... to say "goodbye"
Your call... it came?
Yes.
And the date?
Tomorrow. My papers came 5 days ago
but I've been drinking ever since...
Oh yes... I met Michiko last night.
Aren't you marrying her?
Tomorrow you then it'll be me!
But that needn't be the end.
I'm a born optimist and I've had
my share of earthly pleasures.
I only regret...
That I haven't left the germ of life
in the womb of some loving woman.
I may regret it, too.
But I can't be as optimistic as you.
The boss wants me... wait for me inside.
No... I'll see you tonight.
That's so.
See you.
Kaji seemed a bit upset.
Is something wrong?
Going to remain just friends forever?
You had the spunk to come
to work out here with him.
Throw yourself at him!
I did do.
He rejected you?
No. 12 and No. 13, stop that chatter!
I'll report you!
Supervision of Colonial Labour
I've read it twice.
Very interesting.
Smells of leftist tendencies, though.
What are you trying to say?
That men should be treated
as men, that is all.
In colonial territories it...
It's difficult?
That's right.
We profit by exploiting Chinese
labour... wasn't that the idea?
That's right.
Doesn't that conflict with your theory?
That's true.
Mind if I smoke?
No, I don't mind.
What do you think?
Without the contradiction my theory
isn't needed.
In other words, you feel it's possible
to improve work records... is that it?
A possibility. By the way, I want you
to take over at the Loh Hu Liong mines.
Any objections to being sent off
into the hinterlands?
I'm not forcing you.
You've analysed the situation
quite well... on paper.
Would you want it to end up only on paper?
Of course not.
Whenever you're ready to put
your theories into actual practice...
I'll do my bit to help...
by having you exempted from army duty.
Exemption? From military service?
You're not alone in the exemption.
There are dozens of others.
No. What I meant was...
It's just the idea...
Of accepting military exemption in exchange
for the Lo Hu Liong job that worries me.
A bad habit! Leave well enough alone.
The savage fighting continues
with only one way of resisting.
By facing a life sentence in prison.
Neither of us had the courage
to face up to it.
Yes... you're right.
A gift from Heaven!
Not even the commander of the
Kwangtung Army ever dared slap me!
Go to Loh Hu Liong with Michiko.
Michiko... his sweetheart? Is pretty?
The most beautiful girl in the world.
But to me you're much more beautiful.
Hey... You called yourself a
shepherd's dog didn't you?
Why not? A good dog can
lead sheep to greener pastures...
And can earn their eternal gratitude.
If such things exist.
Me? I'll take this one.
My little Mannon, your hair
has the aroma of dried grass.
Michiko...
My best wishes go with you!
Go with Kaji to Loh Hu Liong!
Let this war go to the dogs!
You mustn't let happiness...
He may never come back...
I won't be called up
Loh Hu Liong is a tiny
Manchurian village.
All we'll find there are iron ore
and labour camps.
Would you go with me to such a place?
I'd follow you... anywhere!
It may affect your whole life.
Think it over!
If the army ever called you
to active duty.
I... I'd even been planning to have
a child by you.
Is that too absurd?
What a honeymoon!
What did you say?
The wind... and this dust!
I don't care! It's wonderful!
Like gravel in my mouth!
Loh Hu Liong
You must think I'm blind!
What?
Trick me into giving
you special rations? Oh no!
Kaji from Head Office?
That's right.
I'm Okishima. We're working partners.
We can dispense with the niceties.
What ever made you come to this hole?
Come.
Thank you.
Anything for love's sake, eh?
Yes, how do you do?
Please, this way.
Haul their bags to their new quarters.
I read your report...
the one about supervision of labour.
Filled with fancy words...
Oh, madam... please!
Men here don't go for fancy talk.
You'll have little in common.
Thanks for your advice.
What's so funny?
Sorry! Your own fancy talk sounds
so out of place.
Very well written! Reaching the pith
of the matter.
Yes! Reaching but not quite grasping...
Why is that?
If I knew, I'd write a book!
I'll take your wife.
You go see the boss.
Say, Furuya... show him the way!
I know this is nothing new, sir.
But our first shift requires 2,500 men.
Only 1,500 turned up this morning.
How can we be expected
to make our production goal?
We're at war, Okazaki!
We must expect such shortages.
But...
You can't produce unless
all conditions are perfect, is that it?
I didn't mean that, but Labour
must help us.
Kaji... reporting for work, sir!
You're Kaji?
I'll introduce you.
2nd Pit Supervisor, Mr Higuchi.
His Foreman, Mr. Kawashima.
1st Pit supervisor, Mr Koiki.
And his Foreman, Mr. Okazaki.
This is Mr. Kaji... sent by
Head Office as Labour Supervisor.
Pleased to meet you.
You're just in time. Please, sit down.
We're discussing our labour shortage.
Any good ideas?
I’d like to talk to Okishima first...
And find how many men are available.
If their labour conditions are improved,
all the men will report for work.
Yes... and in more concrete form?
Our employment system
must be changed.
The labour boss must be replaced
by a direct employment system.
You'd be throttling the mines.
It's ridiculous.
You agree Kawashima?
And why so?
Because... your name was Kaji?
You should know better!
We have some 200 labour groups here.
How many have no rake-off system
or don't cheat on food rations?
I doubt if such a group exists.
But our problem is how to raise
our work attendance rate.
Labourers lose the desire to work...
If, basically, labour condition are evil.
Regardless of how things are basically,
labourers aren't what you make
them out to be in theory.
Once they earn more than they need,
they pour it into the crotch of women.
A difference in opinion.
Such methods never gain results.
But, Kaji, the theory may be correct
and yet not apply in reality.
Then... either the theory is wrong.
Or the application is incorrect.
Be that as it may. Try it your way.
I respect revolutionary ideas.
Moving on. Yours is not a desk job.
It covers all aspects of the men's lives.
Food rationing, the disposal of
the excrements of 10,000 men,
handling menstrual cases among women.
Of women?
We have comfort quarters for our men.
As Okishima will point out,
there are 60-odd Manchu women.
From today... you're their boss.
I'm glad to see you're not a bachelor.
Go home now and do your duty
by your wife... but don't overdo it!
But why must our group be disbanded?
Poor records... you've been
raking off too much.
Are you joking? What's it all about?
Shall I show you the evidence?
Why need the company make trouble
over our contracts with the men?
Our money is for the labourers.
But Foreman Okazaki says
our men work very hard.
Yes... but your rolls have been
over-padded.
But Mr. Okazaki...
I'm not Okazaki... I'm Kaji of Labour!
Mr. Okishima, put in a good word
for us. We're like old buddies!
That's probably why I'm mouldy.
And Kaji has been scrubbing me until
I'm practically raw!
Mr. Supervisor... poor living quarters,
and poor food make our men sickly.
I know! Inadequate quarters...
Poor food! Men can't work that way.
But there is still greater evil.
Must I tell you?
You're that evil!
Now get this... I give the men my word!
The food situation will improve.
Better quarters will be considered.
But it's no use as long as
you exploit them.
You make a practice of lending money,
to transient labourers and binding
them for life.
You squeeze as much profit out of them
as you can.
Your slave-drivers torture those
who try to escape.
I won't allow such methods!
You won't? And so what?
You're a mere employee of this company.
Won't allow it, eh? Try and stop us!
Hey! Any more threats and I'll kick
your nuts in!
The gentlemen are having a bad day.
We'll come back.
Mr. Muta!
You can keep this!
And I've sent your packages back.
They left too peacefully!
They're up to something.
A tour of inspection?
I'm grateful to you gentlemen.
By the way... see to it that
we get the men we need.
The old man won't take excuses.
Sure, you'll get them.
But don't kill 'em off too fast.
What happened?
The lazy dogs refuse to move!
Beating them senseless won't help.
Cruelty makes them worse.
I take orders from Okazaki... not you!
What goes on here doesn't concern you.
Then you refuse to stop?
Of course.
Good! From tomorrow you'll have
no men to beat.
What's that? You're in the pit now.
You can't pull rank on us down here!
Lazy ones... You don't wish to work?
Then... don't!
From tomorrow you needn't come.
Remain by the cosy
fireplaces in your barracks.
But remember...
You will receive no food!
Just returning home?
Did you want something?
Just one question. Did you threaten
to shut off our supply of labour?
Well... how about it?
We can discuss it in the morning.
Morning? I can understand why
you'd prefer it so.
Especially with one's wife watching...
Do you think so?
Answer my question!
What's with you?
Your brutality may cow your labourers,
but I'm not impressed.
I warned your man.
Mr. Kaji! You surely know how
important that ore is to us.
What's so wrong about beating the men?
As long as the ore keeps coming out,
why the fuss?
Which is more important...
the ore... or the men?
I never think of things in that way.
One doesn't compare men with minerals.
Kindness will produce more ore.
Let me make it clear that Okazaki
of Loh Hu Liong can't be changed...
By any of your half-baked ideas.
I stick to my own way. Remember that!
I will! And I'll stick to my own ways.
These gentlemen from the KEMPEITAI
are offering us 600 special labourers.
Special labourers?
Prisoners from North China.
All you need do is keep them fed.
A heaven-sent blessing!
We're short of men here.
Completely unexpected!
Yes! Our Head Office will certainly
be pleased.
Kaji... talk it over with Okishima.
In what way?
I'll give the instructions.
I never repeat my instructions...
Is that Understand?
First: Special labourers must be
isolated from ordinary labourers.
Second: Their quarters will be
enclosed with barbed wire.
This barbed wire must be electrified.
Is that understood?
Food and labour are left in your hands
but they must not escape!
How much electricity can you supply?
About 3,000 volts.
Good enough!
They will be delivered to you
a week from today.
Arrival time will be notified later.
You understand?
We won't be ready in a week!
What?
Not too anxious to get help?
Kaji!
Why should we take over
supervision of POWs?
Make all preparations.
Wait!
I need your answer!
We understand! We'll be ready.
To be safe we need a whole
platoon of armed men.
I hate being either aggressive or
defensive. Go if you wish!
Why play the hero in front of me?
Some day you'll appreciate me.
Chen... how's your mother?
She's in and out of bed all day.
Ill? Take good care of her.
Yes.
Mr. Kaji... I wish to ask a favour.
May I have some white flour
from the storeroom.
For your mother?
Yes.
I wish I could help but I can't
make any exceptions.
Here she comes!
Chen... how does all this strike you?
They are your fellow countrymen
who lived in anti-Japanese areas.
They may be friends of your
mother from Shantung.
My mother raised me so as not to be
anti-Japanese.
In a battle area, you'd be murdered
as a sympathizer.
The key!
We haven't received it yet.
From Loh Hu Liong?
That's right.
Are you in charge?
What's your name?
Kaji.
Yes... Kaji! I never forget a name.
Good! I transfer the labourers to you.
Never forget that these men
are prisoners of war.
To deal with them you must be
military men at heart.
Civilian negligence will not be tolerated!
You understand?
We understand.
You don't understand Kaji!
You think your seven men can handle
600 prisoners?
What if they escape?
We received no special instructions.
I assumed this meant
no special danger.
You're quite a bold one!
How old are you?
I am 28.
You're married?
May I have the key?
You're a stubborn one!
l like 'em that way.
You'll witness the transfer?
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm on official leave.
You seem to feel that the army
can make mistakes.
Don't worry!
When the army says 604... it's 604!
Send in a receipt immediately.
I don't care if they all die
but they must not escape!
Dirty scum!
Get up! Get up!
They unload this mess on us?
Hey! Open the others.
Get up.
Hurry up! Get off!
Get off! Get off!
Line up... double file!
Mr. Kaji... Mr. Kaji!
This looks bad!
What is it?
Hurry! Hurry!
They've steamed to death.
Help me! Help me!
Don't let them eat! Stop them!
Mr. Kaji!
Get back! Get back!
Don't eat that!
You'll all die!
Give me the whip!
Kaji! Here!
The special labourers
are unfit to work.
Let them have a month's rest
They're half dead!
Meaning these anti-Japanese elements
will be fed without working?
If you had witnessed the scene
I'm sure you'd agree with me, sir.
They are POWs. Is that why
12 were allowed to die?
If you want 'em dead, stuff them
with raw beans... they'll die!
Say... watch that tongue of yours!
What you're saying amounts to
a denouncement of the military.
I'll adopt your opinion just once more.
Just once more?
Yes... just once more!
And why so?
You'd like to know?
Despite all your convictions,
l just got a report from Furuya.
150 men under your supervision
have just walked out on us.
I shall overlook the matter this time.
I give you all warning.
I know you all want to escape.
However... you cannot escape from here.
If you even try...
This mongrel's fate will be yours.
Chen... release the dog!
Tomorrow means a new month
of still higher production goals.
The Directors have even discussed
replacement of all top men here.
I will accept this disgrace if
production increase is impossible.
However, we have not yet
done our utmost.
Until we attain the 20% production
increase demanded of us...
We must continue this crash program.
Are there any dissenting opinions?
In the name of final victory, I refuse.
to listen to any of your excuses!
Mr. Koike... tell him he has my word.
I, Okazaki, vow that Pit No. 1
will top the new goal.
And I'm sure you've no objections
regarding my methods.
Do as you think best!
The goal must be achieved.
Understand? Lash them on
with still greater fury.
Any Chinaman who shirks may be killed.
Push them! Whip them!
We need that extra 20%!
Men who top their quota
will be amply rewarded.
Remember! We're at war here... at war!
Anyone here feel he can't do this?
Good! Give 'em everything you have.
I'll assume all responsibility.
Starting tomorrow, you will go to work.
Rations will be kaoliang and bean-lees.
The same as ordinary labourers.
You don't smoke?
I did formerly.
You stopped?
When we run out of tobacco, we suffer.
I can't believe Japanese will
keep us supplied.
Now that we've revived you,
you would bear a grudge?
We were not fighting men.
We have the right to demand release.
I haven't the authority to free you.
I am only authorized to detain you.
Master... when we be free?
We all not soldier. We no fight!
Japan soldier come...
Make bad all Chinese woman...
Take away all man... Bring here.
No give us food... Many die!
Not die... They killed!
I cannot set you free but I can
promise that you will not be killed.
Japanese speak clever words.
Also write clever words.
But never they keep promise.
I believe your name was Kao?
Now remember this...
You have been
placed under our supervision.
Whether that barbed wire remains
or is removed, depends on you!
Walk faster!
Come on!
Step along there!
Mr. Kaji, if men escape,
it mean trouble?
Why need they escape?
Those men work before in own village.
Do they wish to work here?
Here they have no mother...
no wife... and no children.
Kaji... how about those special
labourers? Why so many left?
They're the sick ones.
Make sure they're not feigning illness.
I didn't come to find fault,
but I'd like to see their quarters.
This way...
No signs of any breaks?
No, I don't think so.
They must be given some incentive.
I think so too.
What do prisoners dream of the most?
Freedom, I suppose!
Freedom? You must be a poet.
It's women! If they're men
they dream of women.
What did you dream of as a bachelor?
Of the ways of the Empire? I doubt it!
The way to make prisoners work...
is to satisfy 70% of their bodily lust.
But... women...
Very simple! You supervise the
comfort girls... send them inside.
Is it really necessary?
You... do you want a woman?
See? The word "woman" alone
brings joy to their hearts.
What is man? He's not a poem!
Nor is he mortality!
A mere mass of matter
formed of lust and greed!
I shall ask their leaders.
Who gives your orders? Prisoners or I?
I'm concerned over their welfare.
See that it's carried out!
Stop loafing!
Hurry up!
You dog!
Master... this man sick!
He maybe die.
What did you say?
Have mercy... he sick man!
Save your whining for Kaji!
l don't care if you all die! Dogs!
Kaji! Mr. Kaji! No want to see?
Sister Jin!
Mr. Kaji... welcome!
Mr. Kaji, you sleep with me?
l no want money.
I'm sorry but I need 30 girls
for the special labourers.
The Labour Office will pay for them.
They go inside barb wire?
Like all dogs... all sleep together?
If you don't like it,
you may refuse.
It can't be helped...
we work girls.
I send 30 girls... tomorrow.
Jin. Don't be crazy!
We can't work with people watching!
Do you realize how many men
there are in that compound?
Don't come if you'd rather not.
I refuse... even if the others go.
You want to be a shirker?
What do you mean?
I said it for all of us.
Talking big aren't you?
Go... if you wish!
Be quiet! You don't make the decisions.
So what?
Enough.
Stop your bickering.
I'll decide what to do.
Night time... 30 girls go... all right?
Yes... send them.
What's wrong?
The foreman did him in.
Where?
Pit No. 3.
Okazaki, eh? Rush him to
the First Aid Station.
He can't be allowed to
get away with this!
I'll charge him with manslaughter.
Come, now... relax!
It was unwise of Okazaki to use force.
But he only did it in his eagerness
to increase production.
After all, his motives were patriotic.
Okazaki may be a brute.
But only with this brutality.
can one operate that large pit.
We need him just as we need you
to keep our 10,000 men in line.
After all we're at war!
To achieve the ultimate victory,
one must overlook the minor errors.
An error? A human being was murdered!
Kaji... I warn you again... relax!
Think it over... you'll see!
Can we exchange a good,
hard-working Japanese.
for the life of one mere labourer?
That's not the point!
If you insist on pressing charges
include me as an accomplice.
I'll see that the suit goes
unfavourably for you.
I can do it, you know.
You'd dare distort the truth?
Sir... will you see that it
never happens again?
How shall we report it?
Well now...
Report it as an accidental death.
Say he fell off a ledge...
It does happen you know.
You think I'll write that fake report?
What else can we do!
No. I refuse to write it!
Yes, you will!
If I fake that report
I'd become an accomplice.
What are you going to do?
I'll get Okazaki!
You fool! Why try to be a hero?
You'll just run out of wind!
Why ruin your own future with his?
Mr. Kaji.
One of our men was persecuted.
What became of him?
He died.
And the culprit...
was he arrested?
He's still working.
Will there be no trial?
I suppose not.
If you wish to make excuses
make them before my men.
No... I'm waiting for some girls.
You promised not to kill!
You're no better than other Japanese!
If you treat me like a murderer
just because I'm a Japanese...
You'll be losing the only friend you have.
Friend?
You needn't believe me.
That's enough, Kao.
Does this man's death mean
that we may also die?
I won't let them do it!
Women... women!
Open the gate!
Let the girls in.
10 girls to a barrack...
Time limit: 10 p.m.
Yes!
We're here... as I promised.
Why do you send us women?
Think as you please!
I'm just obeying orders.
You send us harlots.
And let us sleep with them like dogs
so that we will work harder?
What's that about harlots?
I wouldn't talk so big if I were you!
You wouldn't understand at all.
Why make such a fuss?
You're no better off than we are.
Do you feel no shame?
I didn't come of my own free will!
I refused to come!
Isn't it just the same with you?
Do you enjoy digging for ore here?
I'm sorry.
I didn't realise.
Welcome home!
You must be tired.
Look... isn't it wonderful?
Her first egg! She cackled so loud...
That I went out to see
that was going on...and there it was!
What is it? Is anything wrong?
Not necessarily...
Don't you want to come home?
What happened?
Tell me about it.
Would you want a husband
who runs a whorehouse?
What do you mean?
You'd vomit if I told you.
What happens... with 600 men
and only 30 women?
And now I'm an accomplice of murderers!
That's not true!
Even the prisoners won't
trust me any more.
Given time... you'll gain their trust.
Leave me alone for awhile.
I'm sorry.
What for?
Since those men came
you've changed completely.
You think so?
I feel that I'm fighting
a lone battle.
You leave early every morning...
And you always return late.
During that time... you work.
Meanwhile, I putter around the house
and go out to do my shopping.
It's like doing nothing.
Yet... I try to convince myself.
that what little I do
will help to keep you going.
Otherwise, I'm nothing but
an ordinary housekeeper!
I'm sorry... forgive me!
It's now become an obsession.
Stop worrying about it...
Just for now...
It was nice talking to you.
When one is confined here...
One loses contact with the outside.
Thank you!
What's the matter?
I'm a professional woman!
I'm sorry to have taken your time.
I just wanted to talk.
You plan to escape, don't you?
It's impossible...
with all that barbed wire.
And it's charged with electricity.
Man put electricity through it.
You mustn't do anything rash!
Man is such a weak creature.
No amount of squirming
ever changes the course of events.
You're wrong!
Man can become as strong as he wishes.
He need only find
the cause of his unhappiness.
Want to make some money?
By selling my girls elsewhere?
I don't go in for such deals.
It's not women!
More labourers?
That's not quite what I meant.
Those prisoners?
Too dangerous! A single mistake
and it could mean this.
It's easy! Escaped prisoners
bring big profit.
If you help me
I'll split the profit with you.
It's easy money!
What do I do?
The best way... is to do it like this!
The electricity... just flick it off!
Someone asked you to do it?
My buddy... the Japanese assistant,
Muta, who was just fired.
It's too pitiful... to sell those men!
You can't expect any sympathy from me!
I'm a Korean... looked down upon
by both Japanese and Chinese!
Keep moving!
Learned One.
The Italians seem to have surrendered
Oh? The downfall of Germany cannot
be far off. Our time nears...
When will it be?
Six months... perhaps a year!
We must be patient.
What's going on here?
You scums!
Thanks! This'll help revitalize
my man and our young assistants.
If Okazaki picks up any more vitality,
it'll mean trouble for you.
Didn't you know? Women prefer it
that way.
Ma'am... it might be wiser to send
some of that flour to Kaji's wife.
Why, yes, a good idea! I'll do that.
Good day, sir!
Welcome!
You want dumplings?
Can you loan me a bag of white flour?
My mother wishes some before she dies.
One bag?
Why don't you go get some?
The Japanese sneak out
our rationed flour...
And they're eating their fill.
I can't do that.
After all... Mr. Kaji trusts you.
My flour was sneaked out by
the keeper with the big mole.
It's stolen property!
You still wish to buy some of it?
Let him have half a bag!
OK. OK.
Young one... don't forget that
you are Chinese...
And born of a Chinese mother.
Go ask the one with the big mole.
Don't do things so openly.
What are you saying?
I saw Okazaki's wife leaving here.
I hate to butt in,
but you're making a mistake.
People appreciate the mistakes I make.
It's an old custom here.
It's one that should be broken!
Unpleasant as it might be,
that's my job.
If it ever happens again,
I'll have to order an inventory.
Mr. Kaji.
We often wonder if you're one of us
or just a puppet of the Chinese.
So what?
Oh... that's all!
But your sense of justice is tempered...
By the fact that you can't take home
some flour to your own wife.
Remove your dirty feet
when speaking to me!
Do you need my help?
You fool! They'll see your light!
Go easy tonight.
Hurry! It's the watchman.
What's taking you so long?
Get going!
I'm so happy!
You've never slept with a woman
before, have you?
You'll do it for me, won't you?
Talk to Sai at the power station...
and have him shut off the current
for just three minutes.
I'll see that you're well rewarded.
Then you can buy all the flour
you want...
Without pretending to be a thief.
Can't you make up your mind?
Hey... Big Mole!
Well, Chen... how'd it go?
Did you get a good price?
Or... did you eat it?
Free white flour must taste good!
What's up, Matsuda?
Well, now... I wonder...
It seems that even saints have
thieves as underlings...
Mr. Kaji.
I'm willing to overlook it this time.
However... for my reference, I'd like
to see how you handle this.
Chen... stand up!
Look at me!
You didn't do it?
I did...
You did it alone?
Yes.
Matsuda, I hope you're satisfied.
Before I expose all your
dirty doings... get out!
Chen... what's the matter?
I was a thief... and Mr. Kaji
struck me.
Kaji? He struck you?
It's nothing! Mr Kaji is Japanese...
I am Chinese
It's all that simple!
Sister Jin is occupied now.
I think the man is a Korean.
A Korean?
Cute one...
Have you been fighting?
Let me use your room a while.
What's ailing you?
I can't understand it myself!
Foolish one! You act like one
having her first love affair.
I can't seem to forget Kao.
Love at first sight... with a man
inside that barbed wire.
Why not use your room?
It's in disorder.
Why do you ask?
All Japanese are the same!
They don't consider us human beings.
Please...
Go to the power station
and do as I ask you.
I can't! I couldn't commit treachery
for money.
I realize that! You're a good man.
But those men in there are prisoners.
They'll be exploited and later killed.
Can they really be saved?
Of course!
But the only one who can do it...
is you!
Later... please!
Go do as I ask.
I understand.
I'm Chinese, too!
I'm ready to do my bit.
At exactly 1 a.m.
When the siren sounds,
I'll cut the current.
But only for 2 minutes! That's
the best I can do.
Two minutes?
Watch out!
That packs 3,300 volts!
Be careful! Don't let them see you.
Sai!
Yes! They mustn't see you leaving.
My regards to our brothers inside
the barbed wire.
They're in love!
It's not business.
If it's love we won't pay.
You're joking!
A prisoner and a harlot in love!
It's so romantic!
But... what will come of it?
Nothing can come of it as long as
there is a war going on.
All they can hope for is their love.
Can't you let them marry?
Yes... I'd like to if it's possible.
I'm sure you'd want to help them.
I'd like to... but it ends right there!
Have some... they're delicious!
What’s that?
Rare, isn't it? It was given to us.
By whom?
Try to guess! - It was Okazaki's wife!
Send them all back!
We can't... now!
I can't send them back now!
Return them! Tell her that I was furious.
But... why?
You ask me why?
Why so angry? She brought them
to try to make up with us.
The murderer stole that flour!
Can't you see?
Can't you understand what I'm
trying to do here at this mine?
I'm afraid not! How could I when
you never tell me anything?
Of course, even I can guess where
the flour and sugar came from.
But women can't always live by
hard-headed rules.
I didn't accept for myself!
Well, you needn't have bothered
accepting for me!
Because it was the Okazaki's?
What if it were Mrs. Okishima?
I'd still refuse!
Yes... you're just the kind who would!
I understand you struck Chen...
I know you didn't want to...
yet you did! Why?
Because he committed a wrong?
No! You could have forgiven him
such a minor matter.
You did it because he made you
lose face in front of others.
For one who plans great things
you've a small mind!
It's all beyond you!
That's not true!
I even know what the people
are saying about you!
And what are they saying?
That you try to take all the credit.
I didn't believe them! I thought
it was merely spite... but now...
Believe as you wish!
Where are you going?
I've kept thirty women waiting!
Marriage? It's impossible!
We can marry!
After the war is over.
Is it ending soon?
Not very long now... it will end.
But... they'll take you away again!
No, Chun Lan.
It is ending in victory for China.
We are going to be free again!
I... I'd prefer things as they are.
Why?
Chun Lan!
When that day comes,
I won't be able to see you.
But... I'm asking you to marry me!
There are plans to escape from here.
But I will not run away
as long as you are here.
Kao! You won't run away... you promise?
It seems I'm running to extremes again.
You brute!
I'm thinking of helping
those two get married.
Hello. What's that?
They escaped?
Yes... we'll be right over!
Eleven men! Escaped!
I won't bother asking for information.
We'll soon know who planned the break.
I won't ask for details.
But I want you to understand one thing.
We've tried our best to help you.
If you cannot trust us and
continue in your efforts to escape.
those who remain behind
will face reprisals
and a further increase of hard labour.
And I will not raise a finger
to protect you!
You think that you can get away
with anything while here.
But if Kaji and I decide to do so.
we can always pack you into those
freight cars and send you back.
They escaped without our knowing!
We only serve liaison purposes.
We can't stop them even if
we learn of the plot.
Don't lie! What if I said that
Wang Heng Li plotted this break?
It no lie... we don't know!
I no run away.
You fools! Do you think we'd
take you words for it?
I wish you'd all run away!
I will not run!
I will stride boldly out of this compound.
Where will you go after you leave?
Not all Japanese are soft-hearted.
Run away and see for yourself.
I will not keep you!
Wang, whether this camp remains a haven
depends on your future actions.
Ultimate responsibility to the
KEMPEITAI lies with me... not you!
Investigate the matter thoroughly.
And find some alibi for the KEMPEITAI.
Where's Kaji?
You stood by while those men escaped?
That's not true.
You took all precautionary measures?
Must you be reminded...
That those prisoners cost us dearly?
You damaged the prestige
of our imperial forces.
Start explaining!
What's to explain?
The only explanation
is their desire to escape.
Why did you let them escape?
Answer me!
There's no need to shout.
We have 10,000 labourers here
aside from your prisoners.
No matter how hard we try
they'll manage to escape.
One question...
OK.
We reported the truth.
If I had reported them dead...
I could have avoided
trouble with the KEMPEITEI.
Doesn't the KEMPEITEI want the truth?
I admit your honesty.
But inadequate supervision
cannot be excused.
I shall overlook your negligence
on this one occasion.
No more men must be allowed to escape.
If they do, I shall personally slay
the leader of that group.
You understand?
We understand.
How about it?
Do you want me to intimidate them?
It won't be necessary.
Refusing aid from the military
indicates your supreme confidence.
Hereafter, I'll hold you personally
responsible in this matter.
I understand.
And you? Do you understand?
I do.
That's all for today.
No... wait!
Wait!
Leave me alone!
Don't take it out on the men.
You did! You struck Chen in a fit of temper!
Don't try to pull your humanism on me.
Yes... and I already regret it.
But why need you ape me?
Don't let your ire ruin my work.
Your job?
Yes... my work!
We've kept you in step so far
but you're turning away.
Can't you see? Force has meaning
only when overcoming tyranny.
I know!. I've had enough of your lectures!
You intend to leave them alone?
I'll talk to them.
I mince no words! I don't want
your men to keep trying to escape.
As far as you men are concerned,
l am your friendliest enemy.
I pride myself in the fact that
there is no hostility in my work.
Despite the dilemmas which come
of our being at war,
I have tried to protect your interests.
What you say... is difficult.
Is it? Eat your fill.
We can talk at our leisure.
When one of your comrades was killed...
I did not adopt just measures
to protect you.
Therefore, you no longer trust me.
This is only natural.
However... I shall do my utmost
to correct this mistake.
This may take considerable time.
But I hope you will trust me
and be patient.
No one wishes to risk dangers
to break out?
Let me speak for my friend, Kaji.
Since Kaji arrived here...
The labourers' has greatly improved.
This also applies to you.
However, if you continue to break out.
I cannot say what the
KEMPEITAI might do.
I don't know how Kaji feels.
But the only way to save my own neck...
is to send you back to the KEMPEITAI.
He speaks no falsehoods.
We can talk over our mutual problems.
How about you, Kao?
If you can marry Yang Chun Lan,
will you stay until the war ends?
Tales which begin with the word "if"
Do not interest me.
Can't you understand?
We want to talk things over.
Fawning toad-eater!
It's the same old Japanese trick!
They always promise to do this
and to do that...
But they never carry it out.
Stand up!
You dog! Go to Yang Chun Lan and
learn the ways of human beings.
By the way, Wang... if I...
There's the "if" again.
If I gain for you the freedom
enjoyed by other labourers,
will you promise to remain here?
To wait seems to be
the only safe liberty.
You promise?
Wang... you must trust me!
Do you think they trust me?
You want to believe they do?
I want to believe Wang
when he said that he'd wait.
You plan to continue sending
the girls inside? Why?
Just a hunch...
And I also plan to take about
50 men for outside work.
With guards?
No... just myself.
Such strange hunches aren't like you.
Why not be honest?
What about?
Admit that you'd let them
escape... if you could!
That's nonsense.
When that happens, I stand to lose
my neck, too. Remember that!
When they come here, they seem happy.
Your mother... is she still ill?
Yes.
Does she still yearn
for white flour?
She's given up hope.
I'm sorry that I struck you.
I'm hard-headed in some ways... I know!
That's all right.
Is Sai who works at the
power station a friend of yours?
Yes.
The current was shut off...
And Sai was on duty that night.
If he did it, he mustn't do it again.
All right! Back to work!
They could have run away.
They're beginning to trust you.
No... they're just being wary.
They fear a trap.
You're giving it up?
No... I'll continue.
It's dangerous!
They might kill you and escape.
I don't think so.
This bath feels good!
Why don't you come in, too?
I think I will.
If the labourers calm down,
let's go on a vacation.
Let's do it! How many days
can you take off?
Three days... at most!
That's wonderful!
Well... if they really calm down...
Some day you'll be a great supervisor...
But youth will have vanished by then.
That's not for me!
You win!
What you say is probably the truth.
Will you?
Sure... we'll go.
Make no mistakes, Cho...
fix that barbed wire!
Kaji will be off on a 3-day leave.
We'll do it while he's away.
There's more of a profit in it
but it's more dangerous.
With things going smoothly,
Kaji has relaxed his guard.
But watch out for Okishima!
It's an ideal chance!
Let's pull another fast one
and make ourselves scarce.
Yeah... getting away is the
important thing.
Is Jin Tung Fu in?
She's in bed with the cute one.
How about you?
I'm having trouble!
Chen won't help any more.
He won't do it.
Once is as bad as 100 times!
He dislikes our company.
Oh? Except when he's in bed with you?
He wants me to break away, too.
Has the dog squealed on us?
He wouldn't do that!
How do you know?
Don't stop him. Send him home!
Hey, Jin Tung Fu is some woman, eh?
Was it good?
I hear Kaji is going
on leave this Saturday.
Have the power cut while he's gone.
Sai isn't going on duty
during those nights.
Well then when?
Friday night.
Then make it Friday night.
He can't! He's under suspicion.
By who?
Mr. Kaji...
What can he do without evidence?
Listen carefully, you brat!
Play it straight and I'll fix it
so Jin Tung Fu will be all yours.
You'll do it...
you'll be a good boy!
If you refuse...
you and Sai will die!
Oh! I feel great!
We arrived in a whirl of dust
but it's nice today! You're worried?
I'm wondering why I didn't
do this before.
Really?
I mean it!
When we arrive in town,
l must phone Yasuko.
Do you mind?
And then?
And then we'll have lunch together and
go to the apple orchard.
It's all so wonderful...
l feel as light as a balloon!
I beg just one liberty.
What's that?
Just one hour... will you let me go?
What for?
Our record is improving,
I want to see the director...
About the status of the prisoners.
Just one hour?
Yes. The remainder is all yours.
All right! I'll give you 2 hours,
But not a minute more!
Mr. Kaji!
They escaped again!
What?
And Okishima?
He's over at their camp.
OK. I'll go right away.
No... please!
It can't be helped, but I can't go now.
Go on alone and have
a good time with Yasuko.
It's not Yasuko... I want you!
But this is my job.
I don't care! You're on vacation.
Why do you have to go back now?
Leave it to Okishima...
I can't do that.
It can wait till after lunch, right?
I'll never make it.
You don't want to do!
Stop it!
Your work's important...yes!
But do you know
how important this is to us?
I'll make up for it!
You needn't bother!
Why the fuss over such a tiny matter?
Such a tiny matter?
You don't care
how I feel about it.
At any rate, there's no way I can leave now.
I see! Then I'll go by myself.
Stop it!
From now on, I do things my own way!
And ruin everything I've done?
This is the only way of
making them understand!
Brute force solves nothing!
Do you realize how many got away?
18 men escaped led by Hwang and Sung!
You still want to talk it over?
I'll assume all responsibility.
Foolish!
If you don't like my methods,
you can quit and save your own neck.
OK. I accept your offer.
Wang!
Stand up!
I've despaired of you all!
You gave your word.
I may seem like a fool to you
but now I've had enough!
Another break and you all go
without food for 3 days.
I'll break your authority in the camp.
All Japanese are the same!
Devils!
So be it! I shall act accordingly.
All promises are hereby retracted.
I realize now that there can be
no truth between us.
Mr. Okishima!
And the report to the KEMPEITAI?
We're in for it this time!
I won't report the incident.
What?
If it leaks out,
I'll assume all responsibility.
I know it's not all your fault.
You think someone shut off the power?
I couldn't say.
How about a Japanese night shift?
We couldn't... without evidence.
Should I increase the night watch?
I'd have to check each night
to see if they're on duty.
Eighteen men... that's a big loss!
I've achieved our new production goal...
and I want no trouble of such nature.
May I report that Okishima is herewith
relieved of all responsibility
for the prisoners?
Tell me!
Who paid you the money?
Okishima favours aggressive measures
but Kaji always vetoes him.
Meaning he gives tacit
consent to the runways?
I wouldn't say that...
but it does all seem rather suspicious.
There is one way
we can teach them a lesson.
How's that?
Let them plan another break,
and we'll foil them.
With your permission, I'd like to try.
Sounds interesting! If it brings
results, I'll try anything.
Give it a try.
Boss's orders...
flour and oil rations
for just the Japanese of course!
I'm sure you don't approve.
I do not!
Unfortunately however,
you're not the manager.
It's fortunate for you that I'm not!
Mr. Kaji! It's Mr. Okishima...
Kill the rat!
Let us take care
of this Korean dog!
You stay out of this!
Swipe men from under my nose, eh?
Not stopping me today?
You want me to?
You disapprove? Should I lay off
the ordinary labourers, too?
Your so-called humanism is apt to
harbour rascals like this one.
Chen... the medical ward!
Leave the cur be!
His boss will pick him up.
Take him!
Call... Furuya...
Don't worry, young one!
They can't make me talk.
Chen... it seems I know more about you
than you do about me.
Go tell Kaji the wounds are slight.
We don't want him around here.
Well? How is he?
He'll be all right.
Mr. Furuya is with him.
Furuya?
Furuya... send a telegram to Muta...
That rat Okishima!
The man says he'll sue Okishima.
Help him arrange it. He's your friend.
You needn't explain! I'm not that dumb.
Was it money?
Or just to make trouble for me?
Don't worry!
I won't tell the boss.
See that your buddy is hospitalized.
But you're paying for him... not labour!
You've already made enough.
What kept you so long?
What's wrong with you? You're drunk!
You think I came to make trouble?
I had a drink with the boss
but I'm not drunk.
I bring tidings! They're issuing
commendations to the deserving.
Okazaki will get one of them.
I told the boss that you were the one
who earned the award in the labour end.
The boss felt the same but he feared
that it might hurt my feelings?
Do you think it would hurt my feelings?
Why have you turned to brute force?
The boss asked the same question.
Just say... I was born a brute.
How long will you carry on as you are?
What do you mean by that?
You're ignoring the contradictions
and trying to justify them.
I ran out of breath waiting.
If I'm in your way, just say so.
Lao Kao!
Jin!
I was afraid you
might have escaped.
That is all I could buy today.
Thank you.
Thank you greatly.
We can't meet for the time being.
I... I won't be able to come here.
If you run off by yourself...
I'll die on this fence.
I'll take you with me when I escape.
When will that be?
After I learn how the others have fared.
I can't take any chances with you
accompanying me.
You will stay here?
They might let us be married.
Don't believe them!
The learned Wang says the war
will soon end.
Japan will be defeated.
Now that I have you...
I'm willing to bear anything.
Lao Kao.
I wish we could meet
like this every night.
But... it's better not to come so often.
They'll become suspicious.
This cursed wire!
Watch out!
God is unjust!
Chun. I love you!
Lao Kao. And I love you!
Can't you sleep?
Kaji would have been happier
if he had married a girl like you.
Probably.
You're too much the wife, Michi.
You're forgetting to be a woman.
What do you mean?
Being a wife is a profession.
But it's the woman that men love.
When you typed Kaji’s reports,
you studied it like one possessed.
I never understood a word.
And now? Do you talk about his work?
He hates my pestering him.
If I were you, I'd pester him
until he told me about everything.
Then... I'd ask more questions.
What's wrong? Was I too outspoken?
I wanted to apologize.
I was a poor wife... and a poor woman.
I couldn't sleep.
This is your home... lie down
and get a good rest.
Promise me... that you'll share
your joys and sorrows with me.
Sorrow for one is enough.
It's not! The road which you take
is also the road for me.
What matters if we get lost?
l want you to take me along.
I will follow you.
And I'll do my best to keep up.
I understand.
If I'm slow... will you slow down
just a tiny bit?
Just a very tiny bit?
Of course.
I won't repeat a question twice.
Through fitting leadership in the pit
you have helped achieve the 20%
increase in ore production.
You have rendered valuable
service to our armed forces
and have proven yourself a fitting
example for other employees.
You are herewith officially commended.
Chairman of the Board, Jushiro Kitada.
Read in proxy by Junichi Kuroki.
Looks like we'll have rain.
Rainy nights are ideal for escapes.
When you deliver their food,
tell them they can break out tonight.
Tonight?
Then you go to the power station
and say that Kaji wants the power cut...
But... Mr. Kaji.
I'm under direct orders from the boss.
You want me to tell
the KEMPEITAI about you?
About how you and Jin Tung Fu
helped them escape?
And how Kaji knew about it but
pretended not to notice?
It's the only way to save your neck.
Mr. Kaji, I look forward to
your continued favours.
You're young... but you're quite a fellow!
On the day you first came...
when it was snowing...
No... just windy!
Was that right?
On that day, I thought
that a young squirt like you
could never handle this mine.
However... things did work out
as you said.
You're really great!
But, Mr. Kaji... I've been watching.
You haven't been drinking...
Lend me a hand.
If you want to try,
tonight is your last chance.
Why this suddenness?
Let it pass if it's inconvenient.
But my friend is being shifted
to day duty from tomorrow.
There's no mistake?
On behalf of the men in the pit
and for the sake of friendship,
I challenge Mr. Kaji to
a friendly drinking bout.
Here here!
I'm beaten already.
No... that won't do! You can't be...
we haven't started yet!
I'm really beaten.
Does your spirit show only
when you're snarling to me?
Come on... take it like a man!
Right!
Good! If you want to drink...
Drink with this!
Get drunk and let down your guard.
He's right!
Okay!
Good luck Mr. Kaji!
There he goes!
They can take it! They're used to
being wined and dined.
Women, too! They run the whorehouse
and have their pick.
We're wined and dined, eh?
And the whores are ours for the taking?
Bring on your wine and women!
I'll take 'em on!
Chen.
Delivered their meal?
Special flour rations for the Japanese.
You're welcome to mine.
But your wife.
My wife has abandoned hope.
Mr. Kaji...
It's nothing.
I just wanted to say, "Thank you."
I should say "Thank you." I was afraid
you wouldn't accept it from me.
That's a shapely rump!
Stop it! You act like a dog in heat.
What do you mean?
Sow your seed in your own paddy field!
I wouldn't act so big, Okishima!
If guys like you and Kaji would
mind your own business,
I could have topped our goal long ago.
And if we hadn't butted in,
you'd have 10 killings to your credit.
And be dining in the pen.
You rat! If you want trouble, come on!
Hey! Chen... what's the matter?
What should I do?
I won't be able to see you again.
I've fallen into a trap.
Go to the station and have him
cut off the power.
If I should do so
and the men are captured...
They'll kill me!
This is a Japanese plot.
No matter what happens,
you won't be killed for doing what they ask.
You talk as if it didn't concern you.
If I'm caught, I might confess everything.
Don't frighten me.
You dragged me into this.
Where are you going?
I'll warn them!
You'll never get word to them.
I can try.
Wait! I have a better idea.
Chun Lan.
Kao is breaking out tonight.
Kao is escaping?
Tell him it's dangerous tonight.
I won't let him escape alone!
Drink it! It will relax you.
I couldn't contact him!
Are you sure he's escaping?
You met no one?
With this downpour,
I couldn't see a thing.
Not a soul?
Is he really breaking out?
What'll we do now?
If he runs off by himself...
I'll kill myself!
The power must be cut off!
We mustn't anger the Japanese.
What will you do?
The best way is to confess
the whole thing to Mr. Kaji.
Don't! He's the severest of them all.
Where are you going?
Go to the station!
I expected so much!
Did you do as I told you?
I did.
You didn't mention the matter
to Kaji, did you?
I didn't.
Whether you did as I ordered... or not.
We'll soon find out.
If you betrayed us... you'll die!
We'll report you as having been shot
helping the men to escape.
We'll even be rewarded.
They're coming!
Mr. Furuya!
The power... I haven't...
What?
Dog! You want to be killed?
I can't believe that Chen
was behind it all.
I've been blind!
Furuya -
I hadn't believed you capable
of such a diabolic plot!
Go brag to the boss of your brave deed.
And you, Wang!
You're not always right either.
Mistaken leadership caused this.
You refused to trust us.
The result is charred human flesh.
It serves you right!
Lao Kao!
Why did you do it?
Kao!
Chun Lan!
Gaze upon he who murdered his friends.
Okishima came and told me about it.
Why didn't Chen come to me?
He was afraid... probably.
Because I struck him?
Okishima was saying that
you'd brood over this incident.
It's not my fault that I'm Japanese!
Yet... my worst crime is that I am!
Though I struck Chen...
he still liked you.
And he understood how I felt.
Yet... look what happened!
That dog Furuya!
The boss put him up to this!
They'll never meddle in
labour affairs again!
Let's go home! Some nice hot soup
will help you regain your vitality.
Let's go.
It may not help but I wish
you'd talk to them
about the treatment of the prisoners.
I'm asking you though it's
no longer your job.
Yes, I'll talk to them,
My trip will cool us both off,
I'll fix it up for you.
But the boss thinks more of Okazaki.
I'm boarding this run down truck.
You prefer the train of humanism...
I won't stop you.
You seem willing to pay the price.
Something I shouldn't know?
I've already offered my apologies.
We didn't say anything.
From now on, we'll have to escape
from the work areas.
Wang wants us to lie low for a while.
And we haven't received any news
from the others.
What's going on here?
Hide!
Wait!
How about it? They're offering us
500 more prisoners.
We lack the accommodations.
No accommodation?
And also supervision?
Boss! We just caught 7 prisoners
who tried to escape.
Captured them?
Yes.
Good work! You've done well.
The rascals almost got away.
From the pit?
From the ore dump.
That's not true.
You weren't there! How could you know?
Escape? In broad daylight?
Look at this! Only the desperate
would throw ore at me.
And so it's a break?
I'm not the only witness,
It took 15 men to capture them.
Inside the compound?
You call that a break?
Why do you defend the Chinks?
Please excuse me...
You needn't bother!
Where are they?
They're in the guard house.
Captain... I request instructions!
Let's see! Shall we do it
the way you suggested?
He's an expert swordsman.
How many men did you slay in China?
Please wait! We don't have any proof yet.
Silence! We have a witness,
Any objections?
Yes! An impassioned witness
can't be trusted.
They all want to escape!
Would you have them all executed?
Why you!
Enough!
We needn't debate the matter here.
The important thing is that
we recognize it as an attempt.
Sergeant, they will be executed
tomorrow! Details are left to you.
They will be executed tomorrow, sir!
Any objections?
You shall be witness to the execution.
By just giving testimony,
you'll be saving the lives of men!
It was an attempt! They ran!
They should have stayed
and taken their beating.
What's going to happen to us?
If injuring Okazaki was a crime,
why not just investigate me?
Heed me well!
You're all guilty of attempted escape.
Keep quiet!
Dog!
An investigation will bring out the truth.
Investigate us!
The investigation is over.
I cannot believe that it was
an attempted escape.
You're delivering us to the KEMPEITAI?
I don't intend to.
You were the one who never trusted me.
Perhaps it is better to continue
to doubt my words.
Those men have authority.
I have no authority.
I'll do what I can
until tomorrow evening.
The KEMPEITAI will listen to you!
It's an object lesson, Kaji.
It can't be...
Personally, I don't approve of it.
But Head Office says...
leave it to the KEMPEITAI.
Why?
Must there be a reason?
Please, wait! Human heads are
about to be chopped off.
If the company protested...
Don't forget... we are at war!
That's no reason!
You don't think so... but I do!
An idle discussion.
If you wish, you can talk
to our Head Office.
I certainly will!
Hello. Yes.
Sorry, no answer! He's in conference.
He shouts and screams like a madman!
Yes... one moment, please.
Someone else will take it.
Okishima? We're in real trouble.
You know about it?
Hello... I can't hear you!
Speak louder!
I can't hear you!
What's that?
Give up?
Ridiculous!
Okishima! Please... talk to them again.
Yes... yes... please, try again!
I'll be waiting.
I'll be honest...
Only one chance in a hundred!
Just as my companions stand
on the borders of life and death,
so do you now stand at
an important crossroad.
That's true.
If you should fail now,
no one will ever trust you again.
You will also lose faith in yourself.
Very true!
Yet... you would do nothing?
What can I do?
Must one outside this barbed wire
ask me such a question?
All Japanese working here are
not murderous devils.
Their combined opinion objecting
to this execution
will be more effective than you alone.
If I always acted as you wanted me to,
there would be no Kaji here today.
I wish I could watch you when
you're in my position.
Minor mistakes... you will make
and so will I.
Such things can be forgiven.
But an error made at a crucial
moment is an unforgivable crime.
Your life has been a series of errors
stemming from the conflict between
your work and yourself.
Such errors can possibly be corrected.
But not so for the crucial decision.
Then?
Then will be revealed the murderers
who wear the mask of humanism.
And the ones worthy of the
beautiful name... "man"
I realize that.
You have less faith in men
than you try to believe.
Regardless of how you might feel,
true men will always find
fellow companions... somewhere!
What will happen to my man?
I only wish I knew myself!
When will we be released?
They won't kill Kao, will they?
Honestly? He won't be killed?
Hello... Okishima? What's the decision?
Calm down and listen!
The manager is no help...
What?
The old chump!
Hello? Hello?
Wait until the morning...
I'll talk to the Chairman.
What? The Chairman?
Yes, the Chairman!
I'll make him listen to me.
Go away... please!
I want to be alone.
Mr. Kaji. Save my man... please!
He wouldn't run away!
We planned to be married
after the war ended.
Don't let them kill him!
Don't let them do it!
Please... please.
Go to sleep... you needn't worry!
I won't do anything.
There's nothing that I can do.
Can I really set my mind at ease?
Really?
Don't worry. Go to sleep
I'll try to sleep, too.
What is it?
Where are you going?
I'll free those men!
Don't do it!
What will happen to you if you do?
It doesn't matter!
You've done everything you could.
Don't you care what happens to you?
I won't let you!
Michiko, don't torture me!
I'll call for help!
I won't let you do it.
You always go your own way.
Perhaps you are right.
But if you free those men...
then they'll surely kill you!
They'll kill you for sure!
Please... don't go!
I'll follow you... I'll shout for help!
Michiko... I'll no longer be a man!
Are my words those of some stray dog?
Even you... you don't want to
give up this life... do you?
Remember... you promised!
I'm sorry... go and do as you see fit.
Perhaps I'm the one who's wrong
I couldn't bear standing in your way.
I don't want you hating me...
or not loving me.
I'm just no good!
All ready!
Good work.
It's best to wet the blade.
Keeps off the fat.
Kaji!
Stay there! You're acting as my
official witness.
Kaji... you may tell the men for me
to attempt escape is to die!
- Next!
- Yes!
Want to try?
Yes!
- Next!
- Yes!
No... I don't need it!
I demand an explanation!
Why are we being executed?
Damn you!
Japanese devils!
Stand up! Stand up!
I'll go by myself!
Inhuman wretch!
This is your true form!
The face of a man...
but the heart of a beast!
Good! You show grit.
Stay calm! Slash him!
Hurrah for China!
You fail because you think it's
a human head. Relax and try again.
Next!
No more!
That'll be enough!
What?
Stay out of this or I'll kill you too!
I'm no longer afraid.
Slay me if you dare.
Good... I'll oblige.
Enemy sympathizers are better off dead.
Stop this massacre of our comrades!
Murderers! Murderer! Killers!
Murderer! Murderer! Murderer!
The execution is called off!
Go... go back to them!
You're coming with me.
Private Tenaka... take very good
care of our honoured guest.
I'll return later. Go!
Kaji won't be home today.
Did... did he do something?
Do something? He refused to let us
execute those enemy dogs!
He may be away some time...it depends!
Did he hide anything?
No!
It's because his way of thinking is no good.
Open the desk drawers.
Place everything on top of the desk.
Well... you feel like confessing now!
I only regret that I let you
behead the first three victims.
You don't say!
You're a hopeless one.
Private Tanaka... you should show
our guest more courtesy.
Kaji... don't you miss your wife?
She was crying. No one to ride
her belly from tonight.
What have I done?
I'm no boor... I'd like to put you
back on your wife's belly
but in order to do so, I must have
more cooperation from you.
What's so funny?
I neither pick pockets nor steal.
What shall I confess?
Interesting! You needn't confess to
anything until we make you.
Your bravado won't last long.
You let 11 POWs escape and
failed to report it.
I'm waiting for an answer.
I didn't report it...
but I never let them escape!
You used Chen to contact the prisoners!
Show me evidence! Will you lose face
if I'm not found guilty?
You wanted something?
I didn't mean it to end up like this.
Quarrels over work are one thing
but I don't need outside help for that.
I came to...
I understand.
But I didn't think Kaji would dare...
Kaji would dare do what...?
Oh... nothing!
I don't know how the others feel...
But I feel that what he did...
only he could do.
If that's how you feel,
you can do as you please.
I dropped by to see if I could
help you in any way.
Your help will not be needed.
What you can do is to admit that
it was not an attempted escape.
Admit it! You and Wang Heng Li
helped them escape... didn't you?
Answer me... you scum!
Wang Heng Li was arrested and
has confessed everything.
Wang was arrested?
He now awaits execution.
When will it be?
It worries you? After all...
he was your friend!
Wang instigated the uprising at
your request... am I right?
When will he die?
Answer my question!
All right! Today I'll make you
weep like a women.
I hope your wife hears you.
WANG HENG LI
In Memorium
Wang... you have died without
awaiting the dawn.
But your comrades will surely bury you
by the light of the newborn day.
Come... out here!
Go inside!
Kiss her... don't let me stop you.
Michiko! Why did you come?
Don't worry... go home!
I brought some rice balls...
may I offer them to him?
Won't you have some?
Michiko... when you need help,
talk it over with Okishima.
Okishima... look after her.
Mr. Okishima... he's being transferred.
I came to say goodbye.
I see.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to help.
I had a row with the manager
and I'm being ousted.
I see.
I wanted to stay and argue
some more with you.
Furuya takes over my spot.
That'll be the end.
Is there anything you need?
Nothing.
That means... I won't see you anymore?
I learned so much from you.
No... that's for me to say.
Though you have paid a bitter price,
you finally caught the humanism train.
Oh, yes... Wang Heng Li...
Unnecessary conversation is
not permitted!
Your time is up.
Private Tenaka!
Michiko!
As a special favour, I'm releasing you.
But I'm not setting you free.
Remember... my eyes will follow
your every move.
Go where you may...
I'll always be there first.
I report back, sir.
It has come... Kaji.
Emergency Call to Military Service.
I suspected as much!
So you wring me dry and cast me out.
I can't afford to lose you
but there's nothing I can do.
Forget the smooth talk!
It's the easy way to rid yourself
of the unwanted.
Far better to have trusted the harlots
than the directors of this company.
Kaji... Turn your duties over to Furuya.
We need a new leader for the prisoners.
Good men are scarce since
Wang Heng Li escaped.
Escaped? Wang Heng Li?
Along with 30 others.
So he got away! Good for you, Wang!
Wonderful! I hope they all get away.
Sir... I wish you'd inform Furuya...
That Wang's escape saved him
from a thorough beating.
I was going in there to thrash him...
not to hand over my work!
But suddenly... I've changed my mind!
Probably because I found that
I was in good company.
Japanese devil!
Kill me... like you murdered Kao!
Kill me!
Why don't you kill me? Japanese devil!
He murdered an innocent man!
Murderer!
Mr. Kaji.
Be not angry.
I know you have a good heart.
But you're not able to save Kao's life.
That's why...
You'll stumble, Michiko!
Welcome home!
Thank goodness!
One of the wives told me you had
come back in terrible shape.
But it's not true! You're looking fine.
Thank goodness, really, thank goodness!
This... what is it?
But they couldn't.
No... it's not fair!
They promised you military exemption.
A dirty trick!
This is too much... it's unfair!
Michiko... there's nothing that
can be done now.
Why must they do this to you?
I've done nothing.
But I had hoped to accomplish things
with you when I returned.
Why must you always be persecuted so?
Why do they pick on you?
You're so thin... and so full of scars.
And now they send you to the front.
Michiko!
You mustn't die... we must live again!
When will we be able to meet again?
You'll come back... I know you will.
Japanese devil!
You die!
Michiko, let's go! We still have
24 hours together.
Japanese devil!