Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Please do NOT hardsub and/or stream
this episode using our English subtitles.
To be honest...
Before Seong Min died...
Soo Hyeon, Kwang Hee, and I
donated our sperm...
And the baby that was born is Ha Seon.
What?
You donated what?
Sperm donation!
What are you talking about?
Sperm donation?
Na Yeong, we're home...
Na Yeong, this is for stone therapy.
You put it on your back, and...
Say that again.
What do you mean sperm donation?
I...
Na Yeong
So you're saying...
That the three of you went behind
my back and did what?
- Na Yeong, it's not what it sounds like.
- Kyeong Tae, what are you doing?
Kyeong Tae said, but whatever he said,
don't believe him. He's wrong, okay?
No, I want to hear it from Kyeong Tae.
Is what you said true?
Na Yeong, it's not what it sounds like.
That's...
Yes.
It's true.
Oh my god!
How can this be?
No.
We should have told you earlier.
What kind of situation is this?
So, Ha Seon isn't Seong Min's child?
Na Yeong,
Na Yeong!
Is it okay to leave her like this?
What should we do?
I think the shock was too much for her.
It would be strange if she didn't faint.
We announced that Ha Seon
isn't Seong Min's baby.
Kyeong Tae, that bastard!
Soo Hyeon!
Kyeong Tae, where are you?
- Where are you?
- Soo Hyeon, this isn't the time.
You two come have a seat here too.
Mother...
I said come sit here!
I heard everything from Kyeong Tae.
How much did you tell her?
I told her the whole truth.
How much of the truth?
That I think Ha Seon is my child.
What?
Mother, I think Kyeong Tae
is largely mistaken here.
Mistaken?
So you three didn't donate your sperm?
No, that's not it.
So then why did you hide that
from Ha Seon's mom and me?
What were your intentions?
Mother, we didn't have any motives.
Seong Min asked us to keep it a
secret until the day we died.
You think that kind of secret can be kept?
It's a matter of bloodline.
Bloodline?
I called and told your mother
to come, Kwang Hee.
My mother? Why?
It's a matter of blood.
The adults have to discuss what we're
going to do about Ha Seon and her mom.
What?
You kids.
Do you have any idea
what you've done?
Why can't you think about your
actions? You thoughtless kids.
My goodness. What kind of
strange situation is this?
Sperm donation all of a sudden?
I'm going to go crazy
and jump off a bridge!
No.
This could be a good thing too.
Kwang Hee would have lived alone
all his life and give me a headache.
Yes.
If I can use this opportunity to get
him married, it could be a good thing.
I knew there was something
familiar about Ha Seon.
Hm?
Get the door, it's your mother.
Mom.
Father? What are you doing here?
Your mother called me
and told me to drop by.
Is there something the matter
with my daughter, Na Yeong?
She was saying something
that I couldn't understand.
Something about sperm donation.
What is she talking about?
That's...
Oh, you arrived here first.
How have you been these days?
Have you been well?
There have been some special issues.
Mom, why?
Why? Why?
How can you even ask that?
Okay, okay, let go and talk.
Go sit over there.
Hello Mother.
Mother.
Hello Father.
You've arrived.
It's good that you came.
Have a seat over here.
Have a seat.
You guys, have a seat too.
What do you think you're doing?
Kneel!
The thing that you said earlier,
what were you talking about?
Sperm donation?
My goodness.
So they're saying that this
could be Kyeong Tae's baby?
What are you talking about?
She looks exactly like my Kwang Hee.
Look here.
See what?
Don't be like that.
As soon as we do a DNA
test, we'll know everything.
I guess so.
Of course.
There are rules in this world. We
have to find out who the father is.
He could even become my son-in-law.
Na Yeong.
Looks like your consciousness
has returned.
Are you okay?
You must have been really shocked.
Have some water.
Ha Seon, where is she?
She's sound asleep.
Don't worry about her.
Here.
You still don't look well.
Why don't you lie back down.
I'm okay.
Father, how did you...
I heard everything.
How is it that Ha Seon is
not Seong Min's daughter?
Father!
What are you talking about?
Ha Seon is Seong Min's daughter.
Don't even put those words in your mouth.
Anyway.
What should we do about this?
Na Yeong, I'm sorry to bring this up.
But we have no other choice,
so please don't be upset and
think about it from our side.
What?
Are you crazy?
Are you out of your mind?
You couldn't even keep the secret
that Seong Min asked of us,
and you had to go tell
everything to your mother?
What could I have done?
Mom was telling me to kick
Na Yeong and Ha Seon out.
You should have done everything to
change her mind, aren't you a man?
How can I lie to my mom?
I can't do that.
Fine. Good for you.
I knew you'd do this.
I told you many times to watch what
you said, and you messed up repeatedly.
And finally you messed up big time.
What are you going to do now?
Be quiet. You yelling isn't
going to change anything.
What are you going to do?
How are you going to fix this?
I'll take care of it.
How? What are you going
to take responsibility for?
Anyway, don't worry about it.
In any case, Ha Seon's my baby,
so I'll take responsibility for her.
You bastard.
Let go and talk.
Go ahead, hit me.
Hit me.
- You're still out of your mind. Stop it!
- This isn't going to change anything.
Na Yeong, don't be like this,
hear us out.
What do you mean paternity test?
Don't ever say that in my presence again.
But we have to do the test to
find out who the father is.
We should do this right. It's
not just a matter of Ha Seon.
Ha Seon is Seong Min's baby!
Na Yeong, Na Yeong, Na Yeong!
Hold on, hear us out.
I thought that the reason
you three were kind to me
was because of your
friendship with Seong Min.
But this is what it was about?
How could you do such a huge
thing without me knowing?
How could you trick me like this?
Na Yeong, first, please
calm down, and hear us out.
We didn't mean to lie to you.
We did it for you and Ha Seon's sake.
Why can't you believe us?
It's true.
You know how much
we all love Ha Seon.
Then you should have kept
it a secret until the end.
Why now?
I'm sorry.
It's all my fault.
No.
It could be a good thing
that I found out now.
Don't ever talk about
sperm donation in front of me.
And from now on
I don't think I can see
the three of you anymore.
And the three of you should give
up on seeing Ha Seon ever again.
What?
Thank you for everything until now.
I will do anything I can to repay
the debt that I owe to you.
Good-bye.
Na Yeong, where are you going
in the middle of the night?
She's going to stay with me for now.
Please get out of the way.
Na Yeong, let's go.
Na Yeong, Na Yeong!
What are we going to do?
Na Yeong, Na Yeong, no!
Please don't leave.
Na Yeong, let go of your anger,
and listen to what I have to say.
How can you just leave like this?
Ha Seon.
Taxi, Taxi!
Na Yeong.
Mommy? Where are we going
without my Daddies?
I want to live with my Daddies.
Apba! Papa! Daddy!
The room is as small as a booger,
but the air is great.
We even have a front yard.
I'll clean the yard first
thing in the morning.
Let's go inside.
Come in,
Come in.
I did mop the floor.
Have a seat
- Have a seat.
- Yes.
The room is somewhat small, but it should
be enough for you and Ha Seon.
Once I go out to the human market
(a place for daily waged jobs)
I don't come home for days from the
construction site, or I return late daily.
Dad, you go to the human market?
You and your daughter are in
this situation because of me.
I'm ashamed to see you.
Isn't it hard?
Of course, it's hard.
The only thing I ever did in
my life was play Go-Stop.
Oh, let me get the blankets.
You know what? I'm going to
go to the corner supermarket.
What for?
The only thing there is to eat is ramyeon.
I need to get some rice and side
dishes for breakfast tomorrow.
Here's some money.
No, no. I have money!
Grandpa wants to get something
yummy for his granddaughter,
so don't be like that.
I have money.
Ha Seon, Grandpa will be
right back, bye bye.
See you later.
How could this be?
This doesn't make any sense.
No sense at all.
She looks just like Seong Min.
I can't believe it.
Why are you like this?
Why are you crying, you're a man.
Ha Seon and Na Yeong
left because of me.
This is all your fault, Mom.
What?
You think this is all my fault?
Hey, you. You, jerk!
Think clearly about this.
Ha Seon's mom is Seong Min's woman.
Do you know?
Seong Min's wife!
How can you fall for
your friend's woman?
I don't know.
My heart is exploding.
Do you want to see
my insides reversed?
It's not late. Try to harden your
heart and set right your feeling.
Do you understand?
It should be here somewhere?
It's too thin for me to see.
Mom, aren't you leaving?
Yes, I will.
What are you looking for?
I found it!
Do you think this is it?
What?
Ha Seon's hair.
We can do a paternity test and find
out whether she's your child or not.
Mom!
What?
If she's not yours, there's no problem,
but if she is, then we can keep her.
I wish she were yours.
Mom, are you crazy?
Don't worry about it for now.
I'll take care of it.
Oh, and I need one of
your hairs, give me one.
Gosh, really!
Sorry, I pulled too much.
Give it, give it!
Spit it out, spit it out!
It's gone, it's gone.
Say Ah.
It's gone.
You jerk.
Mom, that's enough, just go.
Alright.
Come on, go.
Alright, alright, just hold on.
- I'll go even if you tell me not to go.
- Then hurry and go.
You listen carefully.
Don't go looking for Ha Seon's mom.
Do you understand?
Have a safe drive home.
Mother, have a safe drive home.
We're sorry to have caused you concern.
That's okay. I'll call again.
Don't come out. Go on in.
Go in, go in.
Yes, go in.
Bye Mom.
Go up.
What are we going to do about this?
How is this something to smile about?
What's so good about this?
Why are you smiling?
There's something like that.
I'll leave now.
If I test this, we'll solve
this issue quickly.
Na Yeong
Na Yeong, we didn't mean to trick you
Na Yeong, I'm sorry.
The promise that I made with Seong Min
made me have to lie to you.
Na Yeong, we never thought
things would go so far.
Please forgive us.
But we weren't taking care of
Ha Seon for the sense of duty
We really love Ha Seon.
You too.
I miss you, Na Yeong.
Na Yeong, where are you?
I'm really sorry.
Are you okay?
Is Ha Seon okay?
Na Yeong, let's meet.
We'll meet, and I'll explain everything.
Na Yeong.
Where are you?
Please call me just once.
I'll wait.
Seong Min.
Why did you do it?
Why did you do it? Why?
Say something.
I want to have a baby.
Let's talk later.
You really hate going to
a hospital that much?
Can't you do this for me,
no matter how much I want it?
Okay.
Then I'll put that on.
No, you don't have to put that on.
No. I will.
Let's go to the hospital one more time.
What are you doing?
Hm?
I'm going to put these in the
office and have it diligently.
Seong Min, who do you want
our baby to take after?
I hope that baby looks a lot like you.
Me?
The baby can't take after me.
It has to take after you.
Seong Min, did I make
it difficult for you?
Was I too greedy?
Is that why you made that kind
of request to your friends?
Behind my back?
Then this is all my fault.
Ha Seon, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
That doesn't mean that
Mommy doesn't love you.
You know that, right?
You're my daughter.
I love you so much.
Maybe.
Maybe if Daddy didn't do that
for us, we may not have met.
So let's be grateful to Daddy, okay?
Congratulations, you're pregnant.
- Thank you Doctor!
- Na Yeong!
If you're happy, then I'm happy.
This baby is a gift
from the heavens.
Seong Min,
thank you.
I won't think otherwise anymore.
Ha Seon is a gift from the heavens.
The greatest gift
that you left for me.
Is this the place
for paternity tests?
Yes.
Would you like a paternity test?
Does that work with strands of hair?
Yes. Did you bring the hairs
that you wanted to test?
Yes.
This is the father's.
This is the baby's.
Yes.
Oh, it's moving.
Wow, he's strong!
It moved again.
I'll make you a diaper, here.
Oh, you're so stubborn, here.
Ha Seon, I could never leave
you in a place like this.
Never.
You're my daughter.
It's fun, isn't it?
It's fun, it's fun.
Dad.
Papa.
I don't know who it will be,
But that woman who marries
you will be very happy.
Na Yeong.
Please come back, I'm begging you.
That place was pretty good
Director, I'll buy tomorrow.
Na Hwang, are you on a diet?
He isn't eating or drinking at all.
It's almost as if you raised our Ha Seon.
Are you really walking on your own?
Kwang Hee, your work is so good.
You're really funny.
Keep drawing.
You have a warm and delicate side.
Don't put on a front.
Just be your usual self.
My usual self?
Gentle and friendly.
Let's begin the picking up event.
The most important thing,
today's purpose is money.
I've been told that a special preparation
for money donator has been made.
Han Soo Hyeon
Han Soo Hyeon, where are you?
Yes, please come forward.
Applause please.
He's very good looking.
Please give us the money.
How much will it be?
The anticipation is heavy.
That's it?
It's only 10,000 Won.
Everyone, let's tell him to spend more.
Everyone, "spend some more,
spend some more!"
Please spend some more.
Just a moment...
It's coming, it's coming.
A lot is coming out!
A total of 50,000 Won, 50,000 Won!
Wait, wait, where are you going?
You can't just leave money and go.
For the future of Min Seo!
How about one song.
Everyone, do you want to hear a song?
"sing a song, sing a song!"
Yes, I ask you, please.
You were born to be loved.
And you’re receiving that
love in your life now.
You were born to be loved.
And you’re receiving that
love in your life now.
God's love that started from
the beginning of time,
Produced fruit
through our meeting
Because of your
existence in this world
You are a great joy to us.
You...
were born to be loved...
I'm sorry, I think I'll stop here.
Congratulations on your
baby's first birthday.
Have you ever seen a hyena
(famous song: Leopard of Kilimanjaro)
hanging around looking for food?
I don't want to be a hyena,
I wanna be a leopard.
I want to be the leopard
of Kilimanjaro.
I'm glad you're here.
Can you do something about that friend?
I can't come like a wind then
go like a dew...
Let's go.
Han Soo Hyeon,
what are you doing here?
Sing a song.
Come on, sing.
He's going to sing a song.
Go on.
Why did you drink so much?
I don't know.
Na Yeong,
Na Yeong is gone.
And she took Ha Seon.
It's all my fault.
It's all my fault, everyone!
It's my fault!
- I'm sorry everyone.
- My fault.
My fault.
Are the results of the test available?
Yes.
Is he the true father?
Uh.
No.
Really?
That's strange.
They look the same.
What?
They look the same?
Yes. The way my son looked when he was
young, and the baby looks exactly the same.
That's not possible.
Was there a mistake?
Can you do the test again?
There's no need.
You brought a dog hair.
What?
A dog hair?
To be specific, a white maltese whisker.
Whisker?
Yes.
A dog whisker.
This author is so funny.
Where was this kind of skill hiding?
Uh oh. I called it garbage.
He won't even see me if I contact him.
Why aren't you uploading a
new comic today?
Something came up, so I may be taking
an extended break.
I'm very sorry.
Hi Mom.
Did you clean the baby's room?
Why?
I brought the wrong hair.
What hair.
Mom, what are you talking about?
I told you, you can't do a paternity test.
Then what are you planning on doing?
Don't you care who's baby Ha Seon is?
No, I'm not curious at all.
I cleaned Ha Seon's room, there's
not a thread lying around, so mark my words.
I'm going to clean really well so that kind
of talk doesn't resurface again.
What happened?
You two came home together?
- Take Kyeong Tae
- Na Yeong.
Ha Seon.
Na Yeong.
Why did he have to bring it up,
if he was going to be like this?
I know what you mean.
I'm going to clean the upstairs room,
so you can sleep there from now on.
- In my own room?
- Yeah.
I don't think Na Yeong is
going to come back.
You said you were uncomfortable
sleeping downstairs. Go sleep upstairs.
I can't do that.
It's still Na Yeong's room.
You said downstairs was uncomfortable.
I know, but let's leave it for now.
I'm going to go wash up.
Not too long ago, you were throwing
a fit about being uncomfortable.
How did we get like this?
Woof, woof, this is a puppy.
Woof, woof.
Hi Ha Seon, I'm a puppy.
This is a birdy.
Tweet, tweet, I'm flying.
Hi, Ha Seon!
And there was a bunny too.
Bunny was...
How was I supposed to make a bunny again?
- Hi Bunny, let's be friends.
- Hi Puppy, let's eat the Bunny.
Ha Seon...
I'm being silly.
I'm thinking about your uncles.
Uncles were really nice to us, right?
Ha Seon...
You look exactly like your dad to me.
But you're actually supposed to look
more like one of your uncles.
I can't believe it.
It makes no sense.
It's broiled eel.
Ha Seon, let's eat.
Yes, Dad.
Ha Seon, the tail is mine.
Dad, you bought this fish?
I bought it, with my blood money.
Haven't I earned the tail from that?
Well, that's true but...
You should be grateful that I at least
let you eat the body of the fish.
No! No way.
You can't become cheap because
you take after your dad, okay?
What?
Ms. Choi, I can't hear you.
Speak loudly!
Hi Ms. Choi, we can meet later.
Why don't we go to Pagoda park where
there're a lot of good-looking people.
(Pagoda park is for aged people)
Okay.
Dad, where are you going?
I'm going to meet Ms. Choi.
Good for you then.
Can I come home late
after dating Jun Oppa?
Didn't you say you were
going to meet Min?
Min Oppa is for the morning.
Jun Oppa is for the afternoon.
You know this already Daddy.
Okay, then don't meet
more than three people.
No, no way.
You can't be a player, no way.
That's even more of a nightmare.
Na Hwang Ha Seon
Be careful Ha Seon.
I lost, Ha Seon.
You lost again, Dad.
Ha Seon, do you wash your feet?
Dad, there's no time for Korea's
police to wash their feet.
We're busy catching criminals.
No.
That's wrong too.
What am I thinking of?
How could I think these
things about you?
I'm sorry, Ha Seon.
But Ha Seon, you can't be like
those three people at all, okay?
You have to be just like
your Daddy, okay?
Ha Seon.
- Ha Seon, Grandpa's back.
- You're back.
Ha Seon, did you
have fun today?
I brought some strawberries.
Wash them for Ha Seon.
You didn't have to do this.
How are you, Grandpa's home.
So you found a place to leave Ha Seon?
There's a space in the day
care down the street.
The facilities are decent,
and the fees are small.
Oh.
All of Ha Seon's things
are in that house.
Ha Seon's things?
All of my clothes are there too.
What should I do?
But it's not like I can
go there myself.
Really? I'll go tomorrow
and pick up your things.
Na Yeong,
I've been meaning to say.
How about getting a paternity test,
like those fellows' mothers were saying?
Dad.
Not you too.
Think about it.
How long do you think you can
raise Ha Seon on your own for?
It's not too late to find out who
the father is and live together.
What do you mean together?
Just because this happened,
doesn't mean that one of those three
men can become Ha Seon's father.
Well...
I'm not saying that you should marry
the father right away.
I'm just saying that it would be nice
if we knew who the father was.
All three of them seemed like decent men.
We could get some child support money.
Dad!
Ha Seon was born between Seong Min
and me, no matter who says what.
If you keep talking about that,
I'm going to take Ha Seon and leave.
Okay, okay.
I won't talk about that again.
Have a strawberry,
Grandpa brought it for you.
Have it.
All three seemed like good guys.
Dad!
Hi, Team Leader.
Are you enjoying your vacation?
Where are you?
Why is it so noisy?
We're updating the interior of our office.
Interior?
Have you forgotten that the president told
us that our team must take more supports?
Song Na Yeong, Assistant Leader.
What?
What did you say?
We will start getting
more team members,
You can't continue
to be a team member.
Na Yeong, please take the role of
Customer Service Assistant Leader
Really?
Once you become Assistant Leader, you'll
get more busy, so enjoy your vacation.
How's Ha Seon?
She's doing well.
It hasn't been long since I've
seen her, but I miss her already.
Ha Seon misses you too.
Really?
I meant that I missed you, Na Yeong.
Ah, I'm flattered...
Hello?
Did you hang up?
No.
Don't tease me.
Anyway, Song Assistant Leader. Enjoy
your vacation and I'll see you next week.
Yes.
Ha Seon, Mommy got promoted!
Mommy got promoted!
I'm an Assistant Leader!
Doesn't that sound fancy?
Assistant Leader!
Aren't you having lunch,
Detective Na Hwang?
I'll buy you something yummy.
How about spawn stew for
old time's sake? For 8000 won.
Go and eat, officer Nam.
But it's 8000 won.
Okay.
She was caught in the
act of committing a theft.
Okay, go to your business.
On Friday morning at 11am at a
local supermarket, 15 packs of milk...
She stole 32,000 won in products.
Why did you steal so much milk, Ahjumma?
I have a 3-year-old daughter.
My husband got in a car accident
recently and is hospitalized.
I have no more money.
And I can't go out to work in the
restaurant where I used to work.
I'm sorry.
Yes.
She did it for a starving child.
I'm not saying that what
the woman did was right.
But how do you think a mother whose
baby was hungry would have felt?
Please forgive her this one time.
I do feel sorry for her, but I have to take
responsibility for my family too.
The profit from selling these
things isn't very much.
If I let this person or that person,
get away with this kind of thing,
how can I provide for my family?
Okay how about this?
I'll give you 50,000 to compensate you for
your troubles, and we put this behind us.
Well if that's what you want
to do, it's okay with me,
but what about you,
Police Officer?
Oh, then let's do that.
Here you go.
I don't know if this is okay for me to take.
What are you looking at?
The baby is very cute.
I thought you didn't like kids, Soo Hyeon.
Kids are cute and pretty.
Really?
I hate kids.
Noisy and crazy.
I was like that too, back in the day.
So you're saying you like them now?
Hm?
I'd like to be clear about this.
It's about our future,
so if we feel differently, don't you
think it will strain our marriage?
Oh, no, I don't like kids
very much even now.
I don't want to waste
my life for raising a child.
Aren't you coming?
I'm coming.
Then go on in.
I enjoyed lunch.
Oh, Soo Hyeon, this is for you.
What's this?
I thought it suited you well,
so I bought you a shirt.
Oh, you didn't have to.
It's silk so you have to
take good care of it.
Don't leave your iron
on it like last time.
Oh, that won't happen again.
- I'll go now.
- Bye bye.
- Is this everything?
- Yes.
If I find anything, I'll give you a call.
Okay.
Please don't call for now.
It's hard for me to answer your calls with
Na Yeong around.
Oh, really?
Anyway, thank you very much for
taking care of Na Yeong.
Please tell your friends the same.
Yes.
- I'm going
- Go ahead.
Oh.
Are Na Yeong and Ha Seon okay?
Of course, they're good.
Na Yeong was really shocked,
so please understand.
After some time has passed,
she should come around.
I'm going.
Father.
Can I have at least have the address?
I could get in big trouble
from Na Yeong for that.
I'm going.
Let's go.
Go on in.
Thank you so much.
You even gave me food to eat.
No matter how difficult it is,
I shouldn't have stolen.
I don't know what bit me.
Here, this is for you.
What's this?
It's for you for your emergency.
No, no.
It's not much, please take it.
I even thought of killing
myself and my baby.
Don't think of things like that.
You have to be stronger in these times.
If you ever need more help,
give me a call. Okay?
I'm so thankful,
I don't know what to do.
Go ahead.
Thank you so much.
Bye bye.
Ye Lim.
Thank you, bye.
Bye.
I wonder how Na Yeong is doing.
I wish I could see Ha Seon just once.
I found out where Na Yeong
is staying. Wanna come?
Gotta go.
Hereafter, if the rate
of interest is fixed,
the bond price will be down,
dollar will be up,
and the stock market will be stable.
Accordingly...
Team Leader!
I have to go to and visit a company.
Can't you wait until the end
of the meeting? It's almost over.
I have to go right now.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Han.
Mr. Han!
- That's the house?
- Yes.
It must be hard for her to go up
and down the stairs with Ha Seon.
Hey, look at that railing.
What if Ha Seon were to fall off from there?
Ow, my foot.
Here, shoes.
Oh, thanks.
What's this?
Just put them on,
they're from the police station.
Why couldn't you buy me a new pair?
I didn't have time for that.
Let's go, let's go.
Let's follow her.
Where's she going?
I don't know, but follow her anyway.
I guess she's leaving
Ha Seon at the day care.
What if the day care has a fire?
Watch your mouth.
That bastard!
- Hold it in.
- Did you see the plate?
I will catch him right now
as "riding without helmet"
You lower the volume.
Okay.
She's gone.
I didn't even get to see
Ha Seon's face, thanks to you.
Seriously!
At least we found out where she was.
Now we can see her everyday.
How's Ha Seon?
She's doing gonji gonji.
(baby's finger play)
What? gonji gonji?
Send me her picture.
Okay.
What's this? I can only see her feet.
Hey, I had to risk my life
to take this picture.
This is no good.
Let's take this opportunity for
each of us to buy a good cell phone.
One that does video.
Do you know how expensive
a video cell phone is?
I have no money, it's dog whiskers.
- I'll help you pay for it.
- Me too.
Ha Seon is good at Jjak Jjak Goong.
Na Yeong's wearing the
outfit that I bought for her.
What?
Nothing.
An expensive cell phone
makes a difference.
I don't feel like I
wasted money at all.
Here are all the shoes
that we bought for her.
Hey, hey, show me the running
shoes that I bought for her.
It looks like she's never
worn my running shoes.
It's brand new.
Don't be so sad about it.
Kwang Hee, behind you.
Behind you!
Behind me? What?
What are you doing here?
I was just on the
phone with Kyeong Tae.
Hello, Na Yeong.
Ha Seon, how have you been?
How did you know to come here?
Uh.
Did my father tell you?
No.
I followed him.
Please leave.
I have nothing to say to the three of you.
Na Yeong.
Please don't even come here again.
If you keep coming, then I'm going to
run away to a place that no one knows.
We were just worried about Ha Seon.
Don't worry about Ha Seon.
I'll take care of her.
I'll say this again, but I hope that
we won't run into each other again.
Please don't appear in
Ha Seon's presence again.
Kwang Hee, I'm sorry.
But there's nothing I can do.
This is the only way the
three of you will move on.
Ha Seon, were you happy
to see Uncle Kwang Hee?
All that time, you grew quite
fond of your uncles, didn't you?
Anyway, we can't anymore.
We can't see them anymore.
I'm sorry, Ha Seon.
Sorry, Ha Seon.
Anyway, Na Yeong seemed
to be very angry.
We might never see Ha Seon again.
What can we do to
soothe her anger?
Anybody home?
It's officer Na Hwang.
Did they go somewhere?
Are you home?
Ahjumma?
I bought some milk and snacks.
I'm the officer.
Are you home?
Ahjumma?
Ahjumma.
Are you home?
What is this?
Mom!
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Main Translator: jysung
Spot Translator: saturn
Timer: julier
Editor/QC: annchong
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Please do NOT hardsub and/or stream this
episode using our English subtitles.
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!!!
Get it for FREE @ d-addicts.com