Subtitles brought to you by the Glorious Team @Viki
Episode 21
We...
You said that we are going to see other for a long time, right?
I also want to do that.
Seo Jae Woo,
can you be my brother?
I don't really understand your words. But tell me why you are suddenly acting like this,
so that I can understand.
I came from meeting my father.
My father, you know him right?
You saw him at the police station so you must know what kind of person he is.
I can't see him because it's too embarrassing.
I have more pride than it seems.
If I become your oppa, it won't be embarrassing?
Yes.
-Jeong Da Jeong!
-My father...
asked Ahjussi to give him money.
I feel so ashamed and embarrassed to see his face,
but you know it's a little better thinking of him as my mother's Oppa.
Thinking of him as my mother's brother at times like those and
thinking of him as your father when I see you is laughable.
It's not laughable but shameless.
I don't want to meet a man by going so far as to do that.
I have something to talk about with Mom.
I will go in first.
Wait.
-Seo Jae Woo!
-You said that I am your oppa.
Then do it.
Do it if you want. I will become your oppa.
Where is Da Jeong?
Yes. I knew that you sent her.
You raised the kid well.
Where is she?
How would I know? She just shouted at me and left.
(He crosses out Da Jeong's name as a source of funds.)
No matter how little I have, you shouldn't do that.
Did I ask the president of the rice cake shop for money?
That guy told me that he will give money.
What? You asked for money...?
Are you a human?
(Now circling Rice Cake shop president.)
I couldn't receive it because that hotel CEO or whatever took it.
I didn't get the money, but I have to pay some money.
What am I supposed to do?
Come here.
If you want to see me, you should come. I'm not scared of a thing like you anymore!
Oh, really?
I'm really going. Should I go?
Hello.
Hello? Da Ae's mom!
Hey...
Yes, Father.
Do you have somewhere to call?
No.
Father...
Da Jeong is good at working, right?
What you said about her being better than me when I first started learning,
are you being sincere? I'm hurt.
It's true that she is better than how you were.
Father...
Even if that's true, what does it matter? She has a job.
I can't ask her to change her job, either.
You like Da Jeong that much?
In Woo doesn't have a good eye for women.
It is hard to find a girl like her.
Is that kind of household okay?
Her single mother isn't living comfortably either.
Hey, you...
You don't even have that kind of a single mother.
Are you becoming like Sin Ae?
Why are you looking at households?
Da Jeong!
Mom!
I'm taller than you. If you are tired,
lean on me.
Han Song Jeong, why did you do that?
If you lie next time, I'm not leaving you alone.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
Let's tell Unni and Da In.
I will tell them. Give me just one day.
Just one day.
Writer Han, do you really have no eye for men?
From now on, meet someone after I allow it.
When did you grow up so much?
You are the same.
You are still pretty.
Let's go home. I'm hungry.
I'm hungry. Let's go, Mom!
Where are you? Are you drinking?
How can a woman drink at this hour? I will come and get you. Where are you?
Da In, age doesn't matter.
Promise me to wait six months.
That's not right. How can she wait six months?
I understand you.
But a woman alone shouldn't drink this late.
She is with Hee Joo.
Hee Joo?
Are you with Hee Joo...?
Hey, Han Da In, where are you? I told you not to see Hee Joo.
Put him on the phone.
This kid, you are a man, a man! Tell her!
Tell me where you are!
What? Little kid? Hey!
Yes. Little. Kid!
You can't come in here even if I tell you where it is.
Minors are not allowed in here.
That's right. I'm going to date Hee Joo. Why?
I hope your heart bursts.
Why are you being mean to the kid?
It's a punishment for lying to me.
Perhaps, you like Yoo Ji Ho?
Are you crazy? A high school student.
Hey, I like old guys.
I want someone cuddly as a father, who can forgive me no matter what I do.
Just drink and stop talking nonsense.
Da In,
can I board in your house?
-What?
-I think I have to move out of the house I'm living in right now.
It will be for a short time, before I go to the military.
-Professor Kang is doing it, too.
-He left.
And we have to move soon.
To where?
I don't know. If I talk about that, I'll get even more upset.
Drink, drink. Quickly.
I thought that he would call me again, but he isn't.
He has no perseverance.
You, if Ji Ho calls you, tell him that we're dating.
Okay?
-Come here, come here.
-Let me go! She said that she is with Hee Joo!
You shouldn't call her.
Hey, that's why you won't do.
You have to end it right now for Da In to become impatient.
If you call her again, you are out.
Hyung, what should I do then?
Doctor Seo is too busy nowadays.
Look... The thing is,
women are-
- Does your girlfriend listen to you well?
Come here, come here.
Come here! This is why you won't do. This is why...
Yeah, when I say something to my girlfriend, she listens to me right away. What are you going do?
Softly, softly!
Can you accept him just as a brother?
In Woo...
- Aigoo, you...
Sit down.
- Sit down quickly.
What about Jae Woo?
He went to bed early last night.
Then..
- Why are you dressed already?
- Are you going somewhere?
Yes. I have to leave early because I have a lot of work.
Even so... What time is it now?
Well, you and Grandfather go to work every day this early.
Jeez, this is so tiring. What should I do? Sit down.
- Eat at least a spoonful before you go.
- It's alright.
- I'll be going.
- Oh my...
Hey, your stomach is going to get upset so eat something when you have time.
- Yes, I'll do that.
- Aigoo...
His company should give him a special award.
Da Jeong.
Pardon?
Why aren't you saying hello when you see your brother?
Work hard.
What did my brother say? "Oppa"?
Something happened between the two of you, right?
It's 4 AM again. I'm going to go crazy.
Aigoo, how long is it going to be like this?
Prepare the breakfast and send it up.
It was ordered 30 minutes ago so it was sent up already.
I did?
When did you get here?
Has it been 30 minutes?
Uncle, your introversion must still be bothering you.
Did something happen?
There is always a lot of work...
I lied saying I have to go to work.
I'm going to try telling some lies now.
They were all fooled. It was fun.
What's the reason for the change?
You have a lot of younger sisters around you, don't you?
Hey... Where do I have any younger sisters, punk?
You know you have a lot of women around you who call you "oppa".
Why do women do that?
- Continue talking...
- Jeong Da Jeong asked me to act like her brother.
A little more...
She says she wants to see me for a long time. So...
Exactly...
She's trying to organize your relationship.
In any case, the women of that house are all very strong.
They are having a hard time because of the problem with the father.
Then she should discuss it and lean on you.
Han Song Jeong thinks she is a lone towering pine tree or something.
She is always trying to overcome things by herself.
I'm talking about Jeong Da Jeong.
I'm saying this because the mother and daughter are both the same.
Look at Writer Han! She doesn't even call me once even after that incident happened.
Just thinking about it makes me angry!
This is dangerous...
- What is?
I started like that with Jeong Da Jeong.
Uncle... No way...
Jeez, no, no. I'm not!
It's because I feel sorry for her. Because I feel pity!
Dad said to differentiate between love and compassion.
You're no help.
This little punk.
Jeez, I'm not!
It isn't!
Hey, dearie! When did you get here?
There are few points to better explain the relationship between the model and the product but
I don't think it's too bad for first draft.
I came early to to show off the work that I already did before.
Since we should just check out the initial layout,
I'll ask them to proceed when we settle the layout.
I see that dating makes you full of passion.
Should I call Jeong Da Jeong in order to raise your energy level more?
Here. These are samples; I got one for you and Jung Da Jeong.
And this is makeup.
Since Flying Squirrel has become the face of our company, she should take care (of her face).
I think she will like it.
I'll deliver them to her.
What's the matter?
Since you are taking care of all of the days work at a top speed,
let's call Jeong Da Jeong and tell her she should buy us some food today.
Today is the day she gets $5000 for the photo shoot.
She's busy.
She says she is learning how to make rice cake.
Rice cake?
You guys came early, I see.
Oppa has to work so let's delay the move. I'll see you later.
Eun Woo, did you get a girlfriend?
Oh, it's my little sister.
I was thinking... If somebody else heard you, they would think you have a girlfriend.
Everybody around me misunderstands, just like you.
Aigoo, I'm envious because my brother is my enemy.
Every time he sees me, he always asks me for money.
My brother does that ,too. He makes go on errands and does nothing at home.
When we were young, I used to wrestle and get head locked.
I almost got my arm broken.
He does those things with his younger sister?
Of course!
Everybody is the same, whether it's a younger girl or a guy.
Why are you messing up the reality?
Younger sister is better because you can watch movie or travel together.
You travel (with younger sister)?
You're showing that you don't have a girl. You watch when you get a girl.
Is that so?
Travel?
Wow, it must taste good.
Oh, yes.
The healthy sticky rice cake.
Yes. Yes. Thirty of them. I'll put the order in.
Why? Are you expecting a call?
Yes?
No.
President, I got an order
but I can't understand it because they want me to take out this and that.
Wow. You still can't take orders properly?
You guys take care of this.
Look here, Da Jeong.
Yes.
Did the things go well when you met your father?
Ahjusshi, I have a favor to ask you.
Even if my father comes around again, please don't give him any money.
Oh, okay.
Your heart was burdened because of that I see.
Hey, be careful.
I used to get hurt in the past. Here, wear this.
Okay.
When these things come out, they are soft.
But when they harden, their edges get sharp.
Jae Woo and Jae In use to use these to have sword fights.
Oh, by the say, my mother is going to tell Unni and Da In everything soon.
I'm trying to convince myself that this is better.
It's easier since I am wearing this.
Oh, is that so?
Mom.
She drank with Hee Joo yesterday.
She must be upset because of Ji Hoo.
Do you need to go now?
I can go after lunch. Do you have something for me to do?
There's a boarder again in Dr. Kang's room.
Mom!
He's a dentist.
He has a son who is in middle school.
Huh?
I'm not giving my permission.
I will be observing again.
Mom!
Da Ae, let's talk.
Yeah.
Mom, what is it?
I... deceived you guys.
But listen and forgive me.
Your father... is alive.
Da Jeong met him yesterday.
She said she saw someone similar, it turns out she's right.
Somehow she recognized him, I guess.
You knew he was alive?
It doesn't matter.
Even if he is alive, he's already dead to us.
Da Ae.
Da Jeong and I remember.
You did nothing wrong.
Don't be sorry towards us.
There was nothing I could do for you back when I was young,
but we will protect you now.
If you find it hard to tell Da In, should I tell her?
No, I will be the one.
I will tell her.
It's alright, Mom.
Da In will also understand.
Mom.
Stop crying.
Han Song Jeong.
You think I won't be able to come if you tell me to?
I should settle my 10,000 Won.
Okay. For me, it's fight to the end. Fight to the end.
Grandma! Is your leg okay?
Yeah, it's gotten better with your heat treatment.
But doing this... it's so hard, I thought I would die while trying.
I will find an easier one next time.
I will be going.
You're better than my daughter.
Are you Da Ae?
I saw Da In and Da Jeong.
You are Da Ae, right?
Who are you?
Don't you recognize me?
Da Jeong even recognizes me, how can the eldest not?
I... am your father.
My father already died.
What?
Why not even one...
You brat!
Why are you doing this to me?
Did your Mom ask you not to recognize me?
How could she change so much.
In the 20 years I haven't seen her she's become so tough.
I don't know who you are but don't curse my mom!
This brat...
HEY!
I'm not a bit scared even if you shout at me.
JEONG DA AE!
Huh? Da Ae?
Wait... that person.
Isn't that the one who said he was connected with their mother?
WHO ON EARTH ARE YOU TO BE CALLING MY NAME?
Seriously.
Hey,
aren't you being too mean towards me?
Fine, let's say I haven't done my role as your father,
but I'm still your father.
How could you, so rude!
Father?
No... Da Ae, what is he talking about?
Nothing, Grandma.
Go inside.
No... What do you mean "father?"
Did you drink in the middle of the day?
You probably are not in your right mind.
Seriously, I'm going crazy.
Hey! Tell her properly!
Grandma, go inside.
It's alright.
Hey! Tell your mother to come out!
Da Ae.
Dr. Kang.
What's wrong?
- Eun Chan, welcome.
Who is he?
Did something happen?
Doctor.
Da Ae, did you get married?
You had a child this big already?
Doctor, please chase that person out.
What?
Seriously, okay.
Okay.
Dr. Kang.
That person is strange.
Oh my! He's heading to the house.
HEY! WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
Doctor.
- Look here!
Who are you?
I'm Da Ae's father.
Leave.
I said I'm her father.
- I SAID LEAVE!
All sorts of things are happening.
Hey, Sin Ae!
Hey! Hey!
Hey! There's a crazy person in front of the house.
Crazy person?
Yeah. I don't know if he's drank in the middle of the day
but he's saying that he's the neighbor's father.
What is that again?
They said a crazy person stopped by the the rice cake shop, too.
The rice cake shop, too?
I don't know. I don't know.
They said there was a crazy person eating all the rice cakes.
No... hey... that...
It's alright since Dr. Kang chased that person out.
Hey, the eldest daughter and Prof. Kang
I think there's something.
Prof. Kang?
He has a child.
That's why. It's big trouble if both of them like each other.
Mom, what nonsense are you saying?
I'm telling you I'm right!
Did you drink in the middle of the day?
Where is the crazy person?
How is it? Do you like it?
It's nice.
If you use it here around your ankle, you won't have to worry about the rice cake room (temperature).
You must be having a hard time going to work since dawn
and because of this you dropped by?
I stopped by after going out for work.
Da Jeong.
- Yes?
Team Leader also has something for you.
There's cosmetics too, it's in the car so I will give it to you at home.
Yes.
Father, we were scolded for playing with those long rice cakes, right?
That's right.
Well, that...
In Woo was worse.
What do you call that... he wanted to use it for sword fights.
He would take the entire container and the whole family would be running around searching for him.
Yes.
Da Jeong, your oppas played around like that.
Honey! Honey, honey!
What's the matter?
I just have something to ask him.
What are you doing here?
I dropped by while I was out for work.
Grandpa, would you be able to adjust it by yourself?
It's not a problem, it's easy.
Honey, the crazy person appeared at home.
He was making a fuss saying that he's Da Ae's father.
What?
What are you whispering about?
Huh? Nothing.
Mom saw, Prof. Kang chased him out.
I will go out for a while.
Grandpa, I will be going too.
Okay.
I will use it well.
Da Jeong, Oppa will drop you off on the way.
Oppa?
Come out.
Get in.
- No.
If I run, it won't take long.
What's wrong with you?
- Pardon?
You asked me to be an oppa so I did, but why are you so cautious?
You didn't want to (be cautious), isn't that why you asked me to be your oppa?
I will be late as well.
Let's go.
Do you like it?
What?
Do you like making rice cakes now that you've tried?
Yes.
- If you have any favors to ask regarding your dad, ask.
I couldn't hit the father of the woman that I like.
I couldn't give money, either, but it's better since I'm your oppa.
Now I can do it all.
Seo Jae Woo.
You said I'm your oppa?
I can do it, but isn't it that you can't be my younger sister?
I didn't ask you to be my oppa so that you can do this.
An oppa can watch movies together, give allowance, and even go on vacations
and help when the dongsaeng (younger sibling) is having a hard time, they say.
If you need money, tell me.
If you want to go on a vacation, let's go too.
What's wrong with you?
You already know why I said that.
I don't know.
Why? Did my father tell you not to date me?
I guess he didn't know I would be able to see you longer like this.
Please let me off.
We're almost there, wait.
You can go.
♬ Even one step is hard for me..♬
♬ Just that I can see you, my heart is okay.♬
Eun Chan.
How did you come?
- Together with my dad.
Are you back?
I think so.
We're busy moving that I don't have time for school.
Well done.
Even if he's alive, to my children, they do not have a father.
Can you be understanding of that?
Yes.
While I was gone, something like that happened.
Mom.
Dr. Kang.
- Have you been well?
Yes.
Now, I just need to tell Da In.
I already told them.
Unni, did you meet him?
Yeah, for a moment outside the house.
You're not worried about me, right?
I'm alright.
Yeah.
If you need anything, please tell me anytime.
While I'm here, I will protect you.
I feel assured.
Mom, it would be better if you tell Da In faster before she finds out.
I should.
But telling Da In is the hardest.
Dr. Kang!
Have you been well?
He's back.
If so, why did you leave?
Anyway, welcome!
Thank you for the furniture.
It's a relief that you like it.
But what were you all doing leaving me out?
You weren't talking behind my back, right?
We do it even if it's not behind your back, you know?
Mom, she's going around drinking.
She needs to be scolded.
That's right.
Da In, do you have time today?
I'm busy because I have to help the professor. Why?
Okay then, come home early after you're done.
What's wrong with all of you?
Is today a special day?
Could it be...
a consolation party for me because of the Ji Hoo incident?
Regarding Jeong In Seong's family, his wife died of an illness two months ago
and now he is living with his 21 year old son, Jeong Hee Joo.
He has a son?
Yes.
He's the same age as Han Song Jeong's youngest daughter.
It seems like the youngest daughter was born after the divorce.
He abandoned a woman who was pregnant?
He's not human then.
Where is that bastard?
In one hour, you have meeting with the city director regarding Young World Tower construction.
I'm asking, where is he?
I took 20,000 Won but had to give up 10,000 Won.
I have to settle the matter with that guy from the hotel.
Why isn't he coming out?
Should I go in?
Go... don't...
Go... hide!
Hey, if that crazy person comes, call me right away.
Don't worry.
The men in our family backs off so they won't do.
I need to be here.
Just wait til I catch him, I'm not going to let him off the hook.
She goes...
Comes...
- Hey, should I just wait here?
I feel like he's going to come today.
Just go, I can also throw a punch.
Oh, look.
Why are they in such a fuss to catch me?
Is it yummy?
I only ate one.
It's alright if you eat it all.
Where did you go?
- In our house.
You have a house but why are you living here?
It's better to live together than just being with my dad.
That's right.
It's been so long since we've seen you, do you have something you would like to eat?
Soybean paste stew.
You like soybean paste stew?
My dad does.
- So filial.
Everyone is inside, right?
Let's go inside.
My legs.
- Are you alright?
My legs won't listen to me.
You should listen well.
Let's go. Let's go.
I was on my way to bring this.
Let's eat kalguksoo (knife noodles) together tonight.
Yes.
But Da Jeong is home so you should tell her to take it with her.
You have to take out the clothes that needs laundering.
Yes.
You're here.
Grandma is here.
That... please bring this.
Tell them to come home early after work, we'll be eating kalguksoo together.
Yes.
You're going out like that?
Hey, go and change your skirt.
I'm wearing shorts.
Grandma, this is also in style.
I will be going.
Hey! Come home early!
Grandma, I'll enjoy the food.
I'm going.
That... give me a cup of water.
You need to manage your daughters well.
Yes.
Do you have something to tell me?
Pardon?
No... your eldest daughter and the professor have something going on, right?
Dr. Kang says he likes my daughter.
No! No! No matter how nice a person can be, how can she raise someone else's child?
That's why I'm opposing them.
But, my children's business are not going the way I want.
Should I step in?
No. I'm just keeping an eye on them.
Would you want to keep an eye on them with me?
I think elders see it better.
There's nothing to watch.
Is there something?
- No.
What brings you here?
It's my brother's store.
What business do you have here?
Well... I... just some rice cakes...
Isn't it about time for you to be looking for your settlement money?
I'm going to go and get it now.
From my brother?
It's the next door's uncle.
- Da In.
Don't loiter around this area.
Well... is this your...
It's not like it's your street.
Do you think I don't know your intentions?
Okay... here.
Why do you live like this?
You're still young (and able), you should work instead.
It would be better if you begged for a position to work in instead?!
Uncle is really cool.
That person...
- Let's go.
Why are you grabbingme?
Unni!
- Let's go.
Da Jeong.
Go. Don't let the kids see this side of yours.
Leave.
What's wrong with you?
Let go.
Then.
Seriously, why are you like that? You're just strong for no reason.
Uncle.
Hello.
Right.
Do you know that person?
He's strange, right?
Oh... where are you going?
Should I give you a ride?
Really? I'm going to school.
That's great then.
Let's go.
Thank you.
So cool.
Jeong Da Jeong.
It's alright. Go and work.
Why are you not getting married?
There's not one man who wants marriage.
The moment a man gets married, love cools.
Why do you think that way?
There are a lot of people like Grandpa and Grandma who live very long while loving each other.
My parents didn't live like that.
Well... my father passed away so soon, my mom's the pitiful one.
I think marriage is hard.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Don't even talk about it.
He deceived me.
I just found out...
he's a high schooler.
Wow!
Where is that punk?
We need to catch him.
It's nice even just hearing it.
I would be nice to have a father like you.
Do it, I think you will be an awesome father.
Marriage... I won't do it.
Yes.
- I will do it.
Today he is going on a date with his sister.
What's with a younger sister? Hurry up and meet a woman.
Hello.
I came to see Chief Seo Jae Woo.
Who?
Check it well.
Chief Seo, who am I?
He's my brother.
I'm Seo In Woo.
Your brother is so cute. He's totally different from his brother.
I'm a whole lot better.
Aigoo... So you work in this place.
What's the matter?
What do you think about it?
Samjin Capitol June Lease funds in the amount of 1,280,000 Won, could not be withdrawn due to insufficient funds.
It wasn't your sunbae's car?
I came to make this deal.
Before I spill out that you and Jeong Da Jeong are secretly dating you should offer a bribe.
Would you say it instead?
- Hyung.
She found out about her father.
She asked me to be her oppa.
Jeong Da Jeong is going too fast... she's asking you to get married.
An oppa becomes a darling, and then becomes a honey... that's the order of dating.
It's too fast for marriage.
Don't joke around, it's serious.
Hyung, at times like this especially you should think of it simply.
When the other party is serious, if you were to come out serious as well,
then it's the end. Bye, bye (in chinese).
That's why I'm being her oppa.
Wait. Then we're in the same boat.
I'll be going first.
Where are you going?
- Fair play!
What fair play?
I was wondering where you went.
You're here.
- You're not going to make dinner?
Welcome.
We're doing it. When it's so hot, what's the use in preparing dinner at both houses?
Hey, since we're cooking Chicken Kalgooksoo (Hand Cut Noodles) here, let's just eat here.
Aigoo, why are you like this?
I heard you went on a trip Professor Kang. I guess you had a good time.
Your face is so bright!
Is that so?
Aigoo. My mom is so excited without lifting a hand.
With two assistants.
The chef is very picky.
You should knead the dough properly, it'll get separated.
Just cut it well, they're too thin.
They're too thin.
Da Ae.
- Hey!
Do I have to tell you with words? Massage my shoulders.
Oh... okay.
Is it refreshing, Mom?
Yeah. It's really refreshing.
Dr. Kang.
I haven't given my permission yet. You should be careful in front of the elders.
Yes.
We'd better make the fresh (unripe) Kimchee at least, right?
Let's finish things up. They said that they're making Kalgooksoo (Hand Cut Noodles) tonight.
Yes.
Grandpa, I'm here.
I'm back.
- Both of you are coming in together.
I'm so lonely so we will be going together from now on.
Da Jeong, Oppa came and you're not saying your greetings.
Did you come?
Look at her. She has lost all her energy. Shouldn't you scold her?
She's my sister.
Da Jeong, I will give you allowance so say hello nicely.
Me too, allowance.
Nevermind.
Hey, both of you should come often.
I feel good with us gathering here.
Is this functioning well?
It works well.
Should I help you?
I... I'm done.
There are a lot of orders these days, aren't there? Which ddeok (rice cake) is the most popular?
These days...that's right,
electric...and some other
The family is over there, right?
Come over to Jae Woo's house for a bit.
I'm good, right?
That... if I got there... it's a bit...
Then come out.
I will be standing by the gate.
I was intending to come and see you soon.
Then... should I have waited until you came?
You should have told the kids.
Until when are you going to hide it?
You must be busy,
but you are concerned about me.
Now, I will handle my own problems.
I lived while working hard.
But this is all I amount to.
The same with Min Sik oppa and Chairman Nam Gong Yeong too...
Thank you.
I told you not to pretend like a woman.
I have never thought of that even once.
Just...
Just... I'm embarrassed and thankful, that's all.
I'm also thankful.
Pardon?
- You should have just accepted when I said I would invest.
Then things wouldn't have become this noisy.
The problem about Jeong In Seong, whatever it takes, believe in me this once.
For living while working so hard,
it's my gift.
I was going to tell him just this one thing.
Do you think you know me?
In the past, I used to do very well. Why are you being like this?
You know, I got...
humiliated in front of my children.
Say something.
Hee Joo's mother,
I turned out like this because of you.
Why did you like me so much?
Why did you make me this way?
Aigoo, stop with the nonsense bullcrap and get a hold of your self.
That young man only came today and settled your tab here.
That kid is my son.
Besides him, I have three other daughters.
While you don't even know well.
Aigoo, drink according to your limit!
Ahumma!
--Aigoo, really!
I'm already dead so I don't get drunk!
Han Song Jeong,
you're a bad woman.
I can do it by myself. I'm still strong.
Oh, I'll do it.
Love is timing. Your timing is amazing.
You're going to set your sights on the gap when Ji Hoo is not here.
Is that so?
It's not like that. Da In is like a younger sister to me.
Younger sister?
There are lot of younger sisters here around here. Isn't that so, younger sister?
Please wipe it, oppa.
The thing I will..
I'll put these in your room.
Uh, men aren't allowed up there. Hey...
Professor Kang, we're not a men but oppas.
Hey, hey, hey. Extend the legs.
Is it because it's a girl's room? It's charming and nice.
Why are you doing this?
What?
--Seo Jae Woo.
There you go again. What is this with Seo Jae Woo? Do you want me to be your big brother or what?
You doing this is bothering me.
You said we should do this.
Come down.
Seo Jae Woo.
Don't take it lightly.
Be your big brother? Think carefully.
Aigoo, this is refreshing and nice.
Do you know how much work it takes to make this even if it doesn't seem so?
I wanted to make you something delicious,
but the Professor and Da Ae did it all.
Aigoo, hey.
You're different that you appear on the outside.
When I first saw you, do you know that I was afraid of you?
Back then, the situation was a bit...
Who are you?
I am Jung Hee Joo, I'm Da In's friend.
He can't fit in here. If he does..
You look much like your father.
I don't think so...
Kang Eun Chan.
No, Eun Chan, you're cute. Don't lose your confidence.
I like him better.
Elder, that's kind of harsh...
Anyone for more portions?
Give oppa some more.
Take good care of your younger sister. It's what an oppa's suppose to do.
I was going to.
Our company's employee says that he sees movies and goes on trips with his sister.
Not trips!
So what, when she's a younger sister?
Da Jeong helps with the rice cake shop work very well and she's praiseworthy.
Oppa will show you a movie this weekend. Let's go.
You're really liking saying that 'Oppa, Oppa'... Hey, Jae Woo, why are you doing that?!
What am I doing?
Why should you... watch a movie... with Do Jeong?!
Aigoo, that's true. Hotel CEO, do you know?
Our Jae Woo has a girlfriend now.
Wow?
Is that right?
I'm awfully curious who Jae Woo's girlfriend is.
Me too, me too.
So what's the point of having one? He should show her to us.
On this kind of day you should call her.
Da Jeong!
I asked you to pour me more. What are you doing?
Thank you.
Shall we give you more?
Jae Woo Oppa's a little weird.
I know, right?
Father, should I give you a glass of Makgeolli (rice wine)?
That'd be nice.
Me too!
Oh, but...Writer Han can't.
Her drunken habits...
In Woo, just a moment.
Here it is.
Did Jae Woo say anything to you?
What does that mean?
Hey, you'll know that Da Jeong and Jae Woo are dating.
You know too, Father?
Jae Woo, why's he like that?
I'm just trusting and telling you since it's you, Father,
but he said that Jeong Da Jeong asked him to be her Oppa.
Oppa?
Is as an Oppa not okay?
The words are just like that, she's saying they should break up.
Hyung was being watchful of Mom's notice and couldn't say anything and one-sidedly he got kicked to the curb.
Are you really also against the two of them meeting?
Mom, Poop Grandma, even Father. There's no worse luck.
It makes sense that Hyung is going crazy.
Are you eating too much since your mood is good?
It's delicious.
Hey, this fresh kimchee (unripened) is delicious also.
Da Jeong, eat some.
This looks nice.
Aiyoo, it must be nice that Oppa's looking out for you.
Yes.
Aiyoo, really. My Puppy is doing things that he never in his life used to do.
I have to keep doing it, when I'm her Oppa.
Da Jeong, give Oppa some water.
I'm done eating.
Thank you. Da Jeong, eat a lot.
I'm going crazy.
Seo Jae Woo.
Even like this do you still want me to be your Oppa?
Jae Woo.
Han Song Jeong!
What's this?
- What's that?
Come out Han Song Jeong!
Where is that coming from?
- I'm telling you to come out!
Han Song Jeong, come out!
Seo Jae Woo!
Jeong Da Jeong.
Now what should we do?
♫  When love has started, this moment I ran into you, ♫
♫ Forever in my love, a little bit,♫
♫ A very little bit, I've fallen into you, ♫
Glorious Day Preview
♫ Love is a present, ♫
Seo Jae Woo!
Just let them be!
They like each other so how could you stop them?
I'll request it of you like this. Does it make sense, my Jae Woo with Da Jeong?!
Don't you say that the children's dead father is alive,
What are you talking about right now?!
Father is alive? What is she saying?
- Da In.
Can't you like me? I will do well.
♫  My love has started, ♫