(Cole)
Previously on 12 Monkeys...
Daughters shall make from 12...
an army!
12 is not primary.
(Cole)
All this traveling through time,
- it's killing me, isn't it?
- Yes.
How many jumps
have I got left?
Not as many as I'd like.
Why are you doing this?
'Cause you're important.
He has plans for you.
- Jose, this is Sam, your son.
- Hello.
You got to stop.
I watched her die.
The mission
is all that matters now.
You're not erasing my son.
Get it through your head.
There is no future.
Your son's already dead.
_
(Dr. Adler) It's been 72 hours since we got
the new core from Spearhead.
Splinter sequence 44 Alpha
was successful.
Mr. Cole is now in 2015.
The new core is functioning
at maximum capacity.
Recalibrating tracer scan
for return.
[loud thudding and clanking]
[object clanks]
[clattering, thunking]
What are you doing
with those?
Jones needs it.
She sent you?
Yeah.
Are you lying to me,
Mr. Ramse?
Yeah.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
_
[rain falling, thunder rumbles]
I got it.
Skydiving.
I don't know.
It's kind of played.
Are you serious? Have you ever
jumped out of a plane?
They strap you to instructors.
I don't like it.
Okay.
Rock climbing?
Mm.
Hang off a 500-foot cliff
by ropes and those
little metal key chains?
Okay, they're called carabiners,
first of all.
You know that.
When did we become
such adrenaline junkies?
Filling the void.
Here we go.
- What do you think?
- Perfect.
[atmospheric music,
singing]
♪
[thunder rumbles]
[objects clatter]
♪
[loud banging]
[banging, clattering]
[door closes]
No, no, no.
No, you can't be here.
Nice to see you too.
It's not over?
No, it's not.
You're alive.
So are you.
The virus
is still out there.
12 Monkeys got their hands
on it somehow.
But we destroyed M5-10
in Chechnya.
We burned it,
all of it.
The CIA has satellite photos
that prove that.
The Night Room is destroyed.
The Remains, the origin is gone.
Leland is dead.
- We missed something.
- We? No, you.
You missed something.
(Aaron)
How is this still happening?
Because it was never
just Leland.
There's Oliver Peters.
He was at the CIA
during Operation Troy.
He gave them the virus.
We need to find him.
Langley barely
let us off the hook last time.
We can't open that up again.
- Aaron, we have to.
- Why?
Look, I know this is hard
for you to understand...
No, I get it.
The world is ending.
You're a time traveler
who doesn't know
what he's doing.
Back off.
- You got her killed.
- And then I got her back.
Yeah, how many times are you
gonna be able to do that?
How many times
does she have to die
before you figure
your shit out?
- Cole.
- You don't know, do you?
Stop it.
You're right
about one thing.
The future's pretty bleak
if you're all they got.
The fact
that he's here again...
You have no idea
how to stop this.
[coughing]
This is the last address
the CDC has on Peters.
It's not
a Markridge property.
(Cassie)
Checked.
So...
what happens now?
I don't know.
At least before, I had hope
that we could beat this.
Yeah, well, nothing stays
the same.
I went looking for you
in Chechnya.
I know you did.
What happened?
I ever tell you
about Ramse?
You grew up together
on the outside.
You're like brothers.
You look worried.
I am.
[sighs]
[sniffs]
Whoa.
[groans]
No, it's okay.
I know what that is.
The petals...
that's how I found Jeremy.
What's with our Tall Man
and flowers?
He uses them to mask
the smell of death.
(Cassie)
It's an old plague trick.
[flies buzzing]
That's not Peters.
It's his husband.
Peters is gone.
They must've gotten
to him first.
And his hard drive.
We destroyed the virus,
but not the man who made it.
[sighs]
We haven't changed anything.
[groans]
Are you okay?
[sniffs]
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Proust...
Remembrance of Things Past.
He had this with him
at the CIA.
If you have something
that you know other people want,
what do you do?
Hide it.
Peters' private journal.
- What is all that?
- Recipe for a plague.
[click]
[Blue Oyster Cult's
Don't Fear the Reaper]
♪
It's that thing
from the Night Room.
The "Annapurna Remains."
His notes say it was excavated
from the Himalayas in the '80s.
That's where the virus was born
thousands of years ago.
What's this?
It's Japanese.
Tokyo.
White Dragon.
Wexler told me
about this place.
He knew
about the 12 Monkeys.
They're connected
to this place somehow.
1987... that's the date
Leland Goines
said he met me before.
But that hasn't happened
for you yet.
No, but it will.
[scoffs]
I think this is it.
This is where it all started.
We found it.
Good for us.
Listen, this is the only
connection we have to Peters.
I need you to help me
find him, Cassie.
[chuckles]
It'll be my pleasure.
I don't think
that's helping you.
If Peters is recreating M5-10
for the 12 Monkeys,
he'll need animals
to test it on.
CDC can get a list
of suppliers,
and then I'll be able
to track him down.
Just like the Big Burn
and the Night Room.
Then splinter,
apocalypse,
rinse, repeat.
Hey, what is this?
What are you doing?
You're not supposed
to be here.
You think
I want to be?
Go.
I'll find Peters.
See you soon.
Maybe.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Do you think I haven't noticed
the nosebleeds, the headaches?
All this splintering
is killing you, isn't it?
I'm gonna be fine,
okay?
[rumbling]
[machine whirring]
[power up whine]
[breathing heavily]
I know where Leland Goines
got the origin of the virus...
Tokyo...
November 21, 1987,
a nightclub called
the White Dragon.
What is it?
How could he do this?
[groaning]
Ugh...
[thud]
James.
_
Were you followed?
A couple of scavs
a mile back.
Where are they now?
Okay...
Glad you're back.
Elena was worried.
Where is she?
- Thank God.
- Hey, you.
When Cole gets back,
they're finished.
They're not going to be
splintering anymore.
I wrecked
the place pretty good.
And I got this.
What is that?
They put it in his blood
before he goes in the machine.
Without it,
he can't go back.
They're gonna come
for that.
If they find us,
we have insurance.
But if they get that back,
they'll just try again.
They'll stop the plague,
make it so that we never meet.
Sam is never born.
Hey...
we're gonna be
long gone.
- They ain't gonna find us.
- Are you sure about that?
You have to trust me.
I'm gonna fix it.
- Okay?
- Okay.
(man) Incoming!
Southeast corner!
- Scavs.
- We got a caravan coming!
- Stay here.
- Be careful.
[man shouting orders]
That didn't take them long.
It's not them.
The Daughters.
At least that's what they call
themselves.
Nomads.
All women.
Blame men
for the apocalypse.
Hard to argue there.
[horse whinnies]
Tough crew...
surviving out in the open
all this time.
Well, it seems like
they don't know we're here.
Let's keep it that way.
(Costa)
What is it?
Nothing.
Shit.
_
Dr. Railly
with the D.C. office.
I'm looking for a list
of test-animal suppliers,
but my expertise
is in clinical virology,
not zoonosis.
Right, so the best test
subjects?
Macaques.
[chuckles]
Monkeys...
of course.
_
Your condition is worsening.
The splinter process
has deteriorated your body
further than I anticipated.
What is that thing?
It's a reconditioning system
for molecular stabilization.
It won't reverse the damage,
but it will keep you together
a while longer.
I don't need it.
Come on, let's fire up
the Beast one last time.
1987,
the White Dragon.
You will die trying.
[groans]
You find Ramse?
Do you know
where he might be?
- Maybe.
- Tell me.
- I'll send Mr. Whitley.
- It should be me.
You have to take
this treatment now.
We'll take care
of Mr. Ramse.
He's just trying to protect
Elena and his kid.
At this point, we cannot let
your friendship
stand in the way
of this mission.
Where's Ramse?
Tell me he won't get hurt.
Why would that matter
if you are successful?
Because getting Ramse killed
can't be the last thing
I do here.
You have my word.
Ramse is likely
at the old park, out west.
Half a mile north
of the highway.
I know the place.
Those injections...
it's our last supply.
We don't have any material
to make more.
But we also need
Cole's continued cooperation.
So that means Ramse...
stays alive.
That might not be so easy.
I didn't say it was easy.
You know, anything we do,
even if we undo it,
it happened nonetheless...
in God's eyes.
That sounds like Foster.
You getting
superstitious on me?
I don't think
that God's wrath
requires my belief.
What if I have to choose?
Injections or Ramse?
We need those injections.
[glass clatters]
[guns cocking]
I don't want any trouble.
I just have a few questions.
That symbol.
The face.
I know it.
It's from before.
Army of the 12 Monkeys?
Is that you?
[footsteps, wood creaking]
[woman chuckles]
12's not primary.
You feeling okay?
Well, it turns out Scotch
doesn't stop the apocalypse.
Why am I here, Cass?
I didn't know he was coming
back, Aaron.
What am I supposed to do?
Not follow him blindly.
I'm not following him blindly.
Cass, after everything
that's happened to you...
kidnapped. Killed.
Unkilled...
- That's not gonna happen again.
- It is gonna happen again.
It's gonna happen
over and over again.
Listen to me.
If Cole is right...
you and I don't have a future.
Cass.
I can do this alone,
but I don't want to.
[somber piano playing]
♪
Please don't make me.
_
[monitor beeping]
He's ready.
[grunts]
All right, let's get this
over with.
[brooding music]
♪
Brave.
Don't make them like you
anymore.
Most stay away.
Whispers.
Some come for my herb.
It gives you pictures,
you know?
Pictures in your head
you can't erase.
Hmm.
They don't work
unless the leaves are red.
And they're not red
unless he's been there.
Why don't you tell me about
the Army of the 12 Monkeys?
Monkeys?
[chuckles]
No.
No monkeys here.
Who are you?
(old Jennifer)
We're the Daughters...
of mothers and midnight.
And fathers.
It's all out of order.
But there's still time
for you and me.
- We have work to finish.
- What are you talking about?
- What work?
- All kinds.
Undo what I've done.
You've done.
What Cole's done.
- You know Cole?
- Cole.
Cole.
Eyes that see.
Poor Otter Eyes.
Can't stop the plague.
No.
Can't undo that.
You know who started it?
Yes.
No.
There's only one
who truly knows.
Sees.
Did see.
Will see.
The Witness.
How do I find him?
Tell me where Cole is
and I'll give you what you need.
Cole's gone.
I don't know where.
How do you know what I need?
[giggles]
Take it.
It's yours.
You're gonna need it
later.
You're a good friend.
Not yet.
But you will be.
Wait. There's something
you need to know.
Open up.
Today... something happens
that will change things
for you...
(man) Where's Ramse's bag?
Where does he keep his stuff?
(old Jennifer)
Not everything is preordained...
no matter how it may seem.
Hey.
- Shit!
- You can't be here.
These people have done nothing.
(old Jennifer) They say things happen
for a reason...
[scoffs]
that is a lie.
- Stop. Stop it!
- [overlapping shouting]
- [gunshot]
- Oh!
(old Jennifer) Death can be both
cause and effect.
That's how it works.
No straight lines.
You're ready.
It's time to go.
[somber music]
♪
I know what happened
to your mom.
It's not fair.
It's not right.
It's what it is.
You're not alone.
You always got me.
Always gonna protect you.
Always.
I gotta do something.
And I gotta go away
for a little bit.
Okay?
But I promise you,
I'm gonna come back.
Promise.
Take care of him.
[low pulsating
synthesized strings]
♪
It was an accident!
- I made it right!
- Really?
Is she alive again?
Those injections are essential
for this mission!
They may be essential.
But I'm not going after Ramse.
With whatever time is left,
he should be a father
to that boy.
You know, you're right
about one thing.
Someone...
someday...
will judge us
for what we've done.
_
(Cassie) All right, so the trail of 25
Pagai Island macaques
that I tracked from Sumatra
to Guam to Panama
goes cold right here.
And that matters why?
Because these particular monkeys
are perfect for viral cloning.
And it's the only shipment
of its kind
for the last two months,
Could be a coincidence,
but I doubt it.
We're looking
for one of these numbers.
[rain pattering on car roof]
Ready?
Okay.
You check out that row
of containers.
I'll start on that side,
and we'll meet in the middle.
Hey, be careful.
(man)
Hello?
Yes, I can hear you.
Dr. Peters?
(Peters)
Who is it?
It's Cassandra Railly.
(Peters)
Please, help me.
Ugh.
[exhales]
Ohh...
The virus.
Where is it?
[laughs]
It's done.
It's gone.
It... it's...
it's completed.
How?
It wasn't hard.
A simple matter
of reconstituting
from the DNA I sequenced
at Markridge.
Why would you do this?
For Jason.
They said if I didn't finish
the job, that they would...
Where are they taking
the virus?
I don't know.
They wouldn't say.
They just kept...
they kept talking about
the... the Messengers.
The 12.
- It's part of their plan.
- The 12.
Who are they, Oliver?
Tell me.
Jason's dead, isn't he?
Jason's dead.
What I know...
even if you stopped them,
I could just make it again.
I'm too dangerous alive.
Please.
[whimpering]
[gun cocking]
You need to get out of here.
Stay off main roads.
Do not try to leave
the country.
Find a hole and disappear
into it.
(Striking Woman)
Aaron Marker.
(Aaron)
Who are you?
We haven't met.
You're one of them.
I want you to listen to me.
And consider everything
I'm about to tell you.
Dr. Railly is very important.
To us and to you.
So tell me.
What are you willing to do
to keep her alive?
_
[dramatic music]
♪
Just couldn't keep away.
[body scanner whirs]
[tone]
- [clank]
- [distant buzzer]
Leave the case and go.
I can't do that.
I need to speak to Jones.
What for?
Assurance.
That you'll leave me
and my son alone.
You got what you want.
Let me talk to her.
Hands behind your head.
Look, what happened to Elena...
I'm sorry, Ramse.
[grunting]
[gunshots]
[groaning]
They told me what you did
to the guy who shot Elena.
I know it wasn't your fault.
[beeping]
_
- _
- [klaxon blaring]
Whitley.
Whitley, come in.
(man)
Move, move, move!
Down to the gate!
Double quick!
Adler, we have to revive him.
I'm going to start
the splinter process.
We have to send him back
to 1987 now.
Do not let him get involved.
Max, what's going on?
You're gonna be okay.
Mr. Cole, the effects
have not worn off yet.
Cole, I will go check it out.
Bring the core to full power.
We'll have to augment every
conduit for a jump this far.
Input coordinates.
Double check. There's no margin
for error here.
I want all the exits sealed.
- [gunshot]
- Oh!
[thud]
[panicked whispering]
(Ramse)
Get away from the control.
Now!
[gunshot]
- Ooh!
- [thud]
You thought you had everybody
fooled, huh?
Huh?
This is all over.
It ends today.
[beeping]
Move.
Ramse, it's me.
Leave!
Now!
I can't do that.
What do you mean you can't?
Ramse, I want the same thing
you do.
A better life, okay?
For all of us.
She took Elena from me.
I'm not gonna let you take
my son.
She succeeds in this mission,
he's gone.
Maybe he'll have
a better future.
I'm his father.
"Maybe"... not good enough!
Tell me, Mr. Ramse.
The love that you feel
for your son,
can you imagine that
a thousand fold?
A billion.
Just think of the loss
across the world
that hit parent after parent.
Hannah.
That's your little girl.
The plague took her from you.
That's what this is for you.
The plague happened.
My son is the future.
Your daughter, she's the past.
Do it.
Ramse, don't.
[gunshot]
[groans]
[gunshots and ricochets]
Mr. Cole.
[gunfire and ricochets continue]
[alarm buzzing]
Shit!
Soldiers will be here soon.
There's nowhere to go.
Give up, Mr. Ramse.
I promised my son
I'd always protect him.
I can't do it now.
I'll do it then.
[grunts]
[softly groaning]
Max.
Ramse.
Don't let him go.
Hey.
Hey...
[grunts, breathing hard]
You.
(Ramse)
You wanna live?
Send me back.
(Jones)
No! Don't!
Ramse!
[groans]
Uhh...
[music]
You really think Peters will be
able to outrun the 12 Monkeys?
He's a genius.
He'll figure it out.
Maybe you should have left
the gun with him.
Let him do it.
It's too late to stop him
from making the virus.
That damage is done.
I think that's enough.
Okay.
But he's not innocent.
He thought he was saving
his husband.
But he still made a choice.
And I get it.
You do?
Helping to destroy the world
to save just one person?
One person that you love.
In the end,
isn't that all that matters?
No.
Where is he?
Your jump to 1987
was pre-programmed.
But with the serum
so freshly administered,
it's very difficult to say
where he might've landed.
Why can't you just
bring him back?
He was never synchronized.
We have no tracer signal.
His trip was one way.
[teeth chattering]
You all right?
Yeah.
This treatment was a temporary
solution for your condition.
It just gives us one more jump.
James...
we are out of time.
1987 is the endgame.
You must find the source
of the plague
and you must eliminate it.
James...
if Mr. Ramse survives the jump,
he's going to try and stop you.
And when he does,
I'm gonna kill him.
_
[rumbling]
Ah!
[panicked breathing]
[yelling]
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com