THE SOFT SKIN
CROSSING
I just called your office.
The subway broke down, not a cab in sight.
- Hello, Odile.
- Hello, Pierre.
- What's your departure time?
- I've got 40 minutes.
In this traffic? Never!
- I must try it, Franca.
- I've packed your suitcase.
- Hello, Daddy!
- Hello, princess.
- Will you take the car?
- If you come along to park it.
Only if you do the driving.
I make you too nervous.
It's my husband.
- It's a tie rack.
- Stop kidding.
What's up?
Pierre's late. He's lecturing in Lisbon.
- I can drive you.
- Franca will do it.
Go ahead, you're a much better driver.
That's right, he is.
Bye, princess.
Bye, Daddy.
Be good now.
Can I ride to the airport?
You know you can't.
Why not? She'll enjoy it.
Okay, you can come.
Mademoiselle,
would you get Sabine's coat, please?
Call to tell me where you are staying.
Here's an article about you.
I'll read it later.
Please be careful.
He can always catch another plane.
- What's the time?
- It's 3:45.
We'll never make it.
Is your talk on Stendhal?
No, on Balzac.
There's a speed limit, but what the hell.
A cop! If he's after us, we're sunk.
You just leave it to me.
Bye, Michel. Thanks.
- Porter?
- No thanks.
The Lisbon plane, can I still make it?
I'm not sure...
Mr Lachenay for the Lisbon flight?
Let me check.
They might have taken the ladder away.
Check in Mr Lachenay's luggage.
This way, please. Let's hurry.
They're taking the ladder away.
No, it's going back.
Let's hurry.
Quick, the door!
Please fasten your seat belt,
and no smoking. Thank you.
Seats forward, please.
Will you wait here, please?
We can go now.
A photo with the stewardess, please.
This way, Mr Lachenay.
Here's the bathroom.
Fine.
Perfect.
For you.
BALZAC AND MONEY
Why Balzac and money?
Well, I'm a fan of Balzac's
and I don't despise money.
But all joking aside, that happens to be
the title of one of my books.
How about a book on Balzac and love?
Why not?
There's a full house.
We'll need some extra seats.
- What's Ionesco up to?
- He's doing fine.
- We'd better go now.
- I'm ready.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
As soon as I am through
with the introduction...
I know what to do. See you later.
Ladies and gentlemen...
We've got a small problem
with the microphone.
I present you Pierre Lachenay.
How about lunch tomorrow?
Sorry, I leave at noon.
What a pity.
Look, it's Pierre Lachenay.
We hope to see you in Paris very soon.
Goodbye.
Here's where I get off.
I'll call you.
Yes, tomorrow.
I forgot to ask you your floor...
That's quite all right.
I'm sorry.
Thank you, sir.
Would you ring room 813?
Hold on.
Hello, room 813?
Miss, I was in the elevator with you...
I wanted to apologise...
Apologise for what?
You got off at the 8th floor...
Of course.
Well, since I'd past my floor anyway,
and you had so many packages,
I should have helped you with them.
Not at all. That's perfectly all right.
Well, forgive me.
Look, I wonder...
Could we have a drink together?
Right now?
Yes, right now.
Do you know what time it is?
Oh, it's past 1 a.m.
And the bar's closed.
Then, could we have a drink tomorrow?
There's really no point, you know.
I see. I'm very sorry...
Good night. Please excuse me.
Look, I didn't mean to be so rude.
It was very kind of you to call me.
Let's have that drink together.
Fine. In the morning?
No, I've got to go shopping.
Can we make it in the afternoon?
Yes, of course.
In the bar at 6:00?
All right.
- Good night.
- You too.
Do you enjoy your work,
or do you dislike it?
I like my job.
I started a year ago.
They said I'd soon be fed up.
Maybe.
Many girls do quit after a few years.
What happens to them?
They get married.
I love my parents...
They live in Bordeaux.
That's where I'm from.
Papa used to say it's a job for a snob,
but now he doesn't mind.
- Don't you know her?
- Yes, I do.
They're friends of mine.
That's Frank.
He's the co-pilot of the plane you came on.
We almost met six months ago.
What do you mean?
I knew a TV writer
who worked with Louise de Vilmorin.
She had us to dinner once.
You were expected.
We waited, but you never showed up.
I just couldn't help it.
I haven't read all of your books.
In fact, I haven't read any.
But I've seen you on television.
So, at the airport, I recognised you.
So Balzac decides
to put out a novel a month.
Not slim ones, mind you, but huge volumes.
He writes a chapter a day.
He can't live on what the publishers pay him,
so he buys his own printing plant.
But business is bad,
and his partners pull out.
He decides to do it all by himself,
casting his own type,
setting it himself,
even making his own paper.
But he loses everything,
including Madame de Berny's money.
Wasn't she his mistress?
Yes. I'll tell you how that came to pass.
Madame de Balzac wants
a wife for her son, Honoré.
Madame de Berny
has two daughters to marry off.
Honoré meets the two young girls,
who leave him cold.
But he falls in love with the mother.
That's marvellous!
I've been talking for hours.
It was fascinating!
I'll lend you some books, if you'd like.
I didn't realise it was getting so late!
Look how kind these folks are.
In France, the boss would have
put us out hours ago.
I'll ask for the bill.
It must be daylight by now.
Coming, Madame.
Matches?
- Surprised?
- A little.
It was easy.
I called your secretary,
then your Lisbon hotel,
checked with the airport, and here I am!
Michel and Odile are coming over later.
I knew you'd be tired
but it was only possible today.
They are going to Japan.
How does one turn off this heater?
I guess we can turn that off.
- I hate sports programs.
- So do I.
The other day,
on the way back from the airport,
my car broke down on Saint-Denis Street.
What were you doing there?
Tell us all about it.
Not Saint-Martin, Saint-Denis.
I was just going to the Japanese art shop.
To buy some prints, I suppose.
You guessed right.
I meant to ask you...
- Ice cream?
- Yes, please.
Where you stay in Tokyo?
The Takanawa Hotel is pretty good.
- Listen.
- What is it?
That's Sabine.
I'll go this time.
Is it your first trip to Japan?
No, I already went there two years ago.
As soon as you put a cigarette
in your mouth, a woman lights it up.
What are you doing?
I'm looking for my book.
It's late. You should be fast asleep.
I have slept.
Yes, but not enough.
Back to bed, now.
Here.
And here.
That's enough, now.
I'm closing the door.
Open it more.
Is that enough?
A bit more.
No more than this.
They're going.
You might at least say goodbye.
So you're off to Tokyo?
Not yet. They are leaving next month.
See you at Suzanne's tomorrow.
Let's go together.
We'll see. I'll call you.
I can rely on you to call.
Have a good trip back.
Goodbye.
Were you bored?
No, I like them.
They're nice.
By the way, Kanayan called. He's furious.
Again?
What is it this time?
It seems that in the latest edition,
his article was put in last place.
He said, "I know it's petty",
"but as I'm from an underdeveloped country,"
"I've got a terrible inferiority complex."
I felt like quoting that joke...
"That's no complex, my dear,
you're really inferior!"
But that would be going too far.
Once you know him, he's really a nice guy.
Pierre LACHENAY, President
5th floor, left
- What about that call?
- The line's busy.
Can we do the mail now?
If you like.
For Mr Kanayan, 17 Street so-and-so.
My dear Kanayan.
You're decision to stop writing for us
is due to a misunderstanding...
No. I'll lunch with him instead.
- And the other letters?
- Later.
What about the calls?
I'll take these if they call back.
So I'm not calling anyone?
No one else.
And your appointment?
Yes, I remember.
- I'm going out.
- And your appointment?
I'll be right back.
When you called, I was on my way out.
When's a good time?
It's hard to say. My hours are so crazy.
I lose many friends that way.
People invite me, but they are never sure
I'll turn up, so they stop asking me.
Well, I'll never stop.
I'll always be there whenever you need me.
God, it's windy!
Do you have to go to the gym?
It's part of the refresher course.
What's that?
We practise first aid, safety drills
and how to handle lifeboats.
It's late, I must run.
- Guess what I've got!
- Something for me?
It's a record.
A little girl singing?
No, something nicer.
Haydn's Toy Symphony.
You hear toys and birds calls in the music.
Wait and listen.
It's lovely.
Where's the paper that was here?
I didn't touch it.
It's not here and I need it!
Let's see if it's up there.
It had a book review I meant to keep.
I'm sure it's around.
Here it is.
This isn't the one, God damn it!
Calm down.
Our news dealer can get it for you.
I want it right now!
Is that so?
Well, get your lousy paper yourself!
I love you.
Ever since knowing you,
I've become a new man,
one who cannot conceive
of living without you. I love you.
Are you coming or going?
We take off in half an hour.
I'm taking the bus. Are you coming with me?
Catherine, please, I've got to see someone.
All right, bye.
You're still here?
I saw a plane take off
and assumed you were on it.
Lots of planes take off from here, you know.
They're changing a wheel,
so we're delayed.
Are you asleep?
You're mean!
I'm sorry I carried on so about that paper.
It wasn't that urgent.
Besides, I found it 10 minutes later.
Let's go away for a few days.
We haven't been alone together for years.
Sabine could stay with Odile.
What do you think?
A few days in the country?
Maybe. We'll see.
Hello, Mr Lachenay.
How is Madame Lachenay?
She's fine.
The menu.
- Did you wait for me yesterday?
- Yes, you were late.
What happened?
A snowstorm in Frankfurt. I'm sorry.
Next time we're held up, I could cable you.
Or call my office.
What about your secretary?
It doesn't matter.
I didn't expect you.
Glad?
Yes, I was feeling blue.
Here's a present.
You can use it to make notes
during your lectures.
Thank you.
I'm most pleased.
Can I sleep at your place?
I'm not expected home.
Look, I hate to say no,
but I'm scared
of the concierge.
Besides, the landlady's
an old friend of my parents.
No one's ever spent the night there.
We can't.
Don't be angry.
I want to stay with you, too.
I understand.
Why don't we sleep some place else?
All right. First, I'll pick up a dress.
Then, a nice restaurant.
A place where we can dance?
Choose a place.
I warn you, I don't dance.
I never learned how.
Even when you were... I mean...
Yes, even when I was young.
That made it hard to find a wife.
Don't be silly!
Go ahead, dance.
What will you do?
I'll just look at you.
That will be my pleasure.
LUXURY STUDIOS
OPEN 24 HOURS A DAY
- A room please.
- No reservation?
Sorry, not now.
You can go upstairs.
But I'll have a room in 15 minutes.
Can you wait?
Fifteen minutes?
Please, Pierre, let's go.
Of course.
Disappointed?
No, I felt the same way.
I'd no idea it would be so sordid.
We need a place of our own.
I'll take you home.
- I'm off now.
- One more kiss.
Listen.
We'll be careful. Come on up.
Come.
I'll go first.
It's too risky.
You'd be worried.
There's another way. When do you leave?
In two days. I'll be back Monday.
Next week, I've got a lecture in Reims.
You'll come along.
We'll have two whole days on our own.
That'll be wonderful.
Paris is no good for us.
Yes, you're right.
Think of me.
Where are you going now?
Home.
I'll tell my wife I just got back.
I don't want you to go there.
What's the matter?
Just looking at your blue jeans.
You disapprove?
Well, I prefer you in dresses.
Did you bring any?
Of course.
Great.
We need gas.
Here?
Fill it up, please.
50 francs.
Look at your picture!
Are you giving a lecture in Reims?
No, I'm to present a film Allégret
made before Andre Gide's death.
I accepted only so that we can have
two days together.
Look up the hotels in Reims.
The Grand Hotel's the best.
The sponsors will be at that one.
What's next?
Next, The Lion d'Or.
That might be risky too.
The Michelet just has rooms.
We can eat out. Where is it?
It's Place Michelet in Reims.
A room for two.
Did you make a reservation?
Number 12 is a double.
Does it have a bathroom? We'll take it.
Any luggage? I'll show you the way.
Excuse me, Madame. I'll go first.
It's very quiet here.
Thank you. That's for you.
A nice little room. Michelet's a good name.
I'd better unpack and bathe.
There goes my last pair!
I'd better run over
and let them know I'm here.
I won't be long.
I need stockings and a ticket for tonight.
Don't forget my stockings!
- Hello, sir. Any luggage?
- No luggage.
- Your suite is all ready.
- No need, I can't stay.
We'll take care of your luggage.
- Do you want to rest?
- I'm not staying.
- How are you, old man?
- Fine and you?
Want to freshen up first?
I'm all right.
When I invited you, I was sure you'd refuse.
But they know we're friends, so I had to try.
Is your wife here?
She's in Paris.
Give her my best.
Let me introduce you.
Father Cote, our welfare chairman.
Pleased to meet you.
Mr Bertrand, our theatre manager.
Madame Leloix's in charge of...
Cultural exchanges.
Tonight's affair.
Our cultural director and his wife.
Why the dinner?
Didn't you know?
Out here we squeeze a celebrity dry,
like a lemon.
I must get my car fixed.
- Will you be long?
- Five minutes!
Okay, I'll keep them busy with the canapés.
Hurry back!
Don't forget my stockings...
Zibeline...
NEAMAT STOCKINGS
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry, we're closing.
I'd like to buy some stockings.
I bought you two pairs.
There are complications... A dinner for me.
Then I'll eat next door, but stay a while.
Impossible. They're all waiting for me.
All right, never mind.
You understand, don't you?
See you later.
My ticket!
Just buy one at the theatre.
Which one?
- The Capitol, I think.
- But where is it?
Ask the hotel people.
I wonder why I'm here.
- You brought it back?
- They're too busy.
I swear that if it were me... Come on.
You're at the head of the table,
a lady on each side.
Are you married?
I am.
Why isn't your wife with you?
My wife's home.
Oysters or potage, take your choice.
Do you know Reims?
Any children?
A real interview!
I'll answer you one by one.
I have a child.
I've never been here.
And you're leaving tonight?
What about the smile of Reims?
Only André Gide could get me
back to the movies.
Last time was to see Charlie Chaplin.
To fix a clock,
he opened it with a can-opener.
I first saw the sea at Paramount.
Last month, we had Daninos.
You know him?
Not personally. How was it?
It was awful!
Everyone was late, it rained,
and my dress was a disaster.
- Was it the colour?
- No.
It made me look terribly fat.
The affair was a real disaster!
Don't worry if our public seems cold,
we never applaud.
Did you know Gide?
- He sells books.
- I also happen to admire Gide.
I met him twice,
the second time, shortly before his death.
Tell us about it.
I'd rather save it for my speech
so as not to repeat myself.
As you like.
A young lady to see you, sir.
Are you sure?
I'm sorry to bother you,
but since I can't stay for your talk,
would you autograph this book for me?
Of course.
My name's Christiane Duchant.
With a that's right.
Thank you very much.
He doesn't let anyone walk over him.
Next year, it'll take us 72
minutes to go to Paris by train.
Excuse me.
I must check the box-office.
Thank you for coming, Mr Lachenay.
Thanks to you, we're sold out.
A rare event in this movie crisis!
Forgive me if I'm blunt,
but I'm a businessman.
Tonight's big turnout isn't for Gide,
it's for you!
They've seen you on TV.
Time to go.
This way.
Take this.
I must leave you now to check the hall.
See you later at the reception.
I'm sorry, I can't stay for it.
I must be back in Paris tonight.
What a pity. Thanks again for coming.
And good luck!
Put your coat down.
I make a quick announcement.
We turn the lights on.
Then you walk on.
We shake hands. Then you're on your own!
All right.
Shall I go?
The friendship of a great man is a godsend.
There's no need
to introduce Pierre Lachenay.
But I'd like to thank him
for coming here tonight.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I've learned that men's unhappiness arises
from the inability
to stay quietly in their own room.
Had I recalled this a few hours ago,
I wouldn't be here now. Frankly,
I'm rather nervous.
I'm not a cinema expert,
but I had the great pleasure
to meet Andre Gide twice.
One ticket please.
No more seats.
- The balcony?
- We're all sold out.
Can I stand inside if I pay?
That's impossible.
- Really?
- Absolutely. I'm sorry.
This lady insists on going in.
All seats were sold out in advance.
You can close up now.
Everybody has read or held a book
from the famous Pléiade collection
which publishes the entire work
of an author in one tome.
Gide got the idea for this collection
by reading the Bible.
He said, "My dear Lachenay",
"our talk today will help you read my books."
"Am I the man required?"
I reassured Andre Gide.
But time flies... In conclusion,
I should like to read
a few of Gide's final words.
"I offer no doctrine,"
"I refuse to give advice"
"and I shy away from discussions."
"But I know that many today are searching"
"for someone to believe in."
"To them, I say,"
"trust those who seek the truth,"
"beware of those who've found it,
question everything,"
"but believe in yourself."
And now, Marc Allégret's film.
Great speech!
- You think so?
- Really. It was perfect.
Listen, in playing this,
your fist concern is to generate emotion...
Our friend Gide is great.
- He looks like a wrestler.
- True.
Not merely your own,
but for others as well.
Now, do it again.
No, just from this part on.
Do you want to see the rest?
Not really.
Let's have a drink.
Can you imagine me a provincial...
buried out here?
But I've kept my studio in Paris.
Did you forget something?
Let's go.
You talked but I'm thirsty.
Bertrand should have a bar in his theatre...
- Let me pass.
- Don't run away like this.
But he won't listen to me.
After 9:00,
it's tough to get a drink around here.
There was a place, but it's closed now.
The owner had a fight with the cops.
Do you want one?
Nothing doing out here,
but inside those walls, who knows?
You remember that girl,
the recluse of Poitiers?
I think there's a place nearby.
I've been there once, a month ago.
Shall we go in?
Friends first.
What do you want? I'll have a beer.
Two draught beers.
It'll limit the damage.
The film runs over an hour.
Cigarette?
What's wrong?
Too hot in here.
You seem upset.
Clément, let's get out of here.
You do look awful.
Can I finish your beer?
Let's go back to the hotel.
A little nap will do you good.
You'll be peaceful in your room.
Those jerks would demoralize anyone.
Getting you here
is like throwing pearls to swine!
Your speech was really great and I mean it.
In fact, all your work is first-rate.
All they do here is eat!
Lachenay in Reims? Presto, a dinner!
They eat their heads off for free!
That's why they go for culture.
Damn that shoelace.
I'll try and fix it. It's
the second time tonight.
To every man, his own woes.
Mine's shoelaces.
I hate them, so I always wear moccasins.
But I put my best shoes on, in your honour,
and they're killing me!
You might say I'm caught in a pinch!
Remember Lachere's wedding?
At noon, the bride hadn't even turned up.
What are you doing here?
That's a good question.
Forgive me, I've got to shake that pest.
I won't be long.
I couldn't figure out where you'd gone.
You vanished into thin air,
like a flying saucer.
To quote the defeated general,
"I searched high and low and all around me,"
"at a loss to know
what happened to my army."
God, you look awful!
This town shuts down at 9 p.m.
In Spain and Italy,
people stay out half the night.
In France, we're so stingy,
we go to bed early just to save electricity.
You look really tired.
You'd better have a nap at the hotel.
I'll pick you up for the reception.
I'm not staying for it.
Do they know?
They'll be sore as hell.
Not at all. I told them about it.
I didn't know that.
In that case, I don't have to go either.
- Are you driving to Paris?
- Right now.
Great! Take me along.
- To Paris?
- Yes, I'll go with you.
All right.
Is your car here?
I'll get my bag, wait here.
And bye-bye everyone!
Only be a minute!
Get dressed. Let's get out of here.
This town is getting on my nerves.
We're leaving!
Nicole, did you hear me?
Go if you want to. I'll stay.
What do you mean?
I mean I'm fed up.
Don't you want to go?
Go yourself!
I'll take a train to Paris in the morning.
Just leave me alone.
Go away!
I didn't ask to come. It
was entirely your idea.
And then you're ashamed of me.
It was all so humiliating.
That creep trying to pick
me up in the street.
I felt humiliated too.
But what could I do? I was trapped.
It's been a real nightmare.
Please forgive me, my darling.
You want us to stay here tonight?
No, let's leave right away.
I'll run down to pay the bill.
The bill, please.
Right now? They're all asleep.
I can't do bills. Wait till morning.
Sorry, but I must leave now.
I'll help you with the bill.
We'll work it out.
How much for the room?
40 francs.
Add a few extras... That's about 80 Francs.
Here's 120!
Anyway, you've got my address.
Let me carry your bags.
Never mind. We'll manage.
Damn it, we have to pass the Grand Hotel.
See that guy?
With the tan coat?
God!
He says, "I'll go too!"
What did you do?
I was stunned, but when he went inside,
I ran off like a thief.
Crazy, isn't it?
Forgive me.
Sacha Guitry said,
"When they yawn,"
"it's time to say bye-bye."
- Is the Colinière good?
- According to the guide, yes.
They say it's a nice inn
with separate cabins.
That's right, come closer, darling.
Go to sleep.
Forgive me.
Here's the bathroom.
Do you need anything?
No, thank you.
You asleep?
You're tired.
When my brother bet
he'd shave his head with his electric razor,
Papa told him not to come back
till his hair grew in.
So he left home.
And why did you leave?
To take the airline job.
- How'd you get it?
- By passing a test.
I know a little Spanish,
I studied English in London.
Well, nearby. For a year.
- Any friends there?
- Not at first.
I was homesick,
but my parents made me stay.
- Later, I made friends.
- Why couldn't you go home?
In Bordeaux, I'd had a crush on a boy
and my parents wanted me to forget him.
Was he your first?
No, the first was in London.
An Englishman?
No, a Frenchman.
Did you love him?
No, it was silly, it didn't last.
And after him?
Two or three. They didn't mean anything.
I was too young, I guess.
But the first time it mattered physically
was last year.
I didn't want him, but he was always around.
Finally, he almost raped me.
It's strange. He thrilled me,
yet, I didn't love him.
It didn't last very long.
I felt squeamish, as if I'd been soiled.
When I got home, I'd take a bath.
It was ridiculous.
I even hated the clothes he'd touched.
What did he do for work?
Gosh, this is heavy!
Is he in aviation?
Yes, a pilot. You've met Frank.
I knew it!
I sensed it before our dinner in Lisbon.
And when we met?
There was no one.
And Frank?
I broke off with Frank months ago.
- Others?
- No one at all.
I like to make love,
yet I can go without for months.
Do you mind me talking about it?
Are you sure?
I don't really know Frank,
but I hate his type.
What do you mean?
He's too sure of himself.
Not really,
but I don't care enough to defend him.
Anyway, why talk about Frank?
Wait!
In profile.
Look at me.
One more.
I don't like your legs like that.
Don't cross them.
Let me show you.
Like this.
There.
My legs hurt!
One more with the automatic shutter.
Now, you and me together.
See, I'm lucky at games.
Have you always been
so interested in women?
Funny, it's only since I've known you.
I must be stimulating.
Where do you go in summer?
My kids love Brittany.
The cleaner can get it out.
Look, Pierre.
See that woman?
I used to be a blonde, real cute!
You don't believe me?
Now, look there.
What do you see?
The same blouse.
Right.
Leopard skin.
Women who wear them like making love.
There's something wrong. What is it?
Nothing.
I know you. I can tell you're worried.
Something I did?
Something I said?
It's awkward...
I know, you've got to call your wife.
That's it.
Couldn't you just say so?
I'll be outside.
Tell me when you're finished.
Connect me with Passy 42-70.
You're all right, Franca?
Yes, and you?
I'm fine, but something came up.
They wanted a repeat performance
so I had to stay over. I'll be home tonight.
You calling from Reims?
Yes, Reims.
Really? I called Reims two nights ago
and was told you'd just left for Paris.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Do you love me?
Yes.
Why won't you say it?
Because you don't like to spell it out,
is that it?
That's it exactly.
Don't forget me.
I know you were with a girl.
Answer me.
Kanayan told me his article
wouldn't be ready in time.
So I called the hotel in Reims,
you'd left the night before.
You were driving, I became frantic.
As if you care!
How could you treat me that way?
Listen, Franca.
Was that asking too much,
a few days with you?
We could have gone off
right after the lecture.
I've waited for five years.
You exaggerate!
No, I've counted them.
I was upset. I needed to be alone.
If you'd only said that to me.
You'd never understand it!
Not so loud.
Sabine never wakes up.
Maybe not, but the nurse is here.
After all, I might want to go out.
I need some fun too!
Franca, I'm tired.
So am I, but it's high time we talked.
Say something!
If I'm wrong, say so.
I'm not up to talking just now.
If there was a woman, tell me.
It would hurt far less if I knew.
- I was alone!
- I don't believe you.
I don't care!
Thanks a lot!
You expect me to be kind? In what way?
Be considerate.
What for? You're not sick.
Yes, thanks to you, I am sick!
I haven't slept in two nights.
Pierre, maybe we should separate.
I'm serious.
All right, I'll go.
I didn't mean all that.
I'm upset. I was nasty.
Look, I propose we try an experiment.
No fighting for a month.
After that we decide.
We've experimented for years.
I won't forgive this.
Hello, Dominique.
Yes, I slept here.
- How did you get your flat?
- The Chaude Agency.
Better call them, I've got to find a flat.
I'm going out for coffee.
Madame Lachenay.
I'll take it in there.
Did you sleep well?
Well, I was up all night.
This is just to thank you
for walking out on me.
I'd forgive anything but that.
Odile's cousin will act as my lawyer.
- As what?
- My divorce lawyer!
I suggest you get someone too.
Why waste time?
I won't be alone long.
Your bags are all packed.
Pick them up any time.
I called your office, but you'd gone.
You can't stay. My father's in town.
He's on his way here.
And I'll be away till Friday.
Let's have dinner Friday.
I've got important news.
Important? Tell me now.
No, you're rushed and this takes time.
Come on,
you tell me you've got big news
and now you won't talk. Tell me.
Nothing doing!
Just tell me if it's something pleasant.
I'm not sure. But it is
serious and important.
What is it?
I meant to explain it properly.
It's just this...
My wife and I are separating
by mutual agreement.
Listen,
there's my dad, you'd better run.
See you Friday.
We won't meet at the airport, but here.
All right.
Excuse me, sir.
- Hello, daddy!
- Hello, darling.
I'm almost ready.
See, I walk like a lady.
My lawyer's waiting to hear from yours.
It's not that urgent.
Yes, it is. I don't like
ambiguous situations.
We can't talk here.
Then let's go to the study.
Sit down.
I'd rather stand.
I'm taking this one.
That one too.
Your bags are ready, they're in the hall.
I didn't know where to send them.
Where do you live?
I sleep in the office.
I plan to take a flat.
You fool!
- Listen Franca!
- I won't listen.
What got into you? Weren't you happy here?
- What's got into you?
- Not in front of the girl.
Now he thinks about her.
Go play with Mademoiselle.
Sabine, go and see Mademoiselle.
Come here, Sabine!
Kanayan called.
I gave him the office number. You were out,
so he rang here.
I told him you weren't living here any more.
What else could I tell him?
The truth. We decided to separate.
We decided to separate!
You'd like me to say that.
Don't count on it.
I'll say that you left me.
Isn't it true? You were fed up?
Calm down, Franca.
You're a louse!
Forgive me, Pierre.
I didn't mean to do that, but I'm so tired.
Come here, sit by me.
I'm sorry for all I said.
You must loathe me.
No Franca, I loathe myself.
Kiss me.
We'll play in your room.
This will go to the cleaner.
I'm taking her out.
Bye, darling.
Bye-bye, daddy.
Come on, we're leaving.
They probably forgot something.
I'd better come back later.
No, stay here. Anyway, Pierre's leaving.
I must be going.
Call me tonight. I'd like that.
Really?
You got some Champagne from Reims.
Just keep it in the cellar.
Here's the Foujita.
What for? I gave it to you.
Take it back.
I don't want it, it's yours. Keep it.
Want to come back for supper, or to sleep,
or just for supper?
It won't work, you know,
with all that's happened.
I'm sorry, Odile.
I can't go with you, I don't feel well.
What a fool I am!
I should have known better.
What's Pierre done to you?
What did he want?
That's what he wanted!
Top luxury apartment block
Ready for AUTUMN 64
Franca, you've got to calm down.
You need some sleep.
Let me have a sleeping pill?
You said you'd be right down.
I'd better stay.
Franca's very upset over Pierre.
I'm afraid she might do something foolish.
In the plane today, we ran into a storm.
One of the passengers,
an American, was scared.
He drank so much whisky,
he went berserk.
He drove us all crazy, it was real wild!
Don't talk so loud, people are staring.
You're charming tonight.
Did your dad enjoy Paris?
Did he have a good time?
I don't know.
I'm tired. Please take me home.
Why? The programme starts in 10 minutes.
Take me home.
You were so eager to come here.
Well, now I'm tired. I leave tomorrow.
Mad at me?
You're sure?
Positive.
I wasn't very good company, I know,
but you must understand,
I've had a pretty rough week.
Franca, the separation...
I thought you both wanted this separation.
Yes, of course,
but it's not so easy after 15 years.
You told her about me?
No. I thought the later, the better.
I don't agree.
If it was me, I'd prefer the
truth even if it's another girl.
You know the score.
I didn't see it that way.
Speaking as a man,
I tell you, it's a mistake.
You may be right.
I'll tell her, but it won't be easy.
You see, it's been hard on me too,
harder than I thought.
We're used to each other,
and there's Sabine.
I'll miss seeing her every day.
If that's how it is, you sure goofed!
You can give Sabine
some calves liver for lunch...
I'll get the door!
And some mashed potatoes.
The suit from the cleaner's.
Hold on.
We found this stub in the pocket.
Thank you.
PHOTO ENLARGEMENT
This is the living room.
There, my study and the library.
That will be our room,
with Sabine's next to it
for when she visits us.
I'll get an extra room for the nanny.
So you want to marry me?
If I say yes, you'll talk to my father.
Is that it?
Listen to me,
I've discovered some facts of life lately.
There's a misunderstanding.
When you looked me up in Paris,
I was pleased because
I thought you might misjudge me
after what happened in Lisbon.
On the way here, I guessed...
But now that it's out, I've got to speak up.
It's just as well you brought it to a head...
it was all happening too quickly.
Because it just would have dragged on
to wind up the same way.
What's the point?
In the restaurant last night,
I irritated you, I could tell.
You almost hated me.
It's true.
To plan a wedding when you reach
that point, it makes no sense!
I know you're hurt. I feel bad, too.
If you'd like, we could
meet from time to time.
I'm truly sorry.
Bye, Pierre.
- How much is it?
- 14 francs.
Need some help?
How about a little walk?
Why hurry home?
We can go to a café or up to my place.
Who the hell are you?
What are you after?
Do all women go for you?
You take them to the country?
Irresistible, a Don Juan...
God's gift to women?
Ever take a good look at yourself?
Come and have a look.
- Look again!
- Leave me alone!
Take Sabine to Madame Odile's.
Look Mummy, I've finished it all off!
After her homework?
No, right after she eats.
And the homework?
She'll do it at Madame Odile's.
All right, Madame.
A token, please.
Odile?
I want to thank you for everything.
I'm off for a rest tomorrow.
Ask Franca, can I see Sabine before I go?
As you wish, Pierre. But it's such a mess.
What can I do about it now?
It's too late.
Since you'll be seeing her,
would you let me know?
Let you know what?
If you can still change your mind?
If you really want to go back to Franca,
I'm sure she'd agree if you ask her yourself.
You may be right, Odile.
I'll do it next week.
Why? The sooner the better.
Call her right now.
Now?
I'd rather wait awhile.
What for?
Do you think she'll sit around for 10 years?
Pierre, I beg you, don't put it off.
You're probably right.
I guess I'll do that.
- Another token, please.
- One more?
That's right.
I'm going out.
Will you lunch here?
No, I'm not eating here.
Madame Lachenay's place.
Is this you, Mademoiselle?
- My wife, please.
- She just this minute went out.
Look in the hall.
Hold on, sir. I'll see.
No, she's left the house.
Then she's in the street.
Call her from the window.
I'll have a look.
I'm sorry, but her car just pulled out.
Any message?
Tell her that I phoned and
will call back later.
I'll tell her, sir.
That's all.
Call the police!