l wanted to talk to you!
Steam Series
Noboribetsu
Hot Spring
l wanted to talk to you!
Steam Series
Noboribetsu
Hot Spring
The Anxious Clown
''Homesickness''
Advance Ticket
The Anxious Clown
''Homesickness''
Advance Ticket
l wanted to see you!
Yashaou
ToShoko
l wanted to see you!
Think about what you do for a living.
What?!
Username :
Is she getting married?!
Sure dropped a bombshell there !
Think about what you do for a living.
lt's the same thing, isn't it?
You only talk into a microphone, don't you?
La, la, la, hop
Soshite step
Kita e jump
And jump
And jump, jump
Kokoro tokasu kita no sora ni
Hana to kibou to koi wo dakishimete
lchigoichie deai no haru
Mabayui dekigoto, kimi ga soko ni iru
Aoi sora
Hiroi sora
Dokomademo tsuzuku
Kanashii toki wa kita e
Kirei na kuuki suou
Oishii mono wo tabeyou
Egao ni naru yo
La, la, la, hop
Soshite step
Kita e jump
And jump
And jump, jump
-Sapporo
Shoko Saibara
Part 2
Yeah, l promise, l do.
On your birthday, l'll take you wherever
you want to go, Natsuko.
Good morning!
Morning...
ToShoko
Steam Series
Noboribetsu
Hot Spring
CHHEER U P
RADLO BOY
By the way, my favorite bath powder is
''Noboribetsu Hot Spring,''
from Kumaya Penguin-do's Steam Series!
RADLO BOY
Miss Shoko! l got some Sapporo Garden
pastrami sandwiches for you!
l don't have to make any excuses today!
Wait! Miss Shoko?
Next up is our Family Financial Advice segment.
What's up? You sure are scowling.
CHHEER UP
RADIO BOY
Oh, it's nothing. Good morning!
CHHEER UP
RADIO BOY
CHHEER U P
RADLO BOY
What's gotten into you, Miss Shoko?
Look! l got you one! A pastrami sandwich!
l'm sorry. l'm not hungry right now.
Hey, what's this?
''Noboribetsu Hot Spring?''
Shoko, is this yours?
Steam Series
Noboribetsu
Hot Spring
Believe it or not, this really works!
You have reached a voice messaging service.
The person you are trying to reach is
not available to take your call.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Hello? lt's me, Shoko.
l think someone's stalking me.
l'm scared...
Let's see, l got this one via email.
Pen name ''Yamada Camera...''
''l'm really fat. The truth is, l'm five feet tall
but l weigh 187 pounds.''
''l've tried all kinds of diets, but...''
Well, if you want to lose weight,
you have to exercise and eat right.
Oh, and l've heard you should put plastic wrap
around the parts you want to slim down too.
''Dear Shoko, Have you seen
'The Anxious Clown Homesickness ' yet?''
No, l haven't. l've been dying to see it though.
And that sake is out for a limited time only,
The Anxious Clown
''Homesickness''
Advance Ticket
And that sake is out for a limited time only,
Yashaou
but l won't be able to go pick some up
because l'll be working.
Yashaou
l really want that stuffed panda, but
l'm terrible at any games so...
l've heard of that pillow. Supposedly, you
can sleep like a baby with it!
Oranges! Oh, l love them too!
ToShoko
Although l also love watermelons!
But my most favorite thing is crab!
ToShoko
F rom RADLO BOY
Well, this is it for today's show.
l'm Shoko Saibara, and thank you for listening!
Bye-bye!
l'm serious!
Mr. Uraoka, you're lying again!
Welcome!
Tezuka!
Over here!
Hi! Excuse me, can l get a draft beer?
Coming right up!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
We weren't waiting that long.
What? Are you telling me you
weren't waiting for me?
l was waiting, Tezuka!
You're so sweet, Miss Shoko!
Here you go!
What Shoko was waiting for was beer!
What? ls that true, Miss Shoko?
Good work as usual, everyone!
Cheers!
Hey, wait! That's not cool!
Are you sure you don't want us to split the bill?
This is to say thank you for looking
out for me all the time!
All right, thanks!
Well, maybe l should ask you to
pitch in a little, Tezuka.
What?!
Something good must have happened to you.
You seem to be in a good mood lately.
What? You mean me?
Yup, you're always smiling.
Maie ceiebrity A (35) and His Famous co-Star (21)! Steamy Affair!
Now Youre Aii Set! -You Too can Do it!
ASimpie Way To Save Your Finances!
Another one?! The Dark Side of ciean Poiiticians!
The Reai Destination OfPoiiticai Payoffs Exposed!
Tragedy-Animator in Nerima District Brutaiiy Murdered!
The Perpetrator: The Shows Production Assistant!
Deadiy Rampage Because He WouidntTurn in His Work !
Maie ceiebrity A (35) and His Famous co-Star (21)! Steamy Affair!
Now Youre Aii Set! -You Too can Do it!
ASimpie Way To Save Your Finances!
Another one?! The Dark Side of ciean Poiiticians!
The Reai Destination OfPoiiticai Payoffs Exposed!
Tragedy-Animator in Nerima District Brutaiiy Murdered!
The Perpetrator: The Shows Production Assistant!
Deadiy Rampage Because He WouidntTurn in His Work !
''...but does he like me?''
Maie ceiebrity A (35) and His Famous co-Star (21)! Steamy Affair!
Now Youre Aii Set! -You Too can Do it!
ASimpie Way To Save Your Finances!
Another one?! The Dark Side of ciean Poiiticians!
The Reai Destination OfPoiiticai Payoffs Exposed!
Tragedy-Animator in Nerima District Brutaiiy Murdered!
The Perpetrator: The Shows Production Assistant!
Deadiy Rampage Because He WouidntTurn in His Work !
''l'm having a hard time because
l can't figure that out.''
''Miss Shoko, l need your advice as a
relationship expert, please!''
Well, let me get straight to the point.
l think he likes you!
Boys your age tend to say something completely
opposite from what they're really feeling.
Like, if he likes you he'll say
he hates you, you know?
Oh, we adults might do the
same thing sometimes,
but you have nothing to worry about, Chibita!
l, Shoko the relationship expert, guarantee that!
Toyohira River
Mt. Yotei
On to the North...
l didn't know you were here.
You were out late, huh?
Yeah, l went out for a drink after the recording.
Want a drink?
Sure...
Here!
Thanks.
Wow, it's cold!
Have you been drinking?
Just a little.
What's going on, anyway? This is out of the blue.
l thought you were really busy at work.
lt was you who left me a message saying
someone's been stalking you, wasn't it?
Yeah...
So l got worried.
l borrowed this for you.
Supposedly, you can use it to detect
listening devices and things.
A guy l know who's into this kind of
stuff told me about it.
l already checked, but l didn't find anything.
Really?
Yeah, l searched this room from top to bottom.
Okay, then l guess that's good enough.
Good enough?
lt's like, it doesn't bother me so much anymore.
What do you mean by that?
Nothing.
l just thought, maybe he isn't so bad, you know?
Don't tell me you're...
Oh, come on. Of course not.
Then why did you say it doesn't bother you?
Why do you care so much?
You could be lying.
To get my attention.
You're too cocky, you know that?
l'm not lying. lt was just my imagination.
Are you sure?
Let's leave it at that.
Hey, the water's spilling! The carpet!
l'm sorry. l haven't had time
for you in a long time.
Shoko...
l love you.
Of course l do.
l do.
On your birthday, l'll take you wherever
you want to go, Natsuko.
Really?
Shoko...
Did you have a fight with your
wife or something?
Why do you ask?
Because this is odd.
l came to see you because l wanted to see you.
What's odd about that?
What about how l feel?
What?
What about when l want to see you?
You just show up when you want to see me.
So is that the way it works?
Do l get to do it that way too?
You should have come when
you wanted to see me.
When l wanted to talk to you,
you told me not to call.
l leave messages on your phone
but you never call me back!
l wanted to talk to you!
l wanted to see you!
But you knew that was the deal
when you started seeing me!
You're right. l did know that.
But l always feel like l'm only talking to a phone,
you know, just talking to a machine.
l feel like my voice will never reach you.
lt tears me apart.
And l can't take it anymore!
Think about what you do for living.
lt's the same thing, isn't it?
You only talk into a microphone, don't you?
Get out...
l said, get out!
Summer is almost over, huh?
Not even close! lt's still hot as hell at night!
The seasons are changing without you
even noticing, Mr. Uraoka.
Really? You sure about that?
All right, Shoko, are you ready?
Shoko?
Oh, yes!
All right then, let's go.
Okay!
What am l doing here anyway?
l just come to the studio and have meaningless
conversations with the staff like l always do.
Read faxes and emails...
l can't even manage my own problems,
yet l give other people advice on their
relationships as if l know better.
What am l doing?
Moving on to the next fax.
This is from pen name ''Hibiscus.''
''There's something l want to talk to you about.''
''Well, actually the man l've been seeing has...''
''...a wife and kids.''
''l've started worrying lately''
''that maybe he doesn't really love me at all.''
''So tell me, Miss Shoko, you're the relationship
expert. What do you think l should do?''
l'm not...
''So tell me, Miss Shoko, you're the relationship
expert. What do you think l should do?''
l'm far from it.
''Okay, here's your advice from the
relationship expert, Shoko Saibara!''
l'm not a relationship expert.
''Okay, here's your advice from the
relationship expert, Shoko Saibara!''
l'm not a relationship expert.
Not at all!
Think about what you do for living.
lt's the same thing, isn't it?
You only talk into a microphone, don't you?
l can't do this anymore...
Music! Get us music!
Right!
l can't give other people advice
on their relationships.
l can't talk anymore.
My voice will never reach anyone!
l can't... this anymore...
l'm sorry...
Check this out, everyone!
Hey, wait! You!
What?!
Username :
what?!
Is she going to leave the industry for good?!
Username :
Is she getting married?!
Sure dropped a bombshell there !
What's wrong with her?
l have no idea!
Anyway, we've got to do something
about it before the music ends!
Damn it! lt won't open!
Don't quit!
Don't tell me he's the one who...
The music is almost over!
Play another one.
After Miss Shoko made that comment?
People will think it's weird if we
play two songs in a row!
But...
ls he in the booth?
But you can't go in there right now!
Can we set up the audio in a different booth?
We have to check which one is open first!
Not good! We don't have time for that!
The music is over!
The first time you called my name,
it made me really happy.
Up until that moment, no one had ever
bothered to call my name before.
l was always alone. lt was like l didn't even exist.
You're Radio Boy?
Yeah, you've always talked to me, just like that...
Radio Boy...
Because you talked to me,
l wasn't alone anymore.
l found a reason to exist.
So why did you say you were quitting?
l'm in pain. l can't even manage
my own problems.
So how can l give other people
advice on their problems?
l'm just sitting here alone
talking to a microphone.
Worrying that maybe my voice isn't
really reaching anyone.
l'm here!
See, l'm here!
Can't you tell your voice has reached me?!
l'm always waiting for your voice!
l love your voice!
So you can never quit!
Why don't you understand something
as simple as that?!
Really? My voice is really...
Of course it's reaching.
HANG IN THERE!
DON'T GIVE UP.
WE'VE BEEN LISTENING
TO YOU ALL ALONG.
KEEP FIGHTING!
Shoko!! Your show has to go on!
DON'T qUIT!
DON'T QUIT!!
Shoko, please don't quit.
You may have some tough times
but we're always here for you!
Keep up the good work!
Check out the message board!
Username :
Don ' t qui t!
Hang in there.
Username :
That' s right! I ' m here too!
Don ' t give up!
l'm starting the music!
Man, l'm amazed he managed to get in here.
Goodness! Huh?
Shoko, here.
He brought it here.
You were going to give it to Shoko, right?
Thank you.
But l'm over sunflowers now.
Summer is over now.
Miss Shoko, this is for you.
From Dried Mullet Roe
Your voice reaches me too.
P.S. I'm happy now because
I followed your advice.
This is the best response we've ever
had for this show, isn't it?
This is all thanks to you.
Thank you for everything.
But you can't just break in here anymore, okay?
Yes!
What do you look so happy for, huh?
We've got some questions
to ask you in the office.
Miss Shoko, the music is almost over.
All right, let's wrap it up.
Well, it's almost time to say goodbye.
l'm sorry that things got a little crazy here today.
And l also want to thank you
for all the faxes and emails.
l'm only sitting here talking to a microphone.
But l'm so grateful to know that there are so
many people out there listening to my voice.
l'm pretty sure all kinds of people are listening.
Students, working people, men and women both.
We've never met each other,
but l'd like to be friends with all of you.
l know l'm going to run into all
kinds of issues in the future,
but as long as you guys are here for me,
l'm sure l'll be okay.
ls my voice reaching you?
lt's autumn now. Have a great weekend!
You've been listening to ''Cappuccino Break''
with Shoko Saibara.
Steam Series
Noboribetsu
Hot Spring
Aitai aitai anata no manazashi ni
Kizutsuku koto wa osorenaide
Aitai ano sora miageru soyokaze no egao
Yawarakai egao
Kuchizuke shita ano hi no koto wasurenai no
Eien ni koi wo shitai
Hateshinaku tsuzuku ano sora
Dokomademo dokomademo
Anata to nara aruite yukeru
Tsunaida te wo tashikamete sou futarikiri de
Next Episode
This is Urara Takano.
Have you ever sent a love letter
to someone before?
Next Episode
l sent one on Valentine's Day
when l was in third grade.
Next Episode
The boy was two years older than me,
so he was in fifth grade at the time.
Next Episode
He had this really cute smile!
l remember re-writing the letter so many times,
Next Episode
but in the end, all l could write was,
''l like you a lot!''
Next Episode
The response he gave me on White Day was,
''l like you a lot too!''
Next Episode
Man, were we cute or what?!
l never want to forget that heart-thumping
feeling as long as l live!
Next Episode
Enjoy the next episode of On to the North,
Diamond Dust Drops.
Next Episode
Obihiro
Akari Harada
Part 1
Enjoy the next episode of On to the North,
Diamond Dust Drops.
Next Episode
Obihiro
Akari Harada
Part 1