1922. Colonial Vietnam.
The long-standing French
occupation of the country
has inflamed
anti-French sentiments.
At the height of the conflict,
resistance forces
emerge in many towns
to drive out the foreign invaders.
In response, the French employed
elite units of Vietnamese agents
to track and destroy these rebels.
Return Indochina back to its people!
We, the Vo Trong Canh rebellion,
hereby convict the French Indochina
Secretary of Security
for the crime of invasion,
and call for his execution.
"The Frightfulness."
So what?
You have to see for yourself.
It can spit out a firestorm
and level this city
in the blink of an eye.
It's a piece of junk against the rebels.
With the secretary soft-handling
these rebels,
full-scale war is inevitable.
It shows what people want,
but the sky is out of reach
if you're trapped at the bottom of a well.
That's why they need men
like you and I.
Do you really think the French
can kill all the rebels with this?
The way you talk,
we may as well join them.
Among us, you resemble them most.
Cuong,
you're a smooth talker.
Why don't you go ask the rebels
to join forces with us?
The simplest solution is
to cut off all their heads,
gather them up,
and set an example for once.
Vo Trong Canh's band of rebels
Excuse me.
Where's the train station?
I don't know.
A man like you doesn't know?
I'm sorry.
Sorry to have bothered you.
Drive straight through!
Freeze!
Put the gun down.
Put it down!
What a surprise.
What are you
standing over there for?
What the hell is wrong with you?
Where is your father's hideout?
Fess up.
Where's the hideout?
Be a good girl.
Tell me.
Only cowards torture women.
I've had enough of her.
She has no manners.
Secret Police Headquarters
This is the third recent assassination.
De Canh...
has no respect for the French.
He's a coward.
He is nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
And this?
Also nothing?
I imagine if my father was a drunk,
completely stripped of all his rank,
I'd feel like
a complete failure as well.
What a pity
that children are incapable
of killing their fathers.
I've been here for 10 years.
I'm waiting for the day
I can go home.
But once I'm gone,
they'll need someone
to take my post.
Bring me De Canh's head.
Prove to me you're not
the imbecile your father was.
Tell me, child.
Tell me, and the pain
will go away.
Where is he?
Where's daddy's hideout?
No?
Mute?
Stubborn?
What are you doing?
Who's in command here?
Who?
Do you need smelling salts
to wake her up?
That's enough.
Stay still.
Put the gun down.
Put it down!
You knew in advance.
About what?
The assassination.
Where's your proof?
I saw you shoot the assassin
before he made a move.
Good.
I'm impressed.
- So what?
- Hey, we're all brothers here.
I don't have to
tell you everything.
Derue will see right through you.
You threatening me?
You let them kill
the secretary for what?
- To catch a few rebels?
- That's it.
Good question.
Sit down.
Sit down!
None have made it out alive.
Your father and his men
will live in peace and prosperity
if he surrenders.
And become traitors like you?
Where have you been?
When blood is spilled,
it makes heroes out of men.
How can a killer find peace?
You're not a killer.
You're an officer of the law.
What do you know
about De Canh?
That roach is still alive?
Kill a man like him and
a hundred more would rise.
The Emperor
was once worshipped like a god,
but now he's just
a puppet of the French.
You must see their power
and their knowledge
and aspire to it yourself.
It was the French
that took your power.
Now they steal your soul
with this opium.
They gave me a noble son.
You're wrong!
Mother was the one
who gave you a son.
If you see it that way,
then do as I say
for your mother's sake
and not for mine.
All this time
did you ever love Mom?
The most precious thing
in this world
is a woman's love.
Never disappoint her
like I have disappointed
your mother.
Scared?
...must accept capital punishment...
There are worse things
than death.
Of course.
But I need you alive.
This is a trap.
And I'm the bait
to catch my father.
You're smart,
but that's a turnoff.
My father will kill
every last one of you!
Before your mother
passed away,
she made me promise her...
not to let you fight this war.
I failed her.
There are worse things than death.
Like losing a daughter.
Your sacrifice
won't save your father.
There is a mole
in your organization.
Remember the death
of the rickshaw coolie?
Six guards,
two French officers,
and a sharpshooter.
Why are you doing this?
Does it matter?
You have nothing to lose.
Open the door.
Hold it.
Put yourself over there.
Turn around.
Open it!
Do as she says.
Open the door.
Next.
Stop!
Cover the perimeter!
What's this?
She escaped, sir.
Find her!
Yes, sir.
Get the dogs.
Come with me.
Where are we?
Safest place in the city.
I'll get you another outfit.
Who is the mole?
Tell me!
If I'd known, the assassination
wouldn't have happened.
And they wouldn't have
had you to bait your father.
So what's the trick?
If you think this is a trick,
then why did you escape?
What choices do I have?
We don't always
have that luxury.
Except you.
Why are you helping me?
There is still a chance for you,
your father and his men.
Why do you care about us?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
Let's hear it.
I'm tired of all the bloodshed.
Haven't you had enough?
And now you want redemption?
I just want to live
in peace and order.
By killing your own people?
Murderers must be punished.
"Murderers"?
These "murderers" are only
fighting for their homeland.
In my eyes you're the murderer!
If you feel this way,
you can take retribution
for your friends now.
This is too easy for you.
You have to live
and face your own guilt.
There is a manhunt out there.
I have to inform my father
about the mole.
You'll need me
to get out of the city.
Long night?
Where is your loyal servant?
Looking for this?
Of all the beautiful women
you could have,
you betrayed me
for this bitch.
Sy!
We have to lose this car.
I need a tax I D card.
You're putting everyone at risk.
Just help me.
Finish those IDs.
You think it's that simple?
That's why I need you.
Tell me the truth.
Why are you doing this?
Do you know what it feels like
to shoot somebody?
I know I can't change your mind,
but remember this-
if you do this,
there's no turning back.
Also, you and the girl
were never here today.
I need to do one more thing.
But I don't have time.
Give me 10 minutes.
It's about my father.
Give me my papers.
I have become a wanted man.
This could be the last time
I see my father.
I have to leave the city.
I don't know when I'll be back.
Make me proud, son.
No matter what I do,
it will never make up
for what you did to Mother.
That way!
Did you see the girl?
Has anyone seen the girl?
Stop right there!
Hands in the air!
Take that!
Bastard..
Bastard!
Quickly, quickly,
come on!
Faster!
Stop!
Come down out of there.
- Go.
- Get in the truck.
Don't.
- They have nothing to do with this.
- Why do you care so much about them?
Our people are on this truck.
Time to use your head..
or what's left of it.
Think really hard;
Cuong must have
told you something.
All I remember
is the smell of opium.
Allow me to refresh your memory.
Hold it.
Please have some tea.
Enough of this.
Let me cut out his tongue.
Then how is he going to talk?
Now what else
do you remember?
He said... go to hell.
A tiger would never eat his cub.
Yes, Colonel.
It's me...Danh.
Give me what you've got.
They killed the informant.
Thank you.
You're a freedom fighter?
- Where are they taking us?
- To the iron mines.
Come down.
You'll die of thirst up there.
We have to divide them
and we have to send
the prisoners to Hanoi.
With the complicity
of the prisoners...
My mother was Indo-Chinese.
I share half your blood,
but France is my country.
I'm proud of who I am.
And your mother?
Wasn't she a whore?
What a pity!
I have work to do.
Perhaps I am mistaken
about you.
Tessier is dead.
You got that?
He's dead!
You are not the right man
for this situation.
Cuong...he's the one
with the talent.
I have talent, sir.
You have talent?
Then act like you have it!
Give me De Canh!
You have to stay calm.
Oh, Mom! Oh, Mom!
Stay calm.
You, come here!
- What's your name?
- Hung.
- Hung what?
- Pham The Hung.
Wrong, moron.
There's nobody here
by that name.
Now that you're here,
that name no longer exists.
From now on
your new name is 3709.
You got it?
Now, I ask you again.
What's your name?
My father called me Hung.
We just assume
that you never had a father.
Men to the right,
women to the left.
Move!
What are you looking at?
The woods.
I can see that.
But this place is a goddamn prison.
How did you end up here?
Couldn't afford their "self-tax."
I'm just a servant.
Everyone is subject to the law.
What about laws
that sanction slavery?
No such law.
You think people volunteered
to come here?
One way or the other,
we will all end up on that truck.
Move away!
Stand up!
Lazy scum.
- Ow!
- Don't play games with me.
I said stand up!
Please don't hurt
my husband!
Get up!
No food or water
for these two today!
Sir, I beg you.
Please forgive him.
No food or water
for these two today!
Understood?
I see a way out of here.
Be quiet!
Is that all you can see?
They left the key
in the ignition.
Look at them.
Have you ever seen a bunch
of lazier bastards?
We do the work while they sit there
filling their bellies.
Our white man's burden.
Take it. You don't want
to have a miscarriage.
Who gave food to these two?
Who gave food
to these two?
Nobody?
No one?
I am going to beat
these two to death!
I did.
Come here.
Turn around.
Put your guns down!
- Drop them!
- Put the guns down.