Announcer:
Nevada prison officials
Are scratching their heads
this morning
Over the disappearance
of bank robber julian goddard,
Who escaped during last night's
electrical storm.
Goddard was serving time
for his part
In the daring
silverado bank robbery
Three years ago in las vegas.
Goddard's unidentified
accomplice
Was never apprehended
Nor was the money
ever recovered.
Sounds like it's going
to be a busy day
For cops and robbers alike.
Ah-choo!
( horn beeps like
the road runner )
( beep beep )
Need a lift?
Matter of fact, I do.
I'm going to las vegas.
Where else?
( car doors close )
( engine starts )
( ned albright's "the seventh
son" playing )
Man 1:
What are you, a gambler?
Man 2:
Who isn't?
Name's destiny. Johnny destiny.
Man 1:
Well, I appreciate the ride.
'68 road runner, right?
This baby's a '69.
446 barrel.
Air-grabber hood
with a coyote duster.
Sweet lines.
Friend of mine had one
just like this,
Only his was a '68.
Same color too.
He used to call it
"monkey-bottom blue."
Yeah, well, nothing
beats detroit iron.
Johnny:
Vegas.
That's a town.
Anything can happen there.
You know what I mean.
I don't have to tell you.
It's an explosive situation,
that's what it is.
You got men looking for women.
Women looking for men.
And they're all
looking for money.
Quick money.
The whole town's a tinderbox.
"lucille."
She why you goin' to vegas?
Hey, you don't have
to say anything.
I know what's goin' on.
Johnny destiny has seen
that look before.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Heh heh heh heh.
Heh heh heh heh heh.
( on radio ):
♪ I'm the one
♪ yes, I'm the one
I'm the one ♪
( man snores )
♪ and I'm just a devil
with love to spare ♪
♪ viva las vegas
Aah.
( telephone rings )
Hello?
Uh, hey, ralph.
Yeah, I can talk.
10:00 rehearsal?
What do we need
a rehearsal for?
♪ turn the day
into nighttime ♪
♪ turn the night
into daytime ♪
♪ if you've seen it once
♪ you'll never
be the same again ♪
Ok, ok. I'll be there.
I'm not tense. You're tense.
I'll do the singing.
You just make sure--
♪ viva las vegas
♪ viva, viva las vegas
So long, doll.
♪ viva las vegas
Oh, god.
Destiny:
The marilyn motel.
Thanks for the ride, mister.
Anytime, man.
( starts engine )
( tires screech )
Come back here,
you lousy bastard!
If I only had a gun.
One shot. One shot.
That's all I need.
Oof.
Don't touch me!
I can do it myself.
Dirty shyster.
Oh. Gold chains
dripping off his neck,
And he leaves me
a lousy 20 bucks.
Johnny, is that you?
Is it really you, johnny?
It's me, sugar. In the flesh.
I'm sorry, johnny.
I couldn't control myself.
It's ok, honey.
You sure are a sight
for sore eyes, johnny.
I've been rolling snake eyes
ever since you left.
Bad luck. That's all it was.
Repeat after me.
Luck changes.
It always does.
See ya later, amigo.
See ya around.
I doubt it.
( car door closes )
Johnny:
Well, you never know.
It's a town
of limitless possibilities.
( car door closes )
Johnny destiny.
How ya doin', thoreau?
Julian.
Three years late, but I made it.
Better late than never.
I heard about you on the radio
this morning.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. The news fellas was
comparing you to harry houdini.
I kinda figured I'd see ya
headed this way.
Yeah. You're probably
not the only one.
Well, what do you
think of the place?
It's all mine now.
You didn't buy it, did you?
Well, let's just say
I acquired it.
Well, I gotta hand it
to you, thoreau.
I mean--I mean, it really--
it really looks like shit.
The universe
is expanding, julian.
It's beyond one man's power
to stem the tide of chaos.
You can make an attempt.
At least put some water
in the pool.
That ain't no pool.
That's the devil's
watering hole.
Thoreau:
So...
Have you seen lucille yet?
Nah. I came straight here.
So what's the shot?
Well...
I want my share of the money.
Then what?
And then I'll get lucille.
Mm-hmm.
And then after that,
I figure I just...
I head for the border
and just...
Just keep on goin'.
Just me and lucille.
That sounds like
a hell of a plan.
I'm glad you like it.
I do.
Couple of problems, though.
First off, lucille hasn't
exactly waited for you.
Well, she didn't
leave town, did she?
No. She's still here,
But she's tuerto's girl now.
He's a big shot now.
He runs the stardust.
Ohh. Ohh.
Well, this is...
This is truly...
Truly offensive.
Aah.
( glass shatters )
Aah!
( crash )
Oh, lucille.
Now...
You said...
That, uh...
There were a couple problems.
Yes, I did.
Well, let me have it.
It's about the money, julian.
Thoreau...
I spent three long
years in prison
Dreamin' about that money.
Whatever you do,
Don't tell me it's gone.
It's gone.
What do you mean...Gone?
I mean...Gone.
As in...Away.
Do you wanna know what happened?
No. I wanna hit you again.
I--I didn't lose it.
I didn't squander it.
I was robbed!
It wasn't my fault.
Ooh.
You went back for lucille.
Oh.
That's what screwed things up.
Can you hear me, julian?
All right, for the sake of the
rest of this conversation,
I'm just gonna assume
you can hear me.
Now, you left me here
In this god forsaken place...
With all that damn money.
I was a sitting duck.
Oh. You know, I figured--
I figured you could
take care of yourself.
You know, I just don't
get it, thoreau.
I just don't get it.
I mean, you had a gun, a car.
You had your wits about you
when I left ya.
You are seriously
underestimating
The power of the forces
Which were aligned
against us, julian.
What are you talking about?
What am I talking about?
I'm talking about
The inescapable forces of fate.
fire and water!
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
Don't tell me you gone
and got god on me now.
Please don't tell me.
I'm not putting
any names on him,
But he was here,
and he stole our money!
He?
Tell me there was more than one.
One was enough.
Thoreau:
If you recall, we had an
appointment at silverado bank,
But, of course, you and lucille
Had to choose this
particular moment in time
To have a relationship talk.
You promised me that
we would leave tonight.
You promised me.
We need some traveling money,
don't we? Huh?
After tonight, we're gonna
be on top of the world.
Then what?
And then--and then we'll leave
This god forsaken town.
With the cops chasing us?
There ain't gonna be no cops.
Julian!
Thoreau and I got it
figured out, baby.
It's gonna go like clockwork.
What if something goes wrong?
Nothing's gonna go wrong.
Julian, let's leave now.
Forget about the bank.
We don't need the money.
Let's get out of here
before it's too late.
Don't--don't worry, baby.
You wait here, and I'll be back
Before you can say acapulco.
You have this power over me.
It is ripping me in half.
Part of me wants to stay,
but the other part of me
Wants to clear out of here
right now.
Which part wants to stay?
Thoreau:
Now, we'd done more than our
fair share of thievin',
But we never managed
to get ahead.
The cash in that bank vault
Would make idleness
a way of life.
( tumblers open )
( yelling instructions )
Thoreau:
The wheel of fortune
Was most certainly
spinning in our favor.
That is until we got back
to the marilyn
To pick up lucille.
Sweetheart.
I'm back.
Lucille:
Don't try to find me.
Just know that
a piece of my heart
Remains yours forever.
Lucille.
Smell that. Ha ha ha.
I'm not picking that up.
That goes out of your share.
She's gone.
Let's get the hell out of here.
I gotta find her.
What about the cops?
Fuck the cops! I gotta find her.
Wait here.
I do not support this decision!
Thoreau:
Well, I waited,
just like you said.
The hours passed.
I knew something was wrong,
But I just kept on waiting.
( thunder )
( indistinct whispering )
When I woke up...
Car was gone,
Money was gone,
This pool was empty.
What's up with you, thoreau?
What the hell you still doing
here after three years?
I'm waiting.
People left, this place
fell to ruin,
But I'm still here,
and I'm waiting.
For what?
He's coming back.
That pool means
something to him.
I hate to disappoint you,
thoreau,
But there ain't no way in hell
this guy's coming back.
Whoever he is.
Well, you never know.
It's a town
of limitless possibilities.
Why did you say that?
I don't know. It just
popped into my head.
Why do you say anything?
Aw, it's...It's nothing.
Guy that dropped me off was
driving a car just like yours.
Only his was '69.
Julian, mine was a '69.
Thoreau, yours was a '68.
It was mine. I owned it and I'm
telling you it was a '69.
Aw, it's just a coincidence.
Like hell it is.
Plymouth only made 615
446 barrel coupes in 1969.
And 388 of those
were four speeds.
Now you figure the odds on that.
What the hell do you
think you're doin'?
He played me for a sucker once.
It ain't gonna happen twice.
This time, I'm ready for him.
Thoreau...
What about all the lightning?
Non-conducting rubber soles,
my friend.
I'm always thinking.
( car honking )
Ralph:
All right, bring up the reds.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, well--
give me a hint of blue.
A hint.
Okay, yeah, all right,
now turn slowly, baby.
All right. Turn around.
That's it.
That's it. Beautiful.
Beautiful. Ok, mark it.
All right, come on down,
sweetheart.
How come the band's
not up there?
Because the band's
not auditioning
For a record contract, ok?
You are, ok?
And don't be afraid
to show some tit,
You know, open up a little bit.
I mean, honestly, you know,
Nothing makes a song
sound sweeter than a little tit.
Ralph, you're a dirty bastard,
you know that?
Yeah, well, ok.
You only get one shot with this
guy, so don't fuck it up, ok?
All right, now pay
attention to me, ok?
Now, uh, all right.
I got it fixed, ok,
So he's gonna be
sitting right here, ok?
Here he is, ok?
Ok, now, he's here,
"oh, boy, I can't
wait for the show.
"I heard this girl's
really good.
"I don't know. Maybe she's not.
I don't know. Let's see."
What you do is just
play it cool.
Work the crowd.
"hey, how you doin'?
Good to see ya here."
da-da-da-bing. Badda-boo.
But this is the guy you got
to play to, all right?
Give this guy what he wants.
This is where you
lean right into him
And, "hooray! Wonderful.
She's the best in the world.
Sign her up. Give her a car."
But you're gonna be
terrific, baby, ok?
You're gonna be great.
He's gonna love you.
I love you, ok?
Now get out of here.
Go home and get some rest
and have a snotch.
Snotch--it's like a nosh
and a snack, I guess.
Hey. Boss wants
to see you. Pronto.
Thanks, francine.
So who's the geek
with the shiny head?
Who?
The nervous guy in the lounge.
Oh. His name's ralph.
Ralph dellaposa.
He's an agent.
A real smooth operator
from l.A.
He thinks I might
sound good on records.
Really? Does tuerto
know about this?
No, he doesn't.
And he's not gonna
find out, either.
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm. Not until I get
my ticket out of this town.
Well, my lips are sealed.
Thanks.
( door closes )
Oh, you really ought
to get out more.
I mean, spend some time
with people.
Goin' to see lucille?
Ah, well, you know...
Sure thinkin' about it.
My great-great-grandfather
once said,
"beware of all enterprises,
That require the use
of new clothes."
Now, tell me something.
Where did you get these
mod threads, man?
Well, the kind of people
that stay here
Tend to disappear in
the middle of the night.
Or they kill each other.
Either way, I wind up
with their stuff.
You seen my father lately?
I heard he was
camped out up north.
Hey, you better hide
that face, desperado.
Hey, thoreau.
I knew you'd wait for me.
I knew you'd be back.
¡hola, mi amigos!
Oh, what brings
you boys back to town?
Business or pleasure?
Business. Business.
Business?
♪ baltimore oriole
♪ took a look
at that mercury ♪
♪ forty below
♪ no life for a lady
♪ to be draggin'
her feathers around ♪
♪ in the snow
♪ leaving her mate
♪ she flew straight
♪ to the tangipahoa
♪ where two-timin' jaybird
♪ met the divine miss o
♪ I'd like
to ruffle his plumage ♪
♪ baltimore oriole
♪ messed around
with that jaybird ♪
♪ 'till he singed her wings
♪ forgivin' is easy
♪ it's a woman like now
and then could happen ♪
♪ thing
♪ send her back home
♪ a home ain't home without
her warbling, I know ♪
♪ make a lonely man happy
♪ baltimore oriole
( piano solo plays )
♪ send her back home
♪ a home ain't home without
her warbling, I know ♪
♪ make a lonely man happy
♪ baltimore oriole
♪ come on down
from your bough ♪
♪ fly home to her now
♪ baltimore oriole
Man:
Yeah. All right.
( applause )
I like the way you sing.
I can tell.
You shouldn't
look at me like that.
Like what?
Like you're thinking about
falling in love with me.
I'm not sticking around
long enough to fall in love.
Then you should've
left yesterday.
( horn honks )
All right. So what's
the bottom line?
Atlantic city? Come on, herb.
Come on, cut the crap.
What? Hey, fuck the numbers!
That's bullshit. Bullshit!
You're talking bullshit.
Shut the fuck up, herb.
Look, I believe in vegas
because vegas is vegas.
It's not some has-been
grimy shithole.
It's a town of limitless
possibilities.
Herb, have you been
to atlantic city, huh?
Well, it's depressing.
I spent three days there.
You know what happened?
I lost my tan.
Yeah, and then I lost
my self-respect.
No! Absolutely not.
No money goes to the east coast.
None. Zero.
Call me when you got
a better idea.
Jerk.
Accountants are all
the same. No style.
Hey, baby.
Mm.
Tuerto:
Beautiful, ain't it?
Life doesn't get more
beautiful than that, baby.
Look at that. Somebody just won.
Lucky bastard, huh?
You wouldn't have won that
big in atlantic city, pal.
Ahem. Francine said
you wanted to see me.
I do.
What about?
I just want to see you.
Well, take a good look
because I'm going home.
Wait, wait, wait.
Come on, honey.
Sit down. Have a drink
or something, will ya?
Did you get anything to eat?
Let me order you something up.
What do you want,
a fruit plate or something?
Tuerto, I don't have time.
Time? What is time, lucille?
It's the middle of the morning.
I never see you anymore.
You know that?
Get off my back, tuerto, ok?
I just--I need some rest.
Ok. I just thought maybe we'd
have a conversation
Or something. That's all.
I'm not in the mood
for conversation.
Ok. Ok.
But when you are,
let me know what you think
Of these numbers
I picked for you.
What, are you crazy?
This isn't my style.
Cher sang this lineup
at bally's last week.
Why argue with success?
What is it with you?
Your underwear
too tight, or what?
Excuse me?
You keep touching your thing.
You're always touching
your thing.
So?
Why, I just wanna know.
Are you checking to see
if it's still there?
Hey, back off.
It's there! Stop worrying.
Hey, tuerto don't worry
about his thing.
Keeps me company, that's all.
Which is more than you've been
giving me lately.
What's with you all
of a sudden, huh?
What's up your ass lately?
When's the last time
we made love, you and I?
Every time I touch you,
you give me the big freeze.
I don't have to take this.
It's so cold between us,
I have to wear
snow shoes to bed.
When you climb into bed,
The automatic thermostat
kicks in.
And what's the matter
me grabbin' my thing?
I can grab my thing anytime
I want to grab my thing!
It's my thing, it's there
for me, it's arm's reach,
Who gives a shit?
You know, a woman in your
condition shouldn't smoke.
Wise choice.
Lucille!
Aah!
Ah! What?
Ralph, you scared me.
Sorry. Listen, you
have to nix that nap.
But I got great news for you.
Vinnie vidivici wants
to have lunch with you.
I thought you said he wasn't
getting into town 'till tonight.
He checked in early.
He calls me from his suite,
Says he wants to meet you
before the show.
I say lunch, he says chinese.
I say noon, he says 12:30.
Some dumb luck. Now, be on time.
Vinnie vidivici does not do
lunch unless he means it.
What should I wear?
I don't know.
Just the way you are is fine.
Oh, hey, hey, hey.
I know. Show some...
Right. Ha ha.
( car honking )
Julian:
Lucille!
( honking car )
( whispering ):
Ahem. Okay, I'm just gonna
walk straight.
Need a lift?
Hmm.
I thought you were in prison.
Well, they let me out
on good behavior.
When did you get into town?
This morning.
When are you leavin'?
Well, that all depends...
On what?
How long it takes you to pack.
It has been three years,
Couldn't you just
leave it alone?
Oh, no, baby,
it's been left alone too long.
Come on, sweetheart.
Let's vamoose
out of these parts.
Come with me.
Anywhere you want to go.
I'm talkin' about zihuatanejo,
tierra del fuego...
Julian, you know what--
you name it...
I don't need this today.
I really don't need this.
I got plans--I got big plans.
And they don't include you.
Oh, you got big plans?
Big--big plans.
Ah, well do these big plans--
they include tuerto, I suppose.
They include me, all right?
So, just leave me alone,
you're nothing but trouble.
Hey, what's the matter?
Move your car, eh!
Come on, move the car!
Can't you see I'm talkin'
to my girl here?
Like I give a shit!
Man:
He don't give a shit!
Move your car or I'll move it
for you, you son of a bitch.
Man:
Son of a bitch!
Oh, you're gonna move the car
for me, huh?
You're gonna move
the car for me?
Let go!
Thoreau:
Marilyn monroe, you drove men
crazy with desire.
Where's goddard?
Detective dravec. Gage.
Julian goddard. Where is he?
Oh, last I heard,
He was learning the trade of
license plate manufacturing.
Don't mess with us, thoreau.
He broke out yesterday.
We know this is the
first place he'd come.
Well, you know the routine.
Look around. Take a look.
Sign giving you trouble,
thoreau?
Ah, neon is so temperamental,
these signs.
You looking for this?
Who are you, mister?
What do you want from me?
Actually, we met...
But we weren't introduced.
You can call me johnny.
I was hoping to have
a word with you
About the sorry state
of this establishment.
I'm particularly concerned
about your pool.
My pool?
Your pool.
( thoreau groans )
You want me to fix the pool,
I'll fix the pool.
Make sure it doesn't leak,
I'll make sure it doesn't leak.
Then maybe you'll
get off my back!
Eat that.
( sniffles )
Hey, you're johnny's friend.
From this morning.
You cry a lot, don't you?
( sniffles )
It's that louse!
I thought things
would be different,
But I should've known better.
You can't tie down a guy
like johnny.
Yeah, well, you know what they
say about love...
What?
I can't remember.
But it was right on the money.
Oh.
Listen, about johnny,
You know where I can find him?
Nobody finds johnny,
he finds you.
Hey!
( tires screech )
I mean, some schmucks might blow
a lot of hot air at you
About taking the public's pulse,
Like the public has
a heart or something.
Well, vinnie vidivici
is here to tell you
That the public
has no heart. Huh?
Take it from me,
This business is nothing
but a craps shoot.
That's pretty funny coming
from such a successful guy
Like yourself, vinnie.
Hey.
Ain't that right, lucille?
Ain't that right,
what I just said?
That is definitely so, ralph.
You know, honey,
I'm doing ralph here a favor.
Nobody, but nobody,
Comes to vegas looking
for fresh, new talent.
This is where careers go to die.
Jeez.
The whole place, if you ask me,
It just stinks of formaldehyde.
I hope you're not wasting
my time here, ralph.
What? Are you serious, vinnie?
I would never waste
your time, you know.
'cause I know
how important time
Is to a gentleman
of your stature. So I--
Vinnie:
Good.
Ok. Now, if you'll excuse me,
I gotta go to the can.
Oh, ok. We'll wait
for you outside, vinnie.
Ok. Do that, please.
What the hell is wrong with you?
We're sitting here
eating lunch with a guy
Who can make or break
your career,
And you're staring at the fish
Like what's going on in
there's more important.
Sorry.
Well, you know, forget about it
Because I tell you, you know,
Despite your efforts
to screw up, you know,
I think he likes you.
Come on.
No, he does.
That's just his way of saying,
"hey, cutie,
what you know? Hey."
Oh, please.
No, it is.
I mean, what's not
to like, huh?
You feeling ok? I mean,
You haven't even touched
your mu shu at all.
Let me grab some
of this before--
I'm not hungry. I need some air.
I'll meet you outside.
( mumbles )
Boy, I'll tell you,
those chinese kill me.
With that mu shu this
and the sub gum,
But they're cute.
And I'll tell you what.
Now, listen, listen. Here's what
I want you to do, all right?
Go home and take a bath and tuck
your yourself in, get some rest.
Ok? I want you looking
fresh as a daisy
When those lights
come up tonight, ok?
All right? I'm serious.
You need to relax.
And you know, you--
what, you know him?
Lucille:
Uh, he's just some guy
I haven't seen in a while.
Ralph:
Yeah? Why do I get the feeling
he ain't just some guy, huh?
Oh, he's coming over here. Ok.
No, this isn't any good.
No. See, I smell trouble here.
No. Lucille, look, look.
Listen to me. Look at me.
All right?
Clarity of the mind.
No, no, no. Look at me.
Clarity of the mind, ok?
Be here. No complications today.
Clarity-ness is next
to godliness.
Oh, hey, vinnie, hey.
Uh, I was, uh...
Oh.
"you will inherit the earth."
What else is new, huh?
Ralph:
All right.
Vinnie:
So, where we at? I have to get
back to the hotel.
Ralph:
Oh, come on.
I'll give you a ride.
All right?
We'll take my car.
Make sure you
knock me out tonight.
I will give it my best
shot, mr. Vidivici.
( mumbles )
We just broke bread.
You call me vinnie.
Vinnie.
All right.
Where's your car?
It's over here.
It's next to the jaguar.
Vinnie:
Next to the jaguar?
Julian:
Lucille, come here.
I just want to tell you
one thing. Ok?
Just wait up.
Not a day went by--ok, ok.
Not a day went by that
I didn't think of you.
Look, I never meant for
you to get busted, ok?
I figured if I left,
you'd go on without me.
Well, you figured wrong.
Well, I'm not sorry.
I'm not asking you to be.
You could've just gone,
you know.
Everybody makes
their own choices.
I will choose you every time.
Julian, you can't--
You can't just walk back
into somebody's life
And expect things
to be the same.
Things are different.
I'm different.
I am trying to be more
serious with my life.
And that's why we can't
see each other anymore?
That's right.
No, that's wrong.
What's important is you and me.
Don't you tell me
what's important
And what's not important.
I got a lot of stuff on my mind,
And you--you're starting
to confuse me.
Hey, look at me.
Look at me, baby.
I love you.
Is that confusing?
You don't understand.
I do understand, baby.
I understand so much.
You know that too, don't you?
Oh...I was afraid
this would happen.
Julian.
Yes, my love.
There's something
I gotta tell you.
You tell me anything
you wanna tell me.
Kiss me again.
Isn't that your car?
Julian:
Uh, yeah. Well, not exactly.
Um...
You son of a bitch!
Oh.
Honey, I didn't steal it.
I just borrowed it.
Oh, yeah! Like you were
about to borrow my heart.
For a joy ride.
Don't do that, lucille.
Don't walk away from me.
What do you expect me
to do, julian,
Go for a ride
in your stolen car?
Some things never change.
Oh, that's right, lucille.
Some things, they never change!
Like the way I feel every time
that you leave me!
You are breaking
my heart, julian.
No. I'm just borrowing it,
remember?
Thoreau.
Pappy!
You ol' desert rat!
Where's that errant son of mine?
He went downtown to see lucille.
I knew he was here.
My old scar started
itching last night,
And I knew trouble was brewing.
This scar hasn't lied
to me in 32 years.
And last night,
I was scratching
something fierce.
So, at first light,
I packed into the truck
and set forth.
You are expecting him
back, aren't ya?
Well, pappy, I never expect
anything from julian.
Oh, it sure is good to see you.
This calls for a toast!
Why don't you put your stuff
up on the porch,
And I'll go get us a bottle.
A toast to welcome me back.
( coyote howls )
Sign says "no vacancy" but, uh,
It looks like you might
be able to squeeze me in.
So happens we had
a cancellation.
Here, fill this out.
"smith." mr. John smith.
What an unusual name.
How long will you be staying
with us, mr. Smith?
Just leave it open-ended
if you don't mind.
All right. You're in the
"some like it hot" suite.
Need help with that luggage?
Yeah. Uh, no. I can manage.
Pappy:
Something strange
about that fellow.
Thoreau:
He's a cop.
Piece of shit bike.
There's a cop in the
"some like it hot" suite.
Bingo!
( static )
Aah! Mr. Smith to dispatch.
Come in, dispatch.
Request backup
at the marilyn motel.
( static )
( knock on door )
Thoreau:
Room service.
I, uh, I didn't order
any room service.
It's complimentary.
Delicious cookies and lemonade
To make your stay here
more enjoyable.
All right. That's far enough.
Where's your buddy?
I'm sure I don't know
what you're talking about.
Don't play coy with me.
You don't know julian goddard?
Oh, him. He's standing
right behind you.
Yeah. And my shoelaces
are untied.
As a matter of fact, they are.
God, son. You look old.
Joint rough on you?
Wasn't no place for a man.
I wanted to get up there
and visit you,
But one thing led to another.
You know how it is.
Besides, prisons
make me nervous.
How's that girl
you were seeing?
The singer?
She won't see me anymore.
Ah, hell, that never
made no sense.
A gal like that going out
With a rattlesnake like you.
I reckon it's my fault.
This ain't got nothing
to do with you, pappy.
Don't deny me
my parental rights, boy!
I passed on
a twisted chromosome!
A doctor up in bixby,
He explained to me
the whole process.
He said I got an
overproductive pineal gland.
And I reckon you got one too.
Pineal gland?
Overproductive!
Overproductive pineal gland.
It's right here...
In the back of the brain.
All swollen and angry.
Hardly leaving any room at all
For all what else
that's back there.
Doctor said not
to worry, though,
On account of nobody ever died
From an overproductive
pineal gland.
But I know something he can't
tell from all them x-rays.
I know what it does to a man,
How it sets him off
to the desert
Just to protect
the ones that he loves.
That's the curse
of our affliction, son.
It renders us incapable
Of living with civilized folks.
Oh, maybe you, but not me.
Hey, what are you doing
with that hose?
Giving yourself an enema?
He sure as hell needs it.
Heh heh heh heh.
I fixed the pool.
Now I'm gonna fill it.
Yeah, that's all you need,
thoreau,
A little project to focus on
And take your mind
off of things.
It's for johnny.
He came by earlier.
That guy was here?
Yeah.
I just saw him downtown.
Why didn't you kick his ass?
Because his butt
is unkickable, julian.
He ain't like us.
Near as I can figure,
he's an animistic spirit.
You mean like the manitou?
Exactly.
What's a manitou?
Sort of like a god,
with a small "g."
Thoreau:
Think of it this way, julian.
Millions of people come
to las vegas to gamble.
They pin their hopes and dreams
On one spin of the wheel
or roll of the dice.
It's a ritual,
like a rain dance.
Or a circumcision.
And this repeated act of
gambling has conjured a deity.
Uh-huh. And that's
this guy johnny?
Exactly. It's his job
to dole out the luck.
And the beautiful part of it
is it's all random.
Wait a second. Let's just go
back to the beginning.
Why are you putting water
in the pool?
He said if I help him,
he'll give us our money back.
This pool's his path
back to the spirit world.
Well, you see? You see?
Now everything
makes perfect sense.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm glad to hear you
say that, julian.
To tell you the truth, I was--
I was kind of afraid you were
gonna think I was off my nut.
That's exactly what
I think, you freak!
Did something happen to you
while I was locked up?
Dropped on your head
or something?
Somebody's making
a fool out of you
And doing a damn good job of it.
You used to be harry thoreau,
The scourge of the west.
And now you're
a freaking pool man.
Fuck you, julian.
Yeah, well, fuck you too.
If he came around here while
I was here, I would've--
I would've thrashed him
within an inch of his life
And demanded some kind
of restitution.
You wanna kick his ass
so bad, tough guy,
He's staying right down
at the stardust.
What are you guys,
pals or something?
Thoreau:
We have an understanding.
Well, maybe I'll go
pay him a visit
And reach an understanding
of my own
With his teeth and my knuckles!
( both talking heatedly )
I call you for backup.
( continues to argue )
Guaranteed to bring you luck.
All right. Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Hey, little joe from kokomo.
How're you doing today?
Where's my taste, huh?
I'll have the money
for you next week, boss.
I'm tired of you being late
on these payments.
Tell you what. You take
these flowers to lucille,
We'll call it even.
Yo, boss.
Detective dravec was here.
Good work, kid.
I get to deliver the flowers.
Maybe if you throw
in the shades.
Oh, you drive one hell
of a hard bargain.
Come here.
Hey, boys. How ya doing?
Good to see you here. Welcome.
Hey, robert,
Why don't you give the boys
a casino discount card?
You know what?
You go down to baird's,
Get yourself
a nice suit, all right?
Comfy?
Sorry to keep you waiting, boys.
What can I do for you?
We're looking
for julian goddard.
Goddard. Goddard's in the can.
What rock do you live under?
He's out.
He was spotted in vegas.
What's that got to do with me?
You used to know goddard, right?
Sure, I did. Everybody did.
That don't mean anything.
He's a nut. He's a wild man.
He's completely unpredictable.
It's come to our attention that
he used to put the moves
On your girl...Lucille.
That was before she met me.
She's done with him,
finished, finito.
She dumped him,
hasn't seen him since.
What about today?
You are giving me
a fucking headache, dravec!
Hey, don't get your bowels
in an uproar there, huh?
We're gonna just take
a quick look around
And talk to a few
of your employees.
You don't mind, do you? Thanks.
Dravec...
You do what you got to,
only do it quiet.
Cop noise disturbs
the customers.
Get it?
( sniff )
Bring the car around back quick.
( rock music blares )
Julian:
Oh, hello there, mr. Policeman.
What do you think I am, stupid?
Good behavior, my ass.
( glass breaks )
Dravec:
You seen this scumbag?
Seen a lot of scumbags.
What makes this one so special?
( slap )
Ow.
He was here this morning,
looking for lucille.
Did he find her?
I don't know,
But he didn't strike me
as the kind of guy
Who would stop looking.
Satisfied?
Dravec:
Hey, let's go
and talk to lucille.
Rarr.
( romantic music plays )
What are you
still doing here, huh?
I'm glad you stayed, but...
I thought you hated las vegas.
It's a tough town to leave.
Why did you come back?
Uh...
The road only
went one way, baby.
The road...Can go two ways.
Oh, not for me.
And not for you either.
That's why you're still here.
You waited for me,
Just like I told you.
( moaning )
( rock music blares )
He loves me not.
I love him.
Tuerto:
Hello, doll.
Guess you got the roses.
Tuerto.
Why so surprised?
( toilet flushes )
Company?
Tuerto loves a party.
How ya doing, tuerto?
Mr. Goddard.
Long time, no see.
Mm-hmm.
You were always
a snappy dresser.
Hey, would you like me
to put a hem in that?
No.
Ok, boys and girls,
we're gonna get dressed now,
And we're gonna go
for a little drive,
Just the three of us.
Come on.
What are you gonna do, tuerto?
I haven't decided whether
I'm gonna kill him myself
Or feed him to the cops.
Now get dressed.
Come on.
Oh.
Oh!
Mmm!
Mmm! Mmm! Mmm!
( muffled talking )
God, son of a bitch
took lucille!
He never comes during the day.
What was he doing here?
I'll tell you, this shoe
really comes in handy.
Ok, there's a cop out front.
I'm gonna duck down,
And all I want you to do
is just fly right by.
Ok.
Julian...I have to talk to you
about something.
Honey, this is not the time.
Please, let's go.
Julian, it's very important.
Honey, let's go!
Ok, stay down.
You got three goons out here.
Hi. How's it going?
Cop: How you doin'?
Hi, fellas.
Tuerto'll be right out.
Nice suits.
Looks like my old buddy dravec.
Punch it, baby. Let's go!
I'm punching! I'm punching!
That's it. That's it.
I want you to blow right through
the stop sign, baby.
Lucille:
Ok.
Hang a left.
Don't hit the brakes.
Just take it real fast.
Hard left. Come on.
Go! Go! Go!
Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Julian, honey, I really need
to talk to you about something.
Honey, please, please.
Hit the horn.
Hit the horn!
Lucille: Aah!
( blares horn )
Look out. Look out.
Aah! Aah!
Ok, let's have some fun.
I pull the brake,
you cut the wheel.
Go, baby, go!
What are you doin'?
Cut the wheel!
I'm cutting!
Whoo-hoo!
Aah!
That is an illegal u-turn.
Yeah. We add that to the list.
Come on. Come on!
Hang a left. Hang a left.
Lefting, lefting.
We got you now, loverboy.
We got you now!
What the fuck is that?!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
God, I hate that.
I think we lost them.
Beautiful job, sweetheart.
Thanks. I love you, baby.
I love you too.
Look at that sky.
On a night like this...
Julian.
Anything can happen.
I mean anything.
Anything, anything.
Come on.
Honey...
Marry me, lucille.
Marry me, baby.
I'm all yours.
Julian, I'm pregnant.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's not what you think, baby.
It's not tuerto's baby.
No, it's yours.
Mine?!
Yeah.
You better watch
yourself, sweetie,
'cause I'm startin' to get...
I'm startin' to get real mad!
Julian...
I haven't slept with
tuerto in a long time,
And there hasn't
been anybody else.
It's the truth.
The truth?!
The truth is that
I've been in prison
For three years!
And, according
to everything I know,
Two people have to be together
Basically in the same place
to make a baby!
Julian...
What if we were together?
I think that I would
remember, lucille.
I didn't remember it myself
until this morning.
When I saw you
down on the casino floor,
It all came back to me.
What all came back to you?
One night about a month ago,
I just couldn't sleep.
I don't know why,
but I got in my car,
And I drove to that old motel.
Lucille:
I got real sad
lookin' at that room,
All messed up,
just the way we left it.
I guess I was hoping
you'd be there somehow.
( howling )
Maybe it was just a dream.
I don't know.
But that's when it happened,
julian.
That's when you and me
made this baby
I have inside of me.
I don't blame you
for not believin' me.
I had the same dream.
It's holding water.
I wish julian was here.
I got a funny feeling
about all this.
I'm gonna go look for him.
Keep an eye on things.
( people chatting happily )
Whoa. Excuse me.
Sorry.
Woman:
Good luck. Congratulations.
Where you taking me
on our honeymoon?
Oh, baby, I just
figured we'd just...
We'd just keep driving...
Mmm.
Until we run out of road.
I love the sound of that.
I'm gonna call thoreau.
Mmm?
I'm gonna tell him good-bye.
Ok. Hurry up.
Be right back.
Hurry, hurry.
Hey.
Look at that.
( telephone rings )
Ooh. Feels good.
Come on, thoreau. Come on.
( honk honk )
One second, baby.
Be right there.
( telephone rings )
Surprise.
Lucille:
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Oh, boy.
Get outta here.
( takes deep breath )
Boys told me
you were in your car,
Waiting outside some
chintzy wedding chapel.
What's that about?
And, on top of that,
I hear you and dellaposa
Are marking cards
behind my back.
I give you a house,
a car, a job.
Everything you have,
You have because
of tuerto's generosity.
Oh, lucille.
Party's over, lucille.
I'm cashing in your chips.
( sighs )
Now get outta here.
Tuerto...
I played you for a sap.
I'm sorry.
It's just that there are...
Things going on with me
That I can't explain, and...
I don't even understand.
Where you going, missy?!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Get your mitts off of me!
What do you want, dravec?
Where's your boyfriend?
I don't know.
I'm tired of being
jerked around here.
Hey, you take three baby steps
back, copper,
And pop a breath mint
while you're at it.
Can't you see the lady's
had a rough time of it?
Well, maybe she likes it rough.
Does aiding and abetting
a fugitive mean anything to you?
Come on. Tell us where he is.
I told you, I don't know.
That song is getting old.
Where you go, he goes.
What time is your show tonight?
There ain't no show tonight.
I just fired her.
She's going on the schedule.
Yeah? Says who?
Says me, hot shot.
Look, you play ball,
or I'll shut down
This tarnished
xanadu toot suite.
Powder your nose, sweetheart.
I want you to sing
it like you mean it,
'cause I'm goin' fishin',
And you are the bait.
( whispering ):
Oh, julian.
You're not gonna kiss me,
are you, thoreau?
Not unless you ask me real nice.
( groaning )
Ow.
Somebody jacked you up,
but good.
Yeah.
Tuerto's stooges.
And they got lucille.
( telephone rings )
Marilyn motel. May I help you?
It's him.
Yeah, it seems
to be holding water.
Well, what--what time
should I expect you?
Midnight? Ok, sure. Midnight.
Gimme that damn phone!
Now, you listen to me,
you cowardly son of a bitch!
I want my--
Now, do you believe me now?
Do you see what
I'm telling you?
It's all coming full circle!
And in a little more than...
Oh, hell, in no time at all,
We're gonna get our money back.
And all we have to do is wait!
Well, that's what you do best,
isn't it, thoreau?
You sit around, and you wait!
Well, not me!
Always sitting!
Where you going?
To get lucille.
Give me the keys.
You're in no
condition to drive.
You're in no condition to stop
me. Give me the keys.
You can't leave. We gotta stick
together this time.
( choking )
Thoreau!
You're my partner
and the best friend I got,
And I love you like a brother,
But that don't mean I won't kill
you if I have to.
Now, give me the keys.
Ok.
( coughing )
( small splash )
Ha ha!
There's water in that pool.
You know I can't swim.
Looks like you're
gonna have to learn.
Goddamn.
I can't even
see 'em down there.
I wouldn't go in
that pool if I were you.
He threw the keys in the pool.
Then they're gone.
What do you mean "gone"?
I mean gone...
As in "away."
You went in that pool, pappy?
I seen some
mighty strange things
In the desert--
Hallucinations,
visitations, mirages--
Call them what you will.
But what I seen down there...
I wouldn't go in
that pool if I were you.
You guys are givin' me
the heebie-jeebies.
I promise to bring her back
without a scratch.
( snapping fingers )
Johnny, where have you been?
I've been saving a seat for you.
Katrina, I'm sorry.
I didn't get the time.
Look, I'm telling you,
I'm not the guy for you,
And I told you that
before, ok? I'm sorry.
( snaps fingers )
Buck up, big fella.
For every ending,
there's a new beginning.
What are you,
a goddamn fortune cookie?
( katrina crying )
Give her something, jerry.
( snapping fingers )
Seat taken?
Knock yourself out.
Thank you.
What if he doesn't show?
You get a look
at that dame lucille?
Yeah.
He'll show.
Hey, how do you feel?
Ah, all right, I guess.
All right, you look fantastic.
What a package.
They're gonna eat you up.
I'm gonna ride shotgun
on the lighting board,
Make sure that bozo
doesn't fuck up, ok?
And remember, smile at vinnie.
All right, good,
you'll be great.
You know your mark?
All right, 15 seconds
to blackout.
Ok.
( applause )
( whispering ):
Psst.
Lucille.
Julian.
I thought I'd never
see you again.
You've gotta get out of here.
It's a trap.
Come with me.
I can't. They're watching me.
They want you.
Nobody's gonna get me.
( drumstick beats time )
( music starts )
( wolf whistle )
Oh, my god. Drop 'em.
What the hell was that?
All right, all right.
Let's try it again.
Uh, bring up the backlight.
♪ moonlight magic
♪ has me in its spell
♪ that old black magic
that you weave so well ♪
♪ those icy fingers
up and down my spine ♪
♪ the same old witchcraft
when your eyes meet mine ♪
♪ the same old tingle
that I feel inside ♪
Yeah, yeah. Go, baby, go.
♪ ...Elevator starts its ride
♪ and down and down I go
♪ round and round I go
♪ like a leaf
♪ that's caught in a tide
♪ I should stay away...
Why do they always
write songs about love?
♪ I hear your name...
What else is there?
♪ aflame with a burning desire
♪ and only your kiss
♪ can put out the fire
♪ for you're the lover
I have waited for ♪
♪ you're the mate that fate
had me created for ♪
♪ and every time
your lips meet mine... ♪
Hey, look. Over there.
That's the guy we almost ran
over this afternoon.
This bird can sing.
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black magic
called love ♪
♪ I should stay away
♪ but what can I do?
♪ I hear your name
♪ and I'm aflame
♪ aflame with a burning desire
♪ and only your kiss
♪ can put out the fire
♪ for you're the lover
I have waited for ♪
♪ you're the mate that fate
had me created for ♪
♪ and every time
your lips meet mine ♪
♪ baby, down and down I go
♪ round and round I go
♪ in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black magic
called love ♪
♪ in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black magic
called love ♪
♪ called love
♪ doo doo doo doo
doo doo du du doo ♪
doo doo du ooh doo ♪
( cheering and whistling )
( applause )
Ohh! Ohh! Ohh! Ohh!
Phenomenal. You were
transcendent, amazing.
No, no! You're gonna
get your picture taken.
Ernie, go! Get a good one!
You got her face in it?
It's all right?
All right. Good.
You were a knockout, babe,
I mean, absolutely fantastic!
You know, when the lights
came up, I'm thinkin',
You know, we're through,
you know?
How the hell did that
schmuck get onstage anyway?
It doesn't matter.
Who the hell cares, right?
It's over, and the important
thing is you were fantastic.
( knock on door )
oh, come on.
I told you the lady said
she couldn't--
Hey, vinnie.
Come on in. Hey, enter.
If I didn't see it
with my own eyes, ralph...
I gotta hand it to you.
You certainly can pick 'em.
Yeah.
This bird can sing.
Hot stuff. Hot stuff.
Especially that
opening number with the kiss.
Oh, that'll sell records.
She could be the next streisand.
Ralph:
So, uh, so you liked the show?
Liked it?
I loved it.
Yeah.
Mwah. Mwah.
I loved it!
You touched me.
I was moved,
And vinnie vidivici
is not easily moved.
So, uh, what am
I hearing, vinnie?
What you're hearing
is that you got a deal.
All right.
( door opens )
( gasps )
Ma'am.
Hi.
Great show.
Thanks.
So, what happened?
With what?
The record contract.
Did you get it?
Oh, yeah. I sure did.
So, um, I guess
this all your now.
Julian:
Come on, baby, let's go!
You are lookin' good. My, my.
Go, go, go, go!
Mmm.
So, any sign of him?
Nope.
She still in there?
Yep.
Hey, you.
Rowrr.
They had no idea
what they were doin'
When they built this place.
Tapped straight into the cosmos.
( harry and thoreau laughing )
Hey, harry.
Whoo! Good to see you.
Honey, this here is my father.
Pappy, this is lucille...
My wife.
We got a certificate
and everything.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Whoa.
This calls for a toast.
Perhaps I ought to kiss
the bride myself.
I notice it's coming up
on the witching hour, thoreau.
So where's the bogeyman?
He'll be here.
Well, he better make it snappy,
Or else I'm liable
to turn into a pumpkin.
Lucille:
Hey, everybody, look at this!
It's glowing.
Why does it do that?
Yeah, thoreau,
why does it do that?
Wish I could tell you.
Honey, scooch away
from the side there.
Listen. No, it's not
a good idea, baby.
Uh, this--this
pool is busted, ok?
( thunder )
It's all there.
Mister, I don't know
what your game is,
But at this point
in the evening,
I say let bygones be bygones.
Come on, thoreau.
Let's split it up.
( thunder )
( water crackles )
Surf's up.
( crackles )
What's down there?
Well, lucille,
That's all the roads
you didn't take,
And that's all the
choices you didn't make,
And that's all the numbers
you didn't bet on.
That's everything
that could have happened
Had things been different.
Looks like we travel in style.
Come on, lucille.
Let's hit the road.
( siren approaching )
With cops chasing us, julian?
This ain't no time
to play games, baby.
We gotta get out of here.
Let's go!
Lucille, come on.
Lucille!
No.
You gotta go, julian.
I'm not goin' with you.
You love me, don't you?
With all my heart.
Love...
Love is all that matters, baby.
Listen, baby.
We can never be together
in this crazy world.
What are you talking about?
You've just gotta go.
Go now, before it's too late.
I ain't goin' nowhere
without you.
No. Goddamn it, julian! Just go!
I ain't goin' without you!
Damn it, julian!
Get the hell out of here! Go!
What are you talking--
Johnny:
Julian!
You could come with me.
I--I ain't goin' nowhere.
I ain't goin'
nowhere without her.
You're a cute couple.
Well, don't think
it hasn't been fun.
Freeze, goddard! Drop the bag!
Drop it! Easy!
Hands in the air!
Keep 'em up! Move it!
Julian:
Ok, fellas. You got me.
I'm clean.
Real slow. Slow and easy!
I got nothin' on me.
Got nothin' on me! I'm clean.
Come on! Come on!
I'm just takin' it off.
Back away from the girl!
Real clean.
Move it!
I gotta hand it to you guys.
You're really good.
All right! On the ground!
I guess you were right, lucille.
We'll never be together
in this world.
Get down! Get down!
Hit the ground.
So long, fellas.
( water crackling )
Where'd they go?
Did we get 'em?
I don't know.
Where the hell are they?
Dravec:
I saw them get in this pool.
I did too, ed.
All right!
Nobody move!
Now, I don't know where
the hell your buddy got to,
But you ain't goin' nowhere,
Except maybe
the federal penitentiary
If you got in that bag what
I think you got in that bag.
What bag?
That bag.
Oh, this bag.
G-go get it.
I-I'm not goin' in that pool.
What? Go in the pool
and retrieve the evidence.
Gage:
You go in the pool
and get the evidence!
Are you saying that you're
not gonna go--
That's exactly what I'm sayin'.
( sucking )
( pop )
( gurgling )
( smith screaming )
( thud )
Now, who the hell are you?
Ahh.
Sergeant kaminsky, sir.
Code name: Smith.
Arrest that man for aiding
and abetting a fugitive.
Get out of the pool, moron.
Eddie, what are we
gonna tell 'em downtown?
Nothin'.
Absolutely...
( moaning )
Where do you think they got to?
Don't suppose we'll ever know.
At least they're together.
Damn shame
about that money, though.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about how you could
throw your take of the loot
Into the--into that abyss.
( whines )
That there's my cut.
So what went down there?
A bag of your dirty laundry.
Switched 'em.
Hope you don't mind.
Are you kiddin'?
I hate to do laundry.
Let's have ourselves a drink.
You'll stick around a while?
No.
I had enough excitement
for a spell.
First light, I'm gonna head on
back to the desert.
Well, you always have
a room here if you want it.
I appreciate that, thoreau.
Wouldn't think
of stayin' anywhere else.
( coyote howls )
Lucille:
Julian.
Julian:
Yes, my love?
( giggles )
Kiss me again.
Man:
♪ old black magic
has me in its spell ♪
Woman:
♪ old black magic
that you weave so well ♪
♪ those icy fingers
up and down my spine ♪
♪ the same old witchcraft
when your eyes meet mine ♪
♪ the same old tingle
that I feel inside ♪
♪ and then that elevator
starts its ride ♪
♪ down and down I go
♪ round and round I go
♪ like a leaf
caught in a tide ♪
♪ I should stay away
♪ but what can I do?
♪ I hear your name
♪ and I'm aflame
♪ aflame with
burnin' desire ♪
♪ and only your kiss
♪ put out the fire
♪ for you're the lover
I have waited for ♪
♪ you're the mate that fate
had me created for ♪
♪ and every time
your lips meet mine ♪
♪ baby
♪ down and down I go
♪ round and round I go
♪ in the spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black
magic called love ♪
♪ oh, in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old
black magic called love ♪
Both:
♪ in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black magic
called love ♪
♪ I should stay away
but what can I do? ♪
♪ I hear your name
and I'm aflame ♪
♪ aflame with
♪ burnin' desire
♪ and only your kiss
♪ put out the fire
♪ oh, you're the lover
I have waited for ♪
♪ you're the mate that fate
had me created for ♪
♪ and every time
your lips meet mine ♪
♪ baby
♪ down and down I go
♪ round and round I go
♪ in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black
magic called love ♪
♪ ah, in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old
black magic called love ♪
♪ in a spin
♪ lovin' the spin I'm in
♪ under the old black magic
called love ♪