Order up!
Where my greens at?
Two more drinks
for table six.
Got it.
- She got fired.
- What'd she do this time?
Well, she was washing dishes
in the kitchen,
but then she told the manager
- she wanted to be a wait...
- Dona?
- Roger.
- Hey, how long you been back?
A couple days.
You look good all changed up.
Thanks.
How you making it?
Yeah, I'm doing all right.
I know your folks
glad to have you back.
Yeah, they are.
Son, can we get our food today?
It's really good seeing you.
You, too.
He's sweet.
Always was.
Why'd you break up with him?
Had things I wanted to do.
Besides, I got a man.
Now, you see how
he taking care of me.
- He must be rich.
- He ain't starving, that's for sure.
- Pssh.
- You guys want a refill?
Oh, yes, thank you.
Y'all should come back with me.
And be a model like you?
You dreaming.
Maybe you ain't dreaming enough.
I ain't even know I was alive
till I went up there.
I'm a country girl
through and through.
Plus, I like eating too much.
I heard that
them New York models
got to have sex with whoever's
doing the hiring.
- That's true?
- Not if you don't want to.
What about you?
I do what I want, when I want.
You come back with me,
you see how it can work.
So, did you hear
about Leon Davidson?
He wrecked his daddy's Mustang.
Drove it right into a ditch.
What? Does Nancy know?
No, girl, I heard
he was with some other girl
he met down in Charlotte.
- Oh, my God, Nancy know?
- Where you going?
- Outside for a little.
- So, did Nancy find out?
Oh, yeah, she is mad at him.
- Hey.
Pretty day.
I guess.
I heard you talking back there.
You a model?
Yeah.
In New York.
New York City?
Damn.
Yeah.
Okay.
Been a while, huh?
- Feel 10 pounds lighter.
- Yeah, I bet you do.
All right, G. l. Joe, up and out.
I need the room.
Mmm, no, I'm not a whoremaster.
Nobody said you were,
but, Vince, come on.
This guy is offering to set us up
with another business!
- Am I right?
- Us?
Whether thou goest...
Wait, is it whether or whither?
What the fuck do I know
about a massage parlor?
So you'll learn.
Or, shit, I'll learn.
All right? I'll be the pussy hound.
All you gotta do
is say yes to Rudy.
It'll be clean work for you.
- Clean work.
- Hey, do you mind?
You should've stayed put at Kim's.
Once you start saying yes
to these guys...
I can say no to Rudy on this.
And I'm gonna.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
little brother, come on.
Just slow down, here.
Let's talk about it.
I got a question for you.
What, you got an opinion
on this, too?
Korean entree. Bi bim blank.
Bap. It's bim bup... Bap.
It's bap.
- Bap?
- B-A-P.
In like Flynn. All right.
I got enough on my hands
with this here.
Which reminds me. Hey.
You put us
into the bar guides yet?
- Thanks.
- Yeah, we're in.
The gay one, too?
What's it called? Michael's Stick?
Michael's Thing.
Whatever.
You know, it might help
if we place a few ads, too.
I checked the rates.
They're not bad for a half-page.
Okay, draw something up.
- Me?
- Yeah.
- I can't draw.
- I thought all you guys were artistic.
I'll do it.
You got the time?
I'll fit it in my schedule.
I know a few of the women now.
They get a little hinky
when their pimps are around,
but if you catch them alone,
they talk.
After that,
I wanna talk to the pimps.
Also alone,
run interviews side by side.
He says, she says.
Contrast and compare.
Black pimps misusing white girls
from wherever?
I can deliver near as many black women
being pimped as white.
Sandra, all we're doing
is reinforcing the stereotypes,
just like those goddamn ghetto flicks
out there now.
Everybody cheering
for the pusherman.
I'm giving you life as lived.
We have Les Matthews for that.
He's got the street stuff covered.
And his copy reads smooth.
But this, it's not news.
- It's not for us.
- Oh, right. Uplift only.
Sorry.
We stand up for our own, Sandra.
At least let me write something longer
and show it to you.
- He's gonna notice money's missing.
- Don't worry about that.
- But how much do I take?
- Just don't give him all of it.
Well, how much?
Excuse me.
Hey. What are you doing
hanging around here?
Waiting for somebody.
I'm flattered, but I'm not gonna get
out of here for hours.
Somebody else.
Mystery date?
Mystery to you, maybe.
Hey, what can I get you?
I'm looking for Abby.
She works here.
Uh-huh. Abby.
Hey, Evan.
Is that it?
That's him.
That's what I said.
Okay. See you later.
I got your camera back from Darryl.
Cool. I've been missing it.
Keep it for me.
Hey, you two kids
have a swell time, okay?
Hey.
Think he's good-looking?
He's not my type.
Yeah, well, pretend you're her.
He's nothing special.
Yeah, exactly.
Oh, Jesus, Eileen.
Let me... Let me do it.
Oh. Like that?
Yeah. Yes, just like that.
- Yeah.
- Oh.
Oh.
Oh, Oh! Oh.
Did you come?
- I don't think I'm quite ready.
- Sure, you are.
No, I'm not.
Eileen, seriously, I'm not.
So, did you come that time?
I told you three.
You told me three last night.
Every night three.
Till Darlene gets back, the two of you
are gonna have to start
making up for the losses.
Where the hell is Darlene, anyway?
You do not need to concern yourself
with where Darlene at.
She on a mission for me.
Hell, send me on a mission.
- Oh, you gonna start bitching, too?
- $400.
Can we put that toward tomorrow?
Hey, that's what
I'm talking about.
You start busting it like that,
you could take a whole snow day.
I'll make it up tomorrow.
Come on, Larry.
My feet are killing me.
You in pain?
Then you should learn
to walk on your hands, bitch.
What you honking at?
Shut up!
I never said that.
That was different.
For you, maybe.
Yeah. I guess for me, yeah.
All's well that ends well, right?
You're different.
How so?
Well, I meant that
as a compliment.
Okay.
But how did you mean it?
As a good thing.
Good how?
I'm fucking with you, Jack.
Jesus.
Listen, what are you doing
Saturday night?
My boss is having
a get-together at his place,
hors d'oeuvres, cocktails.
Come on, it'll be fun.
Gotta see how my week's going.
Where are you going?
I got an early morning tomorrow.
Oh, okay, well, maybe next time,
we'll stay at your place.
It'd be nice to sleep in the same bed
and have some breakfast.
Yeah.
But now I gotta go.
Oh, um, at least
let me get you a cab.
- No, no, I got money.
- No, really.
Such a gentleman.
I graduate and I'm looking at
a bad number.
- Really bad.
- Party's a bummer.
We should find a movie.
- How bad?
- 74.
No way I stay clear of the draft board
with a number that low.
- You seen that book they got, 4-F?
- Yeah, read every page.
Shit, I'm hoping McGovern can get in
and end the fucking war.
Me, too.
So, why the army jacket?
Irony.
- Everybody wears them.
- Everybody's ironic, huh?
I was thinking of going for
a creative writing master's next year,
but when I told
my father, he said,
"Anybody who'd write a poem
would suck a dick."
You should look into the copyrighting
program at the B school.
This way, you get to write
and get paid for it.
How about you, Abs?
When are you coming back to school?
You're a barmaid, right?
Hey, if I stick with it,
a year from now,
I'll get promoted to mermaid.
Seriously, I...
I don't see what the big deal is.
So, Play Misty for Me
or Straw Dogs?
Show of hands.
So, my theory is with fucking,
the men are always
wanting more, more, more, more, right?
And the women are like, "More?
You fucking kidding me?"
So, when it comes to frequency,
lesbians, both being women,
they do it the least, right?
So, they get the bronze.
Straights, one of each now,
it's "Push me, pull you."
But still, it's worth a silver.
But with you people,
it's all dick all the time, right?
No one gets a headache.
Just dick, dick, dick,
dick, dick, dick, dick!
I mean, you're like
the fucking East German track team.
You get a gold fucking medal
every time you hear the gun go off.
It's a little more complicated
than that.
Yeah, bullshit.
But you wanna know
why I'm not gay?
Not enough holes.
Mr. Martimo.
- Vincent.
- The usual?
Yeah, a short one.
And the courtesy
of your reply to my employer.
Well, I appreciate
the faith you put in me,
even making the offer.
But?
I thought about it.
I did, Tommy,
and it's not for me.
Look, everything they go through...
I got a lot of respect
for those girls.
But running them?
A parlor?
I don't know the first thing about it,
and I don't want to.
Hmm.
Are you telling me
I can't say no to Rudy Pipilo?
Of course you can.
It's, uh... It's an opportunity
he's offering, is all.
If you wanna pass, you pass.
All right, well, just tell him
I'm putting everything I have
into building up this joint for him.
- All right?
- He'll hear that.
All right, we'll see ya, Vince.
What?
And he's got the world
so ordered in his Nixon brain.
He loses his mind if someone new
parks in the driveway.
Shit, we missed the nine o'clock's,
but we can still make
a late show, though.
Misty is 11:20.
No, but they're all on that
fucked up frequency, though.
I had to throw
everything I had at my father
just to get him
to back down from law school.
Straw Dogs, 11:40.
I gotta go.
What, you don't
wanna come see the movie?
Nope.
Hey.
You Okay?
You should go back in.
Thanks for my camera.
Surrender or die!
Die, die,
you Amerikaner "schwine"!
Hey, I told you to cut that shit.
Not in the goddamn house.
I'm trying to think here.
Come... Come on, Joey!
Take it upstairs.
Christ, go drive
your mom nuts for a while, all right?
Die, die!
Surrender or die.
I die for "zhe" fatherland.
Turn around.
Hey, Frankie, over here!
This is what you bring back?
How old are you?
- Twenty.
- "Twenty."
Twenty going on 16.
God damn it, Darlene!
I told you to bring back somebody
who was street ready,
not this chocolate Gidget
gonna get me sent to Rikers.
Put her back on the bus.
Look, she here, Larry.
She need a job.
Then drop her ass off
at the McDonald's
or the Calico Kitchen
or Childs.
But now that I think about it,
Childs is the right place
for this one right here.
"Street ready"?
- I can explain.
- I get it.
I'll tell you one thing, though.
I ain't finna get back
on that bus.
You like the movie?
Want some company?
- Give me the third one.
- Okay.
With wheat toast. Thank you.
Two eggs over easy,
bacon, and wheat toast.
So, you ever done
any real modeling?
You gonna eat them fries?
Come on, mama,
let's get it going, sweetheart.
Three eggs scrambled,
ham, home fries...
- Hey.
- In the van, sweet pea.
- Whoa, on what charge?
- Hey, come on.
- Soliciting.
- Who did I solicit?
- My partner here.
- This is total crap, guys.
Be that as it may,
get your faggot ass in the van.
Let's go, let's go.
You, too, get in there.
Make room.
I mean, it's gonna
get done, right?
Them guineas are gonna do it
whether or not we say.
I already said no.
You were there, you heard.
You can't change your mind?
Let me get this straight,
you, with all the seniority
in the world,
union card since you were 18,
married to my sister,
fucking rug rats
all over the house,
Mr. Bay Ridge himself,
you're gonna run whores
for the fucking wise guys?
You fucking hate
those guys, remember?
They beat one of your people
last month.
Fucking tore into me
like my name was Gambino or something.
Now you're gonna work
for them?
Doing this?
Give me a fucking break.
I go back to a job site,
doctors say I'll stroke out
within a year.
That's what they say.
I need money, Vince.
You're not doing this so you can
go pussy hound on me, right?
I mean, my sister finds out...
Fuck you think of me, Vince?
I wouldn't poke those girls
with your dick.
But if it's true what they're saying,
that the whole thing's
fixed with the city?
Yeah. Which might be bullshit.
If it's true, then this could be
a lot of fucking money.
And I understand
how you feel about running whores,
but me, I look on it
like if it's me,
I'm gonna be better
than some asshole
who ain't even gonna try to be fair.
I mean, I've been a supervisor, right?
I made shop steward at 26.
You gonna rep these girls, Bobby?
What are you gonna do,
get them to work the contract?
Time-and-a-half on weekends?
Come on, Vince.
You'll see the money's right
and front to Rudy and them,
but I'll take care
of everything else.
I will.
Fuck you.
She said she's 20.
Looked like jailbait.
Fifteen would not surprise me.
Fake ID, homeslice.
Ain't no thing.
Maybe. All the same,
I don't need another child to support.
Start calling you Charlie Brown.
- Good grief, motherfucker.
- Plus, she's gonna be a lot of work.
I mean, like,
from the ground up type work.
Shit, I'll take her off your hands.
You want her, you buy her.
She a looker?
Eye of the beholder.
Bring her to Leon's.
I like what I see,
I'll throw you 2K
and maybe a player
to be named later.
Mmm-mmm, you too good.
Keep your Mayer-
Two five.
Hey, so how'd the big date
go last night?
It went.
Hi-Hat.
Hey, Paul, we're slammed over here.
Where the fuck are you?
Oh, well, I'm honored that
I was your only phone call.
No, fuck it. It's cool.
Yeah, I'm on it. All right.
Mike, can you do me a favor?
Can you go over
to the 14th station house,
bail out our bartender?
Okay.
Did I say you could do that?
Relax. Just a hobby.
I'm working on something.
Yeah, well, work on making me
another Jack and Coke instead.
Have you ever had a job, Reggie?
You think this ain't a job?
I see Shay and Melissa
doing all the work.
I don't know
exactly what it is you do
except count the cash
and treat them like shit.
Well, what you don't know
about me would fill a library.
You think I don't know your type?
- Shit, I read you like a comic book.
- All right, Reg.
Which is not to say
that I don't admire
those pert little nay-nays
you got in that onesie
you wearing.
I'm not serving you.
Shit.
Girl take my picture without asking
and then won't fix my drink?
I feel downright exploited.
Hey, how about both of you
back this bullshit up, all right?
Vince, you ain't heard the news?
Sexism's out.
If you want pussy nowadays,
treat it equal.
Ain't that right, Miss Chrissy?
Well, now...
Don't start
the revolution without me.
Too late. Shit's already started.
Hey, man, you best
hit that shit before I do.
Where the fuck
did that come from?
Just taking a fucking picture.
This is a bar.
Look like an art studio?
You like to watch?
Yeah?
Oh, mother...
Get the fuck off me!
I want the money.
The money!
Where's the money?
Okay, I'll give it to you!
I'll give it to you!
Just don't hurt me.
Get it.
All Of it.
Just wait here.
Motherfucking piece of shit!
You bitch!
Hendrickson, Paul.
Here.
Big mistake
every time, you know?
Hey, thanks.
These fucking cops
and their bullshit rousts.
You know?
We should go.
No humanity in these motherfuckers.
- Am I right?
- Such a lovely couple.
Better watch
your mouth there, slick.
No stitches.
Well, maybe just
a butterfly bandage will do.
Oh, probably don't even need that.
You're lucky.
Lucky me.
You just let it go like this?
Sure. Why not?
They need to make a living, too.
What he means to say
is the timing's all wrong.
- Timing for what?
- For OT.
A lot of guys on 4:00-12:00s
don't get serious about pross collars
until around 11:00 or 11:30.
You work past shift, you make
time-and-a-half on the overage.
Because?
Because you go home,
sleep a few hours,
and then you're in court
the next morning.
Pick up eight hours
of time-and-a-half
that you can bank
for vacation if you want.
I'm guessing the charges don't stick.
Girls are back on the street
by breakfast.
There was this dude
in Greek mythology
that the gods punished
by making him roll a boulder
up the side of a mountain,
only to see it come back down
the other side.
So, he had to do it
again and again and again.
That'd be Sisyphus,
except he didn't get paid
each time he made it up to the top.
Meaning what?
- Never mind.
- I earn my money.
What, you think you can
have us drive you around
and just say any snide shit
that comes in your head?
You have no idea
what we have to deal with around here.
- Sorry.
- I earn my money.
- Got it.
- Are you hungry?
I could eat.
Drop us off at Leon's.
Gladly.
Hey.
Thanks for tolerating
my back and forth on this.
Hey, you like to think things through.
That's a good way to be.
So, with the girls,
the cops, your weekly nut,
what's gonna be left for us?
Plenty. And if I'm wrong about that,
we'll adjust my end.
I'm not greedy, Vincent.
I make money, you make money,
just like the bar.
You're saying that this is
all fixed with the city?
They want this.
They want as much
shit off the street as they can get.
They're offering
five locations like this one.
We make this one work,
there's gonna be plenty
right behind it.
- You'll see.
- Yeah, so no raids, no arrests.
There's a raid
now and then for show.
We'll know it's coming.
You and your people
take the night off,
kick back up the next day.
This is gonna spread me a little thin.
But you're okay
if I bring in Bobby?
He'd run the shop and I'd give him
Black Frankie on the door.
Who you hire is your decision.
You're in charge of your own, Vince.
I'm not gonna interfere.
As long as the money's right,
I don't care.
Yeah, well, this shithole's
gonna need work to get it
where it needs to be.
Well, that's my cost,
but nothing too fancy.
I mean, make it classy,
but keep it simple.
- Classy but simple.
- Yeah.
Well, I guess Bobby
could handle construction.
Two things.
You're gonna wanna rig
some kind of back entrance
so guys can come and go
without being seen from the street.
- And also a VIP room.
- VIP?
For spenders, you know.
There needs to be
a little high-end in the place.
Yeah, not everything in life
is a $20 drip job, you know.
- Oh.
- You made a good decision here, Vince.
- This is gonna be real good.
- See ya, Vince.
Penny for your fucking thoughts.
Someone gonna sell the pussy,
someone gonna buy the pussy.
We're just landing the cut, man.
Right.
She don't get out the house much
'cause she got arthritis
and everything.
Doctor doesn't give her
any painkillers?
Yeah, but she's stubborn.
- You know him?
- Richie?
Sure.
- You don't want him.
- Why not?
Richie is not exactly
the typical mack.
One time, I brought his girl in
for beating on him.
- Guess I need a better pimp, huh?
- Mmm-hmm.
Most of the guys
just give me the stink eye.
Don't worry, they'll start talking.
They love to hear themselves talk.
I was hoping maybe you could make
some introductions.
Maybe.
I'll look into it.
You know, I've been reading
about the testimony
that went over
to the Knapp Commission,
what's coming out now,
all that stuff about the pad.
Well, that guy was in Queens, mostly,
working narcotics.
Anyway, it's supposed
to be widespread.
They're saying whole precincts.
So they say.
Is it true? The pad?
I wouldn't know.
I mean, I just thought
you were so up front about the OT...
All I know is what
I read in the paper, just like you.
I'm done. You?
You're getting too agitated.
How do you want your eggs?
Got it.
Record your message now.
Hey, I'm just calling to say
what a great time I had
with you the other night.
Uh, really great.
I feel like we're starting
to get to know each other a little.
Um...
l hope you feel the same.
And I also wanna check in,
see if you had any more of a handle
on coming to the party
with me Saturday night.
Okay, call me when you can.
Bye.
- Kind of young, ain't she?
- Mind your business.
One order up.
Two eggs, mesh, bacon.
This is Rodney.
You're with him now.
- What now?
- Think of yourself as a ballplayer.
They get traded all the time.
I'm Bernice.
Ruby. She Tiffany.
- Ruby?
- That's my name, Rodney.
It wouldn't kill you
to use it every now and then.
Yeah, all right.
He broke you in yet?
Break me in?
Rodney, you're embarrassing her.
If she the embarrassing type,
she in the wrong line of work.
I'm all right.
That's good.
One thing, though.
Ain't nobody wanna fuck a girl
named Bernice.
Pickup for Maria.
I think I'ma call you Ginger.
Everybody, say hello to Ginger.
You don't like it?
Not really.
Well, it's better than Ruby.
Ain't that right, Thunderthighs?
Get your hand out of my face.
How many girls
are we talking about?
Fuck do I know?
Well, they each need a room, right?
What kind of bed?
Fuck do I know?
And a john?
They each need a bathroom
or they go out to use the toilet?
Fuck do I know?
We put locks on their doors?
- Fuck do I know, Bobby?
- On the inside of the doors.
Do we want them locking themselves in
with the customers?
Fuck do I fucking know?
You're not much help here.
Sorry.
Don't worry, fucko.
I got this surrounded.
Great.
I can't believe Art didn't wanna come.
He loves to dance.
I didn't invite him.
This hide-and-seek game
that he plays with his job, I'm done.
You mean the job
that pays your rent.
- Whose side are you on?
- Honey, I'm Switzerland.
I'm just pointing out
that it might be easier to be out
when you serve cocktails
to old queens for a living.
Fuck it, I wanna be in the world.
So, when's Art moving out?
As soon as I can afford my own rent.
- He's with me.
- Okay.
Jesus, three dollars
just to go dancing
and they don't even have beers?
No booze, no liquor license,
no raids, and no mob owners.
- And no profit.
- Sweetheart,
some things are
more important than the bottom line.
Love saves the day.
Hey, Daddy.
Looking for a date?
Hey there, Candy girl.
CoverGirl shit don't quite do it.
What are you,
a fashion photographer?
No, though I'll say this,
it don't look as bad as that
ass whooping you took last Christmas.
- Girl, you looked a mess that time.
- Rodney.
- Yeah?
- I'm working.
Yeah, about that...
I always wondered
how you gave head with a busted jaw.
Or turn tricks
with that cast on your arm.
No, wait, that was another time.
Uh, April maybe. May.
That one had you
over at Lenox Hill if I recall.
Fuck off.
Oh, no, no, mama.
Okay, now, wait a minute, now.
See, you got me all wrong.
I ain't out here to bust on you, baby.
It's just that you keep
expecting better,
but you keep getting worse.
I mean, you go it alone.
come the dark hour, you are alone.
May I?
Now, what could be
more lonely than that?
So, what are you offering?
Next time I get my ass kicked,
I can cry on your shoulder?
What's the cut you take for that?
Ain't gonna be no next time
you come with me.
I'ma have your back
everywhere you go, baby.
Aw, no, no, no.
See here. No, no, look.
Look here, baby.
Or maybe next time you hook up
with some hacky sack,
wack-ass motherfucker...
...we'll need to come by after
and sweep up what's left of you
from under the bed,
take it out to the cemetery
in a cereal box.
You and me out here...
You kidding me?
I'm talking world-famous, baby.
Mmm.
You like that, huh?
Give your number
to my secretary.
See, what always
fucked me up about you was
what the hell some high-class acting,
movie-looking individual
was doing down here
to begin with, huh?
Walking around here,
smiling down your nose at everybody
like some cream filled,
tiara wearing
"I shit beige" bitch
- got everything under control.
- Rodney, Rodney.
Everything and everybody
all under control.
Rodney, why don't you
just hop back into that piece of shit
- pimp chariot of yours...
- Look at your face.
...and drive into a fucking wall!
Hoping to slob a johnson tonight
for not enough money, baby.
- You don't control shit down here!
- And you do?
Now that I think on it, baby,
that high-post act of yours
has got to make you
the saddest, "pathetic-est,"
craziest bitch on this stroll.
- I'm the craziest?
- What happened, Candy?
Daddy have his way with you
back in the day?
Yeah, you don't know shit.
Pass you around
to his drinking buddies?
- You don't fucking know shit.
- I don't have to.
You the one need to do the knowing.
Whoa!
- Bro, did you see that one?
- You like that?
All that woman all to myself?
Hell, yeah!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Paul?
Yeah, it's me.
- Who's that?
- My roommate.
- Is he cute?
- Yeah, he's cute, all right.
Does he want to join us?
Mmm, maybe.
Hello.
Hi.
Sorry if we woke you.
You didn't.
Would you like to join us?
You have some catching up to do.
Hey, you free?
Wow. You are beautiful.
How much?
How much, sweetheart?
What the fuck?
Hey, you think
you're better than me, huh?
Right on.
Yeah, well, they talk about it, right?
That sound... How do they get it
and keep it so consistent?
What's the secret sauce?
Well, here's the secret.
Ain't no sauce, brother.
It's the pipes.
- Voice pipes?
- No, man.
Pipes, pipes. Pipes in the building.
See, they sing
all that shit downstairs
and record it upstairs.
Smokey, Stevie, and all them killers.
They voice go through the ducts
and pick up the soul
of the place on the way.
Ain't no expensive
recording equipment,
ain't no high-tech bullshit.
- Just pure innovation.
- There you go.
And see, that's what separates us
from the white man.
See, we can turn
a dime into a dollar just like that.
And why?
That's all they gave us, baby.
Berry Gordy, for real.
"Make do with what you got."
- It's what we do, brah.
- That's the genius of the race.
Listen, I've been
talking to a reporter.
- Mmm.
- Doing a story on the street trade.
She want to rap.
You say rap,
I hear "enrapment."
Right? She comes out here,
catches a little naughty business,
and then your people pull up,
and there goes Reggie Love,
dumbest mack on Earth.
- Man, would I do you like that?
- Shit.
She just wants to write
what goes on down here.
Tell it straight.
Let me ask, is she that
uppity afro queen
I seen you with?
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, Officer Alston
just trying to get on her good side,
so he could jump that thing.
Coming to Reggie Love talking about
some, "She just wants to write
"about what's going on down here."
Ooh, telling it real.
Man, are you in or not?
Well, it might be bad for business
if people see me
talking to a reporter.
Well, it might be bad for business
if I go through
your pockets right now.
See? You catch more flies
with honey, what I heard.
Shit.
She want to know about my game?
Man, somebody should write a book.
Oh, my God, just...
- Oh, don't stop, baby.
- Yeah.
Oh, baby, just keep going.
Oh, God, right there.
Right there.
Not yet, not yet, not yet.
No, no, don't,
don't, don't, don't stop.
I'm so close.
Finished without me?
Sorry, babe.
I got nothing left.
Make sure you get
the money up front.
- All right.
- Rodney ain't as bad as the others,
but you gotta bring in your piece.
You keep getting took, shit gets bad.
What kind of bad?
Abby, baby.
Come meet Bernice.
Abby works at the Hi-Hat
just down there.
Place jumps till late.
You new in town?
Just came up from Carolina.
She know Darlene.
Actually, we just met down there.
But I do know
some of her cousins, though, so.
Ah.
Well, uh, welcome to New York.
- How is Darlene down there?
- What?
You saw her down in Carolina.
How is she doing back home?
She here. She come back with me.
So, what kind of bad?
Count it if you need to.
What's wrong with her now?
Oh, had an encounter out there.
An encounter, huh? Just one?
We need some time alone here.
Here you go.
How come she don't
gotta wear the leotard no more?
The elastic was chaffing.
Oh, yeah? Well, mine, too.
Hey, that's the uniform.
Wear it or walk.
You, too.
What?
- It's our trademark.
- Ah.
- What can I get you?
- Gin, please.
Gin.
Did you see your family?
I stayed with a cousin.
What about your parents?
If I went to see them, they'd probably
want money or something.
- Why?
- I don't know.
They think I owe them
for being born or some shit.
- Welcome back, Darlene.
- Thank you.
I wish I could go home,
just for a night.
- What for?
- Kill some people.
You seen any of the new
Saint Laurents?
No.
I don't know
what the big deal is.
Most of them look boring to me,
but there's this green fur I like.
No.
She said she was leaving.
Can't believe I fell for that.
Who?
Darlene.
Larry's girl.
She left. Now she's back.
Why?
Maybe she likes her life
the way it is.
You ever think of that?
The way he controls her?
Did your daddy
pay for your college?
- So what?
- Oh, but then I heard you quit.
Is he still helping you out?
Paying your rent and shit?
- No way.
- Mmm-hmm.
Daddies, husbands, and pimps,
they're all the same.
They love you for who you are
until you try to be someone else.
At least pimps are up front about it.
Yeah, that's, um...
I'm a little surprised you called.
Tell you the truth,
we have a lot of the same questions.
Except for a few.
I want you to meet Reggie Love.
Reggie Love.
Your name rings out.
Yeah, I cut a wide swath in Midtown.
Sandra Washington, Amsterdam News.
Thought you was with The Times.
Reggie Love does not play
in the rec leagues.
I'm sorry, I thought
Officer Alston had...
Why didn't you tell him
that I work for...
Reggie Love is fucking with you.
I'll leave you to it.
You know my fee, right?
- Twenty an hour?
- Twenty?
You see me in coveralls,
cow shit on my shoes?
Forty.
Time is money, baby.
Pretty girl like you
gots to know that, right?
That the first rule of pimping?
First rule of pimping
is look a man in his eyes
when you're talking to him.
- Got it.
- Mmm.
Forty.
She got you all fucked up, partner.
I can see.
- She's in your head.
- It's just a favor.
Yeah.
Whoa!
You know, it's customary
to signal your intentions
before pulling your vehicle
into traffic, Officer Flan-a-gan.
It's customary
to signal your intentions
before licking my hairy Irish ass,
Officer Haddix.
Sweeney took the day tomorrow,
so juice flows today.
He wanted to get to you before
you went end of tour and missed him.
All right? Behave yourselves.
Guys are fucking testifying
on this shit downtown,
and this assholes tossing envelopes
around in the street.
Guess they figure the worst is over.
That's what I heard.
From who?
Steaks tonight. Tad's, maybe?
- I might have dinner plans.
- Oh, shit.
So, Why'd you change your mind?
So, what, you got anything?
Or there's still no film
in the camera?
Matter of fact,
there's been a change.
What kind of change?
In the law.
Or the way they're reading it.
That's what my lawyer
is telling me.
Something about community standards.
What about community standards?
Apparently, New York has none.
So, you're back to filming?
When do we start?
From the looks of it,
you might need a couple weeks.
How's Wednesday after next?
Great.
- Hey, Ralphie.
- Hey, Bobby.
- Oh, that looks good.
- Yeah, thank you.
I figured about two foot per person,
so that's room for five, maybe six.
- Right here?
- Yeah, looks fine.
Your guys do good work.
As always, pays to go with the union.
Anyway, here's for the real action.
We fill the bowl with water
so the girls can...
I get it. I got it.
Anyway, by the end of the month,
the only thing will be missing
will be women.
All right.
I'll talk to Frankie,
he can talk it up
with the pimps he plays cards with.
Okay.
I gotta get home, your sister's got
some kind of Tupperware festival
happening tonight.
Later, Vin.
Here.