- What do you want?
- I got a writ I need you to sign.
What kind of writ?
I need the release of a prisoner
from San Luis to help me in a case.
- Must be a big case.
- The target's a major counterfeiter...
- ... involved in the murder of a federal agent.
- I never sign such writs.
Why are you still here?
I spent all morning on this.
I would appreciate it if you would be
kind enough to look at it.
Okay. Now I've looked at it.
Look, I gotta have this guy out.
Didn't you come in here about a week ago
and ask me to hold him without bail?
Yes, and I'll assume full responsibility
for getting him back.
I don't need the headache.
Cody is an associate of Rick Masters.
Masters has been making a mockery out
of you, me and this whole system.
That doesn't change the fact that he's on
a no-bail hold awaiting arraignment.
He killed my partner, man.
The answer is still no.
If I was one of your cronies...
...you'd be spread-eagle on your desk
to do this for me.
Don't say something you'll regret later.
Come back here!
Let me look at it again.
If this prisoner escapes from custody...
...I'll make you testify in open court
about how he made a fool out of you.
Now get the hell out of here.
If you cross me, I will dedicate
my life to putting you back in here...
...and I will make sure you do
all five. You got that?
You have my promise.
I wanna know where Masters prints
and I want you to take me there now.
Then we're going downtown
to swear out your statement.
- Can I ask a favor?
- What?
My daughter's in the hospital.
She's pretty sick.
Do you think we could stop by
Santa Fe Hospital?
It's on the way
to where I'm taking you.
- You're pulling my dick.
- I swear, man. Check it out.
- What's your daughter's name?
- Rozanne Brown.
Lincoln 14-3-1
to Los Angeles base, over.
Go ahead, 3-1.
Yeah. Request you phone
Santa Fe Hospital.
Find out if they have a patient
named Rozanne Brown, please. Over.
Roger.
You have any kids?
Well, I tell you, it changes
the way you look at things.
Yeah?
I'm not looking to screw up anymore.
Rozanne Brown is in room 306.
The elevators are over there.
Thank you.
You have to come up
to the room with me?
Come here.
- What happened to your daughter?
- She was in a park, and this little monkey-
Rozanne Brown is a black woman.
She's recuperating from a fall
she took from a bicycle near USC.
She's married. Her husband is listed
as serving time...
...for armed robbery
at San Luis Obispo Prison.
Thanks.
I think you ought to let us
take a look at you.
I don't have a lot of time.
I'm in the middle of a trial.
- What kind of trial?
- It's a dope case.
A client got busted smuggling
50 pounds of cocaine.
I should be able to get him off.
The search warrant's weak.
Weak?
The color of the house is listed as brown
on the warrant...
...when, in fact, it's beige and yellow.
You should be ashamed
of yourself.
I don't make any apologies
for being an attorney.
If I didn't accept the case, somebody else
would without a doubt.
Without a doubt.
It's too bad about Jim Hart.
Masters has been calling me
in the middle of the night...
...trying to order me around
like I was one of his mules.
The other day he even had
the balls to threaten me.
The man's an animal.
Frankly, being house counsel
for Rick Masters...
...doesn't sit very well with me.
I've had it up to here,
as a matter of fact.
Good for you.
How bad do you and your friend
want him?
I don't have to explain
what would happen...
...if there was even a hint that
I set up one of my own clients.
Aren't you afraid
you'll wind up on his hit list?
- It crossed my mind.
- Your name will never come up.
- You never met Rick, have you?
- No.
I'll set up a meeting.
Mr. Masters?
How you doing? Ben Jessup.
- My associate, Dr. George Victor.
- A pleasure. How do you do?
Cut yourself shaving,
Mr. Jessup?
No. As a matter of fact,
I got hit by a tennis ball.
- You're in from Palm Springs, huh?
- Yeah.
- What's the weather like there?
- It's really nice.
We've been up here
the last few days.
I've got a friend in Palm Springs,
Lenny Green.
He owns the Oasis.
Do you know him?
I got a friend in Hollywood,
Donald Duck. You know him?
I understand you gentlemen
do some island banking.
- That's right.
- Where?
Cayman Islands.
- Good business?
- Not bad.
What sort of banking?
We're a Dutch Antilles company.
We loan money to various
enterprises here in the States.
Loans aren't secured by real estate
or anything else down there.
Hey, Rick, you got a phone call, man.
Which one is it?
There's nothing in there.
Some tennis rackets
in the trunk...
...men's clothing with Palm Springs
store labels...
...some business letters with return
addresses in the Cayman Islands.
What did the letters say?
Something about "Please forward the stock
we discussed," or something like that.
Who were the letters addressed to?
Caribbean Banking Unlimited,
Dutch Antilles.
Did you notice the names Jessup
or Victor on any of the letters?
- No.
- Okay.
Thanks.
What kind of paper
are we talking about?
Hundreds and 50s paper. We need
at least 10 different serial numbers.
- How much?
- A million dollars.
How you going to use it?
What business is that of yours?
It's always my business,
Mr. Jessup.
Nothing will be passed up here.
Our play involves a gentleman who wishes
to launder bonds, protect his tax position.
My end is 20 percent.
We never pay more than 10. We have
limitations that we have to abide by.
Different serial numbers are
a real pain in the ass for me.
I gotta make different plates and wear
rubber gloves during the whole operation.
Have you ever tried to work
with rubber gloves on?
Fifteen percent.
I don't negotiate.
I might if I knew you, but I don't.
And I don't like what I see.
All right.
I start as soon as
I get a down payment.
In this case, I'll take
30,000 up front...
- ... and the rest on delivery.
- What?
Everybody knows Rick Masters
won't go near a job without front money.
You should also know that I've never
fucked a customer out of his front money.
I've been coming to this gym three
or four times a week for five years.
I'm an easy man to find.
My reputation speaks for itself.
The fact is, that if you can't
come up with the front money...
...you're not for real.
No way I can get you
30 K to make a buy.
You'd hear laughter
all the way from Washington.
Masters beats the government
out of that much in a day.
We've got a chance for a hand-to-hand
buy which he cannot beat in court.
You're not the first agents
to get next to Masters.
He always asks for big front money.
Nobody ever approves it,
and he stays on the street.
The limit for buys is 10 grand.
I don't make the rules.
Look, you could get this
approved if you wanted to.
302.5.
- What?
-302.5.
You violated section 302.5.
The manual says:
"The agents must notify
the agent in charge"...
...that's me, "of all
ongoing investigations. "
You violated this section, and
I'm not gonna cover your ass.
- Yeah, well, I'm not asking you to.
- You lost a federal prisoner!
And I want Cody back!
Where the hell were you?
- He wasn't with me, all right?
- Why not?
Look, I lost him.
I'll get him back.
Thank you, Gilbert.
I think we should have offered
Masters the 10 grand.
- I bet he'd have gone for it.
- Never happen, Johnny.
Let me try something on you.
Yeah, what?
Ruth tells me there's a guy coming in
Thursday to buy stolen diamonds.
He's gonna be carrying
$50,000 cash.
So?
So, what do you think?
What do I think about what?
The guy comes in Thursday,
Union Station.
No muss, no fuss.
If everything doesn't look like
a piece of cake, we just walk away.
- Jesus! You gotta be kidding.
- When you came to me, I told you...
...that I was gonna get Masters
and I didn't give a shit how I did it.
- So now you want to commit a robbery?
- I wouldn't call it that.
What would you call it?
Taking down a douche bag
who's trying to break the law.
- If it turns to shit?
- We say, "Fuck it," walk away.
The front money is the only way
to get Masters to print.
I don't give a shit. I won't pull a heist.
I don't care.
- He's a fence.
- Who do you think I am?
If he gets ripped off,
he can't call the police.
Why don't you just blow his brains out?
That's what you want to do anyway.
All I'm asking you to do is drive the car.
Steal real money to buy counterfeit
money? How's that gonna look in court?
- His word against ours.
- His lawyer is Bob Grimes.
- It's Masters' word against ours.
- You got a couple of screws loose, pal.
Listen, I say we go to Bateman
one more time.
Oh, fuck Bateman. He's a pencil-neck.
He's out to save his ass.
I think you're pushing it too fast. We can-
It's happening Thursday.
We gotta go down in 24 hours.
My father was a cop, brother's a cop.
You're ask-
Give me a break!
You got the wrong guy, okay?
You got the wrong guy.
You're right I got the wrong guy, pal.
You ain't my partner.
You ain't even my fucking friend.
Let me give you a piece of advice:
You better get into protection...
...because you ain't shit on
the street, you understand?
You ain't got the nuts!
Kiss my ass!
Pussy motherfucker.
How sure is this thing tomorrow?
- You said you weren't interested.
- Well, now I am interested, okay?
All I know is what I told you.
He's on the number 11 Amtrak leaving
San Francisco 7:00 in the morning...
...getting into Union Station
at 4:35.
How do you remember that?
You wrote it down or what?
Who's the seller?
A guy I know.
What did this guy you know
tell you?
That a Chinaman comes down
from San Francisco...
...buys diamonds, gold, whatever.
What's his name?
Ling. Thomas Ling.
What's your end?
- Nothing. Just a guy I know tells me things.
- A guy you know.
A guy you know actually gives you
the train the buyer's coming in on?
Of course not.
I called Amtrak
and got his reservation.
Why?
Why did you do that?
ID and $1.50.
You were planning on having someone
else take him down, is that right?
Thought about it.
- Why are you suddenly interested?
- It fits some other shit that's happening.
- You gonna bag him?
- I might.
How you gonna do it if he's carrying
real cash and hasn't committed a crime?
I can do whatever I want.
How much is in this for me?
How much of what?
Don't shit me.
I know what you're gonna do.
And they're gonna think I set it up.
- All right. I'll give you 5 G's.
- Not enough.
And my promise not
to throw you back in the joint.
Mr. Thomas Ling, please come
to passenger services.
Passenger Thomas Ling,
arriving on Amtrak 708...
...please come
to passenger services.
I'm Thomas Ling.
- You know what this is?
- What's the game?
- It's no game. Just walk.
- Why?
Why? Because if you don't
I'll blow your fucking heart out.
- Where's the key?
- I don't have it.
He doesn't have it. What a guy.
Over the chain.
Come on, get over the chain!
Grab the wall. Right there.
Hold him.
Damn it!
Fucker!
Come on, man. What the fuck?
We got people all over the fucking place!
That's very funny.
Look, he doesn't have the money!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Where is it?
Son of a bitch, move one more muscle
and I'll blow your brains out!
You got that? Freeze!
Get down on your fucking knees!
Put your hands
behind your fucking head!
Goddamn it.
You're wearing it, ain't you?
Get your clothes off.
Come on, two hands!
Take your shirt off!
Ah, that's great.
- That's it.
- Get your pants down.
- What?! Let's get the fuck out of here!
Fuck. Shit.
- You all right?
- Oh, Christ.
Let's get out of here. Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Come on. Come on!
Come on!
- You hit?
- I don't know. I don't think so.
- Look out, for God's sake!
- Get them out of there, Johnny!
- Move the truck!
- What are you doing? Trying to hurt-
Shut up! Whose ever truck that is,
move it out of the way now!
Back it up, Steve, back it up!
Look out!
- Get out of there!
- You fucking assholes!
Go left!
Hold on. Hold on!
- I think we lost the mothers.
- I don't see them, man.
I don't see them.
You fucking did it, man!
- We made it, baby!
- We did it!
Goddamn it, we did it!
Oh, shit! You had me scared
out of my fucking mind, man.
You had me scared out of my fucking-
Sons of bitches!
- Is it the same guy?
- It's two different guys.
It's two Chevys!
What the hell is going on?
- Who the fuck are these guys?
- They're all over the place.
Hang on. Hang on, Johnny!
Piece of cake, huh? You son of a bitch!
Cap one off, Johnny.
Get them off of me!
They're all over the place.
We're going this way.
Get the fuck out of here!
Fucking asshole!
- Look out!
- Crazy fucking asshole.
Hold it!
Shut up!
Get out of the way!
Get out of there!
Oh, my God!
Get out of the way!
God, no!
There's a minor tie-up on the north
Long Beach right near Henry Ford.
A couple cars tangled there. Shouldn't
take too long to get this to the shoulder.
It's a very simple affair,
no injuries involved.
It shouldn't cost more than a few minutes
if you're heading north on the 710.
I'm Stacey Binn
for Metro Traffic Control.
What are we gonna do?!
We're going to an auto-parts
store and get a new window.
If we'd have totaled it,
we'd have been screwed.
We'd never have gotten it back
to the motor pool.
We lucked out, Johnny!
We lucked out!
Listen, I'll have to get back to you, okay?
- What happened? I called you all day.
- Clockwork, baby.
Like fucking clockwork.
Did you hear anything?
My friend called. He said
the Chinaman never showed up.
He sure didn't.
God, 50,000 bucks.
Fuck. Quintin Dailey got 30 points,
they said.
That guy's unbelievable, man. Say all you
want about Michael Jordan. Great player.
They'll know somebody
set the Chinaman up.
Quintin Dailey's
got a gun like a howitzer, man.
Thirty feet. Boom, boom, boom.
He gets hot, he's fabulous.
Fucking Orlando Woolridge-
I'm worried. I'm worried!
The stars are God's eyes.
What's the matter with you?
The last item on the agenda
is a bulletin from the FBI.
"On January 24th, FBI
Special Agent Raymond Fong...
...of the bureau of San Francisco
field office was kidnapped and robbed...
...of $50,000 in government funds.
Fong, who was acting
in an undercover capacity...
...as part of a bureau-sponsored
sting operation...
...was abducted and murdered
shortly after arriving at Union Station.
The suspects are described as white males,
30 to 35 years old...
...one with black, the other
with brown hair.
They eluded Fong's covering agents
and fled in a beige, late-model Chevrolet.
Anyone having information...
...contact the special agent
in charge, FBI, San Francisco. "
- Is there a license on the vehicle?
- There's no plates on the vehicle.
This is what happens when proper
covering procedures are not followed.
We got an FBI agent killed.
You hear that?
- What do you want me to do about it?
- It's just a matter of time before they ID us.
- They got a good look.
- A face is shit without a name.
They got a make on the car!
They wouldn't have sent it out if they
had anything. They're grabbing at shit.
Oh, Jesus. So, what are we
gonna do about the 50 grand?
We'll make the buy from Masters,
just like we planned.
Are you out of your fucking mind
or something?
Ray. Hey, I want
a standup ashtray.
These guys are stealing
all of my ashtrays.
Just like we planned, amigo.
Over here.
Who are they?
Who are you?
This is Mr. Jessup...
...whose name isn't really Jessup.
He says he's from Palm Springs,
but doesn't have a tan.
You're not wired, are you?
Is this my package?
Look okay?
You're beautiful.
When do I get delivery?
How about Friday night?
If I don't hear from you by Friday
I'm coming back to get this.
That's understandable.
Oh, Mr. Jessup...
...like your work?
Your only defense is to say
you were working undercover...
...without the knowledge
of your supervisors.
You were trying to get next to Masters
and things got out of hand...
...and you intended
to return the money.
The problem is, you'll have
to take the stand...
...and the prosecutor
can ask you anything he wants.
Frankly, I don't think
you can beat the case in court.
Because I represent Masters
I can't get deeply involved in your case...
- ... if you see what I mean.
- So, what should I do?
You beat them to the punch with
the U.S. attorney and you make a deal.
What kind of deal?
You offer to plead guilty and
to testify against your partner.
The FBI's not gonna want
a lot of publicity on this.
I suspect they'll go along
with a guilty plea.
How much time
would I have to do?
I could probably get you off
with seven years.
You won't have to do seven,
of course. Probably a year and a half.
- But you can't get involved, right?
- Not directly.
What would it cost
for your indirect involvement?
Fifty thousand dollars.
I know it's a tough call...
...but it's one you're going
to have to make rather quickly.
I can't hand up my partner.
I can't do it, even if I have to go
to the joint.
Who is it?
Who's there?
Honey?
Shit, you okay, Carl?
- Guess we all screw up, huh, Carl?
- How did you find me?
Your bimbo girlfriend's listed
in the Screen Actors directory.
- Carl, I swear I never saw this guy!
- Sit down, Claudia, and shut up!
You know, you're a lucky man.
I didn't tell the judge
you played hooky on me.
Now you're gonna help me,
aren't you, Carl?
Come on, asshole, let's go.
Move!
Hi. Is Chance there?
I want to talk to Chance.
Is this 471-4421?
This is John Vukovich. Where is he?
There's no one here
by that name.
Who is it?
John Vukovich.
John.
Listen, I got Cody back.
I know where the plant is.
We gotta talk. We gotta go to Bateman.
I can't live with this any longer.
I talked to Masters. We're on tonight.
- What are you talking about?
- We're on with Masters tonight.
- Do you need me tonight?
- No, I don't think so.
What time do you get off?
- About 12:30.
- Okay.
I got a few things to do, and then
I'll drop by and pick you up at the club.
All right?
You look beautiful.
I got a little surprise for you.
You packing?
Check and see if you got
a wire on there, brother.
- Let's see that bag.
- You don't touch me.
- Look, dickhead!
- Keep your hands off me.
If you want to get up them stairs
you gotta go through me.
You go tell your little friend
that if he thinks I'm a fed-
It's okay, Jack.
Well, go on up, tough guy.
So, what's in the briefcase, doctor?
Hey, we're the ones who fronted the 30
grand and agreed to do this on your turf.
Before you touch shit,
I want to see the funny money.
Locker 38.
Okay?
You're beautiful.
- You're under arrest! Turn around!
- Right there, asshole!
Hands on top of the locker!
Go on, grab the top
of the fucking locker!
That's right! You're under arrest, moron!
Go on, cuff the ape.
- Don't move!
- How you doing, pal? Huh?
This is from Jimmy Hart. From the desert.
Remember this? Suck on that for a while.
- Freeze it up, pal!
- Jesus Christ!
Oh, God.
Talk to me. Talk to me, man.
Talk to me.
Talk to me!
Oh, God.
You can't do this to me!
Why didn't you take the deal
Grimes offered you?
Wouldn't roll over on your partner, huh?
Get up.
Get up, you son of a bitch!
You might want these.
They're very personal.
Yes.
I can't seem to find
any of his paintings.
He told me he did
two large portraits of you.
They might be worth
a lot of money.
He used to burn a lot of things.
Maybe he burned them.
I can't understand how
you stayed with him so long.
Why did you work for him?
It was just business.
- Who is it?
- John Vukovich.
- What do you want?
- Chance was my partner.
- I know who you are. What do you want?
- Did you know he was dead?
- I'm busy now.
- Open it.
You going somewhere?
I'm leaving the city.
Well, there's a little matter of 20 grand
that belongs to the federal government.
Chance said he left it with you.
We want it back.
Look, part of that money was mine.
I had debts, people leaning on me.
- I got ripped off for the rest-
- You set us up, didn't you, Ruth?
You knew that Chinaman was FBI.
What? Are you crazy?
Come on. Don't shine me on.
If you're gonna start by bullshitting, we're
gonna get off to a very bad relationship.
What are you talking about?
You're working for me now.