What's wrong now?
The great love?
Could you not start small?
No, the big right!
Stef, before 't end of the week
I find you a chick.
And you just have to pop.
That goes without saying.
I know your combines out.
No, thanks.
Well, the last time was t ...
I admit, that man was really
insane ...
a clinically hopeless case.
But one thing I tell you, Stef ...
We may perhaps lat
not impose high.
However, a moist within trien do
is not so simple.
That kind of wives is
terribly suspicious.
We address the middle class to.
Before 't end of the week
you meet the true Jakoba!
Dikkenek--large mug, bladder jaw,
stoefer,
sir -- or madame--wiseacre.
Monique with me. Do me a favor.
Say this arrangement with 2 Kiekens
the TV school.
Equipment I have spoken
not the time.
Such rete heads me
the pot on.
Which school?
-- 'T IAD.
't IAD? Never jamais of my life
not heard.
Is it that famous year--end work?
How long will that last? 7, 8 minutes?
Go ahead. I am ready.
You do not say 'action'? Ho, say!
I suggest for me -- I am
Claudy Focan ...
semi--professional photographer ... No, explain
everything quiet. Cut!
I say this because I have lens
had to see.
This is digital, right? 35 mm.
I am a photographer of ...
I ... charming pictures.
But it does not matter.
Shall we go?
I am equally for Focan Claudy.
Mr. Focan, precise.
Director sales and marketing manager
's slaughterhouse of Anderlecht.
This is the sales hall.
The animals are 150
in a lorry.
Why 150? If they do not stumble
during 't transport.
On arrival follow the white line.
And we lead them irrevocably two
every two to slaughter.
Perhaps less amusing, however.
And we never 2 times
After shooting each other.
This is about my peccadillo.
Once it beast the pipe is off, are you,
not, of course ...
Say 's, you is becoming my balls from
your micro.
I just got him close to my face!
't Is now' s from!
Sorry, I'm nervous here.
You can 't help.
But it seems to me that she 's lower
from the can 't have sent IAD.
And the frikadel, how do you do?
Since I just come.
Everything in its time.
Say you do not what to say.
And what about the frikadel?
Two things you should know.
On a beast of 700 kg
is 350 kg case
as a matter or scrap
not suitable for consumption.
In a butcher shop, you will never nostrils ...
a scrotum, anus or intestines n
find.
What happens to the intestines?
The bowels are never more
digested than grass.
Also commonly called 'shit' said.
What is it? We dump the whole
sprain in large vats ie 'pools'.
Since then products by: anxiolytica,
antibiotics, dyes ...
our precarious existence, called
'Belgian' form.
Once they have returned to meat appears
we stop in intestines ...
and leaves than the fritkoten,
The commerce, by the way ...
as frikadellen, merguez.
All kits, Polak?
A large pack of chips with sauce, please.
What sauce?
No idea. Dallas -- sauce, but do
the sauce separately.
And three balls.
Omar! The sauce separately or on the fries?
On the balls! And also 's
6, 7 frikadellen!
Seven frikadellen with ...
-- 10 beers, please! 10 stars.
Gener you not!
Are you sometimes blind?
I was just 't order.
You're playing with your life!
Sorry, I had not seen you.
I thought ...
What does that whore young? Come on!
Calm down now.
-- N Problem, Aziz?
That cross me over and excuse themselves
disagree?
Are you polite or not?
Do not.
-- Loser!
Are you not bosklas?
I knew you 't was. With your old
focus of rapzanger. Hiphop!
And that spuwt everywhere ... as a lama.
That works great on my system.
Hey, Stef.
You know each other?
-- He's my size.
And you save a different tone to it on.
Sorry, now!
Excuse ...
-- 'N beer?
No, I drink beer.
-- What is that?
Frikadellen. Sometimes hungry?
You know what is in it?
I have read about it.
Anyway no pork.
-- That certainly is not.
But give that a dog
and he eats there is not.
There is a stain.
Can I ask you something?
Summarize it the wrong way.
What do you actually do
as it starts school?
Because Baudouin and I put our demand.
If you see your results ...
The unief, all best, but you must
still a little studying.
You can not continue every year
tubes.
On the slow start, good long
sleep ...
there you all
no difficulty.
I unief not finished.
If I cap today is that
my fault.
I had not asked 17. Nothing!
I wish law school, no snot monkeys
with that other asshole!
I wanted in a great psychologist
become.
Help people ... service, MSF,
the bunch.
And all this because I 'n night
teut was.
And when your parents died,
My life changed.
Just on the day of the funeral I had
mother. Just. Hello, croquette.
Listen, baby, do not drum
wrong way,
but I always like my own
daughter.
I do not want it bad you pass.
-- Listen, tantetje ...
I also thought.
I see you as my mother,
I see you happy.
And the more I think about it,
the more I think ...
meaning that I have to just do
like you.
Why? What do you say?
-- Free blow perform.
Like you. Finally, that is
's goal in life, huh?
Succeed not blow to carry out.
Forward! Here. Follow me!
Cindy? It 's always the same.
Say 's, gourmand, you can not read?
Forbidden to eat in museums!
Hopefully this visit beneemt
no appetite! Yah!
Hello. The small envelope.
Please. Welcome to 's Museum
of fatalities.
In short, we can not
repeat belt!
Rather a small 'click' with your clicks
and rattle out of the car fly!
Well, children?
Who wants to play dead?
Who has been a car accident?
You?
You? Nobody?
That comes later.
At 18 you start to drink ...
and do you want your friends
impress ...
and guaranteed against a tree
if you come back from Louvain--la--Neuve.
Charlotte, do you know what a windshield is?
Well, if you today more Albator
seems to CANDIE ...
is that your mama pimpelt!
Nice fence, huh?
The guy in question had 137 fractures.
137 fractures, it's much, huh?
Not to say, impressive!
Come, come look!
Come closer, it does not bite!
You want to sit on the engine, huh?
I feel it!
You do not want to? Not bad. Go ahead!
Next attraction!
The teacher is dead!
Now we go a minute silence to
for all those people behind me.
That 's it!
That zetst there but loose.
Is this is a porno theater?
What? Come anyway.
What is this reject?
About two girls looking for sex
identity.
Sexual identity? What does that mean?
That you have me 's out!
't Is it terribly slow. Whenever I
movie ga, I fall asleep.
Ferme loezen, a round belly,
thick buttocks ...
Is' s something different than leaves, huh?
My hand off it 's back
rete fuss is about!
The sexual identity!
What is it? Have we met?
Fabienne?
How I know you 't you?
Your name was on it screen.
Excuse me!
-- Are you stupid.
Want to go outside but a phone call?
-- Shut up! I'm busy.
No, that was not against you,
but who voze deb here.
Ga outside call or otherwise turn off your mobile.
-- What? Huh?
Are you sometimes deaf? For the last time,
ga outside call you bitched!
You want to fight, huh?
Put it on, bitch.
I wait! Come on!
-- This guy is stekezot!
You stay upright in the cinema?
Sit!
And look just right before you!
That view, madam?
And as he spoke to me!
Call me sometimes in the bios?
Yes, Fabienne? No, it's nothing.
Any shoot here ...
This guy does it express!
No, I don 't do to you!
You never know what, stupid bitch!
No!
-- The 1st is because you are a dickhead!
The 2nd is for 's principle ... and 3rd,
because you never 2 without 3 you!
Who is this?
-- JC.
Say 's. .. JC, right?
What are you doing on August 15?
I have four then my 18th
birthday ...
with a party in 't Zoute.
's tendency, I need the whole of Belgium.
What a tuttebel! Is it sometimes
too close to the wall gewiegd?
Here. Compliments of the baby manager.
Nog 'n afsluitertje?
Jakkes that must hurt!
What I think this dancing so cool,
that palace--like way.
Pretty Woman. This little ...
'S wrong foot stepped on in bed?
All right, Dominique?
Oh, yes, those times when you Albanians
had left within ...
Should you watch. Can you not do that.
it should remain ... you know?
I have nothing to say because
people, but ...
Not wrong, huh?
The dance floor there already seen?
All right, Dom? Sometimes you sleep here?
Since you have the hottest of them all!
-- Daisy! I had not seen you ...
Further news?
a beer, please. I stitching of thirst.
And?
-- Well ... 't is not obvious.
't Is not ... currently ... I
the wind.
And it stinks like the plague
I get to smell.
I swear, it's really ... I get
well on my face.
The universal law of series,
as they say.
Huge problems with rabies,
dioxin ...
Always the same things again come
but ...
About old sows speaking, how is it?
-- What is always in common with me!
's more' n witticism than anything else.
-- Vlot 's that girl there?
You yourself should not be fooled, Daisy.
If I so often as well
I pet ...
is that for my money,
and not how I Riek.
And that compares.
I am perhaps the only one in Belgium
to know, but ...
's Natacha, right?
Wow, do you hear that? Michael Jackson!
They think I keigoed!
The only white person who makes music
as Zwartjes.
Note that this is not so difficult ...
That's him! I am keigek on!
In two words: above him there
nobody, under him there is none!
Carmelo, add 's as loud, I'm
the only one here who dances. The nave is!
Is it to my gear that you look?
Too crazy. A semi--automatic Czech
gun, light plastic, 17 shots.
Stops a moving school bus.
Maybe even a plane!
Never tried, but I consider 't.
Firearms are my passion
of when I was little!
Is no explanation for. As some
dolls like ...
Can we go now?
-- Say it again ...
I was assaulted in the cinema
by 2 guys.
They strike me down ... almost now she
had no knife ...
but she tamped me, questioned my jacket
and stole my brand new mobile phone!
Fortunately I have judo, so I could
the situation more or less be the boss ...
And how did you guys look like?
Something like this here?
Of course not.
They saw it mount? Suddenly.
-- Non.
Dan 's this? 't were the same.
More or less ...
Come 'n inspanninkje, otherwise I
you do not help.
It was this guy there.
Yet something in that nature ...
What, he? He would
done?
Why?
For fun?
They are heavily in her box will
believe me.
What? This here?
Make no mistake! I have a horse dose
in done.
I've searched everywhere. I thought
you are away.
Here ...
I sat at my convenience at the cinema,
with a young girl ...
And then my mobile phone so
have.
Ho but before the movie you say
your phone off.
And 's after the advertising.
They are not every 5 minutes ..
the lights to call you to say
you should sell your mobile phone?
I had him off!
-- True or not?
Yes or no? Am I right?
-- Yes!
I did that when I with my wife
movie ga.
First, bad seats ...
than all the mobile phones which are transferred,
all those people who are a tetteren ...
Because the film starts with 't concert.
I ga still my buddy Maurice
in Sabam 's call.
It was not a singer! You listening?
I don 't al We say
out like that.
We are a robot are portrait.
However, I'm not bad,
but I do not sign as Tintin.
Tintin 's character.
Just what I say. I sign
as Tintin.
How did he look like?
-- He was ... small ...
't Face! The shape of the face ...
Angular ...
Long, greasy hair ... in the neck.
'n Klein mustache ...
And a nose ... a thick nose ...
Yes, 'n kokkerd! And he smelled the booze!
The whole room was their ruin.
Where do I find a Mercedes coupe?
Yes, I know that it streamlined
Arika to go.
Damn exciting, your orders
's last minute!
Stef, I'm 't call!
Is my BMW ready? What? I am otherwise
always good enough for you to repair.
Damn, check that 's!
Klotebak, goddamn it!
JC, look!
-- Damn! What a pack of notes!
What does this asshole now?
With me. Greg!
Damn, I got a big problem!
You are not dead, it's' s most important.
-- They have stolen my mobile!
I do not know. And you calling?
Should you cancel?
That does not! It's something I found
have e--thingies. Not to pay.
Please, Fabienne, come fetch me!
Draw your plan on. For a time
the bus.
This is a public cell!
Do not have a mobile phone?
Two seconds ...
-- Wanker!
Thirty seconds is that?
No, but a ball grab.
Well, you 't understand?
You should definitely come and get me!
-- Where are you?
You are here 't Poulaerplein,
not on the Croisette!
I leave you, because that guy starts
slightly red to save it.
I ga that 's on his Japanese
stairs at his face.
Wait. I leave you.
Chef! Whether you come out or I
get out! Decide now 's!
Come on, Come on!
-- D'you get out or I d'out!
Chef! You're crazy, chef!
And now out!
I still get 'shit to you,
dickhead!
Your glasses klootvis! Maybe see you then
next time better!
Mama, in Claudy.
I let carjacking.
I let carjacking, tell me.
They have the car stolen!
No, I could do nothing, I have
after they tried to run,
but what do you want to start with ... No.
With my learning is employed,
with 70,000 balls in ...
No, I am really sick! No ...
Your glasses? What did you popular, mama?
In the glove compartment!
's glove in the car
remained. No ...
Say, you can not come to where I
as a child snookerde with Dad?
Go to the cafe where it big 'Duvel'
state.
Right now, and shoot because ...
I want to go from this city! I am here
mad! All this violence!
Keitof, your desk!
Dear Help!
Goodbye, madam.
What a heat, huh?
I'm wet.
I'm also a little with my head
in my hole, but ... 't going to go.
Yes, I am up late.
'n Man must now and then as steam
indulgences.
The bow can not always tense stand.
Say 's, Stef ... I got a small question.
't on my niece Natacha.
Currently it is not.
a small post--adolescence crisis.
You know about whom I 't have?
But yes!
a small peach that is always in her blootje
looking for her slip.
Surely not.
Do you not drink?
We may meet perhaps tutoyeren?
Would you like something to drink?
Yes, I would like.
Alcohol? Soft?
I would a beer lust.
'n Vedette, please.
Soft is not your thing, huh?
Not really ...
What is that?
No, Aziz. Watch it! Scratches everywhere!
Imagine my place! Who I ga
that sell? On a different brown?
Okay, 50 for two.
To take it or leave it.
-- Do you have jackets? In Kroko?
Kroko has dismissed.
Slang is very weather.
But rather than learning.
Want a learning style?
Then aside. Hey, Marco?
When you're done, get that jacket
back 's.
Pak 't look in the back!
Hurry up in mind.
Has the other mèches you put?
't Is nothing, huh?
-- Pretty on the red side.
I ga 't cut, I think.
But the other looks like long hair.
I leave you. Draw your plan but
your cowhide.
See that guy. 'n Mooi learning style.
Pull 's.
This is fashion, you say? Do you remember?
-- You are not here at H & M, Aziz.
Do you sometimes' n pashokje?
's too big guy!
Hang me for the monkey?
What did you say?
-- No, that came naturally ...
It seems to me however ...
-- Excuse me.
No, it's not too big! Look!
-- Do you?
It 's your good! This is now in fashion.
You start there wives to skate with us!
Damn, man, your jacket stinks!
That 's teachings.
-- On 's head of my mother! Back to the pig!
Was it then, what do you want me to say!
Okay! The 2 handsets' s jacket.
Agreed?
Tell 'n Play Station you nothing?
-- I have a.
I want that bike.
It should cost 400, but I
let him you 350.
't Is' n Eddy Merckx,
So no brol!
's Real?
-- Yes, 'n real.
Hey, viking! I'll pay you tomorrow!
See you, JC.
Say 's, you know that your a chick
with cocker--eye in your trunk are you?
Can you immediately pay for the car?
-- Okay. You grab your spare it.
Day. I'm JC.
Is it?
When you drive in a Child?
Two beers!
Not everything at once, fatboy!
Do you smikkel him see.
Just such a moist nature as his father.
We got him like places,
but it does not succeed. That beer!
It's like 3 Suisses,
they bring him back always!
Sorry, I had not seen you.
Do me just a beer.
I stitching of thirst.
And cool, as it can!
Yeah, same!
And also bring a different glass with us!
This here tastes like soap.
I like a little foam, but
you should not exaggerate!
Hold it people stupid balls?
Do more 's vol.
Same, so?
-- Do more 's full, I have your answer.
Please 't be good at? Excuse me.
I go 's.
-- No! Sit tight.
Still a lucky I my mouth
not open it.
Is it the laugh--scream--roar break?
You have the ice cubes! In the fridge
there is no more. What happened here?
I got it from my wife!
Ga you play with your mower, you idiot!
Give me the ice 's!
Would you calm down? What has
the guy you wrong?
You talkin 'to me?
Well? If you need money
for your messages, then it 's good!
Come on, go play!
-- I'm gone!
Did they teach you never to eat
with your mouth?
I got it to you!
I like next to a garbage truck
into force sta!
Bitched.
It's great exciting someone chips
to hear the food for those who do not eat!
Understood? 'n Minimum education!
In the slaughterhouse would it not be true!
Small cock ...
With his big game thing.
a small dick ... as Baudouin.
I brought this.
There are many more.
Thank you. Very nice of you.
I just came from. Come on.
Coming, my little Dim.
Fuck!
Filthy sow!
Hey, Mama! Mama!
Goddamn it, always the same song!
Embrace you mother?
I can not, Mama ... crazy
what is me.
A second but has it lasted,
I tell you!
I only now realize what happened.
Nothing I can do!
I really ...
... I am down from
or how do you say that?
I can not, I am
at the end of my Latin.
I want to go home, pick up my shuffle
and out!
Look at me not to, otherwise I can
this does not explain.
What 's history. Alcoholism is really
the scourge of the century.
But worst is that he never
is drunk. Never!
While I have 2 glasses after all
ga embrace.
Today 's somewhat hommeles
with Baudouin.
I see 't.
-- What? Because ... that?
No, this is your wife.
Excuse me.
I have heard that they ...
not really your wife is.
She comes back.
When they need money.
If it can help, Baudouin also
gescharreld. With a Asian,
and then ... But that is now history.
If they come back, will you be r
need testing ...
We draw it to rubbertjes.
I don 't understand. She has everything.
We go 3 times per year on holiday,
we go to the movies ...
Note that this is just for people
to see, because ...
I got a Home Cinema.
More than 300 DVDs.
Soon 800, thanks to the Internet.
I like the movie.
You should go to the movies.
We go to the movie.
Say 's, I would not interfere with ...
Take it a bit with the drink.
Lifting As you say!
Six months ago I saw a advertisement.
It said: "Urgent.
Professional Photographer looking young girl. "
So I go to him and I asked him
or it was naked.
He: 'No,' t is no nudity,
but art '. I know a lot.
And he looked nice from.
I had to do with him going home.
Pull it, do you want?
Claudy! Come quickly, I got you
everywhere!
No, I'm shooting now.
With my model.
With whom? Natacha?
Again that little whore!
Judge her not. You know 't
and you assess her al
Balls or chips as dinner?
Or croques. I'm doing, Mommy.
's Whatever.
Is that not somewhat vulgar?
-- Vulgar?
You will find that vulgar?
-- Yes.
's already. I understand now.
Hear 's, Natacha, on the side aristieke
ga me, so difficult you do not.
Why I ask you those shoes
to contribute?
I work here in zلrt--white,
so I must emphasize the colors ...
whether it is pale. You know not,
because you know nothing, because 't
your work is not.
Trek also that piece off.
Why, no?
But what are you doing here?
Your charm for photos
and you want to spend anything?
I do not have mandatory
here are, to my knowledge.
You are here by choice.
And then you come here to serve.
If it is so, will it here
rap made.
You should not with my balls
play!
You're tight like a cramp.
-- Not true.
Yes it is. If I tell you that you tense
you is so.
Say you not so. I tell you
you're tense.
So you say: 'Yes, Claudy,
I am not at my ease. "
You must be forwarded to me,
and I'll do you really get.
Why you only photograph naked
teenagers?
What? What say you now?
Say that 's!
Are you in your blootje?
Are you naked?
It's really what you do. You let
me off as a dirty smoke.
Come now do not bully me.
They do enough on 't work.
This is for my pleasure, you know?
I do not do
the costs themselves.
I'll be more than around. Money is
for me no problem.
For you, maybe. Yeah, huh?
You are here for the monetarist.
Then maybe you stressed
are.
Frustrated cunt.
And bend now.
So much is not, right?
Yet from it. See you.
Is that so much to ask?
Pull your panties off.
Do I doing?
See?
Still ... yet.
No, that's too much. Keep up.
Don not.
Is it?
And do you love on me.
Still ... still a bit ...
a tiny bit. This is t.
Now I take the picture.
Don not, get the pony.
You are not easily scared.
What a story!
He is just rutted
to my sense.
And it's not my fault
as dick throttle was on me.
We are here.
If something goes wrong ...
you can always call me.
Thanks for everything.
Goodbye.
Who knows quite how they 'thank you'
must say!
And even do some apple drink.
That?
-- That there.
These triangles.
-- The samosa's.
Excuse me. 't Schoot me suddenly
to make, but ...
... you may not sell ...
What is that again?
... stuff?
Five hundred.
Thank you.
Everything good?
-- Yes, and you?
That take, I wanted to ask you something.
a friend of mine is a time
stay.
Because she has' n. .. heart problem.
I wanted to warn you that it
may be somewhat noisy.
Because it's a romp?
Something like a tigress?
Whip, leather, latex, sex moped?
However, my only King Kong I
not you, girls!
Do not worry. No, it was previously ..
water bottle always at hand ...
schoolteacher ...
Nothing more. And how is it
with Evelyne?
That pruilt. She is a mug
in her boudoir.
Because I drink to the stink
as I do my work.
And also to the cigarette.
Then memt them: 'It's just
I 'n uitlik ashtray.
35 years and I have 't geniept
smoking!
And with her cocaine,
is it better?
I am cop, and
she gets it from.
It's the world upside down. Find me
a broad, and he picked her!
Hey, két! Your pal here, I think.
You are here?
-- Yes, I am here.
Sorry, had a small setback.
I see 't.
Say hello, Sabine.
-- Hello, Sabine.
Ga in the cafeteria waiting for me.
Come on, my little cat.
Games we still match?
Where is the ball?
The ball is waiting for you ... like me.
And now you wait for me, because I
am Brazil 't beat.
Am I not?
Did you 're not cold?
I got it computes cold.
You are so quick here. With the car come?
-- Yes. Such a dumb box.
Only for him to open, there are
4 alarms on the key.
And they talk at a stretch!
'Take that off! That means no! '
But the reverse can be found!
He has lent you his car!
I 'm not requested.
Also, you should have seen how he
rampage went.
"Nadine, I love you!
I never go out! Promise!
I never drink more! I swear it! '
Words, words ...
Foeteren he sure.
What do you have in your bag?
You like attention: Room 1
your two favorite German bitches ...
Greta and Cynthia ...
accompanied by their shepherd ... also
German!
Hall 2. Young girls in black
long tisjen!
Is it here sometimes rush hour?
Goddamn, look over the cabin anyway!
No way!
Hey, you!
-- Me?
You shall not blow off. Come here
with your swab.
I will you "s to work.
This cabin has been 's view?
Do you clean that?
No, I ask you, do you clean that?
I would like to ease my seat.
I do not want a leg break.
't Is there a real slide. Hurry up!
I have something else to do.
The cards ... The cards!
Yes, take me.
That is 300.
Thus you have a lubricant is needed.
Is that you, sir?
I hot or not Arthur, but you
can 't thank.
Here, I treat you to a turn.
't surprise me that my 50 euros
I do not come around.
And now we hope that it still paste.
Hello, saam!
Swap, please.
Coins in the parking meters.
Was that blonde in her microwave not working properly?
Yes it is.
It had a touch of romance
to have.
There rest you have little time
to the woman of my life.
Want your empty promises ...
all blanks!
-- Ho but here 's your bag to go.
Not to take away.
And hear, I had you there
in the holes.
It was a test. Now I ga
's ideal female targeting.
And now that peepshow 's forever.
In the food like you do not
with hygiene.
I mean that the fines
are draconian.
So a worker who does not complete
equipment works, you can not.
a small example will say more
than words.
Yesterday I versnijzaal the inside
always unexpected, 2 times per day ...
And one Giovanni had his hat on.
Then it to me right outside!
You understand that ...
Come not from 'I was just
get my keys. " Not with me!
There is never on the fucking TV!
Baudouin, you will not believe me!
The bastard has already replaced her!
Who you talkin ', chou?
-- About Dimitri!
He has already replaced his wife!
And the other seems to me a real del!
He is not his whole life
continue, bitch!
Thus, it 's good his balls
Empty!
I think you are not very distinguished,
Baudouin.
Just the best hooker
within it!
Wait!
Ho but he spuwt on her!
What a force!
But that zothuis ... he pulls on her hair!
Well done!
-- I never even talk to that guy!
Also, I haven 't always smelled.
It's the drink. The drink!
The drink, Baudouin.
-- Yes, the drink. That you know not.
No, but ... she is on the ground.
Not possible, she is unconscious.
Damn, almost goal!
I am sure he has toegetakeld r
to revenge on Nadine!
Is anyone here?
-- Yes it is, there is someone!
Mich! Who has taken your seat.
There are not enough chairs,
you just picked mine?
Forward, ga 'n other address.
Since we have. Here is one.
You give me back, okay?
You should avoid ...
You should fucking racists
of your stroke to avoid!
Say that 's?
-- You can all your hard seat.
I do not mean good.
What did you say, bitched?
Was not headbutt with New
enough? You can get a!
And a Duvel, please.
Say 's, lolbroek?
Would you like some beer?
Barks that imbecile of a man of your
always like a Teckel?
You already get this in your face!
This refreshing, huh? On my costs. Cheers!
'n Lekker number. What is it?
-- That is Ghinzu.
It's English.
-- Hear me. Set louder, please.
Same?
-- Yes, the same!
In any case, there buddy what are you!
He pinches him in his shit hole!
I recommended not all.
But when I see who do not
I wonder if I really
so very much.
What now? Is she back face
't draw?
It's always something.
Once I make my photos, smoelt them.
So that.
It's not jealousy, but
it seems.
If they think I am all the time
will be. See that ...
Claudy! This thing does not work!
That they fall 20 kg and walking
to exceed!
Claudy! Did you hear me?
I come from, I tell you!
I'm still crazy.
I have you already said 20 times
to strangle.
Lap, he left.
You know sometimes what time it is?
In two words, I am a photographer ...
and I'm looking for models.
My number. If it interests you ...
I wouldn 't be interested.
'n Klein ass. Well, that Flemings ...
For once that a good chickenshit
in between!
They are so prude!
's see. It's true that they Romans
koleirig made.
There are quite a few ads: 'Parts'
'child', 'room to rent.
So, that looks better already!
Hopefully the fish bite.
Miss?
-- Is your stuff quite paid?
Whether you stuff quite paid?
-- That depends on you, poppeke.
Why, a book on
between women and animals?
Exactly! It is a book about the relationship
that there may exist
between a first animal and a woman
other.
Is it not sexual
photos?
Listen, if it interests you,
here is my number.
Otherwise, the cost and salut!
What do you think I say more?
Is it possible ... I see you?
Everything is possible. Everything is negotiable.
There is no price tag attached.
Are you epilated or not?
Have your friends or not?
But you have not really missed!
Was it from a horse or a sow?
You phiz ever seen?
We can if necessary also a book
Halloween on it!
Dirty bastard!
Ga you do about it! Alien!
'n happiness that they get it up or I
knalde my stapler in her mug.
My husband has as it were, a subscription
that kind of situation.
We already have something 's been
at Palma de Mallorca.
I am also fond of Portugal.
That was it for a sunbed.
But here he bled like a pig.
And he has not begun, but the other.
I swear it on the heads
my twins.
Still a lucky man that my time
was not armed.
Well, first we make a robot portrait.
Then we issue a detection message.
In short, the conventional procedure.
What did that guy look like?
Brown!
Brown ... in maroon?
-- Yes, dark!
Black Brown. Slightly burnt? You had
it must begin, because ...
Flink sunburnt.
-- Also by coincidence, huh?
I said nothing!
Damn. What now?
Is it the batteries?
Do you have lights burning?
By day, right?
I'm so stupid yet.
I look ga.
't Is the engine.
Boel Shit!
If the engine is not the front?
-- Of course not!
In sports, the engine always
back.
However, this model is it perhaps
front.
Well?
You will not believe me, but here is
no motor.
Call me a guy on?
Fucking phone! Goddamn!
JC?
-- You're t.
Am I not?
-- It's crazy, but I was just thinking of you.
Say it, do you mind
of mechanics and engines?
Engines disassembled and I am I
back together with my eyes closed.
And en passant, I'll give you even
's turn.
In any case, it's not for you,
my dove.
No ... not really.
And ... what are you doing this afternoon?
Right, yes. They have me as yet though
be had.
For a move.
Well, I will be loved.
Where are you?
In Chasse Pierre.
Is it? Is it not hard working?
Why can not ga at Roland--Garros balls
turnips? I know the big boss as well.
I must throw them back. Else
I can 't not mow grass.
I just read a book on the dismissal.
I'm only in Chapter 2
and I know everything already.
's of a certain Jean--Marie Messier.
What is still stupid!
This guy is really stupid!
Keep it all up. You know what? You are
'n niksnut. No ass worth!
You lie there with your clicks
and rattle off!
Born idiot, and you'll fool
die!
You hanging from my balls! You consider
not blow out! Get outta here!
Wait, you mess here!
Forget nothing and get on!
Kloot Bumblebee!
Fuck you! I have never seen!
Fuck you!
What a knock that pee!
Strontgat 's ass!
Nadine.
-- Jean--Claude. Nice. Is it?
We find the ... the engine anymore.
-- The engine. Right, yes.
Do not worry, I understand.
What does your husband for a living?
He must have the means
for something to buy.
Usually he is here.
He may cross
's glove.
Hot, huh?
And mosquitoes that are here!
Where is Natacha?
Well, what is it?
We found the engine.
Do not you topless?
Get her not to?
Do not be shy.
Who is the master?
Come on, pig!
Can I join?
But I have never done.
Not on my arm support, which hurts.
My heatstroke.
Damn! Glad forget!
My aunt is today!
Do something! Quick question!
If you see them, they kill you, than me,
and then makes them part of itself!
No, no, no!
-- She is!
I 't!
Three hours to 10 km to go
on the motorway.
Because there just before us a mobile home
was tilted.
D'r was not over! They were
all dead! 's Real BBQ!
Sir! Do you sometimes that we
a mattress lay?
What is this game? Shall we enter?
-- Do not laugh! Soon he bezeert still.
Oh, he's quite sturdy.
How long does he persist?
Net 'n zweetcel here.
Let's illustrate.
I will.
One of these, I send you my Polish.
Wait, poppeke, save me
of a doubt.
You have surely not all
soldier made? -- No, not.
That hurts, huh?
You know the weird girls there?
They are always together. Certainly legs.
Ga pads underneath to get to.
Pak prefer the puff. Not green
that is moist.
The person we brought in the Sahel ...
er, Israel. Is the same.
Gepikt ones we had?
-- 'We'? Gepikt you had!
Every time I come here, they are there.
And always the white wine.
I do not tolerate lesbians.
Just to see them, are my hair
straight.
At home they still
what they want?
Wait 's. .. d'r is a naked
in 't gras!
He searches his slip, just like you.
Nice that! As you jump, staple ...
-- Sorry. Am forget my underwear.
Now I remember ... Are we
remember your birthday?
Because we are currently around
like chicken without head.
Always pressure pressure pressure, thousand
things to do.
's next Monday
Even better, if we forget it not.
View this does!
I already told you about Natacha's
girlfriend?
She is away from her husband.
Come on, get up. Straight!
Is still awake, man!
With your air of beaten dog!
Stop now 's' s life to undergo
and always a victim to be!
The sun will be on without you!
And if you do not stand up, no one can
a bag that cares!
Yes, it's all good! I get up.
And pull out that ugly underwear!
You need me for a stupid ball
keep Stef.
This is not "social assistant", huh?
Day, madame. Can I sit?
-- Sure.
I'll actually Momo,
for my proof of the school.
Because I had so recently
a turntable gepikt with ...
Right, yes! You are a plague lids guy!
But You look honest from you smikkel
like me. I note that on.
However, it is good for once, huh?
's see. "I, the undersigned ...
'I' with 'e',
as adjective and plural ...
If you go to school, you
know.
"I, the undersigned, Commissioner
Laurence Cochet ...
declare on my honor ...
... have heard ... '
Neige, huh?
'M. Aziz Alami, date of ... ''
When was that? The?
The 12th, I knew t. 12am to 12!
Thus rhymes' t. Etcetera, etcetera!
We make it very formal.
Iglesias's small and still a punk
wait outside. What do I do?
Nothing wrong, that his comrades of mine.
-- You have many friends!
Always the whole gang there?
Can you now and then 's not alone?
He one degree me, but I like him much.
Fuck you.
You look good today.
-- I got a girl met.
Is it true? Good. What is it?
Fabienne.
-- And she has a cabinet of a villa!
Do you like her to her house or her?
-- To both.
Take it on. Give her gifts
and stuff?
Why, you don 't know? You gotta 'let r
dream! You must ... I know a lot!
Give her pebbles gift, add a heart to
and she is happy!
She thinks it 's from the heart is!
Will they believe me?
-- Yes. Against women, you lie.
You gotta love, you have to ...
We will not get ... Stay you here
far that is?
I do not know ... Coffee?
-- Did you not work?
Sure I want coffee! That is good!
Black .. black. Of course it is not yellow!
I get coffee? No, kidding.
Ga out there but drink.
And I do not care too soon weerzie.
I like that snul please.
Hello? Yes. With whom I have the honor?
Ms. Michels? Hello, Ms. Michels.
You must however, submit proposals for ...
You are not my only client,
if I may so express.
a small customer, also.
You know, it is 17h 45
everywhere in Belgium and ...
we would like a piece of
weekend.
That 's not, but if you have 10 minutes earlier
had called, I had something to do.
Now the machines are cleaned ...
and 't most of it staff
is gone.
For a cat a cat called
we have a pot 's address.
Yes. Second.
Ludo, which is still pork?
Alive.
That little sick this morning
arrived, did you have?
Ms. Michels, we do it this way:
I get you a live animal
and a dead animal.
't Live throat I even spot ...
and 't dead I already covered to.
I'll be in public, so I do not load off!
And such a beast weighs 40 kg, so
do not come with a grasshopper.
Roger, Mrs. Michels.
I know that it is a schijtkut,
that my balls uithangt.
Of that type who thinks that the whole
world revolves around them.
But will they pay, though.
Because I am counting the VAT not to
but they will still supplement.
Silly me! I send you a SMS
and you are sitting next to me!
I had you still said that they my mobile phone
were stolen, bitch!
Me 'n care, I' m still missing.
She called me often.
I had no private life anymore.
Think you just the way you
Shitbrick?
Wind you not! The guy can hardly
on the car before him jump.
Shut up, will you? You know I do not
tolerated that you talk when I drive
Move! From the way! I am here
the king of the road!
Ready for your spanking, Stef?
You still have your shell made
I shoot bangers off, dude!
Okay? Here he comes!
's already.
That was a easy ball.
Not again that mobile phone!
First that palooka in the cinema!
Not in a gym! Turn that off,
You know it makes me aggressive!
'n Secure Fabienne invites me to
't Zoute for her birthday.
The cunt, I was completely forgotten.
Fabienne.
This is again supermarket music,
ge--remixed by thick jean networks.
Would you not ask your wife ...
to her friend Nadine to come?
Listen 's right, Stef. I ga je
a favor done.
We go to sea.
But first I ga you a thorough
decorate course. Okay? Listen carefully!
's from point A to point G.
Try not original.
Your head is original enough.
You have no scoop on top of it.
So listen up.
A: Make sure you remain soft.
Two: If you have her talk ...
avoid with her tits
to negotiate.
Three is something that I have
tried.
This is called 'sus of his fall.
-- What?
Sus of his fall.
-- Sus?
You act like you 'n slaptitude get.
You get a fit of hysterics, in French.
Your head is always
just a meter above the ground.
Your risk is not that you bezeert!
Okay, listen. If you can stop ...
What?
-- Dan doe je 'r in.
That would surprise me. I am
blood in shape!
Love you with that asshole doing it.
-- Do not miss that car!
Sports. Bit tricky to get off.
Have you 's identity, young man?
-- Yes. Minute.
But I know you! Yes it is, 't hearing ...
I look like you 1000 per day,
so I know you not.
Paper 's vehicle, driving license,
registration, insurance,
tutti quanti.
Never thought that I had so much beer.
-- Sir!
Ho but kastaar! Almost done!
Calm down! I badly parked?
Do you know how fast you drove?
No. But when I look around scheurijzer
therefore never been to the counter. 200?
Exactly 200.
That joke hole soon 200,000 balls
costs.
What is it?
Excessive speed.
-- Wait, you.
Excessive speed?
Can I ask where ... I look
out of my caps and ...
I look at you, however. Exaggerated
speed? 's Mobile or' n. ..
's radar, sir.
-- A fixed?
a fixed radar post? Wait 's. ..
I know that you are on bridges,
transverse now, but I have not seen you.
If I see you, I immediately on my brake
stand! Then go here cogs turning!
't I do not care a straw.
I know high--ranking figures.
Good as that.
How old are you?
Day D--1, but I got my license
bought ... achieved.
Then you start
with practice.
Take 't drive, and Mr is
the killing place.
No, because women in 't make me send ...
-- Shut up! Follow me to go to the station.
Very good.
Better a good system than a poorly
process, as they say.
Indeed.
But be plumes by a delicious
chicken, that's something else.
Thanks.
Bourgeois as pigs.
The older ...
Get your paws off of my seat, you!
Where should I park here?
I put me here, I lock the whole lot.
If the red road will, move me
as I want it.
Tedju! You see where the money goes.
That is not a residence,
just a holiday.
Tedju ...
As in the movie.
You see me? You see me?
Draw a long face?
Not, I say you. If they do not
with 200, get back with me.
You're on top. 'S case.
As a precaution. From professionalism.
We are now once true professionals.
Come now. Come, come.
Let me not ...
How are we now?
It seems nothing. Come, come now ...
Nothing to ado, so that once.
It's like a dog, nothing more.
Stay with me, because I do not know
I must go.
Goal!
Stay there, you!
Is it not, no?
Dirty snot monkeys!
Times it back to your caravan,
bohemerin dirty!
Who is the king who lives here, huh?
Bastard!
What a cute piggy! a Really?
No, a power.
-- Claudy Focan, pleasant.
Director 's slaughterhouse of Anderlecht.
-- Fabienne Michel.
Al 2 Dool I am here in the neighborhood around.
They put me out ...
very friendly, moreover,
your mom or your grandmother, no idea ...
a white house with a red roof.
But you see nothing else here.
Is this a quote or something?
-- No, no cite.
I park in front me, I watch 'house.
Gray with a black roof. Did they 't
herschilderd tonight?
Say 's, Nat, is' t now between JC
and you?
I mean ... are you in love?
What you actually see in him?
He is not a playboy.
He is unpredictable, shy ...
very sensitive. I know, you see
absolutely not, but ...
He still has a large mug.
And living with that guy?
That I do not understand.
He always has money in his pocket,
and he does not work.
Tell me that he is a thief.
-- No.
He takes the money where it is.
Not just money.
These bikes, for example.
Tell me that he has rented!
Not rented, but stolen, yes!
If you rent a bike, there is always
a yellow label
with rental Rene 'or something like it!
Here only Eddy Merckx 'on!
Cheers! And relax now.
But I do nothing else!
And how do you Stef?
-- Herbegin not your thing with 4!
Nadine, I am talking about Stef and you.
He is sweet, but he is
totally my type.
Had I known, I had
brought my swimsuit.
You combed with a two over this morning?
-- How is it?
At his convenience.
Day! I feel like you pipes.
That way.
Goddamn! What a waste!
If I remember that that guy 'r is
bepotelen, I am not good!
a very nice body. Let 's see.
Curious what's under shorts that is.
Even with money, and that is now mustache.
Note 's over, I'm still
t go.
Not now, Greg! I have things to do!
D'r is a package people!
I 've also pressure pressure!
And it is just a birthday?
This Mr with his glasses. This is your man.
Help with you sir 't pig?
What pig?
-- 'T Pig! And hurry!
Ga don 't unload pig?
-- Apparently so.
You are so thin like a smelt.
't Is heavier than you.
Where is that pig?
In the silica, in my car.
's Yellow Silica.
If you enter the left of me.
't Beest is in the suitcase. Here.
Thanks, boss.
I had you a beer asked, not Mozart.
That's only 10 in cl.
Goddamn!
Damn, my mom will kill me!
Surely, that pig?
Nadine is keischattig.
And the smell of 'r.
She smells a bit like a baby's neck.
I am a little stressed
for tonight.
Keep it on with your drivel! You know
7 points on your hand!
No, but without sedaris ...
I can not ...
Although, I do not know whether it will succeed ...
No, kidding!
So you're Fabienne?
And your anniversary?
Happy birthday, then.
Take it shoots.
Is it not, no?
Sorry, but I do not want them
come to my breasts.
's but breasts!
Damn, it zeikt blood from my nose!
I am sick of it!
'Night. Shall we know
what you doing up there?
I make a photograph of the eclipse.
Apparently, there are stars to be seen.
That you 't know, the moon is called
behind you.
What 's aggressiveness, say!
Calm down, I did nothing wrong.
Cool, man.
-- Nobody is bepoteld.
Who are you?
In some lout her aanklampt?
We do not have the whole night.
If you want to reach point G, then for!
Stef And how do you do?
Again, that tells me nothing total.
Like that is always with the flu.
If he talks, you hear only
the consonants.
Ga anyway!
You must all be fooled!
Lifting it!
I 'm never without glass
seen in his hand. View 'm.
Is it?
Come here, you.
What is your name? You're good for, say!
Dan ga but I 's again ...
my husband, who 't judge with a whore.
Stop it! What are you doing?
View all yourself if you got drunk?
Beware, you fall in the water.
Damn! He has it made!
What is he doing at the bottom of it pool?
What awaits them? Spring still
in the water!
But I know him not ...
Here is t.
-- Is this your school?
See you then.
I got a very good evening spent.
Would you hug me?
What?
I wanted to know whether you wanted me
embrace, because ...
because I want to be happy.
Me too.
We call each other.
The past 3 weeks you are 15 times
assaulted become.
Successively by a psychopath,
rich kids ...
In short, a real national
of bitter!
According to me, it maybe time
to get back into question.
Because everyone seems it is fully
agree ...
it 's perhaps a bit
your fault could be.
So I ga 's address
from a friend ...
psychologist. That is not a big word,
please note.
I would you can help.
His name is Dimitri. Winners.
Will 's what else.
I want my mommy!
Does anyone know what a scourge is?
I see no lit fingers.
Who has something out?
Nobody?
Last week ...
everyone still remembers
's visit to the' t Museum ...
of accident victims.
Well, I should ...
from the bottom of my heart ...
to apologize.
Honestly!
Children ...
tell you how ...
I love you!
Because I ...
I was not in my ...
we say, normal to do.
I know it for some ...
must have been terrible.
Especially for you, Candy ...
Charlotte!
The debt of these!
Stuff!
Stuff ...
is a pest!
I've never felt something intense.
While we vreeën, she looked me
with her large eyes Labrador.
I know! 's Old monkey you should not face
learn draw!
I think she has never
received a turn.
I say this not to stoefen.
Because she has cried afterwards.
This is a classic, man!
After all the drug problems of the r. ..
and that gerotzooi by three.
You mean ... that gangbang?
I am proud of you. You have a flawless
path to point G!
Thanks to me, means welt!
-- Thanks, JC!
Sure, man.
Good as that.
You are now a barker could buy.
I have a house on it rural
's eye.
You've no need
to move, huh?
If you have no children?
Why are you tonight
no rabbit food?
Rabbit? Keilekker!
-- Yes, with roots!
Only is it we never succeeded
these poor creatures to develop.
Say 's, JC, would you not be?
Sure. I have my cutter not,
but it will probably go.
Please note that rabbit I clean
but not the roots!
Be careful! The main ...
... He was a firm tick in his neck
it.
Without hesitation! So!
After you have him only his frakske
still pulling ...
and I can even 'n cap
them for your sweet.
Sensitive souls, now please the eyes
be closed.
Goodbye, miffy!
It's not very elegant you take
in my suitcase.
If I had his head Florent Pagny,
I 'm really different.
Believe me or not ... Vanessa.