Captioning made possible by
trimark home video
[classical music playing]
How are you doing?
Enjoying the party?
I'm enjoying
the music.
[Applause]
[Blowing]
My dear, I would
like to thank you
for accepting
our invitation,
and I'd like to introduce
you to the gentleman
who first suggested
your presence here...
Colonel Peter vojnovic.
Unfortunately, colonel,
she had an emergency come up,
and she has to leave.
I will remember this night
for a long time.
You may never
forget it, mowgli.
And I want you to know
the United States government
is grateful for your help,
miss chernynko.
As soon as I get
my green card.
Very interesting,
the turnout.
Yes. so, what...
I'm--
colonel?
[Gasping]
Careful!
careful!
Oh, my god!
What is this?
Aah! aah!
Let me go!
[Flushes toilet]
Unh! there is no--
oh, my god.
[Banging on door]
Goran? what's going on?
[Banging]
This is unacceptable!
[Hiss]
I must go into
this facility!
You'll have to wait.
No! I have to--
hey!
You can't keep me
from going to--
we've changed your hotel,
sir, for safety reasons.
The building across from
the Sheraton is empty.
This makes it easier
for us to...
Colonel?
Yaah!
Woman: the following
is a special report
of the European-
American network.
Colonel Peter vojnovic
will be the first
of 4 high-ranking officers
to be tried on Friday
for crimes against humanity
in the Bosnian
war crimes tribunal.
Vojnovic was the leader
of a serbian military unit
known as the brown hats.
This group tops the list
of human rights
organizations around the world
as perpetrators of
inhuman acts of attrition
and so-called
ethnic cleansing
against croats and Bosnians
during the Bosnian war.
Since the capture
of the serbian colonel
by American military forces
some 3 months ago,
numerous bomb threats
have been made
against the u.N. Prison
compound here in the hague.
Steve: high fences firewall.
Not getting in that way.
If you can't jump it, go around.
Let's try Parker's domain.
Children--none.
wife--deceased.
Secretaries, valets,
housekeeper, subordinates,
uh, driver.
Pets--cats, dogs,
a hamster, a horse.
The horse is gift
from...Ha ha!
Nsc advisor gene Parker.
Name--goblin.
How sweet. Goblin.
Stubbs: 5 seconds.
I'm in.
Deep enough to see
that nsc advisor Parker
has awarded a certain
"bibi" 3 stars.
Stubbs: what time's
your plane, Mitchell?
About 35 minutes, general.
My kid's outside sleeping
in the limo right now.
Oh. well, good hunting.
Oh, by the way,
Mitchell,
does Mr. Parker's
information reveal
exactly what bibi does
to rate 3 stars?
She bites.
She bites?
I hear the girls in
Romania are pretty sexy.
You said the same thing
about Poland.
I said that?
But I've never seen one.
All I ever see are those
not-so-sexy secretaries
in another ugly embassy.
Bucharest is the last one,
and it's only 3 days,
I had better things
to do, Steve.
Wait a minute.
For 2 years, all I hear
is that we gotta spend
more time together,
and now you've got
better things to do?
Taking me to work with you
is not exactly what
i meant by more time.
Look, Chris...
You thought any more about
what we talked about?
I know you love
your grandma--
I don't want to live with
my grandparents, Steve.
How's that going to help
things between us?
I want to live with you.
Look, Chris...
I'm not a very good dad...
And I'm never going to be
a very good dad. Period.
I'm a cranky, irascible,
impatient workaholic,
and you don't have
very much fun with me.
I mean, let's face it.
I don't make you happy.
The truth is
i don't make you happy.
Morning, sarge.
Hi. Steve Mitchell,
Chris Mitchell,
to see ambassador gannon,
please.
Welcome to Bucharest,
Mr. Mitchell.
I will let deputy tomberlin
know you are here.
Mr. Mitchell.
Hi.
I am dora Pratt,
ambassador's governess.
How do you do?
This is his daughter Gina.
Hi, Gina. This is my--
we were just about to catch
a bus tour of the city.
Perhaps--Chris, would you
like to come along?
Perhaps Chris would
like to--excuse me.
What?
Chris: I brought
stuff to read.
You kidding? That girl's
hotter than a pistol,
plus it'll keep you
out of another embassy.
He'd love to come.
Dora: ah, good.
Ha ha ha!
She's waiting for you
in the old security room.
You'll be meeting
ambassador gannon at lunch.
Very good.
Thank you.
Otherwise, your time
is pretty much your own.
Chris?
Hi, George.
Come on, let's go.
[Engine starts]
Thank god they finally
got around sending you guys
to update those
computer systems.
Mr. Mitchell?
Yeah.
[Coughs]
Steven Mitchell,
this is Erica long.
I'll be downstairs
if you need anything.
[Door closes]
Ha ha!
Nice to see you,
bubbles.
Uh...
Of all the computer rooms
in all the embassies
in all the world,
i gotta stroll into...
We were bound to run into
each other sooner or later.
Just the luck
of the draw, right?
Did you do Moscow?
Uh, yep. And Warsaw
and east Berlin.
Who was your liaison?
You know
that's classified.
You can talk about a miracle,
but never mention the angel.
Yeah, right.
I've done 4.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Prague was the best.
Budapest wasn't bad,
either.
I can't believe
we haven't been together
on one of these before.
So what do you say
we go see the ambassador
for the security access
and head down to the site?
There's no rush,
is there?
I mean, that thing's
been down there
since the first day
of the cold war.
How'd you do it?
Luck of the draw.
[Chuckles]
Something tells me that
you used some serious grease
to get us here together.
What else is that
something telling you?
[Laughs]
Erica: does this belt
really open?
Excuse me, sir.
You two find everything
you need here?
So far so good.
Thank you.
Good. ambassador gannon's
ready for you
whenever you're
finished up in here.
Hopefully before lunch.
Ok. thank you,
sergeant.
Ohh...
[Giggling]
[Metal detector beeps]
Ma'am, I need you to step
through again, please.
Oh, yes.
Right this way.
Um, step back.
Metal detector's
not working.
Guard on radio: Command,
the metal detector
in the lobby
is not working.
Steve: so what else is there
to do in this town?
I hear the Russian circus
is in town.
Ha. the Russian circus.
Ok, that's an idea.
We could do that.
So how's the wife,
Steve-O?
Car accident.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Kind of
a bad start, huh?
At least you got a chance
for a little bit
of that domestic life
you were looking for.
I never figured you wanted
to go that way, so...
I never heard you ask.
So what's the security gimmick
down here this time?
Ambassador'll let us know.
That's why he's waiting.
Well, let's get on
the good foot.
Sergeant nakajima, this is
my liaison Steve Mitchell.
Yeah, hi. We met.
Good to meet you.
Why don't you stay here?
The sergeant will show you
how the computer system works.
I'll be back
in 5 minutes.
Right.
Well, um...
Nice to see you again.
All right, this place
may not look like much
to a world traveler
like yourself...
"Used to be" is right.
It's older than dirt.
I've still got all the
surveillance connections here
so if I want to take
a walk through the lobby,
or take a stroll through
the streets of Bucharest,
I just press this button,
and I'm outside.
Look, it's a wedding.
How charming.
Talk about starting off
on the wrong foot.
What's that,
rumanian foreplay?
Actually, they call it
preludeu.
Preludeu. tough.
[Woman yelling]
Shit.
[People screaming]
[Sirens]
[Door bangs open]
[Alarm blaring]
[Men shouting orders]
[People screaming]
Down! move! You, sit!
[Explosion]
Down!
[Alarm stops]
Move.
Man: the ambassador.
There's one on the second
floor, west corridor.
[Gun cocks]
And another one
in the kitchen.
Aah!
He's cleaning up with
a thermo-tracking device.
They'd have to get a sensor
in here to use that thing.
And on the third floor,
across the stairs, 2 people.
Shit, that's us.
This place was done over
in the fifties, but it works.
Goran, there is nothing
across the stairs.
Aah!
come on!
Come on now!
Man: [whispering]
Are you ok?
They've cut
communications.
Hell, that's cold.
What are you doing?
Disappearing.
[Tapping keyboard]
You're about to witness
the shortest hostage
crisis in history.
What are you--
what are you doing?
Just keep your eye
on the desk.
The desk is rigged?
Just watch the desk.
One step closer.
One step...Gotcha.
Uh-uh.
what?
Zoom in on
this other camera.
I seem to recognize those
pretty blond curls, don't you?
Sir, she's not
in the line of fire.
You kill Erica
instead of him,
this thing gets
a hell of a lot worse.
I need to erase some
classified information
in the basement
of this building,
and I need her
to access it.
I'm going for that woman
before he picks up that
thermo-tracking again.
Parker: thank you
for coming, gentlemen.
I appreciate
your quick response.
Who's closest
to the embassy?
Buck swain.
He's putting together
a combined special forces
unit as we speak.
Elite of the army, Navy,
air force, and marines.
Bates: what I want to know
about is the security breach.
Security in our embassies?
Tell me another story.
[Shouting orders]
[Whispering]
ambassador.
Ambassador gannon.
I need the security code.
It's not gonna do
much good in here.
I don't plan on staying.
6...
G...
3...0...
Goran: ambassador gannon.
That man is the American
ambassador to Romania.
And you are?
Diplomatic attaché
Erica long.
Your name must have more to do
with your legs, miss long...
Than your lifespan.
At least I still have
a lifespan.
Oh, boy...
We got a live one here.
Tim, I'm at
the north corridor.
All right, um,
stay to the left
to the rear
of the building.
Did you get that? Sir?
Step out there
and read this.
Wait.
The whole world
is going to be watching.
Male reporter: Someone
has just been pushed out.
It looks like U.S.
ambassador Jacques gannon.
[People talking]
[Sirens blaring]
[Cameras clicking]
"The serbian
liberation front
is holding
37 prisoners of war."
"Their fate is in the hands
of the United States government
"who now must arrange
for the immediate release
"of colonel Peter vojnovic
"who was criminally
abducted 3 months ago
from the Russian embassy
by American military forces."
"Until that time...
"One hostage will be
killed every hour
"the second is being
chosen as I speak.
The first will be..."
"Ambassador gannon."
Me.
Reporter: he's coming down
slowly. Almost at the bottom.
[Cocks rifle]
Reporter: there's a palpable
tension here in the air
as ambassador gannon steps away
from his besieged embassy.
Ambassador gannon is approaching
the rumanian police lines.
He's just a few short feet
from safety.
Unh!
[Shouting]
Reporter: ...Whisking him into
a vehicle under heavy guard.
As you can imagine,
chaos has broken out,
but it appears the ambassador
has been successfully saved.
[Beeping]
Reporter: the vehicle
the American ambassador entered
seconds ago has blown up!
God damn it!
How'd I know
you'd come for me?
We have some unfinished
business, don't we?
Thought we were pretty much
finished for today.
Enthusiasm is
the greatest aphrodisiac.
Tim, second floor
good to go?
Go! go! Go!
Go! go!
What's telling me miss long
was helped out of here
by the guy
that doesn't exist?
Go get her.
Ok, Tim, we're in
the third floor
emergency stairwell.
What up?
All right, sir. Stay towards
the rear of the building.
The living areas.
There are no cameras there.
That's not going to help
with the thermo.
There isn't any
thermo-tracking device.
[Muffled explosion]
Yes!
Steve, why are we going up?
Shouldn't we be heading down?
Not until we know
how to get down
listen, if those guys
do know what's down there,
they also know it's old,
and they're not going to have
to buy much time to get
control of that thing.
Trust me.
You've got to be
kidding me.
Weren't the fifties fun?
Wouldn't know.
I wasn't born yet.
Gentlemen, I think
we should take advantage
I suggest you let me bomb
the shit out of them.
There are 37 people
in there.
Did you make all those speeches
after the Iran crisis
about shooting first and
asking questions later?
He was going through
a divorce at the time.
Oh. sorry, general.
I suggest you let me call in
an immediate air strike.
General swain is
already halfway there.
We've already decided
on a policy--
Parker:
gentlemen! gentlemen!
This is more of a...
Special situation.
Early in the cold war,
we found a way to
position atomic bombs.
We determined areas
of primary defense.
We decided the best strategy
would be to have these bombs
already planted at
these designated targets
in the capitals of
these communist nations.
This way we would have
first-strike capability
before the enemy could even
launch their missiles.
A nuclear defense wall,
so to speak.
Where we could most easily
conceal these weapons...
In our own embassies.
[All arguing]
Bates: who the hell
made that decision?
How much of this nuclear
wall still exists?
I might have...
If they hadn't attacked
on tday
we sent 2 operatives
there to disarm it
and ship it back.
Is there any way we can shut
down the system from here?
It's a monitoring system.
It doesn't regulate.
These terrorists know
something we don't...
And even more likely we don't
have any way to stop them.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
I don't think he knows
a thing about this.
I can't permit that.
The previous administration
ordered the joint chiefs
to keep silent about this
before you were one of them.
That order's still valid.
No. this is
national security.
Right. need I remind you
who is still responsible for
making a final call on this?
Hang it up, ed.
We are not going to get down
there in the open, baby.
The ventilation
shafts.
No.
there's a pressure sensor
that'll send an alarm
to security.
What if we change
the pressure?
Co2.
All right, all this
seems like a lot of trouble
to erase some information.
What is it going to take
for you to tell me
what's going on here?
I'm still one hostage short.
Did you find that woman?
Goran, there's
some commotion outside.
Female reporter:
I don't see anything yet,
yes, it is a young,
13--maybe 14-year-old boy.
Or should I say
a very brave young man.
[Cameras clicking]
Unh!
As we stand here watching,
one of the terrorists
is lifting the boy from
the ledge onto the roof.
This poor boy has spent
the last 10 minutes
dangling high
above the ground.
Ok?
yeah.
Sorry.
aah!
Gaah!
God.
Erica: we are not
getting paid enough
to be part of
this kind of work.
I mean,
do you have any idea
what we're worth
in the real world
doing what we do?
It just doesn't
feel right.
Feels pretty good
from here.
Come on.
I'm not kidding.
I'm not kidding, either,
but you got to
consider the perks.
International cuisine,
beautiful hotels,
beautiful museums,
interesting people,
exotic places...
Right. where else
would I get to see
the inside of
a ventilation shaft?
Maybe we should
ask for a raise.
Yeah, there you go.
Yeah.
[Beeping]
Tim: you guys
are in the red.
What's taking so long?
Come on!
Come on.
Tim: pressure's up already.
Cool it down.
Yeah.
Yeah, ok.
What, do I look
like a fireman?
I don't know what's
wrong. It's clogged.
Ok, it's not working.
We'd better get out of here.
Faith.
just a little faith.
[Beeping]
They know where you are.
Get out.
You guys hear me?
You...
[Beeping stops]
Tim: ok, ok, go.
Straight or left?
All right,
take it to the left.
Let's go.
Aah!
I think I've got my 1:00.
Ean TV has just picked up
this live transmission,
said to be coming from
within the United States embassy
in Bucharest.
I have decided...
That this young man...
Will be my next message to you.
I will shoot him
unless I'm given proof
that colonel vojnovic
has been released...
In, uh...
9 minutes.
Son of a bitch has his own
satellite transmission.
I want nothing
that happens
in that embassy
on the air!
Scramble it, and feed it
into our system.
God damn it.
Ok, Tim, we're
at a crossroads. Which way?
And then call me at
the next intersection.
Ok.
go.
Tim: son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch. He's
gonna kill some kid.
I didn't see
a kid down there.
How old is he?
Tim: uh, 13, 14.
What color jacket
has he got on?
Jean jacket,
wearing a walkman.
It's Chris.
What the hell
is he doing there?
Steve, you don't follow
protocol here,
I don't have any choice.
Well, you shoot me,
you can't do very much
with that bomb, can you?
I can't do
anything with it
if you leave me alone
here, either.
God damn it, Steve!
We are here for a bomb.
We have to do this.
He's my son, Erica.
Help me.
[Cocks gun]
I'm in the John
on the second floor.
Tim: all right.
Just sit tight.
I'll let you know
when you're clear.
You have 2 minutes.
I still don't see the colonel.
The clock
is still ticking.
He have to do something.
What the hell can we do, huh?
With what he's sitting on
and a gun pointed
at a kid's head?
They still got
a gun on my kid?
Yeah. a minute 30.
Well, get me there.
Ok, ok, go--
no, no, wait.
I gotta go.
Ok, ok, go.
You're clear.
Chris!
Come on!
Aaaaaaah!
Secure that room!
Where is the kid?
[Hinge squeaking]
Move!
Oh, no boy!
Chris, are you ok?
Up, here.
You sick murderer.
The lady of the house
will be your next 1:00.
Goran, NATO
is causing problems
getting the colonel
out of prison.
They need more time.
[Whispering] help me,
god. Help me, please.
I give you another hour.
Son of a--
[gunshot]
I'd like to recommend
we send for vojnovic,
only to get Goran
out of the embassy.
Gene, you know
American foreign policy
on war criminals
and terrorists.
How are you gonna
explain to the president
we let vojnovic out of
jail after just 2 hours?
The president is not gonna
authorize the release
unless we explain why we
have to get that terrorist
we're talking about
an atomic bomb here, gene.
Then it would seem we're
going to have to tell him.
[Door unlocks]
Before we take
one more step...
You should know...
I'm a croat.
Ohh!
Man: come on,
get in there.
The keys, damn it!
Man: do something!
Come on, hurry!
Where the hell is swain?
Saddle up!
I'm colonel vasilescu.
Welcome to Romania, sir.
Thank you, colonel.
It's ok.
They get anything
important?
No. everything important
was in my throat.
And what are you doing here?
You're supposed
to be on a bus,
not getting
your brains blown out.
I put you on a bus
with a cute fat girl,
and what is this?
You don't
like embassies,
you don't like my work.
What are you doing here?
TV announcer: We understand
they are under the command
of Michael "buck" swain,
highly decorated field commander
who took part
in operation desert storm.
Get in position.
Man: set!
Move up, move up, go!
Captain.
I want to put Alpha squad
right in their face,
Baker at the back door--
excuse me, general.
We should discuss
whatever movements
you plan.
The embassy
is United States territory.
On this sidewalk,
you're in Romania, sir.
Oh, ok, excuse me.
Uh, captain.
Yes, sir.
Find me a spot to place
an operations command post.
Right away, sir.
And, colonel,
since your people
do seem to be having
such a great deal
of difficulty
dispersing that
crowd back there,
perhaps when
the shooting starts,
you'll keep 'em on
your side of the line.
General swain here.
Goran: I was hoping
they'd send you, swain.
All right,
who is this?
Your old schoolmate, buck.
Goran mladinov.
I know all the options,
swain.
Nothing you do will work,
unless delivering
colonel vojnovic.
Steve: these tunnels
lead to a fork.
That means she and i
have got to go left.
Well, looks like that tunnel
opens up to the river.
If you want to get your kid
out of the embassy,
how do I know all these
goons don't know about it?
Sir, they haven't
bothered us in this room,
so they're not working
off this map.
Ok, I want you to take
Chris down that tunnel,
and I want you to get
him out of the city.
Off the continent.
You hear me?
So, who is this
mladinov guy?
Well, he finished at the top
of his class at ft. Bragg,
and then trained
by delta command and the CIA.
Serbian parents,
but raised in America.
Ended up heading what's left
of vojnovic's brown hats.
Do they teach what he
knew about that embassy
in bragg, general?
Then how did he
know about it?
I've been told that
the metal detectors failed.
Could be a coincidence,
but highly unlikely to me.
He could be clairvoyant,
but that'd be a longshot.
I'm no intelligence officer,
but if I had to guess,
I'd say Goran had
some people on the inside.
Which means he may know
everything you know...
And probably knows
more than I know.
Standard operating
procedure
until you hear
from me, general.
[Hangs up phone]
He's going to kill everyone
before we can get in there.
I say we go back
to using vojnovic
and get Goran
out of the embassy.
Have you been with us
for the last 2 hours?
I've been in touch
with interpol
and come up with
a few options.
Actually, a few very close
choices to vojnovic,
all in Europe.
Bates:
this isn't going to work.
Dalton: even if
he buys it, gene,
it's only gonna work
till they get together.
Right. at the airport,
outside the embassy.
That's all
we're trying to do here.
Go back to the guy
before, number 2.
Borghelli.
"Car thief turned chief."
Doesn't say of what?
It says chef,
not chief.
Oh, right.
I'll do what I can.
[Italian pop music playing]
[Humming]
Giorgio borghelli?
CIA.
You guys are fast, huh?
Hey, borghelli!
This vojnovic guy
had taste,
huh?
You think
i make this for you,
I can maybe
keep the shoes, no?
Of course.
Sure.
Mama Mia.
Look at this watch.
An important mission I am
helping with here, no?
I don't know why.
I don't even know
one American.
Agent:
is the camera ready?
Ok, you don't have
to do anything
except sit.
And try to look
like you're thinking
about something important.
But that's difficult,
you know?
I mean, who knows
I'm sure we can arrange
for you to keep the watch.
Great.
And a little trip
to Miami?
Maybe?
I've never been
to America, hmm?
And a little
spending money.
5,000, 10,000.
We'll find somebody else.
Bãne.
take me back. Finito.
No. you know too much.
What?
Take me back.
The camera's not on, is it?
I'm sorry you had
to be involved in this.
Your, uh, chief borghelli
looks a little chunky.
He's gotten fat.
Give him today's paper.
I want to speak to him.
We've got a little problem
with the sound up here.
We're gonna work it out.
We have a big problem
with the sound.
We don't have any!
Look, relax.
We can do this.
The moment I started
looking for a face,
I knew I needed a voice
to put with it.
This little pig went to market.
This little pig went home.
This little pig had roast beef.
This little pig had none.
Went wee wee wee wee wee,
all the way--
excuse me.
Go through that
"wee wee wee" stuff
again, please.
This little pig went
"wee wee wee wee wee wee wee wee
wee wee wee wee"
hello.
That's it.
He's on
the line. Go!
Colonel?
Captain.
You have done well.
Your courage
and that of our men
has won the day.
I'm sure our countrymen
will be very happy.
Your wife and daughters
will be relieved.
I understand.
I have arranged
for a plane.
We brought
our own pilot.
Excellent.
Well, I guess I'll see
you at the airport.
One daughter.
One.
Yes, you will.
Good-bye, sir.
Captain.
Yes.
How long have I been away?
3 months.
How is it possible
my wife has had another
daughter in that time?
It is not, sir.
I understand.
I'll see you soon.
[Hangs up]
Nice recovery.
Yes.
yes.
This is a fork.
The exit's that way.
Take care of him.
Dad.
What?
Yeah?
Yeah? what?
When the guy had
the gun in my face,
I was thinking that
if I'd listened to you,
I'd probably be
sightseeing right now.
Look, maybe it's not
all you, you know?
Maybe I'm just as bad
at being a son
as you are at being a dad.
Take care of him.
Let's go, buddy.
Come on.
Seemed like a nice kid.
He's a great kid.
That's my problem.
You'll find
a common ground.
Gee, where have I heard
that one before?
Who said that?
Did I say that?
Maybe you just need to spend
some more time together.
That I've heard before.
You're not doing a little
better financially.
You'd have some more free time
to deal with your life...
Bubbles.
Ok, colonel,
bring it in.
TV announcer: We understand that
this bus that you're seeing now
will be taking the hostages
to safety.
If the rumors are true
that serbian colonel vojnovic
has been released from prison,
it would be a reversal
of long-time U.S. policy
of no negotiation
with terrorists.
TV announcer: We're still
waiting for confirmation--
wait a minute.
There appears to be a group
exiting the compound
at this time. Yes.
I'm counting 7, 8, 9 people
being used apparently
as human shields by--
Goran: go get 'em.
TV announcer: A woman has just
burst out of the building,
and she has a gun.
She's grabbing...
No.
Petra: back! Get back now!
Shit!
What the hell happened?!
Quickly.
In your places,
all of you.
[Woman sobbing]
I wonder if you two
could help me.
TV announcer: There has been no
explanation as to why--
a man has just stepped
out of the compound.
We can't tell
whether he's a hostage
or one of the terrorists.
TV announcer: He's walking
towards the military personnel
who have been on ready alert
since this siege started
some 5 hours ago.
You are...
You are swain?
He said you are a liar.
Where is the real
vojnovic?
That is the real
vojnovic.
You can't lie
to me, sir.
He said
he'll kill my wife
if you don't
tell me the truth.
I'm not lying to you.
Thank you, sir.
Soldier: gunfire!
Incoming!
Let him go.
Let me go!
Soldier: hold your fire!
Bastards.
Getting a confirmation
on vojnovic.
Get me the Pentagon.
Sir.
Attends.
He said...
That is the real
vojnovic.
Colonel vojnovic had a few,
shall we say, unusual habits.
He believed that every second
of his time was precious,
and he eliminated
everything and anything
that might take
that time away from him.
So...
What is wrong
with this picture?
What's wrong in his dress
that is time consuming
even in
the smallest degree?
Come on, come on.
It can't be so hard.
The shoes.
They have laces.
Laces?
He never wore laces.
I know they don't give
laces in prison.
Those shoes, he would
have had to buy.
Never.
Goran: that general
knew what was at stake,
and he lied.
He threw your
husband's life away.
It wasn't me
who killed him.
I put a little something
in your pocket
that will show them
what you're feeling.
You lied.
TV announcer: I can see
a man down on the ground.
There's total chaos
here at this time.
Let's get a medic
in here now!
I'm all right.
TV announcer: It appears that
general buck swain was shot.
Someone's
gotta call him.
I'm not calling him.
You should have told me
about vojnovic!
this asshole was dead!
Dalton: sorry, general.
Couldn't chance a leak.
We are doing the best we can
here, general.
Why is it that I have
the funny feeling
that you don't have a clue
to what you're doing?
If you have any suggestion
as to an alternate strategy,
you know,
we'd love to hear it.
Ok.
Ok, ok, ok,
cards.
You were, uh,
of course,
thinking that
was the last place
they were
gonna look.
I figure if they
searched this far,
they wouldn't notice.
Before all hell
broke loose,
I don't suppose
you had time
in your chat with
the ambassador
to find out how to
turn these things off.
No.
No worries.
No worries?
Kiss me for luck.
Last time we kissed,
some very terrible
people showed up.
Yeah.
All right, listen.
I brought swain up to date
on those tunnels
under the embassy,
and I've got a couple
of technicians
that can go down there
with the un-disarming codes
and get close to the bomb.
If the terrorists
see them coming,
that bomb's
gonna start ticking.
No. we should
position them
and then that piece will allow
them to get by them,
they'll disarm it
before he gets back to it.
And then make a fast move--
or we could...
Make it slower.
Could you run through
that first part again?
Yeah, that's fuckin'
genius, stubbs.
I got it. It's gonna
take hostages.
Well, so is waiting.
You got any ideas?
I don't care
who you are.
I only know
that this museum
is older
than your country,
and you're not
digging a hole
in the middle of it.
[Jackhammering]
[Curator protesting
in native language]
Soldier: go ahead!
Hey, hold on.
Wait a minute.
Who the hell are you two?
I'm afraid I can't
tell you that, sir.
Swain: wait a minute.
Who are they?
That's on a need-to-know
basis. Top secret.
Bullshit!
buck!
No! if this is gonna happen
on my watch over here,
then somebody is gonna
start talking now!
They're computer
specialists, buck.
There's an atomic bomb
under that embassy,
and it has to be disarmed.
It's in the small room
attached to the rear tunnel
in the schematic.
You could have
told me that.
I'm sorry.
Oh, sorry.
Watch where you're
pointing that thing.
Ok.
[Beeping]
Uhh!
Cakewalk.
[Beeping faster]
Oh, shit.
What did you
just do?
I got about 10 seconds
to pull one of these wires.
Red, white, or green.
Isn't green
your favorite color?
All 3?
How did you know that?
Hey! he didn't bring
this briefcase down here
just for one
of these things.
He's probably
got this entire matrix
Steve, come on.
We've got to do this now.
Baby, if I don't
do that now,
we can kiss that
good-bye.
Man: drop your weapons!
Drop your weapons!
It's rigged!
It's booby-trapped!
Shit!
[Screaming]
Swain: red caboose,
red caboose,
delta Charlie, over.
Red caboose, red caboose,
Altschuler:
yes, general. Go ahead.
It's altschuler,
computer technician.
The tunnels--
they were rigged
with explosives.
How many down?
I'm the only one
left, sir.
Can you make it back?
Altschuler?
Yes. I can
make it back.
Roger that.
Swain: I need to tell him
about vojnovic now.
He's sitting on
an atomic bomb, general.
You're not even sure
he knows about that bomb.
But with an assault,
we get the jump on him.
If we tell him,
he pushes the button.
Announcer: the man walking
toward the embattled embassy
is general swain...
And he appears
to be unarmed.
It is not precisely clear
at this time
as to what
his purpose is.
I don't understand
how you ended up here.
I never imagined you
as a terrorist.
Freedom fighter.
Freedom fighter?
Your cause
doesn't define you
as much as killing
civilians.
I remember everything
they taught me over there.
Your colonel vojnovic
was killed leaving
the prison today.
You kill
another hostage,
and we're coming in.
You may have time
to kill half of them
but we are coming in.
You have to surrender.
Surrender?
I don't remember that class
at fort bragg, swain.
Goran.
It would take
an atomic bomb
to keep me
out of there.
[Breathing heavily]
Nice of you to join me.
Sorry I'm late.
I've initiated the sequence
on both terminals.
Ok, I got the primary.
You got the secondary.
Primary access code.
Done. you got
the secondary access code?
Done.
Disarmament
activated. ok.
Right. uh...
Time to detona...
Time to detonation.
Erica, you got this?
It's time to detonation.
The bomb--
the bomb is ticking.
Did any of what I was saying
earlier make any sense?
About us not getting
what we deserve?
Oh.
Oh, god.
You did this?
You just lit the fuse
on an atomic bomb.
For starters.
These guys who shot
their way in here,
these terrorist pricks--
you let them in?
They have not behaved
as we had planned,
but somebody needed
to keep the army off us
while we get the money.
Money?
what money?
The government will blame
what are about to be
dead terrorists
for taking it.
Are you nuts?
How about we should teach
our government a lesson
for putting
this damn thing in here?
Very moral bullshit.
How about there's
20 people dead up there,
and there's going to be
another 2 million?
How about since I know
you activated that bomb,
you've got
an override code.
How about you
give it to me now?
You've gotten everything
you're going to get
from me today.
Except for these.
Put them on.
Detonation in
less than 30 minutes.
Goran didn't take
your news well.
We should've done it
my way from the get-go.
The president has given you
the go-ahead--
whatever means necessary.
Wildfire's hot.
The terrorists
activated the bomb.
I'm sorry.
Heh!
It seems Goran's
not angry enough
to blow Bucharest
off the map.
The brown hats will let
bygones be bygones.
Now that vojnovic
is dead,
we should ask
for someone else.
[Cell phone rings]
Yes?
It's swain.
Why don't we ask
for money?
For god's sakes,
what are you doing?
Same thing we've been
doing all day.
We still want that plane--
fully fueled.
I need confirmation that
that nuke has been disarmed,
or we're not talking
any further.
Look, you're under
20 minutes now.
This is no time
to play games.
What is it you want?
Goran?
Goran!
[Hangs up]
Did you ever find
Erica long?
What?
Swain: all right,
listen up.
Your lives, those of
thousands of others,
as well as the reputation
of your country
depends on how fast
you do your duty.
Move!
To your stations.
Man: go, go, go!
[Yelling]
Go.
Get him!
I got him!
Push these people
back! Move!
Come on, everybody
against the wall!
[Groaning]
Go!
All right.
[Yelling]
Hostages are against
the south wall.
Stay away
from the south wall.
[People screaming]
Go! go!
Go!
[People yelling]
Where's Goran?
[Gunfire outside]
[Knocks]
[Hollow knock]
[Gunshots]
Bitch.
[Yelling]
Soldier: move! Move!
Uhh!
Aah! uhh!
Aah!
Ooh! uhh!
Soldier: all right!
[Gunfire stops]
Move it! Move it!
How long before
we're toast?
9 minutes.
Where's the egghead?
Sir.
Sir,
here I am, sir.
All right, let's go.
How much are you
extorting them for?
[Sighs]
What do you care?
I've trusted you
with our cause.
You never mentioned
putting a gun to a kid's head
or shooting a hostage
every hour.
Is that how you intend
to get respect for your cause?
This, coming from you...
Who is holding
the whole city hostage?
Now, you're going
to shut that thing down
and standby while I make
some real demands.
Uhh!
Ohh!
It seems to me
we both got fucked here.
Maybe you got it worse.
[Gunshot]
Ok, Erica.
The game is over.
End of the line.
The jig, baby, is up.
Now give me the code
before I kill you.
You shoot me, you never
get past that bomb.
Well, I can't do
anything with it
if you leave me here
alone, either, can I?
It was never supposed
to go this far,
but it's too late
to change anything now.
Erica!
That's it.
Ok, get in there.
Go, go!
Have you seen
Steve Mitchell?
Jesus.
Trooper!
[Breathing heavily]
Hey, hey, hey!
What? What?
The tunnel
was sealed.
Take my son
out of here, please!
Get him out of here!
Hold it! Hold it!
Steve: I'm the bomb guy!
Don't shoot!
I'm with the bomb!
I got to get to the bomb!
You try all
the back doors yet?
Closed out.
I don't get it.
Damn, she loaded
a virus in it.
Shit.
Any other back ways
you know of?
It's just too late.
Think!
I'm thinking.
I'm...
There's only one way to go,
and that's straight up.
General, I'll make a deal
with you.
Give me a minute,
will you?
If you get my kid
off this continent,
I'll take this thing
out by hand.
We got about...
I guess, 90 seconds.
Do it.
He's going to take out
the core of the bomb.
The radiation will melt him
like butter.
Swain: altschuler,
shut up!
Get moving!
Go!
Go! go!
I know he's doing this for
his country and all that...
Maybe he's doing it for
all the people this would kill.
Maybe he's doing it for you.
Think about that.
Now run, boy!
[Buzzing]
[Cell phone rings]
[Rings]
I love it when you're
sentimental, bubbles,
calling me babe.
Erica!
Give...
Give me the code.
I just gave it to you.
Sir?
[Cell phone rings]
[Rings]
Hi. what are you wearing?
$25 million.
Well, that ought
to be enough
to give you 3 days
at Chanel.
Uh, listen, you know,
downstairs, I was, uh...
I knew you wouldn't really
let that bomb explode,
would you?
You really should get
to know me better.
I intend to, baby.
I'm coming after you.
Oh, good. Well,
I'm counting on it.
I can hear you breathing.
You really should
keep that phone close.
I'll make it easy
for you to find me.
Your dad's
a hero, hmm?
What's the matter?
Oh.
Aah!
So, first night in town--
what do you think
we should do?
Well, I hear the Romanian
girls are pretty sexy.
I had you all fixed up,
and what did you do?
You got off the bus.
I never got on the bus.
Well, there you go.
Well, then i
might as well go home
and live with grandma.
Steve:
grandma?
Where'd you get
that idea?
Who said that?
Did I say that?
You're sticking
with me.
What do you say...
We hang around
Europe for a while?
Chris:
another embassy?
No. let's just say...
I'm expecting a call.
Captioning made possible by
trimark home video
captioned by the national
captioning institute
--www.Ncicap.Org--