THE FOLLOWING IS BASED
ON A TRUE STORY
Excuse me, sir.
You've come in the wrong way.
I'm sorry.
This is the old entrance.
The visitor's center's
back out and left.
All right... I'll
wander over there.
Well worth it. Been through
some amazing times.
This nation should
commit itself...
to achieving the goal,
before this decade is out....
of landing a man on the moon
and returning him safely.
Liftoff. The clock is running.
Godspeed, John Glenn.
We choose to go to the moon.
To go to the moon in this decade
and do the other things...
not because they are easy,
but because they are hard.
Liftoff. Go control
Tminus 1 minute,
35 seconds and counting.
Ignition sequence start
Tower clear.
Apollo 9, you're go all the way.
Apollo 10, your trajectory
and guidance are go.
Man is about to launch himself
on a trip to the moon.
Neil Armstrong.
Edwin "Buzz''Aldrin.
Michael Collins.
Next stop for them, the moon.
The lunar age is about to begin.
When the guy counts down...
the 3 astronauts will take off
in Apollo 11 for America.
The rocket will fly to the moon...
Landing module.
Landing module comes off
and lands.
The astronauts come out and get
shot my Martians with lasers!
- Damien.
- And their heads explode!
They they'll fly to
Earth and kill us!
That won't happen.
It might.
Next? Graeme.
Just a minute, Graeme.
- Melanie?
- I haven't done the moon landing.
Thank God.
I've made a model of the
telescope and dish in Parkes.
When Neil Armstrong lands
on the moon...
the world will be watching
television pictures...
from the radio telescope in Parkes.
Mr. Callen, the prime minister
wants to see you.
- Can it wait?
- I don't think so.
What's it about?
He just got off the phone
to the White House.
- Do you know who just phoned?
- No, sir.
The President of the U.S.A., Nixon.
I wasn't aware...
Thanking me for allowing NASA
to use our facility.
And something about an upgrade?
What was he talking about?
- There was a briefing...
- I don't read those bloody things.
- Are we raising this in the House?
- We should.
- What's this all about?
- Nixon referred to our telescope.
NASA requested its use
in the Apollo program...
originally as a backup receiver.
- Originally?
- They upgraded its role.
When Apollo 11 gets to the moon,
Parkes is the receiving station.
- Meaning?
- We've got the moonwalk.
The people at this place
know what they're doing?
- I believe so.
- Bloody well hope so.
Why'd they pick us?
It's the largest in the
Southern Hemisphere.
What's it doing in the middle
of sheep paddock?
The Parkes telescope, or as
we call it, the Dish....
will track Apollo 11's journey....
gathering astronauts'signals,
telemetry from the spaceship...
and most important, the TV
signals from the moon itself.
It's 210 feet in diameter,
weighs 1,000 tons....
and can point in al directions.
The most powerful in the world.
Can I have their full names
and specific roles?
This is Ross Mitchell, responsible
for maneuvering the Dish.
Glenn Latham, in charge
of the electronics.
Glenn's a Sagittarius.
He enjoys knitting...
Mitch, don't write that.
From NASA, Al Burnett.
Al's here to get all signals
to mission control.
Enjoying your stay
in Australia, Al?
Very much.
The people are warm...
Great.
You, Cliff, what's your
official title?
Cliff Buxton, director.
Or the Dishmaster.
Now I'll add a few
personal details.
- Married?
- Yeah.
- Glenn?
- Fiancé, Janice Kellerman.
She's not. I don't have one.
Married. Two boys in Houston.
And you, Cliff?
Married.
And just finally...
I mean, no offense, but...
the Americans spent 10 years,
billions of dollars...
to watch man walk on the moon,
and it falls to you blokes.
How do you feel about that?
Much better before you
opened your trap.
We feel confident that we have the
expertise to complete our role.
But, Cliff...
it's amazing, isn't it?
Yes, it is amazing.
And so Australia becomes a vital
cog in this grand endeavor.
Early this morning...
I conveyed to President Nixon
my long-term interest...
and commitment to this project.
It will be one of the
proudest moments...
in Australia's scientific history.
And I've accepted the invitation
of the mayor of Parkes...
to be there on Monday
and witness firsthand...
our vital contribution.
That is an R.S.V.P.
The prime minister
coming to Parkes.
- I'll frame that.
- It's icing on the cake.
- Know why this means so much?
- It helps your political career.
- No, Len.
- Oh, it doesn't, yeah.
The PM with the candidate.
Brown-nosing.
- Licking arse.
- No.
It's a vindication.
Oh, a vindication.
Of my campaign to get that
dish here in the first place.
That was an episode.
You know what people said
when I proposed Parkes?
You were grandstanding, it was a
stunt to big-note yourself.
Who said that?
They said I was a dreamer.
A visionary.
Yeah, that's right.
"Bob Mclntyre, you'll
never pull it off."
And now...
which town is part of
the Apollo 11 mission?
Honeysuckle network, Net Two.
Confirm Parkes is up
and configured.
As Apollo 11's readied
for launch...
NASA is completing fibal checks
on its deep space network:
The vast array of telescopes
and cable links...
including a number
in Australia...
with Apollo 11 on its
historic journey.
The repeaters will send
signals to Sydney.
They strip the TV and
send it to Moree.
Both receivers.
Sorry. Go on.
The rest will go to a demodulator
at Honeysuckle Creek.
Can the telemetry feeds be
sent on separate lines?
Mitch?
Yeah, no problem.
Separate lines.
That's a big book, Al.
- Hold on.
- What is it?
These coordinates have changed.
- You sure?
- This is unacceptable.
Glenn? Come here.
What?
Every coordinate has been changed.
Yeah.
I changed them.
- You what?
- I changed them.
Why?
They were wrong.
- Why were they wrong?
- Don't know.
What about them was wrong?
The figures NASA sent us were
for the Northern Hemisphere.
We're in the Southern Hemisphere.
I can change them, but
you're pointing the wrong...
It might be a good idea
to tell us these things.
I didn't want to worry you.
Cup of tea, Al?
- No, thank you.
- I'll have one!
Thank you, Glenn.
- We must double-check.
- All of NASA's work.
Everyone's work, unless you
have a problem with that.
I don't have a problem with that.
- I got a problem.
- Okay, Mitch.
Let's get on with it.
I'll unstow the Dish.
Hi, Bob!
Bill!
Keith.
Major Mclntyre.
I'm a long time out of uniform.
But you fought a war.
- You'll get your chance.
- I hope so, sir.
- Kid's a cadet.
- Keen.
- Hello, Bob.
- How's it going, Pearl?
Busy as a bee.
The whole town's abuzz.
They'll talk about something
else soon.
I can't say, but we might
be getting a visitor.
The prime minister.
May phoned.
And the American ambassador.
That woman. Can you
keep it under your hat?
- I don't think so.
- Not to worry.
- How are the boys at the Dish?
- Raring to go.
- The American settling in?
- I think so.
Came in yesterday,
wanting pretzels.
Pretzels?
Yep, it's a world event.
The prime minister.
Better get a jiggle-on.
- See you later.
- See ya.
The countdown at the Cape
is proceeding to schedule.
Now back to Cape Kennedy and
correspondent Fred Turner.
What impresses me is we've
got excellent weather.
It was predicted we'd
have some overcast...
and now we'll see the launch.
The launch is going ahead tonight.
The ball is Friday night.
Can we get back to...?
Yeah. It got another surge.
I could rumba right now.
- I hope we have slow numbers.
- Yes, Mrs. Spiers.
And a new song.
Who's it by?
James Hendrix.
Let's hear a couple of bars.
There's a slower version.
- That's not to go above three.
- Yes, Mrs. Spiers.
- You learned the American anthem?
- The what?
Are you saying you've not
prepared the American anthem?
How does it go?
You've got 48 hours.
I knew it when he came.
NASA's renting the Dish.
But, how about some respect?
- I wouldn't worry about it.
- We're a professional unit.
You right?
Sorry, mate.
Still not flat enough.
I'll give it a tweak.
Drop it a couple of clicks.
Probably on NASA settings.
We're of the radio physics
department, not mugs at this game.
He asked me if we have
a dress standard.
That's hard to believe.
Wish he'd gone home with the
others. What's his problem?
He's just feeling the pressure.
The pressure.
He's got to learn to relax.
I'll tell you a little secret.
He's not the only one.
We got word from Houston.
It's go for launch.
Now the party can start.
Come on in.
Pick up the phone, and I yell
"Yeah, what?"
- You know who it was?
- The science minister.
Another devil on horseback?
- They've got families.
- It's extraordinary.
- I wouldn't let Don go to the moon.
- I understand.
How do you reckon they
go to the...
up there?
- I suppose they hold on.
- Four days?
- They're expecting the dance.
- It's a ball.
They don't eat meals, just pills.
You can't hold on for 4 days.
One of these would block
them up for a week.
All is still go as we
monitor our status board.
How's it looking?
It's full of liquid hydrogen.
- Can they fix that?
- No, that's go for launch.
Oh, hydrogen.
- About the prime minister.
- He'll be here on Monday.
- Would they lunch?
- In Melbourne.
Man on the moon, eh?
Yep, and we're a part of it, Dad.
But we're slap bang
in the middle of it.
There could be an announcement.
It's not official yet...
Bob's got the nomination
for Parkes.
- We're not telling anyone.
- What?
Bob's got the nomination
for Parkes.
Congratulations on
the nomination.
Bob, the nomination, well done.
May!
Dad, they're talking about Parkes.
Crikey!
The signal from the radio
telescope at Parkes...
will come over the postmaster
general's video system.
We building a new
antenna in Australia.
- Who's that?
- Wilson Hunter.
Bigwig from NASA.
Dad looked after him. He's
the scientific representative.
That's what it's all about.
Sucking up the bigwigs.
No, that's not it.
All indications to the control
center indicate we are go.
Our board indicates the
third stage pressurized.
Tminus 60 and counting.
The passed Tminus 60.
55 seconds and counting.
All still go at this time.
Neil Armstrong replied
when receiving good wishes:
''Thank you. We know it
will be a good flight.
Good luck and Godspeed.
40 seconds to Apollo 11 liftoff.
All second stage tanks
pressurized.
35 seconds and counting.
We're still go with Apollo 11.
30 seconds and counting.
Astronauts reported,
"Feels good."
Tminus 25 seconds.
20 seconds and counting.
Guidance is internal.
Yep, guidance is internal.
11, 10...
- Ignition sequence starts.
6, 5, 4, 3....
2, 1, 0.
All engines running.
Liftoff! We have a liftoff.
32 minutes past the hour.
Liftoff on Apollo 11.
Tower cleared.
Neil Armstrong reportíng.
Apollo 11's on proper heading.
Roll is complete and
pitch is programmed.
Plus 30 seconds.
Downrange one mile,
altitude 3, 4 miles an hour.
Godspeed.
Velocity 2,195 feet per second.
Apollo 11 is now over
the Indian Ocean...
approaching the western
shore of Australia.
As you perhaps know....
the crew will make one and
1/2 revolutions of the Earth.
The Apollo 11 has had a perfect
launch on itsjourney.
The Saturn rocket rose on a
pillar of flame from Cape Kennedy
at 11:32 at night,
eastern Australian time.
The spaceship and rocket are
now orbiting the Earth...
Morning, Marie.
Visitor entering compound.
Awaiting identification.
You're being stupid, Rudi.
- Visitor offering resistance.
- You've got a gun.
Official NASA requirement.
Armed security.
Does Mum know?
No, and don't tell her.
She'll come and take it.
- This is getting cold.
- I've got to sign you in.
Entry authorized.
- And a bikkie too.
- Hello, everyone.
Morning, Mr. Buxton.
If it isn't the most
beautiful girl in Parkes!
- Morning, Mr. Burnett.
- Thank you, Janine.
Morning, Mitch.
- Hello, Glenn.
- Hi, Janine.
I put extra cheese in yours.
- Thanks, Janine.
- You tiger.
- How's Mum?
- Getting ready for the ball.
The whole town's over the moon.
It's so exciting.
The ambassador arrives tomorrow.
Over the moon.
The prime minister on Monday.
On the news they showed Parkes.
- They saw the Dish?
- Everyone's proud.
PKS, Houston Flight Control.
GNC awaiting downlink.
PKS. Roger, Houston.
Was that Armstrong?
No, we're not on-line now.
Sorry?
There's two tracking stations,
us and Goldstone.
- Goldstone?
- California.
If the moon's on our side of
the world, Parkes is on-line.
If it's on the other,
it's Goldstone.
Right, but...
Explain it, Glenn.
Imagine the Earth
is a basketball.
- This'll be good.
- And on top is a...
What do you put the pump into?
- The hole.
- But it's got a name.
The valve.
Say the valve's Goldstone.
- On the other side, another valve.
- Only have one.
What has two valves?
- Tuba?
- It must be round.
- Tambourine.
- That has no valves.
Coconut.
Let's just say the
basketball's got two valves.
When the Goldstone can't see
Apollo 11, Parkes can.
- That's it.
- Good work, Glenn.
How do you know where
Apollo 11 is?
Computer.
In seconds, it does what used to
tame me hours with a slide rule.
And a basketball.
Does the computer move the Dish?
- Mitch does that...
- We have to get back to work.
Thanks for the refreshments.
It was a pleasure.
- Thanks, Janine.
- See you, love.
She's a lovely girl.
Yeah. Not much of a driver though.
You must ask her out.
Ask Janine out?
I don't know, Cliff.
At the cricket club everyone
wants to talk to her.
Gary Kenny's always calling.
They may be dating.
Do you reckon?
Yeah, I reckon.
What if she said no?
Sometimes you got to take a risk.
Armstrong, Aldrin and Collins
started 19 hours ago.
Where are they now?
The astronauts are
93,250 miles from Earth.
The moon is 146,750 miles ahead.
Looking on this scale, which
is not drawn to scale...
Pity they don't mention
who got the Dish here.
- Come on, love.
- You've never got due credit.
I've done all right, Maysie.
Don't call me Maysie in
front of the ambassador.
What do I care if some bigwig
yank sees I love my wife.
The blue or the lemon?
- The yellow.
- Lemon.
Maysie, give us a kiss.
- What did ljust say?
- No idea.
If you get into Parliament,
will you abolish the draft?
Anything for you, sweetheart.
Dad, it's a political issue.
Leave it with me.
I don't want you and Mitch to
think I'm holding on too tight.
You've got a lot on your plate.
Now the teams have gone
back, I'm responsible.
Am I holding on too tight?
Well, you know...
There's a lot at stake, Al.
There's no guarantees,
a lot of variables.
We'll be right.
Zenith. 55.
56, 57, 58...
59, 60, 6001.
Hold it there.
Nothing.
HGA?
Pre-limit.
Run APP prime.
Antenna pointing
processor running.
We got a signal.
Weak.
Peak it up.
Azimuth 8522, 24, 26.
- 28.
- It's up.
90 DBM.
Solid.
- Hello, Apollo.
- Switch to M.E.
- Equatorial control locked on.
- Variable rate?
2.5.
Set...
and holding.
Acquisition of signal.
We are go for command.
PKS, Houston, NC.
Houston Network Control.
Go ahead, Parkes.
Standing by for handover.
Copy that, Parkes. All stations,
Net 2, switching to PKS.
Who's for a cup of tea?
Manual.
Good read-back and would
like a crew status report
Battery charging is complete....
and crew status report
is as follows:
PDR, VMP, LMP,
negative medication.
Fit as a fiddle. Over.
Copy, 11. Thank you.
We're all concerned that
they'll be able to rest.
We're sure how to land man
on the moon.
... following the Apollo 11
mission intensely.
Go ahead, Houston.
Can we have a CSM switch
to high bit rate, please?
1-3-0.
Roger. Signal strength is
negative 1-3-0.
Solid lock on prime.
Stand by for UDB.
Data buffer standing by.
- What was that?
- A CSM switch. Not to worry.
- Won't be long.
- Take your time.
Can you run a verification...
of projected plot points?
- Done it.
- But not with adjusted bearings.
Oh, well, I stand corrected.
No, you're wrong!
You got a problem?
Yeah.
You treat us like a
pack of galahs.
That's a kind of parrot.
Just because I don't wear a tie
and bury my head in a manual...
doesn't mean I'm a drongo.
- That's a hopeless...
- I get the idea.
I've got complete respect
for your capabilities.
I'd appreciate the same
in return.
- It's time to get along.
- Let me know if...
Don't worry.
Hi, Mr. Burnett.
Guys, I've been calling you.
It's been switched off again.
Testing, one, two...
What are we calling about?
What's that?
Oh, it's just the...
Routine call?
Yeah, Mr. Buxton,
it was the routine call.
I'd better get back to my post.
Are we all right here?
That's why I was calling.
Acamera crew's downstairs...
and entry's been authorized.
The ambassador's taking his time.
Must still be at the motel.
You organize that fruit platter?
Yep. Nice big one.
- Major Mclntyre.
- Keith.
Is Marie here?
No. The ambassador's a
cultural imperialist.
She's gone in.
- Be careful, son.
- Yes, sir.
Boy's about to get a taste of war.
Soon we'll be watching TV
pictures from the moon.
Could you explain how these
pictures will be received?
Got a basketball?
When Armstrong emerges from
the lunar landing module...
he'll activate a small
camera here...
which will capture pictures of
him descending the ladder...
and walking on the moon.
- How will they return to Earth?
- Carrier pigeon.
A small transmitter will send
the images back to us.
It's amazing technology.
Will the entire...?
Carrier pigeon.
We'll have to go again.
The ambassador of the U.S.A.
- Got a lump in my throat.
- Stop eating those party pies.
You're right, Len. It's
a big day for Parkes.
It's a vindication.
They're here.
What do we call him,
Your Excellency?
He's not bloody royalty.
It's important. We're his
first impression of Parkes.
On behalf of the people of
Parkes, we welcome you.
Thank you, Bob.
I can call you Bob?
- Absolutely, Mr. Ambassador.
- Howard.
- And this is...?
- Len.
Good day.
My wife, May. She's the lemon.
Apollo 11, Houston,
accept the minute 49.
Continue your sequence...
and we'll analyze
the data afterwards.
Time for a cup of tea?
I haven't been treated like this
since I was striping harvesters.
He's a know-it-all who thinks
only Americans work properly.
Aren't you being unfair?
What's happened to you in
the last couple of years?
I'm sorry. That came out wrong.
This was always your dish. You'd
never let anyone else run it.
We're part of a team.
We're part of NASA.
And what's NASA?
Money, equipment, and
everything you ever needed.
No, Mitch.
NASA'sjust a bigger bunch of us.
- You considered this attempt?
- Of course.
We're in the middle of the
greatest feat ever attempted.
This is science's chance
to be daring.
What are you doing?
Standing around, bitching.
Rudi.
Fellas.
Janine brought food
from the dance.
Lovely.
Then her and Glenn are
down there alone?
Yeah. If you guys have noticed,
Janine really likes Glenn.
Is that right?
Rudi, what's with the gun?
It's official NASA installation.
We may need it.
I've tasted it.
- What?
- The food.
Could've been tampered.
We can't take chances.
- You want a couple more?
- Thanks. I'm still starving.
Leaving Sector A.
I thought the foyer
was Sector A.
Yeah, it was.
I've decided to go
alphabetically from top down.
That's not locked in yet.
This whole thing...
I can't believe I'm a part of it.
I certainly can't believe
Rudi's a part of it.
Me too.
Helen would've been proud.
Ladies and gentlemen,
distinguished guests...
please remain upstanding...
for the national anthem
of the United States.
That's not the anthem.
PKS, Houston. Confirm
handover at 17:00 hours.
Roger, PKS. Copy 17:00.
PKS out.
Where'd you get the chocolate?
Janine.
I will, Cliff. I promise.
Everyone wanted to come
but can't find the car keys.
- About to call a cab and...
- The keys hanging on the door.
Why don't we all have a dance?
Why don't we.
Keys were hanging out
the door, Howard.
- Not too racy?
- Oh, no.
Marie.
- What?
- Would you like to dance?
Are you stupid?
No.
Would you?
I wouldn't be in the way?
We'd be honored to have you visit.
Sorry about the mix-up earlier.
No harm done, Bob. Sometimes I
wish it was our national anthem.
Oh, beauty.
You'll love this bloke.
Fly me to the moon, let me
swing among the stars.
- He's from Brisbane.
- Really?
He's a little like Frank Sinatra.
If not better.
In other words, take my hand.
Who's playing funny buggers?
Shit.
- Sorting it out.
- Not the pie warmer again?
- What happened?
- A blackout.
Control panel's dead.
Have it fixed in a jiffy.
- Receivers?
- Negative.
- Demodulators?
- No.
Whole rack's dead.
Bloody hell.
How about the backup generator?
Shit.
Sorry about that Howard.
No trouble, as long as everything
is fine at the installation.
They have all that under control.
Backup generators, the works.
Still, I'll check with Al.
Where's Al?
Anything?
Nothing.
And we've lost lock.
What happened to the generator?
The fuel pump.
- What about it?
- When I drained it...
I forgot to prime the lines.
You forgot? Jesus!
How could you do that?
- This is what happens...
- Don't you dare!
All right.
We must find that ship.
Switch to manual drive.
Get a lock.
What's its position?
Come on.
I think the computer's wiped.
Shit.
- Are we stuffed?
- Kinda.
Yep, we're stuffed.
What's that noise?
- It's moving.
- How?
- M.E.'s chasing its own tail.
- Shut it down.
We'll have to override...
How far did it move?
Far enough.
Are we sending anything?
Sydney, this is Flight Control.
Are you receiving a
signal from Parkes?
Negative, Houston.
PKS, Flight Control here.
Do you copy?
Flight Control, this is Parkes.
We copy.
Parkes, we'vee lost your
signal. Confirm status.
Houston, Parkes here. We
still have a strong signal.
Must be a relay problem.
Copy, Parkes. We'll look
into it. Stand by.
Parkes standing by.
That's bullshit.
You bullshitted NASA.
That's not good.
I bought us some time.
Let me get that straight.
You've lost Apollo 11.
Yeah.
Southern Hemisphere's prime
receiving station...
has no idea where Apollo 11 is?
On it's way to the moon.
Computer can't lock us back on?
No. If it loses power,
it loses data.
I thought we had an
uninterruptable power source.
It was, but you see, the
generator didn't kick back.
How come?
Ltjust didn't, that's all.
- Power's on. It's under control.
- Except we've lost Apollo 11.
Except for that.
We still have the data.
It must be programmed back in.
How long will that take?
Hours? A day? Months?
How long, Glenn?
Take a shot.
12... 24 hours?
It's a lot of calculations.
We're not relaying data.
Houston would've noticed.
Well, they did call.
What'd you tell them.
I told them that...
the problem wasn't at our end.
- You lied?
- Bullshitted them.
- We have to tell them.
- That we stuffed it?
Like they stuffed the Southern
Hemisphere coordinates.
- Call for a current position.
- They say we're not required.
Excuse me?
We're dickheads who can't
maintain a signal.
- Cliff, NASAwill...
- Listen, Al.
We can reprogram the system.
Just keen NASA off our
backs for a while.
I am NASAand I say
we tell them now.
PKS, Houston N.C.
Go ahead, Houston.
Spoken to INCO. No closer
to finding this breakdown.
Are you sure it's downstream?
PKS...
it's still on-line. Confirming
loss of signal downstream.
Roger. We'll maintain
alternative feed.
What have I done?
- You bullshitted NASA.
- Good man, Al.
Let's get cracking.
I've never been more proud
of being mayor of Parkes.
Plus, I went home with the
prettiest girl at the dance.
- You look great in yellow.
- Lemon.
Lemon.
Who's that?
Crikey!
Press will come and
won't be mugs.
All right...
what if you come clean?
Just tell NASA.
- Tell them what?
- That...
we lost Apollo 11.
- I wouldn't say that first.
- What would you say?
"You'll never guess
what happened."
Bob, it's Apollo 11.
What would they do?
- I'm not sure.
- Pull the pin?
Not officially, but
they'd downgrade our role.
We'd lose the moonwalk.
Keep a lid on that.
This will be a joke.
Who goes there?
It's just us, Rudi.
Oh, okay.
Who?
Cliff and Bob!
Oh, hi, Bob.
Rudi!
How are you?
Good. Fine.
Nighty-night.
We know when they reappear,
but not where.
- Same place as yesterday.
- They were orbiting.
Now they're translunar. We'll
have to redo every angle.
That'll take forever.
You can get an approximate
fix, and then scan.
That should do it.
I'll give you a hand
with the figures.
- I know about the generator.
- What?
I forgot to prime the fuel lines.
Well...
those things happen.
Let's get to work.
If we come on stream tomorrow,
it never happened.
You think you can do it?
I made a commitment to NASA...
and I intent to fulfill it.
No tone for a while.
Remember trying to sort out
that contract with NASA?
"What about this or that?"
2 hours, and you finally speak.
"Gentlemen, this should be
the contract:
We agree to support
the Apollo 11 mission."
Just one sentence.
It was wonderful, man.
But this isn't.
This is a shithouse moment.
Halt. Who goes there?
I'm not sure.
- You said you were confident.
- I am. I was.
It's got to be in this range.
If we sweep here, it may be
outside and we'll miss it.
If we sweep wider, we
still might miss it.
You confident about that?
They're in the service module.
The rockets aren't on.
- They just sit and wait.
- Is that right?
- The fastest man has traveled.
- Go on.
It's the most chauvinistic
exercise ever.
That's why nobody asks you.
Here you go.
- I'll get my Saturn V rocket.
- Yeah, go get it.
Thanks, love.
Is everything all right
at the Dish?
- Can you keep a secret?
- No.
What's happened?
What if we split the difference?
Ship's moving too fast.
Let's call Houston,
ask for coordinates.
They'll know we bullshitted.
Let's say what happened.
That we lied?
That'll go down well.
I don't it will.
Morning, everyone.
How's it going?
- Good.
- You were on the new last night.
Is everything all right?
Yeah. It's fine.
Glenn was just checking...
- some stuff.
- Really?
I'd better let you get to it.
- Sorry for interrupting.
- Not at all.
- Thanks for the food.
- It was my pleasure.
What do you wanna do?
Let's give this some thought.
Sector G, come in.
Let me try something.
- Not now, Rudi.
- You've got a visitor.
It's the ambassador.
From America.
Oh, God!
- Is this thing working?
- Just a moment, Rudi.
Roger, Sector G. Confirm
Sector A. Hold on.
Didn't think he'd come so soon.
Well, he's here.
Space nut knows
all about Apollo 11.
He know where it is?
Let's make the brief.
Send him up, Rubi.
Roger that.
This is the main control panel.
That moves the Dish up and
down, and that sideways.
It's incredible.
You can pinpoint a tiny spaceship
thousands of miles away...
and lock onto it.
Pretty much.
The ambassador didn't sign in,
but I've let it go.
I didn't want to pull rank.
The other facilities, North
West Cape and Honeysuckle Creek...
also have voice and telemetry?
But in TV, yours is the
only dish large enough?
Yeah.
How does that make you feel?
Where do you get them glasses?
I'm afraid that we're
entering overlap now.
So you'll be getting transmissions?
Yeah.
You'll be able to hear Armstrong?
Yep, just by hitting
a couple of buttons.
Oh, let's do that.
Sure.
If I... I don't think...
You're right. I don't...
Just a brief listen, then I'll go.
Not a problem.
I'll have to reorient the...
Al?
If you could patch the audio
in for mezzanine three.
Columbia, Houston, systems
O.K. You're go for audio.
Copy that.
Neil, telemetry reports O2
and CO2 are O.K. And steady.
Biomed telemetry reads...
vital statistics as being
adequate, within the limits.
Copy that.
Neil, we have you currently...
at 124,000 nautical
miles from Earth and....
at approaching velocity
of 32,000 feet per second.
Copy that.
Columbia, Houston.
Get back to work.
Copy that.
Is that you, Neil?
This is Sector A.
Is that you, Mr. Armstrong?
Must be crossed line from
Honeysuckle Creek.
We're really going to have
to get back to work.
- Understood.
- I'll see you out.
I'll just move the Dish.
That's incredible.
That was a true highlight.
I was going to say good luck...
but after what I've seen,
you don't need it.
Thank you very much, sir.
- You'll never guess what happened.
- Later, Rudi.
- Should he sign out?
- Just wave, Rudi.
That's got to be a felony.
Let's find the ship.
Impersonating a person in orbit.
It's a moving target.
Everything is moving. If we
had a point of reference...
Take a punt. Choose a sector.
- Still a long shot.
- Thought you were confident.
I know where Apollo 11 is.
On its way to the moon.
Your point of reference.
They've gone 150,000 miles.
There're within 3 or 4 degrees.
That might be okay.
I think that might be okay.
We can rub this out?
5707.
5708.
There's your moon.
Have a fish around.
6730.
6731.
We've got a signal!
It's Apollo 11!
- Definite?
- 2.28.
It's the tin can.
Yep! Signal lock!
Houston, Apollo 11....
PKS, Houston Net Two.
Houston, PKS.
Parkes is on-line.
Copy, Parkes. We are
receiving your signal.
Switching to master equatorial.
And with 15 minutes to spare.
It's enough time to
check the generator.
That's great news, Cliff.
I got to dash.
I appreciate the call.
What?
Yeah. Bye.
- Major Mclntyre!
- Keith.
What?
I wanted to ask Marie something.
Fire when ready.
Marie, it's Keith!
Want to watch the moon
landing with me on Monday?
Don't you get it?
Get what, sir?
I think that's a "no".
You're a brave lad.
Apollo 11, here Houston, over.
Go ahead, Houston. Apollo 11.
11 this is Houston. You
are going for LOI, over.
Roger, go for LIO.
Houston, can you give me
a time check?
I give you a mark at 13 minutes
and 30 seconds to ignition.
Roger, out.
Apollo 11, this is Houston.
All your systems look good.
- See you on the other side.
- Roger.
... on orbit of the moon,
preparing for lunar descent...
- on Monday afternoon.
- That's all we need to know.
- Vol-au-vent?
- Thank you.
The boys gave you a tour?
Yes. Very impressive facility.
You actually heard Neal Armstrong?
I had the privilege.
How did he sound?
Like he was next door.
That was a day and a half.
I'll be 52 on Monday.
Happy birthday.
And half of them in radio-
telescope mapping the stars.
Then this came along.
Your pipe?
No, the moon mission. Know what
I thought when I first came up?
You beauty?
I thought:
"Imagine stuffing that up."
Isn't that odd?
What?
That I was more scared
than excited.
That's not odd.
I feel like that all the time.
How come you changed?
My wife said something:
"Failure is never quite so
frightening as regret."
That's good advice.
Pretty good.
I wish someone would tell me that.
God bless you, Glenn.
When I said I was sorry...
I was sorry for everything.
- Oh, Mitch, that's not...
- No, no, no.
When you first arrived I felt...
you're a hotshot from NASA and
I'm a dumb country kid...
with the arse fallout
out of me daks.
- Your...?
- Pants.
I was wrong.
I never thought of you with
your ass falling out of your...
Daks.
Not everyone at NASA's
a college genius.
The guy I most admire is
from a one-horse town in Ohio.
What's he do?
Tomorrow he'll walk on the moon.
Who's the guy?
Armstrong.
It would have been okay
to tell Houston.
Things go wrong there
all the time.
Mission control goes blue when
50 people hold their breath.
Do you know how many
rockets blew up?
- That's a while yet.
- 6 weeks ago.
Testing the lunar module.
10 simulations without a hitch.
On the 11th, the controls
jammed, it crashed.
Any idea why?
We still have no idea why.
Let's hope 11 isn't
an unlucky number.
We pray for those brave souls...
who, as we speak...
are taking the 1st steps in
exploring God's great universe...
and for the technicians and...
scientists who contribute
to this brave endeavor.
You think this Apollo 11
thing's big here?
- You can't imagine.
- Really?
What were you saying last night?
You shouldn't drink so much?
If you'll excuse me.
He came for dinner.
Imagine 2 basketballs. One
there, one there and a valve.
- They won't televise always.
- Wouldn't think so.
Bounces off the basketball,
and then off Goldstone.
Could they hide behind a rock?
Depends on doing a number...
or doing a number...
What was that, Ray?
We're talking about
the TV coverage.
Where can I take a...?
Thanks for the sandwiches.
- Thanks for fixing the bumper.
- That's okay.
- Maybe...
- Janine, I was won...
- You go first.
- No, you.
- What were you going to say?
- Nothing.
What about you?
Nothing
Has he asked her out yet?
This is painful.
I really like weekends too.
And Fridays cause you're
looking forward to the weekend.
What were you going to say?
Nothing.
- What were you going to say?
- Nothing.
All right.
- See ya.
Want to go out Friday night?
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
Did you say: "Want to
go out Friday night?"
Maybe.
I'd love to go out Friday night.
With me?
Yes.
Right-o then.
He ask her out?
I'm not sure.
I had a chat with Al this morning.
Really?
He's not such a bad bloke.
You should give him a chance.
- You'll be right?
- Yeah.
- Lf you got any problem...
- I'll call Rudi.
- That's Parkes lamb.
- I've got enough.
Plenty more.
- I'll have the vegetables.
- Yes, dear.
- This is wonderful.
- Glad you could get away.
The boys have it under control.
- When are you up?
- At 4.
Tomorrow's the big day.
All being well.
Man on the bloody moon. Gravy?
Sending men off into the galaxies
as the world watches.
Takes your mind off concerns.
Elbows.
The whole school will watch it.
Every school will watch it.
- What are you estimating?
- 600 million.
600 million!
600 million.
- Peas?
- No.
Can people in India watch it?
Yeah, but all on the one telly.
- I'm serious.
- Far too serious.
- How they going to film it?
- Cliff?
A boom outside the camera.
When Armstrong's outside the
module, it'll swing out.
- Is there an antenna on the roof?
- Transmitter, Dad.
It's the size of that bowl.
- Pumpkin?
- Yes, please.
All this effort for TV.
NASA hardly mentioned TV.
Interesting change.
Not sure what's more important,
astronauts or pictures.
How lovely!
Elbows.
Can I ask a question?
Sure.
Is this mission funded by the CIA?
Not entirely.
Really?
No.
How do they know they won't sink?
- Good Lord!
- Crikey.
We know a great deal
about the moon.
Soil composition, density,
gravity. Not many mysteries.
If we know so much, why go?
There's one thing we don't know.
What, Cliff?
Whether we can get there.
Elbows.
Well, let's start.
Man on the moon or not,
we've still got to eat.
You'll like that.
Back to work, eh?
It's all go.
That roast lamb was magnificent.
- You don't get that in Houston.
- No.
- We can't have you wasting away.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much, May.
It's been quite a while since
I've had a good roast.
- Good luck for tomorrow.
- Thank you.
Marie, it was an absolute
pleasure to meet you.
Really?
Really.
How you feeling?
Fine.
I heard the prime minister
on the news.
Could he shut up about it?
Don't you wonder what we're
doing in the Apollo 11 mission?
They'll knight you for this.
Or behead me.
Dad!
About face!
Quick march!
Boy's not a soldier,
he's a kamikaze.
- What are you grinning about?
- Nothing.
You've had a smile all day.
- No, I haven't.
- Yes, you have.
All right?
How was lunch?
- Wonderful.
- We ate an entire sheep.
All in order?
- I was gonna check the receiver.
- I'll do it.
- I'll stow the Dish.
- I'll take a hayride.
Hayride?
What's a hayride?
When it's down, we can't
get up the core.
- It's quicker to go for a ride.
- Interesting.
Okay, Mitch.
Yet strangely, this
is not in the manual.
Curious oversight, right?
It was good what you said at lunch.
What?
We don't know whether
we can get there.
Yes, that's easy to forget.
Before I left Houston...
the scientists had planned
everything for Armstrong.
Rock samples,
measuring radiation.
Flight director put his foot
down. So they say:
"When Armstrong gets to the moon,
what should he do?"
F.D. Says: "Get off it."
That would be number one.
I kind of felt for him.
There's really only one
thing I want to see.
There's something about putting
a footprint on the moon that...
Makes our spirits soar?
Yeah, exactly.
Did you come up with that?
I'm ashamed to say I didn't.
It was my wife.
She died last year.
Sorry to hear that, Cliff.
She was so excited by all of this.
Made me realize I should
be excited too.
And I am.
The only thing is,
she's not here to share it.
So... there it is.
34, 36...
Hold it there.
- Strength?
- Negative one-forty.
Intermittent lock on prime.
- Do you want me to...?
- No.
Glenn, run AGC.
Auto Gain Control running.
Negative 90. Solid lock.
We're on.
- Switching to M.E.
- Got it.
All yours, Al.
Houston Net Two, PKS.
Houston Net Two.
Parkes is on-line.
Apollo, Houston. RCS
went to super dust.
We're all go.
Roger. Mike,
would you confirm...
thruster B-3 and C-4
are off? Over.
C- 4 and B-3 are off and
I've got roll jets back on.
Jets maneuvering, right?
Will be shortly, Neil.
Apollo 11. Houston,
we are go for undocking.
Roger. Understand.
Eagle, Houston, we see you.
Roger. Eagle undocked.
- How does it look?
- The Eagle has wings.
Rog.
Roger, Neil. Give us
cooling data.
You're a go for PDI. Over.
Roger. Understand.
Rod McNeil with another
Apollo 11 update.
Eagle module descent has
entered 5th and final hour.
According to Houston
Flight Control...
status is still go
or a landing.
Eagle module is in critical
stage before touchdown.
In a matter of minutes....
astronauts Armstrong
and Aldrin...
will attempt to land
on the surface of the moon.
Rudi. Sector 5A. D. E.
Rudi, over.
They're about to land.
Eagle, we have to go around.
Angle S-band pitch minus
niner yaw plus one eight.
Roger. You're a go to continue.
Go to continue powered descent.
They're landed?
Almost.
You're looking great.
2,000 feet.
Into AGS, 47 degrees.
Roger.
37 degrees.
- You're go.
Program alarm.
He said alarm?
- 1201.
- Roger, 1201 alarm.
1201. Excessive overflow.
Computer's overloaded.
They'll abort.
- Okay, we're go.
- We're go.
- They're going it.
- 723.
540 feet, down at 15.
350, down at 4.
Altitude, velocity light.
31/2 down. 220 feet.
Coming down nicely.
200 feet, 412.
5 and a half down.
100 feet, 312 down,
9 forward.
75 feet. Guys looking good.
Down a half.
- 6 forward.
- 60 seconds.
Lights on.
- Fuel?
- I think so.
30 feet down, 212.
Picking up some dust.
Faint shadow.
- 4 forward. Drifting right.
- 30 seconds.
That's a fuel call.
- What?
- 30 seconds of fuel left.
Contact light.
Okay, engine stop.
We copy you down, Eagle.
Houston....
Tranquillity Base here.
The Eagle has landed.
Roger. Tranquillity.
They're on the moon.
About to turn blue. Breathing
again. Thanks a lot.
Bloody hell!
30 seconds of fuel.
- What happens now?
- Sleep break.
It's a good idea.
Confirmed: Armstrong and
Aldrin are on the moon.
Both are preparing for EVA.
- What's that?
- Extra vehicular activities.
The moonwalk.
They got rid of that hydrogen?
They needed that for fuel.
These are not to scale.
- The prime minister's on his way.
- He's a fascist!
I beg your pardon!
Bob, speak to Marie.
I might just shut that.
What?
Wind.
Glenn's under the Bureau.
- What's it blowing?
- 15 knots.
- We're related to...?
- 30.
So, we're fine.
- For now.
- Come on, Glenn.
If it goes above 30?
Above 10, we stow the Dish.
That's pointing up. We've
got to be pointing east.
We understand that.
Forecaster says it
doesn't make sense.
- Great.
- He say anything else?
Hello and goodbye. Very polite.
30 knots can't be the
absolute maximum.
It's the theoretical maximum.
- It's never been tested?
- No.
The Disc can take more than...
Al, we don't know.
And I don't want to know.
1,000 tons is above that
azimuth track.
That's not good.
All right, let's just...
We got 9 hours till they walk.
Could this blow itself out?
Yeah, I reckon it could.
Yeah.
Just ringing to say good luck.
Hang on.
There in a minute!
It's a bit breezy this morning.
That wouldn't affect...
Right.
What happens then?
Oh, I see.
You reckon?
Crikey.
It's a special day, Bob.
The prime minister
arrived in Parkes....
received by the United
States ambassador....
and local dignitaries eager to
see the historic landing.
This is Cliff Buxton, the
director of the facility.
Governor-general. That was
the official opening.
Why did they build it here?
If I may, Bob?
Weather, prime minister.
Parkes has the stable
climatic conditions...
conducive to the operation
of large radio telescopes.
Fire?
We hit 30 knots.
- Get back to the bureau.
- Sure.
- What's up?
- Relax, Rudi.
What's the bell for?
Let's us know it's windy.
I knew that. It's blowing
a bloody gale outside.
- Well done with this.
- The ladies helped.
No, Apollo 11. Your dish.
Thank you, prime minister.
And congratulations on the nod.
Party needs performers.
- How are they going out there?
- Good. Perfectly.
We sit here for 5 bloody days,
not a breath of bloody wind.
And then, out of nowhere...
when it's our turn, a bloody
cyclone parks on us!
Sorry lads.
I might just...
go check some bloody thing.
Obviously nothing's foolproof.
There's always limitations.
There are no guarantees,
all things considered.
Life, I guess.
You're joking, aren't you?
Yeah, everything's fine.
We have a saying in the Party:
- "You don't fuck up.!
- And?
That's it.
- What?
- They're going to walk early.
Armstrong's overruled
the sleep break.
He told NASA:
"We don't want to sleep."
Armstrong goes for it.
- When do they walk?
- Soon. Now.
- So we're off the hook.
- No.
Goldstone has problems.
They want us from the start.
We don't see the moon till one.
12:56.
Come 12:56, if Armstrong
hasn't walked...
this Dish points to the moon.
This is locked down. I
don't care who turns up.
- No one gets in. Understand?
- I understand, sir.
We must move this dish.
- There's a safety issue.
- I understand that.
We're under no obligations.
Mitch, what will happen?
Don't know.
What do you think will happen?
It's a big sail area.
The wind grabs hold of it...
We wait.
Come on.
They're going early.
Could happen any time.
Come on, you'll miss it.
If I'djust landed on the moon,
I wouldn't want to sleep.
Like telling a kid to sleep
on Christmas morning, eh?
- More tea, prime minister?
- Yes.
Lovely.
- They're going early.
- I know.
- You all right?
- I am now.
Sorry?
Goldstone can take the pictures.
Goldstone?
Cliff can't move the Dish
in this wind.
Good Lord!
Lt'll die down and
they'll use us later.
It would have been nice to
be there from the start.
Doesn't matter what pictures
are caught by who.
We're part of a team.
That's the most important thing.
- You're right.
- Your shirt, Bob.
The boys at the Dish will
be able to relax.
Getting worse. It's gusting to 50.
We can't move this dish.
PKS video, Houston TV, Net 2.
PKS video. Go ahead.
Got problems with Goldstone.
Need you as prime receiver.
Prime?
The signal between Goldstone
and Houston is dead.
It's gone to ground and
it's still go for walk.
We'll advise when in position.
Roger, PKS.
Soon as possible, please.
Glenn, come here.
Mitch, talk to me.
- Shaking in upright position.
- What?
It's not designed to take
these sort of forces.
Finish what you're saying.
It could collapse.
- Man's about to walk on the moon.
- And he will.
But no one will see it.
There are 5 lives at risk.
I'm responsible for those lives.
Many would say that's sufficient
not to move the Dish.
Everyone'll accept that.
But will you?
This is science's chance
to be daring.
If we don't move it,
it might as well be rubble.
Al.
I still think 11's a lucky number.
- Glenn.
- What?
Sometimes, you got to take a risk.
All right.
Let's do it.
I like Cliff. He goes for it.
From North to South, they
come from near and far...
to witness man take to the sky...
in search of moon and star.
But ponder this as rockets fly.
Jesus!
65 miles an hour.
Keep going, Mitch.
'Tween Armstrong and Buzz
Aldrin the lunar surface near.
What's happening now?
We can tell Armstrong has
commenced evacuation.
We expect TVpictures
at any moment.
What the hell was that?
Drive cogs must've slipped.
Or Janine's trying to park.
Stick with it, Mitch.
I'm staying, whatever happens.
Okay, Houston, I'm on the porch.
- He's out of the LEM.
- He's outof the LEM.
He's outside.
Columbia, this is Houston.
1'30''to LOS...
all systems go. Over.
Houston, we copy...
and stand by for your cue.
We're in position.
Good boy.
Glenn?
Nothing.
Neil, this is Houston.
Loud and clear. Break.
Buss, this is Houston, check
and verify TVbreaker in.
Roger, TVcircuit breakers in...
and read you five square.
Parkes, please advise status.
PKS in position. Signal...
negative.
- Glenn?
- Moon's still not high enough.
Go lower, Mitch.
I'm at 60-0-3.
Next stop's concrete.
- Offset feed!
- Offset!
Okay, that's good.
Come on.
Got it.
We're getting a picture
on the TV.
- But man will...
- Armstrong!
- Travel so far from...
- Thanks, Betty.
I've got another 2 verses.
Man's about to walk on the moon.
You got a good picture, huh?
There's contrast...
but with a fair amount
of detail.
That's Armstrong!
On the moon!
Verify the position of the
opening on the camera.
Neil, we see you coming
down the ladder.
I'm on that first step, Buzz.
It's not collapsed too far...
but it's adequate to
get back up.
- We copy.
- It takes a good little jump.
Switch back to main axis.
- How's that?
- Fine.
The LEM footpads are only...
depressed in the surface
about 1 or 2 inches.
Although the surface
appears to be very...
very fine-grained.
It's almost like a powder.
I'll step off the LAM now.
That's one small step for man...
one giant leap for mankind.
That beautiful from here, Neil.
It has a beauty all its own.
It's like the high desert
- Dad, he's on the moon!
- I know, mate.
It's very pretty out here.
Thank God for that hydrogen.
Are you getting a TVpicture,
Houston?
You bet ya.
Neil, yes, we're getting
a TVpicture.
You're in our field of view.
I'm on the top step.
It's simple to hop from
one step to the next-
You got 3 more steps
and then a long one.
There you go.
Beautiful view.
Isn't that something?
Magnificent sight out here.
You can stay this one.
Enough.
For those who haven't read it...
we'll read the plaque on the
landing gear of this LEM.
It says:
"Here, men from the
planet Earth....
first set foot upon the moon.
July, 1969 A.D.
They came in peace
for all mankind."
It has the crew member's
signatures...
and the signature of the
president of the U.S.
Columbia, this is Houston
reading you loud and clear.
How's it going?
The EVA is progressing
beautifully.
Great.
You're the only person that
doesn't have TVcoverage.
That's all right. I don't mind.
How's the quality of the TV?.
It's beautiful, Mike, really.
Beautiful, just beautiful.
It's a wonderful day for Parkes.
They're good pictures.
The president of the United
States is in his office...
and would like to say
a few words to you.
That would be an honor.
Go ahead, Mr. President.
This is Houston, out.
Hello, Neil and Buzz.
I'm talking to you by phone
from the oval room.
That was Cliff on the phone.
The pictures.
They came from us!
You bloody beauty!
Bloody fantastic!
Here's to Parkes!
500 million people gathered
at TVset...
The date's now indelible.
It's going to be remembered
as long as man survives.
This has to be the proudest
day of our lives.
People all over the world...
I'm sure they too join...
with Americans in
recognizing what...
an immense feat this is.
What you have done....
- the heavens...
- Well done, guys.
A part of man's work.
What sector is Rudi, again?
"A"?
Copy that, Sector A?
Well done, Mr. Armstrong.
Columbia, this is Houston
reading you loud and clear.
The crew of Tranquillity Base
is back inside their base.
Everything went beautifully.
Hallelujah.
Tranquillity Base, this
is Houston, over.
Roger, go ahead.
We'd like to say from all
of us here in Houston...
and from all in all countries
in the entire world....
you've done a magnificent
job up there today, over.
Thank you very much.
It's been a long day.
Thanks, Bernie.
The official telegram will
go to your primer minister.
But "Congratulate Parkes
Radiotelescope personnel...
for the outstanding support of
man's first lunar expedition.
C. Charlesworth, Apollo 11
Flight Director."
We did it, eh?
Yeah, we did, Al.
Good work, Mitch. And well done.
Thanks, Cliff.
- Congratulations, Al.
- Cliff.
- Good knowing you, Glenn.
- Thanks.
And happy birthday, Cliff.
Thanks, Glenn.
This should be it: ''We agree to
support the Apollo 11 mission."
It's extraordinary, sending
men off into the galaxy.
You wonder what we're doing
in the Apollo 11 mission?
It inspires us to redouble
our efforts...
to bring peace and
tranquillity to Earth.
For one priceless moment....
in the whole history of man...
all the people on this
Earth are truly one.
I'm going to have to ask you to
go through the public entrance.
- I'm sorry.
- Tours are on the hour.
Maybe not today but, I may
come back another time.
I'd do it. People get
quite a buzz here.
I'll bet they do.
Do I know you, sir?
No, I don't believe so.
You look familiar.
Well, I better be off.
Back out and around to the left.