Subtitles by DramaFever
Episode 14
My husband has been
beating me for 10 years.
'I'm sure he won't do it again.'
'It'll be better tomorrow.'
My husband is an orthopedic doctor.
He hits with such calculating precision.
It's time to reflect, right?
What do you mean domestic abuse?
Do you have evidence that I abused her?
There is no one in this world
who loves my wife more than I do.
If it was to the point that their
child couldn't hear her scream...
We need to find a person
who witnessed the abuse.
Lawyer So,
Look.
- Run!
- Stop right there!
Stop! No!
Pi Hae Young! Pi Hae Young.
Pi Hae Young!
- No! No!
- Pi Hae Young!
Mr. Han Dae Man!
Go Cheok Hee!
Sir!
What happened?
That lady did it.
You have been caught in the act.
You are under arrest.
You may obtain a lawyer, and you
have the right to refuse testimony.
Cuff her.
[Let's just love]
Did you see Mr. Han Dae Man get
hit by the trophy you threw at him?
No. After I threw it, I came out
and he was already passed out.
So, you didn't see him get hit?
Yes.
What is his condition right now?
He is unconscious.
Wait... what about the
witness's testimony?
That family's child said
she saw the scene of the crime...
Stop right there!
Pi Hae Young!
No! No! No!
The little girl said Mr. Han Dae Man
came out of the room
and she saw him pass out from the trophy
Ms. Go Cheok Hee threw at him.
- What about Ms. Pi Hae Young?
- She said she didn't see anything.
Cho Reung!
She was too busy running away
from Mr. Han Dae Man
until she realized she left without her
daughter, so she went back to get her.
By that time, her husband was
already passed out on the floor.
Please get up.
Wait! Wait!
How can you arrest her
without any other evidence?
Are you just going to take
the word of an 8-year-old girl?
You know very well children can
change their story as much they want!
Even so, there is also no evidence.
That proves she isn't the culprit.
We have no choice.
Detective! Detective!
Hang in there. I'll do whatever
I can to take care of this.
Cheok Hee!
Cheok Hee, what happened?
Dad.
- Why are you in there?
- It's not a big deal, Dad.
This happens once in a while
when I take on a case.
You brat.
Mr. So, will this girl be okay?
Will she be able to come out?
So Jung Woo, I'm sorry,
but please take my dad home.
I'm not going anywhere! How can I leave
when you're in here? I'm not going!
Send him home. Huh?
Cheok Hee!
Let go!
She'll be more concerned
if you stay here, sir.
What if she ends up going to jail?
No arrest warrant will be issued
as long as we find evidence
that proves she is not the culprit.
Don't worry. Please trust me
to take care of this. Go home now.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Ms. Mi Hwa.
Soo Ah!
What brings you here?
Your favorite, spicy rice cakes!
It made me think of you,
so I bought some.
I'm going to go.
You came all the way here carrying this.
Are you going somewhere?
Jung Woo is staying overnight
at the police station.
I was going to take some clothes to him.
The police station?
If it's the Gangnam police station,
it's close to where you live, right?
Yes.
Then on your way...
go ahead and take this to him.
He left.
Thanks... You go home too.
- Go Cheok Hee.
- Go.
How can I go when you're here?
If it's that uncomfortable for you...
Fine then, I'll go.
But... I'll go after this case is over.
So Jung Woo.
I swear it. I'll really
leave after it's over.
Let me be next to you until then.
Jung Woo.
Soo Ah.
How did you know to come here?
I went to your house, and Ms. Mi Hwa
asked me to take this to you. Here.
Man, why did she make you do this?
I have to go in right now.
What should I do?
Go in.
I made you run around for nothing.
I'm so sorry.
It's fine. Just treat me
to a meal next time.
- Okay. Thanks, I'm going to go. Bye.
- Sure.
Hey, Lawyer Jo.
What? Go Cheok Hee is
in the police station?
Do you think Mr. Han Dae Man
will be okay?
- I hear he is still unconscious.
- Don't worry.
I have every faith he will wake up.
For three years, I waited for the day
my suspension would be lifted.
If I get sentenced to prison...
I'll be permanently banned this time.
It wasn't deliberate.
Not to mention, there isn't any
clear evidence that proves you did it.
I'll do whatever I can to prevent you
from getting sentenced to jail.
Just trust me.
Go Cheok Hee.
- Cheok Hee.
- How did you know I was here?
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Min Kyu!
Just how are you handling the situation?
You should be the one in jail!
Why is Go Cheok Hee in here?
Hit me again.
What?
It kills me that she's in here
instead of me
so go ahead and hit me again!
What's the condition of the victim?
He's unconscious.
Then our first priority is for
the victim to gain consciousness.
In that way, we can try to make
some sort of settlement.
It's still too early to determine
that Manager Go is the culprit.
She only threw the trophy.
She said she didn't
see him get hit by it.
I'm sure I did it.
I was the only one there.
Don't worry, Go Cheok Hee.
I'll gather every skilled doctor
in the world if I have to.
I'll make sure that punk
wakes up in 48 hours.
And don't blame yourself.
The fingerprints and the results
of the blood exam aren't out yet.
It might not be you.
Dr. Kim, Dr. Park, Dr. Choi,
Dr. Lee, Dr. Wang.
For what reason did you
call all of us here...
- Have you seen patient Han Dae Man?
- Yes.
There is some bleeding in the brain,
but it's not in a dangerous region.
Fortunately, surgery won't be necessary.
Good.
According to the neurology exam,
there are no abnormal reports.
We can't predict how long it will
take for him to regain consciousness.
- You must wake him up at all cost.
- Director Bong.
I will no longer ask about his
condition or what the prospects are.
Just make sure he wakes up.
- Well...
- I won't listen to any explanations
nor any excuses.
Wake him up.
Use whatever necessary medication
and hire more doctors if needed.
Yes, sir.
If you see any signs of improvement...
- Please call me right away.
- I understand.
How is Cheok Hee doing?
Well, she acts like she's fine.
Hold on... where is the study?
I think it's over there.
In all my years, I can't believe
I'm worried about Cheok Hee.
- Kyung.
- Yes?
Throw a trophy from there.
One more.
Are we good?
What is it?
It should fall over here,
but it keeps going over there.
How strong can Cheok Hee be?
Maybe she wasn't strong enough.
Hey, Yoo Mi.
The results of the blood exam are out.
The blood on the trophy
matches Mr. Han Dae Man's blood.
- What about the fingerprints?
- The fingerprints...
Cheok Hee's fingerprints and
Mr. Han Dae Man's fingerprints
were both on the trophy.
Also... I overheard
the detectives talking...
Judging from the shape and angle
of Mr. Han Dae Man's injury...
They're saying it's
most likely the trophy.
Yes.
Okay.
Jung Woo, the detectives are
saying that he got hit by the trophy.
Let's go for now.
What is that?
I'm not sure.
Ah, it's that! It's the safety pin!
- A safety pin?
- It goes into the fire extinguisher.
How are you doing in there?
All I'm doing is sitting.
That's the hardest thing for you.
Just sitting.
Go Cheok Hee.
Cheok Hee.
Yes?
Because you're in there...
Now I know.
Whether you hate me
or try to push me away...
that's not important.
I just...
I just want you out of there.
Think of it as if you're outside.
- What?
- I'm the who's locked up.
Where you are right now...
just think of it as if you're outside.
Have you found anything?
Not yet.
Cheok Hee.
Did you even get any sleep
on this stone floor?
Strangely, I slept really well.
It's as if my mom put me to sleep.
Yes, Dr. Kim?
Pardon? Yes, I'll head to
the hospital right now. Bye.
Cheok Hee, Mr. Han Dae Man briefly
gained consciousness in the morning.
Really?
If he wakes up, I'm going make a deal
and settle it once and for all.
- Don't worry and stay put.
- Thanks, Min Kyu.
Sure.
Three...
There were clearly
five trophies back then.
Out of the five, three are here.
One is in the crime laboratory.
Then where is the last one?
Go Cheok Hee, how many
trophies did you throw?
One.
- You haven't touched anything else?
- No.
I have to go.
I'll be back.
There were originally
five trophies here.
Two trophies are gone,
but Cheok Hee said she only threw one.
If that's the case, the trophy that
was at the scene of the crime...
What if there is a possibility
that Cheok Hee didn't throw it?
But Cheok Hee's fingerprints were on it.
She could've touched that trophy
after the crime occurred.
Then where did the last one go?
That's what I'm saying.
Let's try to find that missing trophy.
I don't think it's here.
Let's check the bedrooms.
Jung... Jung Woo.
Kyung... I'm going to
head out to see Cho Reung.
Call the lead detective and tell
him we found new evidence, okay?
- Okay.
- One more thing.
- Get the fingerprints.
- Okay.
What brings you here?
I was hoping I could get a chance
to talk to Cho Reung for a brief moment.
Please make it quick.
She has to go to cram school.
I will.
I'm just curious about something.
You said you saw your dad get
hit by the trophy that day, right?
Yes.
Besides the trophy that lady threw,
have you seen a different trophy at all?
What? No!
That lady didn't throw that trophy, I...
No, I don't know.
I don't remember.
What did you say?
- Mom, I don't like this guy.
- Cho Reung...
Please stop,
you're hurting her feelings.
- Good bye.
- Wait...
- Wait a minute.
- She's late for class. I'm sorry.
Jung... Jung Woo.
- Hey, Kyung.
- Jung Woo, about that trophy.
The results are out. Cheok Hee's and
Cho Reung's fingerprints were on it.
What?
- Goodness, President Bong, you're here.
- Hello, sir.
What happened?
Is Mr. Han Dae Man awake?
Not yet. He has to regain complete
consciousness in order to talk.
It's going to take some time.
The warrant is going
to come out in an hour.
What's going to happen to our Cheok Hee?
Are they going to lock her away?
Don't worry, sir.
Even if she does get arrested, I'm going
to get her out by any means necessary.
- See you soon.
- Be careful.
How did you get here?
- May I see the fire extinguisher?
- Excuse me?
Why?
Ms. Pi Hae Young, do you have anything
to say about this fire extinguisher?
Run!
As soon as your husband started
to get violent that day...
you called Go Cheok Hee for help.
Pi Hae Young.
- Pi Hae Young.
- No!
Thanks to Go Cheok Hee,
you had an opportunity to run away.
As you ran outside,
you discovered the fire extinguisher
and you changed your mind.
The trophy Go Cheok Hee
tried to save you with
did not make contact
with Mr. Han Dae Man.
It fell in front of Cho Reung's room.
Right away...
you struck Mr. Han Dae Man's head
with the fire extinguisher.
Surprisingly, there was a similar trophy
near where Mr. Han Dae Man passed out.
Go Cheok Hee mistook that trophy
for the actual trophy she threw.
After you ran away...
There was only one person
who witnessed this whole fact.
Cho Reung was probably confused.
Mr. Han Dae Man!
So out of fear and concern,
she decided to hide it.
The trophy Cho Reung hid...
was tucked between the mattress.
What are you talking about?
Just as you wanted to protect
your child from domestic violence...
Cho Reung was also trying
to protect her own mother.
Nevertheless...
are you just going to stand by and
let an innocent person take the fall?
You more than anyone else...
hoped your daughter would grow up
to be an upright person!
Please stop.
- Don't take my mom away!
- Cho Reung!
I hate you, mister!
Don't make my mom cry!
Cho Reung, come here.
Mom, don't cry!
I hate seeing you cry!
The truth is,
I heard everything in my room.
I heard you cry after Dad got mad.
What?
Do you know how sad I was
whenever that happened?
So don't cry, Mom.
I won't cry. I won't cry.
I'm sorry, Cho Reung.
I am so sorry.
Cho Reung, I am so sorry.
The arrest warrant must be out.
Ms. Go Cheok Hee, please come out.
Goodness, what are we going to do?
Cheok Hee, don't worry
and stay put, okay?
Ms. Pi Hae Young confessed
a little while ago.
She said she struck Mr. Han Dae Man
with a fire extinguisher.
What?
What just happened?
Are you serious?
Why did she suddenly confess?
The charges have been cleared,
so you're free to go.
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you!
Thank you, President Bong!
You're out.
They said Ms. Pi Hae Young confessed.
That's great.
Then like I promised...
I have to leave, right?
Right.
Thanks for everything.
Mr. So is here.
Now you're here.
Cheok Hee, let's go.
You've went through a lot.
Let's get you a proper meal to eat.
Goodness, yes.
Goodbye, sir.
You too, Mr. So.
Take care of yourself.
Let's go. Goodbye.
Let's go.
Cheers.
- Good job, Jung Woo.
- You too.
Everything turned out well.
Why do you look so down?
Kyung.
The way I like someone...
I thought I was supposed to
express everything in my heart.
I was wrong.
I guess it could make that person
feel more uncomfortable.
Don't talk about Go Cheok Hee.
How could you fall for that woman?
You're right.
I've completely fallen for her.
That's why it's hard to let her go.
Jung Woo, set your mind to it and end it.
Like when you first came to the office.
You're the lawyer and Cheok Hee
is just the office manager, okay?
You're here.
Who are they?
She's been making tofu
for 50 years in Chodang.
I brought a tofu artisan.
This is her daughter-in-law.
Are all these tofu?
We didn't know what you liked
so we prepared
a variety of different tofus.
This is black bean tofu
and this is firm tofu.
President Bong, I don't know
what to say. You are too kind.
When Mi Hee was at the police station,
he took care of the settlement money...
What do you mean?
- No, nevermind.
- What do you mean?
Cheok Hee, it wasn't that much.
Dad! How could you
accept Min Kyu's money?
Cheok Hee, it wasn't your dad's fault.
It was my fault.
Of all days, I had money on me
at the time. I had no choice.
Seriously, I can't believe you!
Cheok Hee, don't hurt their feelings.
They went out of their way to come.
First... have a bite and
let's not ever go there again.
- Here.
- I swear!
Just a moment please.
- You came to work.
- Huh?
Yes.
Mr. Han Dae Man's condition
has gotten much better.
I'm glad. Ms. Pi Hae Young's act of
self-defense should be accepted then.
Depending upon
Mr. Han Dae Man's condition...
Please submit the divorce petition.
Oh... yes, sir.
I keep forgetting to
change the passcode.
I'll keep it short, and then I'm off.
Tomorrow afternoon at 2 p.m. in
the sapphire room of the DK Hotel.
You said there's addition and
multiplication in your life
but there is no division
or subtraction, correct?
I must take after you
more than I thought.
I only go forward in my life.
There are no u-turns.
Today is the last day.
I'm going easy on you!
I never denied you anything because
you had to grow up with your mother.
Can't you go easy on me just this once?
What?
Instead of loving things
like buildings...
can't you love your son just this once?
I've said too much.
I let my emotions get the best of me.
Your house, buildings, cars, and land.
Everything you own can disappear
with just a word from me.
Tomorrow afternoon at 2 p.m. in
the Sapphire Room of the DK Hotel.
4.5 million won a month with
a 30 million won deposit.
3 million won a month with
a 50 million won deposit...
Wow, why is it so expensive?
I won't be able to sign a lease
even if my suspension gets lifted.
Have you come to threaten me too?
- Was someone here?
- Yes.
The patriarch of this family.
Your boss.
It's the rent money for the penthouse.
I'm going to have to stay longer.
Don't pay me back with money.
- Pay me back with advice.
- What kind of advice?
Go Cheok Hee's suspension
will be lifted in several days.
So... I'm thinking of proposing to her.
- Really?
- They broke up.
Shouldn't I jump at this opportunity?
The location...
where would be a good place?
I'm not sure. Women normally
like big and fancy things.
Plus, it's even better if the
location was meant just for her.
A location just for her.
You.
Dad.
Do you have some money on you?
Where? I don't even have money
to leave behind when I die.
Why? Do you need money?
I want to open my own practice
once the suspension lifts.
Can't you just work as
a lawyer at that firm?
There is someone
I shouldn't be running into.
If he's good to me, I get concerned.
If he's cold to me, it breaks my heart.
It's just better not to see him.
What should we do?
The traffic in Gangnam
lately isn't so bad.
This rascal always takes
the Olympic highway.
It seems this is the end of
DK and BF's relationship.
Let's go.
President Lee.
If you're concerned about a lawsuit,
I'm sure BF is sick and tired of it.
Let's make this quick and simple.
When will you return
the property in Seocho-dong?
He has a tender heart.
It's only because he thinks too much.
- Please let go of your anger...
- If you come out like this...
We'll have to take you to court.
I had no idea we would
go to court for this.
If that's what you want,
then let's go ahead and do that.
The media will go into a frenzy,
but it's better to end it cleanly.
- President Lee...
- You should've done one or the other.
You should've been more discrete
before the building went up.
Or you should've
handled your son better.
I'll call you after you've been served.
Let's go.
Yes, Director?
Real estate, stocks, investment funds...
Investigate everything that's
under Bong Min Kyu's name.
- Yes, sir.
- What about my will?
- Bring that as well.
- Even the will?
When is the completion
date for the new building?
In October, sir.
I also want to know
the official value of it.
Yes, sir.
Pick one out.
I'll buy it for you.
Why are you buying me a gift?
About Mi Hee's settlement money...
I won't be able to pay
you back immediately.
Accept the gift for now
and give me an extension.
Well, if that's what you really want.
Thanks.
Okay, pick something out.
I know you only wear clothes from here.
[12 million won]
What should I get?
Socks. Socks.
- I need socks.
- Socks?
- Seriously?
- Yes.
I don't have any red socks, so it hasn't
been very fun wearing clothes lately.
- This one is nice.
- Are you sure socks will be enough?
Yes.
- Can I wear this?
- Yes.
Have you taken care of the
situation at the police station?
Yes.
I was so busy that day, I didn't
even greet you properly. Sorry.
I'm getting a nice steak dinner
for bringing your clothes.
I don't think I suffered any losses.
Who is this?
Lawyer Bong.
Lawyer So, do you know this?
If it's made from a G7 nation...
The quality of the socks
is also quite different.
Please pass the ketchup.
Am I wrong? Maybe it's so fine
because you bought it for me.
Min Kyu.
Why is this so sticky?
What's up with this?
Are you two out on a date?
Have you exchanged gifts as well?
- It's not that...
- Seriously, what is wrong with this?
It seems you two are
the ones out on a date.
Just the two of you in
this nice restaurant.
Well, it just happened.
I noticed you two looked
very good together walking in.
Is this red pepper paste? Come on.
Lawyer So!
- I'm so sorry.
- Are you okay?
Fortunately, the socks are fine.
Cheok Hee, I'll be back.
I'm going to go to the bathroom.
Okay.
Be careful, will you?
What a relief.
I heard your suspension period
will be expiring soon.
I don't think I need to tell you
about my personal life.
Are you going to keep
working at that firm?
That office doesn't
need additional lawyers.
I've been looking around for office space
so I could open up my own firm.
Are you free tomorrow?
What?
The color is close to colorless.
A level D.
The clarity is amazing.
The diamond is internally flawless, sir.
You said you're also
a certified jewelry appraiser.
As I expected, your expertise
is beyond impressive.
Thank you.
- I'll take it.
- Yes, sir.
Shall I cancel the one we saw earlier?
- I'm going to get both.
- Excuse me?
I still don't know what
Cheok Hee really likes.
I'm going to buy a variety
and have her pick one.
Director, where is this
rancid smell coming from?
I'm sorry.
I've been wearing these
socks for several days.
You never wear the same
pair of socks twice.
How could you wear
the same pair of socks?
These are not the type of socks you
throw away after wearing once!
If you take it off, I can at
least have it dry cleaned for you.
No, I don't want to.
- Here you go.
- Ah yes, thank you.
Let's go see the next ring.
You didn't smell anything?
Some new blinds and it's pretty
much ready. What do you think?
What's your reason for
showing me this place?
You said you were looking
for an office space.
I planned on using this space for
my own firm, but something came up.
If you looked around, you know
it's hard to find a place like this.
Exactly. Why are you
looking for my office space?
Because I think we feel the same way.
You feel uncomfortable
being with Jung Woo.
I also feel uncomfortable
when you're with Jung Woo.
I already paid the down payment.
If you don't have the means
right now, you can pay me later.
Think about it.
I'll take it.
I want to come out as
quickly as possible.
[Lawyer Go Cheok Hee]
Keep it.
Something that gave you
good memories once...
will happen again someday.
It happened,
just like you said it would.
It's eel juice.
Drink it.
It should help you regain some
the energy you lost earlier.
What is this?
'Bar eligibility registration form.'
The suspension has been lifted today.
I'm going to reapply again.
What's with the look on your face?
Are you sure you're free
to practice law again?
It's so strange. I thought I was
going to be so happy today.
I'm more depressed than when
I got my license suspended.
That's weird. Why?
If I think about it...
instead of the six years
I worked as a lawyer...
I was much happier during my
brief time as an office manager.
I learned a lot... I fought a lot...
- and I liked them a lot.
- You brat.
You really enjoyed working there.
Will you be able to leave?
I have to.
I'm going to go and pack
my belongings tonight.
- You startled me!
- Look at it.
Isn't it adorable?
Yes, yes. It's so adorable that I'm
getting goosebumps all over my body.
'Lawyer So Jung Woo.'
[So Byun]
Go Cheok Hee!
So, kissing is love.
I'm still nervous...
- Where's Manager Go?
- Jung Woo, I think she left.
Her desk is completely empty.
She could've said goodbye.
I can't believe she just left.
Don't be too upset.
Go Cheok Hee...
has something better waiting for her.
- Who is it?
- It's me.
What are you doing here
so early in the morning?
President Bong, you came.
Sir, is it okay if I take
Cheok Hee to a party later?
A party? What kind of party is it?
Cheok Hee is free to practice now.
I would like to celebrate
this wonderful day with her.
- Of course! Please go!
- Forget it. What party?
Go. The President is
throwing a party just for you.
Come to the 'S' shopping mall
by 2 p.m.
A shopping mall?
I told you.
The best part about meeting you
is exactly this.
The mystery of discovering things
that I've never experienced in my life.
What is it, Ms. Yoon?
It's nothing. I was just...
Ah, I wanted to check
the cleanliness of our office.
There's a lot of dust in here.
This is what I think, Lawyer So.
- What...
- If the Director is a pearl necklace...
then Go Cheok Hee is a pig neck.
Don't you think a pearl necklace
should be placed around
Audrey Hepburn's neck
instead of a pig's neck?
I wonder if it already started.
Just what are you trying to say?
It's nothing.
Oh, these documents...
2 p.m. at the 'S' shopping mall.
What?
I hear someone is going
to propose over there.
- Who?
- I don't know.
However, if the Director
is a pearl necklace
then I think Go Cheok is a pig's neck.
- Where is it again?
- 'S' shopping mall!
I never mentioned who it was.
What did I just do?
What do I do?
- This is wrong.
- I'm sorry, ma'am.
- The shopping mall is closed today.
- What?
- Why all of a sudden?
- We don't know either. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, but we're closed
for business today.
Why?
Some customer rented out
the whole shopping mall.
What kind of
crazy bastard would do that?
Cheok Hee.
I know none of these rings are worthy
enough to put on your finger.
Think of my sincerity
and at least put one on.
No, you idiot.
I didn't know what you preferred,
so this is what I prepared.
If you see anything you like,
pick one and put it on.
Did that come out too strong?
What do I do?
I've never done this before.
Welcome!
Me?
- Where am I supposed to go?
- Go this way, ma'am.
Ah thank you.
Is this place going out of business?
Why aren't there any customers?
The shopping mall is closed today.
- Excuse me?
- I'm sorry.
This way, ma'am.
Stop!
Stop! Shoot!
- She's on her way up, sir.
- Okay.
Welcome, Cheok Hee.
Min Kyu, what are you doing here?
Sit down for now.
Why aren't there any customers here?
I rented it out.
You rented it?
Why?
The thing is...
How much are all of these rings?
They look like they're
all over a carat each!
Cheok Hee.
Don't think about the cost of the ring.
Think about the person who prepared...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10...
Wow, there are 10 rings here!
If you ran off with this, you could
live off of them for several years.
Don't you agree? Let's say it's
about 10 million won a piece.
No, is it over 10 million
won for a carat these days?
Cheok Hee, that's not it...
Is there a diamond event
going on at the shopping mall?
Who brought all these rings here?
They're yours!
These rings... are mine?
Cheok Hee.
I know none of these rings are worthy...
No. I think I know what
you're trying to say.
I'm sorry. My answer...
is no.
I swear.
Yes, hello?
It's me, Pi Hae Young.
- I want to apologize.
- I understand.
Thank you, Manager Go.
Please give my regards
to Lawyer So as well.
Thanks to him, I was able to confess.
- Excuse me?
- You didn't know?
Lawyer So sought me
out and convinced me.
If he hadn't done that...
I wouldn't have had
the courage to confess.
Yes. I understand.
They said Ms. Pi Hae Young confessed.
That's great.
So Jung Woo.
Go Cheok Hee!
So Jung Woo!
- Go Cheok Hee.
- So Jung Woo.
How did you know to come here?
I'm sorry.
- About what?
- I can't do it.
About forgetting you.
I tried my best to do it.
It's not something I can do.
I can't. I won't.
Let's just love each other.
And if it's hard?
Then it's hard.
And if it hurts?
Let's hurt.
If it's painful, it's painful.
If it's sad... it's sad.
Just like that... just...
Let's just love each other.
Subtitles by DramaFever