Watch and Download App at official site FastDrama.Co to support us
Is this where Daeguk's CEO lives?
- Who are you? - Who am I?
I'm Oh Jeong Hoon's future mother-in-law.
My niece is going to marry him.
What?
Why look so shocked?
You didn't know he was engaged?
Get out. Get out of my house.
Don't you yell at me.
Your daughter stole a man.
What? She stole?
Yes. They were engaged...
and you stole him away with money.
What? With money?
My niece dated and supported Jeong Hoon...
for four years while he studied for the bar.
Now that he passed the bar,
you waved money before him to pinch him.
Do you think I'll let you do that?
My goodness, no!
What are you doing?
Get out. Get out!
If you don't get out right now, I'll call the police!
What? The police?
Do you think that scares me?
Call them. Call the police.
I will turn this thieving household upside-down.
What? "Thieving"?
Who are you calling a thief?
Hey, I've been through more than you think.
Do you think I won't be able to deal with the likes of you?
- Let go! - How dare you?
- Let go! - Who are you?
What do you think you are?
That woman is all brawn and no brains.
She's no CEO's wife. She's a thug.
I'll leave for now,
but do you think I'll let you steal Jeong Hoon?
As if!
My goodness.
What's all this? What's this mess?
Mom, what happened?
Do you know what just happened because of you?
What happened?
Why is this room a mess?
Jeong Hoon promised to marry someone else.
Her aunt just came and did this.
You didn't know about that, did you?
He conned all of us.
He didn't con us.
He ended it with her.
What?
Then you knew he had been dating someone else?
How could you still think of marrying him?
She supported him for years!
Where are you going?
This is just unbelievable.
I was worried about you and...
wanted to see you.
I didn't know you worked with my aunt.
She isn't at work?
If she left home,
she'll show up later.
It's hard, isn't it?
I can tell just by looking at your face.
Do you know why Jeong Hoon...
suddenly changed?
What did he tell you?
He's seeing someone.
That won't be true.
I think he lied to make me give up.
There has to be another reason.
Don't you know what it is?
Not really.
Can you talk to your brother?
I really don't know why he's acting like this.
Sure, I will.
Go back inside.
You should rest.
Okay.
Bye.
Floor manager?
You're looking for me?
You hadn't come to work,
so Mr. Jo sent me.
I can't work today.
Tell the boss that I'm ill in bed.
Then...
- let's have a chat. - About what?
What did you just say?
You're Jeong Hoon's brother?
I met Soon Young at your home...
and just found out you're her aunt.
This is a mess.
You're Jeong Hoon's brother, so let me ask you something.
When did he...
get together with Daeguk's CEO's daughter?
Are they discussing marriage?
Don't think of lying.
Mal Soon the seamstress knows.
That means she visited the family.
Jeong Hoon was originally her tutor.
He changed and...
I feel sorry and angry for Soon Young.
Do you know where I just was?
I went to Daeguk's CEO's home and tore up the living room.
What?
Give your brother a message.
I won't let him desert Soon Young...
and marry into that family. I just won't.
Soon Young doesn't seem to know yet.
We'll never be in-laws.
Your brother ruined that.
I don't think you should tell Soon Young for now.
She's still in a state of shock.
This news will just make it worse.
I'm so angry.
Don't just sit and mope.
It's a horrible sight.
You missed work?
Jeong Tae was just...
We met.
He's Jeong Hoon's brother.
I found out just now when he came to find you.
Where did you go instead of to work?
I went to see Jeong Hoon...
Did you go to his home again?
No, to Daeguk...
It's best you don't know.
What do you mean?
Don't ask. You don't need to know.
Jeong Hoon.
It's not yet over with her?
What do you mean?
That woman's aunt caused a scene at my house.
You promised you'd end it and you should have.
How could you let them come to my house?
Did you lie to me?
She supported you for years.
How close were you that...
the aunt would say that about you two?
Why won't you say anything?
It's over between us.
What more must I say?
I'm sorry that the aunt trashed your house,
but I find it very unpleasant that you don't believe me.
I don't want to marry you...
if I have to keep lying.
You're out of line.
You're angry with me?
I feel unpleasant.
However much I like you,
if you're so indecisive that you can't end it with a woman,
I'll have to...
reconsider marrying you.
What? Jeong Hoon had a fiancee?
Yes.
Her aunt was here today...
and caused a scene.
Honey.
They dated for four years and acted as if they were married.
You didn't know about this, sir?
Why won't you say anything?
Mi Jin knew that he had been seeing someone.
Did you know as well?
He said he'd end it with her.
He promised me.
What?
How could you think of letting him...
marry Mi Jin after that?
Do you know what the woman's aunt said?
She called us thieves!
What?
We used our money to take another woman's man...
and she called that stealing.
She supported Jeong Hoon...
for four years while he studied for the bar.
Why would he leave her to marry Mi Jin?
It's because of this, our money.
Mi Jin's home.
Where were you all day?
- Come and sit down. - I'm tired.
Can I go upstairs, Dad?
Did you meet Jeong Hoon?
Yes.
- What did he say? - He ended it with her.
The woman's aunt came here to cause a fuss...
and it's over?
Jeong Hoon broke it off and she...
came here because she was angry!
I will never accept him!
I can't let Mi Jin marry someone who has...
an ulterior motive to marrying her.
Sir, do you think you can trust Jeong Hoon?
You keep quiet.
You're back from work?
Is Jeong Hoon in?
Yes. Why?
Jeong Tae's home?
Yes, but he went into Jeong Hoon's room.
Did he?
Are you still getting married?
Yes.
If you want to try to change my mind, get out.
Today, Soon Young...
You two broke up.
Is it Ms. Uhm now?
Anyway, her aunt went to Daeguk Construction's...
CEO's house today.
What did you say?
Soon Young's aunt went to Mi Jin's home?
How do you know that?
Soon Young's aunt works where I do.
She missed work so I went to get her and...
found out who she was.
You can guess what happened, can't you?
I'm telling you because she...
told me to, not because I'm worried.
I told you, so I did my part.
They didn't know about Soon Young.
They'll be in shock.
Jeong Hoon.
It's not too late to...
We won't break up because of Soon Young.
(Storage)
The storage room is always dirty.
Bok Shil.
Sorry for letting you down.
But I can't give up on becoming a singer.
I swear there was an egg in here.
Where did it go?
It's not like...
eggs have legs with which to run off on.
My goodness.
Gosh.
What's wrong with your face?
- What's that? - Raw egg to make me pretty.
I need to make sure...
I don't get betrayed.
What do you mean?
Why do you think Jeong Hoon left his girlfriend for someone else?
Kyung Ho's CEO's daughter is pretty,
that's why.
Do you think it's because she's pretty?
He fell in love with her money.
What's wrong with your face, Choon Ja?
You look like a yellow ghost.
- A yellow ghost? - A yellow ghost?
You look scary.
Kyung Ho, have breakfast.
I'm not hungry. See you.
Why aren't you hungry?
Do you feel unwell?
No. I'll grab something if I feel hungry.
See you.
Is something on his mind?
Why would he leave without breakfast?
Open the door.
Give me that.
The missing egg from the kitchen...
went on your face?
Yes.
Don't make me talk, my skin's too taut.
You silly thing.
You're pretty enough that you don't have to do that.
Wash your face.
I'll bring in the breakfast table.
You don't even have...
a boy who cares about you.
I do. Jeong Tae...
Jeong Hoon.
Are you here to see me?
Yes. My CEO's nephew...
wants to see you.
Me?
That's his number.
Do you know him?
Sort of.
Okay, thanks.
Bok Shil.
Shall we meet after work?
Okay. I'll come to your company later.
Okay.
(Cha Sang Pil, CEO)
(Lucky Entertainment)
Can you lift your legs?
Leave it and go.
I'm not done mopping.
Get out.
Why yell at me?
Can I speak to Mr. Han Kyung Ho?
It's Cha Sang Pil.
Did you tell Oh Jeong Hoon that I want to see him?
Wait.
Is our company working on something...
in cooperation with Daeguk Construction?
Why?
Mr. Cha was on the phone.
There's nothing right now.
Why would you want to know?
What?
It's nothing.
Okay.
Mr. Han.
Are you working on something with Lucky Entertainment behind my back?
Pardon?
You left me out last time to work with...
Mr. Cha on something in Vietnam.
Will you stab me in the back again?
Not at all. It was about a personal matter.
I'm stressed as it is because the complex is being delayed.
You should pay more attention to that project.
Why is he blaming Mr. Han...
for the delay?
He's afraid the CEO...
will ask to see him then yell.
He should check the site out himself, then.
He's always handing his tasks over to Mr. Han.
- Are you going out? - Yes.
Jeong Hoon.
Are you going out because...
Soon Young's aunt went to their house?
Goodbye.
What did you say?
Soon Young's aunt went where?
She went to Mi Jin's home.
What?
Who told you about that?
Jeong Tae works with Soon Young's aunt.
He went to her house and found out.
That means...
she must know what happened.
She'll have caused a huge mess at the house.
What are you doing here?
Why don't you reconsider marrying Mi Jin to Jeong Hoon?
It bothers me that he...
dated someone for four years.
I already know about that.
Jeong Hoon didn't lie to me.
Even so, I think he wants to marry...
for a shady reason.
It's not your place to comment.
Come in.
You said you'd deal with the other woman...
and you haven't yet?
- I apologize. - Why are you...
Sang Pil, leave.
Go on, I said leave.
Is this the best you can do?
How could you let her trash our house?
I'm sorry for the trouble.
I'll make sure this never happens again.
You haven't sorted it out yet?
I ended it completely.
You needn't worry.
I knew you had a girlfriend at the time,
but I gave permission because you said you'd break it off.
However much I like you,
I can't accept someone who breaks my daughter's heart.
That won't happen. Don't worry, sir.
Then...
I'll give you one more shot.
Don't cause any more trouble and end it properly.
If not, I can't trust you.
And the marriage with Mi Jin is off. Okay?
Yes. Believe me.
(Daeguk Construction)
Let's talk.
Did Mr. Han Kyung Ho tell you that...
I wished to see you?
Yes, he did.
But what for?
Mi Jin's like a sister to me.
I can't pretend that I'm not concerned about her future.
Get to the point.
I will, then.
To be frank, I don't think your motive of marrying Mi Jin...
is purely genuine.
You studied for years and passed the bar,
then suddenly gave that up to marry Mi Jin...
and join Daeguk and I don't understand that.
Not to mention the girlfriend you had.
Mr. Hwang already knows about that,
and I never deceived anyone.
So you're blameless?
What do you want to say?
This marriage.
Is it about Mi Jin...
or...
Daeguk Construction?
Before I answer, I'd like to ask you a question.
You said our engagement bothers you.
Is it about Mi Jin or...
Daeguk Construction?
You can't answer.
Of course it's about Mi Jin.
What answer did you expect?
Here's my answer.
I'm marrying Mi Jin because I want to,
and I'll join Daeguk...
to help my father-in-law.
Will that do?
If that's all you want to know,
I'd like to leave.
Grandma, I'm off.
- Are you going to work? - Yes.
Let's go somewhere on the way.
- Where? - You know where Soon Young lives.
I want to meet her, so lead the way.
Why would you see her?
Just lead the way.
Grandma.
- Where is she going? - You don't need to know.
Jeong Tae, there aren't that many pretty girls at your cabaret.
What?
I checked the place out yesterday.
They all dress so sexy,
but I was way prettier.
Don't you agree?
- Good for you. - What is?
You have no sense of reality. Life must me so easy.
Don't you dare get distracted by things like this.
Okay?
Will you please stop?
Grandma.
I know about reality.
I know exactly.
Why do you want to see Soon Young?
What will you say?
Where does she live?
- Is this it? - Yes.
Call her.
When we met yesterday,
she was half-dead with grief.
I felt so sorry for her.
You won't be mean to her, will you?
You grew to like her too.
Will you stop talking nonsense and call her?
I trust you.
Is anyone home?
It's Jeong Tae.
Soon Young, are you in?
Soon Young.
Ma'am.
- Hello. - Let's talk.
Come in.
- You can go. - Grandma.
What is she going to say?
You look terrible.
Soon Young.
Yes, Grandma.
I came...
to ask you to do something for me.
Can't you...
give up on Jeong Hoon?
Grandma.
At first,
I disapproved of you.
But the more I got to know you, I realized how sweet...
and gentle you were.
That's why I thought...
you'd make a great wife for my grandson.
There's nothing I can do because...
Jeong Hoon's so adamant.
I accepted you because...
Jeong Hoon said he couldn't live without you.
Now he has...
completely changed his mind.
Ok Boon is very distraught over all this,
and what's worse,
it's causing a rift between the kids and I can't stand that.
So...
I came to ask you for a favor.
For Jeong Hoon's sake,
can you not let him go?
I'm so sorry that...
this is...
all I can say to you.
As you know,
I owe Jeong Hoon a lot.
That's why now...
I want him to live in comfort.
That's why I'm being so nasty to you.
Can you do this for me?
Madam Gu, what happened yesterday?
Why didn't you come to work?
Didn't the floor manager say?
I was sick.
I'm sure you were.
Everything went wrong at the last minute.
Why did Jeong Hoon change his mind?
He passed the bar and wouldn't want for anything more.
Why would he go for a CEO's daughter?
I thought about it and I'm positive that...
the CEO's daughter chased him.
That's why she came to see him a few times.
- She did? - She did.
Any tree falls if you chop at it enough.
A rich young lady followed him around,
and Jeong Hoon fell for her.
What did I say?
The rich young lady and her tutor.
It's a perfect way to get the girl.
It's always about money.
If your niece had been rich,
Jeong Hoon wouldn't have left her.
You're right.
Why aren't you getting ready for work?
Why did you miss work yesterday?
I told you that she was very sick.
What do you have?
Money? Anything?
You just have your body.
How can you serve our customers if you're so sickly?
I'm already annoyed...
and now you belittle me because I'm poor?
Why are you yelling at me?
- Get ready for work! - Yes, sir.
I hate my life.
Jeong Tae, will you really not work at the demolition site?
I told you I don't do what I said I won't do.
Come on, boss.
Let's just get the boys and take it down.
Leave it to me.
I'll flatten the rest of the houses just like that.
What if someone gets hurt?
This is just insane.
Oh Se Ra.
Let's talk.
Talk.
I missed a few days of practice because of exams...
and you practiced instead?
What's wrong with that? Can't I sing too?
You just clean the office.
What are you to take up my practice slot?
If you want to keep it,
come every day instead of slacking off.
What?
- Hey. - Hye Rin, that was too much.
Not at all.
Mr. Cha, you tell me.
Am I like her?
How dare she take up my practice time?
She's just a cleaner.
How long will you two go on fighting like this?
Do I have to get involved with this too?
You can clean this up.
I did what I have to do. Can I go now?
You finished early?
Yes.
Why didn't you order anything?
Do you want coffee?
We can order later.
Kyung Ho.
I didn't tell you I joined Lucky Entertainment...
I'll go first, Bok Shil.
You lied to me.
Okay.
I don't want you to sing,
so you couldn't tell me. I get that.
But now that I know,
I don't want you to go on working there.
- Leave. - Kyung Ho.
The CEO makes you clean.
You went to sing.
Does that make sense?
So quit.
I'll contact the company that offered the clerk job.
No.
I'll become a singer and succeed.
Bok Shil.
If you're going to object to my being a singer,
then stop minding my business.
You asked to see me, so I thought about it.
I can't give up on my dream.
You give up.
Stop liking me.
How can you say that so easily?
It wasn't easy.
I thought and agonized over it.
I haven't worked at Lucky Entertainment for too long.
Even if you see me, pretend we're strangers.
I'll feel uncomfortable if the CEO were to know.
I have to go.
Bok Shil.
What? Jeong Hoon's grandma was here?
And? What did she say?
She asked me to...
let Jeong Hoon go.
What?
Now the old woman's trying to get rid of you too?
She asked me to do her a favor.
Jeong Hoon's mother is very upset,
and she can't stand watching Jeong Hoon argue with his siblings.
She held my hand and pleaded.
It's all about the money.
What did you say? Did you just sit and cry?
There was nothing...
I could say after that.
You should've spoken your mind.
Why didn't you?
What? You met Soon Young?
Yes.
I asked her to give up on Jeong Hoon,
so that's that.
How could you go all the way there...
and ask her to do that?
Should we just sit and watch, then?
Do you think Jeong Hoon will change his mind?
Don't you know your own son?
Why wouldn't I know my son?
He didn't leave Soon Young because he fell out of love...
and he isn't marrying Mi Jin because he loves her.
He's lashing out because he thinks his father...
ruined his life.
That's why we must stop him.
He didn't make these decisions with a clear mind.
We must stop him.
Yes, like you said,
because of his dad, his acceptance to...
the judicial institute was cancelled...
and he can't work anywhere.
Should he just give up like that?
He'll have to work as a manual laborer.
Can you deal with that?
If they will offer him a good career,
we must grab hold of whoever we can.
That way,
Jeong Hoon will get a life of his own.
Don't you try to stop me.
Did you talk to Jeong Hoon?
Yes, he came to my office.
What did he say?
He said he'd end it properly,
so I gave him another chance.
Why won't he call me then?
I told him that I'd have to think about marrying him.
You said that?
He said it was over,
but the woman's aunt caused a fuss and I got angry.
What do you really want?
Did you really decide to reconsider marriage?
No, Dad. I blurted that out in anger.
If he were to come and ask for forgiveness,
I'd forgive him for everything.
Why hasn't he called?
He's not that easy to manipulate.
He knows you were angry...
and is waiting for you to calm down.
That's why I feel worse.
It's like I always give in to him.
Why won't my heart slow down even after I take a pill?
You, come here.
What for?
You can't marry him.
I'll do whatever it takes...
to break you two up.
Will you stop it?
I'm upset too.
Why should you get upset over him?
When you can just give up?
It's my marriage. I'll deal with it!
Mi Jin!
Sang Pil, what is she talking about?
What will she deal with?
She's not over him yet, is he?
I think you should talk to her.
Jeong Hoon wants to marry Mi Jin for a reason...
and that bothers me.
Right? You think so too?
I will cancel this engagement.
What's this stink?
This is the house.
- Wait here. - Yes, ma'am.
Who are you?
Does Oh Jeong Hoon live here?
Yes, he does.
Are you his mother?
Yes.
I'm Mi Jin's mother.
What?
This is unbelievable.
Do you know why I came all the way here?
I'm here to call off the engagement between our kids.
(Through the Waves)
Do you know how shameless you both are?
You should be more aggressive.
Just because your son is smart,
you sell him over.
How can you say that?
- Let's go and eat. - What?
What should we do now?
You won't understand or accept me.
That's what's happening.
I like you as...
you are now, not as a singer.
What'll you do about Soon Young?
Doing this won't change anything.
I won't do that kind of job.
Just make sure that nothing goes wrong.
Get out the way!