That's it!
Hundred honors and 90 below.
Nicely done, Strangways.
l have to give it to you.
l must leave you for a few minutes.
Order a round on my chit, professor.
Damn it all! Must you break off
at this time every evening?
Sorry, general.
My director is a creature of habit.
l get a call every day at this time.
Hurry back
before the cards get cold.
Twenty minutes.
Don't doctor any hands while l'm away.
Same again.
Bless you, master.
Hurry, man!
Get away quick!
W6N, W6N, W6N...
...calling G 7W.
How do you hear me? Over.
G 7W, London, G 7W, London,
Receiving you, Over,
Stand by to transmit.
Wait. Out.
Here.
Hello, W6N, report my signals.
Over.
Hello, W6N. Over.
Foreman of Signals. Urgent.
Right. Get me
Ml6 radio security control.
What is it?
-Kingston, Jamaica broke contact.
-Broken or faded?
Broken. Carrier wave
is still established.
-Did you check both frequencies?
-Yes, sir. No joy on either.
Keep trying. Let me know
when they come up again.
Hello? Hello, W6N,
report my signals. Over.
Foreman of Signals, sir.
Jamaica's broken off mid-transmission.
No, sir, it's not a technical fault.
Yes, sir.
Will you tell him, sir?
Very good.
-Excuse me, are you a member?
-No, l'm looking for Mr. James Bond.
-What name should l say, sir?
-Just give him my card, will you?
Would you like to leave your coat
over there, sir?
The house will cover the difference?
l need another thousand.
l admire your courage, Miss....
Trench. Sylvia Trench.
l admire your luck, Mr....
Bond.
James Bond.
Mr. Bond, would you
care to raise the limit?
l have no objections.
Now.
-Looks like you're out to get me.
-lt's an idea, at that.
Eight.
-Excuse me, sir.
-Thank you.
Andre, l must pass the shoe.
l hope you'll forgive me,
but it's most important. Thank you.
Have those changed, will you?
Too bad you have to go, just as
things were getting interesting.
Yes. Tell me, Miss Trench,
do you play any other games?
l mean besides chemin de fer?
Golf, amongst other things.
-Tomorrow afternoon, then.
-Tomorrow?
We could have dinner afterwards,
perhaps?
Sounds tempting.
May l let you know
in the morning?
Splendid.
My number's on the card.
See if he's there, will you?
James, where on earth have you been?
l've been searching London for you!
00 7 is here, sir.
He'll see you in a minute.
Moneypenny!
-What gives?
-Me.
Given an ounce of encouragement.
You never take me to dinner
looking like this, James.
You never take me to dinner, period.
l would, only M
would have me court-martialed...
...for illegal use
of government property.
Flattery will get you nowhere,
but don't stop trying. Now.
-What's all this to-do about?
-Strangways. lt looks serious.
We've been burning the air between
here and Jamaica for three hours.
ln you go.
Don't forget to write.
Good evening, sir.
lt happens to be 3 a.m.
When do you sleep, 00 7?
Never on the firm's time, sir.
Sit down.
Jamaica went off the air tonight.
Right in the middle
of the opening procedure.
Strangways has disappeared.
So has his secretary. She was new.
We had just sent her there.
Was Strangways on
something special?
He was checking an inquiry
from the Americans.
They had complaints about interference
with their Cape Canaveral rockets.
They think it comes
from the Jamaica area.
-Does "toppling" mean anything to you?
-A little.
lt's throwing the gyroscopic controls
of a guided missile off balance...
...with a radio beam?
More or less.
Five million dollars worth of missile
aimed at a spot in the south Atlantic...
...but finishing up in the middle
of the Brazilian jungle is bad enough.
Now they're going to try orbiting
a rocket around the moon.
The American ClA sent a man
to work with Strangways.
Fellow by the name of Leiter.
Do you know him?
l've heard of him
but never met him.
Has he found out
anything important?
Ask him. You're booked
on the 7:00 plane to Kingston.
That gives you exactly
three hours, 22 minutes.
Armorer.
l'll have background papers
sent to you at the airport...
...in a self-destructor bag.
You can study them
during the flight.
l want to know what's happened
to Strangways.
Take off your jacket.
Give me your gun.
l thought so. Damned Beretta again.
l've told you about this before.
You tell him,
for the last time.
lt's nice and light,
in a lady's handbag.
No stopping power.
Any comments, 00 7?
l disagree, sir.
l've used a Beretta for 1 0 years.
l've never missed with it yet.
No, but it jammed on your last job.
You spent six months in hospital.
You carry a double-0 number. lt gives
you a license to kill, not get killed.
Since l've been head of Ml6, there's
been a 40 percent drop in casualties.
l want it to stay that way.
You'll carry the Walther...
...unless you prefer to go back
to standard intelligence duties.
No, sir, l would not.
Then from now on you carry
a different gun. Show him.
Walther PPK.
lt's 7.65 mil, with a delivery like
a brick through a plate-glass window.
Takes a Brausch silencer with very
little reduction in muzzle velocity.
-The American ClA swear by them.
-Thank you, Major Boothroyd.
Thank you, sir.
Good night, sir.
-Any questions, 00 7?
-No, sir.
All right. Best of luck.
Thank you, sir.
-00 7?
-Sir?
Just leave the Beretta.
Miss Moneypenny, forget the usual
repartee, 007's in a hurry,
Good luck.
There! You made me miss it.
You don't miss a thing.
How did you get in?
Never mind. You're here.
l decided to accept your invitation.
That was for tomorrow afternoon.
-Do you always dress this way for golf?
-l changed into something comfortable.
l hope l did the right thing.
You did the right thing,
but you picked the wrong moment.
l have to leave immediately.
Oh, that's too bad.
Just as things
were getting interesting again.
When did you say
you had to leave?
lmmediately.
Almost immediately.
Hello, New York. Your Pan Am 323
just landed in Kingston, Jamaica.
-Taxi!
All right, go ahead.
Help yourself.
-Taxi!
-Mr. Bond, sir?
Yes?
l'm Mr. Jones.
Chauffeur from Government House.
Fine, we'll drop my bags at the hotel.
l want to check my reservation.
-l can do that.
-No. You just take care of the bags.
-Government House?
-Yes,
-Principal secretary, please.
-Hold the line, please,
-Who wants him?
-James Bond. Universal Exports.
Welcome to Jamaica, Mr. Bond.
Yes, your head office alerted us
this morning.
-Free for lunch today? One o'clock?
-That'll suit me fine.
By the way, have you
sent a car for me?
l didn't think you wanted
an official reception,
Quite right. One o'clock then.
Forgive me if l'm a few minutes late.
-Where to first, sir?
-Government House, but no hurry.
Just take me for a ride.
You always drive this fast?
l told you l wasn't in a hurry.
Sorry, sir, but l think there's
some fellow trying to follow us.
Then l suggest
you try and lose them.
Take the next right turn.
Now, Mr. Jones, talk fast
before your friend doubles back.
Who are you working for?
l don't know what you're saying.
l was sent to meet you at the airport.
By whom?
By Government House.
l don't think so.
Both hands on the wheel!
l'm a nervous passenger.
Get out. Move!
Keep your hands
where l can see them.
Get up!
-Now talk.
-All right.
Let me have a cigarette.
To hell with you!
Sergeant, make sure
he doesn't get away.
Cyanide in a cigarette?
-Fantastic.
-No less.
-Well, Duff, what have you got?
-The car was stolen.
We haven't identified the driver yet.
But he wasn't a Kingston man.
Wherever he was from,
news of my arrival leaked.
We didn't advertise it,
l can assure you.
Perhaps not.
lt seemed someone
had been selling tickets.
Anything more we can do for you?
l'd like to meet
the last people to see Strangways.
Nobody saw him after he left
our bridge four at the Queens Club.
-Who were the others?
-Professor Dent.
Metallurgist. Runs a test laboratory.
Respected. Clean bill.
-Potter.
-General, ex-army. Been here ages.
Start with those.
-Want them brought in?
-Lord, no! l'll meet them socially.
l'll introduce you
at the club tonight.
Fine. l'd like to take a look
at Strangways' place.
l'll run you up there now.
Go on in.
Oh, yes, that's a blood patch.
-They've grouped it as O-Rh positive.
-That's her group, all right.
The set was still switched on
when we came round.
We tried to get through on
that frequency, but it was dead.
And it'll stay dead. All frequencies
are changed when security's broken.
Receipt from Dent Laboratories.
Geology a hobby of Strangways'?
Not that l know of, no.
Who is the man with Strangways?
One of the local fishermen.
-He drove the car that tailed me.
-That so? That gives us something.
-l'll have a check made on him.
-You do that.
l want to have a bath before
l meet Pleydell-Smith at the club.
One medium-dry vodka martini,
mixed like you said, sir, not stirred.
-Anything else?
-No, that's all.
Very well, sir.
Curious, old Strangways
just vanishing like that. Or is it?
His secretary was very nice,
very nice indeed.
-Did you know her?
-l'd seen her around, you know.
l suppose none of you could throw
any light on what happened?
His conversation? Any hint?
l never heard him talk about anything
but big-game fishing and bridge.
He started fishing three weeks ago
and was out practically every day.
Must've cost him something. These
fishermen ask the Earth to charter.
-And Quarrel's the most expensive.
-Quarrel?
Cayman lslander.
Keeps a boat in the harbor.
l see.
-Excuse me. Where do l find Quarrel?
-Him.
Thank you.
Your name Quarrel?
Maybe.
l'm a friend
of Commander Strangways.
Ain't that nice!
l like people who's friends of people.
l thought you might be able to tell me
what happened to him.
As far as l know, nothing happened.
Unless you know different, captain.
Where did you take him
in your boat?
See that?
That there's the Caribbean.
That's where. Fishing.
l'm interested in fishing.
l'd like to charter your boat.
l'm sorry. lt's not for hire.
-Seems l came to the wrong address.
-That's all right.
Now if you'll excuse me,
l've got business to attend to.
Hey, Puss Feller.
Well, if it ain't my friend
what gets addresses mixed.
You got the right one now
if you like good eating.
l do if the conversation matches it.
Back at the boat, too public.
-ln there, it different.
-After you.
Sure thing.
-See we get a bit of privacy.
-Nothing but.
Nothing but.
-Pick a seat.
-l'm fine.
Okay, mister, supposing you start
the conversation. How's about it?
Ain't no use struggling.
Puss Feller wrestles alligators.
Right! Up slowly
and face that wall.
Hold it.
Gently, gently.
Let's not get excited.
Frisk him.
Nothing.
lnteresting.
Where were you measured for this?
My tailor. Savile Row.
That so?
Mine's a guy in Washington.
Felix Leiter,
Central lntelligence Agency.
You must be James Bond.
You mean we're fighting
the same war?
l spotted you at the airport.
When l saw you drive off with the
opposition, l figured l must be wrong.
Quarrel's been helping me.
-No hard feelings, l hope.
-Only a sore hand. Glad to know you.
That's Puss Feller.
He owns the place.
-Hope he cooks better than he fights.
-You could find out.
Nobody died from my cooking yet.
There you are.
Cape Canaveral is screaming.
They don't want anything to go wrong
with this moon-rocket launching.
You say Strangways didn't think the
interference was coming from here.
-l suppose you cased the joint.
-l checked unofficially.
You limeys can be pretty touchy
about trespassing.
Strangways and Quarrel
checked the offshore islands.
-You found nothing?
-Not a thing.
-Where did you look?
-Just about most everywhere.
-Fire lsland, Crab Key, Morgan's Reef.
-Checked them all thoroughly?
Except Crab Key.
We have no right to go there.
-Why not?
-lt belongs to a Chinese--
Get her, Quarrel,
and the camera.
Evening, missus.
You're hurting!
Captain wants you
to have a drink with us.
-You're hurting me.
-You can't mean it.
Good evening.
Why do you want
another picture of me?
l only got your hat at the airport.
Tell this ape to let me go.
Why do you want a picture?
-That's the way l earn my living.
-Who pays you?
The Daily Gleaner,
-Anything l can do?
-Ever seen this girl before?
She comes here sometimes.
She being a nuisance to you?
You want me to get rid of her?
No. Ring the Gleaner and find out if
they sent a photographer here tonight.
They didn't send me.
l work freelance.
Freelance? For whom?
You--
Tell us and he'll stop.
We don't get nothing out of her.
Want me to break her arm?
Another time.
The second time nothing's come out.
Give her her arm back.
Run along, freelance.
You'll be sorry!
You'll all be sorry, you rats!
One takes cyanide, another
would have let her arm be broken.
Neither would talk. Who puts
that sort of scare into people?
We better find out but fast.
What's so special about Crab Key?
Why can't we go?
lt belongs to a Chinese character.
He won't allow anyone to land.
l had our naval reconnaissance planes
take a look.
They found nothing
but a bauxite mine...
...low-scan C-H radar setup.
But there's nothing
illegal about that.
That Crab Key scares me plenty.
Friends of mine went there
after seashells.
Only trouble,
they never came back again.
None of the local fishermen
will go there.
Commander Strangways and me
slipped in at night.
He take samples and we came back.
Don't do to hang about there.
-What kind of samples?
-Bits of rock, sand, water.
l see. Crab Key
begins to interest me.
What else do we know
about this Chinese gentleman?
Nothing much, except his name.
Dr. No.
-l'd like to see Professor Dent.
-Have you an appointment, sir?
Tell him it's James Bond.
We met yesterday.
Very well.
He's somewhere in the lab.
ls Professor Dent there?
Never mind.
Good morning, professor.
Mr. Bond.
Anything l can do for you?
Yes, l came across this in
Strangways' office. Your receipt.
-Yes, that's right.
-Can you tell me anything about it?
Poor old Strangways. Bit of a bug
of his, this amateur geology.
He brought rock samples in for testing,
convinced they were valuable.
Were they?
No, of course not.
Just low-grade iron pyrites.
Can l see them?
No, l threw them away.
-Do you know where he found them?
-No, he didn't say.
-Crab Key, perhaps?
-Definitely not.
Why so certain?
Not geologically possible.
Thank you very much. lt's kind
of you to spare me your time.
You're very welcome, Mr. Bond.
Professor?
Allow me.
Morning.
-l've got to get to Crab Key.
-You know the procedure.
There's no time for that.
l'll take responsibility.
-l hope you know what you're doing.
-Come on!
-l radioed. They're expecting me.
-Go ahead.
Sit down,
Why have you disobeyed my
strictest rule and come in daylight?
l had to.
Bond came to see me this morning.
l know, l gave orders that he should
be killed, Why is he still alive?
Our attempts failed.
Your attempts failed,
l do not like failure,
You are not going to fail me again,
professor?
No. l came to warn you.
Warn me?
Tell you.
Bond discovered those rock samples
of Strangways' came from Crab Key.
He's not a fool.
He's sure to come out here.
l hope not, lf he does,
l shall hold you responsible,
l make myself clear?
Yes, quite clear.
Go to the table,
You see what is in the cage?
Pick it up,
Tonight,
-l'd like to send a cable.
-Yes, of course.
The car you ordered,
it's been delivered.
lt's in number five parking lot.
-Thank you. Good night.
-Good night, Mr. Bond.
-Morning, Pleydell-Smith.
-Morning, Bond.
Sorry to trouble you,
but l need some information.
All you have
on Dr. No and Crab Key.
Miss Taro,
bring me the files on Dr. No.
-Sit down.
-What do you know about the island?
Not much, except there's
a bauxite mine there.
Dr. No runs it
like a concentration camp.
l've heard funny rumors, but no one's
ever complained officially.
Miss Taro, just leave them here.
l'm very sorry,
but we can't find them anywhere.
What do you mean?
Who had them last?
Commander Strangways. Both files.
All right, Miss Taro.
Damn nuisance,
their disappearing like that.
On the contrary.
l'd have been surprised
if they hadn't .
That came for you from London
in the plane, in the diplomatic pouch.
Present from home.
Can l get out that way?
That's a naughty little habit.
Listening at keyholes?
l wasn't listening.
l was looking for those files.
Anything that can't be found,
l get the blame.
Forget it. l'm sure it's not
very important anyhow.
l'd hate to think you'll spend
the afternoon looking for them.
No. l have the afternoon off.
There's a coincidence. So have l.
Why not show me around the island?
What should l say to an invitation
from a strange gentleman?
You should say yes.
l should say maybe.
Three o'clock at my hotel, maybe?
Yes, maybe.
Good.
The luminous dial activates it.
Hold this.
Where did Commander Strangways
place those samples?
-About where your feet is.
-Good.
Hi there.
Lose something?
Take a look at this Geiger reading.
Those samples Strangways brought
back from Crab Key were radioactive.
Yet Dent told me they were
worthless chunks of iron ore.
He's either a bad professor
or a poor liar.
l intend to find out which.
How soon can you get us to Crab Key?
Well, it's like this, captain.
Commander Strangways, he done
take samples of all the islands.
Supposing we check
the nearest ones first?
No. l'm interested in Crab Key.
l took the commander there,
and we got away without trouble.
lt don't do for a man
to tempt providence too often.
You see, there's a dragon.
What?
Native superstition.
Started by Dr. No, probably.
All right. We don't want to force you.
Leiter and l will go over after dark
if you'll give us directions.
l get my directions from my nose...
...my ears, from my instincts.
Anyway, l'll be here about 7.
Fine.
Mr. Bond, there's
a telephone message for you.
-Johnny, what have you done with it?
-lt's right here.
Hello?
Oh, Mr. Bond. l was thinking.
Why don't you collect me
at my apartment?
lt's lovely up here in the mountains.
Nice and cool.
All right. You leave the
Port Royal Road out of Kingston.
Then along the Wentworth Road
until you get to the cement factory.
Then you turn left.
Follow the road up the hill,
down the other side,,,
,,,and two miles further on,
on the left,,,
,,,Magenta Drive, 239 1,
l'll be waiting for you,
How did it happen?
l think they were on their way
to a funeral.
Just a minute.
You did invite me, remember?
Of course. l just didn't
expect you here so soon.
Yes, come in.
l'll go put some clothes on.
Don't go to any trouble
on my account.
Please.
Forgive me. l thought l was
invited up here to admire the view.
l feel one of us should answer it.
Hello? Yes, l know.
He's here now.
l don't know what happened.
All right. l'll try and keep him here
for a couple of hours.
All right--
l'll have to go now.
All right. l'll call you later.
You believe in living dangerously.
l can see that.
What do you mean?
Sitting around with wet hair,
you'll die of pneumonia.
-lt is rather beautiful.
-Thank you.
Do you always wear it up?
-Don't you like it that way?
-Very much.
With your sort of face,
it's wonderful.
What's going on behind my back?
Nothing.
Look, no hands.
l'm hungry. Let's go out and eat.
l'll make dinner here.
No. l'm feeling ltalian and musical.
The Blue Mountain Grill.
l'd rather stay here.
lt's more fun alone.
Yes, but l don't want you
getting dishpan hands.
l like cooking.
Forget it. May l use your phone?
Who are you ringing?
Taxi.
James Bond here.
Can l have a car sent to....
2 1 7 1 Magenta Drive?
As soon as you can, please.
Thank you.
-l thought you came by car.
-Wouldn't start. Engine trouble.
That explains--
Explains what?
Why you need a taxi.
Why l need a taxi?
Careful, my nail varnish!
-The lights.
-No, l always leave them on.
What's going on?
Forgive me.
Book her, superintendent.
And...
...be careful of her nail varnish.
Drop it, professor!
Behind you.
l thought you'd turn up
sooner or later.
Sit down.
-The girl talked.
-But of course.
l was suspicious
at the Queens Club anyhow...
...when you were the only one who'd
seen Strangways' new secretary.
Then at the lab...
...you didn't mention
that Strangways' samples...
...were radioactive.
Very clever, Mr. Bond.
You're up against
more than you know.
Shoot me, you'll end up
like Strangways.
You killed him?
He was killed,
but never mind how.
Who are you working for?
l'll tell you. You won't live to use
the information. l'm working--
lt's a Smith & Wesson...
...and you've had your six.
Better late than never.
-Everything ready?
-For the last two hours.
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
You say so.
Bottom of where my belly
used to be tells me different.
For me, Crab Key's
going to be a gentle relaxation.
-From what? Dames?
-No, from being a clay pigeon.
This is as far as we go
with the engine.
Make with paddle and wind
from now on in.
-Let me go with him.
-No. We settled that. lt's my beat.
lt's my head in the noose
if anything gets unstuck.
Canaveral can only wait
48 hours for that moon shot.
We'll be back in 1 2.
lf not, it's your beat.
You better bring
your marines with you.
Quarrel, if you see a dragon...
...you get him first
and breathe on him.
With all that rum in you,
he'll die happy.
Better drop the sail
in case their radar's on scan.
Hard about, captain. Now!
Cover it up.
We'd better get some sleep
before it gets light.
l'll be down this end.
Who is that?
lt's all right, l'm not supposed
to be here either. Are you alone?
What are you doing here?
Looking for shells?
No, l'm just looking.
Stay where you are.
-l promise l won't steal your shells.
-l promise you won't either.
-Stay where you are!
-My intentions are strictly honorable.
What's your name?
-Ryder.
-Ryder what?
Honey Ryder.
-What's so funny about it?
-Nothing. lt's a very pretty name.
What's your name?
James.
Tell me, did you use your sail
all the way up to the reef?
Of course. l always do.
Then they'll know we're here.
They have radar.
My boat is too small
to be noticed.
And l often come here
to get shells.
At first they tried to catch me,
but they couldn't .
Now l don't think
they bother anymore.
They will this time.
Don't bother with those!
Don't bother?
Are they valuable?
This one is worth $50 in Miami.
Fifty!
You promise you won't tell anyone?
l promise.
-Come and take a look!
-lt's all right. He's with me.
Captain, what do you think of that?
What's the matter?
That's a high-powered boat.
Take some cover. Come on!
They're here, all right.
Okay, folks.
Come out and you won't get hurt.
Stand up and show yourselves...
...or we'll be forced
to open fire!
Come on out!
We know you're there!
We've been expecting you.
Just walk out with your hands up
and you'll be okay.
This is your last chance.
They're bluffing,
but keep your head down.
All right! You've been warned!
-This is it!
-Lie still.
lt won't last long.
They don't know we're here.
Fire!
You coming out?
All right, then.
We'll be back!
We'll be back with the dogs!
Full speed ahead.
l told you there's
something wrong here.
That was a machine gun,
not a dragon.
There's a dragon here too.
-She's right.
-You've seen it?
Yes, l have.
He had two great, glaring eyes...
...short tail and pointed wings.
He was breathing fire.
You don't believe me, do you?
Little gal, l does.
l tell you, Mr. Bond.
Let's get out of here.
Listen, both of you.
There are no such things as dragons.
What you saw
was something that looked like one.
l'm trying to think
what it was.
How do you know there aren't ?
What do you know about animals?
Did you ever see
a mongoose dance...
...or a scorpion with sunstroke
sting itself to death...
...or a praying mantis eat her husband
after making love?
-l hate to admit it, but l haven't .
-Well, l have.
She's right.
They've gone. Honey,
you're getting out of here.
l'll get out when l'm ready,
and that's never in daylight.
This time you are, and fast.
Where's your boat?
Fetch my shoes.
Look what they've done!
lt's all your fault!
l'm sorry. l'll get you a new boat
when we get back to Kingston.
What are we going to do
with her now?
lf you like, l know a good place
where we can hide.
That'll do for a start.
Leave what you don't need. Quick!
All right, all right.
-Must we come this way?
-lt throws the dogs off the scent.
-Damn mosquitos!
-Rub water all over yourself.
lt's the salt they're after.
Quick! They's coming!
Across there!
Cut some of those reeds!
Give me the knife.
Over there.
They're coming closer.
-Quiet!
-Something's biting my foot!
lf you disturb the mud,
they'll know we're here. Get down.
Look like they're onto something.
Down. Get down.
-Why?
-Because l had to.
The guy knew his business, trailing us
after we'd let the others pass.
Let's get out of here.
Where's your hiding place?
Up there.
Come on.
You smell nicer already.
Oh, thank you.
Mr. Bond! Quick!
-What now?
-Look!
Those are dragon tracks.
Look! That's where he breathed!
You ought to get some rest
if you want to.
l stay out here and watch in case
he smells us and comes looking for us.
Right. l'll take the second watch.
We'll be out of here by midnight.
l never met a detective before.
-Are you going to arrest Dr. No?
-Someone is.
We can't have him trying
to kill everyone who comes here.
He doesn't just try.
-l'm pretty sure he killed my father.
-What do you mean?
You see, my father was
a marine zoologist.
We came to the Caribbean
for him to study seashells.
One day, he came to Crab Key,
and l never saw him again.
They said he must have drowned.
But he was too good a diver
for that to happen.
Didn't the police investigate?
What about your family?
They investigated for a long time.
Then they said,
"Missing, presumed dead."
l haven't any family.
There was only my father and me.
You're here alone?
Where did you live
before you came here?
All over the world.
The Philippines, Bali, Hawaii.
About anywhere there were shells.
You went to school somewhere.
l didn't need to.
We had an encyclopedia.
l started at " A" when l was 8,
and now l've reached "T."
l bet l know a lot more things
than you do.
Didn't anyone in Kingston help?
Well, there was this man who owned
the place where we were living.
He let me stay on for a while
without paying.
Then one night,
he came up to my room.
Well, you know.
l scratched his face, and then--
But he was stronger than l was.
What happened?
l put a black widow spider
underneath his mosquito net.
A female, and they're the worst.
lt took him a whole week to die.
Did l do wrong?
lt wouldn't do
to make a habit of it.
Do you have
a woman of your own?
Quick! Down here!
Whatever's coming,
it's coming this way.
This time, l want to see it.
And hurry!
There's less than 1 2 hours to go.
Stay where you are!
All of you!
Stay right where you are!
Okay, captain.
lf that ain't a dragon, what is it?
A dragon that runs on diesel engines.
Forget the spooks.
When it's closer, take the driver.
l'll take the headlights and the tires.
You keep safe out of sight.
Come on.
-l said to stay there.
-l was frightened.
Then get down.
Don't look.
Come on out!
Hands where we can see them!
And the dame! Quick!
Unless you want an extra navel.
Hold it. Drop that gun.
Kick it away from you.
The girl will stay where she is.
Walk towards me, hands out in front.
Come on! Hey, you!
Where do you think you're going?
Sorry we ain't got any flowers.
Come on, let's go.
Come on! Let's go.
Give me that knife!
-Leave him alone!
-Get out of the way!
Get inside!
Keep an eye on the man.
Be careful. They've been in the swamp
and they're contaminated.
Check that Geiger reading.
He's reading 95, chief.
She's 88.
Too much for the monitors.
Scrub them down but quick!
Turn around.
-Reading 72.8.
-The mud's soaked into their clothes.
All right.
Take off all their clothes.
What'll he do?
We picked up
radioactive contamination.
-Do the girl first.
-We give the orders here!
Fine, but do something about this.
Come here, you.
Here.
Use the high-temperature jets.
Full pressure.
Sixty-eight.
-She's reading 4 7.
-All right. Put the man through.
He's now clocking 40.
lt is still high.
Reading 38.
Thirty-two.
-Down to eight.
-Hold the girl. Stage three.
He's now 1 8.
He's now at eight.
-Practically zero. She's clear.
-Good. Get the man ready.
He's got a count of four.
-Check his fingernails.
-Put your hands in there.
-He's okay.
-l'll notify reception they're coming.
Decontamination here.
They're coming through now.
Come in. Come in.
You poor dears. We simply
didn't know when to expect you.
First, it was teatime yesterday,
then dinner.
lt was only a half-hour ago
we knew you were on your way.
Cigarette? There's American,
English and Turkish.
l'm Sister Rose.
This is Sister Lily.
We're here to make
your stay pleasant.
-That's kind of you, but--
-You'll be wanting to see your rooms.
Breakfast is already ordered
and then you'll want to sleep.
The doctor left orders you're
not to be disturbed until tonight.
He'd be delighted if you'd join him
for dinner. Shall l say you'll be there?
-Tell him l'll also be delighted.
-Splendid.
l know he'll be pleased.
Here we are.
This will be your room, Mr. Bond.
This is your bathroom in here.
And for you, young lady...
...this is your room.
You'll find fresh clothes in here.
l hope they fit.
We didn't get your sizes
till last night.
Ring if there's anything else
you want. Anything at all.
Such as two air tickets to London?
l'll leave you two dear people
in peace.
Let's have some breakfast.
-How can you eat at a time like this?
-Because l'm hungry.
We don't know when we'll get
a chance to eat again.
Here. Take this.
Careful. The whole place
is probably wired for sound.
Have you--
Have you any idea
what they'll do with us?
No idea.
No door handles
or windows either.
-lt's a prison, then.
-Mink-lined, with first-class service.
What's the matter?
l don't feel so good.
l feel so sleepy.
Damn coffee!
How do you feel?
Sleepy.
What made us
pass out like that?
The coffee was drugged.
Time for dinner. We don't want
to keep the doctor waiting.
That would never do. Ready?
l suppose so.
You're doing fine.
Come on.
Am l properly dressed
for the occasion?
-Quite suitable.
-Suitable for what?
This way, please.
l'm glad your hands
are sweating too.
Of course. l'm scared too.
So be natural,
and leave all the talking to me.
ln here, please.
l hope you enjoy your dinner.
Come and look.
Artificial light.
We could be hundreds of feet
beneath the sea.
Look at that. Sea tulips.
They do not grow above 200 feet.
One million dollars, Mr. Bond.
You were wondering what it cost.
As a matter of fact, l was.
Forgive my not shaking hands.
lt's awkward with these. A misfortune.
You were admiring my aquarium.
Yes. lt's quite impressive.
A unique feat of engineering.
l designed it myself.
Convex glass, 1 0 inches thick, which
accounts for the magnifying effect.
Minnows pretending they're whales.
Just like you on this island, Dr. No.
lt depends, Mr. Bond,
on which side of the glass you are.
A medium-dry martini, lemon peel.
Shaken, not stirred.
-Vodka?
-Of course.
We'll have dinner at once.
There's so much to discuss,
so little time.
Well, Dr. No, you haven't
done badly, considering.
A handicap is what you make of it.
l was the unwanted child
of a German missionary...
...and a Chinese girl
of good family.
Yet l became treasurer of the most
powerful criminal society in China.
lt's rare for the tongs to trust anyone
who isn't completely Chinese.
l doubt they should do so again.
l escaped to America with 1 0 million
of their dollars in gold.
That's how you financed
this operation.
lt was a good idea
to use atomic power.
l'm glad you can handle it properly.
l'd hate to think your decontamination
chamber wasn't effective.
My work has given me
a unique knowledge of radioactivity...
...but not without costs,
as you see.
Your power source had our
organization puzzled for some time.
They are still puzzled.
Not any longer.
l sent a complete report.
You've not contacted headquarters
since you requested a Geiger counter.
There are so many files
open on you already.
Our own, the ClA's ...
...the one from the tong society
that you robbed.
When trouble comes, you'll find
this is a very small and naked island.
An expendable little island.
When my mission in Crab Key
is done, l destroy it and move on.
But the habit of inquiry
is persistent.
l see you're wondering why,
where, when.
l only gratify your curiosity
because you're the one man l've met...
...capable of appreciating
what l've done...
...and keeping it to himself.
Just a minute.
No point in involving the girl.
She has nothing to do with us.
Let her go free.
She'll promise not to talk.
-No, l'm staying with you.
-l don't want you here.
l agree this is no place for the girl.
Take her away.
l'm sure the guards
will amuse her.
Let me go!
That's a Dom Perignon '55.
lt would be a pity to break it.
l prefer the '53 myself.
Clumsy effort. You disappoint me.
l'm not a fool,
so please don't treat me as one.
That table knife,
please put it back.
We can't all be geniuses,
can we?
Tell me, does toppling
American missiles...
...really compensate
for having no hands?
Missiles are only the first step
to prove our power.
"Our power" ?
With your disregard for human life,
you must be working for the East.
East, West. Points of the compass,
each as stupid as the other.
-l'm a member of SPECTRE.
-SPECTRE?
SPECTRE: "Special Executive
for Counterintelligence...
...Terrorism, Revenge, Extortion."
The four great
cornerstones of power...
...headed by the
world's greatest brains.
Correction. Criminal brains.
The successful criminal brain
is always superior. lt has to be.
Why become criminal?
l'm sure the West would welcome
a scientist of your caliber.
The Americans are fools.
l offered my services, they refused.
So did the East. Now they can
both pay for their mistake.
World domination.
That same old dream.
Our asylums are full of people
who think they're Napoleon or God.
You persist in trying to provoke me.
-l could've had you killed in the swamp.
-Why didn't you?
l thought you less stupid.
Usually when a man
gets in my way--
But you were different.
You cost me time, money, effort.
You damaged my organization
and my pride.
l was curious to see
what kind of man you were.
l thought there might
be a place for you at SPECTRE.
l'm flattered.
l'd prefer the revenge department.
My first job would be finding the man
who killed Strangways and Quarrel.
Unfortunately, l misjudged you.
You are just a stupid policeman...
...whose luck has run out.
They're waiting for you
in the control room, Dr. No.
No hurry. They won't have started
their countdown check yet.
You won't get away with it
this time.
The Americans are prepared
for any trouble.
l never fail, Mr. Bond.
What do we do with him?
Soften him up.
l haven't finished with him yet.
Have you got
new fuel elements loaded?
All ready, sir.
The roadblock is 3000 feet away,
Everyone in that area's pulled back,
No traffic allowed,
The launch area
is cleared for safety,
The only personnel within
the area are the crew,,,
,,,inside the blockhouse
and the test counter,
The alarm hasn't been given,
but the time must be near the count,
The vehicle is now at
its full weight of 2 40 tons,,,
,,,and all automatic transistors
have been put on the vehicle,
We will run up to half-power
for 30 seconds.
Control interlocks free.
Fuel elements, 1 2.5.
-Control?
-Control rod actuators operating.
Core temperature, 1 1 3.
-Converters?
-Converters standing by.
lgnition meters on.
-Radiation?
-Counters 1 2 1 , 1 41 , 1 09.
-Energy stabilizers?
-Energy steady at 0.8 megawatts.
--system of tracking stations
are plugged into Mercury Control,
Fuel elements?
Fuel elements! Where's Chang?
Chang! What are you doing?
Get on the gantry!
Hurry!
-Shut down.
-Shut down reactors!
This is where control should
make a second go or no-go decision,
This is Mercury Control,
The countdown for the--
Reactor shutdown,
temperature 22 7, falling.
-Converters off.
-Convertors off.
Radiation reading.
Radiation zero.
Shutdown procedure complete.
Reactor safe.
-Stand by.
-We'll stay on spacecraft control,,,
,,,for final countdown,
This is Mercury Control,
Check indicates
all systems are go at this time,
The countdown is now
four minutes, 30 seconds,,,
,,,and counting,
This is Mercury Control,
The spacecraft pilot, the launch,,,
,,,the tracking crew
in case of emergency,,,
,,,and even the weatherman,
have given us the word "go, "
Remain on standby.
Approximately two minutes to go.
Control rod actuators
standing by.
Converters standing by.
Synchronize radio beam for toppling.
Synchronizing radio beam
for toppling.
Radio beam synchronized
Zero in your mark now.
We will stay on Mercury Control
for final countdown,
Stand by.
Run to full power.
Fuel elements, 2 1 .
Attention, all controls.
Going into operation now.
Control has been made,
The umbilical is retracted,
All elements of progress
and operation are in good condition,,,
,,,for the flight,
We are in T-minus 1 9 seconds
and counting,
T-minus 1 5 and counting,
Ten, nine,,,
,,,eight, seven--
Stop, you fools! Shut down!
,,,two, one,,,
,,,zero,
Danger,
Blast off!
The tower has been jettisoned,
There's the rocket against
that gray sky, and it's green!
We can see the outline of the rocket,
The engines are burning,
You can hear that the roar
still sounds good and true,
lt's above the fourth tank,
lt's a very hot rocket,
You can see the flame of it
coming into clear, blue sky,,,
,,,up in the sunlight,
beginning to gleam,
Very good, steady climb,
All systems go!
Honey! Honey!
-Where's the girl l came in with?
-l don't know!
Where's the girl
they brought in with me?
-Number 1 2.
-Show me!
We've run out of fuel.
What are we going to do now?
Well, we can swim or--
Or what?
Come here.
Ahoy, Mr. Bond! Ahoy, Mr. Bond!
Well, well! What's the matter?
Do you need help?
l'm quite sure you don't .
Now that you're here,
give us a tow.
Throw us your line.