I got it.
I'm going back to the limo.
- Natalie.
- Nice to see you.
Pardon my incredulity, Natalie,
but I'm very surprised
to see you here.
Pleasantly so, of course.
I'm a little surprised to see
myself here, too, Mary Alice.
Pleasantly so, of course.
Were you here last year?
No, I wasn't invited last year.
Oh. Curious.
That must have been an accident.
Oh, do you know Libby?
No, I don't believe I do.
Libby, this is Natalie Standish.
Natalie is Reed's...
oh, is it all right to, uh...
Say that Reed got me pregnant
when I was a barhop
at your country club,
married me to avoid scandal,
spent the next 10 years
sucking the life out of me,
got bored with me, dumped me
and screwed me in court?
Sure. Go ahead.
Natalie is Reed's ex-wife.
Oh. Libby Percy Holt.
Natalie Warjecheski Standish.
Well, are you
unescorted tonight?
No, I'm with someone,
a friend, male.
Well, if the new fella comes by,
be sure and point him out to us.
Oh, I don't think
I'll have to do that.
You'll know him
when you see him.
Oh, great. Come on.
Get out of here.
Feisty little guy.
I don't care for caviar.
I make it a rule
never to eat anything
a fish deposits in a riverbed.
Right?
It's been awfully nice
meeting you...
- Dutch.
- Indeed.
Nice meeting you.
- Hi.
- How are you?
I missed you.
Hello, Natalie.
Reed Standish.
Dutch Dooley.
You look great.
I didn't expect to see you here.
I didn't expect
to see you either.
I thought you were going down
to spend some time with Doyle.
Something came up.
I have to go to London
in the morning.
How does Doyle feel about that?
Haven't been able
to reach him yet.
Well, you'll be talking to him.
You can tell him.
You haven't told him
you're not coming?
I'm sorry. Could you excuse us?
This is personal.
Where the hell
did you find him?
Look, you can call Doyle, okay?
I'm tired of doing
the dirty work for you.
I'm being very nice to you.
I gave you a house to live in
with your truck driver.
- He's not a truck driver.
- Don't interrupt.
You get a monthly check,
a house to live in,
and you get joint custody
of Doyle.
You give me a hard time,
you'll lose it all.
You wouldn't dare play fair,
would you?
I wouldn't dare lose.
Have a nice holiday.
Excuse me.
I know that what you were saying
to Natalie was personal.
I understand.
I'm involved with her now,
so this is personal, too.
You hurt her, and I'll hit you
so fucking hard,
your dog'll bleed, okay?
Nice meeting you.
I just feel weak and used.
He took you out of your life,
put you in his and took off.
I mean, you don't need him
or his house or his money
or his friends.
Make it on your own.
There's only one thing he has
that I want.
Well, what the heck would you do
with a set of tiny
little genitals?
- I'm being serious.
- I'm sorry.
He has my son.
Hello.
I'd like to speak
to Doyle Standish, please.
Oh.
Yeah. Hold on.
Doyle.
- Do you know how to knock?
- Your ma's on the phone.
Do you know how to knock?
The door was open.
It wasn't open.
It was unlocked.
Someone from any sort of decent
background would knock.
And she's not my "ma."
I don't have a "ma."
You may have a "ma."
I have a mother, okay?
Do you wanna take
the call, shithead?
I could have you written up
for profanity.
Yeah? I'm terrified.
I will have you written up.
Working in the kitchen
will be good for you, Teddy.
You can have a taste
of what your career
at Burger King will be like.
What makes you think
you're so superior?
I don't have to think.
It's sickening how much
you love yourself.
Yeah.
I guess it would be
to someone who's enrolled here
only because his father
is an employee.
At least I have a father.
- Yes?
- Doyle?
Hi, sweetheart.
What do you want?
I'm calling about Thanksgiving.
What about it?
I'd like you to come home.
For the umpteenth time,
I'll be with Dad.
Dad can't be with you, honey.
He has to go to Europe.
Um, he told me last night.
So if he's made
any plans with you,
obviously he'll have
to break them.
I... I really want you
to come home, Doyle.
So you can get my approval
of your new boyfriend?
To appease your guilt?
Look, you are old enough
to be objective
about me and your father
and to understand
why we're in
the situation we're in.
Yeah, I know. I understand.
You couldn't make it work.
If you could see both sides,
you'd know that that isn't true.
I love you, honey, and...
and I want you home.
I... I've booked you
a flight on Wednesday,
and I expect you to be on it.
Forget it! I'm not coming home
to spend a holiday with you
or the idiot you're sharing
the house with, okay?
He is not sharing
the house with me,
and he is hardly an idiot.
I love you, sweetheart.
Little trouble
on the home front?
- Aww.
- What a jerk.
You talk to your son yet?
Mm-hmm.
And?
I don't know.
I have a ticket for him.
I know he won't use it.
Do you want to go down
and get him?
He won't appreciate that.
How about if I go down?
There's no better way
for two guys
to get to know each other than to
spend a couple of days in a car.
Dutch, he doesn't
want to know you.
Well, from what I can gather,
all he wants to do is sit alone
in a room and hate people.
There's a fair amount
of truth in that.
Let me go down and get him.
I'm an interested third party.
I'm a communicator.
I'm a breakthrough kind of guy.
You know, I've handled some
pretty tough birds in my time.
And when the smoke cleared,
almost without exception...
I had a new friend.
Smells good.
I want to do this for you.
It's important.
If we're gonna be together
from now on,
I'm gonna have to have
a good relationship with Darren.
Doyle.
What do you want?
My parents wanted to know if,
since you're not going home,
you'd wanna come over
to our house for Thanksgiving.
Don't think I could handle
that much fun.
Is that a no?
That's a no.
Great. Have a nice weekend
rotting in your own
pissed-off world.
Peggy, it's me. I'm at O'Hare.
Listen, I'm flying
down to Atlanta
to pick up my girlfriend's kid
from school.
Yeah, it came up unexpectedly.
Tell Tug and Fritz
I'll be incommunicado,
they should take care
of anything that comes up.
I'll be back on Monday.
Listen, lady,
don't jerk me around, okay?
I have a letter from him saying
that he's going to pick me up.
Now give me
his number in London.
When my father finds out
that you refused to give me
his number, you're fired.
Yo.
Doyle!
Doyle?
Christ!
Dad!
Doyle?
Ohh!
Damn! Jeez. Ahh.
Ow!
Stand up.
What the hell?
I said, "Stand up"!
Hands over your head.
I don't think
you know who I am.
Ohh! Son of a...
Ow!
Give me the gun!
Give me the gun! Ahh!
No, you don't.
Sit.
I'm Dutch Dooley.
I'm a friend of your mother's.
I know she called you.
What the hell are you
beating me up for?
I feel the pain in my crotch
in my teeth.
Does campus security
know you're here?
Can you say, "I'm sorry
I hit you with a golf club,
kicked your face,
mashed your testes,
shot you twice"?
If that's too much,
a simple hello would do.
Answer my question.
You can't say that?
Of course I can say it.
I choose not to.
- Now can you?
- No.
Well, I have to shoot you.
Now, since we might be
legally related someday,
I'm gonna give you the option
of taking it on the backside.
Won't hurt as bad.
If you shoot me,
I'll have you arrested.
Well, I'll have to make it
look like an accident, then.
All right, you win.
Clearly. Now leave.
I told your mother I'd take you
home for the holidays.
I have plans.
Stay here? You gonna watch
the football game,
make a turkey sandwich
and hang yourself in the toilet?
I said I have plans.
Leave it at that. Now please go.
Waiting for your dad?
I don't have
to tell you anything.
He's not coming.
You don't know my dad,
so shut up.
I know he's in London.
Is that a fact?
We have a very big problem here.
I suppose we do.
I have a problem because
I said I'd pick you up.
And you have a problem because
the last guy that punched me
has a dent in his forehead
about the size
of my pinkie ring...
and he dribbles when he smiles.
Grab your stuff.
Listen one last time.
I'm not going anywhere
with you!
What do you like to do for fun?
Oh, you like to wiggle
and grunt. Me, too.
I like the back roads.
You know, the only thing you see
on the interstate is concrete.
You warm enough back there?
You know, I owe you an apology.
I lost my temper,
and I shouldn't have.
I was a little crazy.
I wasn't thinking
too clear, so...
I'm not 100% sure
those undershorts
I jammed in your mouth to shut
you up were clean or not.
Stop the car.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
This is only a two-lane.
That's a soft shoulder.
I said, "Stop the car."
You can't beat a Ford
for good brakes.
I'm gonna have you
prosecuted for this.
What, you mean like
in big people's court
or some school teen court
where if I'm found guilty,
I gotta roll naked in the snow
or make a bed with my teeth?
My father is one of the most
powerful men in the country.
When he hears
what you did to me,
he'll sue your working-class ass
into complete
and total destitution.
How you do you know
I'm working class?
From your cheap shoes
to your ridiculous hairstyle
to your crude vocabulary
to my mother's taste in men.
You scream it.
Huh. All right.
Is working class bad?
If you want to get into
a political discussion,
I'll shred you.
No, it's not bad.
Solid economy
needs hand workers.
Well, I used to drive
a cement truck.
My father was a bricklayer.
My mother used to work
in the laundry
at the Ponchartrain Hotel
in Detroit.
You must be very proud.
I am.
I still owe you
that shot in the ass.
You want to get it over with,
in case it's gnawing
on your mind?
You know, you might be
the toughest little whacker
in the junior high,
but in my world,
you're about as worrisome
as a cloudy day.
You got anything to say?
Me, I like to talk.
I love to talk, live to talk.
You got any amusing anecdotes?
I'm living through one
right now.
There's some truth there.
Yeah, this is a trip
we won't soon forget, huh?
You can count on it.
These are
the Cumberland Mountains.
Beautiful, aren't they?
You know what?
The more you babble,
the more you reveal yourself
as an insecure fool
who's deathly afraid
he's gonna blow his chance
at my mother.
What chance, Duncan?
My name's Doyle.
And the chance I'm referring to
has dollar signs in front of it.
A chance at your mom's money?
Bingo.
I may not look like I could
finance a trip to the zoo,
but the truth is I make
a pretty good living.
My income's a damn sight more
than your father
gives your mother to live on.
Oh, yeah, but my money doesn't
count in your neighborhood,
because I worked for it.
Working for your money
doesn't matter
in your part of the world.
It's whose crotch the doctor
yanked you out of, huh?
You're disgusting.
Fill it up, please,
unleaded, regular.
Mm-hmm.
We're gonna have some fun now.
You like fireworks?
Is that a yes, a no, a maybe?
Your testicles descending?
What?
Fireworks are illegal
in Illinois.
Yes, they are,
but this is Tennessee,
so it doesn't matter.
You're gonna detonate
this material now?
No, not here in the gas station.
Are you nuts?
Go down the road a piece.
I got M-80s.
I got dragon tongues.
I got, uh...
I don't even know what this is.
I got Jersey stinkers,
Bombay bugles,
and, for later,
I got a bag of pretzels, and
I got a deck
of racy playing cards.
Huh?
You know what?
You're like a great big,
demented child.
Ah, that was fun.
Can't beat
a good fireworks show.
Well, I guess you wanna eat.
Earl, we need
two orders of fries.
Coming right up.
Put it down here.
Thank you, darling.
Okay, sugar, what'll it be?
What won't make me vomit?
I know you're lying.
No, we're getting along great.
Ah, a few problems.
Nah, nothing serious.
Smoke bother you?
Yes.
You're asking for it so bad.
I'm not kidding.
You have no idea
how serious I can get
when I want to let somebody
have it.
Mmm.
You know, you might be able
to do some damage
to the small and exclusive group
of people that care about you...
but I don't think you could
raise a welt on my fanny.
Because, frankly, I don't care
if you live, die, or grow
mushrooms in your crack.
Get you so bad.
I don't think so.
You wanna put some money on it?
- How much?
- $5,000.
$5,000.
I bet you got it, too, huh,
in a little gilded box
under your bed.
Keep it modest. 20 bucks.
It's a bet.
Hey! Aah!
Ow!
God damn it. Aah!
Bitch! Bastard!
You little son of a bitch!
Go to hell!
I won the bet!
Yaah!
Throw one more...
throw one more,
and I'm leaving you.
Promise?
Guaranteed.
Good riddance!
Here. I'll see you at the motel
about 50 miles down the road.
Wait a minute! Stop!
I'll die!
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Shit.
You wanna close the door?
I could have frozen to death,
you asshole.
I don't think you would
have frozen, not solid, anyway.
It's not quite cold enough
for that.
Here's something you should
know about me, Dale.
I don't screw around.
You piss me off, I react.
I'm not your dad.
I'm not your grampy.
I'm not your uncle.
I'm a working-class nobody,
and I don't take crap
from kiddies.
Where's my bag?
Oh, I didn't bother
to bring it in.
I figured you for dead.
Give me the keys.
Lock up when you're through.
- Doyle!
- Whoa!
Doyle! Just what the hell
are you doing?!
Get back here!
Damn it.
Goddamn...
Doyle.
Doyle!
I never saw a thing!
It came from out of nowhere!
Doyle!
Doyle.
I think this makes us even.
You're a lucky man
you're not hurt.
Thanks.
Hey, thanks for going along
with my story.
I really appreciate it.
The kid's got
emotional problems,
and the last thing he needs
is police trouble.
Take this.
Put it towards any repairs
you might have and your time.
If it's not enough, call me.
My number's on the card, okay?
Thanks. I appreciate it.
If it wasn't for your daddy,
I'd have busted every bone
in your body.
Show's over. Go home.
Go home.
Listen, you little son of a bitch.
You could have killed somebody
with a stunt like that.
That poor bastard was on his way
home to see his family,
and because you wanna play some
kind of a spoiled-brat prank,
you put his life in jeopardy.
Now, what gives you
the right to do that, huh?
I guess
I didn't think about that.
Well, you better start thinking
about a little something else
besides your own spoiled ass.
I took on
this idiotic assignment
because I love your mother.
I gotta wonder how nuts I am.
Man, I've met some scum
in my life,
but you beat all, man.
You are absolutely worthless.
You know what?
This isn't a joke anymore.
This is a full-blown mission.
You're not gonna beat me.
I've had my head split open,
my nose mashed.
I've been kicked and beat
and left for dead,
and when I set you down
on your mama's doorstep,
you're gonna be
one whipped little puppy.
Don't flatter yourself.
Get your hands down.
I'm not taking
any more of your crap.
You touch me once more,
you'll be sorry.
You wanna go, is that it?
You want me to go?
Hell, I'd love to go.
You wanna go?
- Yeah.
- Okay, fine.
Let's see if your punch
is as big as your mouth.
Only, this time,
no sissy kicks, okay,
no geometry,
no kamikaze tricks,
no sucker punches,
just good, all-American
street fighting.
Let me show you
how to do it, all right?
Here.
Give me your little digits.
Here. That's it.
Curl your little digits,
and you wad those up in little,
bitty balls like that.
Watch your little thumbies.
Put your thumbies out here
so you don't break 'em.
Get loose. That's it.
Bend your little knees.
That's it.
Okay, let me see you
fight like a man, okay?
Now, you take the first shot.
Give me your best punch,
all right? Come on.
Come on.
Give it to me, pipsqueak.
How'd you sleep, ace?
- Okay.
- Good.
How's your face?
Fine. No problem.
Partial apology if I did
any permanent damage.
It'd take
a lot more than you got
to give me
any permanent damage.
Now, my doctor wants me to get
my cholesterol to under 1,000,
but, uh, hot cakes and bacon
on a cold day, pretty sexy.
I want you to know that I could have
hurt you a lot more than I did.
- Yeah.
- Seriously.
- I'm a high brown belt.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
I been training for three years.
Your working-class ego
can't handle a kid
of my position and standing
beating you up, can it?
My working-class ego
can handle that
and a hell of a lot more.
Are you admitting that
I could defeat you in a fight?
Why don't you shut up?
I beat you mentally.
Then I beat you physically.
You know, yesterday
you had nothing to say.
Today you're a parrot.
I'm ready here.
You know,
for a split second last night,
I sort of respected you
for how you handled the cops
and the accident,
but today I see my initial
impression is correct.
You're a clod.
And the cool part is
I could say that
and you can't
do anything about it,
'cause I can kick your butt.
Well, I won't cop to that,
but I will say this.
There's one thing I can do
that you can't.
What?
I can pay for my breakfast.
Nothing burps better than bacon.
Your water looked tasty.
You're insane.
Do you have any idea how
dangerous it is to hitchhike?
You have a high brown belt.
What are you worried about?
You're an idiot.
You got a better way
to get home?
We're not without means,
for God's sake.
We are at the moment.
We got 20 bucks.
You ever heard of a telephone?
Call my mother.
I'll call my grandfather.
You know, someday you're
gonna get into a situation
where you can't call for help.
You'll have to depend
on yourself,
and you'll let yourself down.
I'm not calling, because I
don't want your mother
to think we can't
make it home on our own.
Call it male pride,
old-fashioned, pigheaded,
working-class
pre-fax machine/car-phone,
masculine pride.
No accountants, no lawyers,
no mommies, no daddies,
no Washington lobbyist,
just a man and his wits.
Yeah, that's helpful
when you're facedown,
dead in a ditch.
That's part of it, too.
But you roll the dice,
you take what you get.
We're not doing too good here.
Excuse me.
Does that music
have to be so loud?
Thank you.
What'd you pay for them shoes?
Did you steal 'em?
I charged them.
Hmm.
See, my friend here
really wants those shoes.
Well, we're really
movin' now, huh?
It's your mother.
Come on, talk to her.
Getting hungry
for your turkey dinner?
Remember, I'm your dad.
I got a bad heart.
Dale, look at me.
Is that your most pathetic look?
This is my "death to you" look.
That's not gonna get us a ride.
Be pathetic! Try it!
Pretend that you're not gonna
get $10 million when you're 21.
You have no plan, do you?
I got a rough outline.
Actually, I'm the idiot
'cause I'm going along with it.
See?
Hands up. Try it.
Come on.
Look up. Look up.
Come on. Come on, come on,
come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Hurry. It's freezing.
All right. Oh, no.
Oh, my God.
That's it. Smile, smile.
Smile. That's it.
Smile with that face.
Attaboy, attaboy.
Oh, help us here, please.
It's pathetic.
It is really pathetic.
Beg. Help me.
Help me.
I don't have a ride.
Help me. Help me.
We have to help them.
You want a ride,
you gotta look grievous.
Huh?
Hey, kid!
We're going to Hammond.
Do you wanna come along?
Get the suitcase. Let's go.
We got a ride.
Come on, let's go.
Not too fast, but not too slow.
All right, that's it.
Wave it to her.
That's it, yeah.
You guys on vacation
or something?
We're going home to Hammond
for the holidays.
Both our families
are from there.
Oh. We're going home, too.
- You got a nice kid.
- Yeah.
So, what's the word on you two?
- How do you mean?
- Well, are you drifters?
Well, yeah. Yeah, more or less.
Yeah, I thought so.
- How about you?
- Brock?
Yeah?
Dutch wants to know what we do.
Well, I don't want to be nosy,
you know.
I was just making conversation.
It's not important.
- No.
- No, please. It's fine.
- No, tell him.
- Stop.
We're call girls.
I didn't want to say prostitute
in front of the boy.
I appreciate it.
So we were down in New Orleans
at the Superdome
for the housewares convention.
Well, we also do
a little dancing.
Naked?
Don't worry about it.
I have a little brother.
Just on top, sweetie.
So your parents know,
and they haven't disowned you?
No, not yet.
Don't you think
that's a little amazing?
Mm, not really.
I'm honest about it.
And I don't hurt anybody,
not on purpose.
You don't think
it hurts your parents?
Well, eventually,
if you live long enough,
you're bound to hurt
your parents somehow.
Yeah.
It's none of my business.
So do you get along
with your dad?
Guy's not my dad.
That's my mother's boyfriend.
I hate saying that.
It's so sick.
He's picking me up
for Thanksgiving break
'cause I go to this
private school down south.
I hate his guts.
He's trying to get to know me
'cause I think he's planning
on marrying my mother.
Is there something wrong
with that?
I'm not too crazy
about my mother to begin with,
and he's just a slob.
The less I know, the better.
Yeah, well, he seems
to be going through
a lot of shit to get you home.
It's on purpose.
See, he's got
this ridiculous plan
to drag me around
until I break.
He's got a shock coming, though.
I don't break.
Hmm.
So, what's wrong with your mom?
She divorced my dad
for starters.
Yeah, well, it takes two
to make a thing go bad.
She didn't make it work.
Hmm.
You know, maybe it's
just easier to blame her.
You know, maybe you should stop
knocking your mom so much
and try to make things
work with her.
I don't think
that's gonna happen.
But I really like
talking to you.
Well, maybe I'll come up
and visit you sometime.
That would be excellent.
Brock.
Brock, hey.
You wanna wake up
your little friend
so he can stretch his legs?
Mm.
Hey.
Hey, wake up.
You want to go for a walk?
Yeah.
Yeah. I was just
dreaming about that.
Ugh.
What time is it?
7:30.
I'll drive the next shift.
I'm fine. Could you do me
a favor, though?
Could you go inside
and get directions?
I just want to make sure
I don't get all screwed up.
Sure.
We got enough time to eat?
Yeah, yeah. You go inside,
and we'll take care of this,
and we'll meet you inside,
all right?
- Let's go, Dobie.
- Uh...
I'll come in with Brock.
Uh, no, you go ahead, babe.
I, uh... I have to get
something from my bag.
I'll meet you inside, okay?
Okay.
Bye.
Yes, yes, yes.
I lifted the toad's wallet.
Ahh!
Why?
Because it was there.
Well, I was just beginning
to feel respectable.
Let's not waste
a lot of time eating, okay?
Uh, I want to get back
in the car and keep moving.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know why you want
to keep moving.
Let me tell you
something, Dwight.
Those two gals are
a couple of pros.
You know, I got half a mind
to refuse the rest of the trip.
Do you know
what your mother would say
if she knew
what you were doing?
You refuse the ride,
I'll tell her in detail.
You know, you really are
a hypocrite, aren't you?
A couple of hookers...
couple of hookers got a set
of rockets, that's okay,
but anyone else in their station
in life is scum.
That's not true.
Well, you and I are riding
in the back seat from now on
because what that
missile twister can teach you,
you don't need to learn
till you're in prison.
I'll decide what I need to know,
and she's not like that.
She listens.
That's her job.
Shit!
My wallet!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
I can't believe it.
Believe it.
Your angel
with the dirty wings flew,
taking my wallet,
my luggage, my last cigar.
She was so understanding
about my problems.
Stuff your problems!
If you weren't such
a spoiled little worm,
such a whining little rodent,
I wouldn't have had
to come down here for you.
You asked for it,
and you got it.
- True.
- It's not my fault.
True.
Yeah, it's your mother's fault.
Why is it her fault?
Because she gave birth to you.
- And what about your mother?
- My mother's a saint.
For what, having puppies?
Oh. Oh, you want more, huh?
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I do.
Come and get it.
Chicken!
Ahh!
Ohh!
God, you're pathetic.
Here's the deal, Dobsy.
I had 200 bucks in the wallet.
- You said you were broke.
- I lied.
You dishonest, stupid jerk.
We had money all this time?
We could have been home.
Probably, but I had this plan.
- Yeah, I know.
- No, you don't know!
I know you were playing around,
stretching this whole thing out
so we could
get to know each other,
and then it blew up
in your face.
I blew it. I'm sorry.
I'm also out of ideas.
I'm just gonna sit here
and hope I get arrested
so I can get some sleep.
Call your mother.
Have her send somebody for you.
You can call, can't you?
I don't want to call.
I'm sitting here, and that's it.
You talk to your mom.
You tell her
that I said, uh, good luck.
Tell her the Dutchboy's
calling it quits.
You're dumping my mom?
I'm sparing her of a life
of this kind of misery.
She's gonna blame me.
I'll write a letter for you,
nice letter, okay? Go on.
I thought you loved her.
I've talked and talked
and talked to you
until I could puke coat hangers.
I'm me. You're you.
There's no reason on Earth
why we should spend
any more time with each other.
Okay. I just think it's really
sick that you'd cut my mom loose
because you can't
get along with me.
Why? You hate her.
Don't fret. It's okay.
She puts up with your crap,
she can handle mine.
I never said that I hated her.
No. Gee, I'm sorry.
You're "the picture's
worth a thousand words" guy.
Yeah. Now, go on. Go on.
Make your call.
Give me some peace.
I don't hate my mother
for the record.
Kiss my ass for the record!
Act like a rodent around
somebody else.
You've busted my balls.
Congratulations.
Go on.
Did she ever say
that she thinks I hate her?
Don't get it.
Hello.
Is... is Mr. Standish in?
He's sleeping. Who's this?
Mmm.
Who was it?
Some kid.
Come on.
We can make it home.
We got this far, didn't we?
- Where you going?
- Home.
How?
I'm calling your mom.
Enough of this.
Wait a minute.
It would really mean a lot to me
to not have to call
my mother for help.
You remember this?
I still owe you one.
You let me call your mom,
I forget about it.
- No dice.
- This isn't working out.
We're not masters
of the highway.
We were robbed
by homebound hookers.
Only because you fell asleep
and I got...
...horny.
You did?
Sort of.
Congratulations.
Slap it.
There you go.
See, I'm not
such a bad guy, huh?
Yeah, yeah, you are.
But I'm still going
to get you home.
We're here.
Where?
I don't know.
Well, there's got to be a...
there's gotta be a guard around
here somewhere. We'll ask him.
Get out of here.
Don't come back.
I could sue you for this.
Hey, the kid doesn't mean it.
I do so.
And you can't hit me,
'cause I'm a minor.
Hey, hey.
Hey, you okay?
Hey, I told you guys
to get out of here.
Hey, what the hell
is wrong with you?
- What the hell...
- Hey!
We don't want any trouble,
all right?
Hey! Give me my stick back.
Relax, all right?
Why don't you guys go inside
and we'll hit the road,
all right?
- Get away from him!
- Yeah, yeah.
I said leave him alone!
Al, knock it off.
You, get your pal out of here!
You're outnumbered now, boy.
Come on, you little kid.
- Hyah!
- Ohh!
Ohh.
Are you okay?
- Ooh, we're gonna get you, kid.
- Yeah.
You got me mad now.
You really got me m...
Doyle, listen to me. Listen.
I'm gonna make you
eat that gun.
All right, now you guys
really did it.
You got him angry.
Pete, let's go.
You don't have to shoot 'em.
Pete, you don't
have to shoot 'em!
You don't have
to shoot 'em, Pete.
The kid is crazy.
Don't be crazy, Pete.
Tell the voices
that you just killed somebody.
You know, that guy.
You just killed somebody!
Yeah!
Uhh! Ohh,
I just killed somebody!
He just killed somebody.
They won't listen.
Don't shoot me.
I gotta do it.
I gotta get rid of the voices!
Listen, listen,
it's the holiday season.
These guys
probably got families.
- I do!
- Yeah.
- I do! He's single.
- Why'd you say that?
Now I gotta kill
your families, too.
Calm down, Pete.
Look, forget these guys.
We'll find some nice motel
you can burn down.
Yeah, motel, lots of people.
Okay.
You guys are very lucky.
This kid hardly ever backs off
once he gets his neck up.
So long, guys.
Excuse me, but would you
please get out of here?
This isn't a warming house,
you know.
Boy has a wound on his head.
We need to use the restroom.
I'm so sorry,
but from time to time, these
road people wander in.
Excuse me.
I said out.
- Can he wash his face?
- No!
I'll go outside.
Let him use the bathroom.
Robert, you want to come over
here and help me?
Excuse us.
Excuse me. Excuse me, sir.
You're on the road?
Yeah. Why?
The boy's your son?
That's right.
We're up from Georgia
on our way to Chicago.
Lost our car. We got robbed.
- Oh, God.
- It's all right.
They'll take good care
of you here.
Who?
Well, this is a center
for displaced families.
Mike's supervisor
is on the board.
So, good luck, all right?
Don't give up.
Okay?
Have a little faith
in your father.
He's doing his best, okay?
All right. Bye-bye.
Let's go, hon.
Bye-bye.
And, uh, all our best
for a happy holiday.
Would you like
to see the wine list?
That's mine.
You can have it.
That was nice.
Jeez!
Son of a...
You have to click it.
Is there a problem?
No, no, I got it. Thanks.
Ahh, jeez.
Shh!
Trying to get some sleep here.
It's all right now. Come on.
Doyle. Switch cots with me.
Mine won't hold me.
How do you know it'll hold me?
Because I'm 15,000 cheeseburgers
ahead of you in life.
Hi.
You from Hammond?
- Chicago.
- Oh.
I'm from South Bend originally.
Came to Hammond to look
for work, me and my husband.
Lost his job in June,
worked for one of those auto
part companies that went broke.
We've been here
for about a week.
It's nice.
We was living
out of the back of our car.
That's kind of hard.
What about you?
We got here tonight.
You and your daddy?
Yeah.
Do you have a mother?
But she's not with you,
though, huh?
Where's she at, Chicago?
Yeah.
And I bet you'd like
to be with her
right now, wouldn't you?
Yes.
Yeah, I would.
It'll happen.
Hope so.
That's all any of us
in here can do.
What?
Hope.
You'd better get some sleep.
Okay.
Doyle.
While you were brushing
your teeth, I called your mom.
I told her we were
at the Holiday Inn
so she wouldn't worry.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
You know,
'cause I said I wouldn't call.
No. No, that's okay.
Good night.
Did you hear me talking?
No, not really.
I meant it.
I appreciate it.
You still gonna shoot me
in the ass?
Yes.
Good night.
That's them.
He'll be so happy to see you.
Hello, Natalie.
I'm sorry.
Were you expecting the mailman?
You take care,
the both of you, now.
Now, you call the office
first thing Monday morning.
I'll see what I can do for you.
- Doyle, happy Thanksgiving.
- I will.
- Thanks.
- Good luck.
Okay. Happy Thanksgiving.
Hey, buddy!
Surprise. Huh?
Mom.
I'm sorry.
Could you step outside?
This is a family matter.
Now, why don't you say goodbye
to your mother?
Why don't you come to my house?
We've got a lot
to talk about, huh?
I canceled
an important overseas trip
to spend this holiday with you.
No, you didn't.
I called your house,
and a lady answered.
- You lied to me.
- Don't talk to me that way.
It's true.
You make up your mind
right now, Doyle.
Are you coming with me
or are you staying here?
Your decision is final.
I'm staying here, Dad.
Ah, fine.
I want you
out of here by Monday.
Excuse me.
You wanted Natalie out by when?
Monday.
I'm sorry, I didn't quite...
I said...
Friday?
Well, she's probably gonna need
a little more time. Uh...
- How's six months sound to you?
- No problem.
And you're gonna be a little
more respectful of Natalie?
Absolutely.
And you're gonna work on being
a nice guy with your son
because he still loves you.
He's a great kid.
He doesn't deserve
having his feelings hurt
or his mind played with,
especially not by his dad.
I like him a lot.
I'm his friend,
but, see,
I'm never gonna be his father.
That's your job.
You'd better learn to do it.
Yes, sir.
Good.
Pleasure seeing you again.
Happy holidays.
- Thank yo... thank you.
- Hey.
Whoa!
I'm okay.
And here it is.
- Oh, good.
Oh, wow. Thank you, dear.
A thing of beauty.
- That looks good.
Uh, Dave...
Yeah?
Before we start,
run in the other room
and get my coat, will you?
I got something in there
for your mother.
- Right now?
- Yeah.
Can't it wait?
Well, it's something
very special.
Okay.
Move over.
Yipes!