We're back, Mother.
She's not home.
- What are you doing?
- Well...
Where's Mother?
She's at Uncle Kyung Ho's.
Why?
Aunt Myung Ran was crying.
She didn't say why.
- We bought some fruits.
- Okay.
Did Uncle Kyung Ho cheat on her?
Why would a grown-up woman cry?
Don't get in trouble by
saying something silly again.
Go change and wash yourself.
Who is this?
It's me, Myung Ran.
You didn't have to come here.
It sounded like something serious.
I just had a breakdown.
Come in.
Have a seat.
Myung Ran.
You know how I've been living.
What is this all about?
So Hee is getting married.
If Jae Ho treated you like dirt,
how long do you think you could stand it?
Myung Ran, well...
It's just the way Kyung Ho speaks.
- He doesn't treat you that way.
- All right.
I know that no one in this family...
is on my side.
No one has ever looked at
it from my perspective.
Not even Mother has.
Even when there are other people,
he yells at me and insults me.
Yet no one has ever defended me.
I've been hurt so many times.
You had to work your butt off,
but Father and Mother
recognise your efforts...
and your husband respects you.
I was always jealous of you.
What's the point of saying all this?
It's all in the past now.
- Myung Ran.
- I told him to end it.
I can't keep living this way
for the rest of my life.
You've come so far. Just
consider it as a bad habit.
See? I'm dying here,
and everyone else cares just that much.
I see.
I gave up everything...
and pretended I was an idiot,
but I don't want any of this any longer.
If I continue doing this,
my life will be so pathetic.
What did Kyung Ho say?
He didn't think I meant it.
He never takes me seriously.
So Hee is getting married.
We'll get to the paperwork
after her wedding.
So Hee doesn't take it seriously, either.
Do you see?
No one takes me seriously.
His father gave his apartment to him...
before he passed away.
I see.
He even has a small commercial building.
The rent isn't apparently very high,
but it's still better than
working as a salary-man.
Of course.
If So Hee continues working,
they'll be very well-off.
No one can predict the future,
but he seemed nice.
I should trust him. What can I do?
Of course. It's up to So Hee now.
Leave it up to her.
They've known each other for a long time.
That's a good thing.
Don't you know?
Even if you've been apart for decades,
you can always catch up with
your old friends very fast.
That's right.
They insisted that they were just friends,
but I knew there was something going on.
They went from friends to lovers.
He should meet Father and Mother, too.
Of course.
Have you told them?
I'm going to tell them on my way home.
All right.
We have so many things to celebrate.
That's right.
Should I try making pork and kimchi rice?
You should always remember
Hye Kyung's efforts.
She prepared three meals
a day all year around.
After breakfast,
you think about what to make for
lunch while washing the dishes.
After lunch,
you think about what to make for dinner.
We spend all our lives eating.
We spend our lives sleeping, too.
For the rest of the time, we
worry about our children.
Life is nothing special after all.
We spend all our lives fretting,
thinking life is something special.
Still, Min Ho is having a baby at his age.
Your life is a success.
You're right. I do hope I'll get to...
see the baby.
It'll be all right. Soo Mi is strong.
You're right. I hope so.
What are you doing?
They're fresh. Dad should eat
them raw while they're fresh.
They're for you.
You're making me octopus soup.
How's Aunt Myung Ran?
I'm not sure. She seemed determined.
What happened?
I didn't even ask because
it was so obvious.
They'll get the paperwork
done after So Hee's wedding.
Did Uncle Kyung Ho agree?
So Hee and Kyung Ho don't
take it seriously...
which upsets Myung Ran even more.
She's put up with him all her life.
There's not even much time left.
It's a silver divorce. I understand her.
Uncle Kyung Ho is the
worst kind of husband.
She should have set things
straight in the beginning.
My goodness.
If they're getting married this
September, you must be busy.
We are. We should start by
deciding whom to invite.
We're not going to do like you did.
We're going to invite as
many guests as possible.
Do whatever you want.
Only invite those really close to you.
Don't invite anyone who'd
think, "Why is he inviting me?"
I'm going to invite everyone
whose wedding I attended.
That's reasonable.
Oh my. What brings you all here?
You don't have to stand up.
How have you been?
It's nice to see you.
I heard you stop by at the
kids' store from time to time.
I do.
Se Joon works too hard.
I feel bad for him.
It seems like...
they have a lot of customers, though.
I'm so proud.
That's right.
Sit down. Go back to your conversation.
- Okay.
- Well, then.
Thank you for coming here
every once in a while.
Well...
All right.
When the weather gets cooler,
I'll treat you to a dinner
at Gwangcheon Restaurant.
Okay.
All right.
It's done. Let's sit down.
Well...
- It's about Father's apartment.
- Okay.
He wants Aunt to have it later.
- Is that true?
- The whole apartment?
Of course. Would she get only a half?
I mean...
Isn't that too much?
Mother worked so hard.
Father contributed a little as well,
but Mother should take most credit.
Still...
Aunt helped Mother out a lot.
Hasn't she been rewarded enough?
She lost all of it,
but Father and Mother rewarded
her more than enough.
Father decided to do so.
We have no say in this matter.
Kyung Ho.
I do understand, but I'm
not happy about it.
Father never gave me any money for free.
It's just that Mother is
giving her apartment to Aunt.
Forget it. I won't pay Father back.
What did I tell you? I
knew this was Aunt's plan.
That's not true.
How do you know for certain?
Or was it your plan?
Aunt is Mother's only sister.
This way, Father and Mother
will be less worried about her.
In any case, this is just too much.
Call me greedy.
What's so funny? Have
you been aware of this?
I just found out. How
would I have been aware?
Then why did you laugh?
Your bingsu is melting. Eat it.
What do you need?
You should take a look at this.
Are you looking for an apartment?
You can move in here from next March.
Yu Ri's mother wants to
rent this place out to us.
She wanted to get a 130m² one,
but I told her 100m² is enough.
- I see.
- I'm considering it for Yu Ri.
Do whatever you want.
We can't do it for you anyway. We're
not in the position to butt in.
You're making him uncomfortable.
Why do you talk like that?
You don't seem happy.
Do you expect me to say,
"That's great. Live off
your mother-in-law"?
You don't have to be so stubborn
unless you feel inferior.
Once you move out, Yu Ri's mother
will give you more help than we do.
Do that. It's okay.
Thank you.
This is the first time
you've ever thanked me.
- I'll send Yu Ri down.
- It's okay. There isn't much to do.
Has she given up making them live with her?
There won't be any difference.
I lost both sons.
Men care more about their
in-laws once they get married.
Fine. I don't care.
If I was going to lose them anyway,
why did I fight so hard
against the in-laws?
Mother.
We're going on a trip for a few
days before her belly gets bigger.
Can't you wait until the
weather cools down?
She wants to go to Yongpyeong.
It's cooler there.
- With Yu Ri's mother?
- Yes.
They have a house there. It's
close to Gangneung as well.
- Go ahead. No one's stopping you.
- Okay.
We'll go out and buy some clothes
at Uncle Min Ho's store.
Okay.
I'm definitely not a saint.
Why was he so stuck up at first if
he was going to change so fast?
I can't stand him.
Why did you lock the door?
What are you doing in there?
Are you drinking?
- Hey, Myung Ran.
- I'm doing something. Wait there.
- What are you doing?
- You can't come in now.
I need to lie down.
Can't you lie down somewhere else?
Oh, right.
I completely forgot.
Hi, Min Ho.
Where are you? Are you with Mother?
I'm almost home. See you.
I stopped by at the bookstore.
I need to study.
Why didn't you ask me to come with you?
It's not far away.
You shouldn't drive alone.
Can't you be more careful?
I'm sorry. I won't do it again.
I have to stop by at the
store before dinner.
Okay.
Next time, I'll bring the price analysis.
I was going to ask you to.
I already rearranged ramyeon and snacks...
according to the data you sent me.
- Here. Drink this.
- I'm okay.
Drink this and help us more.
Do you think this will do the trick?
If we give you more than
this, we'll be punished.
We'll do our best to make
your hard work pay off.
Oh, right. We only have bananas
under the snack shelves right now.
We're going to order fruit salads as well.
Washed apples, too.
Everything's selling out so fast.
You're amazing.
We're just starting out now.
- Welcome.
- Dad.
Father.
I came to buy some ice candy.
I see.
Please come. It's that way.
Why don't you pick some out for me?
Okay. How many do you want?
- About 10 of them will be good.
- Okay.
Se Joon.
So Hee is getting married.
- Really?
- Is she marrying someone?
Yes. He already met her parents.
They'll get married in September.
She told me she didn't want to get married.
Did she say that?
Yes. She said there is
no guy she can trust.
I'm sorry, Father.
It's fine.
One is for the beach, and the other
is for when we go to the temple.
Just buy one.
I'm sick of wearing the same clothes.
I'll be sweating, so I have to change.
You should buy two as well.
I'm fine with this.
My mum will give us a lecture for
wearing the same clothes twice.
Fine. I'll buy just one.
You should go and try this on.
Let's see what suits you better.
I'll just buy this.
Please try it on. You
might feel differently.
See?
My gosh.
I'll take 2 shirts for each of us.
That's 4 shirts.
Here is my card.
I'll give you the discount
for family members.
All right.
Uncle Min Ho.
What brings you here?
We're going on a vacation
next weekend for a few days.
Is that so?
- What's that?
- Yes, Sir.
Don't charge it. I'll take care of it.
No, Uncle Min Ho. You shouldn't do that.
- It's fine.
- No, it's not.
Don't do that.
- Charge it, please.
- Hey. I can buy it for you.
Uncle Min Ho. It's fine.
I think you moved to a great place.
This place is bringing you good luck.
What?
Are you talking about
having a late grandchild?
That, too.
What about Se Hee's accident?
That also happened after they moved.
Except that.
So Hee is getting married, Mother.
What? Is she seeing someone?
Yes. She found one.
He just came to see us.
I'll introduce him to you soon.
Goodness.
This must be a lucky place indeed.
This is another great news.
So do you and Myung Ran like him?
Well, we will have to see,
but he looks fine.
He has a decent job, and he is
from a middle-income family.
One flaw is that his mother is
divorced and getting remarried,
but it's not even a flaw these days.
Myung Ran says she's glad his mother
won't give So Hee a hard time.
Is his mother going to get married again?
Yes. She's getting married
to someone in the States.
She would come back once or twice a year.
So Hee picked a great guy. Don't you think?
Gosh.
What's so bad about living
with one's in-laws?
You must feel so relieved.
It's a bit disappointing,
but I do feel relieved.
Father. You were home.
Yes. Is it night-time already?
The sun hasn't set yet.
So Hee is getting married, Jong Chul.
What did you say?
He's not wearing his hearing aid.
So Hee is getting married!
Who is doing what?
How can his hearing be this bad?
Just go to the bathroom.
- Go and get his hearing aid.
- Okay.
No.
Nothing happened.
Well... Hye Kyung.
I told them about Aunt and the apartment.
You finally told them.
Are they okay with it?
Kyung Ho complained a little
saying it's too much,
but they all agreed.
Good.
What else?
There was nothing else.
Should there be more?
So Hee is getting married.
I know that.
So Hee came by when we were out.
I see.
Myung Ran wants to divorce Kyung Ho.
What?
She says she can't stand him.
She wants a divorce.
She was crying on the phone,
so I went to see her.
She said she told Kyung Ho about it.
Didn't he say anything?
No.
He seemed happy that So
Hee is getting married.
As far as I know, she has never
mentioned divorce until now.
How can he be so indifferent?
He's totally ignoring her words.
This is why Myung Ran wants to divorce him.
Why does she want a divorce?
Why do you think? He must've yelled
at her and looked down on her...
in front of So Hee's boyfriend.
Even so, Kyung Ho does that all the time.
I thought she is used to it now.
How can you get used to
something like that?
Why are you angry at me?
I didn't do anything.
I think she made up her mind.
She looked different.
She's mad at all of us. She thinks
we just stood by and watched.
You should know that.
Myung Ran must be really upset.
I don't think they'll get divorced.
Getting divorced isn't easy.
She will forgive him soon.
- Hello?
- Myung Ran.
Hye Kyung told me...
you're angry with Kyung Ho.
I wish I was angry.
I'm not angry, Jae Ho.
You know that Kyung Ho
is just like a child.
Yelling is just his bad habit.
You've been patient with it until now.
Kyung Ho seemed fine.
He was excited about...
So Hee's marriage. He looked very happy.
Jae Ho.
Yes.
That's why I can't live with him any more.
I told him that I wanted to
divorce him for the first time.
How can he look so happy after hearing it?
It means he thinks so little of me.
That's...
He wouldn't have thought
you were being serious.
He must've thought you were just mad.
Are you saying he just didn't
care about what I said?
That's not what I meant.
Did he just ignore me then?
Myung Ran.
I don't want to speak
to his family any more.
I'll hang up.
He must've been harsh on her.
Min Ho. Where are you?
I'm at my shop.
I'm about to go home now.
What?
Yes.
I can't believe him.
He must've been so mean to her
to make her upset like that.
What happened?
Divorce?
He didn't look like he heard it at all.
That's the problem with Kyung Ho.
Even my wife is upset that Kyung
Ho looks down on her that much.
Kyung Ho clearly has a problem.
Of course. I doubt that they
will actually get divorced.
I don't think so, but Hye Kyung
said Myung Ran looked different.
She does seem different.
She hung up on me.
She says she doesn't want to speak to us.
Yes.
Right.
Okay.
Min Ho says...
we should wait and see.
What else can we do? Did you
call for a family meeting?
No.
Lie down.
I'll give you a massage.
Do it gently.
Okay.
I think her phone is on silent mode.
- When is she coming back?
- What?
Whenever she wants.
It feels weird without her.
I know.
I feel like I'm missing
one side of the wall.
Deep down,
she must resent me.
I think she does.
Ask her yourself later.
She will say she doesn't resent you at all.
I got to know what kind of person she is.
She may be resenting me,
but not you.
She thinks about you and
me in a different way.
She told me to become a decent guy...
and a decent adult.
I don't know if I can do it.
It'll be tough to meet her standards.
Let's see.
It's done.
I want to take a picture
of it and send it to her.
Sure.
I got a haircut, got it
dyed and got my nails done.
I don't even know how long that took.
I also checked out some wedding dresses.
I'm exhausted.
Okay. I'll call you later.
Sure.
I can check this one off my list.
Where's Dad?
He's not home.
I'm doomed, Mum.
I spoke to Mother earlier and she said...
it's been 10 years since they
renovated their apartment.
She wants to paint the walls,
change the bathroom tiles
and get new toilet and tub.
We're changing the curtains as well.
But she wants me to
change them to my style.
You should do it then.
I would ask Se Hee for
help if she was fine.
She has a good taste.
But with her in that condition,
I can't even bring it up.
We don't have that much time left
and Joon Woo has to go to work.
I have to do everything.
I have to call up people, get estimates...
and put them to work. It's all on me.
Did you speak to Dad after I left?
I'm not kidding...
when I said I didn't want
to live with your dad.
Women in my age...
act differently from when they were young.
As you age, you don't always have
to take care of the husband.
They have a say and go on trips overseas...
with their husband and friends.
It's okay if I don't have a say
or don't get to travel overseas.
Your dad always complains,
but it's more difficult for
me who's slow with things.
I try to do as he says, and I
never meet his expectations.
At some point, I just gave
up and lived like a fool.
I don't want to do this any more.
I was busy making ends meet that
I never took care of my parents.
Never mind.
When they went bankrupt,
your dad did take care of my parents.
I give him credit for that.
Still,
he would always call me an old wretch.
"What do you think you're doing, woman?
Be quiet."
He doesn't let me say anything...
and treats me less than a human.
I didn't know my life
would turn out this way.
I brought this upon myself, so
there's no point complaining.
It's just pathetic that I have no one...
to complain to.
I understand what you're saying.
I understand you fully.
When I was young, I thought you were
a fool, but you're truly incredible.
That's what I think now.
Fine. Dad deserves to be punished.
You should punish him so that
he never does this again.
I'll file the divorce after your wedding.
Mum, are you being serious?
Do you mean it?
That's right. Corns are in season.
- That's hot!
- Oh, dear.
Mother, we are...
so busy with our restaurant that
we never eat seasonal fruits.
Myung Ran is not so clever.
She's capable of only working
at the restaurant. My goodness.
Don't say that. She's doing
a lot of work for her age.
- I don't want it.
- Why not?
- I can't chew it properly.
- Fine.
By the way, Aunt.
We're going to eat dinner soon.
Why would you feed us this?
Just break off a piece.
This is good.
- Aunt, can I...
- Gosh, fine.
Didn't you hear Sook Ja
telling me to make enough?
I didn't.
Then...
What's going to happen to Dad?
I feel bad for him.
I understand your point of view,
but what would Dad do without you?
I can't imagine it.
What do you mean?
He has his parents and
his wonderful brothers.
I'll be pathetic without
a family of my own.
And you're worried about your dad?
You two were getting along
fine all these years.
Is this your idea of being understanding?
It'd be a different story if you
two didn't love each other.
That's not the case between you two.
What love are you talking about?
Your dad is a sadist who loves to abuse me,
and I'm the masochist who suffered
through it and lost self-respect.
Both people are mentally ill.
You don't have to be so extreme...
What if I lose it and hang myself?
What?
- Father, dinner's ready.
- Okay.
- Se Hee.
- Yes.
- Are you in a lot of pain?
- Yes, it's still there.
I don't think octopus soup tastes good.
But it even heals ill cows.
It's hot.
Thanks to Se Hee, we all
get to eat healthy food.
Yu Ri says it's not too good.
Come on, Se Hee!
It's not for the taste.
It's for your recovery.
It's so refreshing. What
is she talking about?
Let's eat. Let's eat and spring
up to our feet in the morning.
Go ahead.
- You're so cute.
- What?
- Yes.
- It's me, Soo Mi.
Congratulations, Kyung Ho.
So Hee's finally getting married.
Yes, she is. Here.
I'm coming from Mother's house. Try this.
They're corns.
- See you.
- Hey.
I need to talk to you.
What is it?
How nasty were you to your wife?
Look at what she's doing.
- What did I do?
- She wants to get a divorce!
How did you...
She was talking to Hye Kyung
on the phone and cried.
Myung Ran wasn't acting like herself.
What did you...
It's nothing. I didn't do anything wrong.
She woke up one day and was
drinking coffee I made for her...
when she exploded and
slammed the door on me.
It was all hysteria...
and she asked for a divorce out of nowhere.
Are you serious?
Are you saying you didn't do
anything wrong and she did that?
Why is this woman spreading the word?
Hey!
Don't worry. She should be fine now.
She usually lasts for 3 hours.
It's been 6 hours already.
Go inside.
Can't you be better?
How could I be better than this?
Do you think I'm scared?
So Hee.
Here are some corns.
It's the glutinous ones.
Have some corns. I got them from...
What are you doing?
Leave.
What did you say?
Didn't you hear me? I said to leave.
You must be insane. Where would I go?
I don't care where you go.
Did you think I was joking?
Don't underestimate me.
Hey, So Hee. What's wrong with your mum?
Leave, Dad.
- What?
- You did whatever you wanted...
until now, so listen to her for once.
- This punk.
- I can't help it but take her side.
Mum endured through so much,
and she didn't have any regard for
herself while taking care of you.
She wants to live without you. Let her go.
I didn't do anything wrong today!
Stop talking and leave.
No, you didn't do anything wrong.
You acted like you always do. You're right.
But the trigger went off...
while I was recollecting myself.
- Ha Myung Ran!
- Shut it.
What do you know?
What?
You said that to me thousands of times.
I get it. I'll...
Look, Kyung Ho.
You just say that you get it.
I wouldn't have lived miserably,
had it not been for you.
Miserably?
- Did I starve you or what?
- Shut it and leave.
What's gotten into you?
Can't you watch your language?
Did I beg you to live with me?
Did I say I couldn't live without you?
Fine. It's over.
Still, you can't tell me to leave.
This is my apartment.
You can do whatever you want
after So Hee gets married.
I can't live under the same
roof with you any longer.
I'm sick of your footsteps,
breaths and smell.
What if I strangle you
while you're sleeping?
I don't know what I'll do when I explode.
So just leave.
What?
Are you trying to threaten me?
My goodness.
- Why?
- Where are you going?
- I'm just going out.
- Is your mum crazy?
How can you do this?
You're the perpetrator,
and Mum is the victim.
You deserve to be punished.
Punished?
Thank you.
Do you think reading is fun?
I do.
I keep being distracted while reading.
After all, nothing remains in my head.
Every line seems new when I go back.
After repeating that a few
times, I just put away the book.
I almost never finish any book.
It must be a torture for you.
Do you know how to be a good reader?
I'm not sure. It just came naturally to me.
I've never thought about
how to be a good reader.
I hope Happiness will be smart.
Is it your phone?
- Yes, it is.
- Stay here.
It says Na Jae Hyun.
Hello.
I got cut off.
Call him back.
Later.
You don't want to be bothered.
That happens.
Wait. He has the same last
name with your husband.
What do I call his family?
He'll be Happiness's uncle.
I still don't get it.
What were we talking about by the way?
- I have no idea.
- Are you going in?
- Yes. I want to lie down.
- Sure.
Why don't you take this with you?
It's okay.
Oh, right. Na Jae Hyun.
Na is not a common last name.
Is he related to Hyun Woo?
- Yes.
- Who is it?
You're curious about all kinds of things.
I am.
Curious people are often smart.
I'm sure Happiness will be smart like you.
I hope Happiness takes after Se Hyun.
- Take some rest.
- Okay.
Ms Yoo.
Yes. Talk to me.
Someone else answered the phone.
She's my brother's wife.
Did you enjoy your spaghetti?
Yes, it was very tasty.
I ate too much.
It looked delicious. It's one
of your dad's specialities.
Ms Yoo. I don't feel as lonely as before.
That's great. I'm so proud of you.
It's all thanks to you.
No, it's because you recognised
that I care about you.
If you had rejected me,
this wouldn't have been possible.
It's all thanks to you.
That's your way to control me.
Control you?
Don't you know that has a bad connotation?
If you deliberately chose that
word as a joke, that's fine.
I'll let it slide.
Okay. Keep up the good work.
I'll talk to you again.
Bye.
Yes?
I'll make you abalone porridge tomorrow.
You're spoiling me.
I should call Uncle Min Ho and thank him.
Do that.
I hope you get better even
a tiny bit every day.
I am getting better.
Reading makes you tired.
What else would I do?
I'm grateful I didn't hurt my eyes.
It would have been terrible.
By the way,
why did you tell me those things that day?
You never did that before.
I don't know, Mum.
Leaving those two behind,
I felt somewhat proud of myself.
But then, all of a sudden,
I felt sorry for feeling that way...
after leaving you and Dad in shock.
That's why...
I wanted to flatter you.
In the intensive care unit, my
consciousness came and went.
Later, I wondered...
if my soul had foreseen the future.
Why am I so stupid?
I was just so happy.
I bragged to your dad so much.
How could you know what'd happen next?
Do I have something on my face?
It's nothing.
I wonder what your dad's doing.
Would it be a really good idea...
to get married?
Your parents weren't particularly
a happy couple, either.
How many couples stay
happy all their lives?
We might have to cut each other
some slack for our children...
or look after each other
for old time's sake.
We'll be all right.
What if we want to get a divorce?
If that's the best option,
we'll have to choose that.
Don't you think?
If you're unhappy in your marriage,
you have to get out of it.
Is that what you think?
My parents considered
each other a stranger.
They thought, "You have your
life, and I have mine."
"I'm not you, and you're not me."
"Don't try to change me the way you want."
"That's just being selfish."
Dad lived his life and Mum hers.
I was the victim.
I had to grow up alone as a result.
I understand all that, but I can't
marry you with a divorce in mind.
You don't seem to understand my point.
If you have to get a divorce,
that'd be the worst case.
My dream is...
still making a happy family.
I'm really tired of...
my dad yelling.
But come to think of it,
I find myself losing my temper so easily.
I do that especially a lot to Mum.
I hate it when Dad looks down on Mum,
but I can't say...
I've never done that to her.
I feel so bad.
I was so mean.
So Hee.
Mum must have suffered so much.
Why didn't I...
think about this before?
Honey.
Myung Ran.
We need to talk.
Ms Ha.
Honey.
That stubborn old lady.
Open the door!
Open it!
Gosh. Don't worry.
They won't get divorced
after all this time.
It means she's very upset.
Myung Ran will never be
able to divorce him.
- I'll eat my hat if she does.
- Do you think so?
She won't divorce him, right?
She used to come to work sulky,
but she became fine when Kyung
Ho said a few words to her.
She has put up with him until now...
because she is broad-minded. That
won't change. I'm not worried.
Gosh. I can't learn golf now.
That's not my fault.
Gosh. What are you talking about?
Whose fault is it then?
She said she will go through
it after we get married.
Things will be settled until then.
She's upset now, but she will
feel better after a few days.
That's what I think and hope.
I don't want to go home.
I'm such a coward. I want to avoid it.
Why is my mum home at a time like this?
The timing couldn't be worse.
- Should we get a hotel room?
- Joon Woo.
I'm not in the mood for that.
Fine.
What did my dad do?
He couldn't get any worse.
- Do you think he hit her?
- No. He wouldn't do that.
Did he pinch her?
Do you want to die?
Don't be so serious. They will be fine.
- Hello, Ji Sun?
- I heard you are getting married.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Were you asleep?
Na Young told me.
I was going to call you right away,
but I was working and I forgot about it.
I sometimes get forgetful. I'm sorry.
It's him, right? Your friend from school.
I thought so.
I knew there was something
going on between you two.
Se Hee and I knew you would marry him soon.
Please hold on, So Hee.
I have another call.
Would you?
Let's talk later then.
Bye.
Yes, Ji Il.
I was on the phone.
My aunt bought these for you as
she was coming from Jeju Island.
- This is...
- I have a meeting at 10pm.
I would ask you if I could
come inside if I had time.
I'm unlucky. Take these.
No. I'm in no position to
take something like this.
I didn't even have time to park my car.
Come on.
Don't work until too late.
- Okay.
- You sound half-hearted.
What else can I say?
"I can take care of myself"?
- When are you leaving?
- I'll know after the meeting.
- I see.
- You sound half-hearted again.
Do you even care about when I'm leaving?
That's...
Do you want me to stop
bugging you and leave?
Are you a mind reader? You're good.
Come on.
- Please tell her that I thank her.
- Sure.
Bye.
Where are the keys?
You don't know, right? Of
course, you don't know.
You never know where things are.
Open up. Open the door!
Open it now!
Do you want me to break the door?
Is that it?
Myung Ran.
Ma'am.
I need clothes to change into!
Dummy!
- Get out.
- Gosh.
- Stop acting so stupid and get out!
- Goodness!
- You might kill me with that.
- Get out if you don't want to die.
Get out, you jerk! Get out!
- Get out!
- I'm sorry. Don't get worked up.
Calm down before I call the police.
I wish I can hire someone just like Soo Mi.
If I had known, I wouldn't
have arranged their marriage.
I didn't know I was digging my own grave.
Miss Shin wouldn't be enough, right?
You just had to wake me up.
Aren't you worried?
Gosh.
What is it?
- Are you home?
- Not yet.
Your mum is crazy. We should
take her to the hospital.
She's smashing down things.
I think she lost her mind.
- She kicked me out, So Hee.
- Just leave her alone.
Where would I sleep? I have nowhere to go.
- You can sleep at your restaurant.
- My restaurant?
That's true.
Right. I can go there.
All right.
Hey. Are you just going
to sit back and watch?
Come home and do something about your mum.
Hello? So Hee?
Fine. I'm good.
Do what you have to do. Darn it.
- Stop. It's too much.
- I'll put a little bit more.
It won't taste good if you
put too much. Stop it.
Do you want me to throw this away?
I told you not to make too much.
Just hold still.
He eats anything I make for him.
He says it's hard to eat
everything to please you.
- Really?
- Stop feeding him too much.
Gosh. That's so nice of him.
Did he eat it for me?
- Se Joon.
- Yes. I'm coming.
- Hurry up and come out.
- I'm here.
- You should eat it while it's hot.
- Okay.
Take a seat.
Don't try hard to please me.
Eat as much as you want.
It's okay.
Okay, Mother.
- Mum.
- Yes. I'll have only one glass.
How was today, Se Joon?
- Yes. It was good.
- Gosh. I told you not to do that.
- Let's drink.
- Okay.
- Cheers.
- Let's go!
- Eat this.
- Okay.
- Mum. Let him eat on his own.
- All right.
How is it? Is it good?
Se Joon. My friend said...
travelling to South America is tiring.
I heard it's over 30 hours of flight.
Yes. Even if it's a direct flight,
it takes 25 hours in the air.
It's 30 hours including the waiting time.
Exactly. Don't you think it's too much?
How's the security there?
Why don't you start with Asia?
You can start off somewhere close.
Mum.
Why are you worrying about it already?
And it's not something
for you to worry about.
I know, but I'm...
still worried.
Travelling alone might sound easy.
But why would you do it?
I still don't understand, Se Joon.
I know. My parents said the same thing.
They still probably think the same.
It's been his dream since middle school.
Nobody can stop him.
The only way to stop him...
is for you to get pregnant with triplets.
- What?
- Sorry?
The phone is turned off. Please
leave a message after the beep.
Let's talk first, Myung Ran.
Let's talk it out.
I still don't know why you're acting...
like this all of a sudden,
but let's try to communicate.
(Let's try to communicate.)
I'm scared that something
bizarre is going on...
in your brain.
Let's go to the hospital tomorrow
to get your brain scanned.
Who is it?
It's me. Sleep.
What is it, Mum?
I'm going to sleep next to you.
Let's go to bed.
Medical school is so arduous...
that she struggled so much with it.
And we never pressured
her to become a doctor.
Yes.
The fact that parents force
their kids into a profession...
is to satisfy their desires.
Being a nurse is such a great occupation.
When I see So Hee,
she's so agile and detailed.
I think it's a perfect job for her.
Thank you for your compliment.
She comes from a big family.
So Hee is not impolite or impudent.
She's not selfish.
I heard that from Joon Woo. He
told so much about it already.
Young women are only concerned
about themselves these days,
but she's not like them.
He likes that about her.
Yes, she'll never stab somebody's back.
I know she'll try her best
with everything she does.
I'm just thankful that she
agreed to get married to him.
On top of that, she is such a good girl.
I must be so lucky.
You're so generous to say that.
My late husband used to tell me that
I say things right but that's all.
Sorry?
Oh, right. You're filing a divorce?
How...
I heard that from So Hee.
She said you endured all these years
with irreconcilable differences.
You should have done it earlier.
But it's better late than never.
Life is short.
You lived through most of it.
I couldn't agree more.
Proceed with the divorce.
Yes, I'm planning to.
I appreciate your understanding.
You should visit the States
when you get a chance.
I'll introduce you to a gentleman.
Mum says you can do whatever you want.
I can't do that.
It's okay. Even if she visits Korea,
she's going to stay at hotels.
This is all ours.
It's all yours.
It's not like it's going
to be a joint ownership.
Do you want it to be? That's not difficult.
Luck is on my side.
It's not luck.
I thought I was going to die single.
For all the blind dates I went to,
I had only terrible guys.
I thought luck was never on my side.
You didn't know I was next in line.
We are going to get married now.
I don't even have to worry about in-laws.
What a good timing, too.
My mother-in-law is going to live overseas.
And everybody starts off
with debt in the beginning,
but look how lucky I am.
My fiancé is a fool, though.
A fool? Me?
Let's renovate our house
with half the budget.
This is too fancy.
I like this company.
You like this one? I like it, too.
- See you again!
- Thank you!
- One ureok maeuntang, please.
- One ureok maeuntang!
Did you enjoy your meal?
- It's for table number two.
- Yes.
- Thank you. Bye.
- Enjoy your meal.
- Hello.
- Welcome.
- Hey.
- Welcome!
- Please get them seated.
Please follow me.
Hello, Aunt.
I thought you stopped working.
Where's Myung Ran?
Well... She...
She's meeting So Hee's
future mother-in-law.
I see.
Mr Kwon. Can I have some
seasoning for maeuntang?
Sure. Seasoning for maeuntang, please!
- Sure.
- Octopus jeotgal as well.
- Octopus jeotgal as well!
- Sure.
Did I do something wrong?
Why are you not saying hi?
Do you not want to give them to me?
Should I pay for them?
No, that's not it.
What is it then?
What's the whole point of having family?
When it comes to nothing big,
you always gather around...
and create a big scene.
Why are you guys turning a blind
eye to my family's affair?
- That came out of the blue.
- Aunt.
Aunt.
Come out. Come out, Aunt.
What's he talking about?
Myung Ran asked for a divorce. She's
not coming to work for six days.
What?
Sook Ja!
Sook Ja, we have a problem!
Kyung Ho is getting divorced.
Kyung Ho is getting divorced, Jong Chul.
(That's the Way It Is)
This is so nice.
Aren't you thankful that
I'm always by your side?
Aren't you happy you got married to me?
- What brings you here?
- I'm on my way to the airport.
I'm getting transferred
faster than I expected.
It's all my fault.
I don't want to deal with this any more.
After So Hee gets married,
I'll file the divorce, Mother.
Your heart might be broken, but
all my organs are rotting away.
What's wrong, Mother?
- Can't you sleep here today?
- You must be crazy!
- We're getting married.
- Don't even think about it.