"Lily...
I brought you here today to ask you
a very special question".
"What is it?"
"Well, I've never felt this way
about anyone before".
"Same,
but it feels really natural".
"Yeah, same.
I feel that too".
"Now, Lily...
Will you be my girlfriend?"
"Yes.
Yes I will".
"Awesome".
"You have made me the happiest man
in the whole restaurant.
I love you".
"I love you too."
Hi.
Hello. Welcome to Meaty Boy.
I'm Lily. Can I take your order?
What?
Hello. I'm Lily. Welcome to Meaty Boy.
Can I take your order?
Ah, yeah.
Just a Mega-Meaty meal, please.
Sure. Could I interest you
in the crazy burger?
It's meat and then bread and then more
meat. It's like an inside-out burger.
- No, just the, the Meaty Meal.
- I'll just go get that for you.
Kaylee, can I've a Mega-Meaty meal.
- Okay, Lily.
- Takeaway.
- I'll just make it, okay?
Yep.
- Hi, Tony.
- Hi.
Hey, Jenny.
Thanks, Kaylee.
Okay.
Thanks very much for dining
at Meaty Boy.
Please, come back again. Bye.
What size are your...
Keep up the good work,
Meaty Girl.
Hi, I'm Jenny. Welcome to Meaty Boy.
Can I help?
Oh, no. You guys can't come over here,
because my till's broken.
Can you please, go over there?
Please, not me.
Please, not me. Please, not me.
Like I said, it's management.
They make these decisions.
Please, not me.
Sorry, Lily.
It's okay.
Okay, guys.
Let's get back to work.
Sorry it's, it's unlucky.
- You can finish up the week.
- Yep.
The shark is often
a solitary animal.
It's only social contact...
Oh, no. No.
Look, you've eaten already.
Winston's trying to eat
my fish and chips.
Cute.
Attracted from the considerable
distance by the distressed or wounded.
You are apples
I am tangerines
We're different fruit
From the same tree
That sounds really cool.
Here.
I got the idea when Winston
tried to eat my fish.
Thanks, Damon.
I like that a lot.
I'm really sorry
you lost your job.
They don't know
what they're missing.
And if Mum and Dad were alive,
they'd say the same thing as well.
Thanks, Damon.
Well, it's true.
Goodnight, Sis.
Goodnight.
Hello. I'm Lily McKinnon.
Welcome to Meaty Boy.
What would you like to eat today?
A Big Boy Burger Meal, I bet.
Yes. A Big Boy Burger Meal,
please.
Okay.
Do you want the big fries?
Ah, no.
It's free.
I'll give them to you.
The big size, free.
You'll save a dollar fifty. Free.
Okay.
Do you want cheese
on your burger?
- No, thanks.
- It, it's free too.
I'll give it to you.
You'll save sixty cents.
No, thanks. No.
Why?
It's free cheese.
Can't eat cheese.
Okay. No cheese.
Okay, I'll just go
and get that for you.
Okay, order up, Kaylee.
One Big Boy Burger Meal, please...
hold the cheese,
and one large fries.
Come on guys,
let's try and make this happen.
- You work at Screen Blasterz, eh?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I know that.
There you go.
Hey, do you know that chick,
Jenny?
Yeah, yeah. She's my best friend.
Would you be able to give her this?
It's an invitation to my party.
Oh, cool.
Yeah, it's gonna be pretty cool. You get
to dress as your favorite animal.
And there's gonna be games.
My friend has a helmet and he's gonna
let us chuck shoes at his head.
- Oh, cool.
- Yeah.
Yeah, so...
- Thanks for the fries.
- Bye.
Hi, Jenny.
A guy came in today with this invitation
to give to you.
- It's for a party, for an animal party.
- An animal party?
Yeah. You go dressed
as your favorite animal.
Think it's gonna be really cool.
Do you think there's any potential way
that I could come with you?
Oh, yeah. Cool.
That sounds really cool.
Dick.
Cool costumes.
- Thanks.
- I'm Duncan.
- Hi.
Can you guess what I am?
- Snake?
- Yes.
Hey, Jarrod.
This is Jarrod.
He's my flatmate.
- Hi.
- Who are you guys?
- I'm Lily.
- She gave you free fries.
- Damon.
Oh, yeah.
- I got some free fries.
- Cool.
Oh, yeah. I told you, eh?
Yeah, you told me.
Where's that chick, Jenny?
Why isn't she here?
She's a lesbian.
She went to a lesbian party.
- Typical.
- Awesome.
Oh, well.
It's getting too crowded here, anyway.
I like your costume.
Thanks.
It's pretty much
the second-best outfit here.
So, your favorite animal
is a shark?
- Yep.
- Pretty cool.
I almost came as a shark,
actually...
but then I realized that
an eagle is slightly better.
- What are you supposed to be?
- Tarantula.
- Seven o'clock, Jarrod.
- Okay, let's do this thing.
- What's happening?
- It's the Fight Man competition. Come on.
- Cool.
- It's neat.
It's a knockout tournament.
The finalist gets to fight Jarrod.
But you most probably won't win.
He's the undefeated champion.
You guys competing?
Um, yep.
- You?
- Oh, no. I'm just a spectator.
What's your combat name?
What?
You know, you're combat name
for when you're competing.
Jarrod, he's the Eagle Lord.
And I'm Blaze.
Mine's...
The Dangerous Person.
Okay.
Fight Man.
Hi, everyone. Welcome
to the second annual Fight...
third annual Fight Man competition.
First up we have Valkyrieblood
and the Ice Elf Queen.
Let's fight, man.
Fight.
Victory.
Tony, you're up.
Fight.
Destroy him.
Victory.
Next up is Dangerous Person.
Choose your destiny.
Who are you?
Fight.
Destroy her.
Outstanding.
That girl sure knows
how to play her video games, bro.
She's alright.
Victory.
That's it. Primo!
Fantastic. Flawless victory.
Fuck.
- Good stuff, Lily.
- You're good.
Okay, so that's the end of the list.
And we're into the finals now.
And Dangerous Person
will take on last year's champion...
and the year before
that's champion...
Eagle Lord.
Gidday.
Fight.
Nice.
But no cigar.
Kill her.
Victory.
You win.
Yeah.
- Awesome.
- Great.
It's time for my game.
- Impressive fighting, Dangerous Person.
- Thanks.
Where'd you learn to play
like that?
I don't know.
I guess I just got into it.
Well, you had some pretty cool moves
for someone who'd never played before.
Takes more than cool moves
to defeat a champion.
Don't forget that.
This is a plane I made.
Cool.
Guitar, emery board, fret board.
Painted eggs.
Jewellery.
Watch wallet.
Wow.
This is the area
where I make my candles.
Flame within a flame.
Conceptual.
Giant pencil.
Ancient coin.
Probably sell these
to the Muslims.
Sell this one to the Yanks.
Make a mint.
Cool.
I guess I've gotta keep creating
or I'll just die.
Wow.
So who's that Tarantula guy.
Is that your boyfriend?
Oh, no. He's my brother.
He's a cartoonist. And he's
very good at accents and impressions.
My brother's dead.
Oh, I'm sorry.
My parents are dead too.
Yeah, well...
My mum's dead as well.
How did your parents die?
Heart attacks.
Were they too fat?
Oh, no.
My Dad died when he was 72...
and then my Mum died
because she really missed him.
Yeah well...
my Mum got kicked in the head
by a cow.
Can't go near cows now because of that,
because I think about her too much.
I'm so sorry about your mum.
And your brother.
It's cool.
You're pretty beautiful.
Same.
Oh, I mean, you are too...
sort of, more handsome.
- Do you wanna kiss?
- Yep.
On the lips, though.
Yep.
Okay.
- Do you wanna have a lie-down on my bed?
- Yep.
Okay.
Do you wanna have sex?
Yep.
Sorry.
- Hello?
- Hello, is Eric there, please?
- Who's speaking?
- The Police.
Okay.
Hello?
You're fuckin' dead,
you fuckin' Samoan... fuck.
Ah, who is this? Stop...
Oh, hi.
What are you doing here?
Um, I just had a sandwich and I was,
you know, nearby.
That was some pretty good sex
last night.
Okay, well.
I'm going back to work.
Okay, bye.
- See ya.
- Ah, what are you up to tonight?
- I don't know.
I might go to a movie.
You can come if you want.
It's the new Wolverine movie.
It's got Hugh Jackman in it.
Apparently I look like him.
Gets pretty tiresome.
"Hey Jarrod,
you look like Wolverine."
Sometimes I wish I did have knives
that came out of my fists.
Anyway, it's 7:30 at Cine-saurus Rex.
If you want to come...
- You can come, I don't care.
- Yep.
Do you?
Okay. Okay. See ya.
See ya.
- Jarrod?
- Yeah?
- Eagle, eh?
- What?
Your favorite animal? Eagle?
Yeah, or cobra.
But, yeah,
pretty much eagle rules.
- Okay. See ya.
- See ya.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Yeah, so I didn't end up going
to that movie. Did you?
Yep, oh, no.
I knew it.
How did you find out where I live?
I got my flatmate
to ring up your work.
Tell them it was an emergency.
You probably shouldn't go in there.
They think you're dead.
Yeah. I had to be alone.
I got depressed about something.
I suffer from depression.
Fifty.
Break.
Yeah,
that makes me pretty intense.
I just do stuff without thinking.
What's wrong?
I need to go home.
To my hometown.
Oh, that sounds cool.
No. It's not cool.
It's necessary.
Why?
Because of my mission.
It's time to put my training
into use.
What do you have to do?
Kill a man...
probably.
- Who?
- Eric Elisi.
He's Samoan.
Why? What did he do?
Nearly ruined my life,
that's all.
He's my high school Nemesis.
He's been living in Samoa,
but I just heard from my contact...
that he's gonna be coming home
soon.
When he gets back...
guess who's gonna be forming
the welcoming party?
- You?
- You got it, girl.
What exactly
are you gonna do to him?
I'm gonna kick his Samoan arse,
that's what.
It's time to pay the piper.
He's gonna reap what he sowed
and it sure ain't corn...
or wheat.
When are you going?
That's the fuckin' point.
I can't leave!
Sorry.
I told you, I just snap sometimes.
It's my depression.
Sorry.
- Why can't you leave?
- Because I don't have any wheels.
How the hell am I gonna get there
if I got no wheels?
- On a bus?
- I'm not gonna take a damn bus.
It'll take ages. I'll get there in,
like, two weeks or something.
- Why don't you hire a car?
- Okay. Sure.
Have you got, like,
a million dollars for me?
- What about Damon?
- Who?
My brother.
Oh, yeah, sorry.
He's got a car.
He's got a Ford Laser.
Shall I ask him?
Yeah.
Damon, would it be alright
if we borrowed your car...
to take Jarrod to his hometown?
Yes.
He said yes.
I heard.
Thanks, man.
You're cool.
Horse.
Damn.
I've got fourteen now,
you've only got eight.
You're too good.
How many have you got,
Jarrod?
None.
- Horse.
- Damn.
Look, I don't even get it.
Just whenever you see a horse,
you say "horse".
And whoever in the end has
the most horses wins all the horses.
Well, no. Not so much really,
just like pretend.
Yeah well,
it's not even a real game.
I don't really want to play
this game anymore, Damon. It's dumb.
Hey, so.
What did the Samoan guy
do to you?
Damon,
that actually might be personal.
It's cool.
Him and some other guys from school
used to gang up on me.
I used to be a bit of a nerd.
Would've been okay one on one.
Even one on two...
me against two of them.
But, I'd usually have to fight, like...
eight of them.
That's awful.
Sometimes my brother would help out
and then we'd kick some serious ass.
But usually they'd find me
when I was alone...
and I'm like, " Oh okay,
now I have to fight eight of you.
Come on then, bring it on."
Anyway...
I don't really want to talk
about it.
Jarrod...
Get out of the car.
I need your clothes
and your boots and your motorcycle.
- Know who that is?
- Arnie.
- It's Arnie.
- He sounds just like him.
Hey, I bought some apples
for you guys.
Thanks.
I'll have one later.
Oh, yuk.
This is rotten.
Thanks very much
for trying to kill me, Damon.
So are you gonna introduce us?
- This is Nancy, my sister.
- Hi.
- This is Doug, her husband.
Ah, this is Dad. He's my Dad.
- This is my friend, Damon.
- Hello.
And this is Lily.
Lily's like, the best female
Fight Man player I have ever seen.
- And she's a dancer.
- Cool.
No, I'm not.
I thought you said that once.
I like your jackets and your pants.
Thanks. This is
our own label, "Awesome Apparel".
- It didn't really take off.
- Which actually makes these quite rare.
- Really?
- You wouldn't find these in any shops.
We've actually got some surplus stock
if you guys are keen... to buy anything.
Oh, yeah.
- Are you keen?
- I am.
Yeah?
Dad.
I made you this.
Thanks, Jarrod.
So where are you guys going to sleep?
There's no room in the house.
- Oh, what about my room?
- Our surplus stock's in there.
- What about Gordon's room?
- Dad's in there.
- Well, who's in his room?
- Us.
- Who's in your room?
- Zane.
Yeah, Vinny's in here.
It's not fair.
Where am I supposed to sleep?
- Pitch the tent.
- I don't want to sleep in a damn tent.
This is typical.
No one ever thinks about me.
That's because you're a loser.
You're a loser. Bitch.
- Cock hole.
- Bitch.
- Stop calling me cock hole, bitch.
Cock hole.
You're a bitch.
And you're gonna die of diabetes.
I'm twenty-eight years old.
Treat me like an adult, bitch.
Hey wow. That's you.
What? Yes.
Wow.
That's so well done.
It's okay.
My brother did it.
- What's all that stuff?
- Stuff.
More candles?
Yes. Rejects.
Ones that aren't good enough.
Hey wow.
It's a hand.
And it's pointing up.
Give me that.
Who gave you permission
to touch that?
No-one. Sorry.
How would you like it
if I went over to your place...
and just started touching
everything?
Like your books and your oven,
or your computer.
How about I just started messing around
on your computer...
and changed all the settings.
Changed your bloody
desktop picture?
I said I was sorry.
This candle was supposed to be
for my Dad, but he thought it was dumb.
Well, I think it's cool.
It's a reject.
How did your brother die?
Sorry.
He was saving a kid
from a fire at the school.
Wow.
Well...
I'll be back in a week, right?
Yep.
You need anything you just...
- give me a call, okay?
- Yeah, okay. Yep.
Thanks, Damon.
Yep.
Oh, wait.
- Safety grass.
I'll be back.
See you later.
Cock hole.
See ya. Love ya.
Done.
I like your family.
Doug and Nancy are very nice.
They're idiots.
Except for my Dad and me.
- I like them.
- Yeah, well...
they're still idiots.
This is Mason Hutchinson.
He's the best computer hacker
I know.
Gidday, Mason.
This is Lily McKinnon.
She's the best female
Fight Man player I've ever seen.
Hi.
Down to business, Mason.
Any developments?
When's the bastard getting back?
Not today, but the next day.
Tomorrow?
Yeah.
Good work.
How did you find out this information?
I asked his mum.
She lives in his house.
Good.
I'm glad he'll have someone
to wipe his arse...
when I turn him into a vegetable.
You've got pornography
on your computer screen.
Oh, Baby.
It's got a virus.
Lilies.
Go. Move.
Hi, Dad.
Hey, Zane.
You still playing guitar?
Yep, yep.
Me and Zane are in a band.
Wow.
He does the music and I dance.
Cool.
Lily plays guitar too. She's really
good. She's good at finger picking.
- Really?
- No, not really.
Just, sort of, teaching myself.
- And she's got a degree.
- No, I don't.
Hey so,
what do you your parents do?
- They're dead unfortunately.
- They're dead.
Good one, Nancy.
They had heart attacks.
Sorry, Lily.
It doesn't matter.
She's an orphan.
Like Oliver Twist.
Well, I suppose
I should say a few words.
Why?
Now we're all here I'd just like to say
that I'm really happy...
that we're all together under the same
roof. It's always great to come home.
And I'd also like to say
that this Saturday...
I'll be having a scheduled fight
with Eric Elisi.
- He's Samoan.
- Oh, yeah. He used to beat you up.
- Yeah, and me.
- Yeah, and him.
He was the toughest guy
at our school.
He used to pick on quite a few people,
actually.
Anyway...
you're all invited to attend.
It'd be great to see you there.
Thank you.
Why are you fighting him, uncle?
Well, Zane... Basically, I'm gonna
restore honor to the family name...
to your family name.
My family name is Davis.
Eh, Dad?
Yep.
Dangerous Davis back in the day.
- Yeah, I'm a Davis too.
- Yeah, well it doesn't matter, does it?
We're family.
That's what matters.
Why didn't you tell me
you had a little girl?
I don't know.
- How often do you see her?
- Not very.
- How old is she?
- Nine.
- Were you married?
- No.
What is this Crimewatch?
We met at a party, we had sex,
then a baby came out.
End of story. Finito.
How many boyfriends have you had?
Three.
Who?
Sam, Sam, another Sam,
and Raymond.
How many girlfriends
have you had?
About five.
Actually, eight.
I forgot some.
Who?
That's irrelevant.
- Lily.
- Yep.
You can hold my hand if you want.
Okay.
Good morning.
- Morning.
- Hi.
Hey.
Look at all this stuff.
How much do you reckon you'd pay...
for all this make-up?
A bag, like this?
Dunno. Maybe a hundred bucks?
No.
All this is only thirty dollars.
And,
it's dermatologically sweet as.
- Yep. But you can have it for twenty.
- Cool.
Five.
- Twenty-five dollars...
- Twenty-five.
Because you're a guest.
Combination.
Kick, punch, block,
spin, double kick.
Kick, spin...
kick, punch...
double kick.
Okay, ball.
Block.
Stick, block.
Hoop.
Through, yes!
Hi.
- Hey, Trace.
- Hi, Tracy.
Hey, Trace-meister.
Hey, let's take a break.
Good work everyone.
Who's that?
That's Tracy.
Their dead brother's fiancée,e.
- Hey, this is Lily.
- Gidday.
Hi.
She's good at sports.
Netball, darts...
- Here, Jonah, here's that tape.
- Oh, thank you, Trace.
Hey, Trace-meister.
I heard you made team captain.
Yeah, Naomi got run over
in the weekend. So, they...
- yeah...
- Oh, that's wonderful news.
- I'm so proud of you, Trace.
- Oh, thanks.
Hey, Lily.
Show them your hula hooping.
Oh, no.
I'm not really that good.
Yes, you are.
She is good.
Show them. Go on.
They want to see it.
Why'd you drop it?
Sorry.
Dad, what do you think
of my new girlfriend?
She's an artist and a musician.
Amongst other things.
She's pretty cool, eh?
I don't know.
Yeah.
- Hey, what's good to buy for girls?
- Socks.
- I don't know.
- Vitamins.
Flowers, eh?
- Chicks like flowers.
- Yes.
What kind?
I don't mind.
Doesn't matter.
Chicks, they just like flowers.
Chilly.
I have to dump you.
Okay.
My life's just too complicated.
I guess, what I'm saying is...
I gotta be alone right now.
Oh, yeah.
And I'm busy
with the revenge mission.
I'm sorry.
- I didn't know this would happen.
- Oh, it doesn't matter.
And we can still be friends,
right?
Yep.
Damn it.
I'm too complex.
Hello.
This is Bond, James Bond.
I'm away on a mission
for Her Majesty's Secret Service.
Please, leave a message.
Shaken not stirred.
Hi, Damon. It's Lily.
I might have to come back
a little bit early.
So do you mind giving me a call,
please, on 8153373?
Thanks, bye.
Hello.
This is Bond, James Bond.
I'm away on a mission
for Her Majesty's...
Hey, bitch.
Hello. Who's this?
Oh, sorry.
Hi, is Eric there please?
No, he's not back
till later tonight.
We go to the airport.
We've got a mini-van. You wanna come?
No, thanks. It's okay.
Okay.
You wanna leave a message for him?
Yes.
Could you tell him that
justice is waiting for him?
Is waiting for you. Okay, Justin.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
No, justice.
Justice.
- Hey, Tracy.
- Hi.
Can I come in?
Yeah.
There's no buses today.
They only go on Sunday's.
That's like
three whole days away.
I heard you broke up with Jarrod.
No. He broke up with me.
Did he?
Would...
do you wanna go out with me?
No, thanks.
Yeah well, I wasn't even serious.
I was...
I was joking and you fell for it, so...
I was joking...
I was joking.
Just joking.
You fell for it.
Hello.
This is Bond, James Bond.
I'm away on a mission
for Her Majesty's Secret Service.
Fuck it.
Hi.
- I don't want to go up there.
- What?
I don't want to go up there.
Take me home, please.
That's where my Uncle Gordon died.
I thought he died in a fire.
Na.
I need to go to the toilet.
Come on then.
Come on.
There's my Dad.
Ouch.
Have you checked out
our local social scene yet?
Yeah, oh, not really.
Well, we're going to a party tomorrow
night. You can come if you want.
- Thanks, but I'm trying to go home.
- You sure?
Yeah.
Does anybody want to hear a joke?
What's the name
of the Emperor of Farts?
What?
Gaseous Maximus.
What's so funny?
- Oh, Lily just told a funny joke.
- Yeah. Where have you been?
Just hanging out with Tracy.
We've been pretty much laughing
the whole day.
Like this,
but about ten times more laughing.
Wow. That's heaps.
Excuse me.
Thank you for that very lovely dinner.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Gordon. Gordon. Gordon. Gordon.
Get out of it.
Dad, me and Tracy are going out.
I don't know how it happened,
but...
It's pretty serious.
Just thought you should know
the good news.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing. I'm asleep.
- Why don't you go sleep in the tent?
- Ah, I'm alright.
You go in the tent.
I'll sleep out here.
No, you go.
You go. You're the lady.
I can handle it.
I've got my sleeping bag. I'm good.
You don't complain about anything,
do you?
Well, there's some people in the world
who don't even have sleeping bags.
There's a weird smell down there.
I don't like it.
Think it's probably
a dead hedgehog or something.
Disgusting.
If you get cold,
you can come sleep in my tent.
But please, don't wake me up.
It's the last thing I need.
You seem to be getting on
pretty well with my family.
I told you, I like them.
Yeah, well...
don't get too close.
They'll turn on you, that's for sure.
What was that joke
you told them?
Just my favorite.
One of Damon's.
Can you tell it to me?
No.
- Oh, what are you doing?
- Nothing.
You sucker, you better watch out.
You fool.
Yeah, hey fool. Hey fool.
Sucker.
You foolish, foolish sucker.
- Better wa...
- Hello.
- Hello, is Eric there, please?
- Speaking.
Hey sucker.
Who is this?
This is the piper.
And I want to be pied.
Paid. Paid.
Who's this?
- It's Jarrod.
- Who?
- Lough.
Jarrod Lough.
We went to school together.
- Did we?
- Yes.
- I assume you got my letter.
- No. What letter?
Invitation.
- To a party?
- To a fight.
- What fight?
- Our fight.
Hold on. Hold on.
Alison!
Is there any mail for me?
Oh, yeah. There's something here.
It's a letter. Should I open it?
Yes. I'll call you back.
It's long.
- Hello.
- Hi, it's Jarrod.
- Oh, hey there, man.
- Did you read it?
- Yeah, look man. I'm sorry, you know...
- You will be sorry. You will be.
Meet me, 3 pm at the school playground.
We're gonna have a fight.
- Now look, I...
- No you look and listen.
You better be on that playground
on Saturday.
I'm gonna be there
ready to fight you.
And if you don't turn up,
everyone's gonna know you're a pussy.
- Because I'm gonna tell them, fool.
- Alright. I'll be there.
- Okay.
- Yep.
- Good.
- Alright.
That's all. See you later.
You're going too fast.
Jarrod!
Are you alright?
Help me up.
Get this bike off me.
What happened?
I had an accident.
Some chick in a Trans Am.
Reckless bitch.
- What are you guys up to?
- Nothing. Walking.
Oh, yeah.
Dad, do you want to come with me?
We could hang out and train.
Lily and I are doing something.
Okay, cool.
Well,
I'll see you guys later then.
Have a good day.
Who does he think he is?
You were right to break up
with him.
No, I didn't break up with him.
He broke up with me.
Oh well, you would've.
Given time.
- Take me away from here.
- Where?
Anywhere.
Help me escape.
Okay.
Where shall we go?
Where do you wanna go?
Home.
I wanna go home.
Oh, home's horrible.
You must wanna go somewhere else.
Dunno. Be Australia.
Na, not there.
My ex-wife lives there.
What? Is she alive?
Who cares about her?
She's a lesbian.
Okay, don't put the blade out.
Wow!
- Wow.
- Stop the press.
- We've got a fashion model in the house.
- Yeah.
- Is that the makeup you got from us?
- Yep.
- And your skin's alright?
Why?
- We were just wondering.
- Oh, nothing.
I was wondering if perhaps I could
potentially still come to that party?
Sure.
Thank you.
Is this sort of appropriate?
I just don't really have
any sort of party gears.
- Lily!
Did you have a nice time
fucking my friend Mason Hutchinson?
What?
Did you have a nice time
fucking my friend Mason Hutchinson?
Or did you do everyone
at the whole party?
I didn't do anyone.
Anyway what do you care?
You've got Tracy.
We're not even going out.
We haven't even kissed.
Could've if I wanted to,
but I've been too busy training.
Where did you sleep last night?
In the bushes.
Great. Meanwhile, I'm up all night
wondering where the hell you are.
I thought you were dead. You could've
left me a note or something.
It's easy, " Dear Jarrod,
don't wait up all night long.
I'll be sleeping in the bushes.
Thank you".
I didn't get any sleep last night
and you know it's my big day.
What am I going to tell
your brother?
"Oh, yeah. Hi, Damon,
your sister, Lily...
Na... Oh, she went to a party
and got killed.
Here's a bit of her leg,
that's all that's left.
You should be more careful
next time...
because I'm not gonna be there
to wait up for you.
Gotta go.
- Are you ready for your fight?
- Yes.
I'm gonna cut his damn head off.
Not that you'll be there.
You'll probably be off
having sex with heaps of people.
I'll think about it.
Can you remind my dad to come?
Because he might forget.
Hi, this is Michael Jackson.
- Damon, it's Lily.
- Lily.
I tried to call.
How's it going down there?
It's been pretty weird.
Do you want to come home?
I can come and get you if you like.
Oh, no, no. It's too far.
I'll just catch a bus.
You sure?
I can leave right now.
Yeah, no, no. It goes tomorrow.
I'll be home in time for tea.
I'll make your favorite...
Shepherd's Pie?
Oh, yum.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah. It's just really nice
to hear your voice.
Okay.
Well, I'm right here, okay?
- Yeah, I know.
- Well...
You have a shaggadelic day baby,
yeah!
- Do behave.
- Yeah. Bye.
Bye.
Gordon jumped off that.
Look at it, sticking up there
like a bloody tombstone.
It was so wonderful when he won.
I just wanted...
him to keep on doing better,
you know, to keep winning.
Maybe that's why he did it,
because of me.
I'll never know now.
My whole life
is a complete disaster.
You know...
life is...
full of hard bits, I think.
But...
in between the hard bits
are some...
really lovely bits.
I mean, Jarrod's a lovely bit.
Jarrod?
Yep.
Yeah.
- I just don't think you know him.
- Yes, I do. I know my family.
Better than you do.
Oh, what's Jarrod's
favorite animal then?
- A giraffe.
- No.
- An octopus.
- Well, a cheetah then.
- No.
It's an eagle.
Okay.
Or a cobra.
- Good luck, Eagle.
- What?
Eagle.
I know.
There he is.
Kick his arse!
Is this a trick?
No, it's not a trick.
Mason?
Mason? Is it? Is he tricking?
- Can you move?
- Yeah.
- Your legs.
- No.
- Can you feel anything in them?
Fuck off.
- You felt it.
- No, I didn't.
- Well, did you feel it or what?
- No.
- You screamed.
- Of course I screamed.
You hit me with fuckin' nunchucks!
- You're a cripple.
- Yeah.
He's a cripple...
I don't fuckin' believe it.
Mason. Why didn't you tell me?
- I did, kind of.
- No, you didn't.
Yeah, on the phone,
before I came here.
You said, "when I'm finished with him
he won't be able to walk".
And then I laughed.
- Is that what you meant?
- Yeah.
But I've been training.
I was gonna kick your arse.
- When did it happen?
- About a year ago.
- How?
- Accident.
What kind? Car accident?
- No.
- What kind? How did it happen?
- I was skiing in Aspen...
- Oh, shut up. I don't want to know.
- Listen...
- Shut up. I'm trying to think.
I'm sorry.
What?
- What did you say?
- Sorry.
For all the things I did.
For picking on you at school.
For... Jesus.
It was such a long time ago.
- I'm sorry.
- You ruined my life.
Jarrod!
I'll get you.
Jarrod! Cut it out.
Come here.
Leave him. He's had enough.
Hello.
- How's it going?
- Fucking terrible.
Stop following me.
Let's dance
Put on your red shoes
And do the blues
Let's dance
To the song playing on the radio
Put on your red shoes
And do the blues
Dance the blues.
It's "dance the blues",
not "do the blues".
Let's dance
Put on your red shoes
And do the blues
You're still watching me,
aren't you?
Yep.
Why don't you go away?
I don't want to.
Why?
I mean, what a loser.
Yep.
Why are you hanging around me?
You loser.
It's not worth it.
Yeah, it is.
Do you know
we've got the same mole?
What mole?
This one.
See?
I'm a loser. Aren't I?
It doesn't matter.
I have two things to say.
One...
I'm leaving tomorrow on a bus.
Two...
That could change.
Hey, Dangerous Person.
- Lilies.
- Oh, yeah.
Wow.
Horse.
- Yes.
- Damn.