In 2011, a scientist from
the University of Cambridge
William Tunstall-Pendoe
input over 3 hundred million pieces of data
into a supercomputer
in order to determine the precise date
of the single least meaningful day of
the last century
it was a peaceful day, with not much
happening of international import
except that by some strange coincidence
I managed to be born
I've been spending over 30 years
ignorantly passing through this tunnel called life
I see the same people every time when I get drunk
they tell me to get out of this tunnel
as soon as possible
and go to see the outside world
I'm Sammi
I do makeup for the dead
What
Fortunately modern Chinese culture
still has room for shrimp dumplings and shaomai
When I see them together, inseparable
I can't help but think of Romeo and Juliet
Iove and hate mixing together
So powerful!
20 please, Miss
20 my ass, never paid more than 14
Well here's a discounted package for you then
It's a set menu. Night Lovers For Two
When shrimp dumplings meets shaomai
on this honeymoon banana split
the original price was 26.8
now it's only 20 for you
because fate had us meet here
I didn't ask for a banana split
Miss, this banana is mine
Please get a new bag of shaomai for this lady
It's quarter to midnight
only 1 5 minutes to March 1st
that's when these shaomai expire
fate doesn't have to be decided by god
it's managed by our company mostly
"Table for 6"
it's a speed dating service specially
designed for singles
keep changing till you find the right one,
no 10% service charge
You shut up
Hey Miss, don't leave yet
You really need our service
You know why?.
take a look, according to our database
the women who come to convenience stores
at this time of night...
...are sad, why?.
They must be workaholics
- Of course not
- Well, even worse
no boyfriends taking care of you
it's ok to refuse me
but don't refuse fate
My first name is Seven
Last name is Eleven
Then I'm Circle K
- Hey Hey!
- don't follow me
You're a pro, perfect!
don't move! freeze!
What are you doing?.
Let me check you out first
I just want to see if it's love at first sight
According to the theory of
the psychologist professor Pandora from Harvard
the first time two people meet
if one's body temperature stays
a constant 38.6 degrees Centigrade
there is an 80% probability of love at first sight
bullshit
I don't believe in either love or marriage
Well said
Having sex without love,
living together without marriage
Either is ok with me
Alright?.
Hello? what's wrong dad?
Huh? Shenzhen?
What are you doing in Shenzhen?
Just watching her move
I can tell she's no ordinary woman
what's more she absolutely is no ordinary woman
"1 980's pop sensation"
"the Wynners"
"Kenny Bee as the Zombie""
Look at your dead looking face,
goofing around your whole life
What goofing around?.
It's my job to be a zombie
You called me urgently yesterday
I called back but your phone was off
I called your home and no one answered
Have a little common sense
I'm up to my ears in debt,
how can I turn on my cellphone?
You're kidding me?. you're in debt again?
Not me this time, it's your mother
I'm sorry, it's stepmother
We broke up seven times within two years
It's getting hard to keep her in line
Harder than raising a daughter
You deserve it
She is the most vain of all my classmates
and you picked her?
if you hadn't called her up to fix the computer
how was I supposed to make her your mom?
I didn't call her
I called her boyfriend Tommy
and she invited herself
What are you reading uncle?
Horse Racing Tips
Those tips are a scam
Here's my tips for you
I'm off now uncle
Scarlet, where are you going?
Back to home to wait for a call
Wait for me
ok! I'm going to Betting Center
Wait
What is it?.
Race 2, 3 hooks 38, 90, 12
What's Scarlet running away from this time?.
She promised a businessman Charles from Guangzhou
to hold The Wynners' 38th anniversary concert
and already spent the 500 thousand deposit
Just have the uncles come out for help
Hey! aren't you supposed to
scare people as a zombie?.
You can't just stand around
Jeez! You scared the shit outta me!
You think I didn't call them?
they all have work to do
That's right,
I just can't understand
why every one from the Wynners has work
only you could end up like this
What? Like what?
at least I stand on my own two feet
Being a zombie is
a perfectly respectable occupation
I beat three students from Hong Kong University
when I had my interview
I didn't scare those last two guys,
I'll try harder next time
Is there any point so low that
I haven't seen it with my own two eyes
and yet with millions of
Hong Kong citizens watching me
I can't make a single wrong move
for fear that I would let them down
Showtime
Hello!
Is Bee with you?.
Scarlet you stupid bitch
Not answering Mr Charles's call?
where's your wife?
Stop! freeze!
- You're at Art Capital?
- Ah!! Go!
Tell your dad to meet me
Art Capital
Was it Scarlet?
Yes! said she found knock off Wynners
Jump...
What are you doing?
They told us to jump
Who?
Roger. The fourth bird from the side
next to her is his cousin Elaine
My God, you understand bird talk now
Yes, I do understand
It's been happening a lot recently
Get them back to see Mr Charles
Yes! Don't say I didn't warn you
Wow! I can't believe we survived the fall
It's God's will that
I go to Guangzhou to chop that bitch
They are down there
The birds are pecking them
It's mutation of bird flu Dad
Thank you Roger
Daughter, I've heard there are lots of singers
staying in Art Capital hoping to be discovered
Well, your wife is "lucky" this time,
let me tell you
I'm here to chop her up
I'm heading back to Hong Kong
after I'm done! Got me?
No way! If we could just handle this concert
I could turn over a new leaf
What if those knock off Wynners get popular
I am their manager
Art Capital, please
Megan, here's my chance
If I become an actor
I could finally get close to you
Roger
I am Wen from Foshan
I graduated from the movie Yip Man
and the sequel
Hey Driver
Don't drive so Donnie Yen
Just a little more Lynn Xiong please
Hey!
We have no money
but talent and strong will
I am a policeman
weeding out the bad and
protecting the good is my sworn duty
It's Method Acting
I just turned Yip Man into a policeman
using only my imagination and a gun
but his name is still Yip Man
Fantastic
Well, I'll give you a chance
Alright, character, role, personality?
taxi driver
Ok! sit tight
This is crazy, does he has driving license?
...You two talent scouts, I could take on
it's just like flying a plane!
...ten Donnie Yens!
What are you doing?
I'm looking for singers, not circus performers
dad
What do you want?
I'm looking for my wife
Scarlet
What you said has inspired me
I'll sing a song for you
You are not the only singer here, I can sing too
manager
Go
Miss Jade! Miss Jade!
It's too dangerous here
they're just jealous of your music talent
why don't we just go home?.
I scarred my face and ran away from home
you think I'm an idiot?.
OK, dad would make me to be his CEO if I go back
but now I just need those two managers
to give me a chance
I want to sing
Bravo
why don't we invite managers home
then talk about the details?.
home my ass
hello, My Dear Lord, how are you
I almost persuaded her to come home
I am Noah and this is my ark
we are family from now on
and your business is mine
and my business is yours
don't go manager!
come on! come on!
hurry up dad, we're running out of time!
Bing, hold me tight
Yes, and you hold me tight too, Miss
guys I just wrote a song
it's called Don't Be Jealous of My Talent,
wanna hear it?.
not necessary
- Hello
- help me
where are you honey?. we are at Art Capital
you son of a bitch, you are a good troublemaker
and a great swindler
but not much of a wife
your husband got his ass kicked because of you
son of a bitch, how could those bastards find me
if you didn't lose the phone?.
bitch, I'm looking for my husband,
it's none of your fucking business
where the hell are you?.
I'm coming over to chop you up now
hey, be quiet, where are you?.
she's at Shengshi Financial Center
see me at 9AM if you don't want anything to
happen to your wife
who are you?.
I'm Charles
the boss who was cheated out of
500'000 by your wife
you leave her alone
excuse me, you two are scouts
or gangsters?.
they look like scouts, actually they are gangsters
this character has so many levels
I'm following the right person, bro
I'll drive you to chop...
there's a man!
about to crash!
dad
We can't find your mom, kid
I'm not surprised
hurry up
I can't imagine what that
Charles could do to Scarlet
why are you caring about her so much?.
when we see Charles later
we have to make the first move, stun him first
Xiaofang
it's a miracle
it can't be explained
I'm telling you
I've never believed in miracles
your father was dead
but somehow he came back to life again
I can't accept this
to prove that there are no miracles
I'm asking your dad to jump off the rooftop
OK?.
If he survives this, I'm a believer
dad
I'm warning you! I'll be really angry
if you push me away again next time
""dad almost killed you by not paying
attention""
"I saw a woman just looking like your mom,""
""so I lost my mind and ran out to the street""
"I was trying to get you
a new record on your video game""
"but I didn't only lose the game
I deleted your save as well"
"I'm so useless, no wonder your
mom left me"
it's not true
you transformed into superman when you hit the car
"you read too many comics"
it's not like that
I'm a run-away, I can't give you my address
are you on twitter?. Email?.
and them too
a man and a lady
both flew out of the car
and transformed into super heroes
Listen, Xiaofang...
Every time the Eight Heavenly Dragons
return to the mortal world
there is always a witness
since the Dragons lose their memory
from previous lives
you will be the one to pass
their secrets on in this life
At the beginning of the world,
humans were good by nature
so God sent the Eight Heavenly Dragons
to the mortal world
to protect mankind from turning to evil
but one of the Dragons called Yaksha
couldn't resist the pleasures of the mortal world
he killed the other seven Dragons
before they even knew what was happening
but Yaksha only destroyed their physical bodies
he couldn't destroy their souls
so they returned once every generation
to fight with Yaksha for revenge
unfortunately they lost every time
I hope in this life they can find a way
to dissolve this hatred
and the eight of them could reunite once again
and carry out the mission of
guiding the mortals to the path of goodness
finally he said bye bye to me, and that was it
did you record it on your cell phone?.
I want to post it on twitter for Megan Fox
No! he said this was confidential
he couldn't get involved
damn!
this crazy boy is bullshit!
their story truly inspired me
Bing, guitar
this song is called My Talent is Bullshit
how great a father's love is
hello?. Dear Lord Father
Yes! Yes! I've successfully
convinced her to come home
See you then, bye-bye
You two, you guys knocked her out
Yes
A-men
Hey, kid, you have quite the imagination
you should be an actor!
He's so good at making things up
you should encourage him to be a scriptwriter.
Such a waste
think about it, what kind of a dad are you?.
dad, he doesn't believe me
"stop lying"
even you don't believe me?. I'm not speaking to you
""reported this morning-""
""six miraculously survive car crash-
more on A4"
I can come up to talk to you today
it means we are brave and determined
Well! In a word,
I'll return the half million deposit
in five years
otherwise we die together...!
OK, you need time to think about it
I count down from five. 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
it's a deal sweetie
sweetie my ass
you are Mr. Charles now, not my dad
could you try getting into character?.
whatever
you really think this'll work?.
it works every time
didn't you lose your tour guide license
Iast time you tried to intimidate
your customers into shopping
no one would marry a woman like you
give me break, I don't believe in love or marriage
Mr. Charles is waiting for you two
Whatever, I'm not scared of you
he didn't follow the rules, he attacked us first
He thought he could get the upper hand
by striking the first blow
He will know the meaning of badass
William Shakespeare used to say
during difficult times
one can tell the real character of a person
today you dare come talk to me with empty hands
it shows bravery and determination
it proves sincerity and willpower
in a word, get me the million in five days
what?. isn't it half a million?.
I know, a million, you need time to think about it
5, 4, 3, 2...
dad?.
a pro is a pro
you can give two people a haircut at the same time
but why did you give me a Beatles cut?.
I used to be a hairstylist ten years ago
everything I have now
I got from a pair of scissors
I'm an expert at everything,
finance, real estate, trade
I want to try my hand at entertainment this year,
my first case is The Wynners
and you're telling me it can't be done?.
I'll lose my reputation if people find out
my stocks will plummet
Mr. Charles, it's not that
we don't care about your reputation
I did ask my old buddies
they are really not available, I tried my best
did you?.
- honey!
- Scarlet!
I spent all the money
there's still a handbag I didn't pay for
I know you need time to think about it
One second, OK or not?.
OK!
Let her go
Yes, boss
didn't you say you came to chop me?.
birthday cake?.
son of a...
Iet's celebrate our getting back together
for the seventh time
bastard
surprised me every...
time
I did want to chop you up, bitch
but the cake saved you
Ha...
surprised me again
surprised me too, if it wasn't for getting you out
I never would have promised
Charles to manage this concert
I am doomed this time
don't worry, one must bear
the consequences of their own actions
the worst thing is to be sold as a prostitute
plastic surgery, breast enlargement
will help get a good price
but I don't want to sell you
sell me?.
aren't we talking about her?.
- you bitch! fuck you!
- Peace, peace, peace
somebody call the police
Lord will out in 1 5 minutes
get the car ready, over!
Copy!
Lord
Bing, ask Miss Jade if she'd rather
study medicine in the US or
study law in Britain?.
Miss, My Lord has compromised already
you don't have to be CEO of the company
he only begged you to go to college,
please show some respect
did I ask you to beg her?.
Iove well, hate well
I completely felt your fatherly love from the slap
but did you feel
any filial affection from the back of my head?.
Get out
OK
I am fine
it was fine to make mistakes when you were younger
now you're grown up,
you can't make any wrong moves
wasting youth is a huge mistake,
one you have to recognize
you always make the others apologize
which woman were you with
the night my mother died?.
considering my social position now
I don't have to apologize to anybody
apologize for what?.
I feed a lot of people
I contribute to this family
and this society! I'm not like you
you are still wearing your dead mom's crappy scarf
playing that crappy music
daughters always belong to others, My Lord
don't worry My Lord, I'm with you
I will be tough and mature
have you thought about adopting me?.
what the hell are you talking about?.
Only if I lost this unfilial daughter
Oh, I see My Lord
We are getting in the car
OK
- what are you doing?.
- get in or I'll kill you
dad, Ah!
you
don't blame me
The Lord asked me to do this
Ah...! what are you doing?. Ah...
Oh My God
that kid's heavenly dragon story is true
Miss, I spent days and nights
thinking of ways to make you transform
and came up with this idea
it was to stab you
and it worked
what did you do?.
Yeah, I think it would work on you too
where are you taking me?.
scared?. you'll be free once we get the ransom
the money is not a problem
as long as you let me go
a ghost
Ieave me alone! what do you want from me?.
what are you scared of?.
I thought you were fearless?.
beat me
I'm warning you
don't you ever stop your daughter
from playing music,
you hear me?.
no matter how much money you have,
no matter how many people
you take care of out there
you have never taken care of you family
including the woman standing behind you
that makes whatever
you've done out there meaningless
You heard so many women saying they loved you
but have you ever said that to the woman you loved
You selfish bastard!
it's easy to lose one's temper
after a transformation
don't blame her, bye!
I did exactly the same thing as the others
how come I transformed into a one armed swordsman?.
even worse...a lefty
Cousin
Cousin Da Xiong
A Qiao knows you've been upset ever
since you two separated
So we came by to visit you
Why don't you just move out
since you are not happy here
"Move out?. I don't have any other
place to live"
Just rent his place
that way it's easier for you
to take care of Xiaofang
And my three daughters as well
Then he can focus on taking care of me
"Where can I get money for the rent?. "
Here! I bought some contracts from the usury
You'll get your money once you sign these papers
just sign it, make it simple!
I can't be your wife
but it's fate I become your landlady
Sign here
Here, sign here, and here, here you are
dad! dad!
"Why did you get into a fight?. ""
The kids at school beat me up
because I said you were Superman
Su...
Superman?.
Stop with the nonsense, Xiaofang
I'm not lying, my dad is Superman
Right! He's not lying. I'm telling you
his dad is a Superman
Kid, I'm with you
Let's find the taxi driver Wen right now
How are you?. Are you alright?.
You did this?. are you the driver?.
I remember your license plate
Your pained reactions
need some levels. You didn't show it
And...your blood
as for the blood, you should be spouting
Really?.
Are you getting paid for
all of this teaching you're doing?.
Horsy
Just exchanging some acting tricks,
and who are you?.
I cover this area
for extorting money. Got a problem?.
No problem, very clear, no problem
Wen
My friend is calling me, I'm off
Ok! I know this place very well,
let's see how far you can go
What's up?.
Do you remember him?.
Of course, the great screenwriter
We truly are gods...
What?. no kidding?.
- Shhh!
- Why are you dressed like this?.
So they can't recognize me
You stupid bitch
trust me, you are not going anywhere
dad, sneaking out like this isn't your style
Scarlet must have forced you
You bitch...Shh!
Shh!
I'm part of this, I'm an accomplice
dad, you gave him your word
you keep saying millions of Hong Kong citizens
are watching you
how can you break your promise
what's the big deal with Charles
if you and I work together and put on a great show
then we can settle down
huh?. immigrate to Guangzhou?.
She blinked! damn it
What?.
Her eyes are blinking
What are you doing?.
Every time she cheated on exams,
played hooky, lied
she never blinked before
she is blinking now
What are you trying to say?.
She wants to stay and seduce Charles
Impossible! no one knows her better than I do
she doesn't believe in love and marriage
I'm sorry
I had the wrong reaction
My baby! I'm so happy you found Mr. Right
but I can't find the Wynners
Don't worry, dad, it's enough to have you
and we can find people to fake the other four
fake?.
Hmm! Well. This concert
is going to have a theme, Wynners in Space
so everyone needs a mask
how can the audience tell the difference?.
Ha...! You think the audience
is as easy to fool as your dad
We can tell the audience that
the climax of the concert
Repair and Synchronization by
Syful Noa Bluebiru
is to have those spacemen take their masks off
and you take off first, dad,
and then the other four
once they take their masks off
I'll cut the power and set fire to
the stage, start chaos
After the concert is over,
Charles has nothing to say
Good idea
Get to the point
Hey...!
Right
The point is that I want to
get a chance to meet Charles
a Harvard psychology professor once said
if a man and a woman stay in a room alone
and their body temperature stays at 38.6
degrees Centigrade
there will be an 80% probability of
love at first sight
Dad, you've got to help me
It's not that I don't want to help you
but we don't have enough people
to fake the Wynners
Manager
You have to believe we all are supermen
and space supermen
It's God's will
Yeah!
Boss, why the Wynners?.
aren't they too retro?.
We are making a good image for Shengshi stock
nostalgia is the mainstream
to support a Wynners concert
will help build a positive image, understand?.
We want our money back!
Get away!
Boss!
Mr. Charles, let's shake hands, best of luck
but we will succeed even without shaking hands
Excuse me, Bee
how can you go to the concert with that haircut?.
I'll just put on a wig and
be as handsome as I used to be
You've got to be kidding
What are you up to?.
I'm up to the things that I do
before I know what you're up to
Good! I like cautious man
so what are you up to exactly?.
You cut my hair the other day
I thought you...you know...me
so I want to check your body temperature.
According to what...
the Harvard psychology professor,
Pandora once said
if a man and woman stay in a room alone
and their body temperature stays a constant 38.6
degrees Centigrade
the probability of love at first sight will be 80%
So...
you really fell for me...
fifteen years ago before I became a barber
I lead the life of an intellectual
I worked my way through Harvard's
Psychology Program through correspondence
Love at 38.6 Degree
was the essay I wrote for the entrance exam
Pandora is my pen name
and I made it all up
for those ignorant fools
After that I realized I made more money
by cutting hair than writing articles
so I decided to be a barber, understand?.
In the future,
please don't touch random womens' hair
it gives people the wrong impression
Didn't I only cut your hair that day?.
why didn't your dad misunderstand?.
I'm very sorry to leave you alone in the elevator
I should've been with you
it wouldn't be boring if I was with you
Wynners! Wynners! Wynners!
Stop looking at me like that
I don't think of myself as Juliet now
I can live without Romeo
these days you still have to work,
eat and shit even if no man wants you
that's a heroine
come on
are you screwing with me?.
I'm not! I just don't want to be screwed with
mask off!
ARE YOU READY?.
Today's masquerade
is not just for myself
but also for my dad
5!
- take it
- 4!
- what is it?.
- 3!
- I don't want my dad to be controlled by you
- 2!
1!
damn bitch! you are good
I know
Ashura! You hate Gandharva so much in this life
did you know that you sacrificed yourself
for her in a previous life?.
You should cherish your karma this time
I am able to communicate with animals
the kid is on the level
"Naga"
""Kinnara""
Yeah!
""Deva""
"Garuda"
Ah, what's up?.
Wow! The Crippled Master?.
I know, last time I lost a hand
this time, grew a leg
never once has it been normal
Let's see if you're making any progress?.
Help them!
Ok!
"Mahiraga""
Huh?. It's soft, didn't hurt at all
it's made of flour
Flour - parachute
Bee, I love you!
Grandma, you like Bee so much
you'll live forever
I love you! Ultraman!
my baby!
Huh?. free milk?.
This god is so considerate
who are you?.
You bitch
I'm no bitch
I'm Ganharva
"Ganharva"
""Ashura""
who are you?.
Sammi told me
you're the type that only thinks of themselves
so I'd be wasting my time explaining it to you
Don't leave
God! God!
You left so early last night without calling me
dad help me!
I'm doing a test on him
I think your son is Yaksha
since we are the Eight Heavenly Dragons
when we aren't busy saving people
we can find something else to do as cover,
like having a band, or playing music
to carry on the spirit of Woodstock
Iove and peace
wrong! we should be flying around
shopping for smuggled goods
Europe first and then Japan for cosmetics
with our power
we could definitely get the limited editions
You dummy, we are gods
not gaudy
millions of Hong Kong citizens are watching me
I can't afford any mistakes, right?.
Right! Not only millions, all of China now
so I say we make a Chinese Avatar
We'll beat James Cameron! Why?.
we'll do real stuff instead of special effects
You guys are not united at all
how can we find the eighth one?.
I have reasons to think the woman
in green is the eighth
Why didn't she reunite with us?.
- Why?.
- I know why
- have no idea?.
- Why?. tell me
calm down, sis
""IMPASSIONED FANS SAVED BY IMMORTALS""
what do you want?.
Iast night's concert made headlines today
so what do you think?.
Alan Tam and the band have gone already
how can we sing with just a bunch of assistants?.
they are ok
But your friend is the important one,
the goddess who saved me
I've never done business with Gods
just ask her to name a price
Hmm?. how come your ears are turning red?.
anyway you get these gods for me
Heee, he is in love with my double! Haha
one-two-three-four!
freeze!
stay away!
I've saved you seven times,
so you won't become sashimi
you just keep swimming back
just inform the whales to
stay away from the Sea of Japan
it's radioactive
We're out of money this month,
what can we do, son?.
don't worry, I'm here
I have lots of gold, here you go
I'll change the bars into cash next time, sorry
Wow! all four limbs
that was a perfect transformation
Really?.
Congratulations
Running away?.
You thieves
I ordered this handbag a long time ago
They paid for it! Not thief!
Give it back to me!
Someone call an ambulance,
we got a brain-damaged god here
What?. You got my signature last time,
and now you want an autographed photo?.
why would I carry my picture around with me?.
Hey at least I'm a god
You think I am your son?. do everything for you
This fan is crazy, got a name?.
Jackie Chan
You're dead
Forget about it, I won't make movies with you
Jackie Chan again?.
Stephen Chow
You piss off so many big bosses
you don't have a future
Ah! Stop! it hurts
""After she comes back, you have one hour"
"to tell A Qiao about all your evil deeds"
"and break up with her, the harsher the better"
Brother, the cops are everywhere
"Why make it so complicated?. ""
""Why not just kill the thieves?. "
We're better of saving than killing them
Iet them see through the veil of life and death
and become enlightened people
the most important thing is
to see through Shall I compare thee
to a summer's day?.
Thou art more lovely and more temperate
"Good poem! but what's the meaning"
Brother, are you Ok?.
I'll avenge you! I'll kill all those cops
Su Junior
Who is it?.
Doctor
Zhivago
What are you doing?.
You're losing too much blood,
anybody got type O blood serum?.
Yes! Take it!
What?. what are you doing?.
- What are you doing?.
- Giving him a blood transfusion
awesome, isn't it?.
Ieave Su Junior alone
calm him down
try to think about something else
just don't about...you know
otherwise the blood will spout out
of your thigh
Why are you saving me?.
Don't you like being thief?.
I want you to keep having fun
Right! Iet's play I'd-rather-die
Ah! it hurts
Brother
Wow, his kidney's like a sieve
change it right away!
just a minute
Yes!
use yours
Awesome!
surprised me again
calm him down again
now you can think about it
that way you won't feel any pain
Yes, I just transplanted
one of your kidneys to Su Junior
and removed a kidney stone from the other one
Stop saving me
It's alright! Let's play again
I'm not going
Go
Get ready for a face replacement! Got a face?.
Yes, doctors are kind-hearted
take mine
I don't want his face, mine is fine
Maybe he doesn't like this type
Iet's help him find his inner beauty
Well then, you don't appreciate it
No! I won't be a thief ever again, leave me alone
Su Junior
calm him down
Yeah?. You like that?.
take your time
pick one out for Su Junior
You're kidding?.
you can make him look this good?.
Alright!
Beautiful
Brother
Who are you?.
Bro, I'm your younger bro Su Junior
Ah?. what happened to you?.
Those seven oriental gods
not only stop crimes
but also save the environment
many young people are copying them
suddenly
they've become a focus of media attention
all over the world
""HOT GODS"
Come down here if you have guts
You made so much dirty money, Charles
You'll die before you can spend it all.
Come down here if you have guts
Always complaining, I'll fire all of you!
Boss, actually the spit just now...
Boss!
Look
Have you ever thought what
if you died like that just now
everything you have would be meaningless
I'm blessed and lucky all the time
And I have a friend like you, what am I afraid of?.
To people like you, everyone below you is a slave
whoever is against you is an enemy
and whoever you can benefit from is your friend
If I'm so terrible why did you save my life?.
there is no good, no bad
no rich and no poor in god's eyes
mercy is our most basic obligation
We've saved so many people in the last seven days
there are a lot just like you
they think because they have support of
the gods they are important
and as a result they become
more selfish, more careless
someone said that there was one day
that was the last century's least meaningful
because nothing important happened on that day
I don't agree, it was a nice day
Hey
Hey! Don't you leave me! Take me down!
38.6 degree
Iove at the first sight is real
I'd been drinking so much iced water the other
night, trying to reduce my body temperature
but it didn't work
I'm still feverish
Hey!
What are you doing?.
I watched The Omen again last night. It's so scary
What are you scared of?.
we watched it dozens of times
The lead in the movie
Iooks just like the woman in green the other night
It's a bit of an Omen
What do you see?.
Underwear
Omen! Nothing
Omen! Nothing!
Hey,
I just wrote a new song
It's pretty good
Give me a break, could you sing for the others?.
They all listened, you are the last one
Why did you save someone like him?.
just leave him to die
Thank you for building a school for our kids
No, they thank him
The Shengshi protests had been getting worse
until last night the Chairman Charles
announced a package of amendments to
put down the protest
In addition to raising their salaries
the company also will also invest 80%% of
their profits every year
on employee welfare
"Do you think it's a con?. "
Could you just find a pen to write it down?.
I can't understand you
""This is a con""
I see
""He is much smart than you"
Will this decision affect
the other companies?.
This is his personal business decision,
I won't do that.
I bet the stock of Shengshi will drop
profiteer
It seems your new decision
is not popular with your business associates
William Shakespeare said
The time of life is short
To spend that shortness basely
were too long
You wouldn't have said something like this before,
what changed?.
A friend of mine reminded me
Is your friend one of your business partners?.
My friend isn't a businessman
but I have learned from her values
Iike how young people nowadays
don't know how to share their success with others
As a man I am able to sense
that he is chasing after a pretty young thing
Boss, the God Imitation Competition we sponsored
has been opposed by the most of our shareholders.
Care to give it a second thought?.
Whatever! I will not change what has been decided
All the girls playing god tonight
will receive a 1 00%%% annual salary bonus!
Thank you boss
Think about it, boss
It's late, go home
Let's get out
Come out
Playing with me?. save it
the party is not over yet,
go ahead
"Your decision is helping people""
"Don't let this passion down"
"Please keep it at 38.6 degrees Centigrade"
Say something, Mr. Charles
why did you sponsor this competition?.
I hoped the young people
could imitate something good
the whole city is imitating those gods
You call me every five minutes, aren't you tired?.
I need sleep even if you don't
I know I am annoying,
but I don't know what else I can do
Could you do me a favor?.
The god came to see me the other night
but I missed her
I wanted to say to her...hello?. hello?.
Mr. Charles
""The God Imitation Competition"
GOD BE WITH YOU God Imitation Competition
I've informed them already, what else?.
Nothing
I just want to see the god
I've been busy these days
I'll tell her next time when I see her. Wow...
What are you doing?.
Why are you calling me right in front of my home?.
I, I just see that...
You don't see a thing!
Exactly
It's a feather, and it's pink
You got me
I'll tell her to see you tomorrow at sunset
For real?.
Hello!
Sorry, I'm late
It's ok, saving lives is more important
Mortals are different than immortals
we lack confidence most of the time,
that's why we drink alcohol
we can say anything after we're drunk
It seems you have a lot to tell me
Sammi and you are right
I should be straight
I fell in love with someone
at first sight
I have a letter here I've been writing for a week
Iet me read it for you
The first time I saw you,
I remember my temperature
stayed a constant 38.6 degrees Centigrade
but I didn't have much experience
and was too proud
and afraid of being hurt
To hide my feelings
I cut your hair
Are you alright?.
It's ok, keep going
When my fingers touched your hair
I felt a tingle
so I had to cut your dad's hair
to distract myself
Shakespeare said
A murderous guilt shows not itself more soon than
love that would seem hid
In the whole time I've known her
I've never found it as easy to speak with her
as I do with you
Why is that?.
I grew up an orphan
you saved me last time
it was like being with my mother,
I felt so safe with you
Mom, how should I tell Sammi my feelings?.
OK, after mom freshens up a little bit
Silly Boy! I'm not your mom
I'm your girl!
Hello?.
This is Jade! something has happened
Da Xiong's Son and my dad have been kidnapped
How did this happen?.
I have no idea
They just left behind a souvenir from the TV tower
I thought I would never
have a chance to tell you...
actually I was the god
in your office the other night
I know, I knew it a long time ago
It was a setup, otherwise
how could I have trapped all of you idiots here?.
What's on your lips?.
A Love Poison made especially for the gods
you succumbed to me like this in the last life
but you've forgotten
mortals lack self-respect
and an immortal with
a mortal's feeling even more so
I saw every one of you fell for
the ones around you
and I realized that what these mortals called love
could be better used for deception
daughter! Do you hear me?.
How did this happen?.
My shadow caught them all
do you want to meet my shadow?.
Omen! Omen!
Who are they?.
Every single time after we kill them,
they forget what to call us
why don't you help them remember clearly this time
Ha...I am the eighth dragon
you've been looking for this whole time
Yaksha
Huh?. total eight or nine?.
huh?. Yaksha is bisexual?.
So it's like Laurel and Hardy
How about showing some respect to Mr. Laurel?.
you can't just play with Hardy! Yeah!
Scarlet!
What did you do?.
I owed...you in the...past life...
You two fight over everything
even over dying
Every time you guys died and were reincarnated
I sat and waited patiently here for you to show up
figuring out a way to kill you
it was the only thing that gave me pleasure
for last eighty eight thousand
and eight hundred eighty eight lives
What are you laughing at?.
Your life is boring as hell
what are you laughing at?.
What?.
What do you mean what?.
you'll have to wait for decades
before you can kill us again
and during those years
What the hell you going to do, fool?.
He's got company! His shadow
What's the use of talking to a shadow?.
What if it's a cloudy day?.
Where are you Hardy?. Iike this?.
If we're going to die, let's put up a fight
Ok
You think you can win?.
Please be accurate! Please!
how can you fight with me
if you can't beat my shadow?.
My mom's scarf! Bing!
Got it! Miss
Stop it!
I surrender
Huh?. feel something?. hurt?.
Isn't it all very sad?. Haha!
You've met me in so many past lives
but I didn't know that
it could be so painful to love you
I see
This is not fun at all
I got you guys so easily
each life is less interesting than the last
Wait! Let me finish my last word
Even though the seven of us couldn't defeat him
in any of our past lives
but we lived and died together
in these eighty eight thousand and
eight hundred and eighty eight lives
wherever in heaven, hell or the mortal world
We can still play music together ok?.
Ok
"This is true happiness""
Scarlet
""I LOVE YOU"
Huh?. playing the friendship card?.
You've never tried this before! Haha!
This is the first time
in my life giving a hand to others
and it got broken
and it's my right hand
Thanks
Ah! it's hurt, Miss
daughter
Ya! OK, got it
I knew you've been secretly fond of me
I could be son-in-law if I can't be godson
Hey! I'm Wen from Foshan,
it's very nice to meet you in this life
See you next life
""38.6 degrees Centigrade""
Ok! See you next life
It's not over yet
Listen to me
We still have an old man and a boy to play with
Iet us see the boy kill the old man
Where'd they go?.
they can't have gone too far
Let's get down! Come on!
OK! everybody
Group suicide was a great plan, let's not waste it
Ok! Iet's roll
- OK
- Move
It's heavily polluted here
no wonder he has so much anger
Hey! We're running out of time
We have to get it done before we reincarnate
Oh!
Be quick
Well, I wanted you to kill the boy for me
You disobey me?.
Iet me strangle you to death, you old fool
Let me help you
What did you do?.
Hey?. What did you this time?.
I have no idea
I just feel that it's more comfortable
to kiss him than strangle him
don't you think so?.
Yes...yes...
Yes my ass
Don't be afraid! Iet me do it
Don't you come over! don't you come over!
What now?.
I don't know! I can't control myself!
When a woman is in love
she cares how much she can give
instead of how much she can get
It's fine that you couldn't do it this time
But next time when you meet a girl you like
please remember
that a woman's heart should be cared for
not deceived
What the hell are you doing?.
It seems she is not dead yet, and she's inside me
What are you talking about?.
I can't control myself
That woman...
Don't you listen to her!
Don't you listen to her! Listen to me!
Why?.
Why do you care
when you never listened to her in any past life?.
Are you listening to me?.
I'm so confused
Don't panic! Don't panic!
I'll get in there and kill her
There was only me in his heart
What are you doing sneaking around
trying to group suicide?.
Oh, just help him to find his conscience
His conscience is fine as always
Give me a chance Jade Emperor
They died by my hand in every life
but I never thought they would
still return with kindness
now I understand that
forgiveness is key to releasing hatred
please take my life in exchange for theirs
What?.
Have you thought it through?.
Yes, I have
coward!
I've hurt her in every on of the last
eighty eight thousand and
eight hundred eighty eight lives
I hope it won't happen again next time around
No...!
I'm not letting you die for her!
Before the concert starts,
you are going to present
with the sponsors on stage
Here's the draft, please take a look to see
if there's any changes?.
Hi
Thank you everyone, thank you Alan
Don't mention it, it was our pleasure
It couldn't have been done
if you guys didn't help Bee
Of course we support Bee
and we also want to help our niece
Niece?. who?.
It's Sammi, it was her
who put everything together
You are Sammi?.
Bee's daughter?.
Yes!
Why I have never seen you?.
I was in Hong Kong contacting all the Wynners
that's why we've never met
I'm Charles
Sammi
The Eight Heavenly Dragons
are immortals but not gods
your abilities are beyond those of human beings
but beneath those of the gods
so you can't return to heaven
until you finish your austerity observance
Yaksha decided to practice from
the beginning this time
it means that the karma between you has run out
his memories of you will cease to exist
If you want to help him,
you should keep the secret
and secretly help him to
become a good immortal again
Boss, we're starting
if I could choose
I'd rather forget a love I shared
than remember one that was forbidden
Subtitle by
Syful Noa Bluebiru