Episode 10
Who are you guys?!
Why are you doing this?
Open up!
.:: Translation and subtitles ::.
Saeed
:: SKA192 ::
vampire9253@yahoo.com
Hyeong Woo!
Wake up! Pull yourself together, Hyeong Woo!
Hyeong Woo, wake up! Please open your eyes, Hyeong Woo.
Hyeong Woo...
Save us!
Is anyone there?!
Please help us!
Hey, Beom Soo. Wake up.
What is it?
Haven't you seen your older sister?
I came back in the middle of the night so how could I see her? She should be sleeping.
I'm saying this because she's not in her room.
You older sister didn't come in yesterday night.
Huh? Really?
Ah...what is this?
Is she really falling in love with someone?
Ah, I guess she woke up early and went out somewhere. You're a heavy sleeper in the early morning.
Is that it?
Il Joo.
I was drunk yesterday.
I'm sorry.
But we're a married couple.
It's a given that we should sleep together if we're married.
I'm a man too.
Did you get-
My body isn't the only thing that's hurt.
You ripped me to shreds.
Hyeong Woo...are you awake?
Can you see me?
You're alive.
I thought you were gone...
Are you fine?
I'm fine.
But...you lost a lot of blood.
What are you doing?
My phone...
It's gone.
They took our wallet, phones, everything.
We don't even know where this is.
Why are you like this?
Hyeong Woo...
This is the sea.
We're heading towards the sea.
What happened?
Who would do something like this to us?
There's only 1 person who's trying to get rid of me. It's Kang Seok Hyeon.
Why would he try to get rid of you?
Because I also have resentment built up against him.
The code document you saw.
Truthfully...that wasn't my father's slush fund.
It was Kang Seok Hyeon's slush fund.
My father was just someone who took care of it.
I wanted to reveal all of his slush funds to the world
and reveal that my father was innocent.
I lived the past 15 years only thinking of that.
He noticed.
So the reason you got injured last time...
Because of that, you got pulled in.
He must have noticed that
you were the one who saved me.
I'm sorry, Eun Soo.
You became like this because of me.
No. It could be because of me, not you.
Before he fainted, I said something I shouldn't have.
I asked him why he killed my husband.
What?
When he returned from the hospital, he said he didn't remember the events of that night
but that could have been a lie.
Madam Han, why did you come by yourself today?
Where did your cute son who trails behind Il Joo go to?
It seems he drank with his friends until late at night.
Ah-ha...
Thank you.
Ah, seriously. My eyes hurt that I really can't watch you.
Do you really have to show that you're a newlywed couple in front of a single woman? Like each other when you guys are alone.
Team Leader Go.
Yes?
Why can't I see that woman?
-Excuse me?-The maid named Shin Eun Soo.
She didn't come to work today so I called her
but she won't pick up her phone.
Hyeong Woo.
You can't fall asleep, Hyeong Woo.
Pull yourself together. Hyeong Woo.
Eun Soo...
I want to go back to that time...
under Koo's tree.
There were so many things I wanted to do with you.
I wanted to go on many vacations
and when I left for work,
I wanted to feel your fingers as they tied my tie.
At night, I wanted to lend you my arm as your pillow
and I wanted to talk about things that happened that day.
Why did we become like this?
Hyeong Woo...
I'm not me.
I've lived like a monster. Not even once...
I've never been comfortable.
Why did I let go of you at that time?
Hyeong Woo.
Hyeong Woo!
I told you can't fall asleep. Wake up, Hyeong Woo.
Hyeong Woo! Is there no one outside?!
Anyone?!
Are you going to the office?
I'll drop you there.
Aide Jin drank a lot yesterday...
I'm sorry.
Save us! Save us!
Is there no one outside?!
Save us! Is there no one outside?!
Hyeong Woo.
Hyeong Woo!
I told you can't fall asleep.
Please get it together!
Hyeong Woo! Hyeong Woo!
Hyeong Woo!
Aigoo you ate so much.
Mister, balloon.
.:: Translation and subtitles ::.
Saeed
:: SKA192 ::
vampire9253@yahoo.com
Are you okay?-Hyeong Woo, the person that was with me.
Where is Jin Hyeong Woo?- Who? Jin Hyeong Woo?
You guys called me, saying that he was hurt.
They made a call to 119 (911).
Ah. They are just now done with surgery and are being moved to a hospital room.
Surgery? Did you say surgery?
Hyeong Woo. What's going on? Hyeong Woo!
How did this happen?
What in the world did you do to Hyeong Woo?
I asked you what happened. Why is he here right now?
I don't... really know either. He was suddenly kidnapped-
What? Kidnapped?
Why were you two together?
Well...
Last night, my daughter called me so I went there but Hyeong Woo was there.
But suddenly some men appeared.
Do you really think that makes sense?
Even if you made up a story, you should've made up a story that makes a sense.
Aunt, just a minute.
Let's talk for a minute.
Eun Soo.
We're friends, right?
Yeah.
If you really think of me as a friend,
tell me the truth.
I'm telling you the truth. What I told Madam is everything.
You know that's not everything.
You lied to me the last time too.
Hyeong Woo slept at
your house all night then left.
People really don't change.
Just like when we were young, you are still backstabbing me.
I wanted to at least stay friends with you.
So even if I gave you two chances,
you still lied to me.
Il Joo. -I will give you one more chance.
Hyeong Woo...
Why did he sleep at your house?
I got off work and on the way home I found him fainted.
He was really hurt. -Hurt?
Then you should have taken him to the hospital or his home. Why did you take him your home?
I'm sorry. I can't say anymore.
What did you say? -This isn't because I don't think of you as a friend.
You should ask him yourself.
If you really love Hyeong Woo.
You should protect Hyeong Woo.
Then we...
are no longer friends.
From now on, I don't owe you anything in mind.
With this,
let's end our childhood relationship here.
Why has she turned off her phone?
Does she really have a guy so she doesn't care for her mom or child?
Um... they are many dishes piling up in the kitchen. What are you doing here?
I'm going!
Did an accident happen or something?
Do I have to report this to the police?
No, w-why? Did something happen to Eun Soo?
This rascal didn't come home yesterday night
and she hasn't even called me yet.
She spent the night out? Eun Soo did?
That punk...
That punk?
Hyeong Woo, are you awake?
If you're looking for Eun Soo, she already left.
How did this happen? Exactly how did you get injured like this?
Why am I here?
Who rescued me?
That's what I want to ask.
What does it mean that you were kidnapped?
We received a call from the hospital. Someone rescued you
and then they disappeared after leaving my contact information behind.
It's someone who knows your contact information?
They say he came together with the ambulance. After checking,
it said you went to Samcheok, why did you go there?
You installed a tracking device on her?
Yes.
If she's someone who can dig through your study,
I thought we shouldn't underestimate her rear.
Thanks to the tracking device on her shoe, we found that she fell into the ocean.
Who did something like that?
Is it that this woman became useless now?
Or...have they realized that we're suspecting this woman?
We're checking the CCTV of where Aide Jin's car was.
Father says that I need 2 wings to become
the President.
Jin Hyeong Woo wing for the brain and my husband wing for the public opinions.
But I'm
going to clip one of those wings.
Even though it'll take a long time with 1 wing,
even if I get tired because I'm powerless,
I want to try flying with just 1 wing.
Il Joo.
By any chance, you...
Yes. I'm going to get a divorce.
I'm not going to live in misery behind a mask.
Have you still not understood the Prime Minister's words?
This is something with your life and my life on the line.
It's a relief that it's not only your life.
If it's together with you, I'll go until the ends of hell.
Was the Kang Il Joo I knew only this much?
All of the humiliation and insults you received from that family,
you're going to forget all of that?
Then exactly why did you dream of the President in the first place?
I can abandon everything.
But did you want the President Kang Il Joo,
not the woman Kang Il Joo?
Even if I wasn't Kang Seok Hyeon's daughter and just Baek Sang Yi,
would you still have protected me?
Exactly where were you yesterday?
When I so desperately wanted you yesterday, where were you?
Are you sure we're going down the same path?
Is it, Hyeong Woo?
What happened? She's not even picking up her phone.
This wench...
Eun Soo!
Where were you that you're only coming back now?
Oh? What's wrong with how you look?
What about Mi Rae?
What do you think she would be doing at this time? She's sleeping.
Why didn't you pick up your phone?!
Were you really together with a man?
No.
Don't try to just pass by it and tell me for certain.
I even heard from Boss Ma so why are you trying to pull yourself out of this one? You even spent the night out.
Mom, I'm not feeling well.
Let's stop now.
What?
.:: Translation and subtitles ::.
Saeed
:: SKA192 ::
vampire9253@yahoo.com
Il Joo.
I'll apologize for what happened yesterday.
Let's start anew.
[Voice message]
Hyeong Woo...please come to me. Hyeong Woo...
Exactly where were you yesterday?
When I so desperately wanted you yesterday,
where on earth were you?
I'm going to reveal why my husband died.
I don't care how much my body gets tired.
But to my child, I'm not going to let her suffer the pain of thinking her father is a criminal.
Ahjussi?
Ahjussi, it is you.
Oh. It's you, Mi Rae.
Did you come here to see my mom?
Yeah. But why are you outside at this time?
My mom is sick. She has a really high fever too.
So I bought some medicine from the convenience store...
but aren't you sick?
My mom said she was pelted by the rain a lot.
Wasn't she together with you?
Is anyone else at home except your mom?
My grandmother and my uncle both haven't returned from work yet.
Mom, are you okay?
Mom, get up and have some porridge.
That way, you can take the medicine and get better.
Aigoo, did you buy all of this?
The handsome Ahjussi came by.
I bought the medicine you're supposed to take when you have a runny nose
but Ahjussi bought new medicine and porridge.
He told me to give this to you.
My Mi Rae needs to eat too.
I came back from eating something delicious with Ahjussi.
Mom, quickly eat the porridge.
My Mi Rae grew up a lot. You're even taking care of me.
I'll do my homework in Uncle's room.
[Jin Hyeong Woo]
Hello?
Yeah, it's me.
Your body isn't feeling well so how did you come all the way to my house?
I'm a lot better.
The day after tomorrow, I will be discharged from the hospital.
Are you okay? It's said you were sick.
I'm fine.
Don't go to work tomorrow.
No. I was absent today so I have to go to work tomorrow.
That's not it.
You said Kang Seok Hyeon might have done this to you, so
I'll look into the situation, so don't go anywhere and stay home.
Are you listening to what I'm saying?
What about you?
If he's aimed at you, not at me, then you're in danger too.
Even if so, since Il Joo came by,
there shouldn't be any problems for now.
Don't worry about me, and take care of yourself. You have Mi Rae.
Listen to me. Alright?
Yes, thank you.
Unni.
Hye Jeong.
What happened? You were absent for 2 days and you are even late today.
I was sick that's why, but is Prime Minister at home?
He left earlier but why Prime Minister?
Never mind.
She came to work and she was looking for Prime Minister.
What kind of guy are you?
Exactly what do you go around doing that you almost died without anyone knowing?
I'm sorry.
You got attacked when you were with a maid?
Why did you meet that woman?
You know well exactly who that woman is.
Before, it was a person who was involved in my Father's incident.
It was uncomfortable to see her in your house, so
I met her to tell her to leave.
Why are you so concerned over matters in the past?
It is not your job to decide whether to hire or not.
Don't value your life so lightly.
From now on, there are many things to do.
If it wasn't for General Manager Jo, then you would be dead right now.
Are you saying General Manager Jo saved me?
Yes.
Then do you know who made me like this by any chance?
I'm looking into it. I'll let you know when I find out.
How do you manage the workers so she could be absent without a notice?
Isn't it necessary to let a person be in this house who was irresponsibly absent without a notice and late for work?
I'm sorry.
I didn't speak to you. How dare you butt in when we have systematic orders here?
Are you saying 'systematic orders'?
System, system that prevents from being creative world!
Hey. Because of people like you,
the sentimentality is getting dry out.
Everybody! Life is to relax,
love is borderless, and idea is beyond age.
Oh my, things like that are coming from my mouth.
Yes, yes, yes. Thank you.
Everyone, listen up. This one's mine.
If you mess with her, then it's the same as messing with me.
Be warned.
Let's go, my love!!
Go, go, my love!
You! Where is the anthology? Are you sure to throw it away?
No.
I told you to throw it away.
I like that anthology.
I'm sorry, but I can't throw it away.
Really? You're pretty faithful.
Man is strength, and of course woman is faithfulness.
Do you carry the bag I gave you?
Ah that,
Perhaps, did you sell it?
No... It was pickpocketed.
Oh my god!
Was that fantastic bag pickpocketed?
That is your fault that you used the public transportation!
I'm sorry.
You know your wrongdoings,
so you are my slave this afternoon.
.:: Translation and subtitles ::.
Saeed
:: SKA192 ::
vampire9253@yahoo.com
Eun Soo.
Let's have a talk.
Why did I not know that when weeds and flowers are together, they can be pretty?
Isn't that's how the mother's feel?
You're raising a kid, so you would know.
Mom's selfish that she wants to raise her own child the best.
It's certain to over-affectionate toward her own child when a child is raised by herself.
That's why I seem going through fire and water for Hyeong Woo's sake.
And I treated you more harshly.
I hope you understand the motherhood that is growing more venomous.
When we see each other very often like this, let's not hold grudges.
Your clothes are thin, you'll catch a cold.
After your husband left you like that, you raised your daughter by yourself right?
Yes.
Now,
I am seeing you as me of 15 years ago.
Are you okay?
Thank you.
Prime Minister, I found it.
A truck that contains the container was caught in CCTV on the highway to Samcheok.
We caught the driver and are inquiring him right now.
Yes. Did you find out who it was?
Who is it?
I don't have a good appetite these days so I invite you at my regular restaurant .
It's your first time here, right?
Yes, father.
Is something wrong with you and Il Joo these days?
No.
Then why did you try to kill Jin Hyeong Woo?
What are you talking about?
The people you hired, told me already
It doesn't look good that you deny it.
I don't know what you've heard about Il Joo and Jin Hyeong Woo's past, but
It's all in the past and something I've taken care of.
Il Joo won't be getting tangled in those matter, I'll give you my word.
You, seriously...
You stay still.
Jin Hyeong Woo is a family member that I really need.
From now on, if anything happens to Jin Hyeong Woo, then be prepared to have a divorce.
You do the most you can for your husband as well.
You have to make sure that your husband can trust and love you.
Let's eat.
A person's mind is such a scary thing.
Did you hear about Aide Jin and me from my brother?
Yes.
Is that why you trampled on me like that, last night?
You tried to kill Aide Jin, and...
Il Joo, that...
Everyone has painful past,
I was about to marry with love,
but I failed.
Don't you have those kind of past?
I knew you as a gentleman.
There was hurtful things, but your respecting and understanding heart for me.
I was in the process of opening my heart to you.
But now,
I despise you and my skin trembles.
How could you try to kill a person,
and rape a person? What are you?
I'm sorry.
I,
I wanted you, Il Joo, to love only me.
As precious as you are, I shouldn't have broken you.
I, I must have been crazy.
It's right that you're crazy.
Please get mental counseling first.
Don't place your hand on my body.
For what we should do from now on,
Let's think a bit more and decide.
The night you went to Eun Soo's house, I heard you got hurt.
Why didn't you tell that to me?
Did Eun Soo tell you?
Why did you go to her house and hide there?
I thought Prime Minister was trying to get rid of me.
The warning to break up with you,
he did something again because I didn't listen.
So I couldn't go to the hospital either.
I couldn't go home either.
And with me going to Team Manager Kang as well,
because of that.
You dummy.
That's not my father's work.
My husband did it.
After finding out that you and I were going to get married,
my husband did that.
This one too.
Because of me, you almost died so many times.
Because of me.
.:: Translation and subtitles ::.
Saeed
:: SKA192 ::
vampire9253@yahoo.com
No, no, no. That's not my style, put it away.
OK, that one is good.
Miss, that dress is worth ₩ 3,000,000-
Hey, don't determine the value of beauty through money.
If you're going to buy me clothes, you can buy me clothes from somewhere else.
You must be mistaken or something, I'm not buying these clothes because I like you.
Ah, really. If I treat well, you surely try to presume on me.
No, I was just sorry to Ahgassi.
You're sorry to me, right?
Good. Then, from now, you're going to try on the clothes that I like for three hours.
Go, go, go!
Since she is well proportioned, try new clothes on her.
Now, hurry up. Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up!
Hello?
Did you find where the book is?
I couldn't ask because I don't know what that book is about.
They are calling that book a coordinate book.
A coordinate book...they call it that?
Before Kang Seok Hyeon's condition gets any worse, hurry up and find that book.
We don't have much time left.
What do you mean?
The longer you hesitate,
That your child may be in danger.
This looks good on you.
You looked cheap but now you look good when you wear this. You are beautiful.
- She isn't as good as you, Ahgassi.-Hey!
How could you compare me and her?
-No, that's not what I'm say-  -I don't want to hear what you want to say.
This. That. That. Pack those for me.
Next round, go!!
Let me see...
These seem kind of old, right?
What is it? You like these?
No.
Yeah, why don't you get some glasses?
You need to look like intelligent.
Originally, the intelligence belongs to be. I am intelligence itself.
Well. Show me the new ones.
Excuse me.
Jin Hyeong Woo: Come to the hospital.
Eun Soo.
So it was Il Joo husband's doing?
Yes, thankfully our suspicion was wrong.
Kang Seok Hyeon isn't the culprit.
But still you've to be careful.
For now, just pretend to follow the orders the man over the phone is giving you.
I'm looking into it.
Don't approach Kang Seok Hyeon recklessly either.
Il Joo's husband,
does he know about you and Il Joo getting married?
You must've heard from Il Joo.
You aren't in any position to worry about me.
You know how much Il Joo loves you.
It's not right to worry about other things and to hurt Il Joo.
She got married with a man whom she doesn't like to save your life.
I don't think it's right for you to be worrying about me.
I'll handle my own problem.
Don't worry about me.
That's why I told you to leave that house!
How many times have I told you to disappear, so I don't have to worry about you?
You've made me this concerned.
How could you ask me to not worry now?
I'm sorry. Just,
think of me as a person that's not there, and ignore me.
I'm so mad, really! What kind of world has a crazy person like that?
Now, she treat me beneath a maid ahjumma.
Did I study in a secretary major to be treated like this way?
Honey, still if you please that idiot on your side well,
you will receive something.
The crazy bastard on my side uses fists whenever he gets angry.
Aigoo. Since such a person was born with silverware, he can be an assemblyman and a president of foundation.
Looking at that, hey, it's Korea!
I guess you have a lot of stress too.
Still I've to endure it.
Even though it's dirty and cheap, there isn't a job as good as this one.
I'm sorry. I only whined without thinking of you at all.
Today, I'll get rid of your stress.
What are you doing? Why aren't you wiping it? It'll leave a stain on my clothes.
I'm sorry.
Hey, how can you ask your classmate to do it?
Your class is dropping.
Even if they were in the same class in high school,
their status is different when they come out into the society. She has no choice.
Hey, since when was your status high?
I've only been classmates with this woman for a month.
Also, being classmate and friend is different.
Father, why aren't you eating?
They call it the coordinate book.
Coordinate book? They call it that?
Before Kang Seok Hyeon's situation gets worse, find that book.
We don't have much time left.
What does that mean?
It means that the longer you take, the more danger your child is in.
How is it?
The voice was changed not to reveal it's characteristics.
Each voice has its own characteristics like the fingerprints.
Can you check the voice before it was changed?
It's possible with a vocal analysis, but it'll take some time.
I'm hungry, will you make me some ramen?
Not bibimbap?
No, I'm thinking ramen.
Yes, I understand.
Cheong Mi.
From now on, we might have to only eat ramen.
What are you talking about?
I left my house today.
With this bag.
Assemblyman.
Don't call me that from now on.
Tomorrow, I will retire from the assembly position.
It's my last time being in this office.
I will throw away all of what father-in-law gave to me.
I will start a new life with you.
Go back to your house right now.
Cheong Mi.
This is the path into a pit of fire.
Who am I to block you from reaching your destination?
You're not blocking my path,
we're just going in a new path together.
If Minister or your wife finds out this,
we'll die together.
It doesn't matter, you know it.
How sick of this life I feel!
Politicians who grabbed the power after slaughtering people! My job is to extort money from business and fill their stomach with it.
Don't you think I studied so hard to do this?
Not anymore, even if I've to die.
I can't survive any longer under these people.
Don't worry.
I'll protect you.
No.
Assemblyman have other things to protect than me.
Assemblyman, you just go your way.
Why are you doing like this to me, Cheong Mi?
I said I don't need anything else.
You,
Can you live without me?
Answer me.
No.
I don't think I would be able to live, either.
That's right.
But, I have something I want to ask.
Love is stronger than fear of death.
Why are you all like this?
Shin Eun Soo.
Last night, what did you speak to my father about?
Excuse me?
For what reason did you wear scarf and even glasses, and approach my Father?
Why are you being like this?
I bought her the glasses. Why did you gather all these people for that reason?
Disguising as my Mother,
I'm saying this because she approached Father.
Omo. Isn't this woman trying to confuse Father's mind,
and take money? She is an ex-convict.
No, it's not like that.
Ahjumma. Give me your bank book.
I don't carry that around.
Then, it would be with phone banking. Try calling the bank.
Why are you being like this all of a sudden?
Because I watched something.
Where is it?
In the bank.
Can't you give it to me?
Why do you need it?
I'm Cheong Mi.
Are we not in the type of relationship to share secrets?
Did I see and hear wrong?
With what intent did you approach my father?
What are you doing? I told you to call the bank.
To check the deposit, press 1...
Honey, put it on speakerphone.
November 3rd, ₩ 200 million was deposited to Shin Eun Soo from Kang Seok Hyeon.
.:: Translation and subtitles ::.
Saeed
:: SKA192 ::
vampire9253@yahoo.com
Glamorous Temptation
Really, I didn't receive any money. Madam, I really don't know about it.
Really, it's not me, Madam!
Because of you I could get divorced.
If I become like that, then be prepared as I won't leave you alone.
The moment I let go of your hand...
If I didn't that time, you wouldn't be like this right now.
Will I be able to hold your hand again?