Like to have your picture taken?
No, maybe tomorrow.
Where do you come from?
From Sweden.
The champion, what's your name?
- Harry.
- Harry... It takes two seconds
Don't worry, it's free.
No problem.
I make you the beauty picture
together. Come on.
Come this way. Here.
It takes just two minutes.
Look this way.
Very nice.
Are you a champion ski?
Yes, you are.
Are you
the world champion, Harry?
Come next to your brother.
Madame, next to your daughter.
And mister, next to your wife.
You stay two minutes.
Look at me this way.
I want a beauty smile together.
Mister, come next to your wife
like this.
Very nice. Look at me...
Stand up together.
One, two, like this.
Smile. Good one.
Another one like this.
Look at me...
Very nice. Another one
like this. One, two...
Very good. Now...
Mister, can you put your arm
like this?
Very good. And together. Can you
put your brother like this?
Yes, very good.
Look at me together.
Harry, it's okay for you?
Champion ski!
One, two...
Look at me this way.
Okay, smile.
Very nice.
One more like this.
Another one.
And now, mister,
put your head on your wife.
Head on head together,
put your head on.
Yes, very good.
One, two, one, two... Smile.
Good one!
Mm-hmm.
Woman:
Tomas:
- It's nice.
- Yes, this is nice.
The light and everything
is perfect on the pictures.
- Oh, his eyes...
- He's very beautiful.
These are good together.
Like this.
- What's her name?
- Vera.
- And his?
- Harry.
Tomas:
Woman:
Vera:
Tomas:
Woman:
Mmm.
Vera:
Woman:
Tomas:
Harry:
Man:
Woman:
Child:
Vera:
Woman:
Man:
Tomas:
Vera:
Harry:
Oh, hello...
Sorry...
Not much skiing today.
Yes... Later we will...
- Bye-bye.
- Thank you. Bye.
Hi.
Tomas:
Ebba:
Hmm?
Huh?
Tomas:
Vera:
Ebba:
Harry:
- Hello, darling.
- Hi, sweetie.
Good?
So, how was your day?
Um... It was fantastic.
I had a great day.
I met this one.
I mean... yeah.
Yeah, I mean we bumped
into each other this morning
at the queue to the lift.
And I guess we were both
longing for someone...
Just kidding.
No, we had a great day.
Good snowboarding
and really nice talks.
You told me
that you're very religious.
- I... didn't say that.
- Yes, you did.
Not that I'm very religious, no.
Yeah, you did.
It's all right.
What's wrong with that?
I told... "this one"
that I'm not an atheist.
Excuse me?
Who the fuck is "this one"?
You said it before.
- Did I?
- Yes, you did.
"I met this one..."
It's a joke.
Anyway... Did you guys
brave the crowds today?
Um...
- What did you say?
- "Brave the crowds..."
There were a lot of people
on the mountain today.
So I meant, "Were you brave
enough to get out there?"
Yeah, it was great.
It was great,
we skied all morning...
...and actually,
we went home after lunch,
because we had some
kind of experience, actually.
Well, we were sitting
at the top restaurant,
with this magnificent view...
It's a nice spot.
And they had a...
Yeah, we saw an avalanche.
- An avalanche?
- Really?
No shit!
Yeah, but I mean...
Sorry, it just sounds
very strange
when we say it in English.
"An avalanche."
- What should I say?
- No, it's...
No, anyway... We're sitting
there and it was...
It was, like,
a controlled avalanche.
So, it was...
A controlled avalanche, yeah...
But quite quickly
it grew kind of big.
I've never seen
such a big avalanche.
And it was like...
For a moment it looked
like it would...
- smash into the restaurant.
- Wow.
It was quite shocking.
Yeah, when I talk about it
I still get these goose bumps.
- What did you do?
- There's not much to do.
It was horrifying, actually.
- It scared you?
- Poor thing.
- Kids are all right?
- Yeah, everyone is fine.
You got a bit afraid,
but it wasn't that...
It was controlled and
they know what they're doing...
He got so scared
that he ran away from the table.
What?
No! I did not.
- No, no...
- Come on.
No, no, no...
You ran away from the table.
What? No, I did not.
Yes, you did.
Oh, okay.
No. I did not.
Huh?
Tomas:
Yeah, I think we're
still, like...
under the influence from it.
It's kind of shaky.
Can you not run in ski boots?
What?
I mean...
Tomas says you cannot run
in ski boots.
It's ridiculous!
But isn't this a situation
that kind of comes really quick?
How do you know how to react?
You cannot run in ski boots?
Not "run" run... No.
You know,
I haven't skied in years,
so I suppose I'm really not
the person to ask.
Oh shit... This is...
Lovely, lovely.
Shall I take your wine?
Hmm?
Okay.
Ebba:
- Can we have some privacy?
- What do you want?
Can we please have some privacy?
We're just having a talk.
Please?
Yes?
Hi.
Woman:
Harry:
- Yeah.
- Harry:
Hey, watch out!
Give us some warning
next time, yeah?
Say "bar down" or something.
- You okay, hon?
- Yeah.
Wow.
Ebba:
No?
Tomas:
Harry:
Woman:
Man:
Ebba:
Okay.
Fanny:
Ebba:
Tomas:
Mats:
Um...
Ebba:
Tomas:
Shh, shh.
Ebba:
Mats:
Tomas:
Ebba:
Hmm?
Tomas:
Mats:
Mm.
Third floor.
Fanny:
Mats:
Okay.
Tomas:
Mats:
Harry:
Ebba:
Vera:
Harry:
Tomas:
Mats:
Huh?
Tomas:
Mats:
Hello, guys...
- Are you having fun?
- What?
- Yeah, sure.
Great place.
Yeah, yeah...
I just came to tell you that
my friend sitting over there...
She thinks you're the most
good-looking man in this bar.
Okay. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Have a good time.
- You too.
- Cheers.
Excuse me,
I had to come back again...
Uh-huh?
I made a mistake...
She didn't mean you.
She meant someone else,
my friend.
She didn't mean you.
- Okay.
- I'm sorry, it was my fault.
- No, it's fine. Thank you.
- Just have a good time.
Listen, it was my fault.
I'm really sorry for this.
I was actually
pointing at someone else, so...
- Let's go. Take it easy.
- But just... don't worry.
Hey, hey, hey.
- Hello... Are you funny?
- No, no.
Think we're funny? What?
Did we do anything?
- We just came to apologize...
- Yeah, yeah...
Take it easy.
I didn't talk to you!
I didn't fucking talk to you!
Ebba:
Harry:
Okay, um...
Tomas:
Ebba:
Vera:
Harry:
Ebba:
Tomas:
Vera:
Harry:
Tomas:
Yeah.
Vera:
Woman:
Yeah?
Can you please
drive a little bit more careful?
Woman:
I want to get out of here,
can you open the doors, please?
Can you open the doors, please?
She's really scared here.
Come on...
Man:
Vera:
Open the doors, please.
I want to get out of here!
Open the doors!
Open the fucking doors! I want
to get out of here. Please!
Tomas:
Hey, hey, hey!
Calm down!
Everybody calm down!
Act civilized,
or people will get hurt.
One at a time, please.
Let the women
and children out first.
Please.
Everybody, nice and gentle...
Very good.
Very good. Nice and gentle...
Be aware,
going out on the road there.
Ebba:
Mats:
Fanny:
Ebba:
Mats:
- Want a smoke?
- No, thank you.
Actually, can I take one?
- Yes, of course.
- Thank you.