DramaNo1.Com
How can she give such cheap smiles?
- Where did you two go?
- Why are you so curious?
Hey, Oh Jin Hee! I called you so
many times but you didn't pick up.
- Where do you think we are?
- Seriously...
[The heart that can't be hidden?!]
About your dismissal notice...
Don't worry too much about it!
He talked even to the
hospital director.
Chief Gook did?
[Emergency Couple
Best Moments from the Last Episode]
We'll have CPR practice.
Precisely.
What the heck are you doing right now!
What's wrong with you, bastard?
What the heck are you doing,
disguised as practice?
[Emergency Couple]
[Episode 9]
Quiet, quiet...
Be quiet!
Stay quiet!
- Hello?
- Dr. Oh, where are you right now?
- We have a patient.
- I'm coming over right now.
This way.
My baby is burning up!
Please calm down...
He only had a little bit
of formula all day...
but he threw up all of it just now.
- How old is he?
- He's six months old.
Does he have any problem
going to the bathroom?
No, he pooped a big
mound this afternoon,
and it wasn't even
anything loose.
It's 39.5 degrees.
I'll check the baby's throat.
His tonsils are swollen.
He has a fever, too.
Tonsils?
Then why did he throw up and...
Babies throw up when they have a fever.
Did you give him any fever reliever?
Fever reliever? No, no...
I don't even know where
it is at home...
I was just so scared, so I
took him and ran over here.
- Only if my sister-in-law was there...
- Your sister-in-law?
- Oh, my wife's sister is a doctor.
- She is?
I'll prescribe a fever reliever and
something for the inflammation.
Please give him the medicine
and check his fever.
Yes, I will.
You can leave after the
baby's fever is down.
Give him the medicine and if he gets
worse tomorrow, please come back.
Yes, I got it.
My goodness... That's a relief.
Your throat just hurts a little...
If your mom was around, you'd
get better in no time, right?
I envy you.
You're a competent specialist
and you know how to enjoy
your hobby in your busy life.
- You can do it with me.
- How can I be your partner?
You can start from the basics again.
How many years has it been
since I learned it from you?
Wouldn't you do it better this time
since you've already tried it once?
Dating is like that.
Even marriage, too.
I think I can do better
if we start again.
You did well. I'm always the problem.
Hello? Yes, speaking.
Which hospital is it?
Excuse me, I'll call you back.
Why? Is someone sick?
It's nothing. You don't need to worry.
I'll get going first.
Go ahead.
Bye.
Mom, it's me. How bad is Ji Min doing?
I got a call from the hospital.
You should've called me sooner
when something like that happened!
Don't worry about me. Just call me
when the kid is sick next time. Okay?
How is he doing now?
That's a relief.
Yes, I'm going to call
the hospital again.
Okay, bye.
Hello? Yes...
My back!
How long did I walk
with her on my back?
For such a small person,
she's so heavy.
Why can't I get away from
Oh Jin Hee and things be different?
My back! My disc in my back...
Good morning.
Here is the chart.
Thanks for working overnight.
- Go now.
- Yes.
Right, Oh Jin Hee!
I'm crazy! Crazy!
Why was I sleeping in there?
Alcohol is my enemy!
Taxi!
- Hello, taxi!
- Get out right now!
Oh Jin Hee, where is your home?
Oh Chang Min, that punk
threw me in there!
You...
How am I going to face Chief Gook now?
You stupid foolish idiot!
You really don't know?
You had no idea?
No.
Then why did you come in here?
Just... I thought I'd take a short nap.
Then you were here together
the whole night...
What's this?
It's Oh Jin Hee's.
Take a nap. This is my spot,
so go somewhere else.
What? Yes.
Just where... is it?
No way...
I'm sure it's not.
It can't be, right?
It's not, please? No...
No... What do I do? I'm going crazy...
Good morning! Oh? You're here early.
I do come here early.
It looks like you never
went home last night.
It just happened that way.
You were drinking a lot last night.
I wonder how you behave
when you get drunk.
Oh, right! Professor Shim was
looking for you just now.
- Me?
- Yes.
It can't be about sleeping
together, can it?
Who did you sleep with?
How gross... Gross!
This is driving me nuts!
I heard... you were looking for me.
Oh Jin Hee...
why do you think I called you?
Well, I'm not sure...
I know you're an intern full of
energy, but you're not too young...
It's not at all because
I'm full of energy.
I just somehow fell asleep there...
I didn't know it was Chief Gook's bed,
I didn't know he was sleeping there...
I was crazy for a minute... I'm sorry!
What are you talking about right now?
Pardon?
You slept with Chief Gook in his bed?
Isn't it why you looked for me?
I heard your dismissal decision was
reverted and you get to work again.
That's why I said this.
You're an intern
full of energy who
started late...
so please don't cause
anymore trouble and focus
on your work unless you
want to get fired again.
And now what?
You slept with Chief Gook?
What do I do? What do I do?
How can I trust him?
Oh Chang Min, this mutt...
This Oh Chang Min, seriously!
Come on, come on, come on...
Did you drink last night?
Yes.
Why? You don't like the
female staff room?
There was no empty bed?
Is this how you're going to behave?
I'm sorry...
Chief! Where are you going right now?
I'm meeting with the director. Why?
Well, it looks like you have
something on your pants.
What?
The other side...
It looks like a piece of gum.
There is nothing.
On the other side... Here. Yes!
Chief, what do you have here?
- What is it?
- Hey...
It's gum!
- Who put a piece of gum here?
- Hey, let go of it.
- Hold on.
- What are you doing?
- It's almost done, almost done.
- Just a little more.
- Hey!
Hold still. I got it all.
What are you two doing right now?
Hey! What now? It hurts...
- What did you do with the Chief?
- What do you mean?
He had a piece of gum on his
pants, so I got it off.
His pants? Not his butt, but his pants?
His butt? What are you talking about?
Oh, that's right. You threw me away
in the male staff room and left.
- How can you do that?
- Stop...
- Do you like him?
- What?
I'm asking if you like Chief!
Yes. Why?
- You do? You've gone completely mad.
- What?
So, are you going to date him?
What does it have to do with you?
It has a little bit to
do with me, since it'll
put me in an extremely
awkward position.
Why would you feel awkward
regardless of who I like?
Hey, Oh Jin Hee! In front of me...
How can I not feel awkward when
my ex-wife is dating someone?
- How can a human being not?
- Hey, Oh Chang Min!
You and I are over.
What relationship do
we have between us?
Tune yourself out!
- What a joke.
- Hey! Hey!
- Give those to me. I'll carry them.
- Thank you, Yong Gyu.
I'll do this, too! Let me.
Thank you!
Where should I put this...
I should be doing this.
What's with him?
After sleeping together for a
night, this girl is seriously...
Someone had one night stand?
One night stand?
That's right.
My lips didn't even get to touch it.
- Yong Gyu.
- What?
What on earth... do you call this?
What do you mean?
This part right here... Look, here...
Things are boiling over right in here!
- Isn't it diarrhea?
- That's not it, punk!
Right here... This is driving me crazy!
Did I go crazy?
For me, it's really hot
right here these days.
Sometimes it tickles...
and sometimes it feels like
it's going to explode.
Do you have a heart problem?
That's not it!
No!
I didn't even get to take one sip!
He can't even put it in the trash can.
It looks like you spent a
lot of money on this...
but you have no one coming.
How can you run a business like this?
Well, that's because we got fined
once, and the rumor spread...
Don't worry.
We have a group reservation later.
Really?
My, my, my... it's true!
If you're that worried, why
don't you bring clients?
For a man to be sitting at home...
Of course I want to do that...
but who's going to
take care of my Gook?
If you'd take care of him...
Why would I? What's his mom doing?
Go find her!
Even if I find her...
Both of us should be working.
How else can we make a living?
And... just like Jin Ae,
I'm also a musician, too.
Musician, my butt...
You seduced my daughter and didn't
even have a wedding ceremony...
You just had a baby...
What's going on with
him all of a sudden?
Gook! Gook!
- Gook!
- What's going on?
You said his fever went down earlier.
Let me see... Oh my, he's burning up.
Doctor... The one I saw earlier...
Excuse me, but please register first.
The doctor who treated my baby
yesterday, come out right now!
- What's going on?
- My Gook, my Gook...
He's sick again.
- He had convulsions, too?
- Yes.
His eyes flipped on the way here...
Did you give him
fever reliever?
Of course, the doctor
prescribed it yesterday...
- Who was on night duty last night?
- It was Dr. Oh Chang Min.
If he's still in the hospital,
tell him to come.
I'll call him.
After taking fever
reliever, if you leave the
baby in many layers, his
fever won't go down.
When babies have high fever,
they can have convulsions...
Purpura...
What's this? What's going on?
It's blood coagulation called purpura.
Hurry up and get ready to give a line.
Call Chief Gook, too.
Yes.
You came last night...
Fever, vomiting,
convulsion, purpura...
what should you suspect?
Oh Chang Min!
- Meningococcal meningitis...
- What disease is it?
- Is it serious?
- Let's get the test done first.
- The baby is in danger now.
- In danger?
You said he was fine and
told me to leave last night!
What did you check?
His tonsils were inflamed, so I
thought it was a common cold...
Let's save the baby first.
Give me the line.
Who the hell are you? A cold?
Are you sure you're a
doctor, you bastard?
- Let's move him to a room.
- Yes.
What the heck are you doing?
You're a doctor here?
He's the doctor who
almost killed my Gook.
Are you okay?
He has difficulty of
breathing and cyanosis...
and his pulse is 140.
Get ready to cuff saline and
prepare for lumbar puncture.
Yes.
Did you get the blood test result back?
It's 9200 for white blood
cells and 9.2 on CRP.
Oh Chang Min, are you the
one who sent him home?
Other than inflamed tonsils,
there wasn't any...
Stop with the excuses!
Don't you know you to
check for meningitis for
babies under two even if
symptoms are not clear?
What about the baby's mother?
It doesn't sound like
she can be reached.
What?
You have to take this right now.
I'm not sick.
- Just my Gook...
- It's from contagious bacteria...
So it's preventative medicine for
people who were close to him.
- For the baby...
- Okay, I'll take it.
It's meningitis, caused by bacteria.
He can recover quickly
with antibiotics.
What's the worst case scenario?
As long-term side effects, it could
cause neurological and organ damage...
But the probability of
recovery is higher.
It's all my fault.
Because I was stupid...
I just made Jin Ae go through a lot...
She's worried a lot about him...
I called her.
If you'd seen him in the first place,
things would've been different.
Why is that stupid bastard
calling himself a doctor...
He's an intern! Just an intern!
I'm an intern, too.
Even if it was a
specialist, not an intern,
it's not easy to tell it
apart from a cold.
Even if that's the case, I'm
going to kill that bastard!
Brother-in-law!
It's you, my brother-in-law, right?
It's me! Jin Ae!
Jin Ae? Oh Jin Ae?
Yes, it's me, Jin Ae.
You became really cool looking.
Awesome!
Hey!
- Sister.
- Sister? Brother-in-law?
What a joke. Follow me!
Let go of me!
Talk to me after you let go.
Where is my Gook?
Are you even worried about him?
As if it wasn't enough to leave
home, you got knocked up...
What are you doing right now, after
abandoning your child as a mom?
Are you out of your mind?
Do you want to die at my hands?
You became a doctor, and the first
thing you say is you want to kill me?
You're no joke.
- You're seriously...
- Brother-in-law!
- What are you doing?
- Please help me! Spare me!
Shut up and come here!
That's enough.
Send her to the baby first.
Who are you to meddle
in my family business?
I treated the baby and
she's his guardian.
- Where is my Gook, Brother-in-law?
- Brother-in-law?
I told you to shut up! Come here!
Please stop her, Brother-in-law!
Stop.
Go in.
Are you his guardian?
Yes.
Please come this way and hold the baby.
Like this.
Is Jin Ae here?
You two were talking.
I'm... sorry.
Let's talk later.
- Are you giving 20 CC an hour?
- Yes, it's going fine.
- What about vitals?
- Blood pressure 80/50...
pulse is 120 and
respiration rate is 35.
Lumbar puncture is over.
Take her outside.
Please wait outside.
It's okay. Gook will get better soon.
Don't worry.
His dehydration is severe and
his blood pressure is too low.
Purpura is not going away either.
It might also be encephalitis,
not just meningitis.
Encephalitis?
Please get a monitor
ready to lower the ICP.
Yes, I got it.
I'm really going crazy...
He's through the critical point,
so don't worry too much.
We'll use general antibiotics, and
he'll get better in a few weeks.
Thank you. Thank you!
Do you know them?
It's my sister. She's my little sister.
Really?
Then it's your nephew.
- You must've been very worried.
- I'm okay.
Thank you for your hard work.
Then...
I hope it doesn't
spread to encephalitis.
- Why? Are you worried about something?
- Huh?
It's nothing.
You were good with the
baby patient, too.
It's the worst moment for a
mom when her baby is sick.
How do you know so well
when you are not a mom?
No way! I'm sure she thought
it was someone else.
It's true! I definitely heard it!
Some flimsy punk girl came up to Chang
Min and called him 'brother-in-law'!
Then what happened?
Did he recognize her?
Huh? After that, I didn't get to see
what happened because I was busy.
- I was really busy today.
- See?
So how can you say that?
I'm going home now.
Ah Reum!
If you have time tonight, why
don't we have dinner together?
I made a reservation at a nice place.
No, I'm busy...
Well, I'll head out first!
Excuse me, Ah Reum! Ah Reum!
I'm so tired...
Excuse me!
Are you... better now?
I'm sorry about earlier.
When I think about my
Gook, I still get upset.
But I'm letting it go for Jin Hee.
- Look...
- I heard you're her intern colleague.
Here.
What is this?
It's not much...
It's a collection of my favorite songs.
You didn't go home and stayed
at work because of my baby...
You can just listen to it.
- No, it's okay.
- Thank you.
Loud!
My love is leaving...
My love is leaving from me...
About Dr. Oh Jin Hee's nephew...
His ICP is down, but his blood
pressure is not going up.
Is it DIC?
So I had a FAP added on and
secured a line with a needle.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Can I ask you something?
With Oh Jin Hee...
It's nothing.
Why do you stop in the middle of it?
What right do I have
to ask you about it?
Anyway, weren't you the one who stopped
Oh Jin Hee from getting fired?
I thought it was resolved after you
met with the hospital director...
but I guess that's not what happened.
- What are you saying?
- I don't know the details either...
If you're curious, you should
ask the ER director yourself.
What are you looking for, Miss?
I'm buying a gift... for a man.
Do you have any preference
for color or design?
Well... I don't know much about that.
What's the age range?
- I'll just take a look around.
- Yes, please do.
Chang Min!
Ah Reum!
Wow, you look great.
Aren't you tired?
You've been on night duty.
I'm really tired, but I
can't fall asleep tonight.
You must have a lot to think about.
Did something happen?
It's nothing.
I've been staying up late these days
to help with Resident Jang's paper...
But I got stuck, so I came to exercise.
Oh, the paper that Professor
Ahn is preparing?
Yes. Do you have any helpful
books, by any chance?
It's up there.
Wait.
Why haven't you accepted...
my request to start dating yet?
Here.
Of course dating doesn't start
with 'ready, start dating!'
But I get more calls from
your mother than you...
so I feel a bit awkward.
My parents are curious about you, too.
I want to learn about
how you can be so
passionate and
hard-working as a doctor.
But I'm not interested in
dating or marriage yet.
I'm sorry.
I see.
I don't want to put pressure on you...
But... please keep me in
mind a little longer.
I'm a pretty nice girl.
By the way, I heard someone called
you 'brother-in-law' today.
Yong Gyu heard it.
He could've misheard it.
Well, Ah Reum.
To be honest, marriage was...
I'll get going now.
Thanks for the book!
Okay.
Yes, Mom.
I hear someone leaving.
- Was someone there?
- It was Ah Reum.
Really? I shouldn't have called you.
She left.
Why would you let her go at this hour?
Are you sure you're a man?
Really...
I guess you're dating here and there.
- Of course you should.
- What's going on?
You asked Uncle for something, right?
Your aunt told me.
She heard him talk to you on the phone.
What?
Well... there is nothing like that.
- Are you sure?
- Yes. Good night then.
- Chang Min!
- What now?
I asked your dad for a divorce.
Really?
Yes. So please, let's see
some progress with Ah Reum.
I need to get you married
off before my divorce.
Did he agree to it?
We'll get a divorce
when I say we get it.
Who cares about him?
Do you think getting a divorce is easy?
You told me to get a divorce.
Why do you keep flipping?
I know because I've done it myself.
Think carefully one more time.
My son, what's wrong
with you these days?
Anyways... I have to wash
up and go to bed. Bye.
Hey! Chang Min!
Divorce...
- You understand what I mean, right?
- How many times did I say I do?
So my brother-in-law is not
in this hospital, right?
You keep saying 'brother-in-law'!
Then what should I call him?
Ex-brother-in-law?
Seriously...
What's wrong with being together?
Do you want Mom to have
her inside flipped
out and her blood
pressure exploded?
You alone are more
than enough right now!
Anyway, I'm sorry about
the whole thing.
Take good care of my Gook.
- What about you?
- I need to make a living.
I have three part-time jobs.
You got any money?
Seriously, you!
Mom is almost here, so behave!
She only has two daughters, but how
messed up are we, you and me both!
How can you say that
to your older sister!
So make sure to behave!
Is Gook really okay?
That's what I said.
Let's see how it goes.
I should've come with him earlier!
But the group came all together...
I'm sorry.
Look... Is that Jin Ae?
Yes.
Get out. Get out right now!
- Mom, we're in the hospital!
- Come out now!
Mother! Mother!
Even if we were not in the hospital,
I wouldn't leave you alone tonight!
I'm sorry, Mom! I'm sorry!
Honey, come here and beg!
Mother, please forgive us since
it's already happened...
Forgive? I did not raise
my child in a proper way.
What's this hair and this look?
Mother, please calm down!
Please calm down!
Please hit me! Please hit me instead!
- You punk...
- No, no!
Mom, stop! Stop!
You came here because
you're worried about Gook!
My baby!
My baby... My my poor baby...
I'm sorry you didn't get to see
your Grandma for six months.
You must've wanted to
see me for six months.
Yes, of course.
Yes, get better soon. Okay?
If Goddess of Babies doesn't help you,
I'm going to fire her right away!
Ah Reum, I'm seeing a different world
and greeting a beautiful morning.
- I'll send you a beautiful song.
- What the heck is with him?
Is he proposing to her in public?
Ah Reum, please look closely!
Awesome!
Take a look at this!
Already a response...
Of course Ah Reum would...
It's Chang Min...
Are you proposing in public?
What is he talking about?
Proposing in public?
What's this?
What the heck is this
early in the morning?
- Congratulations.
- Man, it's a group chat room!
Yong Gyu, are you being taken?
Goosebumps!
Be mine? Awesome.
Please share something like
this between the two of you.
What is this?
Well, it's not anything special...
Just a token of appreciation...
What appreciation?
Just for a lot of things...
I appreciate you let
me continue working...
And I'm sorry about what happened
in the staff room that night...
I'm okay, so take it back.
Please just consider it as
my thank you and accept it.
Big Rock.
- Why do you have this...
- Why do you think?
It's from the staff room that night.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Okay, you can go.
What's going on? What's with her?
What's this?
This? It's nothing.
Did Oh Jin Hee give that to you?
I should knock before
I come in next time.
What's going on?
I wanted to ask you about this patient.
- Hello.
Here he comes!
- Yo baby!
- Yo baby, yo!
You're cute!
- Oh my god!
- Good morning, everybody!
- Did you see?
- What?
You haven't seen it?
Yong Gyu proposed to you in public.
You really haven't seen it?
What?
Give me your cellphone.
My cellphone was broken, so I left it
to get it repaired on my way here.
- Yong Gyu!
- Are you okay?
- My head.
What's this about proposing in public?
Yong Gyu, what does that mean?
Did you propose to me?
It's not that...
Then... is this flower pot also you?
Oh... really?
You left it here?
I wondered who it was.
- You didn't know, Ah Reum?
- No.
Where did it go wrong?
My head...
You're really not going to tell me?
What did my son ask from you?
What did Sung Ja say to you?
Don't blame her. Just tell me!
How can there be a secret?
Especially in the family!
- I'm busy. I have to go right now.
- Sung Gil!
There is no secret.
Sung Ja heard it wrong.
Chang Min is not moving his lips!
How can there be no one on my side?
- I am the outcast of this family.
- You're right about that...
but it won't be used against you.
So just keep quiet.
Against me?
What's for me and what's against me?
Think about the best possible
case for you right now.
Are we playing 20 questions right now?
What are you doing?
I'm keeping it buried for
later, so don't try to dig.
And don't bother your busy
son who's working hard.
I'm dying to know!
You're here.
Have a seat.
What did you want to talk about?
I thought you should know...
Do you know how Oh Jin Hee got
to continue her internship?
The hospital director...
Of course he reversed
the dismissal decision.
But... it happened because
Director Yoon Sung Gil's word.
Yoon Sung Gil? You mean, Yoon Hospital?
Yes, Oh Chang Min's uncle.
Then Oh Chang Min did...
He must've wanted to resolve
it since they did it together.
Anyway, he used his family
to spare our intern.
I wonder if we should be nice to
Oh Chang Min going forward...
What?
Nothing. That's great.
It's good that we got to save her.
Did he go somewhere again?
He has an important meeting
with the governor today...
I'll tell him you came by.
I called ahead, so you
don't need to worry.
Yes.
Where did he leave the divorce paper?
Did he sign the paper or not?
I couldn't fall asleep
because I was curious.
Is it here?
What's this?
Did he actually get this from a girl?
How is your health in this cold winter?
Thanks to you, Father, I
passed the intern exam.
I'll become a good doctor
who helps people in need.
Thank you for everything.
From Oh Jin Hee
Oh Jin Hee?
My baby!
Is he going home?
Baby, don't get sick, okay?
What a nice picture.
You guys look good together.
By the way, you're not
married yet, right?
Why do you ask such a thing?
You look too good together
just to be colleagues.
It would be nice to have two
doctors in the family, right?
By the way, I'm not sure why she was in
such a hurry, but she's done it once...
Do you mind?
Being a 'returned single'
is not a flaw these days...
She's pretty nice, no?
Of course, of course.
Keep quiet.
Stop the nonsense and let's go home.
Anyway, thank you.
He needs antibiotic
treatment, so make
sure to keep the
scheduled appointments.
And if something goes wrong, you can
go to a pediatrician or to the ER.
Yes, I got it!
- Oh, music from the CD was good.
- Right?
Those are the best songs I selected.
- I have musical talent.
- You gave him a CD?
Yes. Something happened
before you came.
- Anyway, get home safe.
- Okay.
See you at home, Jin Hee.
Bye.
You'd faint if you
knew who that guy is.
Who is he?
Is he really famous?
Secret! I'm not going to tell you!
Why? What is it?
We discharged him after
the antibiotic treatment.
His blood test result came
out to be close to normal.
That's good.
Chief... did you open what I gave you?
If you don't like it, I can exchange...
No, I don't like it. Take it back.
Pardon?
Chief...
I think Oh Chang Min
should receive it, not me.
What do you mean by that?
The one who saved you...
was Oh Chang Min.
Pardon?
Professor!
- Thank you.
- For what?
For... taking care of the baby I sent
home thinking that he had a cold.
- Just in words?
- Pardon?
Someone gave a gift
of appreciation...
When would I be treated
like that by an intern?
Who gave someone a gift?
Oh Jin Hee.
She got Chief a nice, pretty
jacket for her appreciation.
I only gave him socks.
- Work hard.
- Yes.
- Quit right now and get out.
- Just forgive me this time.
You might be upset right now,
but you'll thank me later.
Chief... Thank you!
I need to talk to you.
Come to the rooftop.
Why? What do you have to say?
Why the heck do you do this?
Why are you doing this?
What is this about?
Who are you to lift
me up or put me down?
Tell me so that I can understand.
Did you save me with your
amazing family background?
Why? Did I look that pitiful?
Did I look like I would never
be a doctor without your help?
Why are you doing this to me?
So are you getting angry at me?
Whatever it took, we
did the same thing...
So why did you get into his arms
but you're getting mad at me?
Let go of me!
Do you know how you look these days?
I'm warning you...
Don't ever smile in front of him!
Don't ever get into his arms again!
Don't make that face I told you
about in front of other bastards!
DramaNo1.Com
What's going on between
the two of you?
It's not an accident?
Why am I thinking of Oh
Chang Min right now?
Is your stomach hurting really bad?
This is crazy! Crazy!
How does it start in the beginning?
Miss Oh Jin Hee.
Your last name is Oh, just like me.
Really?
- Where are we going right now?
- Next door.
Can it be helped with human power?
It's fate.
Are you interested in Oh Jin Hee?
Yeah, man.
Oh Jin Hee! Jin Hee!