[Rock music plays]
[Barking]
# Somebody's drivin' my car #
# Somebody's usin' my name #
# Somebody's kissin' my girl #
# So why am I doin' time? #
# This ain't no
pink champagne #
# Doin' time #
# This is a ball and chain #
# This ain't no swank hotel #
# Doin' time #
# This is a mile-wide hell #
# If it don't fit the crime #
# How come you get off,
and I'm doin' time? #
[Guitar solo]
# Somebody bake me a cake #
# You'd better sneak in
a file #
# You'd better buy me a judge #
# I've been set up,
and I'm doin' time #
# This ain't no
pink champagne #
# Doin' time #
# This is a ball and chain #
# This ain't no swank hotel #
# Doin' time #
# This is a mile-wide hell #
# Honey, please don't leave me
hangin' here #
# Can't you see
the end is near? #
# Its a crime #
# You get off,
and I'm doin' time #
- [Crickets chirp]
- Bobby, run!
Hold it! Red light!
Green light!
Go!
[Mechanical whirring]
[Grunts]
[Whirring continues]
[Muttering]
Okay, go! Lets go!
Red light.
Green light.
[Billy club bangs]
[Shoe squeaks]
Did you hear that?
It came from over there.
[Whirring continues]
- [Handle jiggles]
- Locked.
[Whirring intensifies]
Freeze!
Oh, hi, fellas.
[Machine whirring]
Hi.
Ernest, how many times
do I have to tell you
about bank procedure?
Do you realize
you could've caused
a serious accident here,
perhaps even a blood bath?
[Exhales deeply]
This man is a coiled cobra
ready to strike
at the slightest
irregularity.
I'm sorry, fellas.
- [Flicking rapidly]
- I-I just got to workin' on
this old polisher switch,
and I just forgot.
Okay.
I'm gonna
let you off this time
because you're one of us
and you work at the bank.
Yeah.
But I won't always have
this job.
Someday I'll be able to wield
the financial muscle
of this institution.
I'll be able to
move assets around
like chessmen
on a financial chessboard.
Someday corporate managers will
shudder in their wingtips
at my approach,
for I will be... a bank clerk.
- [Polisher roars]
- Aah!
[Motor revving]
Ow! Ow!
A- A-A-A-A-Ah!
[Crash]
Aah! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Bob, I'm sick of this
police band.
Lets listen to something
with kick to it!
[Calypso music plays]
[Squawks] Yeah!
Help! Chuck!
Ouch! Aah!
[Motor revving]
Oh!
[Creaking]
[Grunting]
It won't turn off!
Help! Help! Help!
Aah!
[Metal rattling]
# Don't make me climb #
# These aren't
my tree-climbing shoes #
[Beeping]
Stop! Stop!
[Screeching]
Huh?
Whoa!
You can't go up
the wa-a-a-a-ll!
Ow! Ow!
Aah!
[Motor stops]
[Grunting]
[Coughs]
Aah!
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
# ... tree-climbing shoes #
[Electricity crackles]
Uh...
Huh?
[Metal rattling]
[Stammering] Uh! Uh!
Uh! Uh! Uh! Uh!
Uh! Uh! Uh!
Yaa! Yaa!
[Suspenseful music plays]
Uh! Uh! Uh!
Yaa! Yaa!
[Metal rattling]
[Chair squeaking]
Aaaaah!
[Squeaking]
[Metal rattling]
[Rumbling]
[Squeaking]
[Metal rattling]
# Anyway, man,
monkeys have been up there #
# Yes, put that down!
Put that down! #
[Grunting]
[Bangs and squeaks]
Ah heh heh heh heh heh.
[Rattling]
Huh?
What?
Uh!
[Grunts]
My hands are stuck!
I'm doomed!
[Grunts]
Aah!
[Mumbling]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Groans]
[Thud, metal rattling]
Security check five.
No problem.
[Alarm blaring]
Man: There has been a breach
in security.
All prisoners,
return to your cellblocks.
[Indistinct shouting]
[Grunts]
[Whistle blows]
Hey, you!
[Indistinct shouting]
[Grunts]
[Alarm continues]
Mr. Nash,
you got to help me.
I just killed a guy.
What about it?
You got to help me!
[Whistle blows in distance]
[Deep voice]
I help no one who
can't help me.
Its your mess, Rubin.
You clean it up.
Mr. Nash, you...
you got to do something!
[Indistinct shouting]
Help me!
[Birds chirping]
Good morning, Frank.
[Gulping]
Morning, Chuck.
Did you have a problem
last night?
[Exhales deeply]
N-Nothing we couldn't handle.
Oh.
Not again today.
You might as well go ahead
and, uh, show him some kind
of I.D., Miss Sparrow.
I have to,
and I'm his brother.
What in the Sam Hill
do you think you're doin'?
Ernest?
Ernest!
Oh.
What happened?
Uh... uh, I-I was just
guardin' the money...
you know,
bein' extra careful, uh,
walkin' that extra mile.
Ernest, this is the biggest
mess you've ever made.
If Mr. Pendlesmythe
sees this...
It wasn't my fault.
They followed me in here.
It was awful.
You can't imagine...
especially these two.
Ernest, whatever happened,
you've got to clean it up now.
Come on. I'll help you.
Did you read those books
that I gave you?
I tried, but
they were real tough.
There weren't any pictures,
and the print was real small.
Ernest, you've got to work hard
if you want to get ahead.
I know,
but I get discouraged.
And besides,
Mr. Pendlesmythe's not gonna
give me a chance.
Ernest, you got to
believe in yourself.
Y-You've got to have
faith in the system.
You're right, Charlotte.
After all,
I am Ernest P. Worrell,
an upwardly mobile American
at his best,
and I know that
if I pay my taxes, bathe,
and floss regularly,
I will ascend the ladder
of success, hand over foot.
Ernest, do you think
the floor needs a polish?
[Grunts]
Come on. Walk this way.
Come on.
Two minutes for me,
man.
[Grunting]
Man:
Attention to cellblock...
exercise time is over
in five minutes.
[Chain creaking]
[Grunting]
Today's your deadline,
Eddie.
I want that money
you owe me.
I'm sorry, Mr. Nash.
I just need
a little more time.
Not good enough,
Eddie.
Lyle...
See if you can help Eddie
with his attitude.
[Breathing heavily]
I'll get it for you.
I swear.
Oh, I know that, Eddie.
The question is when.
Tomorrow...
I'll get it for you tomorrow.
Today's your deadline.
I hate to encourage tardiness.
[Chain creaking]
[Whimpers]
Please...
I'll get it for you tonight.
I swear.
See that you do, Eddie.
See that you do.
[Grunts]
[Sobs]
There.
All cleaned up.
That should pass
Mr. Pendlesmythe's inspection.
Right you are, Charlotte.
And Mr. Poodlesmurf is lucky
to have me on his team.
As a matter of fact,
one of these days,
I'm gonna walk
into that office,
and I'm gonna say...
- "Oscar, babe..."
- What?
Uh, good morning,
Mr. Puddlesmoot...
Smiddlepit...
Smooglepoot...
Pendlesmythe,
you idiot!
Uh, yes, sir.
Can't you get anything
right?
Why are you
such a screw-up?
[Door opens, slams]
Ernest, you've got to be
more careful.
I know.
I'll never get to be
a clerk.
I'll be lucky if they let me
stay on as a janitor,
know what I mean?
Hey, maybe I can help you
with that promotion.
All you need
is a little more
self-confidence.
You're right,
Charlotte. I need to
think more positive.
I need to think...
I'll get that job.
Why, that man is putty
in my fingers.
I'm just toyin' with him
now,
like a kitten
with a June bug.
I was just thinking
that, uh,
- Yeah, like a...
- since you're not working
tomorrow
that maybe we could get
together,
talk about the job,
maybe have dinner.
- Dinner?
- [Typewriter clacking]
Did you say "dinner"...
like just the two of us
in the same town
on the same day
in the same restaurant,
possibly
at the same table?
Well, yes, but...
just as friends, right?
I mean just as friends.
I mean, we'll get together,
we'll talk about the job.
I can give you
some, uh, insights
based upon my experience.
Experience.
Oh, yeah.
Well, I suggest you bring
your willpower, young woman.
Be forewarned... the
Worrell charm is merciless.
Oh, sure, Charlotte.
You just want to show me...
the ropes.
You just want to give me
a leg up to the bottom rung
of that little ladder
called "success."
Oh, yeah.
Come on, Rimshot.
We have to choose
just the right ensemble.
No.
Too formal for dinner.
[Groans]
Ah, the perfect choice...
European styling with
a decidedly American flair.
[Beeping, whirring]
Charlotte has more
than a professional interest
in yours truly.
And who can blame her?
I've never understood
why I have such a profound
effect on women,
but why argue with success?
[Hinge squeaks, machine whirs]
[Babbling]
[Machine stops, hinge squeaks]
[Spits]
[Whimpers]
Yeah, I'm a man who has just
found his parking space
in the fast lane.
[Machine whirs,
water splashes]
Who knows what lies ahead
for such a man?
[Water splashing]
Aah-aah-aah-aah!
Aah-aah-aah-aah-aah-aah!
- [Banging]
- Aah-aah-aah-aah-aah-aah!
Aah-aah-aah!
[Sighing] Ahhhhhh...
[Exhales deeply]
[Click]
Wh-o-o-o-oa! Uh!
[Grunting, panting]
[Grunting]
[Click, machine stops]
[Breathing heavily]
[Hinge squeaks]
Well, there's my problem
right there.
Looks like this little wire's
got a little sh...
[Babbling]
...hhhhhhhhhhhhh...
...ort in it.
[Electricity hums]
Gosh! Not again.
Woman: [Laughing]
Oh!
[Soft classical music plays]
Bonsoir.
Dinner for two?
Right.
I'll be your waiter
this evening.
You may call me Philippe.
I'll just give you a moment
to look over your menu.
I had a long talk
with Mr. Pendlesmythe today.
- [Electricity hums]
- It took a lot of convincing,
but he agreed to accept
your application
for the clerk's job.
He did?
- [Electricity hums]
- But the thing is...
y-you've got to be
more careful.
I just know
I can win him over.
We'll have that little talk
around the old water cooler
about... team sports
and transmissions,
jock itch... things
that just guys talk about,
know what I mean?
I'll have him eatin'
- [Electricity hums]
- Right out of
the palm of my hand.
I know that its hard,
Ernest,
- [Electricity pulsating]
- But Mr. Pendlesmythe
can't stand mistakes.
And between you and I,
I don't think he can
stand people, either.
Oh, thats okay.
I'm not like other people,
know what I mean?
[Chuckles]
Frankly, Ernest,
I don't even know
why you want the job.
I mean, he's a horrible man
to work for.
At least
where you are now,
you only have to see him
once a day.
Want to hear something
really funny?
- [Electricity hums]
- I thought I was gonna
get promoted
to branch manager
this time last year.
What a laugh, huh?
Y-Yeah, but did you hear the one
about the 3-legged dog
- [Electricity hums]
- That walked
into the saloon and said,
"I'm lookin' for the guy
that shot my 'paw"'?
[Pa]
Ah heh heh heh heh.
[Laughs]
Ernest, this is fun.
[Gasps]
I mean, you're pretty
good company.
I come from a long line
of bon vivants.
We're known for
our charm, wit,
and sparkling
dinner conversation,
know what I mean?
[Electricity hums]
- [Crash]
- Ernest?
Ernest,
are you all right?
[Grunting]
[Breathing heavily]
I recommend the lobster.
Ah heh heh. Ah heh heh heh.
Sir.
Man: There he is.
Hey, warden,
we don't come to your house.
[Indistinct voices, laughter]
Open C-12.
[Door rattles, thuds]
Well, well, well.
If it isn't the infamous
Mr. Nash.
My sources tell me
that you and your guard dog
got in some trouble yesterday
down in the weight room.
Just mindin'
my own business, warden,
somethin' you might want
to try sometime.
[Toilet flushes]
Now, you can make things
easy on yourself,
or you can make 'em hard.
Its up to you.
You hear me, Nash?!
Yeah, I hear you, warden.
Now you hear me.
When you step out
of that cozy little office,
you're on my turf.
And if I were you,
I would watch my step.
[Chuckles]
If thats a threat,
its a weak one.
Your day's comin'
real soon, Nash...
and we both know it.
[Chuckles]
[Door rattles]
Man: Close C- 12.
I've got to get out
of this place.
Chuck:
Ernest, you wouldn't believe
the new security system
we have for the van...
maximum protection
and minimum carnage...
[Brakes squeak]
And three levels of power!
Ernest, I...
Thanks, Chuck.
Thanks, Bobby.
I'm not finished talkin'
to you about this!
This is really neat!
[Hinge squeaks]
[Rimshot barks]
Here, Rimshot.
- Here, boy.
- [Barks]
Thats a good boy.
How you been?
Miss your daddy?
Good boy.
Lets see what we got
in the mail.
All right!
Down you go.
[Barks]
[Door squeaks]
[Mechanical whirring,
bell rings]
[Door closes]
[Barks]
[Clicking]
[Bell rings]
[Horn honks]
[Squeaks]
[Thud]
[Whimpers]
[Up-tempo music plays]
Wow!
This is great!
I don't believe it!
Jury duty!
Look, Rimshot!
I've been chosen for jury duty!
This is great!
Chuck!
Bobby!
[Mechanical whirring]
[Bell rings]
Chuck! Bobby!
Alley-oop. [Grunts]
Uh-oh.
[Gunshots]
I hate this minefield.
[Gunshots continue]
Its a miracle!
I'm so happy! I'm ecstatic!
Uh, uh,
its a dream come true!
Chuck, Bobby, guess what!
Ernest, you're in the line
of fire! Move it!
Go! Pick 'em up, put 'em down!
Go! Go! Go!
I hate this part!
- [Whistle blows]
- Ow!
[Exhales deeply]
I'm the luckiest guy
in the whole world.
They chose me.
Out of hundreds of thousands
of other people,
they chose me for
United States jury duty.
- [Gunshot]
- Isn't that great?
- [Gunshots]
- Yeah, great.
Bobby, soup's on!
I mean, the
opportunity to decide...
right or wrong,
good or evil,
regular or unleaded,
to hold a man's life
in the palm of my hand
and decide,
"Should I crush it...
or allow it to go free
like a bird
on the wings of time?"
[Feathers rustling]
[Bird chirping]
Burn him.
[Bell rings, gunshot]
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury,
one of the most precious
guarantees in our Constitution
is that of a fair trial.
Every defendant has the right
to one.
This defendant is no exception.
It is you who must decide
his case, not I.
You must weigh the evidence
carefully.
Counselor, you may proceed.
Thank you, your honor.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the state will prove that
the defendant, Rubin Bartlett,
who is a known henchman
of the notorious crime czar
and bank robber
Felix Nash,
did, in fact, murder
- [Pen snaps]
- A fellow prisoner
while in jail.
And for this,
the state asks that you extend
his remaining time
of five months
into a sentence of life
without parole.
[Man clears throat]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the defense will show
that the deceased was not
killed by my client.
In fact,
he wasn't killed by anyone.
He died as the result
of a tragic accident,
when,
in a poorly lit stairwell,
he tripped over
an inadequately placed railing
and plunged, regrettably,
to his death.
If there is a guilty party
in this case,
it must surely be
the system,
to allow such unsafe
conditions to exist.
Once you've heard the evidence,
I'm sure you'll agree with me
that the charges against
my client, Mr. Bartlett,
are completely spurious,
and that you will find him...
not guilty.
[Chewing loudly]
Ah heh heh heh.
Excuse me, sir.
Are you all right?
Uh, just fine, thank you.
This guy looks
exactly the same as Nash.
Are you crazy?
I...
look, the guy's perfect.
Its downright uncanny.
We can't just...
Itll work.
It will.
[Clears throat]
Your honor... to allow the jury
to fully understand
the case for the defense,
we feel as though
its imperative
that they see
the environment
within which this
unfortunate accident occurred.
Therefore, we move that
these proceedings be continued
to the site
of the alleged crime.
Well, I find this request
highly irregular.
However, if the prosecution
has no objections...
Prosecutor: Uh,
no objections, your honor.
So be it.
These proceedings will reconvene
tomorrow at 10:00 a.m. At the
Dracup Correctional Facility.
[Gavel bangs]
Oh, boy!
A field trip!
[Chewing loudly]
I'm telling you...
this guy is right on
the numbers.
Its so simple.
Towel.
We make the switch,
you get in on the jury
and find me innocent,
then you walk away
a free man,
and I make sure
this guy Ernest gets
whats coming to you.
In and out...
wham, bam...
and its over.
Yeah.
I'm a real big fan
of the early release program.
[Both laugh]
[Man talking indistinctly
over intercom]
[Brakes squeak]
[Metal clinking]
Attorney: I would like to thank
the members of the jury
for bearing with us.
Dracup Prison is...
Okay, Lyle, we got one shot
at this, so make it count.
... there are those
that must endure its reality.
So, what we are here
to talk about today...
is death... horrible...
frightening,
something to be avoided.
But is death murder?
Is murder death?
I think not.
And yet, though we must feel
some sympathy for the victim,
we cannot...
Psst!
By wrongfully accusing...
And that, ladies and gentlemen,
is exactly what...
The state has made no case.
Psst!
They've presented
no compelling evidence.
Come here, you.
Why? Because there is none...
Am I me?
Nash: Come here.
Huh?
We don't dispute that.
Of course, all of us,
as reasonable human beings,
mourn them...
Ugh!
[Groans]
Attorney: Certainly...
Hurry up, Lyle.
And keeping this in mind,
I would like to move these
proceedings to the staircase...
Man: Right this way,
please.
Heh heh heh.
[Indistinct conversations]
All right, Rubin,
lets go.
[Groaning]
Nash! Wake up!
No napping
during exercise period.
[Man talking indistinctly
over intercom]
No talking.
Yes, sir, officer,
whatever you say.
Boy, this is great!
A brief workout
to gather our thoughts,
then its off to
the jury room to decide...
very ingenious.
And they even gave us
these nifty workout clothes.
Boy, I love jury duty,
don't you?
Whatever you say,
Mr. Nash.
Oh, you don't have to be
so formal.
You can just call me Ernest,
Ernest P. Worrell.
Hey! You know the rules.
No talking.
Yes, sir.
Kind of strict,
aren't they?
Man: Cellblock B-29,
move to the left.
The rest of you, move...
Man #2: "C" to the left,
"D" to the right.
Ah, lunch...
how thoughtful.
For the mind to work,
the body must have fuel.
A lot of jurors here today.
There must be
a lot of trials going on...
a sad commentary
on our disintegrating society,
know what I mean?
[Whistle blows]
Man: All right,
brace it up.
[Conversations stop]
[Clinking]
[Clinking continues]
[Thud]
Oh, uh, I don't think
our table has any steak sauce.
Get up!
I-I'm sorry.
Where are my manners?
I should have waited
for the others.
[Whistle blows]
Eat, greaseball!
[Conversations resume]
I didn't order greaseball.
Wrap it up.
Man: All right,
stand to the back.
Backs against the wall.
Open up "C" block.
- [Whistle blows]
- All right,
lets move it!
Come on, come on,
come on, lets go.
Ernest: We're sequestered,
a- and on top of that,
we can't even leave.
Oh, this is great.
This is just great.
Uh!
I hope you've got a good
story to tell my boss.
After all, I do have
a living to earn.
Now, look, Nash...
My name is Worrell,
Ernest P. Worrell.
Oh, Mr. Funny Man, huh?
Yeah, Mr. Funny Man,
you'll think funny
when you're tapping
to the tune of 220, son!
[Door closes]
That is
the rudest bailiff
I have ever seen
in my life.
Ugh!
- [Thud]
- Oh! [Gasps]
Wait a minute.
- [Thud]
- Ooh! Oh!
Man: Hey, come on,
knock it off!
You're that guy.
Bailiff! Bailiff!
You're in big trouble
now, pal.
Bailiff!
What is it, Nash?
You see that guy?
Yeah. So?
No, I mean look...
look at him.
- [Thud]
- Come closer. Look.
You see that guy?
He's not on the jury.
This man is a prisoner.
[Gasps] I ought to
throw you in the hole
for that, Nash!
- The hole?
- Yeah, the hole!
The hole, like...
like in solitary, the hole...
like in real prison,
like in real,
really, really, really,
really, really real prison?
The hoosegow, the slammer,
the joint,
alcatraz, San Quentin,
Sing Sing...
Oh, no, I... I'm in...
I'm in...
jai-i-i-i-i-i-i-i-i-I!
[Echoing] Jail!
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Your honor, we have
reached a decision.
[Stenograph clacking]
We find the defendant,
Rubin Bartlett, not guilty.
[Spectators gasp]
Have you... carefully weighed
the evidence?
[Man clears throat]
Yes, we have,
your honor.
The defendant,
found not guilty,
will return
to the state penitentiary,
where he will complete
his previous sentence.
[Gavel bangs]
Mm-hmm.
Good night.
[Crickets chirp]
[Sirens wailing]
[Tires squeal]
Lets go!
Ernest,
we're late for work,
and Mr. P. Does not
appreciate tardiness.
So, how'd it go,
Mr. Juror?
[Wailing continues]
[Engine turns over]
Now, on to the real
important question...
how did your date go?
Oh, we had a nice time.
Nice time?
Now, whats the deal
with the hair?
[Chuckles] You bringing
the wet look back?
I'm just trying
something new.
Oh. Where's your, uh,
where's your sky piece,
you know, your lid,
your brown cap?
I never see you
without that brown cap.
I must've lost it
somewhere.
Bobby...
...there's something
bad wrong here.
This guy...
is in love... L-U-V!
Ernest is in love!
Ha ha ha ha!
# Ernest and Charlotte,
sittin' in a tree #
# K- l-S-S-l-N-G #
# First comes love
and then comes marriage #
# Then comes Ernest
pushing a baby carriage #
Ha ha ha ha
ha ha ha ha!
[Engine turns off]
Chuck: Ernest, you're not
gonna believe this,
but we have a new security
system at the bank.
[Car door closes]
A bank?
I work in a bank?
[Laughs]
Lets go!
[Dog barks in distance]
Man: Close "C" block.
Look, look, I tell you...
I'm not this guy Nash.
If you're not Mr. Nash,
how come you look like him?
Because he's obviously
a very attractive criminal.
[Laughs] Yeah,
thats right, too.
Lyle, tell him who I am.
Man: Hey, Mr. Nash,
did he fall for it?
Thats real funny,
Mr. Nash.
Open up C-12.
[Door rattles]
Did you miss me,
Mr. Nash?
Close it up.
You! You know
I'm not Nash.
Of course you are...
Ernest.
[Sighs]
You've got nothing
to worry about.
I'll make sure
this thing plays
just the way
we laid it out.
Just make sure
everything stays
in line on your end.
I've got another deal
working here,
and there'll be
a cut in it for you.
That idiot
you switched me for
has a job in a bank.
I don't believe it.
Sometimes the cards
just fall your way.
Yeah.
You just make sure
nobody figures out
that idiot isn't me.
Listen, little man,
you've pushed me
as far as you're going to.
I've got
some big things riding,
and if you know
whats good for you,
you'll play ball.
O-Oh, great!
What position?
[Chuckles]
You do like we say,
or Lyle here
will break your back...
- [Snaps fingers]
- Like that.
[Snaps fingers]
Well, then he'll just
have to break my back
like... like that thing
you guys did.
Real men
are not intimidated
by physical threats against
their personal selves,
and ironically,
neither am I.
What about violence
against other people?
What do you mean?
I mean, while you're being
Mr. Nash in here,
Mr. Nash is being you
out there.
Yeah,
he's living your life,
working at your job
at the bank,
hanging out
with your friends,
and if you don't behave,
he may have to get
very strict
with someone
you really care about.
Charlotte? No!
That your girl?
Well, sort of.
Well, she's gonna
"sort of" be dead
if you don't play along.
You lay one finger
on her, and I'll...
Hey, relax.
She'll be all right
as long as you behave.
Okay,
what do I have to do?
You've got to be Nash.
[Gulps]
Okay, Lyle, this guy Nash,
he's a tough guy, right,
he's a gangster.
Okay, how about this?
[Imitating James Cagney]
You dirty rat,
you're the guy
that shot my brother,
and I'm the guy
thats gonna shoot you.
[Imitating Walter Brennan]
Y-You dirty rat,
y-you're the guy
that, eh, eh, shot my brother,
and I'm the guy
thats gonna shoot you...
every goddang one of you.
[Normal voice]
Too old, huh?
[Imitating Sylvester Stallone]
Hey, yo, Murdock,
you're the guy
that shot my brother, right,
and I'm the guy
thats gonna shoot you, eh?
All right.
[Imitating Humphrey Bogart]
Of all the gin joints
in all the cities
in all the world,
you've got to waltz into
my place and shoot my brother.
Play it, Sam.
The piano
will cover up the shot.
[Imitating Barry Fitzgerald]
Why, you dirty rat,
you're the guy
that shot my brother,
and I'm the guy
thats gonna shoot you.
[Imitating Southern redneck]
Why, you're the dirty,
scum-suckin' pig dog
that shot my brother...
[Imitating James Mason]
And I'm the man
who's going to destroy you...
[Gruff voice] 'Cause
I'm just that kind of guy.
How 'bout that?
Hey, what are you
doing here?
Uh, oh, I was just, uh...
Well, at least
you're not in the vault.
What would I be doing
in the vault?
Who knows why you're there
every morning?
Yeah, right.
Well, how do I get in there,
you suppose?
[Sighs]
I don't know.
Hey, whats the matter
with your voice?
You sound different.
[Clears throat] Oh,
I've got a little laryngitis.
Hmm, I'm sorry.
Hey, I wouldn't let
Mr. Pendlesmythe
catch me in his chair
if I were you,
and I'd get my feet
off his desk
because you know how he feels
about his famous golf trophy.
[Laughing] Yeah.
You know, by the way,
I had a real nice time
the other night.
I think it was
really good for me
to just get away from work
and just have some fun.
Yeah, I had a nice time,
too, baby.
[Laughing]
"Baby"?
Ernest, sometimes
you can be so weird.
Good morning,
Miss Sparrow.
Good morning.
And what are we doing
behind the bank
presidents desk?
I was just gonna
leave you a note.
About what?
About, um...
Uh, Ernest wants to
formally apply
for that clerk's job.
Yeah, yeah, thats it.
Ha. I see...
Ernest the clerk.
Hmm. What a great idea.
Well, now you don't have to
leave a note, do you?
So get out from there!
Whats the matter
with your hair?
Is that some sort
of punk thing, huh?
I was just trying
something new.
Just look at you.
You are a poor excuse for
a member of the human race.
You and that big nose
and ugly face
have caused so much trouble
around here,
I should be given a medal
for tolerating you.
I would choose my words
differently if I were you.
Oh? Should I use
smaller ones?
How 'bout this?
No!
Now get out of my office,
both of you!
[Sighs]
Oh, I'm sorry, Ernest.
He promised he wasn't
gonna do that.
Well... well, who cares
what he thinks anyway?
I'm really proud of you
for trying.
I mean, you're starting
to take stock of yourself.
When you were in there
talking to Mr. Pendlesmythe,
it was as if you were
a whole different person.
What do you mean?
Well, I-I mean
that I'm proud of you.
Ernest,
do you have any idea
how long you've made
me and Bobby wait in that van?
[Beeping]
7.5 minutes.
I want to tell you
something about time.
My time is worth money,
and I don't think you
make that kind of money
to pay me for my time.
Now, lets put
the hammer down.
Okay, today will be
your first test as Mr. Nash.
Don't worry, fellas,
you are talking
to a consummate actor,
a brilliant interpreter
of character and nuance,
a professional practitioner
in the style and method
of the great Stradivarius.
Man: Bring the sheets
back over in the corner.
Just pile them up.
Yeah, just throw 'em
anywhere.
Man #2: Hey, Jesus, don't
overstuff the machine again.
Man #3: Hey, Bill, we need
more starch over here.
Man #4: All right,
come on.
You got something
on your shirt?
Ah heh heh heh heh.
[Steam sprays]
Today's the day, Nash.
My boy's ready.
Not now, Vinny.
Mr. Nash doesn't have
anything to prove.
Everybody's waiting.
You're not gonna
chicken out now, are you?
I don't know the meaning
of the word "chicken."
Man: If you lose
this one, Nash,
we're gonna run things.
I know you've
never lost, Nash... yet,
but my man Spider here
is gonna change all that.
[Growls]
Okay?
- Go!
- Grrr!
Ernest: Wait a minute!
I wasn't even ready!
Thats not fair!
Listen,
where I come from, mister,
you're supposed to say,
"Ready, set, go."
Thats the official way,
and I want a rematch.
Nash, you're a glutton
for punishment.
You're in
way over your head, man.
They're gonna
figure you out.
He was just lucky.
I can take this guy.
[Indistinct conversations]
Man: Okay, here we go.
Ready... set...
go!
[Grunting]
Come on, man!
Come on, baby!
Come on, Spider!
Come on, man!
Right there, right there,
right there!
[Grunting]
Come on, Spider.
Come on, baby.
[Indistinct shouting]
Smoke?
Man: Aw, man!
That was close.
Next case.
Man, why don't you
shut your mouth?
The real Mr. Nash
don't say much.
Well, maybe
he ought to, right?
I mean, after all, I'm just
reaching for the character.
What do you know
about the pain
an actor
must go through...
You straighten up,
or I'll show you pain,
and don't you forget
your loved ones
on the outside.
[Brakes squeak]
Chuck: Ernest, Ernest,
we're sorry.
Bobby didn't know
the mace can was loaded.
Bobby, how many times
do I have to tell you...
- [Barks]
- Yuh! Get off me,
you mutt!
Get out of here!
[Barking]
[Door squeaks,
barking continues]
[Click]
[Motors whirring,
bells jingling]
This is pathetic.
This guy's better off
in jail.
[Horn honks]
Whoa! Ugh!
[Thud]
Ugh!
[Clicking]
[Bell dings]
[Chimes jingling]
[Click, whooshing]
Oof!
Eee!
[Footsteps]
I will effect my escape
using a bar of soap,
a common, ordinary
household spoon,
and a tin of shoe polish.
Thank goodness
I paid attention in art class.
Don't worry, Charlotte,
I'll save you.
Your hero is on his way.
[Raspy voice]
Hey, screw!
Yeah, you!
Come here!
What now, Nash?
Open the door
or I'll waste ya.
[Normal voice]
Ah heh heh heh heh.
Assault rifle on a rope,
the perfect gift
for the mercenary
who has everything.
Ah ha ha ha ha.
Ah ha.
Man: Shut up!
Chuck: Mr. P.!
Mr. P., could I have
just one moment
of your time, sir,
please?
I want to introduce you
to our latest arsenal
in the war against crime.
Look...
Eh! Mr. P.,
its very, very special.
Well... all right,
but I'm late for dinner.
Great. You'll eat.
Just follow me,
please, sir.
Okay, can I have you
here, please? Thank you.
You won't be needing this.
Lets... lets go.
Lets open up.
Open up. Thank you.
Bobby...
Please.
[Beeping]
[Whoosh]
Mr. P., do you have
that funny, little acidy taste
in the back of your throat...
like that?
Uh-huh.
Can you taste it?
Do you know what that is?
Unh-unh.
Fear.
Thats what your common,
class-X criminal
would be feeling
at this moment
if he were in your situation.
- Oh.
- Bobby...
its only a simulation.
[Suction pops]
- [Electricity hums]
- I don't think I'd touch
those bars, Mr. P.,
unless you want
200,000 volts of electricity
jolting through your body.
Think about that.
[Humming stops]
Bobby...
[Snaps fingers]
[Beeping]
[Motor whirs]
[Briefcase clunking]
Mr. P., uh, have a nice dinner
and a... and a good
nights sleep... sir.
Eh, he's had
a real hard day.
Ernest:
Don't worry, Charlotte,
I'll soon be flying
into your arms
with my superior knowledge
of mathematics and geometry.
The square root and angle
of your lower hypotenuse
times the angle of your pi...
and that sort of thing.
Let the countdown begin.
3... 2... 11/2...
1... 3/4...
zero... fire!
[Whoosh]
Whaaaaa!
[Thud]
[Whoosh]
[Broom clanks]
[Siren wails]
[Whooshing]
[Tapping]
[Whooshing, metal jingling]
[Paper crinkles]
[Whoosh]
[Snoring]
You see, casting
is all in the wrist.
Its a sport of kings,
a game of inches.
[Whooshing]
[Metal jingles]
And as soon as your game fish
takes the bait,
'tis important
to give the line a sharp tug
in order to set the hook,
and then quickly reel it in.
[Fabric tears]
Ha ha ha ha!
[Stomps]
Ah heh heh heh heh heh.
I was gonna throw it back,
honest.
[Chain rattles, thud]
Nooo!
That ought to hold ya.
Don't you have anything
in a pastel blue?
[Door opens]
Accessories
are so important.
[Door closes]
- [Snaps fingers]
- Accessories!
[Chain jingles]
The way they run
this institution is an outrage
for a poor, tired, old,
lonely woman like me,
her only son a felon,
though not a terribly
successful one.
Young man...
Young man.
Young man, could you please
open that gate?
I left my car running
outside.
Ma'am, can you tell me how
you got through this gate?
The visitors' area is on
the other side of the prison.
I brought him up
as best I could,
but sometimes a bad seed
falls from even
the most fragile flower.
Ma'am, you're not going
through this gate.
Is this the way you treat
your mother?
Is this the kind of abuse
that poor woman
must endure?
Well, I guess my mother
is a little bit mad...
Mm-hmm. You ought to be
in the slammer
with the rest
of these misfits.
If you had any remorse
at all for the horror
you put your own mother
through,
you'd open that gate.
I have a car overheating
as we speak.
Okay, okay!
Lets open the east gate!
There,
now are you satisfied?
I'll tell your mother
how her son has improved
despite his shaded and
somewhat checkered past.
[Chain jingles,
balls thud]
The doctor told me I'd
only have to wear these
until after the surgery.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
- [Thud]
- Ernest, since you're part
of the night family
here at the bank,
I'm gonna show you
something new.
[Thud]
You see that?
That is only to be used
during an officer-in-distress
situation.
Do you understand?
Which, I might add,
we hope will be
few and far between.
[Drawer slams]
What could happen
in a quiet, little bank
like this?
Eh... will you take
the edge off, Bobby?
I mean... Hey, Bobby! If
I was going by the book,
I wouldn't have said
anything,
but its only Ernest!
Ha ha ha!
He... Bobby!
Well, Mr. Nash,
how's our special prisoner?
Just fine, thanks.
Of course, the place
could be a little homier.
Maybe some curtains...
[Deep voice] I don't
need nothin' from nobody.
I especially
don't need nothin'
from no lousy screws.
Tough guy... right to the end,
huh, Nash?
Just about 24 hours to go.
Well, yeah, whats it
to you, warden?
Besides, I'll be getting
out of here soon.
Yeah, you'll be getting out
all right...
horizontally.
[Chuckles]
- Man: Close cellblock "C."
- [Door rattles, thuds]
Did you hear that?
I'll be getting out
in 24 hours.
You just have to know
how to talk to these people.
Don't worry, Rubin,
I'll put in a good word
for you, too.
Mr. P.
Can I talk...
wait, wait.
Hey, can I... can I talk
to you for just one second?
What is it now?
Lets go this way,
please.
[Clears throat]
Mr. P., I want to talk
to you about laser beams...
little bundles of light
that can actually trigger
a high-tech, state-of-the-art
security device.
Bobby... please.
[Beeping]
So?
Whats the matter
with it?
Pbht! Nothin'!
Thats the beauty of it.
Now, Mr. P., could
I just have your attention
this way, please, sir?
Please, Mr. P.,
come this way.
[Sighs]
- [Thud]
- Ohh.
Oooh.
Space-age plastics
at work for you, Mr. P.
Its invisible, tasteless,
odorless, colorless.
And the best news yet, sir...
its bulletproof.
Bobby, if you... please!
No!
[Gunshots]
[Laughs]
Uhhhh.
Uh, y...
Its got a few bugs
there, Mr. P.,
but you get
the basic idea, right?
[Mumbling]
Help me get this off
of him.
Mr. P.'s a very rich
and busy man.
[Bird chirping]
Ernest: 24 hours, Lyle.
I'm outta here in 24 hours,
and, boy, am I ever glad.
This hasn't been
a really bad experience, though.
I mean, the food's good,
and I met a lot
of new friends.
But now I'm ready to go back
to my job and my dog.
You know, I got a feeling
everything's gonna turn out
all right from now on.
You know, Lyle, its really
good to be alive.
Whats bothering him?
Ernest,
I can't believe this.
This place is spotless.
I am so proud of you.
Has the value of pride
diminished?
What?
Well, the last time
you were proud of me,
I got a kiss.
Mr. Pendlesmythe: Ernest, I
want to see you in my office.
[Exhales deeply]
Well, Ernest, you've made
a drastic improvement
in your job performance.
And so I've decided
to take Miss Sparrow's
recommendation.
You'll be joining us
working days as a bank clerk.
So, Ernest, do you have
anything to say?
[Glass breaks]
Mr. Pendlesmythe: You idiot!
You smashed my golf trophy!
Get out of here!
Gosh, Mr. Pendlesmythe,
does this mean
I don't get the job?
"Don't get the job"?
I may have you shot!
[Door slams]
Ernest...
Did you see his face?
You didn't do that
on purpose?
He'll get over it.
Ernest, what has gotten
into you?
Look, we got to talk.
Okay.
How 'bout tonight?
But itll have to be
early.
Why?
You have a lot to clean?
Yeah.
Tonight I'm gonna clean out
the whole place.
Man: Open C- 12.
Warden: Nash, your lawyer's
got something to tell you.
I'm afraid I've got
some bad news, Mr. Nash.
Our last appeal
was turned down.
It was our final hope.
I'm afraid there's nothing
more we can do.
Come on, Nash.
Lets go.
Go? Go where?
You're going to the row.
The row?
Well, whats that?
As in death.
You know, death row.
Oh, well...
death row?!
You mean like the chair?
The hot seat?
Dead meat, deep six,
its over, pal,
you're outta here, bub,
the groundhogs are bringing
your mail,
you're picking turnips
with a stepladder,
like the no-tomorrow row,
that kind of row?
Oh, no. The row?!
Uh, but, uh...
You've got to tell them
who I am, fellas.
I'm Ernest P. Worrell.
I'm not Nash.
I'm Ernest.
Zip it up, Nash.
Get him outta here.
Warden, you're gonna feel
terrible
when you find out what
a big mistake you made.
And, you, pal, you're not
getting any more of my business.
I'm not Nash, I tell you.
I'm Ernest.
- [Laughs]
- I'm Ernest P. Worrell.
Close "C" block.
- [Knock on door]
- Come in.
# Two hearts
racing toward love... #
# Two lips trembling... #
[Sighs] Ernest, this
wasn't what I expected.
Its, um,
i-its different.
Have a drink.
Oh. Okay, sure.
Why not?
Uh, sit down. Make yourself
more comfortable.
# ... Burning in the night... #
A toast... to
the successful completion
of all
of tonights endeavors.
To a long and happy life.
[Laughs uncomfortably]
I'm up for that.
Um, Ernest, I-I didn't
come here to have...
I was... just wanted
to speak to you
about what happened
at the bank today.
We can talk later.
Ernest.
Ernest, stop it!
What has
gotten into you?!
- Stop it!
- [Growls]
Get off me!
[Barks, growls]
Get away from me,
you mangy little mutt!
You are slimers,
P. Worrell!
[Growling]
[Door closes]
Here,
you little rat ball.
[Engine turns over]
[Growling]
[Barking]
[Sighs]
So its come to this.
A pointless, miserable end
to a shallow, meaningless life.
But its as it should be.
Its the hand I've been dealt,
and I have to play it
as it lays.
Oh, I'm not going to cry
because life's thrown me
a curve.
I'm... I'm not going to whine
because I got mashed potatoes
when French fries
is what I really wanted.
Its time for me to...
step up to the plate,
belly up to the bar!
Its time for me to look fate
square in the eye,
flare my nostrils,
breathe life's last breath!
Its time for me to lie down
with lions
so I can soar with the eagles!
All right!
I'm ready!
Come and get me!
Lets do it!
Come on, Nash.
Its time.
[Crying]
I don't wanna die.
[Sobbing]
[Indistinct talking]
[Ernest whimpering]
[Dramatic music plays]
Is it fixed yet?
No.
Would you like
a cigarette
or a blindfold
or something?
No, I'm afraid of the dark,
and cigarettes will kill you.
Maybe a few last words.
Nash,
take it like a man.
But I'm not Nash.
I'm Ernest.
"And what is an Ernest?"
You might ask.
A man with a past rich in both
history and tradition.
Should we punish this man
for crimes he did not commit?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Can't you
speed things up?
Okay, okay.
Such a man should be
set... free.
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Silence]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Silence]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Silence]
Oh!
[Electricity crackling,
metal rattling]
Hit the alarm!
Run for it!
[Alarm ringing]
Lets go!
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Ringing continues]
Whats wrong
with the door?!
Whoa!
Thanks, Nash!
[Indistinct talking]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
Man: There's been a breach
in security.
All guards
to your emergency stations.
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
Hey, whats going on
here?!
All prisoners,
return to your cells.
Return to your...
Lets go, Lyle.
Get outta my way!
There he is!
Stop him! Fire!
All: Aaahhhhh!
Come on!
Get outta here!
Lets go! Lets go! Lets go!
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
Cut him down now!
It worked before.
[Grunting]
All: Aaahh!
Ahh!
Diii-ha!
Yihaw! Yihaw!
Yiiiihaww!
Yihaw!
Ahh!
Open sesame.
[Explosion]
Not so fast.
You better watch out,
Rubin.
I'll zot you.
You're a dead man,
Worrell.
Very well.
You asked for it.
After all, I am
Ernest P. Worrell, Electroman.
[Electricity fizzles]
[Fizzling]
[Metals clink]
[Laughs nervously]
Did I ever tell you
that you have a really
classic Greek profile?
Shut up.
Let him go.
Lyle, you talk.
Thats great.
Have you flipped?
Come on.
We got to get rid of
this guy before he blows
the whole thing.
No, he's different
than us.
Shut up and get out
of my way.
You better go.
Mr. Nash is probably
robbing the bank right now.
Nash?
Well, come with me.
I don't belong out there.
I got a place in here.
Well, I'm gonna miss you,
good buddy.
Ernest, things won't be
the same without you,
you know what I mean?
If anybody does...
So long, Lyle!
I'll send you a cake!
There he is!
[Indistinct yelling]
Come on!
All right!
We got ya!
Come on, Lyle.
Back inside.
Don't let him get away.
Get the dogs!
Come on!
Move it!
Nobody has ever escaped
from this facility
since I've been warden,
and they're not gonna
start now.
All right, lets go, men.
Consider the prisoner
extremely dangerous.
What are you doing now,
Ernest?
Thats it.
Is everyone who works here
a moron?
Can't you see
what I'm doing?
I'm robbing the bank.
I'm gonna blow the safe,
take the money, and leave.
I'm robbing the bank.
I'm stealing the money
that you are paid to protect.
I'm robbing the bank.
[Laughs]
Ppbbhhtt!
[Chuckles]
[Laughing and wheezing]
[Chuckling]
- [Thud]
- [Laughing]
[Thud]
[Chuckles]
[Gasps]
I've been vandalized...
by Elvis.
I can't believe it!
First Ernest and now this!
[Exhales deeply]
I am acting like
the victim again.
I need to tell Ernest
exactly how I feel,
and I need to do it right now
while I'm still mad!
Ah.
- [Flicks finger]
- Thats better.
[Whistling]
Rimshot. Rimshot.
Here, boy.
[Whistling]
Rimshot? Rimshot.
Rimshot?
[Rimshot barking]
[Barking continues]
[Whistles]
Rimshot?
Rimshot.
Rimshot!
How did you get in there?
What kind of a person would
throw away a perfectly good dog?
- [Barking]
- Come on, Rimshot.
Lets go.
[Dogs barking]
[Sirens wailing]
Don't you worry
about your diet, chubby.
As soon as I set this fuse,
you're gonna lose
all that weight.
[Dialing telephone]
Mr. Pendlesmythe,
its Charlotte.
I-I know
you won't believe this,
but it looks like Ernest
is robbing the bank.
I know,
but I am here right now.
[Barking]
[Sirens wailing]
Look, I don't know
whats gotten into you,
but you can't go through
with this!
Ernest! Ernest!
Look...
I am not this Ernest guy.
I just happen
to look like him.
I switched with him,
you get it?
You what?
Look,
would the real Ernest
have been able
to knock out Chuck
or set a time bomb without it
going off in his face?
And look at the floors.
Did you notice how clean
they've been lately?
You are an imposter.
What did you do
with the real Ernest?
Where is he?
He's dead by now.
What do you mean
he's dead?
I don't believe you!
What have you done with him?!
I haven't done anything
with him.
Your dedicated public servants
down in the state pen
put him in the chair
hours ago.
Well, I'll be seeing you,
sweetheart.
Or rather, I'll be seeing
parts of you.
Ha ha ha ha.
Parts of you...
ha ha ha ha ha!
[Door slams]
[Beeping]
[Sirens wailing]
[Barking]
Shh. Rimshot,
don't say a word.
[Barking]
Uh... uh.
Charlie!
[Barking]
Ow!
Chuck: Thats it.
Get him in position.
Ow! Chuck!
Ow!
Whats gotten into you,
Chuck? Its me! Ow!
You sure have a funny way
of saying hello.
Do you think I'd let you
get near me
after what you did
to Ernest...
one of the sweetest,
kindest men who ever lived?
[Sirens wailing]
Gosh, Charlotte,
I-I'm touched.
[Sirens wailing,
dogs barking]
Okay, now, listen to me.
When I give the signal,
I want you to hit him
with everything we've got.
What?
Sir, we got civilians
in there.
Worrell.
Nash.
[Shrieking]
Now, Nash,
this is Warden Carmichael.
Now, we've got you surrounded.
Come on out with your hands up.
Nash, let the hostages go.
Looks like I got myself
another hostage.
Too bad.
I thought you were dead.
Not yet.
So... it comes to this.
Man to man,
mano a mano,
toe to toe,
nose to nose,
shirts and skins,
eggs over medium.
Be careful, Ernest!
Ohh!
Chuck:
He should've ducked.
Here, let me help you up.
I want to show you
your new desk.
Stop it!
- Get up.
- Chuck: Yeah, stop it!
I can't believe I was
fooled by that man.
I sensed it immediately.
- [Thud]
- [Chuckles]
Freeze, punk.
Make your play.
Chuck: All right, Bobby!
Burn him!
[Groaning]
What are you waiting for?!
Burn him!
[Gunshot]
[Barking]
Bobby!
The gun!
[Barking]
Get away from there.
[Beeping]
Nash: Give me that gun
or I'll rip your lungs out.
Give it here!
Chuck:
Bobby, go to plan 12!
Let go!
Let go.
Ohhh.
Warden: You haven't got
a prayer, Nash.
You're completely surrounded.
Give it up.
Chuck: Bobby!
What do you want me
to do now?
Deploy them around
to the back.
Okay, second team,
lets move.
You heard him!
Lets go!
Toast time.
[Electricity crackling]
[Laughing]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Thud]
[Whimpers]
It looks like one way
or another,
this was just his night to fry.
[Laughing]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
[Whimpers]
[Electricity crackling,
Ernest babbling]
I'm floating.
I'm lighter than air.
Whats happening to me?
He's polarized.
He... he's weightless.
Gravity's lost its grip.
I'll show you polarized.
Ahhhhhhhh!
- Time to put your butt
on spin cycle.
- Ahhhhhhh!
Ahhhhhhhhhh!
Right down the middle.
[Thud]
[Wind whistling]
[Barks]
Ahhhhh!
Ahhhhhhh!
Oh, no! No! No! No!
- Ugh!
- [Thud]
Chuck! Bob...!
- Stop it!
- Doh!
Uhhhhh!
- [Thud]
- Oh!
Uhhhhh!
[Thud]
[Creaking]
Oh!
[Thud]
Ow!
Oh!
[Thud]
Nash: To the moon,
bozo!
Leave him alone!
Uh!
Chuck:
Ernest, you're in control!
Thats it!
Nash, listen to me.
Let the hostages go.
Yeah, right, warden.
This'll take care of him.
Ernest, incoming.
3:00. Maybe 2:30.
50... 3/4...
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
Ahhhhhhh!
[Splat]
Wa-ahhhhhhhh!
Get this thing
off of me.
Watch out, Ernest!
He's getting up!
Aaaahhhhhh!
Chuck:
Ernest, grab the lamp!
Be careful.
Those lamps are expensive.
[Cracking]
Go back to plan "B."
[Gasps]
I'm gonna kill him.
Ahh!
[Glass shatters]
Huh?
W-Whats going on
in there?
Get your head down!
Who is this guy?
Its my bank.
Peter Pan,
eat your heart out.
[Humming]
Here. Have a seat.
Ahhhhhh!
[Thud]
[Machine whirring]
Ugh!
Ahhhhhhhhh!
[Thud]
Ernest: Let go of me!
Pull on it!
Pull on it! Chuck!
I am.
My wrist is beginning
to chafe.
Ernest!
Stop this thing!
Somebody, stop...
Nash: Come on, get me
off of this thing!
Hey, Nash, you'll never get him
now. [Laughing]
Please be sure that your
seat backs and tray tables
are in their full, upright, and
locked positions before landing.
Let me
off of this thing!
Thanks for shopping with us.
Ah heh heh heh heh.
No, don't touch
that button.
No!
Aaaahhhhh!
[Crash]
All right!
E-e-e-e-e-w.
15 seconds, Chuck!
[Shrieking]
Bobby, unlock me!
Ernest, the bomb!
I'm coming.
Don't worry, Charlotte.
I'll save you.
Give me that.
Up, up, and away-y-y-y-y-y!
[Glass shatters]
He's getting away.
[Wind whistling]
- [Explosion]
- Whoa!
Wow!
[Crying]
Oh... my buddy's gone.
[Whimpers]
He's been here all right.
I recognize his work.
Ernest saved us,
Mr. Pendlesmythe.
He saved your stupid bank
and all your stupid money.
Ernest wasn't a thief.
He was a hero.
[Indistinct talking]
Well, maybe you're right.
Stick a sock in it.
Unh.
Put 'em down, boys.
Nice and easy.
And all of you, move over there.
Come on, move.
Nash...
you'll never get away
with this.
Oh, yeah, warden?
I think so.
She's my ticket outta here.
Come over here, sweetie.
Ahhhhhhh!
[Thud]
Uhhhh. Uh-oh.
Ernest, you're alive.
[Rimshot barking]
[Coughing]
I came. I saw.
I got blowed up.
[Thud]
[Imitating Humphrey Bogart]
Play it, Sam.
The piano will cover up
the shot.
# Don't make me climb
the coconut tree #
# That would be a catastrophe #
# I would not make it halfway,
you see #
# I'm wearing the wrong kind
of shoes #
# Don't make me climb
the coconut tree #
# I think I owe you
an apology #
# But ask anyone who grew up
with me #
# I'm not one
to easily bruise #
# Don't make me climb #
# No, don't make me climb #
# These aren't
my tree-climbing shoes #
Hey, man, if I had known
you were back, man,
I wouldn't have worn
my wingtips.
Look, there's no tread left
on these.
See? Look.
You can't eat those coconuts
anyway, man.
Monkeys have been up there.
Eh, put that down!
Put that down!
Don't! Don't push, man.
Don't make me climb.
# No, please don't make me
climb #
# No, don't make me climb #
# These aren't
my tree-climbing shoes #
# Ah, don't make me climb #
# No, don't make me climb #
# Don't make me climb #
# These aren't
my tree-climbing shoes #
Wha...
[Music continues]