Ahhhhh!
Ahhh! Ahhh! Ahhhh!
Ahhhh! Ahhh!
Ahhh! Ahhhhh!
Ahhhhhh!
Grab him!
Grab him, Judas! Take him!
We got the monster that wants
to hack up our children.
Get the chains on him.
I got him.
The ancient evil has
followed us here to this new world.
He has stolen our children
and tried to resurrect
his wicked race.
But we, in our righteousness,
have prevailed.
My babies-- he took my babies!
And here he shall be buried,
and this oak tree
will seal his fate.
Its roots will be his prison,
which must never be disturbed.
Hear me, Phineas Worrell.
When the face of death
covers the moon,
one with your blood
in his veins will release me,
and victory will at last
be mine!
There, there, Francis.
We'll get them back.
You'll see.
I banish you
to eternal darkness.
"So in the hours
just before midnight,
"the people of Briarville
buried Trantor the Troll
"in the cold, damp ground.
The end."
Thank you, Elizabeth.
Class, what did you think
of her report?
That's bull!
It's not bull!
I read it in a book.
Yeah, it was a cool report.
It probably just went over
your head.
The reports were supposed to
be on the history of the town,
not "Nightmare
on Troll Street."
Now, settle down, class.
Lay off her, Murdock.
What are you gonna do
about it, runt?
Elizabeth scared Kenny
with a spooky story.
The dork likes her.
Although Elizabeth's report was
a bit unusual,
legends and myths are
a real part of history,
especially here in Briarville,
with our unique past.
I think it was a clever idea.
Ernest!
Stop the truck!
So, uh, Elizabeth,
what was the curse
the troll put on Phineas?
Well, legend has it
that from that moment on,
Phineas' descendants would
get dumber and dumber...
and dumber.
Yeah, when they hired me
as sanitary engineer,
they had no idea that I was
actually Ernest P. Worrell,
man of destiny,
ruler of refuse,
a man who has taken dominion
over his environment...
... a brilliant innovator
in the fertile field
of recycling.
The czar of jars,
the baron of bottles,
the duke of dust--
Oh, no!
Uh, the switch is on the fritz!
Uh, Rimshot! Rimshot!
A little help here, Rimshot!
Rimshot!
Rimshot, the clutch!
The clutch!
The clutch, Rimshot!
Help!
Rimshot, the clutch!
Rimshot! Whoa!
Wa-aaaah!
Ahh.
That was close.
Oh...
I'm gonna be squooshed!
Rimshot, help!
Do something! Rimshot!
Aah! Aah!
No, no!
Don't stick my head in those gears!
But i-it's me or you!
But I have
a family at the doll factory!
I'll send them a nice card.
You'll never get away
with this, Ernest! I know where you live!
Ah heh heh heh heh heh.
Wa-ahhhh!
Those Murdocks are
major jerks.
If their IQ's were any lower,
they'd be plants.
Rimshot!
Something's wrong!
Help! Let me out of here!
Ernest!
This should open it.
Way to go!
You did it!
Well, no
need to thank me, little lady.
Just some
routine hero work.
Aahhh!
Sheriff...
I've just come
from the Hackmore place.
It's an absolute mess.
It violates every code
in the book.
I want it cleaned up, and I
want it cleaned up immediately.
Yes. Well, mayor, I served the papers, and
Ernest said he would get right on it.
If he can't handle it,
you fire him.
Yes, sir.
There goes that idiot
now.
Ha. And he's going away
from the Hackmore place.
That was close.
Yeah, my dad said we can get
in big trouble riding in here.
Well, it is against
city regulations and all,
but as driver
of a garbage truck,
I feel like captain
of my own ship,
master of my own fate,
able to make my own rules,
a man above the law.
Uh-oh.
It's my dad!
Uh, was I speeding?
Sometimes the raw power of this
vehicle just gets away from me--
Ernest, I told you to get
out to the Hackmore place--
Shh!
You two--
get out of there and
get in the car right now.
Dad, I--
No, I don't want to hear it.
Get in the car.
It wasn't their fault.
I-I'm the captain, and--
No, look, I told you to get
out to the Hackmore place
and clean it up,
and you haven't done it.
Well, uh, I don't have
a toxic-waste permit.
Uh, I just took a cold pill, and I'm not
supposed to operate heavy machinery.
Look, if you want to
hang on to your job,
you'll get out there
and do it.
See you, Ernest.
Come on, boy.
We've nothing to fear
but fear itself,
plus the known fact
that Old Lady Hackmore
will turn us into
a couple of drooling,
red-eyed zombies
if she catches us here.
Well, nobody home.
I guess they're out
robbin' graves
or bitin' the heads off chickens
or whatever's in voodoo vogue.
Get off of my property!
What are you
doing here?!
Ma'am, I'm just here to
pick up all this garbage.
Got no garbage here,
only the expressions
of the soul.
Uh, ma'am, I'm
an official representative
of the Briarville
city government,
and, incidentally, a close personal
friend of Mayor Murdock's.
Aren't you
that Worrell kid?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh... you will bring down
the curse on us all!
Woe to you,
oh, ye seed of Worrell.
Get out of here
and don't come back!
I wish you'd reconsider.
Recycling is a... a very important
part of good citizenship.
Yeah.
And you'll be
a dead citizen.
When the poisons of
the evil courses through
the portals and channels
of your body,
you will lie a quivering, toxic
mass of screaming flesh!
They will have to load you
and the rest
of this backward town
on a meat wagon
with a pitchfork!
So in other words,
it might be better
if I came back another day.
Aahhhhh!
Ahhhhhhhh!
Pretty scary scream,
huh?
My heart
was in my throat.
You have a rare gift.
You haven't seen
the grand finale yet.
Come here.
See, they'll come in here
and go through that door
and up this way, where Joey hits
'em in the face with a mop.
A wet mop.
Then they'll have to crawl
through all these peeled grapes
while I'm screaming,
"Where are my eyes?
Don't step on
my eyeballs!"
Gross!
But I love it.
It's the Murdocks!
Look out, witch!
It's an earthquake!
It's a big one--
5.3 on the Richter scale!
Quick!
Let's run out the back!
It's caving in!
Get out!
You're gonna die!
We're caving in!
Let's run for it!
Go! Go!
You buttheads made
a big mistake!
Hey, where do you think
you're going?
The fun's just beginning!
I don't know what to do.
They wrecked our haunted house.
They-- they wrecked
your haunted house?
Yeah.
You know, what you need
is some of that
hysterical perspective,
know what I mean?
Not... really.
You need to
learn a self-defense lesson
from... tiny Botswana,
that...
plucky little nation
that defeated the...
giant Ottoman Empire.
Ernest, what does that
have to do with me?
I'm glad you asked.
It was a dark
night in lower Botswana.
Giant bula bula flies droned
in the still air.
Then it came--
the screeching war cry
of the Ottoman hordes.
Wa-aah!
We're the Ottomans,
and you're not!
You're in a world of it now,
pal!
Oh, my. I'm afraid.
Sure, I'm scared.
E-everybody in Botswana's
scared.
It looks like curtains.
This place is just screaming
for drapes.
Don't worry about the Ottomans.
They're just wussies.
They're all talk.
I knew an Ottoman eagle scout.
He got a merit badge
in wholesale slaughter.
Aah!
Come on, Ottomans!
Take a piece of me!
What we need... is
the high ground.
The high ground is no good
without trees.
Friends, Romans, Botswanians,
lend me your tree.
There ain't no trees
in Botswana.
Unh-unh. I know.
I am a Botswanian lumberjack,
and I ain't never had a job.
We need dress shields.
You need the high ground
to keep away from us
'cause...
'Cause we're the Ottomans!
Aah!
Ernest, I know! I know!
What we need is...
a treehouse!
I thought we needed
dress shields.
Ernest!
Direct hit.
Way to go, Ernest.
Do you smell fish?
The first step
in treehouse construction,
which I'll refer to
as "step one,"
is tree selection.
With the right tree,
we can build
an impregnant fortress
armed with nuclear rays,
disintegrator beams,
and all the latest
electronic technology
to afford us a safe haven
against advancing hordes
as well as offering
truly elegant country living
in rustic surroundings.
Nah.
Too much bass.
This one's nice.
Ah heh. Too many
termites. Ah heh.
This looks like
a good one.
Inhabited.
Oh, jeez.
What's the big idea?
A tree is a tree.
We've got to find one big enough
to keep the Ottomans out.
The Ottomans?
Don't ask.
Oo-o-o-o-o-o-h!
This is neat!
Go on!
It's okay.
I don't like this.
Well, I didn't see
any poison ivy.
The worst thing
that could happen
would be Dutch elm blight,
and none of us are Dutch.
Remember, if any of us
get separated,
there's an old pioneer way
of finding north--
the bark always grows
on the outside of a tree.
Is he serious?
I'm afraid so.
This is it!
The foundation
of the high ground--
tree of the stars!
This is a tree
to die for.
Come on, kids.
This'll be fun.
I've been collecting
this stuff for years.
Well, I guess we got to
give it a try.
No guts, no glory.
Yes, just as the journey of 1,000
miles begins with a single step,
a treehouse begins
with a single nail.
Observe.
Here he shall be buried,
and this oak tree will seal
his fate.
Its roots will be his prison,
which must never be disturbed.
Return this evil
from whence it came.
Ahhhhh!
One treehouse--
under construction.
Crank 'er up.
All right.
This is really working.
This is great!
All right, Joey.
Over here.
- Another wall coming up.
- Good work.
One more side to go.
This is really looking
great.
The spirits are loose again.
Who would dare enter here?
- All right! We did it!
- Yeah!
This is really neat.
This is your high ground.
I felt it! I felt it!
Heaven help us!
The signs showed me--
the sun,
the moon, the stars--
oh, horror will once more
walk among us.
The nightmare will begin
again.
Well, it's not the greatest
treehouse in the world,
but I wouldn't call it
a nightmare, either.
Worrell!
What have you done?!
What have you done to the tree?
A whole world of trees,
and you had to pick this one!
Well, we didn't know this was your land,
or we would've asked if it was okay.
It will open the ancient door
and all that lurks inside!
Flee this evil place!
Flee!
Old Lady Hackmore!
Wow! I thought she never
went out of her house.
Probably some simple
misunderstanding.
Maybe I should go
and have a talk with her.
They will return...
Well, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
We're not really on your place,
more like above it.
- Couldn't we talk air rights?
- Get away. Get away.
- That was spooky.
- Yeah.
Come on. I think
they went this way.
Yeah. They got to be
around here somewhere.
It's the Murdocks!
All right.
Battle stations.
Let's see how this baby works
under actual field conditions!
Let's go!
Time to get even.
Tearing up this place
will be major fun.
Yeah. I wonder
where the wimps are.
- Get down!
- Watch this!
I've got 'em in my sights...
lock and load...
and... fire.
Aah!
Load me up.
Ammunition coming in--
pepperoni and cheese.
More ammo, Rimshot.
Good boy!
Let's go!
Fire.
Fire three! Got him!
Bingo!
Chicken liver comin' up.
Now!
Way to go, Joey!
Ugh!
That's delivery, boys!
Aah!
Direct hit!
Ew! A pizza mess!
Binder, this isn't
the end of this!
Yeah.
They're on the run!
And no collateral damage,
either.
All right!
That was great!
Halt! Who goes there?
Uh, don't shoot.
Don't shoot.
I'm on your side.
Sorry, Ernest. I guess
we're still a little bit jumpy.
Guess what happened.
The Murdocks came by.
But they never had
a chance.
Yeah, and the Botswanians
kicked butt.
Told you.
Hey, Ernest, what was
Mrs. Hackmore going on about?
Oh, she still believes in
trolls and magic spells
and things like that.
Trolls? Like hide under bridges
and eat little girls?
Cut it out, dork.
It's like the legend
of Trantor.
Elizabeth, get a life.
Just because you write
a report about it
doesn't mean it comes true.
She told me about this troll
that had red, glowing eyes
and walks like this.
And if he ever gets loose,
he'll go after
the children first.
And he turns them into
little wooden dolls,
which gives him his power.
And that ugly little rascal
is still alive...
down there.
But...
He can
only be awakened
on the night
before Halloween...
Like tonight.
... when a Worrell...
Like you.
... places his hand on a tree--
like this-- and says,
"Yea, I call thee forth, Trantor."
But what are the
chances of that happening?
Looks like some rain!
Wouldn't be safe here!
Uh, hey, wait a minute, fellas.
Wait. Hold on.
Hey, guys, wait for me!
Hurry, Elizabeth!
Hurry!
Let's go!
Hey, everybody,
where are you going?
Can't you see I'm up here
all...
Alone?
Easy, Rimshot.
Easy, boy.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
After all, we've got the... high ground.
Yeah.
Good suggestion, Rimshot.
Why didn't I think of that?
Why don't we go on home?
How 'bout it?
Aah!
Boy, I sure hope
you're from Keebler!
You better back off!
You don't want to fight me!
I know tai chi, kung fu,
Shao-lin.
I saw Hulkamania
three times, once in slow-mo!
Back off!
Oh, don't kill me!
Don't kill me!
I don't want to die!
All right.
Civilization.
See you, guys. I'm already late,
and my mom's gonna kill me.
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm out of here, too.
Later, dudes.
See y'all tomorrow.
Aah!
Somebody help me!
Help-- anyone!
Help!
Somebody! Ernest!
Kenny! Elizabeth!
Where are you?
Oh, no!
Oh, help! Come on!
Hey, I got ya.
Thanks, Ernest. You saved me.
I thought I was a goner.
A-a-a-a-a-a-ah!
Sheriff!
Sheriff Binder!
Sheriff Binder! Open up!
Aah!
Sheriff Binder, open up, please!
Help!
It was a monster!
It was awful!
The tree and the lightning
and--
and it had great, big teeth
and things on its ears like this
and its head was at least
this big and about this long--
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Ernest, slow down. What happened?
Ernest, do you know
what time it is?
Maybe Old Lady Hackmore was
right-- maybe it was a troll!
Luckily, I was there to beat it
within an inch of its face--
Hold it.
Old Lady Hackmore?
Yeah, the kids and I built a treehouse
out there, and she got real steamed--
You took Kenny and the kids
out there,
trespassing
on that old lady's land?
Yeah, but what happened?
Sheriff, I saw a troll!
I really saw a troll!
Dad, something really strange was
happening in those woods tonight.
Yeah, you got to
believe me, sheriff!
Yeah, look, Ernest, whoa.
Listen, you just had a nightmare, okay?
- So pinch yourself...
- Ow!
... and go on home--
No, I'm not dreaming. This isn't a
nightmare. That really hurt.
- We'll talk about it tomorrow.
- This thing was huge!
It had this great,
big head--
Good night, Ernest.
It was probably just--
well, it was more about--
it was about this tall,
and it looked like a giant,
big Mr. Potato Head,
only as big
as a watermelon...
Grow, my children, grow.
Oh, Miss Hackmore!
Miss Hackmore!
I'm sorry to bother you.
You have bothered
the whole planet.
You're cursed, now you're
rubbing it off on me.
But it's about
what you said.
I...
I let the troll out.
Uh...
That which has been promised
is delivered.
I-It was huge!
It had a great, big head and
little, tiny, beady eyes,
and great, big noses!
They were...
it was horrible!
You haven't seen horrible till you
see what it does to the children.
Heaven help us.
Them that dies will be
the lucky ones!
Oh!
I felt it!
Heaven, help us.
After all these years,
that thing is loose again.
Oh! Vampires,
werewolves...
Well...
I can handle that.
A few crucifixes,
a little garlic...
perhaps a silver bullet.
Ahhh.
Ghouls, zombies...
It has been
my lifelong wish
that this book
would never be opened,
but, of course,
you've changed all that.
That's him!
That's the guy!
The prophecy fulfilled.
"From the innocence
of five,
"an evil army shall arise.
"When blossoms
shower down like rain,
"my dark kingdom
will come again.
"There is one who can
stop me if he will dare,
"with the heart
of a child...
and a mother's care."
Are there
any more pictures?
You've got to stop him
before he gets the children.
He's got to get five before
midnight tomorrow night!
Me? Stop that thing?
You've got the wrong guy.
You are the direct
descendant
of the Reverend
Phineas Worrell!
It's your legacy!
Yeah, but I'm me,
and-- and he's he,
and we're talking
real danger here--
"stand and deliver,"
"firing line,"
"moment of truth,"
"end of the line,"
eighth-level
"Mario Brothers."
You are the only
troll fighter we've got.
You're the seventh son
of the seventh son.
You're the baby.
You're the boy.
You are the great
redneck hope.
The great redneck hope.
" Hallelujah "
Troll alert!
This is not a drill!
An actual troll
has been sighted
in the Briarville area!
Please remain calm!
Do not-- I repeat--
do not panic!
Children should remain indoors
until further notice...
What's Ernest
yelling about now?
Something stupid
about trolls.
Make sure your shoes
are on the right feet
and all your furniture
is pushed up against the wall!
Work with me, people,
work with me!
We've got a situation here!
Trolls!
Get off the streets!
Prepare for the worst!
The trolls are coming!
Hurry, Bobby, hurry.
Come on, time is money.
Time is money!
We got a lot of
merchandise to move, now.
Are you ready?
Roll 'em.
Hello, friends,
this is Tom Tulip
with Tulip Brothers'
One-Stop Salvage.
This is my big brother,
Bobby.
A fella comes in here the
other day, and he says to me,
"Will Tulip Brothers
give me a good deal
on an outboard motor
and some taxidermy supplies?"
And I said, "Does
a fat puppy hate fast cars?"
And then he says to me,
"Well, will you give me
a good deal
"on some surplus government
canned goods
and assorted socket
wrenches?"
And I said, "Does a one-legged
duck swim in a circle?"
But, no,
seriously, folks--
Tom, you got to help me!
There's a troll
on the loose, a troll!
Ernest, Ernest!
Cut, Bobby, cut!
Can't you see we are engaged
in mass communication here?
But I got serious
problems-- trolls!
Oh, trolls! Bobby, our friend
Ernest is seeing trolls.
Trolls?
Trolls.
Oh, this is your lucky day,
but, of course, you knew
that when I was stationed
in Germany
with the 82nd airborne,
I was in charge of
the troll-destruction unit.
Have I got a deal for you.
Huh ah-huh huh huh.
Sorry I'm late.
Isn't Joey here yet?
No, Joey never got home
last night.
What do you mean?
You said Ernest came by our house
last night yelling about trolls.
Do you think maybe--
Come on, there's
no such thing as trolls.
But Ernest saw something
out at the tree,
and he's never lied
to us before.
Yeah, but trolls? Come on,
let's go check out the treehouse.
Maybe Joey's there already.
I don't know.
You're not scared,
are you?
Four tin cans,
Troll Away spray,
$ 19.95 apiece,
two Bolivian Army
slingshots...
Oh!
- $9.95 each,
Day-Glo troll waders,
$ 119.50,
oh, troll ninja
nun-chucks, $9.95,
slimeproof troll gloves,
$49.95,
chopped troll bait,
$3 a pound...
50 pounds,
14 No Troll strips,
only $9.95 each,
and one trolling motor,
$ 79.95,
for a grand total of...
$ 1,749.98...
- Plus tax.
Does that include
the giant album
with every troll love song
ever written?
Do rattlesnakes
kiss carefully?
Joey?
This place
looks different.
Joey?
Something really weird's
going on here.
I told you.
It's the legend.
Look at that!
That hole wasn't there
yesterday!
It looks just like...
Joey.
What if it is Joey?
- What if it really is?
Something's there!
Run for it!
You see before you
the state-of-the-art
troll fighter of tomorrow.
This multidirectional,
unitized,
high-tech fighting machine
is salt-free, tuna-safe,
and comes complete
with 15 megabytes
of double-density,
wafer-thin alloy,
forming a virtual reality
of modern
troll extermination.
Need I say more?
Ernest is here!
Come on!
We can't go in there!
That's Old Lady Hackmore's place!
It's all right.
He'll know what to do.
Oh!
Aaah!
Anybody home?
Anybody here?
- Hi, guys!
- Ernest!
- We went to the treehouse!
- And there were five holes!
And in one of the holes, there
was a little wooden dolly.
And it looked
just like Joey.
Ernest! With every passing hour,
the danger grows greater!
Who are they?!
A mother's care--
what does it mean?
Don't pay any attention to her.
She's a Gemini.
And besides,
i-it's a full moon,
ah heh, know what I mean?
Ohh.
The troll
is getting stronger.
He has one child
already.
By now, the tree is sprouting
its cursed pods.
Pods?
Pods!
And if they touch the ground,
all is lost!
He needs four more souls
before he can release
his army
and start to capture
the children
all over the world.
Just the kids?
Listen to the last two lines
of the troll's poem.
"There's one who can stop us
if he will dare,
with the heart of a child
and a mother's care."
So...
we need a heart...
a child's heart!
You wouldn't really sacrifice
someone, would you, Ernest?
Yeah,
that was pretty crazy.
Well, human sacrifice would
definitely be a last resort.
Now, traps
is where it's at.
You see, Mr. Big, Bad,
Short, and Ugly
will probably come strolling
through the woods
saying something like,
"Oh, I sure could use a rest,
"maybe catch a movie
on the cable.
Think I'll check in
to this troll motel."
And then we got him.
And with this alarm system,
the minute something steps
in our trap,
the beeper will go off.
And endo trollo,
comprendo?
Aaaaaaah!
Ahhhhhh!
Come on, I'll walk you
to your house.
Hurry up, Kenny,
we got work to do.
I still don't see why I
can't go with you guys.
Just leave
the troll fighting to us.
I'll find my dad.
He'll know what to do.
What about the party?
You stay here tonight.
Another soul.
Feed and grow strong,
my little ones.
Thanks
for the ride home, Ernest.
Okay, here's the plan--
Troll Fighter One--
that's me--
will be roaming
the streets of Briarville
like a rabid dog --
no offense--
whilst Troll Fighter Two--
that's you--
Um, Ernest, how about
I just get my dad
and meet you at the tree?
Yeah, your dad
might get mad
if we wrap this one up
all by ourselves.
What's the matter, Kenny?
Did a troll make you
wet your pants?
You're such a wimp,
Binder.
Kenny, what is going on?
Nothing. I'm okay.
Where's dad?
Where have you been?
I-I was with Ernest
setting troll traps.
Kenny, you have no business
being with Ernest.
Mom, I got to find dad.
It's really important.
Kenny-- Kenny,
you come back here!
Bye-bye!
Happy Halloween!
Be careful! Bye-bye!
Take care!
Honey, you hardly touched
your dinner tonight.
Now, this is just
Halloween.
It's supposed to be fun,
playing dress-up
and trick-or-treating.
But, mom, that little doll
looked just like Joey,
and Ernest said--
Honey, we have been
through all this.
There are no such things
as trolls.
Uh, mom...
while you're in here,
could you check
under the bed?
I thought I heard--
Stop acting
like you're 2 years old.
There is nothing
under the bed.
Now, put on your costume
and come on downstairs.
We're all going over to
the Halloween party together.
But, mom--
Elizabeth,
don't be silly!
There's nothing
under the bed.
Oh, Snuffies...
it's just you.
Aaaaaaah!
You know, Rimshot,
when it comes to
catching trolls,
sometimes the old ways
are the good ways,
know what I mean?
You disguised
as a yummy, little child,
will be the bait,
and this should put an end,
once and for all,
to the beast of Briarville.
You know, Rimshot...
you're a cute, little dog,
but you are
one ugly little kid.
Okay, Rimshot,
now, bring me the stick.
The stick, boy.
Bring me the stick!
Please, Rimshot,
I was just kidding about
that ugly thing, honest.
Rimshot!
Ow!
Wa-aaaaaaaaaah!
Well, Rimshot, it's time
to get our blood sugar
back up into the combat range,
you know what I mean?
This is serious.
I better use my C.B. voice.
Blue Leader,
this is Troll Fighter.
Come on back,
how 'bout you?
Roger, Troll Fighter.
This is Blue Leader.
Bobby, don't worry--
safety first.
Get to work.
What's your 20, Troll Fighter?
Come on over.
We are en route
to the big tree,
where we will be AWAC
at 2300 hours
and some change.
Well, this is it,
the big night,
the great confrontation
between man--
that's us--
and the country-and-western
troll you're so fond of.
Trolls.
Right, Ernest, right.
Now, you stay alert.
You see anything,
you give us a holler.
Over and out.
Come on, let's go.
Oh-oh-oh-ohhh!
You know, Jimmy,
a hungry lion hunts best,
but an army travels
on its stomach,
know what I mean?
You going to the big party
over at the school, Ernest?
Nope, someone has to
stand vigil over the town,
stay at his post,
row the boat,
be ever alert,
floss between meals,
remain steadfast
and truncated,
know what I mean?
Gosh, Jimmy,
what's got into you?
Oh, oh, charades. I love charades.
Let's see, something big.
A-A big mouth?
Let's see, big.
Uh, big bill?
big bird?
Big bill? Big beak?
Big, uh, uh, sounds like--
uh, two, two, "T"--
tea for two?
"T"-- two "T"?
Tea for two?
Two for tea?
Desmond Tutu?
Uh, two barrels?
Ah ha.
Boy, Jimmy, when you play charades,
you really play for keeps,
know what I mean?
Oh! Ah ha.
Hey, Greg,
have you seen my dad?
No. Where's your costume?
We're supposed to be
at school now.
Kenny.
Did you hear that?
Yeah, it-- it sounded
like Elizabeth.
Over here, Kenny.
Elizabeth?
Elizabeth, is that you?
She's not in--
Over here, Kenny.
You cannot escape.
It's time to join
your little friends.
Faster, Kenny.
I'm catching up.
Hurry, Kenny.
I'm right behind you.
She wouldn't leave
through the window!
- Cliff, she didn't even want to go out!
- Joey never came home.
- Why aren't you doing something?
- We are doing something, all right?
My trash hasn't been picked up
in two days, Cliff.
I'm having houseguests!
Cliff, Cliff!
Hush! Hush!
- Hush, hush, hush, hush, hush!
- What?!
- Cliff, have you seen Kenny?
- No, he's supposed to be with you.
No, he ran off
to find you.
All right, listen, he's probably
already just gone to the school.
- I don't know where he went.
- Just go to the school and look for him.
I have houseguests
coming, Cliff!
Listen! Listen!
They're probably already
over at the school.
Hey, kid, get out
of the street!
And you in the costume,
watch out!
Yeah, Rimshot,
we've got to stay focused
tonight.
We've got to keep our senses
honed to a razor's edge,
know what I mean?
We are the thin line
of defense
that lies between victory
and certain death,
and I guess you know
the one I'm hoping for.
Troll alert!
Troll alert, Rimshot!
We got him!
We got old hockerhead
himself!
We did it, Rimshot.
We got him.
Listen to him howl.
Yeah, but it's too late
for Mr. Big, Bad Troll.
You picked the wrong guy
to tangle with...
Squid Lips.
Dad, there really is a troll!
I saw it with my own eyes!
It was horrible!
It used Elizabeth's voice!
It turned Greg into a doll!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Listen, young
man, you are in big trouble.
You disobeyed your mother, and now
she's worried sick about you.
Cliff, it's my boys.
They're gone, vanished.
They were supposed to meet me hours
ago, and nobody's seen them.
Have no fear,
Ernest P. Worrell is here.
And, sheriff, I captured that troll
that's been stealing all the children.
Ernest, what do you mean
you caught that troll?
Yes, with the aid
of the most advanced
troll-fighting equipment
known to modern technology--
Shut up, Worrell!
Cliff, you got to get out
a search party for my boys.
Dad, Ernest and I
set troll traps!
Listen to him!
He's not lying!
Yeah, I've got him
right outside, sheriff.
All right, listen,
I don't know what's going on
here, but let's take a look.
Come on, let's see it,
Ernest.
Uh, Cliff...
I want an all-points bulletin
out on my boys now!
You leave the police work
to me, mayor.
Ernest, open it up.
You want me to
squash him flat, sheriff?
Just open the damn thing,
Ernest!
Slowly.
Oh!
Some heads are gonna roll,
ain't they, daddy?
Blech!
Boys.
Boy, you've done it
this time.
Ernest, I don't believe it!
Of all your screw-ups!
But, mayor, there really is a troll.
I saw it.
Ernest is the only one
trying to do something.
Kenny, that's enough
from you.
That does it, Worrell.
You're fired!
Uh, but, uh, I--
the beeper!
You park the truck,
you turn in the keys,
and you get outta here!
Let's go, boys.
Ernest, you've been acting
like a child
about this troll thing.
It's time to grow up.
But I saw them.
They were--
Kenny, come on.
Kenny...
Tell him.
Kenny, get in the car!
I guess I really blew it
this time.
We're finished
in this town.
So much for being a hero.
Thanks, but it's no use.
I'm a Worrell...
cursed...
bottom of the gene pool...
no money down...
nothing to live for.
Yow!
Rimshot!
Thanks!
I needed that!
You're right.
I've never been a quitter.
Why-- why, I've never known
when to quit.
Just ask
my fourth-grade teacher.
He never knew
when to quit.
Oh!
Eliza, Michael,
Allison, Joshua...
Your time has come,
my children.
One more, and the cycle
will be complete.
Well, Rimshot, I-I guess
there are no trolls here.
Ha ha.
Golly!
Do you believe that?
This reminds me of that
moment from the movie
"Brain Barnacles
from Planet Tycor,"
you know, when the brain
barnacles were getting set
to latch themselves onto
the brain of Queen Paternia?
And then--
Golly!
They look just like
Brussels sprouts.
I hate Brussels sprouts,
don't you?
We better go tell
Miss Hackmore.
Gosh, Rimshot, pretty
soon, kids won't have to worry
about eating
their Brussels sprouts
'cause the Brussels sprouts
will be eating them!
Aaaaah!
Quick, Troll Away!
I can't believe it!
It worked!
Oh, but not for long!
He's on the roof!
Uh-oh!
We've got to do
something!
Aaah!
Tom, Bobby!
Tom, Bobby, help!
Mayday, Mayday,
Christmas Day, Columbus Day!
Tom, Bobby,
do something!
He's on the roof!
Tom!
Come on in, Troll Trapper,
this is Blue Leader. Come on back.
Tom, Bobby!
Tom, Bobby, help!
Aaaaah!
You're gonna pay for the sins
of your forefathers!
I didn't have four fathers,
I just had one father,
and I didn't know him
that well!
Ah ha ha. Too smart
for you, huh?
Aaaaaaah!
Aaah!
Aaah! Aaah!
Get away from me,
snot locker!
Whoa!
Wa-aaah!
Okay, stubby, how 'bout
a little off the top?
En garde!
Uh-oh!
Aaah!
Aha!
Little did you suspect
that I am a master
of hedge-clip-kito,
the secret oriental fighting
art of Japanese gardeners.
Yuh!
We did it, Rimshot!
We got him!
I am Troll Fighter
Number One.
Uh-oh.
Rimshot!
I don't believe it,
Rimshot.
He's pulling against...
200 horsepower.
Put it in reverse.
Oh, no!
How 'bout a bumper sandwich,
booger lips?
Ah heh heh heh heh heh
heh heh heh.
Bonsai!
Bingo!
You got him, Rimshot.
Way to go!
Where'd he go, Rimshot?
Where'd he go? He couldn't
have just disappeared.
By now, he must be
a greasy spot on the road.
Where did he go?
Wa-aaaaah!
Aaaaah!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Watch out, Bobby!
Oh!
Uh! Uh! Uh! Uh!
Ow.
So I was mesmerizing him
with my lightning moves--
Ow! Ah!
And I was about to lower
that coup de grass--
Ow! Ah!
When old booger lips
here-- Ow!
Called timeout--
Ow!
And sucker-punched me.
Oh, look. Look at this.
There's--
there's two pages
stuck together.
"How th--
looks like 'thou'--
canst destroyeth a troll."
"Thou canst destroyeth
the troll with-- "
Uh, M-I-something-K.
We can destroy a troll...
The pods
have not yet dropped.
Midk.
Trantor still seeks
another child.
That's it!
Authentic Bulgarian miak.
They're at the school.
We've got to go.
Ow!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Look, kid, go inside
and find your mother
and stay with her.
And I don't want you to leave
her side for any reason.
- Do you understand me?
- Yes, sir.
All right.
There you go.
Tom...
Tom, have you seen
Elizabeth?
Uh, no, I haven't.
Kiwi fruit, kiwi fruit!
Everybody loves it!
Kiwi fruit!
Kenny?
Kenny.
Tom and Bobby's
own recipe.
Stir-fried sushi.
Good evening and welcome to
the Briarville Halloween gala.
Smile, smile.
Mrs. Johnson,
have you seen Kenny?
No, I haven't, and we really
can't wait any longer.
Ernest's troll probably
got him.
... the hottest band
in Taylor County--
The Fun Box.
Come on, Rimshot.
Of all the people
in the world, why him?
Look, you wanted to be
in the costume competition,
and this is the costume
you picked out at the store.
This thing looks silly.
And I'm not gonna wear it.
Don't you talk back to me.
Now, you march right
in there.
I hate you!
Well, I'm not too fond
of you either!
Mommy... I'm sorry.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Unconditional love.
That's the heart of a child.
Trolls! Trolls!
Save the kids! Trolls!
Tro--
Uh.
It's my privilege
to welcome you
- to the costume competition--
- Run for your lives!
Trolls!
Ernest!
Will somebody get him
out of here? Now!
Run for your lives!
Shh. Shh.
Now, as your mayor,
it's my privilege to bring you
the costume competition.
And to start it off--
our first contestant
is Rachel Benson
from Miss Johnson's
fourth-grade class.
Rachel...
Eeeww, scary costume.
I know a dork
when I see one.
Matt!
Matt! Matt!
Help! Help!
Aaaahhh!
Please,
I've got to find Ernest.
It's the end of the line
for you, shortchange.
Aloha, sayonara,
el rancho grande.
You're history, pal.
You're Elvis.
So, come on, crater face,
I'm ready for you.
Let's see how you like
a little miak.
Miak?
Yeah, miak.
I bet you thought I couldn't
find any this time of year.
Well, I'm a little
too resourceful for you,
a little too light
on my feet.
So, come on,
eat miak and die--
Uuuhhhhhhh!
Rimshot, come back!
Ohhhh.
Wa-aaahhhh!
Ahhh!
Uh! Uh!
Huh?
Huh.
What happened?
Oh, Ernest,
are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah.
When that thing saw who
it was fooling with,
it was drop back and punt,
regroup,
troll trauma time.
Yeah, this guy
is bad to the bone.
Ernest...
Rimshot.
Rimshot, old boy.
What am I gonna do?
He's all I got.
Don't worry, Ernest.
We'll find some way
to beat this thing.
I'll tell you
how we beat this thing--
how we do it--
my great-great-grandaddy
put him in that hole,
and so can I.
Somebody with a runny nose
is gonna die.
Yeah! Go get him!
Mother's care...
milk.
That's it... milk.
You're one dead troll,
you pint-sized,
sawed-off bucketmouth.
That thing's got my son.
We've got to kill it now!
It's up to us!
Wait, what are you talking about?
Kill what? Go where?
Ernest says it's at a tree
at the Hackmore place.
Yeah, dad, it's milk.
Milk kills the troll.
Let's go.
We're wasting time.
Hang on, mayor.
What?
It's the mother's care,
the ice cream-- milk!
Let's go.
Murdock--
Kenny, listen,
wait here, all right?
Your mother's looking for you.
We'll take care of this.
Murdock!
What's the matter, boy?
There's no time to waste.
My dad told me
to stay here.
Sometimes you got to do
what you know is right,
no matter what
anybody tells you.
What good's a wooden dog?
Oh, sure, they swim better,
but what am I gonna call him?
Splinter?
Hey, Binder...
Sorry about Matt.
How do we take
this thing out?
Follow me.
- Yeah! Come on!
- Yeah!
Come on!
One final soul
to set my children free.
Raaaaaarrr!
Okay, booger lips, it's time
for troll squish-kabob.
Aaahhhh!
You okay, Rimshot?
Good.
Another advantage of being
a wooden dog.
Where'd he go?
Uh-oh.
There's your big-time
Brussels sprouts.
We can't let these
hit the ground, Rimshot.
Got that?
Got it.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
Uh-oh.
Oh, no.
This looks real bad.
Ooohhh.
Not another one.
Heh heh heh heh.
Time to put a lid on this.
A little body pressure
should do the trick.
Wa-aahhhh!
Hit the end of the aisle
and split up!
What are you kids doing?!
It's an emergency!
- Hey, you can't ride in here!
- This is important!
Get out of this store!
Go for the ammo!
Those costumes
don't fool me!
Move it!
Let's go!
The milk!
I'll get the milk!
Let's go!
Come on!
Kenny Barton, when your father
hears about this, he's gonna--
Wait! Whoa!
We're running
out of time!
Yeah! Ha ha ha!
This is getting out of hand.
Devour the human.
And the crowd goes wild.
This one's over the fence
and out of the park.
This looks like three more
R.B.I.s.
Uh!
Diihh!
Attack! Attack!
Spread out.
We'll find it.
There's nothing to worry about, folks.
I got it all under control.
Uh!
Hold it right there.
Hold it.
You-- hey, stop.
Wait a minute.
Let go of me.
Give me that.
Let go of my shotgun.
Yaaahhh!
Don't you have any respect
for authority?
Come on, you!
There's another one!
Uh huh!
Uh, your shoe's untied.
Think of a number between 1 and 10.
Was it 2?
Ahhhhh!
Ah-ahhhhh!
Ahhhh!
Oh, no.
They're gonna blame this
all on me.
Oh ho ho ho ho ho.
Bobby, pictures of these things
in the National Enquirer
will make us rich
beyond our wildest dreams.
Get the camera out.
Go, go, go.
Oh, gorgeous.
Money, money, money,
money, money, money.
So you want
to play rough, huh?
Ahhhhhh!
Ha ha ha.
Oh, I can just see
the headlines now.
"Briarville businessman has close
encounter with alien nation."
There's more.
Let's go.
Hoo hoo.
Help me! Help!
Get it off of me!
There's a troll on my back!
Worrell selects a ball
and steps to the line.
It looks like
a tricky 7-10 split.
A hush falls over the crowd.
There's a troll on me!
Help!
Here it comes.
The famous Worrell twist...
the release...
Yes! It's good!
The crowd goes wild!
I'd like to thank you,
each and every one,
for this beautiful
bowling trophy.
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
He never knew
when to quit.
Oh.
Kenny? Kenny!
We can't stop now.
Bring me the head
of Ernest P. Worrell.
Say, I'll bet you guys have
trouble meeting girls.
Don't know what to say, what
to do, how to get things going.
Heh heh heh.
Well, here's the answer
to your problems.
It's the Pimco largemouth bass CD
and home-entertainment center.
A state-of-the-art sound system
mounted on genuine veneer.
But wait, there's more.
Ahhhhh!
I'm too young to die.
Don't kill me.
Ohhhhhhh.
Don't kill me, please.
I hope I'm not too late.
Ohh!
Give me back that gun!
No! Put that down!
That's loaded!
Hey!
Oh, no, not the bullets.
Too fast for you?
Too smart for you, too.
- Ow!
Gotcha.
Ah heh heh heh heh.
Here we go again.
No, no, no.
Here, here, get the milk.
Come on.
Let's go.
Dad.
No.
You sure this milk thing
is gonna work?
We're gonna find out.
Whoa. No.
Kenny! Kenny, no!
No! Kenny, no!
Milk works, dad.
It really works.
Yes!
Get the key.
Here. I gotta go.
Kenny!
Go get 'em, Kenny!
Come on, guys.
Let's go get 'em.
Ahhhhh! Ahhh!
I've only got a couple
of things left.
Ernest!
Hold on!
I'm coming up!
Stop it.
This is just the kind of Halloween
prank that gets people hurt.
Ow!
Hey, butt breath!
Huh?
How'd you do that?
It's the milk.
It eradicates them.
Yeah, it gets
rid of 'em, too.
Sayonara, snot wad.
E-e-e-e-e-w.
Evil demons...
make me strong.
Ahh!
Your time has come.
Tonight the spell
will be broken.
At last our prayers
have been answered.
Soon, my little ones, soon.
Aaahhh!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhhh!
Hey! Let me go!
What are they up to?
Don't worry, kid.
We got the high ground.
Did you hear something?
Boy, I sure did.
We came, we saw,
we took the high ground.
Even though some of us
are very tired.
Trolls, is it?
Oh, great,
I have to defend the fort
with a multiple personality.
Ew, look, they're using
those hook things.
Where's my machine gun?
Where's my little machine gun?
We were looking for a good scrap
when we found this one.
Now, chin up,
every man jack of you.
A little nasal hygiene
would go
a long way, young man.
Here you go.
I hope you're grateful.
Little trolls in China
don't even get milk.
Ahhhh!
Hair spray will fix
anything.
This is big money.
Posters, troll action
figures, trading cards.
Hey!
You, come back here!
Bobby, do something!
He's eating the film!
No!
Oh.
Bobby...
This was our ticket
to the big time.
We're finished.
Only a few more to go.
Load it up.
You sure this will stop
them trolls?
They look awful
goddang fierce to me.
Anybody can whip a troll.
Ace, the wall.
Eat lactose, slimeball.
Hold on, dad!
Son, stay back!
Stay back, son!
You fellas like, uh, a little
bit of this milk punch?
That milk
must have gone bad.
I'm sorry, men,
but the dropper is the only way.
Oh, no, not the dropper.
The doomsday dropper.
Oh, no, not that.
Is there no mercy?
I like it.
A woman's work
is never done.
I guess I'll have to
finish this myself.
Come, demons.
Work your worst.
Make me now invincible.
A whole troll army wiped out,
and they leave the last two
for me.
Victory is ours.
All right!
We'll never be hungry again.
Talk about relief, oh.
No muss, no fuss, the trolls
are dust, know what I mean?
Yeah. We did it.
We won.
You know,
I knew when the chips were down,
I could count on you,
pilgrim.
Thanks, Ernest. You did
pretty good yourself.
You're a great bunch
of guys.
All right, Kenny!
Way to go, Kenny!
All right!
You don't understand.
It's not over yet.
Uh-oh.
Kenny, behind you!
We've got to do
something!
Kenny!
Oh, my God!
Kenny, get out of there!
Kenny, jump!
Kenny,
I told you, it's the legend.
Ernest!
I've grown too strong
for that.
Not even milk
can stop me now.
Errrneeeeest!
Kenny!
No!
Kenny... Kenny...
Ah!
You've had a nasty cold
ever since we met.
It's going around, you know.
- You know what they always say--
starve a fever,
feed a cold.
Or is it feed a fever,
starve a cold?
I always get that confused,
like 30 days hath
September.
It's my club and you're
a member, and, uh...
Worrell, now you die.
Come on, double ugly,
you do pretty well against
little kids and dogs.
Let's see how you deal
with a real man.
Come on.
Come on!
Kill him!
Come on, snot wad.
I got something for you.
Come on!
Ernest doesn't understand.
It's not the milk.
Unconditional love,
the heart of a child.
Unconditional love.
Yeah!
Kill him!
Heart of a child,
unconditional love.
Kill him!
Come on, little fella.
Oh, you're so cute.
E-e-e-e-e-w.
Great. You did it.
You're a real hero.
Yeah, you really did it.
You're a legend.
Yeah,
he never had a chance.
With my brains and speed,
he never knew what hit him.
Yeah,
it almost wasn't fair.
Here, he had
some good moves,
but when the chips
were down...
Huh?
But, you know, when you're
fighting those trolls,
you gotta sock 'em one...
- Kenny!
- right in the kisser.
Like my ancestor Phineas
used to tell me,
"Ernie baby,
keep your weight down low."
Son, are you all right?
That was
really weird.
Mom, I told you
there was a troll.
Mike,
I'm glad to see you.
Kenny, I thought we'd
never see you again.
Mom.
Son, I did
a lot of things wrong.
I should've listened to you.
I'm so proud of you.
Thanks, dad.
Stay low,
stay sitting...
You know, Ernest,
in recognition of your
magnificent achievement,
consider that
Troll Away spray a gift.
Maybe we should open
a laundry.
Francis?
Sister Francis?
Is that you?
My sister.
Ohhh. I missed you so.
Michael, Michael,
I missed you.
How'd you get so old?
There is a lot to talk
about, but now,
everything is okay.
What's the matter,
Ernest?
There's nothing
in that tree for me.
Rimshot.
Rimshot!
Boy,
where have you been?
Did you miss your daddy?
You were gone and stuff.
And you were a wooden guy.
Now you're back, and you're
not even gone anymore.
You know
where we're going?
We're going for a ride
in the truck,
and we're gonna--
gonna go home and--
and we'll eat
nothing but the best...