KoreanDramaX.com
This drama is a fiction motivated by the people in the history. So it's different from the actual history.
Byeong Yeon.
Arrest him immediately!
No one, no one move!
His Highness's safety has to be top priority!
Everyone, make way!
Although it'll be a very difficult fight, I need to know what kind of society the White Cloud Society is and
what the wall that separates me and the people is.
Now, I must find out.
It'll probably be over that wall.
Huh?
The nation you want to create will be over that wall.
Is that it?
I really wish to see it, Your Highness.
If you really want to see it, I'll really need your help.
Please forgive my rudeness, Your Highness.
Byeong Yeon.
I believe that the world the White Cloud Society is waiting for
isn't different from the nation you dream of, Your Highness.
Over the wall that separates you and the people,
the nation that you will create,
I really want to see it.
Don't withdraw your sword!
The moment you put you sword down, I'll lose you.
Your Highness--
Don't withdraw your sword!
This is a command.
For...not being able to obey your command,
I apologize, Your Highness.
No...
No! No...
Stop!
Byeong Yeon!
Move aside.
Y-Your Majesty! Escort His Majesty!
I told you to move aside!
Byeong Yeon.
Don't forget that
if I could trust only one person in this world,
without change, that person would still
be you.
For...
trusting me...thank you  (informal).
Byeong Yeon.
Byeong Yeon! Byeong Yeon...
I wish that in my last moment,
I could just be your friend.
Stop.
Why are you leaving the palace at this hour?
Open the door.
It's a Royal Command to transport the criminal to the Royal Investigative Office immediately.
Head Eunuch. I understand.
Open the door.
They're traitors! Close the palace door!
Hurry!
What are you doing? Come out, hurry!
I'll buy some time.
Head Eunuch.
What are you doing? Escort them away, hurry!
-I apologize.-Wait...
We have to leave now.
Hey, wait. We just need a minute.
Look here, I'm his close friend. Would you allow me to at least take his corpse?
Wait!
Byeong Yeon...
Episode 17  The End for the Beginning
Your Highness, did you cough? One month later
Your Highness, did you cough?
Your--
Your Highness...
You couldn't have coughed, because you're not here.
You wouldn't have gone to the library either...it's fine.
I can just accept the scolding and the punishment, don't be worried.
Now, let's go to get scolded.
This is your first time visiting our House, isn't it?
Is it?
I've had too many drunk days that I cannot remember.
From now on, please come often.
I'll think about it.
The Crown Prince skipped the Palace Meeting again?
At first, he went against command to execute the criminal on the torture grounds,
and now, he's taking his duties as the Crown Prince so lightly.
Your Majesty.
Those royal petitions are only the 1st batch of the
royal petitions from the Confucian scholars who believe that the Crown Prince should be dethroned.
I said that I wouldn't talk about that matter anymore.
You have to.
Please do not danger this nation's peaceful politics anymore, Your Majesty.
The Crown Prince isn't the one who has endangered this nation's peaceful politics.
You accused him of being connected to the White Cloud Society when you weren't even certain, object to whatever he wants to do,
and whenever you dislike something, you ordered the Confucian scholars to write royal petitions for him to be kicked out of the palace.
That's why I'm saying this.
Your Majesty, the Crown Prince has now lost all respect and sense of duty.
Isn't this obvious as he visits the Courtesan Houses more often than he visits the Palace Meeting Hall?
Do not complicate this nation's political affairs any longer. I believe that dethroning the Crown Prince
and establishing a new Crown Prince is the right thing to do.
-Please reconsider. -Please reconsider.
Please reconsider.  Please reconsider. Please reconsider.
-Please come back again, My Lord!-Please come back again, My Lord!
Let's go back in.
Look here.
Look at me!
Is the Prince growing up well?
Yes, of course. He's getting healthier by the day.
Yes, he has to.
He'll become the Crown Prince too, of course he has to be healthy. That is also a huge advantage.
What?
Father, w-what did you just say?
Why are you so shocked?
The Crown Prince's quarters will need a new owner soon, so you should prepare.
Are you serious?
Yes, it will be finalized soon.
Yes. Yes, father.
This is regarding the newborn infant snuck out of the palace through the back doors.
If that child wasn't dead but alive, would the story change?
Your Highness, it's Eunuch Seong!
Come in.
Byeong Yeon, I'm here.
When will you reply to my greeting?
Is Byeong Yeon all right?
His physical wounds are healing.
Perhaps he wants to rest a bit longer.
He's had such a exhausting life.
Perhaps it's because he's preparing to face you.
Is there no word about Ra On?
Yes.
Are you disappointed?
No.
I'm enjoying myself having lost the sense of time.
Game of chasing tail.
I am paying attention to all of Kim family's activities including land registrations, money transactions and people.
Yes.
However, the hunt is not over when you grab hold of the tail.
They could cut the tail off and escape. Please be careful.
Yes, I will keep that in mind.
I'm all prepared.
Please prepare yourself to fill the big hole that will come about at the Royal Court.
Did you look into it?
That is...
Oh dear.
Will you not tell me straight?
Your highness, Sir Kim Yoon Seong was right.
What?
Are you saying that child is really alive?
Yes...
I saw the child being taken care of by the giesha.
Being dethroned does not necessarily lead to unhappiness.
Some have lived a long life enjoying hunting and such.
In some way, that might be a better life than being on the throne.
It does sound attractive but there is one thing that's holding me back.
It is you Prime Minister.
I don't think I can leave the Court as long as you are here.
Grandpa.
Was there no one tailing you?
No. I've checked a few times but it was fine.
I see.
It must've been tough on you.
I heard from mother.
Is Hyung Kim really here?
Is he really alive?
He didn't gain consciousness yet, but he's recovering.
That's a relief. What a relief it really is.
Follow me.
Hyung Kim.
It's me, Sam Nom.
You're still not going to wake up even though I'm here?
It must have been so hard for you to repress and hide yourself all this time.
Is that why you're resting for so long?
Fall might pass at this rate!
You have get up before all the leaves fall off the trees, ok?
Hyung Kim, when it snows for the first time, how the palace look?
When the snow falls on the big court yard at the Repentance Hall and on its low roof
it must be beautiful.
It is beautiful.
Very very much.
Hyung Kim. Are you awake?
You are such a pain. Talking your head off still.
Hyung Kim.
It hurts, it hurts...
♬ Will my heart show through those clouds and the moonlight ♬
♬ I hide at the foot of a faded wall ♬
♬ Even if a nameless wild flower joins me ♬
♬ Why am l just shedding tears by myself? ♬
The one who has more to give than anyone else in Jeseon.
I, Hong Sam Nom, give you this love.
♬ I miss you, because I miss you, you're someone I can't forget anymore ♬
Do you by chance know what Crown Prince's nickname is?
Geez, what is it?
Flower Crown Prince?
The Poop Pavilion.
I'd heard there is no one who doesn't know!
Come on!
You laugh? Geez!
I thought you had a problem smiling!
Were you disappointed that it was me?
No.
I was just a bit surprised.
Actually, I suffered a heartache recently by myself.
Because of the wedding ceremony?
I've found out who is in your heart.
I've become a Crown Princess on a deal
so it would be laughable for me to expect anything else.
So, I've decided to concentrate on my main role.
Though I am unable to comfort you like that woman,
I will remain as your assistant so you can remain as the Crown Prince,
because I'm the one who will remain at your side until the very end, Your Highness.
What have you summoned me here for?
Are you asking because you don't know?
The Crown Prince will be dethroned soon.
When will you stop being so nonchalant of the competition between you and the Prince on who will become the new Crown Prince?
Your Highness the Queen, no, Aunt.
The reason why I am keeping quiet despite knowing the truth...
Though I do not wish to acknowledge, is due to this lame reason of our bloodline.
Even so, I thought you would want to see her for once...
I'm talking about your child, His Majesty's child, that you so pitifully abandoned because of your thirst for power.
Shut up.
Confess it yourself.
That's my last act of consideration I will bestow onto you.
Your Highness, we cannot delay any longer.
Let's hurry and enter the courts.
Wait just for a while.
Your Highness, the Ambassador Jeong Deok Ho has arrived.
So, how did it go?
He was arrested at the pier on the moment he was about to escape from the capital.
After confirming, it was indeed the person who gathered the assassins that time.
Alright.
Let's go.
Without any apology or punishment for the various scandals so far
Now he even goes to the kisaeng and to the gambling.
Not fulfilling the duty of the crown prince and dropping the honor of the royal family,
an order should be made so that his behaviors like this to be stopped immediately.
Your Majesty! The Crown Prince has arrived!
Let him in.
Crown Prince, did you leave the palace again?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Where did you go?
As the Prime Minister said, I went to Courtesan Houses and gambling centers, Your Highness.
They say that you can only be a good ruler if you listen to the cries of the people.
I can't hear anything if I just remain inside the palace.
Thus, I spent the entire night with the people and listened to various worries and advice.
Are those citizens courtesans and gamblers?
That's right. Why? Is that wrong?
Your Majesty, this is something that cannot be allowed.
From ministers and officers of six ministries
the letters of asking to dethrone the Crown Prince is showering.
Your majesty, I ask you earnestly to dethrone the Crown Prince and expel him.
Please consider it
I understand all your intentions.
But even if it's time for me to go,
I was thinking of telling some interesting stories I heard while going around the brothels and gambling dens.
Would you listen to them once?
I ate it well.
Why are you so thin? Was it because your mother wasn't there when you were recovering from birth--
Mother? Watch your mouth.
I beg your pardon, Your Highness.
Where is the child?
Child?
That child that the courtesans took in and are now raising, where is she?
Your Highness, why are you looking for that child?
Could it be...
No...It cannot be, right?
Where did she go?
Just now, someone who said they were from the palace took her.
From the palace?
Crown Prince, what are you doing now?
Your Majesty, please grant me some time.
Go ahead.
Please look at these drawings carefully to see if these faces are familiar.
But...why are all their eyes closed?
Well...What do you think?
It's because they are all dead.
Some times it's because they opened their mouths wrongly; for some it's even before they opened their mouths.
It's probably because the dead do not speak.
I was surprised too. They left quite many evidences.
I traced the corpses of the assassins who raided the East Palace,
and found out who first gathered them together, gave them money, and gave them their orders.
Did we not already find out that that was the doing of the White Cloud Society?
We'll know if we ask them.
Bring him in.
Is the person who told you to gather the assasins in here?
Yes, Your Highness.
Point him out.
It is them.
Who has sent all of the farmlands to these men?
After thorough investigation, it was the Minister of Personnel's.
These are the Minister's secret books.
Your Highness, this does not make sense.
Hurry up and tell us, who's the one who told you to blame the assassination on the White Cloud Society?
It was... the Minister of Personnel and Minister of Finance!
I have committed an unforgivable sin, Your Highness!
Ministers, is what the Crown Prince speaking the truth?!
Your Majesty, how can you believe the words of Crown Prince who is surrounded by gisaengs and gamblers?!
This is all...baseless accusation!
Are you still trying to make excuses?!
Listen, Royal Investigative Officer.
Yes.
Imprison those two immediately at the Royal Investigative Office and investigate their crimes thoroughly!
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Majesty, I am wronged!
Let go! Are you not letting go?
Your Majesty, I have been maligned!
Your Majesty! Let go, let go! I am wronged!
You said that when the tail has been caught, it doesn't mean that the hunt is over, right?
If I want to stop it from escaping by cutting off its own tail, what should I do?
It is of course not easy to catch a tiger with a large body.
First its right hand, then its left.
Until you finally cut off its head,
you must never let your guard down.
There is one more thing I want to show you, Prime Minister.
This is the face of a palace maid who died without a sound a while ago.
It's said that she had given birth to a child right before her death.
However, the child was nowhere to be found.
What might be the hidden story?
Are you not curious about this woman?
So pretty!
Peek-a-boo! Peek-a-boo!
Oh there, there.
Oh...
There, there.
Peek-a-boo! Peek-a-boo!
The child...was taken by somebody supposedly from the palace.
The Crown Prince...a child?
Yes. For some unavoidable reasons he needed to take care of her.
He left her to the East Palace court ladies but I found her so adorable after seeing her
so I begged him to take her with me for a while.
I see...
Please take a look.
Is she not elegant?
Does it not hurt?
Yes, Your Highness.
Why did you sleep for so long?
I guess I did not have the face to see you, Your Highness.
You protected the woman I love and I, didn't you?
More than anything else...Thank you for coming back like this.
That person comes here occasionally and looks after me.
Once I have finished all preparations, I'll bring her back to my side.
I'll make it so that we can laugh, chat,
and be happy like in the past, by my side.
We're almost there.
When the time comes. Shall the 3 of us go back to Repentance Hall
and have a drink?
What did you say?
I asked you why that child must go up on the King's throne.
He doesn't have the blood of a Lee anyway.
How could you say such sophistry...
Please do not insult the royal family of Joseon.
There is nothing more of an insult than trying to foul the royal family's blood.
That child is definitely a prince of this country that I have given birth to.
Yes. So that everyone in the palace believes it,
so that nobody suspects,
you will have to put in effort from now on.
Father.
In the case you are unable to do so,
there will be no way for you to avoid death.
Prime Minister.
Please sit.
Did you think you would survive, Prime Minister?
Are you threatening me now?
I have no choice. What kind of person are you, Prime Minister?
Are you not a person whose lifeline is tied to me?
You are the one who sat such a vulgar woman like myself on this position.
But for that very reason your lifeline is tied to mine, do you really not know?
How could you
place a rootless child who doesn't even know of her own father's face raised by Gisaengs onto the Queen's position?
Is there a bigger sin of treason in insulting the royal family of Joseon
than this?!
Are you not going to shut that mouth?
Be forewarned if you are going to mess with me,
you'd better be firm in your resolve.
When I was young and naive I was very envious of you.
No matter how capable and powerful I become
I would always be a mere servant.
I know. That's why,
I was always hungry for a friend.
No matter how close we seemed
to you all
you are always the Crown Prince we had to bow our heads to.
Is that why
we can always be what we are now?
You, Byeong Yeon and I.
Why can we not avoid fighting each other?
I've always wanted to run away
from my grandfather and
the position of the oldest legitimate son of Kim family.
Though I'm not sure if you would believe me.
I do.
I too wanted to throw away many a times
only if I could.
I am going to do what I have to do.
Please do what you think is right.
But,
just in case you get hurt,
it worries me.
I too worry...that I might become wanting to protect my family.
Therefore, even if something happens
I think we don't need to feel sorry.
For both you and I.
It's not like we started not knowing it could happen.
(8 years ago)
Did you have a look?
Yes, I just looked at the Crown Prince very closely.
Right, what do you think?
He certainly has the face that gives an energy of royalty.
But...there is one more thing...
What is it? Don't hesitate and tell me.
That...is. He's fated to have a short life.
Further, one of his friends
has an extraordinary energy.
Yoon Seong
Uh, grandpa!
A warm personality and a strength as great as a general.
he undoubtedly has the true face of a great king.
An embroidery of a crane on the hat...
If we are to end the reign of the Lee Dynasty...
we need to find a new owner worthy of the throne.
Did you call for me?
Your Highness. The Crown Princess is here.
Please have her come in.
What brings you at this late hour?
Your highness, I've been told that the royal doctor has been bringing you a tonic
to ease your fatigue but you've been refusing them each time.
Please drink it.
Crown Princess.
Please help me to fulfill my duty as a Crown Princess, your highness.
KoreanDramaX.com
Wait a minute, your highness. Do not drink it!
Your highness. Your highness. Your highness.
Your highness. Your highness.
♬ I miss you and miss you so much I could never forget you. ♬
♬ My tears are calling for you. ♬
♬ I love you and love you so much I can't let you go. ♬