Let's travel all through the worldwide seas
Raising our battle cry
If you've made up your mind, let the signal for departure...
Ring out
We were able to escape from the set course
Translation and timing:
Vegard Aune
Along the boundary between sky and sea
Now we're rowing our way
To a hidden adventure at the dark bottom of the sea
Partially based off
One Piece HQ's manga-translation
Song-translation:
Cornman from Vegapunk Fansubs
Doesn't it sound fun just thinking about it?
Let's travel all through the worldwide seas
Raising our battle cry
If you've made up your mind, let the signal for departure...
Ring out
That feeling we had when we set sail
Is something I'll never forget
Because of that
Nothing will be able to scare me
Now, as the TRIP approaches, our racing heartbeats
Engrave a rhythm of adventure in our shy hearts
Get all the treasures
While laughing out loud
Give them all out at a big party
Making a splash
Fill your empty heart with dreams
Spread your wings
If you color your heart with the blowing wind
You will move on
Get all the treasures
While laughing out loud
Give them all out at a big party
Making a splash
Wealth...
Fame...
Power.
The man who had obtained everything the world had to offer;
The Pirate King...
Gold Roger.
The last words he spoke before his death...
Sent people from all over the world...
To the seas.
My treasures?
If you want them, they're yours!
Look for them...
I left it all at that place.
Men then traveled to the Grand Line, in pursuit of romance.
The world has now entered...
The Great Age of Pirates!
This guy is... One of the Seven Warlords of the Sea!
The Tyrant... Bartholomew Kuma!
If you were to go on a vacation, where would you like to go?
Messing with me...
I was overwhelmed by your huge reputation for a second...
But I have no need to fear you...
Negative Ghost!
And... Special Hollow!
With you snapping at me like that, I doubt you will tell me where Moria is...
That girl...
You are the "Burglar Cat", aren't you? One of Straw Hat's companions...
Huh? What? This guy... He came over here in an instant?!
He warped?
Is he after Luffy? I have to let him know...
I finally caught you... Moria!
I've been chasing his... Shadow?!
DAMMIT! HE TRICKED ME!
Odz + Moria
The Ultimate Combination of Brawn and Brains
Damn, he switched places with his shadow without me noticing!
Why you...
HEY! WAIT! MORIA'S SHADOW!
DON'T JUST LEAVE ME HERE!
WHERE AM I?!
HEY!
He got me! This is bad! I said I'd get back everyone's shadows!
Without my shadow, I'm in trouble too!
Wait, what happens if you don't have your shadow, again?
AAAAAAAAAH!!!
That's right! If we don't do anything, we'll be melted away by the sunlight!
Once the sun rises, we'll be in big trouble!
Damn, I have to hurry before the night ends!
How could this happen?
Anyway, I have to get to wherever Moria's shadow was going!
Zoro, like I said, we've got no choice but to wait for Luffy to beat Moria!
I've finally obtained the Black Blade, Shuusui...
With a huge guy like this in front of us, there's no way I wouldn't try using it!
Wah, you...
Odz!
Huh?
Now, come! I'll fight you!
Gotcha.
You're gonna fight him alone?!
Hey, Zoro! No matter how many times you try it, it's impossible for you alone!
Get back here, and stick to the plan!
Come to think about it, this sword is a lot heavier than Yubashiri...
The black blade, Shuusui...
Hey, Zoro! Out of the way!
If it's this heavy, then...
Awesome! He redirected the punch with sheer force!
Three Sword Style... 108 Pound Cannon!
It's huge!
Damn, it missed him!
He avoided that?!
Shuusui's attack... Absorbed the power of the other two and released all of it in one shot!
But there's too much random destruction around that hole...
That's proof that I'm still not good enough at using this sword...
It's really powerful, but it seems like this sword isn't very well-behaved.
This is some blade you've given me... Swordsman Ryuuma!
Did you do that? Seems like your weapon's pretty powerful.
You bastard!
I'll crush you!
Die!
Zoro's gonna be...!
Is he alright?!
You...
I've gotta get further away from him, or all I can do is dodge!
Yaaah!
This is it!
Three Sword Style 10-
This should crush you too!
Zoro!
Heh heh heh... Now, I've flattened you, right?
Huh?
He ain't there...
Where'd he go?
Dammit, I can't tell with all this smoke...
Three Sword Style 108 Pound Cannon!
That was close...
Hmph, you dodged again huh, damn monster!
Little wimp, you just keep running away!
Zoro! Hey, don't overdo it!
Even if you DO beat him, we'll only get Luffy's shadow back!
We have no idea where yours or Sanji's shadow is!
But if Luffy beats Moria, all the shadows will return at once!
Nobody has to die, and nobody gets hurt fighting a huge zombie like that!
Let's trust Luffy and keep distracting this guy!
I trust him, but he's got plenty of obstacles too.
Huh?
Trickery... An invisible man...
A spirit-being... A shadow master...
This island is full of people with abilities that mess you around.
We don't know if the enemy will even give Luffy a chance to fight properly!
You have a point.
Yeah.
If they delay Luffy until dawn... Him, me, the cook... All three of us will be unable to fight.
But if we can return Luffy to normal before dawn...
Then we'll make it, somehow!
I don't think we even have thirty minutes left until dawn...
But this sea is covered in mist... The sunlight won't reach everywhere.
The sun's about to rise, huh? So the mist is our last hope once dawn comes...
I've got to admit, I'm getting a really bad feeling about this.
Ah, found you, little ones!
What?
What's with this shaking?
What's this?
The ship got caught up in another wierd current, like earlier!
Huh? Oh! Hey, look at the sky!
You can see the early morning-sky!
The mist is starting to clear up!
What's going on?!
Could we have left the Florian Triangle?!
It must be because Odz messed around with the helm before!
Damn him... WHAT WAS THE POINT OF THAT?!
This is a really bad situation...
Thriller Bark has come out from the mist!
We're doomed!
The sun's about to rise! Then we'll die too!
It's still too early to give up!
Our "rays of hope" are fighting right now!
Hey, look at that!
Moria's shadow! It's flying towards the mansion!
What about it?
Idiot, don't you understand?! Straw Hat is chasing him...
...So if he follows that shadow, he'll end up here!
In other words, if we just wait patiently here...
Ah, I get it!
Okay, tell the captain and the others! We'll make sure to stop Straw Hat here!
Yeah, I got it!
Moria-sama! It's terrible!
Thriller Bark has left the mist!
It's Odz's fault!
Moria-sama!
I know, what about it?
We're pirates! It doesn't matter where we sail.
Uh, but...
Anyway, I have an important guest right now, so leave!
Right, "Tyrant" Kuma?
The only one of the Warlords who actually obeys the government!
I would say, "Stop distribution of this once it's been licensed", but that would be retarded, so...
Please support the series by buying the DVDs when they become available.
Right, "Tyrant" Kuma?
The only one of the Warlords who actually obeys the government!
The government propably appreciates having you around, but what are you up to?
You're the one who worries me the most out of you guys.
If you were to go on a vacation, where would you like to go?
Hey, drop that! I know what your ability is.
Did you come here to fight me?
Well, speak up! Why are you here?
I have an important message for you.
Message?
The successor to the demoted Warlord, Crocodile, has been chosen.
Kishishishi... Why didn't you say so sooner?
Which sea did they pick him up from, and who is it? They've got a lot of pirates to choose from.
The successor's name is Marshall D. Teach.
The man commonly known as Blackbeard.
Blackbeard? Never heard of him.
He used to be part of Whitebeard's first division. He has caused a lot of trouble in the world...
Dark Whirlpool!
Holy Flame, Unknown Fire!
Damn!
Die in darkness!
Great Blaze Commandment!
Flame Emperor!
I guess the news haven't spread to the sea of mist...
He was accepted after proving his power.
So, what was his former bounty?
Zero.
I get it, an unknown value... I'm surprised the government noticed him, kishi...
Well, it's good that they've filled the missing spot, right?
Now, the world's equlibrium or whatever should be restored, right?
No, I imagine it would be the exact opposite. Well, no matter.
Hmm?
The government is more worried about something else.
Ever since the Enies Lobby-incident, they've been keeping a close eye on the Straw Hats's movements.
If they followed the log from Water 7 to Fishman Island, there was a high chance they would end up here.
So, do you understand what they're afraid of?
Hmm?
The government fears that another one of the Seven Warlords will fall at Straw Hat's hands.
Are you kidding me?! They're worried about me?!
You're telling me you came here to protect me from a bunch of puny little pirates?!
If necessary, I would not object to assisting you.
WHO THE HELL DO YOU THINK YOU'RE TALKING TO?!?!
You seriously think I could be beaten by a tiny, inexperienced crew like that?!
We can not be 100% sure of how a battle will end.
During the Enies Lobby-incident... Who would have guessed that Rob Lucci would lose?
JET GATLING!!
So you're telling me that the government is so afraid of this crew that they're sending two Warlords to deal with them?! Huh?!
I am only here to give the report. I have no specific orders to help you.
Then take a good look at what's gonna happen, and tell the government this:
"The Straw Hat Pirate crew, which caused you so much trouble, have all become part of Gecko Moria's Zombie army!"
Kishishishishi!
The mist...
This is terrible.
The mist was our only hope!
Who managed to set things up so the mist cleared up now?! Now, the morning sun will hit us straight on!
Damn, in this awful situation, we have to hurry and do something about Odz...
Kishishishi... Unexpected, but the pure night sky is beautiful.
M-Moria... It's Moria!
Where?! Where?!
Hey, quit joking!
It's almost dawn. Do you guys have time to be standing around?
Why are you here? What about Luffy?!
Huh? I'm hearing Master's voice...
Hey, wait, Usopp! Where did you say Moria was?
He's right here! Look! His stomach! He's inside Odz's stomach!
His stomach?
There he is!
Kishishishishishi...
Damn that Hogback... Is this his doing, too?!
What's Moria doing there?
Then, did they manage to trick Luffy after all?
Or did he...
No way Luffy would lose!
Right.
Wierd... I heard Master's voice, but...
Ah! There! A cockpit? Why's there a cockpit in my stomach?
Kishishi... Huh? Hey!
Heh, this is pretty well made... I wanna try ridin' it too...
Hey! Moron! Don't put your fingers inside the cockpit!
Yes, Master!
This is awesome! I'm like a robot!
I'm a Giant Robot!
That was close!
I'm the Giant Robot: umm... Odz Bomber! Nice to meetcha!
What do you mean, Odz Bomber?!
Odz Bomber?
How can a zombie be a robot?! A robot needs to be more like.. Clang! Clang!
Heh heh! Giant Robot... This increases the tension!
Odz! Cut it out! Stop shaking!
Yes, Master!
Kishishishi... Now, I'll give you a chance to fight me!
If you beat me, I'll release all the shadows!
Feel free to attack all at once! However, if you don't beat Odz, you can't touch me!
That bastard... That's cheap!
If we don't beat Moria, we can't stop Odz... But Moria is inside Odz!
Nah, our target just got a lot simpler.
We've just gotta do this!
Usopp! That tiny amount didn't work, so go find a mountain of salt!
We'll purify Odz with that!
We'll just weaken him as much as we can!
Right! Leave this to us!
Hurry!
Alright, I got it!
I'll go get it!
I'm sure there was a kitched back in the mansion at the beginning! There should be more than enough salt there!
More than enough, right? Salt, huh?
Hey, Odz! Take out the Long-Nose and the route to the mansion! Don't let him get to the kitchen!
Yes, Master!
Usopp!
What's- AAAAAAH!!!
Damn! Usopp!
Usopp!
Kishishishishi...
Damn! With Moria added into the mix, now Odz has some brains on his side too!
Usopp! Where are you! Speak to me!
He is fine!
I thought we might need a lot of salt, so I went to fetch it!
BROOK?!
You saved me...
I am your Brook!
Who're you guys?
We're the Risky Brothers!
We're gonna give you an incredible power!
What's that? Stop it, AAAGH!
HOW'S THAT?!
Yeah! The power is overflowing! I can't stop!
Next time, on One Piece:
A Crazy Strategy to Turn the Tables
The Creation of Nightmare Luffy
I'm gonna be the Pirate King!