Yee-ha!
Yee-ha! Ya-hoo!
Yee, yippa-hoo! Yeah-ha!
Hi-yah, hi-yah!
¡Yviva! Hi-yah!
Hi-yah, hi-yah, hi-yah!
Come on, Sophie!
Hey! Ha ha ha ha ha, whoa!
Hey! Ho hi hi hi!
Whoa!
- Texas?
- Chihuahua steers!
- Howdy!
My name's Clanton!
This is my boy Ike! My oldest boy!
Any sweet water up beyond?
Yeah, two, three miles,
straight up the trail!
Cattle look pretty scrawny!
Yeah!
Me and my brothers
were trailin' 'em on to California!
If you ain't got 'em committed to no shipper,
I'll take 'em off your hands!
Not interested!
Make you a good offer!
Pay you in silver, three dollars a head!
Nope!
Might raise it
to five dollars silver!
Made more than that in Mexico!
They'll be a sorry-lookin' lot
by the time they get to California, son!
They'll feed out
when we get to grass country!
Sure is rough-lookin'country.
Ain't no cow country!
Mighty different where I come from!
- What do they call this place?
- Just over the rise there!!!
Big town called Tombstone!
- A fine town!
- Tombstone?
Yeah, I heard of it!
Well, me and my brothers
might!!! ride in there tonight!
Get ourselves a shave, maybe!
Glass of beer!
Yeah, you would enjoy yourself!
Wide awake, wide open town... Tombstone!
Get anything you want there!
Thank you!
James, this is mighty fine chow!
One of these days you're gonna be
as good a cook as Ma!
Well, I'm learnin', tryin'!
That's what I keep tellin' him! Corie Sue
ain't marryin' him 'cause he's so pretty!
'Cause he's such
an awful good cook!
There goes that chingadera again!
That sure is a mighty
pretty piece of brass!
Brass? That's solid silver!
Twenty-five American dollars worth
of solid silver! Ain't it, brother Wyatt?
Yeah, it sure is, James!
Don't let him fool ya!
It's gonna look mighty pretty
with them yellow curls of Corie Sue's!
Ain't that the truth now!
Let's mount up!
If we're going to town, let's get goin'!
$25 gold!
By garnies,
you sure got a bargain!
Whoa, girl. Whoa!
- So long, James.
So long, Wyatt! Morgan!
So long, Virgil!
There it is... Tombstone!
Let's go!
Good evening, gentlemen.
Welcome to the Bon Ton Tonsorial Parlor.
- Barbershop?
- Well, if you wanna call it that!
What can I do for you?
- Shave!
- Haircut?
- We give baths too!
Shave!
I don't know how to work it so good!
Only had it a week!
Come all the way from Chicago!
- Say, you fellas miners?
- No!
Prospectors, huh?
We're cattlemen.
Just passing through here.
Shave, please!
Hey!
- Hey, barber!
What kind of a town is this?
- Barber!
Well, Luke, you know your duty!
You and your marshals
go on in there and get him out!
That's Indian Charlie
in there, drunk!!!
And I ain't commitin'
suicide on myself!
- Me neither!
- No, sir! I ain't a-goin' in there!
What kind of town is this anyway?
Excuse me, ma'am!
A man can't get a shave
without getting his head blowed off!
You're the marshal?
Go get that drunk Indian outta there!
Why don't you go in
and get him out yourself?
- They ain't payin' me for it!
- And they ain't payin' me enough either!
- Ay!
Young man, you be careful!
Yee-ha!
- It's all right, ladies!
I don't blame ol' Luke!
I wouldn't go in there either!
What kind of a town is this anyway?
Selling liquor to Indians!
Put a knot on his head
bigger than a turkey's egg!
Indian, get outta town
and stay out!
How would you like to stay on here?
As marshal, I mean!
Nope! Barber!
- 200 a month goes with this badge!
- Not interested!
I'm just passin' through, tryin' to
get me a relaxin' little shave!
- We'll make it 250!
- Not interested!
Hey, Mr! Bon Ton!
- Shave, please!
- Well, we sure wanna thank you, Mr! ...
- Earp! Wyatt Earp!
- What?
You're not, by any chance,
the marshal from Dodge City?
Ex-marshal!
The cattle's gone!
James?
James!
- Mayor, is that marshalin'job still open?
- It sure is!
- I'll take it!
- It's yours!
Providing my brothers
are my deputies!
- When do you wanna start?
- Now!
Who runs the gamblin'
around here?
Doc Holliday, mostly!
- Who runs the cattle?
- The Clantons!
Old man Clanton
and his four sons!
Good evening, Mr! Clanton!
Good evening!
I'm the fella
with the trail herd, remember?
Oh, sure, I remember you!
You was right!
I didn't get very far with them!
They was rustled this evening!
That so?
Well, that's too bad!
Guess you'll be heading
for California, huh?
No, I figured
on stickin' around a while!
Got myself a job!
- Cow punchin'?
- Marshalin'!
Marshalin'? In Tombstone?
Well, good luck to you, Mr! ...
Earp. Wyatt Earp.
1864!
1882!
Eighteen years!
Didn't get much of a chance,
did you, James?
I wrote to Pa and Corie Sue!
They're gonna be
all busted up over it!
Corie Sue's young, but Pa!!!
Guess he'll never get over it!
I'll be coming out
to see you regular, James!
So will Morg and Virg!
We're gonna be around here
for a while!
Can't tell, maybe when
we leave this country!!!
Young kids like you
will be able to grow up and live safe!
Hyah! Hyah!
Well, what'd you find out?
I followed their trail
from Clanton country to the river!
They're moving cattle all right!
Well, get yourself some sleep!
There's coffee on the stove and some beans!
Morg's riding shotgun to Tucson!
Say, maybe I'd better ask around
the banks while I'm down there, huh?
No, they're too smart for that!
Chihuahua, sing us
the one about the old blind mule.
Hey, Mac, l...
I hear Doc's coming back tonight!
Maybe he is and maybe he ain't!
I ain't heard!
Well, uh, do you know
where he's been?
Tucson. Over the border.
Who knows where Doc goes?
I love poker!
Yes, sir, I really love poker!
Every hand a different problem!
I gotta do
a little figurin' here!
What would I do
if I was in your boots, Mr! Gambler?
You drew three cards
and I stood pat, and yet you raised me.
Now the question is:
What should I do?
Yeah, mighty
interesting game... poker!
Game of chance!
Listen, miss, I admire poker,
but you're increasing the odds!
I catch you doing that again, I'll run you
back to the Apache reservation!!!
- Listen, Mr! Tin-star Marshal!!!
- Where you belong!
This is Doc Holliday's town,
and when he comes back...
Oh!
Sorry, gents, but I don't like
eight-handed poker games!
Oh, Mr! Marshal,
you don't think that l...
No, no!
Well, where were we?
He just raised you, Marshal!
Oh, yeah! Well, seeing as you know
I got three of a kind!!!
I guess I'll...
Hiya, Doc!
Have a good trip?
Doc Holliday.
Nice-lookin' fella!
Doc, don't let us
have any trouble, huh?
I told you to get outta town
and stay out!
Oh, Doc, I'll cut you in
on the game!
I told you to get outta town!
Check me in, will you?
That door's for ladies
and gentlemen!
Go on with your game, gentlemen!
Well, you can cash me in!
It's getting late! I'll see you all later!
It sure is a hard town
for a fella!!!
To!!! have a quiet game
of poker in!
- Howdy!
- Good evening!
- I'm...
- Wyatt Earp! I know! I know all about you!!!
And your reason
for being here, but...
Heard a lot about you too, Doc!
You left your mark around
in Deadwood, Denver and places!
In fact, a man could
almost follow your trail!!!
Goin' from graveyard
to graveyard!
There's one here too!
The biggest graveyard
west of the Rockies!
Marshals and I usually
get along much better when, uh!!!
We understand that right away!
Get your meaning, Doc!
Good! Have a drink?
Thanks, believe I will!
Mac, a glass of champagne
for the marshal!
Make it whiskey!
You're my guest, Marshal!
Champagne!
Champagne it is, Mac!
Plan on staying here long?
A while!
Till you catch the rustlers
that killed your brother?
It's the general idea!
What's the specific idea?
I don't follow you quite!
You haven't taken into your head
to deliver us from all evil!
I hadn't thought of it quite like that,
but ain't a bad idea!
It's what I'm gettin' paid for!
Let's get down to cases, Marshal!
I, for instance!
How would you handle me
if I took a notion to break the law?
You already have!
For example!
Runnin' that tinhorn
outta town!!!
That's none of your business!
I see we're in
opposite camps, Marshal!
- Draw!
Can't!
We can take care of that
easily enough!
Mac!
My brother Morg's gun!
The big one, that's Morg!
The other one, that good-lookin' fella,
that's my brother Virg!
This is Doc Holliday, fellas!
- Hiya, Doc!
- Howdy!
Howdy!
Have a drink!
Don't mind if I do, Doc!
- Join us, Mac!
- Yes, sir! Thanks!
Gentlemen!
- Your health!
- Your health, Doc!
Thank you!
Come, come, my good man! Let me have service,
or I'll take my patronage elsewhere!
Your foot, sir!
Champagne!
That's the actor
in tonight's show!
Shakespeare in Tombstone!
Coming right up, Mr. Shakespeare.
It's been a long time
since I've heard Shakespeare!
How would you like to
join me tonight, Marshal?
Yeah, fine!
Better see he gets to the theater,
or there won't be any show!
Mac, cash in for me, will you?
Yes, sir!
Dad, take Mr! Thorndyke
over to the Bird Cage!
Bird cage? You're incarcerating me
in a bird cage, sir?
- That's the name of the theater!
- The theater?
The show! Good heavens!
The show must go on!
Lead on!
Drinks on the house!
¡Tortillas! ¡Enchiladas!
¡Con cerveza! ¡Tortillas!
¡Enchiladas! ¡Con cerveza!
May I present
my friend Wyatt Earp!
- Him? A friend?
- "He," not him!
Well, he or him,
he ain't no friend of mine!
What she's trying to say, Doc,
is, uh, we've met before!
Sort of found ourselves together
in a eight-handed poker game!
Ladies!!!
- And gentlemen!
Owing to circumstances
that I had nothing to do with!!!
The show, The Convict's Oath,
will not appear tonight!
But, as if I didn't already
have enough trouble!!!
That eminent actor,
that sterling tragedian!!!
Mr! Granville...
Thorndyke!
Has completely disappeared!
Wait a minute!
What are you acting so mad about?
Why, this is the fourth time
this year this has happened, Marshal!
Bird imitators!
Bird imitators, that's all we get!
- Gentlemen, I can explain!
- What are you fixin' to do about it?
Marshal, be reasonable! All we want
to do is to ride him around town!!!
- A couple of times on the rail!
Well, that sounds
reasonable enough to me!
Oh, no, not that!
Oh, no!
Wait a minute, boys!
Wait a minute!
I got a better idea!
Just give me 15 minutes!!!
And I think I can find this Mr! ...
- Thorndyke!
- I'll bring him back here!
Now sit down! Take your seats again!
Have another beer!
Look, Yorick! Can't you give us
nothing but them poems?
I have a very large
repertoire, sir!
Great! All right, Yorick!
Go ahead! Shoot!
Minstrel, pray help me!
Wait! I wanna hear this!
Thank you!
To be, or not to be:
That is the question!
Whether 'tis nobler
in the mind!!!
To suffer the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune!!!
Or to take arms
against a sea of troubles!!!
And by opposing end them?
To die, to sleep, no more.
And by a sleep,
to say we end the heartaches...
and the thousand natural shocks
that flesh is heir to!!!
'Tis a consummation
devoutly to be wish'd!
To die, to sleep!
To sleep, perchance to dream.
Ay, there's the rub!!!
For in that sleep of death,
what dreams may come!!!
When we have shuffled off
this mortal coil...
That's enough!
You don't know nothin'
but them poems!
You can't sing!
Maybe you can dance!
Leave him alone.
Please go on, Mr! Thorndyke!
- Thank you, gentleman!
Must give us pause!
There's the respect!!!
That makes calamity
of so long life!
For who would bear
the whips and scorns of time!!!
The law's delay,
the insolence of office!!!
And the spurns that patient
merit of the unworthy take!!!
When he himself
might his quietus make!!!
With a bare bodkin?
Who would fardels bear,
to grunt and sweat!!!
Under a weary life...
life!
Please, help me, sir!
But that the dread
of something after death!
Would you carry on?
I'm afraid!!! it's been so long!
The undiscover'd country!!!
From whose bourn
no traveler returns!!!
Puzzles the will and makes us
rather bear those ills we have...
than fly to others
that we know not of!
Thus, conscience does make
cowards of us all!
They're waiting for you
at the theater, Mr! Thorndyke!
Thank you, sir!
Shakespeare was not
meant for taverns!!!
Nor for tavern louts!
Yorick stays here!
¿Qué pasa? ¿Qué pasa?
¡Parece que hay bandidos!
My apologies, Marshal!
Ike and Phin have had
a little whiskey!
Sure! I figured they was just
having themselves some fun!
Come on, Mr! Thorndyke!
I'll take you to the theater!
- Stop!
- Stop, Pa! Stop!
Stop!
When you pull a gun, kill a man!
Yes, Pa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Tombstone, folks! All out for breakfast!
All out for breakfast!
- Come on, giddap there! Come on, giddap!
- How's it going, Earp?
- Fine!
How are things in Deadwood,
Mr! Gambler?
All right, I guess!
- Brother with you?
- No!
Get yourself some flapjacks!
Stage is leaving in 30 minutes!
See you're on it!
Thank you!
I'll prepare a room for you.
Can I help you, ma'am?
Oh, Dad's usually here
to take care of the...
Is that your duffel up there?
Yes!
How about just giving me a stack of
buckwheat cakes and plenty of molasses!!!
And a steak, blood rare,
couple hunks of bacon if you got some!!!
And a big pot of!!! coffee!
I'm looking for Dr!John Holliday!
You mean Doc Holliday?
- Well, I imagine so!
- Oh, Doc Holliday!
Why, he rode out of town about 3:00
this morning, heading south!
I don't know
when he'll be back, ma'am!
He'll most likely
be back suppertime.
Maybe you'd like to have some breakfast,
freshen up a bit!
Oh, I would like some coffee!
- Have you got a room for Miss...
- Carter! Clementine Carter!
Thank you!
See ifJosephina can't get
a couple of buckets of hot water!!!
- So she can take a bath!
- Yes, Marshal!
It's Doc's room!
You're right across the hall from him!
John's room?
Oh, that's John with a mustache!
He is a good surgeon, isn't he?
I wouldn't know, ma'am!
That's a nice picture of you!
All right, folks, all together now!
Hip, hip, hooray!
The town ofTombstone is most grateful
to you for a wonderful performance!
Mr! Mayor, I am most touched
by your tribute!
- Have one of my cards!
- Thank you very much, sir!
Sorry you're leaving, Mr! Thorndyke!
Here's your bill!
The bill!
Thank you!
Great souls by instinct
to each other turn!!!
Demand allegiance
and in friendship burn!
Good night, sweet prince!
- Good-bye, Mr! Actor!
- Parting is such sweet sorrow!
- Hyah!
Would you like
a glass of beer, ma'am?
No, thank you!
I'm looking for Dr!John Holliday!
- Who?
- Dr!John Holliday!
Oh. Well, uh, I'll see if I can
find him for you, ma'am.
Thank you!
- Go right in, ma'am!
- Thank you!
- Gentlemen!
- Buenas noches, señorita.
Hello, John!
Clem!
I'd, uh, like you to meet a friend of mine,
Wyatt Earp! Miss Clementine Carter!
We've met, John!
Good evening, Mr! Earp!
Howdy, ma'am!
I'll see you both later!
- Let's eat!
- What are you up to?
It's wonderful
to see you again, John!
You are pleased that I came?
- My coming has made you unhappy!
- It was ill-advised!
Any less ill-advised
than the way you left Boston?
How did you know I was here?
I didn't!
Finding you hasn't been easy!
From cow camp to cow camp,
from one mining town to another!
Well, I should think
that if nothing more!!!
You'd be at least flattered
to have a girl chase you!
Look, Clem!
You've got to get out of here!
- But I'm not!
- This is no place for your kind of person!
What kind of a person am I, John?
Please, go back home, Clem!
Back where you belong!
Forget the...
Does this happen
to John frequently?
Oui, mademoiselle.
Each time it's worse!
You're ill, John!
So that's the reason you left!
That has nothing to do with it!
Foolish, foolish John,
as if that would have mattered!
I tell you, Clem, the condition
of my health has nothing to do with it!
I don't believe you, John!
Then I'll give you the truth!
The man you once knew
is no more!
There's not a vestige
of him left! Nothing!
Come! I'll take you
back to the hotel!
Please, John, you can't
send me away like this!
You can't run away from me any more
than you can run away from yourself!
Now I know why you don't care
whether you live or die!!!
Why you tried
to get yourself killed!
I've heard all about you,
John, and you're wrong!
So wrong!
You have no right
to destroy yourself!
You have a world of friends
back home who love you, John!
And I love you!
There's a stage leaving
in the morning for the East!
Take it!
If you don't, I'm moving on!
Very well, John! I'll go!
Dr! John Holliday!
From where I'm standing, Earp,
that tin badge you're wearing!!!
Doesn't give you the right
to stick your nose in my personal affairs!
- What's eating you, Doc?
- Why didn't you tell me Miss Carter's here?
She told you why!
She wanted to surprise you!
Gimme a clean glass, Mac!
You're not gonna start
drinking whiskey again, are you?
Gimme a glass, Mac!
I'll pour it!
Doc!
That stuff will kill ya!
Why don't you go away?
Squall your stupid little songs
and leave me alone!
I'm gonna see
if I can get Doc to bed!
Oh, why don't you
finish your supper?
- Have a drink!
- No, thanks, Doc!
I said have a drink!
No, thanks!
I just finished supper!
Look, Doc!
I ain't tried to poke my nose
into your personal affairs!
But from where I stand!!!
A man would have to go a long ways
before he finds a finer girl than Miss Carter!
Or a prettier one,
for that matter!
Ain't a man west of the Mississippi
who wouldn't give his shirt to...
Marshal, you've said enough!
Just as you say, Doc!
And this isn't
any of your business either!
Keep that up,
and you'll be outta business!
You've just given me
a brilliant idea, Marshal!
It's time I tempted fate!
- Let's see!
Who's in here
I don't particularly like?
That's a sucker game, Doc!
There's probably 50 fellas around town
just waiting to see you get liquored up!!!
So they can fill you
full of holes!
Build themselves up
a great reputation...
the man that killed Doc Holliday!
Mac!
Gimme a hand!
Let's get him to bed!
- Don't think that's kinda...
- No, sir! No, sir!
New chair gets in next week
from Kansas City, Kansas!
Fine! Fine!
- Sweet-smelling stuff, Mr! Earp!
Sweet-smelling stuff!
Have a good breakfast?
Yeah, stowed away
a whole skillet full of ham and eggs!
Feel good!
Uh, figured on getting
a buckboard!!!
And maybe goin' up and seeJames!
Good idea!
Thinkin' I might ride out there
later this afternoon myself!
If I wasn't in the territory, I'd swear
we were back home on a Sunday morning!
Yeah, with Ma scrubbing
our necks to go to camp meeting!
By golly, I'll bet that's what it is,
a camp meeting!
Could be!
You know, I swear I can almost smell
the honeysuckle blossoms!
That's me!
Barber!
Whoa!
- Good morning!
- Morning!
You gentlemen are coming
to church this morning I hope!
We're having our first social gathering
to raise enough money to finish the church!
See, what'd I tell you!
It's a camp meeting!
Camp meeting! No such
a dad-blasted thing! Regular church!
Oh, is that what
they're building?
I was wondering what that
fresh-cut lumber was for!
Yes, sir!
Roof will be on next week!
Yes, I was hoping
that you single men would come!
- Be awful nice for the dancin'!
- Yeah!
Sis here is single!
Dad-blasted good dancer too!
Well, thank you, ma'am, but my brothers
got sort of a job of work to do!!!
And I oughta
stay around the place!
Well, keepin' the peace
is no whit less important!
Get goin', Sis! Good day!
- Good day.
- Good day!
You know, there's probably a lot of nice
people round here! We just ain't met 'em!
Come on, Morg!
Let's get started!
I'd kinda like to get back
for that dancin'!
And as for you, when Doc finds out
you butted him last night!!!
He'll twist that tin badge
around your heart!
I'm Chihuahua!
I'm Doc Holliday's girl!
Just wanted to make sure
you were packing!
- Stop slamming the doors!
People bellowing, dropping pitchers
on the floor! I get no rest!
I'm sorry, darling!
You're not mad, are you?
Sure not! What right have I got
to be mad at anyone or anything?
She's packin', Doc!
She's leaving town!
Happy, aren't you?
I ain't sad!
Get me that thing, huh?
Chihuahua,
I'm going into Mexico!!!
For a week or 10 days,
and while I'm gone...
Take me with you, Doc, will ya?
Why not?
Tell FranÇois to fix
a bridal breakfast...
flowers, champagne!
You get in your prettiest dress!
Tell him the queen is dead!
Long live the queen!
Oh... Oh, Doc!
- Mornin', Miss Carter!
- Good morning, Mr! Earp!
Are you leavin'?
Yes, I'm leaving
for the East on the stage!
Eastbound stage don't leave
till noon on Sunday!
It's a mighty short visit!
Some people think I've
overstayed my visit already!
I don't know, ma'am, but!!!
If ya ask me, I-I think
you're giving up too easy!
- Marshal, if you ask me, l...
I don't think you know too much
about a woman's pride!
- No, ma'am, maybe I don't!
Girls, don't forget to be back in time
for Sunday dinner now!
I'm sorry about your bags, Miss Carter!
I didn't get a chance to get 'em down!
The girls put together
a packed lunch for you...
Well, bless my soul!
He did it!
Good morning, miss!
Good morning, Marshal!
John Simpson said he'd
have a church and he has!
Church bells in Tombstone!
I believe that's the first church bell
I've heard in months!
Yes!
Well!
I love your town
in the morning, Marshal!
The air's so clean and clear!
The scent of the desert flower!
That's me!
- Barber!
- Oh!
- Marshal, may I go with you?
You are going to
the services, aren't you?
Why, yes, ma'am!
- I'd admire to take you!
- Thank you!
Now, folks!!!
I hereby declare
the first church ofTombstone!!!
Which ain't got no name yet,
or no preacher either!!!
Officially dedicated!
Now I don't pretend
to be no preacher!!!
But I've read the Good Book
from cover to cover and back again!!!
And I nary found
one word against dancin'!
So we'll commence by havin'
a dad-blasted good dance!
- Will you oblige me, ma'am?
- Thank you!
- Hold it, folks! Dad-blast it, hold it!
Sashay back and make room
for our new marshal and his lady fair!
Yoo-hee-hoo.
Ya-hoo!
Well, by gollies!
Marshal, I hope you're as good
a dad-blasted carver!!!
As you are
a dad-blasted good dancer!
- Oh, you know...
What's your preference?
It makes no difference,
Marshal. Anything. Anything.
Now you know the church. You know...
Pardon me for intruding
on your dinner party, Marshal!
It's all right, Doc!
Sit down and join us!
Look, Clem, I told you last night to leave
Tombstone and go back East!
I also told you if
you didn't leave, I would!
Hey, Doc!
Just a minute, Doc!
That's the second time in three days!!!
You've been tryin'
to run somebody out of town!
That's my business!
That's what I'm gettin' paid for!
Miss Carter or any other
decent citizen!!!
Can stay here just
as long as they want to!
We're through talking, Marshal!
My advice to you
is start carrying your gun!
That's good advice!
Hyah!
¿Mamacita?
Doc's gone!
He's left town!
He was goin' to Mexico and!!!
Take me with him!
He was gonna marry me!
Well, you're leavin' too!
What's the matter, Miss Carter?
I think it's just a common
case of hysteria, Marshal!
- Oh, it is, is it?
- What are you doin' here?
- None of your business!
- Why don't you behave yourself?
- Go on back where you belong!
- I'm not gettin' out till she leaves town!
Why, do you want me
to take you over my knee and spank you?
You take your hands off me!
Leave me alone!
What do you know about it anyway?
What do you know about Doc and me?
We was going to Mexico
and get married!
Yes, he was gonna marry me,
till this Miss Milkface!!!
Comes pussyfootin' along and...
- Where'd you get that?
- Doc gave it to me!
- Where do you think I got it?
- You ain't lyin'?
Why should I lie about it?
He gives me everything I've got!
I got a whole roomful
of stuff down there!
Keep your door locked,
Miss Carter.
See that this wildcat stays in her room,
will ya? And tell Virg to stick around!
What's up?
Doc Holliday!
Where's Holliday?
He came in about a half an hour ago,
got his saddlebags!!!
And a sack of gold out of the safe
and left in a hurry!
- Were you lookin' for Doc?
- I am!
Well, he left on the bullion stage
riding shotgun!
- Left town?
- For Tucson!
Get my bay mare and have her
up to the jail, will you, Jess?
Sure!
You!
Whiskey for my boys!
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
I think the Wachucha Pass
is your best bet, Wyatt!
Good luck!
Thank you, Jess!
Hyah!
Hyah! Hah!
Hey! Hey! Hyah!
Dinnego, how long ago
did the stage come through here?
- About 15, 20 minutes ago!
- Doc Holliday on it?
Yes, he was, and he was
sure going to town!
I need a couple of fresh horses!
Cut me out two stout ones!
- ¡Ándale, fuera!
- One that'll lead well!
All right, Marshal!
That bay looks good.
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
Get on!
Hey, hey! Hey!
Hey!
Get on there! Get on!
Get on!
Hey! Hey!
Get on there! Get on!
Get on!
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
Hyah! Get on!
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
- Pull up!
- Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa! Easy! Whoa!
Whoa!
I told you I'm through
talking, Marshal!
You're comin' back
to Tombstone with me, Doc!
Sorry, I'm not going back!
Hell, in that case,
I'll be takin' you back!
Pull for your gun, Marshal!
You call it, Doc!
- Who is it?
- The marshal.
Why don't you go
chase yourself up an alley!
Who do you think you are,
busting into people's rooms at night...
Chihuahua, open this door!
Doc? Is that you, Doc?
I said open this door!
Yeah, Doc!
Yeah!Just a minute!
Chihuahua!
- Yes...
- Open this door before I kick it down!
- Yeah, Doc! Let me get something on!
Well, hurry up!
Chihuahua!
Come in, Doc!
Chihuahua, why did you
tell the marshal I gave you this jewelry?
W-Well you did, Doc!
You give it to me!
I never saw this piece of junk
before in my life! Who gave it to you?
Well, you can't remember
everything you give me, Doc!
Sure you did!
Don't you remember?
- When?
- T-Two or three days ago!
I don't know!
What difference does it make?
That being the case, Doc, I charge you
with the murder of my brotherJames Earp!
- Doc, he's foolin', ain't he?
- I ain't foolin'!
It was stolen from him
the night he was shot in the back!
Now do you still insist
I gave it to you?
- Oh, no! No, of course not!
- Then who did?
I ain't gonna be a squealer, Doc!
Let's go, Doc!
When you told me
to go away and!!!
Squall my silly little song
somewhere else!
So I came up here
and had a good cry!
There was a knock
at the door, and!!!
I thought it was you!
I opened the door, and...
- It was Billy Clanton!
Hyah, hyah!
Billy Clanton!
Go get him, Virg!
- Hah!
- What's happened?
- There's been a shootin'! Stay outside, fellas!
Wyatt, she's badly hurt.
Mayor, you'd better send
to Wachucha for an army doctor!
We have to operate immediately!
That'll take
five or six hours, Doc!
You're a doctor, ain't ya?
Doctor!
Morg, go over to the Mansion House!
Get Miss Carter! She's a nurse!
Tell her to stop by Doc's room
and get that doctor's bag!
- All right!
- Mac, you and Buck go clean up the saloon!
Put a couple of poker tables together
and put some lights around 'em!
Sure!
Doc, you're gonna operate!
- Rub her feet, Kirby! Rub her feet!
- Hurry, Doc!
Mac, the light! Over here!
Doc's here, honey!
She's been right brave!
I'm sorry, Doc!
Still mad?
No, honey!
Look! I haven't got anything
to put you to sleep!!!
So this is going to
hurt like blazes!
Yell, scream, holler...
anything you like.
Tell me when you're ready!
Bite on it! Bite hard!
Oh... Oh, Ma!
There, there, honey!
Doc's gonna help you!
I'm looking for
your brother Billy Clanton!
He's right in there, Mr! Earp!
My boy Billy...
shot down on the streets
ofTombstone!
Murdered!
It's too bad it had to
end this way, Mr! Clanton!
Get mounted!
Hi, Doc!
You're all right!
You've been a brave girl!
All right! Lift her up gently!
Doc, l-I mean, Doctor!!!
I'm gonna take her to my house
and take good care of her!
Can't I do that, Marshal?
Sure!
Phew!
- Doctor Holliday!
Thanks!
I'm awfully proud of you, John!
Thanks, Clem!
She was a brave girl!
Mac!!!
You ever been in love?
No, I've been
a bartender all my life!
We'll be waitin' for you, Marshal,
at the O!K! Corral!
- Marshal!
Well, the Clantons are at
the O!K! Corral, all right!
They're barricaded down there,
all four of'em!
Marshal, we want you
to count us in on this!
We ain't fightin' men,
but we'd sure like to help you out!
Thanks, Deacon, but this is
strictly a family affair!
What's the matter, they too yellow
to come out and fight?
They'll come!
Easy on that keg, son!
How's Chihuahua?
She's dead!
"DoctorJohn Holliday!"
When do we start?
Sunup!
Sunup, Ike! Phin! Sam!
Sun's comin' up, Marshal!
Got everything straight?
- Yeah!
Let's go!
Here they come!
Doc Holliday's with 'em!
Wait till they
get closer, you fools!
Phin, cover your brother!
Mornin', Mr! Clanton!
Let's talk a while!
Ike!
Well, now!!!
You go right ahead and talk!
I got a warrant here
for you and your sons!!!
Chargin' the murder
ofJames and Virgil Earp!
There's also a charge
of cattle rustlin'!
I'm givin'you a chance
to submit to proper authority.
Well, you come on right in here, Marshal,
and serve your warrant!
Which one of ya killed James?
I did!
And the other one too!
Then I'm gonna kill you!
Hyah!
Throw your gun down
and come on out, old man!
My boys! Ike! Sam!
Phin! Billy!
They're dead!
I ain't gonna kill you!
I hope you live
a hundred years!!!
Feel just a little
what my pa's gonna feel!
Now get out of town!
Start wanderin'!
Wyatt!
- Doc?
- Yeah!
Good-bye, ma'am!
Mighty nice to have made your acquaintance!
Get along, horses!
There are so many things
I wanted to say!
Now nothing seems appropriate!
Yes, ma'am, l...
Yeah, I know!
The mayor says you might be
stayin' here a while!!!
Maybe help him
get a school started!
Yes! I'm the new schoolmarm!
That's mighty nice, ma'am!
Me and Morg are goin'
out to see Pa!!!
Tell him what happened!
I might come east again,
get some cattle!!!
Maybe stop by here again!
- Stop by the schoolhouse?
- Yes, ma'am, I sure will!
- Good-bye, ma'am!
- Good-bye!
Ma'am!!!
I sure like that name ...
Clementine!