-Reverend.
-Camille.
www.mybellyfatburner.com
-Aren't you cold?
-Sharpens the mind.
-Even if contemporary people
deny it,
even if they ridicule
Christianity,
modern culture was built
on this moral law.
And our hunger for
the certainty of this law,
for a spiritual anchor,
for an immutable, eternal truth
is proof... of it's existence.
Especially now,
after a few decades of
relativistic situational ethics,
our society is tired
of constant change.
And as we approach
the millennium...
-Transformations are
a basic staple of mythology.
Transformations from human form
to animal forms and vice-versa;
of gods into humans
and humans into gods;
of wind into blood,
flesh into water,
ugliness into beauty.
The human need for change,
progress, movement,
is reflected
in the ancient stories,
which are told over and over
again in different forms.
[ bell ringing ]
Okay, uh, Chapter 12
for Thursday. Thanks.
-Professor Baker.
l was wondering if you could
help me with something.
-Of course, Professor Bergin.
What with?
-Uh, well, I have to prepare
a speech on very short notice.
-What speech?
-Well, it's just
the keynote address
to the lnternational
Theologians' Conference
in Chicago.
-Professor Bergin...
That's wonderful!
-Yeah, it is!
So...
Let's do something exciting
tonight, huh?
-Yeah, something really crazy.
-Okay...
-Hey, remember, Martin,
Calvinists are not supposed
to have sex standing up.
-I know. 'Cause it might lead
to dancing.
-Camille. Martin.
-Reverend.
-If you have time, I'd like
to meet with you later today.
Four o'clock in my office?
-Sure, Reverend.
-And don't book anything
immediately after.
I'd like for us
not to be disturbed.
-Hugh really is brilliant,
you know, Bob?
Bob?
Ah no...
Oh no!
Bob, come!
Bob? We went over this,
remember?
"Come" means "come here".
Oh, Tillie.
-I'm 47.
-Yeah, that's great.
But have you seen my dog?
-Ah yes, he walked by here
about half an hour ago.
I remember because
it was the first time
I'd seen him without you.
He was charging along like he
had an appointment or something.
Thatta way.
-Thank you.
-Don't you love it the way dogs
sometimes get this look
like they got a hectic schedule
to follow? Busy, busy!
-Bob...
-Are you all right?
-My dog just died.
-Oh. I'm sorry.
-I loved him so much.
It's pathetic, really.
-No. No, it's not pathetic.
It's, uh... Animals love you
in a way people can't.
So uncomplicated,
really, you know?
Whether you're successful
or not, or ugly or beautiful...
they don't care.
-Yeah. Thanks.
-Oh... It's okay, it's okay.
How did he die?
-I don't know.
I don't get it.
He... he wasn't that old...
He just snuck away and...
I found him in an alley.
And you know what?
I realized that...
I loved him more than anything,
anyone, I'm suppose to love.
Oh, dear...
What a blubbering idiot!
Il think everything good
just goes,
eventually.
-Yeah.
[ washing machine beeping ]
Oh, they're done.
I'll get yours.
Yeah.
-Thanks.
-Yeah. Just relax.
You know,
I really didn't expect
to be this long. l gotta run.
-Oh. l'm sorry.
-Uh... sorry about your dog.
-It's okay. Thanks.
[ door opening ]
-Hello!
-Hi!
-Hi.
Hi.
-Ah... Where'd you get that?
-Do you like it?
-Yeah. It's...
It's wild. Where'd you get it?
-Oh,  just picked it up.
I think it has a certain...
reckless charm, don't you?
-Yeah... Yeah...
It's fun.
-Yeah.
-Okay, we should get going,
honey.
-Yes.
-Uh...
-What?
-We are going to a meeting
with the reverend, remember?
-Yes.
-Very funny.
-What?
-Camille, you can't wear that.
He's gonna think you've lost
your mind.
-So?
-And I've lost mine.
-Martin, this is the era
of the individual, remember?
You've got to stop worrying
about other people's opinion
of you.
Okay? Let's go.
-But if I do take their offer,
we'll need someone else
to fill the role
of chaplain.
An appropriate successor
would concern me... greatly.
-Well, chaplain certainly is
a very exciting position,
especially in these times.
I'm sure you'll have
lots of takers.
-It's not takers we need,
it's givers.
-It was just a manner
of speaking.
-And of course, whoever took
the position would have
to be beyond reproach, for
the more conservative element
of our college constituancy.
We have to remember
that not long ago,
we were still debating
whether or not
Christians could use
rock 'n' roll
to convey a godly message.
-Remember when old Mrs. Lindow
said that...
all rock 'n' roll led
to sexual intercourse,
because the music...
no, it was the rhythm
of the music matched
the rhythm of the contractions
of an orgasm.
-lt's easy to laugh,
but we have to remember that
Mrs. Lindow is as much a member
of God's flock as anyone else.
-Yeah.
-All I'm trying to say is
that...
the chaplainship of the college
could well go to a man
and woman, together.
And as one of our star
theologians, Martin,
you're more than qualified.
And Camille, your book
on Christian ethics,
your student counselling
last year
and your general behaviour
as a fine Christian woman
make you a credit to the college
and to the faith. But...
if we were to hire
a man-and-woman team,
they could not be suspected
to be...
to be indulging in the physical
pleasures of marriage
without actually being
married...
even if their sexual relations
were very much in the closet,
as it were.
-Well, we're both...
very committed to each other.
Well, you want to skip
the restaurant, then?
-Well, in fact,
I should get some grading done.
-Yeah. I don't really know
what I'm going to speak about
yet anyway.
-No?
-You sure you're going
to be okay about Bob?
-Sure.
-Okay.
Bye, then.
-Bye.
-Easy, easy. What is this?!
[ background chatter]
-Excuse me.
[ a woman ]: Okay, next!
-I'm sorry,
I'm looking for, uh...
-What do you do?
-Uh, I teach mythology.
-That's new. And?
-And I'm just looking
for someone.
-And what happens?
-This is funny.
I'm not an acting person.
I have her laundry, you see?
Petra Soft?
-Oh, I see,
you have her laundry.
Uh... she's right over there.
-Thanks.
-Timothy?
Are you gonna look at these?
We don't wanna have
to call them back.
-Honey, I'll be with you
when I'm free.
Right now, however,
I am... occupied.
-Right. You're occupied...
Okay, next!
-Okay, Tim, can we bring in
a third one?
-Unfortunately, I only have
two hands available, you know?
-Does that mean "no"?
-Uh-huh.
-Excuse me...
Can I talk to you for a moment?
-Oh, yeah. Uh... Tim,
could we call it a night?
-Uh, Petra,
before we call it a night,
I have an idea I'd like to try,
and my idea is...
Uh... Okay, it's a night.
It's a night, go.
-Hello.
-Hi.
-Uh... A funny thing happened.
l don't know if you've checked
your laundry yet,
but I think we did a switcheroo
by mistake.
-A switcheroo, yeah.
I did realize that. How are you?
Are you feeling better?
-Oh, yeah, yeah. Much better.
I... I wanted to thank you...
[ all ]: Ah...
[ Timothy ]: Shit!
[ Tory ]: Timothy!
[ Timothy ]: Marcus!
[ Tory ]: Don't panic, everyone.
Perhaps the electricity is
a little too much to ask for...
[ Timothy ]: Why do I have
to do everything myself?!
-Come back to my trailer.
I've got your stuff there.
-Don't worry, honey,
I'm getting it fixed.
-''Don't worry, honey''...
That's what you said just before
the tent went up in flames!
-One small fire and
I'm responsible every time
some little problem...
Just keep your hair
on your head!
-Thanks, I will.
-So my name's Petra, by the way.
-Yeah, I saw that on your card.
And mine is Camille Bak...
Camille.
-Camille. That's nice.
I like it.
It's like 'come here'.
It's nice.
[ loud growling ]
-Hey, Petra!
-Shut up, Jim.
So your accent,
is that from Quebec?
-Yeah, originally from Quebec.
But my father was a minister,
so I moved around a lot.
-Well, this is my house.
-Oh, well...
This is really... nifty.
-Yeah, I like it.
I wanna do that wall in some
kind of fun-fur and slate
or something,
but slate's really expensive.
-Yeah. Well...
here's your laundry.
-Oh, right.
So, uh, can you join me
for a scotch?
-Oh, l'm not much of a drinker,
really.
-And some music.
'Cause without music,
life would be a mistake.
-So, I have a confession
to make.
I wore one of your tops.
You know, the one
with the zipper?
-Really?
-A school teacher
at a Christian college
has to get her kicks somehow.
It did make me feel a little...
racy, for a while.
-I'm sure it looked great
on you.
Your man must've liked it.
-What man?
-Oh... I just thought, you know,
someone as beautiful as you are
would, uh...
-Oh, well...
-You have an exquisite mouth,
you know.
-I do?
-I have a confession
to make too, actually.
I did the, uh, switcheroo
on purpose.
-Why?
-I wanted to see you again.
-I don't know. You moved me.
-Because I was so pathetic,
I suppose?
-No. No, I can't explain.
Um... I'm sorry if
that's embarrassing.
-No. No, I mean, I...
I think you were... really...
very tender,
at the Laundromat.
You touched me.
-I wanted to.
Camille, I'd love to see you
in the moonlight
with your head thrown back
and your body on fire.
-Okay.
That was uncalled for.
-True. But if you wait
for what's called for,
usually nothing happens, so...
-Well, I am clearly
a bit out of my element here.
Can I have my... my laundry?
-No. No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Sit down. I was just...
-I must be fun to shock
or something.
-It's true, you are, but I...
-Well, I'm nobody's fool.
-No.
No, no, no. Of course you're
not. I'm the fool. I'm sorry.
I...
-Can I have my laundry?
-So you're a school teacher,
huh?
-My laundry. Please.
Thank you.
[ Tory ]: lf the foundation
money comes through,
we might be all right.
We might be able to squeeze by.
But what do you mean,
good authority?
Did you talk to the foundation
yourself?
'Cause if the money doesn't come
through this time, I don't--
Timothy...
-That is the problem here.
-I swear to God,
I've just about had it.
If I'd known it was gonna be
like this, I would've--
-What? What, gone back
to your racoon act?
-Don't start that.
It was a good idea.
-Yeah, racoons.
-How was I suppose to know
they were so selfish?
-You know, I think maybe
it's this fuse here.
-How did you find me?
-There aren't 20 Christian
colleges
with someone named Camille
teaching here.
Listen, I wanted to, uh...
apologize for being
so aggressive
last night.
l don't know anyone here,
and I just...
-Come.
-Let's go.
You look great.
-Thanks.
[ laughing ]
-That's good! Most impressive!
So, we've covered abortion,
church and state,
predestination, drug abuse,
prostitution...
Ah yes, homosexuality.
How do approach
the homosexuality problem,
Camille?
-Well, uh... I'm not really sure
I'd consider it a problem.
-Honey, what you said at Tom's.
Camille said that
it's important to love
the sinner but hate the sin,
so that, uh... you're allowed
to feel the desire
but not act on that desire.
-Well, in heteros...
in retrospect, sorry,
I've come to think that there's
a lot of room for multiplicity
in God's creation.
-You are aware that
that is contrary to doctrine
in this matter?
-God... God cannot be so cruel
as to decree that people
like... like that...
can never, ever be contented.
I mean, one's devotions
are not entirely chosen.
-But the Bible. I mean, there
isn't one condoning passage
in the entire Bible.
Not to mention
that every other holy book
of every major religion
opposes homosexuality.
-I know, yes.
-As a chaplain,
how would you counsel
a young Christian
who came to you
and said that he was struggling
with his desires
for another man?
-Well, I...
I would try to determine
whether sh...
he is reacting out of, uh...
Uh, it's a very controversial
issue, as you well know,
and I don't claim to have it
all worked out.
I don't know.
-But you do acknowledge
that this institution
and the book upon which
this institution is based
characterize homosexual acts
as unnatural and sinful.
And as chaplain, you'd have
to support this doctrine.
-Of course.
-Camille?
-Yes.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. Yes, l'm fine.
-The reverend wants to see you
in his office.
-I don't really want to talk
to him right now. It's just...
-I know what's going on,
you know.
-You do?
-It's okay. I understand...
I think.
-You do?
-Camille, you've been saying
the same thing
about a million different ways.
The buying of the top,
talking about orgasms
in front of a reverend,
and now this almost-sabotage
of the interview...
-What am I saying?
-That this pressure for us
to get married
just forthe sake of a job
feels like a sham.
You don't want to be
this career Christian
who just does what she's told.
And you know what?
-What?
-Maybe it's a blessing
in disguise.
We've been together
for almost three years.
Maybe we're just being cowards.
-You think so?
-Yes.
I love you, Camille Baker.
Oh, I love you more
than anything.
Any job, anything.
And maybe you can...
imagine more intoxicating
options...
but it's okay.
It's what imaginations are for.
-Oh, Martin...
-Let's not wait any longer.
Just marry me, whether we take
this job or not, okay?
I-I still have to think, Martin.
I...
-All right, take five everyone!
-I'll be back in a second.
-What were you doing
at the school?
Are you stalking me
or something?
-I'm sorry if I threw you
by showing up.
I mean, to interrupt
you and your man.
-That's what I came
to talk to you about.
Petra, uh...
What happened this morning...
was an aberration.
-Of course.
-So, don't think that I'm a...
-Oh, I won't, I won't.
-I'm sorry I lied.
I think I was just flattered
by your attention but I'm not...
I'm not really like that.
-Okay.
Well... it was nice meeting you.
-Well, I mean, we could,
you know...
-What? We could... could what?
-Well, don't people like you
just have friends,
sometimes?
-Yes, people like me do.
-And...
why couldn't I be one?
-I'm attracted to you, Camille.
-It's okay, but...
It's okay.
We're not animals.
We don't always have to act
on our attractions. I mean...
-What would we do... as friends?
-Have fun.
-Fun.
Sounds like a buddy movie.
-Yes, exactly.
Like Thelma and Louise.
But without the guns.
-Oh, well, no guns...
I don't know, I don't know.
-Well... I don't have
any classes
this afternoon.
-Oh.
I had something planned.
Uh... I suppose you could
tag along.
-What?
-Will you accept
to be surprised?
-Hey, Petra!
-Yeah.
-You must be kidding.
-Huh-huh. You'll love it.
You'll love it, Camille!
It's fucking mind-blowing,
I promise you.
I've done it like
three million times.
You have to try it.
-Can I see your rating, please?
-Oh, yeah. Here.
-Okay. I'll need a number,
in case there's a problem.
-What kind of problem?
-Don't worry, it's just
a formality.
-Thanks.
-You have to try it, Camille.
How will you know
if you don't try it?
-Well, I haven't tried shooting
myself in the head either...
Just one question, Petra...
Why?
-Why?
-Why? Because...
Because fear is what you pay
for adventure, Camille.
-Petra...
If you wanna do this, like,
the wind is perfect right now.
But night's falling,
you better hurry.
-Exactly. You hear him?
-What?
You think I should kill myself
because it's getting dark?
-Don't be such a wuss.
-Okay.
Okay, Petra, this is all very
poetic and everything but...
no, really, I'll watch.
-Woooo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
You have to ride with the wind,
not against. Do you feel it?
-l feel it and I hate it!
-Look at that!
-Oh, dear...
-Sorry. Whoa!
Hang on.
Shit!
Camille, you're really
throwing me off.
Wake up, Camille!
Wake up!
Oh, gosh...
Oh, God, are you okay?
-Oh...
-What?
-I hit my knee on something.
-What, your knee, is it fucked?
-I don't know.
-Oh, shit! Where's the guy?
We should get you
to a hospital, okay?
-No, no, no, it's okay.
-Oh, I shouldn't have
pushed you to do it.
I'm such a fucking
steamroller sometimes.
I haven't done it that many
times. I'm so...
I'm sorry.
-lt's okay.
lt's okay. lt's okay.
But I did it, didn't l?
[ They laugh. ]
How does it feel?
-It hurts.
-It helps to swear.
-It hurts like a fuck.
-You know, you probably strained
some other muscles.
Here, roll over.
Good.
-Hmm, it's very, uh...
healing.
-So, what do you teach?
-Mythology.
-What, like Zeus
and Cupid and stuff?
-And stuff, yes.
They're beautiful
stories.
-So tell me a story.
-Cupid, for instance,
was a god who fell in love
with a beautiful mortal, Psyche.
Now, this was a big taboo,
you see, because, uh...
gods and mortals
were not allowed to mix.
So, uh,
Cupid stole her away
to a secret palace...
-Where they made fabulous love.
-Mm-hm.
But Cupid wouldn't let Psyche
see him.
They only made love in the dark.
Until, uh...
until...
This makes me nervous.
-Me too.
I think it's supposed to.
So then what happens?
-Then, uh...
[ doorbell ringing ]
Shit! God... Sorry.
-The boyfriend.
[ Camille ]: Hello?
-Hello. Camille, it's Reverend
DeBoer. Can I come up?
-Uh... Okay...
Oh, you-you're gonna have to,
uh...
-I am not gonna climb out
the window.
What's the problem?
We're just buddies, right?
You haven't done anything wrong.
-Sorry, Reverend.
Please, come up.
Okay, uh... Sorry.
I met you at the Laundromat
and we just switched laundry.
You know?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Coming!
Oh... Hi, Reverend.
-Good evening.
-Come in.
This is Petra.
Um, l met her at the Laundromat,
quite... randomly,
and we switched
laundry by mistake.
Just one of those things,
you know? And she just came back
to return mine.
And this is Reverend DeBoer,
the chaplain at the college...
where l teach.
-Enchanted.
-How do you do?
-Um...
Well, Petra,
thank you for returning
my clothes and, uh...
it was nice meeting you.
-Well, I hope that you can make
some time for me in the future?
-Yes, uh...
Reverend?
Reverend...
Reverend, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
She's just a street kid,
quite disturbed, really.
And I can't seem
to get herto leave.
I flattered myself to think
that I could teach her
something.
-Well, you do what you have to,
Camille, but we have to talk.
-Sure. I'll come around
tomorrow.
Petra?
I love you.
Why don't you just tell them
you're sick?
-I'm not,
and l gave them my word.
-I like this new, uh... you,
though.
See you Monday.
-Goodbye.
[ knocking ]
-Ahem!
Ahem... Petra, uh...
I think I should tell you
we may have to
leave here very soon.
-Why?
-Well, unfortunately,
I think they are going
to call in the loan,
and then they will want to take
the trucks and the equipment
and before I let that happen,
I will make very sure
that we, uh, run away.
Maybe very soon. I don't know.
Petra...
you're not thinking
of jumping ship, are you?
Because, uh...
Well, because, uh...
-No, No.
Of course not.
-Are you very serious
about this girl?
-Oh, I don't know.
I think she might, you know,
just be experimenting.
I don't know.
You know, all good things go
eventually.
-Yes, but, uh...
but for you, Petra,
what does it mean for you?
Oh...
Come here.
It's okay.
-You knew we didn't get it.
Why didn't you tell me?
I've been counting on
that stupid grant.
-I didn't want you to worry.
-All this change,
change, change!
I'm not cut out for it!
A little house in the suburbs
is sounding pretty good, right?
-Is that a fact?
-You know, Timothy, sometimes
I have this dream of just...
picking up and running away
from this circus.
-Oh, grow up, Tory.
-I couldn't help it.
It's like something that is...
stronger than I am and...
I...
-It helps to put names
to our feelings.
Naming things gives us power
over them.
-Yeah.
Maybe it gives others
power over me, too.
-You have nothing to fear
from me, Camille.
-It's not that I've been unhappy
with Martin.
It's just that I'm...
I'm happier with...
Oh, God...
Why did I get into this? Why?
-Our community has been remiss
for many years.
It takes long to change.
But yes, I think
we have been guilty
of homophobic cruelty
and excluded people like you
in the past.
-People like me.
-But what I'd really like to do
right now...
is to pray.
-I'm not here to pray.
-You do still believe?
Please.
Camille!
[ loud music playing ]
-What's going on?
-We have been invited
to a circumstance.
-Circumstance?
-Circumstance is a festival
for the Modern Circus
in San Francisco
and it is very prestigious.
And it is all expenses paid.
And to me, this is... okay.
Yeah?
-Hi!
-We have to talk.
-Camille, we have to dance!
-No, Petra, I'm not much
of a dancer. Really, I...
-Oh! Oh, I can fix that.
You're so lovely
it breaks my heart.
[ a man ]: Hey, Petra!
Who's your lovely new assistant?
[ Petra laughs. ]
-Why don't you show us your
tits, Sweet-pea.
-Petra...
Petra, stop!
-What?
[ a man ]:
Oh, dear, trouble in paradise.
-Camille, I'm sorry.
-That was vulgar!
-It was not, Camille.
It was just fun.
-It was tasteless and...
and crass!
-Yeah, well... you're...
Are you ashamed of me?
What, I'm your dirty
little secret?
-Petra... I just don't like
being laughed at.
-Oh, really.
Well, aren't you cute!
Hey! Good luck, then,
sweetheart,
'cause these are some
of the kindest people
in the world, Camille.
when the really mean fuckers
of the world
start making fun of you? Huh?
Cause they will, you know.
They'll use it against you
and they'll be laughing up
a storm, Camille.
-Not if you show
a little dignity.
-Dignity?
Wha...
What could be more dignified
than dancing with the person
I adore?
[ Martin ]: Camille, it's me.
I'm at the island airport,
I'm back in town.
I got them to switch around
my second lecture
so I could get back sooner.
Huh... You must be out
walking Bob.
Anyway.
I'm sorry.
Huh... I'm gonna come over
to your place right now and...
I've missed you, sweetheart.
I'll be right over.
Hello!
-I love your sex.
I love your wisdom and the...
way you say ''switcheroo''.
I love that sadness that you get
in your eyes sometimes.
And other stuff.
-But?
-But...
we might be leaving tomorrow
and I can't stay
and you can't leave.
[ answering machine ]: Your
mailbox has no new messages.
If you would like
to change your--
-Why are you so defeatist?
-'Cause I've loved before, see?
And lost.
-I know what my obligations
are...
[ people arguing ]
-Pardon me.
Makes sense to anyone here?
-She's over there,
in the black trailer.
-Okay, thank you.
-Listen...
I love to look at you.
I love to talk to you.
I love your openness,
I love what you do,
I love...
I love you.
-Everything gets ordinary
eventually.
-Ordinary with you
would be... wild.
-What would you do in a circus?
-Well, I have a few ideas.
-I smoke pot.
-I drink. Cherry brandy.
-I don't know.
Make your own decisions.
-But do you want me?
-Something awful!
-What's your name?
-Petra.
-l'm Martin.
-Excuse-me.
Would you like a drink of cider?
-No. Thanks.
-Can I do anything?
-No. But thank you.
-She answers a kind of...
wordless question in me.
Yeah, that's good, that's good.
A wordless question.
I can explain.
I...
No, in fact, I can't.
-It's okay.
I know he meant a lot to you.
-Huh... yeah.
Well...
Don't bother telling me
it's neurotic.
-It's probably hard to talk
about without feeling...
foolish?
-Well... it is foolish.
I...
I distracted myself.
-I could've been
a little more receptive.
I mean, the pressure of
the promotion, my proposal...
It probably shook you
to your foundations. Hum?
-Well...
-You probably hardly recognized
yourself.
-I...
Martin, I...
I wanted to talk to you
about something.
-I'll help you bury him.
-Thank you.
I have something to say--
-Are you not gonna ask me
about my trip?
-I'm trying to say something--
-It was wonderful.
They're gonna publish
my speeches
in the bi-annual review.
-That's great.
-And there was a...
a beautiful talk by...
by some guy from Sweden,
just at the end, about silence.
And he said this contemporary
obsession to voice everything
sometimes does more damage
than good,
and that the only real dialogue
is with God.
And it felt... true.
-But... I rememberyou saying
that when you hide one thing,
you hide many.
-He was saying that sometimes,
it's selfish to give yourself
the relief of saying something
when the consequences
far outweigh the relief.
See?
Anyway, I'll help you
take care of Bob.
-You said that.
Martin, listen...
-No. No, you listen.
This is what I know.
I love you.
For we have something,
you and me, don't we?
-Of course we do. Yes.
-I can understand everything.
I mean, I'm not such a bad deal.
-No, you're not a bad deal.
-These things pass.
-What things?
-These... passing things.
Just think, please.
Please, just think
before you speak.
Okay?
You are what you say you are,
Camille.
Just be careful when you say it.
-I'm sorry.
[ Petra ]: Camille, it's me.
I hope you're okay.
Listen, we're leaving tonight.
I thought maybe you wanted to...
Oh God, I don't know
what I thought.
Just call me. Please.
-Coffee?
-We're off, gentlemen.
-...I said, ''Why don't
you prove it, scumbag?
Give me one good reason why
I should believe your bullshit.''
And he had nothing to say.
The guy dropped right down
to his knees.
-Oh, shit! Hang on,
I dropped the hang strap.
Oh, shit... Hey, guys?
Come here!
-What?
-Come here!
There's a body.
-Oh, Jesus!
Hey...
This is the woman that was
gliding with Petra
the other day.
-I can't tell
if she's breathing.
-We should call an ambulance.
-I'll get to a phone.
-I'll go back and get the stuff
from the truck.
-Yeah.
[ phone ringing ]
-Hello?...
Well...
Where?
[ tires screeching ]
[ siren wailing ]
Where is she?
-She's in here.
-What happened?
-I don't know.
We just found her.
I think she was drunk.
-How is she?
-She... hypothermia.
I don't know.
-Well, can't we get her
into town?
-The ambulance is supposed
to get here any minute.
-Can we at least put her
in your truck or something?
-No. They said, "Don't move her.
Just keep her warm."
-The best thing to do
for a hypothermia victim...
[ The voice becomes an echo. ]
[ whispering ]:
Please, please, fate...
God, Zeus...
Science...
Anybody...
Okay...
I promise to love her
and I promise to cherish her...
And to follow her
and to lead her anywhere...
-Yes...
-Oh!
"Hallelujah"