Subtitles by KBS World
What about me?
You think you never hurt me?
You've hurt me too, you know.
How did I ever hurt you?
Tell me. What was it?
That.
I would never forget that.
Never.
That? That's...
How was that my fault?
If it weren't for you...
Forget it.
Tell me!
If it weren't for me, what?
How was that my fault?
- But you!
- I said stop!
You better take that one to the grave.
The edited article is out?
Yes, have a look.
It came out nice.
[Profession Women Dislike
"Heavy Equipment Operator, a 3D job"]
But this is different from what I wrote!
How? That's exactly what you got for us.
The concept's completely different.
And the subtitles are different, too.
How could you...
I wanted to raise the alarm to the society that only looks at the education level
and talk about how blue collar works can make a great living using their skills,
without having to worry about retiring.
So how could you ruin it this way?
Do you know how proud and respectful he is about his job?
How could you blur his pictures?
Imagine how he'd feel if he read this?
That's his problem.
You have to think about the readers.
Even if that's the reality,
our magazine could change their views.
Isn't that what journalists are for?
It wasn't my decision!
It was decided at the editors meeting!
You wrote several articles for me before.
What happened?
Why were you so off?
I was off?
Ask any woman who's getting married.
Ask if they like heavy equipment operators!
They don't know and I was trying to let people know about it!
Do you want to ruin my magazine?
You be the editor then.
Then take this article out.
It's already at the printers.
You can't take this out?
It's too late.
I wired $50 just now.
Don't skip your meal, okay?
Yes, honey. I love you.
You!
I'm going to kick your butt!
Honey, I'll call you later.
Are you crazy?
You're the one who's crazy.
I'm off?
And here you are, supporting a college graduate who's not interested in getting a job for 5 years?
You think he'll make it big someday?
Yeah, right!
He's in his thirties, getting allowance from his woman!
Even if he does make it, he'll dump you.
Why? You think I'm wrong?
Oh, man.
I don't believe this.
Compared to your loser boyfriend,
he's a thousand times better, can't you see?
Why would you belittle a hard worker like him?
You don't know anything about men.
And that's why you're dating that loser!
Why? You think I'm wrong?
You don't want to work, do you?
No! I don't want to work!
Not with you, no!
And don't forget to wire me the payment.
Hey!
Hobak.
That was quick.
Where are you coming from?
The magazine editor's office.
I should learn to control my temper.
I got fired from my part time job.
Oh, that editor is mean and horrible.
It's people like her who are driving this country into ruins.
I'm too upset to worry about the country.
I must be adopted.
Now what's wrong?
I had a fight with Subak.
Both mom and Subak...
Whenever something happens, they blame me.
I thought that since I was little.
Maybe my real mom is out there somewhere.
How...
I even had dreams.
Dreams where I was waiting by the front door,
in case my real mom came for me.
People don't remember when they hurt others,
and they only dwell on their pain.
I guess you can't help it.
Hobak.
Anyway, I'm going to pay for mom's party.
You?
We'll have lunch at a Chinese restaurant and send them to Jeju-do island.
I'll pitch in for half.
You pay for lunch, and I'll pay for the trip.
How does that sound?
But you're not working.
I was a teacher for 7 years.
I can afford it.
Okay, then.
But mom might get mad if I tell her,
so can you talk to her?
Okay. Let's be good daughters to her like this.
Give this to him and get some bone soup.
And don't forget baby formula.
Okay. I'll be back.
You're successful because you're so kind to your employees.
Everyone else is in trouble, but not us.
I'm really lucky, thanks to you.
It's thanks to Sangnam.
Without him, you and I would be lost.
You're right. I have to go too.
I have to go grocery shopping.
Thank you, Mr. Choi, for coming to see us in person like this.
And thank you for the baby formula.
Thank you, Mr. Choi.
Don't worry and get well soon.
Without you, it's boring at the site.
Huh?
- Hello.
- What are you doing here?
I'm going home and this is a shortcut.
Is this where you live?
Uh, yes...
Oh, isn't the magazine out?
You said today.
No, I had to brush something up.
Are you brushing up my face?
Why would I need to do that?
Your face is perfect.
I should've called you. I'm sorry.
There's no need to be sorry.
What's going on?
No, nothing's going on.
What could be going on with me?
That's odd.
Something feels very different.
What happened?
Oh!
Your blind date didn't go well, right?
Daebak told me things often don't work out.
That's not true!
It's a special issue, so it's late.
Wow!
I'm getting excited here.
This is my first magazine debut,
so please make sure I look good.
And don't forget to give me the list of all the women who ask for my number.
Don't leave any of them out.
I won't.
Goodbye.
Your family's obviously very important.
You never missed work, even when I was sick.
When Sintong got surgery you still worked,
saying you had to make money.
Then you should grow up.
And pick up Bangtong from preschool.
They are cleaning up there.
Okay, ma'am.
Pretend you didn't see it.
Hand that over.
Please!
Do you want me to hit you now or later?
Where are you going?
Hand that over!
You're so mean!
How can I survive on $3 a day?
Then get a job.
I'm going to get a credit card, then!
If you do, I'll kill you and kill myself.
I had to pay for your credit card debt off just last year.
Don't you remember?
So grow up before I get real violent.
Understand?
Man!
I'm going nuts.
It's me, Anggeum.
My birthday party at the hotel buffet,
I canceled it.
People don't celebrate their 60th birthday so extravagantly.
People look down on it for making it such a big deal of it.
People live to be 100.
Turning 60 isn't a big deal nowadays.
So I'm canceling it.
Oh, this is crazy, just crazy.
How sad?
What did I do to deserve this?
It's me, Anggeum.
I canceled my birthday party at the hotel.
People don't celebrate their 60th birthday so extravagantly.
People look down on it for making it such a big deal of it.
People live to be 100.
Turning 60 isn't a big deal nowadays.
What's wrong with Anggeum?
Has she gone mad?
She hasn't, but she's almost there.
So don't bother her.
What if she turns completely mad?
Egh, hyo, hyo, hyo.
Gwangbak, can you go to the supermarket?
Okay.
What?
Remember me?
Deduct it from my doctor's bill!
- Can I try this?
- Go ahead.
Oh, it's yummy. It's yummy.
She says she'll buy some.
Oh, man...
Oh, yes, yes.
Oh, if you cry, you don't look pretty.
Peekaboo!
I made some noodles.
Get up and have some.
I don't feel like it.
Nobody eats because they feel like it.
You like noodles, mom.
Try some.
Just leave it there and get out.
Wait.
Let's go.
Mom!
Subak, I'm here.
Mom, get up. Mom, eat something.
- Mom.
- Subak, come out.
I made your favorite, tofu stew.
I made it with handmade tofu.
If I bring it here, you might throw it again, so I set up the table in the dining room.
Should I bring it here?
Look who I brought.
Look at Jungji.
Mommy... Mommy...
I don't want to be bothered.
Get out and take them with you.
Aeji, let's go.
The food's ready, so eat.
Gwangbak and I will take care of mom's party.
So don't worry too much.
I'm sure you won't starve.
Starve? Starve?
You think I'm afraid of starving?
For you, food may be everything.
So what would you know?
As long as you have food, you think you're set!
But I'm not like you, okay?
How can you eat at a time like this?
How can you be so indifferent?
I heard you made your sister angry yesterday.
How can you only think of yourself?
Delicious!
She called everyone one by one,
saying she canceled her party.
She was all laughing about it.
I'm going to tell everyone the truth!
Serves her right for bragging about Minjung.
I thought only daughter in laws have issues,
but I guess son in laws have them too.
That's what happens when the parents don't know better!
That darn woman!
I'm loving this.
She was going to show off, using Subak and her husband, but she failed.
Oh, when I think about that, oh!
The heartaches I've suffered could fill a dozen 5 ton trucks.
Get back at them by becoming successful.
Don't worry, mom.
My life isn't going to end like this.
Not one plan but you sure are ultra positive.
I envy you, Sedal.
Guys! Let your dad eat, please!
Eating with them is impossible.
Why didn't you get me my own bowl?
Just eat, will you?
So annoying...
Hey, don't cross this line, okay?
Dad, I hate you!
Don't get mad.
This isn't the first time.
You!
Mom, come with Yeongdal.
Come and eat.
Why would I expose myself to stress?
Stress?
But I'm paying for it.
Actually, you're not really paying.
Fine. My wife's paying for it. So what?
I'm going to hold my head up this time.
- Me too!
Go!
Hey, go!
What is it?
We're holding mom's memorial service today.
Why didn't you come yesterday?
I don't believe you sent these.
What did I send?
Oh, we'll talk when you get here.
Hello?
Parcel service!
Is anyone home?
Hey! You woke up my baby!
You know how hard it was to make him sleep?
I don't believe you!
Attention, at ease.
You have to be quiet today.
- I'm starving here.
- Attention.
At ease.
Attention.
Hey!
Minjung.
Uh, it's been a while.
So the rumors were true.
I couldn't believe it.
Well, I'll see you later. I'm busy.
Hey, hey!
Cheer up and don't miss the class reunion.
Don't feel embarrassed.
Where are you?
Everyone's waiting for you.
Okay. I'll be right over.
Parcel service.
Where are you?
Where's my rice?
I was just there, but you weren't home.
I was waiting but I had to go to the market.
Please bring the rice right away.
I can't right now.
Can I come tomorrow?
But we have to eat!
You want us to starve?
But I have to make the next delivery...
Hello?
Everyone's hungry, so should we start?
It's your birthday.
What should we do?
Order the food.
Why? Minjung's not here.
He shouldn't make others wait for him.
He's so inconsiderate.
You're the one who's inconsiderate.
You used to call him "My Minjung," remember?
He should've stayed a successful businessman.
Things happen.
He didn't do it on purpose.
He's busy because he has to make deliveries.
That darn parcel service!
I used to like getting packages in the mail, but not any more.
When will you grow up?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Egh, hyo, hyo, hyo, hyo.
Minjung, we were all waiting for you.
Now that you're here, let's start.
Let's order. I'm starving.
We'll order first and cut the cake.
Are you proud of that?
What?
Why didn't you change?
You should be embarrassed.
Oh, you wreak of sweat!
I'm sorry. I was in a hurry.
It's okay.
Where are they?
Hey, the menu.
Bring it over here.
Can't you tell who's paying for it?
Why are you acting like a child?
I'm an expert on acting like a child.
Father, mother, what would you like?
I think this side and this side looks good.
They must be cheap.
How did you know?
Just kidding.
Pick anything you want.
What do we know?
Minjung, you pick.
Like how you used to.
You always know what's good.
But I'm not a regular here...
Sedal, order something they'd like.
Today is my old friend's sister in law and my only mother in law,
the woman with lots of emotional baggage,
Ms. Lee Anggeum's 60th birthday.
Happy birthday! Applause!
It's mom's first memorial service.
Is your mother in law's birthday so important?
Why aren't you applauding?
We'll cut the cake now.
Loser, take some pictures.
Okay, get ready to cut the cake.
Take the knife.
Please cut the cake.
Okay.
Applause!
She's the best cake cutter I know!
Next is a special performance by the 4 daughters in tacky matching dresses
the sames ones they wore at their father's birthday.
Subak, Hobak, Gwangbak, and Haebak will sing a song in Anggeum's honor.
Applause!
Start the song!
Forgetting the pain from giving us life
You've spent nights and days raising us
Washing us clean
Working your hands and feet to the bone
You've given us so much! Beneath the sky...
I'll come after lunch.
How can you help out if you leave then?
How can you do this on a day like this?
Wait. I'm coming.
Delicious, delicious.
You worked so hard taking pictures. Eat.
Mom, enjoy.
What's wrong with you?
Excuse me?
You're here, so why can't you smile and say happy birthday?
Instead, you've been sitting there with a scowl on your face since you've arrived.
Why did you come?
Go deliver your parcels!
- Minjung.
Sit down.
Ugh.
Today's your mother's memorial service, right?
You should go.
Things were crazy, so I had forgotten.
I realized it when I checked the calendar.
You didn't have to come.
But it's mother's birthday.
It's okay.
Nobody will get mad at you.
And don't take to heart what she does.
She's just upset and in shock.
She used to cherish you.
Take Subak and go.
Subak, come.
I'll go later.
Where are your manners?
Come out right now!
Is this how I raised you?
You're someone's daughter in law!
You have duties to uphold!
How dare you come here and enjoy yourself like that?
It's your mother in law's first memorial service!
Go and fulfill your duties.
Why would you make her cry?
Be quiet!
Come out right now!
Oh, boy!
The Korean War was nothing compared to this.
Egh, hyo, hyo, hyo.
What's your dream?
There he goes again.
I want to grow up and marry you and live happily ever after.
Yours is also an impossible dream.
Have some corn.
That lunch was awful.
I'm starving.
Have some.
- You too, mom.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Grandmother.
- Yes?
What should I become when I grow up?
Why? Are you worried about your future?
Yes.
Don't worry.
All you need is 3 meals in a day.
Life isn't that special.
Eat well, pee and poo well, and sleep well.
It's bad to be greedy.
Watch the news.
All these powerful people are getting arrested.
That's all because of greed.
They're already powerful, but want more.
Hey, it's your birthday.
Go lie down.
Then who would fold the laundry?
Mother, let me help.
Go have corn.
Daebak, don't worry.
You could sell spicy rice cakes and still live well enough.
That'd be great.
I could eat spicy rice cakes everyday!
Daebak, you can't make money selling that.
So how can you think about eating it?
You must save money for our children's sake.
How can you tell him to sell spicy rice cakes?
Why not?
I don't know about that...
If life is good as long as you don't go hungry.
My family wasn't poor.
Does your family have gold cow or something?
Everyone had that in the old days.
My family had a pair, a male and a female.
Why don't you say they had a calf, too?
They did, twins.
Gold cows are nothing.
My servants ate with gold and silver spoons.
After eating, they'd try to steal them,
but we didn't even pay attention.
There were gold and silver spoons everywhere.
We had gold buttons on all our clothes.
They were so heavy that I envied poor kids.
We even played with jacks made of gold.
We played with gold pieces this big,
so my wrists hurt when the weather's bad.
Same here.
My toes hurt in bad weather.
Why is that?
Did you kick around gold nuggets?
You're so quick.
There was gold everywhere, so I kicked them,
and that gave me calluses.
I had to kick them here, kick them there.
I couldn't walk because of the gold nuggets.
Is it going to rain again? Ouch...
Mom, isn't this your nap time?
You go take a nap, if you want!
Hey, have you ever wiped your butt with silk after pooing?
Excuse me?
If you haven't, don't talk to me.
Others were wiping their bottoms with grass,
and my family was the only ones who hung silk in the bathroom to use as toilet paper.
Oh, that was what you did?
My family used money for that.
What?
We used Chinese silk at first, but when we ran out, we hung money to use instead.
Brand new bills were too slippery,
so my father wrinkled them to make them soft and hung a bunch of them.
There was so much dirty money in the bathroom that our neighbors would come at night,
take them and washed them to use.
How come you married my son empty handed?
Why didn't you bring some of that money?
Why didn't you bring any of that gold with you when you fled during the Korean War?
I said it was too heavy to carry!
Hey, stop lying and go make dinner.
It's your birthday, so I'm letting you off.
Miho, learn this and use it on her later.
I want her to go crazy.
How dare you laugh?
What's that?
You know that bakery on the corner?
That ugly girl goes there often.
When you see her, teach her a lesson.
Oh, man...
Yes, Daese?
Thank you.
Thank you, Daese.
For me, a month goes by so slowly.
For me, it flies by.
I turn around and it's pay day.
How is Sangnam doing these days?
Is he doing okay?
I don't think he's over his first love.
I was cleaning his room today,
and he still has things she sent him.
That's why he can't get into a serious relationship again.
They don't even last a month...
I hope he finds someone special soon.
I know.
What's going on with that girl on the phone?
It won't last longer than a month.
Whoever it is, I feel bad for her.
It's all her fault.
When I think about her...
I'm sorry, Daese.
But you're a victim, too.
But she's my sister.
I'll go prepare dinner.
Smile.
And don't say anything to my family.
Father, I'm here!
Minjung's here!
It's so nice to see everyone.
Minnam, how's your business going?
It's going okay. How about you?
Me too.
Minhye, you're having a second baby?
Congratulations.
Let's have a drink.
Mother must be happy to see us all.
Father let me pour you a glass.
Yes. Good job, everyone.
Let's eat.
Subak, eat.
Okay.
I have something to say.
Look. Do you think mom would eat these?
How could you send these?
I ordered them off the internet.
I heard that's what everyone does.
This is what everyone does?
But this was her first memorial service!
You sent these for us to set the table with and show up this late?
Subak, how could you do this?
You know I can't cook.
I thought ordering off the internet was better than trying something I can't do.
Everyone said it was nice,
but I can see it's not all that.
Minjung, this is all your fault.
You should've paid more attention.
Is her mother's birthday more important?
Why wouldn't my mom's birthday be important?
It's her 60th birthday!
To be frank, don't you think the living are...
Be quiet.
Making you prepare for mother's first memorial service was my fault.
I'm sorry.
Dad, I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it. I'll prepare the dishes.
Your mother was sick so I know my way around the kitchen.
If you feel bad don't act like this,
and if you feel sorry don't do these kinds of things.
Also, I'm saying this on behalf of everyone here,
Minjung, take father to live with you.
That's enough.
Father let me speak.
I don't want to ask you again.
Take father with you.
I'll have his luggage sent over.
You can't suddenly dump him on us.
Dump him?
Don't you get it?
Minjung's priority is being the first born son.
You should be doing what's expected as the eldest daughter in law.
Out of all four children, Minjung has benefited the most,
and you're also enjoying those benefits.
Did these benefits include parcel delivery?
Shut it.
We'll take him in.
How will you take care of it?
We can't take him now.
You live in that huge apartment and drive expensive cars, but you can't?
You said your old place was too small, so my father sold his land and gave you money!
And you kicked him out in less than a month!
I didn't kick him out.
He said he couldn't get used to Seoul and left.
He had no choice but to say that.
Subak, just think about it.
From the time you got married until now,
have you ever prepared a meal for my parents at all?
Whenever we visit Seoul you had a housekeeper do everything.
What did you ever done for them?
You come during the holidays but you don't help out at all.
You just treat yourself like a guest.
All the money you spent is earned by Minjung.
Let's not talk about this anymore.
Just respect my brother and let him fulfill his duty.
Minjung, keep your promise.
You said you'll take care of him if mother passes away.
Don't yell at Minjung.
I can't take him.
Let's do this later.
Later when?
Don't you feel bad for father?
With mom gone...
Imagine how lonely he must be in this house.
He's even thinking about getting a dog!
If I were doing well, I wouldn't ask you.
I'd take him.
I won't let you.
I will take him.
So take him then!
But we can't afford to take him in right now.
Please understand.
This is too much.
Your flashy apartment,
whenever we go there, our jaws drop.
Who made that possible?
You stole Minjung from our family...
If I were you, I'd volunteer to take him.
Don't you feel the least bit sorry for him?
Stop it.
It's been so long since we're all together and you're arguing?
Do you think your mother would be happy to see this?
You don't have to take care of me. Go home.
Don't get mad at me.
I...
I wasn't going to say this, but...
- Stop it.
- They should know.
- I said don't.
- Minjung went bankrupt.
His company went bankrupt.
He completely lost the company so how can we take father in?
There's nothing else to do so you should go home.
It's getting late.
Minjung.
Minjung!
Father.
You must be dying inside.
You couldn't tell anyone.
I know how you feel.
Mother.
Oh...
Mother, you're still up?
You're home?
Are you ill?
Oh...
If I die, bury me next to your father.
You still have years more.
I already told father I'm keeping you here.
What good will that do?
There's someone who's out to get me.
Was Anggeum's family rich?
Excuse me?
Did she use money as toilet paper?
She said there were gold nuggets lying around the house.
Is that true?
Oh, why didn't you let her win?
Did you really have to go that far?
But mother started it.
I never met anyone from up north who wasn't rich, or so they all say.
She was lying through her teeth,
so I decided to do the same.
If you want to yell at me, yell at her too.
What?
You used money as toilet paper?
Where did you get that idea?
If we had a bet, I would've won.
I had more things to say, but I didn't.
Like what?
Like how the pot we used for cooking rice for the servants was so big
that neighborhood children bathed in it.
How we used the leftover rice to cover our roof.
Oh, boy...
You and mother are like twins.
Me? Are you insane?
I can't believe you just said that!
Goodbye.
For the road.
I made rice balls and boiled eggs.
Father, take care of yourself.
I'm going to make it again.
I'll come back to get you.
Your mom had an amazing dream before you were born.
Don't worry.
You'll be successful.
I'm not worried, father.
I know I will be.
Get in!
Go. Drive carefully.
Goodbye, father.
Okay.
Let's stop by the rest area.
Unless you have to use the restroom, let's not.
I have parcels to deliver.
I'm hungry.
I haven't eaten anything since yesterday.
Oh, it tastes funky.
I think it's spoiled.
It's not. It tastes fine.
It's spoiled.
But he made it this morning.
Food spoils fast in the summer.
Don't you watch the news?
Food spoils fast in the car.
I'm sure he wasn't careful making this.
He probably added whatever in it.
Don't eat it, then. I'll eat it.
It's spoiled, so don't eat it.
But I'm eating it.
It's not spoiled.
It's delicious.
What? But I'm telling you it's spoiled.
It's fine. Why do you keep saying that?
Do you have to insist that it's not spoiled when it is?
What if you get sick?
Don't worry about me!
Don't eat it out of anger.
I'm not angry. It's delicious. Really.
It's delicious because my father made it.
You never liked rice balls.
I've always liked rice balls.
They are my favorite.
You never made me anything like this.
Don't be so childish!
Fine! I'm childish!
Didn't you know?
Oh, it's yummy.
This is crazy yummy.
It's not much, but I hope it helps.
Is that from your father?
Don't cry!
It's pointless for grown man to cry.
Leave me alone so I can cry!
I'm using my father as an excuse to cry!
Why can't you be more understanding?
Let me cry! Just let me cry!
Stop the car!
Ugh!
Hello.
[Jobs you don't want for your husband!]
- Hello?
- It's me, Sangnam.
Is the magazine out?
Well, it's not out yet.
It's in the printer's now.
I'll send you one when it comes out.
And don't go to the bookstore in my neighborhood.
I'll send you lots of copies.
Just forget about it so you can focus on your work.
Okay.
Call me when it comes out.
[Jobs you don't want for your husband!]
[Profession Women Dislike
"Heavy Equipment Operator, a 3D job"]
Why are you still driving that car?
You were supposed to turn it in.
I'm sorry.
I said I would use it until today.
What's going on?
They're taking my car, too?
Oh, no! My car! My car!
What's going on?
Oh, no! No!
My car! My car!
My car!
What are you doing?
What are they doing?
What's going on?
Let me go!
Don't touch that!
That's mine!
You bastards!
Call the police, Minjung.
Call the police!
What are you doing?
Don't touch the things we put stickers on.
And please move out by the end of the week.
Let's go.
We're confiscating these.
Uh, no!
Give me back my babies!
No! Those are mine!
Not this one!
You can't do this.
We're only enforcing the law here.
Please!
I can't live without this one.
Please let me keep this one!
It's brand new.
I've only had it for a month...
This can't be happening...
What am I going to do?
Yes, Minjung.
Subak?
Okay.
Subak!
Minjung, what happened?
Oh, no...
Are you okay?
Do you need to go see a doctor?
Subak...
How can this be...
What do I do now?
I didn't know it was this bad.
They even took my car.
And we have to move out.
We have nothing.
Say something!
What are we going to do now?
How could you not tell me anything?
How could you betray me like this?
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
You think that's enough?
Okay. Blame me.
Yell at me and hate me.
What are we going to do? What?
Let's move in with my father.
Your father?
Stay with my father.
Take the girls and when I...
Stop. Don't utter another word.
Mom!
Miho, can you take her?
Yes, mother.
Make her some formula and change her diaper.
I can do it, mother, so you can go.
It feels like an unlucky day for you, so be careful.
Ugh!
Whats this?
What's all this?
Oh, mom!
Mom, don't touch them!
It's against the law!
Law? What law?
Subak hand picked every single one!
How could you let this happen, huh?
I'm sorry.
How can she live in the countryside?
How can you even suggest that?
She couldn't be more miserable right now,
and you tell her to go live with your father?
Take your mom and go home.
Let's go home.
Why won't you say anything?
Why are you so quiet all of a sudden?
Subak can't even poo in an old style bathroom!
She can't even wash her own underwear,
so how can you send her away with the girls?
I won't let her go! I won't!
I'd rather die than see that!
Mom...
I can't believe my eyes.
How can she fall asleep to the dog sound?
Shh...
I think they know what's going on.
They wouldn't go to sleep.
The person you are calling is temporarily...
Your sister won't pick up the phone.
Subak?
She's not here. Isn't she there?
She's not there?
No. Minjung thought she was here.
I hope she's not doing anything stupid.
- Subak!
Mom, mom, that way!
Minjung, let's not...
Let's split up.
You and dad go that way.
You and uncle turn left.
- Okay.
- Mom and I will...
Subak!
Call me!
- Did you find her?
- No.
She's not here, either.
Let's go that way.
Father.
- What happened?
- You must be tired.
Go home. I'll keep looking.
Subak! Subak...
Mom!
- Subak!
We've been looking for you everywhere!
Subak.
Let's go home.
You can't eat, you can't sleep...
You're going to get sick.
Mom.
Yes?
I'm exhausted.
I don't want to do anything.
I don't want to move a finger,
and I don't want to see my girls.
I have to force myself to eat.
I go on living because I'm alive.
Everyone else in the world is having fun,
but I'm here, feeling all miserable.
I feel lost and angry.
Oh, no, what should we do...
Subak...
I want to close my eyes and die.
Oh, no...
What should we do...
My poor Subak...
Subak...
Huh?
Mom.
Are you busy?
Look at how sweaty you are!
You look awful.
How did you find this place?
This is where my darling daughter works.
What's going on?
I have something to talk to you about.
With me?
Subtitles by KBS World
It must be hard for you.
Father, can you talk to Subak?
I saved every penny I could,
and I wore clothes people throw out...
I can't use this money on anyone else.
I'm going to use it on my kids.
How can you do this to your own mom?
I can't stand you, so leave!
Let's tell Subak to move in with us.
No way!
Please close out all my savings accounts.
Were you playing with me?
Why wouldn't you reply to my text messages?
You left me hanging.
Why are you acting this way?
I was honest with you,
and you made a fool of me!