Fifty thousand billion cells
make up the human body.
Each of these cells contains the entire
genetic heritage of our parents.
DNA is the universal
code for living.
In a way, our genetic code
is the memory of humanity,
the record of evolution.
But what exactly
does this code transmit?
The color of our eyes?
The size of our feet?
Our intelligence?
But what else?
What about a person's
temperament?
What about impatience...
aggressiveness...
courage?
Are we the helpless prisoners
of our genetic code...
or are we free to forge
our own identity?
Michèle!
- You promised.
- It's not my fault. Nicole insisted.
When you hit a winning streak,
you go with it...
No more credit cards.
- I know.
- No more advances on your pay.
I'm docking your salary.
Mimi, it's because I love you.
Love me? Oh yeah?
That's a good one!
How about I love you,
so I rat on you
for selling steroids?
- Is that a good deal?
- Get in.
- You're a fucking madman!
- Mimi, are you okay?
- Don't touch me!
- I didn't mean to.
- Let me see.
- I'm bleeding, shit!
- Let me take a look.
- Shit, I'm cut.
No, you're not cut.
You're just bleeding a little.
Hello?
You okay?
Yeah, sure.
I thought you were in bed.
Where were you?
I slept over at Sara's.
Without asking me?
You weren't home.
Fuck, these are mine!
What's going on?
I'm sorry for snooping, honey,
but we're in a hurry.
In a hurry? Why?
"I promise I'll pay it all
back some day.
Forgive me, Big Boy.
Thanks for everything.
Love, Mimi."
I'm not leaving.
Margot, this isn't
the time for games.
What's the rush?
Let's say, Scott won't
be happy if he finds us.
You, maybe.
I didn't do anything.
What about a visit
to your godmother?
In California?
What happened to you?
Okay, move it.
We're leaving.
I'm not going.
Shit!
Where are they?
This sucks.
I liked it here.
Hello? Mom?
Sweet Jesus,
this is a surprise!
Hi there!
Margot, my love!
How are you?
You're almost as sexy
as your grandma!
- Where are you going?
- We're coming back.
When you get tired of your mom,
get yourself a one-way
ticket for Ibiza.
It's paradise for young people
like you and me.
Are we just going
to stand here?
- What happened?
- A Tae Kwon Do accident.
It's your turn, Mom.
Wow.
Good move.
Well, the school's important.
But so is the teacher.
- You can get a bad one.
- You don't say.
But our real education
takes place at home.
That's where knowledge
and values are passed on.
Family is the foundation
of who we are.
What are you talking about?
I don't want Margot to end up
with a dumb job, like you.
Like "yours".
- You should have got a degree.
- With what money?
Besides, I teach,
like François.
Really, you teach aerobics!
Right, as a registrar,
you can date classy profs.
My job is a lot more complex
than you think.
She's my daughter,
and she likes her school.
Can you please
change the subject?
I win!
Hold it, something's fishy.
What?
Mom, you cheated!
You switched cards!
Come on!
- Madeleine!
- I didn't!
Mom?
Could you lend me some money?
$750. You'll get it
off my next pay.
Did you screw up again?
I can't, Michèle.
We just got back and...
It's okay.
No need to apologize.
Have you talked
to Chloé recently?
We could go visit her together.
Here, wait a second.
It's better than nothing.
A centavo saved
is a dollar earned.
Wait till you see
what I brought you.
It's so cute!
- Do you like it?
- Yeah, really!
I love the colors!
Thank you!
What is it?
It has ice packs on each side.
Only you come up
with gifts like this.
- Great!
- A new fashion trend?
Yes!
I didn't know...
it's not what you think.
- We have a doorbell!
- So I see.
I know, I...
I should have rung.
It's just...
it's your drapes.
I love your drapes.
Forgive me.
Really, I owe you an apology.
My name is Béatrice Lacombe.
I'm an interior decorator.
I was driving by and noticed
your gorgeous drapes.
- Really?
- Yes, the color...
it's exactly what
my client is looking for.
Those were the good old days,
before those darn computers.
Nowadays everything
is virtual, digital.
Networked.
My husband's
a "programmator"...
a programmer.
A computer scientist.
You're married?
No, but I like to say "my husband."
It sounds more official.
Thanks!
It shouldn't take long.
If they like them, I'll have the same made
and I'll bring them back.
It's so nice of you.
You barely know me.
My pleasure.
I hear you need money.
You fucking perv!
I just want to help.
- What do think I am?
- Wait.
Okay, that's enough.
What's eating you,
for Heaven's sake?
If it's because I cheated
at rummy, okay.
Mea culpa.
- But you'd have done the same.
- It's for the best, Mom.
At least stay one night.
I don't know
what you're after, Mimi,
but one day there'll be
no one left to help you.
Fancy words. Bye.
- Michèle?
- Janine!
Hello!
Why, come in!
I'm so happy to see you!
My beautiful Marguerite,
you've changed so much!
It's been, what, a year!
You sure don't look a day older!
Come in!
I'm so embarrassed.
The house is a pigsty!
You should have warned me!
Wonderful surprise, huh?
But what brings you...
it's great! Fantastic!
What does the place
look like when it's tidy?
You still listen to J-Lo?
You gave it to me.
Yeah, like 10 years ago!
Don't you have any electro,
or jungle, or anything?
Will you be staying here long?
No way, man!
We're going to California.
It's an iPod.
What's that?
What are you doing there,
my baby?
How did you get there?
What is that, a rat?
No, it's Rosalie.
Hello!
- Mom sent me.
- Get lost.
You wouldn't believe
the threats he made.
He completely flipped.
He wanted to keep my pay.
Like that, for no reason?
He's a control freak.
He's jealous, selfish,
super possessive.
It couldn't go on.
The guy needs therapy.
Goodness, what a story!
I've heard about men who are
on steroids and go berserk,
but I never thought
I'd know one.
Steroids...
they bulk up your biceps
and shrink your brain.
Tell me the truth.
Was it the first time
Scott hit you?
Janine, I don't want to impose.
Please, don't worry.
Could we sleep here tonight?
Of course. I insist on it.
Could I make
a long-distance call?
Sure.
Michèle, you still owe me money.
I'm not a bank.
How long does it take
to drive to California?
- What are you hatching now?
- What does it cost?
With gas, motels, everything?
It's pretty expensive.
Why?
I really miss you, Chloé.
So does Margot.
You're her godmother, after all.
I wanted to surprise you,
but so what?
Margot and I are
moving to California.
Cool, huh?
Michèle,
I don't know what shit you're in,
but you're not going
to live off me, okay?
That's why I left home.
I also need a break, you know?
Listen, just lend me
enough cash for the trip...
not much:
$500 or $600 US.
I have what, 10 years'
experience as a waitress.
You find me a job and
keep my first two weeks' pay.
Now's not a good time, Michèle.
I'm busy.
We'll talk later.
- Bye.
- Wait!
- Margot said to say hi.
- Give her a kiss for me.
Sorry for interrupting you.
Don't forget about my job.
I have to get going.
But stay here today.
- No, I don't want to...
- No, I insist.
- Enjoy the pool.
- Are you sure?
That's so great!
Bye.
Gabrielle?
Alexandre?
Janine?
I feel really
awkward asking, but...
I'm, like, completely broke.
I need my prescription.
I got a big rash.
- It's stress.
- Sure, I understand.
- Thank you!
- Is that enough?
I feel so cheap.
I promise to pay you back.
Can I stay with them today?
Sure, why not?
- Camp's boring!
- You're so spoiled!
Lots of kids would love to go.
Take care!
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Sorry, I spread out...
- No problem.
Just wait, I made my sauce.
- Like some wine?
- Sure.
It was one night, then another.
Now she's looking for a job.
I don't want her settling in here.
I've enough
with the house and kids.
- And you're always away.
- It makes for company.
Well, then tell them
to leave, sweetie.
You should see her face.
Scott beat her up.
I can't.
Put her on, I'll tell her.
Where are you staying?
The Plaza Inn... or Resort
or something.
- Is the weather nice?
- So-so.
I work indoors all day anyway.
Poor darling.
- Is someone with you?
- No.
Well, in fact, there is:
A charming news anchorwoman.
Is she pretty?
Did you hear?
Russia's invaded Chechnya.
- It's awful.
- Yeah, it's awful.
Darling, I...
I feel like making love.
Right now.
Over the phone?
Undress me.
Say something sweet.
Sure.
I long for your body,
for your bum,
for your thighs,
for your tongue.
Caress yourself.
My love, tell me
what turns you on.
You.
You, now.
All of you.
I love it when...
when your tongue
glides over my thighs,
over my sex.
My mouth is burning,
it wants to kiss you!
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm going to be late.
We'll continue on Saturday.
Okay? I promise.
See you on Saturday.
I kiss you all over.
And kiss the kids for me.
Okay. Bye.
Five, six, seven, eight!
Five, six... again!
Take your time.
Come on, it'll be
good for you, Janine.
I don't know...
Just the side kick, all right?
You'll see, it's
a great stress-reliever.
Lower your arms, that's it.
Elbows up, make a fist.
Now kick with your foot,
like you're closing a car door.
Go on, kick.
That's it.
Again, kick!
That's great. Super!
Good!
Yeah, keep it up!
Good, slam the car door.
Slam the door!
Slam the door...
- This feels great.
- You bet.
Slam it!
- That's okay.
- Go for it!
This "bungle" is way cool.
It's "jungle"!
Wanna go to the mall?
- It's a 20-minute walk.
- Cool!
What's wrong?
I'm not allowed to go
that far alone.
You gotta be kidding.
You're not alone,
you're with me.
Want to chat online?
Girl, Montreal, 16.
Well, almost.
In three years.
REALLY WANNA FUCK.
YOU?
FUCK WHICH WAY?
S & M.
YOU MASTER.
ALREADY HARD.
CUFFS?
I SCRATCH YOUR SKIN WITH RAZOR,
LICK THE BLOOD.
I SUCK YOUR COCK
TILL YOU EXPLODE.
I PISS ON YOUR FACE.
Hi.
I'm in deep shit.
It's bad timing, looking
for a job in the summer,
with vacations and all.
I don't know how to say this.
Could you lend me
some more money?
Look, I take it back.
Forget what I said, Janine.
We're imposing, huh?
I'm not perfect, but at least
I know when I'm not wanted.
We didn't want to bother you.
I'm sorry.
- We'll clear out.
- Wait.
No, don't worry.
I understand.
What if I offered you a job?
Nothing complicated.
You'd help me out,
run errands, make phone calls.
You'd earn a bit of money.
Janine, I'll make it up
to you 100 times over!
Okay, put on your best clothes,
we'll start now.
This is pretty much
my winning outfit.
Okay.
A Provençal green,
very luminous,
to highlight this painting,
which is quite magnificent.
Yes, I think that would work.
For the drapes,
we have lots of options.
I brought you some samples.
I don't know, I imagine
something cheer,
floor-length.
It would be way glamorous!
It's just an idea.
What color do you suggest?
I don't know, maybe
some kind of orange,
nothing too harsh.
Kind of like this,
a yellowish-orange,
but not too intense.
Hello!
Hi, how are you?
- I brought wine.
- Great, put it inside.
- Still the beauty!
- Still the player!
No, is this Marguerite?
My little Margot,
you're all grown up!
My big Margot.
My Queen Margot!
Hi, Dad.
"Queen Margot"
has a nice ring to it.
I'm so happy to see you.
We should do it more often.
- Come and visit us some time.
- Get real!
Why not? I mean it!
Margot, my queen?
What did I say?
What's my phone number, Dad?
Your phone...
Hi, Gabrielle, little ladybug.
Anthony... Marguerite.
We've already met
at the club.
Were you there too?
Sorry, that night's
a total blank.
Man, I woke up
in the bathroom at 6:00 am.
- Were you on chemicals?
- No, I don't touch that.
I had a few drinks, but...
- do you go to Montreal often?
- With my new car, you bet.
A car, wow!
My darling little sister.
You're sweet to take in
Michèle and Marguerite.
Unlike you.
- A quick game of cards?
- Great idea.
- Is she still a casino regular?
- What do you mean?
- Lucien!
- What?
I'm no fool.
I know you still gamble.
That's Estelle, my dad's mom.
Our grandma.
A tightass...
black tea and dry biscuits.
- How about him?
- Her husband, Lucien.
- A real cool guy.
- We like him.
The blonde beside him is my mom.
- Miss Energy.
- She's a one-woman powerplant.
I wish my mom
were as cool as her.
Yeah, real cool.
Here's my Aunt Janine...
"No dirty shoes on my lawn."
Her nickname's Hitler.
My mom.
- My dad's sister.
- Your dad's?
- My dad's.
- His dad is my dad.
You have a sister?
A step-sister.
But I've never lived with my dad.
Dad slept with her mom
while he was with my mom.
Laurence.
No, Laurence is
our step-brother Nicolas' mom.
My mom lives in France.
Hi, everybody!
Hello, my darling.
- When the cat's away...
- Yes, it's a bit improvised.
You, improvise?
It took a game of cards
to get the family together.
- A drink for my Chuck?
- Certainly!
Me too!
You're the Punch Queen, Mimi!
- How you doing, Michèle?
- Good.
- You're at home here.
- Thanks.
Hey, we're starting
to think you live abroad.
It must be some kind of scheme
to save on taxes!
You were always the smartest one!
I'm sure that if Charles could,
he'd work nearby.
I should declare myself a single mom
to get a family allowance.
You can't anymore.
You have a girlfriend.
I have to admit, Michèle's
as messy as any man.
- Shall we play?
- Yeah, come on!
Mom will never let me.
It's simple, you look her
in the eye and say,
"Don't worry,
I won't be home late."
She'll never let me.
The trick is,
you can't look away,
not for a second.
What about your clothes?
- Are you sure?
- They look better on you than on me.
- She'll never let me.
- Don't forget.
You look her straight
in the eye and say...
"Don't worry, Mommy,
I won't be late."
Mom, not Mommy.
Mom!
- What?
- Forget it. Just go with it.
It's just that Olivier
invited us to a friend's house.
That's nice of Olivier.
Can we go?
We won't be home late.
Why not invite them here?
It's not the same.
If it's close by,
I'm okay with it.
Super!
- Go change your clothes.
- Don't worry, I won't be late.
You look vulgar.
Hi.
Shall we go?
Boys, take care of the girls now.
- And no drinking!
- Can I come to the party too?
Wear the dress I got you
for your birthday.
You know, the cute white dress.
After three times,
you French-kiss.
Come on, she's my sister!
Yeah, who made that rule?
French kiss!
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
It makes the beer work faster.
- Have a swig.
- I'm not thirsty.
Want to play Trust?
Turn around.
Go!
My purse!
Thanks!
Don't mention it!
It's so late.
Who cares?
Shit, the light's on.
One phone call!
Just one call!
"Hi, I know it's late, but don't worry,
we're coming home."
It's 4:00 am!
We looked everywhere for you.
What were you thinking?
Do you know
what I was thinking?
Attacked, kidnapped,
raped, hit by a car...
a mother's worst nightmares!
You have nothing to say?
You don't care!
What's this?
You're hurting me.
I will not let my daughter
turn into a tramp!
Is that clear?
I'm sorry, Mom.
That's great!
You're an expert now.
Thanks to you!
Turn! Turn!
You're good!
Okay, give it some gas!
This way, Grandpa?
Hit the breaks! Stop!
Margot, you all right?
Get ready now!
Here it comes!
Now kick!
Straight ahead!
To the side!
Look how pretty this is.
Don't you like it?
Michèle would love this.
Michèle...
Why doesn't she
stay at her mom's?
It would be more normal.
You can't just
show up uninvited
and just take over
someone else's place like that.
How vulgar.
- Michèle's become very vulgar.
- Mom!
Why do you accept it?
What difference
does it make to you?
How would it look
if I didn't help her?
We grew up together.
And Marguerite is
your granddaughter. Remember it.
Poor Francis.
Having her wasn't his idea.
Stop protecting him,
your little angel.
He was asking for it.
After all,
he is responsible
for his actions.
Can't a mom and
daughter even talk?
Why don't we check the antiques?
Maybe we'll find your bench.
Good bye. Thanks.
- I got everything!
- I made you run all over.
A present.
Thanks for the job.
- No, you shouldn't have.
- I insist.
Really.
It's my pleasure.
Open it!
- Wow, it's lovely.
- Not bad, huh?
Gab thinks maybe I have mono.
You have been looking pale.
But if you had mono,
you'd be flat on your back.
It must be hormones.
It's normal at your age.
It'll pass.
I had a feeling you'd like it.
- It has some...
- It's very sweet. Thank you.
But please, no more gifts.
You need to save
so you can leave.
For California.
We're in no rush.
We're so happy here.
One more week
won't change anything.
- Where will you put it?
- I don't know.
Kick to the side.
One, two, three, four!
Kick straight ahead.
To the side.
One, two, three, four!
Straight ahead.
To the side.
One, two, three, four!
Do you hate Francis
for not being there for Margot?
Well, I think it sucks, for sure,
but I can't force him.
And Margot has me.
I have her.
We have each other.
Sometimes I ask myself...
why I stay with Charles,
my phantom husband.
I think your setup's all right.
You're never together to bicker.
Or do anything,
if you know what I mean.
Take a lover.
No, don't be stupid, Janine.
I'm tired of depending
on someone...
always wondering
what he's doing on his trips.
Okay, let's switch identities for fun.
Janine: Single mother
with no income,
no fixed residence,
forced to crash
at her friend's house
until she has the cash to go
start a new life in California.
You know, it sure
sounds good to me...
having my own home,
sitting in my own kitchen,
choosing the right color...
raspberry red
or cranberry red.
Speaking of decorating...
This is the piece for Mrs. Pépin.
Show it to her.
If she likes it, buy it.
This is the dealer's
address in Montréal.
Be careful, he closes at 5:00.
You pay him cash, no taxes.
Got that?
Would you mind
babysitting tonight?
Of course not.
I'd be glad to.
Ask for Dr. Leclerc.
He's Grandma's friend, Jean-Claude.
Remember him?
Here, take a taxi home.
Will you be okay
on your own?
I'm not four anymore.
Mom!
I'm not here to lecture you.
But you and your boyfriend
should have been careful.
- You're pregnant.
- No way.
I've never made love, not once!
It happens, Marguerite.
You're not the first
14-year-old girl to have sex.
- But condoms...
- Stuff your condoms!
I've never made love or even
come close, understand?
And I'm in no hurry.
Couldn't it be mono?
You're of legal age to make
your own decision.
But you're still
a young adolescent.
I can refer you
to an abortion clinic.
The staff is very competent.
But you should talk it over
with your mom first.
Marguerite!
Come on, baby!
Thanks again.
It's to celebrate having met.
Thank you.
In this heat, maybe we could
have sangria in the garden.
I love Naïve art.
It exaggerates expressions
we don't dare show in real life.
Does she live nearby?
A six-hour flight
from here, in England.
Like the rest of my family.
Do you miss them?
A lot.
But love...
My daughter, Anaïs.
Do you have children?
Yes.
- Two.
- She's very sociable.
No, it's been so long.
I wouldn't want to...
- Are you all right?
- Yes!
It's the sangria, I...
- where's your bathroom?
- On the right.
You had kids at a young age.
Today, you have
a fascinating job.
I can't wait to go back to work.
I'm used to a lifestyle
that's more...
And with my husband
who's never there,
I have no time for myself.
But that doesn't stop me
from wanting another.
Does your husband?
Not now.
But I've thought about
giving him a big surprise.
Don't be crazy!
I don't want to judge you.
You're so young.
Everything's still possible.
Absent husbands...
believe me,
I know what it's like.
Michèle, don't waste your money
on the machines.
There's a poker game tonight.
- We're one man short.
- Sorry, I can't.
Sure you can.
- We're not pros and the ante's $5.
- Thanks, but I have to go home.
Come on, Michèle.
11:00 tonight.
Forget it.
I've never made love in my life.
With nobody, guy or girl.
Or any... guinea pig!
No one!
I swear to God and spit on it!
Yuck, you spat on Rosalie!
Stop it, she's clean enough.
You'll drown her.
Here, take this.
It may sound corny, but...
I want my first time
to be special.
With the man of my life!
Maybe not my whole life,
but a boyfriend
I've dated a long time.
We have to be deeply in love.
I'd hate it to be just anyone.
Maybe it was an angel.
Whatever.
- Did you take religion in school?
- Because?
Well, like the Virgin,
Jesus' mother.
Maybe it's true if we still talk
about it 2000 years later.
Yeah, right.
What does that make you,
the Virgin Margot?
Yeah.
Great timing.
How are you?
Fine.
Where were you?
Did you leave the kids alone?
I didn't notice the time.
Besides, they're not
kids anymore.
Shoot, this isn't
how I raised them!
They're teenagers all right.
How you raise your girl
is your business, Michèle.
But when you're responsible
for my children,
I expect a modicum
of responsibility.
Not kids?
Alexandre's only eight!
What if there'd been an accident?
Come on! Janine!
Relax, everything's cool.
Hello, my darling.
- Aren't you a little too close?
- No.
"How the Virgin became pregnant."
- "The Songs of Paradise."
- That sounds good.
How do you think the Virgin got pregnant?
Gross!
"Young virgin
knocked up and nailed."
Excellent!
FREE PORN!
FREE ANAL VIDEOS!
Hello, darling.
What are you up to?
Not much.
Well, you see,
someone sent us the link.
But it's dumb, the site is...
Yeah, it's really dumb.
It's totally gross.
I swear, we didn't do it on purpose.
It's not our fault!
- You!
- Don't you touch her!
No Internet in this house
until I say so.
Go to bed!
- I'm turning it off.
- Gabrielle!
She didn't share penis stories on the Net
before your daughter arrived.
Maybe it was time she did.
Mom?
How did the Virgin Mary
have Jesus?
I mean, how did she conceive
if she was a virgin?
Interested in religion now?
You said it was stupid.
Gaby's putting ideas in your head.
I'm surprised you go for it.
- What are you doing?
- I can't sleep. I'm going out.
See you, sweetie.
I see your 10 and raise you 5.
I call.
Ray, this must be worth 400 bucks.
- Come on, Michèle!
- No, look.
How much?
We'll play more another time.
Ray...
$100.
Thank you!
Okay, let's go.
Good Lord!
- You're not in bed?
- Insomnia.
I shouldn't have blamed you
for the Internet thing.
I should've stayed here.
Michèle, what are you doing?
I'm a wreck.
My head's spinning.
Your cigarette!
Scott called last night.
He's looking for you.
Your mom told him you're here.
Of course.
He wants his money back.
I said I didn't know
where you were.
Janine!
He asked me to tell you
to take care of yourself.
Look, Janine,
I wanted to say...
Thank you.
Thank you, Janine.
Take two aspirins
with lots of water.
Hello, this is
a message for Charles.
Actually, I'm not sure
I have the right number.
But anyway...
Charles, I just
wanted to tell you
I really enjoyed our time
together the other day.
I've thought
about you ever since.
I'm being direct and sincere.
I'm waiting for you.
Hello?
Mrs. Pépin!
Hello, how are you?
Okay, time to let your inner
demons out! Aerobox!
Is this a bad time?
Mrs. Pépin says she paid cash,
but she didn't get her bench.
That's a big sum to forget.
I didn't say you could sit.
I needed it.
- What?!
- It's temporary, a loan.
I'll pay you in a few days.
Lie to others, but not me.
- I was in a bind.
- I'm not naïve. I know you.
You're irresponsible,
you have no respect for others.
You have no morals.
You'd rob your mother
for a game of cards.
And your daughter and yourself,
if you could!
Easy, you control freak!
How can you feel so superior?
Maybe you haven't noticed,
but you're all alone...
no husband around,
your kids mock you,
- and you have no friends.
- Aside from you, you leech!
You're frustrated.
You know what?
You resent my freedom.
You're afraid of me
'cause I have guts!
I never want to see you again!
It's better that way anyway.
Uptight people like that
freak me out.
Californians are
way more laid back.
What will we live on?
We'll need gas to get there.
Don't worry, it's all planned.
I already have a job lined up.
Chloé's going to be
so happy to see us!
I have a bit of money,
if it helps.
You're sweet, but
everything's under control.
How about a video game?
Video arcades suck.
I'm going to pee.
What's your problem?
I want my cash!
Shush, I can feel
the jackpot coming!
Good bye.
I'm going to hitchhike back.
I hope a pervert picks me up
and fucks me up the ass!
- Grandpa!
- Where are you?
It's Mom. She's being swallowed up
by a video poker machine.
See if there's anything
good on the radio.
Are you going
to sulk much longer?
Margot, lighten up.
I'll pay you back.
No wonder Dad didn't
want to be with you.
All I can say is
that I wanted you.
Ever wonder what I want?
A handsome boyfriend,
stretch jeans, new CDs,
and lots of love.
All I want, Mom, is real simple:
I don't want to be like you.
It's this one.
It's a mess inside.
I use it mostly to store tools.
That's my toy.
Lucien, I can't
thank you enough.
I'm glad to help this time,
especially for the kid.
But get a grip on yourself.
You're worth more than that.
All this is ridiculous.
Your daughter deserves
better than that.
Come on, come see.
Margot, come see!
You've never slept with a girl?
No, it's just...
if I'm too nervous,
I come too fast.
Worried about
premature ejaculation?
Roofies are the thing.
What's that?
Rohypnol.
- It stops you from coming?
- No, it makes you forget everything.
It's the size of an aspirin.
You bang a girl and the next day,
she's forgotten all about it.
Takes the stress out.
Yeah, right!
Hi.
Gaby!
Little ladybug!
I thought we could go visit Margot
at the campground.
Olivier, since you're the only one
with a car, I thought...
Great idea.
Not now.
Sorry, I have a date.
Did you put roofies
in my juice?
What?
Rohypnol.
Come on.
Maybe that's what
happened to Margot.
The night she passed out.
- I don't get it.
- Sure, at the club.
The night you and Olivier
met her there.
This is going
to sound pretty wild.
I don't know where to start.
I don't know if it makes sense.
- Who's on the phone?
- Shit!
Hi, Marguerite.
Look, I'm truly sorry
about what's happening.
I never understood why my dad
has a trailer in that dump.
Anyway, Gabrielle can't
talk to you right now.
She's restructuring her life.
She needs to spend time alone,
without visitors or calls.
So have a nice day,
and enjoy the lovely weather.
Bye!
It's for your own good, dear.
Don't you have piano practice?
Marguerite is pregnant.
Excuse me?
It's not surprising.
She's as irresponsible
as her mom.
Do you understand now, dear?
Do you understand?
It's for your own good.
We have to help her.
Mind your own business.
Is that clear?
Ladybug's dreaming
of her boyfriend!
Leave me alone!
You're dumb, you're vulgar,
and you're a pest!
"I'd never choose her
as my mom.
No way!
I want to live
with Margot in California.
That would be totally awesome.
Margot's so lucky!
Me, I'm stuck here with...
Hitler!"
Mom, tell him to stop!
Lock him away or something!
Mom, are you all right?
How long have you
been spying on me?
Who do you think you are?
And what about me?
What does that make me?
Your plaything?
Your doll?
You can't control me anymore!
I have a boyfriend now.
You didn't know that, did you?
And you know what?
You can't do anything about it!
And one day,
I'll make love with him.
Me...
your daughter!
I'm fed up with you
controlling me.
- I'm fed up with living with you!
- Gabrielle, come here!
Since he's retired, all your dad does
is make a mess.
I spend my life
cleaning up after him.
Can we drop
by the esthetician later?
Have you tried her new cream?
It's done wonders for my hands.
Look!
I can't fathom why people
insist on having pets.
They stink, they're dirty,
they're noisy.
This is so much better.
You can enjoy their beauty
without the inconvenience.
I don't know how you put up
with Gaby's furry pet.
She hates me.
One more reason to get rid of it.
I read her diary.
I had no idea I was
such an awful mother.
I don't know my own daughter.
And she calls me Hitler.
You do have a little moustache.
Laser's the way of the future!
I'm thinking
of having my legs done.
That's adolescence.
It's normal.
My baby!
Get a hold of yourself!
Don't let her walk all over you!
Gaby's been influenced
by Michèle and Margot.
I told you not to take in
those two airheads.
Take my advice.
Be firm with Gaby or you'll find her
with a needle in her arm.
I can't handle it anymore.
I'm losing it,
I've hit rock bottom.
I need help, Mom.
Come on.
Come on, Janine.
I raised you to have more grit.
If I'd given in to my emotions
at your age,
your brother and you
wouldn't have all you have now.
We'd have had
real problems then.
Come on.
A bit of shopping
will pick you up.
Come on.
Mom?
It will pass.
Believe me.
Come on.
Tips aren't included.
Have an excellent day, sir!
Why, a new face!
Two hotdogs and fries, please.
Keep going, take it all off!
Where's my mother?
Some posit that every experience
is worth living.
Do you agree?
It must be hard for a woman
with your brains and drive
to find herself in such
abject circumstances.
Do you have to teach philosophy
to spout such crap?
And with your daughter, too.
Michèle...
I've got $100.
What do you have to offer?
- Tell your wife I sucked you off.
- Sucked me off?
You?
That's worth more than $100.
- $200?
- Go to hell!
$300?
If you go to the casino
tonight with $300,
you'll leave with how much?
Twice that?
Three times?
Michèle...
do you want
to get Margot out of here?
Hello, darling!
Béatrice, this is Charles,
the man of my life.
I've heard lots about you.
I have to make a few calls.
A big client.
I'll be back.
Come on, Michèle!
That's good.
That's it.
That feels good.
Yes, keep going.
That's it, eat me.
You like it, I can tell.
A real pro.
Yes, that's it.
You're a slut like your mom.
No, don't stop.
Keep going!
Do it for yourself,
for your daughter.
Hello, darling.
You sure have
a gift for fucking up.
Did you come here to preach?
I came to see Margot, not you.
She hardly talked to me.
But who'd want to chat,
living in a shithole like this?
She didn't deserve it,
especially not in her condition.
Will she have an abortion?
I went to see Jean-Claude
for my hormones.
He was worried,
he hadn't heard from her.
He blurted it out.
He thought I knew.
And he thought right.
I should have known,
don't you think?
So I pretended I did.
You're taking hormones?
How's Jean-Claude?
Michèle, really!
Couldn't you have told me?
I mean, I'm your mother!
I guess we don't
choose our mom.
Funny, that's exactly
what Margot told me.
Michèle, come on!
Mimi!
What's going on?
It'll be okay, darling.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
It'll be okay.
I'm sorry, Béatrice.
Charles isn't himself.
He works too hard.
We'll take a vacation soon.
I should be going.
It's late and my kids are waiting.
I got my first paycheck.
It's just part
of the money I...
that I owe you.
Margot...
I want you to know...
I know my life's a mess,
I know you deserve a way
better mother than me...
but you're the most
precious thing I have.
I love you.
And I'm here for you.
Completely... any time,
for any reason, always.
And you can tell me anything,
no matter what...
I'm pregnant.
Don't ask any questions.
I hate him!
I'm ashamed.
- I'm scared.
- It's okay, it will work out.
This is for you.
Is that me?
I love you!
Turn over, I'll rub your back.
That feels good.
Dad?
Dad!
Hi, little man!
We'll play later.
Janine, I...
Hello, my big girl.
Yes, I'm fine, thanks.
Is my Gaby here?
Gaby!
- Hi, Grandpa!
- Hello, angel.
- Are you ready?
- I'll grab my stuff.
- We're off to a movie.
- No...
no, no, we're having guests
over for dinner.
I promised her. We wanted
to treat ourselves.
Have dinner with us.
You can see the movie
tomorrow or whenever.
Hello, Béatrice.
Thanks for the invitation.
I was feeling a bit lonely tonight.
You look ravishing.
You're right on time.
Kids?
This is my father, Lucien.
- Hello. It's a pleasure.
- My son, Alexandre.
And you know Charles.
Everybody, this is Kate,
Dad's other wife,
and their daughter, Anaïs.
Gabrielle?
Gabrielle, this is Kate.
Hello, Gabrielle.
I'm very happy to meet you.
You're bigger than I thought.
Kate is Dad's other wife.
Let's eat and get
to know each other.
I prepared dinner.
Dad, what's going on?
Gosh, sit down. I want to enjoy
this lovely time before I leave.
- You're leaving?
- Yes, missy.
I'm leaving...
for Europe
to hitchhike
and smoke some pot!
Don't look so stunned, Gaby.
You must have smoked too.
I'm 20 years late,
but better late than never.
Dad?
- Dad, what's going on?
- This was Gaby's birthday.
They grow so fast.
Dad!