Modern Farmer
Noona.
Where are you going?
Oh...
I need to rent tents for the marketplace.
I see...
By yourself? You want me to go with you?
No, I'm fine.
You don't have to.
I'll go with you.
I said I'm fine.
I said I'll go.
Let's go.
There aren't any grasshoppers.
Just catch what you can.
Jeez, where did Hyuk go?
We have to catch grasshoppers
for the marketplace.
We have to get our instruments later, too.
He's not answering the phone.
He must be sleeping somewhere.
100% for sure.
Oppas!
Hey.
What's all the fuss about?
I didn't come to see you.
Please.
But...
Where's Kang Hyuk oppa?
Don't know. He must be hiding
out sleeping somewhere.
Why?
You know what?
Oppas became really popular.
Popular?
What?
Look at this. This.
[Awesome fish slap]
[Who's in the back?]
[Is that a carp?
Matilda, your dad's back! Behind you!]
Dad!
Why is this going around on the Internet?
Jeez, how embarrassing. What the heck?
There are over a million views already.
Not only on every websites, but also
on all the cafes, blogs and twitters.
Oppas...
You really became stars!
Star, my ass.
This is nothing to be proud of.
The promotion for "Excellent Souls"
went really well.
- Didn't it?
- Enough!
Who recorded this and
posted it on the Internet?
Forget it.
Don't worry about it.
We can just focus on the grasshoppers.
Ki Joon, go to Man Gu ahjusshi's house
and get two more plastic bottles.
What for?
To sell grasshoppers at the marketplace,
we need to fill up at least two more bottles.
Okay, stop making me do this stuff anymore.
Hey.
Would Seoul people buy pea
puffs and grasshoppers?
Of course. This is 100%.
Aren't we also Seoul people?
Trust me.
So, hurry up and catch
grasshoppers. Come on, come on.
There aren't any grasshoppers.
Let me help you.
If you look deep inside, you'll see them.
Hyung, where's Man Gu ahjusshi's house?
I don't know. Figure it out.
Hey, grasshoppers aren't... Are there?
Oppa, I'm scared of grasshoppers.
I'll go over there and find
them. There're none here.
I got one!
Why are you here?
You'd give me more time.
I'm not here to collect your money.
By the way...
I have something to ask you.
What is it?
You want to do "Weekend Farm" here?
Yeah.
Well...
Such fresh air...
I like the village, too.
Moreover, they started
getting atopic dermatitis.
Stop eating already, punk.
So...
we planted some lettuce seedlings yesterday.
But when we came this morning,
they were like this.
What's going on?
You want to farm when you don't
even know this? Farming is no joke.
It's the elks.
Elks?
They eat this stuff?
They go crazy over this stuff.
We went through so much because of elks.
You know, I'm the god of farming.
Such a man is standing right next to you.
This is in fact...
There's cresol soap solution.
If you plant that around the field,
those elks go "My nose is rotting,"
and won't come around the field.
Wait a second. Write this down.
I said stop eating and
write this down, punks.
C... what?
I was saying...
C...
Forget it.
I'll just take care of it.
Don't do anything.
The way you talk...
The way you talk to me is rather annoying.
Did you forget our relationship?
I can forever boss you around.
What are you trying to do, punk?
I'm sorry.
Where did I see him?
What if Bul Ja is there?
I can't run into her.
Oh, my goodness!
Ahjumma, you scared the heck out of me.
You've never seen a facial mask?
Why are you here?
You're here for Bul Ja.
Bul Ja's not here.
Jeez, it's not like that.
I came for plastic bottles.
- Oh, bottles?
- Yes.
Go to the storage. You can find them there.
Thank you.
Don't go around like that.
I can do whatever I want to do at my house.
You just take the bottles.
She always brings up Bul Ja.
Where are the bottles?
Where are they?
I'm home.
Oh, no. What timing...
Where to hide?
Jeez.
Not just a pretty face
but her figure is also...
Oh, my.
Han Ki Joon, what are you
thinking about? Close your eyes.
Thank you.
Noona.
They're all loaded.
Yeah. Thank you.
Let's go home.
Noona.
When we go back,
can I drive?
You?
No way. I can't trust you. No way. Never.
Noona.
You can teach me, noona.
I said you can't.
Noona.
- Noona.
- Jeez.
Okay.
- You'll be responsible for any accidents, okay?
- Okay.
Hey, why do you keep going straight?
Noona.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Right.
Stay calm.
This is your last chance.
If you can't get off this time, there's
no other way to get to the village.
If you get off here, there's a way.
This is your last chance.
Turn on your signal without
getting flustered.
Without getting flustered...
Signal.
There you go. Good. It's flickering.
Now, wait for the right moment
and start moving to the right.
Just move in, okay?
- Right.
- Wait.
Wait.
Now!
I just can't! I can't. The car
behind me is coming too fast.
We are now on the overpass, punk!
Jeez, dang it.
Why did I tell her I liked americano?
I've been drinking it for days.
Wait a second.
I like it.
My sense is so...
Ahjusshi.
Can I borrow your phone?
Phone? Why?
Just because. Come on.
Hello.
Daddy.
It's me, Eun Woo.
You know, the participation class
I told you about is tomorrow.
You can make it, right?
Don't worry. I didn't tell mom.
Okay, then I'll see you tomorrow.
Ahjusshi.
Keep it a secret from my mom.
Okay.
I got it.
You...
Don't even think about driving again.
Okay.
Noona.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Noona.
Over there. Look.
What do you want me to look at now?
Jeez.
Wow, the beach!
Come on, noona.
I don't wanna go.
No way. You must come.
Really. I said I really don't wanna go in.
Noona, you must go into the
water when you're at the beach.
I just want to take a walk.
Jeez.
You're happy to see the
ocean thanks to me, right?
Jeez.
What nerve.
Do you know how much you
shortened my lifespan?
I'm sorry.
Don't stay mad.
Jeez, it's nice to see the ocean.
How long has it been?
You smiled.
Right?
You were frowning all day like
this and you're finally smiling.
Yay! It was worth coming to the ocean!
No one's here.
Hey.
He wouldn't have destroyed
our instruments, would he?
Where's Ki Joon anyway?
Forget it.
We have to take them out when
he's not around. Let's go.
Can't you go alone?
Sure. What?
Come on. Follow me.
There they are.
Let's hurry and take them.
We don't know what'll happen
to us if we get caught.
You go ahead.
We finally got it.
Look...
Isn't that a snake?
Snake?
It looks like an eel.
It's getting late. Let's go.
Noona.
Shouldn't we eat sashimi
since we're at the beach?
Sashimi?
I'm hungry.
Let's just have one dish.
Jeez.
Let's just go home and eat.
See?
You're hungry, too.
Noona.
Let's eat.
Huh?
Then...
just one dish, okay?
Cool.
Oh, my.
Sashimi tastes the best at the beach.
Say ah.
It's okay.
I have my own hands.
You're embarrassing my hands.
Say ah.
Ah.
You eat so well.
But...
now that we're eating sashimi,
don't you crave soju?
Let's just have one glass.
Are you crazy? Who'd drive?
And I need to go to Min Ho's school tomorrow.
Just one glass.
Jeez...
Just one glass, okay?
Cheers.
Soju's perfect with sashimi.
Sashiso, Sosashi.
Sosashi. Sosashi.
By the way...
isn't this too little?
Can't we just have one more glass?
Jeez...
I hear there aren't any check points today.
We finished it already.
We still have plenty of food.
Noona.
Can't we have one more bottle?
No way.
Who'll drive?
We can use the driving service like before.
Oh, my...
then just one more bottle?
We're home.
Hi.
What happened to your faces?
We got slapped by eel.
It was fish slap yesterday.
And eel slap today.
Hey, doesn't it hurt less when you
get slapped by more expensive fish?
Fat chance, punk.
Min Ho, why is your mom so late?
Noona's not home yet?
What about Hyuk and Ki Joon?
I don't know. They're not home yet either.
No...
No!
There's no way I like Bul Ja.
No way.
But...
[Aunt]
What a relief.
What is?
You seem to feel better.
Because of Min Ho,
you've been frowning all day.
I was worried and bothered.
Aren't you proud of me?
Sure, I'm proud.
Noona, me, too.
What are you doing?
Do what you did to Min Ki earlier.
Okay.
Hyuk, you did such a good job.
So good.
Satisfied?
You said you're a med student.
Aren't your parents against
what you're doing now?
My mom passed away and...
as for my dad...
it's like he's not around.
We don't get along. Me and my dad...
Why?
You're not respected...
unless you're a doctor in my family.
He's ashamed of troublemaker like me.
But...
when did your mom pass away?
Eight years ago.
She overdosed...
on pills because of her depression.
Oh, my goodness.
But I didn't even know she was depressed.
My mom also...
pretended to be strong like you all the time.
In this world...
I was the only one who can protect her.
But I couldn't protect her.
So...
I won't make the same mistake again.
You, too...
Depend on me.
When you're tired...
and worn out...
you can depend on me.
I'll protect you.
Depend...
The phone is turned off.
Her phone is turned off.
What's up with Yoon Hee?
Hyuk didn't come home either.
Perhaps...
Aren't they together?
Jerk.
Wait 'til he comes home...
Good going. A mom sleeping outside the home.
Hey, Little Rockstar.
Going to school?
I'll go to school.
Min Ho.
Let me take you to school today.
Let's go.
Jeez, by the way, what'll we do
about his participation class?
What the heck is this ahjumma doing?
Oh, my head...
Why am I here?
This is crazy.
8 o'clock?
Hey.
Hey, hey!
Wake up!
Jeez.
Come on.
Wake up!
What the...
Did we...
...sleep here?
This is nuts. That's why
we shouldn't have drank.
Nothing good happens when I'm with you.
Right.
Min Ho's participation class is today.
This is crazy.
Oh, my head...
I'm not sure if I can drive.
Noona.
You shouldn't. I'll drive.
Jeez, it's okay. Who are you trying to kill?
Noona, don't worry. Just wear the seatbelt.
Jeez.
Forget it. I can drive.
Noona, trust me.
How can I trust you again?
I'll take off.
What the?
You taught me.
Now I'm better.
Hold on tight.
If you embarrass me at school today,
I'll stop going to school, okay?
Okay, I got it.
I got another perm.
You can't come, Mom.
Okay?
Okay, I won't go.
Don't worry. Go and have a nice day.
- Darling.
- Come on.
Go.
Guys, play with me.
My dad is a CEO.
He has lots of employees. He has a huge car.
Wow, really?
So amazing.
Min Ho.
What about your dad?
He doesn't have a dad.
What?
Is there anyone without a dad in the world?
Teacher's coming in.
Attention.
Greeting.
Hello.
Today, we have a dad participation class.
You know we have one day teacher, right?
Yes!
You must listen to him and behave, okay?
Min Gook's father will teach first period.
Come in please.
He's a grandpa.
Right, he's old.
Hello.
I am Min Gook's dad.
Huh?
Aren't you his grandpa?
I'm going to teach today...
I mean...
Something you like...
How to farm sweet and juicy strawberries.
Quiet.
Strawberries are...
one of the perennial fruit vegetables...
that thrive in cool climate.
Please go on.
What? What's going on?
What?
Seedlings are...
planted after mid September...
What again?
Father?
What's going on?
I...
Teacher...
I'm sorry.
Can I change the subject?
Of course, do as you like.
Thank you.
"zdra-stvooy-tye"
What?
What this is...
It's "Hello" in Uzbek.
Repeat after me.
"zdra-stvooy-tye"
Isn't it fun?
Yes!
Then...
shall we listen to a native speaker?
Yes!
Just a moment please.
Sure.
Darling.
Come in.
Come.
Come in. It's okay.
This is...
Min Gook's mom.
Isn't she pretty?
Yes!
Min Gook's mom...
...is from Uzbekistan.
So, she's fluent in Uzbek.
Listen carefully and repeat, okay?
Yes!
Try it. Do it.
"zdra-stvooy-tye"
Then...
this time...
in Uzbekistan...
Kim Tae Hee plows the field, and...
Song Hae Gyo raises sheep?
Shall we listen to that
from a native speaker?
Sure!
It must be so nice.
It's fun. Do it for them.
Then, Teacher.
How do you say...
"I love you"...
...in Uzbek?
"ya lyublyu tyebya"
Come on. Repeat after her.
One more time! What did you say?
"ya lyublyu tyebya"
What?
This is so good.
This Rice Winelatte.
This is rather addictive.
Hello.
Who's this?
This is...
...Eun Woo's father.
She made a call...
...with this phone earlier.
Oh, yes.
Hello.
I have an emergency.
I can't go to her school today.
Please tell her I'm very sorry.
Okay, I will.
Thank you.
Then bye.
Okay. Bye.
Jeez, he should've called earlier.
Damn. My ass.
Did you like Min Gook's
father and mother's class?
Yes!
A big round of applause!
Next is Eun Woo's dad's
turn, but he's not here yet.
Eun Woo, your dad said
he'd be here today, right?
Yes, he promised me that
he'd come. He'll be here.
Who...
I received a call from Eun Woo's father.
He said he can't come
because of an emergency.
Oh, really?
Instead...
can I do it?
I'm like her uncle.
Oh, really?
It's fine with me.
Okay.
I'll teach you today...
That is...
Jeez.
Right.
I'll teach you how to open rice
wine bottle without spilling over.
You know, rice wine is...
You need to mix first and drink.
To one direction only...
If you don't want to spill,
you shake it in one direction.
You shake it like this.
After that...
you twist the cap a little and push the
belly button. You ask, "Did you eat?"
"Yeah, I did". You get the
answer and twist the cap again.
Like this. And push the
belly button. Like this.
And then, now you can open the cap like this.
This...
Oh, my.
This shouldn't have spilt over.
It's because I ran here.
Uncle's way of opening the rice wine
bottle without spilling over...
How to store rice wine...
and Rice...
It's Rice Winelatte.
Rice Winelatte.
Oh, yes.
You learned how to make Rice Winelatte.
Yes.
It's Min Ho's turn next.
Min Ho, your mom's not here yet.
Well...
She can't come because she's busy.
Oh, really?
Today's dad participation class is completed.
Wait! Wow. Jeez.
My heart...
Hyung!
I...
I am Min Ho's uncle.
Can an uncle participate in
the dad participation class?
Huh?
Oh, sure.
Really? Thank you.
Hey, kids.
This is a music class.
Special...
Rock and roll!
I'll invite you to...
the world of rock and roll.
Let's go.
Everyone, get up!
Shake like this.
Oh, yeah. Everybody, rock and roll!
Shake your head like this.
Noona.
What are you doing? You're in a hurry.
- Run. Go.
- Huh?
Hurry up.
Rock and roll!
Yeah!
Come on.
Shake your head like this.
Eun Woo.
Eun Woo!
Listen to me, Eun Woo.
That punk...
Min Gook.
How did your mom and dad do today?
Weren't we great?
Yes, kids had so much fun.
They said you're super pretty, Mom.
Really?
Shall we go to town and eat
some pork ribs you love?
Pork ribs?
Come on. Let's go.
Let's go!
Where were you yesterday?
That...
We went to the beach...
...inadvertently.
We had a drink inadvertently.
Good going, a mom... You really...
I'm sorry.
Min Ho.
I'm so sorry.
No, it was so fun because of Min Ki hyung.
Mom.
We're going on a picnic tomorrow.
Can I go with Min Ki hyung?
You can't. He's busy.
I can go.
I worked so hard.
I can take a day off. It's okay, it's okay.
Really?
Wow, you're the man. High-five!
I'm so happy. Min Ki hyung's the best!
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
It's nothing.
I mean it.
I really appreciate it.
Min Ho, let me go with you.
So sly...
You scared me.
What are you talking about?
You're so sly, jerk.
He's really...
Hi, Yoo Na.
What's up?
Nothing.
I just thought of you.
How's your country life?
It's good.
The cabbages are...
...growing so fast.
That's great.
Should I...
quit being a singer...
and become a farmer like you?
What are you talking about?
Just because...
I'm just getting tired of this.
You're full of it. I'm growing
cabbages to make an album.
You, wait right there.
I'll be up there soon.
Okay.
I have a shoot. I have to go.
Why don't you answer my call?
The CEO wants me to bring you.
I said I won't go to a party like that.
They are heirs to well-known conglomerates.
There's no harm looking good to them.
Do you want me to be
treated like a toy again?
Moreover, they do drugs. You know that?
Just go along with the atmosphere.
Others are dying to go there.
Then take whoever is dying to go there.
Hey, are you really gonna be this way?
Yoo Na.
I really hate this.
The CEO wants to bring you no matter what.
For my sake,
please go today.
Please?
I hate Dad!
Dad is bad!
Well...
He had an emergency.
He's really sorry.
So, don't hate him, okay? Understand?
Stop crying.
What are you talking about?
Mi Young.
What do you mean Dad?
Did you call Dad?
You know...
It's not her fault.
I... I called him.
I heard about the dad participation class.
What?
Who are you to do that? How dare you?
I'm sorry.
You think saying sorry is enough?
Let's say she's just being immature.
You should've stopped her.
Okay.
I was thoughtless.
I'm sorry.
I'll go.
Eun Woo, I'll go.
Don't make her cry.
It's warm. So warm.
So good. Jeez, so nice.
Thanks.
You know...
About today...
Thank you so much.
I said don't mention it.
I'm glad Min Ho liked it.
I know.
I don't even know when was the last
time I saw him smiling like that.
It's been so long since
I saw you smiling, too.
So...
don't frown. Keep smiling like that.
You know...
can I ask you something?
What?
I'm grateful you're being
nice to Min Ho and me.
What's your intention though?
What intention?
If you don't look good,
it bothers me.
If you cry,
I'm sad, too.
If you smile,
I'm happy, too.
I wish you happiness.
You're my first love. I should
offer some after service, you know.
It's cold. I'll go in. Goodnight.
Okay. Go inside.
Mi Young.
What are you doing at this hour?
I'm sorry...
...about earlier.
Not at all.
I overstepped my boundary.
It's all my fault.
No, I was too much.
It's okay.
I understand you.
Let me have one.
Sure.
I was busy fighting when I was married.
He had so many women.
I lived like that from the moment I got
married 'til the moment I divorced.
For Eun Woo's sake,
I endured...
endured...
...and endured.
I couldn't stand it.
When I asked for a divorce,
he threw money at me and signed the
paper as if he was waiting for it.
This is...
the punishment I got for leaving you.
What are you saying?
What kind of life is this?
Don't cry.
Don't...
Jeez.
Oppa...
Stop it.
It's all in the past.
Don't say...
Why am I sleepy at the start of the day?
Jeez, I might just fall asleep.
I'm so sleepy. So sleepy.
What's all this mess?
They should've cleaned after
themselves. Who did this?
Crazy jerk. He left a sock.
Jeez, so crazy.
Jeez.
Oh, my...
Ki Joon, come here and eat.
Hey.
Ki Joon!
What's wrong with you?
Looking like a ghost...
I said it's nothing.
Why can't I daydream?
Never mind. Why are you
getting mad at me, jerk?
It's because you keep saying absurd things.
A group of heirs to the conglomerates were
smoking marijuana in Seoul and got arrested.
[Singer Yoo Na caught smoking
marijuana with heirs.]
The famous singer, Yoo Na
was with them at the scene.
Hyung, look at this.
The test results were negative
and she was sent home tonight.
However...
it's expected to have a
negative impact on her image.
Noona, I'm sorry.
I don't think I can go today.
Aren't they ever gonna sleep?
They're camping out in front of the agency.
All scheduled events are canceled.
The advertisers are threatening
to sue us for breach of contract.
What should we do?
We totally stepped in shit.
Why did you get involved
in a marijuana scandal?
Where are you going?
To the bathroom.
Min Ki.
Follow me.
Where did Min Ki hyung go?
Did he go to Yoo Na noona?
No way.
What can he do even if he goes to her?
By the way...
do you know the singer on the news earlier?
Yeah, we were apprentices together.
Really?
Right.
You guys said you were singers before.
Yes.
We failed, but...
What are you doing?
Ah...
It's Sang Eun's birthday tomorrow.
Sang Eun?
That idol wannabe?
Why do you care for her birthday?
You don't need to know.
Right.
I don't need to know.
I'm sorry.
Oh, my... my puppy.
Did you have fun at the picnic?
No.
Why not?
Did you fight with your friend?
No.
But is Min Ki hyung home yet?
Huh?
He's not here yet.
Dad.
Tomorrow, you're going to Seoul
direct marketplace, right?
On the way home,
buy me a cell phone...
for my birthday gift.
Why?
What's wrong with listening to music?
You always say you have no money.
Fine. Forget it.
I'm an idiot to expect anything from you.
Frustrating. Jeez.
Damn it. Why do rocks keep coming out?
Was this place a quarry or something?
Let's take a break, hyungnim.
Jeez, sure.
Why did I even start doing this
"weekend farm" thing anyway?
Hyungnim.
Where are you going?
Hey, I'll be right back.
You two, pick out rocks.
Excuse me.
You're In Ki, right?
You're Han In Ki, right?
Don't you recognize me?
It's me.
Seung Chul.
Where are you going, punk?
We have a lot to talk about.
What the heck are you doing?
Are you teasing me?
What the heck?
What's wrong with you?
Huh?
[I'm sorry.]
You think saying sorry is enough?
Huh?
Do you even know what happened
to us after you disappeared?
Sang Pil drives a taxi and
Gun Tae sells fruits on a truck.
I became a loan shark who lends money...
and live off interest, punk.
Hey.
Tell me.
Why did you disappear
without a word back then?
Jeez, punk...
You must have a glamorous life after
you ruined others' lives like that.
What kind of life is this?
Tell me.
Why did you do that?
Huh?
Is it...
...because of Sook Kyung?
[Practice is the only way.
Let's not get lazy smiling.]
Hey, hey.
Are you all ready?
Yes, we are.
You know the Dream Record
CEO is coming today.
If you do well,
you'll make a debut. Debut!
Debut! Debut!
Hyung, don't you worry.
We have In Ki, you know. Right?
If In Ki's on stage, everyone will die!
In Ki.
You can do well, right?
Don't worry.
I'll pretend this is my last
chance and do it for my life.
Let's succeed and...
...have a good life, okay?
Let's stop living in a basement
and breathing in all that dust.
Jeez, that damn ramen.
I'm so sick and tired of it.
Right, we're counting on you. Okay?
- Okay.
- We only got In Ki.
Hello.
Yes.
Hold on a second.
In Ki.
Take the call.
Hello.
Yes.
What?
Hey, where are you going?
Sook Kyung...
...collapsed.
I gotta go.
Punk.
Are we in a situation to think about that?
If you go now, it's all over for us. Over.
I'm sorry.
You punk...
Hey, In Ki!
Han In Ki!
Um...
Yoon Sook Kyung...
Where is she?
Oh...
Are you Yoon Sook Kyung's guardian?
Yes.
Come this way.
Congratulations, Yoon Sook Kyung.
You just delivered a princess.
Dear.
Are you okay?
Dear...
Thank you, honey.
Your performance...
You want to hold the baby?
Excuse me? Yes.
She's bleeding.
Check her blood pressure.
Are you okay?
Hello!
Her blood pressure is going down.
There's no way.
Let the guardian out. Prepare for surgery.
Hand over the baby.
You must leave now. Right now.
Sook Kyung.
Sook Kyung!
Oh, no! Sook Kyung!
So, you live like this because of that?
That's why you ruined your friends' lives
and live in this remote country, punk?
[I'm sorry.]
Sook Kyung...
...died because of me.
Why is it because of you?
Your wife died while giving
birth. Why is it your fault?
Where am I supposed to dig today?
I paint during the day and dig at night.
I'll die of fatigue even
before I find the money.
Hello.
I told you not to call me.
Did they...
...come again?
Don't even talk about it.
They come whenever and...
threaten me to spill where you are.
You're having a hard time because of me.
I'm sorry.
But...
where are you anyway?
That...
I'll explain later. Later.
Okay, wench.
Anyway, take care.
If anything happens,
call me, okay?
Okay.
Forget it.
You don't need to explain.
Now that I think about it,
I understand everything.
The reason why you never told me about mom...
The reason why you never bought
a cake on my birthday...
My birthday...
...is mom's memorial day.
It's all because of me.
If I had not been born,
mom wouldn't have died...
and you wouldn't be like this.
I'm so sorry, Dad.
Let go.
I don't want to talk to you right now.
Sang Eun.
Sang Eun!
It's not you.
Mom?
Why are you coming out?
Go inside and rest.
I'm fine.
By the way...
You have an important performance today.
Yes.
The CEO of an agency who
is interested in our band
is coming to see us.
If things work out,
we might be able to make an album.
Great!
Do a great job today.
Fighting!
You know...
If things don't go well this time,
I'll give up on music.
Endure a little longer.
Don't say such a thing.
I trust you. Never give up.
Okay?
Thank you.
I'll get going.
Wait a second.
It's okay. I don't need money.
Men shouldn't go around with empty pockets.
If it works out,
have a drink with the members.
I'm sorry. You're suffering because of me.
I can't face you.
What hardship?
Hurry up. Go.
Leave, honey.
Okay. Anyway...
I'll be back.
- Bye.
Do a great job. Fighting!
- Go inside.
- Okay.
Straighten your shoulders.
- Sure.
- Your hair.
I'm back.
Jeez, your husband is so shameless.
How can he make his wife
work who's about to deliver?
Don't say things like that.
My husband will soon...
become more famous than Cho Yongpil.
Cho Yongpil, my ass.
He's a musician who can't even make a living.
Don't be like that.
My baby might hear that.
Oh, baby.
Your daddy is a great man.
Then...
I'll clean up the rest.
Okay, take it inside.
Sook Kyung!
It's...
It's all my fault.
I...
I wanted to make music...
If I didn't insist...
your mom...
I...
I killed her.
No.
You didn't.
Hey.
Hey, be gentle.
If you damage it, you can't
sell it at the market tomorrow.
Okay.
Mom.
Can you call Min Ki hyung
and ask when he'll be back?
He'll come when it's time.
Min Ho, it's cold. Go inside.
No, I don't want to.
I'll wait until he comes home.
It's Min Ki hyung.
Min Ki hyung!
Hey.
It's Yoo Na!
I'm sorry, noona.
Let her stay for a few
days. She has her reasons.
A princess has come.
Why are you talking like that?
Don't like me. I said we can't be.
What kind of relationship does
that woman and Soo Yun have?
It doesn't make sense at all.
What did I do wrong to you, Ki Joon?
Don't look at other men. Don't
talk to them. Don't smile at them.
Excuse me?
You should've cared for her.
Am I her maid or something? You do it then.