- Here; option one is the cheapest.
- But paragraph 2.2...
- Hi, Sami! - Excuse me.
- Hi, Baba.
Are you good? Look, I got the fish.
You can cook it tonight.
- Great, thanks.
- Don't forget spices and salt.
- How is Amanda?
- Fine. She's working.
What working? I told you,
she have baby, no work, must rest.
- It's fine, Dad. I can't talk now.
- Okay. There's potatoes in there too.
- Fish is good. You like fish?
- Yes, it's good stuff.
- You eat fish, live many years.
- To an old age.
No, not old, just live extra.
- OK, Sami, see you tonight.
- Bye, Baba! - Sorry. My dad.
- I understand.
- So, 2.2.
- Right, sorry. 2.2...
- Hi, Juan. Are you good?
- Hi, Aziz. Just fine.
What you doing?
- Fixing lamp, good. Coffee?
- Please.
Dill, got it. And low-fat milk? Okay.
Roast... Roast beef.
- Hi, boss!
- Hi, Aziz. - No, Aziz came in.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- Look.
- What is it?
Ah, the cord goes this way.
It's like this in old lamps.
Hi. I need a bit of help
with my bike.
- It is broken?
- I can't get the lock open.
- It is your bike?
- Yes, it's my bike.
- You have papers?
- No... it was my Mum's, she just died.
- Uh-huh.
- Yes, it was very sad.
- How much you want to pay?
- Uh, 20 kronor?
- 20 kronor? What you saying, 20 kronor?
- Juan, you hear him? 20 kronor.
- A hundred.
- That's good. - You pay 300.
- 300? The lock isn't worth 80!
- 300 or I call the police.
- 300 is great.
- Good! Juan, get the tool.
Wait, wait, don't open, Juan.
300 kronor first.
Now open. Okay.
- Thank you. Thanks a lot.
- Thanks, goodbye.
He a thief! Paid 300!
- Aziz? What's going on?
- We oil chain only. 100 kronor.
- Okay. Look, I need help inside.
- I be right there.
So, 100 to you, 100 to me.
Is good.
- Can you manage the shop a while?
- No problem, boss.
Mum will come and tally up sales.
- Your wife call?
- Yes, I have to help her at home.
- Jörgen, she always call, you run!
- Nothing strange about that.
Very strange! You must be man,
strong man. Or else she say goodbye.
- What are you talking about?
- Okay, have it your way.
- Hi, Mum! All right?
- Just fine. Jörgen, helmet!
- Hi! Are you good?
- Good, just fine. You?
- Good too. If you're good I'm good.
- Then we're both good.
Dino...
Dino!
Dino boy. Puppy...
- Juan, Dino sick?
- He's been droopy lately.
Are you in pain?
Does it hurt?
Your legs? Do your legs hurt?
- What colour do you want?
- I was thinking white.
- How much? The whole way?
- Yes, what can it be, 2-3 metres?
Something like that. I'll measure it
so I don't make extra work for myself.
- What was that about?
- I wanted to borrow a hedge shear.
- Hedge shear...
- Come in and eat!
- Had a good day?
- Yeah.
- Sami, can you get that?
- I'm about to get a high score!
You're so unbelievably lazy!
"High score"...
Hi, Aziz!
Fine, how are you?
Your son? He's playing video games.
I know, childish, isn't it?
Here he comes.
- Video games aren't childish.
- No, they're very mature.
- I'm very hungry. The fish ready?
- I'll check.
- Amanda, is the fish ready?
- What fish?
Yes, it's almost ready. Okay.
See you tonight. Bye.
- Sami, I want to finish this!
- I promise, I'll do it later.
You... I know, but... You think it's a
pain pretending all the time, too.
- All he wants is grandchildren.
- We're going to have kids!
We're going to adopt.
I mean... Kids of our own.
- What, you feel the same way?
- No, of course not.
I promise, everything will be perfect
when he meets a woman.
I swear! He'll drop the grandchildren
thing and focus on her.
- Of course... Brilliant idea...
- I think so!
- I'll put him on some dating site.
- Remind me, why did I marry you?
- Seriously, no dating sites.
- Why not?
You just... Have to try harder.
He... No. We could call Gunnel
and have her come over.
- Gunnel who?
- My colleague. She's really pretty.
She's always saying
she wants to meet someone.
- You think she'd like Dad?
- Yes. But what he'll think of her...
- Let's try it.
- Okay, go ahead.
I'll do it!
- Can you get my shirt?
- Of course.
- It feels so gigantic!
- The old one was too small.
- Wait... Should the navel be here?
- Shit, I put it on upside down.
- There.
- Does it feel okay?
- Are you sure it's not too big?
- No, this is the right month.
- Sure?
- There he is.
- Hi!
- Hi, Amanda, are you good?
Good. Ah, he getting big, the baby.
Good, good.
- What's Sami doing?
- Cooking. Let me take yourjacket.
- He's a decent cook. You're better.
- Thank you.
Hi, Sami! Are you good?
Amanda, have you thought
what to name baby?
We've thought a bit, but we'll wait
to see if it's a girl or a boy.
You don't know what it is?
Wait, I'll say...
I think a boy. I know when I see woman.
90% I'm sure it's boy.
- So we need boy's names.
- You find a good name.
Sami, come! Come see,
dad bring great present.
- What's that?
- Family tree, very nice.
Look, that's me, your mother,
you Sami, and Amanda.
It's you and me!
And then four empty ones.
Ah, four empty. There is soon baby
here, and maybe three come later.
- So we're having four kids?
- Four.
- If you want more I can put here...
- No, four is good.
- Four good?
- We'll start there.
- What you say, Sami?
- Four is good.
- Wine or beer with dinner?
- I'll have a beer... water.
- Baba?
- I drink arrack.
- Double or single?
- Big, your dad don't drink small.
- Who's that?
- A friend of Amanda's. She's nice.
Hi, Gunnel! Come in!
You look fabulous.
- I'm not late, am I?
- Of course not! Come in.
- You won't forget?
- Don't worry.
- Aziz, this is Gunnel, my colleague.
- This is Aziz.
- This is my son.
- Sami. Glad you could come.
- Nice.
- Thank you.
So, have a seat!
- Here, Baba.
- Thanks.
- Thank you for cooking.
- It was very good.
Baba, you know they work together at
the hospital, Amanda and Gunnel?
- Yes, Amanda said.
- We have fun together.
- Good.
- Good co-workers are important.
They're almost more important
than the job itself.
Of course, we prefer
the coffee breaks.
Good...
- So, what do you work with?
- Who, me?
You want know where I work?
I work with mafia.
You know mafia?
- No...
- You don't know mafia?
You know, sometimes also
we go around town. Drink little beer.
We get tired, what we do now, so we
take gun and shoot people on street.
We don't like their face,
we shoot them.
- You want see the gun?
- Baba!
Dad has a different sense of humour.
He's just kidding.
Amanda, your friend think,
she scared from me.
- Be nice now!
- I'm kidding.
- So... what are you doing tomorrow?
- Nothing.
No?
- I feel like dessert.
- I'll get the ice cream.
Don't drive right into the wall.
You have to pass the other cars.
- Thanks for coming.
- It was fun.
See you.
- You have to turn the car around.
- This is hard!
- That went well...
- What you say?
Nothing, I'm just tired.
Good night.
- Good night, Aziz.
- Good night, Amanda.
- You've already lost.
- I'm too tired to play.
Sami, I must ask: Why you bring
Gunilla here today?
She's a friend of Amanda's.
She came for dinner.
That's it? I see in your eyes
you have something else to say.
Tell.
To be honest, Dad, I do want
to talk to you about something.
What?
- Maybe you need to meet people.
- What you mean?
- Maybe meet a girl.
- A girl? No thanks, I am happy now.
Why you think this?
I have you, Amanda, soon babies.
- I am very happy.
- I know.
But maybe you'd like
someone besides us.
You know I can't do that.
I think of your mother all the time.
- I love her, that's why.
- I understand.
It's the same for me. I love her so
much. I think about her every day.
But it's ten years since she died.
Maybe it's time to move on.
It could be fun, Amanda and me
and you and your girlfriend...
Your grandchild will have a grandma,
we could be a big family.
- What do you think?
- Okay, I'll think about it.
- I can help you look.
- No, I don't need help.
Thanks. Okay.
- Okay Baba. I'm going to bed.
- Okay.
- Will you sleep here?
- Yes, I'll sleep here.
Good night.
Baba... I didn't upset you, did I?
Sami! You're my son, should
you make me upset? Never!
- Forget about it. Good night!
- Good night, Baba.
- I'm going to make some tea.
- Let me.
- I'll pause this.
- Nah, it'll only take a second.
- It's more fun to watch together.
- Okay, pause it.
- You don't have to get mad.
- I'm not mad.
Lotta, is something going on?
You can talk to me.
- I'm a good listener.
- Nothing is going on.
- I'm just going for more tea!
- I'll take care of it.
I just thought it felt wrong when
you didn't want to watch the film.
I wanted tea.
It has nothing to do with us.
"Us"? What do you mean?
- That's not what I meant!
- What did you mean?
- I'm going to bed.
- We have to talk!
I can't stand it when you act
this way. AII... wimpy!
Good night!
Mariam, how are you?
My darling, my life...
I want to ask you something,
but I don't know how to say it.
Our son wants me
to meet a new woman.
You know how much I love you.
What do you think I should do?
Well...
- Nothing wrong with him, eh?
- He has hip problems.
- What's wrong with him?
- Arthritis. It's common in old dogs.
Are there medicines,
or an operation?
I wouldn't operate on such an old dog.
I recommend putting him to sleep.
You're a doctor! You're supposed
to save lives! Not execute my dog!
I'm very sorry.
No! No! We're leaving!
Come, Dino!
- Juan, what's that you're building?
- For Dino. His hip hurts.
See, this will make him well.
You'll see.
- Hi, boys! All good?
- Hi.
- Boss good too? Little massage?
- Why not?
- Ow, ow! No massage.
- You not strong, boss!
- Hi, Aziz!
- Hi, Edith!
- Work going good?
- Just a little paperwork.
We get these new ones.
Good quality, good you ordered them.
- I take my clothes. Okay?
- Okay!
- Jörgen, must order ball bearings.
- Ah, okay.
- I use them now.
- They'll be here tomorrow.
Speaking of balls, Aziz,
I had fun with two chicks last night.
- Two chicks? What you mean?
- Big party!
You can handle two chicks?
No way. You got a thing like this.
Are you crazy?
Mine is like this.
- If yours like this, mine like this.
- Macho, macho!
Good!
- Jörgen, you have big or little one?
- A normal one.
- Large? Medium?
- More medium, maybe.
Size isn't important, it's how you use
it. There are different techniques.
- What techniques?
- There are books about it.
- Oils and spices and tantric sex.
- What trick sex?
No, tantric sex.
With... Pillows and candles and things.
You sit and look at each other and
fantasise about touching each other.
That's what's good about it,
according to the Chinese.
In your imagination,
your organ is... More sensitive.
- Juan, what is this trick sex?
- Tantric sex, it's like... Mental sex.
Metal sex? What that?
What is this?
- Boss... You have wife problems?
- No, why would I?
- You don't get home action.
- How many time?
It varies; I don't really know.
Maybe... Two, three times a month.
- Two time a month? Oh, big problem!
- Is it?
- Juan, what you say? Two time month.
- Problems.
Big problem. He don't work good.
No, no, no. He don't work good.
Jörgen, you my friend.
You listen, I help you.
This trick sex metal,
you need to throw it all away.
When we close here, you go home,
say, "Here I come!" and get hard.
Take her hand
and go right to bedroom.
Throw her on bed
and go in right away.
- Listen. Ask Juan.
- True, true.
Boss, I take Dino for a walk.
Dino, come now,
come now!
Jörgen, I must ask:
Your mama, how old is she?
- Mum? Why is that?
- She is very pretty. Nice lady.
- Aziz, she's my Mum!
- I'm just asking.
- That hardness thing... How hard?
- Women like a man is hard.
She say black, you say white.
She say yellow, you say blue.
See, you be in charge.
Do that, it will be good.
- Have you got any ideas for dinner?
- No, what do you think?
- You first.
- Hmm... Minute steak?
- No... No, I don't want that.
- No?
- Fish. I want fish sticks.
- Okay.
What? You want fish too?
But you just said you wanted meat.
- Yeah, but now we said fish.
- So you want fish now?
- Forget that. I mean, I want meat.
- Fine then, meat.
- Make up your mind!
- What's with you?
Have you decided on fish?
Well, forget it, I want meat.
- No! I want fish!
- I said meat.
Meat... I... Lotta!
- This is cool! Are you nervous?
- Why should I be? Maybe you are!
No, I think it's great!
Who are you going out with?
- I have many, can find many women.
- I don't doubt you. I'm just curious.
Don't need to be curious. Didn't you
say I should get woman? I did!
- Okay.
- Yeah, okay.
- Here you go.
- This very good, genuine fabric.
Try it on, let's see.
Check out, your dad
is model.
All the women come and say hi, hi,
your dad is a hot one.
This is very good.
- Amanda...
- What will you do with your hair?
- What do? Nothing to do.
- You sure? No gel or wax or anything?
I don't use those things,
just a little water here and here.
...like an old model, you know.
Women all like old models.
- Cool.
- Your dad, he know!
That was a friend.
Can we go home now?
- We need to go. Have fun tonight.
- Okay, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Amanda, okay.
Take care of baby, okay?
Amanda, who was it?
What is it?
- He might see!
- It doesn't matter anymore.
Honey... who was it?
- It was Ann from the adoption agency.
- What did she say?
She said... Something happened, so...
We're not getting our baby.
What happened?
There must be something we can do.
I don't know.
- Hi.
- Hi. Do you have Arrack?
Arrack. You don't understand?
Beer. Give me beer, please.
- Hi.
- Here you are.
- Thanks. Here.
- Can I buy you a drink?
- No. I'm waiting for my husband.
Oh, you have husband.
Okay. Good, good.
Good. Okay. Bye.
Tell your husband hi from me.
- Hello. May I sit here?
- Okay, sure.
- So then he says, "Hey, sweet thing. "
- No way!
- Let's have a toast instead.
- Cheers.
That hit the spot. So...
- Do you want to dance?
- No thanks.
- Maybe later?
- No, we don't like to dance.
There's that song.
We have to dance.
So, you do want to dance, good.
I come soon.
- This is a best seller, a classic.
- What does it sound like?
- How far does the sound carry?
- Maybe... 50-60 metres.
- In a tailwind?
- Um... I don't know...
- What about this one?
- These are typical on Chinese bikes.
- I can't hear it.
- Jörgen, you do what I say with wife?
Aziz, I'm with a customer.
You want buy bell? Buy this.
- It's very good!
- Thanks.
- Aziz!
- Wait, wait, I help.
- Good dog.
- Head goes in here? Oh, I see, good.
Then this goes under here
and through here.
- That's it, good.
- Ah, this good job!
- Let's see if it works.
- He can walk now.
Dino! Dino, time for a walk!
Come, Dino!
Oh, oh! Good! He walk by himself!
Very good!
- Good! Good job!
- Dino, good boy.
Juan, I must ask.
- Can you find for me a woman?
- A woman? For you?
- I thought you are the maestro?
- Yes, but I thought you had extra?
- A new flavour? What kind of women?
- Just one. One is enough.
- But what should she be like?
- Nice and pretty. Look good.
- Pretty, nice?
- And look good.
I have one. You two will be perfect!
- She is good?
- Great. I guarantee it.
Here's what we do: I cook, you come
to me, and hermano, we party!
Party, party!
That sound good.
- I'm really sorry about this.
- I don't understand...
We've received photos of him,
we've sent him presents.
I know. Sometimes complications arise
and lead to these situations.
- But I... Can't we do something?
- Not in this case, I'm afraid.
But of course we'll apply
for another child.
- How long will that take?
- As I said on the phone...
- It can take six months to a year.
- But we've waited so long!
We've been evaluated and approved,
we've taken courses...
- Then you can wait six months more.
- We need our baby now!
I'm sorry.
This is hard to digest.
There is one option, if you'd consider
a child from another country.
From China, for example. The
waiting times are much shorter there.
You mean...
we'd have a Chinese baby?
That's up to the two of you.
This Chinese baby...
It'll look very...
...Chinese?
- Yes, of course.
Amanda, what do you say?
I want to have a baby with you.
I don't care what it looks like.
Okay... Okay...
Should we... Go for it?
Yes.
Okay. We'll take it. I mean,
that's good. We'll do that.
Okay. Then I need you
to fill in these papers first.
- Hi Juan!
- Hi Aziz!
- Are you good? Pal!
- Welcome.
- Look at you, nice!
- This very good quality!
- Genuine fabric.
- Macho, macho!
- Wow, look at all this! Nice!
- All the best for Aziz. Come and see.
Look. The best gourmet food.
Cojones.
What that, cojones?
- Sheep testicles.
- Testicle?
Sheep testicle?
You serve women sheep testicle?
This is an aphrodisiac.
You eat this and your blood boil,
and I swear you get noche loca.
- You think they eat sheep testicle?
- Women go wild, I promise!
I think they get scared
if you say sheep testicle.
- What do we say then?
- What can we say? It sheep testicle.
What can I say?
- Hello ladies!
- Hi!
- Adelante pasar!
- Juan! Chico!
- Hi, I'm Aziz.
- Hi. Deborah.
- Flowers for you.
- Oh, thank you!
- They smell so good!
- Nice flowers, smell good.
I hope you're hungry, ladies,
because I have such damn good food.
Yes!
- Are you good?
- Yes, fantastic!
Look at the weather,
the sun shining!
I love the sun
and heat!
I love heat too.
You love heat, too?
Yes, you get so warm and
soft in your muscles.
You know, I do yoga. I've done it
since I was a little girl in Nairobi.
At an ashram.
And heat is very important...
...that it goes into your muscles
and affects your breathing.
So you breathe deeply,
from your stomach...
...and blow out
through your mouth.
And in...
That's good.
Here we are! Juan Special.
It smells good!
- So, what is it?
- It's... Lamb.
Lamb... It looks like eggs.
It smells like eggs.
Eggs... Yes, it's lamb eggs.
Lamb eggs?
- Lambs don't lay eggs...
- In my country they do. All the time.
- I believe you. Anyway, I'm hungry!
- Me too. Thanks!
This is yours, Aziz,
and here's mine, the biggest one.
- It's good.
- Very good.
It's very good, Juan.
This reminds me
of when I was in Dar-es-Salaam...
We were walking along the main
road, and the sun was shining.
...and the wind blew through my hair.
...and I stood in the shade of
an oleander tree and breathed in...
- Aziz, come and dance with us!
- I be there soon.
- Aziz, come on!
- I don't feel like dancing.
- Juan, come and dance!
- I'm coming, chicas!
- Aziz? You don't like the women?
- No, they very good.
Very kind. But I don't have
strength to dance with them.
OK. Fine.
- But thank you, very kind to me.
- You don't have to say that.
Dino? What's wrong, boy?
- What he has?
- Dino...
Does it hurt again?
- He aches all the time.
- Does it hurt, Dino?
- He sick, he hurt.
Listen to me. You need find
a woman for Dino.
You know, he must have children.
You can have many Dino.
My father, he die. Then I come,
then come my child...
...then my grandchild.
That is life.
S'okay, s'okay. Not to cry.
- It's so cute!
- Look at the little tail!
Honey... Do you think Dad
is going to realise...
...why it doesn't look like us?
- No, absolutely not.
- You don't think so?
- Do you look Chinese?
No, but you can look a little oriental
in certain lighting.
No, really, I mean, parents and
children don't always look alike.
Some genes can skip a generation.
I've read that.
They can be recessive and suddenly pop
up, like that albino kid in Africa.
We could say
it came out wrong.
- "It came out wrong"?
- It must happen sometimes...
Like it didn't get enough oxygen
and doesn't look right.
The only thing coming out wrong
right now is you.
This is nice. Maybe a little frilly.
What do you say?
Absolutely! Very nice.
What is it?
Honestly... I'm not sure if I can tell
Dad about adopting a baby.
- Are you serious?
- I know I should, it's just...
- Then do it.
- He'll think I'm useless!
He'll stand there with his family tree
and his puppy dog eyes...
For god's sake! "Dad this
and Dad that"... what about us?
You and I are starting a family.
You're going to be a dad.
I think it's there.
I'm so nervous!
Look, Juan, look!
See the beautiful dogs!
Hi, dogs! Hi, dogs!
Look, Juan, there! There!
It's same dog as Dino!
- Oh, it's the same kind!
- Dino, he be happy! Very happy!
- Hi. Juan Rosen.
- Roland.
- Hi. Aziz.
- Nice animals.
- Nice girls too!
- Thanks. I'm proud of my kennel.
You want to meet the pro?
He's in the car.
- Dino.
- Take look.
- What's that thing he's wearing?
- That?
That's special equipment
that enhances mating efficiency.
- The ad didn't say that. He's sick.
- What sick? He very strong!
Juan, help me.
- See? Very strong.
- But the wheels?
The wheels? Is nothing.
He like to play he like a car.
- Like that.
- I'm sorry.
Look here, what big testicle.
You can feel.
- He make babies first try. Feel!
- No. I'm sorry.
Don't say sorry me.
Say sorry your wife. You have wife?
- Dino, he want wife too.
- Not here.
- Just a quick one?
- I'm sorry.
You not nice. You bad.
There are others.
Good luck.
Don't say goodbye. Come.
- We're almost there!
- Is that the shop?
- That's it! Ow! Ow!
- You! Come here!
- You sold my bike?
- No.
- Tell me! How much he charge?
- Three hundred! He sold it to me!
I've never seen him before.
You must talk to my boss.
- I'm Jörgen, what's the prob?
- What kind of thief are you?
- Take it easy!
- Shut up! Sit down, damn it!
I'm sure this is a misunderstanding.
If the bike is broken, let's talk.
So, it IS you sell my bike!
- How much they charge?
- 300!
- Did you sell him a bike?
- Never!
I don't understand...
There's no need
to resort to violence.
- There's no need for violence!
- Come on, fight me!
- Juan!
- I watch the shop!
Come on! Damn thieves!
Cheap bastard!
Stop, stop, I kill you!
- Wait, wait, what you do?
- He thief!
Who thief?
He no thief, he my boss!
- He your boss?
- What you do?
- I dare you to do that again.
- Okay.
- One more time...
- Fine.
- Shit!
- What "shit"?
What, you play Kung Fu?
Think I be afraid?
Yes, I do!
Damn you! You want bike now?
You want bike? Get out!
- Shit! Fuck you!
- You fuck you!
- Fuck you! Next time I see you!
Jörgen? Are you okay?
I thought I was going to die.
You just did that, and he...
- Weren't you scared?
- Aziz never scared, Aziz strong!
- Yeah, but...
- Notjust body, must be strong here.
Can you teach me?
Teach me to be strong in the head?
I can teach you. You be so strong,
your wife say you the best husband.
- Wow, really? That's great!
- Of course. You my best friend.
- I just need help with one thing.
- Sure, what?
- I want date with your mother.
- You have to drag her into this?
- I don't think she's your type.
- She my type, yes.
- No, no.
- Yes.
You help me, I help you.
I will make you strong man.
- Like Mike Tyson, you know.
- That's really strong. Okay...
- What are we doing, Aziz?
- Open door, jump right out.
- Out of the car?
- Yeah.
- But... isn't that dangerous?
- No danger, I do many times.
- Justjump out?
- Yeah.
- Can't you slow down a little?
- You want be strong, must do this.
- I don't like this...
- I help you. Bye bye!
Now I make you man! Big man!
STOP!
Good job, good job!
Look. Must look right in her eyes.
100%, just in her eyes. Okay? Go.
- Hi. Is dinner ready?
- No.
- Let me know if I can help.
- I say do not say help!
Watch me. - I will be in living room.
You tell me when dinner is ready!
Hey. I... I'll be...
Ow.
That one is wicked.
- Will it scare people?
- Well, it looks angry.
- Maybe I should have words under it.
- Plain text or a banner?
You can damn well go to h...
Go for it!
- What's wrong with you?
- What the hell is that all about?
What the hell are you doing?
Stop that and go make the salad!
Tomatas!
Lettuce!
There you go.
Here, macho salad.
Check this out.
Death. Death.
- You're sick. You can eat alone!
- Lotta!
Lotta, come on!
I was just trying to... Lotta!
- Hello, boys!
- Hi, Mum!
- Hi, Edith, are you good?
- Of course! The sun is shining!
You know why the sun shine?
It come from your face! It's true!
- Need any help, Mum?
- No. Are the receipts ready?
They're on the desk.
- Jörgen, do it now.
- I've been thinking...
I don't think it's such a good idea.
I mean, you know...
Then I thought, she has a friend,
Louise. Very nice.
- Maybe you could date her instead?
- Jörgen, I don't want date Lewis.
I want date your mother.
You promised.
I helped you be man.
We must help each other.
I don't know if you...
Okay, I'll do it.
Come.
Come, come. Yalla yalla.
Hi, Mum. Um... isn't it lunchtime?
Already? I just got here.
- Yeah, but... I feel like a kebab.
- Just let me finish this.
- Wait, I have to man the register.
- Jörgen, I can go with your mother.
Buy kebab. I also like kebab.
Very good.
- Great.
- Okay?
- Good idea?
- Good.
- Then you two go.
- Okay!
Kebab ready! Abo El-Pip
make best kebab in all Sweden.
Very good. Smell.
- Actually, I have no sense of smell.
- Why not?
When I was little I fell and
a tiny bone here cut off a nerve.
- It's no big deal.
- When someone fart you can't smell!
You have very pretty face
when you smile.
- Go ahead, eat.
- Thank you.
- Good?
- Good!
- You know I cook too.
- What do you cook?
- I make warak arish, you know that?
- No.
Grapes leaves, we make with rice
and meat and wrap in leaves.
- That sounds good.
- Very good. I can make for you.
- Yes, I'd like that.
- Okay.
- Do you also cook?
- I'm a great cook. I make Italian.
You are so pretty when you laugh.
Your eyes, nose do like this. Pretty!
- Nah, I'm so old.
- Who tell you old? Maybe blind man?
- You very pretty. Really!
- You're kind of cute too.
- Is good.
- Very good.
Too slow!
- You're cheating. You psyched me.
- You can't accept that I'm better.
- Hi, Baba!
- Hi, Sami! Are you good?
Where is Amanda?
I want tell you, very good day today.
She's in the kitchen, cooking.
Let me get yourjacket.
- She'll be right here.
- Tell her come too.
- Have a seat, I'll be right back.
- Okay, I'll wait.
- You'd better put on the belly.
- Aren't we going to tell him?
- Not now, he seems so happy.
- We can't keep pretending!
I promise, it's the last time.
Please, please, please.
So, Baba, what's your news?
Amanda is just changing clothes.
Then I can wait.
There is no hurry. Wait, wait.
- You're so secretive!
- I am happy. Wait a little.
Hi! Thanks for waiting,
I just had to change.
Don't work too much, you must rest.
Now I want tell you:
I have found a woman.
Notjust found,
I am going to marry her too.
What? You're getting married?
That's great, but... who is she?
Her name is Edith. She is very pretty.
And happy, she laugh all the time.
- How long have you been seeing her?
- Many times.
- That's fantastic! Congratulations!
- Thank you.
- Sami! You are not congratulating.
- Sorry, I'm just surprised! Congrats!
Thank you! Thanks!
- When can we meet her?
- Soon, I cook and you meet her.
I can't believe
you haven't said anything before!
No! Not be four - Be five!
You forget baby come soon.
Oh, that's right...
Sami, you must help me,
I need buy new suit.
- With a nice tie.
- We'll take care of it, Baba.
- Sami, check out Dad in this suit.
- Nice, Dad!
- Look good?
- Great!
- Like Charles Bronson.
- Mafioso!
- How about a little moustache trim?
- No thank you.
- Man without moustache, no good.
- You could trim the edges a bit.
Never! You must moustache too.
What you say?
- Moustache good for men?
- Yes, men should have moustaches.
Women like moustache on men.
Thank you.
Hello?
- What are you doing?
- Moving in with Jenny.
- Why?
- I can't take this anymore.
Neither can I. This isn't easy
for me either, you know.
- What?
- Being what you want me to be.
Tough and macho
and hollering all the time.
I've tried; itjust isn't me.
Having a moustache and wearing black
and barbecuing hotdogs...
What are you talking about?
Where did you get that idea?
I never said
I wanted you to be tough and macho.
- So what's the problem?
- I don't know; you're acting weird.
- So you don't want macho?
- I don't know why you thought that.
I'm sorry.
- It's my fault.
- You've been so bizarre.
I know. I was so worried
and got strange ideas.
- It really upset me.
- I know. I was a jerk.
- I'll be the wimp I really am.
- Why do you get such weird ideas?
- I thought you wanted a tough guy.
- I've missed you.
Really? I've missed you too.
And I got a tattoo for no reason.
- You're kidding. That was real?
- Yeah.
- Wanna see?
- Holy crap...
Okay, go ahead!
Go on!
Dino, up and at 'em!
Pretty girl! Look! She like you!
Pretty girl, smells good!
Go on, smell her! Dino!
Dino... Dino, boy...
- Excuse me, that's my dog!
- It ran away.
- I caught it for you.
- Oh, thanks!
Bad girl! Why do you always run away?
Come on now!
- Hello?
- Hi, Edith, it's Aziz!
- How are you?
- Hi, Aziz! Fine, I'm out shopping.
Very good. I must tell you:
Tonight I make warak arish.
- You know, I told you about it?
- Yes, I remember.
My son and his wife are coming
for a little party. You can come too.
I don't have any plans. I'd love to
come, if I wouldn't be a burden.
- No, I be happy if you come.
- Then I'll be there.
- Should I bring something?
- No, everything taken care of!
- Just you come.
- I'll be there!
- See you!
- Bye!
- There. Are you ready?
- Yeah.
What is it?
I apologise for being so...
weird and difficult and cowardly.
There is nothing I want more
than for us to have this baby.
I'm going to talk to Dad tonight.
So, tonight I meet
my stepmother.
I can't believe he's getting married!
- Put on some of this.
- Stop that. Cut it out!
- You'll ruin it.
- You have to look good for her!
- You look great!
- So do you!
Come and help me.
She will be here soon.
- Can you whip that?
- It smells so good, what is it?
- Warak arish, good stuff.
- Is it done now?
- We take this.
- I'll put a little of this on it.
- Is anything missing?
- It's great, relax Dad.
- I think we need more bread.
- Good idea.
I'm coming, I'm coming!
- She here.
Hi, Edith! Welcome!
Come in, come in.
- You look great!
- You look great, too. Good colour.
Come in.
- Hi!
- This is my son and Amanda.
- I'm Sami. Nice to meet you.
- Edith.
I'm Amanda.
It's so good to finally meet you!
- Have a seat. This is your place.
- Oh my goodness!
- It all looks so fabulous!
- It does, doesn't it?
This is a meal you won't soon forget!
- Is this what you were talking about?
- Yes, warak arish, very good.
- It looks so good!
- Very good. Help yourselves.
- I can help you.
- Do you drink white wine?
Thanks.
- You know what, you're so beautiful!
- Thanks.
- Aziz?
- Just a half glass, please. Thanks.
Please.
- You two look so much alike!
- You think so?
- A son should look alike.
- You've the same eyebrows and nose.
- But I only got the good looks.
- He say he more handsome?
- I show you.
- No, Baba!
- Look, Edith, tell who most handsome?
- Oh, no contest!
- What a hunk!
- Show Amanda.
I have to say that your dad wins.
I'm sorry!
Your dad is more handsome. But you're
not ugly. You do have similar noses.
- The noses and the eyebrows.
- They are similar.
But in looks only, not as individuals.
Sami tends to take his time.
His dad is faster. Like tonight.
How long did it take you to propose?
- 2½ years.
- Three years!
How long did it take you two?
- What do you mean?
- It's great how fast it went.
I think the two of you
make a great couple.
And I'm so happy to meet you.
Oh, I forgot something. Wait.
Edith, you will marry me?
I got rings and everything.
You will marry me?
What?
- I don't know what to say.
- Say yes.
I will be your husband,
you will be my wife.
- You laugh, I laugh. We good match.
- Oh, Aziz...
Soon come grandchild.
Ask Sami, ask Amanda.
I will be granddad. You be grandma.
We be big family.
I think I have to leave now.
But it was nice meeting you.
Edith...
Edith!
I will be back.
Edith. Edith!
Why you won't marry me?
- We barely know each other.
- I am good man!
Are you good woman, too?
Together we be very good!
It doesn't work that way for me.
I'm sorry if I've hurt you.
Aziz...
- Did you talk to her? Is it okay?
- No, is not okay.
She seems to really like you;
I think she was just caught off guard.
No, I don't want any more.
Baba...
Be honest, how long
have you known her?
Can you tell me anything about her
personality? What makes her happy?
- What her interests are?
- She very kind. Very good.
I don't know why she say no.
- It doesn't work that way.
- What you mean?
Baba...
There's something...
I have to tell you.
What you tell?
I... I can't have children of my own.
Amanda?
Aziz... we...
Oh hell...
I'm sorry.
This is your grandchild.
We're going to adopt.
I'm sorry, Baba.
- Boss, I'm going to buy me a parrot.
- Are you?
One that roams around free,
that I can talk with.
- What will you say to it?
- Venting things. Emotions. Sorrows.
- Hi, guys. All good?
- Very good.
- Hi, Edith!
- Hi.
Edith, have you thought
if you will marry me?
Aziz, we talked about this.
- It won't work.
- Why it won't work?
I joke with you, only joke.
We are just friends.
Friends don't marry each other,
only joke.
- I want say I'm sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
- Not sad?
- No!
- You want marry me later, you call.
- I'll do that!
Now I go visit my grandchild.
You know, I have little baby.
- Oh, give them hugs from me!
- I will. Goodbye.
Bye bye!
- Hi.
- Hi, Amanda. You good?
Fine.
- Won't you come in?
- Thank you.
- Hi, Sami.
- Hi, Baba.
- I got a bike for baby.
- Thanks. It's beautiful.
Thanks.
- Do you want to hold him?
- Yes, please.
Oh, he's handsome.
Such a handsome boy.
You know who I am?
Aziz, your granddad.
Sami, good job.
- What he name?
- We haven't decided yet.
Look at face. He look like Bruce Lee.
How about Bruce Lee?
You know Bruce Lee? He strong,
play Kung Fu. He be strong too.
- But I don't want to call him that.
- Amanda, what you think, Bruce Lee?
- Bruce Lee? Wicked, let's do it!
- See, Amanda want too.
- We'll think about it.
- Maybe Charles Bronson better?
Bruce Lee or Charles Bronson.
One of the two. We'll see.
- Come here. - Can I carry?
- Of course.
Come, come, we go.
Come, I show you.
Come and see. Granddad will show you.
Look at trees. See trees?
See birds? Pretty birds!
See, other birds fly there.
Look, there a car.
Want to dance?
Up little one. Up little one.
Very good. You want more?
Okay, more.
Lot of fun!