- Are you ready, Virge?
- Anytime.
Turn him out!
- Ya-hoo!
- Go get him, Bo!
Make time, Bo!
Get on him, Bo!
Turn him over, Bo!
Get him over! Get him over!
Good time! Good!
What was my time?
- Five-eight.
- Five-
That's good enough to win just about
every prize they got at that rodeo!
♪ I'll give to you a paper of pins ♪
♪ And that's the way our love begins ♪
♪ If you will marry me, me, me ♪
♪ If you will marry me ♪
♪ I'll give to you a feathery bed ♪
♪ With downy pillows for your head ♪
♪ If you will marry me, me, me ♪
♪ If you will marry me ♪
♪ But you don't want my paper or pins ♪
♪ And you don't want my feathery bed ♪
♪ You want my house and money instead ♪
♪ That is plain to see ♪
♪ Well, here they are
Take everything ♪
♪ My house, my money
My wedding ring ♪
♪ And in the bargain I'll throw in me ♪
♪ If you will marry me ♪♪
Bo, when you was five,
I just throwed you on a horse- smack-
and there you was ridin'.
- Remember?
- Yup.
When you was eight,
I throwed you in the creek- splash-
and there you was swimmin'.
- Ain't that right?
- Sure, Virge.
Splash!
Bo, you're 21 years old...
and we're on our way to
a big city- Phoenix, Arizona.
It's time you met up with a gal.
A gal?
Oh, it ain't nothin' to be scared of.
In a way, women and swimmin'
is pretty much the same.
You got good reflexes, boy.
You'll make out just fine.
So long, Bo.
Bring back some prize money.
Take it easy, Orville!
Two for Phoenix, Arizona.
We goin' down for the rodeo.
I figure I'm gonna win me just about
every prize they got down there.
Well, that's nice.
Now sit down someplace.
You got a long ride ahead of you.
- Bo, the lady's hat!
- Hmm?
- Oh, sorry, ma'am.
- Why don't you look where you're goin'?
It was an accident, sir.
He ain't used to travelin'.
- This is his first time off the ranch.
- Virge, that's a lie!
That's a lie and you know it!
I been all the way to Helena.
That was when he was 12 years old-
to have his tonsils out.
Well, that still counts!
Here, give me that.
♪ If you will marry me, me, me ♪
♪ If you will marry me ♪
♪ I'll give to you a petticoat red ♪
♪ All stitched around
with golden thread ♪
- Virge?
- ♪ If- ♪
I've been thinkin'.
You know, about what you said.
What was that?
You know. About me findin' a gal.
Oh, what- What about it, Bo?
I don't know anything about gals, Virge.
Nothin' at all.
Well, that's what I mean.
It's about time you learned.
It ain't nothin' to be scared of, Bo.
You know how much you like swimmin'
when you got used to it.
Besides, I know the idea
crossed your mind once or twice.
I seen you lookin' at them
pictures in Orville's magazines.
♪ I'll give to you a feathery bed ♪
♪ With downy pillows for your head ♪
Maybe I glanced at them pictures
a couple of times.
But if I do find me a gal,
it ain't gonna be one of them gals
from all those magazines.
I already decided.
I'm gonna get me a...
angel.
- An angel?
- That's right.
I wouldn't set my sights
too high if I were you, Bo.
You just figure on pickin' out
some plain-lookin' little ol' gal,
with a cooperatin'nature
and a good personality.
I mean, we gotta be realistic.
What's some angel gonna want
with a cowhand like you?
What's that got to do with it?
That steer this mornin',
he didn't wanna get throwed, did he?
Well, I throwed him.
Some wild horse you're breakin',
he don't wanna get broke, do he?
But you don't let
what he wants stop you.
What makes you think
a girl's any different?
This trip is gonna be
mighty educational.
♪ Kiss me quick and go my honey ♪
- ♪ Kiss me quick and go to cheat sur- ♪
- Listen, Virge.
I'm gonna find me an angel.
I'm gonna find me a real
hootenanny of an angel!
She gives me any trouble,
she's gonna find herself...
with them little old wings
just pinned right to the ground!
Oh!
- Mornin', ma'am!
- What are you doing?
Push-ups, ma'am.
Gotta get the kinks outta my bones.
Hey, cowboy,
get up off that floor!
Thirty! Whew!
I can do 30 set-ups, too.
Pipe down and stop botherin' folks.
You woke up everybody in the bus.
Well, it's mornin', ain't it?
It's time to get up.
That's the trouble with you city folk.
Lay around in bed all day long...
and you get soft.
Hey, when do we stop for breakfast?
Look! There's a place!
Hey, you passed it!
Look. This ain't no taxi.
It's a public vehicle.
Stops where it's scheduled to stop
and no place else.
And meanwhile what's
a passenger supposed to do?
Just starve to death?
Poor old lady back there, you can hear
her stomach rumblin' from here!
Bo! You're out in civilization!
Forgive him, ma'am.
He didn't hear a thing.
Our next official bus stop is Grace's
Diner, a couple of miles up the road.
That's where we stop-
Grace's.
Can we get some breakfast in here?
Hello, Grace.
Well, look what the cat dragged in.
- Hello, Elma. You the passenger?
- That's right.
- She's goin' for the symphony concert.
- And to see my sister.
How about a little service?
Sounds like your passengers are hungry.
Oh, I'll go ahead and wait on 'em.
Ah, some crazy cowboys.
That young one there,
he's a real troublemaker.
His friend ain't so bad.
He just sits in the back of the bus
playin' his guitar.
A little music's real nice
when you're drivin' along.
I'm very fond of music myself.
Are you, Grace?
I didn't know that.
Yeah. I'm a very musical person.
Well, come on in.
I'll fix you somethin' to eat.
Ahh.
Ma'am, uh-
Ma'am, I-
Give me about three hamburgers.
- Three? How do you want 'em?
- Raw.
- Honest?
- Well, sure.
That's the only way to eat 'em, with
a big hunk of onion and some piccalilli.
And a piece of pie.
And you'd better set a quart of milk
beside him. He's still a growin' boy.
- Well, all right.
- Pie and coffee for me.
I'm still growin' too,
but in a different way.
Gotta watch my figure.
Real nice place you got here.
As much as I've seen of it, anyway.
What's that supposed to mean?
I was just thinkin'.
I'll bet that apartment you
got upstairs is real nice too.
Love to see it sometime,
how you got it fixed up and all.
Hmm, don't pour it!
Ahh.
Okay, mister, let's get goin'.
We're never gonna make Phoenix...
sittin' around this broken-down,
miserable restaurant.
Hey! You!
All aboard, folks.
Now wait a minute!
I happen to be the owner of this here
broken-down, miserable restaurant.
Don't pay him no mind. You're only the
twelfth human bein' he's seen this year.
- Just his way of talkin'.
- Well, it ain't a way I care a lot for.
- I don't blame you a bit.
- Virge!
Bo, you're plumb wrong
about this place.
It's nice and clean and well-run!
And you certainly couldn't ask
for a prettier or a more charmin' owner.
- Wait a minute, cowboy.
- I mean it, ma'am.
And I wanna apologize for
this young barbarian here.
- Hey, what ya doin'?
- It's just somethin' I seen in a movie.
- It don't offend you, I trust.
- Oh, of course not.
Only you just caught me
up short, that's all.
Hand kissin'?
That ain't my idea
on how to get a gal.
- We know that, Bo.
- Bye, Grace.
So long, honey.
- You the one that plays the guitar?
- That's right, ma'am.
I'm real fond of music myself.
All aboard.
Bus loadin' right away.
Good-bye, Grace.
See you in a couple of days.
- So long, Carl.
- Come on, cowboy.
- Good luck at the rodeo, cowboy.
- Thanks, ma'am.
Come back real soon, you hear?
- So long, Carl.
- So long, Grace.
Come back soon, hear?
Talk about angels. How about her?
Well,
she may be an angel, Virge,
but she ain't my angel.
How can you tell?
I'll know.
When I see my angel,
I'll know right off the bat.
Fasten your seat belts and take off your
coats. We're startin' to lose altitude.
Landin' in Phoenix
in about an hour.
Well, I'm sorry to leave you folks,
but this is where we get off.
"Welcome, cowboys.
The town is yours."
Yee-haw!
That's us, Virge! That's us!
So long, fellas.
Don't let him take any wooden nickels.
I'll be drivin' you back
tomorrow night.
That is, if you're still in one piece.
Don't you worry about us, mister.
We're gonna be all right.
You just drive your bus.
Come on, Virge, let's go register.
Is that our hotel?
Bo!
Bo, wait on the corner.
You gotta try to remember:
They go when it's green,
they stop when it's red.
Never seen so many gals.
Must be a hundred head of 'em.
Bo!
Wait till it turns green.
♪ Kiss me quick and go
my honey ♪
♪ Kiss me quick and go ♪
♪ To cheat surprise and prying eyes ♪
Bo, you're gonna wash yourself down
to a nub! What are you doin' anyway?
Ain't got nothin' like this at home.
Shower and bath at the same time!
Bo, you have a terrible habit
of overdoin' everything.
- Come on!
- Yee-haw!
Listen, Bo,
if you're gonna take all night,
I'm gonna step across the street.
That there Blue Dragon place
seems kind of interesting.
You go ahead, Virge. I'll be over there
in a couple of minutes.
Just wait outside.
- Why ain't you outside where you belong?
- Aah!
I've heard enough of you,
you ignorant hillbilly!
Now get out there
and get to work!
You'd better change into
your costume, honey. You're late.
And he called me an ignorant hillbilly.
How do you like that?
Well, ain't ya?
I don't mean ignorant.
I mean, but you do
come from the Ozarks.
I ain't sung hillbilly since I was-
Well, not since
I turned "chantooze."
I've been tryin' to be somebody.
Can you imagine if Hildegarde...
was jumpin' down between her numbers,
sittin' in some truck driver's lap?
I don't know why you just don't quit.
I can't.
Look.
I don't get paid till Wednesday.
I owe for my room and everything.
Besides that,
it took me too long to get this far.
What's that line for?
- That line?
- Uh-huh.
You might say that this line here...
is the history of my life up till now.
- See right there where it starts?
- Yeah.
That's River Gulch,
the little old town where I was born.
River Gulch.
I never even heard of it.
Well, it ain't there anymore anyway.
Floods come and washed us all away-
all except me and my baby sister, Nan.
- Oh.
- I just picked her up...
and took her along here, this line.
- Yeah?
- Till we got to Lubbock, Texas.
- You know what happened there?
- What?
Nan got this job as a waitress,
and I got to workin'
in Liggett's Drugstore.
- Yeah?
- And, uh, this amateur contest opened.
And, uh, Nan said to me,
"Honey, why don't you enter
yourself in that contest?
You've been watchin' people in movies."
Well, Nan and I used
to live in the movies.
"You've been watchin' people put over
their songs and gestures," you know.
And so, um, I did it, and I won it.
- First prize?
- No. Second prize.
A couple of boys jugglin' milk bottles,
they won first prize.
Anyway, that's how I got
my direction and all.
Direction?
Oh, sure.
If you don't have a direction,
you just keep going around in circles.
And look. You can see by this
just how straight my direction is.
River Gulch-
that's where I started-
this is where I am now,
and look where I'm goin'.
- Where?
- Hollywood and Vine!
Look, straight as an arrow.
River Gulch- whew-
Hollywood and Vine!
What happens when you get there?
What happens?
Honey, you get discovered.
You get tested,
with options and everything!
And you get treated
with a little respect, too.
What's goin' on in here?
She's changing into her costume.
You want her to go out there naked?
Get out there and
take care of them tables.
Come on, Dinah Shore.
Them cowboys is gettin' real lonesome.
Zip her up.
Go zip yourself up!
He looks like the safest.
- Oh, I never know what to say to 'em.
- It's easy.
Just say some cute
little joke, like, um,
"Hello, mister. Buy me a drink.
I'm so dry, I'm spittin' cotton."
That's a real cute one. Go on.
Hello, mister.
- Howdy.
- I wonder if you'd buy me a drink.
I'm so dry, I'm spittin' cotton.
That's a good one.
It sure is.
Whiskey for the lady.
Beer for me.
♪ I'll give to you a paper of pins ♪
♪ And that's the way our love begins ♪
♪ If you will marry me, me, me ♪
♪ If you will marry me ♪♪
You sure have a good head
for whiskey, ma'am.
I don't wanna sound like I'm
keepin' track, but that's four in a row.
Oh, that's the way I am.
Sometimes I can just drink
all night long. Happy days.
Hey, what ya doin'?
Let go of me.
- That ain't whiskey!
- Let go of my arm!
- That's tea!
- I can't help it.
That's all they let us drink here.
Last night I had to drink
15 tea and sodas.
You've been hustlin' me for drinks,
60 cents a shot!
One thing I can't stand is a woman tries
to make a sucker outta me!
- Come sing a song.
- I'm sorry!
Ladies and gentlemen!
I know you ain't payin' no attention.
You're all too busy havin' fun
and enjoyin' yourselves.
But we got this little floor show,
and we have to do it.
Hope it don't disturb you none.
Okay, baby. Take it away.
♪ That old black magic ♪
♪ Has me in its spell ♪
♪ That you weave so well ♪
♪ Those icy fingers ♪
♪ Up and down my spine ♪
♪ The same old witchcraft ♪
♪ When your eyes ♪
♪ Meet mine ♪
♪ The same old tingle ♪
Bo.
- That's her, Virge.
- ♪ That I feel inside ♪
- That's my angel.
- Angel?
She's just a gal works in a saloon.
Look at her gleamin' there,
so pale and white.
♪ And down and down I go ♪
Shh! Quiet!
- ♪ And round I go ♪
- Quiet! Shh!
Keep quiet over there!
♪ Like a leaf
that's caught in the tide ♪
Shh! Shh!
♪ I should stay away ♪
♪ But what can I do ♪
Bo, Bo!
That's better!
Now let's keep it this way!
Can't you see the little lady's
tryin' to sing?
- Aw, sit down, cowboy.
- That goes for you too, mister!
Quiet!
Okay, miss, I reckon you can
go on with your song now.
- Whereabouts were we, Henry?
- "I should stay away."
♪ I should stay away ♪
♪ But what can I do ♪
♪ I hear your name ♪
♪ And I'm ♪
♪ Aflame ♪
Yee-haw!
♪ Aflame with such ♪
♪ A burning desire ♪
♪ That only your kiss, kiss ♪
♪ Kiss ♪
♪ Can put out the fire ♪
♪ For you're the lover ♪
♪ I have waited for ♪
♪ The mate that fate
had me created for ♪
♪ And every time ♪
♪ Your lips meet mine ♪
♪ Darlin', down ♪
♪ And down I go ♪
♪ Round and round I go ♪
♪ In a spin ♪
♪ Lovin' the spin I'm in ♪
♪ Under that old black magic ♪
♪ Called love ♪
♪ Love, love ♪
♪ Love, love ♪♪
What you all starin' at?
The lady's finished.
You can start your yammerin' again.
Well, go ahead!
Start yammerin'!
My name is Beauregard Decker, ma'am.
I'm 21 years old and I own my own ranch
up in Timber Hill, Montana,
where I got a fine herd
of Hereford cattle, a dozen horses,
and the finest sheep and hogs
and chickens in the country.
Now, I come down for the rodeo tomorrow
with the idea in mind...
of findin' me an angel,
and you're it.
Now, I don't have a whole lot of time
for sweet talkin' around the bush,
so I'd be much obliged to you
if you'd just step outside with me...
into the fresh air.
W- What'd you say?
My name is Beauregard Decker, ma'am.
I'm 21 years old and I own my own ranch
up in Timber Hill, Montana, where I-
Yes, I- I know.
I heard all that part.
- Okay, let's get outta here.
- No, uh-
I'm mighty grateful to you
for what you did,
but, uh, we're-we're not allowed
to go out with the customers.
But you could buy me a drink
if you wanted.
I'm so dry, I'm spittin' cotton.
Don't ever use the stuff.
Besides, I ain't got time for a drink.
- I wanna be in bed by 10:00.
- Huh?
I'm ridin' in the rodeo tomorrow,
so I need my sleep.
- Oh.
- So will you come on?
Well, we're not supposed to-
- Bo.
- Hold my hat, will you, Virge?
- Where you goin'?
- Splash!
You're sure a good singer.
I'm a "chantooze."
Oh.
That's why I call myself Cherie.
That's my name: Cherie.
That's all the name you got?
That's all you need.
Like Hildegarde,
she's a "chantooze" too.
Cherry.
Cherie! It's French.
It means "dear one."
Well, my name's kinda French:
Beauregard. It means somethin' too.
What's it mean?
I ain't gonna tell you.
You'll laugh at me.
- No, I wouldn't.
- Yes, you would.
Honest, I wouldn't.
Well,
it means "good lookin'."
I never told that to a single person
in my whole life.
My ma was French.
She gave it to me.
That's a real pretty name.
Beauregard.
You are, too. Real beauregard.
Everybody just calls me "Bo."
- Cherry.
- Cherie.
It was real nice the way
you made everybody shut up in there,
like you had respect for me.
You made them have respect too.
- I liked that.
- You did?
- Yes.
- How about me? Did you like me too?
Well, when I first saw you,
I thought you was
some kind of a hooligan,
yellin' and stompin' like that.
But when I realized
you was doin' it for me,
I was attracted to you.
Attracted?
You was?
- I still am.
- You still are?
Really attracted?
Uh-huh.
'Course, it's only what you might call
a physical attraction.
Physical?
I mean, you're so
big and strong and-
well, so darn healthy-lookin'.
Guess I am in pretty
good shape for the rodeo.
'Course, you gotta be when you're
competin' in all five class-A events.
Cherry.
Beauregard.
Pardon me, sir.
Have you seen Cherie?
That little gal you was settin' with?
No. She went off with another customer.
I was worried.
It's about time for the second show.
Virge, I want you
to be the first to know.
After all, it was really your idea.
What was?
I found me that gal,
just like you said.
Cherry and me- we're engaged.
- We're what?
- Engaged.
Virge, I want you to meet Cherry.
Cherry, this here's old Virge.
- He'll be livin' with us, of course.
- We already met.
Now wait a minute. Somebody's got
the wrong idea around here.
What do you mean, Cherry?
My name ain't Cherry.
I told you, it's Cherie.
I can't say it fancy like that.
Anyway, what's the matter with Cherry?
Well, it ain't dignified.
- Bo-
- Now, tomorrow afternoon...
is the preliminaries for the rodeo.
We'll get married out there!
Married? Out where?
At the rodeo.
Tomorrow night, after the finals, we'll
all three of us catch the bus back.
Bo, you don't know nothin'
about this gal!
I know she's my angel.
That's good enough for me.
Well, your angel
was hustlin' me for drinks!
Sixty cents a shot!
And come to find out, it weren't
whiskey she was drinkin'. It was tea!
Of course it was, Virge!
Angels don't touch no liquor!
Cherry, I just gotta kiss you again!
I can't help myself!
Stop! Cut it out!
- Everybody's looking.
- Let 'em look!
Ain't no crime for two people
to show a little affection,
especially when
they're gettin' married tomorrow!
Cherry, I just know
we're gonna be very happy together...
till death do us part!
Hey, I better get goin'.
I gotta get into bed.
Virge, come on. Let's get goin'.
Cherry, we're gonna make all the rest
of the plans in the mornin'.
But meanwhile,
for a weddin' present...
I'm gonna get you a deep freeze,
or an electric washer,
or any other major appliance you want.
Good night, darlin'.
Come on, honey. You're on again.
What's the matter? What happened?
You know somethin'?
I'm not quite sure.
This whole thing is probably my fault.
I told you it was about time you started
learnin' somethin' about women.
Now, I ain't sayin'
this particular gal you picked out...
ain't a good one to practice on.
But a fella can't go around marryin'
the first gal he meets.
Why not?
You better get your mind
on that rodeo.
Fellas back at the ranch
bet their money on you.
Anyhow, she has no intention
of marryin' you.
Oh, yes, she has, Virge.
She's got a physical attraction to me.
- Oh.
- She said so herself.
Oh!
- Virge?
- Yeah, Bo?
What's the difference between a-
a physical attraction and, well,
just a regular attraction?
Well, a gal can be
attracted to a fella...
for lots of reasons.
His mind, for instance.
- His mind?
- Sure.
Like if he's smart or reads poetry...
or somethin'.
- No kiddin'?
- That's right.
- I can read and write.
- Mm-hmm.
I don't know no poetry.
But I can recite the Gettysburg Address.
Would that count?
It might, Bo.
I doubt it, but it might.
♪ Magic has me in its spell ♪
♪ That old bah-duh
duh-buh-duh-duh-duh-duh ♪
♪ I should stay away
but what can I do ♪
♪ I hear your name ♪
Cherry!
- ♪ And I'm aflame ♪
- Yes?
Good morning, ma'am!
♪ Aflame with such- ♪
Say, wait a minute!
Wait a minute!
I told you, we're gonna be married!
- I'm just wakin' her up for breakfast.
Cherry.
Cherry, wake up! It's me, Beauregard!
Good morning, Cherry!
She didn't say nothin' to me
about gettin' engaged.
- Why's it so dark in here? Let's get
a little air. - I don't allow callers-
Cherry, come on, get outta bed. We gotta
be in time for the parade at 10:30.
- Listen, young man!
- Ma'am, I don't want trouble from you.
How do I know
that you're engaged to her?
Cherry, wake up and tell her
you know me!
What?
Oh, it's you!
- You see? She knows me.
- For the love-
- I don't know what's goin' on in this-
- Cherry?
Come on, come on. Get outta bed.
We gotta get goin' because
we're gonna be married today,
and we got a lot of things to do.
What's the idea
of bustin' in here like that?
What time is it, anyway?
Well, it's after 9:00.
I've been up for hours.
9:00? I didn't even
get to bed till 5:00!
5:00?
Well, no wonder
you're so pale and white.
Cherry, know what that is out there?
That's the sun.
Will you get outta here
'fore I call the police?
You shouldn't stay up
so late like that.
When we get up
to the Suzie Q Ranch,
we're gonna be in the old sack
every night at 7:30.
Listen, Bo. I think we oughta
get somethin' straight.
I have no intention in
the world of marryin' you,
so you might as well
get it out of your head.
We're gonna talk all that over
on the way to the parade.
You see, Cherry,
the whole problem is that...
you just haven't had time yet
to get attracted to my mind.
Your mind? I know all about your mind
I ever wanna know.
And do you know I can say
the Gettysburg Address?
Come bustin' in here
like a wild Indian.
Sometime-
Cherry?
Well, what?
"Four score and seven years ago,
"our fathers brought forth
on this continent a new nation,
"conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition...
- Bo?
"that all men are created equal.
"Now we're engaged in a great civil war,
"to determine whether that nation or any nation...
- Bo, listen.
"so conceived and so dedicated
can long endure. - Bo-
"We are met here on a great
battlefield of that war.
I hate parades. I'm not goin'.
"The world will not long remember,
nor little note, what we say here,
"but it will never forget
what they did here.
- Bo?
- "Rather it is for us, the living,
Please let me sleep.
to be so concentrated
and so dedicated-"
If you go any further, Mr. Lincoln,
you're gonna miss the parade.
- Elliot, got anything?
- Great.
- Would you hold it, please, miss?
- Hold it?
Uh, we're from Life.
Life Magazine?
That's right.
"Life Goes To A Rodeo."
Or "rodeo" to you.
They wanted me to ride
in the parade too, but I said,
"If I ride in it,
how can I see it?"
Just come right in here, Cherry.
Excuse us, everybody.
Come on up here.
We're gonna see us a parade real good.
Can't we find a place
to sit down, Bo?
I'm tired.
You didn't let me get no sleep.
- You hop right up here on my shoulder.
- No!
You can rest, and see the parade
at the same time!
- You put me down!
- Hey, this is a nice arrangement!
Can you see everything?
Too much.
Boy, look at that!
I'm glad I'm not in this parade,
so I can see it.
Here comes some of Daniel Boone's men!
We're seein' us a real hootenanny
of a parade, ain't we, Cherry?
Look at them boys dancin' it up.
Ain't they talented?
Ain't they resplendent, Cherry?
Hey, Cherry, look!
There's cowgirls, and they got-
Hi!
Hi! Where is he?
- You gonna marry him?
- No!
Then you're gonna go to the rodeo?
- No.
- Then what you gonna do?
Run away.
Hey, what's goin' on up there, Cherry?
Who were you signalin' at?
To... Vera.
She's a friend of mine.
She's gonna get two tickets to
the rodeo this afternoon to watch you.
Get two tickets for the rodeo.
Two?
Hey, there's ol' Virge!
Ya-hoo!
- Whoa! Stop it!
- Virge, here we are!
We been watchin' you, Virge,
and you're doin' just-
Hello, there. Stop it, Bo!
Oh, sorry, lady.
You're over there in the bleachers.
Over there?
But it's so much nicer
right here in the shade.
That's right.
Come on, honey.
Oh, they got us over here
with the livestock.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we go into our first event of the
afternoon: cowboy saddle bronc riding.
The contestant is required
to ride ten seconds...
until the signal
from our timer's horn.
That was Duane Howard of
Minnewaukin, North Dakota.
The second rider up is Guy Weeks.
And here's our next rider,
Casey Tibbs-
five times World's Champion
Saddle Bronc Rider,
twice All-Around
Champion Cowboy of the World.
- Watch the work of our pickup man
as he makes the recovery of Casey Tibbs,
Fort Pierre, South Dakota.
Cherie, wake up! It's him!
- Tell him to go away.
- No, I mean it's him.
He's gonna ride now.
Oh, we're at the rodeo.
What's that green thing.
That ain't green, Virge.
You know what that is?
♪ It's that old black magic ♪
♪ That's gonna make me win ♪
What's that he's got around his neck?
Ain't that your scarf?
So, that's where it went!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a newcomer here this afternoon.
- From Timber Hill, Montana, Bo Decker.
- Go!
- I can't look!
- You are stuck on him! I knew it!
Good work, Bo.
How about a hand?
Hey, Cherry! Ya-hoo!
Ya-hoo! Ya-hoo!
- Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- You know, I think he is crazy.
Sure he is.
Crazy as a bedbug.
I told you he was.
He thinks we're gettin' married
this afternoon here at the rodeo.
What makes him think that?
I don't know.
Sure weren't nothin' I said.
This mornin' after the parade,
he dragged me down to the city hall
and bought us a marriage license.
You didn't sign nothin', did ya?
Well, I had to do somethin'.
He was makin' such a fuss
in front of all those people.
Honey.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here's a ride to watch.
The cowboy has drawn one of the toughest
horses in our bareback riding contest.
Don't fall off.
- He fell off.
- I'm sorry.
Hey, is that a diamond?
Well, it ain't exactly a diamond,
but it ain't exactly
not a diamond either.
He paid $43 for it.
- No kiddin'.
- Plus tax.
He made me take it,
but it ain't on my finger.
And neither is that
wedding ring he bought.
It ain't gonna be either.
Weddin' ring?
Oh, honey.
Cowboys' calf roping
is our next contest.
This is a race against time,
and every second counts.
Notice the work
of the horse at all times,
keeping the rope snug and tight.
I'm just gonna pretend
that little ol' calf is Cherry.
I'm goin' after her
and I'm gonna get her.
- When I get her, I'm gonna rope her.
- Don't let the calf get away.
Get goin', Cherry!
Here's our newcomer again,
Bo Decker of Timber Hill, Montana.
Was that fast enough for you,
Cherry? Yee-hoo!
Who is she, Bo?
Come on.
Hey, look! Photographers from Life!
They're headin' this way.
Life Magazine?
They're coverin' the rodeo. They almost
took my picture this mornin'.
Where's my lipstick?
Oh! Would you please
hand me my lipstick, please?
Smile!
Basic.
Thank you.
I didn't have my lipstick on yet!
The most dangerous
of all rodeo events...
is the wild Brahma bull
riding contest.
And as an extra star
in this feature,
we have cousin Hugo,
our bullfighting chimpanzee.
It is Hugo's job to ride on the dummy,
and attract the bull over to him.
The cowboy clowns
are also there to distract the bull...
and draw him away from the cowboy
when he gets bucked off.
Keep your mind on that bull,
or you're gonna break your neck.
Don't worry about me, Virge.
I ain't gonna break my neck.
If I was to break my neck,
I couldn't get married.
If he was to break his neck,
that's about the only hope you've got.
Believe it or not,
here's our old friend, Bo Decker.
He's still wearing
that green scarf.
Let's hope it brings him luck
again in the bull riding.
Aah!
Good riding, Bo.
Cherry! Did you see me
ride that bull?
Cherry!
Bo, stop it!
He don't have no manners at all.
No, but he's got somethin' else.
And he's gonna get some little gal.
You just watch.
Well, it ain't gonna be me.
Besides, how can we get married?
He ain't made no arrangements.
Silly.
Cherie, look.
Ain't that a preacher?
Oh, my goodness!
Excuse me, please.
- Hey, where's the cowboy that's gettin' married?
- What?
- Getting married? Here at the rodeo?
- That's right.
- Elliot.
- Boing!
There she is! The cowboy's girl.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Bo Decker is also entered...
in our bulldogging contest.
Get him, get him, get him!
- How do you get outta here?
- The exit's over there.
But to get to it, you gotta
go around the corral, then you-
Where you goin'? Hey!
Cherie!
You shouldn't be crossin' there!
Cherry, where you goin'?
Cherry, what's goin' on here?
Wait a minute, Cherry!
Where you goin'?
Oh, my shoe! Oh, I'll get it!
Cherry, come back!
Stop her! Hey, somebody hold
this thing for me!
I'm tellin' ya, she ain't here,
she ain't been here, and I don't know
when she's comin' back.
I don't believe you!
She's here someplace. I know she is.
Bo, if she ain't here,
she ain't here.
Now we gotta go get some supper, and get
your mind clear for the finals tonight.
I don't care about the finals!
I want Cherry!
- Cherry!
- Ma'am.
He don't give up that easy.
If I'm not careful, I'm gonna end up
in East No Place, Montana,
with nothin' but him
and a bunch of cows.
Hey, what are you doing?
We're gonna pack your stuff and we're
gonna stash your suitcase at the club,
just in case you have
to make a quick getaway.
I can't go back to the club.
That's the first place he'll look.
If you don't show up for work, they sure
ain't gonna give you no advance.
Now listen.
He's ridin' in the rodeo.
You're safe till it's over anyway.
And you just tell that cashier...
that you gotta have money 'cause
your poor old grandmother is sick.
My poor old grandmother's sick.
I just don't understand that boy.
- What's he got on his mind, anyhow?
- Me.
I'm gonna find her and I'm gonna marry
her, and that's all there is to it.
You gotta get her off your mind.
At least till after the rodeo tonight.
- I ain't gonna be in the rodeo tonight.
- If you'll go to the rodeo,
- I'll find her and hold her for you.
- You will?
I don't say she's gonna marry you.
But I'll have her there at
the Blue Dragon when you get through.
- Okay, Virge, if you promise!
- I promise!
My poor ol' grandmother's very sick,
so if I could just have an advance.
Not without the boss okays it,
and he's watchin' the rodeo.
He'll be back when it's over.
Her grandmother'll be dead by then.
Let's you and me have
a little drink, miss.
C'mon. I'm so dry,
I'm spittin' cotton.
Two whiskeys, miss.
Take it easy. I'm on your side.
I don't want him to marry you neither.
- You don't?
- I sure don't.
Oh! I suppose I ain't
good enough for him, is that it?
I didn't say that.
I suppose he's as pure
as a bunch of driven snow.
As a matter of fact, he is.
You trying to tell me-
He never even kissed a gal
before he met you.
You're forgettin' he spent his whole
life pretty far out in the country.
I know what happens in the country.
I'm from the country myself.
I've been kissing boys
since I was knee high to-
Well, that's the point!
You're kinda sophisticated for Bo.
He sure didn't kiss
like it was the first time.
Well, Bo picks things up real quick.
First time, huh?
That's right.
Sure ain't never had that honor before.
I hate to put you through this, but I promised
him I'd keep you here till he got back.
Course, I didn't say anything about where
you might take a notion to go after that.
Oh! Ol' Vera's
sure gonna miss you, honey.
Oh, what was I supposed to say again?
I never was any good at lyin'.
It ain't all that complicated. We just
sit here and talk to him for a while.
Then you turn casually
and you say,
"Bo, the show is gonna start
pretty soon.
I guess I better go
powder my nose."
And then what do I-
And then you go to your dressing room
where your suitcase is.
You change your clothes,
you climb out of the window,
and you get down to the bus station.
The rodeo must be over.
Wonder what's keepin' Bo?
I know what's keepin' him.
He's probably arguin' and yellin'...
and pushin' some poor
little helpless animal around.
Whatever give you
an idea like that, Cherry?
Nice to see ya, honey.
I was afraid ya got yourself trampled
to death in that crowd this afternoon.
Where ya been, Bo?
Well, I had a couple of errands
to run after the rodeo.
I bought us three tickets
for tonight's bus to Montana.
By the way,
there's $4,000 that I got for winnin'
every event at that there rodeo.
'Cept steer wrestlin'. Would've won
that too but they gave me a bum steer.
Don't give me no credit for that one.
One of the other fellas thought it up.
Well, Virge,
I got our gear all packed up
and waitin' outside in a taxi.
All we gotta do is stop by
Cherry's house and pick up her suitcase.
Your nose is kinda shiny,
ain't it?
Huh? Oh.
Oh!
Bo, the show's gonna start
in just a minute, and,
uh, uh, I-I-I gotta go
p- powder my nose.
Why, Cherry? You're not gonna do
your show tonight.
- I ain't?
- No, of course not.
- You gotta go pack your suitcase.
- Oh, it's already packed.
I mean, I-I-I gotta go powder my nose.
Cherry, what's the matter with you?
Are you sick or somethin'?
No, I ain't sick, Bo.
I just can't lie to you
and I can't marry ya,
and I ain't goin' to Montana with you.
And good-bye forever.
Cherry, wait a second!
Cherry, wait!
Cherry!
You ain't got the manners
they give a monkey!
I hate you!
And I despise you!
And give me back my tail!
- Cherry!
- Here's your bag.
- Here's your coat and hat.
- Cherry!
You ain't got time. Change at
the bus station. Put on your coat.
I'm sorry, Cherry. I didn't mean to rip
your tail off. You can sew it back on.
Well, good luck, honey.
Thanks, Vera.
You've been real sweet.
Oh, let her go, let her go, Bo!
What do you mean, "let her go"?
Where's she goin'?
Cherry! Cherry!
Where'd she go?
Ticket to Los Angeles, please.
One way.
Los Angeles bus
leaving from gate two.
Bo, Bo! Wait a minute, Bo!
Help me unload this stuff.
Here, Bo. Forget her, Bo.
You'll find somebody else.
Hank and Orville was tellin' me about
this new schoolmarm who's stayin'-
I don't want no schoolmarm!
I want Cherry!
- Los Angeles bus leaving from gate two.
- Cherry!
Bo, you just can't take people places
like that! There's laws against it, Bo!
- This way, straight ahead.
- Which-
Lady, here's the Los Angeles bus.
Please, miss, to the rear of the line.
Bus for Helena, Montana, now loading.
Gate's closed.
- Cherry, don't get on that bus.
- No, Bo, no.
- I'm gonna get her. Ain't gonna take "no" for an answer.
- You ain't goin' over that fence.
Please, stand to the rear.
You goin' crazy?
What do you think you're doing?
Anything I ever wanted in this life,
I just went out and got!
♪ If the ocean was whiskey
and I was a duck ♪
♪ I'd swim to the bottom
and never come up ♪
♪ Rye whiskey, rye whiskey
rye whiskey I cry ♪
♪ If I don't get rye whiskey
I surely will die ♪
♪ So if I get boozy
My whiskey's my own ♪
♪ And them that don't like me
can leave me alone ♪
♪ Rye whiskey, rye whiskey
rye whiskey I cry ♪
♪ If I don't get rye whiskey
I surely will die ♪
♪ I'll eat when I'm hungry
I'll drink when I'm dry ♪
I'm sorry to wake you,
but could you help me?
- What's the matter?
- I'm being abducted.
Abducted?
You know,
like kidnapped... by him.
Oh, that's awful!
What are you gonna do?
I thought maybe as soon
as we got someplace,
I'd ask the driver to stop
and let me off.
But we've been ridin'
for hours and hours,
and we still don't seem
to be no place at all.
Not only that,
I'm freezing to death.
I don't have much on under my coat.
You mean just your underthings?
No, it's my costume,
but it's just a bitty old thing.
Now it doesn't even have its tail.
Its what?
Its- Oh, it's a long story.
You're shivering!
Don't you have anything warm to put on?
Will you help me change?
Of course.
- Here, hold this up for me, will you?
- Sure.
Cherry? Cherry, where are you?
Cherry!
Cherry?
What's goin' on up here?
Get away from me!
Can't you see I'm gettin' dressed?
Bo, ain't you caused enough trouble
for one night? Come back and sit down!
I can't figure it out.
Why don't she like me? Why?
Of course, if you loved him,
it wouldn't be so bad.
Yeah, but I don't.
Not at all?
There are some gals who don't like
to be pushed and grabbed...
and lassoed and drug into buses
in the middle of the night.
How else was I gonna get her
on the bus?
Well, I'm askin' ya.
Go to sleep!
I don't know why I keep expecting myself
to fall in love, but I do.
Well, I know I expect to someday.
I'm seriously beginning to wonder if
there's the kind of love I have in mind.
What's that?
I don't know. Uh-
You see, I've been goin' with guys
since I was about 12.
Honest?
I almost married a cousin
when I was 14.
But Pappy wouldn't have it.
I never heard of anyone
marrying so young!
Down in the Ozarks,
we don't waste much time.
I sure am glad, though,
I never married my cousin Malcolm.
'Cause he turned out real bad,
just like Pappy predicted.
But I sure was crazy
about him at the time.
And I've been losing my head
about some guy ever since.
Bo was the first one
that ever wanted to marry me...
since my cousin Malcolm.
Naturally I'd like to get married...
and have a family and all them things.
But you've never been in love?
I don't know.
Maybe I have and I didn't know it.
That's what I mean.
Maybe I don't know what love is.
I want a guy I can
look up to and admire.
But I don't want him to browbeat me.
I want a guy
who'll be sweet with me.
But I don't want him
to baby me either!
I just gotta feel
that whoever I marry...
has some real regard for me...
aside from all that... loving stuff.
You know what I mean?
I think so.
This storm is getting terrible!
There's Grace's lights.
I think we're gonna make it.
You can sneak off when I get off.
I can if that wild man don't wake up.
Sure awful rough.
I wish I had my chains on.
Shh!
This is as close as I can get.
You're gonna have to walk from here.
You sure picked some night
for traveling.
Come on! Come on in!
Whew!
Ah.
Grace, this is Cherie. We gotta find
some place for her to hide.
- She's being abducted.
- She's been what?
You know! Kidnapped!
Yes, that's right.
By a man in the bus, a cowboy.
He's out there asleep,
so if I could stay until the bus pulls
out again, I sure would appreciate it.
Bus ain't pullin' out.
Huh?
Road's all closed up ahead.
I got word to hold that bus here.
The highway gang's out,
but it may take the rest of the night.
Oh! The rest of the night?
Mr. Bus Driver, are we
gonna stay here very long?
'Cause my aunt and uncle
are supposed to meet us, you know.
Don't you think we oughta wake
those cowboys up too?
- Well-
- Brrr! It's cold!
- Well, look what the cat dragged in!
- Hiya, Grace.
Who's that with ya?
Ain't they cute!
They're gonna visit
their aunt in Helena.
Looks like they're gonna visit
their Aunt Grace, for tonight anyway.
Everybody is.
Highway's all closed... up ahead.
Oh, now, ain't that too bad!
What's this I hear about you carrying
a kidnapper on your bus?
You mean that cowboy?
He ain't kidnappin' nobody.
He's asleep.
He might freeze out there.
Why don't you go out and wake him up?
Oh, no! I mean, couldn't you just
let him sleep a little longer?
He's had a very busy day.
Two rodeos and... a lot else.
Sure. Let him sleep for a while.
Kinda works out better
for everybody that way.
- How soon is the next bus back?
- Ain't no busses running tonight.
You're all stuck right here.
For the time, anyway.
You know somethin', Grace?
This is the first time you and me have
had more than five minutes together.
So what?
I don't know.
I was just thinking about
that apartment you got upstairs.
Sure would be nice
to sit up there for a while,
listen to the radio or somethin'.
Maybe have a couple of beers.
That wouldn't be a hint
or somethin', would it?
Elma, where is this place
we're at now anyway?
Oh, about here. It's so little,
it's not even on the map.
I sure am way off my direction.
- Whatcha lookin' at?
- Oh, nothin'. Just your hands.
You got real big hands.
Big all over.
- I used to be state wrestling champion.
- No kiddin'!
I always admire a man who can fight.
Hey! Why didn't anybody wake us up?
Me and Virge might've froze out there!
- Hey, close the door!
- Cherry!
Cherry!
- How come you got off the bus without lettin' me know?
- Shut the door, cowboy!
How come you want to slip off the bus,
and come in here all by yourself?
Where was you brought up?
In a barn?
That's right! He was!
What's the matter with you, mister?
You afraid of a little fresh air?
The man's right, Bo.
It's cold out there.
That don't give him no right
to insult my manners.
No man ever had to tell me
what to do, did he, Virge? Did he?
You opened the door, you should've
closed it. That's all I'm sayin'.
The door's closed now,
so what ya arguin' about?
Cherry, let's you and me
sit down and have a-
That's your suitcase, ain't it?
For cryin' out loud,
will you leave me be?
Well, ain't that your suitcase?
Yes, that's my suitcase. Grrr!
What'd you bring it in here for?
Cherry, I'm asking ya a civil question.
What did you bring
your suitcase in here for?
- Now, tell me!
- You keep away from me, Bo Decker.
- Bo, will you- - Virge, you keep outta
this. This is between me and Cherry.
Was you tryin' to fool me again?
Is that what it was?
- Take your hands off of me, Bo!
- Tell me.
Cherry, you tell me!
Okay, cowboy, leave the lady alone.
You better keep outta this,
if you know what's good for ya.
- It ain't none of your business.
- I ain't so sure about that.
A bus driver's kind of like
the captain of a ship.
The welfare of the passengers
is his responsibility.
- If anything happens in the bus-
- We ain't in a bus!
We're in a bus stop!
This is an official,
authorized bus stop!
- Ain't it, Grace?
- When the sign's up.
You still got no right interfering
between two people gonna get married!
We ain't gettin' married!
That's what I've been tryin' to tell ya.
But you're too bullheaded
and mean to listen!
Cherry, I'm tellin' you,
you're gonna marry me,
and I ain't gonna
discuss it no more!
There must be a preacher
around here someplace, ain't there?
Down the road a ways,
but, uh, he's asleep.
We're gonna wake him up,
and put him to work.
- Aah! Help, everybody!
- Oh, shut up!
I'll make ya a good husband.
You'll have nothin' to be sorry about.
- No! No!
- I'm telling you, cowboy. Put her down!
- Open the door, Virge.
- No! No!
Go ahead, open the door!
I ain't gonna open it, Bo.
- You ain't?
- No!
You've been against this
right from the beginning!
That's right. First 'cause I figured
the lady wasn't good enough for you.
But now 'cause I figure
you ain't good enough for her!
That's how it is, cowboy.
Now, are you gonna put her down?
You're gonna get out of my way!
You're gonna have to fight me first.
I love a good fight.
- One thing I can't stand is a bully.
- Who says I'm a bully?
I do!
Quiet! A man's got to fight
for what he wants!
There's a big difference
between a fighter and a bully, Bo.
But there's only one way
you're gonna learn it.
For once in your life, somebody's
gotta beat the livin' tar out of ya!
Go to it, Captain.
He's ripe for it.
I'd do it myself
if I was big enough.
But you ain't big enough!
And neither is he!
Ain't no man ever got the best of me,
and there ain't gonna be.
I'm willin' to try, cowboy!
Just step outside.
Delighted!
Oh, Grace, make 'em stop!
Look, cowboy, why don't you
save yourself a lot of trouble?
- Go tell that little girl you're sorry.
- I ain't sorry!
He never ain't!
That's his whole trouble!
You stay outta this, Virge.
I had just about enough of you tellin'
me what's right and what's wrong.
No, you ain't! You can stand
just a little bit more!
Virge! What're you doin'?
I'm startin' a fight.
He's gonna finish it for me.
But remember this, Bo. Every time
he hits ya, it's me hittin' ya!
Do ya hear that? It's me!
And it'll be me hittin' ya back!
Move over. I'm gettin' cold.
How 'bout that!
And that... and that!
You're doin' great, mister!
- Gouge him, cowboy! Bite him!
- Make them stop!
Now you two come away
from this window!
You don't wanna watch things like that
or you're gonna grow up mean...
like all my brothers
and my cousins too!
Now you sit down there
and behave yourselves!
You oughta be in bed!
Grace has a big bed upstairs,
and a sofa too.
All right, boys,
lay off them gas pumps!
Had enough, kid?
Go put your coat on, honey.
This is gettin' good.
Cherry?
Virge, make him stop
'fore somebody gets killed!
Give up! Come on, give up!
You ain't got a chance.
You had enough?
No, he ain't. Not till he promises
to apologize to everybody in the place.
And quits molestin'
that poor little girl.
You hear what he said?
- C'mon, Bo, you're whipped. Admit it!
- Okay.
Bo?
Get away, damn it!
How 'bout the promise, Bo?
- Is she gone?
- She's gone.
- Okay, I promise.
- All right.
He'll be all right.
Come on, Bo, the storm is over.
I'm sorry it had to be like this.
It's all over now.
Come on inside and wash up,
get some coffee.
Come on!
You can't stay out here.
I, I can't go in there.
She's seen me get whipped.
Carl, honey, you was
just plain tremendous!
Eh!
I think maybe I earned me a bottle of
that cold beer you got in the icebox...
upstairs.
Snowplow's out.
Shouldn't be too much longer.
C'mon, Bo, cheer up.
Bus'll be leavin' pretty soon.
We'll be back
on the ranch tomorrow.
I don't care if I ever see
that ranch again.
Lonesomest durn place
I ever did see.
It's like goin' back
to a graveyard.
Good mornin', honey.
They're sleepin' just fine.
Must've read myself to sleep.
Such an interesting story.
- Can I have a cup of coffee?
- Sure, honey. Elma just run it through.
- Bo?
- Yeah?
This'll be a good time
to keep your promise.
- Why should you be so scared?
- Who's scared?
I'm gonna do it.
Just give me a little time, that's all.
But I warn ya, it ain't gonna do
no good less'n you really mean it.
- I mean it.
- All right then.
Go ahead.
Ma'am, I want to apologize.
For what?
- For causing all that ruckus.
- Ah!
You don't need to apologize
to me, cowboy.
I love a good fight. You're welcome
at Grace's Diner anytime.
I mean anytime!
Thanks.
I must've acted like a hoodlum.
I apologize.
Oh, that's all right.
Thank you, miss.
Have I gotta wake him up?
No, he can wait.
Virge, I can't do it.
I just can't do it.
Why not?
I can't face up to her.
She's seen me get beat.
You made me your promise.
You owe that girl an apology
whether you got beat or not,
and you're gonna say it to her.
Now, go on, Bo. Go on!
Well, don't watch!
I'll do the dishes, honey.
- I can do 'em, Grace.
- No, you go on with the kids' breakfast.
- Cherry?
- Yes?
Cherry, it wasn't right of me
to do what I did to you,
treatin' you that way,
draggin' you on the bus,
and tryin' to make you marry me
whether you wanted to or not.
Do you think you can
ever forgive me?
I guess I've been treated worse
in my life.
Well, I... reckon
that's all there is to be said.
I wish you luck, Cherry.
I wish you the same, Bo.
Here's your bandana back.
Thanks.
Oh!
Here's your ring.
I wish you'd keep that.
All right, Bo.
Well, so long.
So long.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
- Why don't we sit down and have ourselves some breakfast?
- I ain't hungry.
- Just some coffee then.
- I couldn't get it down.
Phone!
Turn the water off, honey.
Grace's Diner.
What?
Oh, it is?
Okay, I'll tell him.
Hate to wake him,
but the road's cleared.
- Hey, Carl.
- Huh?
The road's cleared. But you're
gonna have to put your chains on.
- It's still awful slick. Elma?
- Okay.
Hey, Elma,
better wake the kids up.
The road's clear, folks.
Bus'll be ready to leave soon as I get
the chains on and pull it up front.
Anybody wanna help me?
Uh, sit here, Bo. I'll help him.
Bo?
Yeah?
I just wanted to tell you something.
It's kinda personal
and embarrassing too.
But I ain't the kind of girl
you thought I was.
What do you mean, Cherry?
Well, I guess a lot of people'd say
I led a real wicked life,
and I guess I have too.
What are you tryin' to tell me?
Well, I just figure that...
since you met me
at the Blue Dragon,
that you just took it
for granted that...
I'd had other boyfriends 'fore you.
You had?
Yes, Bo.
Quite a few.
Virge tried to tell me that,
but I wouldn't believe him.
Well, it's true.
So you can see,
it-
You're better off,
'cause I ain't the kind
of gal you thought I was at all.
I'll go wake the children.
Cherry,
would I be molestin' you
if I was to tell you somethin'?
No.
Since you brought the subject up,
y- you are the first gal
that I ever had anything to do with.
I never thought I'd hear myself
sayin' that, but I said it.
Virge told me that,
but I couldn't hardly believe him.
That's the truth.
You see, I lived all my life
on a ranch and...
I guess I just didn't know
anything about women...
'cause they're different from men.
Well, naturally.
Brrr! All ready to roll, folks.
Feelin' better, cowboy?
I ain't the happiest critter
that's ever been born.
I feel a little shook up myself.
How 'bout shaking hands?
- Well- - Go ahead, Bo. He's
just tryin' to be friends.
- I don't mind.
- No hard feelin's?
No hard feelin's.
There's a nice state, miss. Montana.
How 'bout a cup of coffee
for the road, Grace?
- Nice fella, Bo.
- Maybe I'll think so someday.
Maybe we'd better be boarding the bus.
- Cherry?
Hi, Bo.
Cherry, you won't be
gettin' on this bus.
I know that I promised
not to molest ya,
but if you give your permission
that it'd be all right,
I... I'd like
to kiss you good-bye.
I'd like for you to kiss me, Bo.
I really would.
- Bo!
- What?
I think this time
it oughta be different.
Oh!
Golly,
when you kiss somebody for serious,
it's kinda scary, ain't it?
Yes, it is.
- Here they are. All breakfasted.
- I'm still hungry.
- See you Wednesday.
- Keep that beer on ice, will ya, Grace?
Maybe next time
I'll get a chance to finish it.
- Come on, kids.
- I turned down the heater.
- Honey, will you throw this water on the fire?
- Sure.
This bus stop is closed
as of now!
Cherry?
Yes?
- Virge has been figurin' things out.
And, well, he says...
that seeing as how you had
all them other boyfriends before me,
and seeing as I never even
had one single gal friend before you,
well, Virge figures
that between the two of us...
it kinda averages out...
to things being proper and right.
That's what Virge thinks.
What do you think, Bo?
Well-
Well, I've been thinkin'
about them other fellas, Cherry,
and, well, what I mean is,
I like you the way you are,
so what do I care how you got that way?
Bo!
That is the sweetest,
tenderest thing anyone ever said to me.
It's awful hard for a fella
after he's been turned down once,
to get up enough guts to try again.
You don't need guts, Bo.
I don't?
That's the last thing
in this world you need.
Well, anyhow,
I just don't have any now.
So I'll just have to tell you
what I feel in my heart.
Yes?
I still wish you was
goin' back to the ranch with me,
more than anything I know.
Yeah, I do.
I'd go anywhere in the world
with you now.
Anywhere at all!
Y- Y-You would?
You, you would?
- Yes, I would!
- You would?
I would, I would, I would!
You would? You would?
You would?
Yes, I would. I would.
Virge!
Oops.
She's gonna marry me!
Ain't it wonderful when somebody
so terrible turns out to be so nice?
Our ranch is gonna be
the nicest place in the world...
'cause we're gonna have
an angel on it!
- Here's your map.
- Here's your bag.
Oh, this ol' thing!
That's right, Cherry!
I'll show you the way to Montana!
- Okay!
- Come on, Virge.
- Wait a second, Bo.
- Doggone it, come on!
- Now listen!
- Come on, Virge, what you waitin' for?
You asked for a second!
You gotta hear me. Bo, I ain't goin'.
You ain't what?
You don't need me to look after you.
Fact is, you got someone
you gotta look after.
Here's your wedding ring.
Virge, I wish you'd come.
I liked you long 'fore I ever liked Bo.
Gettin' late, folks.
You better hurry.
The bus can't wait all day.
Doggone it, Virge! You're my buddy!
I ain't gonna let you go.
You're comin' with Cherry and me,
'cause we want you to!
- Let me be! Let me be!
- Bo! Bo!
You just can't do it that way.
You just can't!
If he don't wanna come,
you can't make him.
Whatever I got left up there,
the boys can have it.
- Bye, Bo.
- C'mon, Cherry, let's make it fast.
Well, Cherry!
You're liable to freeze
to death in that skimpy little thing!
But what about you?
You'll need something.
Ya-hoo!
Uh-oh!
Bye, everybody!
Bye! Bye!
♪ You can have my everything
My house, my money, my wedding ring ♪
♪ And in the bargain I'll throw in me ♪
♪ If you will marry me ♪