Doctor.
No!
I thought I wouldn't make it.
Your briefcase.
You left it on your desk.
- Are RenoI's papers here?
- Yes.
Don't forget tonight's dinner party.
The class at the University
is tomorrow at 11.
The lecture's in the afternoon.
Please keep warm, and rest.
If there's anything you need...
I'm okay.
Doctor!
I wanted to tell you that...
you have nothing to worry about.
I know you don't like to
leave your office unattended.
It's not unattended.
Can I help you?
- Do I know you?
- I don't think so.
All old passengers look alike.
Are you going to the convention?
You too?
I'm going to a party!
Where were you?
In the cafeteria.
Were you drinking?
You stink!
Would you hold this?
I'm going to the bathroom.
I'll be right back.
Are you sure there's no one else?
I'm sure.
She couldn't leave without her case.
I've checked each and every car.
And the washrooms?
- Maybe something happened to her.
- Check the cafeteria.
Your mother may be
waiting for you there.
- No, she's not my mother.
- Then why worry so much?
I'm sorry.
Doctor?
Dr. Fausto?
Do I know you?
Dr. Fausto, it's you.
What a pleasure!
You don't remember?
You don't remember me?
Well, you should.
You removed my stomach.
Santos.
Santos Vella.
At El ProvinciaI, 8 years ago.
Pancreatic cancer.
A mixed tumor, with complications.
No?
Without the oxygen mask...
- Did I attend to you?
- You said I was terminaI.
We had a rather intense relationship.
But you operated 5 times first.
The last time, to show some
students an irreversible process.
- It seems I was wrong.
- It seems.
You said 3 months,
and it's been 8 years.
Don't apologize.
These things happen.
- I'm not.
- As I said, these things happen.
My stomach?
- What?
- My stomach.
- Your stomach?
- Yes. Did you keep it?
- What for?
- What became of it?
They threw it away, I guess.
In the garbage?
That's not too cooI.
You want us to keep it after 8 years?
Of course not.
I'd like to have seen it.
I'm sure it didn't look too good.
How'd you do it?
- What?
- This.
Live.
Staying away from hospitals.
When I see one,
I cross the street.
I forgot my card.
Santos, Santos Vella.
- It's pronounced with one "I".
- VeI-la.
No, Vella, like mozzarella.
- Vella.
Doctor!
Where are you staying?
Don't tell me.
At the NationaI.
- You're here for the convention.
- Of course.
- I'll drive you.
- No, I'll take a cab.
No problem.
I have to go somewhere else first.
I'll drive you.
It's nice to see you, doctor.
- My stomach...
- Fuck, no!
I'd rather go alone.
Great.
When I get to a new city,
I like to discover it alone too.
We're grown-ups.
Anything you need,
you've got my card.
You got a problem,
you call me. Okay?
Sure.
You swear?
No, I believe you.
It's a pleasure to see you,
doctor.
And thanks for everything.
He's a great guy, lady.
No sweat!
Fuck!
- To the NationaI HoteI, please.
- Right away.
Doesn't that sound strange?
What?
The car.
Not at all.
It's as strong as a bull.
Over 20 years without
a breakdown.
Son of a bitch!
Damn son of a bitch!
Got a problem?
A bull?
It's more like a cow!
What's it about?
The convention.
- TerminaI medicine.
- TerminaI medicine?
That's going to be fun.
I'm gonna fuck your father,
and I'm late!
Well, what then?
You have to go somewhere first?
- I'll go later.
- You sure?
Yes.
It was a lie, right?
You say that to get rid of me.
Admit it.
- All right, I admit it.
- Great.
Great.
I catch on to everything.
I've gotten smart.
Really, I've studied.
I pay attention to the things I should.
You see...
If someone tells you
you're going to die...
you change.
You think: What do I do
with the little time I got left?
You do 4 important things.
This, this and this.
The rest is just shit, man.
It's not worth it.
- That's why I owe you.
- Forget it.
No, no, no. I owe you one.
So...
tell me what you want.
I'll take care of it.
- Don't bother.
- It's no bother.
It's no bother.
Doctor...
I want to make you happy.
- What have you got there?
- I don't know. It's not mine.
Did you steaI it?
Me? Please.
Someone left it on the train...
- You haven't opened it?
- No.
Fuck! That is admirable.
Fausto, Fausto...
Well, here we are.
I'll take that case to the station.
No, thanks,
someone at the hoteI can...
I'll take care of it.
No problem.
Besides,
someone there owes me a favor.
Fausto, how nice to see you.
How are you?
We were betting
on whether you'd come or not.
- Has Quiroga arrived?
- He should have this morning.
Hi, good evening.
Santos Vella. It's a pleasure.
My pleasure.
Vella, pronounced with one "I".
Like mozzarella.
You know the doctor?
Of course.
Me too.
He removed my stomach.
That was a long time ago.
Forget it, man.
You're here for the convention?
Yes.
To talk about your
little tumors and things.
Thank you very much.
He's getting rid of me.
It's a pleasure.
Anything you need, call.
You want a girI?
- I don't understand.
- Man, what a joker!
I don't know him.
He's a patient.
My brother-in-law
went to a specialist and asked:
"Doctor, how long have
I get left to live?"
And you know what
the guy told him?
"That depends.
When will you pay my bill?"
Why must we wash?
Do butchers wash?
Who says they haven't jerked off
before cutting up a sirloin steak?
Although they're butchers...
they jerk off, don't they?
What do you say, Fausto?
"Sagittarius, Capricorn?"
"No, son, what I said was Cancer. "
Cancer, cancer. "
You don't need to be a butcher
to know if they jerk off.
She's Daisy, my assistant.
I've heard that before.
Me too, and I saw it.
The Frenchman, for example,
at the ProvinciaI.
Before each operation.
- Really?
- I swear.
And if he operated 3 times,
3 times.
They call the doctor
"the gardener".
- You know why?
- No.
Because he works with plants.
TerminaI cases.
When we don't know
what to do with someone...
we send them to him
to see what he invents.
You've all ordered mushrooms.
You don't understand him.
What he'd like is to see
all his patients alive.
Who wouldn't?
We should close the greenhouse.
It's useless.
I don't even know if it's
legaI to have all those...
people there.
It's a research center.
We research medicine
to be used in the first phases.
That's fine.
But I wouldn't like
to be in your shoes.
How many patients die a year?
How many this year?
500?
600?
When you get to a thousand,
you'll win a prize!
Never trust a dermatologist.
They skin people alive.
There'll be broads too.
Shit, Bielsa.
They're in coma.
And, so what?
You should see them at the morgue,
with the female corpses.
That's different.
They're dead.
Like Daisy.
20 years in practice
and still thinks...
a practitioner
is a churchgoer.
Excuse me.
Is there a doctor in the house?
Please!
Continue administering Codeine...
only untiI Thursday...
and then give him antibiotics.
His temperature's down to 37.8.
Continue with Naproxen.
RenoI.
Very good.
I have the file in front of me.
RenoI.
Let's withdraw his breather.
- Withdraw it?
- Completely.
The corticoids as well.
And watch his apnea.
Watch his evolution.
- Is his mother still with him?
- She hasn't moved.
Who is it?
Doctor?
- Who is it?
- Doctor?
Dr., are you still there?
Julia, my dinner's here.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Is this for reaI?
Great.
I love luxury hotels.
When I get rich,
I'II live in one like this.
Who are you?
I hear you're eminent.
I asked you something.
I study medicine.
This helps me pay
my registration fees.
I told Santos
I didn't want anything.
I have no idea.
What do you have to do
to be eminent?
Study a lot...
or drink a lot of milk?
I told Santos...
Hold this.
Who is it?
Room service.
Your breakfast.
Come in and leave it
next to the bed.
Okay.
Which one of the two?
The one that was slept in.
Do you want orange
or strawberry marmalade?
- Strawberry.
- Great, me too.
Good book.
A little slow though.
But that's okay.
They never make fuckin' toast properly.
What a pain!
What are you doing here?
- How'd you get in?
- That's easy.
A friend in maintenance
owed me a little favor.
And talking about favors,
now you owe me one.
The suitcase.
The old lady went to pick it up.
We'll never know what was in it.
- How'd you sleep?
- Fine.
- Please leave.
- Sure.
I told reception no calls.
You need to rest up a bit.
Well, what can I do for you?
Get out.
You have to go.
Sure, and so do you.
It's almost eleven...
and from here to the
University we've got...
You're the one who's leaving.
Just a moment.
It's for you.
- For me?
- Yes, for you.
I said I'd be here.
Excuse me. Yes?
Hey, man, what's up?
I'm with a friend.
What is it?
Yeah.
Okay, five minutes.
I can't go with you.
I'm so sorry.
Did I give you my card?
Yesterday.
Well, here,
I get a good price on them.
If you need any,
or anything else, just call.
At any time.
Will you?
Don't worry.
Yes?
- Julia.
- Doctor.
I called this morning
but couldn't get through.
They made a mistake.
Listen.
Do me a favor.
Find a Santos Vella's
medical record.
- With a double "I".
- Like in mozzarella.
Send it to me at the University.
Right away.
For your lecture?
Of course.
Find the origin of the illness
in the body. Surround it...
in an attempt to establish
the progress of the metastasis.
Determining what organs
were infected first.
Who infected who?
Differentiating the focaI point
from the satellites.
A sick body is like a freeway,
full of signs.
Of indicators.
Some are clear, luminous.
Others are concealed.
Illness is a clumsy criminaI.
It leaves clues.
Many times, the body itself
is the origin of the illness.
It creates it and
encourages it along the way.
From where?
Is there an evil gland?
Ancient people spent their lives
searching for it.
They thought that removing it,
they would eradicate the illness.
Today,
in certain Asian countries...
live rats are inserted
in the sick patients' bodies...
to track down putrefaction
amongst the healthy organs.
We now know that gland
is not in the human body.
It's in the soul.
In those occasions, the illness...
is a self-destructive process.
Trying to check it is like...
trying to stop a suicidaI person.
Death...
always finds its way.
It is an end that...
cannot be refused.
It's there from the very beginning.
It's part of the deaI
ever since we're born.
All births...
carry an implicit death.
It is not enough to teach students...
how to eradicate the illness.
We must also learn...
to accept it.
Doctor!
Do me the honor.
You know each other, right?
Listen to me.
I don't know how you do this...
nor why, but I don't care!
I don't want to see you again!
I want you to go,
to disappear from my life!
Watch what you're asking for.
It could come true.
Sir.
I thought you could use it.
Why are you so surprised?
I told you yesterday, in the car.
I'm here to make you happy.
I don't want your help...
and I'm not interested
in your ghost stories.
You're not the first terminaI
case to get better.
You say you're my patient,
but I'm not sure.
I think you're a charlatan...
and you bore me to no end!
- I don't believe a word you say.
- Ask.
What?
Make a wish.
Whatever you want.
I wish...
to go.
Granted.
If someone...
If you could make a wish...
- what would you wish?
- Everything.
More money, to fuck more,...
an orgy with five broads...
and one of them black.
And you?
At 13:46 we register
the first cortical activity.
Sweating, motivity and spasms.
Voluntary medullary movements...
and cornea, labial
and trachea reflexes...
that continue until 13:52.
Oculocephalic reactions after...
lateralization and heave
movements of the head.
Blood pressure stabilized,
and behavioral response...
to nociceptive stimuli.
At 13:59, the oxygen mask and
endotrachea catheter were removed
without symptoms of apnea.
Three minutes later,
he hugs his mother.
17 minutes in total.
Isn't that incredible?
Incredible, yes.
I called the University,
but you had already left.
- Aren't you pleased?
- Of course.
I'll give you the report tomorrow.
I'll take the first train.
Doctor.
It's the most amazing recovery
I've ever seen.
Congratulations.
What are you looking for?
Fausto, have you lost
your speech?
What are you doing?
Please, sir!
God, I just picked it up!
...dying has become so indecent
that it is disguised and sterilized...
between clean
and opaque hospital walls.
Death exists.
It forms part of life.
It may be the non-life.
Santos Vella.
Although it's been repressed,
exiled...
from the sociaI awareness
it had belonged to...
the greatest deceit
for the dying...
Have we met before?
I don't think so.
It is not charity
for those who are to die...
Are you sure?
I think we have.
At a hospitaI, maybe?
I doubt it.
I visit my patients at home.
Then at some brotheI.
...a causaI illness
of progressive evolution...
with a prognosis
of one month to live,...
a treatment of proved
inefficiency...
and a loss of hope for recovery.
The clinicaI reports...
indicate the degree of damage...
or organic insufficiency,
and allow establishing deadlines.
TerminaI processes.
Excuse me.
What did you say your name is?
I didn't say.
Doctor Fierro.
Which implies
an old acquaintance...
who I'd rather not see...
- Doctor Fierro.
- Yes.
- Cardiologist?
- No, dermatologist.
What a coincidence!
You too?
No. I've got some spots.
What do you think?
It's the first time.
...of a pilgrimage that begins...
with the birth of said protocoI.
These images belong to research...
work and surgicaI revitalization
of tissues...
carried out
over a two-year period...
which we call
the blue phase of the project.
They were taken...
during the operations
carried out by...
the professionaI team
coordinated by...
I gave the tape to her.
Shit, it's not my fault!
Your research is very interesting.
We've learned a lot.
Did you film that?
It was you!
What?
Quiroga, I ought to...
You ought to what?
I'll tell you.
You ought to shut up.
And make sure of thing
before accusing anyone.
And show a little more
respect for your colleagues.
But, above all, you ought to...
lend us that tape for tonight.
Fierro.
That means "iron".
Dermatologist.
He prescribed a cream, DisantiI.
I don't know him.
Is she nice?
What?
Your assistant, Julia.
What do you know about Julia?
You never tell me anything.
You want to know things about me,
but never tell me anything.
"Dr. Fausto,
the report you asked me for.
Julia. "
If you want to know anything
about me, just ask.
Who are you?
Your best wish.
Why?
Because you alone aren't capable.
For how long?
UntiI they come true.
All of them.
You're getting old, Fausto.
How old do you think I am?
The same as you.
Do I look it?
I take care of myself.
But you don't
take care of yourself.
Look how you dress.
You earn money and
can buy yourself a better suit.
We're fucked.
I've got something you could use.
There was a Chinese proverb.
How'd it go?
I forgot.
Oh, yes!
Dress you body with elegant clothes
and your souI will smile.
What the fuck do they know,
they wear robes?
My house.
You like it?
How many hours a day
do you work?
You're so surrounded by corpses...
that you look like them
more and more.
Come in.
Make yourself at home.
Doctor, right this way.
Have you ever tried...
leaving a restaurant
without paying?
Or crossing the street
against the light?
No, right?
Have you tried living?
- Certain things can't change.
- That's not you talking.
- It wasn't you who said that.
- No?
- Who did then?
- Your dissatisfaction.
And dissatisfaction is an illness.
Of the souI, but an illness.
Is she nice or not?
What?
Your assistant.
What's her name...? Julia.
Don't tell me it never
crossed your mind.
- How do I know?
- "How do I know?"
Have you taken
a good look at her?
Did you ever kiss her?
Yes, once.
On her birthday.
Blessed Christ
of the Holy Power, doctor.
You two have
an unhealthy relationship.
Your glass.
That wouldn't be bad.
What?
Someone to look after her and...
Not "someone".
Who is "someone"?
Believe me, let yourself go.
For example:
Haven't you ever wanted to break
something really expensive?
No, don't do it.
Have you wanted to or not?
Sometimes.
Let's see.
Number seven.
Well, well.
That's why you're alive.
Because you wished it.
Could be.
Come on, it's very relaxing.
Every wanted to rob a store?
Go to the movies
without paying?
Or drink
your neighbor's whiskey...
and put your feet on the table
like a gentleman?
Doctor!
Have music blasting?
Fuck the neighbors!
To yell and dance...
and jump on the sofa...
and just go crazy?
Come on!
- Ever wanted to kill someone?
- What?
Kill.
Doctor!
- Try it on.
- For me?
Okay?
What?
How is it?
- Why are you taking so long?
- Just a moment!
I'm almost done.
To me that's not funny.
I think it's very funny.
I had to write them a check.
A check?
How much?
Six hundred.
I'm sorry.
Six hundred thousand?
You at least kept the suit.
It doesn't matter.
It's going to bounce.
Fuckin' cooI!
There's no money!
Look at you!
- What day is today?
- How do I know?
My daughter's throwing a party.
Let's go.
No, I should go to the hoteI.
Doctor, your wishes.
Don't you remember?
Besides,
she has some nice girlfriends.
Really, he has a
young friend, doctor...
- Don't tempt me.
- Don't tempt me!
Sure I tempt you.
That's what we're here for.
I love young people.
Doctor Fausto!
Thank you so much!
My case.
I don't know what I'd
have done without it.
You want her?
I can get her for you.
Where's your daughter?
I don't know.
Around somewhere.
What's the matter?
Julia must be worried
something happened to me.
She's worried
you're fucking someone else.
Santos, look at this!
They're Rolex.
Doctor!
I'm so happy to see you!
Do I know you?
A blow job in your hoteI.
Remember?
- That's right.
- What are you doing here?
Roaming around.
You look better.
- Than when I blew you off.
- Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Martita!
Daddy!
Hello, darling!
- Where were you?
- Right here.
A little present!
Look.
My daughter.
You had met, right?
Can I make a wish
for someone else?
- For who?
- For Julia.
Go ahead.
I told you before.
I'd like for someone
to take care of her.
Don't worry.
What do you mean "don't worry"?
What is "don't worry"?
Someone'll take care of her.
"Granted".
ReaI genies...
say "granted".
Not "don't worry".
- Granted.
- That's better.
"Don't worry".
What a shitty genie you are.
Where are you going?
Take a fuckin' guess.
Aren't you a genie?
Genies never guess.
Those are magicians.
He's an asshole.
Manolo, another drink.
Hello.
Your hands are blue.
I know.
Yeah?
And you don't care?
- It doesn't wash away.
- That's how they are.
I dye things blue.
Things?
What things?
I don't know, everything.
You live here?
- In the bathroom?
- No, I mean in the city.
For now.
I love to move around.
- Don't you?
- Moving? I love it.
Today here, tomorrow there.
Adventures.
- What do you do?
- Nothing.
I operate tumors, necrosis,
those little things.
Really?
Or are you putting me on?
"Putting me on"?
What does that mean?
It's something like teasing me,
making fun of me.
"Putting me on".
I like that.
- What's your name?
- Margarita.
For now.
For now?
You like to change names?
Of course. Don't you?
You're "putting me on".
No I'm not.
Yes, I can tell
you are "putting me on".
You're "putting me on".
- She's "putting me on".
- Let's go!
At your service, Fausto.
Why did he say that?
No reason.
It's a very long story.
He spends his time
granting me my wishes.
All of them?
What do you mean?
All your wishes?
The eviI ones too?
I'm sure you have eviI wishes too.
Maybe.
Doctor...
is this going to hurt?
Fausto.
Fausto, wake up.
You're going to miss this.
Look.
It's not very straight.
But it's not bad,
for being my first time.
Santos, get it off me!
Get it off me!
Get out of there.
He hadn't eaten anything,
you know?
Let's see what we've got here.
What was that you said?
Please, Santos!
Is there an eviI gland?
It exists, Fausto.
Do you have it?
Well, I do.
It's an enormous gland.
As large as me.
Not you.
You're good. Yes.
You just have
a very little gland...
that is annoying
and makes you doubt,...
makes you be a little eviI...
but only at times.
Well, let's rip it out
before it grows.
Let's see.
Here it is!
Could this be it?
I don't think so.
Fuck, could I be looking
in the wrong place?
Maybe it's down here.
An atrocity. They've given
him a terrible beating.
OccipitaI trauma with loss,
possible clot, evaluate.
Respiratory apnea
with loss of tone.
OccipitaI trauma with loss,
left vestibular tearing.
Stop, stop!
- Isn't that Quiroga?
- I think so.
Give me the Mayo tube,
fast.
That's it.
Come on, come on, fast.
Doctor Fausto!
Doctor Fausto, please!
Doctor!
Doctor Fausto!
QUIROGA, SON OF A BITCH!
For God's sake,
what have you done?
No, man, no. Please.
I didn't do anything.
I just got here.
He did it.
I'm sure it was him.
He gets in anywhere.
Friends owe him favors,
and here too.
Who?
I don't know who you mean.
The room is in your name.
Everything is broken.
There were many things.
Expensive things, broken.
You must pay.
Why all this?
Because I removed his stomach,
his fuckin' stomach!
Yes.
Doctor?
I'm at the station.
I just got in.
I've brought it all.
The doctor said
I'd see you at lunch.
Doctor?
What doctor?
Fierro. He's very kind.
You shouldn't have bothered.
Fierro. I didn't... Julia!
Fausto, did you sleep well?
Very little, of course.
Let me talk to Julia!
She had a good trip.
Excuse me.
- I was right, she's a piece.
- Leave her alone!
Stay away from her!
Don't touch her!
Julia!
Don't be so possessive,
you never looked twice at her.
Son of a bitch, don't touch her!
If you touch her, I'll kill you!
Why worry?
You wished this, remember?
"Someone to take care of her. "
No, don't thank me.
That's what I'm here for.
I owe it to you.
I will.
Regards.
That man worries a lot about you.
- He sounded a bit strange.
- His voice.
Yesterday
we went dancing untiI late.
Really?
What are you doing,
have you gone crazy?
You can't go.
- You ruined the room...
- The fuckin' room seems yours!
Listen, wait!
Hey, calm down.
It's loaded.
- Easy.
- Don't move!
Freeze!
Fuckin' freeze!
Don't follow me!
- Don't follow me!
- Take it easy.
Attention, security, armed
man. Second floor.
Move it!
He's armed. He's leaving the
hoteI. Call the police.
I hope they show up.
I hope they fuckin' show up!
Where is he?
Where is Santos,
you son of a bitch?
Talk!
Talk or I'll kill you!
It's okay, he's a patient of mine.
Where is Santos?
Where is he?
Talk or I'll kill you!
You bastard!
Let's have a drink
while we wait for the doctor.
I don't know if I should.
I'm a bit tired from the trip.
I promised the doctor
I'd take care of you.
A drink?
- Well, if you insist.
- I insist.
You heard me.
You can check it.
I'm a surgeon.
I'm here for a convention.
He's crazy.
Fuck, you don't understand!
He'll kill her!
He'll kill my assistant!
Finish your drink.
It'll do you good.
I'm a doctor.
Fausto will be here any minute now.
- You're very kind.
- Thank you.
Are you two involved?
I'm sorry if I've said anything
I shouldn't have.
No.
It's not that.
Our relationship is...
professionaI.
Ten years working together,
and with a woman...
like you,
next to him every day...
there's been...
nothing?
Nothing at all?
You're a very speciaI woman, Julia.
- Charge it to 213.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Where'd you say
you visit your patients?
I didn't say.
In private clinics.
I can't stand large hospitals.
All that bureaucracy
was making me dizzy.
I think Dr. Fausto
is going to be late.
Yes.
- Anything planned for tonight?
- No, nothing.
I can't believe that.
- How long has it been?
- Ages.
The uniform looks good.
You're quite a dandy, Alfonsito.
Your wife takes good care of
you. You don't deserve her.
That's the way it goes.
How are the kids?
The elder is eight now.
Eight years?
Time sure does fuckin' fly.
- She was in the cradle.
- This is the baby.
Shit!
- She starts schooI next week.
- You are drooling, my man!
The hoteI has dropped the charges.
Fausto, for God's sake,
what is this?
Have you seen yourself?
Have you calmed down?
Promise him you won't do it again.
Listen!
I operated him many years ago.
He should be dead,
but he isn't.
I removed his entire stomach.
Now he say
he want to make me happy.
That fucked him so much,
now he's after me.
What about my assistant?
Maybe he killed her.
- Please, arrest him!
- Here we go again.
Fausto, don't be silly
or this gentleman won't let you out.
Come on.
Were you really carrying a gun?
You had me fooled.
Julia's an extraordinary woman.
And very attractive.
You should learn
to look at her differently.
I'm sure she'd love that.
She has told me a few things...
about you.
She likes you a lot, you know?
What did you do to her?
What you wanted.
Take care of her.
Shit, stop that,
you're gonna make me fuckin' cry!
Please.
Is there any way...
to stop all this?
Yes.
Of course.
One.
I'm going to miss you.
Okay, okay,
there's no need to say it, doctor.
I know what you're thinking.
The bill for 209, please.
I'm checking out.
All right.
- Dr. Fausto, right?
- Yes.
Someone is waiting in the bar, sir.
Who?
She didn't leave a name.
Julia?
Julia!
- Are you all right?
- Just fine.
And you?
You had me worried.
We waited all afternoon.
My day has been a little...
weird.
Dr. Fierro couldn't wait.
He told me to tell you.
I've brought RenoI's report.
Everything.
I got a research
committee together...
and they want you in it.
They want you there soon.
Today, if possible.
The records you wanted.
The complete originals.
How strange.
It's not signed.
I must have overlooked that.
The next train out today is at 7:15.
That's in 20 minutes.
The next one's at 9...
and the last one at 11:30.
Julia...
we work too much.
We should take the day off.
A day to relax,
and go back tomorrow. Okay?
Have you visited the city?
- No.
- Great!
You'II love it.
Pour me a whiskey, and...
The same.
Have you had fun?
Truthfully...
yes.
Want anything else?
What's wrong?
Nothing. You see...
for a moment...
before seeing you...
I wanted...
to be dead.