What's going on, Hop?
You back again.
Oh sick.
Find a good one.
Ten Tigers of Kwang Tung.
This is gold.
Oh.. Bride with White Hair.
Chinese, no subtitles?
Hop, do you have any
early Shaw Brothers?
There's a guy who does leopard
style, I don't want...
Leopard style, dragon style.
Fight to the air, fight on water.
Crouching Tiger, Sprinting Monkey.
I know you.  I'm not a white boy
who knows no kung fu.
Kick their asses.
Get the girls.
Only storage back here.
Where did you get this?
It was here when my grandfather
open the store hundred years ago.
He waited for a man
to come and pick it up.
Return to rightful owner.
Man never came.
My father took over the shop,
waited too, long time.
Now me.
That's a Northern Temple
style Bold Staff.
Same kind the 13 monks used
to save the Tang Emperor.
I have seen him before.
That exact one.
I had dreams about it.
You know why?
You watch too much Hong Kong movies.
Come, come on.
I will give you five awesome
Bruce Lee movies.
For a very 'sick' price.
You are the man, Hop.
Jason.
Hey.
What's up?
Nothing much. Just,
you know, cruising.
You went down to Chinatown.
What's up with that?
Oh, Kung Fu.
Are you serious?
Not supposed to talk about it.
Not under the Kung Fu code.
Hey look. The new kid is
making time with the hoods.
J boy, you still riding
this loser cruiser?
You need to get a motor
for this shit.
What do we have here?
Just some bootlegs. No big deal.
Enter The Dragon.
The Bride with White Hair.
Yes, it's actually very good.
Come on, let him go.
He ain't a dog. He knows Kung Fu.
What? You think you are Chinese?
You hanging out  with that Chink with a sitar.
What's up with you?
Let's see some moves.
Come on, come on. Let's see some
Kung Fu. Kung Fu master. Huh?
Want some Tae Kwan Do?
Hey Lupo. He is hanging out with
that old Chink. Cash his checks.
You have ties with the old man?
Shut up and do it.
It's late Lenny.
He's probably gone home.
He is not here.
Let's just go.
Who's there? Kung Fu boy.
You're back for more good priced movies?
I told you. Best deal in China town.
Come on in.
Want some tea?
Flush those scum out.
Yankees winning. Very bad.
Who's with you?
Friends?
Where do you keep the cash?
I said, where do you keep
the cash?
Come on old man!
Stay here.
Found the Jack's box.
Jesus, Lupo.
You shot him
Take it.
Must return to rightful owner.
Run.
You see that Yo?
Did you see that?
Beat him with that stick.
Look, cool man. Just don't...
Did you see that?
Calm down, Lupo. Hey, chill man,
come on. Put the gun down.
Shut up! Maybe I pulled the trigger,
but we are all in this together.
But this little cockroach,
he ain't one of us.
Have some tea.
It'll help you to recover.
Excuse me,
I don't know where I am.
I don't know how I got here.
I remember falling...
Old lady found you
lying in the river.
We all thought you were dead.
Let's go! Let's go!
Running away?
Help me!
Please let her go!
Quick, go and grab hold
of that guy!
Stop, stop!
Drop what you are holding!
Try to run and I'll kill you.
Come here!
What is that you are holding?
Where are you from?
This? You want this?
Drop the staff if you want your life.
Please Sirs, some money
to this poor drunkard.
Get lost!
Where did you get that staff?
I don't know what you're saying.
Where did you find it?
I can't understand you.
That is because you
are not listening.
Behind you!
I don't know where I am
Or how I got here. And who are
those guys who wanted to kill me.
Whatever you did
back there was sick.
No, Drunken Fist.
See Crook Kung Fu of the South.
I am Lu Yang, travelling scholar.
What land do you come from monk?
I'm not a monk, I am Jason.
Jason Tripitikas, from South Boston.
Is this a dream?
No, where you came from is the dream.
Through the gate of 'No-Gate'.
Is that like a worm-hole or something?
No, it means you're either a Zen Master
or you're carrying something very special.
This?  - Was in a pawn shop
waiting for a man to pick it up, and ...
return it to its rightful owner.
What?
It has long been fore-told,
that a seeker will come.
To return the staff and end
the reign of the Jade Warlord.
Return the staff to who?
The Monkey King.
Born of stone, on the mountain
of fruit and flowers.
With his weapon in hand.
His 'Chi' became like fire.
His stick fighting like magic.
He defied the order of the land.
But the Jade Army
could not defeat him.
Monkey King crushed every
soldier sent to stop him.
But with his magical staff,
he was unbeatable.
Word of his disobedience travelled
within the Forbidden Kingdom.
To the Five Elements Mountains,
land of the Immortals.
Once every 500 years, the Jade
Emperor hosts the Peach Banquet.
It is here that the Heavenly Ministers
gather to celebrate the longevity
and drink the elixir of immortality.
Into the banquet, the Monkey King
crashed un-invited.
The Jade Emperor was enchanted
by the Monkey King
But the Jade Warlord
was not amused.
As Master of the Army,
the Warlord demanded the
Monkey King bow down to him.
He's a bit unrefined, that's all.
Give the naughty monkey
a title and let him go.
Satisfied all was well
in Heaven and Earth.
The Supreme Emperor left to
begin his 500 years meditation.
Leaving the Jade Warlord in charge
by mandate of Heaven.
The Warlord challenged
the Monkey King to a duel.
High above Five Elements Mountain.
In the Warlord's Palace,
the battle of Immortals was fought.
To prove once and for all,
whose skill was supreme.
Most excellent stick fighting, Wukong.
But without your weapon you
are nothing but a lonely hermit.
No more weapons, no more 'Chi' magic.
Fist against fist.
The Monkey King was too trusting
and believed the Warlord's words.
Laying down his magic weapon.
Realizing he was been tricked, the Monkey King
casted the staff out into the Middle Kingdom.
Martial art is based
on deception, my friend.
Being immortal the
Monkey King could not be killed.
Only trapped in stone, where he
waits for the seeker from the prophecy,
to return to him his great weapon
and finally free him.
That's what I heard anyway,
a long time ago.
How long has he been in prison?
Five hundred years, give
or take a few decades.
They say when the Monkey King is
freed the Jade Emperor will return.
How do I get home?
You must return the staff
to Five Elements Mountain.
You must free the Monkey King.
I can't free the Monkey King.
I got to get home.
Innkeeper, more wine.
Don't you think you had one too many?
Wine is my inspiration.
In some parts, I'm known as a poet.
Cheers!
In other parts,
I am known as the beggar.
Old wife.
Where did this come from?
From them.
Officers, look what they're using to pay.
What is this?
What do we do now?
How good is your Kung Fu?
He who speaks, does not know.
He who knows, does not speak.
Surely you are masterful.
Where did you get that raben?
It's a fake.
You can find anything these days
on the Silk Road.
Out of the way, old fool.
Hand it over.
Hand over the raben
or die.
Go!
Help!
Protect yourself.
What?
Let's go.
Thank you.
Such a skilled child.
Are you from Northern Mountains?
She's Golden Sparrow from the south.
She does not think the Drunkard
Immortal needed his life saved.
You're immortal?
What did you run from child?
Bounty hunters trying to stop her from
reaching the Five Elements Mountain.
I suggest you keep riding west.
And only stop to water your horses.
You are not coming?
The journey to Five Elements Mountain,
crosses barrens and desserts,
unspeakable dangers.
Worst of all, no wine.
His elixir.
Every Immortal has one.
I am very sorry.
Without wine I will perish.
You must understand this.
No.
This is insane!
Do you wish to get home?
Yes.
Then listen well.
If you die here,
you were be found dead
in the world you left behind.
Do you understand?
My jug is getting low.
I must say goodbye. Bye-bye.
Lu... Wait!
Let him go. You are the one
to return staff, not him.
How good is your Kung Fu?
He's got no Kung Fu.
None!
Lu, wait!
Teach me.
Teach me to fight.
Swing soft, cut harder,
at the same time.
He's terrible.
I've been weed whacking
for two days now.
While you sit on the horse
like the King of England.
When are you going
to teach me Kung Fu.
You want to learn Kung Fu?
Ya.
I'll teach you Kung Fu.
That's call strike.
Tomorrow, teach you block.
Let's go.
Swing soft, cut hard.
You think you'll teach me
the no shadow kick?
Oh, and the Buddha Palm Technique.
There's a guy in Virtua Fighter 2
who does the Buddha Palm Technique.
And he does the Iron Elbow.
And he does the
One Finger Death Touch.
The cup's full. Stop!
Stop, it's full.
Exactly. How can you fill
your cup, if already full?
How can you learn Kung Fu,
if already know so much?
Know Shadow Kick, Buddha Palm.
Empty your cup.
Hopeless.
It is hopeless.
It is said that music is a bridge
between earth and heaven.
It's beautiful.
It belong to our mother.
My Lord
How dare you...
can't you see I am busy?
The devine staff of legend...
It was seen in the Middle Kingdom...
Impossible.
The villagers are beginning to
whisper of prophecy...
Mortals are always whispering of prophecy.
It's their opium.
What other offending news
do you have for me?
That is all, My Lord.
Summon the Witch...
The one born of wolves.
Where were we?
Lu Yang.
Lu Yang!
Sparrow!
Jason, what happened?
He took it. The staff!
The Jade Warlord has sent
a bounty hunter.
We are doomed.
That's his horse.
He must be inside.
Why would he want to take
refuge in a temple?
That's what I intend to find out.
Wait with the horses.
Ahh...good to get off my feet.
Long way.
So, where are you from?
Shandong province?
You look like the Shandong province type.
You come here often.
The Staff doesn't belong to you.
You have to give to me
or somebody will get hurt.
What kind of monk are you?
Stealing from travellers.
A silent one I see.
Or deaf.
I'm speaking to you monk.
Praying Mantis very good.
For catching bugs.
But not Tiger!
You try to steal the Staff for the Warlord.
No, fool!
I am on a mission to find
the seeker of the Staff.
You found him.
He's not even Chinese.
We are all the same inside,
Aren't we Monk?
Heaven help us.
What, you find it a sin?
Yes, it is sinful not to share.
Cheers!
How look have you been
searching for the Staff?
As long as I can remember.
An old man and a boy,
They had tea here, Yes?
A Soldier Monk rides with them
Who else?
I do not know
who you speak of...
Men are such liars.
Sparrow...
...where do you nest?
Jason, go dipper.
Must taste bitter before sweet.
Horse stance, grow roots.
Very good.
For taking a duck.
Hey!
Enough from you.
He's my student. Not yours.
Two tigers cannot live
in the same mountain.
Two masters cannot teach
the same student.
Horse Stance!
If he is ready to learn
the Kung Fu,
he must develop the speed,
accuracy and power.
Hey! I know that. It's the way
of the Intercepting Fist. Bruce Lee.
I will punch. You'll block.
Ready?
Ahh! What did I teach you
about the Snake?
Now. You punch me.
Look. See.
Again. You punch him again.
Snake!
It's not right for Snake.
Perhaps Eagle.
Crane, Crane.
Okay?
I had enough! No more!
No more of silent riddles
and no more of tea cups.
First you show respect
to your teachers.
So, what about the two tigers
and one mountain?
We can kill each other
when it is over.
Kung Fu. Hard work over time
to accomplish skill.
A painter can have Kung Fu.
Or the butcher who cuts meat
every day with such skill.
His knife never touches bone.
Learn the form,
but seek from this.
Hear the song list,
learn it all,
And forget it all
Learn the way,
define your own way.
A musician can have Kung Fu.
Or the poet who paints
pictures with words.
And mix emperors with his tubes
is Kung Fu.
But do not name it my friend,
For it is like water.
Nothing is softer than water.
Yet it can overcome rock.
It does not fight.
Formless, nameless,
the true master dwells within.
Only you can free it.
Behold, the tyranny of the Warlord.
He must be stopped.
He must be killed for his crimes
and his head put on a post.
But we must not feel hatred
towards him or he wins.
If he speaks compassion for this devil,
he should go back to his temple and pray.
Our mission is not one of peace.
Go back to your mother and father.
You are but a child.
They are dead.
And she is not a child.
Not anymore.
Her father was a government official
who opposed the Warlord.
To set an example, the Warlord
dispatched his troop into night.
Legion upon legion poured out
of the Five Elements Mountain.
Into the low lands
of the Middle Kingdom.
Screams of innocent people
hung in the night air.
When it was over, charred roofs
were all that remained.
That, and a lonely child
hidden in a well by her mother.
Ruthlessly murdered by an arrow,
from the Warlord's bow.
When she reaches the Warlord's palace,
she will not offer him forgiveness.
Monk, she will offer him this.
A jade dart that can kill any mortal.
Long has she practiced.
Vengeance has a way
of rebounding upon themselves.
Master of Sensitivity.
It is them.
They're headed towards the desert.
They are between me and the River of Sand.
Isn't it just like King Monkey...
...summoning a boy to do a man's job?
This is not a dessert.
That is the dessert.
I hope you know where
you are going, crazy monk.
A monk of the mission.
And where does he lead us.
Across the dessert to nowhere.
We are not going to make it
are we?
And even if we do,
we'll still have to face the Jade army.
What if I can't handle it?
What if I freeze?
Don't forget to breath.
If we don't find water soon,
we will perish.
Perhaps a Taoist immortal
can make rain.
If he truly is a Taoist immortal.
You are an insult to the name
of Buddha. Blasphemy.
Look!
I lead you to the Mountain.
Over there!
Can you see them?
In the clouds.
A two headed lion, right there.
See.
Yes, I see it.
See that one right there coming up
behind it like a wave.
Looks like a green monster.
Green monster?
You mean dragon.
No, I mean family park.
They call the left field fence,
the green monster.
It's true.
It does look like a dragon
doesn't it?
Have you any family, back
in this land you come from?
My mother.
Father?
Never knew him.
Do you ever long for him?
Wonder who he was?
Maybe the only thing I've ever been
good at is pretending that I don't.
She's sorry.
How romantic.
Men will tell you what
they want to here, Sparrow.
But in the end they
will leave you with nothing.
You survived the river of sand.
Impressive.
And you boy, so far from home.
I can ensure your safe return.
Just bring the weapon forward.
I don't think so.
Why do you want the staff?
When I deliver the lost weapon,
the Jade Warlord shall grant
me the elixir of immortality.
An orphan girl, a lost traveller,
an old drunkard,
and a monk who has failed
at the same task for half his life.
Misfits following a misfit
in hope of rescuing a misfit.
Kill them.
Lu, you okay?
Just thirsty.
Lu!
That's okay. He's immortal, right?
I mean he is, right?
Wine. He needs his wine.
There is nothing we can do.
What are you saying?
We have to do something.
I'm afraid the wound is too deep.
He will not survive it.
He needs his wine.
He is one of the eight immortals.
Wine is his elixir.
Please.
We will send our walking monk.
Don't have a running monk?
When I was your age.
I was a scholar warrior in training.
My arrow was good,
so too my Kung Fu.
So I was chosen to take
the several examinations.
To pass would place me in a very
short line of scholar immortals.
I failed.
You're not immortal?
If one does not attach himself
to people and desire,
never shall his heart be broken.
But then,
does he ever truly live?
I would rather die a mortal
who has a care for someone.
Than a man free
from his own death.
I don't want to lose you.
Forget about me.
There is only one Elixir
of Immortality.
It is the Emperor's mead of jade,
cinnabar and salts of mercury.
It is forever stored in the realm
of the jade palace.
High in the jade ferment.
Rarely touched by mortals.
To reach it, one must take North Road
and cross the border of heaven and earth.
Only to face the Jade Army.
I'm sorry. There is no other way.
Yes, there is.
In two nights there should be no moon.
We can take the south side of the fortress.
Under cover of darkness.
We have to go now.
No!
We go now, we all die.
There is more at stake.
An entire kingdom.
You are our best hope.
We will advance in two nights.
When the moon has ceased.
So be it!
I should've met you long
ago in a tea house.
She was lost and frightened.
Not the kind she would stand and fight with.
You have made the most
excellent judgment.
The seeker from the prophecy,
not quite what I'd expected.
A man is dying back on Song Mountain.
I need the Elixir.
Why should I give it to you?
Because I brought you the Staff.
The life of your friend over the
power to rule over the Kingdom?
A most reasonable offer.
This man, a good friend?
And a good teacher.
The man who honours his teacher,
honours himself.
However, there is a little bit
problem with your request.
You see, I promised the Elixir
to someone else.
She didn't bring you the Staff.
I did.
The boy has a point.
My Leech, you made a promised.
There is but one way
to resolve such matters.
A martial challenge to the death.
With pleasure.
The Elixir of Immortality
The prize goes to the winner.
Enough!
The seeker from the prophecy.
I find that quite amusing.
Do you really think even for
a minute, you stood a chance?
I didn't think so.
She will kill you witch.
Not if I kill you first, orphan bitch.
Cheers!
Remember what I taught you.
The Statue!
Use the Staff.
My turn.
My Lord.
Who are you?
The youngest daughter
of the family you murdered.
Come drink with me.
No
Sparrow, Sparrow
Come on, come on.
You're going to be okay.
Jade Warlord?
He's dead.
I...
I thank you.
Is there anything you can do?
Her Destiny was written
by her own hand.
I am sorry.
Traveller.
You have come far through the gate of
No-Gate to fulfill the prophecy of the mortals.
What do you desire, please?
I just want to go home.
Very well.
It is said, master and student,
walk their path side by side
to share their destiny
until the paths go separate ways.
I will never forget you.
I suggest that is what immortal truly means.
You have freed me traveller.
Now, go free yourself.
So, what is it going to be?
You're going to shut up?
Listen, piss end,
I'm not going to ask you again.
Come on Maggie, get up, come on.
You want some more?
Come on.
You don't have to do this.
Take it easy, Sir.
You are going to be fine.
Hop.
How is he doing?
Missed his heart.
He will live.
Of course, I'll live.
I am immortal.
Did you return the Staff
to rightful owner?
Yes, I did.
You are the man.
Is he going to be alright?
Looks like it.
I saw what happened.
I walked across the street.
You were very brave.
See you.
Ya.
Absolutely.
As the legend just told,
that the Monkey King began
his journey west, in search of truth.
While the traveller
return to his world,
to walk the path of the warrior
and find his own truth.
As one tale ends,
so another begins.