- The Cave of the Yellow Dog (2005)
- IMDB #0432325
- English audio dubbed version.
- fps = 25.00 or 30.00
- Length = 1:30:23
- First line = 1:57,684 Last line = 1:27:08,289
- Created by DonToribio (Subscence.Com moniker)
- Posted FIRST to Subscene November 23, 2012
- Credit to Subscener MovieManiac for timings and
- A base to get me off to a good start!
Dad, what are you doing
with his tail?
I'm putting it under his head...
so he'll be reborn as a person
with a ponytail,
and not as a dog with a tail.
Oh, really?
Everyone eventually dies,
but no one is ever really dead.
Let's go.
THE CAVE OF THE YELLOW DOG
Now the ladle's broken, too.
Chuluna, come here.
Look at this.
Hurry up!
There you go, you're home.
Hello, Mom!
Look at you my daughter.
You got so big.
Hey, Dad!
My big girl!
Did you have a good trip?
- Yes.
- How did you get here?
- Dad! I had a driver.
- Ah!
- Did you miss us?
- Yes! A lot!
- Did you learn a lot?
- Yes.
Your uniform looks
so good on you.
Yes, it really does.
Yes, but the collar is really tight.
It's supposed to be like that.
Hold on, I've got your deel.
Hey, Dad?
- Yes, Little One?
- What were you doing outside?
Oh, I was watching the sheep.
That big wolf come back?
It did.
Did you learn a lot of new songs?
Yes.
Teach 'em to your sister, all right?
Here, let me help you with this.
Hey, Dad! Do you want to have a look
at the books I used at school?
Yes! I do!
You've really gotten big.
Show me the books.
- Let's see.
- Okay
There ya go. Look.
Is this your math book?
Your writing is so good.
Look, I got a star on this page here.
You did? Let me see.
That's great.
And another star!
Mom, can I have some dung?
Of course, take some.
Sister, come here, let's play with this!
We'll can build the houses on top of each other,
like I saw in the city when I was going to school.
Okay.
If we were there in the city,
we would live way up at the top.
Because it's much too dark down by the street.
Like this. Pile them on. Okay.
One on top!
Nansal!
Yes!
Can you help me, I need you to
collect some dung to cure the meat?
But Mom, I've never done that!
I don't know what I'm looking for.
Just give it a try, okay?
Come on, Little One,
get up!
- Nansal!
- Yes.
Don't get too far away, please.
- Okay.
- Those two vultures are still circling.
- Yeah.
- Hello, my friends!
- Hey, how are you?
Hi, hello to you.
- How's the grazing?
- Very good.
Been a good summer for you?
- Yes, and you?
- It's been good.
- So, how's the hunting going for you?
- Okay.
- Not bad.
- Yeah.
- Where have you been?
- We were at Baruun Go!
Thanks.
We had to go there to hunt wolves again.
There were a lot of them
there this time, yeah.
So, tell me my friend, is it peaceful by you?
I'm afraid it's not very good.
There's a lot of wolves right now.
More and more every year, it seems to me.
I agree.
Oops! Almost fell down.
Hey! Who's in there?
Seems like everyone is selling-off their herds.
- Yes, I know.
- And moving on.
You know, I really hate to admit it,
but I think that times are changing.
- It's true, I have to agree with you, you're right.
- Only stray dogs are here.
The worst part is those dogs are mixing-in
with the wolves, becoming part of the pack.
I know, just last night they
got two more of my sheep.
Ah, that's bad.
- It's been happening everywhere lately.
- You're right.
Something needs to be done about it
soon or it will really get out of hand.
- Right.
- I agree with you.
When I was much younger, we all
used to fight the wolves together.
But now, unfortunately, fewer
and fewer people live around here,
so it's becoming a much
bigger problem to deal with.
- Difficult.
- That's true.
I have to go check on my sheep.
- Right.
- You get to town much?
Oh, no, no, not really, but tomorrow
I'm heading into town to sell some skins.
Say, I ordered some ammunition
with Badam.
Could you pick it up for me
if you get the chance?
Sure.
- I'd appreciate that.
- No problem at all.
I'm gonna take you home.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Here ya go!
You're so soft, you feel really good.
Wait! Wait! Wait up!
Here, Boy! Come on! Let's go!
Hey! Come back here now! Back!
Get back! Get Back! Get back! Come on!
There ya go!
Gotcha!
Where's your mother, huh?
Do you know where?
Where is she, huh?
Nansal, what have you got there?
Where did you get that dog?
I found him out there.
I want to play with him.
Listen, you were supposed to collecting dung,
young lady, but instead it seems you were playing.
What if that dog's owner wants him back now?
I won't give him back!
Is that right? Well, he is a little cutie.
I wonder if he got lost and
wandered away or something.
Come on, Spotty.
Well, maybe someone left him behind
when it was time for them to move on.
He looks a little hungry.
Give me your belt.
I'm gonna give it to  him.
Here.
I gonna name him Spot,
because he has spots, see?
Hey, Nansal!
- Get rid of this dog, please.
- Uh-uh!
What do you mean, "No"?
Take him back, like I asked you to.
No.
He was probably living with wolves.
There were no wolves
where I found him.
- Oh, really?
- Uh-huh.
Only wolves live in caves.
But I found him.
Now he belongs to me.
Why weren't you stricter with her?
If you'd said no then it'd be easier now.
It could be destiny,
and maybe that's why
he came to us right now.
Get away from that!
Get away! Go!
When you get back tomorrow,
we'll start getting ready for the move, all right?
All right.
Do you need anything from town?
Flour or rice?
I think that can wait until we've moved on,
but I do need a new ladle.
All right.
Make sure the dog goes away.
- Bye! Take care of yourselves!
-  Be careful!
That really hurt.
Nansal, help with the cheese?
I'll lift it up then you pull it out.
Come on.
A little more.
Good job. Okay.
Bring me the wooden board, please.
Be careful, don't fall.
Just put it here. Yeah.
Now, gently pull it up.
Now, stand it up like this.
Yes, just like that.
- Do you cut it in half first?
- Not yet.
- This turned out pretty well.
- That's good.
Know what, I hid Spot in the herd so Dad
wouldn't find him before he went away.
I'm afraid that's just not good enough.
You're going to have to take
him back before Father gets home.
How come you don't want me to keep him?
Why are you being so mean?
He's so cute. I want him.
It's not about wanting him to stay here.
- That should be good enough for now. Let go.
- Okay
Stretch your hand, just like this.
Now try to bite the palm of
your hand. Right there.
I can't do it.
You can't? Are you really
sure you can't. Try it again.
And now? You still can't?
It doesn't work.
Although it seems like it's close,
it's still too far away to bite.
The truth is, you can't have everything.
I can't do it!
- Nansal!
- Yes.
Remember not to leave any of
the young animals behind.
Always keep that mountain in your sight.
And please try not to
get lost this time, okay?
- Yeah.
- You hear me?
- Huh?
- Dad already taught all this stuff to me, Mom.
The tip of the mountain
is my landmark.
Oh! Well, you are a smart girl, aren't you?
Off you go, ride carefully.
Spot, come on! Spot! Here! Here now,
over here! Here! Come on!
- Mom?
- Huh?
Why didn't you wake me up before?
Well, why did you want
to get up so early?
- Because I...
- Uh-huh?
I...I wanted to go to town with Dad.
All right. Why did you want to do that?
So I could look at all the houses.
Oh! Is that so?
And why do you want to do that?
People can go pee in their houses in the city.
Is that right? So, people in the city
can pee inside their houses?
Nansal said so.
Oh, I see.
Can you bite my palm?
Go ahead, give it a try.
Spot, try it.
Go on! Just give it a try, okay?
Go on! You have to do it just once.
You can't do it either, Spot, can you now, Boy?
Spot! Spot!
Now Spot, do you want to go back to your cave
or do you want to stay here with us? Huh?
Huh! Do you?
Does that taste good?
Huh, boy?
- Uh, Mom...
- Ah-huh.
Can I wear the deel
that you're sewing now?
It's going to be too big for you.
It's for your sister.
- She's got to go back to school soon.
- Oh, yeah.
Will she be gone a long time?
Yes, she'll be gone a very long time.
Again.
Then I'll miss her.
So will I.
Your brother's crying, go see what it is, please.
Be quiet, will you!
Where did he get to?
Here, Spot!
Where are you now?
Spot! Spot!
Stay here.
Hey, Spot!
Hey!
Just a minute, Little One.
Here, let me feed you.
Come on.
No, let me do it.
Come on, eat your food.
Eat up, that's good. You're eating.
Good girl. Good job.
The herd came back on its own.
I have to find your sister.
'Kay.
- Can you watch your brother?
- 'Kay.
Do you want more?
There.
Are you finished?
Spot!
Yeah! There you are! Hi, Spot!
What are you doing in here?
I was so afraid that you left me
and went back to your cave.
Hey! You think you can just sleep anywhere? Huh?
Hey, Spot! We have to go home.
Wake up, Lazy!
Stop it! Stop banging on it.
We aren't allowed to play with this one.
You don't play with God.
I'm gonna tell Mom!
I told you not to.
It'll dry nicely here.
Go on. Take a big sip.
Spot.
You're lucky he didn't end up
in the Cave of the Yellow Dog.
What's Cave of the Yellow Dog mean?
I'll tell you the story.
Many, many years ago, a clan of great
wealth lived nearby on these very lands.
And they had a truly beautiful daughter.
One day,
the daughter became very ill.
There was no medicine that could cure her.
So, the father decided
to seek the advice of a very wise man.
The wise, old man spoke. He said, "Your yellow
dog is angry. You must get rid of it."
Confused, the father replied, "But why?
He always protects our herd and my family very well."
And the wise man answered, "That's what I have to
say and what you wanted to know."
The father didn't want to kill the yellow dog...
but he had to do something.
So he hid it in a cave where it was
impossible for the dog to get away.
He carried in food daily.
But one day, the dog wasn't there.
The cave had nothing in it. No one knows
where the yellow dog went.
Eventually the daughter was healthy.
And the reason was...
that the daughter had fallen
in love with a young man.
So, now, with the yellow dog gone...
the couple could meet
without being disturbed.
So, Young One, the point of this story is
that quite often what seems to be going on...
may not really be everything that is happening.
I think the rain is over now.
My daughter took over for her father
today, and look what happened.
- Oh, it's fine.
- Thanks for watching her.
Goodbye. Travel safely.
Spot! Let's go.
Take care of yourself.
Have a good trip home.
My two Little Ones.
Come on, let's put them to bed.
You should get ready for bed, too.
Quietly, please.
Oh, what is it this time?
- Hey, mom?
- Yes.
Do you remember your previous lives?
No. No, not really.
Why not?
Only little children can do that.
That's why they tell colorful stories.
Some say they're talking
about previous lives.
Can I talk about those things?
Of course.
You talked a lot.
What kind of stories did I tell?
Keep it down. Shh! Time to sleep. Lie down now.
Good girl.
There.
Grandma...
The yellow dog story, what happened?
The young couple got married,
and then they had a child.
Perhaps the dog was reborn
with a ponytail.
Really?
Will I come back as a person
in my next life?
Come here.
Let me show you something.
Let me know when you balance a grain
of rice on the tip of this needle.
But I don't think that's possible!
See, my child? That's how hard
it is to be born again as a person.
That's why
a human life is so valuable.
There! I see a boy on a big camel.
Another one. And look, there's
a boy riding on a big horse.
- Where is that?
- Hey! Over there!
- Look! Look there!
- I see...I see one...
I see lots of animals all around.
Oh! I found an elephant!
I see him.
What else? What else do you see?
Look! I see a giraffe.
Oh, really! Where?
Look  at that one, it's round.
That one is all squared out.
Which one?
This one here, see?
Don't get too close.
- Hey! - Hey!
Get out of the smoke.
Here we go.
It'll be okay! I tell you what,
Little One, I'll sing to you,
and you can dance, all
right? Won't that be fun?
Mom, I gotta tell you this!
How can I help you, Little One?
Mamma, Nansalmaa's lying.
She's lying?
What did she say?
We were looking at clouds and
she said she saw a giraffe.
Just let her be,
and don't laugh at her, please.
I guess I could.
I think she's telling another life,
just like you said she would.
Is it a really good story?
Then maybe it's true!
Can you imagine that?
There you go, Precious.
Okay.
Now we dance.
Spot!
Spot?
Hey, Spot!
Hey, Spot! Come on!
Come here! Hey, come here!
- I'm home.
- I'm glad you're back.
Spot.
Did you get everything done?
Are you tired?
The trip wasn't too bad.
I sold the sheepskins.
That'll help.
- Were you able to see Uncle Dorj?
- Ah...yes.
I'm glad you could.
- Did you two discuss Nansal?
- I did.
She can live there while she's at school.
We need to make sure it's all right with her.
Maybe I could get a job at
one of the stores in town.
Yes, well, I'm really not sure that would
be enough money for us to live on.
- Where are the kids now?
- They're outside playing.
Just a minute. Here ya go, just as you asked.
- Oh, thank you, it's nice.
Are you sure it's heat resistant enough
to cook? I really like the color though.
- Hopefully it'll do the job.
- It's light.
Here, I got this for us, too.
What is this? Oh, a flashlight.
That's what I thought.
I thought we could use it.
I figured it'd come in handy.
Yes, that's fine.
Did you find out about the election results?
I heard they're all gonna have
to be repeated sometime soon.
Really? I wondered what
could have happened.
I never found out. How's everything
here, okay? Yes, you didn't miss anything.
How ya doin', Spot.
Sit still, try and help me, don't make any noise.
Hey, hey! Come here, You!
I missed you!
Did you miss your father, just a little?
Come here. And did you look
after your brother and sister?
- Yeah!
- Yes!
- Um, look!
- Here, brought you something from town.
And one for you. There ya go.
And something for you. Here.
Ooh, I almost forgot. I got you something else.
Now, make sure you share this with each other.
Let me show you how to use it.
Just like this.
Wonderful!
That's great. Now don't forget to share it.
Look, look, look!
It's cute! I want to see that!
- Wait a...
- Remember, don't break it!
Don't reach out for it!
He'll come by himself!
- Treat it gently!
- Oh, he likes that.
That's great!
Get out of here!
Nansal! Listen!
Didn't I tell you to get rid of this dog?
- Did you pack the ammunition?
- Yes, I did. Thank you.
This is the dog
I told you about.
He looks healthy.
He'll definitely make a good hunting dog.
- He's got the right color.
- He does, doesn't he?
Is your dog getting too old?
Yes, he is. He won't be able
to help for much longer.
Where did you get him?
My daughter found him.
Is he a hunting breed?
- Could be.
- Is that so?
When I found him he was sleeping in a cave.
In a cave?
Didn't I already tell you,
we're not keeping the dog.
We're moving tomorrow and
he's not coming with us.
You better keep an eye on your sheep,
living in a cave, that's where wolves are.
Here's your deel.
Wasn't the last wolf attack
bad enough?
What does that have to do
with us keeping the dog?
I'm worried.
If he had been living with wolves,
they could follow his
trail and decimate our herd.
We have no idea where he comes from.
Mom! Come quick!
What is it?
Mom! Mom! Come here!
Stand back! Get some water! Quickly!
Be careful! Careful! Don't get burned!
What bad luck.
Bad luck.
Ah! That's such a shame.
Can I see it?
Oh, your father's present is ruined.
Mom, can I play with the flashlight?
- All right, but be careful with it.
- 'Kay.
Nansal!
Nansal, look at me!
Nansal, look now!
Get up.
Come on, let's play!
Hey, Nansal! We need your help over here.
You're doing such a good job!
Look at our Little One!
Ooh, careful you don't
fall! Come on now.
Get him down.
Here we go! Here! Here!
Let go! Ooops!
- Here, let me do it!
- No, it's all right.
Nansal! Come and clean this up!
What would we do without
our Great Little Shepherd?
Come on, Little One! Come on! Come on!
Nansal, come watch your brother!
Got him?
Now watch!
- Thank you for the summer here.
- Yes, thank you.
Nansal, get back up there on the cart!
I was just picking up
Batbayar's belt, Mom!
Chuluna, stop the cart!
Batbayar gone, he's not in the basket!
Nansal, where's your brother?
Have you seen him?
- I can't find him.
- He was in here!
I don't see him.
Where's my son?
Stay with the kids,
I'll ride back.
Mom, what's wrong?
My son! Hey!
Let's look at you.
Where's Spot?
Here! Here!
- Come here, You!
- He'll be okay, again.
Okay, sit in here.
Oh, look how comfortable it is.
You'll like it in there.
- Keep an eye on him!
- Hold onto him tight, now!
You have to hold him
if he tries to climb out.
Oh, this isn't going to work.
I better tie you down.
Get in there.
Help me, please!
Hold on to him!
Ready? I'll take your horse with me, okay?
Nansal, hold on tight there!
- Hooooooo!
- Hup hup hup  hup  hup,  hup  hup  hup hup!
We remind you to vote in the upcoming elections.
There will be town hall meetings on the 21st.
Please stop by to meet the Democratic candidates.
And remember to vote!
We hope you'll make
the right decision.
We remind you to vote in the upcoming elections.
There will be town hall meetings on the 21st.
Please stop by to meet the Democratic candidates.
And remember to vote!
We hope you'll make
the right decision.
We remind you to vote in the upcoming elections.
There will be town hall meetings on the 21st.
Please stop by to meet the Democratic candidates.
SPECIAL THANKS
TO THE BATCHULUUN FAMILY
NANSAL  AND  ZOCHOR  (WHICH MEANS COLORFUL)
You're always asleep
when I want to play.
Maybe...
you were a real lazybones
in a previous life.