They were wearing a school uniform.
Their heights were...
almost 180cm.
It was Gachon High School's uniform.
(Two men, almost 180cm,
Gachon High School's uniform)
Anything else?
Well,
we saw them running away from afar.
We don't quite remember.
He was wearing a blue hat...
and his shoes were white.
Oh, and he had a huge
burn scar on his back.
You have a good memory.
If you remember the shape of the scar,
can you draw it right here?
Is there anything missing?
Well, my goodness.
That's the weird part.
They stole all of my daughter's paintings.
Gosh, they are bad guys.
Excuse me.
I've been wondering for a while.
Aren't you Mr. Han Gyeong Soo?
Yes, I am.
- I'm a huge fan of yours.
- Goodness.
I even have a piece of your painting.
My gosh, thank you.
Goodness.
Those burglars sneaked
back into the house...
and committed that heinous crime.
You said before...
that the perp is probably
proud of his crimes.
Wouldn't someone like that...
hold onto the murder weapon?
I'm sorry. It was an accident.
I'll reimburse you.
Are you leaving?
Something just came up.
What about your clothes?
That's right.
I'll get them for you.
Okay.
Seong Jin.
Thank you.
Here's your modeling fee.
But...
you didn't finish yet.
I won't be painting anymore.
Take it.
Okay.
The painting was an excuse.
I lied, too.
I saw...
that scar 10 years ago.
Actually,
I posted the fake ad looking
for a model with a scar...
in order to meet you.
To meet Seong...
I mean,
to meet me?
Why?
Don't you remember me?
We're pretty lucky, don't you think?
Don't you know who I am?
Do you mean...
you saw my scar 10 years ago?
Sorry?
That's why you looked for me?
So that's...
Oh, my. When did you get back?
Where did you go?
What? I went to the department store.
Without your purse?
What?
Well...
It was more to take a walk and look around.
But what were you doing
just standing there?
Okay, then.
I'll see you again next time.
I have a lot of time now. I'm off duty...
Off duty?
My part-time job has three shifts.
I'd like to see you quietly next time.
I need time to organize my thoughts, too.
Me, too.
Then...
I'll go...
for now.
Go. I'll walk you out.
I guess the modeling gig is over already.
Pretty much.
You must be relieved.
You don't need to see
that bossy brat anymore.
Aren't you tired of dating secretly?
Why don't you just come clean?
Jin Ah is too closed-minded.
She wouldn't understand.
But...
I have a question.
- Hello.
Where did you go at this hour?
You said you wanted sandwiches.
That's right.
Leave them on the table.
What was your question?
Well,
there's a woman...
who is looking for someone after 10 years.
What do you think she's thinking?
Earlier,
it wasn't something that anyone could do.
You seem like a good person.
And...
thank you for today.
Jin Ah.
What is it?
I have a strange feeling about this.
Look. Look.
Oh my gosh. She's giving
you the green light.
Good luck.
Are you sure about that?
Why did she ignore me all this time, then?
That woman couldn't forget you...
and found you after 10 years.
But you didn't remember her,
so she was hurt.
What do you think about her?
What do you think?
Well...
I...
I don't know about anything else,
but I'm curious about her.
What? What?
Those two...
were talking about dating secretly.
But something else bothers me.
Look at this.
Your aunt was holding
this for a long time...
in front of the safe while you were out.
What's so complicated?
She could not have come
up with this herself.
Maybe the two of them
are planning something.
- It's finally over.
What's over for you?
What? Well...
You. I meant you.
You got paid. Lucky you.
What's wrong?
You made 10,000 dollars in 4 days.
I'm going to have to tell
her the truth tomorrow.
About what?
About lying about my identity.
I don't like it.
Hey, you already finished.
Why are you doing this?
What if she reports you?
Well...
she doesn't even know my real name yet.
Do you like her?
Is it obvious?
You took the job to make money.
You got paid so it's over.
You wished me luck.
I meant to have fun while you were working.
I didn't mean stick
around after you finish.
Some guys always waste their time...
at the very end and ruin everything.
Like you.
Why are you so pessimistic?
It may work out.
Did you forget you're lying
to her to make money?
You're making me sound
like a really bad guy.
Just give me the keys.
I gave them to you earlier.
What? That's right.
Darn it.
Why is there so much in here?
Pick them up.
That useless punk.
His friend says he met a
woman he's interested in,
but rather than helping,
he makes me pick up coins.
- What is it?
- A thief.
What?
Stop right there.
Hey.
Nothing's missing. Come back.
Okay.
Was there really a break-in?
But none of the boxes were opened.
Who cares if you get robbed?
What do you have to lose here?
All we need is this.
What about Jin Ah? Did
she suspect anything?
No. She had no clue.
What happened? Did you lose him?
I didn't lose him.
He disappeared.
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
- I'm leaving.
- Hey. Hey.
Stay the night.
It's okay.
I have things to do, too. See you later.
Bye.
Let me drive him to the bus terminal.
- Hurry back.
- Okay.
Back then, at least she was cute.
Did you forget something?
Jin Ah.
Jin Ah, how did you...
The reason I'm here is...
Let me explain.
You must be curious.
Do you want to sit?
Jin Ah, the thing is...
Let's sit down and talk.
Hi, Jin Ah.
Mister.
You were right.
Is something wrong?
It's like you said.
Oh Seong Jin...
stole my paintings.
I'll leave everything to you.
Okay, Jin Ah.
Step away and watch.
I will deal with everything.
You can wait here.
Who... Who...
Whom did you just call?
You heard correctly.
Did you call the police?
A criminal must pay for his crime.
Here we are.
- See you.
- Bye.
Hey, you forgot your backpack.
Remember what I said.
You can never tell what a person is like.
Things can get really twisted.
Stay out of my love life.
Does she even like you?
Go home.
I've had enough of him.
(Don't come here, Seong Jin.)
Whom are you texting?
Let go.
No. It's too late.
Mr. Oh Seong Jin?
How could you fall for someone like him?
He made a woman con someone else.
Do you think he won't con you?
Get a grip.
What do you know?
What do you know about Seong Jin?
He's a good man.
He's the nicest man in the
world, at least to me.
That's what he does.
He nabs a foolish woman...
and bleeds her dry.
All he thinks about is how
to use you and get out.
You're just clueless.
You opened up...
and relied on him.
And even thought...
maybe he's the one you've been looking for.
You had hopes...
and got excited.
What a fool.
- You jerk.
- Hang on.
Oh Seong Jin.
You're under arrest for
trespassing and burglary.
- Wait, wait.
- Be still.
Hello.
We got him.
We're outside.
Okay.
I'll come down.
What if you hurt him? Don't be so rough.
Get out of the way...
before we arrest you for
obstruction of justice.
Exactly. Arrest me instead.
How many times must I tell you?
I'm the thief.
Let him go.
- Take me instead.
- I'll get a warrant...
and search his place tomorrow.
Will you be quiet, Woman?
Did you just call me, "Woman"?
You aren't a man.
What's the punishment for assault?
- This is unbelievable.
- What?
I'm not that old.
People think I'm 10 years
younger than I really am.
Oh Seong Jin.
Who are you?
To Gachon, please.
It just left. The next bus is in two hours.
Okay. That'll do.
Watch your head.
That's not Oh Seong Jin.
What did you just say?
He's not the man...
I've been meeting.
That's Oh Seong Jin. I'm positive.
Look at this.
See?
I never met him until today.
What happened to your hand?
You're hurt.
I fell while rushing out after you called.
Jin Ah.
Find your Oh Seong Jin and
figure out what happened.
Did you forget you're lying
to her to make money?
You're making me sound
like a really bad guy.
Just give me the keys.
Excuse me.
You dropped this.
Thank you.
I'm the one who left with the paintings.
He knew nothing. He just
watched the bag for me.
Right.
Song Ja, you went a little too far.
If you two had issues, you
should've talked it out.
Why did you hide her paintings?
That's childish.
I know, right?
Do you want to sue her?
I'm really sorry.
I pranked you out of anger.
You nagged me about spending too much.
Detective, this is a family issue.
We don't need your help with anything.
Jin Ah, let's talk about this at home.
We have...
Shouldn't we hear Cheol
Soo's side of the story?
You can release them for now.
It's true.
Cheol Soo didn't want to
tell he was a civil servant,
so he borrowed Seong Jin's name.
Seong Jin and Cheol Soo
are really close friends.
So close I'm jealous.
Try to understand in
return for slapping me.
You didn't suffer any losses.
How long have you known Cheol Soo?
We grew up together.
Then you must've jumped the
villa's wall together.
What?
Jin Ah.
Kang Cheol Soo.
He's a fireman with Gachon Fire and Safety.
Where is he now?
At the bus terminal.
Jeong Nam. This Cheol Soo guy...
He seems even less like a murderer now.
We should consider someone
dressed up like him.
Does he have...
the scar you saw as a child?
Does he?
He does.
You just have to do that. Tell the truth.
- But...
- I told you to stay away from your aunt.
Was I wrong?
You should go home. It's late.
What will you do now?
A civil servant committed
theft under a false identity.
We need to catch him and investigate.
What?
I saw something else, too.
What was it?
I'm writing for the first
time from my phone.
Actually, I lied, too.
My name is not Oh Seong Jin.
My real name...
is Kang Cheol Soo.
No, no, no.
Are you looking for something?
Well... Yes.
I need to apologize to a woman.
Your girlfriend?
- No.
- Then a fling?
- It's not like that.
- Is she pretty?
Yes.
There's a popular item that men...
give to their girlfriends.
Would you like to see it?
She isn't my girlfriend.
Let me see what's popular.
Okay.
Here.
Is this perfume?
It's similar.
May I smell it?
Wait. If you want to smell it,
you should call an ambulance first.
Pardon?
Why weren't you picking up?
I was busy. What is it?
- Look around.
- What?
A man in his late 40s, almost 180cm tall,
black jacket, pants, and shoes.
Do you see him?
Who is he?
Run. If he catches you, you're dead.
What do you mean? Why?
I'll tell you later. Just run!
This is crazy.
Who is he? Why is he following me?
What did you do now?
I'll explain in person.
Hide somewhere safe and then call me back.
Where are you?
What's going on?
Did you use my name with a loan shark?
He's a cop.
What?
Why is a cop after me?
I'll explain later. Where are you?
I'm in the bathroom...
Kang Cheol Soo.
Yes? Pardon?
Open up. This is the police.
Are you really a cop?
(Gwon Jeong Nam)
Hey. He really is a cop.
I told you that already!
He knows what you did and
is trying to catch you!
- What?
- Han Jin Ah reported you for fraud.
- Open up.
- Hello?
Cheol Soo.
What are you doing? Answer me. Hey!
Cheol Soo!
Later.
Darn it.
Did...
Jin Ah...
really report me?
Give me your bag first.
- My bag?
- It's protocol.
But...
you seem very familiar.
Where did I see you before?
Earlier, by the rooftop apartment, right?
It is you. It's the same outfit, too.
What were you doing there?
Why did you run if you're a cop?
Where did you see me?
Earlier...
by the rooftop apartment.
- Hey.
- It was you.
What are you doing?
You know...
- they're real bullets from now on.
- Sorry?
Not only did you resist
arrest, you assaulted...
the officer, took his
gun, and threatened him.
Why did you do it?
When... When did I do that?
You did it to yourself...
Now,
after a struggle, the gun
will be fired by mistake,
and the bullet will go here.
Why are you doing this to me?
What about you?
Why did you have to recognize me?
Why... You!
What are you doing? Get in!
Hurry.
He tried to kill me.
He really tried to kill me.
Let's go to the police station. Right now.
- Give me your phone.
- What?
Give me your cell phone.
Okay. Here.
What are you doing?
Open the glove compartment.
Why did you throw out my phone?
Just do as you're told!
Open it.
Okay.
What's this?
An untraceable phone. Use that.
What for?
Han Jin Ah and the detective baited you.
To find or make up evidence
to arrest you with.
The nude model deal was a ruse.
They tried to put you behind bars!
What did I do?
You did it.
10 years ago.
The couple murdered at
the villa in our town...
What?
You don't have to lie to me.
I saw everything.
- Saw what?
- That night,
I saw you leave...
the burning villa.
You must be kidding me. Are you insane?
Go into hiding.
I'll find you a boat out.
Do you mean...
Han Jin Ah looked for me on purpose?
What for?
She's the dead couple's daughter.
Han Jin Ah.
She said she saw you.
Your scar, to be exact.
If they get you now,
they'll put you away for murder.
- Where are you going?
- To the police.
It's all over!
They set the trap for you!
It wasn't me!
I didn't do it.
Then who did it?
I saw...
I don't know!
Maybe your eyes need testing.
The policeman who
singlehandedly fought off...
the armed assailant...
was rushed to the hospital...
with a broken nose and other injuries.
Must you really do this?
I apologized. I said I'm sorry.
I can't live with someone
who stole from me.
Do you care more about money
than your only relative?
Who knows?
It might not end with theft.
What do you mean?
It'll all become yours once I die.
You won't need to steal then.
Is that what you think of me?
That's what I see.
I knew it would end like this.
I knew this would happen.
That's why I did it.
To get something out of you...
before you kicked me out.
A man assaulted a police
officer who only wished...
to ask questions, and then fled.
He even took and shot the officer's gun.
What's shocking is that he's a fireman.
Yoo Jong Hee has the details.
The weapon...
found in Fireman Kang Cheol Soo's bag...
is reported to have been used in...
the murder of famed
artist Han Gyeong Soo...
at his Gachon villa 10 years ago.
Do you work here?
We have nothing to say. Sorry.
Fireman Kang Cheol Soo has
been missing for two days...
and is reported to have
had many issues at work.
You don't know how violent he is.
He actually pushed me off a roof.
It was unbelievable.
I calmly suggested we talk it out...
but he grabbed me by the collar.
I don't believe it.
He was actually a murderer.
You never know what will happen.
I guess you can't.
He looked so normal.
But then again, looks can be deceiving.
I guess they can.
Why is this window stuck?
We should call someone to fix it.
Oh dear.
Why is there...
aspirin in this house?
You know we can't have that in here.
Oh dear.
Sorry.
I've been having bad headaches.
I bought some this morning.
I must've dropped them.
Jeong Soon.
What?
Get out.
I find it very uncomfortable.
Being in the same place as...
someone who knows me well.
(Unarmed Detective Fights Criminal)
Give me that.
Jeong Nam.
Hello.
Are you getting discharged?
I can't stay here. I need
to find and arrest the guy.
Don't worry too much.
It's a matter of time.
I wanted to ask you
something about Cheol Soo.
Sure.
She fell down some stairs.
I was so upset. Have a seat.
How are you holding up?
I'm on edge. I can barely control myself.
By the time I got over it,
I'd sent away my aunt and helper.
Don't blame yourself.
You just need some time to yourself.
- Jeong Nam.
- What?
Your left hand...
You hurt it before you fought Cheol Soo.
You said you fell.
Why did you tell the reporter that...
you got hurt during the fight?
That evening,
you went straight to the
terminal and found Cheol Soo.
How did you recognize him?
You'd never seen his face.
You really are on edge.
Reporters tend to exaggerate.
It's a norm.
I recognized him...
because I had someone send me his photo.
Happy now?
I know you're scared,
but you can't push me away, too.
You'll be left with...
no one on your side.
Hi.
You're Detective Gwon Jeong
Nam's daughter, right?
Do you know who hurt your mom?
If I tell you,
can you save my mom?
I know everything.
You can't beat my dad.
I can't go anywhere.
I'm being tailed everywhere I go.
Don't come anywhere near here for a while.
Should I go to the police now?
If I tell them that I've been framed,
they may uncover the truth.
Do you think you can beat that detective?
Do you have money for a top-notched lawyer?
What if it takes 10 or 20
years to clear your name?
Are you ready for that?
Why must I go through this?
Why me?
There's no reason for bad luck.
You just happened to be there.
What must I do?
You have the money from Han Jin Ah, right?
Hold onto it.
You'll need it to leave the country.
This call lasted too long. Bye.
Hello?
Captain.
Hi, Mr. Kim.
You got a new number so I
didn't know it was you.
It wasn't me.
I know.
It really wasn't me.
I never suspected you for a second.
Come on. You? Cheat on your wife?
That's absurd.
Captain.
Are you well?
You're not coughing up blood
and fainting, are you?
Don't worry. Maybe it's because I'm old,
but even the cancer cells are weak.
Captain.
I thought about...
why this is happening to me.
About 10 years ago,
I sneaked into an empty
house in the woods...
and stole from there.
I was so excited that I didn't get caught.
But...
I think that sin...
snowballed for 10 years...
and pummeled me.
I deserve it, then.
That's why I'm frightened.
That all of this...
is my fault...
Captain.
Do you know something?
You were the first person ever...
to tell me that I did a good job.
I never got to say this before, but...
- thank you very, very...
- Mr. Kim.
Don't give up.
If you give up,
you can't see anything.
You can't even see things that are visible.
There's a dense fog and it's dark.
It's over 40°C. It's like an oven.
Your body feels heavy...
and you can't take a single step.
The rescuer who should be there...
is nowhere to be found.
What will you do?
Give up and leave?
Will you give up and leave?
No.
I need to retrace my steps.
He's there somewhere.
As expected, you are so smart, Mr. Kim.
Then take your time and look slowly.
Did you miss anything?
How did it go?
The car owner is still
in Busan on business.
He'll be back tomorrow.
Okay. Keep up the good work.
Don't lose sight of the car...
until you get the dash cam video.
Captain. There's something I need to do.
Can I help?
Don't die before I get back.
I'll go back and get you your surgery.
Okay. I'll wait.
I got you.
You got caught too easily
for a fugitive on the run,
Kang Cheol Soo.
(Tune in for the finale.)
(Naked Fireman)
I can't trust Cheol Soo.
If he's innocent, he shouldn't run.
The police fabricated evidence...
and is trying to frame him.
Are you with Jin Ah?
Jin Ah and Cheol Soo?
It's my first time ever...
being protected by someone so small.
Things fell through.
You need to get the dash cam video somehow.
I'm being watched by cops right now.
How can I do that with a tail on me?
Just because I can't
trust Detective Gwon...
doesn't mean I trust you.
Ever since you found out my real name,
I haven't lied to you once.
You must believe it without a doubt now...
that Kang Cheol Soo is the
one who killed your parents.
That's absurd.
He killed my parents,
and if that wasn't enough,
he lied to me for 10 years?
You came to me...
because you didn't trust him.
In order to find out the
truth that you sensed.