Summon the power of Five
and save the world, Go-Rangers!
To be continued.
Hi, there.
What?
Why are you open?
It's business hours.
Nobody will shop today!
I see what you mean!
It beats Billy Joel.
I used to think punk rock was
stupid.
You like it?
They're mocking Sinatra
with their version of "My Way."
Now you should listen to this.
Gyaku-rin?
Gekirin. Wrath.
A punk band?
Yes, they're Japanese.
A year before the Pistols.
It was 37 years ago...
Nobody in Japan knew what punk was.
It didn't sell.
No more pressings or CDs were made.
Fish Story.
The Beatles had broken up and
The Velvet Underground had gone weird.
Rock's future was uncertain...
You do know, right?
You are aware that the comet
is on its way.
Who's he?
I don't know.
Hey, watch it!
The impact of the comet crash
will trigger a tidal wave.
Evacuate to elevated places.
I repeat.
A tidal wave is expected.
Evacuate to elevated places.
A 100-meter tidal wave is expected
along the coast.
Immediate action advised.
They won't make it, but everyone
is headed for Mt. Fuji anyway.
5 hours from now, the world will end.
2012.
5 hours to the comet crash.
You never know.
The comet's orbit might alter.
It's 100% certain.
Not 99%. You can see it right there.
Another comet might crash
into it and...
And where is this second comet?
OK, let's assume that the comet
collides with Earth.
It's not an assumption! It will!
It may hit the other side of Earth.
Great. Let's say that it hits
somewhere off Argentina.
But the comet is huge,
at 5 kilometers in diameter
the ensuing tidal wave
will engulf Japan!
It'll be twice as tall as Godzilla.
Even if you ran to the mountains,
you'd die in the volcanic eruptions.
You might survive in the shelters, but
then there will be an Ice Age.
This is the end.
The end is here, no surprises.
But the Americans put nuclear bombs
on the comet six months ago.
Ah, Operation Armageddon?
Their vehicle blew up before
the bombs were detonated.
The bombs are still there.
They could get activated...
How?
By something...
Something?
A... freak accident!
The heroes...
Champions of justice will
save humanity.
Huh?
Maybe Bruce Willis
is still on the comet.
They come in Five.
Five heroes!
Like Go-Rangers.
Right, Go-Rangers.
They are spread out over the world.
Now they know their mission.
I see.
All five of them didn't know
their mission before now.
The five heroes will prevent
the catastrophe.
By operating a robot,
they'll push the comet back.
It's Gundam. That's right,
I remember that.
Oh, are there five Gundams?
No.
There are no Gundams and
no Go-Rangers either.
If you have any other bright ideas,
please share them.
This is the end.
There's no chance of survival.
There is no hope.
For 10 years, I've known that
this would happen.
A Prince with wavy golden
hair will come...
Is this really punk music?
It is. It's punk.
The story of my solitude
If my solitude were a fish
How can solitude be a fish?
This song will save the day.
Music saves the world.
The story of my solitude
If my solitude were a fish
It'd be so enormous, so militant
A whale would get out of there
Don't assume that I'm dead
Music stacked up like wooden blocks
is the only salvation
The story of my failure
If my failure were a fish
It'd be so tragically comic
I'd have no place in the sea to be
1975.
A year before the pioneering
punk rock band,
Sex Pistols was formed.
Gyaku-rin?
It's Gekirin.
"Fish Story by Gekirin"
They broke up about 7 years ago.
Nobody noticed because
nobody knew about them.
Fish Story?
I've never heard of it.
Anything else?
Here's Kaguya-hime.
When it's played backwards, you hear
"I want to listen too."
I heard that one the other day.
What's this?
"Kaleidoscope"
Not that one. That one puts
a curse on you.
There's some moaning in the last
chorus, but it isn't a band member.
Excellent!
The voice gets louder
as you listen to it.
1982.
30 years to the comet crash.
Holy shit!
Got any other scary tapes?
You've got to hear this one.
The Gyaku-rin.
You can hear it if you're lucky.
What do you mean?
That's what I read in
Mu magazine.
The occult mag!
You can hear a woman's scream
in the silence.
Silence?
Right after the guitar solo begins
the sound becomes muted.
After a minute of total silence,
the song resumes.
On the record cover it says,
"There's a silent part."
"The silence is intended.
It isn't an error."
Guys...
What?
Why do you think they put in
that silent part?
To be different.
It would be cool if it
was The Beatles...
It wasn't to be cool, apparently
there was a scream in the recording.
The record company didn't like it
and had it erased.
Why else would they mute part
of a song?
It was muted, but some people with
sixth sense can still hear it.
Now it's a legendary song among
paranormal record collectors.
Get your hands off!
Ouch...
The story of my failure
If my failure were a fish
How can failure be a fish?
There are many rumors.
"The vocalist lost it."
"It's the bassist's curse."
"A groupie with a knife stormed
the studio."
If I heard the scream, would my
car get cursed?
If you heard the scream...
What then?
What would happen?
Hey, it's a red light!
What would happen if I heard it?
Shut up!
Don't open it!
I didn't hear anything.
Told you.
Only people with sixth sense hear it.
Thank you very much for coming to
meet us today.
Cheers!
You're all pretty.
I know the co-manager here.
I didn't expect girls as pretty
as you to show up.
Drink up, Haruko.
Your name's Haruko, right?
By the way...
Who's he?
He's just the driver.
Oh, so that's your car.
Right...
No, the car's mine.
He's just driving it.
Pretend he's not here.
I didn't think I'd have a chance with
an elite university girl like you.
A cursed tape?
We were listening to some.
Hey, don't bring that up now!
Sorry, girls.
He reads Mu magazine.
Haruko is into that kind
of thing too.
Do you believe in
Nostradamus' prophecies?
Hey, cut it out.
"In the year 1999 and seven months,
the world ends."
Of course, it won't.
You never know.
Anything can happen.
Ever since Haruko was a child...
How can I put it?
It's like she's got sixth sense.
You see ghosts?
I've heard of people like that.
Tell us one of your predictions.
She's always right.
Skeptics always just end up making
fun of me.
Not me, I believe in
that kind of stuff.
Same here.
I met a man today...
who will end up saving the world.
He'll play an important role
in saving humanity.
Like stopping the Nostradamus
catastrophes?
Tonight you'll meet a woman
you are fated to meet.
You are here.
He said to pretend that
you aren't here. But you are.
I guess so.
Can you live with that?
Live with what?
With the way you're treated.
Well it's just that he's notorious
for his violent fits.
Have you ever stood up for yourself?
If you don't, somebody will take
the woman you're fated to meet.
Remember that.
What will we do?
I don't know if everybody's coming
to the next place.
Oh, I'm drunk.
Why don't we go there first and
wait for them?
OK.
Excuse me.
Would you like a ride?
Okay.
Do you think...
What do you want?
Don't smoke...
Please don't smoke.
Go left.
Left?
Next on the right.
To the right...
Here we are.
A Love Inn...?
The bar's near here.
It's around the corner.
They're waiting.
But, but...
Come on, Haruko.
The night's not over yet.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
Haruko, what are you waiting for?
It's right over there,
so come on.
Come on.
It's really right
around the corner, Haruko.
Come on, hurry now.
Wait... Hello?
I mean... Hey!
You can go home now.
But...
Scram!
Get out of here!
Have you ever stood up for yourself?
Hey!
Stand up to the bastard!
Why am I doing what he
told me to do?
What kind of wimp am I?
Don't smoke.
I'm a Goddamn idiot!
The story of my failure
If my failure were a fish
It'd be so tragically comic
I'd have no place in the sea to be
Don't you know you're a liar!
Don't you know you're a deceiver!
Music stacked up like wooden blocks
Is the champion of justice!
If my justice really were a fish
It'd be so greedy and arrogant
I'd pump the magma
Out of the ocean bed!
You can hear a woman's scream.
Help me!
What do you want?
Go away!
Let go!
Let me go! Help!
Why did the sound cut out there?
It's deliberate.
It goes out for one minute
during the solo.
It has a meaning.
Guess what it is.
Heroes who save Earth...
Music that saves humanity.
Why can't we have a
sensible conversation?
You know what I'd do if the world
really ended today?
I'd listen to my favorite music.
Have you ever eaten bird's nests?
I have. It's one of the most
expensive Chinese delicacies.
Ever had a threesome?
What's this about?
I have, and one of the women
was a blonde.
Yeah, big deal.
I've done it all.
There's nothing I haven't done.
I did it while you were listening
to stupid music.
I've done everything
my heart desired.
I've tasted exotic cuisines around
the world.
I owned a Countach, had a cruise
around the world and threesomes.
All on borrowed money.
Now I won't have to pay it back.
There's nothing more I want.
Stomach cancer has spread through
my body, eating up my bones.
It's terminal.
I could have had it removed
and fully recovered.
But I didn't.
You want to know why?
Because I knew that this day
would come.
I've known it for 10 years.
The story of my solitude
If my solitude were a fish
It'd be so enormous, so militant,
A whale would get out of there
Don't assume that I'm dead
Your eyes are wide shut
"The man who'd save the world."
Remember that?
Yeah, that was back when we were
at college.
I wanted to talk more with
that girl.
Me too.
You slept with her?
I don't remember what happened.
But I remember her prediction
about a man who'd save the world.
That's why I quit my job
and came to this place.
The 7th month of 1999.
The Great King of Terror will come.
- Nostradamus.
I miss my son.
Come on, you're the one
who asked for the divorce.
Stay with me and you'll be fine.
We're the chosen ones.
"Even if the world would end tomorrow,"
"I would continue to plant my apple trees."
These are my favorite words.
Let's believe in our survival.
We shall create a new world
and be the messiahs
of our new world.
Like Noah's Ark, sir?
Just like Noah's Ark.
It'll be tomorrow.
Are you sure?
It's got to be tomorrow.
I gave up everything for this.
My job, women, everything.
Even if the world
would end tomorrow...
Everybody, behold.
The last sunset of the world.
Nothing happened!
The last sunset? The sun's here
and it's hot! 35 degrees!
You said today was the last so I
quit my job to join you!
Everybody listen. It's just like
we've been telling you.
Nothing will happen in 1999.
We figured out that the
prophecy was off by 10 years.
In reality, the Great King of Terror
won't come until 2009.
We will prepare the Ark
for that occasion.
A Prince with wavy golden hair...
That being a metaphor for a comet.
My reading of the prophecy
is that it will come in 2012...
No, it's 2009!
In the year 2012...
2009!
2012...
My friends, don't be
deceived by this man.
He's a fake prophet.
So are you!
I won't associate with his kind!
That man is a phony!
I'm the prophet!
I'm not like him!
The man who'll save the world...
Friends! Don't give up hope!
The end will certainly come.
It will come soon!
It'll all end!
But don't give up hope!
The world will end!
Where's Noah's Ark?
You don't even have a boat!
I'll take your photo.
Here I go.
That's great!
Passengers, we'd like to thank you
for using our services today.
This ferry continues its voyage
to Hokkaido after leaving Tokyo...
Sir, please!
We can't turn around
just for you.
Didn't you hear the announcement?
It's so loud!
I didn't hear it. When I sleep,
I can't hear a thing.
That's too bad.
Stop! What are you doing?
Let me go! Let me die!
Why...
Why Hokkaido?
"Destination - Hokkaido"
A herd of dolphins have been
sighted on the port side.
For a view of the dolphins, please look
to the left side of the ship.
That's a Yamana High School
uniform you're wearing, right?
It's famous for its smart students.
Many go on to good universities.
... But I failed to get off the boat.
Uh, what's this...?
It's a fruit tart.
Excuse me, I ordered a tart!
I'm terribly sorry.
Sorry about that.
Here's your fruit tart.
2009.
In 3 minutes and 33 seconds,
the ferry will be hijacked.
I didn't order this...
Mind if I tell you
an amusing story?
It's about my father.
Actually, it's about the way
my father raised me.
My life's so ludicrous,
it's laughable.
The ferry won't stop until
we arrive in Hokkaido.
We might as well enjoy the voyage.
The story of my absurd life
will make the trip memorable.
Do you want to hear about it?
You see...
I wanted to be...
a champion of justice.
A champion of justice?
Isn't it ridiculous?
That's what I was raised to be.
To be a champion of justice?
Weird, isn't it?
It's a vague ambition,
when you think about it.
It's not like wanting to be
a lawyer or a soccer player.
According to my father,
the preparation was more important
than the title.
A strong body and a calm mind.
He told me that I had to
acquire those qualities.
I've been working out
since I was a kid.
And I had zen training too.
You meditated?
To have a mind as peaceful
as a stream.
A mind that stays calm and
isn't tempted by violence.
Did you succeed?
I don't know.
Have you ever read
Atsushi Nakajima's Apprentice?
No... I'm a science major.
Let me summarize the novel for you.
It presents a problem.
Often tyranny oppresses
the righteous.
The unjust deserve punishment.
But we hardly ever hear that justice wins.
That's the summary.
The book was from my father.
It left me perplexed.
Was it the wording?
The novel is set in
the time of Confucius.
It's scary to realize how
oppression has always ruled.
Don't you agree?
Justice hasn't won since
the beginning of time.
It's ridiculous.
It's so ridiculous...
It's a shame.
Why did your father want you to
be a champion of justice?
I'll tell you more later.
I have a pie in the oven.
A champion of justice.
We overheard you talking.
We might not be young,
but we have good hearing.
That was some story.
Do you think it's true?
Maybe he has ulterior motives.
We have an announcement.
You are advised to follow the
armed men's instructions.
I repeat.
Follow the armed men's instructions.
You are advised to follow the
armed men's instructions.
It's a hijack.
What for?
People.
Listen.
From now on, this ferry is
Noah's Ark.
To take a voyage to the new world.
What's this about?
Try not to be reckless.
We have many friends.
here and there...
all over this vessel.
You might not know
what's going on but
remember we'll shoot
anybody who resists.
We might shoot you even
if you don't resist.
Look, that's the apple pie we ordered.
The champion of justice.
So it was true.
No kidding?
Didn't you hear them warn you?
Our friends are all over
this vessel.
I had my eye on you,
high school girl.
I knew she'd be perfect
as our first victim.
Please don't shoot her.
Learning how to be a champion of justice
Every day of my childhood
was spent training.
I had no time to play with friends.
And I didn't know what I was
doing it for either.
Do you see what I mean?
How often does a champion of justice
get to use his skills?
When I fought the school bullies...
the teacher lectured me on
how violence was bad.
I often had a good cry with Mom.
But don't get me wrong.
I really loved my father.
When he watched me
do my training
he looked at me so affectionately.
I always had that impression.
Don't talk anymore.
You're wounded.
The bullet went straight through.
It doesn't count as a wound.
Of course it does!
Well maybe...
I feel so grateful to my father now...
I never thought I'd ever get
a chance to use my skills.
If it wasn't for my father...
This won't stop
the champion of justice...
... Here.
Just like that.
I'm glad they didn't shoot you.
He's the champion of justice.
The champion of justice.
I have to go.
Thank you.
Thank my father.
We're saved.
Yes, he'll definitely save us.
I know.
Resuming our broadcast.
We're now back with our broadcast.
5 hours to impact but
we have information
about a space vehicle being launched
with nuclear missiles.
I repeat.
But the Americans gave up long ago.
They're digging shelters.
Is it the Russians or French?
We have news on the space vehicle.
It's an Indian rocket ship.
What? I didn't know the Indians
had rocket ships.
I have no details yet but 5 experts
were sent on this mission.
They're quoted as saying,
"Just as music knows no borders"
"we've come together
in this emergency."
The 5 crew members have never been
on a space mission before...
It won't work then.
They plan to dispatch
nuclear missiles on to the comet.
to detonate bombs left there
by the USA six months ago.
They hope that the comet
will explode into pieces.
That's how they'll do it!
It's impossible.
Striking a small area on the comet
from a moving vehicle is difficult.
Plotting an accurate trajectory
requires complicated computations.
Even with a highly trained crew,
the odds of success are 0.000013%...
... It will be difficult.
They're just getting foolhardy.
Five of them...
Did he say it's a crew of five?
Yes, it's five!
Five heroes to save the world.
This is it! It's them!
Maradonna weaved through five
English players for a goal.
There were the Jackson 5 and
The Finger 5 and... They're all five.
This will save the world.
I've got nothing.
Doing nothing at all.
What kind of noise is this?
It's too loud!
Somebody stop those boys.
Play something quieter.
Give us Enka ballads!
Or folk music!
That's how we like it!
I only love you
I believed what you said
When you said
You'd only love me
Searching,
I'm still searching for my love
Wandering,
Alone with a broken heart
Up and down those
Cobblestone streets
I'm in Nagasaki today
And it's raining again
"Norio Okazaki,
Lemon Records"
The Beatles broke up.
Rock is in trouble.
I know you like the MC5
and The Stooges.
And Jack Crispin.
That kind of music.
But your music is even
more radical and new.
You're on the right track.
It'll take a while for
people to catch on.
But I can wait.
Let me manage you.
Deliver your music to the world.
To the world!
Right, that's where your music
belongs. It'll reach them.
I believe it will.
2 years later
I've got nothing,
Doing nothing at all
Sounds like a hit.
Very good.
Soften it, good.
1975.
A year before
Sex Pistols was formed.
This is going to sell.
Keep going!
This one will sell.
I've had enough of
that rich brat producer.
He understands nothing
about our music!
Why overdub with that keyboard?
Producer Tani has some ideas
we don't.
We never needed a producer!
Right, Shigeki?
When we did that record on our own,
it didn't sell.
Okazaki-san had to do something.
He's a good guy but he can't
make hit records.
You criticizing him, Goro?
That's new.
Okazaki-san doesn't stick
things out.
He said he liked our music
then he brought in Tani.
It's like saying something
was missing.
Shigeki-san.
Drop the honorifics!
If you were older
you'd be the leader.
You've changed. You used to
be the radical one.
We're pros. We can't afford
that shit anymore.
I have to deal with the
record company execs, the media...
I have to everything.
What is it, Goro?
What?
You started to say something.
If they aren't fried, they can't
be called fried noodles.
They're still good.
But they aren't fried.
That's deep, Goro...
I'm telling you, I'll never
play my guitar like those phonies.
They don't play with soul.
Make sure you come tomorrow!
And write some lyrics!
Shigeki-san...
Drop the san, damn it!
I overheard some bad news.
We have to talk about this.
I was dozing when Okazaki
and the President came in.
It's about the Gekirin boys.
What did the President want?
To cancel our contract?
He said, "We can't afford"
"to make three albums with
those talentless losers."
Talentless losers?
You could've told us sooner!
Sorry.
What did Okazaki say to
the President?
"Just this one then."
That's all he could say.
Our last album...
If it sold, then the President
might see things differently...
You know, Shigeki.
It won't sell.
I know.
Nobody understands our music.
And to make matters complicated...
What?
We believe there's nothing wrong
with our music.
So true.
I'd better start looking
for another job to pay the bills.
See ya!
What will you do, Goro?
Will we go amateur again?
Hi.
So Goro told you already?
How come nobody told
us before?
Who can...?
Poor Goro.
He has to choose between a
solo career and his friends.
Okazaki-san...
I didn't know that.
All I knew was that tomorrow's
recording would be our last.
You didn't know...
Did you hear?
That's how it is.
The President only wants to
keep you.
I'm sorry.
Where are you going?
I'll talk to Goro!
No, you don't.
Let go! Why didn't he tell you?
Sorry about this.
All Goro thinks about is Goro!
He doesn't care about the band.
You do all the dirty work, Shigeki.
He's not cut out to be a leader.
You think you are?
Only Shigeki can do it.
Ryoji is too quick-tempered.
Tetsuya has seven kids to feed.
The band only lasted
because of Shigeki.
Shut up, old man!
Yes, ma'am.
Sorry.
If Goro cared about the band,
why didn't he talk to you?
He doesn't care about the
sacrifices Shigeki's made.
The band's nothing to Goro!
As long as he has his own future
worked out.
What does he care about us?
No, Goro cares...
He cares...
Do something, Shigeki.
Goro's going to betray you.
Don't let him...
Sorry about this.
What's this book?
I just grabbed it off the shelf.
You can have it.
"Fish Story"
"The story of my solitude.
If it were a fish"
"it'd be so militant
a whale would fear it."
If my solitude were a fish...
It'd be so enormous, so militant,
a whale would get out of there.
I know it would.
I'm sure it would...
I rewrote a passage from
Okazaki-san's book.
It's not a good idea to steal.
It's not stealing, it's a quote.
Nobody will sue us over this.
Trust me.
I don't believe anything you
say anymore.
You're late.
Here, the new song.
Let's get it done with.
Come on.
This album is taking way too
long to record.
Let's get snappy.
Time is money.
Like Congress, the longer they
deliberate, the more it costs.
This is awesome!
I love the lyrics, it has a beat.
Yeah, a good tune.
I suggest we slow this down.
Keep the guitar down.
Make it mellow.
How can this be mellow?
Why don't we make a ballad album?
Bullshit! I'll play it even faster!
Slow will sell better.
I'm not going to let you
fuck with this tune.
There's no way, man.
Only amateurs indulge themselves.
Shut up, rich kid.
What do you think of this song,
Okazaki-san?
Talk to us, Okazaki-san.
It'll never sell.
Mr. Tani.
I'm not trying to override
your decision but
can we play this the way it is?
This isn't child's play, you know?
I have responsibilities too.
Let us play this song our way.
Listen to me.
Come on, man.
This is the last time we
record together.
Let us have it our way just once.
What do you mean, this is the
last recording?
Just what he said.
We're getting the boot
after we finish this.
Seriously?
What about live performances?
They'll let us do a few.
If this record sells well,
it'll change the situation.
What?
I think you know, Ryoji.
It won't sell.
I know that.
Nobody has time for
a band that makes no money.
Since when did you become
so mature?
I'm nowhere near you.
We've done OK.
Yeah, we've been great.
I've persuaded him.
Let's play it like you did now.
But we only get one take.
We record it and that's it.
One take?
Are you scared?
No. If we fuck up, you'll have
to live with it.
The story of my solitude
If my solitude were a fish
It'd be so enormous, so militant
A whale would get out of there
I know it would
I'm sure it would
The story of my solitude
If my solitude were a fish
It'd be so enormous, so militant
A whale would get out of there
Don't assume that I'm dead
Music stacked up like wooden blocks
Is the only salvation
The story of my failure
If my failure were a fish
It'd be so tragically comic
I'd have no place in the sea to be
Don't you know you're a liar!
Don't you know you're a deceiver!
Music stacked up like wooden blocks
Is the champion of justice!
If my justice really were a fish
It'd be so greedy and arrogant
I'd pump the magma
Out of the ocean bed!
Okazaki-san...
Do you think this will reach them?
Is somebody really
listening out there?
If there's anybody, I want to know.
Is this reaching you?
How can such a great song
not reach anybody?
I can't believe it.
It's got to reach somebody.
Somebody, please...
... please.
The story of my solitude
If my solitude were a fish
It'd be so enormous, so militant
A whale would get out of there.
That was great.
Great performance.
Goro, what was that about?
You threw me off completely.
Yeah! That was kind of embarrassing.
Well, you know...
Imagine if no one listened to
a cool song like that.
So you were complaining?
We'll have to overdub that part.
Let's do it after the break.
Oh, I thought we only had one take?
You have to redo it. We can't
have that in the end product.
We won't record it again.
Like I said, that's it.
It wasn't bad.
It was incredible.
And nothing will make it better.
What are we going to do with that
naive soliloquy of Goro's?
We can erase it. We'll just cut
that part out.
What do you mean?
Let's just mute the sound.
That should work out.
What's the point of muting it?
We should reassemble it.
No. Let's go for something weird.
Come on, they're not The Beatles.
It'll only appear amateurish.
I know I fucked up. Why don't
we do the whole song again?
No, that was good.
It would be crude if we left
it like that.
Trust me.
It won't sell anyway.
Fish Story.
For the song title.
I like it.
It's good.
That's plagiarism.
It's quoting.
Maybe we can change it slightly.
How about Fish Stories?
Why is it plural?
Fish Story...
Fish story.
OK, we'll call it that.
It won't sell anyway.
Now we're going to fade away...
Does that make everything
we've done meaningless?
"If my solitude were a fish..."
What does it mean?
Beats me.
Don't you think there's something
philosophical behind it?
Otherwise nobody would say,
"If my solitude were a fish."
I know what you mean but...
Our song is quoting this book.
It's a deep song.
Our song has got to
reach somebody someday.
But you know...
What?
You don't fry udon noodles.
It's good. Try it!
- You're deep, Goro.
- Try it.
You don't fry them.
An omelet, rice and a beer.
Your kid?
My wife left me.
Okazaki-san, we'll borrow this title
for our song.
Great.
Are we OK about the rights?
Don't worry. Trust me.
We have to worry then.
That's the only copy of the
book in the world.
The only copy?
It's a recalled product.
My aunt used to be an accountant
for a publisher.
She kept this copy.
I don't really get it, but why
were the books recalled?
My aunt told me that after the war,
there was a translator shortage.
The publisher she worked for
was very small.
They looked everywhere for
a translator with no success.
As they'd paid for the book rights,
they had to publish it or go bankrupt.
And one day out of the blue
an American-Japanese guy turned up
looking for a job.
For the company, he was like a savior.
Anybody who spoke English
would have done.
He was hired on the spot.
Nobody checked his background.
He'd been looking for a sales
position, without success.
Work was scarce in those days.
He had a pregnant wife and
needed money.
He agreed to translate the book.
Everybody thought
the company was saved.
But they were wrong.
How come?
He was Japanese.
He looked like a foreigner, but he
was a third-generation Tokyo-ite.
He didn't know any English either.
Word for word, he translated from
a dictionary... and it was terrible.
He thought it was a story
about a fish.
It isn't?
Fish Story means an
exaggerated story.
It does?
That's right.
You'd better study harder.
So, "A fish story of my own solitude"
became, "The story of solitude,
if it were a fish."
So it's all nonsense.
Nonsense?
One of the stories of post-war chaos.
I went to see my aunt before she
died and she gave me the book.
I guess she didn't want it.
What's wrong?
Go-Rangers...
He wanted to watch Go-Rangers.
What are the Go-Rangers?
Five superheroes, like Masked Rider.
My kids love them. They fight over
which ranger they want to be.
I personally like the Yellow Ranger.
You mean they have
five heroes these days?
It's on! Come sit here.
Summon the power of Five
and save the world, Go-Rangers!
To be continued.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't cry.
Let's eat curry like
the Yellow Ranger.
Let's not do it.
No curry?
I'm talking about the title.
Why not?
I don't want a song called
"A big lie".
It's a great title.
I love "Fish Story".
People all over the world will
hear our song one day.
Even if it takes decades.
I believe so, and I'll keep
believing that.
It's a fish story.
But you said the same thing yourself.
I was serious.
Let's not have it as a title.
Yeah.
I don't mind it.
No!
Okazaki-san says it's great.
He jinxed it!
Anyway, we'll get complaints about
the muted part.
You think so?
I think it works.
In what way?
Well, for example...
How about this?
There's a man,
listening to Fish Story.
He's at a cafe or something.
He sits with his eyes closed,
concentrating on the song.
Then comes the muted part.
He hears a woman's voice
and looks up.
What...?
Maybe it was a waitress
who talked to him.
He's startled and looks up.
Their eyes meet and they fall
in love! It's unlikely...
And they live happily ever after.
There you go.
All thanks to your song.
Well, was it really due to the music?
Soon, they have a child.
It goes on?
Of course.
The child becomes a great person.
How's that?
Great at what?
A Nobel Prize winner?
That's dumb.
Maybe the child prevents World War 3
and wins the Prize.
Nobel Peace Prize!
It won't happen.
No.
It's a fish story.
That's what it's called.
If it's a fish story
make it a story of our hardcore fans
saving the world together.
Most unlikely.
Never.
We failed to reach people
of this generation.
But our song goes beyond time.
Something like that could happen.
Isn't it the way the world turns?
Fish Story will one day
save the world.
No way!
Don't say that!
Let's drink to us.
We've come to the last 60 minutes.
Impact will be in 1 hour.
Data is insufficient.
The angle is unexpected.
We need more time to plot
the exact orbit of the comet.
Santos, when will the missiles
be ready?
We have no time.
It's fucked, it's over.
We're not going to make it.
1 hour to impact.
Get ready for the tidal wave.
Evacuate to elevated places.
I repeat...
It won't take long, the final moment.
It'll be over in a moment.
There will be a tidal wave.
Evacuate to elevated places.
The tidal wave will affect
all of Japan...
Japan will be underwater
in the blink of an eye.
The tidal wave will be bigger
than Mt. Fuji.
You're wrong if you think
you could swim out of it.
The impact will shred you
in a split second.
We have zero percent chance
of surviving it.
No escape.
I thought you said you'd listen to
your records.
You'd listen to them even if
the world ended today.
You're running out of time.
Yes! That's right!
That's how you should have behaved
from the beginning.
You shouldn't have pretended
that you weren't scared!
I told you so!
I've been warning you for
10 long years!
I told you and you didn't listen...
The Prince!
What was that?
Was it hit?
Was it the bombs?
Bull's-eye?
The missiles hit the bombs!
The missiles launched from
the Indian vessel hit the bombs.
The comet exploded in pieces.
The Indian vessel rewrote history!
They did it!
I knew it...
There are heroes to save the day!
We have live footage.
It's from the space ship.
I did nothing really.
It was all thanks to her.
She did all the calculations.
She's so extremely clever!
Once asleep, no noise will wake her.
Sorry...
I'm sorry.
"Fish Story"
"The story of my solitude..."
"If my solitude were a fish"
"Fish Story"
Atsushi Ito
Kiyohiko Shibukawa
Toshimitsu Ohkawauchi
Noriko Eguchi
Hidekazu Mashima
Gaku Hamada
Takashi Yamanaka
Kazuki Namioka
Mai Takahashi
Kenjiro Ishimaru
Mikako Tabe
Mirai Moriyama
Nao Omori
Based on the novel by
Kotaro Isaka
Theme song by Kazuyoshi Saito
Producers:
Hitoshi Endo / Yasushi Utagawa
Associate producers: Yasuhiro Masaoka
Kenichi Suzuki / Sei Matsumoto
Screenplay by Tamio Hayashi
Cinematography by
Takashi Komatsu (JSC)
Lighting by Yasuhiko Matsuoka
Sound recording by Yasuo Takano
Production design by
Tomoharu Nakamae
Assistant director:
Katsutoshi Hirabayashi
Line producer: Yusuke Wakabayashi
Music by Yukio Kikuchi
Music producer: Tsugihiko Sasaki
Distributed by Showgate
Subtitles by Dean Shimauchi
2009 "Fish Story" Film Partners