[Man's Voice] Los Angeles
late at night is much like any
big American city late at night.
At 2:00 a.m. People
are either making a mess
or cleaning it up.
Tonight's my night
to do the cleaning up.
My name, most of the time,
is Irwin Fletcher.
I write under the name
ofJane Doe.
That's the kind of gal I am.
This is a Greek seafood house,
part of a very successful chain.
But, believe me,
it's not because of the food.
113,000
from basketball.
List it as codfish.
120,000 from
the Gonzalez fight.
That includes 60 from
our chain in the Valley.
Twenty from Long Beach.
120 total.
Put that
under halibut.
180,000
from the track.
Scrod.
We already got over
two million in scrod
this month.
Scrod's making a comeback,
all right?
[Man #1]
So how are you listing
my stake?
[Man #2] Breakage.
[Man #1]
$ 75,000 worth ofbreakage?
[Glass Shatters]
We're Greeks! We dance,
we break plates, we're clumsy!
[Man #1] Cut the fighting.
We gotta be cross town
in 30 minutes.
You wanna wash up?
[Man #2] Nah. My wife gets
suspicious if I come home and
my hands don't smell like fish.
[Man #1] I got it.
You get the lights.
[Man #2]
Where's Poppa?
[Man #1] In the back.
[Man #2] Tell him to snap it
up. We'll meet him in the car.
Phil, I'll drop you off first.
[Phil]
You better.
- [Gasps] Hi.
- What's your name,
little lady?
My name? Peggy Lee... Zorba.
Peggy Lee Zorba.
- You're cute!
- Do you mind if I
freshen up a little bit?
Splash a little water
on my face.
Whatever makes you
feel sexy.
- Okay.
- [Chuckling]
Just wait outside.
I'll be right out.
What the hell was that?
- Jesus.! If it's a cop, kill him.
- Hi. Mary Poppins!
If it's a reporter,
cripple him.
[Tires Screeching,
Brakes Squealing]
You're never driving again!
I just did what
you told me to do.
There's a new thing
called brakes.!
Will you shut up.!
Good. Brilliant as usual,
Fletch. We'll run it
in the next edition.
Great. See you
in two weeks.
Uh, Fletch, there's...
"Uh, Fletch"? Frank, I see
a double-cross in your eyes.
You promised me a vacation
and I'm taking it.
Right after the sewer story.
What are you talking about?
You can't do this to me.
I spent eight nights on my knees
for you dressed like
Dolly Parton at a funeral.
I got felt up. I got
dishpan hands and sore knees!
Three guys tried to kill me.
And do you give a crap?
You promised me a vacation!
And you're gonna get
a vacation.
As soon as you research and
write the sewer system expose.
You owe me a vacation!
In July you're gonna have it!
That's two months away.
That's why
you're such a great reporter.
You know the facts.
By the way,
the new computer disallowed
your undocumented expenses.
- It'll come out
of this week's pay.
- You can't do that.
There's nothing I can do
about it. It's amazing.
It's all done automatically.
On top of everything else,
I think I'm getting my period.
No wonder I got
a fumigation alert.
How'd you get in here?
The window was open.
I knocked, and I could swear
I heard you say, "Come in."
You really know how to cover
your ass, Gillet. Although
those pants are a huge mistake.
You owe me $4,381
in back alimony.
What? I was married to you?
You're right. I've been
foolishly squandering my salary
on food and heat.
You have one week to comply
with Judge Proctor's orders.
Payment in full.
Otherwise you go to jail.
Wendy doesn't need
the money.
I hear she's been... banging
some balding, wimpy lawyer
who can't get it up.
- May I see that?
- Be my guest.
It's a nice briefcase.
Couldn't guess your weight?
Oh! I'm sorry.
I got it.
Never mind,
I'll take care of it.
Look at this. A note from
the Oakwood Potency Clinic.
"Sorry to inform you,
our machines cannot process
sperm counts as low as yours."
Here we are.
What about this?
Be careful!
Uh-oh!
I am terribly sorry!
You did that intentionally.
No, I did not.
I really didn't.
That was good juice too.
Leave it alone.
Good idea. My mistake.
Where are you going
with that?
My mess.
I'll clean it up.
- What are you doing?
- What's this?
You are damaging personal
property and I'm gonna...
The ink is running.
I didn't expect that.
There we are!
Clean as a whistle.
Thanks for coming by,
Marvin.
Expect to hear
from my lawyer.
Oh, Gillet, one more thing.
Come back here.
It's very important.
They're doing a thing now where
they make an incision in the
scalp, push the hair together.
Or you could try a transplant.
Maybe the hair from your ass
might make you smarter. Bye.
Betty, how 'bout lunch
at the In-N-Out Burger?
I'm not hungry.
Forget the burger. How about
just the "in and out"?
[Groans]
Very well.
How about just the "in"?
[Groans]
Ooh!
[Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
Fletch, answer your phone.
In-N-Out Burger.
May I take your order please?
Mr. Irwin Fletcher?
This is Amanda Ray Ross.
I represented
your Aunt Belle Fletcher.
Good ol' Aunt Belle.
How the hell is she?
She's deceased,
Mr. Fletcher.
Oh. I guess she could be better.
- You're a hard man to find.
- I was touring with the Stones.
What can I do for you?
Didn't you get my message?
No.
I'm the executor
of your aunt's will and
as such I can inform you...
you are the major beneficiary
of your aunt's estate,
Belle Isle.
What about this expense...
$58 for leg waxing?
That's bullshit.
Yeah, but feel how smooth
they are.
[Amanda]
It consists of 80 acres
of old plantation property.
Wait a minute.
Did you say plantation?
Yes, indeed.
She left it to me?
According to her will,
she did.
- Can I get back to you?
- Hair by Ziggy? Who's Ziggy?
5-0-4... Shut up, Frank.
Yeah.
I'll get right back to you.
Can't we just return
some of these things?
What about the lingerie?
- I ate it.
- Be serious for one minute.
I quit.
I'm not unreasonable
about legitimate expenses.
I quit, Frank.
Yeah. On the sewer story,
I'm gonna advance you for
the hip boots and wet suit.
Frank, I'm really quitting.
Fletch, look, I got a little
A-frame up at Arrowhead.
Why don't you go there,
take a couple of weeks,
relax?
I'm really gonna miss you.
Maybe that's an overstatement.
Treat this as good news.
You can always write
myJane Doe column.
You're not gonna quit,
and I'll tell you why.
Why?
You have
journalistic integrity.
Yeah.
And you have a sense
of loyalty.
And you'll never give up
the quest for truth,
will you?
You're right. I can't abandon
the principles that nurtured me
lo these many years.
Wrap them up with the shit
on my desk and have them shipped
to my mansion in Louisiana.
Bye.
What happened?
And my husband said I was
crazy to go 2,000 miles
to have my nose done.
[Snoring]
That's an interesting watch.
Is it a prize of some sort?
No.
It certainly looks
like one.
It's a championship
Laker watch.
Oh! Are you a Laker?
I used to date one.
Only thing I have
to remember him by.
[Sighs]
Lord, what was that?
We just clipped a Piper Cub.
The pilot's okay.
I just saw him parachuting.
[Laughing]
I love a man
with a sense of humor.
What did you say
your name was?
Nostradamus.
I'm Cindy Mae Sample.
I love the Fightin' Irish.
Lord, I hate to fly.
I wish I was gettin' off
in Thibodaux like you.
It's two more stops
to Selma. All those ups
and downs and ups and downs.
[Sighs]
You should try
holding your breath.
Sometimes that works.
[Inhales]
Belle Isle.
* We are calling *
[Fletch] Belle Isle.
* While our heads
are bending low *
* Can you hear *
* Our gentle voices calling *
* Old WhiteJoe **
Thank you, Betty Lee.
**[Humming]
Look, Colonel, the folks
have come to serenade you.
[Betty Lee]
They love you so much.
- I love them too.
- ** [Humming]
Give me that, boy!
[Spits]
Thank you, sir.
Quiet down.
- Uncle Frank?
- Yes, sir?
- You know my favorite tune.
- Sure do, Colonel.
Would you mind if I sat
in your lap, Colonel?
Please do, Betty Lee.
Please do.
The field hands would like
to dance for you.
Dance for me?
Why, I'll dance for them!
[Cheering]
Yes, sir!
* Zip-a-dee-doo-dah
Zip-a-dee-ay *
* My, oh, my
what a wonderful day *
* Plenty of sunshine
headin' my way *
You bet!
* Zip-a-dee-doo-dah
Zip-a-dee-ay *
* Mr. Bluebird's
on my shoulder *
* Ain't it the truth
It's actual *
* Everything is satisfactual *
* Zip-a-dee-doo-dah
Zip-a-dee-ay *
* Wonderful feeling *
* Wonderful day **
You made it,
Mr. Notre Dame.
[P.A. System, Indistinct]
Mr. Fletcher.
I'm Amanda Ray Ross.
I spoke with you
on the phone.
Oh, yes. That was you?
Great.
Do you have any luggage?
Just one piece.
[Amanda]
Plannin' on stayin' long?
Just long enough to see
Mount Rushmore and squeeze in
a little ice fishing.
I'm on the board of
the Pontchartrain Society.
We help preserve
and restore some
of these lovely mansions.
We headed to Belle Isle?
- You must be dying to see it,
Mr. Fletcher.
- Call me Fletch.
Your house is not quite
as grand as some of the
others in the neighborhood.
It doesn't matter.
It's the thought that counts.
Eighty acres, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Isn't it strikin'?
Your aunt tried to keep things
in their natural state.
She ever brush her hair?
- I can see you're disappointed.
- No, not at all!
A little spackling
and some napalm, this place
would make a nice mausoleum.
Oh, my God!
Are you all right?
Oh!
I was aimin' to fix that today.
How do you do?
I be Calculus Entterby.
You be Mr. And Mrs. Fletcher?
I be Fletch. Geometry Fletch.
She be Miss Trigonometry Ross.
Pleased, I'm sure.
Your Aunt Belle told me
you'd be takin' over the place,
and I'm extendin'
my "condulations."
Right. You work here?
Your Aunt Belle and I,
we had an arrangement.
And I was hopin' we could
make an extenuation of it.
Help me get your stuff
out the car here.
Come on.
You mind your step.
Our families go back
for hundreds of years.
Your great grandparents
owned my great grandparents
and that's how it all started.
Did you ever hear of the
Emancipation Proclamation?
I heard somethin' about it,
but I don't recall exactly.
- It didn't get much publicity
around these here parts.
- I'll bet.
Excuse me, sir.
Could you give me a hand?
R-Right here.
Just pull it towards you.
Just pull it.
Come on, come on.
Just pull it on over.
That's it, that's it.
Don't scar the car.
Is there any electricity
or gas?
Everything works.
No cable TV, I guess.
If I'd known you was comin',
I'd have straightened out a bit
and stocked your refrigerator.
No food?
No refrigerator.
We need to do
some paperwork.
Want a lift into town?
What? And leave
my estate unattended?
It's not yours till you sign.
I can make you some dinner,
ease the culture shock.
That sounds great.
Should I be doin' anything?
No, not really.
Uh, soon as you get
that trunk upstairs
and have finished your nap,
I guess you could fix that step
and jump down, turn around
and pick a bale of cotton.
And while I'm gone, see to it
Miss Scarlett stays away
from the Union Army, will you?
[Amanda]
More wine?
[Fletch] You're not trying
to take advantage of me,
are you?
[Amanda]
Not yet.
You need to sign these papers.
Do you mind
if I read 'em first?
Be my guest.
Had you talked
to your aunt recently?
That depends
on your view of history.
It's been 16 years.
Sign all three?
Please.
I was just wonderin'
because she changed her will
three weeks before she died.
Well, lucky for me.
Why'd she do that?
I don't know. She was old.
Seemed to be under
a lot of strain.
Dying always does that to you.
Congratulations. You know,
you can make yourself
some good money out of this.
A Realtor contacted me with
an unusually high offer...
225,000.
- Dollars?
- Mm-hmm.
Let me ask you this:
If they're so anxious, don't you
think if I wait a little longer,
they might go up?
- They might.
- And I just got here,
didn't I?
No sale?
While you're thinking
about it, what are you gonna
do with the land, Fletch?
I don't know. Raise chitlins...
the chitlin' market
as high as it is.
They're mean little animals,
but their coats
are worth a fortune.
$225,000?
What do you think I oughta do?
If I were you,
I would proceed slowly
and carefully.
That's my specialty.
- Would you like some dessert?
- What do you have in mind?
How 'bout something sweet...
and Southern?
[Gasps]
[Fletch]
I borrowed your toothbrush.
Would've used your razor,
but it looks like you've been
doing some gardening with it.
Gee, I can't believe
we slept this late.
Amanda? Want to drive
into Belle Isle?
I guess not.
It was good,
but not that good.
'Morning, Mr. Fletcher.
If that's your real name.
I'm BillyJo Hendrick.
Howdy.
What's your relationship
to Amanda Ray?
She was my attorney.
She was working on my briefs.
[Chuckles]
- You come into town,
y'all just hit it off?
- So to speak.
Sparks just flew.
That's what
you're gonna tell me.
Wonder why things like that
never happen to me?
Wonder why!
Were y'all usin' some drugs
you brought in from
California by any chance?
Just some Beaujolais.
Beaujolais?
It's a pretty popular drug
made from grapes?
- You feel like makin'
a statement?
- A statement?
"Ask not what your country
can do for you, ask what
you can do for your country."
I guess you just wanna make
it hard on everybody.
Well, let's see how you feel
after some time in the tank.
Y'all come.
All of us?
Just you.
- What's the charge?
- Pissin' me off.
Is that a felony
or a misdemeanor?
That's it!
You're cleaner than most
of the ones we get around here.
You smell nice.
I expect you'll be popular.
Do you realize you have
to read me my rights?
Or at least find someone
who can read
to do it for you.
[Lock Locking]
A little gamy in here.
Not much ventilation, huh?
How's the chow?
You know, you really shouldn't
wear so much eye makeup.
It makes you look cheap.
You're sittin' on my bunk.
Sorry.
Shut up!
Take your pants off.
Ah, I don't even know
your name.
Bend over.
Ben? Nice to meet you.
Victor Hugo.
You wouldn't happen to have
a middle name, would you?
Everybody else here seems to.
- What are you in for, Ben?
- Molesting a dead horse.
Ooh, there's no crime in that.
That's your right
as an American.
I'm tryin' to cut down myself.
His missus hit him on the head
with a ball pein hammer
whilst he was eatin' sausage...
and almost choked him
to death.
Okay, beautiful, let's hope
another long night in
the tank has sobered you up.
Ben?
If I don't hear from you
on Valentine's Day,
I'll be very disappointed.
- [Growls]
- [Laughing]
Mr. Johnson, I'm surprised
to see you here.
Judge Watkins usually
assigns these small potatoes
to Billy Ray.
Well, he's on vacation.
This is the price I pay
for the proximity of my office.
Excuse me. Sir?
You don't have a card,
do you?
Or a price list?
Well, matter of fact,
I do.
I'm Hamilton Johnson.
I'm an attorney at law.
You take other cases
or you just specialize in
transvestite necrophiliacs?
Not enough evidence
to hold you.
Just a petty form
of intimidation putting you
in a cell with that Neanderthal.
She wasn't so bad.
If she'd just fix up her hair
and shave her back.
It's so embarrassin',
this sort of thing still
goes on in the New South.
'Course, 20 years ago
a Yankee like you could've
been lyin' in the ditch.
I'm assumin', of course,
that you had nothin'
whatsoever to do with
the death of Amanda Ray.
Sure hope not.
Hop in.
I was shocked
to hear about this.
She was such
a dear friend.
So tragic...
when this happens
to somebody
so young and healthy.
Was she feelin' all right
last night?
She felt great to me.
[Hamilton]
Just smell that soft
Southern air.
It's so sad
to see this beautiful
pastoral countryside...
blighted by the greed
of a few men in pursuit
of the almighty dollar.
That's my place
over there.
The trees just beyond it
screen off the Bibleland
Amusement Park in the daytime,
but at night, they do make
a hell of a racket.
- Thanks for everything,
Hamilton.
- Most welcome. Just call me Ham.
Ham, call me Fletch.
All right, Fletch.
Anything I can do to help ya.
Fletch!
- Might I give you
some personal advice?
- Is it free?
To the sheriff and his sort
of people, you're an outsider.
Guilty in spite of the law.
Should I get outta town
before sundown?
It's not that bad, but...
if I were you,
lookin' for peace and quiet...
Well, they can make it
a might uncomfortable for ya.
It's gonna take time.
Thanks, Ham.
Bye.
My pleasure.
Anything I can do for ya.
Welcome back.
I thought you run off for good.
Does this car run?
Yeah, but Miss Belle
stopped drivin' it
when the brakes ran out.
I run a few errands
from time to time,
but if you wanna stop it,
you got to think ahead.
Hmm. I finally got the place
straightened out for you.
Mm-hmm. When was that?
Back in 1970?
Your Aunt Belle,
she lived in this one room.
Didn't take up much space.
Calculus?
Hmm?
You don't see
a spider, do you?
Spiders is good.
They eats the cockroaches.
Yeah, sure they do.
[Calculus]
Mister Owl.
This is more like it.
This is what
I came here for.
Yes, sir.
Peace and quiet.
Scum, scum, scum.!
Go back to where you come.!
- Friends of yours?
- Nothin' to me.
"The loyal sons of the...
[Klansman]
Buford, where's the cross.
Did you bring the cross?
"White race will not allow
any kind of alien infection...
to invade our beloved land."
Scum, scum, scum.
Go back to where you come.
Let's do it together.
Scum, scum, scum.
Go back...
Get the hell outta here
and go home!
Scum! Pigs!
Sorry I'm late.
Who goes there?
Henry Himmler.
What klavan claims you?
California klavan, Cucamonga.
California?
Yeah. I was passing through
town and was lookin' for
something to do this evening.
There was nothing goin' on
at the Rotary Club.
I heard about this.
Welcome, Henry.
I'm the Grand Kleagle.
Oh.
California thing.
Pig-faced scum!
What's the occasion here?
Oh, some undesirable
carpetbagger... I think.
Damn! Boys, I just got
a closer peek.
There's nobody in there.
We're wasting our time.
[Everyone Grumbling]
- And I washed all these sheets.!
- Wh-Who's this?
Oh. Sorry.
Hi, fellas.
Hank Himmler.
Hi, Hank.
The cross won't burn,
nobody home. Hell,
it ain't like it used to be.
You said it.
I couldn't get more than
13 guys out here tonight.
Five of them are green recruits.
Kinda stand-ins,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
We call 'em Klookies.
Klookies?
That's good! Of course,
it's just a contract job.
Yeah.
Contract job?
Yeah.! We've been havin'
a terrible time down here.
We've had to rent out.
Here I come!
[Speaking Nonsense Language]
[Nonsense]
Gene Hackman, kick your ass.
They're speakin' some kind
of African dialect!
[Nonsense]
Hi.
[Knocking On Door]
'Morning.
- Mr. Fletcher?
- As far as you know.
I'm Becky Ann Culpepper.
Thibodaux Realty.
I'd offer you some coffee
and eggs Benedict,
but we're all out of Benedict.
Thanks.
I've already eaten.
What can I do to...
for you?
Mr. Fletcher, you may have heard
that there's a party interested
in acquiring your property.
A substantial offer.
How substantial?
$250,000.
Whew!
I don't know.
I had big plans for this place.
Mini mall with a yogurt bar
and a tanning parlor.
Well, Mr. Fletcher,
all I know is $250,000...
is a mighty
generous price
for land in this area.
Who's your client?
I'm not at liberty to say.
Well, then I'm not
at liberty to sell.
This is a tremendous
opportunity.
I'll tell you what.
I'll consult with my people
who will contact their people,
and they'll get in touch
with your people.
Who are your people?
- Who are yours?
- As I said, I have
to keep that confidential.
Very well. I'll just have
my people contact each other.
Keep 'em busy.
All right.
Well, just keep me in mind.
Here's my card.
Oh, I'll keep you in mind.
Hope we can do this again
sometime soon.
In about 10 minutes?
[Fletch's Voice]
That night I decided to return
to the scene of the crime.
It gave me a chance to check out
my new car and practice
my parallel parking.
[Squeaking, Squealing Sound]
So far the only really
good suspect in Amanda's death
was me,
and I was pretty sure
that I didn't do it.
Amanda knew more
than she'd let on, but
the only clue she'd left me...
was a reference to Aunt Belle
changing her will
just before she died.
I knew the local police force
was watching her place
carefully...
so there'd be no trouble
getting in.
Over the years I found
Mr. Underhill's credit card
to be a useful tool...
much like Underhill himself.
As usual, I was willing to risk
my lifejust to get a peek
into a filing cabinet.
I love them when they're
unlocked, neatly organized and
tell me what I wanna know.
Belle's legal files
were in good order...
with the exception
of something missing under
the heading of"Bluebird."
My aunt had almost left
Belle Isle to some minister.
Obviously at one time
he must have touched her deeply.
Since she changed her mind,
I guess he didn't touch her
deeply enough...
or in the right place.
[Door Unlocking]
Thank you very much.
Couldn't find
that light switch.
What the hell you doin' here?
This is a restricted area.
Didn't you see the sign?
Signs? Signs!
That's all I see is signs.
Look at this.
Stressed out "dormants"
on the windows, walls that are
deplaning to an alarming degree.
Deplaning?
This house
is obviously infested with
reticulermes Mario Cuomos.
What's that?
What's what?
Reticulermes. You can't even
say it yourself.
They are deadly African
microscopic termites.
They can eat a hundred times
their weight in five minutes.
Much like yourself.
From the look of things,
I'd say...
this place is about
ready to collapse.
Who are you?
BillieJean King, Bug Busters.
My van is parked out front.
Mr. King, I don't know nothin'
about no Bug Busters.
The surgeon general was right.
They've been mighty busy here.
The only time
you can catch 'em
is at night.
Aha! I got one!
See that?
These little buggers
are the piranhas
of the insect world.
The only thing they like better
than wood is human flesh.
Really?
You bet.
If you can't see it,
how do you know you got one?
I'm glad I asked that question.
They make this horrible
high-pitched noise.
It's kinda like
a tiny little scream.
Can you hear that?
It's like a tiny
little piglet.
No? Uh-oh.
I seem to have dropped it
in your ear.
You what?
That's all right.
We better get that.
Can't let that nest in there.
They multiply by masturbation.
The only way to get that out
is to get as close to the floor
as you can.
Go on down to the floor.
That's right. They're drawn
to the floorboards.
Now shake your head like
you're trying to get water
out of your ear.
That's good. But hit it...
No, hit it harder. This side.
That's right.
Now make that scream.
That'll draw 'em out.
Squeal like a pig.
[Squealing]
A little higher.
Hey, I found the queen!
I found the queen!
I don't believe it.
No one's ever found a queen.
I gotta get this to the lab
and get a stool sample.
[Squealing]
[Fletch's Voice] After
my close call with Miss Piggy,
I couldn't wait to get home.
My head was filled
with decorating ideas.
I didn't have a lot of money,
but I could move the pool
closer to the house.
[Brakes Squealing]
I could see I wasn't gonna get
much privacy.
[Baseball Announcer,
Indistinct]
- Who's there?
- It's Avon calling.
Oh.! It's you.!
- I'd like to talk to you
for a minute.
- Yeah, come on in.
Come on in. Have a seat.
Make yourself at home.
What's on your mind?
Well...
[Water Sloshing]
What do you do?
Mud wrestle in this thing?
I'm sorry about that,
but I won it in a raffle.
Must be an art
to sitting in one of these.
Lost art.
You get the Lakers?
I'm lucky if I can get
Wheel of Fortune.
Do you know any reason why
somebody would want
to buy this land?
Insect research.
[TVAnnouncer]
Boston two-and-a-halfback
of the Yankees.
I have an offer
for $250,000.
Take the money and run!
What you thinkin'?
What do you know about
this Farnsworth Ministry?
Jimmy Lee Farnsworth?
Down here
everybody knows about him.
Your Aunt Belle used to
watch him when she was laid up.
...And that is
have you've been saved?
I know that there are a lot
of you out there tonight...
that the devil has got a good,
firm grip around your neck
and is choking you to death.!
Amen!
I want you to send
whatever you can afford.
If you've got a thousand
dollars in the bank,
don't be afraid to send
the whole thousand dollars.
I need your money. Bibleland
is only halfway there.
Bible... land.
The most important attraction...
since the crucifixion
itself.
[Man]
Immediate seating
for the 5:00 service.
The 5:00 service
is about to begin.
Immediate seating
for the 5:00 service.
Welcome, sinner.
Praise the Lord!
Bless you, bless her,
bless him. Hallelujah!
Name please.
Irwin Fletcher.
Irwin M. Fletcher.
Irwin Mahatma Fletcher.
Address.
Seven.
It's time
for the 4,323rd edition...
of the Farnsworth
Television Ministry with...
Mimsy Carlyle,
God's own songbird.
The heavenly feet
of Damon Feather.
Mr. Coco.
The Ringfield Revivalists.
The Bradley Family Singers
and Ted Medly
and the band.
And now, the host
of our show, the ministry's
founder and your friend...
Mr. Good News himself, the
Reverend Jimmy Lee Farnsworth.
I know that there is someone
out there tonight...
who needs to step forward.
Lyda Pearl Shindley.
Me?
Lyda Pearl, come on down here.!
Give her a big hand, folks.!
Make her welcome.!
All right.!
Bless you.
God bless you.
I know that you suffered
a terrible tragedy
when you lostJo Bob...
in the merry-go-round
accident at the State Fair.
I did.
I also know thatJo Bob
left you financially stable.
But answer me
this one question.
Has all of them riches
brung you happiness,
child?
No, they haven't.
I've sinned.
We've all sinned.
I know, but
I've really sinned.
[Man] Please, God,
have her not mention my name.
[Farnsworth]
Say it aloud so your soul
might be cleansed.
I'm so ashamed.
I slept with
my best friend's husband.
[Farnsworth]
You are forgiven.
Praise the Lord.
Amen!
- And I also slept
with my UncleJames.
- You are forgiven, child.
Ladies and gentlemen,
doesn't it take a tremendous
amount of courage...
to come up here on
nationwide cable hookup...
and confess
to human frailties?
And I also shoplifted
this blouse and...
You've been forgiven.
Demons out!
- [Applause]
- Praise be.! Praise the Lord.!
- Ladies and gentlemen,
praise be, praise the Lord.
- Bravo!
Surely Lyda Pearl
was not alone.
Surely there is someone else
out there whose life is full
of confusion.
[Ear Piece] Irwin M. Fletcher
just inherited Belle Isle.
I sense grief.
I sense deep grief
and loneliness.
I sense
a recent bereavement.
Someone who has lost
an uncle or an aunt.
Mr. Fletcher.
- Mr. Irwin M. Fletcher.
- That's me.
Are you out there?
Step forward, young man.
The Lord's calling to you.
Come on up here.
Give him a big hand.
Make him welcome.
Come on down here.
Your Aunt Belle recently
passed away, didn't she, son?
Yes, she did. Yeah.
Are you still grieving
in your heart, son?
Absolutely.
And even her
generous gift to ya
of the ancestral home,
the beautiful Belle Isle,
has not eased the grief,
pain and sufferin'
in your heart now, has it?
Not a hell of a lot.
No.
Irwin, admit
that you are a sinner.
Uh, well I've sinned.
Didn't take any Polaroids
or anything.
But... I've sinned.
Yeah.
The Lord forgives ya!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you. Amen.
What? Other sins?
Uh, I parked
in a handicapped spot
on my way over here.
Actually on
a handicapped person.
I told him I'd be out
in five minutes
so that's not such a big deal.
There have been other things.
They're personal, so I wouldn't
wanna get into it on TV.
But I have sinned
and I'm sorry about it.
Thanks.
God forgives ya!
[Audience]
Amen.!
The good Lord
is gonna ease...
the pain and sufferin'
in your heart...
with a bright light
of grace.
Look out, you demons!
Demons, demons, out!
Oh! That was great.
Praise the Lord.
Another soul saved
byJimmy Lee Farnsworth.
How about that?
[Fletch's Voice] I dangled
Belle Isle like bait in front of
Jimmy Lee and he took the hook.
I could tell, at the heart,
he was a deeply religious man
and I liked his teeth.
Once we've had
a chance to expand,
Bibleland's gonna be
like some kind
of heaven on earth...
if it isn't already.
- There's the hotel.
- Hi, Reverend.
We call it the Heavenly Hilton
and Convention Center.
Beyond that is the
Farnsworth Bible College.
If you look down the road,
you see theJump forJesus
Trampoline Center.
- What do you think?
- It's unbelievable.
You don't suppose
I use too many photographs
of myself, do ya?
No! No!
It worked for the Ayatollah.
Mr. Fletcher, your Belle Isle's
a bit rundown.
That sucker's gonna eat
you alive in maintenance.
You don't know how much your
land would mean to our ministry.
And to God, too, of course.
After all, he does give us
our guidance now, doesn't he?
- Amen!
- You bet your ass.
[Hamilton]
Like my mother used to say,
"There's a tick for every dog."
What did your mother
mean by that?
Why in God's name you let
Farnsworth's ministry burrow
into your fur?
Why would you even think of
givin' away your property when
you got a big cash offer on it?
I don't know.
I guess I thought, after
a lifetime of hedonism,
it was time
to rededicate my life.
Nah, I just wanted to see
what would happen
if I went along with him.
Well, it happened.
The sheriff's office called.
The charges against you
have been dropped.
Is that right?
Mm-hmm.
The ministry has a good deal
of influence around here.
I suppose you've heard
that your...
aunt was under considerable
emotional strain in the weeks
before she died?
Yeah, I've heard that.
So was my mother.
They took advantage of her.
These Holy Rollers.
When she was at death's door,
they preyed on her faith
and her fear.
When she was no longer able
to make rational decisions,
persuaded her
to give away our land
for that amusement park.
My guess is
that your speedy conversion
and your promised gift...
played no small part
in the charges against you
being dropped.
Well, whatever.
At least I'm off the hook.
And who or what
do they think is responsible
for Amanda Ray's death?
The autopsy report
come in today.
They said she died
of a heart attack.
Natural causes.
Either she had
some congenital defect...
or... you're one
hell of a lover.
Probably both.
[Fletch's Voice] I needed
more background on Farnsworth
so I called Frank for a favor.
Maybe I should've asked him
to check out Calculus Entterby.
I liked him, but I wasn't buying
his Amos and Andy routine.
He seemed a lot smarter
than that.
I never took you
to be no murderer.
That's a relief.
So who's the
odds on favorite now?
Nobody.
They're sayin' she dropped dead
in her sleep.
Yeah!
The odds on that?
Same as catchin' a bass
this afternoon.
What's that?
About 258,000 to one.
You sure you
don't wanna back out?
I'm in.
[Door Opens]
This be the morgue?
Have the police come yet?
What?
The police!
They was bringing a doctor
to make a death certificate.
You got a stiff, boy,
you're in the right place.
Where is it?
In my Cadillac.
Put him on the gurney.
Take him in the back
with the rest of'em.
Don't bother me.
I'm watchin The Terminator.
You better put
a steerin'wheel on that.
Excuse me, sir.
I'll be right back now.
- What's that stickin' out?
- His lucky golf cap.
Hey.!
You gotta tag his toe.
- He got a name?
- Eldridge Cleaver.
Take him in the back,
strip him. Hold it.
Let's see what Mr. Cleaver has,
or should I say, had.
Wait a minute.
Shouldn't I get that?
Tell you what.
I'll make you a deal.
You call me whenever
you want, I'll tell you
what time it is.
Now get movin;
- Eldridge Cleaver.
- Shh.
Good evening, Mr. Hoffa.
Amanda Ross. Amanda Ross.
Five.
**[Humming]
Can I take a look?
Yeah, go on.
- Boo!
- [Gasps]
Any mail for me?
You don't have a Tic-Tac,
do you?
What happened?
I black out?
Did I land
the plane safely?
Passengers hurt?
No.
[Fletch]
Everything's okay?
Check that air-conditioning.
[Calculus]
What'd you find out, Fletch?
Cremated. I wouldn't be
surprised if all the paperwork
was burnt up with the body.
[Fletch's Voice]
The morgue proved to be
a dead end.
[Laughs]
But I guess it is
for most people.
I had three questions.
Why was I cleared
in Amanda's death?
Why, if she wasn't murdered,
was the body
so quickly destroyed?
And finally, when it comes
to stewed prunes, are three
enough or are four too many?
When I got back to Belle Isle,
there was a cozy fire
in the fireplace...
and on the roof, on the walls
and on the porch.
It was great.
Think maybe I should pack.
Guess you'll be movin' in
with me now.
Thanks, Cal.
Look at the bright side.
You won't have to bother
dusting anymore.
Yes, sir!
** [Blues]
Here's your diet plate.
Thank you, Miss Selma.
Does everything around here
come with the head still on it?
- You bet, honey.
- Glad I didn't order
a hamburger.
I'd say grace,
but I don't wanna wake him up.
Are you religious?
I believe in a God that
doesn't need heavy financing.
How you doin',
Mr. Barbour?
How's it goin', Calculus?
Fine, fine.
This here's Mr. Fletcher.
He's the new owner
of Belle Isle,
or whatever's left of it.
Yeah, I heard
about your fire.
Sorry about that.
You know, you've had
your share of problems
ever since you've been here.
How about me and the boys
showing you some
real Southern hospitality?
You ever been
on a coon hunt?
Now a coon hunt is like
an English fox hunt, except
we cut through all the bullshit,
all the fancy clothes
and music,
all the beautiful women.
We reduce the experience
to its essence.
Yeah, a bunch of sweaty drunks
chasin' a scared animal.
You're damn right.!
What am I supposed to do?
The dogs do most
of the work.
We just follow the dogs,
they tree the coon,
we get him down.
[Men Laughing]
This drug testing
has gone too far.
Take a jolt.
Kick-a-poo joy juice?
Oh, stronger than that!
[Coughs]
Whoo!
Aren't you coming?
Nah, it ain't safe for a black man
to be chasin' around
these woods at night...
unless he be handcuffed
to a white man.
I'll see you back
at... my "domiside."
You want some of this?
[Men Chattering, Laughing]
[Fletch's Voice]
You haven't lived till
you've been on a coon hunt,
and after that,
you don't want to.
But it gave me a chance to
snoop around the neighborhood.
The ministry seemed so hot
for all this land. Why?
Maybe theyjust wanted a remote
spot to buryJim and Tammy.
[Fletch] Where
the hell are we?
Actually,
this is my place, or was.
I ain't been on it
since I sold the sucker.
This is your property over here
and that's Ham's mama's
old place over there.
Don't you think we oughta
catch up with the boys?
Damn right. There's a couple
of'em I don't think I should
leave alone with the dogs.
[Shouting]
[Barbour]
Oh, wait up.
Jesus! What happened
to my flower garden?
Everything's dead!
Yo, Barbour.!
Rags has got a water moccasin
in his mouth.
Hey, we in luck.
You wanna jerk the head
off a snake?
Oh, no.
I gave it up for Lent.
I'm not gonna miss the fun.
Hey, guys, wait up!
[Rifle Cocks]
[Fletch's Voice]
I never liked guns, especially
when they're pointed at me.
And this night a couple
of people were taking pot shots
in my general direction.
It was time
to get outta there.
11:27 to be exact.
* Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na-na **
[Fletch's Voice]
I was heartbroken to miss
the raccoon,
but all I wanted was
a good night's sleep
so I headed for Cal's water bed.
Welcome back.
Jimmy Lee was
on a roll tonight.
Ten salvations.
Big bucks.
You catch a coon?
I was shot at.
Somebody's sure trying
to scare me off.
And they don't mind killing me
to underline the threat.
You were shot at?
Yep. Now,
who would do that?
Damn shame.
I'll go outside
and see what's goin' on.
[Rifle Shot]
[Dogs Barking]
What was it?
I thought
I saw somethin'.
I just fired in the air
to scare whatever it was.
[Barking Continues]
[Sniffing]
[Fletch's Voice] Didn't sleep
well that night, and it wasn't
the fault of the water bed.
Something was rotten
in this whole situation.
Figuring out that the thug
who dropped my watch...
was the same guy
who stole it at the morgue
didn't take Sherlock Holmes.
Larry Holmes
could've figured that out.
I wasn't sure who'd be taking
the next shot at me,
so I decided to work alone.
Fletch, perfect timing.
I've got just
what you asked for.
Frank, stop salivating.
I'm sending you my Laker
high-tops for lab analysis.
He's behaving very strangely.
He must be in trouble.
Somebody must be holding
a gun to his head.
Fletch, if you need rescuing,
just say,
"I believe Louisiana
is the Pelican State."
Okay, Frank. I believe Louisiana
is the Pelican State...
as a matter of fact.
- What do you have on Farnsworth?
- I've got everything you need.
Jimmy Lee Farnsworth,
former used-car salesman
in Biloxi.
In '77, he pleaded
"no contest" to a charge
of check kiting.
'81, discovered by businessmen
who helped him found the
Farnsworth Television Ministry.
Our sources indicate
he may be a target
of federal investigation.
- Anything else?
- Uh, two marriages.
One daughter goes by
wife's maiden name.
Becky Culpepper.
[Fletch's Voice] It was hard
to believe that beautiful Becky
was Farnsworth's daughter.
But I wasn't gonna hold it
against her.
If I was gonna hold anything
against her, it certainly
wouldn't be her father.
[Brakes Squealing]
[Putting Coins Into Meter]
Fletch, I
heard about the fire.
I hope you're all right.
I'm just fine.
I was just lying in the embers
of my house, trying to calm
my nerves after being shot at.
What? You were shot at?
I was thinking what a good day
to sell my property...
and move back to Los Angeles.
Is the buyer
still interested?
No, I'm afraid
he withdrew.
I still have five minutes
on the meter.
Let's talk in your office.
Now, why don't you tell me
who your client is?
Is it the
Farnsworth Ministry?
Why would you say that?
And who is shooting at you?
Maybe the
Reverend Farnsworth.
Look, Jimmy Lee Farnsworth
may be a lot of things,
but he's not a murderer.
You're right,
he is many things.
A former used-car salesman,
a confessed embezzler,
your father, good square dancer.
That's right,
he is my father.
But I'm also
telling you the truth.
Becky, somebody wants
my land bad enough
to kill me for it.
Now, if you don't tell me
who your client is, I'm gonna
find out some other way.
[Announcer]
It is guest healer's night
with Jimmy Lee on this...
the 4,323rd edition
of our show with tonight's
special guests...
people with
the healing gift.
Excuse me.
May I have your name?
I'm Claude Henry... [Mumbles]
Claude Henry...
Claude Henry.
Claude...
Claude or Clod is good.
Henry.
Smmoot.
Smmoot. S-M-M-O-T-T.
I'm sorry. Two "O's," one "T."
I'm a guest healer.
Smmoot, a guest healer.
Yes. Healed.
God bless you.
With Mimsy Carlyle.
Wait here.
The heavenly feet...
of Damon Feather.
God's simian favorite,
Mr. Coco.
The guest healers who have
volunteered for tonight's show
will followJimmy Lee.
And now the founder
of our show,
your friend,
Mr. Good News himself,
Jimmy Lee Farnsworth.!
[Farnsworth]
You know,
I have a feeling that there's
someone out there amongst us
who needs to step forward.
Gordon JoeJames.
Who are you?
Gordon Joe lost a limb
to a pit bull.
Gordon Joe, will you please
stand and raise your right hand?
Left hand.
[Farnsworth]
Excuse me, left hand.
There you are.!
[Fletch's Voice]
Bibleland Two.
Jimmy Lee's dream.
He was like some deranged
Walt Disney.
It was all in front of me.
Ham Johnson's place.
His mother's bequest.
Belle Isle.
The numbers on the boxes
were certainly not zip codes.
Maybe computer codes.
All I needed now was a computer,
and a ten-year-old kid
to teach me how to use it.
* Cash or check *
* Or MasterCard *
[Chorus]
*MasterCard **
Bobby Ralph?
Peter Lemongello.
Your house is on fire.
What?
They told me to tell you,
your house is on fire.
I'll take over.
God bless you!
God bless you
for believing this shit.
[Fletch's Voice]
There was a new element I hadn't
anticipated: A second suspect.
Becky's client was not the
ministry, but some secret entity
called Everest Development.
She never knew who they were.
Becky was a good girl,
and wouldn't have to be spanked.
Damn it.
Who's gonna be the next one
to get the call?
Who's gonna be
the next one saved?
- Who's going to be...
- T'Boo Ted Marshall.
T'Boo Ted Marshall,
are you with us tonight?
Yes, indeed, Reverend.!
But how can God help my problem?
T'Boo Ted is a...
[Chuckles]
Compulsive gambler.
T'Boo Ted, the first you
gotta do is expose that problem!
Excuse me?
If you can't expose
that problem,
at least to your family,
it grows and grows, and becomes
an even bigger problem.!
That's true!
He's been a compulsive gambler
for 20 years.
Because you've had
this affliction
for more than 20 years,
I think you should
expose that problem to us...
right here... tonight.
I want you to do it.
The good Lord wants you
to do it!
- You really think so?
- I know so!
Do it. Do it now!
[Audience Chattering]
Well, if you say so.
[Audience Screaming]
[Farnsworth] Oh, God,
put your pants back on.!
[Announcer]
Coming right back to introduce
our guest healers.
Let's welcome all of them
beginning with
Claude Henry Smmoot.
Come on out, Claude!
Here we are.
I have a headache.
No, Claude, this way.
You're gonna do just fine.
Now, get out there. Go on.
I said, get out there now!
Here he is!
Make him welcome, folks!
Welcome, Claude Henry.
When was the very first time,
the very first moment
that made the difference
in your life?
Well, Jimmy Lee, I was...
I was, uh,
on my gazebo, on the roof
making some repairs,
and I was struck
by lightning.
I have had acute
migraine headaches and
blurred vision since then.
But praise the Lord,
that was my lucky day
because...
ever since then I have had
the healing power.
Amen. God bless you.
Thank you very much.
Good night. Thank you.
Claude Henry.
Good night. What?
What happened? Yes?
Before you heal another,
would you like for me to attempt
to heal your own affliction?
No, no! No, no.
No, those of us
with perfect faith...
have no need
of perfect vision.
We have no need of wisdom.
We have no need of anything
except the creature comforts
and lots of them.
Hallelujah.! Amen.!
God bless you. Amen.
Thank you. Hallelujah.
Ladies and gentlemen,
he sees more than he doth know.
- Yes, I do.
- [Audience]
Amen!
Claude Henry has the gift.!
Would you use that gift,
Claude Henry?
Would you use it now?
I guess I could.
Praise be.
Reverend, I sense that
in our audience...
there is a gentleman
by the name ofJim Bob.
Jim Bob, would you stand up?
Would you rise, please?
Sixteen, 17...
I sense thatJim Bob
is a young man.
That he is between
the ages of 25, 27.
That's more like it.
I feel the Lord
is telling me thatJim Bob
suffers from the same...
Satanized affliction
that I suffer from:
Migraine headaches.
Don't you, Jim Bob?
Is that you?
Come on down, Jim Bob.!
Praise be.! Hallelujah.!
Amen.!
Praise the Lord!
Be saved!
Jim Bob, welcome.
God bless you.
Jim Bob, how long have
you had these headaches?
About five, 10 minutes.
God... help him!
- And how do you feel now?
- It's a throbbing...
God bless you.
A throbbing headache comes
up through your heels,
up through the hip bone,
the knee bone, up the spine,
up through your back,
through your head
like Satan was belching
through you?
- Is that it?
- Exactly.
- Do you believe?
- I believe.
He believes!
Hallelujah! Amen!
God bless. Amen.
Hallelujah.
[Panting]
Rid this man
of these headache demons,
of these migraine demons.
Heal this man!
Amen!
[Audience]
Hallelujah!
Oh, good golly, Miss Molly!
How do you feel, son?
My headache is gone, but...
God bless him!
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
No! No.
Good! God bless you.
Praise be.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you so much.
Ouch!
I am worn to the bone.
Thank you very much for
gracing us with your presence.
Good night. Praise be!
[Fletch's Voice]
Maybe I was wrong
about Farnsworth.
There was a new player
in the game:
Becky's unknown client.
I had to find out more,
and the only way
was to get into her pants...
I mean, her car.
At least it had brakes.
Her car, that is.
Fletch, what
are you doing?
The guy who works in there
stole my watch.
He dropped it while he was
trying to kill me. I'd just
as soon he not recognize me.
I'd like to keep an eye on him.
Maybe he'll lead us to his boss.
How long are we
gonna be here?
Bored?
Oh, no!
This is exciting!
Fletch?
What?
I have to pee.
The same thing used
to happen whenever
I'd play hide-and-seek.
I always got caught.
You think the morgue
has a ladies' room?
- [Motorcycle Motor Revs]
- [Becky] Hey.
Not so close.
Try to get a little distance
between you.
I'm gonna have to play it
pretty tough in there.
Still have to pee?
I gather the rain
isn't helping a lot.
- There's always the bushes.
- I'll be okay.
If I'm not back in five minutes,
call your dad.
**[Rock]
[Whistling, Whooping]
[Squeaky Voice]
Could I have a soda, please?
Diet Pepsi or a Tab
would be good.
- Hey, pussy.
- Name's Ed.
Ed Harley.
Are you sure
you're in the right place?
I think so.
[Squeaky Voice]
"Think so"!
[Everyone Laughing]
Ed, what are you doin' here?
I'll give you a hint.
Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
Hmm?
You don't get it?
You're the one
that doesn't get it.
Ed Harley.
Harley-Davidson Motorcycles.
You own the company?
Well, my granddaddy started it.
Then my daddy screwed Davidson
out of his half.
Now I own the whole thing.
- Harley-Davidson?
No shit?
- No shit.
Hey, y'all, Ed Harley
of Harley-Davidson!
We're the Nazis from Natchez!
**[Rock]
Who're you callin',
babe?
[Hooting, Whistling]
Knock it off!
Yo, boss,
look who's here!
Harley-Davidson.
Yo, Ed, come over here
and meet the boss.
Hi. Ed Harley, the Third.
Harley-Davidson Motorcycles.
If you need any T-shirts
or decals, I can make
arrangements for you.
I just can't wait.
- What model do you ride?
- '78 XL.
'78 XL? That's a legend!
It's not blue, is it?
- You in luck, white boy.
Come on.
- Oh!
There she is.
Ain't she beautiful?
Original blue!
Oh, she is a beaut.
Gee, golly, I'd love to ride
this '78 XL.
Nobody...
touches my Hog.
- Sorry.
- If you wanna ride that
low-rider, that's all right.
Hell, we'll all ride.
Fire 'em up!
Do you mind if...
Darleen.
- If Darleen rides with me?
- Feeling a little horny, Ed?
Yeah. You know,
my life isn't all hubs
and gears.
Take it easy.
*All right now *
*Hey, hey
We're gonna go out tonight *
Little murky in the oxydol.
We're gonna flush that out,
suck it, streamline it.
Hey, your mustache
looks funny.
Oh, boy.
Hey, look at that!
Came off.
* One for the money
Two for the show *
* Gotta go, let's go
Hey, hey *
* Gonna go out tonight *
* Gonna have some fun *
*Everything
will be all right **
What're we gonna do?
Something that will seem
extremely stupid at first.
[Screams]
Oh, my God!
Yee-ha!
Home!
Oh, my God!
I'm a mess.
You want some coffee?
Sure.
I look like a raccoon.
I gotta get to work, although
I don't know why. All I do
is sit with nothing to do.
The only work I've had
in the last three months
has been with Everest Realty.
And look what that's
gotten me.
Can I use your phone?
Sure, go ahead.
That's toxic waste on the soles.
What have you been doing?
Jogging in the Love Canal.
What do you mean
"toxic waste"?
- It's special. There's only
11 places that make this shit.
- Where?
Frank, just give me the ones
that aren't in New Jersey.
Ah, there's only one.
Yazoo, Mississippi.
Bingo.
I wanna thank you
for everything you've done.
I'm sorry I caused
such a mess.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
Mm-hmm.
Did you finally get
to pee?
Yes.
Good.
You better get cleaned up.
Yeah.
Particularly my mind.
Where's the shampoo?
I'll get you some.
Here. You'll need
a clean towel too.
No, yours will be fine.
[Screams]
Fletch!
[Becky Laughing]
[Fletch]
You're right.
This is too wet.
[Becky Laughing]
[Fletch] You know how
to get to Yazoo?
[Becky]
Well, you're in
the right vicinity.
[Fletch's Voice]
The church seemed less
and less culpable.
Why would they want
toxic waste next to their land?
Why would anybody?
Why are there four S's
in Mississippi?
Four I's and only two P's...
and one "M"
as far as I know?
Bly Bio Chem was the biggest
chemical plant in Mississippi.
My Laker shoes were ruined
by toxic waste produced there.
They probably knew who
delivered it to my backyard.
Now the lead-lined
containers painted
with innocent bluebirds...
added a crucial piece
to the puzzle...
that had begun way back
in Amanda Ross's pants...
I mean, bedroom.
This is a secure area.
I'm very happy for you.
Most people live
in terrible neighborhoods.
Are you the head honcho?
That's right, sir.
Headly Dan Duke.
And what seems
to be your problem?
I agreed to take a shit load
of that Bluebird crap
off your hands.
And it ain't come yet.
I'm very sorry, sir.
And you are?
I are pissed!
Some damn fool told me
it was on back order,
and I'd have to wait.
Whose signature is this?
Who signed that?
I can't...
That's the trouble!
It's typical
of a large corporation.
Lack of communication.
That's why I like
to keep Everest small.
Oh, you're from Everest!
Now you're talkin'!
Elmer Gantry.
Elmer Fudd Gantry.
I'm not
sure there's anything I can do.
You could pull my file
instead of standing there
pulling your pud!
Whatever you say, sir.
Bring me the Everest file.
[Woman]
Yes, sir.
[Screaming]
Mr. Gantry?
I apologize
for my bellicosity.
I've had a hernia operation.
Is that the stuff
I'm supposed to get?
[Duke] Yes, sir.
Why are they wearing
those funny suits?
They're protective, as you know.
That's a very corrosive
by-product they're handling.
Oh, yeah. I guess if they
didn't wear those suits,
those boys would be
so full of holes, they'd
whistle when they walked.
[Groans]
I've been spitting up blood,
pissing blood, bleeding.
I go through five
of these suits a day.
It appears you have
your facts wrong, Mr. Gantry.
Your company is supposed
to get 1500 gallons.
Destination someplace
called Belle Isle in Louisiana.
Signed for by an officer
of your company
and due the 23rd.
So... we're right,
and you're wrong.
Let me see that.
Takes a big man
to admit when he's wrong.
I am not a big man.
We're late again,
because you had
to stay late at thejail.
Hurry up.
Just get out.
[Woman Screams]
Are you all right?
[Woman]
You're wrecking my present.
[Man] My fault?
Wash and gas it.
Check the brake fluid, will ya?
[Clinking Glass]
My friends,
ladies and gentlemen.
With all the fun we've been
having, I hope we don't forget
our real purpose here tonight...
to preserve the legacy
that nature has given us.
We are mere custodians of...
Bob Lee.
Bobby Lee. Bobby Lee.
Bobby Lee.
Bobby Lee Schwartz.
Schwartz.
Schwartz, the Second.
Fletch!
What you doin' here?
- What are you doin' here?
- You know me. I ain't happy
unless I'm working.
Why, Fletch, I'm surprised
to see you here, sir.
Welcome, sir, welcome.
My pleasure, my pleasure.
Thank you
for not inviting me.
Oh!
I do believe we have
something to discuss.
Oh. Well, might I suggest
we repair ourselves
to a quieter place.
Let us remove ourselves,
shall we?
Son of a gun,
we'll have big fun
on the bayou.
My mama's room.
I've kept it
just the way it was
when she died.
Her ashes?
She used to say,
"We come from the earth
and we return to the earth,
and in between,
we garden."
[Chuckles]
A little gardening,
a little polluting.
They spelled my name wrong.
My gun's made of rubber.
How 'bout yours?
No.
I see your point.
Wouldn't do for your
conservationists guests
to hear about...
that load of toxic waste
heading for my land
at Belle Isle.
My land...
at Belle Isle, Fletch.
After you die, who's gonna
prove that you did not sell
your land to Everest?
You may have this town
in your back pocket, Johnson,
but there are a lot of people
downstairs who are gonna be
very interested...
in the hows and whys
of Amanda Ray's death.
She knew about Bluebird.
She started a file on you,
and you found out about it.
That was my lucky night.
The night I found the Bluebird
file, the night you porked her.
I figured it was like an
alligator shoot on the freeway,
if you'll excuse the metaphor.
- It's not a metaphor.
It's a simile, to be precise.
- Whatever.
So you poisoned Amanda,
figuring I'd sell and get out
if I was facing a murder charge.
- I don't scare easy.
I'm too dumb.
- So it would seem.
Now get out of
my mama's chair before I put
the first bullet up your nose.
Are you kidding?
You pull that trigger
and 100 people
will be up here in a second.
My dear boy,
why would I do
my own dirty work?
Those hundred do-gooders
down there
dressed in rebel crap...
will be my alibi.
Now get outta
my mama's chair!
I synchronized
my beloved Laker watch
with Miss Culpepper's Timex.
If I don'tjoin her at
the ministry in 10 minutes,
the whole ugly story...
goes out on
the Farnsworth Network.
Of course, it's cable, but...
- You're bluffing, Fletch.
- No, I'm not.
You think you're not...
but you are.
Swell.
- Did he hurt you?
- Not yet.
That comes later.
Sorry, Becky.
The band won't take
a break for some time, so
screaming would be futile.
Mr. Fletch's convenient
appearance has allowed us...
to move up our plans
for your demise
to coincide with his.
Now I'm goin' downstairs
to be the gracious host.
Do what you have to do.
- The bride of Frankenstein.
- Put my mama down!
- Oh! I'm sorry.
- [Glass Shattering]
Oh, how clumsy of me.
Oops! I'm sorry.
I stepped right on
her mustache.
Get away! Get away!
- Sorry.
I was just trying to help.
- It's all right, Mama.
You should be more careful
where you put your breakables.
I've been careful
all my life.
When she was sick,
I was careful.
Then that goddamn
Jimmy Lee's ministry...
taking everything she had.
Bloodsuckers!
It's gonna be all right, Mama.
And when we're far, far away...
from this godforsaken
chemical swamp,
we're gonna sit back
and watch 'em all
just decompose.
That should be good for
Bibleland's business, all their
customers glowing in the dark.
I hope they all fry
in hell!
- You bloodsucking bastards!
- Isn't this interesting?
- Put that down.
- She really is in there.
- She seems to have lost
a little weight.
I thought you had her
stuffed and mounted.
Here she is. Head's up!
Ohh! Ohh!
Becky!
Swine...
Darryl, are you having
a good time?
[Scream, Ghostly Laugh]
[Gasps]
[Screams]
[Man]
Welcome to great Noah's Ark...
where we have a flood
every 10 minutes.
- In the...
- [Loud Splashing]
[Screams]
No! This way.
[Farnsworth's Voice]
Join our pyramid of prayer.
[TV]
For only $12,
you begin your exciting journey
up the pyramid.
And when you reach the top,
you're gonna be the target
of 20,000 prayers!
A lady in Fargo, North Dakota
broke the chain and began
a five-day fit of sneezing...
that ended in her death.
Daddy?
Well, Mr. Fletcher,
what a pleasant surprise.
And, Becky, what are you...
Look who's here!
Hamilton Johnson!
Friend of the community.
Ham, you look like you've
worked up quite a sweat.
Maybe you should dry
your hair first.
Do you want a towel?
- [Audience Gasps]
- Uh-oh, he's got a gun.
Show your lovely face on
national television. Let 'em see
that greedy glint in your eye.
Let 'em hear
that bullshit chuckle, Ham.
Who's gonna save you now,
Fletch?
You'll have to shoot
through me,
you son of a bitch!
He's not gonna shoot anybody.
Are you, Ham?
You're on television now.
- You haven't got the guts.
- [Gun Cocks]
- My mistake.
- Freeze!
F.B.I. Drop the gun!
I said, drop it.
Harry!
- [Groans]
- [Gunshot]
And it's my plan to rerun
this incident every night
during Sweeps Week.
The obvious question is...
What did you know
and when did you know it?
And how long did you plan
on letting me twist in the wind?
Up to a point.
The Agency was barking up
the same tree you were.
Jimmy Lee's finances.
Yep.
It was easy for Harry
and Field Officer Vincent
to infiltrate the ministry.
Field Officer Vincent?
That's Mr. Coco's
real name.
We've been working on
this case for over a year.
Excuse me, Agent Goldstein,
the officer would like
to speak to you.
Surely.
Goldstein?
[Reporter]
Thank you, sir.
Ding dong,
the wicked witch is dead.
So what's next, Fletch?
Back to L.A.?
There's no place like home.
Unless home is here.
You know what?
We gotta get you away
from this chemical swamp.
I was wondering...
Do you like smog?
[Fletch's Voice]
Back home there was
a surprise party for me.
But the nicest surprise
was an insurance check for
the Belle Isle fire... $ 100,000.
However, no one stopped
Bly Bio Chem from dumping
that toxic waste on my land.
They told me not to worry.
Its half-life was estimated
at 3,000 years.
Everything okay, Fletch?
Betty was a little pissed off
about giving up her office,
and accounting gave me
some flak about the new car,
but trust me,
everything's gonna be
just the way you want it,
maybe better.
I like your attitude, Frank.
Excuse me
just a sec.
What a guy!
I thought I told you...
never to come
to my workplace.
Time's change, my dear Fletch.
Rumor has it that you
have inherited
a sizable piece of property.
Who told you?
I have my sources too.
These sources also suggest
that you may have been
considering skipping town...
and retiring
on this vast estate.
Thus skipping out on your
financial responsibilities.
Would I do that?
Wendy could probably get
half of it anyway.
So in return for the other half,
we would forego
any other claims.
Think about it.
You would never see me again.
Where do I sign?
I'll never see you again?
Never.
You realize this is
my family land?
Does it please you to
rip out my ancestral roots?
I was born and raised
in a briar patch.
Now Wendy can live
a life of leisure.
Clean air, clean water.
This is the way
she was destined to live.
Okay, Gillet.
You've broken me.
I hope you're happy.
*Hey, hey
We gonna go out tonight *
* We gonna have some fun
Everything will be all right *
* Ohhh *
*All right *
*Make a change in your life *
*And make it for the better *
*Don't you wait no longer *
*Itjust set you back further *
*It's not for the young *
*It's not for the old *
*It's not for the crazy *
*It's not for the bold *
*It's not for one generation *
*It's for
the whole damn nation *
*I say, the whole
damn nation *
*Make a change in your life *
*And make it for the better *
*Don't you wait no longer *
*Itjust set you back further *
*It's not for
the black and white *
the yellow and red *
*It's not for
the sick and homeless *
*It's not forjust one race *
*It's not for
one generation *
*It's for
the whole damn nation *
*I say, the whole
damn nation *
*Make a change in your life *
*And make it for the better *
*Don't you wait no longer *
*Itjust set you back further *
*It's not for the young *
*It's not for the old *
*It's not for the crazy *
*It's not for the bold *
*It's not for one generation *
*It's for the whole
damn nation *
*I say, the whole
*Make a change in your life *
*Make it for the better *
*Don't you wait no longer **