It seems like a ridiculous idea!
We should give them a chance.
They have to go somewhere
They are criminals,
Their file says so.
Is that also the opinion of this
parole board?
Well sir, they are not exactly
a family rolemodel,
But... there are clear signs that they
want to better themselves.
It's our duty to offer them
a better place to live.
They've lived on a toxic waste dump
for years without knowing it.
The city was not aware of that either.
But we have a responsibility
If it had taken a bit longer they
would not be alive to talk about it.
Don't bring us to ideas
There are various examples that
show us...
OUCH
Say Milly, can you get a plaster.
This man has hurt himself by his own report
Hey you sonofabitches,
Watch out what you do with that clock.
It belonged to your grandma!
Easy, Kees
Are you ok?
Yeah I got it. Lower it down.
Are there any more crates coming?
Just the boiler.
Hurry up guys. This truck has to
be back at 5 o'clock.
Mom...
You want him to come too?
Where did you find him?
I didn't see that ugly face in 10 years.
It was under your bed.
Get rid off it. I dont want anything
to do with your father.
Is that my father?
His father, not yours.
I'm sorry
I've no idea what you want to proof
with these kind of experiments
I think... the city can't ignore
their responsibility
But putting them in a villa in the
better part of our city...
a place with a high status
Isn't there a more suitable place
for these people?
They rather be among their own kind.
Verschuur. There are more empty
houses in other districts, right?
There's not much choice.
Our files have become pretty thin.
In some districts that were available
people were protesting against their arrival.
- Nobody wants them
- But that's crazy!
The only option that we have left
is the villa in district Zonnedael
That house has been empty for years.
It can finally be used for what it is meant for.
- To have people inside.
- People?!?
No reading now grandpa, we are moving.
Take it to the truck.
You want to poop, old man?
Yeah yeah, I'll be careful with
those trains of yours.
CATCH!
There, almost finished.
It could be that a completely different
living environment in a...
totally different society...
direct or not direct...
and fully or partially being forced in
patterns that are acceptable for our society.
I'm glad that you are so confident
in your case.
- In my report I discover...
- Yeah yeah I've read your report.
During my observations with the family
I've noticed they are willing to co-operate
We cannot let them down.
Deep inside...
they are very sensitive people.
And you really have to fuck off, little shit.
- Mom!  Someone here from the newspaper.
- Newspaper?
- Yeah they want to write something.
- What about?
- What do you want?
- Peters, Daily Breaker.
- Are you from a newspaper?
- Yes, can I ask you a couple of questions?
What do you want to ask?
How do you feel after living for years on a toxic dump.
Are you not extremely happy that you can leave?
Well, we didn't know about that toxic waste.
You knew nothing?
We always have tearing eyes.
And we were itchy.
Especially when it had rained.
- And that smell... It's awful eh?
- What smell?
Nobody protested against their arrival?
Not that I know of.
Well, having criminals as neighbours
Isn't a very appealing prospect.
- We didn't tell them.
- Didn't tell them?! They know nothing?
I think the press will love it.
The city giving a chance to the poor people.
Well gentlemen... and lady...
we have to make a decision.
It's almost lunchtime...
Millie, what do you think?
I dont know... it seems nice for these
people to have... a villa like that.
Yeah showing our good will can't hurt.
And the elections are arond the corner.
Alright, we'll try it for half a year
and after that we will see what happens.
- Have you seen the new house yet?
- No, we only heard yesterday where we are going.
So, a big surprise then.
Shall we make a picture?
- A picture? of what?
- Well, of the entire family....
- Well eh paying...
- a hundred bucks!
- A hundred euros?!!
- No, a hundred bucks. Otherwise no picture.
You understand you are going to
carry a heavy burden on your shoulders.
I know for sure they wont hurt my trust.
I hope you are right.
A little more to the right. Yes.
a bit more.
Quiet you guys
Shut up and sit still
- Hey you will behave, right?
- What do you mean??
- I stay the way I am.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
Watch it, pops.
What a stiff place
Hello ladies!
Hi neighbour!
I feel at home already
- Are you the new neighbour?
- No I'm eh...
a friend of the family.
I have the keys.
It's about time.
This place was empty for a while now.
Do you hear that, Pipita.
You are getting new neighbours.
- What kind of people are they?
- Ehm...
- Just normal.
- If it isn't another doctor.
We already have 4 of them here.
- Always those bloody stories, it makes you sick.
- Well, don't worry about it.
Ah, that must be them.
This must be the place, number 13.
Our lucky number.
Awesome!
What are that?
Hello Johnny.
Hi Sjaak, old wanker.
- Everything went well with the movement?
- No problem at all, Sjakie.
I like this place.
You did a fine job.
- Well Mrs. Flodder, what do you think?
- We dont have much choice, eh.
Well eh, a lot of people would jump
a hole in the air for a house like this.
Get that old fart out of the truck.
Henkie, go get that suitcase.
Look at this Johnny, a swimmingpool!
And the people here?
Is this a good neighbourhood?
- A good neighbourhood?!
- Yeah, I dont want to lower myself.
This is the best neighbourhood of the city.
All kinds of doctors and directors
Nah, we will see.
Everything is provided for.
Swimmingpool.
Big carpet.
Always sun.
Get out of my way, little bastard!
Gimme those keys.
I already took care of the residence permit.
It can be picked up before 11 o'clock tomorrow morning.
11 o'clock!!
Everybody is still snoring at that time.
Hey what the fuck is going on in here!
- This is my room!
- I was here first.
- I'm the oldest.
- Both of you, get lost!
This will be MY room.
- Are you ok, Sjakie?
- Yes... I'm fine.
These boys are so playful.
Mrs. Flodder, you know how much trouble
I went through to get you here, right.
It cost the city a lot of money.
It wasn't very easy.
You will do your best to... adapt a bit.
I mean, you wont let me down.
You make sure that it stays.... nice here.
Dont worry Sjakie. We wont be a bother.
I swear it.
Hurry up, lazy bastards!
Hey dont drop those fuckers!
Come on!
Watch out!
Stop bitching around.
That truck has to be back at five.
Hurry up!
- It is scum.
- What are you saying, my dear?
Our new neighbours.
It's unbelievable.
- How is it possible that they came right here.
- Yeah, they are indeed...  different.
*Praying*
Amen.
Dinner
Look, for you.
Come on grandpa.
Eat a bit faster.
Dont make a mess.
There you go.
On a moment like this I think it's
time to say a few good words.
I think so too
I want to thank the city counsel...
The mayor himself...
That they were able to let us, simple citizens,
live in a simple house like this.
- Also I want to thank one person specially...
- oh yeah, who?
Who stole all our hearts and could not...
unfortunately, be here with us tonight.
Sjaak....  old wanker.
- Cheers!
Hey pass that bottle to me.
Johnny, look at that house,
it's full of antique stuff.
- That's worth a lot.
- Wanna take a look?
Hey no fooling around now.
We promised mom not to pull any stunts...
...for now.
Johnny, look at those horny chicks.
Slow down a bit.
- Hello ladies, how are you doing?
- None of your business.
Can I pick up your balls?
- You watch your own balls...
- If you have any.
Aahh those chicks.
- A bit too young.
- Yeah maybe for you.
Hey wanna have fun tonight!
For 25 bucks I'll arrange a date.
That's too much around it.
*talking gibberish*
There are no trains there.
*More gibberish*
You are not the one that is pushing!
I'm really tired.
*gibberish*
Alright then, just one more block.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Morning Mrs. Wijnberg. Morning Mrs. Frцbel.
How are you doing?
- You're looking good, Mathilde.
- Thank you.
Five days Hawaii with Arend-Jan is wonderful.
Going away is just great.
- It's just that awful jetlag...
- Yes they should do something about that.
Yes exactly.
Van Putten, did you get those snails
I asked you about?
Ofcourse Mrs. Frцbel. Look, ordered especially
for you. Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Goodmorning Mrs. Neuteboom.
Morning.
You dont look so happy.
New people have moved in next door.
- Oh yes? I have to meet them then.
- I wouldn't do that.
How come?
Well well, that's damn easy.
- Ehm, are you looking for something?
- Bloodsausage, 3 pounds... my son loves it!
Look at that.
- Wanna get her?
- Yeah let's go.
Hey, fuck off!
Asshole, give it back!
Give me that cap.
- What are you doing here? This is our neighbourhood
- None of your business.
- You are anti-social people, you dont belong here.
- Give me that cap.
Hey hey, watch your mouth, little bitch.
What did you say buddy.
- Anything else?
- No.
Now fuck off!
What the hell did you do?
He fell into the water.
He always has something.
Well put him in the sun so that he can dry.
- U,h oh.
- What's wrong?
The police, put it away.
Put it away!
- Good afternoon officer, we weren't speeding, I think.
- Papers!
- Give this gentleman the papers.
- Papers?
In the cupboard there.
- Is there a problem, officer.
- Who are they?
These are my brothers.
- And what are you doing here?
- What do you mean, officer?
We are just driving around.
That's not legal, is it?
- Aren't you a bit lost from home?
- I dont think so. We live behind there.
Oh yeah, that's true.
There's the garbage dump, eh.
Did you hear that, Kees.
These gentlemen live here, hahaha.
- I know you... And your family as well.
- Oh really, sir?
And dont think you can pull some shit here.
I'm gonna pay attention to your family.
You in particular!
And if I notice something, I will get ya!
And then you wont get off again so easily.
And I know plenty of colleagues that appreciate
a good private conversation with you.
I like a good conversation.
And now, get lost.
- The neighbourhood is getting worse.
- What?
- The Blommenstein residence has new people in it.
- Oh yes?
I bumped into Mr. Wijberg
According to him they are complete anti social.
How can that be?
How did they get here?
The city seems to be behind it.
Some kind of arrangement.
They didn't ask us anything,
while Mr. Frцbel knows everyone there.
I will call Bredero.
Bredero?
As chairman of the tennisclub it seems like he's
the right person to mobilize the neighbourhood.
We must prevent infiltration of
people that dont belong here.
Maybe something would happen here at last.
Tomorrow I will check it out and see
the nature of the threat.
We can determine our strategy then.
Aye aye sir.
Dirty bastard, dont touch your sister!
From now on everybody stays in their own bed!
- When are we getting a new car?
- When we win the jackpot.
Everyone is driving fancy cars here.
Only we have an old piece of shit.
There has to be a difference.
The guy next door has a car dealership.
Did you know that?
- What, the guy of that CX?
- Yeah, he sells them.
What do you want to do.
Ask for a new car?
Well... Maybe I will do that.
Easy, nice doggy.
Calm down calm down.
Can you start it?
There, for now it works.
Move over. We're gonna get some icecream.
What did you find in the garbage?
Hey you!
Are you deaf?!?
Ah, so you can hear me speak correctly.
Yeah, but I doubt if he'll understand it.
What are you doing here?
I'm just looking. Is that against the law?
- Are you a member here?
- I can't remember seeing that ugly face before.
- Is that him?
- Yeah he's been look at us whole afternoon.
- With that stupid grin on his face.
- It's just a dirty bastard.
- Hey we're not done talking yet.
- He wants to walk away.
- Dont think that we are afraid of you.
- I didn't do anything!
We dont like it when our girls
are being harrassed.
Maybe we should teach you some manners.
So, that will teach him a lesson.
Ok guys, let's have a drink.
Are you coming?
Does it hurt?
Are you sure you dont want to call Van Zwol?
- Otherwise it will get infected.
- No, there's no need for that.
It's not so bad as it looks.
He really got you bad.
It was trained to kill.
Those people are really dange...
dangerous.
I wont let it rest.
In a while our children wont be
able to be safe on the streets.
We dont have children.
I wont have it that a minority
can terrorize us like that.
History has taught us enough already!
Look, there's Kees!
Hey Kees!
- What happened to you?
- You're bleeding.
That tennis club
- A few of those guys kicked my ass.
- Why?
Just like that. I was just looking.
What a bunch of fags.
I would like to talk to those gentlemen
Look out, it's that guy again.
There they are.
Get them, Johnny!
Back!
They are catching up to us!
Hey!
He's crazy!
Isn't it time to refresh the water?
It doesn't look very clean.
Honey, I refreshed the water two days ago.
Well, it looks very dirty to me.
- The water is crystal clear!
- But...
- Guys, next time at our place?
- They wouldn't dare.
Kees! Kees! Give them a round.
Put it on my tap.
Do you have one?
They dont mess with me.
And they certainly dont mess with my family.
Because then they can refreshen
themselves in their own pool.
Ha, they dont get us, right Kees?
- Hey Johnny!
- Hey Animal!
- Why dont you call me anymore?
- You didn't think I'd forgotten about you.
- What happened to you?
- Ow, just a little accident.
Comfort him. He really needs it.
- Can I talk with you Johnny?
- Hey Kareltje, what's up?
- Wanna do a job?
- What kind of thing?
- Purses.
- Purses, I'm not a fag!
Crocodile leather.
Worth a fortune, man.
Someone tipped me from the hague.
5000 purses!
Are you holding them? No way I'm doing it.
With those shoes last time it went totally wrong.
- I thought that went well?
- It was a bit hard stashing all those left shoes.
But this is different.
Hey are we keeping things nice there!
Sorry Kareltje, I'll pass on this one.
No problem, I will find someone else.
Hey, I thought you were away from here, Johnny
I am, but I'm not abandoning my friends.
- How is that new house of yours?
- I'm getting used to it.
He has a big ass house, man.
- A lot of rooms, a swimming pool in the backyard.
- A swimmingpool?!!
Yeah the house isn't so bad.
The neighbourhood is not so nice.
- A lot of stiff people.
- I'd like to see it.
- Yeah exactly, we have to see that house of yours.
- Yes we have to officially open it.
Well, why dont you all come over tonight
to have a swim!
YEAAAAAHH!!!!!
These are the last ones.
We can make it through the night with these
Who wants some more?
What a noise.
If they dont stop you must call the police.
- They are having a party.
- All those damn drunks.
It's outragious.
What are they thinking!
- Just take your sleepingpill.
- I already did that.
What did you think. I took two!
Otherwise I wont sleep at all.
I ehm, I've to take out the... garbage.
Well you better watch out
With that scum outside.
Shhhttttt!
- Hi, Toet. How are...
- MOM! it's for you!
Yeah yeah yeah
- Ha Mrs. Flodder, How are you doing?
- Brewing.
I was just seeing how things were going.
I even picked up your house permit.
Great.
- Are you cooking?
- Just a little bit. Sit down please.
- It sometimes takes a while to get in order.
- You shut up with that music!
Coffee?
A glass of milk, please.
We had a party last night.
- Ah, a house warming party.
- Uh?
- Ehm... a party.
- That's what I said.
Hey hey hey, take it easy.
My head hurts.
Did you get the aspirine.
- Do you still have a headache?
- Man, my head is like shit.
Yeah doesn't surprise me.
Last night you were drunk as hell.
Watch out!
Fuck.
- What did you do? Were you sleeping?
- I'm sorry, I didn't see you.
- You didn't see me?
- No.
- You had shit in your eyes then!
- Hey easy, you dont talk like that to a lady.
- Do you have a lot of damage?
- No, not so much.
If I hadn't moved out of the way
I would have been on top of you.
I can have a bump.
- And you didn't see us either?
- No, otherwise I would have taken another route.
- Jolanda, they are waiting for us.
- Laura, this is John.
- Hello, how are you?
- How much you want?
- What?
- He wants money. Give him 200, we have to go.
- He doesn't want any money.
- Sure he does, they all want that.
- Is 300 enough?
- Do I look like I want to be a few bucks richer?
- There's more in life than money.
- Clean clothes for example.
Put the money away.
Everything is taken care of.
Are we going, Johnny?
- It's nearby.
- I'm sure we can work this out.
Stupid bitches.
Are we going, Johnny?
Johnny?
- You are up to something.
- Who? Me?
You're not going to
do something stupid, right.
You are going to do something stupid.
I always thought you
were a little bit... ordinairy.
It's about time that the children...
It's about time that the children
go to their... new school.
- New school?
- Yes, we agreed on that.
- The Judas College
- They could stay home because of the movement.
That was a week ago.
It really is about time that...
School is not for them.
It's not healthy.
You know what they did
to that teacher, right.
They are just like their fathers.
I dont know, Wim.
Aren't you rushing into things?
We have to do something, Max.
those people are extremely dangerous.
- We shouldn't lose our heads.
- they are the first, who knows what's coming.
Before we know it they are a member here.
Does that sounds nice to you?
Maybe you are right, Wim.
I'm chairman of this club for 23 years now.
I've seen how it started. One court.
Two courts, now we have 12 tennis courts.
We cannot lose what we have build.
We put it on our agenda
for our next meeting.
Seems like a good plan
The tennisclub can be our headquarters.
The centre where we coordinate things.
Are you sure that you are going
to play tennis with that... ehmm
It takes more than that to take me down.
Well Mrs. Flodder, I will see how
things are doing next week.
Sure thing, Sjakie.
Hey Sjakie!
It still drives well?
Ofcourse Sjakie, what do ya think.
- Shit!
- Did you know those people?
I've seen them around.
You must see my report as temporary.
It's impossible ofcourse after a week
to see how the situation will develop.
But so far my impressions are... positive.
I understood your wounds were caused
by several visits at their house.
Little accidents, not so important.
They can happen anywhere.
According to the police it was
caused by a molotov cocktail.
I have to admit that the interaction
with the neighbours is not going perfectly yet.
We have to create a way
to motivate them...
a constructive way to bring these
people together.
You are aware that the ministry is following
this experiment with unusual interest.
I hope that your labrats will
soon know how to adapt themselves.
I'm sure of it that the relationship
with the neighbours will be better soon.
I'm very optimistic myself.
Hello!
Good afternoon.
I saw you arrive and I thought
I should get to know you.
- That's very friendly.
- Are these for your wife?
Eh... yes.
Mmmmmmm, nice!
- What is your name?
- Kees, just like my brother.
- You eh, dont look like your brother.
- Lucky for me I dont.
- Beautiful car!
- That's a CX 25 GTI with fuel injection.
Injection?
That's an engine that injects fuel
under high pressure into the cylinder
- You know a lot about it.
- I'm in the car business.
Oh really?
But sir, what are you doing?
I want you. You turn me on.
- But what about your wife?
- Oh we have plenty of time.
Do you like it?
It could use a bit more lemmon.
You know your stuff.
Yeah, I've been a bartender for years.
That's great.
You can make your own drink then.
Nice brand of Whiskey.
The house of experts.
- That's Wim's favorite brand.
- Wim?
My husband.
He doesn't like it when other
people drink from his bottle.
I dont mind.
A bit more lemmon.
Cheers.
- Mmmmm, excellent!
- Thank you
- I heard there was an accident with your car?
- Yeah.
So we dont have to talk
about the damage then.
No, I just came by to see
how you were living.
There is our Wim.
Cheers, Wim.
Does he have a high rank?
- Commander of a tank battalion.
- Pooh pooh.
A real collector.
That is nothing. Come with me.
Here is his army.
Damn, that's a big battle.
- He can spend nights in here.
- Like there's nothing better to do.
Oh.
- And what do you do?
- I follow my instincts.
- They can bring you into troubles?
- Really?
Hold on.
Nice tune.
- Here?
- Especially here.
That's my favorite rabbit.
Oh, yeah?
I had another one,
but it was smelling bad.
My father got rid of it.
My father works at a bank.
He's in the board of directors.
What does your father do?
He's doing something... somewhere
- Stephanie!
- I've to go. I've my violin lessons now.
Do you like Paganini?
I ehm, I like Chinese.
STEPHANIE!
- That is not a girl for you, Stephanie
- I can talk to her, can I?
- You talk to your friends.
- I have no friends.
- Christine is a good friend of yours.
- She moved away last year.
Well I dont like it.
- Where the hell were you all afternoon?
- Business.
You didn't do anything stupid, did you.
- How did you become so sweaty?
- Why are you in a bath at this time.
- I worked hard.
- So did I.
Johnny, we have a surprise for you.
You look like a model, you know.
And our neighbour doesn't look bad as well.
A big sausage. Very greasy.
That one there.
I dont think it's your turn yet.
Three pieces of that pie, Van Putten.
- That's a big mouth you got there.
- Ladies, Calm down.
If you want to live here...
You should learn some manners.
That son of yours has already
learned his lesson.
Three pieces of that pie, Van Putten.
Or are you sleeping?
Here's your pie, bitch!
Ladies, please!
Out of my way!
Please wake up.
Let me... let me go.
OH NO!
Dont touch me!
*Gibberish*
That way?
But we are far already!
- I wanna go home.
- *more gibberish*
Another time ok.
I'm very tired now.
Tomorrow we will watch the trains.
*Gibberish*
No, you are an idiot!
You are on your own... Whiskey, lets go.
- I'm sorry Mr. Neuteboom, but these...
- It's okay Van Dijk.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
What can I do for you.
- We want a car.
- That red one there.
- Ah, the BX Sport. That's a nice car.
- We thought so too.
Like that it's pretty standard.
What do you think of ehm... some extras?
Sport wheels, front and rear spoiler?
Nice seats, sport steeringwheel.
- Yeah why not, do that.
- Yeah, that's very sportive.
- Electric roof, buffalo leather seats.
- Buffalo?!
It's a bit more expensive, but
that wont be a problem for you gentlemen.
No problem at all.
And maybe a complete hifi audio set.
That wont make a difference now.
- I like a nice piece of music, right Kees.
- Yes, do that too, no problem.
How do you want to pay?
Cash, Diners Club, American Express, Visa?
Polaroid.
- Where's grandpa?
- Oh he didn't want to come
He always got something.
If he's not home in time he wont get food.
*Gibberish*
What the hell.
- Where did you get that car from?
- A present.
From our neighbour.
- What did you do?
- Nothing, he just likes us.
- Yeah, right.
- What an awesome car.
Are we gonna drive a bit?
- No driving, put the plates on the table
- I already did that!
Oh dear, here we go.
Toet!
Make it one plate less.
Yeah, I liked him.
I wasn't so close though.
We actually didn't even know
if he really was family.
He came along  with an aunt.
He stayed ever since.
- Hey, how you like my new car?
- It's nice.
- How did you get it?
- Someone gave it to me.
- You got it in an honest way?
- Do I look like a crook to you?
- You look great... for a criminal.
- You are okay.
You are not like the others.
You have ehm... class.
You think?
Are you romantic?
Sometimes.
On a moment like this,
With the sunset...
Something happens...
inside here.
I'm in fact a very sensitive person.
I love to travel to far away countries.
But Wim doesn't allow me.
He never goes on holiday.
He's always afraid that a war
starts when he's out on vacation.
I dont understand why you are
married with this moron.
- He used to look handsome.
- It's never too late to start all over.
You are right...
We do have a bit of time left.
Well, tiger.
- Is there life left inside.
- Yep, for sure.
How was your bridge evening.
What are you doing up so late?
Did you win?
Dont you have to defend the country tomorrow.
You were not at Laura's this evening.
- Oh, really?
- You were with a man!
- Tell me!
- Let me go, you are drunk.
You are fucking someone else.
You dont think I'm crazy, do you.
Who was it?
Do I know him?
- I order you to answer!
- Order, order? We are not in your army.
- I'm your husband, I've my rights.
- My husband? You are joking.
The only thing you can get up
is the barrel of your tank!
Bitch!
Jolanda, what's up with that suitcase.
What are you doing?
Jolanda, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean for that.
Jolanda!
Jolanda...
What do you want!
Who's there?
- I came for Johnny.
- Oh, Johnny.
Johnny!
There's a lady here to see you.
- A lady?
- She's carrying a suitcase.
- What have you done now?
- Suitcase? I know nothing.
Jolanda?
What happened?
A small fight.
That soldier of yours?
Can I stay here?
Ehhh, yeah... of course, come in.
Who's that Johnny?
Well mother, this is Jolanda.
Jolanda, this is my mother.
How are you doing.
- What do you want from my son?
- Jolanda will be ehm, staying for a bit.
What do you mean? You know I dont
want people to fool around here.
- She can stay in grandpa's room.
- Is that her, Johnny?
Go to bed, now!
That doesn't look so good, child.
Come with me and I will patch you up.
And you pour a drink for her.
She's soaking wet.
- She has grandpa's plate.
- Shut up and eat.
What the hell!
What is she doing here, Johnny?
Shut up, she's staying here for a while.
Jolanda? What the...
Give Jolanda a glass of water.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Stop making a mess and eat.
Ahem, general. Gentlemen.
The success of the mission Charlie
will mainly depending on...
Right
Operation Stanley...
is depending on the speed of the
Leopard Squadrons can move out...
To the coцrdinates... seven.. ehm.
Twenty four and nine eighteen...
In the Alpha sector.
In sector Kilo at the moment will
be our infantry, which...
Colonel, in the sector Alpha will
be our field hospital.
Of course I meant to say the sector Delta.
Because of this the road will be
cleared for the 7th and 12th...
Armour infantry.
With some support of helicopters.
- Everything okay, Wim?
- Oh yeah, fine.
- Everything okay at home, with your wife.
- No, great, excellent, it's going well.
We know eachother for a long time, Wim
And you know...
If something is bothering you,
you can tell me about it.
- Everything is alright, Emile.
- Are you sure?
I will do everything to make
Operation Charlie a succes.
Stanley... Operation Stanley.
Yes, Stanley.
This is the last one.
I can go on again.
I need some new labels.
We have a few left.
- Next week. I'm making new ones.
- Good.
- Hey Johnny, who's the lady?
- that's eh, my fiancee.
Fiancee? Dont make me laugh.
That must be someone from the parole.
I can't hide anything from you eh.
Keep it quiet, you know that people talk.
My lips are sealed.
You got talent.
- You got some more songs?
- I eh, I've to go now.
Didn't you forget... something.
- Who's your new boyfriend?
- Do you like him?
Ehmm he's interesting.
A bit primitive, but interesting.
- Like usual.
- This is different.
You're not going to tell me
that you are in love.
Are you shocked?
You always surprise me.
- It keeps my life interesting.
- And Wim?
- He's getting excited about it.
- Oh that explains your face
- I moved out.
- Isn't that a bit too drastic.
I couldn't be there anymore.
It was like someone...
..was choking me. I had to do something.
- I hope he makes you happy.
We are getting along great.
We have to do something.
The situation is out of control.
I talked to Wim about it.
It's better to act fast.
The sooner they leave the better.
We have to protect the neighbourhood
against the agression of those people.
We should have a meeting tomorrow
here in the club.
My wife almost had a nervous breakdown.
Can you imagine not being able to buy groceries.
- You don't look well yourself.
- Ofcourse not. With all that noise.
It goes on all day and night.
There's no quiet moment.
Alright, I will call them all and
we will see if we should take some action.
What the fuck?!
WHAT THE FUCK?!
- What the fuck?!
- 825.000 bucks.
- Inside those trains of him?
- Nice inheritance.
That sonofabitch.
- All this time he was living from our money.
- Now we can have a nice holiday.
- Or buy stocks.
- We are rich now, Johnny.
Welcome to the club.
- Hello?
- Hello...
HELLO?
- Hello.
- Hello, Wim? Is that you?
- Who's this?
- It's Max.
Ooooh, hi Max.
We have a meeting tomorrow at the
club around 7.30, can you make it?
Meeting?
Yeah what we discussed last time.
About the rotten elements in our neighbourhood.
Oh yes, ofcourse. Get rid of it.
- We must have a meeting then.
- Tomorrow at 7.30pm
That's a damn good plan, man.
We must determine our tactics.
Everybody is coming.
Good. Wonderful.
- Are you going to tell it to Jolanda?
- Jolanda?
- Of course I will.
- Ok then, I will see you tomorrow.
Yeah
I dont like it, you will get in trouble
with those purses.
The purses are good, real crocodile leather.
- Crocodiles
- Mom, crocodiles.
- Johnny, you want more?
- Yeah, thanks.
- I dont know, Johnny.
- What, mom?
- That girl inside our house.
- Jolanda?
- It's a different kind of people.
- But that's not her fault.
We should give her a chance.
- Are you sure she's not after our money.
- How could she know about that money?
I hope you know what you're doing, son.
She loves me, mom.
And I love her too.
And who are you?
Where's my wife?
Oh, I didn't recognize you without
your silly outfit.
I know she's here.
Jolanda!
- What do you want from her?
- Who's this, Johnny?
I want to talk to her.
I'm still her lawful husband.
Jolanda! Your lawful husband
wants to speak with you.
- I dont want to see him.
- Jolanda, we should talk.
She said that she doesn't want to see you.
Is everything okay with you?
Did they abuse you?
I think it's better if you get lost.
Dirty sonofabitch.
I will get you for this.
- Wim Kruisman?
- They threw him out of the house.
- What was he doing there?
- I've no idea.
I will ask him at the meeting tomorrow.
- Maybe he was trying to negotiate.
- That's brave of him.
That woman... is extremely dangerous.
You can see how stubborn they are.
They have to leave our neighbourhood.
There's no other way.
Hey Van Kooten!
That situation with the family
seems to be getting out of hand.
I've heard that the neighbours
are organizing themselves.
I thought you had everything under control.
- I assumed there was a bit of motivation...
- Stop talking nonsense.
The mayor himself is also
breathing down my neck.
One of the neighbours is
a close friend of him.
And we cannot take a risk
concerning our city policy.
I'm going to that meeting tonight.
I'm convinced they are just overreacting.
These are smart people that can
be reasoned with.
You understand that this
is your last chance.
I can't help you anymore.
Only one small thing has to happen...
And we all lose our head.
You understand.
- Mom?
- Yeah.
- Me and Jolanda want to tell you something.
- Oh yeah?
We eh, decided today to become engaged.
That's nice, son.
I'm 27 and I want something steady.
- To lose my wild hairs.
- That's nice, son.
We want to celebrate it tonight
and we will invite everybody.
- Everybody?
- The whole neighbourhood.
Is that a smart thing to do?
Tonight is going to be one big party.
We forget what has happened.
Alright, son.
It will always be my son.
I hope someone is home here.
- The lights are on.
That was the babysitter, everyone
is to a meeting at the tennisclub.
Aint that something, what kind of meeting?
- She didn't know that.
Let's check it out then.
The radical behaviour of these people
is really out of control.
As the nextdoor neighbour
I know what I'm talking about.
Since their arrival there hasn't been
a minute that we could enjoy our rest.
My wife has to take pills to fall asleep.
They search through other people's garbage.
Their behaviour is obscene.
The stench around that house is unbearable.
And the worst thing is...
That they, without any motivation,
hit my wife...
and other of our fellow neighbours.
Mr. chairman, I really dont
want to discriminate...
but we dont tolerate this
behaviour in our neighbourhood.
Thank you.
Mr. chairman, I think we are
rushing into things here.
I think it's a little out of line
to start a witch hunt already.
They come from a different social class.
But they are still human beings.
They drove my son off the road
with his new car.
And destroyed my garden.
They bothered my daughter.
They are filthy people.
And they walk around with weapons.
They threated my son with a knife
and destroyed his bicycle.
Our houses are dropping in value.
They just lived here and my
golden pen was missing already.
But Victor, it was in your other jacket.
It's not about that.
It's the principle that counts.
Please, let us try to see
the case in the right form.
They are criminals! My cousin is a
police officer and knows all about them.
- They should get at least 25 years.
- They are extremely dangerous!
- They are scum.
- Ladies and gentlemen.
Let's proceed this meeting
without any problems.
I want to give the word to Mr. Wijberg
As the neighbour across the street
he knows the family best. Mr. Wijnberg.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I will keep it short...
- It seems like everybody is here.
- Great, then we can invite them all at once.
I want to see their faces.
Do you think they will be surprised?
I think they will.
And yesterday they threw
Wim Kruisman out of the house.
Wim. We know him for years
as a reasonable person.
Mr. Chairman, I think this tyranny
should not be tolerated any longer.
And... and... that...
Hey Sjakie, I didn't know you
were a member of the tennisclub.
Johnny, this is not the right moment...
- This is Jolanda
- Hello.
I've a surprise for you Sjakie
after the meeting is over.
Shhtt Johnny.
Sorry for interupting you, neighbour.
Please continue.
Eh yeah...
Maybe it's ehm... indeed better
Mr. Chairman.
That we dont raise the
contribution this year.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Wonderful.
Everything becomes so expensive always.
- Johnny, I must tell you...
- Later Sjakie, later.
I believe eh this was our
last speaker for now.
Good!
Well then eh...
ehm.
I wanted to use this oppertunity
to make an announcement.
Jolanda Kruisman and I decided
today eh... to be engaged.
I wont interupt you any longer.
You're still in a meeting. I know.
There were some problems with us and the
neighbourhood, but let's forget about it.
Tonight, there will be a
big party at our house.
And everyone here is invited.
Thank you.
- See you later, Sjakie.
- Ehhh Johnny.
Does Wim know about this?
- Where is Wim?
- I did call him.
A party. What are they thinking.
It's out of the question that
we go to that party.
- Why not? Free booze.
- Yeah!
It's outragious that someone like that
is getting engaged with one of our people.
- I didn't even know that Wim had a divorce.
- That woman is not normal.
Last year she was driving naked
through our neighbourhood.
I want to see if it is really
as bad as people are saying.
I dont want to be involved with that scum!
It's interesting to see how
these people are living.
Ladies and gentlemen!
I dont know if it is a good
idea to go there later...
because of the nature of our meeting.
It seems like a nice gesture.
A sign that they want to live
in harmony with the neighbourhood.
I dont think we should reject this offer.
Also, I dont think the city will
appreciate a rejection like this.
They wont see this as
an example of good will.
I wont say that the yearly subsidy
of this club will be cancelled.
But I'll advise you to reconsider
this matter for sure.
Maybe it's not such a bad eh... idea
to accept their invitation, but
everyone should know for themselves.
For godsake, let's do this.
But no longer than 5 minutes.
At least we've showed our good will.
- I rather have a glass of red wine.
- Sure, we have got everything.
Can you get a bottle of red wine
for the lady here.
The men will drink a glass with me, right.
After all, it's a party.
- Hey Sjakie, are you doin' well?
- Yeah!
You can see that we also
know how to throw a party.
- I'm glad everything came out okay.
- Ofcourse Sjakie, what did you think.
You gave everyone quite a scare.
- That was harmless.
- But to get engaged so fast.
Your problem is that you take
everything too seriously.
Perhaps.
- And Wim? Did you invite him?
- He doesn't like parties.
Your papers!
I'm sorry colonel.
I didn't recognize you.
- What's he doing here so late?
- It must be about that training tomorrow.
He must be afraid that
they start without him.
You dont want to try a glass?
- Are you sure I should do that.
- Just to be nice.
Alright, just one glass.
- Ooh, Pepita!
- She's not going anywhere.
- Hello.
- Hi.
How's your eye.
Great, the doctor says I'm
allowed to see everything again.
I'm sorry about what happened.
We got you back pretty bad as well.
You didn't get me.
- It must hurt a lot to make that, right.
- No, taking it off, that hurts a lot.
You are one awesome woman, you know that!
Is that fun, being a surgeon?
The human body is one of
the most fascinating...
... things that exist.
- I'm starting to feel more at home.
- Oh yeah?
- I really enjoy it here.
- I thought it was temporary.
Hey you...
I dont like your face.
Get the fuck out of here!
Let's keep it nice in here.
What's that?
What?
That rumbling noise.
What the hell?!!
WATCH OUT!
Pepita?
Where are you?
Pepita!
Thanks, Johnny.
If I can do anything back.
A second hand car.
Neighbour, this is Kareltje.
A friend of mine.
How are you?
Are you interested in some
real crocodile leather purses?
Who's this?
Sjakie!
Hey Sjakie!
Telephone for you.
For me?
Hello?
Hey you, keep it clean in here!
Mrs. Flodder, I have a big
surprise for you later.
Oh really Sjakie? I've a big
surprise for you later on.
Do you think there's
something going on?
Hello precinct, here's 507.
507, what's up Kees?
Herman, do you know anything
about a party on the Netelroad...
- At the house of that Flodder scum.
- We know nothing about that.
I want to check it out
because I dont trust it.
Hold on Kees, I just got a call.
A tank has been spotted on the Klaprooslaan.
- That's near you guys.
- A tank?!
Ehm, okay Herman, we will check it out.
- What the hell?!!
- Let's have a talk with him.
Hello, papers please.
Say Kees, did you eat Chinese or what.
Pepita.
Little Pepita, where are you hiding?
Like eh, this?
Nice eh!
- Does it take long to feel something?
- No, not so long.
I dont feel anything yet.
Do you want another whiskey?
No, I've to perform a
transplantion tomorrow.
Okay, just a small one then.
Ho ho, you have to pay first.
I've no money with me.
You'll have to pay otherwise
you wont get in.
American Express?
First a nice trip to celebrate.
- I want to go to a warm country.
- Well not too warm.
A country far away.
And I've to get a job.
Something for the long term.
With the police or something.
With sirens. I'd like that.
I ehm, I will be right back, Kees.
- What's going on here, Van Kooten?
- They are having a party.
- For all the neighbours.
- You didn't tell me about this!
And it seems you are having
a good time yourself.
Mr. Flodder, this is the chairman
of the city council.
- He has a surprise for you.
- What kind of surprise?
Mrs. Flodder...
It's my pleasure to tell you that
the city has succeeded...
in finding suitable accommodation for you.
If you want, you can settle in tomorrow.
I dont need another house.
I've just bought this one this afternoon.
An inheritance.
- But, eh.
- I like this neighbourhood.
Bought it?!!
Why didn't you tell me?
What the hell is going
on here, Van Kooten!
Wake up, Arie!  Arie!
BOOM!
I got you!
Is everybody here?
Hey, look at that!
Typically Sjakie,
never knows when to quit
Parties are nice, but they
always leave such a mess.
Hey watch out with that clock,
it belonged to your grandmother.
- Mom!  Someone here from the newspaper.
- Newspaper?
Peters, Daily Breaker.
You must remember me.
- Ehm, must have been quite a party.
- We enjoyed ourselves.
- You are leaving again?
- Yeah, it's a rough neighbourhood.
- Shall we make a picture?
- Picture?
Kids, come here!
They want to make a picture!
A bit more to the left.
a bit to the right.
Smile.
Dear Sjakie...
We are doing well.
How are you?
We want to thank you a lot for
all the things you've done for us.
We really appreciate that we can stay
in your summerhouse in the South of France.
Everyone wishes you well
and give their regards.