We've been waiting for you to come back...
Alice.
It's not this one, it's up here.
Come on.
It's too hot?
We left everything as it was
For you to take a look.
Wilson's funeral...
It was done properly.
Were his parents upset that I wasn't there?
No one can predict accidents.
We thought it was because
you couldn't let Wilson go...
Or maybe that driver wanted to help me.
What are you saying?
Nothing.
Are you better now?
My doctor said...
It's a miracle that I woke up
From a coma
After 6 months... I've earned these times.
Did he say anything?
It was too sudden
When we arrived at the hospital...
He was already...
Why did it happen?
A separated couple
Had an accident at the same time,
in different places.
One is dead...
The other one is still alive...
It's a shame we weren't in the same car
If we were together...
Would we have survived? Or...
We could have died together.
Wilson would be please to know
you are okay.
That is the store room, I'll get the key.
Never mind.
Are you sure you don't want dinner with us?
I'm tired, I want an early night.
We'll talk about the memorial tomorrow.
Call me if you need anything.
Why have you come back?
Please don't kick me out.
Where can I go, I have no one?
I really like you.
Well, I don't like you.
I beg you, please go.
You really want me to go?
Go! Just get out!
Why should I go?
Do you have another girl?
You are so annoying! Leave me alone.
I'm annoying?
What about me?
I'm your girlfriend.
I've had enough!
I hate you, you know?
I dare you to say it to my face again!
I'm really tired,
I don't want to talk anymore.
Grandma
Sweetie, how are you feeling in Hong Kong?
I'm okay.
Are Wilson's friends treating you well?
Yes.
You shouldn't run off to Hong Kong alone,
we'd get worry!
- You never change. - Grandma...
What?
I...
What is it?
This place is weird.
Weird? What's weird?
I told you not to go to Hong Kong.
Why don't you come back?
Give me more time,
I want to stay a bit longer.
Call me if anything comes up.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Alice, this is the address of our shop.
You can follow the map to find it.
Winkie, Crystal, Regen,
Terence and I will all be there.
Do you remember them?
Of course I do.
If you can't find it, give us a call.
Hello?
Alice, where are you?
What's taking you so long?
I don't know.
Where am I?
Stay where you are, we'll look for you.
Okay
- Is she lost?
-Need to call the cops?
- Alice - Here she is.
She's waking up.
She's awake...
Alice, are you okay?
Give her some room.
Alice, do you need mouth to mouth?
What are you doing?
Pervert.
Mouth to mouth, you know...
Who...
Alice, have some water.
How are you feeling?
Need to go to the hospital?
No, no hospitals.
You can tell
she hasn't taken her medicines.
How about I take you home?
Hey, I thought we are discussing
the memorial with her?
What's wrong with you?
she can't talk like this?
Do you want another memorial?
Shut up.
I'll shut you up first.
It's okay,
I'll go to the pharmacy then take you home.
It's such an important mission, I'll do it.
You stay here.
Do you see any customers here?
Plus I know mouth to mouth, look at it.
Come on.
I'll take the glass.
Thank you, Crystal.
I'm Regen.
I'm Crystal!
Sorry.
You two do look alike, maybe
Plastic surgery will help.
Get lost, loud mouth.
It's hot here.
You don't feel it, Alice?
Aren't you hot?
Alice, how about...
I'll go and get some Ice Cream.
You know...
Ice Cream!
So impolite.
You too, no ice cream for you.
Wilson...
Why don't I remember?
How can you do this to Wilson?
What are you saying?
I just want her to be happy.
Looks like you are happier.
Are you jealous of me?
How dare you!
Andy, let go!
You want to kill him?
How come you know...Cantonese?
I... - I...What about it?
It was hard to say Ice Cream in Mandarin.
We should have known,
you were with Wilson for some time.
Unlike you, still mutters, how old are you?
Pretends to be autistic?
Have we made up? Is it funny?
No...
Why would I steal...?
Wilson's girlfriend?
Plus... I don't want Wilson
to visit me at night.
It doesn't feel right here, let's go.
I'm sorry, taking up your time today.
The memorial...
We'll let you decide.
We've got time, just take care of yourself.
Call me for anything.
You can call me too if you are lonely.
-Ignore him. -I've got one more.
- Let's go, bye. - Get lost.
Remember to take these medicines.
Thank you.
Cheer up, still upset?
-Morning. -Morning.
Stop talking, come on.
Where should we have breakfast?
Hello!
Alice, why are you here so early?
You feeling better? Do you need more rest?
I'm okay.
Your dress is so pretty,
where did you get it?
You like it? I'll give it to you.
You're so lucky.
You went shopping, what did you get?
- Let's see. - What is it?
Why are you carrying his photo around?
It's jinxed.
I'm here to talk about the memorial.
I've found Wilson's photos,
that's good for the memorial.
I've also found some CDs.
Why don't we listen and pick a few songs.
Let's sit down and talk.
Okay
Crystal, come on.
Look.
Andy, you are back?
What are you talking about?
The memorial.
Come with me.
Don't you feel
something's wrong with Alice?
What do you mean?
Look at her,
so bright today compare to yesterday!
That's good.
She looks liked...
a person possessed by a ghost.
Watch your mouth.
I was just saying.
Maybe she was jetlagged.
Jetlagged? Jetlagged from Taiwan!
Maybe I'll get sea sick...
from riding the underground!
Bullshit!
Jetlagged,
definitely jetlagged, excellent.
My customer needs me, see you.
He wrote me these letters.
I didn't get them
They're for you, can we read them?
There's nothing unsuitable for kids.
Alice, the letter I've sent you
Has bounced again.
I'm upset.
Why are you hiding from me?
Why did you move and not tell me?
Do you hate me?
Alice, a couple of old friends...
came to the shop today.
They were here for wedding photos.
They asked about you.
And when will we get married.
I didn't tell them, we've broken up.
Alice, it's my birthday today.
I was out celebrating with friends.
We were all wildly drunk.
They asked...
what my birthday wish was.
If I said it then it wouldn't come true.
Do you know what I wished for?
I wished you are back with me.
I've just told you.
I really want you to know, I miss you.
How come this was never sent?
Alice, I shouldn't have made that mistake.
It was just a fling with that woman.
I want you to know,
you are the only one I love.
I've been regretting it
for the past 6 months.
I have thought it through.
I cannot lose you.
So I want to come and find you.
I will bring with me all the letters
I just want a chance,
for you to finish reading them
The letters represent my feelings for you.
Most importantly...
Alice, I've made a mistake
Can you forgive me?
Cheer up, still upset?
Morning.
Where should we have breakfast?
Hello?
Sweetie,
do you still feel weird today?
Much better.
That's a relief.
Grandma
What is it?
I've found letters that Wilson sent me.
Really? What do they say?
How many people?
One.
Over there.
Doesn't she look like a ghost?
Am I welcome?
Of course.
I never thought you would come here.
I remember you, me and Wilson
always came here.
I remember your favourite food is...
What do you two want?
The sausage macaroni here is quite good,
want to try?
Okay.
- Two set A. - Two set A?
Did you sleep well last night?
I didn't sleep.
Why?
I've found some letters from Wilson.
All of them from him?
Never thought... they'd find me.
I hope you don't mind me asking.
Why did you leave Wilson?
He really loved you.
How do you know?
After you left him, he changed.
He used to be cheerful,
we tried to help him.
But in the end, he ignored all of us.
He just drank all day long.
Can you tell me more about Wilson?
Wilson was so silly.
He secluded himself after work,
he wanted to write to you.
I told him, you don't even know
where Alice moved to.
He said, he wants to write down
his feelings for you.
He believed you'll read
the letters one day.
But one day, he was happy, and told us
He has quit his job,
bought a ticket to Taiwan.
That was the last time I've seen him.
Which day was that?
14th of January, I remember.
He came to my birthday party.
This was his last letter to me.
I shouldn't have let Wilson drank so much.
Shouldn't have let him onto that taxi.
I'm sorry. If Wilson got back to Taiwan
I'm sure you two would have made up.
It's not your fault.
I want to thank you.
Waited for me to arrange Wilson's memorial.
He's lucky to have friends like you.
Our pleasures.
That woman..
They've broken up a long time ago.
I know Wilson didn't love her.
Set A.
Thanks.
Let's eat.
What will you be doing?
I know what to do with the memorial.
Did you like the food?
Yes.
We'll come again then.
Alice,
I need to pay some bills first.
It's okay, I remember the way.
I'm happy seeing you happy again.
Thank you.
See you.
Hello!
I've bought dinner.
Come on in.
Do you like it?
Then eat some more.
Don't you think it's cold here?
Maybe it's just your head.
Maybe.
So what are you going to do
with these stuffs?
Haven't decided yet, any ideas?
They are Wilson's memories, you decide.
Why didn't his parents take his belongings?
Because his relationship
with them wasn't good.
Yes, that's what I thought.
But...hasn't it changed at all?
After all, they are a family.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Alice
You should know his father has passed away.
Of course.
You don't seem to know his mum
was his step mum either.
Do you remember
what you said the other day?
Were his parents upset that I wasn't there?
Alice, what are you not telling us?
Since the accident,
I've forgotten a lot of things.
I don't remember Wilson,
I don't remember who I am.
You wouldn't know the pain of amnesia.
It's like the world have left you
behind with nothing.
Everything, every person...
Becomes alienated.
Until you guys found me.
And told me
My boyfriend is dead.
But...
I don't even remember what he looks like.
I only knew I had to come back.
Only through this...
I can find my memories
I can find myself
I didn't lie to you guys on purpose.
I'm just not brave enough
to tell the truth.
I'm sorry.
You're so silly, you didn't have to lie.
We're friends, we would have helped you.
Can you promise me one thing?
What is it?
Help me keep this secret, okay?
Why?
Because I don't want to scare the others.
But more importantly...
I have remembered
many of my memories with Wilson.
Look at it another way...
Isn't this better?
All I remember is the good times with him.
Nothing else matters
Don't you think?
Promise me.
Wilson, is it you?
Wilson!
Are you sure you're not imagining things?
I don't know.
If you're scared, you can move to a hotel.
I still miss Wilson.
You really miss him this much?
The longer I stay in the flat
The more I feel he's with me.
Sometimes I think,
if he does come back to see me...
I want to see him too.
After all, he is my boyfriend.
I shouldn't be scare of him.
Are you kidding?
I just want him to see me once more.
Now you scare me.
Where?
Over there.
What should we have?
Set B.
-Morning. -Morning.
Stop talking, come on.
This? Why don't you eat me?
You're so bad.
Don't you like it?
I like food more right now.
You know them?
No.
Tell me, who was that woman?
Just leave, I need to rent the flat out.
You can't stay here anymore.
What have I done wrong,
for you to kick me out?
Do you need me to die for you?
I'm sorry.
I know you will be upset by this.
But holding on is no good to anyone.
I'll rather die than move out!
Bastard! Kicked me out.
Why don't you come in.
Aren't you tired of crying?
Just leave me alone.
How about some TV.
What's wrong?
Don't bother.
The receptions in old buildings
are always like this.
You live here for long?
Just longer than you.
You've seen me?
You and your boyfriend moved in last year.
What's wrong?
You've broken up with your boyfriend?
He has gone away...
You have to keep an eye on your man
If not he might turn out like mine.
Yours?
He has another woman.
You know?
Men always think they are great liars
The fact is, we like to listen to lies.
But we don't like to be con by them.
If you know he has someone else,
why are you still with him?
Because I'm also his other woman.
You too?
When you know your man
has many other women.
You just hope to be the second one.
Not the third, the forth or the fifth.
Why all the commotions
if you are so cool about it?
He wants that woman to move in
The flat is mine, no one can kick me out!
Can you let me stay here tonight?
Just one night.
I'll go back when he goes to work tomorrow.
Don't you think he'll get worry?
I'm sure he's sleeping
with the other woman now.
Then stay.
Excellent, I'm not fussy.
I can sleep here.
Do you think...
It's getting colder in here?
You feel it too?
I think, there's...
Don't...I'm a big chicken.
Can you get me a duvet?
Come on, hurry up!
My Dear, thank you for letting me
stayed last night.
My name is Mandy,
I don't know your name yet.
But I'm sure the chance will come.
Aren't you scare
your girlfriend might find out?
How about you,
aren't you scare of your boyfriend?
Scare? He's not in Hong Kong.
Excellent, then we can have some fun.
You're so bad.
Let's skip dinner.
Where should we go then?
My place.
Your place again?
You don't want to?
Stop!
Don't run!
Who is it?
She lives above me.
Wait for me! Stop!
I don't want to go home, can I come in?
Do you think I'm stupid and useless?
Why?
I shouldn't be the one who ran away today.
I didn't do anything wrong.
You wouldn't let go if you didn't see it.
But learning the truth,
ended up hurting myself.
You need to be brave to handle the truth.
You sound like an expert.
I'm in a similar situation.
I'm also investigating my boyfriend.
He has another woman too?
He's dead.
I don't remember anything about Wilson.
So I came back to search
for memories of us.
It's good if you remember.
But don't force yourself.
You don't think I should?
There used to be someone who loved me.
When I met him,
he was already in a relationship.
So I told him, we can't be a couple.
But we can be backup lovers.
At first, we were happy.
But one day, he told me
He doesn't want to be backup,
he wants the real deal.
So I told him, a relationship needs timing
If the timing is wrong, then it's rubbish.
So after going away with him, we broke up.
I lied to him about getting married.
And told him not to contact me.
Why did you lie? He loved you.
Because he was too good.
Good things never last for long
I'd rather it ended
before anything goes wrong.
So everyone can go away with good memories.
Since your boyfriend is so bad
Why don't you go back to him?
I'd rather he thinks
I'm having a good time...
That'd be enough.
No regrets?
I chose the path, no one's to blame.
It's like going on a diet
But ask how can I stop being hungry,
right?
That's a funny way to put it.
Remember, it doesn't hurt
if you don't know it.
It doesn't hurt if you don't know it?
Memories are not only from the past.
You can collect them from now on.
Gosh, I'm hungry,
can I have something to eat?
Noodles?
Watch TV.
It's fuzzy again?
It's done.
My boyfriend's home, see you.
Hey!
I thought she was hungry.
Why are you back?
I told you, I've got a girlfriend.
I'm not going to leave.
So don't bring another woman here!
Please, let me go.
What do I have to do?
I can let go of everything...
Except for you!
You're not letting me go?
Then I'll never come back again!
I have to go.
Ok, take care.
Don't get upset, okay?
Call us when you guys get back.
You too.
-Bye-bye. -Bye-bye.
Let's go to Karaoke this Saturday.
Yeah, call that guy too.
Of course.
Let's go, it's boring.
Your brother?
My husband.
Make it a date for the next funeral.
You okay?
Everyone's left.
They were all touched.
They said it was a nice memorial.
We all did our parts.
Regen said you'll go back to Taiwan
in a couple of days.
Why don't you stay longer?
I've done what I came to do,
I want to go home.
I miss my grandma.
Will you come back to visit us?
I'll see how my school works go.
I'm going to study again after the summer.
If it wasn't for the accident,
I'd have graduated already.
The most important thing is
that you are safe.
You can come visit me in Taiwan.
Really?
Alice, Wilson's photos are all here.
Thank you, I'll take them.
What are you going to do with them?
Can I keep them as a memory?
Of course, you are his girlfriend.
Thank you.
I'll take them downstairs.
Who is it?
The memorial was so successful.
Why don't we get some food.
Yeah
How come all the photos are on the floor?
I don't know...
Wilson's back! He's back!
Come on, Wilson... he's dead.
He's really back, go and see for yourself.
I'm not scare, I'll go.
Terence...
I've never seen a ghost before.
Ghost!
Come on...
No, I'm scare...
Is it really Wilson?
Wilson's back?
Nothing's here, look for yourself.
Maybe we can see him, come on.
I saw him in here.
I'm telling the truth, I'm not lying.
He really was here...
Then where is he
Anything would be nice
-He was right there... -Alice
You're tired, get some sleep
- We'll talk tomorrow.
#NAME?
He really was here.
He did come back!
You guys go in and take a look, he's back.
Take a look, I'm not lying.
Alice...Alice!
It's real!
Calm down, it's your imagination
Wilson is dead.
He's not dead!
He's not dead, I'm telling the truth.
He came back, he came back to see me.
He is here, go in and have a look.
Why don't you guys believe me?
He's really here.
- Come on, take a look.
#NAME?
Even you don't believe me?!
Wilson, they don't believe me.
Come out.
Wilson, come out.
Please come out, I miss you...
Alice!
Take some pills and go to sleep.
Alice,
we are all worry about you.
I don't want to sleep.
I want to see Wilson again.
It's your imagination.
Wilson was back, he came back...
Wilson's dead! Just accept it!
Wilson's dead...
But I've only seen him once
That was the first time I've seen him...
And it was the last time.
Even though it was just a glance.
But my memories with him all came back.
I know I still love him.
I still miss him.
Do you know I still love him?
Alice...
Wilson is not a good person.
What are you saying?
Where are you taking me?
I'm taking you to see someone.
Who?
Someone who'll tell the secrets...
Wilson has hidden from you.
No business.
Bitch! What do you want coming here?
- You killed Wilson... - Calm down...
It's your fault!
You stole him from me...
Stop it!
Give me back my husband!
Stop it will you...
Miss, I think you've made a mistake,
he was my boyfriend.
Stop pretending!
If it wasn't for you, he would be alive.
You stole him, he died because of you...
-I want my husband! -Let's go
Ask the man with you, see if I am lying.
Bitch!
Tell me, if she was telling the truth?
It's all in the past.
Tell me! If it's true?
Is it?
Your boyfriend was never stolen from you.
Because it was...
you who stole her boyfriend.
Wilson and Maggie
has been together for 5 years
Planning to get married.
But 2 years ago,
Wilson changed after he met you.
And split up with Maggie right away.
Maggie tried suicide many times,
so Wilson went back to her.
You found out
and went back to Taiwan.
Wilson didn't know what to do,
and was very upset.
Then?
Well... he soon met another girl.
He needed a breather,
it wasn't anything serious.
He said he wanted to find you,
but only when he was drunk.
The next day
he just carried on meeting girls.
His last letter,
it says he'll come and find me.
Is it true?
He's not here,
a lot of questions will go unanswered.
Am I stupid, that I still miss him?
I shouldn't have told you the truth.
I want you to have good memories of Wilson
But I don't want you to look like you did.
Dwelling in a dead relationship.
Alice, you still have a second chance
To live and to love someone else.
Second chance?
I don't even know who I am.
You'll be whoever
you think you should be.
Only you can decide that.
I've already talked too much
I should go.
Andy
Thank you
Cheers
Have you packed?
Yes.
I'll take you to the airport tomorrow.
Okay.
Alice, when will you come back?
We'll miss you.
Me too.
Why don't you stay a bit longer?
You guys can visit me in Taiwan.
We can eat hotpot and go to hot spring spa.
Yeah!
Do man and woman bathe together?
I'm very open minded, I wouldn't mind.
Wake up, it's separated.
Hear that? You pervert.
What? You're the pervert.
Can we take some photos together?
Of course.
It's not like
we never took photos together before.
It's different this time.
What's the difference?
I've lost the old ones.
Want some new ones to keep.
Well...
Let's take some photos.
-No camera. -I haven't brought mine.
Oh yeah.
I have one.
Alice
Wilson
I'm sorry, I made a mistake,
will you forgive me?
I didn't blame you,
I've forgotten what's happened.
You have to promise me.
Live your life to the fullest.
Forget about me.
I can't...
We live in two different worlds.
I'm glad you are safe.
I think I can leave now.
Take care, bye.
Mandy.
Mandy
Dearest Mandy, I'm leaving
This is my Taiwan address,
come visit if you are free.
Alice, I need to talk to you.
What is it?
Aren't we going to the airport?
You came back to search for memories
But do you remember how we met?
Hey, do you see her?
Not bad eh? I want to meet her.
You have a girlfriend.
So? there's nothing wrong
meeting a new friend.
She will ignore you.
Wait...
Do you have a coin? Heads or tails.
Whoever wins goes in to ask for her number.
Lost you phone trick again?
Come on.
Heads.
Excuse me, miss.
Can I borrow your phone,
there's no battery left in mine?
I need to call my friend urgently.
Thank you.
So?
Where are you?
Outside.
Come on, can you see me?
There you are, come in.
Andy, come on, sit down.
She's my girlfriend, Alice.
#NAME?
He's my best friend, Andy.
That was the first time I met you.
You wanted to meet me like he did?
Only he made the move first.
I'm not as lucky as Wilson.
Every time we bet, I lose.
Did you think about telling me
he has a girlfriend?
I couldn't do it, he was my best friend.
Wilson being so smart.
There's no way he didn't know
what you thought.
That's why he asked me out.
To let me know you two are together.
You're so silly.
So when you decided to leave.
I said to myself,
I'm not going to miss the second chance.
There's something I have to ask you...
Alice, can you stay?
Stay?
I know I will never replace...
Wilson in your heart.
You two are perfect together.
But maybe,
there's no such thing as perfect.
There might be someone
who's exactly the same as you.
But fate can separate them.
Even if you do meet,
there can be changes too.
What's important is that
you are sure with your decision.
Then he will be the one.
So I wasn't going to miss this chance.
Alice, I want you to stay.
Because this is the chance for us
to know each other.
Let's go.
I will not forget Wilson.
Because he's my past.
Forgetting him, will be forgetting my past.
The thing is...
We can't forget about the past
We need to take the past forward.
I think...
You will be with me for that, right?
Right, definitely.
Shall we drive on?
There's a lot to buy if I'm staying.
Hey...
Hi.
Where's your girlfriend today?
She's busy.
I thought you said the two of you
have broken up.
How come you two...
were together again?
No wonder you're so happy.
Talk next time, I'm in a rush, see you.
Come again when you have time
Wilson!
9 Months Ago
Taiwan
Stop there!
What are you doing here?
Alice doesn't want to see you.
Can I see her?
She wouldn't be like this
if you didn't lie to her!
She hasn't been happy since she came back,
what do you want?
Grandma, I'm sorry, I really love Alice.
I won't let you see her.
Go, you're not welcome here.
Did you not hear? Go!
Now!
Get lost! Go!
Doctor...Why is Alice like this?
She doesn't remember anything but me.
After the car crash,
there's a blood clot in her brain
Causing this memory lost.
Amnesia? Will she get better?
It's hard to say from her
current condition.
A lot of patients become better...
After a year or so.
Grandma
What are you doing here?
I'm here to see Alice.
It's you, it's your fault
That Alice doesn't remember anything.
Get lost,
I don't want you hurting her again.
Please let me stay with Alice,
I can help her.
Let her come back to Hong Kong
She has a lot of friends there
that can help her.
Wake up, I won't let her remember you.
Why are you so harsh on me?
I beg you, what do I have to do for her
to come back?
Only if you die.
If you are dead,
I'll let her come and see you.
That grandma is such a bitch.
No big deal if Alice doesn't come back.
Don't get upset,
there's nothing great about her.
Yeah, she's not your only girl.
She's not exactly your favourite?
But I really like her.
I need her, you know?
The grandma said
she won't let you see her.
What are you going to do, die?
What if I do die?
You're kidding right?
You still won't see her if you're dead.
No, I mean what if I pretend to be dead.
Not a bad idea.
I have a plan.
But I need your help.
What is it?
Tell us, count me in if it's fun.
If it's toying with that Taiwanese girl,
count me in.
You know how much I hate her, that bitch.
Forget it.
Is it something fun, can I join in?
The cover's been blown,
should we kill her?
I got just the role for her.
What? Do I have to act?
I can act, count me in.
- Bitch! It's your fault... - Stop!
Wait a minute, who's going to play you?
I mean the dead one.
I know who.
Hello?
My Dear, where are you?
I'm meeting a friend for drinks.
Don't be too late.
I've bought dessert to eat together.
Okay.
Miss.
What do you want, sir?
Coffee please.
Yes.
Miss...
Miss, sorry, my phone's battery is dead.
Can I borrow yours?
Okay.
Thanks.
Come on, pick up.
Miss, can I leave your number...
in my friend's voicemail?
And ask him to call you.
Eh...
I'm sorry
But this is a very important phone call.
Okay, my phone number is...
How about, you leave the message.
My phone number is 65766666
Your friend is waiting for you.
Call him, Bye.
Thank you.
You are so nice, what's your name?
My name is Venus.
Hello, Venus, my name is Andy.
Miss.
How may I help you?
I think you've been had.
I don't understand.
I overheard this man in the toilet...
Betting 500 dollars,
that he can get your phone number.
With you telling him.
Watch you mouth, bastard?
Cheque!
Have you no manners at all?
-Hey. - What?
Watch out, bastard.
Just leave, Mussels, get a life!
Thank you, lucky to have you here.
What a weirdo.
But... You are so pretty,
you should be careful.
Mister, how may I call you?
My name is Venus.
Wilson
How was it?
I'm picking her up from work tomorrow.
That's quick! You need to thank me.
Thank you?
I had to scare your ex for you.
You need to get me at least
another handful of girls.
Would that be enough?
What do you think?
Do you know
how hard has the last two weeks been?
Wilson, is it you?
Alice
Wilson
The memorial was so successful
He's really back, go and see for yourself.
I've never seen a ghost before.
Wasn't it a bit over the top
for just one girl.
Had to play dead, and had a memorial.
And, when will you...
return my photos?
She has amnesia,
so I helped her to create new memories.
Memories that love me.
She said she wouldn't love me
if I am the last man alive.
Wilson, I wouldn't love you if you are...
The last man alive!
Look now.
But one day, she might remember
When that day comes,
I might not like her anymore.
Don't need a reason to split up.
You don't like losing.
But you don't want the prize when you win.
I should have made the first move.
Hey, you always lose to me on two things.
What?
One, I make a move faster than you.
Two, I'm luckier than you.
Talk again, I need to go.
I'm meeting someone.
Don't you need to check-in?
I'm not you.
She has nowhere to go but stay at home.
Well, see you, call me.
Take care.
Hey!
I thought you left?
No, I've decided to stay.
Why? You're dating?
Men... can't be trusted.
He won't lie to me, he treats me well.
Sometimes, guys lie to girls,
but they still see...
If the girl they lie to is worth it.
That's true.
When you've heard enough, then split.
You're a fast learner.
Talk later,
my boyfriend has brought me food.
I should go home.
- Okay. - Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Oh yeah.
The note you slipped under my door.
Since you are staying, here.
-Bye-bye. -Bye-bye.
What's the matter?
Where's Mandy?
What do you want?
She was with me...
Miss, that's not funny.
What is this?
When did it happen?
Mandy... She's been gone a year.
I argued with her and she kicked me out.
I received a call, she said...
If I don't come back right away,
she'll kill herself.
I ignored her,
carried on drinking with some friends.
I never thought it was real.
She turned on the gas here...
I know Mandy loved this flat
So I let her stay here.
Maybe it's hard to believe
But I know Mandy is always with me.
Cheer up, still upset?
-Morning. -Morning.
She doesn't like me with other women.
Your place again?
Stop!
Who is it?
She lives above me.
Who's she shouting at?
I don't know, no one's there.
Wait for me!
Stop!
I told her to let me go more than once.
You are so annoying! Leave me alone.
I've had enough
You're not leaving? Then I will!
I don't like you, please go.
Why are you back?
I told you not to come back.
Please, leave me be.
I'm begging you. Let me go.
Miss, you should know Mandy has gone.
The day it happened,
the police said a girl upstairs called.
Weren't that you?
Wilson, I wouldn't love you if you are...
The last man alive!
You'll regret this!
Gas leak?
Anyone home?
Police? There's a gas leak,
I'm at Kowloon City...
I thought you were going?
Wilson's not a good guy.
Stop there, I've called the police.
Where're you going?
I never want to see you again!
Even though Mandy didn't live.
I still want to thank you.
Do you really see Mandy? What did she say?
Did she talk about me?
I think...
She wants me to give you this.
Dearest Keung, when you read this letter...
I won't be in this world anymore.
But I still love you very much.
Maybe this is the only way,
you'll remember me forever.
Love, Mandy.
Mandy did write this.
You're back?
I need a shower.
Wilson...
What did you say?
Hasn't visit for some time.
I don't want to see him anymore.
Sometimes, guys lie to girls,
but they still see...
If the girl they lie to is worth it.
When you've heard enough, then split.
My Darling...
I love you.
She might remember
When that day comes,
I might not like her anymore.
Don't need a reason to split up.
My Darling, I love you.