I told you, I'm only keeping
it if you finish it with her.
Go and tell her now, or that is it.
- Did he love her?
- He was the one that finished it.
That doesn't change anything.
They started last night.
Sometimes people write things
like this on the internet.
- Why?
- Someone wants to get at Mum.
- Who?
- I'll deal with this.
I found these in your flat.
You're going on holiday.
But stay there a while.
You understand, don't you?
I can't do this for ever.
I can't have this conversation.
I'm afraid, last night,
she died in her sleep...
I've changed my mind.
We're all right.
We're going to try again.
Do we have any butter?
Mate, I used it this
morning. Let me have a look.
Did you try the fridge?
Hey, presto...
The butter!
What did your last servant die of?
- Cholera?
- What's cholera?
Cholera is like typhoid.
"What's typhoid?"
- Typhoid is what?
- Typhoid?
- Typhoid, it's very serious.
- What's Thai food?
- Do you want lemon curd?
- I thought you said, "Typhoo".
Typhoo is a brand of tea.
Thai food is... quite nice.
Lemon curd!
- So, he still hasn't admitted it?
- I doubt he ever will.
- And you haven't told him, that you know?
- We're just moving on.
With this massive secret sat
underneath the relationship?!
- Can I speak with you?
- Sure.
Two minutes.
Excuse me.
You're sure you're OK?
It's just very sudden.
After everything, how can
you simply take him back?
Because we have a child together,
a life together, 14
years under our belt,
so if there's any way of keeping
all of that, I have to try.
And you honestly think that he's
never going to see her again?
I'm told when they broke
up, it was very final.
- Nick?
- There's been a complaint.
Fantastic! Another one.
The power of the internet.
The latest yesterday
was that I don't dress
appropriately for a senior doctor.
He was annoyed I wore a skirt.
Um, this one's not online.
He came in and asked to
speak to me personally.
Who is it?
He's requested anonymity
for the time being.
- I'm speaking to the GMC.
- Why the GMC?
Doctors get complaints all the time.
Yes, but as you say, there's
also the comments on the website,
and, um, what... what happened
with your mother-in-law.
My mother-in-law took her own
life, I don't know why everyone...
It's as much about protecting you
as anything. This new complaint.
He talked about your
personal life, your marriage.
Wait.
You really can't tell me who this is?
Sorry.
Fine.
_
Come in.
Gordon!
Long time no see!
- You're not normally sarcastic.
- Sorry?
"Long time no see." That's
what I expect from the others.
Sorry. Come on.
Come in, sit down.
Let's start again.
What's wrong?
My shoes don't fit any more.
- Your shoes?
- Yes.
There must be something
wrong with my feet.
- So, were you sick?
- I don't think you're picking up
- on the right bit of the story.
- Yeah, Mum just said,
when you and her met,
you had a few too many.
Me? No. Only one of us
was tipsy that night.
Oh, shit.
- You OK?
- Yeah, yeah.
You want to be careful with alcohol.
Makes you say things you
shouldn't, and... stand on chairs.
What do you mean?
- I think we need to tell him the whole thing.
- Fine.
It was your mum who'd
drunk too much that night.
She stood on this chair,
looked around, and then saw me,
pointed, and said I was the
best-looking man in the room.
- You?
- Your dad was younger then,
and the room was not
in a very nice pub...
- That's true, there wasn't much competition.
- So, then what?
They started to play ABBA,
I tried to dance on
the chair, but fell off.
Your dad helped me up and said
that maybe I should have some food.
We got a curry.
And that's how we met.
Oh, God! It's today.
That's why you were
talking about it. Ah... !
- Um...
- I'm an idiot.
Don't worry.
- I'm so sorry.
- What have you done?
Every year, since then, on the
26th of May, your mum makes a curry.
And I get her a card.
And you forgot?
Dad, you are RUBBISH sometimes.
Yeah. Well...
Honestly.
It's OK. You've been busy.
Simon!
Um...
um...
oh!
You liar!
Oh, look!
- Can I see?
- NO!
Thank you.
Everything's going wrong at work.
Can I do anything?
Yeah, will you beat them up?
Tuesday?
Perfect.
Everything all right?
Yeah. Just, it's a problem.
At work?
Yeah. Yeah, it's fine.
- Can I have a word?
- Sure.
Ah.
- Sorry, can you sit on this side?
- There's only three of us Nick,
- I'm not sure it matters.
- We should take it seriously.
- Here?
- Thank you.
You've got the outline
details of the complaint there
that you threatened to burn
this man with a lit cigarette.
I'm assuming you deny it?
Of course.
As you know, normally there
are internal procedures.
There are.
But, er,
I spoke to the GMC this morning
and they indicated that we should
consider the wider context...
- What's going on?
- Gemma, if you let Nick finish, he'll explain.
Obviously, the online
comments are anonymous
but we can't ignore them entirely.
To an outside eye, they
might appear to have...
a pattern of behaviour.
Also we've had the police here,
asking questions about the
death of your mother-in-law.
Who talked to them?
- Luke, mostly, he was...
- "Mostly"?
They asked about some things
to do with procedure, as well.
Do you think that I've
done anything wrong?
- There needs to be a process.
- No, but...
- You, personally, Nick. What do you think?
- Well...
You have been going through
a lot lately, in your life.
- How is that relevant?
- You said we were talking personally.
The GMC have suggested we mutually agree
you take a leave of absence, informally,
while the complaint is investigated
and we look at the website.
It would help, as well, wouldn't
it, to have some time off?
No.
What if I don't agree?
Then we'd have to look
at a temporary suspension.
And, Gemma, that would be so much worse.
When?
When do you want me to stop, then?
Immediately.
You don't have to pack up.
It's only a couple of weeks.
Presumably, while I'm away,
you'll become senior partner?
You think I want you to go?
We're following professional advice.
It's not my fault.
I helped you!
I told you everything about Kate
and the baby, I spoke to Simon,
did everything you asked.
Then suddenly you're giving him
another chance which is up to you,
but forgive me if I
stop trying to keep up
and take a step back,
and act professionally.
Gemma!
Whatever's going on, some time off
would be a good idea, wouldn't it?
What did you tell the police?
- What?
- You said they asked about procedure?
- Yes.
- Something was said to them here
to make them suspect me.
All right, well, er, they
asked about our access to pills.
- And I told them what I found in your bag.
- Why were you looking in my bag?
I wasn't looking!
I needed some hand gel and your
bag was there on the side and open,
and when I found it,
I saw that there was...
a bottle of sleeping pills with
some anti-sickness medication.
And then, the next day, your
mother-in-law did what she did...
- They were Jack's.
- So, I...
Jack's?
He wanted to kill himself.
I took them off him.
You still have them, then, in your bag?
Yeah.
I have.
I don't know where
they've gone, I had them...
- Oh, Gemma... !
- Don't!
Don't make me feel stupid.
They were there.
I'll tell the police I made a mistake.
But take this time.
- They said I have to see someone else.
- Yes.
The other doctors laugh at me.
- They don't.
- They do.
- You know they do. What's happened?
- Google me and you'll find out.
Sorry.
Hi.
That's what I thought.
- You're back with Carly?
- Yeah, not drinking any more.
I was suspended today
because of your complaint.
You know why I came round that day.
- She needed help.
- No...
You found out what
your husband was doing.
You were angry, you took it out on me.
- Look, I'm pleased if you've sorted yourself out.
- Not "if".
- Carly's given you a second chance.
- Yeah.
Give me a second chance, too?
Carly showed me the website.
- You're out of control.
- No.
I've been through a lot
in the last few weeks,
but things are better now.
Please. I... I can't
stop working. I need it.
Carly?
They've suspended her.
Um...
OK, Dan, maybe you should tell
them not to go forward with this.
Have you admitted it?
Said that... What happened?
They'd start a disciplinary
procedure and I can't...
How much?
How much to withdraw the complaint.
You really need to
stop offering me money.
Yeah.
OK.
Come on, son.
Go on, Tom.
- Leave it with me. Hey! My favourite doctor!
- Hi.
Hi!
Hi.
Well, your husband's
taking this very seriously.
Well, he was never very good at
sports himself, so it matters.
He's just the same!
How are you?
Good, thanks.
You going out?
- What?
- She's talking about the skirt.
- I had the same question, but she's 20 something...
- 23.
- Yeah, well, apparently I don't get a vote.
- I like it.
- Yeah, I'm sure the boys do, as well!
- Yeah, shut up, Dad!
Get up! At least I could
run in a straight line!
Get up! That's better.
I've been meaning to
say, it is ridiculous
that we haven't all got
together, the four of us.
- It's what happens when you leave it to the men.
- Sounds fun.
I'll e-mail you.
- Bye.
Oh, so close!
Come on, Tom.
Nice ball.
- I thought you were at work?
- I wanted to see our son.
Come on, Tom!
Simon, the, uh...
... the partners at work...
um, have asked me to take some
time off pending an investigation.
- You mean?
- Suspended me, effectively.
Why?
There's been a formal complaint
that I went to the home of a patient
and... assaulted him.
Assaulted him? You?
Ros, she... she's a partner.
- Can't she?
- There's been the stuff on the internet,
and the police have been around
asking questions about your mum.
Apparently, that...
"paints a picture". Sorry!
It's all right.
OK, OK, it'll be all right.
Thank you.
- That was you.
- Yeah.
Right, sorry.
I didn't want to...
- Who is it?
- Work.
OK.
Are you not going to reply?
I don't mind if you want to.
What?
What's going on?
When you got the text, your...
... your body went tense.
I was surprised. That's what
people do when they're surprised.
- OK. Honestly. You can reply.
- You still...
You still...
You think I'm lying?
You still don't trust me?
Look, do you want to see the text?
Time, date, details of the supplies
for the foundations. Here. Look.
No. It's fine.
Well done!
We lost.
Only just,
and not because of you.
Right. Two cars. Who
are you going to go with?
No offence, Mum, but you
don't know much about football
and me and Dad have to talk.
Where to? Somewhere to celebrate?
Celebrate what?
- You, of course!
- Oh.
Pizza?
Yeah, actually, that
would be really good.
Simon? Pizza?
Argh, really sorry.
Crisis.
What?
The thing with the supplies.
We need to talk about
options, today, sorry.
Boring. Um, I'll just be a couple
of hours. I'll join you later.
Pizza is a great idea. You can
teach Mum about the offside rule!
Well, why can't you come now,
and sort out your problem later?
Sorry, mate. It just
doesn't work like that.
I'll be around tonight and
we can catch up then, yeah?
OK.
You already know the offside rule.
Yeah.
Is there anything you don't know?
Quite a lot.
Dad!
He works really hard, doesn't he?
Mum!
You're going the wrong way!
I need five minutes with your dad.
You said we were having pizza.
Do your homework.
I want to come in!
You can't.
- Oh, shit...
- What?
Your face.
I, um... I didn't know
you were coming over.
They normally buzz up.
I told them that I wanted
to surprise my husband.
I'm not having a good
day. Is he in there?
He's on the phone. Gemma, are you... ?
You're holding something back.
I mean...
I mean, you've been doing
that for a long time, but...
... something's changed.
You've suddenly become
really bad at lying.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Does my husband bully you?
I mean, not physically,
but he patronises you.
I suppose, that's why men
want female assistants.
So, they can push at
least one woman around.
- You've been covering for him for years.
- I don't... cover.
- I'd like to believe that.
- Well, you should.
But your face.
Look, if you take a seat,
when he's off the phone,
- I'll let him know that you're here.
- I wanted his support.
I've basically just lost my job,
but from the expression on your face,
I think he's off having
sex with Kate Parks again.
You split with your husband.
So, you can imagine
something of what I'm feeling.
I've known for a while.
They have no idea.
Well, they will now.
I assume it's not locked.
Where is he?
His car's outside.
Well?
What?
He was always worried that someone
might follow him or see him.
They had a system.
You can get out from
the back of the building.
They're back together.
He'll never leave her.
I kept telling him to stop.
I HATE what he's doing.
You went on holiday with them.
- He said he needed me, that they'd be working...
- Where did you go?
Kate's dad has a house in France.
Said she could use it for friends.
Her dad wasn't there?
No. They don't know about Simon.
He'd kill him if he did.
- Show me pictures.
- What... ?
Of the holiday. On your phone.
You, him, her. Neil,
Anna. I want to see.
Why would you want to see?
I thought that I had a
chance to sort this out,
but, clearly, I'm delusional!
Look, not that it matters
but, yeah, you're right.
He can be horrible.
- Especially when he's stressed.
- Can you e-mail these to me?
I...
If you want.
- And don't tell him I know.
- Why not?
I want to do it myself.
- But not now.
- Do what?
- I told you to stay in the car.
- Where's Dad?
Mum, what's wrong with you?
You're so weird at the moment.
Mum!
Why are you such a mad bitch?
It's scary.
Your dad's gone out
for a couple of minutes.
You know Becky, don't you?
Becky, could you text Simon,
tell him that his son's
waiting in his office
and needs some pizza before going home?
And then, when he gets
back, could you explain
that I've forgotten that I need
to go to a conference... tonight.
I need to leave immediately.
- Be gone a few days.
- What?
Your dad'll look after you.
You can talk about football.
- A conference? It's always work!
- Yes?
OK.
Good.
Bye, then.
Bye.
Mum!
You're too clever! All right.
Look, there is no conference.
That's a lie Becky and I
are going to tell your dad,
because I just can't deal
with everything at the moment
so I need to go away
for a couple of days.
And I don't want him to worry,
so... I'm making an excuse.
Now, you have a choice.
You can tell Dad the truth,
or you can join me and Becky
and tell him it's a conference.
It's up to you.
Don't do that!
Your dad does that.
What do you mean, you
can't deal with everything?
Life's hard sometimes.
- How long are you gone for?
- Couple of days.
- OK.
- Good boy.
See you soon.
Shit!
I'm fishing.
Saw it in a film.
Doesn't work.
You OK?
Mary!
Visitor!
My husband used to shout
at me. Now he's dead!
Those two things might
not be connected, Jack,
but are you sure you
want to take the risk?
- Oh.
- Hi.
Jack, make some tea.
- What's happened? You look upset. Where's Tom?
- With Simon.
- Did you tell her?
- No.
What? What's going on?
Can I stay?
Well, I've got no clean towels.
I'll find some. Course. You
can stay as long as you like.
Sit down.
- I thought you didn't have mobile reception.
- Oh, they put a mast up.
I wrote a letter, it made no difference.
He cheated on me.
All right.
Where's that tea?
There. KEYPAD TONES
Problem solved.
Thanks...
for taking Jack in.
He's a pain in the
neck, but, like you said,
he's useful round the house.
- Sorry he's so rude.
- It's the right thing to do, so it must be done.
He's stuck in the past,
that's been his problem.
- He was with David a long time.
- I know.
When you lose someone like that...
when you're going through hell,
you've got to keep going.
Can I help?
No, thank you.
- Don't suppose you have any wine?
- What do you think?
And Jack shouldn't so
don't you dare buy it.
You can have another cup of
tea or there's some squash.
Was it advice you wanted?
Is that why you're here?
- No.
- You'd never be told before.
I just needed to get away.
I see.
You'll want to get back for
Tom, soon, though, of course?
You'll want to get back for him.
I might just... get some air.
Dinner's 20 minutes.
You're addicted to those things.
Same as David, he was
never off his iPad.
- How did you get these?
- His assistant.
You grew up around here.
Yeah.
Mary helped us out.
Picked me up from school.
When my mum and dad
died, she was all I had.
What happened to your
parents? She wouldn't say.
Car accident. When I was 16.
I stayed with Mary
for a year, but she...
I was bored of people feeling
sorry for me, so I went to London.
A levels, medical school, met Simon.
Moved.
Started a new life.
Had a child, then we got the house.
I love that house.
How's this working out for you?
Well, off the booze,
health's improved,
and she's got someone
to do the gardening.
- So, you'll stay a bit longer, then?
- Forever.
But not with her.
Moving on, Gemma.
I can recommend it.
Get Tom on a train up here.
- You don't need to stay in that place.
- Why should Simon win?
Who cares about winning?
Be happy.
I understand all that
but you made a commitment.
She can't stay there.
- Come on!
- Better or worse!
Rubbish! You need to leave.
But it's my town. I've got friends.
It's Simon's town, and if
you're talking about friends,
you could do a lot better.
- It's not fair.
- "Fair"! Gemma, not to be mean,
but that's the sort of thing
you were saying when you were
a little girl. Life isn't fair.
It's how you deal with it.
I was thinking in the car...
what if I never came back?
Women do that sometimes.
Tom would be upset, but
he'd have his dad, friends.
Maybe it'd all work out.
Who would actually miss me...
if I...
vanished?
You shouldn't say things like that.
- You know what it's like to lose a parent.
- I coped.
And he would too.
What do you mean, "vanish"?
You thought about it.
Those pills.
The one person in my
life that ever loved me...
... had gone forever.
- It's completely different.
- I agree.
Right.
- What's happened to me is worse.
- Now, you're being ridiculous!
David died in pain, coughing
up liquid... desperate.
There was nothing I could do...
- At least the time you had together was real.
- You can't compare the two!
It isn't like Simon's just
gone. He never existed.
Every moment that we spent together
was false, because he was never
the person that I thought he
was. Gemma, he's made a mistake,
that doesn't mean he's a
completely different person.
And my parents died, also in pain,
and I don't know exactly
what happened in the crash,
but I bet it wasn't
instant like everyone said.
So, I... know what it's
like to be left behind.
But I'm...
... really sorry, Jack,
I loved David, too, but...
... what's happened to me is
so much harder to deal with,
I promise you.
I'm going to bed.
You need to be careful
when you're upset.
- You've always known.
- What?
Exactly how to hurt people.
Yeah.
- Hi.
- Hi! Where are you?
In a hotel.
The conference. Didn't Becky say?
But you just... left.
I've been trying to call.
I'll be back in a couple of days.
You just forgot about it?
Things have been difficult...
... recently, so, yeah, I forgot.
You asked about that text.
I thought you might've...
- What?
- ... been upset.
- How are you?
- I couldn't sleep. I was worried.
Any news?
What news?
Anything you want to tell me?
No.
OK. Well... look...
I'll call you tomorrow?
- Bye, then.
- Bye.
Gemma!
Shit!
What are you doing?
It's freezing!
I wanted to drown.
I told you, that's...
not...
But then I thought...
No.
What do you mean?
Best put this on before
you get hypothermia.
Gemma, stop.
Wait!
Where are you going?
Home.
I thought you were away?
Simon asked me to pick up Tom.
I need your help.
What do you mean?
You owe it to me.
You're back.
Hey! I saw your car. You said two days.
I changed my mind. I
didn't want to be away.
I'm all over the place at
the moment. Can you tell?
That's why I was worried.
Are you ready?
- What for?
- Dinner.
We're due at half seven.
What? Who with?
Go and get a shirt on.
It's mad living with you sometimes!
What about Tom, who's... ?
- Becky's looking after Tom tonight.
- Gemma called,
said she was coming back, and
wanted to keep this dinner,
but the short notice meant she
didn't have childcare, so I offered.
Thanks.
You really won't tell
me where we're going?
You used to be into surprises.
Fine.
Do I like these people?
You love them.
It's the Parks.
They invited us yesterday.
At the football?
Gemma...
I can't.
What? Why not?
Oh, hi!
Hi!
- What?
- Gemma...
Oh, God. What's going on?
You're not expecting us...
Hello, Fosters!
- What's this? You're... ?
- I think you're a week early.
Really? But this is the... ?
- I thought... You said "Thursday" in your e-mail...
- I meant next week.
- Oh, I'm so sorry... it's my mistake!
- Oh!
- Ah... Come in anyway!
- No, it's fine.
- We'll head back, we're tired actually...
- No! Nonsense!
We can rustle something
up. You're here now.
- That'll be all right, won't it, Susie?
- Absolutely.
For these two, we will make
it work, come on! Come in!
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
Honestly, I think we should go.
We've got the kids in tonight
so there'll be plenty of food,
it'll be fun!
- I'm really not...
- Come on!
God, it's gorgeous.
You have a place in
France? What's it called?
- The house?
- Does it have a name?
We'll talk.
Gemma, help yourself.
How's your love life?
There's been a complaint
made against me.
- What's the complaint?
- Chris!
A man says I threatened to
burn him with a lit cigarette
unless he left his girlfriend alone.
You don't mind me opening up about
the difficulties we've experienced?
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -