"State Commercial Bank"
Thank You.
I appreciate it very much. Ms. Gordon.
Most helpful.
We thought you had to know.
Absolutely you know we bankers can't be too careful.
Give my best to the husband of yours.
Thank You.
Yeah? Yes sir.
Hey, Stirling, Mr. Munroe wants to you.
"Out to lunch"
You sent for me, sir?
That's all Miss King.
Sit down, young man.
Stirling, how long have you been with this bank?
About four years, sir.
Counting the time before the war.
Four years.
I'll go and speak frankly.
There's a great deal of talk going around town,
Talk that aren't good for you or the bank.
- Yes sir. Oh, so you know about this?
- Oh Yes sir.
- Well, young man then you can understand.
In the banking business, we can't be too careful.
The talk's all nonsense of course.
Oh, But sorry it's not nonsense.
Aren't not ... What?
I mean it's true, sir.
But how can such an absurd ridiculous.
Stirling what's the matter with you.
Well .. could I.. , could I tell you about it?
- Tell me?
– Yes, you just let me explain.
- See here I'm an extremely busy man.
- But, sorry. It means my job.
- Well, then ... take it brief..
- Yes sir.
You see, sir.
It all began a few years ago over in Burma.
- Burma?
- Yes sir.
The jungle was the hottest I'd ever known at that day.
Still there was no excuse for me a second lieutenant.
Getting separated from my platoon.
No excuse at all.
When I realized that I was alone   lost behind Jap lines ...
I was scared.
Then I thought   that my company commander...
would say when I told him   I lost my platoon.
and I was really scared.
At last I took refuge  under a tree.
I must have been exhausted,  because I fell asleep.
Our barrage woke me.
My mouth felt dry.
It's funny how wet you can be outside so dry inside.
Hey, watch you, if you don't wanna live, I do.
Keep your head down.
Who said that?
I'd, here.
Where you are? Come on or I'll shoot.
Lieutenant.., you'd better put that gun up before you hurt somebody.
- Who's speaking?
- Me.
- Who's me?
– Me, The mule.
Something ridiculous.
Coming from a Second Lieutenant, that's all most ironic.
- It must be a booby trap to some kind..
- You're all the know.
But it's fantastic.... I don't believe it.
Hey.
- What are you?
- I'm just a army mule...
.. and my name happens to be Francis.
- Francis?
- It's a girl's name.
- Aha.. Let's keep sex out of it.
The name is still Francis, with the an "I"
- Where the sound?.
- Why?
Uh, it's some kind of a trick.
Sent a mule that does talk.
We are facing an extremely serious situation, uh?
- I must decide what a course of action to take.
- Brilliant Lieutenant..
..smug deal of no bore no brilliant.
I must be crazy I'm freaking if you can talk.
The hit of my head must be worse than I thought.
I get to get out of here.
- Say.
- Uh?
- Could you carry me out of here?
Carry you? And slow myself up? Uh! Uh! Uhuh
But I'm an officer!
A second lieutenant.
Why wouldn't be very patriotic.
You mean my life isn't worth saving?
Well.. the question is.. would it be worth risking mine to do it.
What do you mean?
Is there a shortage of second lieutenants? Certainly not.
The War Department have announced that got a lot surplus.
But mules? Ehh.. That is a different story.
Nooo. I just couldn't do it.
It's not with my interest in furthering the war effort.
All ears here!
- My leg, I've been hurt.
- This what happen.
- By the tail of my Greta aunt Regret that won one Derby ...
.. how are leave you here from Jap space?
- Go ahead go ahead, save yourself.
- You know perfectly well I can't leave you now.
Well, I thought you said I was just a second Lieutenant wasn't worth saving.
- A whole name. Wouldn't you become a matter of principle.
- Never mind then, come on, get on my back and I'll take you to an aid station.
- Francis, I have you make this carefull, please.
What as mulas goes through with a couple of straikes.
- Lieutenant Stirling?
- Yes sir?
- How's your leg?
- It's just a flesh wound Capitan.
- I understand getting out of here in a couple of days.
- Fine. Uh, cigarette?
- No, thank you.
- Stirling ...
- I am from G-2.
- G-2?
- What is intelligence wants of me?.
- You lived quite an experience up there, didn't you?
- Yes sir.
- The men of my patrol ...did they all go well?
- They're all back safe and sound.
- So okay Lieutenant, those things can happen on patrol.
- Where we were crawling along on the hillside sir, and then suddenly I was alone.
- I was afraid the call out.
- Lucky for you that mule found its way to headquarters.
- Mule? Oh!, Francis.
- Francis?
- The mule, sir, Francis, he spelled it with an 'i'.
- You seem to know quite a lot about this mule.
- On what he told me sir.
- What, who told you?
- Francis?
- Yes sir. The mule.
- That's what I thought you said.
- But Lieutenant, this doesn't indicate there's anything the matter with your mind?
Where's the reason, sir?
- But.. what you just told me.. a mule talked to you?
- He did, sir..
- You're sure that?
- Yes sir. I.. I ain't believe it at first either but he really did.
- Now.. we're.. take it easy, Lieutenant.
Just ... take it easy.
- Well young feller How are you getting along?
- Fine, sir.
- A little bump on the head too didn't you.?
- Yes sir.
- Doesn't seem do amount to a thing.
- No sir.
- I hear you talk Captain Grant and the mule talk to you, it's that right?
Yes sir.
Well my patients like to have their little jokes.
- But I wasn't joking, sir..
- Come lieutenant, this is no time for leg pulling.
- There's a war going on you know mules can't talk.
- Oh, that's what I thought, but this one talk to me.
You mean the animal talk to you the way I'm speaking now?
Maybe maybe not so loud sir.
Tell me, Stirling ...
Tell me Sterling is it just one particular mule who talks to you?
- or do all the mules talk?
- Oh, just Francis, sir.
- Francis?
That's the mule's name...
It spells it with an 'I'
Do any other animals talk to you? Elephants, rabbits..
..chickens, goldfish?
No sir. Of course not.
The very thought of such things talking is ridiculous isn't that young man?
Yes sir.
Lieutenant! yours is not an unusual case nothing unusual about it at all
In no time we'll have you fixed up good as new.
"Room Neuropsychiatry"
Good morning, boys.
Samuel. Ben.
Hi, Raymond.
Feeling better?
Come, come, lieutenant, up today.
Colonel Plepper wants to see you.
Colonel Plepper?
Yes, sit up, up, Psychiatrist.
Psychiatrist? But I do not need a psychiatrist.
Now, now, come along.
"Sex in Civilization"
Yes?
- Yes? oh, well?
- Col. Plepper, Lieutenant Sterling is here.
Lieutenant ...
This is Colonel Plepper.
No, no my boy none of that, just sit down.
Make yourself like at home.
Thank you sir.
How long have you been with us Lieutenant? Let me see..
Ten days.
Huhum, I see you gain a pound per day?
I've been on a condensed milk diet.
Huhum, Remarkable look into ful man remarkable.
You feel fatter?
- Yes sir.
- It's perfectly natural.
Wonderful the way the army is able to put weight on the men.
This is go to the beautiful art chart.
Now, Lieutenant ...
Suppose you tell us all about your friend the mule, who talks, uh?
Well, Colonel, sir, I must of been wrong about that.
Just imagine it.
It could have been that bang on the head.
Or perhaps I was just shell shocked.
Oh no, we call it combat fatigue.
You're thinking of the last war, Sterling.
Well, I must begin fatigued.
But I'm perfectly all right now so.
Of course you are.
Why don't you report to Colonel Saunders, this afternoon, for assignment on duty?
See how quickly the Army can do you?
Ohoh God
Yeah.. Uhuh
Fine. Then I'll bring Miss. Gelder over right away.
Your calls are all the way. The ladies of the Red Cross are waiting to welcome you.
Oh, mercy. they are so kind to let me stay.
Still under the wing of the army you know?
Yes but maybe so little time before, we're sure that it's safe for you
to return to your father's trading post..
I am so attached with the war and your trouble with me.
Papa would be very grateful.
If only we could find that, all we know you're all right.
But who knows where he is?
The Japanese came in so fast we had to take to the hills ...
we've scarcely time to pack up things.
Then Papa and I got separated.
I was looking for him when your patrol found me.
We'll do everything we can to find your father.
- In the meantime my idea we've better to get you settle.
- Merci , Colonel Saunders.
Merci encore , Colonel Hooker.
I hope you'll be comfortable in your quarters.
Gentlemen.
I hope you are not too busy to attend the staff meeting this afternoon.
- Know what have the Colonel that I haven't guys?
- Ranck, Captain. Ranck.
And me only a second Lieutenant.
And matter of reason for the staff meetings, gentlemen.
Of course this opening in the intelligence action over the usual opportunity for an advancement.
Gentleman I'd like to ask that any officer in this headquarters..
..who feels too he has special qualifications for G2 work. ...
- Lieutenant Brimm?
- Sir, I speak seven languages of the Far East.
- I was a professor at Duke University.
- Fine. Make a note, Lieutenant.
- Captain Norman?
- I've spent nine years in Burma prospecting I know the country and the people.
- Yes sir. All dialects, fluently.
Very good. Note that, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant Stirling?
- Second Lieutenant Stirling!
- Yes sir?
Lieutenant, you have any special qualifications for intelligence work?
No sir. None at all, sir.
I do not even ... No, sir. None.
G-2 Intelligence?
"Limit the City of Angels"
You know it's hard to picture of you, a  young beautiful girl like you  ...
...living in the jungle training post.
- But you find it pretty dull?
- The jungle dull? Mai no...
It is  mystérieuse,  wonderful, thrilling.
And I'm afraid that all of the men around here don't find it so thrilling.
Oh , that is because they are so lonely, nes pa?
It is sacrilege the way that lots of sound would been a wasted.
Yeah, I can hear the Colonel last two red corpse so yelling for reinforcements.
Something reality in the fooll dish.
It's in all their faces.
A sort of ... sadness.
Oh no, no, not sad, my dear, hunger.
They are all hoping I'll drop dead.
Ooh..
...and they're all so handsome, so attractive.
Well, it is a good strategy if I did share you with them.
Come out, I'll introduce you.
Hello.
Lieutenant Stirling?
I know oblive you've better at charming guest, Ms. Gelder.
No no no no no I haven't sir, but it's wonderful.
A pleasure, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant Stirling , he's just been assigned to intelligence.
Oh, and so very young too, my compliments Lieutenant.
- Thank You.
You must be Lieutenant Sterling's friend.
Fascinating.
Simply fascinating.
Ehm, and you can to ask me to dance, Lieutenant?
You mean you would? I, I mean would you?
Me oui, but of course.
After Lieutenant Colonel Sanders, and the two Majors, and ...
Lieutenant. Lieutenant Stirling.
Surprise Lieutenant, someone looking for you.
Lieutenant Sterling was my favourite patience, such as unusual ...
Shall We Dance?
Lieutenant? The Colonels, the Majors, the Captains ...
- What will they think?
- Oh, oh, what have I done?
Forgive me, I'll take you right back.
Me no, I like a masterful man that sweeps me away from everyone.
Oh, gee, I did this night?
"French"
Monsieur, monsieur.  Please, please.
This is the masterful young Lieutenant Stirling.
Bonjourn mon ami, bonjourn.
Oh, Ms. Gelder?
Uh, comment allez vous?
Oh, tres bien, merci, Eh, I see you studies  français.
That is very nice.
Oui.  But when I say it, it does not sound like you do.
Well, this is the same for me that only, English, you see?
And at the trading post I do not learned,
but there's only papa.. and he's worse even than me.
Tell me,  monsieur ...
if your army should have a message from papa...
They will tell me, no?
Well, you see, but you mustn't worry.
Maybe I can, well, look into, and let you know.
Oh, ceci tres gentil. So very kind of you to trouble
I would be most grateful..
..until then..  Au revoir, monsieur.
Ahh, bonjourn monsieur le sergent.
Good morning, sir.
Morning.
"Come at once, Francis."
Oh, sergent, do I for a ride?
All right, yes sir.
Francis, it's me, the second Lieutenant.
Hey, hey Francis?
Remember me?
Sure, maybe I am more crazy.
Most Second Lieutenants are.
All right, all right!
Then, then you can talk?
I, I did hear you the first time.
I didn't imagine this all. I'm not crazy.
That's debatable, Lieutenant.
But, well, then why did you send for me?
Me? Send for you?
Yes, this note you wrote me?
- I never put anything in writing..
- But it's signed "Francis"?
Get smart, Lieutenant, you've been rimmed by your buddies.
Rimmed?
Uh, then the joke's on them,  you can talk.
I'm going to bring them out here and prove it.
Lieutenant, meet the Sphinx.
You mean, you let a laugh at me?
Let them think I'm a mental case?
Nice that you know that you send me home as a psycho.
- So?
- Well, I know what you think ...
a Second Lieutenant,  but even we want to help win the war.
Come back here. You're my rouse ragain.
I never thought I'd have that whet nurse a Lieutenant but...
How'd you like to be a hero?
Me? A hero?
For your information there's a Jap observation post ...
spot in your base about 2000 yards from headquarters.
Oh, don't be an ass.
Be that as it may, that Jap observation post is there.
Well, then why aren't you doing something about it?
- I am, I'm telling you.
- Me? Why?
You know what section you're in?
Well, certainly, I'm in G-2, intelligence.
Than, don't sound so all fired surprised when I give you some.
This must be reported immediately.
Now look! Haven't you been in the army ...
..long enough the knowing that you don't get medals for just reporting?
- But what else can I do?
- What else can you do?
- You can go out and capture that post.
- Who? Me?
Either you're a soldier or an optical illusion?
And that night I have to find out which?
Ohh, that's must be an illusion.
What do you made up for, Lieutenant?
My acking back.
Shows of my great aunt Regret tail..
You're making enough noise to wake up the all Jap army.
Well, well. What are you made up for Lieutenant?
What secret weapon have you got hidden in that pack, huh?
It's a shelter hat.
In case it rains or do you expect to shack up with the all Japs?
Come On.. Get rid of it. Come On!
- Why the shovel?
- We may have to dig entrenchments.
Look, Lieutenant! If there's need to be digging down, then would be to bury you.
Get rid of it.
And that gas mask too.
I have an order to wear my gas mask at all times.
Do you really believe that two Japs in the middle of the jungle ...
Are gonna launch the first gas attack to the war ...
against you, personally?
That go all too.
Now, how many grenades, you got there, uh?
- A dozen.
- A dozen?
Look, Lieutenant. We're going after two.
Get it? Two frightened Japs.
How do you know that are frightened?
Two Japs solo on are always frightened.
One grenade planned it.
A whole dozen grenades.
- Now, that revolver..
- Oh, suppose the tommy gun doesn't work?
Then, you won't need anything except flowers.
Yeah. Huhu...
- Francis, you stripped me.
- Ahhah, we're all ready to go.
And for the love of Burma men, quiet!
Come on.
Hey, go yen. I am sensitive.
I thought you said it was only 2000 yards.
Oh, we haven't even gone 200 yet.
Shhhh, they're right up there.
What do we do now?
I'm gonna get behind them.
You stay here. When I yell ...
- Fire a couple shots to the air.
- In the air?
Shh, shhh, shhh, quiet.
In the air.
Pull down your guns
You're surraunded!
Come down! On a double!
Holding with your men, Lieutenant!
I'm I'm coming!
Forward, men.
I'm Lieutenant Sakia. Please to make your acquaintance.
Save me a bows . One false move will brilliant.
Very good, very good. We surrender.
I hope you kiss a duck, you surrender.
Keep those hands higher, high!
- Come aroud here, Lieutenant!
- Yes sir.
Get them up.
Not need to worry my good fellow.. We know when the game is up.
Eheh.. Quite a call of it in accent, you got there.
- Harvard, I presume.
- Harvard? Certainly not.
- Yale.
- Ohh, "socially". Let's go.
What happened?
"What happened?"
Well, my boy, you've army congratulated.
- G-2 is proud of you.
- No, no thank you, sir.
Yes sir.
Yeah..
- How about one of these?
- No, no. Thank you, sir.
I suppose you realize, Sterling, what you've done all of highly irregular, mind you, but of tremendous value.
And you did it alone. That's give remarkable part of it.
Oh, no sir. That's not quite...
- What's up Lieutenant?
- I mean yes, sir.
The General is dilighted.
And now, Lieutenant just.. a few questions.
- Yes sir.
- The Japanese observation post..
just how did you find out about it?
What's the matter? It's a simple question.
- Yes sir.
- Well?
Well, I don't know, sir.
- What kind of an answer is that?
- I mean, I'd rather not say, sir.
You're rather not say. You Capture a Jap observation post ...
Within 2000 yards of headquarters and you'd rather not say.
- Why?
- Well, even if I told you, sir, you would't believe me.
Well I'll be the judge of that, Well?
- Do you really wanna know?
- I demand to know.
Well, sir, it all happened like this.
The mule ...
Well, Lieutenant, welcome home.
It's, it's... that mule again?
Such a fascinating fun that we have. Such fascinating.
Is Colonel Plepper.
- Good morning, Colonel Plepper.
- Good Morning.
No. No, my boy.
- Well, well. Then how are we today?
- Fine, sir.
Of course. we are nothing serious the matter with us.
Nothing at all.
But you do have a cool feeling at these your fingers?
No sir.
- Then you suffer from a little dizziness, everything seems to be revolving?
- No sir.
I mean there are times when you feel faint, out of breath?
- No sir, I don't think so sir..
- No.
Oh, I understand, Stirling.
The thing that's bothering you is here, Uhm, uhm
You're feeling perfectly all right, then suddenly ...
There's a sharp violent pain?
No.
- Lieutenant did they take X.rays of your head?
- Yes sir.
- And what did they show?
- I've nothing, sir.
Lieutenant, what the devil of the matter with you?
There's nothing about with me, sir.
Nothing? Uh!, I've an attitude for a military man.
Drive my doctors crazy, drive my psychiatrists crazy, drive my entire staff crazy.
- I'm sorry sir.
- Sorry?, uh!
Half of them say you're loco, the other half says you won't.
Me and here docs right think they are loco.
- People mad have a good dose of castor oil and hot bath, if there is crazy resistant ...
- Doesn't make much difference anyway..
- Yes sir.
- How did you ever get your commission Lieutenant?
- In Officer's candidate school, sir.
- absolved your examinations?
- Yes sir.
Doesn't prove a thing.
- Father and mother are living?
- Yes sir.
- Sane?
Doesn't prove a thing.
Well that's it, gentlemen. What do you think?
A clear cut case of hyper imaginative reaction ...
induced by emotional starvation.
Acute symptoms impelled by battle fatigue.
- What treatment would you suggest, colonel?
- Activity.
Violent activity.
Give him 4 aspirins and send him back to duty.
Sterling, the medics have recommended activity.
- For you fortunately I've got just a thing.
- Really, sir?
- Yes. Do you see this area, Lieutenant?
- Yes sir.
We have reason to believe that there is a Jap patrol in there.
- That colose?
- Right.
We don't know the number of men  or just where they are.
So, we decided to send out a patrol tomorrow.
Of course, sir.
- And I've chosen you to lead it.
- Yes sir.
- Who? Me? But ...
- But what?
But ... Yes, sir.
"Secret"
"Hill X246" "Camp"
Yes?
Who is this?
- Francis who?
Lieutenant, please .
But if you can't talk on the telephone?
I'm hearing you're leading  an expedition.
you know what? That's impossible.
For you to lead an expedition  or for me to hear about it?
- You're just guessing.
- "Is Hill X246" guessing?
For heaven sake's, that's top secret.
Now you're showing signs  of basic intelligence.
Then you'll show a little more  and get over here.
Yes sir.., I mean, I'll be there.
How did you know I was lead a patrol?
How did you find it about Hill X246?
If I found out it could be sure the Japs know.
- But that's terrible.
- Why?
Oh, they'll ambush us, well, I have to call off the patrol.
Ohh, nothing of the sort that's the beauty of it.
We know, they know, now all we gotta do is the out manoeuvre on.
Who is "we"?
Well let's just say that we're going to work it out to get there.
- For why'd out?
- The information that the Japs have ...
It gives you a great opportunity.
- For what?
To carry out your mission successfully.
But what have I do?
I don't know why I worry about you, Lieutenant.
I can't even understand why I like you.
I suppose and all these are traces of the mother complex.
Lieutenant? This mule should be in the river, with the rest up.
I want him on to the front.
I know, but that is the way it's done.
Sergeant, shall am I in charge of this patrol?
- Yeah, So they told me.
- What's sir?
Sir.
- Tell them to close up.
- They're close enough.
- Sergeant Chillingbacker!
- Yes sir.
Have a boy, Lieutenant.
- What are we do now?
- Why you just go ahead with the patrol?
This is it. X-246.
Take the men down for our security post on the edge of the clearing.
And tell them to keep alert.
Those are supposed to be 20 yards out in the jungle.
I want them on the edge of the clearing.
And tell them to pitch the tents in the center.
- You mean out there in the open?
- That's right.
- But, Lieutenant ...
- There.
Okay.
- What's sir?
- Sir.
- What now?
Have them give the campfire ready, a big one.
What? I will not.
Are we gonna handle this, Lieutenant?
We are.
What a way to fight a war.
What do we do now? Just wait to be white out?
- Now ... we light the fire.
- Light the fire?
Splendid. Fine job.
And now, Lieutenant, just how did you know ...
that the Japs were going to ambush you?
Yes?
Good morning, Lieutenant. We have a visitor.
- Ohh no.. No another doctor.
- Not this time.
Colonel Plepper says you need stimulation.
Stimulation. Bless that dude
Yes, but who... who is it?
- Are we respectable?
- Yes.
Yes.
You may come in.
No, no, no. Please do not get up.
And how is my Lieutenant?
Well, fine since you came.
Then I'm happy to be here.
- Will you be all right, Lieutenant?
- Oh.. I'll take very good care of him.
I'll be outside.
Just in case.
- Please let me.
- Thank you.
I thought this would pleased you.
Gee.
Thanks. And then thanks for coming.
Oh, Thank you.
Me? What for?
What for? Why everyone know hell courses, we talk of nothing else.
Killing all those ... And not one of your men even wounded.
It was so very wonderful.
- Yes, but wasn't I ...
- Please don't be so modest.
Gee. You're so beautiful, Maureen.
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
Forgive you? For what?
Oh, oh Please.
I like to hear you say Maureen.
Gee. My name is Peter.
Peter.
What is that?
- I don't know.
- Have you ever seen it before?
No, not that I ... Say it look someone's like...
Could it be that someone is trying to send a message to you?
Who would want to reach me? Gosh, I can't read these signals.
At Papa traiding post we had a wireless.
- Can you read that?
- I would try.
BUT ...
QUICK.
- "But quick". Yes?
- F ...
RAN ...
ClS.
- What does it mean?
- "But quick Francis.".
Then must be in trouble. I get to get out of here.
- Going somewhere, Lieutenant?
- No, no.
There are guards out there. What might I gotta do now?
- You wish to get outside?
- I must gotta see Francis.
Oh.. That is very simple. I will go out.
In two minutes, they will not be there.
Francis, Francis, where are you?
Francis, you're hurt.
I got you fast as I could. Tell me what happened.
Nothing. Don't you ever get tired?
I just wanted to tell you ...
Ah, ah.. You've brought company.
- Why don't you wait for me?
- But, well,  I didn't think there wasn't time.
Now, what were you saying, Francis?
- Who are you talking to, Peter?
- Francis.
- Why did you send for me?
- Lieutenant.
It was you to sent signals, wasn't it?
Well? say something.
What's the matter with you?
Don't you realize that I had to escape from a psycho ward to get here?
I could be call martial for this.
Oh, my lieutenant. Do not excite yourself like this.
- Come, let us go back.
- No. he can't do this to me.
Now why did you send for me? Come on, now start talking.
But  mon ami,  come with Maureen.
- This is not good for you.
- Then you think I'm crazy too.
- But I tell you, Francis can talk.
Oh yeah. Yes, of course.
And then very intelligent mulas too.
You must do have he's said.
- But he hasn't said anything.
- You have too excited to hear him.
He said, it was all a big mistake.
And you must go back with Maureen and rest.
The nurse she will be so angry with both of us.
Let us start walking.
Now see what you've done. Why don't you talk?
Please, please, Lieutenant, come let us go.
You got me into this you. You! You!
Oh. Peter, I know. You wait right here.
I'm in right back. Wait like a good boy.
Just one moment. Wait. Uh?
Quite a dame.
Oh, now that ruined everything for me, you talk, uh?
Well I have you know Ms. Gelder is no dame.
That's a matter of view point. Now maybe we can talk.
Francis, stop treating me like a child. Remember, I'm an officer.
Remember? Lieutenant, didn't owns me.
- Oh I now, why did you send for me?
- Cause I've got so highly information.
Oh no. Oh no. Not again.
- Look. Look At Me. You see this?
- Mmm. A pajamas.
- JUS I presume?
Yeah, from the psycho ward where you put me.
Uh, uhu...
Still, it's in credit to be have, and I thought you might just this well ...
Would you please stop trying to bill me up?
A few months ago, I was a perfectly happy second lieutenant ...
Mind in my all business... bothering nobody.
Then I met you and what happens?
I spend half of my time in the booby hatch.
Well, thanks very, thanks, but I've had enough.
Maybe now, I get stay out of the hospital.
Okay. If you're don't minding yourself ...
...bombing in the camp this afternoon, I don't know why'd you worry.
Are you crazy?
Hey.. you're the one in the psycho ward, remember?
N.. Now.. Wait a minute, Francis.
- What do you mean "bombing in the camp"?
- Uh..That's better.
I've got so highly information, and better be pass on fast.
At 4:35 this afternoon, headquarters gets hit. Three waves of enemy bombers.
An array? But this is serious.
I hope to kiss my great aunt Regret it is serious.
Remember: 4:35 three waves of enemy bombers.
Uhh, looks like the dame came for help.
Oh.. What will I do now? They take me back to the psycho ward now, I won't be able the..
Cause then there's an old army maneuver known as "squamen".
Quick, behind those bushes over there. Hurry.
If you are not right about that the array, I'll be klept raid out the army.
Might be a patriotic gesture. Duck!
- You sure that is the place Ms.?
- Oui  I'm sure..
This is the mule. But the poor lieutenant is gone.
Never should I've left not for a moment.
- So that's talking mule, eh?
- Why don't we ask him where his pal is.
Do not waste time with this stupid thing...
while the poor Lieutenant is getting lost somewhere in the jungle.
Oh, he's probably halfway back the camp, right now.
Come then. We must sure.
Ohh, my poor lieutenant.
Remember enemie Bombers at 4:35.
Ohh.. my poor lieutenant.
Lieutenant do you realize the seriousness of this information?
Yes sir.
Where's you'd get it? If you tell me was that, that jackass again, I ...
Lieutenant, I'm in charge of intelligence.
You come and tell me that I've headquarters is gonna be bombard,
ain't knowing it playings.
- You've give me the scedulers and then by finder you, that too in tarnish think you working for?
- For you, sir.
- And you still can't tell me the source of your information?
- No sir.
- Lieutenant, one of us is crazy.
- Yes sir.
- Yeah..
- Do not be impertinent, young man.
- Oh no sir.
- All right. Lieutenant.
- I got to take the chance on your task, than I'm gonna trust you.
- I can afford not to, that's all.
Lieutenant.
Do you know the status of a buck privates and men's are a mean?
well, if the information you gave me isn't right, heaven help you.
I could I have you busted so low ...
.. that you'll have to use a telescope to look up to a buck private.
Yes sir.
Engineers basis. Delaminate. Red alert.
May heaven help you, Lieutenant.
Sergeant, get those boxes and leave.
Lieutenant, the only thing I can say is ...
heaven help you.
Do not complain. This is for the duration of the war plus six months.
Quick. There is heat, are the Japs.
For heaven's sake, Francis, you're not sleeping?
It's after 4:35. It's after 4:35.
Ehh.. usually it is bad this time of day.
But nothing's happened.
I hope headquarters didn't go to sleep on that information.
- Go to sleep.. We brought and find warplanes from every units in Burma.
Francis, Francis, are you... are sure of your information?
- Ohhh.. I suspect it's all right.
- Suspect? Suspect?
Do you know what are gonna do to me?
I' gonna have to use a telescope to look up a buck private.
Oh why had I even listening you.
My career is ruined.
Did a mean. Do second Lieutenants have careers?
Wait a minute.
- I think I hear something.
- And they're mosquitoes.
Francis, they're coming. Look. Up there.
I can see them. Look.
And here come our interceptors.
I knew you're right all the time, pal.
I'm so happy, I could kiss you.
Relax, Lieutenant. I can take it as well as an ex mule ...
but this has a limit to everything.
- Lieutenant?
- No. Thank you, sir.
And as I said Lieutenant, this entire command will be eternally in your debt.
Eternally.
Now come, come. No more nonsense.
You must realize, that this is going the army joking stage.
- But, Sir..
You know, Lieutenant, I'm with you very fond of you.
Yes sir?
- And, I'm on act as your father.
- Yes sir.
And.. Isn't an affaire d'amour, hey, Lieutenant?
I could understand.
D'amour? Oh, oh. No, sir. There wasn't any  girl.
Oh.. No girl.
But what the Great God Jupiter, why that so long find confidential your source of information?
I just can't tell you, sir.
- Why?, Why?
- Because you won't believe me, if I did.
Oh. No, no. No that mule again...
Yes sir.
Hello of you! Is that our cute home mule again?
How fascinating. Simply fascinating.
Lieutenant Humpert, hasn't anyone come to see me?
If, by anyone, you mean Miss. Gelder, yes ...
But the Colonel Plepper's orders are "no stimulation".
No one is permanent can visit you, ...Except
- Except? Except who?
- Except the Commanding General.
Who did you say?
Lt. Gen. Stevens.
Nobody can stop him from seen you.
The Commanding General wants to see me? Oh no.
But it's nothing to be afraid of.
He's just another man.
General Stevens.
At ease, Lieutenant.
- Sit down.
- Thank you sir.
Well, you've been having quite a time. Haven't you son?
Yes sir.
You prop on very service both to your country and to my command.
And you've also caused truly turmoil.
You know that, don't you?
I'm afraid I have, sir, but I didn't mean to.
But, I'm sure that you did.
And I think you and I can get to the crocks of these situations successfully.
Now, in every interview, you're claim an army mule talks to you.
- Is that right?
- Yes sir.
My boy, I want you to understand the position ...
In which you plays ball me and my command.
Now, your actions are worth of the highest commendation.
But your explanation of those actions is an affront ...
the intelligence to dignity of my command.
How do you suppose this tale of the talking mule ...
will sounds when communicate in Washington?
But it's true, sir.
Am I do understand you refuse to tell the real truth, Lieutenant?
Oh no. Sir..
I have told the real truth. It's just that nobody believe me.
Hell I'm stamped. Completely stamped.
You really believe a mule talked to you, don't you?
I know it, sir.
Positively, the wierdest tale I ever heard.
West Point, 35 years in the army ...
nine campaigns, seven children, four of 'em in the army.
I thought I'd seen everything.
But a Lieutenant who insists he know the mule can talk.
May.. May I make a suggestion, sir?
May? Ohh.. I insist that you do.
Well Perhaps.. Perhaps you're going have a talk with Francis.
Perhaps I what?
You mean you want me to meet this animal?
Yes, sir. Then you can ask if what I said isn't that true, sir.
Me? Ask a mule?
Well. If I have did such a thing, I lose my command.
Talk to a mule?
But I should say not.
Lieutenant, this is the animal?
Yes sir. Hello, Francis.
How are you today?
Francis, I want you to meet the Commanding General.
Francis, the commanding general.
Is something that matter?
Sir, I'm afraid I should have told you this before.
Francis is scared that the army will discover he can talk.
What?
He said he was afraid that he sent to the Officer Candidet School.
- The mule?
- But that what he said, sir.
- Well, what are we do?
- Well, sir ...
Francis has been in the army for seven years...
and he takes great pride in the military.
I believe if you're giving him orders, he'd obey them.
Orders? What sort of orders?
Well, perhaps maybe.. maybe you could trick in the talking, sir.
Lieutenant. As an officer, have you required to do some mighty strange things ...
But giving orders to a mule to trichk her..him..it..
..it.. in the talking.
Well, I just wonder what the limit is.
Attention!
Right hand!
Left hand!
About, FACE!
March Hand!
At ease.
Attention!
Renumber!
Want you try it again, sir?
A step forward. March.
Report!
At ease.
A remarkable well trained mule, Lieutenant.
But there is no indication that the animal can talk.
May I try again, sir?
Go ahead.
Francis, you and I have came through a lot together.
We faced death together.
So for my sake. Would you, please ...
please talk to the General?
This all thing is ridiculous, Lieutenant. It is inexcusable.
Some of you junior officers are the army.
You're full up, of broon and broon juice.
You confuse me, you confuse the G-I
You confuse the all war up.
When I think at what you'll use the postwar world ...
The hell that I have left stand to the danger.
General, you said a mouth for.
Just give me some junior officers and then I have the best...
Who said that?
It does my heart good, General to hear you talk that way...
Just echo what I've been thinking ever since Pearl Harbor.
Lieutenant, you're a ventriloquist.
Oh No sir.
Attention!
No nonsense, this is an order.
I want to right answers to direct questions.
- Name?
- Francis.
- Organization?
- 123 Mulas detachment, sir.
- Serial number?
- M-5-2-5-1-9.
- At ease.
That I'll be hand.
I'll be bouble and triple hand.
I'll be hand in 72 languages.
- So you can talk?
- Yes sir.
Lieutenant Stirling, I owe you an apology.
We all owe you an apology.
Yes sir.
You Francis have done a truly magnificent job for the army.
Ohh.. shocks.. I would try to do my duty as I saw exel.
When America hears about you little core more, feel a role in the war.
That's the last thing I want, sir.
And pardon the presumption, sir ...
It's the last thing you should want to.
- What you point?
- For my point here is the three-star general ...
..won't get me further in those army psychiatrists than lieutenant here.
Well, they would say different things when hear you talk.
But they're not going to.
- What? You mean you won't talk?
- That's right, sir.
- What if I order you to talk?
- I hope you won't, sir.
But I'm the commanding general.
And I'm a mule, sir, and I have the right to act like one.
Francis, the one thing I won't tollerate ...
in my command is willful insubordination.
I'll obey any ordinary mule orders, sure. but that's all.
You'll obey any orders you're qualified to obey, talkiong including.
And if I don't? What happens to you?
Are you threatening me?
I mean to remind you, sir, what happened to the lieutenant.
I'm perfectly aware what happened to the...
Lieutenant, but I ...
For the good of the service, I suggest ...
..we forget about this little meeting.
Well. If you going to be stubborn ehm ...
Maybe I have a point on that.
Anyway, for the second strategy, you leave me no alternatives.
But how am I gonna get out of the psychopathic ward?
Hell, that'll be take care of somehow.
Then I think of it. And maybe you're right.
This should go no further.
- Very well, and are we all agreed?
- Yes sir.
Well?
Ohh, Yes sir.
Yes?
Surprise. Surprise, Lieutenant.
Let's gonna start another ducky new basket.
- Here you are.
- Oh no yet. Don't.
As the Colonel Plepper heard from General Stevens jet?
Oh yes. In fact, he is with the General right now.
Lieutenant, is it anything wrong with the General?
Half of the medical staff is over there.
Orders are orders, Colonel, and I order you to discharge Lieutenant Stirling.
Sir, regulations are regulations.
And I can't discharge a man in Sterling conditions.
For the umpteenth time, Colonel, there's nothing wrong with Stirling.
He is perfectly normal.
Normal people normally don't go around truly in conversations with mules.
Gentlemen, I was hoping I'd to avoid this ...
but, for Lieutenant Stirlingt sake, you force me to...
Colonel Carmichael, in according to the army regulations...
You periodically giving me a thorough physically examination?
Oh, yes sir.
- You've always find my reflexes to be normal?
- Yes, General.
You found no sign of neurosis, abnormality or mental elaboration?
- No sir.
- Very good.
Gentlemen, I have news for you.
Lieutenant Stirling's mule can talk.
I've talked with him, and once more, he's talked back.
Really now, General.
Steady, Plepper.
- General..
- What is it?, Colonel Carmichael?
Nothing, sir.
I was mearly trying to remember when you had your last phisical.
Get that through loco on of your eyes , Colonel.
You're not getting me in any psycho ward.
I tell you Francis can talk. Do you understand?
- That mule can talk.
- Yes, General.
If you say so, that mule can talk.
That's better.
Now, gentlemen, for obvious reasons ...
Not a word of this should get out outside this office.
Furthemore, I gave the mule my word.
Tell me, sir. Is it just Stirling's mule who talks to you..
or do all mules talk?
Excuse me, General. Put it right over there, Sergeant.
Hooker, what the devil's the matter with you?
It's just been a transcription of Tokyo broadcast. I think you should hear it, sir.
Colonel Carmichael, when did you last examine Colonel Hooker?
This is Radio Tokyo ...
bringing you the voice  of your Tokio correspondent.
Good afternoon, fellows.  How's it going?
But before I give you the news of the day ...
I picked up a little top secrets  too good to keep.
Believe it or not, the Americans   have talking mule in the Burma command.
Nor mule talk, mind you,  but really important conversations.
He report some Japanese movements,  and helps plans defense strategies.
At least  that with the General plans.
And three-star General  can't be wrong.
Can ya', fellows?
Well, that's the schedule bet, boys.
Of course, it's just barely possible  the poor man can be
Well, you'll guess as it good as mine
But it does make me wonder which jack-ass  would be the better General.
C'est la guerre,  boys.  Not you're, that you, you are.
Turn and blast that thing off.
It is obvious the Japs got wins the Stirling's hallucination...
and they'd reduce this in those damaging propaganda.
- Brilliant deduction Colonel.
- I suggest, General ...
We hence should immediate deny and state the real facts.
But I'd like to know is how the news leaked out.
I'm sure Francis didn't say anything.
Hardly, let we share the lieutenant's delusions about the animal.
Try the funny if have. Imagine if a mule really could talk.
What do you mean "imagine"?
The truth the Mule's idea isn't that to speak up these confidential....
Yes.
I beg your pardon, sir?
A teletype, sir. Urgent.
Well, we're due for a visit.
Plane load of correspondents ...
on their way, they come in heard the Tokyo broadcast.
- They request permission to land.
- Of course, we're refuse this, sir.
What? And make them think I'm really crazy?
That mule is gonna have to talk to the press.
Gentlemen, with your permission.
Colonel Hooker, release Stirling and have him bring Francis here.
Here, sir? Yes sir.
- Colonel Hooker.
- Yes sir?
Tell him do... brush him up a bit.
Yes sir.
And if you think of starting me on a basket...
I have three of you a court martial.
Dismissed.
What's the idea, Lieutenant?
The General's orders, sir.
General, Lt. Stirling and a mule reporting, sir.
Send them in.
At ease.
What catch you, Lieutenant?
Oh, Francis still wouldn't come, sir
He's here now under protest.
- Oh, he is, eh?
- Yes sir.
If you use him to double crossed. He's not gonna talk.
- What?
- I'm sorry, Francis.
An unfortunate development, but that's war.
Francis, I want  you to meet Colonel Hooker. He's being a bit skeptical.
The G-2 men, you know, hard to convince.
Speak to.
It's a pleasure, Francis.
The General has spoken very highly of you.
Now listen, Francis. This is no time for personal feelings.
The morale of this entire command's at stake.
Perhaps you should rest a while, General.
- You looks very tired.
- Nonsense. He's just that stubborn....
He's just stubborn, that's all.
That's plane do in any minutes.
Attention!
- Attention!
- General, please you gotta get wholy yourself.
Get wholly of myself indeed.
My orders being defied by a stupid, insubordinate jack-ass.
- Keep it hit shaft for this.
- It should be, General.
This would solve a lot of problems.
You can't do this, to me.
You're ungrateful, unpatriotic, meansinable ...
Believe me, Francis, I don't know...
Japs got the news, anymore than you do.
Yes, there's a few questions I'd like to ask on that subject.
If he won't talk to me, he won't talk to you.
Oh..I wasn't talk to the mule, sir.
Lieutenant Stirling? Who did you talk to, about Francis?
- Sir?
- Who did you talk to, about Francis?
Well, no one, sir. There is, I'm alone to Maureen..Uh.., Miss. Gelder.
Ohh..  Ms. Gelder?
But I had to prove that I wasn't crazy, sir.
And I just happened to mention that Francis' talked to the General too.
That's all I wanted to know.
Sir. I may have the answer to everything. I should know in a few minutes.
- May I be excused, sir?
- Very well.
G-2 Intelligence!
Ahh, shoot him and we might win this war.
My sentiment's exactly the same.
Francis, I knew you won't let the General down.
Keep you sure, son. The gentlemen of the press will get not copy out of me.
Oh..but how you not use your head, Francis.
You stand on the threshold of fame such as few men ...
Few people ... Few creatures have ever enjoyed.
Oh, I wouldn't that joy, sir.
Just picture it, Francis.
A special unit had activated to handle you. Waited on handled for it.
Millions listening to you every word.
One of the most "report and sales" sucks I've ever heard.
One that follow of it, sir, make me shivers right down on my tale.
Think of the opportunity. Why? You're a nobody.
Well, the "John-nobody", sir, who will win in this mule's war?
Francis, I've given 35 years of my life to the army.
And, in all modesty, up to now ...
I have been considered a pretty sound military man.
But my all career will be ruined today if you don't talk.
And mine will be ruined if I do.
But Francis, think about my family.
You got me there, General. I haven't got a family.
And according to all scientific report, I can never quite one.
But the answer is still  no.
And I'm still the commanding General of this theater..
Have a good mine and a horse sweeped you
Easy now, general. Suppose you raise one little finger to me.
Just a General slap, mind you. Then suppose I talk.
I can see the headlines. "Defenseless Mule, beating by General".
What a story?.
You're.. You're not worth the gun powder to blow you'd use it...
Mess at my life, mess at my command...
Mess at the all war ever.
You too!
Out of my sight, both of you.
Yes sir. Come on, Francis.
- Well, your surly don't argue, you see?
- Lesson, Lieutenant. Lesson.
Get back there, Lieutenant. You can't leave now.
But the General's orders, sir?
Lord, sir, the correspondents have arrived. They are on the way in.
Get that animal another site, keep another site.
Yes sir.
Sir, the correspondents must didn't see the mule.
Why not? Hiding him it wouldn't hide my humiliation.
But you not gonna be humiliated ...
and the correspondents have going in the story.
- Behind the backboard, Lieutenant.
- Stop talking in circle, Hooker.
I'm in no mood for guessing game.
Geeral,  Miss. Gelder has been induced to substitute.
She is ready and waiting for the press conference.
Does that answer things for you, sir?
Yes Yes.
And if she doesn't make them forget what they came for...
I do not know war correspondents.
Very good, Colonel.
I'm afraid I've been a bit testy.
I can well understand, sir.
Come on. Let's meet the press.
Lieutenant, swirling around him.
- The tail show it.
- Yes sir.
- And ... Lieutenant.
- Yes sir?
- Not a word, none of either obvious.
- No sir.
I wonder.. I wonder what Maureen can do to satisfy the correspondents.
Well. How about a fan dance? Yeah.. Hey, hey.
And as you know, this is one of the manly area,
of action of this war.
This strategic situation here is entirely dependent...
..from the army there up and flows supply.
The airlift is, you're aware, definitely limited.
General, what about this Tokyo broadcast?
But, despite of all obstacles, the job is being done.
General, do we can look at this famous mule?
How about a picture to mule talk?
A surprising interview with this amazing mule?
Yeah, what does that Tokyo rose on talking mule?
Oh, yes, the story of the mule..who's winning the war single hunt...
Single footing
What we could do with an army of sent true remarkable creatures.
Ehh?, Colonel Hooker?
Indeed, General. But I did with lot of through without them ...
in despite the enemy ridiculous propaganda.
As much as we may spoil news value for you, gentlemen ...
But I'm not quite ready for the psychopathy ward.
But you're not going on empty-hands.
Colonel Hooker, I suppose you bring the boys a lots of story for them.
Let do General. As you know, both the British and American armed forces ...
They have been operating in this theater with complete collaboration.
Sometime back, British intelligence picked up the trail
of a very beautiful young woman's  ...
supposedly French, suspected of being part of...
a network of agents collaborating with the enemy.
She was last active somewhere in Sumatra.
Recently one of our patrols, picked the supposed daughter of a Dutch trade agent...
Also a very beautiful young woman,
helping her papy at their own trading post in the Burma hills.
No, that's not true.
Shh.. Shh.. Shh..
We suspect it, she was the same girl, but we have no proves.
So we dig around an ingenual young officer ...
Who assigned to intelligence and dangling as bait.
So, that's what you were doing in the G-2, a booby trap.
When you see the girl and then take a look at Lieutenant Stirling ...
you'll realize that her only interested in him ...
could it been for the purpose of getting information.
We've sorted that the Lieutenant give her miss information.
But, when he contact the fantastic story of the talking mule ...
Miss. Gelder couldn't resist it.
She send it over to the enemy and the trap  exploded.
Well gentlemen, there's your story. Well coming worth?
Sure, if you look as good as you listens.
- Bring Miss Gelder in..
- Let me go.
Pigs. So brave, so strong, these Americans ...
Two of them to guard one girl.
- You have no evidence against me.
- No evidence?
You're the only one to whom Lieutenant Stirling...
told that have safe talking mule tale... the story.
And then this information got to Tokyo.
What prove have you got that I sent it?
Who accuses me, anyway? That lunatic Lieutenant?
Ohh. No, Maureen.
I.. I didn't. I haven't it thing in do it this way. I don't it believe any of it.
Sir, this is obvious a terrible mistake why...
- She could not done it.
- But you could. And you did, didn't you?
Anyone crazy enough to think that a mule can talk ...
is crazy enough to send messages to the enemy.
Is not so, Peter?
- Why do you not confess?
- Maureen.
Lieutenant, keep your mouth shut. I'll handle this.
Sir, this dame got in so good be able to say anything.
Silence, Francis, you speak when you spoken to.
So you.. you can talk.
I hope that kiss a duck, I can talk.
And now I'll tell you how she got that information to the enemy.
You know that all Burmese temple after Road of the Peace?
Well you'll find a couple of natives, hanging around the back door.
They're her messengers boys.
Maureen, why do not you say something? Why do not you deny it?
I deny it? You stupid idiot. It's all your fault.
- You and that stinking mule.
- Take her out.
No, you cannot do this.. They have no proof.
Thank you, Francis. I'm glad to have at least one jack-ass at my command.
Gentlemen, I didn't model to deceive you, but in the interest self...
Spy stories, there a dime a dozens, but a talking mule...
But I still don't believed it mass of nosense.
Sure, the whole thigs is a gag.
We're right to be in play per subtle or gonna as balmy as lieutenant.
This thing can't talk.
A mule is the stupidest beast in the existence.
Next the correspondents.
So you're genius that know everything, huh?
Well, I got some news for ya'.
Quote! There's a war going on. Unquote.
So go sell ya' papers. We got some fight that do.
Francis. Please, remember that these gentlemen count thousands of miles to meet you.
And if I had known, I'd have baked a cake.
Francis, these men are leading representative of the press.
Just go to proves what I always said.
The only reliable reading is the encyclopedia.
Well.. what am I supposed to do, is to write their all wash pond?
All we wanted a few statement.
Okay, shoot.
How did you learn to talk?
Hehh stupid question. How'd you learn?
- Well, my mother taught me.
- Must they have quite a struggle.
Francis, a little courtesy. that's an order.
Yes sir.
Francis, how about a couple of shots with you and the General?
Well, That's up to you, sir.
But certainly, certainly.
All right, gentlemen?
Shoot.
Attention!
High!
"The Car of Francis"
You understand, General, I'm making this trip under protest.
Orders from Washington.
They're convinced the correspondents are crazy ...
and do holding the stories until you arrive.
They've assigned six men to you as ordinances.
You will arrive to Washington on Sunday.
And then on you're under the direct orders of the Pentagon.
Everything is being reins for your convenience.
Just what I deserve for not keep my big mouth shut.
But think of the good you can do.
War bond driver, speeches, public appearances.
You'll have a tremendous influence.
Horse peter's. I'm a fighting mule.
I wouldn't be surprised if I'd run out all known shows.
But.. but you couldn't do that, Francis.
No.. I couldn't. But then again, maybe I could.
You better get starting.
Good boy.
You know something? I'm gonna miss you, Lieutenant.
Gee Francis, well, it's only for a couple of days.
I'm going meet you in Washington.
Oh, must be something a matter with me.
Why?
Oh, I ain't to leave you.
Well, keep you about the shine.
Good bye, Francis.
Yes, so long.
- Take care of yourself.
- That's a hobby of mine.
Amazing. Simply amazing.
- Do you have your orders?
- Yes sir. 24 copies I've of 'em.
Right, I'll you proceed directly from the airport to the Pentagon.
Francis would be there.
You will stay with him reporting the General Fullbright Morale services.
- Well your plane will leave in a few minutes.
- Goodbye Sir.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, sir.
Take good care of Francis.
- Good luck, Lieutenant.
- Thank You.
What? Wait, Lieutenant. Wait.
Are you sure?
It's official?
All of them?
No word of him?
Yes, just as soon as you get anything.
I'll wait.
There's been an accident.
What's, sir?
The plane has crashed.
Francis' crashed?
Oh no. What happened, sir?
- We do not know.
- Where?
In the hills of Kentucky, a few minutes ago. No further details.
The Crew?
All parachuted and safety.
The mule refused to leave the plane.
So I was returned the United States.
I've searched directly to the plane.
Francis's body wasn't there.
Then, I've started coming the Kentucky countryside.
I looked everywhere, sir. Everywhere.
And of course, you've never found him.
- What's, sir?
- I say you've never found him.
Ohh yes sir. I found him.
You... What?
- I found him, sir.
- You did?
But what happened to him?
Oh, he is living with me in my house.
- living with you now?
- Yes.
- Would you like you come to meet him?
- Who? Me?
My baby is   the other side of the ocean
My baby is   across the sea
- Is this the animal?
- Yes sir. This is Francis.
Wake up, fella. I've brought the bank's president
Mr. Munroe out to meet you.
He's heard the story and thought am I a little crazy.
So I want to put his mind to rest.
Into your mind that need to rest, not mine young man.
If that stupid looking thing has a thought and take ..
that along.. talk.
And I'm a jack-ass too.
Here we go, again....
"The End"