Boss, they just stopped a customer
from betting a roll of these. Why?
Why? Because that's Confederate money.
Money's money, ain't it?
Blackie, I don't know what I'd do
without you.
- You'd manage.
-Thanks.
Escort the gentleman gently to the deck
and kick him down the gangplank.
No more bets.
You seen Johnny? It's nearly showtime.
Yeah, he made his daily contribution.
He went that way.
- The rabbit's foot didn't help?
-Help?
He lost that, too.
Okay, new shooter. Come on out.
Johnny?
Twelve straight times he drew cards to 12,
on account of today is the 12th.
He didn't even win once?
With me dealing?
- Piano player.
-Yes, Mr. Braden.
Try to play the notes
the way they're written.
I'll use both hands.
And if Johnny is late again,
I hope he can dance with a broken leg.
That's what I like about you, boss.
Always ready with a pat on the back.
Place your bets.
- You seen Johnny?
-Look under the nearest pair of dice.
- Don't you even say hello to your wife?
-Hello, wife.
Peg, how can I get Johnny
to give up gambling?
Easy. A bullet in the head,
poison in his coffee, a fatal knife wound.
Nothing to it.
Where have you been?
I lost your trail at the blackjack table.
Ran into a guy who told me
about a gypsy fortuneteller.
She's got a hot cup of tea leaves.
I'm a coffee man myself.
What happened with your astrologer?
Couldn't read the stars on a cloudy night?
- You got to have faith, Cully.
-And money.
- How much did you lose tonight?
-How much did I have?
That's what you lost last night.
You're holding your own.
Seven years bad luck.
- It was already cracked.
-Okay, only five.
Be over before you know it.
Say, five. That's a hunch. Loan me $5.
I can't afford you much longer.
- Put the $5 on number 5.
-l'll lose my job if I'm late.
I'll lose my confidence
if l pass up a hunch bet.
Hello, Johnny.
Say goodbye, Johnny.
They're wearing mittens out there tonight.
- They just don't appreciate talent.
-No.
- On stage for the Petunia number.
-Always brings me luck, you know.
You need a new horseshoe.
I've got a gal
Oh, what a pal
The apple of my eye
We're something rare
A peach of a pair
But her dad won't let us meet
and I could die
I love Petunia
The gardener's daughter
Oh, how that gal can kiss
My eyes are blue as bluebells
Each cheek a rose to see
How I dance when she plants
her two lips on me
He's as daffy as a daffodil
He loves to kiss me all the time
Tonight I'll steal into her garden
And make Petunia's two lips mine
She makes other girls look just like weeds
I wanna be his clinging vine
Tonight I'll steal into her garden
And make Petunia's two lips
My ever-loving two lips
Make Petunia's two lips mine
- What were those signals?
-What signals?
Between you and Cully. I'm not blind.
Those signals. Nothing.
He just made a little bet for me.
Now you've got helpers.
Can't you lose fast enough alone?
- Where're you going?
-To have my head examined.
- There must be a hole in it.
-You can't help it if you're in love.
You're born losers, both of you!
- What's the matter with her?
-She's crazy about the wrong guy. Me.
I am a loser.
But if l had $20, I could be a winner.
I hate myself for asking, but how?
This gypsy fortuneteller
parked across the river,
I hear everyone who takes her advice
is getting rich.
- So how come she lives in a wagon?
-The wagon is loaded with gold.
You got $20?
Lucky for you, it just so happens...
You are the lowest person that ever lived.
- Peg, my sweetheart, you've missed me.
-You're not what I've missed.
-No?
-NO!
I've missed the $50
I hid in my winter lingerie.
You know, I never could keep out of your...
You didn't have to stab me.
I should've listened to my sainted mother.
She said you were just like my father.
I could never drink that much.
Don't you dare say one word
about my drunken old man.
- Where's the money?
-I lost it, Peg, all of it. Honest.
- And he loaned me the last $5.
-Now you stay out of this.
Just to convince me,
you take off your shoes.
- My Shoes?
-0ff!
Love and trust.
That's what makes a marriage great.
See? I could never lie to you.
Well, there's a $10 lie.
- Now, how did that get in there?
-I wonder.
Good bye, GYPSY-
Hello, Zolita.
Business is awful.
Why don't you have a talk
with your crystal ball?
Maybe these are two live ones.
What shall I promise them?
A long journey or sudden wealth?
As long as it costs you nothing,
give them both.
Gentlemen, you have come
to the right place.
The one, the only, the incomparable Zolita.
The kid's got problems.
Keeps breaking mirrors
and walking under black cats.
Yes, my son,
you look troubled. Deeply troubled.
No, it's worse than that.
I can't break my losing streak.
You are a gambling man.
Every cent I make.
I could sure use some motherly advice.
Mother Zolita can only interpret, my son.
Perhaps the tea leaves will forecast failure,
perhaps success.
I am merely a princess with a rare gift
handed down
from generation to generation.
- Didn't I tell you she was great?
-She hasn't said anything yet.
The leaves are ready to speak.
No lemon?
The tea leaves have spoken.
If you do not mind, I work alone.
What do they spell, Mother?
How lucky you are.
The wheel of fortune
has stopped at your number.
- A wheel? That's roulette.
-And I see a dice table, too.
No blackjack? This boy plays all games.
And a new woman is coming into your life.
Beautiful young redhead.
It can't be a redhead, Princess.
My girl's a blonde.
Take another look.
Now I see a blonde.
But she has been bad luck for you.
The tea leaves say
you will have good luck with the redhead.
I know better. I married one.
Take the advice of a 20-year loser.
- No redheads.
-He must not defy the tea leaves.
How're you gonna explain her to Frankie?
Why explain?
We'll just use her to make a bundle.
You're going to pass off a beautiful redhead
as a good-luck piece?
Good luck.
- If I may be so crude...
-Sure.
If you please, the princess never soils
her royal hands with money.
$10?
When the tea leaves promise
a beautiful redhead, it is $20.
A lot of money for a cup of tea.
That's a gypsy for you.
Takes all your dough,
so you can't take her advice.
Minor problems like that I cannot solve.
Maybe you can get
another advance from Braden.
Not a chance.
I'm already in for five weeks' salary.
That you lost right back into his pocket.
Braden's got a nice little thing going there.
Don't worry.
Did you ever know a gambler who
couldn't promote some betting money?
- You also need chesay.
-Chesay? Who's that?
Chesay is gypsy good luck. Lazlo!
Drink a cup of gypsy luck
Just tip it up
And then you just say chesay
Swallow once then swallow twice
Goes down so nice
Just say chesay, hey!
What's in the drink, chase the devil away?
Lightning, I think, so just say chesay
Chesay, chesay
Brings you good luck night and day
That's the gypsy way
Trouble is my middle name
Though it's such a crying shame
Try and try, there's nothing I can do
But I'm feeling kinda strange
Feel like things are gonna change
Time my lucky star was shining through
Chesay, chesay
Brings you good luck night and day
That's the gypsy way
Drink a cup of gypsy luck
Just tip it up
And then you just say chesay
Swallow once then swallow twice
Goes down so nice
Just say chesay, hey!
What's in the drink, chase the devil away?
Magic, I think, so just say chesay
Chesay, chesay
Brings you good luck night and day
That's the gypsy way
Chesay, chesay
Brings you good luck night and day
That's the gypsy way
Chesay, chesay
Brings you good luck night and day
That's the gypsy way, chesay
Have you seen Cully?
He's been missing for an hour.
- Tried the Lost and Found Department?
-No, I'm afraid they'll find him.
I always know where to find Johnny.
In the casino, losing his shirt.
With the way the other girls look at him,
you're lucky he isn't playing around.
You know what I'd do
if he ever did me wrong?
- Shoot yourself?
-No, him.
One last request before I cross
the great footlights up yonder.
Like what?
Like, would you loan me $25
so I can pay Cully what I owe him?
Cully loaned you $25? Where did he get it?
Between my nightgown and my petticoat.
Do you know how much
you owe me already?
Who's counting?
You sure you don't want
this money to gamble?
Word of honor, cross my heart,
and may you never kiss me again.
You sound sincere.
What would you do, Peg?
What any woman with an ounce of pride
or self-respect would do.
Give him the money.
Greatest little bank in America.
Two greatest little banks in America.
What a shame you don't have
an account there.
$5, $10...
$15, $20, $25. Makes us even, right?
I didn't think you'd get a dime from Frankie.
- How much you got left to play with?
-l'm broke.
But I got a rich friend who will loan me...
$5, $10, $15, $20, $25.
- You better count it to be sure it's all there.
-What for? I trust you.
Now all we need is a beautiful redhead.
Nellie!
Nellie Bly!
Hello, Blackie.
You look great.
How did New York treat you?
They didn't believe my billing,
“The Singing Queen of the Riverboats.“
- How's the action?
-The boss never had it rolling in so fast.
Money isn't everything,
but it never made a man
look less attractive.
- Put those in my old room, will you, Mac?
-Does Mr. Braden know you're back?
No, I want to surprise him.
Is he in his office?
You don't want to surprise him now.
Why don't you go in and win a few bucks
until he spruces up for you?
Who is she?
That's not nice.
Has Mr. Braden ever cheated on you?
- Well, has he?
-Still protecting him, aren't you?
Why not?
Who bailed me out and got me a job?
And who made a gentleman out of me?
And who...
Okay. Go ring the fire bell.
Tell Braden I'll meet him in the casino
after I pretty up for him.
Are you really going to
make me a star, Mr. Braden?
It's not me that'll do it, Mitzi.
It's your talent.
I do have talent, don't I?
You're loaded with it.
Boss, you got one girl too many.
Nellie Bly just came aboard.
When you've got a message
like that, whisper.
Nellie's in the casino waiting for you.
She doesn't know about you and Mitzi.
It's happened to me again?
I don't get my name in lights?
You just don't have the talent, Mitzi.
But a minute ago, you said...
The only woman
who ever gave me bubbles,
like that champagne,just came back.
And she's funny.
She thinks three is a crowd.
Why, you...
Hi, Mitzi.
- The boss in a bad mood again?
-Bad?
He never felt better.
His favorite girl came back.
I thought you were.
I just found out
I've been understudying the part.
In my next life, I hope I'm not a girl.
I could never go through that again.
- Twenty-six, black. Even.
-Let's try another table.
All blondes. I can't go against Zolita.
You're too darn particular.
The gypsy said a redhead,
and a redhead it's gotta be.
Then we're wasting our time here.
Seven blondes. Not one redhead.
Seven. That's a hunch bet
if ever I heard one.
- One stack, please.
-l'll tell the gypsy on you.
- Place your bets.
-On seven.
- No, lady. That's the kiss of death.
-l'm sorry.
Off seven.
Hold it, Johnny.
Maybe that's your lucky redhead.
- Are you?
-The action's over there.
No more bets.
Seven. A winner. Red.
Thirty-five times twenty.
You would've won $700!
If she can do it once, she can do it again.
Are you a real redhead?
I'm a real everything.
- What's your lucky number?
-One.
- One at a time.
-One it is.
Would you mind giving them
your magic touch?
Just for luck.
You better get the bottom one, too.
Place your bets.
By this time tomorrow,
this ship should be the 5.5. Johnny.
- What's your name, lucky?
- Nellie Bly.
- Welcome aboard.
- That's it, Bly!
I need a name to rhyme with “eye“
for a new song I'm writing.
Now I got it. Nellie Bly.
- You're gonna be made famous in a song.
- l've tried every other way.
I don't even have to look.
I know it's going to be number one.
One, red!
- Maybe that gypsy knew something.
-Maybe? My future just got here.
$100.
-$200.
-Place your bets.
$300.
- This is the big break I've been...
-$400.
- Where'd she go? It was going good.
-What about these chips?
Keep counting. I'll be right back.
Nellie, it's been a long year without you.
You never looked better.
You have.
Who's been keeping you up nights?
Who can remember names?
- What kind of a kiss is that?
-We're not starting where we left off.
I like a girl who remembers
the good things in life.
I thought you came back
because you missed me.
I came back because
I wasn't good enough for Broadway.
L'm big in the small time
and small in the big time.
You'll always be my star attraction.
What about the girl last week?
And the girl before her,
and the one before...
- A man gets lonely.
-Lonely enough to get married?
You're not going to
bring up marriage again?
- My mother recommends it highly.
-Your mother doesn't know me.
What would you do
if I got big eyes for someone else?
- Nothing.
-Nothing?
I might arrange to have his neck broken,
but outside of that, nothing. Come here.
Boss. One of the customers
wants to raise the limit.
- How's he doing?
-Big loser.
Losers we always accommodate.
Don't shuffle the cards. I'll be right back.
- You can't do that to me.
-Hello again.
- Do what?
-Disappear.
You may not believe this,
but our meeting tonight was no accident.
- The gypsy sent you.
-Gypsy?
Who believes in them?
I do.
This fortuneteller told me a gorgeous
redhead would come into my life.
That'd be the luckiest thing
to happen to me.
I'm a gorgeous rabbit's foot, is that it?
- You don't know how badly I need you.
-Tell me more.
Hello, boss.
- I finally found my good-luck charm.
-Did you, now?
Sure. With Nellie beside me, I'll break
every casino here before I'm through.
You're through now.
Didn't you tell him who you are?
I don't even know who he is.
Well, allow me.
Johnny, my number one girl, Nellie Bly.
How about that?
She means a lot to both of us.
- She's private stock, all 120 pounds of her.
-118.
Weren't you due on stage five minutes ago?
Ten.
Forget it, Nellie. He's spoken for.
Yes, but I'm not.
To show you how worried I am,
let's go hear lover boy sing.
Wise men have known
Women can't live alone
So a woman should understand
That what every woman lives for
What every woman lives for
Is to give her love to a man
He may not be the kind
you find in picture books
A real-life hero
with dashing handsome looks
He may not be the guy
that you've been dreaming of
But that won't stop you
from giving him your love
So, dear, can't you see
That it was meant to be
It's part
Part of our destiny
'Cause what every woman lives for
What every woman lives for
Is to give her love to a man
And I hope that man is me
Johnny likes her.
Maybe it'll be one big, happy triangle,
and I'll come out on the right side.
What is this?
You wouldn't talk to me last night or today.
What did I do?
Who smiled at Nellie Bly last night,
like she was the only girl in the world?
- Who is she, anyway?
-You really want to know?
- I really want to know.
-Where do you think I got this?
- You robbed a bank.
-$700, and I owe it all to her.
You owe it all to me.
I got nothing but admiration
for a man who pays his debts.
Now we're even, give or take a few dollars.
When I win, I lose.
Who hates you up there?
If you see her again, and my advice is don't,
thank Nellie Bly for me.
Somebody page me?
Anybody I haven't met yet, I'm Nellie Bly.
I'm Mitzi, last week's kisses.
Well, don't go away.
You might get him back on the rebound.
Rebound?
I'm the original rubber ball.
- Looks like Mitzi's got her hands full.
-Looks like you have.
- Hello, everybody.
-Hello.
I heard you wrote a new number I'll be in.
- That's the one I told you about.
-Frankie, this is Nellie.
- Shake hands and come out fighting.
-I just might do that.
Your claws are showing.
And they scratch.
I hear you're Braden's girl, off and on.
-L'm nobody's girl.
-Let's keep it that way.
Could we stop wasting time and rehearse?
- You written lots of hits?
-A trunk full. Wait till Joe hears this one.
Joe, the deckhand?
Joe Wilbur, the music publisher
from New York.
He'll be out here next week.
It's money in the bank if he likes it.
Money you can keep.
- For how long?
-We own half the song.
On account of the title, Frankie and Johnny.
Well, at least the billing is right.
Let's hear it, Stephen Foster.
Frankie and Johnny were lovers
Oh, lordy, how they could love
Just play it.
Frankie and Johnny were lovers
Time they got married.
Oh, lordy, how they could love
Blabbermouth.
Swore to be true to each other
This story has no moral
This story has no end
This story only goes to show
That there ain't no good in men
They'll do you wrong
Yes, they'll do you wrong
Frankie and me, we are lovers
Oh, lordy, how we can love
Swore to be true to each other
JUSt as true as stars above
Frankie, I'm your man
I'll never do you wrong
I knew that I was a winner
When a new gal caught my eye
But I couldn't two-time Frankie
For that chick named Nellie Bly
I'm Frankie's man
I wouldn't do her wrong
Baby, leave me here to gamble
I'll be home before dawn
Don't wait up for me, honey
And don't you worry while I'm gone
Johnny, you're my man
Now, don't you do me wrong
Johnny, he wasn't too lucky
He was a loser that night
So he tried to change his luck
With the gal who wasn't right
He's Frankie's man
But he's doing her wrong
Frankie, I don't wanna make you no trouble
Honey, I don't wanna tell you no lie
But I saw your sweetman Johnny
He was messing around with that Nellie Bly
Well, if he's your man
Then he's doing you wrong
Frankie went back to find Johnny
She wasn't looking for fun
In her sweet, dainty little hand
She was toting a .44 gun
To shoot her man
'Cause he was doing her wrong
Frankie looked into the barroom
Right there in front of her eye
There was her sweetman Johnny
Making love to that Nellie Bly
He was her man
She caught him doing her wrong
Johnny!
Frankie, I beg you, don't shoot me
They'll put you away in a cell
They'll put you where the cold wind blows
From the hottest corner of hell
Johnny, you're my man
But you're doing me wrong
Mr. Wilbur...
He was her man
But he done her wrong
Did I write a hit, Mr. Wilbur?
I'll be honest with you.
You know what's good about this song?
- The words?
-No.
- The music?
-No. Them.
You ought to be on Broadway.
- You didn't like the song?
-lt's fine for their act.
I might even publish it. But a hit?
- I know one when I hear it.
-Well, you heard one tonight.
You're just saying you didn't
because you don't want
to give us an advance.
- Shut up, sweetheart.
-No advance, no song.
Back in the trunk it goes.
Now look, nobody pushes
Joe Wilbur around. Forget it!
- How big an advance?
-Talk to my business manager.
Well, now, Mr. Wilbur,
-$300, and the song is yours.
-$100.
Well, let'sjust split the difference,
shall we? $250.
Well, let's not quibble about it. $200 it is.
Mr. Wilbur, were you serious
about Frankie and me?
I've seen better, but not very often.
-Isn't Johnny great?
-lsn't she wonderful?
All you need is some new costumes,
arrangements, and special material.
Here's my card.
Look me up
when you get to New York. Goodbye.
Thank you, Mr. Wilbur.
We're on our way!
Goodbye, riverboat! Hello, Broadway!
We never got discouraged
We never had a doubt
'Cause sooner or later
Talent must win out
Look out, Broadway, we're coming fast
Now we're gonna see
our names in lights at last
No more hot dogs at Sloppy Joe's
We're gonna dine on steak and wine
at Delmonico's
Rich or poor it's great to have dough
That's one thing we know
Lots of fun, lots of laughs
Signing checks and contracts
and autographs
We're up for N-E-W Y-O-R-K
Look out, look out Broadway
I wanna see all the hustle and bustle
Maybe I can get a date with Lillian Russell
I wanna go out with Diamond Jim
Yeah, if he gives you a diamond
what will you give to him?
Blow the trumpets and beat on the drums
Big town here we come
No more cheap hotels and one-night stands
We'll knock Tin Pan Alley flat on its pan
They'll see that we've got class
with a capital “K“
Look out, look out, Broadway
Look out
Well, all we need is enough money
to get to New York.
A lot more than $200.
- Don't look at me.
-Okay, I'll win it in the casino.
How can I lose
with a beautiful redhead beside me?
- If you're thinking of Nellie...
-Nellie who?
Just remember this,
if she's in, I'm out. Good night.
You would have hated New York, anyway.
We'll get there.
Peg, our half.
Frankie's half of our half.
Where's my half of our half?
Guess.
What am I, a mammary expert?
Got a brand-new rabbit's foot,
a horseshoe from a derby winner,
the lucky cricket Frankie gave me.
Now all you need is a new lucky redhead,
and I know the perfect spot to find one.
Blonde.
Another blonde.
Brunette.
Blonde.
Heaven only knows.
Brunette.
Your guess is as good as mine.
It looks like somebody
cornered the market on redheads.
Let's give it up for tonight.
With this money burning a hole
in my pocket? No.
We could trap a blonde and dye her red.
I'm waiting here for the real thing.
Jackpot.
Watch the old master go to work.
- Hello, Eloise.
-Hello, Charlie.
Wait a minute. You're not Charlie.
- You're Jack.
-That's right, Eloise.
Eloise? I thought you said Abigail.
Pardon me, old master.
Are you alone, Abigail?
Practically.
Boyfriend passed out about an hour ago.
Can't hold his liquor.
And he's letting
a lovely lady like you drift around
by her little old lonesome?
Who's lonesome? I got you two.
She is no gentleman.
- Here we go.
-Place your bets.
Here we go.
- What number do you like?
-Thirteen.
Thirteen?
That's my lucky number,
on account of I got 13 letters in my name.
A-B-I-G-A-I-L.
Thirteen.
Lady, you could stand
a few lessons in arithmetic.
Does it have to be 13?
If you don't bet 13, I'll cry.
No more bets.
Thirteen, black!
You did it!
- What number do you like now?
-Thirteen. I like thirteen.
- Again?
-Thirteen. Bet it all.
Let it ride on 13.
Thirteen!
How about that?
- That gypsy knew something.
-Didn't I tell you?
Let it ride!
- Bet it all.
-All of it?
You can't hit 13 three times in a row.
Don't tell me
you're some kind of a cheapskate.
The lady said let it ride, okay?
The limit's off.
- All of it goes on 13.
-No!
On 31.
- Don't you mean 13?
-I don't like 13 anymore.
I am fickle.
All right, all of it on 31.
He could use a little help.
The winner, 13!
Abigail, don't just lie there. Say something.
Who moved the table?
Frankie, did I wake you?
It's pretty sad music.
Sad? It's a dirge. I almost won $5,000.
$5,000?
Why didn't you quit when you were ahead?
Ask me an easier question.
All right, I will.
Why do I have to love a riverboat singer
whose life is one great big roulette wheel?
Don't you ever win?
That's two questions,
but I can only answer the second.
I wave no magic wand
I own no lucky charms
How then can I explain
An angel in my arms?
Must be beginner's luck
What else can it be?
When someone wonderful as you loves me?
I wave no magic wand
I own no lucky charms
How then can I explain
An angel in my arms?
Must be beginner's luck
What else can it be?
When someone wonderful as you
loves me?
Aren't you going to rehearse?
We're only an hour from New Orleans.
And less than 24 hours from being rich.
I'm dead broke.
Peg went through my pants last night,
with me in them.
- I don't need any money from you.
-You don't?
No. I talked Braden into another advance.
- If I can talk Nellie into meeting...
-Nellie?
She's the right redhead, Cully.
I can win with her.
You can get your head broken.
Frankie and I belong in the big time.
You heard the man from Broadway.
I also heard Frankie tell you
to keep away from Nellie.
Just one hot spin of the wheel is all I need,
with Nellie beside me.
I'll come visit you in the hospital.
The song demands
Down by the riverside
We'll hear them play and keep that beat
Let's get together what a treat
Down by the riverside
Strike up the band, start the parade
Don't let that grand old rhythm fade
Just play that drum, play that number
When the saints come marching in
Shake tambourines, play that comet
Crank up that horn you won't forget
Your heart will hum to that number
When the saints come marching in
The cymbals clang,just pound that beat
Sounds like a hundred marching feet
It's fun to join in that number
When the saints come marching in
See banners wave, oh, hear that ring
We all feel prouder than a king
'Cause everyone, everyone
loves that number
When the saints come marching in
I don't know about you, but I killed them.
- New Orleans loves us.
-What's not to love?
Meet you back at the colonial house.
Peg and I must pick out our costumes
for the Mardi Gras ball.
- What are you going as?
-Lady Godiva. What else?
Lady Godiva?
- That sure ain't fair to New Orleans.
-Let's hope she gets a long wig.
You sure there'll be nobody
at the ball dressed like me?
Madam, in my shop
we specialize in one-of-a-kind costumes.
Let's face it, you're adorable.
How can any man resist you?
My problem is just the other way around.
Allow me, my dear.
Thank you.
Little Bo Peep has lost her sheep.
I don't blame them for running away.
How do I look?
Honey, if l were Louis XV,
I'd make you queen.
I'll get our clothes.
Are you sure I'll be
the only Madame Pompadour at the ball?
My dear young lady,
this is a one-of-a-kind costume
that I personally imported from Paris.
Little Bo Peep is ready for action.
Okay?
Charming.
What Madame Pompadour would've given
to look like you.
Her head. Or was that Marie Antoinette?
Is this a good night
to go out with the wrong man
so that the right man
will ask me to marry him?
For that any night is the right night,
especially on Mardi Gras night.
Harry, give me a hand.
We still have 10 more
Madame Pompadours to get rid of.
Guess who?
- Nellie? I thought you changed your mind.
-Nellie? Why, Johnny, you...
Frankie, I knew it was you all the time.
I was just trying to make you jealous.
Convinced?
That was a guilty kiss
if I ever had one, but let's go.
Go where?
You know Braden's holding open house
in Suite 309.
- Come on.
-I promised to wait here for Cully.
Cully and who else?
Just Cully. I swear.
The left hand?
- All right. I'll meet you there. Suite 309.
-Frankie.
Remember how to do that
after we get married.
Well, it fooled her.
- Watch it, I'm not getting any younger.
-You find Nellie yet?
Braden set her up in Room 306.
She said to meet her there.
Can't I talk you out of this, Johnny?
Not a chance.
Go up in 309 and keep Frankie busy.
I promised to do a number with the band.
Last year's model.
Everybody listen to me
Put a smile on your face
There's no reason to be gloomy
This world's a wonderful place
So when I say again happy
Shout it out
Yeah, get happy now
Well, now, there is no doubt
you've got a lot to shout about
Give a yell life is swell
Shout it out
While there's good food you can taste
While there's music life's no waste
While there's great things happening
There's no end to the joy life can bring
I said come on get happy
Shout it out
Yeah, get happy now
Well now there is no doubt
you've a lot to shout about
Give a yell life is swell
Shout it out
As long as there's someone you can love
As long as bright stars shine above
You've got no reason to be blue
Think what it means
when your dreams all come true
I said come on get happy
Shout it out
Yeah, get happy now
Well, now, there is no doubt
you've a lot to shout about
Give a yell life is swell
Shout it out
I said now there is no doubt
you've a lot to shout about
Give a yell life is swell
Shout it out
There is no doubt
you've a lot to shout about
Give a yell life is swell
Shout it out
Respect for Father Time.
Frankie, where are you going?
Frankie? It's me, Mitzi.
Nobody loves me.
I love you.
Did you know you were dressed
just like Frankie?
That's why I'm leaving.
I caught Braden kissing me
when he thought he was kissing Frankie.
I hate Nellie,
but I'm going to tell her what's going on.
Why tell her?
I want her to be as miserable as I am.
Happy...
Whatever it is we're celebrating.
- That calls for a kiss.
-Go away, old man.
Old man? It's me.
Go away, old man.
Happy...
How about a kiss for the boss?
How about remembering I'm Johnny's girl?
Johnny?
Now, where do you suppose he is?
Where do you suppose Nellie is?
Hello, everyone. It's me, Cully.
Did you know
that you and Mitzi are wearing...
I thought you were meeting Johnny.
Where is he?
Singing with the band.
I never heard him sound better.
His vibrato...
His vibrato had better not be
in Nellie's room.
- Where is it?
-Right down the hall. 306.
I'll let you know if we're both wrong.
Hold it, pedal pusher.
Where is Johnny, really?
Not with Nellie,
if that's what you're thinking.
- That's what he's thinking.
-Shut up, Blackie.
I didn't open my mouth.
Would Nellie two-time you? Would Johnny?
They'd be crazy.
Fill it up, Blackie.
Come in, Johnny. Be right with you.
Get up!
- Who are you?
-You know darn well who I am.
You'll never believe it,
but you and me and Nellie are triplets.
Mitzi.
What are you doing here?
First you got to tell me where I am.
As one Madame Pompadour to the other...
Why did you say, “Come in, Johnny,"
when I knocked at the door?
Because I was expecting him.
Any objection?
If I start to pull your hair out,
I'm not going to stop at your wig.
Johnny thinks I'm his lady luck.
Hejust wants me
to go to the casino with him.
What else does he have in mind?
That depends on how much he wins,
or how much I want to lose.
Attention! I want attention, please.
Wouldn't it be funny
if Johnny made love to me
when he thought
he was making love to Nellie,
only it turned out to be you?
- She's not as dumb as she looks.
-$5 will get you $10.
No, wait a minute. She has a great idea.
Put on your mask.
What do you have in mind?
A little masquerade.
But first, what's the real reason
you're going out with Johnny?
- To come between us?
-Of course not.
To make Braden jealous.
Jealous enough to ask me to marry him.
- You really love him!
-As much as you love Johnny.
Good. Now, let's hear you say,
Johnny, do you suppose
I could come between you and Frankie?
That's amazing!
- And convincing?
-You sound more like me than I do.
Now walk.
You've got to be born with that, but I'll try.
That's good.
Nellie.
- Nellie.
-Come in, darling.
- Sorry I'm late.
-l'll be with you in a minute.
I have to get a handkerchief.
Tonight's the night. I can feel it.
That roulette wheel's gonna light up.
So will Frankie if she finds out about us.
She'd kill me.
Yes, she would,just like in the song.
Ready or not, here I come.
We'll live it up tonight.
Now we're gonna prove
the gypsy was right.
We'll do more than that, won't we?
You're for me, Nellie. All the way.
Nellie, where you going?
Nobody talks to me anymore.
I've been abandoned.
But Johnny isn't with Nellie. I told you.
Where is she?
Why didn't she come to my party?
- Don't go bruising your knuckles, boss.
-I don't need any nursemaids.
- Who's there? Identify yourself.
-Mitzi?
Come in, honey.
What are you doing here? Where's Nellie?
I'm here because I'm here.
Alone, by the world forgot.
I said, where's Nellie?
Her? She went out with Johnny.
I knew I was right.
She's cheating on you.
He's cheating on Frankie.
Why don't you cheat on somebody?
I have been taken.
I haven't.
Two can play that little game.
Two, like me and you?
I just love games.
Welcome home.
Watch the wig. It's rented.
- Who was that?
-Must have been Frankie.
- What was she doing here?
-How should I know? It's not my room.
- You worried about Braden?
-You worried about Frankie?
What she doesn't know
won't hurt her, will it?
Chips, please. And lucky ones.
You stand right over here,
where you were before.
That's it. Frankie's cricket for insurance.
How can I lose? Got my lucky girl with me.
- What number do you like?
-Two. Like in Frankie and you.
Why not? It rhymes.
Spin it real pretty.
- A winner. Two, black.
-How about that?
I can't miss with you.
Pick another number,
and we'll walk out rich.
How about playing your age? Five.
- Five it is. Who wants to grow up?
-You're over the limit, sir.
Then raise it.
- The limit's off, sir.
-So is your hand.
- My hand?
-Off the magnet button.
- Or shall I say it loud and clear?
-We run an honest wheel here, mister.
The two of us will see to that.
Place your bets, ladies and gentlemen.
Place your bets.
Don't be chintzy. Bet it all.
- On the five?
-And cover all the corners.
- You really know the game, don't you?
-I used to go with a gambler.
I'll surround that five so it can't get away.
Broke again. But just for a minute.
We run an honest game, remember?
Five!
- Winner, five.
-Cash me in, will you?
$10,000. I'm a millionaire.
- Didn't I tell you we'd do it?
-Yes, you did.
It's me and you, Nellie.
We'll break every casino they let us in.
Are you with me?
Why not?
It can't be. No two women kiss alike.
It can't be is right.
“From now on it's you and me, Nellie.
Are you with me?“
Maybe she is, but I'm not!
What happened?
He won, and I lost.
And it's just the way I want it.
- We're all washed up.
-I don't believe you.
No? Have a ball.
I might just be in the mood.
- You sure murdered them tonight.
-Yeah. Right through the heart.
Frankie, you came back.
- Nellie! What are you doing here?
-Maybe the gypsy was right.
Maybe we were meant for each other.
Place your bet.
Gee, it's great to be number one again.
Hold the thought.
What happened to your plan
to make Braden jealous?
It backfired.
He switched to Mitzi,
and so I'm switching to you.
- I could do worse.
-I doubt it.
You're still a loser, winner.
I owe you seven weeks' salary plus...
It was only champagne, honey.
He's all yours, Mitzi,
what's left of him.
Back to 306?
No. Back to Frankie if she'll have me,
gypsy or no sypsy.
Alone at last.
Okay. So I got the money for Broadway.
So what?
You're sure Frankie walked out on you?
I can still feel her farewell message.
- Sorry to interrupt the party.
-Frankie.
Look.
Look. This is our big-time bankroll.
We got it made.
- We?
- Sure. The gypsy was wrong.
I don't need a redhead. I need you.
You're my lady luck.
You're the family banker.
You know what I think of this money,
or any gambling money?
I'll show you.
You wouldn't.
You would.
- Money!
-$50 bills!
Lady, you won't believe it,
but some nut's throwing his money away.
I believe it.
Giddap. Come on.
- How disgusting.
-Money! It came out of the clouds!
Money! Let me in there!
Get out of my way!
Out of my way! Let me in there!
Folks.
- The money that flew out of the window...
-What money?
The money from the window.
I accidentally dropped it.
I didn't see any money. Did you?
I don't guess you did, did you?
Hey, kid. Did you see the money
fly out of the window up there?
No, sir. I didn't see any money.
Okay.
Got change of $50, mister?
No. I ain't got change for $1.
I'm really feeling mighty low
No, no, no
I got no place that I can go
Sol got some blues to sing and
So much remembering
Black cats, keep away from me
Take my advice
Go shinny up a tree
I've got hard luck
The hardest kind of luck you'll find
I ain't lying
I've got the bluest kind of blues
Driving me right out of my mind
She's gone
Said toodle-oo
Kissed her goodbye and my-my
my money too
I've got hard luck
The hardest kind of luck you've seen
I mean
The way I'm running lately
My lucky number is 13
Where do I belong?
Everything I do is wrong, all wrong
Wrong as can be
Who's stacking all the decks
Lady Luck has got the hex on me
Permanently
Shove off
Oh, I'm warning you
This thing I caught, you know
Could be catching too
I've got hard luck
The hardest kind of luck there can be
Yes, siree
I guess hard luck always chooses
Natural born losers like me
How long have we been drinking?
Since last night.
How's your head,
the one I opened the champagne bottle on?
You really launched me.
But you did knock some sense into it.
You found out
that it's really me that you go for?
No. It's Nellie.
But Nellie went “Bly-Bly.“
How could she run out on me
with Johnny Nothing?
Women. Whoever invented them?
Come in.
- Did you find them?
-Couldn't find them anywhere, boss.
I turned New Orleans upside down.
How does it look that way?
You want me to throw her out?
It's no bother.
Two more drinks, and she'll float out.
Looks like no Johnny, no Frankie,
no Nellie.
But you've still got me.
Charming, lovable, talented Mitzi.
The girl with a past
and no future.
Maybe you should've done
what my father did to my mother.
- What was that?
-Marry her.
You should've married Nellie Bly.
Maybe.
But I hated to spoil
such a beautiful friendship.
What a world.
Everybody's split up.
You and Nellie, Frankie and Johnny,
me and
anybody-
If anybody cares, I'm back, I'm sorry.
Nobody cares.
Please don't stop
Loving me
You were born
Just to be
In my arms
Please don't stop
Loving me
Your lips were made
Just to be
Kissed by me
When I'm with you
I don't know
Day from night
Wrong from right
You're my world
That's all I know
I love you so
I won't let go
Please don't stop
Loving me
Darling you'll
Always be
Mine alone
- Who is it?
-Frankie.
I'm sorry Johnny and I missed
the show last night, Mr. Braden.
What about tonight?
You still got the show
for a couple of months.
- Only because you paid Johnny in advance.
-Can I count on two months?
If I don't shoot him for real
in the Frankie and Johnny number.
There's a thought.
Come on, Mitzi. We got an act to do.
I love him. He loves Nellie.
There never should've been two sexes.
Never.
Hey, boss.
Wouldn't it be nice
if Frankie shot Johnny like she said?
No such luck.
No. I've got enough nerve now.
Before I do it,
would you tell me something, Pete?
- Before you do what?
-Can a gal get away with shooting her guy?
- What girl? What guy?
-You don't follow too good.
Now, look. This is him.
This is her.
Her shoots him
for two-timing her with her.
Now, does her get away with it,
or does her
get it in the neck?
I'd say not guilty,
but, of course, I ain't no judge.
Thanks, Pete. You're a real pal.
Do you think a girl
should believe a man like Johnny?
No woman should ever believe any man,
but we always do.
- Are you ready to forgive him?
-Not a chance.
- Frankie, honey.
-Yes, Johnny dear?
Remember now, in a situation like this,
always do the honest thing, lie.
-It's me, the reformed gambler.
-Come in, reformed gambler.
She's playing hard to get.
You missed me.
Kid's got a great arm.
Eddie.
Do you think a girl
could get away with murder
just because she's beautiful
and got nice legs?
Not if l was on the jury.
She'd have to have a nice figure, too.
Like Frankie's. Is that what you mean?
If my wife had a face and legs
and a figure like Frankie,
I'd give up work and stay home.
Frankie says
you've been hitting the bottle over me.
Was she telling the truth?
Nellie, you are just in time.
Just in time for what?
I want to propose a merger.
A merger like two companies,
or a merger like two people?
A merger like marriage.
How about it?
Ask me again after the show.
I want to play hard to get for a change.
I forgot Frankie's gun.
All right, folks. Here we go. On-stage.
Frankie, you got to forgive me.
- Why?
-Because Johnny loves Frankie.
I'll tell her if l see her.
This story has no moral
This story has no end
This story only goes to show
That there ain't no good in men
They'll do you wrong
Yes, they'll do you wrong
Frankie and me, we are lovers
Oh, lordy, how we can love
Swore to be true to each other
JUSt as true as stars above
Frankie, I'm your man
I'll never do you wrong
Johnny, he wasn't too lucky
He was a loser that night
So he tried to change his luck
With a gal who wasn't right
He's Frankie's man
But he's doing her wrong
Frankie, I don't wanna make you no trouble
Honey, I don't wanna tell you no lie
But I saw your sweetman Johnny
He was messing around with that Nellie Bly
Well, if he's your man
Then he's doing you wrong
Frankie went back to find Johnny
She wasn't looking for fun
In her sweet, dainty little hand
She was toting a .44 gun
To shoot her man
'Cause he was doing her wrong
Blackie, who do you know
who can marry us right away?
- You and who?
-Nellie and me.
Johnny Nothing
was really nothing in her life.
How about that?
Boss, things are working out just like you...
What's wrong?
I was only doing what I thought
you wanted me to do.
- You know, I was only...
-What are you trying to say?
You know the blank cartridge
Frankie shoots Johnny with?
What about it?
It ain't blank. I put in a real bullet.
Frankie is gonna shoot Johnny dead.
You stupid...
Sorry.
What's the matter with him?
She caught him doing her wrong
Johnny!
Frankie, I beg you don't shoot me
They'll put you away in a cell
They'll put you where the cold wind blows
From the hottest corner of hell
Johnny, you're my man
But you're doing me wrong
Don't shoot!
Close the curtain!
Close the curtain? What for?
What's the matter, Mr. Braden?
- What's happened?
-That was a real bullet.
Johnny, don't die. Please don't die.
I love you.
You can gamble all you want.
- You really mean that?
-I want you any way you are.
Baby, you got me.
But that gun was really loaded.
I did feel something.
It looks like a bullet dent.
But who put the bullet in the gun?
Let's just say, a misguided friend.
I'm asking again,
do you want to get married?
What have I got to lose?
I think I'll give him the air.
Everybody come aboard
the showboat tonight
We're gonna dance till the morning light
We'll have fun the whole night long
There'll be jokes and song
Forget your troubles, forget your strife
You'll have the best time of your life
Hey, everyone, let's go, on with the show
We're down by the levee
Showboat's at the bank
Bring money to spend
You're welcome, my friend
Just walk up the plank
Everybody come aboard
the showboat tonight
Look around at the happy sight
We'll guarantee that you'll have a ball
Come on, one and all
What a great night you've got in store
You wanna keep coming back for more
Hey, everyone, let's go, on with the show
What a great night you've got in store
I bet you wanna keep coming back for more
Hey, everyone, let's go, on with the show