Episode 3
Subtitles brought to you by The Ministry Team @ Viki
Aw! My head.
Can't we get married for real?
Marry for real
Minister, marry me for real please?
What a weird dream. Pssh.
What kind of dream was that?
Pssh.
Where am I?
Jang-Soo method #12. Ha!
One. Ha!
Two. Ha!
Look at your stance!
Stand like a mountain and move like the wind. Forgot it already?
No, we didn't!
Since I became the Prime Minister,
you have to be models to other childrens in Korea.
You children are
your dad's
face.
In that regards,
smartphone?
No way!
Studying English?
Don't even dream of it.
You want to stop kindergarten?
It's a stupid childish thing to say!
Kwon ManSae. Stop crying.
Wei-Soo method. Sang-Soo method. Shim-Sang method.
Practice it 10 times before you come back in.
That's all.
Chief Kang was going to be here. What brings you here?
It's your first day. Of course I should be here.
You'll have to wait a bit.
I have to get rid of some trash.
Trash?
Whoa!
The smell is not going away.
Whoa. How did I get here?
Aww. I can't remember a thing!
Now, I have just got to get out of here in a hurry.
Are you sober now?
Why am I here?
About yesterday. You don't remember?
Nothing at all?
You begged
me to marry you but don't remember that either?
Wasn't that in a dream?
Giving me the duck feet? (means pretending not to know)
Even if I did that, how can you bring me here?
I can't believe this.
You really don't remember?
"When we are together alone"
Us two...
Get a hold of yourself, Nam Da Jeong. We're almost there.
Here. This is your house, right?
No, it isn't.
I've moved!
Really! This woman
If you moved, you should have told me.
So, where did you move to?
House? My house?
The house I lived with Dad?
Hey. Nam Da Jeong.
Minister. Please marry me. Please?
Please! Minister. Please.
Get her on your back.
Uhh. Should I?
Get her on your back!
Me. Uh. I can't because I got the bag.
How can I? It's your girlfriend.
It's my woman so I'll allow it.
Hurry and put her on your back!
Go to the Government office immediately.
At the police station
I bailed you out. On top of that you caused a ruckus like that and you ask
why did I bring you here?
You think I brought you here because I wanted to?
I'm sorry.
Ah really! I don't normally drink that much...
Exactly,
what is the reason in drinking like that?
More importantly,
why did you ask me to marry you?
It's brain cancer.
Walking you into your wedding hall, holding your hand, is my wish.
At the most, 6 months.
I'm sorry, Prime Minister.
I must have spilled my wanting to get married after I got drunk.
Please just forget it, as if it never happened.  Then...
Where are you going?
Nam Da Jeong slept here last night?
I think she was worried that the Minister wouldn't marry her so she had a few drinks.
She threw up and hung on him asking him to marry her.
It was chaos.
That woman asked to be married? She asked it of the Prime Minister?
What do I do about that woman?
Finally, is it really a first day starting as Prime Minister's staff?
Anyway, I wonder how reporter Nam Da Jeong is doing.
Cheif Kang, let me say something.
Nam Da Jeong isn't the woman you think she is.
Ahh! That's a real bad habit-not thanking people.
Look here.
I know you don't like her but you should be thanking her.
Also, no matter what anyone says, I believe Nam Da Jeong to be a good person.
Let's go.
I told ajumma everything, leave after the children leave.
How long do I have to stay here?
Man Se!
Man Se! Man Se!
Aigoo! This rascal, skipping Kindergarten.
If the Prime Minister finds out, there'll be big trouble! Man Se!
Man Se?! Man Se!
Hey, kid. You have to go to kindergarten! You can't miss school.
The car's already left.
But, what are you doing here?
Cleaning.
Cleaning?
Anyway, I have to go. Have fun.
Fine, go.
I'm fine, even if I'm alone and bored.
I always was.
So just go. You can go.
Man Se...
I guess I spilled my wanting to get married soon after I got drunk.
Did she really wanted to get married?
Today, as a man of your stature, you'll be facing a tough situations
So, Prime Minister must be ready.
What do you mean?
In other words, your training will begin.
With endless official greetings to wear you out.
Endless appearances and meetings.
You have to meet him. Please hurry.
This way. Let's go.
Prime Minister!
With their flattery and compliments, trying to get thier way.
You really are great.
Your popularity has reached the sky!
You are considered the best Prime Minister ever!
Stay as Prime Minister forever!
I thought the position was going to be some great thing.
Chief, Kang. I think you underestimated me.
Sorry?
Stop talking nonsense and get out of the car.
We have an urgent meeting scheduled with the Department managers regarding operations.
Cancel that.
What?
We'll start with the Office's budget.
Please prepare a report of this years' expense and planned expense.
The Office's operating is a must. And a report of each departments' itemized expense and their budget.
Please make sure you miss nothing.
If 10 cents is missing or misallocated, then the managing person
may receive probation, suspension or dismissal.
You understand, right?
Then, see you at the meeting.
But, this seems to be the Prime Minister's room. Can you do this here?
This is the safest place.
Because my dad is the King of Prick, if we came in without permission, we're dead.
He is rather prickly.
Tada!
You know the method, right? Now you have a go.
It is triangular underwear.
I think I can start to understand his taste.
Subtitles brought to you by The Ministry Team @Viki
What's wrong?
Huh?
It's nothing.
Wow, you folded it well!
Ahjumma, do you know how to fold a turtle?
A turtle?
A turtle... of course I can!
I'll show you.
Man Se, why are you sucking your thumb?
Because I'm hungry.
You didn't eat breakfast earlier?
I did. Twice.
But you're still hungry?
I'm so hungry, I could die.
Ajumma, do you have any bread?
Bread?
Man Se,
you're not really hungry.
I'm not lying. I'm really hungry.
I'm hungry!
Come here.
Quickly!
Man Se,
you're bored and hungry, right?
I was like that too, when I was young.
But whenever that happened, my dad hugged me,
and I completely forgot I was hungry.
How is it? You're not hungry, right?
No, I'm still hungry.
That can't be.
That can't be!
Man Se,
so you were here?
You still haven't left?
I'm going now.
Man Se, I'm going. Take care.
What about the turtle?
Man Se!
Where are you going?
Aigoo! Aigoo!
Looks like a sly fox. That's why the Minister fell for her.
ManSe, did that person.. Okay. Okay.
Ohh. You're a good kid, ManSe. Okay. Okay.
Wait!
I came to change the light bulb, but I'm finished now.
She met Man Se?
Kwon Man Se,
don't mess around with my phone.
The rest of the kids?
Woo Ri and Na Ra went to school so I didn't see them.
I don't know what she did to him but MansSe got fooled by her.
She was folding origami with him in your bedroom.
Wait, she went into my bedroom?
Yes.
This woman, really!
Dad, don't be surprised and listen.
I'm actually...
not dating the Prime Minister.
This isn't right.
I'm going crazy. What do I say to Dad?
Tomorrow, come to my house. If you don't, you're dead.
Why is he calling me?
Why the heck?
Nam Da Jeong, you dared to enter my bedroom?
And your nerve extends to climbing onto my bed?
What on earth do you want?
With this kind of stunt, you intend to wear me down to marry you?
No, Prime Minister! I really have no desire to marry you!
-That was just drunken nonsense--Forget it!
There's only one way to make a shameless woman come to her senses.
--Arrest her!--Yes!
Prime Minister! I was wrong!
I was wrong, forgive me! Prime Minister!
Prime Minister!
Forgive me!
No. If he was going to arrest me, he would have just called the police.
Why on earth is he calling me?
Who called you?
You sent me a text.
When did I?
Psshh
Look.
Here.
You sent it.
Come to my house tomorrow. If you don't, you're dead.
Are you for real? Who is this?
It's your number! Look!
No...
Come to my house tomorrow. If you don't, you're dead.
How did this happen?
Kwon Man Se?
Man Se this rascal.
Why hasn't ahjumma come?
Did she not see my text?
Man Se!
Aigoo. What are you doing here?
The Prime Minister is in an uproar.
Did you make trouble?
Let's go.
Wait, I'll just go in for a little bit! Just one hour!
No, my Noona is in there!
Ah! Ah...
Editor-in-Chief, they say we can't go in without an invitation. What do we do?
Ah, should I contact Da Jeong?
If she had any intention to take us, she wouldn't have left alone in the first place.
Ah! Reporter Nam, that awful girl.
She doesn't have the spirit of mutual dependence!
Ah, seriously. Here are the dung flies again.
Hey, Scandal News.
If it's possible, let's not see each other in places like this.
You third-rate, low-quality, paparazzi specializing media.
What would you have to cover at the Prime Minister's place?
Ah, you're working hard.
I'm from Korea's main newspaper, Goryeo Ilbo. Byun Woo Chul.
Today is a private banquet.-Huh?
I said, media coverage is forbidden.
Ah...
Aigoo!
Whether it's Goryeo Ilbo or Guryeo (stinky) Ilbo...
Stinky dung-smelling newspapers are sure different!
Ah, you're right. Why would dung flies show up?
They show up because they smell stinky poop.
Gosh.
What you said was right.
They say it was Man Se who sent it.
Really?
Well, you don't have to be sorry. I can just leave.
In any case, you don't have any business with me. Right?
There, there is a Prime Minister's inauguration banquet.
Yes, before people see me,
I will hurry and disappear. Then.
Aigoo.
I didn't know you were here.
We were going to change your light bulb. Should we come back later?
Oh? Really.
You guys replaced it yesterday, but it went out again.
What do you mean we replaced it?
The electrician was on vacation yesterday.
Right?
Yes.
No...
I came to change the light bulb. It's done now.
Yesterday, I definitely saw a man leaving after changing the bulb.
I saw it.
Subtitles brought to you by The Ministry Team @ Viki
Son.
You must be hungry. Go eat something.
So do you think Prime Minister Kwon invited that woman?
I'm talking about his girlfriend.
Is Kwon Yul someone to do that?
Chief Seo, it's been a while.
Thank you for attending. Then.
That Chief Seo. She must have spent a lot of money at the dermatologist.
Indeed. Considering her age,
that kind of skin isn't natural.
Please stop saying such shallow things.
I'm afraid someone will hear it.
Madame Na!
You came?
Oh, you look so lovely today.
How can you be so beautiful?
I searched around your official residence,
but I didn't find any bugging devices or cameras.
Nothing's missing, too.
Ok, I got it.
I'm sorry, Nam Da Jeong...
But today, you'll have to help me one more time.
The only outsiders who entered the residence yesterday
were the employees from the catering company who came to prepare for the banquet.
Since he failed yesterday,
he might try again today.
I need you to attend the banquet
and confirm who the spy is.
Yes.
But...well, I'm fine with it...
Will it be all right with this outfit?
I contacted Chief Seo, so do something about it.
And do something about your hair.
Like this?
No...like this.
Like this? This?
No...I mean, tuck it behind your ear like this.
Ah! I'll do this! This!
Come here!
How?
Towards the back.
Ah, towards the back.
So it looks natural.
Ah...towards the back like this, this. Ok, AHHH!
AH! It hurts! Prime Minister!
Ah, what do I do?
Stay still. Wait, what's with this?
Ah, Prime Minister! It hurts!
I said move your hand.
Stay still! Stay still!
Prime Minister!
It's alright, it's alright.
Ah, it hurts, Prime Minister!
Just stay still!
Y-You can't go in now.
It's...hot right now.
What are you talking about?-Ahhh!
Prime Minister!-No, you can't.
Chief...
Seo...
It hurts! Ahh!
What do I do? Ahhh!
You're here?
Chief Seo.
Try to do something about her.
Chief S...
I'm sorry.
You're truly doing all kinds of things.
I heard you came to the residence yesterday, too. And you came again today.
If you keep this up, when will we announce the break-up?
I didn't come here because I wanted to.
There's really no answer to this.
We can't let you show up looking like this.
But we can't go buy clothes now.
You really became the Prime Minister.
You became a Prime Minister, overcoming that enormous scandal. It's amazing.
Let's just say I was lucky.
I thought you wouldn't come. Thanks for coming.
No need for thanks.
As an underlying, of course I should come greet you.
We'll see each other often at the government complex.
That's good.
As a matter of fact,
it seems like you've gained sudden interest in my personal affairs lately.
From now on, you're curious about something,
ask me directly.
Don't go through such trouble for nothing.
I don't know what you're talking about, but I'll keep that in mind.
Do you think it was really Minister Park?
I don't know.
Ms. Nam Da Jeong needs to find out.
But when did Reporter Nam see that man?
In any case, why isn't Ms. Nam Da Jeong showing up?
Are you celebrating by yourself?
You and Kwon Yul are really something.
You guys know how to make a ridiculous dating scandal.
But the main character wasn't passable.
If it was you, Seo Hye Ju, I would have believed about a half of it.
You must be quite distressed.
You tried so hard to knock down the Prime Minister.
But you failed.
By chance, just because he became Prime Minister,
you don't think he won, do you?
The real fight will start from now on.
Just stop already.
Aren't you tired of it?
That's what I want to ask you.
For 20 years, you're by Kwon Yul, only looking at him.
The 15-year-old juvenile delinquent who was
saved by a college oppa. Isn't this too much to be just a pure love towards him?
I don't want to hear any more. Excuse me.
Minister Park Joon Gi.
In college, your nickname was 'Kwon Yul's bodyguard', right?
When you were immature, being Kwon Yul's bodyguard was at least cute. Now it's a bit hideous.
It seems like you're clinging to him because you have nowhere else to go.
For 20 years, you haven't been able to confess to him properly. You just remained as a college hoobae,
as his aide, and as the Chief of his Secretary's Office.
I can't understand why you're living like this.
Don't try to understand.
I don't want to be understood by you.
And...as long as people like you are around the Prime Minister,
I think the Prime Minister will still need his bodyguard.
45th Prime Minister Kwon Yul's Inauguration BanquetWhat's with your clothes? There was nothing else?
Why? Is it weird?
Of course it's weird. What's with the dress? It's too short.
This is the most decent among Yu Ri
Yu Ri? What is that?
Yu Ri... there
She is the most popular idol these days.
I borrowed this outfit from her.
Wait a minute.
Na Ra said her favorite idol is Yu Ri
That's her?
Liking such loser?
Na Ra, I should ban her from watching TV.
Oh.. Prime minister.. you are so petty
You act that way with kids, they will outcast you.
Petty?
This is none of business.
You make sure you catch that guy.
Understand?
Sorry but let go of my arm.
Separate.
Man Se
So,
you called me out to make this?
Man Se
you can't use your dad's phone to call me, ok?
Alright.
Then, I can call you through home phone, right?
Ehhh...
If you fold loosely, it will not hold at battle
Chief Kang.
Shall I make it for you? I used to be a champion.
That's ok.
Reporter Nam, you look so different with that outfit.
Over exceeed Yu Ri!!
You flatter me.
I might mistake that for real.
It is real.
Pretty, really.
Didn't think we will meet again,
but seeing you now, I am glad.
Me too.
That's the guy.
That guy.
Height 185cm with slim built
disguised as a waiter.
One more thing, he has pierced left ear.
Please be discreet and find him at once.
Yes.
This is chief of education's wife Lee Dal Jang
And this is Chief Administor's wife
Na Yoon Hee.
Ahhh. She is the youngest daughter of Myung Shim group?
Yes, you are right. That's her.
I'm not even a celebrity,
so how do you know me?
Why? Your famous!
When was it? Has it been 15 years?
You got your picture taken with KanHwaDong boogying and that was a big new then.
At that time, MyungShin Group was going to destroy the newspaper company but
That photographer was just fired and it was done.
That fired photographer is the editor-in-chief of our Scandal News.
That's why I know you a little.
Hey, get out the way.
Its bad enough seeing you at school.
I'll overlook it today even if you don't call me Hyung.
Your stepmother is over there.
Unbelievable. That woman came here?
Shouldn't her son and daughter go over there and help her?
Can't you tell the mood? It looks like she's getting walked over by my mom.
If she step over her, I'll be thankful.
You mother talks sweet and gets them.
I wish she'd show her skill here.
She's a really strange woman.
What's the reason in bringing that up now?
Are you trying to humiliate our madame?
No, it's not that...
I'm sorry. I thoughtlessly...
Well, it doesn't matter.
It's all the past.
By the way, I thought our Prime Minister's
taste was refined and composed,
but it totally isn't.
Drops in class.
Aren't all men like that?
If the woman is you and pretty, they don't care about class.
Even so, that shouldn't be.
Look at these women.
You're probably curious as to why the Prime Minister is dating me.
Yes. The Prime Minister is a man too.
So I guess you could say that my young and fresh charm
caused him to fall head over heels.
So you, with your young and fresh charm, overcame the Prime Minister?
That's what you're saying, right?
But then again,
The Prime Minister, too, must have been so lonely for the last seven years,
It must have been hard for him.
It seems you don't like me.
Even so, don't talk of the Prime Minister like that.
You should've been an actress instead of a reporter.
You act like a real girlfriend.
The Prime Minister and I are really dating.
Is that so?
Then you'll get married too, huh?
Why can't you answer?
Seeing as she can't answer, they won't.
All that noise about him dating.
Isn't this like conning the people?
We will get married.
The Prime Minister and I will get married.
So put your worries aside.
Prime Minister...
Are you in your right mind?
How could you say that in front of those people?
With what thought did you spout such ridiculous nonsense?
That...
Those women were cursing you! I unknowingly...
Whether they curse me or not, what has that got to do with you?
Have you become my real girlfriend?
I'm sorry.
Saying sorry is useless.What are you going to do now?
Now a rumour of our marriage is a matter of time.
What are you going to do about it?
How are you going to fix it?
How did it go?
We caught him.
If there's no evidence, there's not much we can do.
Let him go.
Forget it. Go back.
How can I just go?
I caused trouble...
Then,
do you have a good solution?
Last time you saved me by saying we're dating.
What is it this time?
Ah, that's right.
This time, we can just announce our marriage.
I didn't even think of that.
What do you think?
Isn't it good?
Then can we really not do that?
What?
Announce our wedding.
Can't we really do that?
Nam Da Jeong,
are you being serious?
I asked you if you're serious.
Yes.
What?
So what I'm saying is, not to really marry,
but do a contract marriage.
Contract marriage?
Yes.
For six months only. It doesn't need to be any longer.
Just six months is enough.
There's your perspective too, so
until you say otherwise.
What do you think, Prime Minister?
So,
are you saying that you really want to maary me?
Yes.
Subtitles brought to you by The Ministry Team @ VIKI
Fine. Let's get married.
Be that as it may, this incident's number 1 contributoris also reporter Nam, isn't it?
If it weren't for reporter Nam, we could have moved passed it without realizing anything was amiss.
Chief Kwan.
I wasn't going quite mention this, but have you any ideahow Nam Da Jeong that woman spotted the spy?
The day before yesterday, she slept in the official residencedrunk. That's how she came to spot him.
What did you say?
Do you think that's all? She even hung onto PrimeMinister begging him to marry her.
Do you still think Nam Da Jeong is a nice woman?
Mr. Prime Minister.
Rea-lly... Are you really going to marry me?
That's right. I will marry you.
Let's get married.
Thank you. Thank you, Prime Minister!
Except, I...
don't do things like contract marriage.
Wh-a-t?
What do you mean?
It's not like we're playing at child's game. A contract marriage?
Why would I do stuff like that?
If I do, it'll be a regular marriage. A regular marriage!
You do understand what that means, eh?
Using one bed,
and on top of that bed...
you know what comes after even without the explanation, don't you?
Mr. Prime Minister, why are you... acting like this suddenly?
What do you mean suddenly?
Why? Do you want to play coy by pretending you don't understand what I mean?
We-ll, th-a-t's not what I mean. It's just that...
I just...
I wonder why you'd suddenly ask me to marry you.
You played a part of my girlfriend,
now have you come to desire the post of Prime Minister's wife?
Are you saying that as long as you can become the Prime Minister's wife, the fact that he has three children means naught?
Ms. Nam Do Jeong,
listen carefully to what I'm about to say carefully and correctly.
I won't ever do things like "marriage".
Even if I get crazed and get married,
it won't ever be to a person like you, Nam Da Jeong.
Got that?
Take your leave.
Subtitles brought to you by The Ministry Team @ viki
Chief Kang!
You must be on your way out now?
Yes, I should go now.
Ah, I heard you caught the spy?
We caught him, thanks to you, reporter Nam.
Don't mention it.
By the way, why is your face seem so solemn?
Because I heard about even scarier womn
than a spy.
Approached [the PM] with premeditation using the excuse of acting as his girlfriend,
then got drunk and begged him to get married,
and slept in the official residence as well, no?
That scary woman... Is that woman the very person who is standing in front of me?
Chief Kang,
what really happened was that...
I don't think that was your fault, since the one that encouraged you was me.
However, this is as far as it goes.
I had no idea that you were such an opportunist,and thought you a nice, fun, and cute woman.
I don't ever want to see you put on an innocent face.
That's right. I am an opportunist.
Whether you call me an opportunist or a scary woman,
it doesn't matter to me.
As it is true that I did want to get married
to Prime Minister.
I am sorry.
All is well if I apologize like this, right?
That woman really bragged that she'd really
get married to the Prime Minister.
Minister, they're saying that the special delivery is nottransferring well.
I am sorry.
Idiots.
A special delivery? What special delivery?
Never mind about that. Go on.
Honey. Do something.
I really can't attend to some chit like that as the Prime Minister's wife.
Don't go overboard.
They will declare separation soon enough.
She's quite the preposterous one. She dares to bragabout getting married?
Are you saying that as long as you can become the Prime Minister's wife, the fact that his three children mean naught?
I had no idea that you were such an opportunist,and thought you a nice, fun, and cute woman.
I guess I deserved hearing that I'm an opportunist.
I have nothing to say in my defense even when I hearthat sort of reference.
So then what do I do about my dad?
Would it be okay to announce the wedding
in reality?
It didn't seem like she was just throwing it out there.
Just for 6 months.
I don't need it for longer than that. All I need is for 6 months.
It's not something I should concern myself over.I should have them release a separation declaration.
Kwon Man Se!
- This guy is Nancho (a card game suit). My real honey.
My real honey? And who is this guy?
Hey, Da Jeong. What didn't you go back sooner?
Oh, okay. I should get going. I'll go.
Meju... (a card suit).
This, this rascal right here is Gongsan (a card suit).
Dad.
I have something to tell you.
I feel really bad for you, but the Prime Minister and I...
I know. I know everything.
You want to say that if you get married,
you won't be able to come see me often.
Ah, Dad, that's not what I meant...
Ah, never mind.
Once I take you down the aisle,
I'd consider my duties completed.
I won't have anything to regret,
even if I die on the very same day.
Hey you're out of water. I'll fetch some, Dad.
Why do you keep calling this woman, huh?
I told you not to do it clearly, no?
Kwon Man Se, stop! Stop your crying!
From now on, don't ever do this again.
This is an order!
Nam Da Jung, that woman.
Just what did she do to a child?
Scandal News Reporter Nam Da Jung
Don't worry about it. Man Se called you.
Son-in-Law! Your my son-in-Law right?
I'm Da Jung's father.
The marriage between you and Da Jung,
couldn't you do it a bit more quickly?
I would like it if you do it within six months.
Just six months. I don't need it to be longer. Just six months.
Six months.
Why does it have to be six months?
Here's Da Jung's fathers report.
The Prime Minister asked for it right?
Why did you bring it?
Prime Minister. I just have one thing to say.
That woman asked you to marry her.
I know everything.
That woman, this was her intention from the beginning.
But why are you giving a woman like that attention?
Do you by chance have any intention to marry her?
That won't happen.
So, don't worry about it.
That's a relief.
Then, I'll be preparing statement supporting that.
Can't we get married for real?
Prime Minister. Can't you marry me?
I'm not asking for a real marriage. A contract marriage.
Just six months.
I don't need it to be longer. Just six months.
Was it because of her dad's illness?
Prime Minister. You have to go see Man Se.
I don't know what was wrong with him but he didn't eat or say anything.
He just cried.
Ahjumma
Dad
Judo. I learned judo from my dad, brother, and sister.
I don't know why my dad is teaching me such hard judo.
I am doing really well but my dad always yells at me for doing it wrong.
Ahjumma. I got to know a paparazzi reporter ahjumma.
Kwon Man Se. Don't say anything. This man is a very bad man.
She yelled at the bad reporter man.
She even held my hand and let me ride a swing.
I think that ahjumma is a good person.
I want to see her again.
Frog. The Ahjumma folded a frog for me.
The Ahjumma is really good at folding frogs.
She even drew eyes on the frog.
Man Se's frog is the cutest.
When the Ahjumma held me, I was very happy.
I really like the Ahjumma.
I wish that Ahjumma was my mom.
I really wish she was my mom.
"Blue House"
Me too. I want one too.
Me too. Me too.
Unni! You came.
What are you doing here?
Can't you see? I came here to make the kids kimchi.
From now, i'm going to change my image from a dating girl to an angel.
Pretty good concept, huh?
Here, your clothes. I wore them well.
You could have just kept them.
Ah. I threw away your clothes.
Why would you throw away others perfectly good clothes?
That's why I called you!
I waited for Scandal News and didn't call anyone else.
You have to take pretty pictures.
Oh. It's cold.
Why isn't there any reporters here?
They said that if we called Roo Re here, there would be reporters following everywhere.
There's no one here. But if that woman really becomes the Prime Minister's wife,
will she represent us wives?
Say things that make sense.
According to my husband, the Prime Minister will never remarry.
I should have stepped on that bitch so she couldn't utter another word.
But why does she hate that woman so much?
Kang Ho Dong. Kang Ho Dong!
Kang Ho Dong?
The thing she hates the most is
when someone talks of her past. A bit too much though.
That's right.
What are you doing not coming?
Yes.
Why are those people here?
They came to make kimchi That Baek Ha or
a group of politicians wives.
I was invited here.
I don't think I can do this Roo Re.
I'll help you out some other time. Sorry.
Unni, where are you going? Unni!
Bulleye!
Wow. Who is this?
You said that you would be the Prime Ministers wife. So, did you come here to practice community service?
No, I came for an interview.
Oh, so the reporter that Roo Re called,
was you.
Anyways, I wanted to see you.
This is good.
Why?
You. Say it truthfully.
You aren't going to marry the Prime Minister.
I heard some things too so you should tell the truth.
You, your not going to marry. Right?
Why can't you say anthing?
That,s right. Back then, you responded very well.
Yes, that's right.
I'm not marrying the Prime Minister.
Back then, I was just in the moment.
I'm sorry.
Of course.
You, your a lot to handle even though your young.
Saying something about being young and fresh.
Do you want to go around like this throwing yourself around and fix yourself?
Madam. Do your parents know that you go around like this?
Or, were they happy selling their daughter off?
Is it like that? Your wording is harsh madam.
I don't mind being cursed at.
But, don't talk about my parents like that.
But, you don't like us cursing your parents.
Wow. You guys are too much.
On the outside, you guys seems so elegant and royally but how can you say things like that?
Are you not embarrassed as wives of politicians?
What? What are you saying?
A you as the wife of the Minister for Administration and Planning.
I will live my life.
Don't interfere into other's lives and only say good things thinking of the society.
Do you understand? What in the what?
You.
Stop it.
Prime Minister.
No matter how angry you are, this isn't right.
Embarrassing.
You have no shame in fighting.
Is this how a future Prime Minister's wife acts?
Yes?
I heard you came to make kimchi.
I can't do nothing for such a good act.
I will donate one thousand more cabbages.
Then, good luck.
One thousand?
Why are you here?
And, why are you saying things like that?
What things?  A Prime Minister's wife.
What kind of nonsense is that.
I know you did that to help me but there was no need to do that.
Why would I help you. I only said the truth.
What?
You still don't understand?
Wait.
So, your saying that...
Yes. I am saying that I will marry you.
Nam Da Jung,
You will have to marry me.
Subtitles brought to you by The Ministry Team @ Viki
We use one room, one bed.
Are you thinking farther than that?
I don't know if this marriage is right.
A contract?
Since this is a contract marriage, it definitely needs a contract.
I heard your marrying my dad. Just because of that do you think i'm going to call you mom.
In other words, you better be ready.
What are you doing?
Something is stuck? Wait, don't move.
That I can see you Reporter Nam like this,
It's really touching.
Then, should we go in?
Go away.
I'm getting married because of you.
How can you not remember me?