Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Is this a documentary?
No, it's
not a documentary.
It's fiction.
It's a drama.
What's it
about? It's fiction?
This is a
film I made about six years ago.
The subject matter maybe
is a little sensitive...
...with some people.
What is it about, like...
Well, I won't tell you. What
I'll let you do is watch it.
I'm guessing it's about, uh...
...rockets.
No, I'm guessing it's
about male itch.
Hey, turn
on the colour!
Make it better. Turn up
the good, turn down the suck.
Turn down the suck knob.
I think you got suck all the
way cranked to ten, Farrel.
Cranked it right up to ten.
I think you broke
the knob off crankin it so hard.
I'm just sitting here
thinking to myself, oh, I could, yeah...
...really go for a six minute
fuckin' sit-through of shit.
And he played drums late and
he never helped her with her...
...fuckin' homework.
Boo fuckin' hoo. Big fuckin'
deal, he plays drums late.
And her fuckin'
yo-yo was busted. Yo, yo fuckin' blows.
Drive yer own fuckin'
car, let yer woman stay at home.
Whoooo!
Hey, hey, hey!
I'll give you a gummer and I'll
giv'er, an' then I'll come an'
...give it. Come an' give it for
to come and giv'er Deaner.
Give'er, give it, Deaner.
Basically I would say
an uncooperative and rebellious...
...attitude, which um, well, it
worked itself out in, you know...
...long greasy hair, beer
advertisement t-shirts.
Whoo!
Nail 'em!
I recommend you
try another sport.
Like knitting!
Knit yourself a
fuckin' somebody!
Oh, they like to play
some of the worst of the bands.
Oh what was it? Dead Leopard
or Sick Cougar or some of those.
That was
wonderful, you think?
Yeah.
Currently I'm working
at a furniture store.
Yeah?
And I uh... Make tables.
A little under 800 bucks.
For working
one day a week?
Two weeks.
For two weeks?
Yeah, I get 400 bucks a week.
But that's before
the government...
...takes their fuckin'
part, you know?
Tell us about that.
The government takes their part.
I'm trying to use more pneumatic
tools these days so that it...
...does. So that uh... Easier
on the environment.
He... His job was a
swamper. I don't know but...
...if you're familiar with that?
Explain it,
that would be great.
A swamper is a helper,
is a driver's helper.
See, this
is one that I built.
42 inch dewill.
Feels thick, hey?
How thick would
you say that table feels?
The table's actually that thick.
That's why it's called a double...
...edge. Makes it look a lot
thicker. This is solid oak.
He would not be doing
anything other than the manual...
...lifting of furniture
in and out of a truck...
...and into a person's home.
You push it through
and it rips it in half.
He don't
do nothing else.
Are you alright?
Yeah, I just fuckin'...
Ever since I quit smoking, I've
just been fuckin' coughing up...
...the weirdest shit.
There would
be a moon here.
A large rocket.
It'll be all dark space
punctuated by planets.
I would have a close-up,
like, of a lady on a cliff...
...and she would have a giant
fuckin' laser gun, and she'd sort...
...ofjust be, protecting.
My son was a very happy
person and he was really uh...
...really good to me, and then
after he met that, that uh...
...that uh... That
woman, he changed.
Chastity.
I mean right now
we're not exactly, you know...
...together, right? We don't
live together and...
You know what the
problem is. You know how...
...to change. You know how
to fix the problem.
I know, see, it
always comes down to me.
And it always comes
down to, to Deaner.
As it stands, plan b is just
To keep on givin'er, Farrel.
What exactly
does that mean?
Giv'er. You just, you go out,
and you giv'er, like you...
...work hard, that's what that.
Is that, is that a plan?
Yeah that's
a plan right there.
Look man, I already told
you. I fuckin' play the bass.
And that's what I'm gonna do.
Jesus! Ow! Ow!
Well, Dean always
liked to play by himself...
...he had a vivid imagination.
I'm trying to
get a gig with a band.
I was in a band a while
ago called Creeper.
It's ringing. Yeah hi,
is Bill there please? Uh, Bill.
So, like whatever you guys are
into, like, give me a mix tape...
...give me a couple days, and
I'll just fuckin', I'll show up...
...and we'll go from there, man.
It's
in normal tuning.
Oh, it's
normal tuning? Okay.
So we're gonna do...
It's like, as far as
tones are concerned, like the...
...tones are a lot lower, and like
the - Your ear actually has to...
...pick up like, a hell of a lot
more than a guitar player's ear.
You actually
have to get a five-string...
...because it's a whole
step down, you need to just...
Well, I'll fuckin'
just like, I'll just giv'er up...
...top and we'll see what happens.
Yeah, just harmonize.
The taste in your tongue
for the spice is like the taste...
...in your fuckin'
bones for the bass.
He may get in a band,
or he may go solo, or he may...
...teach children how to play.
...fuckin' body check.
Watch my fuckin' nuts.
Aw, fuck!
You alright?
Sorry Dean.
Holy shit.
Do you want me to
get you anything.
Dean,
are you alright?
Just fuckin'. Clear
the fuck outta here, okay?
I'm sorry Dean.
You wanna beer?
Terry, you
play goal okay?
Tron.
How's it going buddy?
Sweet. Kick
fuckin' ass! How's it goin?
My name is Troy.
I guess I was kind of uh...
the party... The party leader?
So what are
you up to now man, what are you doing?
I'm welding now, yeah
I got, uh... I got my own shop.
I got Laurie here, and I'm
looking after her, or is it...
...vice versa? I love
those guys you know.
I think they're probably a
couple of the best, best guys...
I've ever run with.
Okay,
we'll get a cube.
We'll fuckin', then
we'll get a two-six.
You wanna Tron?
Yeah!
Just like old times, man.
Just fuckin' nail it
shut, like a fuckin', one-two-three fuckin'
...split, right?
I'll swing by.
You know
where we live now?
Yeah.
Troy,
we're already late as it is.
Alright, I'll see ya.
So you coming tonight then?
You should swing
by pretty early, like 7ish...
...or something like
that, half past.
No, maybe uh...
No, yeah, you're coming!
You don't gotta work
tomorrow, fuck it.
I'll just say, uh
sorry guys, shuttin'er down...
...uh, no business.
No business!
Not too late,
we'll get started.
Sure, ten after, whenever.
Stompin' boots are goin'
on tonight, that's for sure.
Tron's a buddy
we hung out with, like, two years ago.
And we used
to party a lot, but not so much anymore...
...so whenever we do
get together it's fuckin' awesome.
He's gonna be ready
to raise hell...
...like, he's ain't gunna show
up like, "hey guys" he's gunna...
...show up going "whooo!" And we're
gonna be like, "right on. "
I didn't chack.
That's fuckin' embarrassing.
That's an embarrassment
to pilsner.
Look at his
throat move, man.
Right on... You
didn't finish it.
That's absolute
horseshit. I finished that.
I fuckin' finished it.
That rest was foam.
Like, sometimes you go to a party,
right? And everyone's all...
...fuckin' loaded, and you're not
loaded, so you go up to people...
...and you're like, "how's it
goin?" and they're like...
'whooooo!" and then you're like
"yeah, okay," and you're trying...
...to talk to them a bit and
they're fuckin' loaded and then...
...you realize, the only way
to keep going is to catch up...
...to them, so you shotgun a few
and then you get good and pissed...
...right away.
No, fuck off, fuck off.
Remember last, like,
I don't know, awhile ago...
...the answering
machine was Tron.
And now it's his old lady.
Now it's his fuckin' old lady.
Basically she says,
'if it's not my friends...
...don't fuckin' leave a message'
basically is what she's fuckin' saying.
...fuckin', everybody's just having
a fuckin' wicked time and then...
...it was just like,
fuckin' dead silence.
Laurie came in.
I'm Laurie, she's
like, "Tron"...
...and he just like fuckin'...
...stopped, yeah.
Yeah, and he just kinda
like... Hey, did you see that?
You know I really,
and we went through this right...
...in the very beginning,
I really had no problem.
I went through this whole thing
with him, right from the very beginning.
I was with them
periodically here and there, but I...
I honestly couldn't
see myself living that life.
However, it was like,
if this is the only place that it...
...was going, and if it was going
to be a never-ending thing...
I couldn't handle that.
So it was either them or me,
basically, and it was his choice.
Like that, fuckin' nailed...
Fuck off!
That hurt.
Dean!
I think I hurt - Look,
I'm bleeding, man.
What's happing man?
Hey, I'm bleeding.
There's a fuckin'
brain in your hand.
Probably what's happened
I imagine - Dean. Dean.
This is fuckin'
bullshit man.
Yeah I know,
it is bullshit.
But we don't have to wreck our
house - watch your fuckin' stick!
You know what he's doing, he's
probably got his arm around her...
...and he's probably just like,
"fuck, I wish I wasn't such a...
...slave to my bitch," you know?
I remember a lot of
fun times with Troy.
He's not our buddy.
And you know what?
Troy.
Because when he was
our buddy he was fuckin' Tron.
I came up with the name
Tron for myself based on Troy...
...but uh... More,
I guess, imposing.
Let's give him, let's
give him ten minutes, okay?
...fuckin' two-liner!
Two liner!
I'm trying to get
an idea of what you guys did.
The things that we did,
it wasn't so much the thing...
...as it was that we did them.
Oh! On the line!
We got one on the line!
Right on.
Right on, it rolled.
It was just living each
day blind and going the distance.
No don't, fuck off.
Watch this, my new move.
Like, I hit rock bottom.
Uh-huh, any fuckin' style.
Come on, come on!
Fight me, you
fuckin' - Come on!
I should just keep,
I should just keep doing that...
...like, till I'm, say, 90 years
old. Okay, yeah, you're right.
I really boned this up.
I should never have got,
fallen in love with Laurie...
...for sure, that's a for sure.
Thanks for pointing that out.
And getting a job, yeah,
that was a real left turn.
Where the fuck is Tron?
Fuck Tron man!
You see that? Fuck Tron.
We won't even be here.
Leave a note on the door.
That says fuck you Tron!
Fuck you Tron.
You're like
I mentioned before, you're like...
...a patriarch to them,
uh, a patriarchal character, and...
They're a patriarch to me, man.
What is Tron for you?
Fuck 'em!
Sometimes I worry.
But I think at some
point in your life you have...
...to grow up, and that's
what Troy's done.
The reason why you're not
getting much from him...
...is because of that.
Yeah, he's kind of scared
of going back to the old life.
I just have a hard
time having him go out...
...with them because it's so easy
for him to get pulled back...
...into that life. It's a fun life,
that you don't have to have any cares...
...in the world. No responsibilities.
Whooo!
Tron!
Tron! Tron!
Whooo!
Tron, we're having
a fuckin' party for ya!
Get up!
Dean, get up.
Tron fuckin' blows.
Tron, fuckin', blows.
You know what
this fuckin' says?
It says Tron funking blow.
What the fuck does that mean?
If I have five words left and
I'm about to fuckin' expire...
...and I like, all I have left
to say is to curse fuckin' Tron...
I'm probably not going
to say 'Tron funking blow. '
Get up! Get up!
Terry, my face
is totally bunged up.
You're saying your uncle
was gonna take you on to the...
...on the lake,
because he rented it.
And you know actually
all I remember was like...
...buddy of mine was like...
"Hey Dean, dude. "
You know.
I was like, "Okay buddy. "
Dean!
Terry! Could somebody turn
the stereo down please?
The stereo.
I remember Terry and I
got fuckin' right ripped...
...eh Terry? Got fuckin'
right wrecked last night.
If you don't know
a girl so good.
Yeah.
And she's fuckin', doesn't
want to go down on you.
Yeah.
And you're fuckin' tired and you
wanna crash, or you just fuckin'
...want to continue on with your
night, fuckin' diddle her twat...
...fuckin' get her off. Just go
down there and if you know what...
...to do, it'll take probably six,
seven minutes. Well, you go...
...under the panties for sure, and
you just kind of pet it a bit.
Pet what?
Pet... Her fuckin' kneecaps,
Farrel! Pet her twat!
You got something, you got a
twat you want me to diddle?
And that cousin...
Fuck off!
Have you had sexual
intercourse with one of your cousins?
No, fuck you!
Terry fuckin' got one
of his cousins off...
...he fuckin' fingerbanged...
Shut up!
Terry, you fuckin' fingerbanged
your cousin, man, that's a fact.
...fuckin' fingerbanging,
so spill the dirt.
You don't have
to just tell them that!
He was fuckin' loaded, his cousin
came up to him, and he's fuckin'.
Fuck off!
Don't! Don't! Fuck off.
So his fuckin' cousin...
his fuckin' cousin.
She says, I'm on my rag,
you just have to finger me.
There,
that's a perfect fit.
What, what? What's your
problem with Dean?
Nothing, I don't have
a problem, just trying...
I have no problem with him
staying here, he's like, my pal.
Are you a
little bit concerned?
I seem to see that,
uh, Dean's sleeping, he seems...
...to be sleeping every time
that I come over.
Seems to me that he's taking
advantage of your situation...
...sleeping around...
...he's just, he just needs to...
The house.
Seems like he doesn't care about.
He's sick. He's got cancer.
So you gotta let him do that.
Is this the truth?
Fuck, I told you...
Dean has cancer?
But don't bug him about it.
Hi Dean.
I uh, I was talking
to Terry yesterday.
I know that you
have this cancer.
Talked to Terry.
Dean?
Terry told me.
And you're telling me
that I gotta worry about it?
Like, I got something
to worry about?
You're wrong.
Regardless of like, what other
people say, I'm just gonna...
...fuckin' pull 'er off at some
point in time, and just fuckin'
...stick 'er in the microwave
there, see what happens.
See what a fuckin'
blown-up nut looks like.
Let's cut 'er off and fuckin'
put her on the barbecue...
...and fuckin' hibachi that fuckin'
little nut right up, fuckin'
...cover 'er in whatever and
we'll have a tasty treat.
Dean, this
is very serious.
You're going to have to,
gonna have to let yourself...
Well Dean has a lump
in his left testicle, which has...
...grown in size to the point
where he can't ignore it.
The strategy is really
to explain to him in rational...
...terms that if he doesn't do
anything, the risk of what's...
...going to happen in the next
five years is certain death.
He has cancer
of the testicle...
...and he won't
listen to me.
He doesn't want to get treatment,
and I want him to try and...
...he, uh, I'm,
I want to help him.
I want him to get treatment.
I know this is terrible.
Is he at home?
When did you talk to him?
When's the last time
you talked to him?
Uh... I'm really...
Thanks for telling me.
Trixie!
Dean!
What's going on?
What are you doing
here Farrel?
Hi asshole.
What is your problem?
What are you...
what happened?
Why didn't you tell me?
Dean!
He just comes, he just
comes around and tells you.
You think that's
fuckin' funny, Farrel?
What are you trying
to do, just leave Chastity without...
...a dad, hey? You think
that's not important to her?
You think you're
not important to me?
But you're gonna go to the doctor,
and you're gonna get...
...fuckin' treatment.
You could die, do you understand?
You could die.
You know, it's gonna
be pretty pathetic if you fucking die...
...because of your pride.
Alright, I'll go.
Yeah, you'll go.
What? I said I would.
I said I would.
I know you will.
I was working on a
different level with Dean about...
...getting his nuts fixed. Like,
you went right away, like...
...we gotta... But I was going,
every time they would hurt...
...or whatever, I would just be like,
oh maybe we should go to the...
...hospital, but really, just, you
know, I didn't want to force it...
...on him or yell at him,
you know, like...
I was gonna take
him to get fixed.
I can't fuckin' baby-sit
my fuckin' giant nut all day...
...you know, just sit there and
watch it and hope it doesn't...
...fuckin' grow. So fuckin' treatment
hurts, well fuck, the second it...
...starts to hurt you're gonna hear
me fuckin' start yelling but as...
...it stands right now,
I feel fine, so.
I'm not a scientist.
I can't fuckin' pull out...
...one... A burner and burn up
some stuff and figure it out?
I mean, what do you
want me to do about it?
Worry and get upset? I'll
get cancer from worrying.
Do you believe in God?
Well, fuck rights,
I believe in something.
Like even, a fuckin' guy
like Merlin, you know?
When he died, you know,
whenever the fuck that was...
...he went to heaven, probably,
and you know, and the, the grand...
...scheme being was probably like,
you know, Merlin, you fuckin'
...cast some pretty, you know,
evil shit on some people.
Merlin,
Merlin wasn't real.
Fuck you, Merlin...
It's a
story. It's just a story.
No, fuck, Merlin was
part of fuckin' king Henry's...
...court, and he fuckin' - They, he
won all the wars for him 'cause...
...he cast spells. Fuck you,
man, that shit's real.
He was - He was part
of King Arthur, not King Henry.
Yeah, it's a fable.
A fable is a... is history.
Yeah, no, lately I have
been sort of on the - On the...
...fucking prowl, yeah. I've sort
of been looking high, low, left...
...centre, right, fuckin' front
and back. I'm talking about...
...you know, spreading Deaner
around, fuckin' get the murdoch...
...kids, you know, get 'em going.
I'm one of those guys who's
like, too forward, you know?
Watch the fuckin' road, buddy?
Huh? D'you see that guy?
Yeah, I saw him.
I told you about him.
It's not
fuckin' funny, man!
And some guy fuckin' sideswipes
him and it's two, three...
...thousand dollars worth of
fuckin' paintjob...
Let's go.
I'm not doing this, I'm
not doing this for me, you know...
I'm sort of doing it for
like, all the girls out there...
...who, you know, if I'm gone, you
know, they won't have a chance...
...to see old Deaner.
Just, like, once a week I like
to have this thing where...
...like, I buy like, whatever,
like a Heineken or a fuckin'
Corona or like - A beer you
don't normally see, and actually...
I've been keeping them in
Terry's kitchen. Would you mind...
...maybe like, checking -
'cause I could show you.
Okay, yeah!
I have probably like
eight or nine of them...
There from, like...
Hey, Dean.
- Literally from all
over the fuckin' country...
Yeah, they're from all
over the world. There's some...
...from Paris and actually there's
some, actually from Ireland.
I ain't gonna fuckin' die,
Farrel. All right?
And you know, you don't need
to be so worried about it, man...
...just fuckin' relax about it, kay?
'Cause I ain't
fuckin' goin' down!
I have a poem, would you
like me to read you his poem?
Yes, yes, of course.
'Woman is a danger cat'
the streets are silent my wills...
...are the night black leather
blues calling out to you a cute...
...blonde boogie machine
spreads her wings...
...and comes along for the ride.
It's the only song
I ever really wrote for...
...like the acoustic guitar.
Rock
and roll is my guitar...
...and girls electricity...
...and if I've got both of them...
I've got all, all I need...
I could live life without liquor...
I know that it'd be hard...
...but a life without
girls and rock'n'roll...
...would break my heart.
'cause rock and roll ain't a
game you can stop at anytime...
...it's a really serious
thing like war and crime...
...rock and roll ain't a game
where you know all the rules...
...you gotta pick up
your guitar and play...
...and play the fool...
Your father thinks
you're out at Suzy's place...
...bowling on the classics but
everyone at high school knows...
...you're heavy into gymnastics
one-way street, never mind...
...the signs full charged gasoline
in the tank you're foot is on...
...the gas and your tires say,
yeah. Woman is a danger cat.
You sneak out at night
deep into the night there ain't...
...no halfway house you come
from good blood, right?
On and on, woman is a danger
cat. It's kind of a funny...
...little poem and it shows how
Dean's thinking is kind...
...of cuckoo sometimes.
Dean is a little bit
hesitant, he is not fully on...
...onstream as far as, uh,
giving his consent to go ahead.
You can understand this.
I mean, we're offering him loss
of a body part, and as far as...
...he's concerned if he can pretend
to ignore what is going on...
...he can make it in his own
mind to preserve his body part.
He's gonna say, the best thing
is not to have anything to do...
...with what this guy is telling
me. That's, we call that denial...
...and we all do that to some
degree. And he's scared.
...fuckin' take it?
Or what?
Right now, fuckin' pull it out.
I can take it.
They don't get it.
What?
You wanna take me?
You gotta come now!
I don't remember asking
you any questions.
Can I borrow it for a minute?
I'll borrow your left nut,
right nut, fuckin' nutty nut!
Bring it on, fuckin' come on!
Shower the fucker, huh?
Shower the fucker!
Shower that fucker!
...fuckin' showering it on it!
fuckin' give it giv'er.
Whaaaaaat?
I saw that, bring it
down here, right here.
Showery shower!
Chicken, kickin', come on!
He is very near death,
and at one point, you decide to...
...tell him, before he dies,
those last words, those last things...
...that you would like to tell him,
so that those are the last...
...things that he hears,
in his ears, before he dies in front...
...of you. What would you say?
I'd just fuckin' tell him that
he was like one of the like...
...you know, best friends
I've ever had, and that...
...it would have been pretty
fuckin' boring without him.
I think. Oh yeah,
fuck he's right there.
There he is.
Hey, man.
Oh, it's going okay.
Right on.
Well, basically... Fuck.
You don't have to tell me.
They're cutting
my fuckin' nut off.
Cutting your nut off?
My right nut.
I guess so it don't spread
they're just gonna fuckin'...
Giv'er.
We had it biopsied. It
confirms the presence of cancer...
...and so he urgently needs to
have an operation to remove...
...the testicle, which is the standard
surgical treatment for this kind...
...of cancer of the testicle.
Then he needs to undergo chemotherapy...
...and radiotherapy.
I was thinking Terry,
we should fuckin' do'er.
This weekend, man, just fuckin'
have a fuckin', one last fuckin'...
'cause, like, I'm gonna be out
of commission for awhile...
I guess after I get my nut
wrought off there, they gotta...
...fuckin' shoot me full of like,
lots of electricity and shit...
...and it's gonna affect my overall
fuckin' ability to be normal.
Aaaaaaaaaa-ooooooooooo!
Dean's last fuckin' weekend!
Aoooooooo!
If we act now,
we can offer him better than...
50-60 percent survival.
You gotta get loaded
too, or else you can't come.
Told you. Yeah?
He fuckin' said yes!
Right on.
He's gonna
get fuckin' rip-roaring loaded.
Uh, I don't know
about rip-roaring loaded.
That's the deal!
Yeah, you are!
Oh, I guess
you're not coming!
Gonna get
lo-o-o-o-aded, going camping!
You're surrounded by beautiful
trees, and a fuckin' canopy...
...of stars above ya,
it's a fuckin' real vista.
Yeah.
Did you hear that?
Fuck! That fucking stinks!
Hang on, I think mine's stuck.
Fuck off!
I've been a
farter all of my life.
Fuck.
I guess, I don't know what it is.
Each, every time I eat fried
egg sandwiches, egg salad...
I think it's stuck in the seat.
Or even potato salad,
anything with mayonnaise really.
Fuck off.
That's just gross, like
'Oh, I have an idea...
I'll shit my pants
in the car. '
The second that I farted
I thought, oh, Terry's mom's place.
That's what I, that's exact.
Must be some, must be something
cooking at Terry's mom's place.
Fuck off! Fuck off Dean.
I'm gonna fuckin' puke
if you do that again.
Aw, fuck!
Fuck you, that's fuckin' gross!
Get the fuck out.
I'm serious.
Are you sure
you should be doing this, Terry?
...fuckin' asshole. I mean
fuck, he's just laughing away...
...shitting his pants in here.
I don't care if he's sick...
...you don't shit your pants in
someone's car. That's horseshit...
Really. I want him to remember
it. So how does he remember it?
He fuckin' walks to the town,
and we'll wait for him.
Dean!
I mean, imagine I kicked him
out and then drove back and...
...said, okay, walk to the town and
then I'll - And then it'll be...
...okay, and I couldn't back it
up, I mean, what does that say...
...about me?
I don't know.
What does it say?
It says, it says
you can shit in my mouth.
Okay, okay,
I understand what he did.
Well, I'm thinking
like, if we don't get you know...
...to go camping I'm gonna feel
bad about it later on, you know.
I mean, whoever did what wrong
back there is not important...
...anymore. It's more aboutjust doing
what we wanted to do...
...go camping.
Oh there he is,
I knew it. I knew it.
A spare
is when you get...
Dean!
- One with one ball,
like, some with one ball...
...and the rest with the other.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yeah, that's a strike.
See, practice
makes perfect, there.
And then buddy's like,
where do you want me to drop you off.
I was like, I don't know.
These guys figured I couldn't
find you, but I was like...
I'll find him.
So what I did was
uh, I bowled with my left.
And that one chick, the one
with the glasses, she beat me.
I would say that the
fuckin' best burger I ever had...
...was at a bowling alley, 'cause,
they surprise you there, some...
...of them alleys hire, fuck, some
of the best cooks, and they don't...
...they ain't a restaurant
but that doesn't mean that...
...the cook ain't gonna put some
fuckin' pride in their burgers.
Bindair dundat.
Been there, done that.
That's the paki who's fuckin'
seen everything and gone everywhere.
What's a paki?
I don't know, yeah,
a guy from India...
...sounds about right to me.
Where's Pakistan?
No, you were alluding
to something else.
I worked with one guy
that had the turban...
...on his head, and I mean, you
know whatever, he was a Paki...
...and that was his, you know...
This is fuckin' it!
Yeah man!
Whooooooo!
Right here,
get that smell?
You smell that Farrel?
That's fuckin'
camping, right there.
First things first...
...more cheers more beers,
man, that's it, that's all.
To there - To my right nut,
man - See ya later, fella.
Unpacking.
Watch, I'm going camping.
Let's go camping.
Who's taking a plane?
Come on, roughin' it!
Oh, just some supplies
you know in case, uh, we run...
...into some rough spots, uh.
No! Fuck off!
Whoooah, fuck!
Whooo!
Farrel, just sit down.
Have a chocolate bar.
Chocolate bar, now look
- Put your hands like this...
...on the fire.
Oh fuck, that's a hot one.
You gotta get real low,
'cause heat rises eh?
If you can think of a better
way to get this on the fire...
I'd like to see it.
Fuck, hold on.
'Kay, I think what we gotta
do is undo the bolts first.
No, no, no.
Fuck, that's perfect.
Deaner'll just go right over!
Did you see that?
I'm not
doing a nudie jump.
You're fucking
things up, Dean!
Man, I could go for a
fuckin' smoke right fuckin' now.
No, you quit, remember?
Do you have any dip?
No, no, fuck, listen.
I am.
Think about
there's that one day every year...
...that fuckin' clicks by.
Like Christmas?
Yeah, no, exactly, like
Christmas, except for you don't...
...know it's Christmas. It's like,
you know, like, let's say...
...you die on like, August
fuckin' 10th or something.
Right?
Right, but you don't
know that, right?
That August 10th
is the day you die?
Yeah, but every fuckin' year
from the day you're born...
...you know, August
10th clicks by...
...but you never put
it together like in a journal...
But like, fuck, man, every
single year goes by, you know...
...anniversary, I guess,
of your death goes by.
There you go Farrel.
Nice work, Pal.
Hey, look at that.
Look, he's doing okay.
Oh, oh, oh,
oh, you got it.
Look, his throat's going.
Spitting a little bit.
Oh, you want me to
finish that one off there?
Here, I'll have
a sip of that.
Can I ask you a question?
Here, yeah, here.
Who touched my throat?
How's your movie
going tonight so far?
Terry, you wanna
do the old can test?
Little or no reaction!
Looks like Farrel's
had a few too many.
Hey Farrel.
Yeah Farrel.
The light is up,
and it is up for me.
Hey Farrel,
we got one here.
We just gotta shake
it up and giv'er.
You can feel 'er giving.
Yeah.
Come on, Farrel.
Yeah, we can do it.
Alright.
We'll go find to
gather another tree.
There we go.
Coming down!
This is a tree!
That's coming down! Aaaaah!
A tree is a tree, not me!
Tree!
Do you see this guy's pants?
See this guy's pants?
C'mere, c'mere.
Fuck off!
His pants is very tight...
Hey...
He has very tight pants.
Fuck off Farrel!
I want, I want some wood.
It happened to be wood!
It happened to be wood, one day!
Hey Farrel?
Yes Terry?
What do you do
when you don't make movies?
That's a good question.
What do you do period Farrel,
what the fuck, like?
You're just following us around...
...like it's the be all and the end
all of the fucking universe, eh?
Do you
think that's my life?
Is that what you think?
What do you do on
your spare time?
Is what I meant to say.
What do I do on my spare time?
I don't know,
You make pornos with fuckin' midgets?
I don't know what the fuck
the guy does with these cameras...
...when he's not doing...
Do you
understand what it means...
...to put time into something,
to develop something, that's not...
...necessarily, you know, going
to work and making a table?
I just play the bass
and, I'm an artist too Farrel...
I know how you feel.
I'm just trying to look at you.
You don't even understand what...
I'm trying to do
for both of you.
Without me and Terry,
you wouldn't have a fuckin' movie.
Yeah, sure,
exactly, like you don't think...
...that there's two other
people like you two?
If it weren't for me right now,
where would you be?
Probably right here.
Right here.
When they say cut,
we just keep...
Terry and me just keep going.
Sit down and we'll ask
you some questions.
No, no, no, how
about you do something for me?
How about you listen to me?
Farrel sit the fuck down.
You fuckin' spit at me?
Don't fuckin' touch me,Farrel.
Put your hand down.
Take five, Farrel.
You see that?
Try it, try it you fuck.
Oh no. I think Farrel's
had a few too many.
C'mere,
come on, both of you!
You gotta take
a serious five, Farrel.
No, it's a fuckin'
joke your whole life.
You don't even
fuckin' understand...
...what your fuckin' life is about.
Oh, that
didn't feel good.
You got
a serious fuckin' problem.
Don't fuckin'...
You fuckin' know
what it's about?
Yeah, hey, Farrel,
no, I got an idea. How about...
...you ruin my last fuckin'
weekend by being a total...
...fuckin' idiot?
How bout that?
Fuck this.
I got a good
idea. Hey Terry!
Bring a few tissues,
ya fuckin' baby!
Fuck that chair up.
Fuck it.
...fuckin' grade a pork.
You get all the dogs?
She said just
to fuckin' take 'em.
I don't want a dog yet.
Oh, now I'm fuckin' scared.
Oh, that's gonna be tasty.
Farrel? Farrel?
Where am I?
You're in a ditch.
Went on a bit of a
bender last night, bud.
Don't...
...don't, don't do that.
This'll help you out.
Don't, please.
Don't worry about it,
this is gonna...
Tonight's gonna be
even better, so don't fuckin' stress'er.
You get all the bugs
out the first night...
...you know, and then you get
really back into camping...
...and then the second
night's just fuckin'...
'cause we didn't start
givin'er until around seven...
...or eight. Tonight we'll
be loaded, well, 'cause, you know...
...what the fuck. What is it,
what time did you say it is, 12:30?
Yeah,
it's about 20 after.
How would
you guys feel if I were to...
...if I were to treat you guys
for tonight, if we go to hotel.
You could get anything you want.
You fuckin' serious?
After the hotel we
still have to go for a hike.
Yes, we can do that.
'Cause there's this fuckin'
kick-ass place to go for a swim.
It's not, it's not so super-
close to here, but it's fuckin'...
...it's the, it's
the place to be, man.
Okay, that
sounds really nice.
And tonight we'll
stay in a hotel.
Dean.
Let's giv'er.
Let's fuckin' go.
No, the wardens clean it up.
You're not legal
to shut your fuckin' mouth yet.
The doctor said that I'd
be weak. He said that I would be...
...lacking in a lot of things,
that my sexual activity...
...was definitely going to go down,
which is sort of why this...
...this weekend I was kind of hoping
that something would happen...
...but uh, you know, just
sort of get one in the bag...
...before, uh, you know,
there's a hole in it.
Where the fuck
are we going?
Can you turn this
way? Here, see, right there.
The Motor Motel.
Housekeeping
award winners.
Like going home or something?
No, I'm just out
and about, cruising around...
...enjoying the weather.
Oh yeah,
it was nice today.
Now that it's not
a 1,000 degrees out.
Man, that was hot!
I was in the river there
soaking for a while.
Is that the
big plant here?
Yeah, it's cutting meat here.
Oh yeah?
4,000 pounds a day.
Oh, fuck.
4,000?
Every day?
I just drop
in the flank steaks.
What's that?
The flank, the flank
side of the steak there.
Actually the other day,
I was being attacked by a hawk...
...believe it or not, bizarre.
Yeah, I don't know.
What did you have,
meat on your hands, still?
Uh, no.
Oh yeah, it come to a point,
I had to hold a stick up there...
...because it was coming right,
it was coming, it was making...
...itjust kept doing it,
it would come right -just make...
...it stop. Unbelievable.
You guys from here?
Yeah.
You guys
having a party tonight or?...
Yeah. The river, man.
We're hitting
the highway now!
So you're not allowed
to jump off the bridge?
No, the cops hate it.
One, two, three.
Eeeeeeeeeeaaaaaaaaaaghhhh!
Yeah, the evidence was gone.
From the courts,
nobody could find it.
The cops were just laughing.
Where did it go?
I don't know, the cops
probably smoked...
...lots of cops in this
town smoke the shit.
We're sitting in the
hotel and they're just filming us.
You're gonna buy
these guys some drinks.
To high river!
Whooooo!
You're a survivor.
You're gonna make it, boy!
You're gonna make it.
Just watch you.
They're not
you're type of guys?
No. Back when I was a teenager
I used to like the long hairs.
Yeah... But now I... Yeah.
One word.
Bangers.
I was born and raised,
I moved out of here...
...because it's so fuckin' boring.
You wanna get laid,
you don't wanna be here.
This guy here
will fight me, like this.
I don't want a
barroom fuckin' brawl...
I want a fuckin' true fight here.
I want a true fuckin' match.
I want a fuckin' boxing match.
All right, touch
gloves, let's go.
Fuck me!
'Kay, get that
light over here.
We have to find a
goddamned tooth, sir.
Hey, it's right here.
Put some concrete on that.
Hey, I got some Crazy glue
in my fuckin' car.
Where's that
fuckin' toilet paper at?
So, are you guys glad
that we came here instead of...
...stayed camping?
If you'd stop filming
us I might cum here.
I just wanted you
guys to have a good time.
It wasn't necessarily
a good time.
Where did Terry go?
Mmm, I could just...
I just wanted
to have a fun weekend.
And I did.
And I am.
So it is.
Where'd you guys go?
Deaner.
I got...
I got you something.
Where were you, Terry?
Dean. Listen, look.
Dean. Dean. Dean.
Is it okay
if we film this?
We're not gonna...
...you can'tjust
film this, I mean.
H- E-e-e-e-e-e-y!
H- E-e-e-e-y!
Terry!
Where did you get
the money for that?
Did everybody do it,
or is itjust...
Guys, what the fuck.
Let's fuckin' get out of here.
Just wait.
Close the door.
It's his fuckin' last
night with his fuckin'...
Imagine you were
losing your nuts.
How would you fuckin' feel?
Right.
'Kay, so don't
even ask anymore.
Just let it be what it is.
Asshole.
Are you still
interested in going to your...
...uh, hike place?
She was high quality. Fuckin',
the whores in the small towns...
...are the ones to get too,
'cause they're not as fuckin' uppity...
...as them fuckin' city hookers.
No? It's a shame you
never experienced that, I mean.
It's an experience
all unto itself.
Paying for sex?
Well,
I fuckin' paid for it.
What's the
plan for today, guys?
We're going
to Sasquatch Creek.
Yeah man,
Sa-a-a-squatch.
We're going to jumping point,
that's gonna be so sweet.
Sort of like that,
but there's water.
And we're not scared.
Yeah, and we don't fall
on our necks and die.
We gotta
get down there.
We usually cross
further up, though.
I'd hate to see
you cut yourself again.
How does it look, Terry?
Oh, pretty good.
I'd say it's a bit tight.
Have you
done this before?
Whoooooooooo!
Have you
done this before?
...fuckin' rights.
No.
Fuck you,
you gotta jump in.
Why don't you go first?
You wanna go first?
If you don'tjump we're
gonna say we refuse the rights...
...and properties and responsibilities
for the filming of this film.
Dean!
Just getting warm there.
Aoooh! She's fuckin' cold,
boy, she's cold! Whoo!
That's fuckin' cold,
dude, holy fuck!
Whoooo!
You're up there, Farrel.
You guys wanna jump?
I'll jump.
You'll jump?
Sure.
No, no, no, no, no.
I don't believe this.
I didn't catch that.
Is it on?
It's rolling.
Okay.
Just tell me
when to say speed.
Say speed now.
Speed.
Hey Farrel.
Farrel, you're up, buddy.
Farrel, what the fuck?
Everyone fuckin' - All four of us,
all four of us did it.
Is this your movie?
Whooo! Done. Over.
You don't go home thinking,
I'm a fuckin' pansy.
The four of us, right...
Just -
Farrel, get in there.
Whooo!
Let's fuckin' do it!
Farrel, what
the fuck you doing?
I wanna go home.
Farrel! Farrel! Farrel! Farrel!
Don't think about it.
Justjump in and go!
Come on, Farrel!
Nice on, buddy.
Farrel! Farrel!
Aw, fuck!
I mean obviously
he didn't have that...
...if he's diving headfirst
into the river.
Yeah, I don't think
that ever really hit him...
...overseas.
Just one thing after
another, our whole life...
...growing up.
Yeah.
He always had to be,
like, in the centre of it.
"Oh, it's all about me, look
at me jump, look at me. "
Hi.
This is uh, this is...
Oh, hi...
Sorry.
That's Trixie.
She can come in?
Come on in, Trixie.
She's
fussy, I'm sorry.
Sorry about...
about Farrel.
If there's anything
you need, like, uh...
...we ain't working right now,
so...
We could come by and help
out. Mow the lawn or something.
It's on tape.
You know, it's on
the, you could see it.
We do that, like, I probably
jumped it, like 60 times.
At least, we always,
that was the place we always...
...went to and justjumped
in the water and...
It was really hot.
You guys remember
how hot it was?
It was hot.
I'm getting better
already, I feel better.
It's, kind of have to,
you know, would thank Farrel...
'cause he brung it up to Trixie
there and then Trixie kind of...
...forced me to go get her dealt
with and I'll, you know...
...it was the right thing to do.
It hurts like a bitch, like...
Thank you,
thank you both for coming.
Thank you.
Come and see the cake,
Joan, I want you to see...
...you know Farrel and filming.
Oh, oh my God.
Isn't that
just wonderful?
Isn't thatjust a
beautiful cake, isn't it?
Do you wanna
like to hear a joke, Mrs. Mitchner?
Most...
certainly, yes.
I think Farrel
really liked this one.
Did he?
What do you call
a man who's from Pakistan who's been...
...everywhere and
seen everything?
No, been everywhere and
done everything, yeah?
I don't know.
Bindair Dundat.
Oh,
been there, done that.
Yeah.
Is that his first
and his last name?
Yeah.
Been there, done that.
No, Bindair.
Been dere, oh!
She liked that one.
She's laughing.
I told you.
Oh! Did it take my son
that long to get it?
No.
Well, thank you, boys.
Thank you very much for
thatjoke. We needed that.
Yeah.
Oh hey,
yeah good, hey man.
I thought for sure it was, you
know, over, after, after...
...you know... I keep thinking about
it over and over, like, I recall...
...that day so clear, it's
like slow-mo sometimes.
For awhile there we sort of
stopped talking to each other.
It wasn't even about Farrel or
nothing, it was just us sort...
...of yelling, but I think deep
down that's what it was about...
...he's been going to the hospital
quite a bit, and he's just...
...getting some tests done, and
uh, apparently he's got one...
...more big test, and once they
give him that clear, it's looking...
...good, but we don't know
yet, so otherwise he might have...
...to keep getting
treated, you know.
The chemo was sort of
like a downhill battle, 'cause...
I wasn't doing nothing, I was
just getting sicker and sicker...
...and like, no energy and all
that stupid shit, but now...
I'm slowly building up.
Fuck, I don't
know, we'll see.
He doesn't look
too happy today.
Hey Deaner.
Easy, easy.
Whoa, easy there, Terry.
Imagine you had a truck
up on the hoist, and you're...
...fixing it, and you're fixing,
you're replacing the brake...
...lines, but the whole time
you're worried one day the...
...brake line might break,
like that's just kind of dumb.
Yeah, yeah,
you just fixed it.
Yeah, but
you're working on it.
So you've, it's like, maybe
if you knew the brake lines...
...were fucked, and you kept
driving, then you could go oh shit.
Yeah.
You're getting your
brake lines put it right now.
Oh, he's been doing good, you
know, he's a tough guy right...
...down there from the head to
the heart, and uh, he's been...
...helping me out real good. Like
I say, Terry's my best buddy.
Him joking around keeps me
joking around too, you know.
Like some nights, I'll just
be like, fuck, Terry, I wanna...
...sleep, and he'll just be
like, c'mon fuckin' baldy.
Do you have any
with booze in them?
Will that be all?
Yeah, that's everything.
All together?
Yeah.
But Terry, he just
treats me like old Deaner...
...you know? Basically what I want
to do is just get back, on the...
...in the saddle, so to speak,
startjamming again. You tell...
...me right now that the results
are bad, I go, okay, fuck...
...wheel me into the fuckin'
ward there, I'll giv'er again...
'cause I ain't gonna let it you
know, kill me, capture me...
...take me down now, eh. Before
I was kind of stupid, I was like...
...fuck, I don't care, but now
I kind of care, like I don't...
I'm not gonna let no cancer
take me down. There's no way.
Thank you all for, uh,
coming today to celebrate, uh...
...life and friends and family.
Tomorrow we're gonna have some
big news of what's gonna be...
...happening with Dean.
And um, his tasks in life are done...
...and we'll see what's going to
happen tomorrow, but he's been...
...a wonderful son and a
treasure and a treat...
...and I love you very much.
Anyway, praise
the Lord and let's eat!
Count our blessings!
The chemotherapy does
knock him down a little bit...
...but he's coping it, with a
pretty good sense of humor...
...and that's the bottom line.
Fuck, they took out,
along with my nut they took out...
...my urethra.
I don't know if they
actually did it.
That's gotta be a record.
I was under a lot of
anaesthetic when they said...
...what else do you want done?
You're so full of shit.
Well Dean's, uh,
Dean's a trooper. He came into...
...this pretty sort of fixated
on his, on what he was losing.
I guess is, under the
circumstances you can understand...
...that. First of all, it's -
it's one of two organs and...
...you actually don't need
both of them to function.
And what's function is to be
fertile. So, he's still...
...producing sperm, so if - He can
have children. It doesn't affect...
...his sexual performance,
so he's realized all these plusses...
...and he's turned around
and he's feeling great.
The last time I was
there, he said next time we see...
...you we'll have some positive
results. Certain results...
I guess, would be a better -
the better description.
He said he was gonna
come, you know.
Maybe he worked late on a
Saturday, maybe he worked...
...through the softball
game too, you know.
There he is.
Hey.
Hey, you look like
one of the three stooges.
Yeah, you look
like the other two.
I think you're
gonna make it.
Hey everybody,
it's fuckin' Tron!
Whooooo!
Tron! Yeah!
Let's get her going!
Straight off, there's
no pretty picture here.
This is the most aggressive
tumor he could have had...
...so the outlook is actually bad.
I phoned the hospital
arranged to, uh, give him...
...my extra one, but, they said,
that, uh, the scrotum...
...of an average man couldn't
handle such a big one, so.
There's still only
a 40% chance that he will be...
...disease-free at the end
of this treatment process.
You know what? Either
way, regardless of what tomorrow...
...says to me, whether the doctor
says pain or the forecast says...
...rain. I don't fuckin' care.
Deaner's gonna keep on givin'er.
And that's all there is to it.
You guys, right from
the horse's mouth, eh?
I'm gonna keep on givin'er.
And if it takes another couple
months or a couple of years...
...we'll be right back
here next year.
One news can nudge your head
long into, you know, down, and...
...the other news can sort of flip
you around and push you back.
I feel like I'm
going fuckin' mental here...
...that's how I feel,
like waiting.
Hi Dean.
Oh, hey Dr. Lim.
I just want you to
understand perfectly that uh...
...the results show that
there's absolutely no spread, okay?
So that's good, right?
That's very good.
Aw, right on!
If there was spread,
the prognosis is much worse.
I don't want to pull - Make
unnecessarily, uh, better than...
...what it is. It's still a
serious disease, okay?
With no spread, with
chemotherapy, with radiation...
...therapy, there is still an outside
chance many years from now, okay?
Okay.
But as far as follow-up
goes, you, you'll have...
...the scheduled six-monthly
and yearly visits.
You tell me when to
come down here, doc...
...and I'll fuckin' be here, so.
Sure, great.
Excellent.
'Cause I really don't know why
he didn't lose his moustache...
...hair. Kind mind-boggling, I
guess. Kind of medical miracle...
...but I don't have a good
explanation for why.
Oh, hey Dean,
how's it going?
It's going.
What'd he say?
Can I have a smoke?
Give me a smoke,
man, seriously.
Dean, you're not
supposed to smoke.
He said it might
make you sicker.
Yeah, doesn't seem
to matter no more.
What are you talking about?
Well I don't really seem
to have a lot of, a lot time left.
Really?
Yeah.
He said you're go
- Gonna die?
Could we go out for
lunch or something?
Yeah?...
Like right now?
When are you...
Like, I might not,
I, I don't have...
He said you
were gonna die?
Yeah, I don't really
have a lot of time.
So we should go
for lunch right now.
Are you - Are you
all right? Are you all right?
Dean.
Actually, Terry.
Yes, what?
We might not even
be able to make it through lunch...
...unless we go
somewhere close.
Sure, let's go,
you wanna have lunch?
Sure, I'll buy you lunch.
I might only
12 or 13 minutes left.
Fuck you!
Terry! I'm calling!
What a jackass.
What a f...
you're an asshole.
Terry, don't leave me!
Don't leave me.
If you tell anyone
I fuckin' hugged you...
I won't tell them you hugged me.
I'll tell them you fuckin' tried...
...to stick your tongue
down my throat.
To Farrel.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org