##[Man Vocalizing]
##[Man Singing]
- ##[Continues, Indistinct]
- [Man On Radio] What's up, Los Angeles?
You're driving with Theo,
and that song's dedicated...
to the late Chris Powell, owner of
Powell Gas and Market for the past 40 years.
Mr. Powell prided himself in providing
full service to his community...
which he believed deserved
nothing but first-class service.
I can testify to that. I bought
my gas there every week.
God bless you, Chris.
We're gonna miss you.
Now back to the most nonstop
music in Southern California...
the people's station, hot 92 JAMS.
##[Man Singing Rap]
[Children Playing]
##[Continues, Fades]
[Chattering]
- Is that Damon?
- Damon?
- Hey, Ma.
- Damon.
Oh, baby. I was afraid
you weren't gonna make it.
I'm sorry. I had
some last-minute business.
- Mm.
- You okay, Ma?
I am now.
Now, will you lookie here!
My fine-ass nephew!
- How you doin', Aunt Bea?
- You look like a movie star or somethin'.
- Come on. Give your Aunt Bea a kiss.
- All right. Oh!
I swear if you wasn't my nephew,
I'd get with you, boy. Whoo!
Beatrice, leave that boy alone. You need to
keep your old, wrinkled prune lips to yourself!
I know you ain't callin' nobody old...
not with your old, tired self.
Beatrice, come on, walk me inside.
- Thanks, Will.
- Don't mention it.
It's good to see you again, Damon.
Sorry it's on such a sad occasion.
But let me tell you,
your dad was so proud of you.
Yeah. That's all he used to talk about.
'Sup, big bruh?
What's up with you, man?
You didn't have a suit you could wear?
- Fuck you, Damon.
- Oh, that's it?
If it doesn't agree with you,
just fuck it, right?
No. Fuck you.
Hey, come on.! Enough of this.!
We're here to bury your father.
Come on. Come on.
##[Man Singing]
##[Song Fades]
[Indistinct Chattering]
How you doin', sweetie?
All right.
Loretta. I'm here for ya.
You call me when you need me.
Thank you, sweetie.
I appreciate it.
- You all right, Mama?
- Oh, I'm good. What about you?
How y'all babies doin'?
Oh, Will.
Will, I miss him so much.
Gonna be all right.
I promise.
Been here a long time,
Will. Long time.
Bea, how we doin' in here?
- Oh, how you doin'?
- How's that food?
- Oh, it's good.
- Tastes pretty good, don't it?
[Chattering Continues]
Hello, Mrs. Powell. It's Ed.
Oh, hey, baby!
How you doin'?
It's good to see you.
I'm so sorry about Mr. P.
He was like a father to me,
and I'm really gonna miss him.
If there's ever anything
you need, please let me know.
Oh, baby, that's so sweet, but I'm fine.
Have you seen Damon?
Uh, no. No. Where is he?
Oh, there he is.
- Okay.
- Damon!
[Laughs] Excuse me.
What's up, man?
What's up, boy?
Where have you been, man?
I thought they had you in prison.
Just 'cause you're in San Diego,
doesn't mean you can't visit a brother.
The freeway goes
in both directions, man.
Hell, man. I can't leave L.A. There'd be a riot.
The women of this town would go nuts.
[Laughs] Stupid, man.
Hey, man, I'm sorry
about your pops. You okay?
Yeah, man. I'm fine.
I was torn up when I heard.
I would've come to the funeral...
but I had a whole gang of computers
to install for the police department.
Uh, by the way,
your driving record is now clean.
- Delete, delete, delete.
- [Laughing]
Oh, man! Who is that?
That's the new pastor
down at Plant A Seed.
Wha... That's a reverend?
God... damn!
- Ed, show some respect.
- Man, I'm about to show
a little more than that.
I'm about to show some love.
Yo, introduce a brother.
This is my father's funeral, man!
- Damon.
- Ah, Reverend.
Hello. I just want you to know
that I'm here for you...
and if there's anything I can do for you
and your family, just let me know.
Thank you.
I really appreciate that.
Uh, Reverend Thompson,
this is, uh, my friend...
Deacon! Deacon Edward K. Cunningham.
Well, it is nice to meet you, Deacon.
And where do you minister?
Wherever there is pain and loneliness.
[Chuckles] What are you doin' tonight?
'Cause we could have...
Excuse me, Deacon.
Can I holla at you for a second?
- Can't you see that I'm busy, my son?
- Get your ass over here.
- Excuse us, Reverend.
- Mm-hmm.
- What are you doin'?
- Man, I'm tryin' to get a date.
- She's a reverend, Ed.
- Man, you know what
they say about reverends.
I don't know anything. Why do you
keep thinkin' with your little head?
Hey, look. Ain't nothin' little
about it, all right?
Believe that.
Man, what's wrong with you?
If I had a reverend that fine,
I would be all...
Oh, my bad, man.
You wanna hit that?
No! I wanna hit you.
Ah, man!
That's my bad kidney, dog.
- D., what's up, man?
- Why are you here?
I'm here to pay my respects.
Since when do you start
respecting people?
Why don't you get out of my house, man.
Look, man...
Yo, what's up, my nigga Craig?
- What's up, my nigga?
- What's up, baby?
- How are you, man?
- I'm good.
Dude, I'm sorry to hear about your pops, man.
He was a cool motherfucker, man.
Thanks, man. Come on.
Mom's lookin' for you.
A'ight.
Hello, Mrs. Powell.
How you doin'?
Oh, fine, Craig! How you doin', baby?
Thanks for askin'.
I'm cool. You know I'll be a'ight.
Just wanted to let you know
Mr. Powell was a good brother.
Oh. I want you to have this.
Thank you, baby,
but I can't take this.
- Heck, I can!
- Beatrice!
Yo, Craig, can I holla
at you for a second?
[Indistinct Whispering]
[Laughs] For sure. Come right now.
- See you around, Mrs. Powell.
- Oh, thank you, baby. You take care, okay?
A'ight. Stay up.
Hey.! Gimme that money, boy.!
[Indistinct Whispering]
Hey, man, don't you think you should
stick around here this afternoon?
- You better get outta my face, man.
- What's wrong with you?
- Mama needs you right now.
- What are you talkin' about?
- I'm the one been here.
- [Loretta] You two okay?
Yeah, Mama. I'm cool.
Good afternoon,
Mrs. Powell. Mookie.
What are you doin' here, Mr. Sang?
I came to extend my condolences
to you and your family.
I bet you did. Let me
tell you somethin', Mr. Sang.
If you're here to try to butter me up to get
me to sell you my property, don't bother.
Powell Gas and Market is not for sale.
I'm sorry you question
my motive, Mrs. Powell.
Your husband was a good man.
Please accept this wreath
from me and my family.
Good day, Mrs. Powell.
What was that all about, Ma?
Oh, he's been tryin' to get
your father to sell for years.
Sang has been payin' top dollar for
all the property around the station...
so he can build a Korean mall.
If he's payin' top dollar, maybe you
should sell and get the money.
- That's what I've been tellin' her.
- No.
Your father started that station
with a $50 loan and a prayer...
when there were no black-owned
businesses in this neighborhood.
- That's right.
- I'm not gonna do it.
Besides, it's not mine to sell.
It belongs to you two.
- What?
Your father left the station
to you two boys.
Why would he do that?
That doesn't make any sense.
That's what I told him,
but it's right here in his will.
So hold on. You're tellin' me that...
that we own the station?
Well, not exactly.
Chris had me draw up a codicil to his will
just a couple of weeks ago.
- A what?
- A codicil. It's an addendum.
- [Mocking] An addendum.
- Basically, it states...
that the ownership
of Powell's Gas and Market...
will turn over to you in a year...
provided the two of you work it together
for the duration of that year.
- Oh, this is some bullshit.
- Watch your mouth, boy!
Now, you and your brother are gonna be
workin' together for the next year.
Ma, I got my own business. I'm not gonna
take off a year to work with him.
Oh, that's cool, 'cause I don't
wanna work with you, neither.
Ma, it's all good. Let him go on,
'cause I can run the station.
What are you talkin' about?
You can't even run yourself.
You don't know what I can do.
You don't know nothin' about me.
I know you didn't graduate high school,
and you're still livin' at home with your mama.
- You always runnin' your mouth.
- You listen to me!
[All Shouting At Once]
I said stop it, both of you!
Stop it! Stop it!
[Door Slams]
I, uh... I got to be goin', Loretta.
Thank you for everything,
Mr. Garrison.
- Sure thing. Damon.
- Thanks.
What's your problem, Damon?
- I got my own business, Ma.
- Business?
You don't have a business,
sweetie, and you're bankrupt.
That's right, honey.
I know all about it.
You're bankrupt, and you were
evicted from your apartment.
So don't you sit there
like you got someplace to go...
because you and I both know
that's not the case!
And that money you been
gettin'from Aunt Bee?
It's been comin' from me and your daddy,
because that fool is broke too.
But, Ma, I can't do it.
Yes, you can. Because that's
what your father wanted.
- But, Ma...
- Don't you ‘‘but Ma" me!
Now, you're gonna take your
narrow butt to work tomorrow...
and you and Mookie are gonna work
that station together for the next year!
And I don't want no bad feelings.
You hear me?
Do you hear me?
It's ridiculous the way
you boys are carryin' on.
Must've got it from your daddy's side.
My folks don't act like that.
[Men Arguing]
[Mookie] That's right.! I don't care.!
You don't tell me what to do.!
I don't care!
You don't tell me what to do!
Nobody's tellin' you what to do.
I'm tryin' to have a discussion.
A discussion about what?
Ain't nothin' to discuss!
- I own this station too!
- Who has a business degree?
What the hell does that
have to do with anything?
You can't even open
the damn gate! Move! Gimme that!
Oh, great!
Somethin' you're good at.
From now on, you're in charge
of opening the gate!
Y'all better stop yappin' and get yourselves
some ofJeanine's breakfast!
- [Arguing Continues]
- It's gonna be a long year.
Come on, fellas.
Let's get to work.
[Arguing Continues]
- [Bells Jingling]
- Hey, what's up, shorty?
How you doin', huh?
What you got there?
It's a video recorder. Look.
- [Mookie On Speaker] What's up, shorty?
- That's tight.
Yeah. Hey, I'm sorry
about your dad. You okay?
Yeah. You know, I'm cool.
I just miss him. That's all.
Yeah.
Mookie, smile for me.
- I ain't smilin'.
- Come on. Please?
- Can you strike a pose?
- Stop! Stop...
- Strike a pose.
- No! I'm not striking a pose.
You know what?
You strike a pose.
My word!
Oh, you're hard, huh? Look at you!
[Laughing] That's funny.
- Okay, stop.
- No.
It's my dad.
[Speaking Korean]
- Mmm.
- How are you?
- [Bells Jingling]
- Ten dollars, please.
- [Scoffs] Ten?
- Please. Baby, a ten.
Man...
Thank you.
Mookie? Oh, I thought it was you.
- Mr. Sang, how are you?
- We're all very sorry about your father.
But your mother, she needs to think
very carefully about the offer I made her.
It's very generous, but I'm not sure
I'll be able to make it in the future.
Okay. I'll be sure to let her know.
- Thank you. I appreciate that.
- No problem.
Thanks. [Mutters]
[Bells Jingling]
[Clears Throat]
##[Woman Vocalizing]
[Will] Tickets to heaven.
- [Door Closes]
- Tickets to heaven?
Yeah. Unpaid invoices.
A single mom comes in,
car needin' repairs, no money...
Your dad would fix it anyway.
He called them his tickets to heaven.
More like tickets to bankruptcy, Will.
You got a lot to learn, boy.
[Woman Shouting In Spanish]
Maria, what's the... what's the problem?
- [Shouting In Spanish]
- In English!
Okay. I take Lil Maxso
to school, okay?
And they won't let me drop him off because
his stupid father did not pay the bill.
What am I gonna do with him?
Please, can I leave him here?
Don't ask me. Ask Damon.
He and Mookie are running things now.
I don't know.
Is he gonna be okay around here?
This is no place for a kid, Maria.
- Yo, can I get a Snickers?
- Yes, sir!
There you go.
That'll be 50 cents.
- [Man] All righty.
- [Cash Register Dings]
Hey, thanks, little man.
Thank you for shopping
at Powell Gas.
- Please?
- Okay. He can stay.
My God.
Thank you so much.
I promise as soon as I have the money,
I'll put him back in day care.
Say thank you to Mr. Powell, Lil Maxso.
Thank you, Mr. Powell.
Are you the boss?
Yeah. I guess you could say
I am the boss.
Are you married? 'Cause if not,
my mom needs a husband.
Maxso! I swear, I don't know
where this kids gets it from.
Are you married?
Uh, come on, Damon.
I'll show you the rest of the place.
- ##[Radio; Rap]
- What makes Powell Gas unique...
is that we're one of the few stations
in this part of town...
that offers full service pumps.
What the hell does he think he's doin'?
All right. You have
a good day, all right? Take care.
##[Man Singing Rap]
[Continues, Indistinct]
Good morning.
Welcome to Powell Gas.
Hey, Mr. Chocolate Man.
Can you pump me until I'm full?
Stop bein' so nasty, Elizabeth.
Pop the hood.
Mmm. Did that the minute
I saw your fine ass.
Take is slow, baby. Ooh.
Hit me with the super.
- Hey, Karl.
- Yes, sir.
Are you gonna put your
shirt on, Mr. Chocolate Man?
We're running a business,
not a strip show.
- Sure thing, sir.
- [Elizabeth] Hey.!
- Baby, that's all I need.
- But I'm not finished yet.
Do you think I came here
for the damn gas? Pull it out!
- ##[Continues, Indistinct]
- [Chattering]
[Will] Oh, another thing.
Business went up 20%...
since Karl stopped wearing his shirt.
I mean, women drive here
from as far east as Riverside.
I don't care. We're running
a business here, Will.
Hey, Hector! What does a man
have in common with a gas pump?
Oh, I don't know, Ignatius. What does a man
You squeeze him
and gas comes out.
- [Flatulence]
- [Both Laughing]
So what do you think?
I think y'all need some
air freshener up in this mug.
Come on, Brad. Yo, you let us perform at your
restaurant, you'll be turning people away.
Look, if people are laughin',
they're not eatin'.
And besides,
we serve steaks, not hams.
Okay, hey, check this out. Check this out.
Look. You don't even have to pay us, all right?
I know I don't. And I won't if y'all don't
have my car ready by tomorrow.
- Oh, it'll be ready, man.
Don't worry about that.
- You'll get your car.
Hector, Ignatius,
this is Damon, Chris's boy.
- Hey, man.
- How you doin', man?
- Sorry about your pop.
- I appreciate it. Appreciate it.
So, uh, what is it
exactly you two do?
- We're comedians.
- No. I meant what do we pay you to do?
Well, why don't we just show you?
On the first day, the Lord
said, “Let there be light.! '”
- [Sound Blast]
- Oh!
And there was light, and it was good.
But not good enough. Oh, yeah.
So on the second day...
the Lord said,
‘‘Let there be sound."
##[Radio Blasting; Hip-Hop]
[Men Yelling]
- Ah!
- Oh, and another thing.
Hector and Ignatius's after-market shop
accounts for 25% of our business.
What?
Twenty-five percent of the business!
What's back there?
That's nothing.
That's just junk.
- What junk?
- It's just junk, man.
Dae! Mookie! There's
somebody outside to see you!
##[Continues, Indistinct]
- Dae!
- All right. All right.
What can we do for you, Mr...
Sang. Choi Sang.
And the question is, what
can I do for you, Mr. Powell?
Mr. Sang, my mom's already said no.
Mookie, let the man talk.
Let's cut to the chase, Mr. Sang.
How much are you offering?
Oh, a man who speaks bluntly.
I like that, young Powell.
Okay. Let us cut
to the chase, then.
I am prepared to pay
your mother a fair price.
- How fair?
- What difference does it make?
- Mr. Sang, we really
don't want your money.
- Mookie, please.
How fair, Mr. Sang?
I'm sorry. We couldn't accept this offer
right now, even if we wanted to.
So why don't you come back in...
about a year? Maybe we'll talk then.
Okay. I am a patient man,
Mr. Powell.
Ayear it is.
So, why did you tell him that?
- Damn!
- Exactly.
I got plans for my life,
and working in a ghetto gas station...
fightin' your ghetto ass
ain't on the list.
- Believe that.
- Well, I don't want to work
with you, neither. Believe that!
Good. We finally agree on somethin'.
So let's just get through this next year
without a whole lot of fightin'...
and then we can both
go our separate ways.
Paid.
##[Man Singing Rap]
- ##[Continues]
- [Indistinct Arguing]
- [Arguing]
[Arguing]
- ##[Continues]
- [Arguing Continues]
[All Yelling]
##[Continues, Indistinct]
You don't understand
what I went through today.
I can't even thank you
enough. This is like...
Oh, my God. I couldn't
do anything without my car.
- Thank you so much.
- That's okay, Jeanine.
Just you do somethin' good
for someone sometime when you can.
Will, what's goin' on?
Remember those tickets to heaven?
- This is one of them.
- We're not a charity, Will.
I know. But she can't
make a livin' without her car.
Give me this one.
Just this time.
No more after that.
I promise.
A'ight. There better not be, Will.
- What is that?
- Four.
- And this one?
- Seven.
That's my papito. [Spanish]
Ten, Mom.
Can we do division?
Division? Maxso, you
don't even know division.
Don't feel bad, Lil Maxso.
Karl here doesn't know division, either.
- [Laughing]
- Yeah, your Mama does.
She was over my house
last night doin' long division.
[Laughing]
- Twenty-one divided by seven. Three.
- What?
Ten divided by five. Two.
Sixty divided by four. Four.
- Maxso, who taught you how to do that?
- He did.
- What's up, fellas?
- What's up, Positive Black Man?
- Hey, Shawn.
- What's up, little man?
- Nothin' but the rent.
- What do you know about rent?
I know we didn't pay it last month.
Uh, Maxso, uh-uh. I swear you can't
say anything around this kid.
- Yeah, he's a smart kid.
- He tells me that you
taught him how to divide.
Not really. I just showed him the cards,
and he just started firing answers.
Oh, my God.
That's my baby.
Anyway, here's your mail.
Thanks.
Maria.
I was wondering if you
would like to go out with me...
to a movie or something?
Thanks, Shawn,
but I don't think so.
You know?
I don't think so.
Oh. All right, then. Cool.
- All right.
- I understand.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Okay. See you tomorrow.
- Bye, Lil Maxso.
- Can I walk Shawn to the sidewalk?
- Sure.
- Well, come on.
What do you say we go get some ice cream
after you deliver all this mail for me?
Damn.! That was cold, Maria.!
Yeah. He taught your kid
how to count and everything.
Look. Unless he can count on a check that's
more than minimum wage, I don't care.
I'm sick of dating
these broke-ass niggas.
- Ow!
- Ooh!
- Hey, guys.
- What's up, Sam?
- Maria.
- Sam, how are you?
How you doin'?
So, where's the boss?
- I'm handling it, man.
- You just can't be makin' decisions without me!
- Mookie.
- Hey, Sam.
- How you doin'?
- I'm good.
- So, where's the old man?
- Oh, wow. You don't know.
- Know what?
- Uh, Sam. I'm Damon.
Damon. I know all about you.
Your dad talks about you all the time.
Is the old man around?
I'm afraid not, man.
He passed away two weeks ago.
What?
I didn't know.
I'm so sorry for your loss, guys.
Thanks, man.
We'll all miss him.
Your dad and I go back, what,
20 years I've been sellin' him gas.
- Yeah.
- He was my favorite customer.
So, uh, who's the boss?
- [Together] I am.
- All right.
So remember.
Call me if you need anything.
Sure thing, Sam. A'ight.
Thanks. Be safe.
[Engine Starts]
You hit that, didn't you?
Man, I told you.
She's a reverend.
Man, reverends are the biggest freaks goin'.
Reverend JesseJackson.
Reverend Al Sharpton. Reverend D.J. Run.
Ed, you nasty, dog. You nasty.
Come on. Reverend Ike. Yo, Damon.
Yo, Damon. Where you goin', man?
I need help carryin'this computer.
This thing's heavy.! Damon.!
Put it here.
Man, doin' the invoices,
inventory, accounting is easy.
But computerizing the pumps for
self-service, man, that's a whole other story.
I mean, you need new pumps,
computers, a satellite link...
Yo, hold up, hold up.
Who said that we were goin' self-service?
I was thinkin' of having Ed
catch us up with the world.
Well, who said that
we wanted to catch up?
It's that kind of attitude
that led you to becomin'...
the oldest fourth-grader in the
history of Crenshaw Elementary!
It's gonna lead me
to whoopin' your ass.
- I'm right here. I'm waitin'!
- Guys, guys! Guys!
You're arguin' over nothing.
It'll take at least a hundred grand
to convert to self-service.
Unless y'all just pretendin' to be
broke-ass niggas, I don't think y'all got it.
Hundred grand, huh?
We're officially a self-service station.
That ain't gonna work.
Watch. You'll see.
- How y'all brothers doin'?
- [All Shouting Greetings]
- Beautiful day, isn't it?
- [Shouts Of Agreement]
What did I tell you?
So what makes you think that people will
come all the way inside to pay for their gas?
It's called the honor system, bro.
- The honor system?
- [All Laughing]
Okay. All right. Laugh while you can.
Since we're a self-service station, we'll
be getting rid of a few people around here.
- [Laughing Stops]
- What? Huh? Oh, that's what I thought.
Who wants to pull straws to see who gets
fired first? Or do you want me to decide?
Well, I suggest you get
our money from Councilman Tripp.
He just pulled off without payin'.
- [Laughing]
- Hey! Hey, Councilman Tripp!
- [Tires Squealing]
- Hey, man! Hey!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Come on, Ed.
How long this gonna take?
Wait, man.
I'm almost finished.
- Here, you guys. Today's mail.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Hola.
What's up with the señorita?
- What do you mean, what's up?
- I mean, you hittin' that or what?
What is the deal with you, Ed?
Is poontang all you think about?
No, all right?
I also think about computers.
Check it out.
You're officially on-line.
- Ow.!
- You need help.
- [Horn Honks]
- Who's...
Man... [Sighs]
[All Chattering]
Karl, we got a customer out here.
I told him we was closed.
Closed? Who said we were closed?
I did. We got a church league
basketball game.
What the hell are you talking about?
We can't just shut down
in the middle of the day to play basketball.
- Yes, we can.
- [Horn Honks]
That's the beauty of havin'
your own business.
Mookie, before you do crap like this,
you gotta check with me first, man.
Come on, man. I ain't gonna check
with you on everything.
I'm runnin' this place too.
And besides, the reverend ain't gonna
be too happy if we don't show up.
- She's expecting us.
- Man, I don't care what
the reverend's expecting.
She ain't payin' no bills around here.
We runnin' a business, okay?
Not a basketball team.
Let me tell you somethin'.
The next time you want...
She's right behind me, isn't she?
L-I was talkin'
about Reverend Johnson.
[Nervous Chuckle]
What can I do for you, Reverend?
I just wanted to make sure
you were bringing sodas to the game.
Your father always
provided the refreshments.
Yeah, of course we are.
Whatever you need.
- Great. I'll see you at the game.
- Okay.
[Ignatius]
Mm, mm, mm.! Praise the Lord.!
What y'all lookin' at?
Hey, what y'all lookin' at?
- Let's get goin'.
- [All Chattering]
##[Man Singing Rap]
Yes!
- Yes, yes!
- ##[Continues, Indistinct]
Mookie, give me the ball!
Come on!
Pass the ball.! Come on.!
[Shouting Continues]
Pass the ball, Mookie!
Pass the ball!
[Will] Time out.! Time out.!
- Mookie!
- What?
- Mookie, what are you doin'?
- Yeah. I was open, man!
- You were not, man!
They was all over you!
Cut it out! If we don't play as a team,
we're gonna lose. Okay, here's the plan.
Okay, Hector, I want you
to inbound the ball to Mookie.
Karl, you set a pick
at the top of the key.
If you don't have a shot,
swing it over to Damon.
- You got that?
- I got it.
All right. Win on three.
- One, two, three!
- [Together] Win!
[All Shouting]
- ##[Continues, Indistinct]
- Right here. Right here.
Right here. Come on.
Come on! Pass the ball!
[Shouting Continues]
Don't hog the ball!
[Bell Buzzes]
Man!
Uh, I come from
a family of preachers...
my dad, my uncle and my grandfather
and my great grandfather.
So you're from South Carolina.
Why preach here in L.A.?
Plant A Seed
was my uncle's church.
When he retired, he asked me
to take it over, and...
Hmm. I'm sure the church ladies
weren't too happy about that...
you being young
and female and beautiful.
[Chuckles] Actually,
they've been supportive.
Some of the older ladies
haven't taken to me too well.
They don't like the way I dress.
Well, I bet the men
aren't mad at you.
You got me thinkin' about
goin' back to church right now.
[Laughs] Well, that's a great idea.
I'd love to have you.
Uh, thank you for walking me
back to my car...
and thank you
for the ice cream.
Anytime. Good night.
Good night.
Uh, I was wondering...
What?
- Can reverends go out on dates?
- [Laughing]
Or are you guys like priests or monks
or something? Why are you laughing at me?
No. Uh, yes, we can go out
if we choose to.
- Really?
- Really.
Cool. Just checking.
Good night.
- Good night.
- [Laughs]
Are you trying to ask me out? Because
if you are, the answer is, I would love to.
But I gotta be up front with you.
I'm not goin' to church, all right?
That's just not my thing.
Well, um, I'm not gonna
buy gas from your station.
It's not my thing.
I prefer ARCO. Good night.
- Call me.
- Ajoke.
Bad joke.
[Engine Starts]
- ##[Hip-Hop]
- [Mookie] You put your thing on this one.
I'm diggin'this.
This is nice.
- #### [Continues]
- Thank you.
Yo, all we need to do is double the bass line,
and this track is gonna be phat.
Yeah, that's good stuff.
I'm diggin'that.
- Yo, Mookie.
- What do you want?
- What's all this, man?
- What's it look like?
It's a studio. [Laughs]
- Who said you can have a studio here?
- Pops said.
So why don't you
roll up outta here, man?
Where'd you get the money for all this
equipment? Oh, let me guess, Mookie.
You're sellin' dope for your
punk-ass friend over there.
[Laughs] You still haven't let
that shit go, have you, D.?
Yo, Mookie,
I'm outta here, man.
Holla at me when you get
your situation under control.
Hold up. Hold up.
I got this. I got it.
Yo, D., you done seen everything
you need to see up in here, a'ight?
So why don't you
head the fuck on, a'ight?
'Cause we got shit to do,
unlike some people around here.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Nigga still holdin' a grudge
since high school.
Ignore that nigga. K.B.,
could you hit that, please.
Come on. Let's
get back to work, man.
This track is love.
Come on.
- Uh, premium, please.
- Okay.
- Hey, Hector.
- Yeah?
- Do you know who that is?
- No. Who?
That's Ashir Hammad. He owns
the Laugh Track comedy club in Hollywood.
Man, this could be
our big break, man.
- For real?
- Let's go.
- And do what?
- ‘‘Do what"? Get your ass... Come on, man!
Hey, Karl, we got this dude.
He's a friend of ours, okay?
Okay. It's cool with me.
[Indistinct]
- Hey, Hector!
- Yeah, Ignatius?
How is a woman like a car?
I don't know.
You check her oil with a dipstick,
you never let your buddies drive her...
and when she goes over 40,000
miles, you trade her ass in!
[Both Laughing]
I don't know, Ignatius.
I would never trade my woman in.
Know why? 'Cause nobody wants her,
'cause she's ugly.
Maybe so. But I would rather take
a Hyundai instead of a Ferrari any day...
'cause you could leave her
with the windows rolled down...
and when you get back, her
ugly ass will still be there!
- No doubt!
- Let me guess. You're comedians, right?
- Yeah. Hector.
- And Ignatius.
- We...
- Are a...
- Comedy...
- Team!
Listen. I like you guys.
You guys are very funny.
Look. Here's my card.
Call my office...
and we'll see about getting
you on one night, huh?
- Hey, thanks, man. That's cool.
- Thank you.
How much do I owe you?
Man, don't worry about it.
It's on us.
You guys... You're not only funny,
but you are shrewd businessmen.
I like that. Hammad has to go.
Salaam alaikum. Bye-bye.
- Alaikum salami, bro.
- All right, man!
Have a good day. [Laughs]
What'd you tell him
that for, bro?
You gotta spend money
to make money, man.
That's comin' outta
your paycheck, not mine.
Hey! Damon wants everybody
in the garage now.
[Indistinct Arguing]
- I'm not payin' for that shit.
- It's comin' outta your money.
- All right. Calm down.
Come on. Just come on.
- [Employees Chattering]
All right. Now when you
finish your repair work...
you will fill out
this invoice request form.
You will list all parts and
labor involved in the repair.
This form will then go to Maria...
who will input the information into
the computer and issue the final bill.
Now, no car will be released
without complete payment first.
I repeat, no car will be released
Will, no more tickets to heaven.
I know somebody who's buyin'
himself a ticket to hell.
- [All Laughing]
- What was that, Ignatius?
He said you were goin' to hell.
Now, why are we doing this?
Why? Because we're running a business here,
a business that's losing money.
Now, we can either do this, or we can shut it
down right now. Is that what everybody wants?
[All]
No.
- ##[Reggae]
- What was that?
- #### [Continues]
- Hey, hey! What is goin' on out here?
Maria, get in there and make sure
the kids pay for everything.
Get used to it.
It's gonna be like this from now on.
School started back.
What has that got to do with them playin'
chess in the middle of my business, Will?
Your dad taught 'em how. Told 'em
they could play here anytime they want.
- Well, those days are over.
- No, they're not, man.
Look, they're not hurtin' anybody.
Pop wanted people to be able
to come here and be comfortable.
And that's not gonna change
as long as I'm here.
Look. L...
Okay, kids, look. Just move out
of the driveway. Just take the tables.
Put 'em over there, out of the way
of the cars. Can y'all do that? Thank you.
Okay, you heard the man.
Come on. Let's move the tables.
Come on. Oh, that's checkmate
in four moves. I know that.
Okay, let's go. Here we go.
What's up with your brother, man?
He's just treatin' you
like a straight sucker.
- Yeah, man. I thought
you owned this station too.
- I do.
We don't have to fill
the forms out then, right?
Yeah, you still gotta fill out the forms.
Mookie!
- Man, he's a punk!
- I ain't fillin' out no forms.
- [Horn Honks]
- No runnin' in the driveway!
- Hey, Ma.
- Hey, baby.
Ooh. I brought you
some more clean towels.
Oh, okay. I'll get 'em.
- ##[Reggae Continues]
- You okay?
Oh, yeah, baby. I'm fine.
How are you doin'?
You know, things look like
they're goin' well around here.
Yeah, everything's goin' great.
I got employees who don't wanna cooperate...
Mookie and I have had our
third fight today already...
and we're bein' overrun
by chess-playin' delinquents.
Hey, I told you, stop runnin'!
Ma, you gotta tell me, why
is Daddy makin' us do this?
It's not like anything's gonna change.
I'm not gonna stay, and Mookie and I
aren't gonna magically start gettin' along.
Baby, it's early.
Give it a little time.
[Sheila] Hello.
Somebody's lookin' for you.
- Go ahead, baby. I can make it.
- Thanks, Ma.
Yes, it's early indeed.
##[Man Singing]
What's wrong?
I've just never seen chicken and waffles
on the same plate before.
Well, let me tell you somethin'.
It's good. You gotta try it.
Here you go. Just try it.
Just try it. Come on.
Mmm. That's pretty good.
Yeah, you like that, huh?
[Quiet Chattering]
Excuse me. Uh, do you
have another table?
Yes, in about 45 minutes.
Oh, no, no, no.
This is fine. Hi, Mookie.
[Mookie] Hey, Reverend.
Aren't you going to introduce us?
Jee, this is Reverend Sheila.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Pleasure.
- That's my brother, Damon.
- Hi.
Oh, you work over at the flower shop
near the church, right?
- Yes.
- And your father is Mr. Sang?
- Mm-hmm.
- Sang's your father?
- Yes, he is.
- [Scoffs]
Mookie, what's wrong
with you, man?
- What?
- Do you ever use your brain?
Do you think Sang would appreciate
your black ass goin'out with his daughter?
- What are you talking about?
- I'm sorry.
But I assume we're all adults
here, except for my brother.
What the fuck is wrong with you, man?
Why you runnin' your mouth about
this bullshit now?
Bullshit? If Sang knew you two were dating,
do you really think he'd do business with us?
Whatever, man.
You know what? I'm out.
Jee, come on. Let's go.
I can't believe you, man.
Fucked up a wet dream.
This one's horrible. Yo.
So what's going on
with you and Mookie?
We love each other.
Isn't that obvious?
I'm sorry.
You didn't deserve that.
No. You don't have to apologize.
If you don't want to talk
about it, I understand.
My senior year in high school...
I caught Mookie in the bathroom
buyin' drugs from Craig.
One thing led to another...
I snatched the drugs from Mookie...
and just as the security
guards came in...
Craig and Mookie
jumped out the window...
and I wound up in court
on a possession charge.
But nothin' happened to him.
The nigga only got probation...
'cause it was his first offense
and he was a model citizen.
And he's still mad at you about that?
Well, he kinda lost
his scholarship to Princeton.
- Mookie!
- What? It ain't my fault.
If he was mindin' his own damn business,
he would never got caught up in all that.
That's bullshit, Mookie,
and you know it.
You need to talk to your brother.
Come on, Jee.
He don't try to hear me. You saw how he is.
This ‘‘bobba" is good shit.
It's boba.
Whatever. This shit tastes good.
Come on. Come here.
##[Man Singing]
Yeah, that's what I'm talkin' about.
[Children Playing]
- [Chuckles] Hey, Maria.
- Hi, Ed.
Oh, hey, Lil Maxso.
How you doin'?
[Damon] Yo, Ed.
What you doin' here, man?
Man, I just came by
to check on your computer.
The computer's fine.
What are you up to, man?
Man, I'm tryin' to close the deal.
Oh, Ed, leave her alone.
She's not your type, dog.
- She's got a kid, man.
- What are you talkin' about?
Baby mamas are my specialty.
Kids love me, a'ight?
Check this out.
Hey, Lil Maxso.
Got somethin' for you.
Hand off. Ugh!
- What do you say, Lil Maxso?
- Oh!
- Oh, my God! [Speaking Spanish]
- [Damon Laughing]
- Are you okay?
- No, no. It's fine. It's fine.
- I'm so sorry.
- That's fine, but...
but you can make it up to me by, uh,
lettin' me take you out to a movie sometime.
Sure. Why not. All right.
#### [Singing Rap]
[Engine Knocking]
Man, shut it off!
- Damn!
- Hey, Karl.
- What's up?
- Still no sign of Mookie?
- Nah.
- [Crowd Groaning]
Okay. All right.
All right. That's it.
Everybody go home.
We're runnin' a business here.
- [All Groaning]
- Ah, I don't wanna hear it.
Lil Maxso, get inside.
- Damon.
- Sheila.
Hi. I just came by to say hello...
and thank you for last night.
- Did I catch you at a bad time?
- No. No, not at all.
I think it is really great
that you let the kids...
come down here after school
and hang out.
I've been tryin' to get a youth program
started down at the church...
but looks like you
already got one goin'.
Well, we're committed to the young people
of our community.
[Boy] Oh, man, that's a lie.!
What are you kids just standin' around for?
Get inside. Go play some chess.
Come on. Go ahead.
Look at their crazy asses.
[Children Chattering]
You are truly a saint, Damon.
I hope you know
you're making a difference.
You know, I... try.
[Horn Honks]
- Hello, Mrs. Powell.
- Hi, baby.
- See you in church on Sunday?
- Oh, I'll be there, Reverend.
Okay.
She's a nice girl.
Her skirts are too short,
but she's a nice girl.
Yes, she is.
Boy, stop that gapin'
and get them towels out the car.
##[Car Radio; Hip-Hop]
- Ma.
- Yeah.
I'll be right back.
Lord have mercy. Ooh.
- What are you doin'?
- I told you, man. I'm outta here.
If we don't work this thing,
we don't get the station.
I don't want the station.
It's always about you, isn't it?
Whatever you say, Damon.
I don't really care.
- Get outta my way. I said move, man!
- No. What's wrong with you?
Damon, Mookie, come quick!
It's your mom!
Mr. Powell?
- Yes.
- I'm Dr. Silverman.
- Doctor, how is she?
Well, we've been able to stabilize her,
but she is in very serious condition.
- What's wrong with her?
- She was fine.
I'm afraid your mother
has a brain aneurysm.
- Aneurysm?
- Yeah, what the hell is that?
[Silverman]
Basically, it's a blood-filled sac...
formed by an abnormal widening
of a blood vessel in the brain.
Looks something like that. If it were
to bleed, the results could be catastrophic.
Okay, Doc. We got it.
What can we do?
That's the good news.
Its location makes it highly operable.
With your approval, I'm sure I can have
your mother back to normal in no time at all.
- Well, let's do it, man.
- Wait a minute.
We're talkin' about brain surgery here.
What's the risk she won't make it?
There's always a risk.
I won't lie to you.
But if she were my mother, I'd take it.
[Woman On P.A., Indistinct]
Okay, Doc, do it.
Just do it.
Excuse me. Hi.
I'm Ms. Hughes.
There's some paperwork
we need to go over.
- Would you follow me to my office?
- Yeah.
So, um, it looks like your
mother no longer has insurance.
That's right. My father had to cancel
the plan he had. It was too expensive.
How do you plan on covering
the expenses for her operation?
This is not a welfare hospital.
- Yo, hold up for a second.
- Wait, wait, wait. Look, lady.
We're gonna pay, okay?
We're not destitute.
- Yeah. How much you talkin' about?
- One hundred thousand dollars.
- A hundred thousand?
- Hundred thousand?
And that's up front.
No money, no operation.
So you're just gonna
let my mama die?
- Are you two okay?
- No.
They won't operate unless
we give them $100,000 first.
- Don't worry. I'm gonna take care of it.
- What?
- I said I got it.
- I know you're not goin' to Craig, man.
Yeah, I'm goin' to see Craig.
Would you think for once
in your life, Mookie!
You take money from him,
and you don't pay him back?
He'll kill you, me,
the whole damn family.
- We can figure something out.
- Right now I'm just worried about Mama.
I am too!
Just trust me this one time.
We'll figure something else out.
I promise.
You better not let my mama die.
We're sorry, Mr. Powell.
We can't approve the loan.
Why not? The station is worth
more than $100,000.
We don't care about that.
Your cash flow won't allow
you to service the debt.
Look, I need this. My father
banked here for 35 years...
back when nobody
would bank with a black bank.
Doesn't that count for something?
[Sighs] I'm sorry.
Yeah, you sure are.
Maybe you can sell the station.
Good evening. I'm sorry to hear
about your mother, young Powell.
Do you have the check?
Oh. First things first.
We need a signed contract.
So, where is your brother?
- He's in the back. Don't you hear him?
- Oh.
Yeah. He's not happy
about this whole thing.
So if you'll just give me the contract,
I'll take it back and have him sign it.
All right. As you wish.
Look, my man.
I can handle this.
I'm sure you can.
But he is my notary public...
and must witness
the signing in person.
##[Hip-Hop Blasting]
Look, my man. If he sees you,
he'll flip out and blow the deal.
So let me go inside, get his signature,
then I'll come back out.
You cool with that?
Hey, Mookie, sign the contract.
[Damon Imitating Mookie]
No, I'm not gonna sign the papers, Damon.!
[Damon]
Mookie, Mom needs the operation.!
[Damon Imitating Mookie]
No, Damon.! Get off me.!
[Shouting, Clattering]
[Damon Imitating Mookie]
Stop it, Damon.!
He signed.
You and your brother have made
the right decision in selling.
We're not selling.
This is a loan, payable in 12 months.
I'm sorry.
You're absolutely correct.
My mistake. Ah.
[Sighs] Your copy of the agreement...
and a cashier's check for $ 100,000.
Please give your mother my regards.
May she have a speedy recovery.
[Door Closes]
##[Woman Vocalizing]
- Damon?
- Yes, Ma.
- Mookie?
- I'm right here, Ma.
I want you two to make me
just one promise...
before I go in to the surgery.
What do you want, Mama?
I want you two to stop all that
crazy fightin' back and forth.
You're brothers.
Promise me you're gonna...
you gonna try to get along
with each other from now on.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Whatever you say, Ma.
- You hear me?
- Yes, ma'am.
[Sobbing]
I'm ready.
Okay, baby.
Come on, Mookie, Damon.
We're about to pray.
Let's join hands.
Dear Lord,
please protect Ms. Loretta...
in this, her hour of need.
Give her the strength to survive
this delicate surgery...
for she is one of your best soldiers...
and there is plenty of work
for her yet to do in this life.
And, Dear Lord, please show her sons
Damon and Mark calm and reserve...
so that they can be a rock for their mother
during her time of recovery.
In the name of your son, Jesus Christ,
our Lord and Savior, we pray.
- Amen.
- [All] Amen.
Mr. Powell.
- How is she?
- Please tell me that my moms is okay, Doc.
She came through like a soldier.
- Oh, my God.
- Right on.
I told you she was a soldier. Oh!
[Chattering]
Get in there and work
on that camshaft.
What are you doin' here, man?
I thought you quit.
I made a promise to Mom.
Okay. From now on, everyone
needs to clock in and out.
- What you talkin' about?
- No, we need to clock you!
- What was that, Ignatius?
- Why we gotta do all that?
Because I say so.
I'm the boss.
I'm the boss too.
We need to talk.
- Come here, man.
- Holla at him.
- Mookie, we are runnin' a business here, man.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
But these guys, they work
60-hour weeks at a flat rate.
Now, we start making 'em punch a clock,
they gonna want overtime.
I might not be
a business wizard like you...
but if you do this, we might
as well shut down right now.
Okay. No more time cards.
[Cheering]
You did it, Mookie!
Ow.! Ow.! Shit.!
Come on, man. Let me show you
how it's done, son.
You don't know nothin'
about no fan shroud.
They don't call you guys grease monkeys
because this stuff is hard.
Watch me work, playa.
Look at you. [Indistinct]
All right. What you got?
- Here you go.
- Oh!
[Laughing]
Since I'm a grease monkey,
I guess that just makes you a monkey!
- [Laughing]
- Ha, ha, ha.
Come on, Mama. Here. Here.
All right. I got you.
- Come on, Mama.
- All right. Sit down.
- A chair for you.
- I don't need that, baby.
- Nothin' wrong with my legs. I can walk.
- All right.
[Shouting, Cheering]
[Man] Oh, welcome home.!
Now that everyone's
coding their work...
we know where we're spending our money
and where we're making our money.
[Mookie] Oh, this is good, Damon.
You really know your stuff, huh?
That's what I went to school for, man.
[Chuckles]
- All right. Good job, man.
- Thanks a lot, man.
[Door Closes]
[Shouting, Chattering]
Yo, okay. All right.
Quiet down. Hey, hey, hey!
That's it. You guys
can't hang out here anymore.
- Grab your chess boards and...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What are you doin', Damon?
Come on. You know Daddy
wanted them to be here.
Don't worry, Mookie.
I'm doin' what Daddy would've done.
Grab your stuff.
Let's roll. Come on.
[Shouting, Chattering]
[Boy] All right. Go. Go.
- So when did this happen?
- It was Damon's idea.
Okay, everybody inside.
This is your new hangout.
[Cheering]
[Cheering, Clapping]
Who there, baby?
Who there?
Whoo!
[All Shouting]
[Man] It's good to be here.
I don't mind bein'the only white guy.
I don't care if I'm the only
cracker in the box.
I'm from the South. A lot of white folks from
the South got some black blood in 'em.
I got black blood in me.
What's up? Yeah. Yeah.
I wish I'd got that big dick. That'd have been
cool, you know what I'm sayin', player?
Yeah. Damn it. Instead, I got bad credit.
Ain't that a bitch?
That's how it goes... either big dick or
bad credit every time. Know what I mean?
And a couple of sickle cells about all I got.
But anyway, the 'hood's just different.
We don't have a Jack-in-the-Box
restaurant over here.
We got a Gisette-up-in-the-B'ox.
Can I get a woo-woo-yeah?
And you gotta order like you're from the
'hood, or the guy'll shoot you out of respect.
‘‘Yo, what up, player?
Can I get me a jumbo Gisette?"
And he's testin' me, right?
He goes, ‘‘Uh, with cheese?"
Like, motherfucker,
hell, yeah! Hell, yeah!
And I want to send a shout out to the fry
guy. Got much love for the fry guy. My boy.
And I want a cold drink.
Bow down the cold drink.
And I need a chicken sandwich for
my baby's mama. He was like, ‘‘Word."
Yo, son, I'm gonna repeat that back to you.
Give us away to midnight. Know what I'm sayin'?
You want a jumbo Gisette
with cheese like a motherfucker.
Want to send a shout out to the fry guy.
Got much love for the fry guy.
Holler, holler, can I get a woo-woo
and a shot of A.J. Scott LeRock.
You want a cold drink.
Bow down the cold drink.
And you need a chicken sandwich
for your baby's mama...
#### [Singing]
- [Laughter, Applause]
- Thank y'all so much. Y'all been great.
Fantastic audience.
Hey, our next act I'm bringing to the stage
is actually a comedy duo.
And I don't know about y'all,
but I ain't seen that in a minute.
The last time I saw that
it was like Lil' Kim and her left titty.
Uh... [Laughing]
But bring a round of applause for
the comedy team of Hector and Ignatius!
Come on, y'all! What's up?
- Thank...
- You.
Hey, Hector! You know what I enjoy
about working at a gas station?
No. What is the best thing
I get to pump the honeys
and get paid for it.
- Whoo-whoo-whoo!
- Uh-uh-uh! You funny, boy!
Hey, Hector, man, other day I was changing
a tire and the strangest thing happened.
Really? What happened, Ignatius?
- The tire started farting.
- Wait. A tire can't fart.
This one could. I put air in it, and it started
coming out a little hole in back.
Oh, you mean...
it was passing gas.
[Scattered Booing]
- Calm down, right?
- Uh... [Clears Throat]
- Yo, Ignatius.
- Yo, Hector.
Uh, you know why gas prices
are so high these days?
Why are gas prices
so high, Hector?
Because in the Middle East,
they started growing weed in the oil fields.
[Booing Louder]
You know something?
Forget those people.
- Y'all were... g-good.
- Yeah!
So, uh, why don't you guys
stick around for our next set?
- [Talking, Indistinct]
- Oh, man, we gotta go!
That's all right!
We'll remember this when we blow up!
Yeah, baby. We're gonna be like LeRoy from
Fame, baby. Remember our names!
I'm sorry, man.
I mean, this is some wild art.
I mean, whoever painted this had some
serious-ass issues. [Chuckles]
I mean that is
an angry-ass painting.
Thanks. I painted it.
Actually, I also see a lot of love
in that painting.
Along with a lot oflonging...
and wanting...
and reaching out...
to be touched.
And kissed.
##[Man Singing, Indistinct]
Mm! No. Not while Lil Maxso is here.
Baby, he's asleep, all right?
Shh. We'll be quiet.
- I said no!
- Come on, baby.
Just because you have a kid doesn't mean
you can't be a woman.
That's how he got here
in the first place. Ow!
- Leave my mommy alone!
- [Laughing]
- Oh, stop! Look!
- Maxso!
- You know what?
- Stop it! Stop it!
Forget this.
And the paintings?
They suck.
You... Y'all are crazy.
- [Door Slams Shut]
- Oh, baby. I'm sorry.
Are you okay? Huh? Thank you.
##[Woman Singing]
My pleasure.
You think Hector and Ignatius
are going to be okay?
As long as they stick to fixing cars,
they'll be just fine.
[Laughing]
You know, your year's almost up.
Have you decided
what you are gonna do?
I'm thinkin' about selling
the station and movin' back to San Diego.
Really?
I thought you liked it here?
I do. I just have a lot
of business contacts in San Diego.
It's better for me there.
I just don't know how you, uh,
could sell your father's station...
after all he did to build it up.
I'm sorry. You know what?
Never mind. Good night.
Good night.
##[Rap]
#### [Singing Rap]
Oh, yes!
You're late!
You're great!
- You wrote this shit, K.B.?
- Yeah, I wrote it.
##[Continues, Indistinct]
No, man, I don't smoke.
- Look, K.B., I need you to do my C.D.
- You sing?
No, man. I figure if I had the right people
around me, the rest is gravy.
- You know what I'm sayin'?
- You sure you don't smoke?
What's up with that, son?
Whoo! Yeah, baby!
- My man!
- You like that?
You brought the heat on now.
- What are you doing here, Craig?
- Yo, D.
Take it easy, man.
It's not what you thinkin'.
Oh, really? When are you
gonna grow up, Mookie?
Why are you still hanging out
with drug dealers and acting
like a wannabe gangsta?
- Yo, man...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Easy! Easy! No, no, no.
Look, ain't nobody tryin'
to act like a gangsta.
And Craig...
Craig is my producer.
No, he's not, Mookie!
He's a drug dealer!
[Scoffs] Yo, Mook, man.
I'm gonna just bounce, all right?
- Yo, Craig, man, for real, you ain't gotta go.
- No, no, no, no.
Look, don't even stress it, all right?
I gonna leave, all right?
Hey, yo, D., all your passes,
they all used up.
Next time you step in front of me,
I'm gonna fuck you up, nigga.
Come on, man.
Excuse me.
Yo, Craig. Cra...
Man. Craig, for real, man.
You ain't gotta leave.
[Mookie]
I sayin'hold up, you gotta finish...
[Door Closes]
Damon, man, why do you
always dog Mookie?
I'm sorry, man.
L-I can't support him and his gangsta
rap crap with his drug-dealing friend.
Mookie's not a drug dealer
or a gangsta.
- Whatever, man.
- Have you ever heard Mookie sing?
No one has.
Mookie doesn't sing, Karl.
You don't know nothin'
about him, do you?
[Sighs]
I think you need to listen to that.
[Door Opens, Closes]
##[Hip-Hop]
##[Mookie Singing]
Are you okay?
- [Door Opens]
- [Laughing]
I promise you this, gentlemen. There's
no way they'll be able to repay the loan.
In a month,
Powell Gas will be mine.
- If not, we will withdraw
our support. Understood?
- Understood.
Thank you, gentlemen,
for your time and your support.
[Speaking Korean]
Hi, Daddy.
What's up, shorty?
[Engine Starts]
Thanks for letting me stay
in your house, Mrs. Powell.
Oh, it's Miss Loretta, baby.
And you're more than welcome.
Stay as long as you want.
- Okay, come on, gal. Let's get some rest.
- Oh, no.
Not in my house.
You sleep over there on that couch.
- But, Ma...
- No. I don't wanna hear it.
Now, Jee, come on.
Let me show you to your room.
- Good night, son.
- Night, Ma.
[Dog Barking, Distant]
Mookie?
Mookie, we need to talk.
Babe, let me get
the number two wrench.
Oh, thank you.
Mookie, we need to talk.
Come on, man. You've been
moping around here for the last week.
- Let's just... Let's just clear the air.
- I got nothin'to say to you.
- Jee, can you talk
some sense into him, please?
- You know I can't.
You know what, Mookie?
Get your ass...
[All Yelling]
Get off me, man!
Come here, man!
- I got to talk to you, man!
- Get off!
I'm your older brother.
You listen to me.
- Damon.
- Elliot?
- Uh, everything okay?
- Yeah, man. We're just...
- What are you doin' down here?
- I was listening to
the C.D. You gave me, man.
The track is hot. I want to sign this kid.
Who is he?
It's my brother, Mookie.
You know him, right?
- This is you, Mookie?
- Yeah.
Elliot Straight. I used to live
up the street from you, man.
Welcome to Krusit Records, man.
- I'll carry that for you, Maria.
- Thank you, Shawn.
Congratulations, Mookie!
- Mookie! Mook!
- Mookie!
Now that I know you can sing, we'll
have to get you singing for the church.
Well, I don't know about all that.
I do. And it would be
his pleasure, Reverend.
Hey, Mookie, I guess this is
your last day working here at the station...
now that you're rich and all.
Ain't nobody rich, man.
I just got a demo deal.
Yeah, stupid. Everybody knows
you can't get rich off a demo deal.
Hey, can we open up for you
on your tour, Mook?
There ain't no tour, man.
- Hey, but there will be.
- Leave the boy alone, Hector.
All you could be
is the closing act anyway...
'cause after the people see you two...
all they want to do
is run for the door.
Thanks for giving my song to Elliot.
- Well, it was good, man.
- Still, you didn't have to.
Yes, I did.
That's what brothers do.
- LeRoy from Fame, baby.
You gonna remember our name.
- Back one more time.
- Can I help you gentleman?
- Oh, no, thanks. We're fine.
Well, no, you're not.
This is private property.
Mr. Sang, what are you doing?
I'm surveying the property.
We begin construction soon.
Construction? You don't...
You don't own the property.
Oh, I'm sorry. L... I assumed that
since you hadn't repaid your loan...
that you had conceded that detail.
- Damon, what's he talkin' about?
- Yeah, what's goin' on, man?
Mr. Sang, please get off my property.
As you wish.
We can finish it in, what, 32 days?
Leave now. Please.
Okay. I will get
in touch then, Mr. Powell.
- Damon, what's going on?
- Ma, I can explain.
[All Yelling]
Hey! Hey, easy! Yo! Yo!
Hey, take it easy.
Take it easy. Check it out.
It don't matter what deal Damon signed.
- Come on. I'm half owner
here, and I didn't sign it.
- [Woman] Thank God.
- Yes, you did.
- No, I didn't.
Yes, you did.
I forged your signature.
- Oh! What?
- [All Yelling]
You're an accountant.!
You should know better, man.!
Hey! Hey! Come on!
Yo! Yo! Easy! Easy! Take it easy! Kill it.
Come on. Seriously. What was
my brother supposed to do, huh?
Let my mother die?
Because ofhim,
she's sitting here alive today.
I'm glad he did what he did.
Now, I think if it was your family,
you would do the same thing.
Mookie's right.
Instead of pointing fingers...
we need to figure out
a way to pay Sang back.
- Yes!
- Yeah.
Unless, of course, you intend to sell.
No. I don't want to sell.
Good. Then let's do
something about it.
- Yeah! Come on!
- Yes.
[Woman] All I want to know is,
what's going in there?
A driving range, a Korean market
and a full-service spa.
I'm a charted member.
That's all good for you,
but can't none of us get in there.
What do you care? You don't golf,
eat Korean food or bathe.
- [Laughing]
- Look, look. The point is...
- they're driving us
out of our own neighborhood.
- That's right.!
- And when's it gonna stop?
- Everyone, please.
This is not about us against them.
That's not why we're here.
This is about preserving
what is good in this community.
And Powell Gas is one of
the best things in this community.
- Can I get an amen?
- [All] Amen!
This is about coming together
as a community...
and doing not what is profitable,
but what is righteous.
- Can I get an amen?
- [All] Amen!
This is about putting our minds
and our spirits together...
and figuring out a way to raise
$100,000 to pay back Mr. Sang.
Can I get an amen?
Come on, everyone.
We can do this.
Let's put our heads together.
Within one of us there is the answer.
Who amongst us holds it?
- Lil Maxso.
- Why don't we just have a gas sale?
A gas sale? Young man,
that's the most ridiculous...
- That's a great idea, Maxso.
- [Cheering, Applause]
- That was... That was marvelous.
- Good thinkin', Maxso.
With all the people that Chris
has helped in this neighborhood...
I'm sure everybody would buy gas.
- All we'd have to do is get the word out.
- Yeah!
Wait, wait. Whoa, whoa. Wait a minute now.
There's just one problem.
Now, we only make 14 cents
on a gallon of gas. Tops!
We'd have to sell
over 700,000 gallons.
Damon, I can get you the gas at my cost.
- God bless you, Sam.
- [Cheering]
Whoa, what's that,
another 20, 25 cents?
Unless we clear a dollar a gallon,
it ain't gonna happen.
Even then it'll be tough.
I'll get the station to do
a month-long promotion.
We'll give away free C.D. S and T-shirts
to everyone who fills up at Powell Gas.
- That-That's still not gonna be enough, Theo.
- You not lettin' me finish.
You slash the price of your gas down to
92.3 cents a gallon... our call numbers...
and I guarantee you that Hot 92 JAMS
will put up a dollar...
for every gallon of gas sold
for the next 30 days at Powell Gas.
- Now, will that help?
- [Cheering]
All right, all right. Well, then,
that settles it. Let's get started.
- We got work to do.
- [Cheering]
All right, y'all.
Hot 92 JAMS, the most music. What's up?
You got your boy Theo
in the place to be...
broadcasting live from the Powell Gas
and Market on Crenshaw and 29th...
in beautiful downtown Leimert Park...
where we're selling gas
at 92.3 cents a gallon, y'all.
That's right. Our goal is
to sell 100,000 gallons of gas
in the next 30 days. Why?
To save Powell Gas and Market which
has been serving the community here...
for the past 40 years.
That's 92.3 cents a gallon brought
to you by Hot 92.3 JAMS of L.A.!
- [Cheering, Applause]
- ##[Man Singing Rap]
I know you're hungry, baby.
You been sittin' out here all day.
[Screaming]
- [Screaming]
- Whoo!
- ##[Continues]
- Hey, Mr. Gas Man, come gas me up.
Sure thing. Mmm!
What you ladies gettin' into tonight?
Where y'all goin'?
Don't make me come in there and get you.
You can come in here
anytime you want to, baby boy.
- Oh, hell, no!
- Come on. It's big enough.
Oh, no!
You're good, man.
What about my gas?
We ran out! Go!
Go, man! Go!
- Come on, please!
- Mm-mmm.
I love you! Come on!
I love you, Karl!
##[Continues]
- ##[Continues]
- What are you talking about?
I'd like to get some
breakfast too, you know.
##[Fading Out]
Uh-uh-uh!
Don't do that.
Checkmate, baby. You should've
never dropped out of DeVry, bro.
- Take that home with you. [Laughing]
- [Ignatius] Y'all a trip.
Okay, guys, that should last maybe
another couple of hours...
- the way you're selling gas.
- It's unbelievable, man.
We're almost halfway there,
and it's only been a week.
- Yeah.
- Hey, you ready to open it back up?
I don't know. We've been going pretty hard.
Mook, what do you say, man?
Give everybody the rest of night off,
come back fresh tomorrow?
Sounds good. I'm just worried
about old dude over there.
[Mook]
Maybe somebody should stay the night.
- Yeah, he been there all day.
- He's just watching. Actually, he's very nice.
Still, I think somebody should stay.
- I'll do it.
- I don't know, Will.
You sure you can handle it?
You know how you like your naps.
- [Chuckling]
- You guys kidding me or something?
- I'm a Vietnam vet.
- Oh, there you go.
That was a real war, not this weekend stuff
you got goin' on right now.
Maybe we oughta have
somebody stay here with you.
All right. Okay. Okay.
All right, Will.
We're sold. Everybody,
good night, y'all.
- Come on, now. Let's do it.
- [Yelling]
- You ain't got to tell me twice.
- We're outta here.
[Snoring]
Yo, Theo, good looking out, man.
And at this rate we're
gonna sell 400,000 gallons.
Good, man. But remember,
we're only paying for up to a 100,000.
Oh, that's cool.
Appreciate it, man.
- [Vehicle Backfiring]
- Oh, excuse me.
- [All Yelling]
- Pump the gas! Don't flood the engine!
- Hey, there's your problem.
- What?
- Somebody poisoned the tank.
- With what?
That's a good question.
Whatever it is, it corroded the lining.
- Those large flakes are metal.
- So why don't we get new tanks?
Just the permits alone is gonna take you
a couple of months, not to mention the cost.
How could someone poison the tanks?
Will, did you notice anything last night?
You were up, right?
Yeah, I was up.
I told you I'm a vet.
Okay, I might have
nodded out a little.
- Oh, man!
- [All Talking, Indistinct]
- Come on. It's not his fault.
- You know somethin'? She's right.
We all know
whose fault it really is.
Mookie, come back here, man.
- Mookie, don't!
- No. I'm not lettin' him get away
with it. You know he did it.
No, I don't know that.
And neither do you.
Let me talk to him.
He'll be honest with me.
- Papa.
- What do you want?
I need to talk to you, Daddy.
I know you're upset with me.
You've disgraced your mother...
me and yourself.
I'm sorry, Daddy...
but I love him.
And if you love me,
you'd respect that.
If you respect me,
you would not love him.
Especially someone
who spreads lies about me.
Calls me a thief,
a racist and even worse.
Well, now he's saying
you sabotaged their gas tanks.
And what did you say?
I couldn't imagine my father
doing such a thing.
That you were an honorable man.
Did you do it?
Why, Dad?
I offered them a fair price.
They should have taken it.
It wouldn't have
come down to this.
I did what I had to do.
So we're gonna have a full setup here...
a food court, retail spaces and a day spa.
- May I help you?
- No, no, no. Please, please,
don't get up, gentlemen.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Councilman Tripp.
You know Damon and Mark Powell,
their mother, Loretta, uh...
their attorney, Mr. Garrison.
- The Reverend Thompson.
- Hello.
And of course,
you know your daughter, Jee.
Excuse me, but I'm in
an important meeting.
You will need to
set up an appointment.
You didn't have an appointment when you
sent your boys over to our station last night.
Please leave,
or I'll have you escorted out.
Before you do anything
you might regret, Mr. Sang...
maybe you'd better
take a look at this.
I offered them a fair price.
They should have taken it.
It wouldn't have come down to this.
I did what I had to do.
Mr. Sang, our business is concluded.
Wait. Please.
L-I can explain. Wait!
- [Sighs]
- I'm so sorry to see that happen.
But since you have a few minutes,
perhaps you can hear us out.
In addition to forgiving the Powells
of their $100,000 loan...
we expect you to pay for all repairs
and upgrades to the Powell Gas station...
contribute $10,000 to the Chris Powell
Community Center and, uh...
- I forget anything?
- Oh, yeah, there's one more thing.
I don't want you
takin' this out on Jee.
I swear, I hear one thing, I'm gonna
take this straight to the police.
Please, sign here...
Mr. Sang.
[Cheering, Applause]
We are back broadcasting today
live from Powell Gas and Market.
It's gonna be under renovation
for another couple of weeks, but
the market is open for business.
- [Cheering, Applause]
- And we are down here
having this great block party...
to congratulate the community for giving it
up and helping to save Powell Gas.
[Cheering, Applause]
Coming to our stage,
a new comic duo.
Show some love for Powell Gas and Market's
very own Hector and Ignatius!
Yeah, yeah! Keep it up! Keep it up
for my man, Theo!
- All right, Ignatius!
- Ignatius! Hector!
Maria, do you think I can take you
and Lil Maxso out to dinner tonight?
No.
But you can take me
out to dinner tonight.
Hey, I wanna go!
You always want to go.
Uh, wait a minute.! Wait a minute.!
An Asian dude named Theo?
Yeah. He must be from, like, the east side
ofJapan, like, Watts Abbi!
- [Both Laughing]
- Bong!
[Booing]
So, big brother, we still
selling this place?
I don't think we can.
All these people would kill us if we did.
So does that mean you're staying?
I can handle it own my own
if you don't want to.
Please, you couldn't pay me
enough to leave.
Besides, who's gonna run
this station when you off on tour?
- Of course I'm stayin', man.
- All right.
- Hey, Mook, let me holla at you.
- What's up?
Hey, Mookie, man...
I love you, man.
I love you too, bro.
Chris, baby, you done well.
Honey, you can finally get some rest.
##[Hip-Hop]
Go ahead with yourself.
Go on, playboy, put it down.
#### [Singing]
##[New Song; Man Singing]
##[New Song; Woman Singing]
##[Fading Out]