I don't know where to begin.
Let's see.
This is so embarrassing.
I don't know,
I guess I'm pretty borring.
Please, class.
Show our new student a little courtesy.
Just tell us a little
about yourself, Janey.
I hiccup when I get nervous.
So we've learned.
Jane, why don't you tell us
where you're from?
Everywhere.
I mean, my dad's in the army
or at least he was until he retired,
so we were always moving.
This is the eleventh school
that I've been to.
Eleven different schools
but the uniform is always the same.
Even on Guam.
Chicago's really going
to have to do it's fair
share to impress
a seasoned traveler like you.
Tell us about your hobbies,
outside interests.
Let's see what do I like to do.
I, I like listening to music.
And I like doing gymnastics.
And I love to dance.
Army bases are pretty dead
unless you're in the army.
So I always had a lot
of time to daydream.
And my daydream was always the same:
that someday I was gonna get to Chicago,
because that's
where they make Dance-TV.
Live from Chicago,
America's Number One Dance Show.
Dance-TV is on the air.
Hi, I'm Gary Woods,
and welcome to Dance-TV.
We have an incredible show
for you tonight,
so stay with us as
we bring you one solid hour filled
with your favorite hits.
We'll have world premiere videos.
The last music news from Ricky.
And wayout dancing from
our DTV regulars
who could burn down any house.
So grab your fire extinguishers.
Turn the TV up.
It's DTV time.
Would you cover for me?
Just hold your blazer open.
Like this?
- This got it?
- Yeah, thanks.
Oh, my god!
Thanks.
It's Velcro.
Next to the Walkman and Tab,
it is the coolest invention
in the 20th Century.
My name's Lynne Stone.
Hi.
And I'm going to change
it as soon as I'm old enough.
Why are you doing this?
Do you have a date or something?
No, I wish.
I just know I must be horny.
I'm going to babysit.
You should see me when I go out.
What's the matter?
Oh, I know, you're gonna miss
the beginning of Dance TV.
Yeah, well never mind.
I'm used to missing things.
Well, get over it.
I'm not going to let you miss anything.
She's got a twenty-five inch TV.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Come on.
And you're sure she'll drive me home?
No problem.
I tell you, this woman loves me.
Okay, here we are.
Okay, it just ate,
don't feed her anything.
- Okay.
- Be back at six.
- And write down all phone messages.
You bet.
- Okay, bye-bye.
- Bye.
My little Lemsky.
A.Q. Lemsky, this is Janey.
Janey, stinky.
That's Janey.
Hi.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Jonathan and Lisa are my favorite couple.
You know, his birthday
is the same as mine, almost.
Do you remember when he kissed
her on the New Year's Eve show?
Yes.
They were frenching.
Afterwards he wipes
his mouth off, like this.
It was a dead giveaway.
That's our D-TV dancers.
And how would you like
to become one of them?
Well, now's your chance because
we're having a contest
to find a new DTV regular couple.
You wanna join us?
Well, you can.
All you have to do is come on out
and audition this Friday.
We're going to narrow
it down to seven couples.
And then have a grand final dance off,
right here on our Saturday show,
live on DTV.
Now write this information down.
I can't believe you missed it.
Missed what?
The big DTV news, that's what.
They announced the contest today,
which my own personal
sources told me about a week ago.
What kinda contest?
For a new regular couple
to dance on the show.
This could be our big break.
Hey, Drew,
I told you I won't dance with you.
Your palms sweat.
Very funny. I'm telling you, man,
you got the stuff it takes to win
that contest and on TV.
Oh yeah, I'm a definite TV star.
Me and Captain Kangaroo.
Malene, I can't help it
if I'm a conceptual thinker.
It's a curse.
But I just can't feature you starting
trade school right after graduation.
Jeff Malene, machinist.
I don't see it.
Jeff Malene, regular on DTV.
Oh, it's there. In neon.
I don't need any dance contest
to tell me I'm a good dancer.
Hey, squirt...
Don't call me squirt.
I'm not a little kid.
No!
I can't believe that you're
older than me.
I'm older than you.
Now let's take a little
break from the dancing right now
for the latest music news from my girl,
Now where is that Rikki?
Let's all hear it for steroids.
And now the news.
Did you see it last week
when Rikki roder in on a dog sled?
Oh, god he double's the coolest.
Call House Records at Thatcher Arena,
as their rock 'n roughage
victory tour continues
to sweept through the English countryside.
In other news,
Paul McCartney
bought up the publishing right
to all Locamotive sound effects tapes.
Does this make Paul rich?
But does it make him happy?
No habla ingles.
Well, we're almost out of time
but tune in tomorrow
for a sneak preview
of seven more songs titled: Jump.
Well, this is Rikki saying,
no matter how hard you try,
you'll never be as good as me.
And remember win the contest
and you'll be dancing the day
away on DTV
But until then, for all of you out there,
from all of us here, including Rikki
the DTV regulars, andme,
Gary Woods.
You have yourself a great one.
We'll see you tomorrow
when DTV comes dancing back.
That is the coolest.
We're going to be on DTV.
Listen, I'm a pretty good dancer.
But what I lack in substance,
I make up for in style.
And you, This is you today.
"I love to dance."
I mean, it was perfect.
Look, I think you're forgetting that.
I have General Patton as a father.
But you belong on DTV,
and of course, so do I.
We'll just audition, okay?
We'll just, we 'II go and audition.
Your dad can't find
anything wrong with that.
Lemsky! What's going on here?
I'm sorry, baby,
I'm in the middle of a board meeting.
Now what's this all about?
I already told you.
Why don't you listen for a change.
Yes, baby I I do listen.
I, I, I remember.
You want to be on some kind
of a dance show, right?
Yes, daddy.
I'm going to star on Dance TV.
Don't you think I deserve at least that?
But, but princess,
I thought we were working
on that Seventeen magazine
modeling contest for you.
My shrink is right.
I'm unloved; unappreciated;
I only have one car.
That quack'll say anything
to keep the money rolling in!
Aren't I giving you
a big coming-out party?
Don't try to buy my affections.
I'm going to be on that show, dady
and I don't want
to hear another word about it.
Now you've made me late.
Decisions are the worst.
One phone call? One phone call.
Mrs. Lemsky, my house my house.
Now answer me, did the phone ring?
Did the phone ring or didn't it?
Bye. Thanks for the ride.
- Did it?
- Yeah.
- This is inexcusable.
- Bye.
Don't forget to ask your dad.
Hi.
I like dogs, yeah. Benji.
Boomer! Sandy!
Oh, God!
I like a mad much.
- Hello, honey.
- Hi.
Hi.
Mm, how was school?
It was typical.
But I made a new friend.
You did.
Well, that was fast.
Yes. Listen, dad, could I talk
to you about something?
Hi, sweetheart.
We have met the enemy
and she has B.O.
Zach.
Come on, Zach, come here.
Let's wash the backyard off your face.
Listen, I was, I was wondering
about something.
What's up?
Well, see, there's this contest that
I really want to enter.
A little healthy cometition,
it's good for the soul.
That's the spirit.
Well, see what I do is I go downtown
on Friday and I get to dance
And then if they like me then
I rehearse evert night
and then if I win
I'm going to be on TV, all right?
Negative.
Hey, I don't want you going all over
this town before
I've done any reconnaissance.
Chicago is a tough city.
I've got to install,
an alarm system in this house.
And B: you're too young
to go out at night
except for the occasional
supervised school activities.
When you're eighteen then
you're entitled to some nightlife
Now we had a deal, remember?
We made a deal when
I was seven and a half.
"Nightlife" was The Muppet Show.
Don't sass me.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm doing this for your own good.
Yeah, you forgot to say,
You'll thank me for this one day."
And so I said, "Sister, please,
anybody could have comfuded.
'Hail Mary' with 'Proud Mary',
and besides,
I do a very good Tina Turner."
What did she do?
Made me wash all
of your blackboards, but that's okay,
'cause I broke every piece
of her chalk into tiny little pieces.
You know, you can't wear
that to the audition.
I know.
Are you backing out?
Lynne, look, my father won't let me go
and mymother says that
we have to let him win a few battles
so we can win the war.
Whatever that means.
That means you're going anyway.
Lynne, I can't.
They won't let me go.
Do you do everything you're told.
Oh, god, you do.
Uh look, there's your bus.
Good luck, all right?
And will you call me tonight?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Bye.
Oh, come on, come on,
you can do it, you can do it.
Take my hand...
It's all a matter of appearances.
If you show up at the audition
on a motorcycle, you're a wild kid.
But if you tool up in a Mercedes,
you're a man to be reckoned with.
Drew, when are you gonna get rid
of this thing?
That's your problem, Jeff.
You don't understand
that this car makes a statement.
Yeah. It says, "Hi, I'm garbaga."
I love this car. I told you.
It starts, it always starts.
Yeah, but does it stop?
This is so cool.
This is a mob scene.
You should have parked on the street.
What are you talking about?
There're a space right there.
A parking place right in front.
That's a good omen.
I knew this was going to be cool
I know it. Come on.
Let's do it.
Ladie. Top of the morning to you.
Smile, will ya?
He may be dorky
but his friend's kinda cute,
if your're into public school guys.
Which I am.
Come on.
Let's go, everybody,
we got a T-shirt stampede.
One of a kind T-shirts.
On sale here today only.
Better get them now,
sweetheart, they're not going
to last too long.
Get your Dance TV shirts.
Dance TV T-shirts.
Lowest vender exits Right.
Wait just a second.
He can't do that.
- That was my idea.
- Whoa whoa.
Drew, I hate to break it to you,
man but all right.
Okay.
If, I'll, I'll wait
and sell them after the contest.
I'll call them collector's items,
charge double.
Hey, beautiful, stop looking.
You've found me.
Great.
That's nice going, Drew.
I always wanted you for a brother in law.
She's a punk.
Do you really think I'm a punk?
Wow, that's outrageous.
I mean, it's not as cool as New Wave,
but it's a lot better than pre-teen.
So do all women throw them
selves at your feet,
ot is it just the ones
that can't reach any higher.
Come on, Romeo.
All right let's move along here,
please, thank you.
Yes.
You don't remember me, do you?
I haven't forgotten you or that smile.
God, I'm sorry,
I'm not good with names.
I must have forgotten who you...
It's Jeff Malene.
I'd given you up for dead.
It's a nice uniform.
That's all right.
There are plenty of guys
who go nuts for girls in uniforms.
Name two.
Your father and Captain Kirk.
I know I'm going to die.
Hi, I'm Lynne Stone.
My lucky Carol hands her number 87.
Next.
I have a real way with author-Carol
hands number 35 to Janey.
Somebody.
Thank you.
All right...
Look out!
Are you okay?
Sorry.
Lynne.
Lynne. Lynne.
Think it looks all right?
Thanks, bitch.
Nice car.
I've got exotic wheels myself.
What is it, a Schwinn ten-speed?
Yeah.
All right. Now, are we ready.
All right.
If we could have please thank you,
if we could have
the first group up on stage.
If you don't have a partner,
don't worry about it.
We'll pair you up.
We just want to see you dance.
All right?
So let the games begin.
I want you and, and I want you.
Yes, okay I want both of you...
Good luck.
All right, let's move it along thank you.
Could we move it along?
Thank you.
Oh, my god.
Cut them.
That's good. See that?
Whtch this.
All right, we have we have selected
the following finalists.
Listen, please.
One.
Six.
Sixteen.
Twenty-three.
Thirty-five.
All right!
Seventy-two.
One oh, two.
Is that a fif, fiteen.
Fitteen.
One twenty-five
and one twen-twenty seven.
One twenty-seven.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
You you showd lots of orginality.
Thank you.
Okay, now we'd like
to pair up the contestants...
Way to go, Jeff.
We've chosen so far.
Be patient, I'll be right back.
All right, now,
I'd like to make a few changes.
Miss excuse me,
Miss right here.
I'd like to see you
with the big fella there, please.
Yes, yes, you.
Thank you.
My you are bih.
Yes, well that's lovely.
All right, thank you very much.
If you would please.
Yeah, no, no, no, wat, no, no.
This, this is not right.
You two back together again, please.
Uh, yes, yes, switch, please.
There we are.
There we are. Very good.
There, that's fine.
Yes, that's good.
Well, I like this. Yes.
Sort of "Revel Without a Caouse"
meets "Sound of Music."
You're taking a fashion risk.
I like that.
Just don't do it on camera.
All right, remember to pick up
the list of rehearsal times.
What are you doing,
I no, I want to take just one of those.
You looked great.
Lynne, this is a drag. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
Did you catch my dance partner?
That wasn't dancing,
that was assault and battery.
There he is with that cheese bum.
Lynne, she set this up.
- We're going to tell Ira, okay?
- No, wait, forget it.
You know what's better than getting mad?
Getting even.
Did you get her number?
Yeah, Zero.
Hey, what's the Flying Nun's
phone number.
It's unlisted.
555-4102.
I'm sorry if I hurt your feelings.
I didn't mean to.
You looked great today.
You sure fooled Drew.
Anybody could fool him.
You know, last year I caught him
undressing my Barbie doll.
Am I ever going to grow up?
Maggie, you're twelve.
Next October you'll be thirteen
and then you'll be fourteen
and that's the way it goes.
I don't mean age.
I mean women stuff.
Don't make fun.
Mom never got to that part.
Well, I don't know who's going
to explainn it to you now?
I mean, Dad's no good.
All he told me was
"Don't be embarrassed, son,
and just don't read Playboy
before you go to bed.
Hi.
Hi, Pop.
I take it supper's ready?
Hi, Meg.
So how's work, Pop?
Positively stimulating, as usual.
I take it that's for me?
Absolutely.
Thanks.
You're not too tired, are you, dad?
Again?
You broke it again?
I didn't break it.
It just sorta fell off.
Mags, I don't understand
how that doorknob keeps coming off.
I mean, that's the fourth time
this month, you know.
Thank you Lord for this food.
She dance with it.
What?
So when I finally get asked to dance,
I'll know what to do.
My sister dances with doors.
She's the original slam dancer.
He should talk, daddy.
He's going to dance on T.V.
Maggie!
Care to clue me in?
I auditioned for a dance contest.
And he made the finals.
And then they choose the winners on DTV.
Well, what's the priZe?
He's going to be a regular on Dance TV.
What's this got to do with trade school?
Look you don't want college,
well that's okay with me but
I, I was in a hurry to get going
when I was your age, too.
But you gotta have the skill, Jeff.
You gotta start earning
a living sooner or later.
Look, trade school was good
enough for my father
and it was good enough for me.
It's not funny.
Don't throw a mental, Dad.
I liked it better
when you kids used to humor me.
Hold my calls.
Affirmative.
The credit card does work
on the bathroom lock.
Zachary, you're a pervert.
Will you get out of here.
Telephone. It's a boy.
Want Dad to take a massage?
I still can't write, you know.
Hi.
God, I can't believe you
remembered my phone number.
You still have homework to do,
- young lady.
- Hold on a second.
- Yeah,
- Who is it?
It's, it's my friend, Lynne.
Lynne? Oh, great.
Well, make it short.
I'll just I'll be a secound.
Hi, I'm back.
Look, meet me at rehearsal
hall at nine o'clock.
I'll bring the music.
Hey, watch out!
Bye.
I don't know if I can...
Sorry, I needed the phone.
What for? Are the Cabbage Patch
mothers having a PTA meeting?
You're cranky.
Whenever Emily Holland's brother
is cranky it means a girl dumped him.
You wanna get dumped.
- I'll dump you.
- No! Dad!
Enger.
Just checking.
How about a little status report.
Algebra.
Almost done.
English?
One chapter left.
Biology?
Finished.
History?
No homework.
Say, you up to the French
Indian war yet?
Boy, what a little light artillery
could've done there.
Well, I knew you'd have it under control.
Lights out at ten sharp.
Good night, honey.
All one?
You ever want to practice you moves,
give me a call.
First it was in my bedroom,
then it was 7-11 by your house.
Then it was in George's English class.
Only in this dream sometimes
she wants to listen to George.
She was that J.B.
cheerleader who had the almost
see through underpants.
Drew, can you be quiet for two seconds.
Yeah, sure.
You probably mean more
than two secounds,
I mean, two seconds is like nothing.
One, two, there, that's two seconds.
I hate it when you're in a bad mood.
I'm not in a bad mood.
Sweetheart, when are you
going to buy yourself a nice
sexy Catholic school uniform?
Hey, get off my case, all right?
Come on, Patty, we're not wanted.
Not so fast.
Patty and I have a little
business to attend to.
The term papers are in.
Eisen hower, Johnson, Kennedy.
Kennedy. Oh, he was so cute.
How much?
A date with me.
I'll take Johnson.
Hey, I heard those Catholic
school girls really put out.
Hey, hey, Jeff's very touchy this morning.
He just've had a rough night breaking
in his new dance partner.
Yeah, that's what you think.
He didn't even see her.
She stood him up.
There is a time and a place
for calypso music, young lady.
Open your ymnals to page 57.
We will now sing "amazing Grace."
What page?
Lynne Stone will join us.
Ans sing it like an American.
I waited out there
for an hour and a half.
I tried to tell you that I couldn't go,
but you hung up too fast.
Are you going to do homework now?
That's terrific.
For your information I've just made
some notes about some steps
in case there's some thing you can't do.
I can do any step that you can do.
Really?
Because I was thinking
we'd start out with something like this.
A little babyish, don't you think?
Babyish?
Look, I've been taking gymnastice
and dance for ten years.
What did you have in mind?
Well, I thought we could start out
with something like this.
Yeah.
I saw that on three different videos
and a Levi's commercial.
Come here.
Go like this.
Five, six, seven, eight.
It's good.
Okay, come back to me not.
I'm just gong to spin your out
and I want you to come back
to me, all right?
Out and back.
Ooops. Back.
Come back to me.
Are you always going
to wear that uniform?
Look, I've got news for you.
I had to sneak out of choir practice
to get here, all right?
It wasn't easy and it wasn't fun.
Excuse me.
Do either one of you have change
for a twenty?
Gosh, I don't have anything
smaller than fifty.
Sorry.
My lose. Have fun.
Look, we're wasting time, all right.
Let's get back to work.
Okay.
This is Mr. Glenn.
Yes.
This is Sister Natalie.
Do you know where Janey is?
No, I thought she was in school.
No no, she's not here.
Please tell her if she can't make
it regularly to choir,
I'll have to replace her.
Well, I'll talk to her this evening, Sister.
Thank you.
You're welcome. Thank you.
Just keep going around.
Will you stop showing off.
We're supposed to be partners,
or did you forget?
I wish I could forget.
Oh, really?
Because, you know, if you
want to quit this, it's okay with me.
What's the matter with him?
I hate him.
He's a guy and he's alive.
What's there to hate?
He's just, you know?
I mean, oh...
Well, good.
I like those qualities in a man.
You know, I've been locked
up in a room with him
for over an hour and let me tell you,
it was hiddous.
Is he going to call you tomorrow?
Yeah, I think so.
I'm holding this for ransom.
Did you and Shirley Temple
have a bad rehearsal?
Yeah, it wasn't one of the best
five afternoons of my life.
I'm not really in the mood to shoot
the breeze with you, do you mind?
Fine.
I don't want to hold you up.
But I do want to invite you to the biggest
and best debutant ball of the year.
Mine.
Now you don't have to come.
But I'll save you a slow
dance just in case.
Does he have any redeeming qualities?
All he does is talk about himself
and that stupid motor cycle.
I bet he's a good kisser.
Oh, that is so gross.
I mean, I cannot even imagine
kissing him.
Whenever I'm in a room with a guy
no matter who it is a date,
my dentist, anybody I think,
who are the last two people on earth
that I'd puke if he kissed me.
Zach to Janey.
Yeah, what's going on?
Sister Natalie called.
You're in deep trouble.
Leave two dollars in small change
in front of my door.
Sister Natalie?
Natalie?
Now he knows that
I skipped choir practice.
All right, Lynne, what do we do now?
Leave it to me.
Come on, come on.
- Janey!
- Okay, kiddo, you're home,
you're sefe, you're alive.
My God, want happend?
She overdid it.
It was gymnastic's tryouts.
She hyperventi lated
on the uneven parallel bars.
She almost spun to death.
I had to rip her fingers off.
Okay. Bye.
Call me later if you're not too busy.
Oh, my god.
Hi.
Hi. How you doing?
That could be you next week.
Yeah, but at least
she has a really good dance partner,
you know what I mean?
- Shut up. Come on.
- Bye.
He's so beautiful.
He looked at you.
When?
Twice.
You embarrassed me.
He looked at me. He looked at me.
Do you dress left or Right.
Well, my closet's on the left
side of my bed so I guess I dress left
except if I have to wear something
out of the hamper,
because that's on the right side of sink.
Left.
Am I interrupting anything.
What are you doing here?
Well, it's a free mall, isn't it?
Excuse me, excuse me.
Hey, there's Jeff's partner
and that cool girl.
Where?
Don't lower your arms.
Janey!
Lynne!
Come here you guys, come here.
Hey Janey girls, look.
By day he's high school student,
by night he's a penguin.
I happen to be personally
in vited by Miss Natalie Sands
to a party at the country club tonight.
You wish.
She didn't invite him.
She invited Jeff.
He's just tagging along.
Sorry. You always hurt the one you love.
Natalie.
Be right back.
You move, you bleed.
Hi. We need fifty of these right away.
Lynne.
There's a few people
Natalie forgot to invite.
Make it a hundred and fifty.
Remember, nobody gets in without
on of these. Understand?
Hey, I think your car's being towed.
Some lady was leaning over
to get dome shrimp
and I looked down her dress.
This is a great party.
Hey, there's J.P. Sands.
I gotta thank him.
I am absolutely...
Mr. Sands, Drew Borman
of Borman Interproses.
A pleasure to make your acquaiintance.
Well, how do you do.
Fine. This is a beautiful party.
It must have cost a bundle.
Well, I'll probably recover.
I know you will.
Natalie is worth every penny of it.
Yes, yes, wonderful girl.
She's terrific.
Well, Mr. Borman,
it's certainly nice to see you.
It was a pleasure to meet you, sir.
Thank you.
So how about them Cubs?
I think it's their year.
I love it.
Thank you.
Who was that creep?
What the hell's going...
Let's go!
Can I have this, please?
Please give it to me.
I want you to find
out who those creepe are.
I want to find out who's esponsible
for them being here.
I want to know what happened
to our security.
Look out!
Get out of here!
This means war.
I gotta go.
Oh, No! My god!
One more of those,
Miss Stone and you're staying
after school.
He can't see me like this, all right?
What, you mean as opposed
to the glamorus Holy Grace uniforms?
All right, look, go talk to him.
I'll take care of Sister Sledge.
Sister, would you mind showing
me that routhine you do
on pommel horse?
You do it so well
and I'm just so bad at it.
I suppose I could.
Thank you.
Hi.
That was quite a party Saturday?
Yeah, well, you khow,
if you like that kind of think.
So I tried to call you resterday.
To see if you wanted to rehearse, I mean.
Well my dad made us all
go to the air show.
Well, was it fun?
Two hundred people standing
around like this.
It was a blast.
So can you rehearse tonight?
Can you?
Sure. What, so I'll meet you there?
No, not there.
At the Court.
But I thought that
we were going to rehearse?
We'll rehearse.
No fraternizing!
Stay away from him, he's a boy!
Bye.
Do you mean you can't fix the contest
or you won't?
Princess, you're gonna have
to start learning to fend for yourself.
I keep telling you that.
It's a cold world out there.
Daddy, I don't want
to win the contest for me.
I wanna win it for you.
I couldn't stand it if those tacky kids,
Janey and Jeff won.
After they trashed your party,
and embarrassed you
in front of all your friends.
And on top of everything else,
they ruined your beautiful silver hair.
Are you sure you're feeling all right?
Yeah, I'm fine mom.
I'm just I'm tired, that's all.
Sleep tight.
Goodnight, Mom.
Hi, Jeff.
Hi, Sally.
I'm really sorry to interrupt you guys
I lost the keys to my car again,
and I was thinking that since
you helped me before that maybe
you'd help my again.
I'll just be two seconds. Okay?
Two seconds.
All right.
Phil, your car's being towed.
Hi, Tiffany.
Hi, Drew.
Tiffany, I was wondering, you see,
there's this great game called
"Tune in Tokyo"
and I know you'd be great at it.
You wanna play?
Sure I love games.
I wanna dance with you.
God, I'm really, I'm really tired.
Okay.
Well, I have a date.
I do, I have a big date.
Yeah, with me.
All right, but you gotta go like this.
- Beep Beep Beep.
- Beep Beep.
All right, now picture this.
It's World War Two
and our ship is going down
in the middle of the Pacific.
And our only hope is the shortwave radio.
Tune in Tokyo.
Tune in...
Will you please let me go.
Look, pal.
She's with me, okay?
No, man, you're wrong.
She's with me.
Now beat it.
Okay. I don't want any trouble.
I got an idea.
Let's flip for her, okay?
All right.
This is great,
What, are you going to flip for me?
Heads or tails"
Heads.
Come on, let's go, come on!
So what did you say, you'd flip for them?
No, they flipped for me.
Flippe for me.
Bus running. Get on.
I don't know, is the bike safe?
It's the safest thing you'll ever
have between your legs.
What?
Nothing.
Hold on.
I got a cheek ache from smiling.
I had such a good time.
I'm glad.
And...
And what?
Well, now you're supposed
to tell me how much fun you had.
A lot.
God, I'd better go home.
Wait a minute, come on.
No, I'm, I really.
I can't believe that in two weeks
I'm going to be dancing on DTV.
I bet I get hit by a car.
What?
No, things are going too well.
I mean, besides DTV I have a best friend.
And I mean,
I never dreamed in a million years
that I would have a boyfriend.
Who's this boyfriend?
No no, I mea,
I didn't, I didn't mean I had...
Oh, god.
Look, if you talk to your boyfriend,
you're just going to have
to tell him tough luck.
Cause you're going to be
with me every night this week.
So we're in this thing together, huh?
We sure are.
Bye.
I mean, bye.
Sister.
- Can't sleep.
- Oh, God!
Daddy, really, don't, don't do that.
Go on, sit down.
By the way,
why aren't you in your p.j.'s?
It's after midnight.
Oh, I was dreaming that
I was going to be late for school,
so I woke up and got dressed,
and then I looked at the clock.
Yeah, but you wear a uniform in school.
That's not a uniform.
In my dream I went to public school.
Well, Janey, you know your mother
and I have been talking
and we thought this weekend
we'd send you to St.
Louis on a plane
to see your grandmother.
No!
Oh, I think it's just
what the doctor ordered.
But not this weekend.
Why not?
There's a C-130 transport leaving
on Saturday at 08.00.
Don't you want
to see your grandmother?
Well, yeah.
I mean, I sure do.
Uh, but you see,
I, I have to study this weekend.
You see there's there's this really big
Latin teat on Monday
and I'm, I'm way, way behind.
Since when do you take Latin?
Since last week.
Which is why I'm way behind.
But thank anyway, Dad.
I have to go back to bed again.
Goodnight.
What, are you craZy?
I hope you aren't hurt.
I'm J.P. Sands.
Yeah, I know.
Well, I did't know whether
you'd recohniZe me
wihtout the blue berry pie in my hair.
Are you in a big hurry?
Yeah, kind of.
When I was about your age
I worked in a bottling factory.
I own the factory now.
Matter of face own a lot of factories
including the one where you father works.
I'm very happy for you.
Don't smart mouth me.
You know, I bet you and
I are a lot more like than you think.
I'll bet you don't want your father
to lose his job anymore than
I want my daughter
to lose that dance contest.
By the way, if you'd like to come
to my country club again, let me know.
I can always use a good caddy.
Hi.
Hey, what's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
I just, you know I thought
since you were late.
Excuse me, I didn't realize
we were punching a clock, okay?
Well, we are.
- Come on, today is our last day.
- Not now, please.
All right, it's no problem.
Uh, let's get to work.
Do you have the tape?
No, I forgot it.
Come on, Jeff, that's not funny.
Look, I'm telling ya, I forgot the tape.
I think about things besides
this stupid contest, you know.
All right, so who needs music anyway.
Uh, let's go through the routine.
Do you wanna warm up first?
Look, would you quit treating me like
you're the star dancer
and I'm some poor little clod
you got stuck with.
Now every one needs to warm up.
Yes, they do.
Oh, excuse me, I forgot you're also
the authority on warming up.
Look, I don't know that's bugging you,
but I think we should talk about it.
I said, no.
I'm not dancing
with you until you calm down.
What, are you threatening me now?
I mean, that's what you're doing,
right well forget it.
I'm sick of this whole thing anyway.
God, you were so naive, Janey.
You think we're going to win this thing.
We're not going to win.
We're only going to be in this
stupid contest to make it look fair.
But it's rigged.
Everything's rigged.
So what?
You're just going to quit?
I mean, just like that?
Yeah, it looks that way, doesn't it?
Get out of here, you make me sick.
Thanks.
I'll try and return
the compliment some day.
Lady, you're in big trouble.
Robert!
Now Janey, we have to know
why you lied about your Latin class,
and then you, you skipped
you choir practice and now you,
you snuck out of the house
without our permission.
Why?
I don't know.
Oh, I feel much better now
that you've explanined.
You can't go traipsing all over
a strange city
in the middle of the night.
I'm sorry if you don't understand that.
Why does everybody think that
I'm not going to understand anything?
You are grounded.
Yeah, well I don't
have anyplace to go anyway.
I wonder how the Bears
are going to play this year.
Jesus. Their disabled list
is as long as my arm.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Say, that dance contest is tonight, isn't
Oh, don't be nervous.
I'm not nervous.
I'm not entering.
Well, why not?
Well, Mag said that you
and your partner were
in a dimension beyond reality.
I guess that means you're good, huh?
Look, I'm not in the contest, all right?
They're for people
who are into being 'number one?
Oh, and you're not
into being number one?
No.
Jeff, I hear you're coming
up in the world.
Making the country club scene.
How'd you hear about that?
Bad news travels fast.
Especially when it happens to J.P. Sands.
I hate him.
Don't say that.
Now he's he's a greedy,
stupid putZ, granted,
but don't hate him.
I ran into him last night.
Oh?
What did he say?
He said he could
put your job on the line.
Is that true?
Well, so what?
So I can't dance in the contest can I?
Look Jeff, tell me one thing.
Can you win?
Yeah, yeah, I can win.
Well, then win it.
I'll worry about Sands.
Okay?
Thanks, Pop.
Timber!
Beat it, Zach.
Okay.
But we didn't even get to ask
you about Maggie.
Maggie Malene?
She told me to tell you, Jeff's gonna dance.
Oh, God, I forgot. I'm groundes!
Zach, what am I going to do?
You know what Daddy would say?
When all hope is lost
call for rein forcements.
Zach, you're the best.
Forget it. On the house.
Sweatbands, bandanas, buttons, caps
get your official DTV memor
abilia right...
Do you have a license
to sell these here?
A license, sure thing, officer. Sure.
Driver's license.
Student ID.
You know what's.
Oh, here it is.
It says here you're a member
of the Arechie and Jughead Fan Club.
Hey, I'm only in it for Veronica'a sake.
Hey, man, cut it out.
You can't do that.
Like my hair?
I thought you were
never going to get here. I love it.
Are you ready?
Am I ready.
Becareful, all right?
Watch out.
Oh, eat flame, boZo.
Let's go.
What are we doing?
Releases.
What are these?
Oh, these are the releases, right.
Coffee?
No thank you, no coffee.
Roger, take that.
Jeffrey, I want you and your partner
to sign these releases, please.
She's not here yet.
What?
She's here but she's just,
She's meditating.
Meditating?
Yeah, she says it's like
going to another place.
Wonderful.
Well, when her pass,
port expires would you please
have her sign one of those.
Right.
Thank you.
Does this look all right?
Just a second.
- Hold your mouth still.
- Oh, sorry.
That's a very good color for you.
What's going on?
I mean, why are we stopping?
- I don't know...
- No, I gotta get there.
- We gotta get there, Lynne.
- I know. So hold still.
Really?
Let me tell you something.
You can be replaced.
I lifted the Music News,
to the level of ar tand you are
treating me like cattle.
Okay, moo!
Okay? Moo!
Now you get into wardrobe.
I quit!
Oh, great, great.
Great.
Not great, not great.
What's the prob?
My prob, she's not here yet.
- She's not here yet.
- Okay, calm down.
I got to get this release signed.
Ira juat handed me this thing.
Sign it.
What are you doing?
You can't do that.
Don't worry about it.
Don't! Is that legal?
Am I going to get sued for this?
- I don't know.
- Here!
What is this?
Let's go, let's go. Becareful.
Get the fuck off!
Hey, come back here!
Hey, hey, what's going.
Come on, come on!
Wait a minute! Wait, wait, wait, wait.
It's Rikki.
Lynne!
Lynne! Come on!
Ten...
nine...
- Lynne!
- I'll meet you up there.
Seven...
five...
Janey!
Three...
one!
I want to win if you do.
Let's go.
Live, from Chicago, it's DTV time.
And tonight we've got
a special show for you.
I wonder what time the
M.A.S.H. reruns come on?
After weeks ot open auditions
our staff has selected these finalists.
Here they are,
the six hottest dancing couples
in America, competing for the chance...
Oh, Glenn, leave it on a sec.
This kind of show reminds me
of when we used to dance.
Hey, there's Janey on TV.
So stay with us because
the cameras are fired up,
the Judges are waiting in the wings,
and all we need is you folks
at home watching, Dance TV.
Did you know anything about this?
No.
Stay here, I'm going down there.
Oh, honey, don't.
Our first couple met at a...
Our first couple met at a dance contest
in Parkridge, Illinois.
Please welcome Rick Campbells
and Louise Harman.
Our next couple
call themselves Mirror Image.
And I think you can see why.
Please welcome
the Dixon Sisters from Kansas City.
Are next contestants are
no strangers to dancing on TV.
They dance on a local
show in Miami, Florida.
It's Jim WolKa and Mimi Doyle.
Couple number five comes from
From Lake Forest, illinois, Natalie
Sands and Ben Wolper.
And Natalie tells us she's wearing
a one of a kind
Michele San Germaine. Original.
They're the ones to watch.
You, you wanna give me
a closeup or what?
Our final contestants are
from right here in the Chicago area.
Janey Glenn and Jeff Malene.
She looks great.
She sure does.
Hey, Bob, who is that?
Hey, Ed, how you doin' huh?
Hey, watch...
watch this move, huh?
Hey, we're watching my kid on TV, huh.
Look at him fly.
Here comes the big winner.
The new regulars on DTV.
Incredible.
I can't believe this.
Natalie Sands and Ben Wolper.
All right!
And, Janey Glenn ane Jeff Malene.
We have a tie.
That means we have to have a dance,
off to find the new DTV regulars.
And we'll have that dance off right
after we do this, so stay tuned.
Where's Dance TV.
Get off my tail, Butthead!
Down the hall.
You, you got them it focus?
Hey, hold it there, buddy.
I'm not your buddy.
You see that young woman out there?
Yeah.
She's my daughter.
Janey's your daughter?
Well, all right.
She's the greatest.
And, and just look at her dance out there.
She's awesome, man. Sir.
Look at her.
Come on, Janey!
She's pretty good, huh?
Yeah.
Let's do it.
The judges are unanimous.
The winners are, Janey and Jeff.
Janey and Jeff are the new
Dance TV regulars.
Janey!
Wait to go.
And with new DTV regulars, Miss DTV
will have something to say about that.
Where is that Rikki?
Where's Rikki?
Rikki, this is not funny.
This is live TV.
A new Miss Dance TV.
You almost dropped me in tht lift.
You distracted me during my solo.
- Daddy.
- Why don't you shut up?
We did it, we did it.