- Morning, Scott.
- Morning, Ben
- Morning, Wells.
- Hey, sir.
Ghost Rider, this is Strike.
We have an unknown aircraft.
Inbound Mustang,
you're in Vector 090 for bogey.
- Who's up there?
- Cougar & Merlin, and Maverick & Goose.
Great. Maverick and Goose.
- Talk to me, Goose.
- Roger, I got them. Contact:
20 left at 30 miles, 900 knots closure.
- Cougar, you hear that?
- Roger.
- Merlin, you got them?
- Roger, I've got radar contact.
- I'll get a visual ID, Cougar. You hook them.
- Roger, an' I'll clean 'em and fry 'em.
Mystang, this is Ghost Rider, 203.
I got them inbound, bogey
heading 270 at 10 miles.
- 900 knots closure.
- Ghostrider, take angels 10, left, 3, 0.
- Are we supposed to have visitors today?
- Negative, sir.
- Merlin, see if he's a single.
- Roger.
- Goose, do you see a trailer?
- Negative, Merlin. Looks like he's a single.
- Cougar, I'm gonna go head-to-head with him.
Take it easy, Maverick, I don't like this shit..
I'm gonna break high & right,
see if he's really alone.
- We got a 1000-knot closure, Mav.
He's coming right at us.
Okay, buddy. What's on your mind?
- Shit, there's two of them. MiG-28s!
What the hell are they doing?
What's their position?
- 250 miles out, sir.
- 250 miles? Get 'em out of here!
Cougar, you've got MiG one.
I'm going after MiG two.
I lost him in the sun! Shit, what's
he doing? You got him, Merlin?
He's coming around,
he's coming around on our tail!
Goddamn it. This bogey's all over me.
- What's their range now?
- 200 miles, sir.
If they break 150 miles, launch
the alert-five aircraft.
- Airspeed 300. Go get them, Mav!
- I'm going for missile lock.
Let's see if we can scare him this guy
out of here. Come on, lock up, baby.
I've got him locked. Bingo!
- We got him, Mav. He's
bugging out and going home.
Mustang, this is Maverick.
MiG two is headed home.
- Alright, what's their position?
- 180 miles and bearing 010, sir.
Cougar, he's got missile lock on us!
Get away from this guy!
- What the hell is this shit? He's engaging me.
Goddamn it. Mustang, this is Ghostrider
117, this bogey's all over me.
- He's got missile lock on me,
do I have permission to fire?
Do not fire until fired upon.
- Goose, there they are. Right below us.
The MiG's in perfect firing position.
And he's right on Cougar's tale.
- No way, Goose. He would have fired by
now. He's just trying to piss us off.
Maverick, get down here and
get this asshole off me!
Easy, Cougar. Bring him back,
hard right. Help me engage.
I'm on my way.
I can't shoot this son of a bitch.
Let's see if we can have a little fun with him.
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
Greetings.
Watch the birdie.
Geez, I crack myself up.
This is a great shot, Mav.
I should be a photographer.
Cougar, your tail is clear.
MiG one has bugged out.
Cougar, this is Maverick. We've had
enough fun for one day, don't you think?
I'm getting a lil' low on fuel,
so we're heading home.
We'll see you on deck.
Cougar, we're running low on gas,
we gotta get outta here.
Cougar?
We're on vapour, Cougar.
Let's do it.
Cougar, come on, Cougar!
- Let's take it back to the ship, man.
Come on, Cougar.
- Get him on deck as soon as possible,
he's gotta be low on fuel.
Cougar, we've got to land this thing.
We are way low on gas, you understand me?
Are you all right, man?
Maverick, you're 3/4 to
fall out, call the ball.
Roger. Maverick has the ball.
Goose, Cougar's in trouble.
Come on, Mav, we're getting low
on gas, let's land this sucker.
Cougar!
Goddamn it, Maverick!
What're you doing, Mav?
We've got no fuel for this.
We're going after Cougar.
You tell him to land that
plane. That's an order!
Ghostrider, you're instructed
to land. Land immediately.
Any of you boys seen
an aircraft carrier around here?
Man, we got a little problem up
here, that MiG really screwed him up.
I don't think he can make it back.
You're okay, Cougar. Just stay on my
wing. I'll take you all the way in.
Just stay with me.
Easy, Cougar.
Just a walk in the park, buddy.
You're a little low. You're a little low, Coug.
Come on, buddy, pull up.
Pull up, Cougar.
That's it. Almost there.
A little below glide path.
3/4 over now, call the ball.
Rogerball.
You're too low. You're too low,
Cougar! More power!
Come in.
- Cougar, you should be in a
sickbed, what's on your mind?
My wife and kid, sir.
I almost orphaned him today,
and I've never even seen him.
I don't know what happened
up there, but I was so scared.
Come on, we've seen this before.
No, sir.
I'm holding on too tight.
I've lost the edge. I'm sorry, sir.
I'm sorry.
Cougar?
Thanks, Maverick.
Maverick, Goose, come in here.
- What the hell's going on?
- I don't know.
- Shit.
Maverick, you just did
an incredibly brave thing.
What you should have done was land your plane.
You don't own that plane, the taxpayers do!
Son, your ego's writing cheques
your body can't cash.
You've been busted, you've lost your
qualifications as section leader three times.
Put in hack twice by me
with a history of high-speed passes...
...over five air control towers
and one admiral's daughter!
- Penny Benjamin?
- You, asshole, you're lucky to be here.
Thank you, sir.
And let's not bullshit, Maverick.
Your family name ain't the best in the Navy.
You need to be doing it better
and cleaner than the other guy,
now what is it with you?
Just want to serve my country, be the
best fighter pilot in the Navy, sir.
Don't screw around with me, Maverick.
You're a hell of an instinctive
pilot. Maybe too good.
I'd like to bust your butt, but I can't...
...I got another problem here.
I gotta send somebody from
this squadron to Miramar.
I gotta do something. I still can't believe it.
I gotta give you your dream shot.
I'm gonna send you up against the best.
You two characters are going to Top Gun.
For five weeks you're going to fly
against the best pilots in the world.
You were number two. Cougar was number one.
Cougar lost it, turned in his wings.
You guys are number one.
But you remember one thing:
You screw up just this much,
you'll be flying a cargo plane...
full of rubber dog shit out of Hong Kong.
Yes, sir!
That is all.
Tell me about the MiG some other time.
Gentlemen?
- Good luck, gentlemen.
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you.
During Korea, the Navy kill ratio was 12 to 1.
We shot down 12 of their
jets for every one of ours.
During Vietnam, that ratio fell to 3 to 1.
Our pilots become dependant upon missiles.
They lost some of their dog-fighting skills.
Now, Top Gun was created to teach ACM -
'Air Combat Manoeuvring'. Dog-fighting.
- This gives me a hard-on.
By the end of Vietnam, that
ratio was back to 12 to 1.
- Don't tease me.
- Blinds, please.
I'd like to take this
opportunity to introduce you...
to our commanding officer at Top Gun.
...very first man to win the
Top Gun trophy.
You will not find a finer fighter
pilot anywhere in the world.
Commander Mike Metcalf.
- Call sign 'Viper.'
- Gentlemen...
You're the top one percent
of all naval aviators.
The elite. The best of the best.
We'll make you better.
You fly at least two combat missions
a day, attend classes in between,
and evaluations of your performance.
On each combat sequence you're
gonna meet a different challenge.
Every encounter is gonna
be much more difficult.
We're gonna teach you to fly the F-14
right to the edge of the envelope,
faster than you've ever flown before.
And more dangerous.
Now, we don't make policy here, gentlemen.
Elected officials, civilians, do that.
We are the instruments of that policy,
and although we are not at war,
we must always act as though we are at war.
- What are you doing?
- Just wondering who's the best.
In case some of you wonder who the best is,
they're here on this plaque on the wall.
The best driver and his RIO
from each class has his name on it.
And they have the option to come back here
to be Top Gun instructors.
You think your name's
gonna be on that plaque?
Yes, sir.
That's pretty arrogant,
considering the company you're in.
Yes, sir.
I like that in a pilot.
Remember, when it's over out there,
we're all on the same team.
Gentlemen, this school is about combat.
There are no points for second place.
- Dismissed.
- Nice going.
The plaque for the alternates
is down in the ladies' room.
Oh, Jesus... You kill me.
You really do.
No, no, no. There's
two O's in Goose, boys.
- This is what I call a target-rich environment.
- You live your life between your legs, Mav.
Goose, even you could get laid
in a place like this.
I'd be happy to find a girl
who'd talk dirty to me.
Mav, you wanted to know who
the best is? That's him. Iceman.
That's the way he flies.
Ice-cold. No mistakes.
Just wears you down. You get bored, frustrated,
you do something stupid, and he's got you.
Hey, hey, Slider. I thought you wanted
to be a pilot, man. What happened?
Goose, you're suck a dickhead.
Whose butt did you kiss to get here?
- The list is long but distinguished.
- Yeah, so is my johnson.
- So you're flying with lceman, huh.
- It's Mr. Iceman for you.
Hey, Mother Goose, how's it going?
Doing good. Tom, this is Pete Mitchell.
Tom Kazansky.
- Congratulations on Top Gun.
- Thank you.
Sorry to hear about Cougar...
...you know, we were like brothers
in fight school. He was a good man.
- Still is a good man.
- Yeah, that's what I meant.
Thought so.
- So, you need any help? - With what?
- You figured it out yet?
- What's that?
- Who's the best pilot.
No, I think I can figure
that one out on my own.
I heard that about you.
You like to work alone.
Mav, you must've your soul
under a lucky star, huh?
I mean, first the MiG and then
you slide into Cougar's spot...
We didn't slide into Cougar's spot,
it was ours, ok.
Yeah well, some pilots wait a
whole career to see a MiG up close.
Guess you guys are lucky and famous, huh.
- No, you mean notorious. I'll see you later.
- You can count on it.
- They were abused children.
- We're gonna have a good time. - Always.
Okay, I guess it's my turn, isn't it?
All right, the bet is 20 dollars.
You have to have carnal knowledge,
of a lady this time, on the premises.
- On the premises.
- Come on, Mav... a bet's a bet.
I don't know, it just doesn't seem fair...
for you, I mean. But uh...
She's lost that loving feeling.
- She's los... No, she hasn't.
- Yes, she has. - She has not lost that lo...
- Goose, she's lost it, man. Come on.
- I hate it when she does that.
- Excuse me, miss.
- Hey, hey, hey. Don't worry. I'll take care of this.
You never close your eyes anymore
when I kiss your lips...
...there's no tenderness like before
in your fingertips...
You're trying hard not to show it,
baby...
...but baby, believe me, I know that...
You lost that loving feeling,
oh, that loving feeling.
now it's gone, gone, gone...
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
I love that song. I've never seen that approach.
How long have you two been doing this act?
- I don't know. Since uh...
- Puberty? - Right, puberty.
- I'm Charlotte Blackwood.
- I'm Maverick.
'Maverick'? Did your mother
not like you or something?
No, it's my call sign.
- You're a pilot!
- That's right. A naval aviator.
- Actually, we've only done this twice.
- Oh, how'd you do?
Crashed and burned on the
first one, it wasn't pretty.
And the second?
I don't know, I'll tell you tomorrow.
But it's looking good so far.
Well, 'Maverick'... my friend just arrived,
so it's been great talking to you.
- Perry! - Hi.
- Hi. Here you go.
I'll be with you in just a second, ok.
- Listen, can I ask you a personal question?
- That depends.
- Are you a good pilot?
- I can hold my own.
Great. Then I won't have to worry about
you making your living as a singer.
I'm gonna need a beer to put these
flames out. Great, Mav. Real slick.
- A long cruise, was it, sailor?
- Too long.
What you wanna do, just drop by
down on the tile and go for it?
I actually had this counter in mind.
- That would be very, very comfortable, yeah.
- It could be.
Actually, I came in here to save you
from making a big mistake with that older guy.
Really? So I could go on to a bigger one
with a young guy like yourself?
Maybe.
- I have to get up early in the morning.
- What are you doing?
Your friend was magnificent.
You'll also be trained and evaluated
by civilian specialists.
The civilians are hre because
they are our very best...
source of information on enemy aircraft.
One of the most qualified is our call sign
Charlie. She has a Ph.D. in astrophysics.
And she's also a civilian contract,
so you do not salute her.
But you better listen to
her, because the Pentagon...
listens to her about your proficiency.
All yours, Charlie.
Hello. We will be dealing with F-5s
and A-4s as our MiG simulators.
Now, then, as most of you
know, the F-5 doesn't have...
the thrust-to-weight ratio of the MiG-28.
And it doesn't bleed energy
below 300 knots like the MiG-28.
However, the MiG-28 does have
a problem with its inverted flight tanks.
It won't do a negative G push-over.
The latest intelligence tells us
the most it will do is 1 negative...
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
Is there something wrong?
- Yes, ma'am. The data on the MiG is inaccurate.
- How's that, Lieutenant?
- Well, I just happened to see a MiG-28...
- We, we. - Sorry, Goose.
We happened to see a MiG-28
do a 4 G negative dive.
Where did you see this?
- That's classified.
- It's what?
It's classified. I could tell you,
but then I'd have to kill you.
Lieutenant, I have
Top Secret clearance.
The Pentagon sees to it
that I know more than you.
- Well, ma'am, it doesn't seem
so in this case now, does it?
So, Lieutenant... where exactly were you?
Well, we started up on his six when he pulled
through the clouds. I went above him.
If you were directly above him,
how could you see him?
- Because I was inverted.
- Bullshit.
No, he was, man. It was a really great move.
He was inverted.
You were in a 4 G inverted dive
with a MiG-28?
- Yes, ma'am.
- At what range?
About two metres?
Well, it was actually about 1/2, I
think. I have a great Polaroid of it.
- It was a nice picture.
- Lieutenant?
- What were you doing there?
- Communicating. - Communicating.
Keeping up foreign relations.
- I was, you know, giving him the bird.
- You know, the finger.
- I know the finger, Goose.
I'm sorry, I hate it when
it does that. I'm sorry.
- Excuse me.
- So you're the one?
- Yes, ma'am.
- All right, we have a hop to take.
The hard-deck on this hop will be 10,000 feet.
There'll be no engagement below that.
Move it!
Lieutenant!
Okay, don't be late again.
You look great, honey.
Lieutenant, why didn't you tell me
you were the famous MiG lnsulter?
- Would it have made any difference?
- Not in the ladies' room, no.
And what would've?
I'm an instructor at this
school, I see 20 new hotshots...
every eight weeks. Now, I'm
sure you can figure that out.
Look, Lieutenant. I'd just really like
to hear about the MiG sometime.
You've got security clearance.
You read about it.
Maverick...
I'm curious.
Who was covering Cougar while you
were showboating with this MiG?
Cougar was doing just fine.
Gentlemen, this is your first hop.
The jets you're flying against are...
smaller and faster and more manoeuvreable.
Just like the enemy MiGs. Clock
is ticking, and as of now...
we are keeping score.
- I lost him, Goose.
- Show me what you've got, kid.
- I lost him.
- I'm looking. I'm looking.
I got him, I got him.
He's on our tail, coming hard.
I got him. Here we go.
Alright, talk to me, Goose.
He's still back there. He's closing
in on us. He's closing fast.
You can run, kid, but you can't hide.
All right, Jester,
I'll give you a run for your money here.
Watch the mountains!
I still got 'im, he's still back there.
Come on, Mav, do some of that pilot shit.
Yeah. I got him.
- Come on, bring it right.
- I've had about enough of this shit.
- When I hit the brakes, he'll fly right by.
- You're mine.
Jesus Christ!
- Let's see what you've got now, Jester.
- Ok, man. Let's turn and burn.
- He's going vertical. So am l.
- We're going ballistic, man. Go get him!
He's going for the hard-deck.
Let's get down there first and nail him, Mav.
No way, Jester. You're mine.
I've got you now!
- Jester's dead.
Get your butts above the hard-deck
and return to base.
Yes, sir!
Tower, this is Ghost Rider requesting a fly-by.
Negative, Ghost Rider. The pattern is full.
No, no, Mav. This is not a good idea.
Sorry, Goose... but it's time to buzz the tower.
Goddamn son of a bitch!
Great balls of fire.
- Jester's dead.
- You won? Bullshit.
- Didn't everybody?
- No, man. We got our butts kicked.
30 seconds. We went like this,
he went like that...
...I said to Hollywood, 'Where did he go?'
Hollywood said, 'Where did who go?'
- And he's laughing at us right on
the radio, he's laughing at us.
That was me laughing, dickhead. We won.
- All right!
- They won too, man.
- That's not what I heard.
- No, we did. We got Jester.
- Below the hard-deck doesn't count.
Hard-deck my ass, we nailed that son of a bitch.
- You guys really are cowboys.
- What's your problem, Kazansky?
You're everyone's problem.
That's because every time you go
up in the air, you're unsafe.
- I don't like you because you're dangerous.
- That's right, lceman.
I am dangerous.
Maverick. You and Goose get
your butts outta that...
flight gear and up to Viper's office, now!
Remember boys, no points
for second place.
- You're a lot brighter than you look.
- You shut up. - Don't worry, don't worry.
Two of your snot-nosed jockeys did a fly-by
at my tower at over 400 knots.
I want somebody's butt, I
want it now, I've had it.
Goddamn it, that's twice.
I want some butts!
- Well, that'll just about cover the fly-bys.
- Follow me.
Gentlemen. You had a hell of a first day.
The hard-deck for this hop was
10,000 feet. You knew it. You broke it.
You followed Commander Heatherly
below after he lost sight of you. Why?
Sir, I had Commander Heatherly in my sights.
He saw me move in for the kill...
...he then proceeded below the hard-deck.
We weren't below 10,000 for
more than a few seconds.
I had the shot.
There was no danger, so I took it.
You took it,
and broke a major rule of engagement.
Then you broke another one
with that circus stunt fly-by.
Lieutenant Mitchell, Top Gun
rules of engagement exist...
for your safety and for that of your team.
They're not flexible, nor am l.
Either obey them or you
are history. Is that clear?
Yes, sir!
Dismissed.
I really enjoyed that, Mav,
thanks a lot. Holy shit.
Maybe I could learn how to be a truck driver.
Mav, you got the number of that truck-driving
school that was on TV, Truck
Master, something like this?
I might need that.
State in those reports says it all.
He's a wild card.
Completely unpredictable.
- He got you, didn't he?
- Yeah.
Maverick. I flew with his old man.
Tell me one thing... if
you had to go into battle,
- would you want him with you?
- I don't know.
I just don't know.
- Still awake?
- Yeah.
- What's up?
- Can't sleep.
You kow, when I realised
we were going to Top Gun,
all I could think about was getting that trophy.
I've got to be straight with you, Mav.
Right now, I just hope we graduate.
I got a family to think about.
I can't afford to blow this.
I guess that fly-by
wasn't such a big hit, huh?
Look, man, I know it's tough for you.
The Academy rejected you because
you're Duke Mitchell's kid.
You have to live with that reputation.
But it's like everytime we go up there,
it's like you're flying against a ghost.
It makes me nervous.
You're the only family I've got.
I'm not gonna let you down. I promise.
Get out of here.
A rolling reversal
would work well in that situation.
If I reversed on a hard cross, I could
immediately go to guns on him.
But at that speed, it's too fast.
It's a little bit too aggressive.
Too aggressive?
Yeah, I guess when I see
something, I go right after it.
You didn't tell me who
you were the other night.
You didn't give me a chance,
did you? You deserved it.
I know... but uh... you were tempted...
to ask me out for dinner.
- No.
- No? - No.
I don't date students.
I can see it's dangerous for you.
But if the government trusts me...
...maybe you could.
It takes a lot more than just fancy flying.
Crash and burn, huh, Mav?
Slider...
You stink.
Let's go!
Come on, Mav. Just one more game.
That evens it up.
- I got some things to take care of.
- 'Take care of'? Just one more game.
- Please? For me? - I'm sorry.
- You're sorry... Come on... For me?
Damn it.
Lieutenant?
- What? No singing?
- Look, I'm...
No apologies.
If you don't mind, I'm... I'm
just gonna take a quick shower...
while you're finishing up here.
Yeah, I do mind. I'm hungry.
And then I thought about it.
I thought,
'You know, he's a smart guy.'
'Why don't you just tell him
why you've got him here?'
It's the MiG.
The MiG. You're the only pilot
who's been up against a MiG-28.
I'm trying for this big promotion.
If I get it, I won't be here much longer.
Seems to me you've got it all figured out.
Except you did forget the wine.
Sorry.
- You always get what you want?
- No, not always. Yeah, maybe.
Then relax about the MiG.
This music...
An old friend?
My folks loved it.
I haven't heard this in years.
My mother used to call from her room
and have me play this over and over again...
...I got so sick of it.
But not her. She'd sit up there alone,
just listening for hours.
Just listening.
She died shortly after him.
What happened to your father?
I guess I kinda figured with your security
clearance you'd know more about it than I do.
Well, I didn't get that far.
Well, that's a big mystery.
He disappeared in an F-4,
November 5th, 1965.
The stink of it was... he screwed up.
No way.
My old man was a great fighter pilot.
But who the hell knows?
It's all classified.
- Somebody must know.
- Yeah, somebody knows everything.
Is that why
you're always second best up there?
You are direct, aren't you.
I'm sorry I was late.
- I'm sorry for being direct.
- No apologies.
This is going to be complicated.
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna take a shower.
Thank you. I enjoyed being here.
It looks like you need another shower.
Right.
I'm gonna be honest with you.
Your MiG sighting
is really important to my work, but uh...
I don't normally invite students
to my house. You're uh...
But please understand,
I still have a job to do.
I'm glad we got that straight.
I told her how tough it is here. You know,
my ass dragging like an old tired dog.
I told her you didn't even
have a woman here.
She said, 'Oh, he probably
doesn't have 1, he's got 8.'
- Hi!
- Daddy.
So, Maverick! Goose tells me you're
in love with one of your instructors.
Is that right?
I didn't tell her that. I can't believe
you said that. That was a secret.
The bogey has good position right here.
Freeze frame. A moment of choice.
The F-14 is defensive.
He has a chance to bug out right here.
Better to retire and save your aircraft
than push a bad position.
Charlie, jump in here any time. Now, you stay
in that diamond another three seconds...
...the bogey's gonna blow you out in the sky.
You take a hard right, select zone five...
...you can extend an escape.
You made a bad choice.
- Charlie?
- Aircraft one performs a split S?
That's the last thing you should do.
The MiG's right on your tail.
Freeze there, please. The
MiG has you in his gunsight.
What were you thinking at this point?
You don't have time to think up there.
If you think, you're dead.
That's a big gamble with a
$30-million dollar plane,
Lieutenant.
Unfortunately, the gamble worked.
The MiG never got a clean shot.
Maverick makes an aggressive vertical
move here, comes over the top, and he
The encounter was a victory, but I think
we have show it as an example of what not to do.
Next.
Gutsiest move I ever saw, man.
Now then, this is a perfect example
of a textbook manoeuvre.
Lieutenant?
My review of your performance was
right on, in my professional opinion.
I can't hear you.
Jesus Christ! And you think I'm reckless!
When I fly, my crew and my plane come first.
Well, I'm gonna finish
my sentence, Lieutenant.
My review of your flight
performance was right on.
- Is that right?
- That is right.
But I held something back.
I see some real genius in your flying,
Maverick, but I can't say that in there.
I was afraid that everyone in that
tacts training would see right through me.
I just don't want anyone
to know that I've fallen for you.
- Hey, Maverick? You hear about lce?
- What's that?
- He won another one.
- Really? - Yeah.
- I fell the need...
...the need for speed.
Gentlemen, this is hop 19. Multiple aircraft,
multiple bogeys. Your training is half-over.
The competltion for the Top Gun
trophy remains tight. First place, lceman.
Second place, Maverick.
Just two points behind.
There they are. Three miles, left, 10 o'clock.
I don't think they see us yet.
Ok, I see them. Two A-4s.
Left 10 o'clock level. Continue left turn.
Good morning, gentlemen. The
temperature is 110 degrees...
Holy shit! It's Viper!
Viper's up here? Great. Oh, shit.
Great. He's probably saying,
'Holy shit, it's Maverick and Goose.'
Yeah, I'm sure he's saying that.
- I've got my eye on the northern bogey.
- Roger, I've got the southern guy.
Hollywood, you got the lead,
I'll cover you.
Break now, Jester.
Hollywood, we're losing Viper.
Let's just stay on Jester.
Roger, I'm on 'im.
Goose, find Viper. He's out there somewhere.
Stay with Hollywood, Mav,
we're covering his wing.
- Goose, there's Viper. Three o'clock low.
- Stay with Hollywood, Mav, we're his cover.
- Don't you leave me, Mav.
- Hollywood, you're looking good.
I'm going after Viper.
- Goddamn you, Maverick!
- Mav, don't leave him.
Goose, Hollywood's okay.
I want Viper.
Stand by.
Viper's coming down.
Holy shit. We're head-to-head.
I can't believe we're doing this.
Rock and roll! Here's our chance,
it's a big one, Goose.
Come on, goddamn it.
Come on, keep coming.
Okay, sidewinder missile selected.
Come on, baby.
Come on, Come around.
That's it.
- Jesus, this guy's good. Where's he going?
- Come on, come on. Keep coming.
Come on, baby.
Damn, this kid's good.
He's too close for missiles.
I'm switching to guns.
Come on, come on.
Stick with it...
- Hold it. Check our tail.
- Shit, there's Jester!
Bingo, Maverick's dead.
You're out of there, kid.
The Defence Department regrets
to inform you your sons...
are dead because they were stupid.
Great balls of fire.
Knock it off, gentlemen.
Let's go home. Viper has the lead.
- 30 seconds, Wolfman. I'm coming in.
- Shut up!
That was some of the best flying I've seen yet.
Right up to the part where you got killed.
You never, never leave your wingman.
Maverick... It's not your flying,
it's your attitude.
The enemy's dangerous, but
right now you're worse than...
the enemy. You're dangerous and foolish.
You may not like who's flying with you, they may
not like you... but whose side are you on?
At least Viper got lceman before
he got us. We've still got a shot at it.
That was stupid, I know better than that.
That will never happen again.
I know...
I know.
Maverick, would you go fetch him.
Doesn't he ever embarrass you?
- Goose? Hell no. Well, there was the time...
- Admiral's daughter. - What? !
He told me all about the time
you went ballistic with Penny Benjamin.
Did he? That's great...
He tells me about all of them. How my
lil' angel Goose goes home early for church...
- ...and you! You always go
home with the hot women.
Alright. Thank you, Carole.
I'm gonna go embarrass myself
with Goose for a while.
I'd love to be able to warn you off about
Maverick, but I just love him to death.
I've known Pete for a lot of years now and...
I'm telling you, one thing's for certain.
- There are hearts breaking wide open
all over the world tonight. - Why?
Because, unless you are a fool,
that boy is off the market.
He is 100% prime-time in love with you.
- Hey, Goose, you big stud. - That's me, honey.
- Take me to bed or lose me forever.
Show me the way home, honey.
Come on, brother, sing with the family.
Maverick, you big stud...
Take me to bed or lose me forever.
Okay, gentlemen, this is hop 31.
Two weeks to graduation.
The Top Gun trophy
is still up for grabs, so
Well, it's bottom of the
night, the score is tied.
It's time for the big one.
- You up for this one, Maverick?
- Just a walk in the park, Cazansky.
Contact. Multiple bogeys, 165. Two miles.
Looks like they're going away from us.
- Oh, I see 'em. Right, two o'clock. I'm in.
- I'm in.
That son of a bitch cut me off.
- Come on. Jesus Christ, lce, take the shot.
- Come on, Ice. Get the hell out of there.
I can't get the angle. I'm too close
for missiles. I'm switching to guns.
Ice, fire or clear!
Look at this! Jesus Christ,
I can take a shot right here.
I need another 20 seconds and I've got him.
I'm moving in. I've got the shot.
Come on, Mav, let's get in there. Come on, Mav!
Maverick's getting impatient.
Now, come on, take the shot.
10 more seconds, then I've got 'im.
Come on, get the hell out
of there. Let's do it, Mav.
Ice, Come off my right. I'm in.
- Five more seconds.
- Come off my right. I'm in.
I'm off. Shit.
We're in a jetwash. Shit!
This is not good. Shit,
we've got a flame-out, Mav.
Engine one is out... Engine two is out.
I'm losing control. I can't control it!
It's coupling up. This is not good!
Mayday, mayday. Mav's in trouble.
He's in a flat spin heading out to sea!
Altitude 8,000... 7,000...
We're at 6,000!
I can't reach the ejection handle!
- You're gonna have to punch us out.
- I can't reach the ejection handle!
- Eject...
- Watch the canopy!
Goose... Oh, no!
Oh, God.
Sir, let go of him.
You've got to let him go, sir.
- How are you doing?
- I'm all right.
- Goose is dead.
- I know.
You fly jets long enough,
something like this happens.
He was my RIO, my responsibility.
In my squadron in Vietnam,
we lost 8 of 18 aircraft. 10 men.
The first one dies, you die too.
But there will be others.
You can count on it.
You've got to let him go.
I think maybe it was my fault.
I don't know.
I don't know what the hell went wrong.
I'd like to help. I know it's difficult.
God, I want him back.
I'll be here if you need me, okay?
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick.
He would have flown anyway...
without you.
He'd've hated it,
but he would have done it.
We find that the F-14 flatspin
was induced by the...
disruption of air flow
into the starboard engine.
This disruption stalled the engine...
...which produced enough yaw rate
to induce a spin...
...which was unrecoverable.
There was no way Lieutenant
Mitchell could see or avoid...
the jetwash which produced the engine stall.
Therefore, the Board of lnquiry
finds Lieutenant Mitchell...
was not at fault in the
accident of 29th of July.
Lieutenant Mitchell's record will
be cleared of this incident.
Lieutenant Mitchell's restored to
flight status without further delay.
These proceedings are closed.
Get him up flying, soon.
Come on, kid, come on. Get in there. Engage.
Alright, you've got a bogey at two o'clock low,
Maverick. You got the angle, piece of cake now.
Take the shot, kid.
Take the shot.
You can engage any time, Maverick.
- Hey! Where the hell are you going?
- It's not good. It doesn't look good.
What do you mean, 'it doesn't look good'?
It doesn't get to look any better than that.
Hey, man. We coulda had him...
Hey! We coulda had him, man!
I'll fire when I'm goddamn
good and ready. You got that?
- He can't get back in the saddle,
he won't engage.
You know, he just might not make it back.
Keep sending him up.
Mitchell?
I'm sorry about Goose.
Everybody liked him.
I'm sorry.
Hi, it's Wolfman.
Maverick just quit.
Excuse me...
- May l?
- Please.
I'll have what he's having.
Hemlock, is it?
Ice water.
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
I heard you got that job in Washington.
Congratulations.
Thanks. But I wasn't gonna leave
without saying goodbye.
- It's good to see you.
- Thanks.
Where are you going?
You don't even have a ticket, do you?
Listen, I've seen all the evidence,
and it's not your responsibility.
It's not your fault.
You're one of the best pilots in the Navy.
What you do up there... It's dangerous.
- But you've got to go on.
- You don't understand.
When I first met you,
you were larger than life.
Look at you.
You're not gonna be happy
unless you're going Mach 2...
with your hair on fire, you know that.
No, that's over. It's just over.
To be the best of the best means
you make mistakes and then...
you go on, it's just like the rest of us.
You don't think I know that?
I'm here to help.
Look, thank you. But if I'd wanted help,
really... I would have asked for it.
So, I'm too late.
You've already left.
You didn't learn a damn thing,
did you?
Except to quit.
You've got that manoeuvre down
real well.
So long, Pete Mitchell.
Oh, hi, Maverick, come on in.
How are you doing?
- Good
- Yeah? Sure you're feeling okay?
- Fine.
- Great.
- Jamie, come on. Can I get you a
drink or anything else like that?
No, thank you.
- Ok, why don't you just uh...
- Thank you very much.
- Make yourself comfortable, 'cuz
Mike will be right down, ok?
Ok. Thank you.
I flew with your old man.
VF-51, the Oriskany.
You're a lot like he was.
Only better...
...and worse.
He was a natural heroic son of a bitch,
that man.
So he did do it right.
Yeah, he did it right.
Is that why you fly the way you do?
Trying to prove something?
Yeah, your old man did it right.
What I'm about to tell you is classified.
It could end my career.
We were in the worst dogfight ever
dreamed of.
There were... bogeys like fireflies
all over the sky.
His F-4 was hit, he was wounded,
but he could have made it back.
He stayed in it,
saved three planes before he bought it.
- How come I never heard that before?
The battle occurred over
the wrong line on some map.
- So you were there?
- I was there.
What's on your mind?
My options, sir.
Simple.
First, you've acquired enough points...
...to show up tomorrow and graduate
with your Top Gun class.
Or you could quit.
There'll be no disgrace. That spin was hell,
it would have shook me up.
- So you think I should quit?
- I didn't say that.
The simple fact is, you
feel responsible for Goose.
And you have a confidence problem.
I'm not gonna sit here and blow sunshine
up your ass, Lieutenant.
A good pilot is compelled
to always evaluate what's happened...
...so he can apply what he's learned.
Up there, we've got to push it.
That's our job.
It's your option, Lieutenant.
All yours.
Sorry to bother you on a Sunday, sir, but
thank you very much for your time.
No problem. Good luck.
- Gentlemen...
- Where's Maverick?
- I don't know where he is.
- You know what he's planning to do?
It's got to be hard on the guy,
though, you know.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Thanks, Mav. - Sir.
Gentlemen, I hate to break up the party
before it really gets out of hand...
Some of you have to depart immediately.
We have a crisis situation.
- Ice, Slider...
- Yo.
- Hollywood, Wolfman.
- Yes, sir.
- Maverick.
- Sir.
Maverick, you'll get your RIO
when you get to the ship. And if you don't...
...give me a call. I'll fly with you.
Gentlemen, this is bull's eye. The
communication ship SS Layton has...
become disabled and has wandered
into foreign territory.
A rescue operation is to begin
within the hour. Your mission is...
to give air support to that rescue.
There are MiGs in the area,
and tensions are high.
If you witness a hostile
act, you will return fire.
Those MIGs carry the Exocet anti-ship missile.
They can fire that missile
from a 100 miles away.
Gentlemen, this is the real thing.
This is what you've been trained for.
You are America's best. Make us proud.
Ice... Hollywood, sector two.
Maverick, you back them up with Merlin
on ready five.
- Yes, sir.
- Rise.
Excuse me, sir. This is not personal.
But with regard to Maverick...
is he the best pilot to..?
- I know what's on your mind,
Cazansky, just get on it.
You've got a pair of bogeys,
12 o'clock, 15 miles.
Voodoo One, Voodoo One. 090,
radar contact 15 miles.
They're doing 500 knots.
Roger, that's your bogey.
Dead ahead, 15 miles,
airspeed of 600 knots.
They're at 15,000 feet now,
dead ahead, 10 miles.
800 knots. Dead ahead now, eight miles.
- Wood, you got 'em? - Not yet, I can't see 'em.
- They must be close. I'm getting a hard-on.
Ok, Wood, I'm taking the
lead. Let's identify 'em.
Roger, Ice. You got the lead, I'm
on your leftside, a little low.
- Maverick's up and ready in alert five.
- Good, good.
My bogey's still locked up.
He's drifting to the left.
Still manoeuvring, course 090.
Ok, Wood. Let's bring it to the right,
and we'll get a better angle on 'im.
Ice, we've got a problem here.
Now I have four aircraft on radar,
not 1 pair, 2 pairs. Repeat, 4 bogeys.
Wood, we've got four bogeys.
- Wrong, make that five!
- There's five, sir.
- That's five?
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, shit!
- He's got a radar lock on us.
Get out of there, Hollywood!
Get outta there, goddammit.
I'm hit. We're coming apart.
I can't control it! We're going down.
Wood's been hit. Wood's been hit!
Voodoo One, Wood's been hit.
We've lost Hollywood!
- Repeat, we've lost Hollywood.
- Launch Maverick on Alert 5.
Get a bearing on Hollywood and Wolfman.
And launch the rescue helicopter immediately.
- Iceman, what's your position?
- 090 at 180 miles.
- They're coming in left.
- Three MiGs dead ahead, coming on the left side
I'm going after them.
I'm bringing it around to the left.
We have four on our tail.
That makes six of them!
- He's firing. Break right.
- This is Voodoo One. We are defensive.
Launch the alert fiighters!
Where are they? - 160 miles
and closing in fast, sir.
Ready Willard and Simkin.
Maverick supersonic.
I'll be there in 30 seconds.
Where are you at?
Show up here, I'm engaged with
5, repeat 5. I'm in deep shit.
- What about Willard and Simkin?
- We can't launch any aircraft yet, sir.
- How long?
- It'll take 10 minutes.
Bullshit! 10 minutes! This thing will
be over in two minutes! Get on it.
One MiG 12 o'clock high...
Watch your back!
- Break right!
- Shit, that was close.
Maverick, get your butt down here,
what the hell are you doing?
Come on, kid. Hang in there.
Jesus Christ!
Maverick, how about some help?
Engage, goddammit!
Maverick, we've got a
MiG on our tail.
Watch out!
Sir, we just flew right
through his jetwash!
Get control!
- Good recovery, Mav.
- Okay, let's get in there, we gotta help lce.
Let's get back in the game.
Come on! Get in there, Maverick!
No, it's no good.
- Goddamn it. Maverick's disengaging.
- I knew it. Shit! - Goddammit, Maverick!
- Get in there, Maverick, come on.
- Maverick! What the hell are you doing?
Maverick, get in there, for chrissake!
- Talk to me, Goose...
Ice is in trouble! Come
on, get in there, Maverick!
Ice won't last down there alone,
get in the fight, for God's sake...
Talk to me, Goose.
Maverick!
Maverick's re-engaging, sir.
- I can't get him off my tail.
- Ice, I've got your MiG dead ahead.
I got 'im dead ahead.
I got tone. Firing!
- Where are they?
- 155 miles.
Two MiGs dead ahead,
closer, 800 miles an hour.
I see them. I'm gonna take
them on the left side.
Oh, my God.
Ice is right below us,
he's got a MiG on his tail.
He's firing. Break left!
He overshot!
Coming in, lce. Coming in.
I got two MiGs, dead ahead.
I got 'im, Mav.
One MiG passing between us.
You've got a MiG on your left.
He's gonna fire!
Check the guy to the north!
Banking left.
- There he is. Get him, lce!
- Okay, you guys, I'm coming in.
Maverick! We got a MiG's coming
round on our tail, we gotta get outta here!
I can't leave lce.
He's still coming around,
he's gonna get behind us!
I'm not leaving my wingman.
I'm on his tail. I'm going for
it. I'm going for the shot...
right now. Roger, engaged!
- I've got radar lock.
- I'm taking the shot. Fire!
- Bingo! - Watch it, sucker, yeah!
- Ice, watch out. There's a MiG to your right.
He's firing!
- I'm hit. We're hit in the right engine.
- I'm shutting it down.
Coming in, lce.
Coming in.
Ice, that bogey's still behind
you. I'm manoeuvring for a shot.
Stay with him, Mav, Stay with him!
- Take the shot, nail him, nail him!
- Shit. Ice, I can't get a tone.
Shoot, Maverick!
I can't get him off my tail.
- Maverick, we're hit! We're hit again again!
- We're okay.
Ice, on the count of three,
break hard right.
Three... two... one...
break right!
Firing!
- Damn it, I missed.
- Don't let him go. Keep on him, Mav, keep on him.
I got him. I got him.
Here comes the shot.
Strike three.
- Maverick, move. There's a MiG on your tail.
We got a problem here, we've
only got one missile left.
- Approaching, 110 miles, sir.
- Goddammit.
I got him, I got him.
He's right on us, he's on our tail.
We haven't lost him,
he's still with us.
- What're you doing, you're slowing down!
- I'm bringing him in closer, Merlin.
You gonna do what? !
This is it, Maverick.
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by us.
Now!
I've got a good lock. Firing.
Strike four!
Mustang, this is Voodoo Three.
Remaining MiGs are bugging out.
- Mustang, this is Maverick, requesting fly-by.
- Negative, Ghostrider. The pattern is full.
Excuse me, is there something
I should know about?
Goddamn that guy.
You!
You are still dangerous.
But you can be my wingman anytime.
Bullshit. You can be mine.
- Maverick?
- Sir!
You're on the front pages
of all the English-speaking world.
Even though the other side
denies the incident, congratulations.
Thank you, sir.
They gave you your choice of
duty, son. Anything, anywhere.
Do you believe that shit?
Where do you think you want to go?
I thought of being an instructor, sir.
Top Gun? !
Yes, sir.
God help us!
Hello, Pete Mitchell.
I heard the best of the best
were gonna be back here, so...
This could be complicated.
You know,
on the first one, I crashed and burned.
And the second?
I don't know.
But uh...
...it's looking good so far.