www.addic7ed.com
The Ministry of State has been informed and
they have not observed any irregularities.
- What do you suspect that he wants to do?
- We don't know yet.
- I need a list of everybody in the building.
- That's more than 300.
Everybody has been checked
and we have their IDs.
Any other entrances used by journalists,
maintenance or cleaning staff?
We're sure that everything
is under control.
Even though we only got a very
flimsy description of the suspect.
Excellent, can I see that list?
Sarah, I have just spoken
to my head office.
Nobody at SIS knew about the Prime
Minister's car being in Jutland that day,
or tearing a page out of the notebook.
- No, but somebody must have done it.
- Can I get that list now?
Sarah, we have not torn that page out.
Believe it.
- Everything still points to Ussing.
- Except that the kidnapper says it's not.
- Here is the list.
- How about surveillance?
I would like to see
recordings for the past hour.
Sure, but like I told you we have
observed and checked everybody.
That is very reassuring but I still need
to see the surveillance tapes.
- Lund.
- Brix here, what is going on?
Goodbye. And good luck on the campaign.
Those 3 can become great ministers.
I've decided to carry out our austerity
measures and show our values.
Why did you fire the Minister of
Finance without informing me first?
Because you wouldn't have agreed.
How about Kristoffer?
Has he gone ahead to the meeting?
No, he is at a security briefing.
Even if I wouldn't have agreed,
you should still have consulted me.
I can't have a minister working
against me, right?
Get a hold of Kristoffer
so we can leave.
You are too vulnerable
to do it on your own.
The Zeuthen case is not closed yet,
you need to calm things down.
I do not want any unrest and that's why
we won't work with Rosa Lebech.
You will agree on that, I'm sure.
We are very strong right now.
There are three days to the election.
Ussing and the centre party
are down for the count.
We just need to get
Emilie Zeuthen back alive.
We also have irregularities.
I noticed that when I was looking
for the files requested by the police.
Our vehicle logbook from back then
is missing from the archives.
- What vehicle logbook?
- The vehicle's logbook...
I've just been told by security they
think the kidnapper is in the building.
- The kidnapper is here?
- You have to go back to the Ministry.
- Go now.
- But...
We have checked everybody.
As you can see we do a thorough job.
It could take all night.
The kidnapper could be deceiving you
and he's chasing Ussing.
No, it's not Ussing. He is at the
police station with his lawyer.
Brix says that he is
no longer a suspect.
- I am missing the last hour on this list.
- What you mean he's no longer a suspect?
Apparently he has an
alibi for that day and time.
He was at a hotel with a female member
of staff, and that has been verified.
This is unacceptable, they need to
get home, catch trains and planes.
You had visitors from a photocopier
service company today for a few hours,
and again 20 minutes ago, after normal
working hours, and he shows his ID.
We have background checks on all their
employees. They are here frequently.
His ID is also cleared for the Ministry
of State. I need to know where he is now.
Hey, how do you fast
forward on this thing?
The guy told us that he forgot to change
a toner in the administration wing.
- Is that the administration wing?
- No, the Ministry of State's red zone.
What are they saying?
Why is the kidnapper here?
They are not certain, it's
probably a false alarm.
It's really bad if we arrive
late for that election rally.
- You need to go to the panic room.
- Why?
- Just go.
- Where is Karen?
She was talking about some missing
files and trying to find a backup.
Excuse me.
Is there something I can help you with?
Hello, I'm talking to you.
The kidnapper has been
spotted, he is wearing a cap.
- I'm on it.
- You two, come with me.
You saw a guy fiddling
with the equipment.
I only saw from the back.
When you catch him...
Stop, everybody out of here except
the guys from the forensic team.
No, no, no, no!
Listen here. The kidnapper
stole a hard drive.
- Apparently.
- What's on that hard drive?
We don't know that yet.
Firstly, I would like to know
why the kidnapper was here.
He wants to find out who was driving
the minister's car on a specific day
during the election campaign
two and a half years ago.
Excuse me, Sarah Lund
from the crime division,
and Matias Borch from SIS.
The minister's car was not used
during the election campaign.
I believe I explained
that to you already.
The car was spotted by a boy who wrote down
the registration number in his notebook.
It was on 20 April
on the same day as..
It doesn't matter what date it
was, it can't have been that car.
Why should the kidnapper be interested
in my ministerial car? I don't get it.
It's Ussing who is involved, it has
nothing to do with the Prime Minister.
Ussing has been cleared of suspicion.
Our investigation leads us to believe
that Emilie was kidnapped because the
old case was closed down unsolved,
and that is why we need
to follow every lead.
So you think that we have
something to do with it?
- Not necessarily.
- The facts are like this.
We know that the car was over there.
We need to know who drove it.
Surely you understand it is in your
own best interest to answer questions.
The hard drive that the kidnapper took
apparently contains all the information
regarding the minister's car,
who drove it, where it was, GPS...
Am I to understand that I or some of my
staff are under investigation for murder?
That is not what we are saying.
- I suggest we just calm down and..
- The conversation ends here.
- We don't know what you're talking about.
- One thing is for sure.
The Prime Minister was
not in that car that day.
Your car was in that notebook and that
specific page was torn out.
I know there is something
that you're not telling us.
- You know who you are talking to?
- I am sorry about the phrasing...
That car, somebody put pressure on that
Deputy Prosecutor to close down the case.
If you know anything this
is the time to tell us.
We will get back to you.
Great work, just excellent
We have searched the whole
harbour and all the containers.
We have not found anything
suggesting where Emilie might be.
What about the iPad?
Did you send it to the police?
Yes, it is being tested but,
we haven't heard anyhing yet.
They found the place in the harbour
where the kidnapper was hiding.
They say she was kept there briefly,
before he left the boat in the harbour.
Any signs to suggest
that she is still alive?
- They didn't say.
- Where did he take her? Where?
The police believe that she was
taken onto a ship going abroad,
perhaps in a container.
23 ships passed through
during that period.
The problem is
that was three days ago.
The containers have
gone on different ships
and therefore the numbers of ships that
Emilie can be on has doubled.
Plus harbours...
We will check all the
ships and all the harbours.
- Many of the ships are on the open sea.
- Call them back.
Contact the shipping operators
and tell them we will pay.
It's not enough. Even if we pay
we cannot buy assurance.
She could have been brought ashore.
What about the people
calling in for the reward?
- Anything we can use?
- No, nothing, I'm sorry. Not yet.
Contact those ships.
And keep on taking those calls.
Any news?
I'm going to call and
say good night to Carl.
Hear his voice.
It's not your fault.
Did you know about the iPad?
And that she was in the attic
talking to the kidnapper?
She was angry at us, both of us.
You've told me we will find her,
that's why I know we will find her.
- Okay?
- Okay.
...the calls for them to me.
Lots of people have not managed
to get through to the police.
They have started
calling direct to Zeeland.
100 million reward
is going to make them act insane.
I can see what's happening.
Robert.
It's always the same.
He has been unfair to you
and not paid attention to the children.
The cat, the iPad. I still don't know
if it's all Zeeland's fault,
because they are hiding something.
Robert and Zeeland are
not involved in anything.
That is also what the police are saying.
Hey.
You know I'll do anything for you.
- Maja.
- I want to go now to Carl.
Maritime maps and container numbers
suggest that she has been put on a ship
but we don't know any more.
- Send a copy of the info to Zeuthen.
- Okay.
And she has not left any
clues to where she was going?
If she was here, it was a short stay.
Just changing clothes and moving on.
Anything on the kidnapper?
We have plenty of fingerprints but
nothing that matches our database.
Another homeless knows nothing.
Only that he kept to himself.
What about the connection
to Louise Hjelby's mother?
Anything suggesting who he might be?
He kept a photo of her. So she must
have meant something to him
when she was young
before she got cancer.
Okay, the kidnapper took a hard drive.
As he no longer has his hideaway,
he's going to try and find a computer
so he can check its contents.
Okay I will try to search libraries
and Internet cafes. I will call back.
Thanks.
Somebody must know something.
What about the surveillance?
The photocopier service company?
The kidnapper broke into the company
car and stole a uniform and ID card
while the repair guy was away.
The only thing you see on the tape
is that he walks with a limp,
so it's amazing that he managed
to get away from you.
- Any update?
- Nothing new.
The Ministry of State must
tell us what they know.
If they know anything.
Right now it's just accusations
based on scribbling in a boy's notebook.
I would really like to have known
about these scribbles 12 hours ago,
when we last sat here and you told
us that SIS knew nothing about it.
- We had no knowledge about it.
- Obviously not.
But you must know whether the
minister's car was in Jutland that day.
It doesn't help Emilie that you are less
than forthcoming with information.
It was during the election.
We had better things to do,
than to watch a car in a garage.
Also the Ministry of
State says it is not true
Dyring, but the fact that that page
was torn out suggest that..
Speculations. It could have been
the Deputy Chief Prosecutor.
Or an accident, maybe the boy did it.
No matter what, we have to show the
kidnapper that we are working on it.
We need to focus our investigation
on finding the kidnapper.
For fuck's sake, that is what we are doing!
- Borch, come here
- Let me explain.
Come here.
You have to bring it up with management.
We need to search the Ministry of State.
The small boy collects
licence plate numbers
I don't want to persuade management.
Then you have to figure out something.
We risk that the kidnapper
will never call again
if we don't do something.
I made a request that these
container numbers be given to Zeuthen.
I'll check up with them.
I have just received a complaint
from the Ministry of State.
- What's going on?
- We have a good explanation.
First the opposition party and now this.
It stops now
- Ruth.
- You will apologise to them.
Ruth.
We need to talk.
I don't want these accusations hanging.
I want everything regarding that car
- investigated, right now.
- I'm on it.
The problem is that the hard
drive and information are gone
and so is the vehicle logbook.
I'm trying to contact
the chauffeur of the car.
Okay?
Security has been intensified.
SIS have requested that we
cancel our arrangement for tonight,
so I have moved a
fundraiser till tomorrow.
- What is the chauffeur saying?
- They will call and we will find out.
No, call them in for a meeting now.
If Emilie's life depends
on it, then I have to ask myself.
You don't need to talk to anybody else.
What?
It was me who removed the
logbook this afternoon.
I didn't want it ending
up with the police.
Not before I had a chance to talk to you
because the car was not
in the garage back then.
Who drove it?
What are you talking about?
It was your son.
It was Benjamin who drove the car.
It was during the
last election campaign.
There were demonstrations against the
Banks' involvement in the financial crisis.
It was violent, and Benjamin was
recognised as one of the troublemakers.
He was only 17 so they called me
because they couldn't get hold of you.
I didn't have any option so...
I persuaded one of the chauffeurs
to pick him up in the Minister's car
and drive him to Jutland
where we were at the time.
I arrived at the hotel. He somehow
managed to get hold of the car keys
and got away in the
Prime Minister's car.
It is in the vehicle logbook
20th of April
Passenger Benjamin Kamper
- Why didn't you say anything?
- I wanted to but
I did not want you to get involved
with me misusing the minister's car.
Benjamin was embarrassed and
made me promise not to tell.
He was not one to provoke.
He was angry and drunk.
- How long was he gone, in the car?
- I found him late in the evening.
He called me from some bus terminal.
He was sorry and out of petrol.
Why didn't you say something?
What about the girl? Did he meet her?
No, of course not. He just drove
around till he had calmed down,
and then I sent him back to Copenhagen.
You need to make a statement about
everything that happened that day.
What time he came over, what
he did, and when he was found
Any other files that you lied about?
- Answer.
- No.
Then you have to go to the police and tell
them everything. Everything.
If this comes out, then it will look
like it's us that put pressure
- on the Deputy Chief Prosecutor.
- I don't give a fuck.
The police need this
information right now.
They better see this.
I can confirm that we are currently
investigating events at the Ministry of State
and will continue doing that
until we have satisfactory answers.
- Anybody specific?
- I can't comment on that.
I want to make it understood
that we are doing everything we can
to get Emilie Zeuthen back alive.
I will man the phones and
prepare a press release.
Right.
We need to inform Benjamin's
mother, your ex-wife.
- I'll take that.
- Okay
Karen, can you make sure that
Kristoffer doesn't get anywhere
near me, I don't want to see him.
Of course
Chairman Gidlsford has heard about the
accusations against the Ministry of State
and he's asking for an orientation
but I'll take care of that.
Somebody from the police is here.
It's that woman
- She says it is important.
- Okay.
Unless you can tell me where Emilie is,
we have nothing to talk about.
I just want to know whether you had
time to look at those container numbers
that I sent you.
It was a list of all the
containers in the harbour
three days ago. We have
searched most of them
and we are working on the rest.
Please inform us.
Are any of the containers
of greater interest?
No.
What about the iPad?
Any clues about the kidnapper?
The forensic investigation is still
ongoing. It explains how..
It's Maya. She wants to talk to you,
she's down in the car park.
But I need some information
about some former employees.
- It will only take a minute.
- We are all very busy.
We still believe that the old case
will lead us to Emilie.
The kidnapper is the biological
father of the girl that got killed
and he could have been
employed by Zeeland.
We have already been very helpful,
lists of employees with photos...
The kidnapper is not somebody
who worked on an oil rig.
The guy we are looking
for has detailed knowledge
of computers, has a technical background
and knows everything about the harbour.
It must be in Roberts
Zeuthen's best interest..
Do not tell me what
is in his best interest
- I think I'm better qualified for that.
- Then help me.
We are looking for an
engineer or the equivalent
and something must have happened regarding
his employment when his daughter died.
I..
There were a lot of staff made redundant
21/2 years ago and reassignments.
- Why?
- The financial collapse.
Some of our competitors closed down and
Zeeland took on some of their employees.
But we couldn't take them all.
I will need those records,
maybe we can find something.
- I will make sure you get the information
- Thank you.
I want to make it clear
it would be unbearable for Robert
Zeuthen if Emilie dies
because the police failed
to solve some old case
and it would have ramifications
that go beyond our comprehension.
Hi.
Can we stay at your place?
In the guest room?
- Hi, dad.
- Hi, my lovely boy
- Just till we find something else.
- Of course.
- Come, let's go home.
- Thank you.
I'll get somebody to pick up your car.
We have received a written
statement from the Ministry of State.
They now admit that the minister's
car was indeed in Jutland on that day,
but said that it was the Prime
Minister's son that took the car.
The vehicle logbook confirms it.
His son, what was he doing there?
The son got angry at his dad
and drove around in the car,
and somehow the logbook just
dropped off the shelf this afternoon.
And how can we believe it is time?
It was witnessed by the brother of
the Prime Minister, Kristoffer Kamper.
He will make a statement to us tomorrow.
♪I have moved in with a friend.
Thank you so much for the help, love Eva. ♪
We need to bring the
son in for questioning.
Lund, don't ever read any newspapers
or watch the news? The son is dead.
Officially it was an accident
but as far as I know,
it wasn't, it was suicide.
Only a few weeks after that
Kamper won the election back then,
but of course the head of DSIS doesn't
believe it could have been the son.
Let's pressure them and I will bring
the brother in for questioning.
Yes.
I waited out here for
half an hour, can we talk?
- Sure, come in.
- Thank you.
Did you hear about the
Prime Minister's son?
They are hiding something. It's shit.
That's not the whole story.
- What do you want?
- I have something you need to see.
The file on the Prime Minister's son.
I wanted to make sure that you got it.
- Couldn't it wait till tomorrow?
- Well...
I will not be there tomorrow.
I'm off the case
and I have to stay away,
and I am sorry I behaved like an idiot.
I should have told you
everything from the beginning,
but I really don't know what
happened to that page in the notebook.
I hope you believe me.
The kidnapping seems connected to an old
murder case that had been covered up.
How did Zeeland respond to that?
I have been told that the Prime Minister's
car is now part of the investigation.
- Well, hello.
- Hi.
- What is your name?
- Astrid.
Hi Astrid, my name is Christian.
Shall we take some photos?
I have tried to get hold of Zeuthen's
personal assistant.
I want to explain to him what happened
but he hasn't returned my calls.
Kristoffer's having a meeting
with the police right now.
If anybody finds out about it,
then we will call it a briefing.
Thanks, let's just get through this.
How much time?
First up is a tour with
Ussing and the press
and then you will talk with
the children downstairs.
- We need to talk about something.
- I know the school needs an upgrade.
Benjamin was found very late. There's
half a day that nobody can account for.
He wanted to be alone, Kristoffer
already said it was nothing.
He committed suicide
less than two weeks later.
The police will be able to
put two and two together.
Those events are not connected.
He was depressed.
- Hello and welcome.
- Thank you.
The children are just
about to get ready.
I hope you don't mind
waiting just a little bit?
No, that's fine.
- It is here.
- Yes.
Nice drawings by the children.
The walls look better
with a bit of colour.
Definitely.
I must admit I was quite surprised to find
out that your car was suddenly of interest.
Don't worry, is not something that I'm
going to use for the election campaign.
Thank you.
But do not worry about me.
That's funny, that's
what my advisers told me.
They thought it would only be
fair after what you did to me
with the police and I'm
a trustworthy witness.
That's up to you and your conscience.
On the other hand, the facts are that
the old case was being covered up
- and somebody had a really good motive.
- Let me tell you something.
That you think your brother was a
bit slow in getting the truth out.
You must also be wondering whether his
good contacts in the ministries
might extend to the Deputy
Chief Prosecutor as well.
No, I will not listen to you about
these kind of accusations.
We will see, it will be bad for
your relationship with Zeeland
and the Emilie Zeuthen case.
Aren't we starting soon?
We need to cut this short.
The police need to see you.
What?
I think they suspect that Benjamin
might be behind the killing.
Benjamin Kamper, high school student,
mentally unstable,
bipolar aka manic-depressive disorder,
politically active on the far left wing,
closely associated with
Communist newspapers and so on.
But after a trip to Jutland
does his condition suddenly deteriorate
to the level that he leaves home
and jumps out in front of a
freight train a few days later?
Hi, you have called Eva, leave
a message and have a nice day.
Benjamin Kamper on the
other hand, told us that
there is no reason to believe that
he was near Louise Hjelby back then.
Did you find out anything about
former employees of Zeeland?
They are going to give us more information
later, but we can't wait for that.
Lund.
The kidnapper did not contact you
and I'm sure you can figure out
that there is no future for us here.
If we start digging up
old wounds without cause
into the Prime Minister's personal tragedy
in the middle of an election campaign
It's got to be him. This would also
explain why you would make
a Chief Deputy Prosecutor
cover up the case.
True. Okay, I'll see what I can do
but, it will be
the Prime Minister's decision
whether he wants to meet up with us.
Okay.
The file on Benjamin
Kamper was very useful.
Still, I suggest you don't trust Borch
in the future. Is that clear?
The kidnapper has not shown up at any
of the Internet cafes or libraries.
- What is going on with Borch?
- He has been taken off the case.
Did you find out anything about
Louise's mother, Monica Hjelby?
She lived in Skudehavnen. There' a woman
named Birt I'm trying to get hold of.
But, about Borch.
Borch has been taken off
the case. That's all I know.
Did you have something to do with it?
Is it because you are is still
angry about what happened in Jutland?
- Or is it something else I don't know..
- Listen up, I have no idea.
Then why is his wife sitting
outside waiting to talk to you?
Hi, Sarah Lund.
I'm actually on my way out
so maybe you can call...
He came back late last night.
He didn't go to bed.
I found him in the living room.
At first I thought it was the
case that he was working on,
but that's not the case, is it?
He says that...
that he loves somebody else.
It's you I presume?
Were you together
when you were in Jutland?
Are you in love with him?
It might be that you
have been lovers before
and still have feelings
for each other or something.
But we have two girls together
and he's their father.
Stay away from him.
Lund, let's go. We got the go-ahead
from the Ministry of State.
Okay.
You have our full support
but we do have a business to run.
Can we talk about this some other time?
You are unable to take care of
the daily running of the business.
For good reason, but it does create an
uncertainty throughout the company.
We need to show strong leadership.
That is the reason why we
would like you to step down
and let the board appoint a new CEO.
- I have always had your full support.
- You still have that.
Then you must know that I cannot
accept that Zeeland moves abroad.
There are reasons to reconsider.
Have you seen today's newspapers?
We'll stick to the agreement we made.
Zeeland stays in Denmark.
The Ministry of State is
under police investigation.
My duties can be covered by
the rest of the executives.
And if they can't, then
we hired the wrong people.
Make sure it works.
I will make sure that
Gidlsford understands
that for now he needs to
take these things up with me.
- I will arrange a meeting with him.
- Thank you.
- Besides that, anything else?
- With regards to Emilie,
they think they can narrow the search
down to 15 ships and six terminals.
- What is missing?
- Even with the payment,
it is still difficult to get access
to some ships and terminals.
Rotterdam, Hamburg,
Stavanger, and St Petersburg.
The police say they can't intervene.
I will personally go and talk
to the shipping operators.
Please prepare my jet.
I'll take care of Hamburg and Rotterdam,
you take Stavanger and St Petersburg.
Yes, understood.
My brother kept that Benjamin was
driven to Jutland in the minister's car,
until yesterday, hidden from me.
He wanted to protect me and my family.
It was an error and that is regrettable,
but I have nothing else to add.
Your son took off in the car at the
same time as a local girl disappeared,
she was held captive, raped, and killed
at an abandoned shipbuilders.
The Prime Minister has been made aware
of the old murder case, thank you.
I understand that your
son was manic-depressive.
How did he feel the following
days after that episode in Jutland?
- Anything other than ordinary?
- No, not really.
- Were you in contact with him?
- Yes.
- You were talking?
- Yes, of course we were talking.
There were times, he became reclusive,
but neither me or my former wife
noticed anything out of the ordinary.
So you just saw it
as a depressive phase?
It was a depressive phase.
He had stopped taking his medication
and we only noticed too late
Okay, anything else?
We had a look at what Benjamin was doing
the weeks after he got back from Jutland.
He skips classes significantly
more frequently than before.
He's also absent from his part-time job
and he's buying a lot of wine and hard
alcohol, according to his classmates.
How did you get this information?
Lots of symptoms indicating
that things were not okay
Still you didn't think it was
anything out of the ordinary?
We just assumed that it was his disease.
We are not trained physicians-
I was also absent a lot back then.
Had his condition made
him act like this before?
I believe the Prime Minister has
answered all relevant questions.
But Benjamin himself
expressed that there was something that
had happened that he couldn't go on living.
He showed up on the psychiatric ward
the night before he disappeared
at Fredericksburg hospital.
He expressed distress and
wanted to be checked in by them.
He was informed by the staff
that he was under the legal age
and therefore needed
his parents' approval.
He then left the ward, but before that
he repeatedly told the psychiatrist,
and I quote:
'he had done something that his father
would never be able to forgive him for'.
He was then advised by the psychiatrist
to go home and talk to his father.
Did he do that?
On this specific evening,
I came home very late.
I thought everybody was asleep,
but Benjamin
was awake and..
he came downstairs.
Hmm
He asked if we could sit
in the kitchen and talk.
We hadn't done that for very long time,
so I was very happy.
He had difficulties expressing
what he wanted to say
and I was very tired.
In the end he said that it didn't matter
and then he went upstairs,
to his room.
The next morning when I woke up,
I made breakfast.
Then I went to his room
to try and wake him up.
The bed was empty, he was gone.
It might not be significant,
he was often like that.
Reclusive, restless..
If your son committed the murder
it is most likely that the
evidence will still be in the car
and our forensic team is capable of
finding evidence that is several years old
even if somebody tried to remove it.
He did not do it. It is completely
ridiculous to sit here and...
Stop it! What did Benjamin
say to you that night?
Anything that resembled a confession?
Or about the girl?
It doesn't matter what Benjamin Kamper
said because he is innocent.
The stolen hard drive was found
at an Internet cafe 15 minutes ago.
The kidnapper read the contents of the
hard drive and it confirms that
the minister's car was never near
the crime scene nor the harbour.
And what evidence do
you have to support that?
You can see where the car
had been on the map here.
The car had a GPS tracker installed
and all the data was on the hard drive.
I'm deeply sorry that you
had to go through this.
I expect an official statement from the
police clearing the Prime Minister ASAP,
and I trust you won't
waste any more time.
What happened? Did you put pressure
on him? What did they say?
The minister's car was never near
the crime scene. The GPS proves it
GPS, what GPS?
We don't know the whereabouts of
the kidnapper of Emile Zeuthen.
We have nothing.
Stop it, your are not going to
give up just because of a GPS.
- Did you ask him about...
- Yes, I asked him.
And if you have any doubt, then you can
go up there and ask him yourself.
What about the kidnapper?
Do you have the notebook?
We have checked all 13 cars from
that day, there is nothing.
Can I have the notebook?
One of the owners of the
thirteen cars, an old woman,
kept insisting that her car was never
anywhere near Jutland on that day.
So we have to go back and verify
everything from the beginning.
Your wife came to see me today.
I don't want that...
don't destroy anything.
Hello.
I am outside the Internet café
where we found the hard drive.
The kidnapper has had
about 30 minutes to get away
and he has likely found out that the
information on the drive is irrelevant.
So he's probably not in a very good mood.
I'll see if I can find
some witnesses.
Birte, the woman who knew Monica Hjelby
is at Skudehavnen right now.
I will go out there but
I can't do everything on my own.
Okay, great.
I need to go now.
Sarah, the kidnapper's not going
to give up. Neither should you.
I have to go now.
Leading up to when he left, you
saw somebody by the computers?
Sure, lots of people are by the
computers I don't know who they are.
But the hard drive...
What about that girl?
Do you think she saw something?
The kidnapper was last seen here.
A witness saw him driving
around in a blue estate car.
Check if any have been reported
stolen within the past 24 hours.
He is severely injured
he will seek treatment.
Hospitals, emergency rooms, we
need to check everything again.
The only thing that you will do is to
sit down and wait for briefing from SIS.
You gave the go-ahead
for me to go on TV.
Fom this point on, it will
be SIS that is in charge.
You will do as they ask, and make sure
you get Sarah Lund under control.
Get her to make the coffee.
If I'm going to clean up your mess.
Get back to work. What are you looking at?
We'll continue until we get it in writing.
The plane is ready.
You'll be in Rotterdam before 6 o'clock.
I have notified the shipping
operator of your arrival.
I am going out to see Gidlsford
and then I'll go back home to pack.
Thank you, it's very nice of you.
Annett and the girls are
staying at the house in France,
so I might as well do something useful.
I will keep you updated.
Thank you.
Mr. Zeuthen, can I
disturb you for second?
A witness has shown up at reception.
- Who?
- A sailor from Sweden.
I think he might have seen something.
He is in a room here.
What is it that you have seen?
I was out sailing four days ago
It was about 3 a. m.
and it was freezing.
Suddenly I heard a
speedboat going very fast
and it didn't have any lanterns
and that was a bit strange.
I passed by coastal
vessel shortly after.
I saw the speedboat next to the vessel,
and then I saw a man together with
a small child boarding the ship.
Why did you contact
us and not the police?
I tried but I couldn't get through
So you claim that you saw my
daughter in the middle of the ocean
in a sail boat in very strong wind
in complete darkness at 3 o'clock?
Yes.
Escort this man out.
150 cm high, 40 kg and long blonde hair.
Black wellingtons, blue
raincoat, and no life preserver.
I could see this because
I was only 30 to 40 m away.
A work light was on, so I
could see everything clearly.
- I don't know if I should tell you...
- What?
It looked like she was waving.
What was the name of the vessel?
I would like to sort out
some formalities first.
If what you're saying is true, you will
get the reward without any delays
I would like to get some
kind of assurance of that.
Written agreement and 2% upfront.
- We do not have cash here.
- I can wait.
I will get the process
going, tell me more.
I prefer to wait.
- Can I get you something?
- A cup of tea with milk.
- Okay.
- Thank you
- Are you Birte?
- Who's asking?
Sarah Lund.
You knew Monica Hjelby,
the mother of Louise.
She was my tenant for 10 years up there.
Monica showed up one day.
She was pregnant,
with her nose in the air.
She said she only needed a place
to stay for three months but
But she just kept on staying?
What about Louise's
dad, did you meet him?
No, in the beginning she talked about
a guy who was going to come and get her,
but I have heard that story before.
Do know if she had any
contact with the father?
No.
Did a guy ever come here?
After she died, a guy came.
- Who was it?
- He said that he was an old friend.
- What did he want?
- Information, he asked after Monica.
And?
I told him that he could find
her in a grave at the cemetery.
Did he ask about anything else?
No, I just told him that
Louise was in an orphanage.
Can you describe how he
looked, anything special?
No, I don't remember.
Regular guy,
but it didn't sound like he
knew that Monica had a daughter.
I never saw him again.
Hello, this is Eva Laursen's midwife.
I don't know if you remember meeting me.
Yes, but the timing is not so good
I just want to know if you could
help us get hold of your son Mark?
- Why?
- Eva is at the hospital with cramps.
It's likely that she
will deliver prematurely.
Is it serious?
We can't tell yet, but we would
really like to get hold of Mark.
- Hello?
- I will try to get hold of him.
Thank you, goodbye.
I'm sorry but I have to leave now.
But I'm sending out a colleague
to hear more about that orphanage.
I don't know much, I only know
that it was a public orphanage.
Monica got that "family fund"
- but maybe that's not important.
- What "family fund"?
It was some time before she died
Well, she knew she was near the end.
She wanted to do something for Louise.
I helped write applications,
and when she got a positive reply from
Zeeland's family fund
she was so happy.
- What fund? Zeeland?
- Yes.
For helping people like Monica
who are alone with a child.
Might be that the family
Zeuthen are loaded with money
but you still feel a
little sad for them.
They help so many children and then they
have to go through this with their own.
No matter what the prime minister claims
he owes the voters a proper account
of the government's involvement in the
tragic kidnapping case of Emilie Zeuthen.
Look, the government is not responsible
for the financial crisis or the kidnapping.
- To suggest that is...
- There is a cover-up.
We can only ask ourselves if the Prime
Minister is interested in the truth.
Could you please switch that off?
Thank you.
- I have just heard from Zeeland.
- And?
It sounds like they still
have confidence in us
and they are still backing the
government's austerity measures.
Karen, back then, in Jutland
did you have any
contact with Kristoffer?
No. He did not tell me anything, why?
The police are right.
Benjamin did change
I do not know why you couldn't see it.
In hindsight it's very clear.
Hindsight is always 20/20.
Don't get yourself worked up.
It's only guesswork from the police.
Christopher has accounted
for what happened.
You loved your son,
and I'm sure he knew that.
We saw the debate on TV.
Great work with Ussing.
What really happened?
I know something happened
with Benjamin over there.
- I just want to know what?
- Well...
Stop it.
For fuck's sake, what happened?
He called me from the bus terminal.
I went over there to talk to
him, but he was out of his mind.
- Did he do something to the girl, or..
- Of course he didn't.
But something had happened
that triggered an episode.
He said he had been looking for you,
to make a show in front of the press.
- He said he saw something important.
- What was it?
It was some typical left-wing nonsense,
that we are kissing big business arses.
What happened?
Why didn't you let me deal with it?
I thought he should leave you alone.
He would only fuck things up.
I know he was in difficulties but you
have fought so hard for this election.
- And I wouldn't let him ruin that.
- What did you do?
He was a risk being near the press.
I put him on a bus to Copenhagen
to get his act together.
- Get his act together?
- He threatened to go to the press.
They would have eaten it up.
It was for his own sake, he was crazy.
What did he see?
- Answer.
- He had seen Karen.
She was in Zeeland's pockets and held
meetings with them behind your back.
What meetings?
Just some, guy but he
didn't even know who.
- The money and the contract are coming.
- Thank you.
Reinhart told me to tell you that the
meeting with the chairman went well.
Thank you.
- Where is he, I want to speak to him.
- He won't talk until he gets the money.
But we checked out his ID
and everything seems fine.
The police are here.
I've told them about the witness so they can
start the questioning as soon as possible.
I didn't call the police
We need to verify the information
with the police before we...
He described her blue raincoat
and that's enough for me.
He could not know anything
about that blue raincoat, it was
found at the kidnapper's hide out.
She had likely changed
into something else.
- Where is he?
- He asked direction to the parking.
- He wanted something from his car.
- Seal the building.
Robert, what is happening?
Where is he?
He accessed one of our computers.
Juncker here.
We need backup at Zeeleand.
The kidnapper might
still be in the building.
I was told I could find you at home.
I've tried calling you.
I'm about to leave. We have sent you
the information you requested.
We did not find anything in them.
I have a few very urgent questions.
It's about Zeeland's children's fund.
If we can sort it out while I lock up...
Zeeland's children's fund
is part of our CSR strategy.
We take social responsibility
and help those in need.
We help children in several countries,
but why is that relevant?
Because the girl from the old case was
placed in an orphanage named Mayfarm
that was sponsored by your fund.
The orphanage was closed down. We have been
unable to find information from back then.
The fund must have had good reasons. They
find out what is best for the children.
But I need to catch a flight.
I believe the kidnapper contacted that
orphanage in order to find his daughter.
There must be something
in her file from back then.
It might even have his name and since it
was your fund that ran the orphanage,
then there is a chance that they
might have a copy of the records.
It's important, I need this
file if I going to find Emilie.
I will try to see if I can
find somebody you can contact.
Thank you
- Hello.
- It's Borch.
There is a reason why we
couldn't find that car.
We forgot to think that those numbers
are written down by a seven-year-old.
He made a mistake.
The first letter was the wrong
way around, so instead...
so instead of a Z he wrote S.
What that means is that it's a licence plate
that we have never been looking for before.
And you will not believe it.
It's a Zeeland car.
And the car belongs to Reinholdt,
Robert Zeuthen's personal assistant.
Can you hear what I'm saying?
It's Reinholdt.
He has known the whole time that
it was him we were looking for.
- Name and phone number.
- Where are you? Sarah?
She is the head of Administration,
she should be able to help you.
I really need to get going now.
You knew Mayfarm?
Or you have been there?
I am the chairman of the fund.
I try to bring awareness
as often as I can.
Did you know her?
No, not that I can remember.
Who is it?
Excuse me.
A window might be open.
Stay where you are.