160 Euro, you are crazy!
- 160 Euro is not that much.
Ah, look at me...
Nope, not him! Me, the other one!
Hi, here I am!
A man in his best age.
What a shame.
He could have made a lot
more people happy.
I could just wake up
out of my coma,
and the two fruit loops here
could have
a night out for once.
That's my wife Marlene.
I didn't think she would ever use
that much tissue because of me.
Come here!
What's up?
- I just had the impression,
he just plays dead it and watching us.
That would look more like him.
He isn't that wrong about that.
Playing- gambling- is my passion.
The whole life is a game.
For me this is that.
That is me. That was me.
Last Tuesday.
Born 1947, as Jakob Zuckermann.
If that sounds jewish to you,
you are mistaken.
That was not my club.
Until last week.
In my life, I'm Jackie Zucker.
Born a player, born a winner.
Maybe another time.
- Ah, wait a sec. All or nothing!
See: I bet my Mazda 420 Coupé.
- Alright!
Bad luck.
Really sorry.
Here, rest is for you. I gotta go,
pay my rent.
Hey, I know your ugly face!
You've been a TV-Star in the East!
- Sports anchor, stupid!
Right! What was your name again?
- Rex Gildo.
Rechy Zucker. You tricked me.
Let off me, stupid!
You see,
I am the born winner.
It's not a matter of luck,
I worked hard for that.
Apple juice, ham actor!
Give me my money back!
Gambled too high.
I'm leaving.
- That's Jackie Zucker.
That was him.
Not yet.
Still I'm in the middle of
my wonderful life.
Up to my neck I'm in the shit,
but I got a great view.
New Game, New Luck,
That's my motto.
Think straight ahead.
Somebody once said:
"You have no chance, so take it!"
New game, new luck!
That was the beginning
of a wonderful week.
Well, I'd say,
it was the best week of my life.
Stupid actually,
that it was also my last.
Jackie, it's over,
tomorrow at noon you're out.
You can't be serious, Marlene!
That's a yellow card. Maximum!
Right?
- Wrong!
Is it my debts?
My 2 months rental fee?
Don't act stupid.
- You think I was playing again.
I ran against a door.
- I want you to leave, period!
So, it's a red one...
- Right.
I'm your husband!
- Don't overdo it.
We are still married.
- Not for long!
Give me another chance.
- Non left. Stop that!
Shut up,
you aer such a moron!
You had your appointment today
in our office.
Today? Tomorrow!.
- Today at 9 a.m.!
How are you talking anyway?
Don't be so formal!
I'm happy having my son,
visiting me. At least...
What's going on here?
- Schmöker, bailiff.
Your debts up to this day
are 44.500 Euro.
And as you didn't take your last
appointment this morning...
Come in please!
Ok, here, we can talk.
- There is nothing left to talk.
From your establishment,
the "Club of the Middle" we cannot
extract that sum.
And as you didn't propose any
reasonable solution,
we have to take you into custody.
What? You wanna arrest me?
- As I can see, you packed already.
So we can get going.
- Not so fast...
I got the money.
I can give it to you. What?
My borrowers will pay me sunday night.
Monday at 12 I can pay back
all my debts. Altogether... how much?
- 44.500 Euro.
44.500. Really, promise!
- Aha! Lotto, or what?
We don#t need to discuss any further,
the Management has decided.
There is nothing more we could...
- YOU decided that, son? YOU?
Monday at 12.
I promise on my mother's life.
Ok.
A telegram for Jakob Zuckermann.
Nobody home. May I...
He's just leavinf. Jakob Zuckermann?
Who calls him that? Give it to me.
Wait a second! Who are you?
- I'm his wife.
His ex, his future ex-wife.
Tschüss!
Oh, my god!
Jackie! I call you later!
- Hi!
What can I do for you?
- I want to register.
We wouldn't even start without you.
At the cash desk, Jackie!
The trouble is...
- The registration fee.
5.000 Euro!
- It's for serious players now,
not a gamblers contest. The prices...
- I know! The contest is a dream.
I'm waiting for years for that.
Take a check?
- Ach, come on, Jackie!
You've got 8 hours left.
Get the money,
and we'll meet on friday at 12.
On time!
5 grant, Jackie!
No dream fails for that!
How is your shoulder, Mrs. Kröger?
- Hm...
Lay down, relax.
I'll be with you in a minute.
What's going on?
- I'm in so much pain
in my right shoulder.
So,I thought, perhaps...
You are sneaking into my office
after 2 years without any life sign?
Lay down for a second...
- Your mother through me out.
She wants to divorce.
- Congratulations for that.
Yeah, I know.
Nice, lovely pictures, really nice.
How is little Sandra?
- Sarah. She is fine. Why?
Why? I'm her grandpa!
Or am I not?
Say hello from me, OK?
Ok. On your belly...
Grandpa!
Oh, the right shoulder,
totally jammed.
Doing what?
- I fell.
Are you drinking again?
- No.
Your neck is ruined.
- It's the bank.
Gambling again?
- Nonsens!
How is your business?
- Good. Very good, actually.
We can'*t complain.
Jana, I have a question.
Just a question,
you can say No any time.
Well, those 10.000 Mark,
that you got from me,
that time, 5 years ago,
when I won the competition in Rostock,
that loan, you remember?
- Loan? That was a gift!
"Here dear Jana,
a little jump start for your office."
Yeah, sure, but that was of course...
- Get dressed and leave!
Do you think it's easy for me
to come here?
Out!
- Not like that. Please!
Irene, could you?
- What's that?
This patient refuses to
leave my office.
Who was that?
- My father.
May I? Excuse me...
Mom, please...
- Only 2 minutes.
I need you, Tommy.
I through your dad out,
and now I don't know where he is!
Don't ask how hard it was!
He looked so sad, awful!
And today noon the telegram
for him arrived.
From Frankfurt. From his brother.
Samuel. You don't know him.
Me neither.
- What happened?
"Your mother died." Period.
- My mother? But...
His mother, Jackies mother,
your grandmother, for god's sake!
Jackie's mother?
Oh god, that's awful!
What? You didn't even know her.
- Sorry, I just...
One minute, alright? Come with me.
- She wants to be burried here.
What? Where?
- Well, jewish!
At the jewish cemetry, who know!
Where is Jackie?
How should I know that?
- Because you do!
We have an event of death, Thomas!
Where is he, tell me!
Mr. Zucker! I hope the predjudice
with the suitcases not is right,
is our boss homeless!
- Yeah, looks quite like it.
Where is Linda?
- She has an important client.
Ah, I see.
Have a cup of tea with me?
Oh god, girl!
The game is hard,
if you are behind.
What? We have to close?
Are we homeless?
Who says that?
Ah, Schmöker? But we are...
It's alright, Mr. Zucker.
- Mr. Schmöker!
Thank you.
- You always meet twice in life.
Thanks.
- Jackie, could you?
You're not better than your predecessor.
- No! He stole from you,
I miscalculated, Linda.
- You betrayed me.
Me and my 8 women.
You didn't pay for 12 months!
The club would be gone already,
if I hadn't taken a 300.000 Mark loan.
You shouldn't let a gambler
do the bookkeeping.
Or a nurse do the management!
- Your sarcasm is useless.
We have to close down.
- NO!
On Monday I will have a check
for 100.000 Euro.
Sounds like some kind of cheat.
- No, honestly earned.
Cause I'm the best!
The 5. European Pool Classics...
That's something to win easily like that?
- Yes! It's my time. Skill and Experience!
I haven't lost one game last year
that I didn't wanna loose!
Was a hard job to delay
Mr. Schmöker until Monday.
We are a good team.
- You better win!
I give my life for it.
I'm gonna win, promise.
There is only one tiny...
the registration fee...
My wife! What is she doing here?
She doesn't even know the club!
Jackie! You ruin us all and then
ask me for that fee?
don't get me wrong.
I'm not a client, Marlene,
only the bookkeeper.
- What is that?
A Club for lonely heards,
East German nostalgics.
Crying for the past?
- You could say that.
That's how much you miss the GDR?
- Sometimes. At least I was somebody.
Jackie, everything will be alright.
I want you to come back.
Really? Why is that?
Because we have to stick together.
"Your mother died,
our mother.
She wants to be burried
in native soil.
Contact Rabbi Ginsberg
for funeral. Samuel."
Bring your suitcase.
I won't go to the jewish community!
- Your brother wants you to.
We go there now!
- My brother is a fanatic!
One that's throwing stone on cars
on sabbat in israel.
He's living in Frankfurt. And
you haven't seen him for 40 years!
Your mother died jewish and she
will be buried jewish.
And you'll convert?
The Lord gave it,
The Lord took it.
I really would have liked to
tell her farewell.
She was a very important woman
in my life.
Like a second mom. I hope she
doesn't mind me saying that.
She helped me very much when I
came to Frankfurt as a young Rabbi.
Rebekka Left her Will as a letter
with me.
She wanted a jewish funeral in
Berlin-Weißensee.
Do you agree with this?
Of course.
- Your brother will arrive tomorrow
10:40 with your mother.
Let's include a delay.
To be save, there are so many planes.
Let's perform the funeral at 1:30.
Tomorrow? So quickly?
As stated by jewish law,
deaths have to be
burried quickly. We don't keep them
laying around like the Gojims.
Alright, but what about the hearse
and the formalities?
Do we take care of that?
- No, the community will handle that.
You only have to prepare your
appartment for the Shiwa.
Because your mother also ruled that
you and your brother should
siz Shiwa 7 days after that.
- What, 7 days?
How does she expect us to handle that?
- We will manage...
What exactly is a Schibbe?
- Schiwa.
Schiwa.
- We didn#t have a case of death yet.
- Schiwa, hebrew, means: 7.
The relatives stay at home for 7 days
and celebrate theri grieve.
Great. I like that.
- Samuel Zuckermann
is a very orthodox man.
I don't know, if he will
accept that at your place.
- Ah, we have a big appartment.
You live kosher?
- Average kosher, I'd say.
Not exaggerated.
- You separate milk and meat?
You have to kinds of dishes?
You have the Mesusa at your door?
No pork in your fridge?
- Yes, well... No, no pork.
My mother surely told you
how I'm living, hm?
That I'm a godless communist.
- No, she didn't.
My husband is very insecure.
- I'm not!
Doch! We do live kosher,
but we both are not
religious for political reasons.
- The will counts.
You have to talk with your brother.
- You can't talk with him.
He's got a bullhead, no brain.
- Maybe I didn't make myself
clear enough:
This is your mother's last will.
If you don't want to fulfill this,
you pass on your heritage.
What are you doing?
- Your brother visits us,
to bury your mother.
What's so hard to understand?
436,49.
- It's useless!
It's never too late to
become jewish.
Hey, Taxi! Hello!
Why doesn't he stop?
Milky and fleshly have to be
separated in any case.
Milky, milky...
Eggs, are those milky or fleshly?
Hey! Fix that at the doors,
on the top right.
Come on, be a man of honor
and pay your gambling debts.
Yeah, the full 500.
- Do you have a minute, Jackie?
Why are they interrupting the
grief on Sabbat again?
Did you reach Jana?
- She doesn't answer. I'll stop by there.
That's not my first competition!
Don't be so bureaucratic!
You could make an exception for once!
yeah, midnight, cash!
You are so tall already, Sandra!
We could have conversations!
I'm 10, grandpa. And I'm Sarah.
You don't like that name?
I do! Could you tell something to Jana?
From her Mom and Dad?
16...
- Yes! I have the fee!
Are you ok, Jackie?
- I'll be glad,
when my mother is in the ground and
that guy has left for good.
Why is he sending a telegram?
Is this the middle ages?
There are phone books! If he could
even get our address.
But he is too high up, Mr.
Well-Off-Brother! Dr. Samuel Zuckermann!
Too cheap and too coward!
Don't look at each other like that.
You should have heard him, '61!
"They should castrate you!
And Walter Ulbricht!
And all your communists!"
I'm sure he didn't say that!
- No? You are married to the
only monster in the family.
- That's gonna be fun...
Don't meddle! I have my issues
with you too!
We better don't talk about that now.
- Stop, stop! i take a taxi!
On the freeway?
- I said stop!
Hold your breath, alright?
- Are you mad?
Dad is drinking the enemy's drink.
- Stop your sarcasm!
Soon he will hit on the girl.
- Are you from the east?
Can't you see that?
- Nope.
You don't look that bad.
- Not starved?
I'm eating west soup for 14 years.
- Youhave to help me, Tommy.
I can't do it alone.
We have to try to be,
a normal jewish family.
I know, we are none of that.
But we have to act, you understand?
At least for the jewish mother.
I thought you'd say:
for the heritage.
What have I done wrong with you?
You are getting him!
I was a real star back then,
a real cult figure.
Jackie Zucker. A Rockstar?
Stupid! Sports anchor. Here.
- With signature cards?
Why not?
- Wow!
Only, that my father is normal
at least in that way.
What kind of remark is that?
- I worry about you, my boy!
You meet so many people!
Women as well, even pretty ones.
I mean, you are quite handsome.
- I'm different!
Why didn't you tell me, son?
We would be the last,
to have a problem, if you are...
What did you misunderstand now?
Yes, so I was standing here 14 years
old and had to survive on my own.
Your nose is bleeding.
- That will be gone.
But what's bleeding in here, won't.
Now arriving at gate 8
the delayed flight Dl-473
from Frankfurt.
What does he look like?!
- How should I know?
You recognize your brother, don't you!
- Most likely, he looks like
Osama bin Laden.
- I'm so ashamed.
If your brother sees,
how we treat each other.
Tissue! Look at you!
- I'm bleeding!
There he is.
Tell me I'm dreaming!
Hello, Jakob.
- Hello!
I recognized you immediately.
Yes, that's how we meet again.
And them? They belong to you?
That is my Family,
Golda, my wife,
my daughter Lilly and Joshua.
- Know them, of course.
Why didn't you inform us that
you'd bring them with you?
I did.
- The telegram says...
"Arrival 10:40."
- Really? Show me that.
"Arriving 10:40, Tegel."
Arriving, Plural! So with Mischpoche.
You and mother, that's also plural!
- Don't worry, we'll stay in a hotel.
Impossible,you stay in our place.
Of course.
Why? They are rich!
- No, that won't be necessary.
We are quite an invasion.
And we all together
have a difficult task ahead of us.
- We are a family!
You stay with us, period!
- If they don't want! In the Forum-Hotel...
That's too expensive, 300 Euro a night.
- No problem.
Ha, you see.
- Don't rude! Thank you.
We are happy to stay with you.
300 Euro!
Lilly!
- That's too embarassing, Papa!
So, you take that one...
- Joshua! Take care of your mother.
I take that one, I know the way.
- The drivers do as well.
Than you take it!
- No, we will take a taxi.
Then we can discuss the basics.
I will just tell him. Thanks.
Can I join you?
- N, No problem.
Oh, you stutter, cute. What's that?
- That's Dax.
I was so nervous, Marlene.
I couldn't eat at all in the plane.
A full hour. And my husband,
slept like a baby.
The calm before the storm.
Took care of mom so well.
Why did you never reply
to her letters?
At least after unification.
You are a very nice family.
I expectzed Jakob to be all different.
To be honest, following Samuels
description more like Stalin.
Yes, You wanted to say something?
Ask, maybe... how your mother,
our mom died?
No? And how she lived?
Not. So, no further questions.
And your son...
Thomas, what a beautiful name!
Where did he get those muscles?
- Health club. 2, 3 times a week.
And so quiet, secretive.
I'm sure he's a playboy.
- Well...
And you, what are you doing?
- I study Law. My 22nd Semester.
But actually I'm a princess.
And my hobby are princes.
There you go! I told you,
we should fly earlier.
[hebrew]
What's going on here?
Where did she hide, your mother?
In the attic of the Metropol-Theater,
here in Berlin.
Follow the hearse, please.
And after Hitler, she stayed in
Germany? As a jew, i mean?
Well that's what I call patriotism.
- We'll naever make it!
Jakob! Could you listen a moment?
- I'm not deaf.
We have to delay.
Until tomorrow, 2 pm.
- Tomorrow is friday, impossible.
You can't just fix an appointment
without asking!
Stop it! Why can't you?
- I don't owe any explanation.
Which appointment could be more important
than saying goodbye to one's mother?
Did she ever say goodbye to her
14 year-old son? Nope!
How?! Considering how quickly
you built up your wall...
See! I have to save myself tomorrow,
but nobody cares to
coordinating anything with me!
- Please, Jakob!
We have to get along now
for a week.
Could you take your hands of me?
- You are even more disgusting
than I though. You became an
even more stinky skunk!
Schmock! Not worth a penny!
Forgive me, Mamele, Forgive me.
Sit down please.
Where are the kids?
They should join as well.
There comes the son.
- Are we waiting for the daughter?
I don't know where she is.
- Why are you looking at me?
You... What did she say?
- That she will try to come.
You know her.
- That's not her style,
she would be calling at least.
- Well, let's make an exception.
"For more than 40 years you
are in an ungodly fight.
Now I am dead and take my crying
mother's heart with me.
Let's do it short and quick.
If you, Samuel and Jakob,
get my heritage in equal parts,
which I deposited in my bank
in the form of stocks and bonds?
An acceptable answer to this question
only a collective Yes or No counts.
One Yes, one No is a No."
That's it? The whole letter?
- If you both say No, yes.
I don't say No, you?
In case I say Yes, what's next?
Don't be childish!
- Then I say No.
She will expect you to kiss my
Tuches! - Tuches is the ass.
Nobody blackmails me, I say No.
Is this your last word?
i have lost too much money in
the last 2 years,
as to give up that heritage
just like that.
Especially when my brother is
a bullhead!
Where others have a brain.
- Fine, as you like.
"Hence 5 rules have to  be
followed by you:
1. After the funeral you will,
following the jewish law,
sit 7 days of Schiwa.
2. Your wives and children may,
join as much as possible.
3. For both of you: there is no
exception except sickness or
death.
4. During Shiwa you should not
just sit silent,
but, with witnesses, discuss
truely and honestly about what
lead to your separation and
hostility.
5. You reconcile.
Witnessed and certified by your
family and rabbi Ginsberg.
If you do not follow those rules,
the heritage will go to a
charitable jewish organisation."
Aha...
"Your loving mother,
Rebekka Zuckermann."
If I may ask, what is the value
of the package?
May I ask you to help me keeping
the jewish regulations
while I'm gone, Joshua?
- Maybe I am a little too...
biased?
- No, too strict.
A bissel zisareiisch.
You can do it. I suggest
we give the brothers a minute,
to agree or disagree.
All I say is: New Market!
All I say is: Divorce!
Ah, failed investment...
I am so sorry!
Long live capitalism.
Who spits up,
will get it into his face.
Considering your financial situation
I wouldn't...
What do you want?
Are you spying on me?
That was your job, Jakob!
We didn't have a state security.
I didn't live in an appartment
rented from them.
That is a lie!
- Lie? I bought the house,
and I know from whom!
- What? That was you?
I pay rental fee to you? Wait!
If you already got the house
for quite about nothing,
with your CDU-connections,
then you should know,
It wasn't state security's property
but state's property!
state's property! You heard wrong!
- Ach, I understand.
Great that you understand for once.
What did you pay for it? One Mark?
But raising the rental fee once a month.
- If I hadn't bought it,
you wouldn't live here anymore,
with your communistic payment style.
I might still live here for
130 East-Mark. Communistic!
13 Mark West, 6 Euro 50!
To our loved mom!
- To our loved mom.
The family of your brother is as
kosher as a schweineschnitzel.
Marlene is a Goi! The boy is gay.
And the daughter?
Where is the daughter?
- God Almighty
loves all His creatures, my dear.
- Maybe.
If Joshua find's out about that
we are all finished.
And we even don't know how much.
The 39 tasks forbidden on Sabbat...
Lord, tomorrow night is Sabbat!
I can't do it, Jackie!
You jews, you have too many rules.
There is no space to improvise.
Take care of Marlene.
Help her not to make any mistakes.
I will take care of there
daughter.
That will distract Joshua.
- What are you talking?
Golda, sleep!
I'm not an actress,
I'm a taylor!
You've got to help me, Jackie!
Promise that you stay with me?
Promise! Jackie!
We'll make it.
Hi, Hellooo.
Here they are now. There, milky...
Good morning, my dear.
Hm.
- Jackie! Come.
I need a coffee.
- Take this.
Do not come without Jana!
Call me if you can't handle!
- Samuel would like to go to Jana as well.
That's better for all of us.
Let's make no mistake now.
Oh boy, Jakob!
- Yeah...
Who is it?
- Mail!
Mail?
- Our Password.
Nice to see you, Sandra.
Is your mom already...
Sarah, Grandpa! They are still in bed.
- We can come back in an hour.
Who may I announce?
- Oh, Excuse me. I am Samuel,
Jackie's brother.
- Are you uncle Ayatollah?
Yes, that's right.
- I see.
Still headache?
- Of course.
Me too...
Here, Aspirin...
Still the best.
Already opened.
Thanks.
Do you get along well, Jana and you?
- What do you care?
I also have a daughter.
Daughters always mean Zores.
I don't know her lifestyle, for instance.
A woman shouldn't have more men
than fingers on her hands.
How about your daughter?
She also swops that much?
- No, she has her friend for quite a while.
I see.
- Uncle Samuel! I'm sorry,
to meet first time for this
sad reason.
Yes, yes...
- My condolences.
May I introduce my friend?
We are a couple for 2 years now.
Good morning. Sorry,
Don't care about me.
I'm not completely awake.
- Aha, now I get it.
So? What? That you
don't know anything of my life?
Or, how embarassing all this is?
I'm really sorry, dad, that
you had to find out like this.
- I can handle that,
considering all the happiness with you.
Your open arms your loving heard...
What about yours? Still got one?
As long as I trained my lungs out
and jumped the hurdles
for our global recognition,
I was your loved one.
- I never forced you to anything!
No. But when I told you in Magdeburg
that I'm pregnant and in love and
that I can't run the fucking contest,
cause I was pucking all along,
I was dead for you. Until today.
- Nonsense!
Maybe you both have to...
The funeral for your grandma,
our mother, might not...
But actually we are here to...
What is wrong with me?
The Last Will has to...
Oh, I really feel strange!
- Uncle Samuel, everything alright?
He's got a headache.
We all got a headache!
We are the headaches of our time...
I really feel strange.
Your father has poisoned me.
The water...
Or the aspirin...
Maybe I'm allergic!
- Which Aspirin?
That Aspirin...
- Aspirin!
How many did he take?
- One!
I call the ambulance.
- What's the ambulance for?
That takes too much time, the paperwork!
I'll bring him to a friend...
What was that?
- Ecstasy. If we take it,
we take a half together.
- Is that the drug where the kids
dance all through the night?
- Wrap him up.
He took the wrong pill.
Let him release his energy.
'a massage, Lavender, relaxing...
Schalom, Monsieur Zucker.
- Schalom.
May I invite you to a cup of tea?
She knows what's an orthodox jew?
- Of course, she is from palestine.
And how are you?
You must still be on the trip.
I'm great! I gotta go,
in an hour my contest starts.
You are the greatest, thanks!
Thanks!
Ach, Jana. You...
You were never dead for me.
I see that the opposite.
You turned your back on me,
cause I was a fool. You were right.
But I still love you.
- You are high!
I'm high, and the funeral is at 2!
- I'll be there. I was there yesterday.
We fought for a long time
to have this highclass
international contest finally
come to Berlin.
Good luck to all of the
contestents.
I herby declare the 5th European
Pool Classics in Berlin open!
Great!
-You just won the quickest round
in all history of the EPC!
- I'll be back at 4, Eddy!
There they are
But where is Jana?
Maybe they didn't succeed.
- Here I am.
(Hebrew singing)
Then let's go in.
- Yes.
(Hebrew singing)
I am sorry, Mama.
I have to say something.
I have to think of your favorite joke.
After the concert, a jewish mother
enters the dressing room of the pianist.
"My son plays the piano so well,
you have to support him."
"I never support anyone,"
the pianist said.
"But my son is a genius,"
the mother says and plays a tape.
The Pianist very impressed says:
"He is playing like Horowitz!"
"That is Horowitz," the mother proudly says.
"But my son plays just like him."
You always believed in us, Mamale,
in Jakob and me.
Hw many times you told me:
"Everything will be fine, Samuel."
And when the wall came down:
"Now we'll be a family again."
But we disappointed you so strong.
WWhy didn't we tear down the wall,
tat runs through our family,
as well?
Why did you have to die so that
I can stand here with my brother?
Jackie! Jackie?
Do something!
Jackie!
Help him!
Come!
I'll bring you to a hospital.
Could be a heard attack!
Stay with the family.
- She'll bring you to the hospital!
It's best to let me out here
and I take a taxi.
Are you crazy?
- Too embarassing after all these years...
I won't let you go alone!
- Where are you going?
For 100 grand you can fake an
attack, right?
Even at your own mother's grave.
Show must go on, right?
Thanks.
(Hebrew singing)
(Hebrew)
We worried, Jakob.
- I'm sorry. I hope,
you are not angry, but...
- Of course not. We know everything.
Jana told us all.
- It's good they gave you a checkup.
Better be save.
- How does it look?
Not that bad. I should rest
and come back tomorrow
I have to sleep a lot.
It's best to go to bed now.
Yes, that's the best.
Schalom.
How is it going?
Where do you go?
- To the Synagoge. It's Sabbat.
Stay. That's best for all.
You are not pulling a stunt here, right?
Lenchen! If I only could!
Thanks.
- Pleasure.
8 feet right.
(Hebrew)
"Don't feel well. Going to hospital.
Don't worry. Your Zucker."
No doubt, this is an emergency.
Of course you can call the hospital,
although it's Sabbat. Right, Joshua?
Of course you call!
Ach, you are...
- Sabbat, Schalom, Jakob.
Where are you going now?
- Back to the Synagoge for Ma'ariw.
How are you? You want to join?
- Yes, I really would like to,
but the doctor told me to rest.
- Lilly, come on my dear, it's late!
I'll follow. Thomas will show me the way.
- Jackie!
What took you so long?
I worried a lot.
Yeah, I should have called.
- It's OK. l called.
Although it's Sabbat. In the Charité.
- I wasn't there.
No, you weren'tt.
- They transfered me.
To Zehlendorf, a specialist.
- What did he say?
Doesn't matter. You don't believe me.
- If you are playing a game with us
and think you can run off,
watch out, Zucker!
Why are you so sceptical?
That makes my heart ache!
What hurts me, do you think?
After the mess, Sabbat is over.
then Schiwa starts. You'll be there!
Except, you get another attack.
But I want so see that. Hm?
- You know, you...
Linda, it'S me.
I'm in the quarter finals.
Yes, I could win.
Only, it's getting complicated here.
I need you, yes,
I got an idea.
Damn!
Does it still hurt?
- Hardly.
What do you want from me?
- Ah, you are scared. cute!
They are coming! Lay down!
Always bad luck, that man.
Since unificaiton only bad luck.
I heard even he's a jew now!
- Jackie?
Jackie!
- Go!
Quick, go!
Stop! That's my husband? My god!
- Pardon? Who are you?
You should have stayed in hospital!
- But I wanted to stay with you...
Keep the mask on!
Heartattack, where?
- 1st floor, through glass foor, right.
Ok.
- Are you related?
I'm his wife.
- What is his name?
Jakob Zucker, Zuckermann.
Good luck getting out of here.
Hello! I know him!
That's Jackie Zucker!
I'm looking for Jakob Zucker. He was
just brought in with a heartattack.
You are his wife?
- Yes.
He was lucky. 5 minutes later,
and it would have been too late.
Oh, god! Can I see him?
- Alright.
But make it short,
and keep calm.
OK.
Jackie? Jackie...
Can you hear me? I'm so sorry
I didn't trust you!
But you are such a
professional liar.
I even love you for that,
damn fool!
I love you!
- Mrs. Zucker, that's not your husband.
What?
- There is no Zucker brought in.
Not even in the other stations.
We called them.
I'm sorry...
- Yes. Ha!
I was looking for you!
- How is he?
They brought him to bacteriological
station, spanish flu, maybe.
Kids, go! Only 5 more minutes!
Didn't you have red hair when
you were a secretary?
In Jackie's sport's editorial office.
I forgot your name.
Linda. Yes, I'm Linda.
- You still look great.
That's impossible!
- We cannot change all the
rules just for you.
the winner is Matzjak. Sorry!
My mother died.
We burried her yesterday.
And my brother came for a visit.
An orthodox.
Are you doing it cause I'm jewish?
- You be what you wanna be!
You were 20 minutes late.
- 16! Tell me, if you have problems with jews!
Beat it!
I have no problems with jews,
as long as they don't annoy me!
- I need that money, Eddy!
Else I go to jail.
I lost my family.
At first in the holocaust...
- Jackie, I like you,
but I can't make an exception!
I would have won the contest,
as sure as death and taxes.
So you would have won against me?
- Against you? Blind!
You are good but predictable.
You play like a bureaucrate.
I propose: 14:1, no time limit.
Until 100 points.
Each point counts 1.000 Euro.
But only for the winner.
No risk no fun.
tomorrow, midnight, after the finals.
What do you say?
- How much?
You have no money,
I heard that much.
Let's say 10.000 from you, 90 from me.
The winner get's the 100.000 Euro.
Is that fair?
Thinking is expensive.
I wanna play not calculate!
20, for you 20, for me 80.
The chances...
OK, OK, OK!
Midnight, in my club.
This is it with the heart problems,
promise!
What about the spanish flu?
What?
- The virus, do you ot it?
Did it damage your heart?
- No, I don't have the virus, why?
Ah, thank god!
We can sit Shiwa then?
That's why I came home.
- I suggest, we start our
reconciliation talks tomorrow,
if that's ok with you, Jackie. OK?
I'm always, you know...
So just start!
- Yeah, start! Just talk!
Do we have to stay also when they
don't talk?
She's right. Maybe you have to be
alone for starters,
to get going.
- The letter says so.
Everyone should be there. If possible.
- Right! Should, not must!
Not even all of us are here.
Mother said you don't like
each other.
but you have to get along,
else you don't get the money.
Is that right?
Dad? Are you ok?
Something wrong?
Jakob...
- l have a cramp.
Don't believe him anything!
Don't let him go!
Jackie! The game is over!
- Which game?!
Yours! Now it's my turn.
You wanna know what kind
of people we are.
We are a completely broken family.
I have my business.
He has his business.
I never wanted to know what kind.
But without our son Thomas, he
would have been in jail already.
Both children had no more
interest in him.
I wanted to get a divorce. I wanted
to throw him out when your telegram came.
I tought it's a sign from heaven,
that Jackie might change,
if both of you reconcile. But no...
My husaband cheats us all.
The heart attack yesterday,
the ambulance: all fake!
The heart pain, the doctor: Lies!
It was all a lie!
He doesn't want to risk the heritage
but still do his dirty business.
I'm sorry, but my husband is a
ruthless, heartless gambler!
Alright, I'll talk about my secret
business, Marlene.
If that's OK. Lokk at me,
you Frank sausages!
Here is the typical unification-looser.
Done everything wrong, lost everything.
The only thing I still can earn money
with is billard.
And just this weekend there is the
biggest contest here in Berlin.
My dream contest!
With a chance for 100.000 Euro.
And I just happen to need that money.
Maybe on Monday!
So I don't go to jail.
But the worst is:
I owe it to 8 women in my club,
who trusted me,
and who will loose their jobs,
their income. Understand?
But no, Jackie, that's quite bad luck.
And then your mother dies,
The funeral, the Schiwa...
Hey, do you think I don't care
at all that mom died?
Marlene, do you really think,
I would do that game,
if I didn't have to?
Yesterday's match didn't
work out unfortunately.
I was too late.
I got disqualified.
Come here, Sandra.
Why haven't you told us?
We are your Mischpoche!
Do you think we wouldn't
have understood?
There is one more chance.
That came to me like from God himself.
A Ukrainian offered me a private game.
Tonight, 20.000 Euro...
- I knew there is more to come!
New Game new Luck, right?
- Jackie! Jackie!
Stop playing,
if this is a game!
He doesn't even play!
That's an organic problem,
If dad can't play,
it breaks his heart.
Better he plays than he dies.
If we all keep quiet...
- That's a diregard to the Schiwa!
It's for Jakob's life, his health.
Exceptions are possible.
He should go to hospital then!
- It is a vital business!
That is allowed as well!
- Grandma's rules only accept
the exceptions "Sickness and Death".
Do you think,
I haven't seen through this jewish
acting? I accept it,
because I thought he is honest.
From the beginning Uncle Jakob
broke the rules. You could say:
"We didn't know."
But as confidants,we cheat as well.
I will not participate in that!
What will he do now?
- Go to the rabbi and report.
Joshua! Joshua, wait!
Joshua, please!
Joshua! Boy, please wait!
Joshua, please don't!
That's a stupid role.
It doesn't even suit you!
- One has to play it
in this kosher family!
I loved my grandma.
But on her grave they dance for money.
It's a shame before God.
I am so sorry,
what became of you, Joshua.
Yes, you are right,
we broke the rules.
Yes, my father lies and cheats, and all
of them also think of the money.
Cause it's a lot, right?
But what does your heart say?
It cannot see that Jackie has
an emergency?
He's got problems, a lot, Josh.
More than me and more than you.
You know what's most funny about it?
That I'm on his side,
although we are apart,
since he destroyed our love.
You were f... full age.
Your father made you decide:
Him, his sport and love, or me.
- Yes.
And you made a decision.
- Both of us! You ran of!
And you ran to god.
- What?
Yeah, and I got our daughter.
Joshua! Hello? Joshua!
Don't do something crazy!
Dad?
- What else do you wanna do to me?
Where did you get tbe 20.000 Euro from?
- I don't have it.
The Russian guy,
you are playing against,
is he a good player?
- Why? What are you saying?
We decided that you should play,
If, of course, Jana can stop
Joshua.
You better get some sleep.
- Yes.
The 2
- Ja.
One
The 9
The 6
The 9.
10.
14.
1.
- Yeah.
Jakob?
That was my last week.
For nearly 12 hours I'm
lying in traumatic coma
and wait for a decision.
Somebody up there can't
make a decision,
If Jackie Zucker did win or
loose the game.
If I lost:
Is there life after death?
New game new luck,
even when you're dead?
You are not dead. Hear me?
I'm sorry, Jakob,
that you take the Shiwa so serious.
Don't worry.
The letter of your mother will
make your life better,
you will not loose it.
Don't be scared of the Schiwa.
You haven't lost anything yet.
- What day is it?
Monday.
- What time is it?
12:05.
- How long will I live?
Long time, I'm afraid.
- l have to go to jail.
Jail?
- Ah, nonsense!
Unlucky at cards, lucky in love,
Ukrainians say.
I would have won by the rules,
cause you used your hands
for the last shot.
But who wants to win like that?
Not me. This game has no winner.
Let's do fifty-fifty. Ok?
I payed your debts with your half.
44.500 Euro. That's the rest.
You must be Jackie's wife.
- Yes.
Your husband is a phantastic player.
The first days, Friday, Saturday,
I thought I'd have no chance,
this guy would beat me! Yes?
How could I have known that
this master player
had to burry his mother
at the same time?
You don't just make me a fool
but also your mother.
I think your mother would want
you to loose the heritage.
My honest regrets for
the ignored Will of your mother
and the broken Schiwa.
But, my honest happiness
for my jewish community that will
benefit from the heritage. Schalom!
- Rabbi! I'm sorry.
Mr. Ginsberg!
- Samuel!
My husband gave everything to
keep the Shiwa.
And now he has a heart attack!
And you call yourself neutral?
As the beneficiary of your decision?
- His mother gave us the rules.
He accepted them and broke them.
- Which rules did he break?
The Shiwa has...
- Do I have to tell you?
He faked a heart attack at his
mother's grave!
He went gambling at Sabbat!
He lied and lied and lied!
No! Rebekka's Will was not that!
- She wants peace
between Jakob and Samuel. Right?
- Yes, that's right.
Peace is a strong word for what
is connecting us now.
But, so what?
The rabbi believed it.
He is giving us a last chance to
fulfill mother's Last Will.
The Shiwa should continue here, in
our 2-bed-room.
Samuel and me should reconcile.
Nothing easier than that,
after all we've been through.
First, we extend our 40 years of
silence by 2 more days.
(Hebrew)
My family will try to use that
time as much as possible.
The poor boy, nobody can save you
from that kind of experience.
If noboday else does it, why not
the cousin? It's legal, I mean.
And how...
How was I doing?
Like an amateur.
Aigo.
That was my first time.
Quite old for the first time.
- Because I'm quite ro...
romantic.
- I don't mind.
While Samuel and me are lying
unsuspectingly in hospital,
the mice are dancing
on the table at home.
Bytheway I'm your father, Sarah.
I thought so. And what does
that mean?
That means Joshua and me loved
each other very much once.
And you came out of this.
Why you never told me?
I'm already 10!
There are things that take so long
because they are so complicated.
And some things are so complicated
because they take so long.
My future daughter-in-law is
right about that.
Real problems have to take time.
Men like us have the
right breath for that.
women are much too hectic.
2 more days and the Shiwa is over!
And nothing changed!
Doch, we get along well.
- I don't know,
if I am healthy enough for that.
- Your are very healthy!
I didn't know you've got that
kind of strength in you!
And you lie without turning red,
maybe even now you're faking it.
I promise, to heaven and hell,
if you don't open
your bloddy damn mouth!
- I think that's enough.
They got the message.
I want you to repeat what you told
me when you were high.
What did I say?
- I surely won't tell you.
Well, I must have said that you've
never been dead to me, and that
I always love you, stuff like that.
- Bravo!
Bravo!
- Yes, go on, Jackie!
Hm? It's working.
- Come on.
I'm sorry, Samuel.
Did you say something?
- I am sorry!
Stop it, I don't believe one word.
- I'm sorry for you.
You think, you do everything right,
have nothing to explain,
from your side for once, hu?
Who just ran of that time?
From here, from home?
Mother with her favorite son.
Did you never think how
that felt for me? Hm?
Left alone here?
14 years old, behind walls?
-Ah, stop that!
You know very well, I needed my
leg fixed in Frankfurt.
Ha, "alone, behind walls".
You wanted to stay in sports college,
when they built the fucking wall!
Can you imagine,
how mom suffered because of you?
It was your decision.
We had to accept it.
Socialism was more important than us.
Let's not talk politics.
Fact is that
you never visited me.That's how
stubborn our family is.
Until death.
This was our home! Samuel, here!
We've been a real family.
Even after father's death.
I might have needed you from
time to time.
Not because of the West-Mark!
Come here, grumpy.
Why don't you come?
- Cause I had a heard attack
and you a circulatory collapse
bullhead!
I can't deny that
I also think of the lovely
heritage at that moment.
Also, not more. As all of us.
My whole Mischpoche!
See us sitting there,
all tension head to toes,
how much are the bonds
of our beloved mother.
Don't get me wrong, mom,
but I can't put anything past you.
A chip of the old block.
Pardon?
- New game, new luck,
my dear Jakele.
I had a long sleepless night.
Let's make it quick.
Let's split the heritage in
2 halfs, one for the brothers
one for the community.
Any complaints?
A motivation.
- I think it's a good solution.
Motivation? Temper justice with mercy.
Following the rules strictly
you would have gone empty handed.
Do you think so too, Joshua?
Yes, of course.
- Then we agree.
I look forward to a few new
friends in our community
And a few less foes.
Well, now I'm excited.
Good Day, Rabbi Ginsbergaus Berlin.
Account No: 44-88-53-77.
Yes, I'm waiting.
Thanks. Thank you very much.
It's in the blacks. Maseltow!
She might have left debts
How big black numbers?
Well...
Have you expected anything else but
a worthless bonds package?
Be honest, I did.
I believed in it,
I had no chance
but I took it.
My family as well.
Some travel a lot between
Frankfurt and Berlin.
Why not?
Makes the airlines happy.
Well, and me?
Don't have much time for playing.
I take care of my family.
Monday for Jana,
tuesday Thomas, Friday Marlene,
and on sunday I call to Samuel
for 2 hours.
Wednesday and Thursday I go to
Synagoge and read the bible.
Nonsense, the Thora.
No offence ment!