[subliminal instrumental music]
[rap music playing]
[party chatter]
[girls cheering]
Chance got it.
Chance is fucking at it.
How you been, man?
Come in for a picture.
Oh, my God.
-Cheers!
[rap music continues]
[whispering]
Yo, shh.
[rap music thumping]
[laughing]
I didn't even fuckin' tell 'em.
They just started doing that.
I didn't even fuckin'
tell 'em anything.
Why'd you stop?
What are you doing?
No, Brad didn't...
You want a bump?
You want more coke?
-You guys want a bump? Yeah?
-[girl] Yeah.
[sniffing]
-In your mouth?
-Mmm-hmm.
Your friend's a pro.
You want one?
Let's do it.
Fuckin' A, man.
Whoo!
-You want some coke, Brad?
-No, I'm good, bro. I'm good.
You want a little...
Take a little like this.
A little on your gums?
I'm straight, bro.
-[Chance] Sure? Okay.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Don't worry about it? Mmm?
[Chance] Oh, shit.
[Brett] Oh, man.
Oh, shit.
Leah, Leah.
Come here.
Come in here.
We got coke.
You want some coke?
Come in.
I'm cool.
[Chance] No, you wanna
do a bump?
I'm gonna take off.
Oh, oh. Hey...
What are you doing?
Are you embarrassed
right now?
Huh? No, man. No.
I'm not fucking embarrassed.
I'm just tired.
Okay, you need to
liven up a little bit.
-'Cause this is a sure thing.
-I know.
Right here, it's fuckin'...
I know. I'm just not
into it tonight.
I love you.
I gotta call it
a night, okay?
It's about Leah?
Bro, how long are you
chasing that?
Fuckin'...
Fuck off.
Okay? I'm not leaving
'cause of Leah.
All right. All right.
Dude, this party is
fucking weird anyway...
All right. Tell Mom
and Dad I said hi.
-Okay, I will. I love you.
-I'm sorry.
No, no, no.
I'm just fucking tired...
Just no drive tonight.
[sighs]
[man] Yo, hey!
I know you, right?
Me?
Yeah. Hey, I saw you inside.
Do you think
I can get a ride?
Uh, where are
you going?
Not far.
I'm sorry, dude.
It's kind of late.
I gotta get home.
Come on, man.
It's right up the road.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, sure.
Yeah, this is me
right here.
All right, hang on a sec.
Let me grab my boy.
-Your "boy"?
-Yeah.
Look, it'll just
take a sec, man.
I swear.
Okay.
Fucking kidding me?
Weren't taking off
without us, were you?
No. No, no, no.
I was just waiting.
All right.
[car doors open]
Thanks, man.
All right.
[clears throat]
So wait.
How do you guys
know Colin?
Who the fuck
is Colin, man?
He's the kid whose
house we were at.
Oh, right.
Yeah, it's his boy.
Right, man?
[chuckles] Yeah.
You guys go to Brookman?
My brother goes there.
Brookman?
Nah, man.
We go somewhere else.
Just keep driving.
Straight?
Yeah, yeah.
Keep going.
It's a ways.
I thought you said
it was just up the road?
We, uh,
we gettin' close?
Yeah. Yeah, man.
Take a left.
-What, here?
-Yeah.
Listen, guys. I, uh,
I gotta get back home.
Hey, relax, man.
We're almost there.
I know. It's just late.
Is there some place close
I can drop you off?
-Where do you suggest?
-I don't know, man.
I'm about to turn around
any second though.
I mean...
Hey, man.
What's your problem?
You're freaking out
like a little bitch.
Stop being
such a baby.
[man] For real, man.
I'm not being a baby, man.
You told me it was just
up the road.
I've been driving
20 minutes. Like...
All right. Okay.
All right.
Pull over then.
Look, man. I'm not,
you know...
Stop the fucking car!
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
Your hand's shaking.
Okay. What do you
guys want? Seriously.
Relax.
We're here now anyway.
[car door beeping]
[punching]
[Brad] Stop!
Okay, stop!
Stop...
[coughing]
Look, you don't need
to hurt me, okay?
What do you want?
I'll give you
whatever you want.
[grunts]
[coughing]
What's your ATM code?
What?
Tell me your fucking
ATM code right now,
or I swear to God
I'll fucking kill you.
4-1-1-4.
Don't fucking lie to me.
It's 4-1-1-4.
I swear to God, dude,
I'm not--
Can you please
just let me go?
Shut the fuck up.
Look, I don't
have anything.
Shut up.
Stop talking.
[grunts]
[mumbles]
Stay.
Wanna get in on this?
Come on, man.
Let's go.
[car engine starts]
[dog barking]
[hip hop music playing]
[sombre instrumental music]
[pills rattling]
I'm fine.
Easy, easy, easy.
Just give me a sec...
-Yeah.
-I'm sorry.
I've been driving around
for three hours
with a knife in my car,
trying to find these guys.
Chance is coming over
with his dad's gun.
I swear to God,
we're gonna
fucking kill them.
It doesn't matter, Brett.
Of course it
fucking matters.
They're not gonna get
away with this, Brad.
You're never gonna
find them, man.
Tell me what
they look like.
They don't look
like anything. Okay?
What the fuck are you talking
about, "They don't look
like anything?"
Brad. Fuck!
All right.
[detective] So, did they
have a weapon?
[Brad] No, not that
I was aware of.
But they forced their way
into the car?
No.
So you gave two
complete strangers
a ride out in the middle
of nowhere,
because you're
a nice guy--
-No, I told--
-I'm just trying to
understand.
I told you that
they were at the party,
and that they asked
me for a ride home.
And they tried to
steal your car.
Yes.
I've seen your car.
What I can't understand
is why they
beat you up so bad.
Did you say
something to them?
Call them, something?
Resist, uh...
-Provoke.
-Fuck do I know?
You know what
I think?
I think you were
looking for drugs.
I think you were trying
to buy drugs
from these guys,
and things got
out of hand.
It happens.
This I can help you with.
I wasn't trying
to buy drugs.
Okay.
Not trying to buy drugs.
[sniffs]
I don't know what
else to tell you.
You go home and
get some rest.
We'll follow up.
Fuck.
[grunting]
[painful squealing]
[motor whirring]
What are you
doing here?
Want a beer?
Yeah.
-Nice to see you.
-Yeah. You, too.
Get off Facebook.
-Thanks, man.
-Gotcha.
So what you
been up to?
Yeah, dude. I'm sorry
I haven't been
back before now.
I've just been
crazy busy. You know?
How you doing?
Good.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Mom said you're thinking
about bailing on school.
I'm not bailing on it.
I just don't know if I can
get all my shit together
before the fall,
you know.
But you're already
accepted for the fall.
Plus Phi Sig is
only rushing in the fall.
I don't know, man.
I'm not putting
any pressure on you.
I'm just saying.
You should come
this weekend, though.
We're throwing a huge party
at the lake.
I think Leah is
gonna be there.
Yeah, I know.
I'm sure you do know.
[laughing]
You're gonna...
You know, like
a little ass grab?
-[laughing]
-Oh, Jesus Christ.
Okay.
-Yeah?
-Yeah, I'll come for
the weekend.
Fuck, yeah!
Just for the weekend,
though.
Yeah.
It's all you need.
Just...
Get right in there,
grab that ass.
[laughing]
Oh, Jesus.
It's good to
see you, man.
You too, bro.
[clinks bottles]
[rock music playing]
-Whoa!
-Ho!
Lando!
How you doing, man?
-Hi. How you been?
-You look good.
You all right?
Hey, man.
How are you?
-How you been?
-Good.
-Good to see you.
-You too, man.
-Brought the beer.
-Here you go.
Welcome, Lands.
-Thanks, man.
-Say hello, everybody.
Brett? Brett!
Come over here,
you fucking asshole.
Couple of
my brothers here.
Yeah, good to meet you.
Whoo!
[general chatter]
So where you been
all summer?
Just had some shit
I had to deal with
back home.
Yo, Brad got fucking
rolled up on
by some white trash
fucking rednecks, man.
Those townie dudes
in Dawson are no joke, man.
They know they got
nothing to lose.
These motherfuckers are
literally on their way
to jail,
and they figure shit they
can put you in the hospital
at the same time is better.
So what happened?
They beat my ass,
stole my car.
I'm just saying, man,
you creep up on a dude
like that behind his back,
you're straight pussy, man.
I'll say this, though.
My boy Brad knows
how to take
a fucking punch, man.
Unlike some of us.
Oh! What...
Why are you
flinching, Baity?
Fuck you.
[laughter]
You piece of shit.
Baity, why are
you flinching?
[Baity]
I hate all of you.
[laughter]
[music playing in distance]
-Hey.
Do you mind if I sit?
No, no. Please.
Got some towel.
-[laughs]
-Towel here.
I'm really glad
you came.
Me, too.
Yeah.
How are you?
I'm good.
Yeah, they found a fracture
in my jaw, though.
I mean, I remember
when it happened.
'Cause I could hear it,
you know...
I mean,
this guy's fist
just like...
kept slamming
into my face.
But I remember...
I remember I was
thinking of you.
What do you mean?
Just your last memory
of me was me
abandoning you
at a party.
-And--
-No!
No, you did not
abandon me...
...at all. No.
Seriously.
[Brett] Yo, B.
You seen my keys?
Oh, shit.
Sorry.
I'm gonna go get
another beer, actually.
Okay. Yeah, yeah.
Cool.
Can of beer.
All right.
I thought you said
she had
a fucking boyfriend, bro?
[laughs]
Shh.
You're so drunk
right now, aren't you?
Can you just get me
another fucking drink?
[laughs] You...
Just keep
your voice down.
Why don't you
drive this one.
It's probably a good
idea, buddy.
Probably take a nap
or something
like that?
Yeah. [clears throat]
Easy with
the fucking mirror, bro.
[Brett] It's all good, man.
We're good.
Yeah, I don't have
the keys, bro.
I got it. I got it.
'Cause you had them.
Yeah, here. Right there.
Oh, hold on a sec.
-Do you have them?
-Yeah, I got 'em.
All right.
Okay.
-Brett? Hey.
-Yeah?
Do you think
I'm a pussy?
You're drunk, dude.
Hey, hey.
I don't know why
I didn't fight back.
Okay? I don't know.
I don't know.
-Okay.
-Okay?
You know, like...
If I had to do it again...
All right.
I'm just gonna...
-Can you get this?
-Okay.
There we go.
I kissed her, you know.
I know. I saw you.
Don't try to kiss me.
I won't kiss you.
[laughs]
Just get in the car
Be good.
I'm good.
Everything's good.
[car door shuts]
-That is why
you wear glasses.
-Shut up.
I don't know if you remember
this, I didn't look at
the fucking sun.
Fuck you. What,
did you close your eyes?
I wouldn't
be surprised, man.
Dumbest game ever.
Could you throw me
my hoodie, dude?
When are you
driving back?
Uh, next Sunday.
I've been thinking, man.
I, uh...
I think I'm gonna go.
Go where?
Like, I think I'm gonna
start school on time.
Brad, that's fucking awesome.
Yeah?
That's amazing.
[chuckles]
-Thank you. Thanks, man.
-Yeah.
[sombre instrumental music]
-You good?
-Yeah, I got it.
Six...
Four.
Oh, dude. This room is
way fucking bigger than
I thought it was gonna be.
It's not bad.
That's a pretty sweet TV.
Yeah. Good to go.
Hey, what's up, man?
Uh, one of you Brad?
I'm your roommate.
Will Fitchley.
But people call me Fitch.
Right on, dude.
I'm Brad Land.
It's really good to meet you.
This is my brother, Brett.
What's up, man.
Shit, dude.
Are you in Phi Sig?
I am. Yeah.
Oh, dude,
that's awesome.
Uh, so what's up
with Rush?
Can anybody
come out, or...
Yeah, of course.
Yeah. We're actually
got a party on Saturday.
You should come out.
Brad's coming.
Yeah. I will
totally be there.
That sounds
awesome, man.
All right. Cool.
Oh, we got some
more stuff--
Yeah, we got some
more boxes, man.
-Good to meet you, bro.
-Yeah, dude.
I'll see you in
a second though, man.
It's good to meet you, Will.
Yeah, good to
meet you, too.
[techno music playing]
[people chatting]
[music thumping]
[rap music playing]
[techno music playing]
[all cheering]
[Brett]
Hey, what did I tell you.
It's good, right?
It's just fucking chill.
Brett. Brett.
It's fucking awesome, dude.
Seriously.
These are some of the best
dudes we'll ever fucking know.
Like, I mean that.
I get it.
I got you.
I'm excited.
I'm excited you're here.
Okay. good.
What's up, motherfuckers?
[boy]
Yo, who's this fucking...
Who is this fucking
Ellen DeGeneres here?
Dude, that's my
fucking roommate.
No!
Oh, fuck dude.
I'm sorry.
[hip hop music playing]
[birds chirping]
Shh.
[mouths] Okay.
I'm leaving.
[door shuts]
[laughing]
What's up, man?
How you doing, dude?
-I'm good, man.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-You feeling all right?
You ready?
Hell week's coming up.
Yeah, I'm ready, man.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
Oh, man.
I'm not so sure.
Got some hot girls
in your barn?
-One or two.
-"One or two."
-[laughs] What?
-What are you doing right now?
Where are you going?
I'm just going to class.
Oh, fuck.
We're going to
the bar, brother.
It's kind of early.
You're smart enough, man.
Don't be a pussy.
Come on.
[rock music playing]
So how you been
anyway, man?
-I've been good, man.
-Yeah?
Yeah, I'm doing good,
I think.
Fucking trying not to
sleep through class, right?
No, how you been?
How you been
since the, uh...
Fucking whatever.
Since your accident.
Yeah.
You're gonna
be Phi Sig.
All right?
That shit's never
gonna happen again.
First of all, you're never
gonna find yourself
in that position again.
Ever.
Yeah, I gotta get in first.
Yeah, you gotta get in.
Yes, you do have to
get in first.
Finish that beer, man.
We're doing
shots tonight, man.
-You fucking serious?
-Me and you,
we're doing shots tonight.
We're blacking out tonight,
motherfucker.
Finish that beer.
Yo! Phi Sigma Mu,
motherfucker!
Ow!
Whoo!
Yeah, man!
Don't stop, motherfucker.
Yes? Yes.
Oh, God.
[speaks indistinctly]
What?
I do.
I think I love you.
-You don't mean that.
-No.
[chuckling]
I don't know, I just...
I could love you.
I don't even know you.
Look, um...
I have to be up
really early tomorrow.
I think maybe
you should go.
[clears throat]
[hip hop music playing]
[people chatting]
[Brett] Brad.
Dixon, Brad.
Brad, Dixon.
This is my brother
I was telling you about.
-What's up, Brad?
-Hey, man.
One of those?
Brad, how do you like
all the shit so far, huh?
I don't know.
It's good times, right?
Right.
So you're a business major,
like your fag brother here,
or what?
No.
No, I don't really
have a major yet.
I'll probably just
wait and see.
Cool. Nice.
Good luck with that.
All right, Well, I left
Chance on the grill.
I got to make sure
he's not fucking
the burgers. So...
See you, dude.
What the fuck was that?
What?
All that "good times"
bullshit?
Bro, they're not gonna
let you in here
just 'cause you're my brother.
I can't...
Yeah, I fucking
know that.
'Cause they're weird
about that shit.
You need to fucking
shake their hand,
look 'em in the eye,
let 'em know
you wanna be here.
All right. What do you
fucking want me to do?
I want you to
just have fun.
-Okay.
-And just chill out.
-Right now though,
take a fucking
shot of this.
Some man shit.
Then we're gonna have
a good time, all right?
Come on.
Let's go.
There you go.
Are you good?
Holy shit. Yeah.
[man] All right.
Who's this up in
my motherfucking house?
Oh, shit!
Look who it is.
What's going on, man?
Chance!
How you doing, brother?
-How are you, brother?
-Oh, man. I'm good.
Good to see you.
Yeah, welcome back.
Yo, this is Mitch.
-What's up, Mitch?
-Hey, how you doing?
-Baity.
-All right.
Yo, class of 2000.
Craziest motherfucker to
come through this school.
-Aw, maybe. Maybe.
-Craziest motherfucker to
come through this school.
-Maybe.
-[boy] Mitch? Mitch?
-What!
[Mitch] What's up,
you fucking pussy?
You fucking animal.
Get the fuck down here,
you fucking faggot
and suck my cock
right now!
Show me some
fucking respect!
Now!
Yo, beer.
Oh.
Yo, just one.
I got to go.
"One." [scoffs]
I got to get back
to Vanessa and the kid.
I got a kid now, bro.
-You got a kid?
-I got a fucking kid now.
Fuck that, Dad.
Don't call me
fucking "Dad".
-Yo, fuck you, man.
-Fucking "Dad".
-Fuck you!
[all cheering]
[boy] He's back, baby!
-[boy 1]
Line it up. Line it up.
-[boy 2] Here. Right here.
[all] Cheers.
For the boys.
-Hey.
-[Chance] You guys know Mitch?
What's up, brother?
-Brad?
-Yeah.
Hey, is this the motherfucker
who got his ass beat?
[Chance] Yo, Brad got jumped
by some dickless
piece of shit, man.
It's bullshit.
Brad...
That can't fucking happen.
-You hear me?
-Yeah.
You know why?
This is Phi Sigma Mu.
Okay?
We're gentlemen.
We don't like to fight,
but if we gotta fight,
then we all fight.
Do you hear what
I'm saying?
Some motherfucker
wants to go
through Chance,
they gotta go through
all of us.
They wanna
fuck with Brett,
they're going through
all of us!
It's the same with you.
-Do you hear what
I'm saying?
-Yeah.
Punch me in the face.
-What?
-Punch me in the fucking face.
-No, dude.
-Punch me in the face!
Punch me in
the fucking face!
-I'm not gonna fucking punch--
-Do it!
All right.
Punch me in
the fucking stomach.
Punch me in the stomach.
-Punch me in the stomach.
-[all hollering]
[all yelling]
[yelling]
Punch me in the stomach.
Give me a slap.
Slap my fucking--
-Oh!
-Slap me.
Slap me.
[yelling]
To the greatest group
of gentlemen
the civilized world
has ever known.
[all] Phi Sigma Mu!
Holy Phi Sigma Mu,
we are brothers
through and through.
Seldom cuss
and never lie,
we are brothers
till we die.
Holy Phi Sigma Mu,
we are brothers
through and through.
Seldom cuss
and never lie,
we are brothers
till we die.
[all cheering]
[cell phone vibrating]
I don't know.
Are you guys sure?
I still think these
are too big.
Oh, my God.
Will, relax man.
You look fine.
How do you guys
feel about Hell Week, huh?
Dude, if one more person
asks me
that fucking question...
They're just trying
to scare us, man.
I don't know, Baity.
They did say something
about a goat.
They're trying to
fucking scare us.
[imitates goat bleating]
[chuckling]
Fucking goat.
[guys cheering]
[cheering continues]
Yo, she's
fucking cute, dude.
Have you ever fucking...
Have you ever had
sex with a stripper?
No, have you?
All the time.
No, no.
[guys continue cheering
and hollering]
You guys wanna
get out of here?
You wanna
I have
a surprise for you.
[cheering continues]
[speaking indistinctly]
-No, dude.
Pledges are not allowed
in the fucking legacy room.
You know what else pledges
aren't allowed to do?
Smoke my
fucking Cuban cigars.
Oh, shit.
Holy shit.
Is this real?
Yeah, dude.
My dad gives
them to me for my birthday.
Oh, shit.
You got it?
You good?
I'm going places.
We're smart fucking dudes.
You know?
We're going to do
shit with our lives.
Big shit.
And these
fucking dudes...
I love them,
but they're fucking
trashy dudes, man.
They suck.
They're just not going...
They're not
going anywhere, man.
Brookman's kind of
a shitty school.
No, it's not.
It's not.
Stand the fuck up.
This is a celebration.
-You're good.
-No, 'cause we're...
-I've known him
my whole life.
-That's true.
And now we're brothers.
-Fucking brothers.
-And now we're brothers
forever, dude.
You know, my dad...
Fuck that guy, man.
That guy hates
my fucking guts.
I'm so fucking glad
you guys are here.
[Brett] I'm fucking glad
we're here too, man.
Yo, you guys...
Dude...
You know, I fucking
love you guys.
-You good?
-I'm good.
[laughing]
-Yo...
-Hey...
Yo...
-Phi Sig, dude?
-Phi Sig for life.
Phi Sigma.
[cell phone vibrating]
Hello?
[man] Get your ugly goat
ass to the house in
11 minutes or you're dead.
What?
[line disconnects]
[cell phone vibrating]
You started on
the wrong foot, goats.
You're all late.
If any one of you
are ever late again,
I will rip your
shriveled balls off
and shove 'em down
your fucking esophagus.
Is that understood?
I said
is that understood?
I wanna hear you say,
"Sir, yes, sir!"
[all] Sir, yes, sir.
I am your pledge master.
And you...
are my bitches.
Is that understood?
[all] Sir, yes, sir!
Don't you fucking
look at them.
You look at me
and only me.
When I see Dave Reed,
I don't wanna see
Dave fucking Reed.
I wanna see a mesh...
of all your faces...
in one.
One pledge.
Look at me, goat.
One pledge
of the Phi Sigma Mu.
Let me hear your
motherfucking pledge!
[all] All my strength
is in my union.
All my danger
is in discord.
Therefore be at
peace henceforth,
as brothers live together.
Good. Very good.
Welcome to
hell week, goats!
[metal music playing]
[shouting indistinctly]
-[music continue]
-[all clamoring]
Now!
Go, go, go, go go!
Let's go!
Drink it.
Go on, you fuck.
What the fuck did
you swallow?
Go, go, go, go go!
[shouting indistinctly]
Drink.
Quick! Drink!
Drink! Drink!
Drink.
Drink that shit!
Look at me.
You have no friends.
Nobody's fucking
looking out for you.
Nobody fucking loves you.
Say, "I'm a faggot
and nobody loves me."
[boy] I'm a faggot
and nobody loves me.
-Say it again.
-Why the fuck, you ass.
I'm a faggot
and nobody likes me.
Say it like
you mean it, though.
Say it with feeling.
I'm a faggot
and nobody likes me.
Open your fucking mouth.
Turn your head to me,
right now.
You're gonna drink,
motherfucker.
Pushups!
I don't let no weak
motherfuckers in my frat!
Get the fuck up.
Against the fucking wall.
Headstands!
Get your fucking knees up!
Spread the fuck out,
you faggots.
Get the fuck away from him.
You wanna
go on a date with him?
Spread the fuck over.
Get back.
Take it, take it,
take it.
having a good time?
Sir, no, sir.
On the ground!
Face on the ground.
[indistinct clamor]
[indistinct yelling]
Fucking boy!
You should be
ashamed of yourselves.
[indistinct clamor]
Get it over here.
Hurry the fuck up.
Bring it down.
Here we go, Brad.
[indistinct yelling]
[boy] That was cute.
That's one, you guys.
You got a whole
barrel full.
[laughter]
I wanna hear, "Thank you,
sir, may I please
have another?"
Thank you,
sir, may I please
have another?
[boy] Here we go.
Nice and cute smiles.
Guantanamo style.
There we go.
Got it.
Fetch the bitch.
[laughing]
He's fucking gone.
-You're gonna puke, bro?
-Sir, no, sir.
-Are you sure?
If you lie to me,
I'm gonna do
terrible shit to you.
Sir, no, sir.
That wasn't a question.
All right, motherfucker.
You ready?
Don't you puke.
I think he's actually
gonna be good.
[all exclaiming]
Yo!
Not fucking cool.
Yo, get in the cage.
Get in the fucking cage.
Get in the cage, now.
Fucker.
Yo, lick that shit
off my shirt. Faggot!
Yeah, lock that shit.
Yo, that's
fucking disgusting.
Everybody else,
against the wall.
Get against the wall.
Yo, give me that.
Give me that.
Come on, bitch.
Go in the cage.
[guy] You thirsty?
[guy hooting]
You like them
golden showers, boy?
Look at those
golden showers.
[guys hooting and cheering]
Hey, get that side as well.
Rock a by, Fitch.
Fuck you.
Goodnight.
Morning, goats.
Time to get the fuck
out of our house.
Get the fuck
out of our house!
Let's go!
Get the fuck up!
Get the fuck out of here!
[guys hollering]
[echoing]
Brad, get the fuck up!
[hollering continues]
[spits]
Let me ask you a question.
What the fuck happened
in there?
I don't fucking know, dude.
Okay. Well, Dixon's looking
for a reason to kick your
ass out today.
Okay? It's just
I cheated for you.
-What?
-This shit cannot happen.
Dude, I didn't fucking
ask for your help in there.
I didn't ask
for your help.
Look, I wouldn't do
this myself, all right?
They just fucking do this
to weed out the weak ones.
Show 'em you mean business.
Show 'em you wanna be here.
Okay.
All right?
You got to be tougher.
-You can do this, dude.
-I know.
I fucking will be.
-Come on. Let's go.
-Good.
All right.
Hey, man.
You all right?
I was gonna
go get some pizza,
if you wanna come.
Oh, man. Brad.
I didn't know this
happened to you.
Shit, dude.
Sick of feeling scared
like all the time,
you know.
Hey, I'm sorry that
happened to you, man.
It's crazy.
[Brett] Brad?
Brad?
Bradley?
Wake up!
Get this goat.
You know what
goats eat, right?
Goats eat shit.
What? Go back
in your room.
[guy] Time to eat shit,
goat motherfucker.
[Brad] No, no, no, no!
What the fuck, dude!
Get down.
Grab it.
-Grab the--
-Stop that, dude!
Grab the shit.
Grab it.
[groaning]
You're not leaving
till you taste
some shit, bitch.
Get that shit...
It's just a fucking...
[laughter]
You fucking assholes.
Whoo!
Yo, where's your roommate?
Where's Fitch the bitch, man?
I want my goat.
He's got
fucking class, man.
[guy] All right.
I got to get to class, too.
Just getting started.
[laughter]
You all right?
Yeah.
Thanks, man.
-[knocks]
-Lando.
Yo.
What's up, dude?
Yo, we're going
to the farm.
You, uh...
What are you doing?
What's "the farm"?
What are you
talking about?
Getting the
fucking goat, dude.
Yo, I thought
that was a joke.
No, no. Baity found one
this year.
It's fucking happening.
Got it. Got it.
Is this pledge getting
weirder this year?
"Weirder?"
I don't know. Harder?
What...
Is that a fucking joke?
No, man. It's just...
J-Town put a cigarette out
on my ass last year
in front of the Tri Delts.
The pledgers got
to go through hell,
otherwise what's...
what's the fucking point,
right?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
You're right, man.
[Baity]
Hustle, bitches.
[guy 1] Hurry the fuck up!
[guy 2] You boys are gonna
meet your fucking maker.
[Baity] Step up.
Step up. Step up.
This is just the beginning.
You shouldn't be fucking
this up hard already.
One too many
fucking pancakes.
[indistinct chiding]
[guy] Yo, move your shit.
[indistinct clamor]
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
Jesus Christ,
you're fucking ugly.
Good...
Straight fucking line.
None of this crooked fruity
bullshit. Let's go.
Straight fucking line.
All right, bitches.
We'll play
a little game, okay?
Who was...
the first president of
the United States?
George Washington, sir.
Wrong, drink.
[laughter]
Who shot John F. Kennedy?
-I--
-Wrong. Drink.
[laughter]
What are the colors...
of the American Flag?
Red, white and blue, sir.
Wrong.
[laughter]
Hey, I didn't tell you
to fucking drink!
Look at me when
I'm talking to you, goat.
I want you to slap
Brad in his face.
That's your punishment.
[guy] Oh, no.
What?
Slap Brad in the fucking face.
Are you deaf?
Slap him in the face.
[guy] He won't do it.
-[Dixon] Oh, fuck!
-[guys snickering]
Are you trying
to finger fuck it?
I want you to
fucking get in there.
Slap his fucking face!
[guys] Oh!
Jesus Christ!
You're just gonna stand there
and let him slap you
in the face?
Your balls drop yet?
What the fuck!
-[guys] Oh!
-There you go.
Again!
There you fucking go.
Yeah! Yeah!
There you go!
Okay. The goats
are worthy now.
Dixon!
Fucking stop, dude.
They did it.
They fucking did it, okay?
Good?
-You good?
-All right.
You guys are good.
[Dixon] Drink.
Both of you.
[all hollering]
[hollering continues]
[mock bleating]
[Chance] All right,
motherfuckers.
Here's what's gonna
happen, okay?
You guys look nervous.
You don't have to
be nervous.
This is really simple, okay?
We all did this.
Everybody has to
do this, okay?
It's really simple.
Here's what's
gonna happen.
First you're
gonna fuck 'em,
and then you're
gonna kill 'em,
together.
And then we're all
gonna eat 'em.
[all cheering]
[Chance] You ready
to fuck a goat?
You think I'm
fucking around?
This isn't bullshit, man.
You ready to fuck a goat?
Take your pants off.
You think I'm fucking around?
How are you gonna fuck a goat
with your pants on?
Tell me, Dave. How are you
gonna fuck a goat
with your pants on?
I don't know, sir.
You're not.
You're gonna fuck it
with your pants off.
[guy] Dave's balls are gonna
drop today, boys.
[laughter]
You smell like shit.
You guys smell worse
than the goat.
Hey, it's all
gonna be worth it.
In the name of Phi Sig,
you're cleansed.
[indistinct conversation]
Drink out of
the fucking bottle.
Go again. Go again.
One more.
[guys hollering]
A little surprise
or a big one?
We got something special
in store for you.
-That's my limp dick
in your fucking face.
-Fuck!
You're gonna suck
my fucking dick.
Get the fuck
out of---
Don't you
fucking stop...
Don't you fucking
push against me.
Come on.
Shut the fuck up.
-Oh, you're good at that.
-[laughter]
Suck my fucking dick.
You're good at that.
Look at this
fucking faggot.
You know what's coming?
Does that feel nice?
Does that remind you
of high school?
Is that what you did?
Here you go.
Come on.
Suck my fucking...
Fucking faggot.
Come on.
Open your mouth.
Fuck this shit?
Shut the fuck up
and suck my dick.
Do it, you fucking pussy.
Come on.
Suck my fucking dick.
[all singing]
Phi Sig had
a little goat.
Little goat, little goat.
Phi Sig had
a little goat
that you will fuck tonight.
Phi Sig had
a little goat
Little goat, little goat.
Phi Sig had
a little goat
that you will
fuck tonight
Come on.
Let's go, let's go.
[guys hollering]
[guy] Get in there.
Fucking get in there.
Yeah, lock the fucking door.
[imitating goat bleating]
[laughing]
[door opening]
All right, you goat fucks.
Wake the fuck up.
-Let's go.
-[whistling]
Let's go.
Up against the wall here.
Up against the wall.
Get in the corner.
In the corner.
Turn the fuck around.
[clamoring]
[clamoring continues]
You got fucking Lando here.
[laughing and cheering]
[guys cheering]
Get him. Go!
[cheering and hollering]
Get the fuck up.
Yeah!
[Chance] Listen up.
You guys have three hours
to finish this keg of fucking
warm, delicious beer.
What you gotta do,
you gotta ring that bell
when you're done.
Okay?
If you fail,
I can 100% promise you
you're gonna have to
fuck this goat.
Start the music.
-[heavy metal music playing]
-Go!
[door shuts]
Fill it up.
Come on, guys.
-Who else? Who else?
-Give me more.
Come on.
One way to go.
I can't fucking...
Do it.
[music stops]
[groans]
[retching]
It's fucking tapped.
We tapped it.
It's tapped.
It's tapped!
Two, three...
-[rings bell]
-[all cheering]
[all] Whoo!
[banging on door]
[guys hollering]
-Yeah!
-[ululating]
[clamoring]
[ululating]
[all cheering]
[all whooping]
[echoing]
[indistinct conversations]
[Chance] All right.
Shut the fuck up.
Listen to your pledge master.
[Dixon] Okay.
You guys just
completed Hell Week.
Now you don't have to wear
your pledge shirts anymore.
Thank fucking God,
because you guys
fucking stink.
-[laughter]
-Fuck!
However, you're far
from brothers.
Okay? You still have
the rest of the semester to
be our little bitches.
As you know,
this is your Bordelia Dochet
Throw King James
out the window,
this is your new Bible.
Because of the recent
accusations
from our Greek brothers
and the Delta Beta Gama house,
those fucking
pussy-ass retards.
We are obligated to read
a passage from this bitch.
"The Bordelia Dochet maintains
that hazing is
fundamentally at odds
with the ideals of
the Phi Sigma Mu.
Hazing runs contrary
to our core concepts
of brotherhood,
and is prohibited
in all forms.
Any activities intended to
produce harassment,
embarrassment,
blah, blah, blah,
fuck all, will not
be tolerated."
Our initiation is
a rite of passage,
gentlemen.
That's all.
Are we clear on that?
[all] Sir, yes, sir.
Okay.
[guys] I swear allegiance
to God and Phi Sigma Mu.
All my strength is
in my union.
All my danger is in discord.
Therefore, we at
peace henceforth,
and as brothers
live together.
[bagpipe music playing]
[cheers and applause]
[chuckles] You ready?
It was all in good fun, bro.
-Don't worry.
-Sorry.
Tinsley couldn't make it.
Who?
Tinsley, your big brother.
He had like a Spanish
exam or something.
I don't know.
Where's Brad?
You know Brad.
Good job, man.
Mmm, motherfucker.
You excited?
I wanna see you smile.
Yeah? There we go.
That's a fucking smile.
Hey, what's up, man?
What's wrong with you?
Uh, nothing really.
It's just...
I don't think they're
gonna let me in.
What are you
talking about?
Of course you're
gonna get in.
We both are.
Why would they
give me Chance though,
you know?
The dude literally
hates me.
He said to my face
that I don't belong here.
Fuck him.
It's not his decision, man,
all the brothers vote equally.
I just feel like a pussy.
The dude scares
the shit out of me.
Maybe you should
just quit.
I can't quit.
Why not?
The same reason
you can't quit.
I have no fucking idea
why I don't quit.
Yeah, you do.
Everybody does.
Dude, if you quit,
what else is there?
You know? You just
another guy that
couldn't hack it.
And everywhere you go,
everyone's gonna know that.
That's not true.
Bullshit. Yeah, you can't even
go to a party on campus
without seeing them.
It's just the way it is.
I'm having sex for
the first time in my life.
You know I'm not stupid.
Brad, that's not because
of me.
You know,
if the fraternity goes,
everything goes with it.
Don't give up, man.
Hey, we just got
pinned, right?
We're fine.
Where you going?
To clear my head.
I'll see you
back at the room.
Hey.
What's your fucking
problem, man?
What?
"What?"
Why are you acting like
such a fucking asshole
to me?
Whatever, man.
No, I'm fucking
serious, man.
Why, because I didn't feel
like coming to some
bullshit ceremony?
Why the fuck was Wes
the one pinning me tonight,
and not you?
You're lucky it was Wes.
They wanted to give you Dixon
and I stopped them.
What, you think I can't
fucking handle Dixon?
Fuck you, man.
You are un-fucking-believable.
Can you get out of
my room now, please?
No. Not until you tell me
what's going on with you.
Nothing's going on.
Nothing.
This shit
doesn't fucking matter.
That's what you don't get.
Okay?
None of this shit matters
at all.
This shit fucking
matters to me.
-Don't fucking push me.
-What are you gonna do?
You gonna fucking
kick my ass?
-I'm not gonna fight you.
-Why not?
Why not?
Just say it, goddammit!
Because you don't
belong here.
You don't fucking
This is not for you.
Okay.
-Hey...
-No, that's what I thought.
[metal music playing]
Give me some room.
[guys] Oh!
Can't let Baity win.
Land, you goat fuck.
You're a dead man.
Get up against the wall.
No.
I'm sorry. I think...
There's something
in my fucking ear.
What did you say to me?
Fuck you,
I'm not doing that.
I'm not asking.
You do it,
or you're fucking
out of here.
Uh-oh, Land.
Are you being
a naughty goat?
[bleating]
-[guys] Oh!
-Shit!
Head shot, bitches.
Hundred point. Mark it,
Baity, you fat fuck.
Don't just stand there.
-What?
-I think he's really hurt.
You all right, man?
You all right, buddy?
He's fine.
[Chance]
You okay, buddy?
You're a fucking asshole, man.
Whoa.
What the fuck did you
think was gonna happen?
Dude, I'm fine.
Dude, it's cool.
-You all right?
-Yeah, yeah.
-You okay?
-Yeah, I'm good.
Chill the fuck out, brother.
[cell phone vibrating]
Hello?
[man] Is this Brad Land?
Who is this?
Yeah, this is Detective Bert,
with the Dawson Police
Department.
Look, I've left you
several messages.
We really need you to come
down to the station.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
I got your message.
Well, look. I really think
we may have one of the guys
who assaulted you last summer.
Mr. Land?
Are you there?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm here.
Yeah, do you think it would
be possible for you
to come today?
Uh, today? No.
Okay.
How about tomorrow
No, I can't.
Brad, listen.
I know this is tough.
But it's important--
Look, I'm sorry.
I just can't.
Brad. What's going on?
Hey. I'll be back.
What's going on?
I have to get back to work.
Um...
The cops found them, Brett.
They want me to fucking
come in and ID them.
All right. We'll go back
to Dawson tomorrow.
No, I'm not going.
What do you mean?
You have to go back.
No, I can't.
Brad, you have to ID them.
-You have to
fucking punish them.
-No.
Dude, it's taken me
six months to get away
from this shit.
I'm not gonna
go back now.
Fuck.
I did this.
What? No.
Yeah. I made you
fucking come here.
I made you join this
fucking fraternity.
-No!
-Yes.
If I would've just gone home
with you that night,
none of this shit would
have happened.
What are you talking about?
That doesn't have anything to do
with this shit.
It ha to do with you, Brad.
Okay? And how fucked up
everything has been between
us since this summer.
I'm not gonna quit
the frat, okay?
I'm not letting those guys
lay another fucking
hand on you.
Brett...
This is not your decision.
Okay?
I'm gonna go.
Brad...
[door shuts]
-[knock on door]
-[Chance] Knock, knock.
Errand time, Willie.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, I forgot.
What's up?
I need...
I need one egg roll
from Yang's Palace.
Not the one on
Main Street, all right?
You gotta go all the way
to the airport.
Okay? Don't fuck around.
I can tell the difference.
-Yeah.
-All right.
You want anything, Baity?
I don't know.
Let me see a menu.
[clears throat]
How do you...
How do you pronounce
that one?
What are you doing?
[muffled protests]
Let go of his arms.
[Baity laughing]
Oh, that's
fucking incredible.
Now get that egg roll, buddy.
You got an hour.
Go, hustle. Hustle.
[both laughing]
[breathing heavily]
[sighs heavily]
Oh, fuck.
[breathing heavily]
[serene music playing]
[ambulance sirens wailing]
[knocking on door]
What are you doing?
Just cleaning up his shit.
I know.
It's crazy, man.
You hardly even knew him,
you know.
I knew him.
He was my roommate.
I just feel like he didn't
deserve this, you know.
No, he just had
a bad heart, dude.
You wanna stay over
at the house tonight?
I feel like that will be
better than being here.
Okay.
[organ music playing]
[organ music continues]
[whispering indistinctly]
Hey, Brad.
Hey, man.
-Hey, man.
How you doing?
-Good.
-You doing all right?
-Yeah.
Oh, man.
This must be so hard for you.
I can't even imagine.
I can't fucking
imagine, man.
It's been terrible.
Buddy, I mean...
Dude, you know, um...
If you ever want
to talk to anybody,
or anything like that.
If you ever want to talk...
Get anything off your chest,
-you know I'm
here for you, right?
-Yeah.
-Anything. I'm here for you.
-Thanks, dude.
Thanks, Chance.
Yeah, of course, man.
We're actually doing
a little get together tonight
at the house.
Just brothers only.
Just to chat.
No drinking or anything.
Just to talk.
Just trying to deal about
what we're feeling.
Yeah, I don't think I can
come tonight, Chance.
I just think it's important
that we're all there, man.
That's all.
Or else I wouldn't ask.
I just think it's important
that we're all with brothers.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, all right.
Okay, man.
Okay.
Hey, I love you.
All right? Hang in there.
-Yeah.
-See you tonight, okay?
-Okay. You too. Okay.
-I love you.
Yeah.
[door opens]
[door shuts]
Yo, what's up?
Did he call you?
He said the fucking school's
putting us on probation.
What does that mean, man?
What does probation mean?
It doesn't fucking
mean anything yet.
Okay? It just means they're
launching an investigation.
We'll all probably have to
go in and, you know,
fucking talk to the probos.
[Baity]
What the fuck?
He wasn't even here.
He died on campus.
Yeah, well, someone must
have told them about
the concussion, right.
No, it wasn't
the concussion, man.
We gotta stop saying that.
We need to stop saying that.
He went to the infirmary.
They know that it
happened in the house.
I don't fucking know.
Dude, this is serious.
They could kick us
out of school.
This is serious.
Okay. I don't know who's
fucking telling them this.
-Okay?
-[Chance sighs]
-Fuck! Sorry.
-Look...
I'm sorry.
We need to huddle up
on this shit.
Yeah.
All right? We can't be
telling them anything that
they don't even know.
I'm not gonna fucking
lie to them.
If I lose my scholarship,
my dad's gonna
fucking kill me.
No one's fucking
telling you to lie, Baity.
Look, we haven't been
doing anything
that every other
fraternity on campus
hasn't been doing
for the last...
What?
Fucking 100 years.
-Yeah, I know, dude.
-A hundred years.
-Right?
-I know.
-Yeah. Right.
If you don't have an answer,
just say, "I don't know."
[door opens]
Just keep your fucking
mouth shut, Baity.
Go and talk to the pledgers.
Hey...
Brad didn't show up
to the meet up.
[birds chirping]
[telephone ringing]
[door opening]
Come on in, Brad.
[door shuts]
How you holding up, Brad?
I'm fine.
[clears throat]
You and Will were pledging
together, right?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
That's right.
What was that like?
I don't know.
Just normal stuff.
Were they hazing Will?
Come on, man.
They were beating the crap
out of him, right?
What do you think?
I mean...
Just normal
pledge term stuff.
I mean...
You've been here a while.
I mean, I don't
understand what...
Right? He was
running on the track.
It was a heart attack.
He had bruises
all over his body.
He went to the infirmary
for a head injury
the week before he died.
That was the school's
responsibility
to keep this kind of thing
from happening.
It's my duty to make sure
that this kind of behavior
stops.
And you know what?
It's your responsibility--
It's my "responsibility,"
it's your "duty."
Will's dead. He's dead.
Okay? I don't know
what else to tell you.
Brad, just tell me
what happened.
[exhales]
Dude. Where have
you been, man?
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Okay?
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
What are you
talking about?
The fraternity just
got suspended for
the rest of the year.
What?
Yeah. Somebody
fucking talked, dude.
It's over.
It wasn't you, was it?
No.
I mean, what the fuck
was all that for?
Dude, we never
even got in.
Dude, I had offers, like,
anywhere. All right?
I could have pledged
anywhere at this school.
I don't even care if it sounds
like bragging at this point,
you know.
This is fucked up, dude.
All of that for noth--
Oh, fuck!
Oh, my God!
[bleats]
Fucking laxatives, dude.
Fuck that, dude.
Fuck!
[door shuts]
[students chatting]
[laughing]
-Yo, Chance.
-Who the fuck did that?
Whoa.
I don't know what
you're talking about, rat.
Where's Brett?
No, no. You're not talking
to your brother right now.
You're not talking
You're talking to Baity and
you're talking to me.
Okay. get out of my way.
I need to speak to my brother.
Can I ask you
a serious question?
Where do you get the fucking
balls to show your face
in this house
after you ratted on me?
I didn't fucking rat on you.
Shit. You're gonna
lie to me?
You're gonna fucking
We know it was you.
Just fucking admit it.
No.
Admit you're the rat,
or I'm gonna kick
your fucking ass.
How about that?
-I'm not a fucking rat.
-[spits]
What are you
gonna do, dude?
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna lie to me?
-You're gonna lie to me?
-Chance! Chill the fuck out.
No, dude. No.
Fuck you.
No, no.
Your brother's done, man.
-Leave him alone.
-No, I don't care, man.
He's fucking done.
I love you. But actually
you might wanna go upstairs.
Actually you might
wanna go upstairs.
-'Cause I'm gonna lay in--
-Don't you fucking touch him.
Fuck you, man!
I helped his ass
after he got his
fucking ass beat.
I got him into this
fucking class, man.
I stuck my neck out
for this fucking pussy.
And now, dude,
he fucking
ratted on us, man.
Your brother's a rat.
How do you
feel about that?
No, he's not.
I am.
What?
I fucking told
them everything.
All right?
What did you say?
This shit doesn't
fucking matter.
Okay? None of it.
I don't care anymore.
I just don't fucking care.
It's all fucking bullshit.
Someone's fucking dead.
You're a piece of shit.
-Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
-Don't you fucking touch me.
I'll kill the fucking asshole.
-Chill out, bro.
-What you gonna do?
You're a pussy like
your faggot brother.
What are you gonna do?
Motherfucker.
Brett, come on.
What the fuck are you doing?
Yo, what the fuck?
[panting]
I'm fucking done.
Come on. Come on.
You okay?
[sombre music]
Hey, fellas.
Can I see Brad
just for a second?
-How are you?
-Hi.
Hey, listen. Before we go in,
I wanted to show you something.
That's one of the guys,
isn't it?
So last week,
he makes bail.
That night he goes out and
tries to rob a gas station.
Shot three times
in the chest.
The guy's already
in there.
Before we go in though,
I want you to
think back on that night.
Any detail you
can remember.
Anything about their face,
anything about their body.
Any distinguishing marks
that might help you
identify them.
All right?
All right. Let's do this.
Remember.
They can't see you.
So just take your time.
When you're ready...
Tell me if you recognize
any one of them.
No.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I don't see him here.
Well...
We can actually place
one of them
in the vicinity that night.
So are you sure you
don't wanna take your time?
Yeah, I don't see him.
Okay.
Did you let that guy off?
I don't know.
They all look
the same, you know.
[exhales]
None of this is your fault,
you know.
[exhales]
[sombre music]
This is the spot.
[car door shuts]
[sombre music continues]