[Shoveling]
[Elephant Trumpets]
♪ [Circus, Calliope]
♪
[Ringmaster]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IF I MAY HAVE YOUR ATTENTION.
THE BELOVED FOUNDER
OF THE FLYING SABATINIS,
FORMERLY OF THE FAMED
FANTASTIC SABATINIS,
AND ORIGINATOR...
OF SIX SABATINIS
OF HIS OWN,
IN THIS...
HIS LAST PERFORMANCE.
"DRY YOUR EYES.
NO MAN MINDS
IF A BEAUTIFUL GIRL...
WIPES OFF HER TEARS
WITH HIS SHIRT.
TODAY IT IS
MY LAST WISH...
THAT YOU ALL REMEMBER ME,
MAX SABATINI,
AS I LIVED...
AND NOT AS I DIED."
[MAN] DAMN.
OOP, I'M LATE.
"SO, IN THIS, MY SYMBOLIC
FINAL TRIP ACROSS THE WIRE,
LAZLO, MY LOYAL FRIEND
AND PROTÉGÉ,
SHALL PERFORM
FOR MAX SABATINI.
♪ [Drumroll]
WHEN A MOTHER CALLS HER SON
A BASTARD,
YOU CAN TAKE HER WORD FOR IT.
- FOSTER, MAX TOLD ME
TO GIVE YOU THIS NOTE.
- NOW?
- HE SAID, "AT THE GRAVE."
- "I LEARNED THIS AS A YOUNG MAN
FROM MY FATHER,
WHO LEARNED IT FROM HIS FATHER
BEFORE HIM, WHO LEARNED IT
FROM HIS FATHER BEFORE THAT."
"FOSTER, THE PLAID SPORTS
JACKET WOULD'VE BEEN
MUCH BETTER. LOVE, MAX."
"ALWAYS REMEMBER,
GOD GIVES ONE...
A LEATHER BOTTLE
FULL OF GOLD.
THE DEVIL GIVES
A GOLDEN BOTTLE
FULL OF SHIT.
[Gasping]
LOVE, MAX."
OH.
[Burps]
YOU'VE BEEN CALLED HERE TODAY
TO HEAR THE LAST WILL
AND TESTAMENT OF MAX SABATINI,
YOUR FATHER,
YOUR DEAR FRIEND AND MINE.
- ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS
BEFORE I BEGIN?
- JUST GET ON WITH IT, JULES.
[Clears Throat]
"SAD AS I AM TO DISBAND
THE SABATINI CIRCUS,
THE MONEY FROM ITS SALE
IS TO BE DIVIDED...
BETWEEN MY DAUGHTERS
AND YOU, ALL MY DEAR FRIENDS,
FOR MY ONLY SON FOSTER
CHOSE LONG AGO
TO ABANDON THE CIRCUS...
OF HIS FATHER,
AND HIS FATHER'S FATHER,
AND HIS FATHER'S FATHER."
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE, JULES,
COULD YOU JUST GET ON WITH IT?
[Clears Throat]
"SO, TRUSTING THAT ONCE BURNED,
FOSTER WILL FIND IT
IN HIS HEART...
TO NOT LET ME DOWN
IN MY GRAVE,
I AM ENTRUSTING HIM
WITH MY THREE
MOST VALUABLE POSSESSIONS.
- [Shouts] WHAT?
- TO HIM?
"FOSTER,
MY BELOVED SON AND HEIR,
I LEAVE MY THREE BABIES:
RUSTY, TIGA AND POPPY."
- [Laughing]
- "MOST VALUABLE
POSSESSIONS"!
THE APES?
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED
TO DO WITH THE APES?
PLEASE, A LITTLE RESPECT.
"TO ASSURE FOSTER'S BEING ABLE
TO CARE FOR MY BABIES,
- LAZLO SHALL GO WITH HIM."
- LAZLO?
"AN ANNUAL STIPEND
SHALL COVER ANY AND ALL
EXPENSES INCURRED.
- EVER SEEN
THOSE APES...
- POOP?
"TO MY TRUSTED ATTORNEY,
JULES COHEN,
FOSTER WILL PERIODICALLY
RECEIVE MY INSTRUCTIONS...
AS TO THE DETAILS
OF THIS BEQUEST,
AND FOR HIS CARING
AND LOVING THEM AS I HAVE
FOR TWO FULL YEARS."
I GIVE HIM
TWO MINUTES!
TERRIFIC.
LOOK, JULES, I DON'T WANT
THE FILTHY BEASTS.
"I KNOW HE WILL LOVE THEM
AS I HAVE.
I THEREFORE BEQUEATH
MY ONLY SON FOSTER
MY ENTIRE ESTATE...
OF $5 MILLION."
HE DID IT TO GET EVEN.
HE NEVER FORGAVE ME
FOR LEAVING THE CIRCUS.
DID I EVER TELL YOU ABOUT THE
TIMES AS A CHILD HE CARRIED ME
UP ON THE WIRE WITH HIM?
HE USED TO DROP ME
INTO THE NET.
THE FIRST TIME
HE DIDN'T TELL ME
THERE WAS A NET.
- I NEVER THOUGHT MAX
WAS A CRUEL MAN.
- TO HIM IT WAS A BIG JOKE!
ALL THE SABATINIS
DROPPED THEIR KIDS
FROM THREE STORIES.
HIS FATHER,
AND HIS FATHER'S FATHER.
BE CAREFUL.
DON'T MIX UP
THE BABE'S SPLINTERS
WITH ONES FROM THE CROSS.
- YOU MEAN IT MATTERS?
- VERY FUNNY.
FOSTER, LISTEN,
MAYBE IF YOU TALKED
TO YOUR SISTERS,
YOU COULD WORK OUT
SOME SORT OF EXCHANGE
WITH THEM.
ARE YOU KIDDING? THEY'D BE
SO HAPPY TO SEE ME BURIED UP
TO MY NECK IN CAMEL CACA.
FOSTER.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
ABOUT THE ORANGUTANS?
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
THAT I HAVE NO INTEGRITY
BECAUSE I DROPPED OUT OF TWO
COLLEGES.
THREE.
AND YOU BELIEVE I'M UNDEPENDABLE
AND CHEAP AND CAN'T HOLD DOWN
A JOB. ADMIT IT.
BUT I DON'T NEED
MAX SABATINI'S MONEY.
IT'S NOT AS THOUGH
I DON'T HAVE A GOING BUSINESS
RIGHT HERE.
I'VE BEEN HAPPY
WITHOUT SICK "LOVE MAXIMS,"
WITHOUT THE CIRCUS
AND WITHOUT MAX SABATINI.
WOULD YOU GIVE ME A HAND
WITH THIS DESK?
- DESK?
- GOTTA MAKE ROOM
FOR THEM GODDAMN CAGES.
[Banging Sound]
TIGA, I GOTTA GET YOU PAST
ZABREWSKI'S, SO COOL IT.
TIGA, HE'S GONNA HEAR YOU.
PLEASE, SHH.
- WHAT'S DOING
WITH ALL THE CLUMPING AND...
- AH, MR. ZABREWSKI!
ALL'S WELL.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
IT'S JUST A LITTLE HEAVY.
- I SUPPOSE YOU WANT
SOME HELP.
- AH, NO, NO.
EVERYTHING'S UNDER CONTROL.
I WON'T NEED ANY HELP.
I CAN DO IT JUST FINE MYSELF.
ALL IS WELL, MR. ZABREWSKI.
YEAH?
WHAT'S IN THE BOX?
AH... ANTIQUES!
MY FATHER, HE SENT ME
SOME VALUABLE ANTIQUES.
- FRAGILE.
- ANTIQUES?
THEY'VE BEEN IN THE FAMILY
FOR YEARS.
[Sniffs]
THEY STINK!
YEAH, WELL,
THEY'RE VERY OLD.
I HOPE YOU'LL BE HAPPY,
FOSTER.
WILL YOU STOP?
I TOLD YOU,
IT'LL JUST BE UNTIL I CAN
FIGURE A WAY TO CHANGE
MAX'S WILL A LITTLE.
CALL ME SOMEDAY
AND TELL ME ABOUT IT.
I'LL SEND A CAB
FOR MY THINGS.
WON'T YOU JUST STAY
AND MEET THEM?
SURE, WHY NOT?
I'M A GOOD SPORT.
GREAT! WHICH ONE
DO YOU WANNA MEET FIRST?
AREN'T THEY ALL
THE SAME?
NO WAY.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE 'EM.
OK, RUSTY,
COME ON OUT, LITTLE GUY.
THIS IS RUSTY.
HE'S THE MALE.
- THERE'RE THREE OF THEM?
- NO, THE OTHERS ARE BIGGER.
[Spits]
TIGA!
TIGA, MEET CYNTHIA.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
TIGA, PLEASE...
MEET CYNTHIA!
- AAH!
- GO ON, GET OUTTA HERE.
HEY, OK.
CYNTHIA, MEET POPPY.
THIS IS POPPY.
POPPY, MEET CYNTHIA.
POPPY, MEET CYNTHIA!
THANKS.
- DON'T TELL ME THEY CAN WRITE!
- NO, I THINK IT'S FROM JULES.
EEEK!
IT'S FROM MAX!
- MAX IS DEAD.
- I TOLD YOU
HE'D HAUNT ME.
- READ IT!
- IT SAYS NOT TO READ IT
IN FRONT OF...
- IN FRONT OF WHAT?
- IN FRONT OF THEM.
[Cynthia]
COME ON NOW!
"THE CHICKEN OF LOVE
HAS OFTEN CRAWLED
FROM THE EGG OF PITY.
NOW YOU HAVE MY BABIES.
WILL YOU TAKE THEM
AS I HAVE...
WITH GENEROSITY,
LOVE AND AFFECTION?
IF FOR ANY REASON ANY
OF THE ORANGUTANS SHOULD
GET SICK OR, GOD FORBID, DIE,
YOU'LL FORFEIT THE INHERITANCE
AND THE ENTIRE FIVE MILLION...
WILL GO TO
THE ZOOLOGICAL SOCIETY,
WHO HAVE PROMISED TO HOUSE
AND FEED THE SURVIVORS,
AND THEN WHEN THEY PASS ON,
TO STUFF THEM."
POPPY?
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS DOING?
WATCH OUT!
NOBODY'S GONNA STUFF YOU!
FOSTER, GRAB THEM!
[Cynthia Screams]
HELP! FOSTER!
[Foster]
I'M GONNA KILL YOU GUYS!
NO, I MEAN I'M NOT!
[Cynthia]
OH!
POPPY! TIGA, NO!
TIGA! DAMN IT, STOP IT!
- [Foster]
CUT IT OUT!
- [Cynthia] OH, MY GOD!
CYNTHIA, WAIT!
[Knocking At Door]
CYNTHIA!
IF YOU DON'T CLOSE THE DOOR
IN THE EVENING, YOU CAN'T
OPEN IT IN THE MORNING.
LOVE MAX-A.
WE HAVE TO DECIDE
WHAT TO DO ABOUT
THE SABATINI LEGACY.
WHAT'S THERE TO DECIDE?
WE DON'T GET ONE PENNY...
UNLESS MAX SABATINI'S SON FAILS
TO FULFILL HIS DUTIES.
AND FROM WHAT
I UNDERSTAND IS...
ONLY ONE OF THE DAMN BEASTS
HAS TO DIE FOR HIM
TO LOSE THE FIVE MILLION.
ARE YOU SURE?
[Woman]
HOW'S THEIR HEALTH?
DISGUSTINGLY EXCELLENT.
SABATINI FED THEM WITH...
UH, UH...
ON. FED THEM ON
ORGANIC BANANAS.
YOU CAN ALWAYS HAVE THEM...
BUMPED OFF.
BRANDON, HOW DARE YOU?
HOW COULD YOU SUGGEST
SUCH A THING?
THE WALLS HAVE EARS.
WHAT GRIDLEY'S SAYING
IS "DON'T TALK ABOUT IT,
DO IT!"
DO IT?
DO... "IT"!
WELL...
"IT" COSTS MONEY.
AAH!
JESUS CHRIST!
LISTEN, YOU GOTTA
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING.
THERE ARE MOMENTS
A PERSON NEEDS TO HIMSELF
AROUND HERE.
YOU HEAR THAT?
THIS ROOM'S OFF-LIMITS
TO YOU GUYS.
OK, WHERE'S
THE REST OF THE ZOO?
EVERYBODY UP.
UH-UH, NO WAY.
THERE WILL BE NO WALKS
UNTIL AFTER BREAKFAST.
I HAVEN'T EVEN HAD
MY COFFEE YET.
NO! N-O, NO!
POPPY, THAT'S NOT FOR YOU.
I HAVEN'T READ...
LISTEN, IF YOU GUYS ARE GONNA
LIVE HERE, YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO LEARN A FEW RULES.
- POPPY? POPPY, I SAID...
- [Door Slams Shut]
WHO TURNED OFF THE COFFEE?
TIGA, I LIKE COFFEE.
I DRINK COFFEE.
AND I DON'T CARE
WHAT MAX DOES... DID.
RUSTY, GET UP!
COME ON, DAMN IT.
I'M IN NO MOOD.
RUSTY?
LAZLO? LAZLO?
- [Sneezing]
- OH, NO!
LET'S SEE.
RUSTY!
[Knocking On Door]
[Knocking]
[Cynthia] IT'S ME!
WHY DID YOU LOCK THE DOOR?
I DIDN'T WANT
ANY DRAFTS.
- THANK GOD YOU'RE HERE.
YOU WOULD NOT BELIEVE...
- FOSTER.
I TOLD YOU I NEED
SOME TIME ALONE.
YOU PROMISED!
I KNOW I PROMISED,
BUT THIS IS AN EMERGENCY!
DID YOU SEE ZABREWSKI?
NO. FOSTER, THE MAN
LIVES HERE. YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO TELL HIM.
- YOU CAN'T HIDE THIS ZOO
FOR TWO YEARS.
- I'LL TELL HIM.
I'LL TELL HIM
WHEN THE TIME IS RIGHT.
WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
HIS TEMPERATURE'S 117 DEGREES.
- SHIT. THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
HE'D BE DEAD!
- SHH.
- THEY'RE VERY SUGGESTIBLE.
- FOSTER, THEY'RE ANIMALS!
AH, RUSTY.
HIS TEMPERATURE
JUST HIT 135 DEGREES.
SHOULD WE BURY HIM NOW?
- WHAT?
- I HATE TO TELL YOU,
BUT RUSTY IS A FAKE.
[Foster]
NOW SEE WHAT YOU'VE DONE?
I TOLD YOU
HE WAS VERY SUGGESTIBLE.
BESIDES, YOU HAVEN'T EVEN HEARD
HIM SNEEZE YET.
[Sneezing]
THERE, YOU SEE?
DID YOU BRING THE CHICKEN SOUP?
I WASN'T SURE
WHETHER HE WANTED
MATZO BALLS OR KREPLACH,
SO I BROUGHT BOTH.
[Tea Kettle Whistling]
MY GOOD BOY RUSTY!
SEE? ISN'T IT FANTASTIC
WHAT A LITTLE CHICKEN SOUP
WILL DO?
[Speaking Italian]
I TOLD YOU,
I DON'T CARE HOW MUCH MONEY
YOU GOT.
I AIN'T INTERESTED.
- I DON'T DO THAT NO MORE.
- WE DON'T DO IT
NO MORE.
IT AIN'T THE SAME THING.
THESE AIN'T PEOPLE.
THEY'RE APES!
I GOT EIGHT YEARS FOR
THE LAST GORILLA I ROBBED.
[Laughing]
HEY, JOEY,
HOW YOU EATIN', HUH?
I'M EATIN' GOOD.
LOOK AT THE CALAMARI.
DELICIOUS!
NO, I MEAN HOW YOU PAYIN'
YOUR BILLS?
I GOT FRIENDS.
- THEY OWE ME FAVORS.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
- YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
LOOK. I'LL MAKE IT
THREE THOUSAND, ALL RIGHT?
PASS ME THE BUTTER.
$3,000 IS A LOT OF MONEY,
HUH, JOE?
BAD HABIT, HUH?
[Speaking Italian]
LISTEN, GODDAMN IT.
I'M TELLING YOU, IT'S A
CAKEWALK! I COULD DO IT MYSELF!
- YEAH? THEN WHY
DON'T YOU?
- YEAH, WHY DON'T YOU?
I'LL MAKE IT FIVE THOUSAND.
[Coughing, Wheezing]
- BUT YOU GOTTA DO IT
WITH US.
- DO IT WITH US, THAT'S RIGHT.
[Gulps]
ALL RIGHT.
I WILL. BUT YOU CAN'T
TELL NOBODY, RIGHT?
[Chuckling]
SALUTE.
YEAH. SALUTE.
FOR THE LIFE OF ME, CYNTHIA,
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOU SEE IN HIM.
AFTER ALL THE PRIVATE SCHOOLS
YOUR FATHER AND I SENT YOU TO,
YOU WIND UP...
I HAVEN'T WOUND UP WITH ANYONE.
I WOUND DOWN.
I MOVED OUT.
THEN WHY DOES
MY DALI SKETCH STILL HANG
IN HIS APARTMENT?
BECAUSE I FORGOT IT.
AND TO BE HONEST,
I DON'T REALLY WANNA GO BACK.
MY THIRD HUSBAND GAVE ME
THAT SKETCH.
I'M NOT LEAVING IT TO BE
DESTROYED BY THOSE BEASTS.
THEY'RE NEVER LEFT ALONE,
MOTHER.
BESIDES, HE'S GOT LAZLO.
- WHAT'S A LAZLO?
- HE CAME WITH THE APES.
- CYNTHIA, YOU GOING UP
TO FOSTER'S?
- HI, MARVIN. YEAH.
WOULD YOU MIND TAKING
A COUPLE THINGS UP?
I'M RUNNING LATE.
SURE.
THANKS A BUNCH!
YOU'RE WELCOME.
♪ [Piano Scales]
OH, BY THE WAY,
THE APES?
DON'T SAY ANYTHING
YOU DON'T WANT THEM TO HEAR.
THEY UNDERSTAND EVERYTHING.
GREAT! MAYBE SOMEBODY
IN THIS APARTMENT
CAN GET A DECENT JOB.
[Doorbell Buzzes]
THERE IS NO WOMAN
WITHOUT SOME HARDNESS,
AND NO MAN
WITHOUT SOME SOFTNESS.
LOVE MAX-A.
WILL YOU TAKE CARE
OF TIGA?
- IT'S GREAT TO SEE YOU.
- FOSTER, THIS IS FIONA.
SHH!
FROM NOW ON, RING TWICE...
TWO SHORT, ONE LONG.
JUST OUT OF CURIOSITY,
WHY?
HOW DO YOU DO,
MRS. GOODWIN?
I'M FOSTER.
I WASN'T SURE.
IT'S TIGA.
SHE'S... SHE'S STILL
LEARNING TO DEAL WITH YOU.
- TO DEAL WITH ME?
- YEAH, WELL, SHE'S...
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
TO SAY IT, CYNTHIA.
SHE'S JEALOUS.
WELL, YOU JUST TELL HER
THAT I DON'T WANT
ANYTHING SHE WANTS.
I MOVED OUT. I HATE FRUIT.
AND I NEVER USE SAWDUST
FOR MY TOILET!
THIS IS FOR YOU.
ANYTHING ELSE
WE SHOULD KNOW ABOUT?
NOW THAT YOU MENTION IT,
UM,
THE WICKER CHAIR
NEAR THE WINDOW?
- POPPY LIKES TO SIT IN IT.
- SO DON'T SIT IN THE WICKER
CHAIR WHILE SHE'S IN IT, RIGHT?
- NO. EVER.
- EVER?
EVER.
WE GOTTA WALK AROUND HERE
LIKE WE BELONG HERE.
THE SECRET OF THIS
IS TO ACT... "INSCAPICUOUS."
- I KNOW THAT.
- ME TOO.
AH, WHAT DID YOU DO?
[Groans]
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
HEY, DON'T BREAK MY SHOES, HUH?
I'M A PROFESSIONAL.
I DO MY HOMEWORK.
- YEAH, WE DO OUR HOMEWORK.
- [Chuckling]
YO!
HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
OFF THE SCAFFOLD.
- [Buzzer Rings]
- SUNTAN LOTION.
[Audience Applauds]
[TV, Indistinct]
[Birds Chirping]
ON WHAT BASIS DOES SHE SELECT
THE BOOKS SHE WANTS?
- [Chewing]
- NEVER MIND.
THEY'RE QUITE LIKEABLE
ONCE YOU GET TO KNOW
THEIR IDIOSYNCRASIES.
NO, NO.
JUST LET HER
GET TO KNOW YOU.
IF YOU SPEAK TO HER FIRMLY,
SHE'LL RESPOND,
MRS. GOODWIN.
FIRMLY. IF YOU SO MUCH
AS TOUCH THIS HAT AGAIN,
YOU BOWLEGGED BABOON,
I'LL KICK YOUR
HAIRY ASS CRIMSON.
SHUT YOUR FURRY FACE!
SEE?
- HEY, HABIT,
START PAINTING, HUH?
- HEY, I'M GONNA PAINT.
WE'LL BE OFF THIS THING
IN A MINUTE.
[Speaking Gibberish
Foreign Language]
HMM?
[TV, Indistinct]
HEY. WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT THING?
WILL YOU STOP
BREAKIN' MY CHOPS?
GO TO WORK.
I'M CONCENTRATING.
- IT'S A PERISCOPE,
DOPE.
- GREAT.
[Joey]
I GOT ONE.
THIS IS FANTASTIC.
THIS IS BUCK SOUP!
ATTABOY.
NOW JUST DON'T MOVE.
- LET ME LOOK.
- WHAT'S THERE TO LOOK?
- IT'S ONLY A MONKEY.
- I WANNA LOOK!
- [Birds Chirping]
- OH, MY!
LAZLO!
[Gibberish]
ARE YOU CRAZY?
YOU'RE ABOUT TO KILL A LADY!
- HOW CAN YOU TELL
THE SEX FROM HERE?
- A LADY, DUMMY.
- A STACKED LADY.
- SHE DIDN'T LOOK
SO STACKED TO ME.
♪ [Humming]
FIONA? FIONA, PLEASE.
THE CHAIR, REMEMBER?
GIMME THIS THING!
I SAY WE SHOOT THIS ONE.
WAIT! NO!
JOEY, I'M TELLIN' YA,
THAT AIN'T NO MONKEY!
YEAH? WELL,
IF THAT AIN'T NO MONKEY,
THEN I'M A PURPLE-ASS BABOON...
- BECAUSE THAT THING'S GOT HAIR
ALL OVER IT.
- WAIT, LET ME.
AH... TELL YOU WHAT, JOEY,
I'LL LOOK THROUGH THIS THING,
AND WHEN I TELL YOU TO SHOOT,
YOU COME SHOOT, OK?
NO! HEY,
I'M A PROFESSIONAL HERE.
[Joey]
EITHER YOU TRUST ME
OR YOU DON'T TRUST ME.
- GET OUTTA MY WAY.
- TRUST YOU? I'M NOT GONNA
BE PART OF ANY MURDER.
COME ON, GUYS, COOL IT.
YOU'RE MESSIN' UP
MY WHOLE JOB.
[Yelling, Arguing]
- I CAN'T HOLD ON TO YOU!
- OHHH!
- DON'T LET GO, JOEY!
- I GOTCHA, I GOTCHA!
WHAT, ARE YOU CRAZY?
HELP, HELP!
[Screams]
GIVE ME A HAND OVER HERE.
I CAN'T HOLD YOU!
OH!
[Screams]
♪ [Romantic]
[Doorbell Buzzes]
- YOU REMEMBERED THE RING.
TERRIFIC.
- WHAT'S THE SURPRISE?
- I MADE VEAL PICCATA.
- THAT'S THE SURPRISE?
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE!
YOU DON'T GIVE A PERSON
A CHANCE.
I THOUGHT WE COULD DO THIS
KINDA NICE, YOU KNOW.
AFTER DINNER AND STUFF.
[Birds Chirping]
OHH.
♪ [Romantic Continues]
OK, DINNER'S OVER.
WHAT'S THE SURPRISE?
- DON'T LET ANYONE EVER KID YOU.
YOU'RE NO ROMANTIC.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE SURPRISE?
I WANTED TO DO IT FIRST,
AND THEN TELL YOU ABOUT IT.
- BUT IF YOU GOTTA KNOW...
- I GOTTA KNOW.
[Foster]
I'M GONNA TALK TO JULES.
- [Cynthia]
MAX'S LAWYER?
- YEAH.
I'M GONNA OFFER HIM
A MILLION BUCKS
TO CHANGE THE WILL.
TO SAY THAT HE FOUND
SOME HIDDEN ENVELOPE THAT SAYS
MAX CHANGED HIS MIND AND...
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE GONNA TRY TO BRIBE
MAX'S LOYAL BEST FRIEND
AND ATTORNEY?
THAT'S YOUR SURPRISE?
WHY NOT?
A MILLION BUCKS
AIN'T EXACTLY CHICKEN FEED.
- FOSTER, THAT'S ILLEGAL!
YOU COULD GO TO JAIL!
- WHO WOULD KNOW?
- THE MAN'S HUMAN.
- AND YOU'RE CRAZY!
MY MOTHER WAS RIGHT, AND
SHE DOES LOVE TO BE RIGHT.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I THOUGHT YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
IT'S FUNNY, FOSTER.
I MUST BE CRAZY, TOO,
'CAUSE YOU KNOW WHAT?
I AM SURPRISED!
[Birds Chirping]
I REALLY CAN'T BELIEVE HER,
POPPY.
ALL SHE SEES
IS HER OWN REALITY.
I DON'T THINK IT'S THAT HARD
TO UNDERSTAND.
YOU'D UNDERSTAND,
WOULDN'T YOU?
I EVEN MADE VEAL PICCATA.
IT'S DELICIOUS! TRY IT.
- [Spits]
- GOOD, HUH?
- [Chuckling]
- MORNING, LAZLO.
- HOW WAS THE MOVIE?
- OH, WHAT'S...
NEVER MIND.
FORGET IT, FORGET IT.
THAT GIRL.
THREE YEARS OF MY LIFE.
WHO WOULD'VE BELIEVED IT?
[Gibberish]
AN ITALIAN LOVE STORY?
- I GET IT.
WILL YOU PICK THAT UP NOW?
- NO, NO, NO.
[Gibberish]
- AAAH!
- LAZLO, WHAT'S WRONG?
THE "GRAMP"!
THE "GRAMP" IN MY SWORD!
WILL YOU STOP IT?
[Lazlo Speaking Gibberish]
"VERONA"!
IS FRUIT HEAD.
"VERONA."
HUH?
FRU...
YOU MEAN CYNTHIA'S MOTHER,
FIONA?
THE COWS
HAVE MORE RESPECT...
FOR THE UGLIEST BULL...
THAN THE HANDSOMEST OX.
LOVE MAX-A.
[Changing Stations]
♪ [Loud Rock]
HEY! NOBODY SAID
YOU COULD DO THAT.
♪ [Soft Rock]
- ♪ [Loud Rock]
- WILL YOU SHUT THAT OFF?
♪ [Loud Rock Continues]
POPPY, COOL IT!
- [Changing Stations]
- ♪ [Soft Rock]
LAZLO,
WHAT'S SHE LOOKING AT?
WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
IT'S JUST HAIR, A LITTLE HAIR.
IT'S A HAIR.
OH, CHRIST. SO SHE WAS HERE.
SHE'S A GOOD FRIEND.
- ♪ [Loud Rock]
- WILL YOU SHUT THAT OFF?
- I SAID OFF!
- ♪ [Loud Rock Continues]
LAZLO, DO SOMETHING!
MOTHER, I THOUGHT
YOU'D BE READY.
I WANTED TO PRACTICE
A FEW MORE KICKS!
YOU'RE ALREADY A BROWN BELT.
AREN'T YOU GETTING A BIT
CARRIED AWAY?
[Karate Shout]
READ THE NEWSPAPERS.
I'M A BLACK BELT.
OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
HOW'S P.T. BARNUM?
HAVE THEY CLIMBED
THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING YET?
I MAY NOT LIKE FOSTER
VERY MUCH AT THE MOMENT,
BUT I DO LOVE HIM.
IF YOU EVER GET TO KNOW HIM,
YOU MIGHT LOVE HIM TOO.
LIKE A BOA CONSTRICTOR
LOVES A MONGOOSE.
I THINK THAT'S A COBRA.
YOU SEE, POISON!
-HE WANTS ME TO DYE MY HAIR RED.
-[Karate Shout]
HAND ME A WRENCH.
I'M GETTING TIRED
OF THESE HASSLES.
SNEAKING BY ZABREWSKI'S
APARTMENT LIKE HE'S THE WARDEN.
IT'S DEGRADING.
NO MORE SNEAKING!
WORSE, CYNTHIA DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND,
SHE'S STILL PISSED.
AND OVER NOTHING.
- PISSED!
- BECAUSE I ASKED HER
TO DYE HER HAIR RED.
HOLY SHIT!
FOSTER.
FOSTER, CINDY.
WILL YOU CUT THE CRAP?
- BETWEEN YOUR MOVIES
AND MAX'S...
- CYNTHIA! SOMETHING SPECIAL.
[Gibberish]
BUY.
YOU MEAN,
BUY HER SOMETHING!
NO BREAD WITHOUT YEAST.
AH.
AREN'T THEY EXQUISITE?
IT'S TRULY BEAUTIFUL HERE.
- I DIDN'T WANNA GO
TO THE PARK.
- OH?
IT'S TOO CLOSE
TO THE ZOO.
- I LOVED THE SUSHI.
- YEAH?
ME TOO.
CYNTHIA,
I WISH YOU'D RECONSIDER
MOVING BACK IN.
YOU JUST GOT ME TO WALK
BACK IN. DON'T PUSH IT.
YOU KNOW,
I MADE A DECISION.
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
I'M GONNA DO SOMETHING.
I AM. IT'S JUST GONNA TAKE
LONGER TO PULL IT OFF.
- HONEST?
- HONEST.
LEGAL?
I WANT YOU TO KNOW I THINK
YOU'VE BEEN PRETTY TERRIFIC
THROUGH THIS WHOLE THING.
- I KNOW IT HASN'T
BEEN ANY FUN.
- I HAVEN'T DONE MUCH.
BUT YOU HAVE, REALLY!
IT HASN'T GONE UNAPPRECIATED
EITHER.
I THINK YOU'VE BEEN
REALLY TERRIFIC.
ANYWAY,
I WANT YOU
TO HAVE THIS.
FOSTER, THEY'RE ELEGANT!
THEY'RE REAL ANTIQUES.
THANK YOU!
MUST'VE COST A FORTUNE.
- HEY, YOU SURE
THIS IS GONNA WORK?
- IT'LL WORK!
BECAUSE I'M GONNA DAMN WELL
MAKE SURE THAT IT WORKS.
WELL, IT BETTER.
I JUST GOT THE WORD THAT
WE'RE RUNNIN' OUT OF TIME.
OH, YEAH?
I THOUGHT YOU TOLD ME THAT YOU
DON'T WANT NO ONE TO GET HURT.
YEAH, THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU DIDN'T WANT NOBODY
TO GET HURT.
THAT WAS BEFORE.
REMEMBER NOW,
IT'S THE FIRST DOOR
NEXT TO THE APES.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU MIGHT NOT NEED THOSE.
- YOU READY?
- YEAH.
WELL, COME IN!
[Door Slams Shut]
SO, YOU'VE COME!
HOW WONDERFUL!
JUST AS HE SAID
YOU WOULD.
WELCOME!
- I THINK WE
INTERRUPTED SOMETHING.
- OH, NO, YOU DIDN'T.
CAMEROON SAID,
"THREE ANGELS IN WHITE
SHALL APPEAR BEFORE YOU."
- CAMEROON?
- MY GUIDE.
MY INDIAN GUIDE.
BUT YOU MUST KNOW HIM.
HE COMES
FROM WHENCE YOU COME.
WE DON'T COME FROM WHENCE.
WE JUST CAME
FROM THE FREIGHT ELEVATOR.
LOOK, LADY,
WHAT I WANT...
- THE ANGELS IN WHITE.
- WE AIN'T NO ANGELS.
[Chanting Magic Words]
[Chanting Continues]
CAREFUL!
DON'T TOUCH ANYTHING!
WE DON'T WANNA LEAVE ANY PRINTS.
I DON'T LIKE THE FEEL
OF THIS PLACE.
I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU
LIKE. GET YOUR ASS IN GEAR.
WHEN THESE TANKS BLOW,
THEM MONKEYS GONNA BE NOTHIN'
BUT A MEMORY.
YEAH,
"TANKS" FOR THE MEMORY.
[Chuckles]
YOU SEE? I TOLD YOU
IT WOULDN'T TAKE LONG
BEFORE THEY'D GET TO YOU.
OH, I CAN'T BEAR TO SEE
ANY CHILD SUFFER.
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU BETTER GET DOWN?
THESE FLOORS ARE...
NAW, IT'S GREAT.
COME ON UP.
THANK GOD FOR
THE HORSE RACES.
IMAGINE, A WHOLE DAY
WITHOUT ZABREWSKI.
SOONER OR LATER ZABREWSKI'S
GOTTA FIND OUT. WHY NOT
JUST GO TO HIM AND EXPLAIN...
ARE YOU CRAZY?
HE JUST GAVE D'ANGELO UPSTAIRS
A WARNING FOR TWO GOLDFISH.
AND YOU CAN'T EVEN SMELL
GOLDFISH CRAP.
YOU MEAN TIGA THE QUEEN DOES
THAT KIND OF THING?
SHH. NOT SO LOUD.
SHE'LL HEAR YOU.
- THERE'S SOMEBODY
LOOKIN' AT ME.
- WHO?
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT THEY GOT BROWN EYES.
[Gas Hissing]
JOEY! JOEY!
JOEY. JOEY.
STOP PLAYING AROUND
AND GIVE ME A HAND.
ARE YOU SURE THIS GAS
IS GONNA IGNITE?
- WHAT?
- ARE YOU SURE THE GAS
IS GONNA IGNITE?
OF COURSE.
THIS TIME I DIDN'T LEAVE
NOTHIN' TO CHANCE.
BAD HABIT STOLE THIS HERE
FROM HIS MOTHER'S DENTIST.
- TAKIN' TWO OF 'EM
WERE HIS IDEA.
- YEAH, IT WAS MY IDEA.
DOUBLE YOUR PLEASURE.
[Laughing]
PRETTY STRONG, HUH?
- YOU GOT IT FROM YOUR DESK.
- MY DESK?
[Laughing]
WAIT. UH, UH...
WHEN THE MOUSE EATS THE FLOUR,
HE LEAVES HIS CRAP IN THE SACK.
LOOK. TIGA'S OUT.
- [Cynthia]
I THOUGHT YOU LOCKED HER UP.
- I DID.
[Cynthia]
WILL SHE BE ALL RIGHT?
I MEAN, AM I SAFE?
- IF YOU CHOOSE TO LAUGH AT
HER, SHE MAY TRY TO KILL YOU.
- LOOK WHAT SHE'S WEARING!
[Laughing]
- IT LOOKS JUST LIKE
MY EARRINGS.
- GEEZ, THE EARRINGS.
[Laughing]
IT WAS A SET.
YOU GAVE HER THE NECKLACE?
SHE WANTED THE EARRINGS TOO,
BUT I TOLD HER
THEY WERE FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT!
[Foster]
CYNTHIA!
YOU. YOU!
LAZLO, DO SOMETHING.
OW! MY ELBOW!
[Laughing]
CYNTHIA...
YOU DON'T WANNA DO THAT,
BABY.
OK, THAT'S ONE DOWN.
LET'S GET THE OTHER
HOOKED UP QUICK.
BAD HABIT,
CHECK THE HOSE FOR KINKS.
OK, JUST SHOVE IT
RIGHT BACK IN THERE.
ONE MORE AND WE'RE HOME FREE.
ONE MORE AND
WE'RE HOME FREE?
[Gas Hissing]
GET HER!
- I'M FINALLY OUT OF MY BODY!
- GET HER!
[Woman]
I'M FINALLY OUT
OF MY BODY!
I GOT IT!
CAMEROON, HELP ME.
[Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
QUICK, LIGHT THE GODDAMN FUSE.
LET'S GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE!
- WHO'S GOT THE LIGHTER?
- GIVE IT TO ME.
I SAID, GIVE IT TO ME.
YOU HAVE SCREWED THINGS UP
FOR THE LAST TIME.
[Explosion]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
I SHOULDN'T WORRY, JULES?
SOMEBODY JUST TRIED TO BLOW US
INTO NEXT TUESDAY.
YOU WANNA KNOW WHY MAX
LIVED SO LONG?
HE NEVER WENT CRAZY LIKE YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE CRAZY
TO GET BLOWN UP, JULES.
HOW CAN YOU TAKE THIS SO CALM?
I GET PAID TO BE CALM.
- JUST WHAT IS IT YOU'RE ASKING?
- I'M ASKING WHO THE HELL
IT COULD BE AND WHY.
- I'M TELLING YOU,
IT COULD BE NOBODY.
- THE POLICE DISAGREE.
IN MY BUSINESS,
I'VE SEEN THE POLICE
OVERREACT BEFORE.
TAKE IT EASY,
GO TO A MOVIE
AND FORGET ABOUT IT.
[Makes Clicking Sounds]
DAMN IT, TIGA!
LISTEN, JULES,
I'M TELLING YOU...
TI... TIGA, WOULD YOU...
[Foster]
GIVE ME THAT BACK!
STOP PLAYING AROUND!
HOPE YOU'RE HAPPY.
YOU SUCCESSFULLY DESTROYED
THE ONLY TRUE RELATIONSHIP
I'VE BEEN ABLE TO SUSTAIN.
WHY'D YOU HAVE TO FLAUNT
THE GODDAMN NECKLACE, ANYWAY?
LAZLO, HAND ME THAT RAG.
THANKS.
- [Knocking At Door]
- WHO IS IT?
GET OUT OF HERE.
IT'S ME, ZABREWSKI.
OPEN UP.
OK, THE PARTY'S OVER.
THEY'RE THE POLICE.
WHERE ARE THEY?
- WHERE ARE WHO?
- OH, YOU WANNA BE CUTE,
HUH?
NO MAN HATES HIS NOSE SO MUCH
TO BITE IT OFF.
- LOVE MAX-A!
- SHUT UP!
TIGA? POPPY? RUSTY?
COME, COME, COME.
POPPY?
[Laughing]
- YOU KNOW THEM?
- YOU KNOW,
YOU AIN'T TOO BRIGHT.
MAX WAS RIGHT WHEN HE SAID
YOU NEED SOMEBODY
TO LOOK AFTER YOU.
- MAX? YOU KNEW MAX?
QUIET, LAZLO.
- YOU KNEW MAX?
- MAY HE REST IN PEACE.
- WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL ME ABOUT IT, GODDAMN IT?
- HAD ME SNEAKIN'
AROUND HERE...
- GODDAMN SNEAKIN'!
AHH!
MAX ARRANGED FOR YOU...
TO KEEP THE APES.
WHEN ALL IS WELL AT THE END
OF TWO YEARS, ZABREWSKI
GETS TO KEEP THE BUILDING.
- MAX BOUGHT YOU THE BUILDING?
- THESE GUYS ARE GONNA
LOOK AFTER YOU.
- GODDAMN SNEAKIN'!
- LAZLO, WILL YOU...
THE HORSE DOES NOT
LIFT HIS TAIL
WITHOUT GOOD REASON.
I SAID YOU WERE TAKING
YOUR LIFE IN YOUR HANDS
WHEN YOU WENT BACK!
FORGET THE BOMB!
THAT MONKEY MIGHT
HAVE KILLED YOU!
I ONLY WENT BACK
BECAUSE FOSTER SAID
HE'D MADE A DECISION.
TIGA'S MERELY JEALOUS,
NOT HOMICIDAL.
THAT JUST MEANS
SHE HASN'T KILLED ANYBODY YET.
IF I THOUGHT SHE WAS GOING
TO GET VIOLENT, I WOULD HAVE
GIVEN HER THE EARRINGS.
WHAT? YOU MEAN YOU DIDN'T
SHOVE THOSE EARRINGS
UP HIS BANANA STALK?
NO. WHY?
THEY'RE MINE.
I WANT THEM.
BOY, ARE YOU DUMB!
NO WONDER HE SHARES YOU
WITH AN APE.
ALL RIGHT, I'M DUMB.
MOTHER, I LOVE HIM.
WHAT CAN I DO?
WILL YOU LISTEN TO ME
FOR ONCE?
I MEAN, I DIDN'T BURY
FIVE HUSBANDS BECAUSE
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW TO LAND ONE.
IT WAS KEEPING THEM ALIVE
AFTERWARDS THAT WAS THE PROBLEM.
IF YOU REALLY LOVE HIM,
THERE'S A LOT YOU CAN DO.
- WILL YOU LET ME HELP?
- ALL RIGHT.
AS LONG AS YOU DON'T DO
ANYTHING DRASTIC.
DRASTIC TO FOSTER
IS ANYTHING THAT WOULD
COST HIM TWO DOLLARS.
THE FIRST THING WE DO
IS GIVE THE DAMN EARRINGS BACK.
- BUT WHY?
- BECAUSE, DUMMY!
YOU'VE GOT TOO MUCH PRIDE.
[Buzzing]
- [Gridley] YES?
- YOU BLEW IT AGAIN!
I TOLD YOU HOW LONG
YOU HAD, GRIDLEY.
AND YOUR TIME
IS JUST ABOUT UP.
- YOU DON'T SOUND VERY GOOD.
- NEVER MIND HOW I SOUND!
YES, I UNDERSTAND.
IT WAS A MISTAKE.
I WON'T, UH, UH...
I SHAN'T...
YES, SHAN'T...
MAKE ONE AGAIN.
THERE'S STILL TIME.
THIS TIME I WILL MAKE SURE
PERSONALLY.
PERSONALLY!
[Phone Disconnects]
SO I ASK MYSELF,
"WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT
FOR BRANDON TO KNOCK OFF
A MONKEY, HUH?"
- SO I DID A LITTLE CHECKIN'
ON MY OWN.
- SO WHY, ALREADY?
THESE ARE NOT
YOUR ORDINARY MONKEYS.
TELL ME ABOUT IT.
WE'RE LUCKY TO BE ALIVE.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEAN!
[Italian]
THESE MONKEYS ARE WORTH
FIVE MILLION BUCKS
TO THE GUY WHO'S GOT 'EM.
- THAT'S IF HE CAN KEEP 'EM
FROM CROAKIN'.
- AND IF HE CAN'T?
IF HE CAN'T,
THEY GET STUFFED AND
HE GETS... [Italian]
- FOR WHAT?
FOR SNOT, STUPID!
IT'S WORTH FIVE G's
TO BRANDON...
JUST TO KNOCK
ONE OF THEM OFF.
THEY CAN'T GIVE YOU THE CHAIR
FOR KILLING A MONKEY.
THAT'S NOT IT!
LISTEN TO ME.
IF IT'S WORTH FIVE G's
TO BRANDON
TO BUMP A BABOON,
WHAT DO YOU FIGURE
IT'S WORTH TO THE CHUMP
TO GET ONE OF 'EM BACK?
ONE BACK?
YOU MEAN...
HOW WE GONNA KIDNAP
A MONKEY?
GET BACK HERE.
HEH-HEH.
- SOMEBODY'S IN THERE.
- WHO?
I DON'T KNOW.
[Makes Kissing Sounds]
WE'LL RUSH IN TOGETHER.
- YOU READY?
ONE, TWO, THREE!
- YEAH.
♪ [Headphones]
LISTEN.
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
WE PICK ONE, DO IT AND SPLIT.
JUST LIKE WE PLANNED.
- THAT ONE SEEMS
TO LIKE YOU.
- YEAH.
- LET'S TAKE THAT ONE THEN.
- NO. THAT'S THE ONE
WE DON'T WANT.
TRY KISSING THAT ONE.
MAYBE YOU'LL LIKE HIM BETTER.
- OK, OK.
THEN YOU CHOOSE.
- WE'LL TAKE THAT ONE.
[Bad Habit]
THAT ONE? HOW COME?
'CAUSE I LIKE HER EYES.
'CAUSE THAT'S THE ONE
WE WANT, STUPID!
GO GET HER.
- ME? WHY ME?
WHY ME?
- GO AHEAD. LOOK.
THEY'RE HARMLESS.
BEING SO INTIMATE
WITH HIM ALREADY,
WHY DON'T YOU GO GET HIM?
HOW COME IF ANYBODY WANTS
TO GET ANYTHING DONE
AROUND HERE,
HE'S GOTTA DO IT
HISSELF, HUH?
ONE PUNCH AND SHE'S MINE.
- I THOUGHT YOU SAID
ONE PUNCH AND SHE WAS YOURS.
- SHUT UP!
TAKE CARE OF THE BOX.
AH.
HEY, I READ THIS.
IT'S NOT A BAD STORY.
DID YOU GET TO THE PART
ABOUT THE FUNERAL?
GOOD.
THIS BOOK IS ONE
OF MY FAVORITES.
YOU KNOW THE PART
ABOUT THE GIRL
WHERE SHE SAYS...
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DID I SAY SOMETHING WRONG?
OH. ANYWAY, IN A COUPLE
OF CHAPTERS SHE GETS BACK
TO HER BOYFRIEND,
- WHO'S BEEN LYING TO HER
AND EVERYBODY ELSE.
- [Water Splashing]
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT HIM?
I WON'T TELL YOU
HOW SHE DOES IT 'CAUSE
I DON'T WANNA RUIN IT FOR YOU.
ONE OTHER THING.
DON'T GET FOOLED BY
THE MOTHER'S SWEET TALK...
BECAUSE AT THE END,
THAT OLD LADY, SHE TURNS OUT
TO BE A REAL BARRACUDA.
JOEY, WHERE ARE YOU?
WOULD YOU LIKE
A SIX-PACK TO GO?
AX MURDERER.
THIS ISN'T
AN APARTMENT HOUSE,
IT'S AN ASYLUM.
REMEMBER, LET ME
DO THE TALKING.
[Knocking At Door]
ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT!
- [Knocking Continues]
- COMIN'.
- I'M COMIN'.
- [Doorbell Buzzes]
COMIN'.
- WHAT'D YOU DO TO HIM?
- WE DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
WE JUST GOT HERE.
- ARE THE APES OK?
- OF COURSE.
TIGA, RUSTY, POPPY?
COME ON OUT.
COME HERE.
POPPY?
COME ON, POPPY.
I'M DON'T FEEL LIKE
PLAYING ANY GAMES.
POPPY? POP?
- SHE'S GONE.
- COULD SHE BE
WITH LAZLO?
NO. LAZLO WENT
TO THE MOVIES.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
- THE POLICEMAN!
THAT CRATE!
- WHY WOULD A POLICEMAN...
- HE'S IN ON IT...
THE ONE IN THE HALLWAY.
- BUT...
BUT HE'S UNCONSCIOUS.
THE PERFECT ALIBI.
- UH-OH.
HE'S COMING TO.
- WHAT SHALL WE DO?
HAI-YA!
- ARE YOU NUTS?
- WOULD YOU PREFER
I TELL HIM A BEDTIME STORY?
- WHERE CAN WE PUT HIM?
- I KNOW.
COME ON.
HOLD IT.
COME ON. OK.
WE GOTTA GET POPPY.
IT'S JUST A COUPLE
OF FIREMEN.
[Gasps]
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
A FIRE CAPTAIN
KNOCKED AT YOUR DOOR?
THEY'RE FIREMEN.
THE EXPLOSION, REMEMBER?
MAYBE THEY...
AND MAYBE THAT WAS ONLY
A POLICEMAN WITH A CRATE,
RIGHT?
- WHAT CAN WE DO?
- MR. SABATINI?
- TELL 'EM TO WAIT
A MINUTE.
- [Doorbell Buzzes]
[Whispering]
THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE GONNA DO.
YES, GENTLEMEN?
OK,
WHERE ARE THEY?
- [Foster] WHO ARE YOU?
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
WHERE ARE THE APES?
- THEY'RE GONE.
THE POLICE TOOK 'EM.
- FIND THEM.
- BUT THEY...
- FIND THEM!
THE FOUR OF YOU MOVE OVER
TO THE WINDOW.
AHA!
I GOT ONE!
WAIT!
WE BETTER TAKE HIM
WITH US.
NOW, DON'T ANYONE...
UH, ANYBODY MOVE...
FOR TEN MINUTES,
UNDERSTAND?
[Chattering]
TIGA!
[Groans]
- COME ON. WHEN THEY SHOOT
THAT COP, THEY'LL BE BACK.
- THERE MAY BE MORE OF THEM.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW MANY LUNATICS THERE ARE
RUNNING AROUND.
I DON'T KNOW. HOW MANY
ORIGINAL SLIVERS OF BABE RUTH'S
CROSS HAVE YOU SOLD?
VERY FUNNY.
I THINK WE SHOULD SPLIT UP.
NO. BETTER WE STAY
CLOSE TOGETHER.
I'LL TAKE RUSTY AND POPPY
AND CIRCLE THE BLOCK.
MEET US OUT IN FRONT WITH
TIGA IN FIVE MINUTES. WE'LL
RENDEZVOUS AT THE HOSPITAL.
RENDEZVOUS? HMM?
COME ON.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE STAIRS.
WE'LL TAKE THE STAIRS.
- JULES, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
- I CAME TO SEE YOU.
- YOU DON'T SOUND VERY GOOD.
- NEVER MIND HOW I SOUND.
- YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING.
- YEAH? TRY ME.
- BY THE WAY, WHERE'S
YOUR POLICE PROTECTION?
- HA!
- [Sneezes]
- QUIET, TIGA.
- GEE, JULES,
SHE REALLY HATES YOU.
- [Jabbering]
TO HELL WITH HER!
SHE'S A BABOON,
NOT PRINCESS GRACE.
SHE'S AN ORANGUTAN.
MAX SAID YOU LOVED THEM.
[Sneezes]
JULES, WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
- [Gun Cocks]
- HEY, JULES, YOU?
NAW, COME ON.
YOU'RE MAX'S DEAREST.
DON'T DO IT.
YOU CAN HAVE THE MONEY,
ALL OF IT. I SWEAR IT.
- JUST DON'T HURT TIGA.
PLEASE!
- SORRY, KID.
KEEP THE MONEY.
JUST LEAVE US ALONE.
- DO IT FOR MAX.
- MAX-SCHMAX!
LAZLO! LAZLO!
GET SOME STUFF.
BRING IT OVER HERE.
COME ON, LAZLO, HURRY UP.
COME ON.
COME ON!
HURRY UP.
ALL THIS STUFF.
GET ME THE PHONE.
HURRY UP. THE PHONE!
TIGA, GET THE PHONE.
THANKS.
[Pounding At Door]
LAZLO, TIGA.
YOU THINK YOU GUYS
CAN GET OVER THERE?
COME ON.
GO AHEAD, TIGA.
GIMME SOME ROOM.
WHOO-HOO-HOO!
LOOK AT THE MONKEY.
FOSTER!
QUICKLY. COME!
IF YOU'RE WATCHING, MAX,
THIS IS ALL YOUR FAULT.
FOR GOD'S SAKE,
DO SOMETHING.
COME, FOSTER.
COME.
[Laughs]
COME HERE.
HELP ME WITH THIS.
OUT THE WINDOW.
[Yelling]
[Laughing]
THAT'S IT, MEN!
WE GOT 'EM NOW!
- MOVE ASIDE.
- [Gunshots]
OH, SHOOT!
- HEY, BAD HABIT. I THOUGHT
YOU SAID YOU GOT THE APE.
- YEAH.
[Laughing]
A PIECE OF CAKE.
A PIECE OF CAKE, HUH?
THEN WHO'S THAT?
MOTHER, LOOK OUT!
THOSE POLICE!
IT IS THE APE,
YOU ASSHOLE!
FOSTER. FOSTER.
KEEP YOUR EYES OPEN
FOR FIONA.
AH, VERONA.
[Gibberish]
THERE SHE IS!
GET 'EM!
- AT LEAST THEY'RE NOT
SHOOTIN' AT US.
- [Gunshots]
FOSTER, YOU DUMBASS SON OF A
BITCH, GET OUT OF HERE. WHAT'RE
YOU TRYING TO DO, KILL US?
WHEN HOT LEAD FLYS YOU
DON'T WAIT FOR STOP SIGNS.
THOSE THIEVES
ARE PACKING HEATERS!
STAY DOWN, TIGA!
[Siren Wailing]
MOTHER, LOOK!
IT'S LAZLO!
FIONA,
MY "MELAPUCHIKO."
- FOLLOW ME TO THE HOSPITAL.
- TO THE ENDS OF THE EARTH,
MY "PUCHIKALO."
[Siren Wailing]
- THINK THAT LOCK'S STRONG
ENOUGH TO HOLD A MONKEY?
- WHY NOT?
IT WAS OBVIOUSLY MADE
TO HOLD THE BEASTS.
DRIVE FASTER.
- [Gunshot]
- [Horn Honking]
[Gunshots]
[Siren Wailing]
[Gunshot]
- BLOW OUT! DAMN!
- NO. IT AIN'T US.
WE'RE OK.
- [Gunshot]
- LOOK OUT!
GOOD GRACIOUS!
STEP ON IT!
- WHO'S SHOOTING AT US?
- I DON'T KNOW. JUST GET
OUT OF HERE, DAMN IT.
- MAYBE HE HIT THE MONKEY.
- GREAT.
- GRIDLEY, THE GUY
SHOOTING AT US?
- YES?
IT IS THE MONKEY.
[Rifle Shots]
[Siren Wailing]
[Coughing]
- HEY, JOEY,
YOU AIN'T DRIVIN' SO GOOD.
- SHUT UP!
COME ON. LOOK!
WE GOT 'EM TRAPPED.
[Police Radio,
Indistinct]
CAREFUL.
- TIGA!
- HURRY UP. QUICK.
[Chattering]
MRS. VERONA,
YOU AND ME, WE CAN HAVE A DATE.
YOU KNOW, LEGITIMATE. HUH?
- WE GOT 'EM.
- OK, WE GOT 'EM.
FIONA, I KNOW
A LOVELY LITTLE
LITHUANIAN RESTAURANT.
WITH VIOLINS.
OK, OK.
- SPLIT UP.
LAY LOW BUT STAY CLOSE.
- RIGHT.
COME ON, GUYS.
COME ON, TIGA!
JOEY! OVER HERE.
HEY!
- DEAD.
- HUH?
- OH, DEAD. OK.
GO ON.
[Mouthing Words]
GO ON!
AHH! JOEY!
GEE! GET ME OUTTA HERE.
UP, POPPY.
POPPY, I GOT YOU.
- JOEY!
- BAD HABIT!
- [Groaning]
[Woman On P.A.]
DR. MORROW,
PLEASE CALL...
EXTENSION 2-3-1.
DR. MORROW,
- EXCUSE US. I'M SORRY.
- CERTAINLY. BUT PLEASE,
DON'T RUN THROUGH THE HALLS.
[Gun Clicks]
- [Whistles]
- HEY, JOEY!
LOOK! OVER THERE.
[Door Slams Shut]
[Muffled Yelling]
JOEY. OOH.
GET IN THE CAR.
LET'S GO.
TAKE CARE OF THOSE GUYS
AND BRING BACK SOME ROPE.
COME ON.
TIE 'EM UP.
MAKE IT SNAPPY.
I GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE.
COME ON!
- LET'S GO.
- HEY!
GET UP THERE.
- [Cynthia] OH, STOP!
- [Fiona] WHY DON'T YOU
LEAVE HIM ALONE!
OH, NO!
- PLEASE, DON'T HURT HIM.
HE'S ONLY A BABY.
- SHUT UP! HE'S AN APE!
[Cynthia]
PLEASE! RUSTY.
OH, MY GOD!
TIE 'EM UP GOOD.
[Foster]
COME ON, POPPY.
LAZLO,
THEY GOT RUSTY.
AND EVERYBODY TOO.
MY VERONA!
QUICK. THAT WAY.
COME ON.
I SAW 'EM HEADED
THIS WAY OVER...
STAY WHERE YOU ARE
IF YOU LIKE LIVING.
HEY, JOEY, LOOK.
THERE'S OUR APE.
AH, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE
MY SAYING SO, SIR,
BUT IT APPEARS TO ME
THAT YOU GOT SOMETHING
THAT BELONGS TO US.
I WON'T EXCUSE YOU,
AND YOU ARE MISTAKEN.
WHOEVER YOU ARE,
I WOULDN'T DO THAT
IF I WAS YOU.
YEAH, WHOEVER YOU ARE,
I WOULDN'T DO THAT
IF I WAS YOU...
OOH. HEY, UH, LOOK.
YOU KNOW,
IT JUST OCCURRED TO ME.
MAYBE WE COULD MAKE A DEAL
OR SOMETHIN'.
YES, MAYBE WE COULD
MAKE A DEAL.
LISTEN, JOEY, WHY
DON'T WE GIVE 'EM
THE DAMN APE BACK...
AND LET'S GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE ANYTHING HAPPENS.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
- STOP THE MACHINE.
STOP THE MONKEY.
- STOP THE MONKEY? STOP ME!
OH, MOTHER,
WHAT CAN WE DO?
[Bad Habit]
JOEY!
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
- OH, YEAH.
BAD HABIT!
[Grunts]
AHHH!
[Bad Habit]
DON'T DO THAT. DON'T DO THAT!
DON'T DO THAT!
SOMEBODY HELP US!
PLEASE HELP!
- [Yelling]
- BONSAI!
RUSTY!
[Siren Wailing]
THIS IS IT.
UH-OH.
TIGA, RUSTY, POPPY!
HAVEN'T YOU LEARNED
BY NOW, SILLY?
THEY'RE GONNA BE FINE.
- FINE.
- OH, FINE.
- [Tires Squealing]
- [Siren Wailing]
TIGA! RUSTY!
POPPY!
♪ [Banjos]
♪ ONE-WAY STREET
AND I'M HALFWAY DOWN IT ♪
♪ LOOKIN' FOR AN EXIT
BUT I AIN'T FOUND IT ♪
♪ LOOKIN' FOR
ANOTHER WAY TO GO ♪
♪ ONE-WAY STREET... ♪
♪ IT SHOULD'VE GOT BETTER
INSTEAD IT GOT WORSE ♪
♪ THERE'S GOTTA BE
A BETTER WAY TO GO ♪
♪ GETTIN' ME NOWHERE
GETTIN' ME DOWN ♪
♪ GOTTA FIND HOW
TO GET OUTTA THIS TOWN ♪
♪ GOIN' THROUGH THE DAY
NO WAY OF GETTIN' AROUND ♪
♪ ONE-WAY STREET
I WANT A FOUR-LANE HIGHWAY ♪
♪ NO GOING YOUR WAY
GOTTA GO MY WAY ♪
♪ GOTTA FIND
A BETTER WAY TO GO ♪