(DRUMROLL)
(ROUSING ORCHESTRAL
FANFARE PLAYING)
CC/Subtitles by 3rd eye
(FANFARE ENDS)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING, CRACKLING)
(MACHINE POWERING DOWN)
(BEEPING)
WELL?
MAN:
I'M SENDING YOU THE CODE.
YES, I SEE THAT. THANK YOU.
(BEEP)
WHAT ABOUT MY ACCOUNT?
DELIVERING.
(TYPING)
I'VE JUST SENT IT;
YOU SHOULD HAVE IT.
YES, THANK YOU.
HEY, HEY,
ARE YOU SURE THIS IS LEGAL?
WOMAN:
WE'RE JUST RUNNING A TEST
ON OUR SECURITY SYSTEM, SIR.
IT'S FINE.
YOU HAVE A SEXY VOICE.
UH, IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
I CAN DO FOR YOU? TO YOU?
WE HAVE WHAT WE NEED.
WE'RE READY.
(BEEPING)
(GUNFIRE BLASTING)
(SOLDIER GROANS)
YO, GUESS WHO JUST
MADE 50 G's TODAY.
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(SQUEAKING, CRACKLING)
WHAT'D YOU DO TO MY DRIVE, MAN?
SHUT UP.
I DIDN'T TOUCH IT.
THIS ISN'T COOL.
DON'T EVER,
EVER TOUCH MY COMPUTER.
(BEEP)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(QUIET BEEPING)
(BEEPING)
(MACHINES POWERING DOWN)
(BEEP)
DIAGNOSTICS SHOW NO DAMAGE,
BUT WE'RE CERTAIN THIS WAS
AN INTENTIONAL BREACH.
YOU'RE SAYING WE WERE HACKED?
IT WASN'T
DENIAL OF SERVICE
LEVEL,
BUT THEY DEFINITELY
CRACKED OUR DOOR.
OKAY, OPEN
THE BLACK HAT FILES.
I WANT EVERY HACKER
IN THE COUNTRY
WHO COULD'VE DONE THIS
INTERVIEWED NOW.
SIR, THAT'S CLOSE
TO A THOUSAND NAMES.
WITH THE HOLIDAY WEEKEND,
WE'RE SHORT-STAFFED
AS IT IS.
LISTEN,
WE'RE THE ONES
THAT ARE SUPPOSED
TO KEEP THIS FROM HAPPENING,
AND IT JUST HAPPENED TO US.
GET IT DONE.
SIR, IT'S THE MIDDLE
OF THE NIGHT;
THEY'RE SCATTERED ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
FINE-- GET LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT TO HELP.
SOMEBODY OUT THERE THINKS
THEY CAN SCREW WITH US.
I WANT TO FIND OUT WHO.
BOY:
HEY, JIMMY! WAIT UP, MAN!
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
YOU ARE SO ROCK AND ROLL
BE MY
BE MY, BE MY LITTLE
ROCK AND ROLL QUEEN
BE MY
BE MY, BE MY LITTLE
ROCK AND ROLL QUEEN
JIM! I SAID NO.
LUCY, YOU'RE KILLING ME,
ALL RIGHT?
GET OUT OF THE CAR.
WHAT?
GET OUT OF THE CAR NOW!
DON'T TOUCH ME!
NO MEANS NO, JERKOFF.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
JOHN, STOP IT!
OH, DON'T CALL ME THAT.
I HATE IT WHEN
YOU CALL ME THAT.
NO,
WHOA, YOU KNOW THIS GUY?
SHUT UP. JUST SHUT YOUR MOUTH
RIGHT NOW.
DAD!
STOP IT! I MEAN IT!
DAD? YOU SAID
YOUR DAD WAS DEAD.
McCLANE:
WHAT?
YOU TOLD THIS
JERKOFF I WAS DEAD?
YOU ACTUALLY SAID THAT?
I MAY HAVE EXAGGERATED
A LITTLE BIT.
A-AND THIS GUY'S WHAT,
YOUR-YOUR-YOUR BOYFRIEND?
NO.
JIM:
YEAH.
(GROANS):
I DON'T KNOW, OKAY?
I'M SORRY.
JUST... WE'LL SEE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YOU DON'T ANSWER YOUR PHONE.
YOU DON'T RETURN
MY CALLS.
THAT'S BECAUSE
I'M NOT TALKING TO YOU.
AND WHY AREN'T YOU TALKING
TO ME THIS TIME, LUCY?
WHY NOT?
WHAT, YOU WANT A LIST?
HOW ABOUT STUFF LIKE THIS:
YOU SPY ON ME.
I'M NOT SPYING.
YOU COME DOWN HERE, DRAG
MY BOYFRIEND OUT OF THE CAR.
THOUGHT HE WASN'T
YOUR BOYFRIEND.
HE'S NOT!
THOUGHT YOU SAID
I WAS.
GOD...
SHUT UP.
YOU ARE SUCH AN ASSHOLE.
OKAY.
I'M SORRY I PULLED YOUR
NOT-BOYFRIEND OUT OF THE CAR.
OKAY?
HEY, LUCY, BABE...
COME ON, GET IN THE CAR.
LET'S JUST GO.
NO, NO.
WILL BOTH OF YOU JUST GO AWAY?
JUST TALK TO ME FOR A MINUTE,
LUCY...
I'M TIRED.
I'M GOING TO BED. ALONE.
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT
YOU'RE GOING TO BED ALONE.
(SIGHS)
LUCY, HONEY,
WAIT A MINUTE,
JUST WAIT, HONEY.
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
JUST WAIT.
DAD...
WHEN I WANT
TO TALK TO YOU,
IF I WANT TO TALK TO YOU...
I'LL CALL YOU.
LUCY...
WAIT, LUCY... LUCY!
LUCY McCLANE!
IT'S NOT McCLANE;
IT'S GENNERO.
(CHUCKLES)
CHICKS, RIGHT?
I'M GONNA GO.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
MAN:
JOHN? JOHN?
IT'S SCALVINO.
GO FOR McCLANE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
AT RUTGERS?
HOW DO YOU KNOW WHERE I AM?
WE HAD ALL THE CARS LOJACKED
FOUR YEARS AGO, REMEMBER?
I'M STARING AT EXACTLY
WHERE YOU ARE.
SO THAT'S NOT SOMETHING
I WOULD TURN ON?
YEAH, WE DID THAT.
JOHN, WE... TURNED THEM ON.
LISTEN, THE FEDS
HAVE CALLED IN A FAVOR.
THEY'RE DOING A SWEEP.
THEY WANT US TO PICK UP
SOME COMPUTER HACKER IN CAMDEN.
LAST NAME FARRELL,
FIRST NAME MATTHEW.
WHOA, WHOA. CAMDEN?
WHAT ARE YOU
TELLING ME THIS FOR?
YOU KNOW, IT'S, LIKE,
3:00 IN THE MORNING.
I WAS ON MY WAY HOME.
JUST SEND ONE OF THE JUGHEADS
FROM THE ACADEMY.
THEY'LL BE HAPPY
TO GO PICK THIS KID UP.
I CAN'T JUST SEND ANY UNIFORM.
THE FEDS DEMANDED
A SENIOR DETECTIVE.
THE KID'S A HIGH-VALUE SUBJECT.
I DON'T KNOW.
JUST PICK HIM UP,
ESCORT HIM
TO THE HOOVER BUILDING IN D.C.
THEY HAD SOME KIND
OF A COMPUTER BREACH
THERE THIS MORNING.
McCLANE:
GREAT.
(CAR STARTS)
GIVE ME THAT INFORMATION.
ALL RIGHT,
GIVE ME THAT NAME AGAIN.
WHAT IS IT?
YOU OWE ME ONE, JACK.
(WOMAN SINGING SLOW MELODY)
(SLOW SINGING CONTINUES,
FAST ROCK PLAYING)
I WILL
BREAK!
(FAST ROCK PLAYING)
(PULLS TAB)
(TYPING)
(LOUD MUSIC CONTINUES)
SALVATION, I'M SO SICK
I'M SO SICK
(QUIETLY):
WHAT?
(BEEPING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
COME ON.
GODDAMN IT.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
(TURNS MUSIC OFF)
(PANTING)
WHO IS IT?
McCLANE:
N.Y.P.D. OPEN
THE DOOR, PLEASE.
HI.
N.Y.P.D.? OKAY.
OH, I GET IT.
UM, I'LL HELP YOU OUT.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
EVERYONE GETS LOST AROUND HERE.
GLAD TO HELP. TAKE...
HEY. I'M NOT LOST.
(CHUCKLES)
ARE YOU MATT FARRELL?
MATTHEW FARRELL?
NO. HE, UH, ACTUALLY DOES
NOT LIVE HERE ANYMORE.
COURSE NOT. WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS DAISY DUKE.
GOT A LOT OF SHIT FOR
IT WHEN I WAS A KID.
PLEASE DON'T ADD TO IT.
(CHUCKLES)
CAN I SEE SOME
IDENTIFICATION, PLEASE?
YEAH, SURE.
(LAUGHS):
DETECTIVE!
YEAH, THAT LOOKS REAL.
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT?
TOYS "R" US?
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
AND, OF COURSE...
YEAH.
THAT... THAT ACTUALLY
LOOKS PRETTY GOOD.
MM-HMM.
MAN:
HEY, FARRELL.
SULLY JUST P.D.L.'d
A NEW COPY OF THE KILL ZONE 9,
THE ONE THAT AIN'T OUT YET--
WANNA COME CHECK IT OUT?
NO. THANKS, THOUGH, MAN.
AND GOOD LUCK AT
THE BAD TIMING AWARDS.
OPEN THE DOOR.
SHIT.
CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING?
COFFEE? A WARRANT?
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
I DON'T KNOW.
SOME KIND OF COMPUTER THING.
D.C. FEDS WANT TO
TALK TO YOU, SO...
LET'S GO.
FEDS, HUH?
YEAH. THE FEDS.
(BAG UNZIPS)
BEEN WHITE HAT
FOR FOUR YEARS.
ONCE YOU'RE ON
THAT GODDAMN LIST...
(WHISPERS):
IT'S SUCH A PAIN IN THE ASS.
YOU PLAY WITH DOLLS?
HUH?
UH, C-COULD YOU PLEASE
NOT TOUCH THAT?
LIKE A G.I. JOE.
NO, NO, IT'S NOT, IT'S NOT.
IT'S A LIMITED EDITION...
OOH.
AND...
THAT SUPPOSED TO COME OFF?
NO, IT'S NOT SUPPOSED TO, BUT...
IT'S A LOT MORE VALUABLE WHEN
IT'S BROKEN, SO THANKS FOR THAT.
YEAH. KRAZY GLUE. I'M SURE
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
I GOT SOME OTHER COOL SHIT
IN HERE
IF YOU WANT TO BREAK THAT.
LET'S GO, OKAY? COME ON.
I GOT TO POWER DOWN
MY GEAR, OKAY?
MORE DOLLS.
NOT SPENDING A WHOLE LOT OF
TIME WITH THE GIRLS, HUH?
HEY.
ARE YOU REALLY
TRYING TO ESCAPE?
(BULLETS SHATTERING GLASS,
YELLING)
JESUS!
DON'T SHOOT! DON'T SHOOT!
HEY! GET DOWN!
JESUS!
KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN.
(FARRELL PANTING, MUMBLING)
(FARRELL YELLS)
SHIT.
(GUNSHOTS)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
GO! GO!
LET'S GO! COME ON!
LOW, LOW! STAY DOWN!
COME ON!
McCLANE (WHISPERING):
STAY LOW, ALL RIGHT?
STAY DOWN.
YOU STAY WITH ME, ALL RIGHT?
OKAY.
HERE WE GO.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(CLATTERING)
THAT'S GONNA WAKE THE NEIGHBORS.
GET DOWN! GET INSIDE! GET DOWN!
THEY'RE BACK IN THE ROOM!
ARE YOU NUTS?!
GET OUT OF THERE RIGHT NOW!
NOW!
(PANTING)
TAKE THE RIGHT!
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(LOUD GRUNTING)
(McCLANE, FARRELL YELLING,
GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
ARE YOU OKAY?
GET BACK THERE!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
(PANTING)
(GUNSHOTS, YELLS)
(GROANS IN PAIN)
(GUNSHOTS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
THAT'S IT.
(PANTING)
GET READY TO RUN.
(CAR ALARMS BLARING IN DISTANCE)
(DOG BARKING)
WHAT THE--
(FARRELL COUGHING)
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?!
WHAT?
DID YOU DO THAT?
NO.
SHIT.
I DIDN'T DO THAT. COME ON.
STAY CLOSE.
(FARRELL COUGHING)
THE WHOLE APARTMENT'S ON FIRE.
COME ON.
LET'S GO.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
DAMN IT!
(PANTING)
COME ON.
(FARRELL GASPS)
WATCH IT.
JUST HOLD IT DOWN.
OH, MY GOD.
HEY.
COME ON.
OKAY.
(WHISPERING):
COME ON. COME ON.
STAY CLOSE.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH PANTING)
STAY WITH ME.
COME ON, LET'S GO. STAY CLOSE.
OKAY.
GET IN THE CAR.
GO, GO. NOW.
(ENGINE ROARING)
CAN YOU RELOAD A GUN?
UH, ME? UH, YEAH.
CAN YOU RELOAD A GUN?!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
OPEN THE GLOVE BOX
AND GET A MAGAZINE
OUT OF THE THING RIGHT NOW!
(YELLS, CHOKING)
GRAB THE GUN
ON THE BACKSEAT!
QUICK!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(GRUNTING)
(ENGINE REVVING,
TIRES SQUEALING)
(GRUNTS, COUGHS)
(THUDDING, CLANKING)
(CLANK, THUD)
GET YOUR HEAD DOWN!
(ENGINE ROARING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
JESUS!
IS THE CIRCUS IN TOWN?
(ENGINE REVVING)
(YELLING)
WHOO!
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
DID YOU SEE THAT?
YEAH, I SAW IT.
I DID IT.
(ENGINE ROARING,
TIRES SQUEALING)
CAMDEN BASE,
ONE DOUBLE-OH-SEVEN-SEVEN.
COME BACK, CAMDEN BASE.
ONE-DOUBLE-OH-SEVEN-SEVEN.
DISPATCH:
CAMDEN BASE. GO AHEAD.
I NEED TO SPEAK TO YOUR CHIEF
OF DETECTIVES: POLICE EMERGENCY.
ASAP.
DISPATCH:
STAND BY.
MAN:
THIS IS CHIEF DETECTIVE WEISMAN.
CHIEF DETECTIVE, THIS IS
DETECTIVE JOHN McCLANE, N.Y.P.D.
POLICE EMERGENCY--
I WANT TO REPORT...
A POLICE SHOOTING
IN YOUR JURISDICTION.
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING LOUDER)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
YEAH.
WOMAN:
WHAT'S THE STATUS?
WAIT ONE.
(LOW, INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
THOMAS. WE HAD A PROBLEM
IN NEW JERSEY.
FARRELL'S STILL ALIVE.
SO HE GOT AWAY.
YEAH.
GABRIEL:
I DID SEND
FIVE OF YOU,
IS THAT RIGHT?
I'M SENDING A CHOPPER.
JUST GET AIRBORNE.
WE'LL TRACK HIM DOWN.
THINK YOU CAN HANDLE THAT?
(SLAMS DUMPSTER)
FARRELL:
OH, MY GOD...
McCLANE:
JUST BREATHE.
I AM BREATHING.
I'M, I'M, I'M, I'M...
CAN'T STOP SHAKING.
IT'S THE ADRENALINE.
YOU'RE JUST SCARED.
IT'LL PASS.
YEAH, I'M SCARED.
WEREN'T YOU SCARED BACK THERE?
YEAH.
I WAS SCARED.
REALLY? THIS IS YOU
BEING SCARED?
'CAUSE YOU SEEM
REALLY CALM.
HAVE YOU DONE STUFF
LIKE THAT BEFORE?
STUFF LIKE WHAT?
LIKE KILLING PEOPLE.
YEAH.
BUT NOT FOR A LONG TIME.
SO WHO WERE THOSE GUYS?
HUH?
WHY WERE THEY TRYING
TO KILL YOU?
WHY DID THEY BLOW UP
MY GODDAMN APARTMENT?
THEY WERE THERE TO KILL YOU.
WHY WOULD THEY WANT TO KILL ME?
YOU TELL ME, KID.
YOU'RE THE CRIMINAL.
I GOT SEVEN
DEAD HACKERS SO FAR,
NONE OF WHOM WERE
HIGH ON OUR LIST.
COLLECT THE HARD DRIVES,
START SWEEPING 'EM.
YES, SIR.
(TYPING)
TREY...
MATTHEW FARRELL--
FIND HIM FOR ME.
ON IT.
WHAT'S WITH ALL THE GUNS?
OPERATIONAL PRUDENCE.
THINK OF THEM AS HARDWARE
TO YOUR SOFTWARE.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
RADIO DISC JOCKEY:
GOOD MORNING, D.C.!
WELL, IT'S SHAPING UP
TO BE ANOTHER BEAUTIFUL
FOURTH OF JULY WEEKEND.
IF YOU'VE GOT ANY BIG PLANS,
BETTER GET STARTED EARLY,
'CAUSE IT LOOKS LIKE
THE TRAFFIC IS RAMPING UP.
SO, HERE'S ANOTHER GOLDEN OLDIE
FOR ALL THE COMMUTERS OUT THERE.
(ROCK MUSIC BLARING)
WHAT...?!
WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S CREEDENCE.
CREEDENCE?!
CREEDENCE.
CREEDENCE CLEARWATER REVIVAL.
CLASSIC ROCK.
I KNOW WHO IT IS.
IT'S OLD ROCK; THAT
DOESN'T MAKE IT CLASSIC.
WHAT SUCKED BACK THEN
STILL SUCKS NOW.
YOU DON'T LIKE CREEDENCE?
THIS IS LIKE HAVING A PINECONE
SHOVED IN MY ASS.
(MUSIC BLARES)
OKAY. REALLY?
WOW, THAT'S MATURE.
FARRELL:
COME ON, MAN.
I'M COOPERATING WITH YOU.
MAN:
WE'RE AT A HEADING
OF ZERO-SIX-ZERO.
MAKING ANOTHER PASS.
(QUIET BEEPING, WHIRRING)
GABRIEL:
LISTEN UP, EVERYONE.
ARE WE READY?
TRANSPORTATION HUBS
ARE PREPPED AND SET.
BEGIN STAGE ONE.
(TYPING)
(TECHNICIANS MURMURING)
ANNOUNCER:
...WITH SIX AND A HALF INNINGS
IN GAME...
(RADIO TUNING)
ANNOUNCER 2:
...THIS WEEKEND
FOR TWO SHOWS ONLY...
FARRELL:
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU REMEMBER
TURNING ON THE RADIO AND
LISTENING TO POPULAR MUSIC?
JUST GIVE ME A DECADE.
THE '70s?
I'M GUESSING... WAS
MICHAEL JACKSON STILL BLACK?
PEARL JAM-- I'LL
GO BACK TEN YEARS
WITH YOU... TEN YEARS.
20 YEARS...
THE CURE? NOTHING?
IT'S CALLED NEWS RADIO.
I WAS TRYING TO SEE IF ANY
OF YOUR FRIENDS FROM CAMDEN
MADE THE HEADLINES.
HOLD ON...
YOU LISTEN TO THE NEWS.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM
WITH THE NEWS NOW?
(LAUGHING)
YEAH, I GOT A BIG
GODDAMN PROBLEM WITH THE NEWS.
YOU READY FOR THIS?
THE NEWS
IS COMPLETELY MANIPULATED.
EVERYTHING YOU HEAR,
EVERY SINGLE DAY,
IS DESIGNED BY CORPORATE MEDIA
TO DO ONE THING,
AND ONE THING ONLY:
JESUS...
TO KEEP YOU LIVING IN FEAR.
OH, FEAR?
TOTAL FEAR!
FEAR SO YOU'LL GO OUT
AND YOU'LL SPEND MONEY
ON THINGS--
THINGS YOU PROBABLY
DON'T EVEN NEED.
ALREADY HAVE SIX OF
SO THAT THEIR ADVERTISERS KEEP
BUYING ADS ON THEIR STATIONS.
TELL YOU ONE MORE THING--
YOU READY FOR THIS?
I'LL DO THIS ALL DAY.
I GOT DAYS OF DATA AT HOME.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME.
HEY... HEY!
WHAT?
SHUT... UP.
THAT'S GOOD. THAT'S GOOD.
BE DISMISSIVE...
(TIRES SCREECHING,
LOUD CRASHING)
HORN BLOWING)
(TIRES SCREECHING,
VEHICLES CRASHING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(CROWD MURMURING)
YOU ALL RIGHT?
NO, I'M NOT ALL RIGHT!
JUST STAY IN THE CAR.
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
HEY, MAN... HEY.
HOW YOU DOING?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
DON'T MOVE. JUST CALL
911, ALL RIGHT?
(WEAKLY):
OKAY...
(SIRENS WAILING
IN DISTANCE)
JESUS CHRIST.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(ALARMS WAILING)
(HORNS HONKING)
ALL THE LIGHTS ARE GREEN.
HUH?
LET'S GO.
LET'S GO, RIGHT NOW.
WE GOTTA GO?
LET'S GO.
GET YOUR BAG, HACK BOY.
JESUS CHRIST.
LET'S GO.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
IN A CAR ACCIDENT.
COME ON. YOU ALL RIGHT? WELL...
VERY EXCITING.
HERE WE GO, THIS WAY, COME ON.
HERE WE GO.
EVER BEEN IN A CAR ACC...
YEAH, I'VE BEEN
IN A CAR ACCIDENT.
WHAT ARE WE DOING?
IT'S A LITTLE THING
THEY INVENTED BACK IN THE '60s
CALLED "JOGGING."
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT. COME ON.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(LOW, INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(BEEPING)
SIR, CHICAGO'S REPORTING
A SYSTEM CRASH
ON THEIR EL TRAIN NETWORK.
(BEEPING)
AMTRAK IS FLASHING A LEVEL-ONE
CRASH IN THEIR COMM SYSTEM.
F.A.A. JUST ISSUED
A CRITICAL ALERT.
THEIR A.T.C. NET
JUST WENT DOWN.
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
OKAY, LET'S GET 'EM OUTSIDE
FOR A LITTLE FRESH AIR.
(BLIPPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
THAT'S THE ANTHRAX ALARM.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYONE OUT, NOW!
NOW!
TAYLOR, MOVE, GO! MOVE!
(ALARM BLARING)
MAN (OVER P.A.):
ALL PERSONNEL MUST EVACUATE
AND PROCEED
TO THE TRANSPORTATION SHUTTLES
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS IS NOT A DRILL.
ALL PERSONNEL MUST EVACUATE
AND PROCEED
TO THE TRANSPORTATION SHUTTLES
IMMEDIATELY.
(ALARM BLARING)
(PANICKED SHOUTING)
NO, I'M TELLING YOU,
PROTOCOL SAYS...
WE NEED YOU INSIDE.
(SIREN WAILING)
TAKE THE TEAM. I WANT MEN ON THE
FOURTH FLOOR, GOT IT? MASKS ON.
GOT TO KNOW WHAT'S THERE, OKAY?
WHY DON'T YOU RUN A SEARCH
ON THESE DATA CRASHES?
SEE IF WE CAN I.D.
THE POINT OF ORIGIN.
BEGIN STAGE TWO.
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHOA!
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?!
NO!
(CLAMORING)
THEY'RE ALREADY
STARTING TO PANIC.
OF COURSE THEY ARE.
THEY THINK THAT SOMEONE'S
TAKING THEIR MONEY.
ALL THOSE NICKELS AND DIMES
THEY SAVED HAVE MEANING.
USEFUL IDIOTS,
AS LENIN WOULD SAY.
PREP THE VIDEO PACKAGE.
(CLAMORING)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
D.C. TRANSPORTATION
SYSTEM'S CRASHING,
AND THEY JUST HIT
THE ENTIRE FINANCIAL SECTOR--
EVERYTHING, ALL OF IT.
GET ME THE SECRETARY
OF TRANS AND TREASURY
ON THE LINE AND THE CHAIRMAN
FOR THE S.E.C.
LET'S GO, PEOPLE!
SOMEWHERE, SOMEBODY
LEFT A DIGITAL FINGERPRINT.
FIND IT!
IS DEPUTY DIRECTOR BOWMAN
IN HERE?
NOT NOW. IT'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
NOT TODAY, WAXWORKS.
THIS IS MATTHEW FARRELL.
I BROUGHT HIM HERE
ON DIRECT ORDERS FROM BOWMAN.
SO IF YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON,
GO FIND ME
SOMEBODY THAT DOES.
I'M BOWMAN.
VIDEO PACKAGE
IS READY FOR UPLOAD.
THANKS.
BOWMAN:
LISTEN, JOHN, APPRECIATE
YOU BRINGING FARRELL HERE,
BUT EVERYTHING'S CHANGED
THIS MORNING.
WE ARE NECK-DEEP
IN DAMAGE CONTROL.
EXCUSE ME. I'M SORRY, SIR.
DO YOU HAVE
ANYTHING, UH,
TO EAT, ANY KIND
OF SNACKS AROUND?
I WOULD LOVE, UM...
REALLY LOW BLOOD SUGAR,
AND...
SIR.
NO?
TV REPORTER:
AS IF THE NATIONWIDE
TRANSPORTATION BREAKDOWN
AND ANTHRAX SCARES
WEREN'T ENOUGH FOR ONE DAY,
THE STOCK MARKET FOUND ITSELF IN
A SELLING FRENZY THIS AFTERNOON.
THE FEDERAL TRADE COMMISSION
BELIEVES THIS PANIC
MIGHT HAVE BEEN TRIGGERED
BY A COMPUTER MALFUNCTION
IN THE STOCK EXCHANGE.
WHAT WERE THOUGHT TO BE
UNRELATED EVENTS...
OH, MAN, THAT IS ALL BAD.
REPORTER:
...A TERRORIST ATTACK.
NOT AS BAD AS IT LOOKS.
WE RUN DRILLS TO PREPARE
FOR THINGS LIKE THIS.
THESE YOUR SUSPECTS?
WERE.
ALL SEVEN WERE KILLED
IN THE LAST 24 HOURS.
RECOGNIZE ANY OF THESE PEOPLE?
NO.
NOT ONE?
WOMAN:
SIR.
GOT A SYSTEM ERROR.
(TYPING)
("HAIL TO THE CHIEF" PLAYS)
(MUSIC SLOWS, DISTORTS)
MY FELLOW AMERICANS...
IT IS TIME TO...
STRIKE
FEAR
INTO
THE HEARTS OF CITIZENRY.
ASK NOT...
IT'S AN UNAUTHORIZED BROADCAST.
...WHAT YOUR COUNTRY CAN DO
TO AVERT
THIS
CRISIS.
THE ANSWER IS
NOTHING WHATSOEVER.
OUR MILITARY
STRENGTH
-IS -IN -THIS -CASE
...USELESS.
GEORGE H.W. BUSH:
READ MY LIPS:
-THE -GREAT -CONFIDENT
-ROAR -OF
-THE AMERICAN -PROGRESS
-AND -GROWTH -HAS -COME -TO
AN END.
-ALL THE -VITAL
-TECHNOLOGY
-THAT -THIS -NATION
-HOLDS -DEAR
ALL COMMUNICATIONS
TRANSPORTATION
THE INTERNET
CONNECTIVITY
ELECTRICAL
POWER
CRITICAL
UTILITIES,
THEIR
FATE
NOW
RESTS
-IN -OUR -HANDS
WE WILL NOT TIRE.
WE WILL NOT FALTER.
AND WE WILL NOT FAIL.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW THEY'RE GETTING IN.
THANK YOU.
-AND A -HAPPY
INDEPENDENCE DAY
TO EVERYONE.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
THAT WAS CREEPY.
I TRIED TO FIND MORE NIXON.
THINK THEY BOUGHT IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
(DISTANT SIREN BLARES)
OKAY, I WANT TELECOM,
TRANSPORTATION, ANY AND EVERY...
JESUS CHRIST, IT'S A FIRE SALE.
WHAT?
IT'S A FIRE SALE.
HEY!
WE DON'T KNOW THAT YET.
IT'S A MYTH.
CAN'T BE DONE.
OH, REALLY?
PLEASE TELL ME SHE'S ONLY HERE
FOR SHOW AND SHE'S ACTUALLY NOT
IN CHARGE OF ANYTHING.
WHAT'S A FIRE SALE?
IT'S A THREE-STEP...
IT'S A THREE-STEP
SYSTEMATIC ATTACK ON THE ENTIRE
NATIONAL INFRASTRUCTURE.
OKAY, STEP ONE:
TAKE OUT ALL THE TRANSPORTATION.
STEP TWO: THE FINANCIAL BASE
AND TELECOMS.
STEP THREE: YOU GET RID
OF ALL THE UTILITIES--
GAS, WATER, ELECTRIC, NUCLEAR.
PRETTY MUCH ANYTHING
THAT'S RUN BY COMPUTERS,
WHICH, WHICH, TODAY
IS ALMOST EVERYTHING.
SO THAT'S WHY THEY
CALL IT A FIRE SALE,
BECAUSE EVERYTHING MUST GO.
HEY, L-LISTEN, LISTEN.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
FARRELL?
KEEP YOUR VOICE DOWN, OKAY?
NO ONE HERE'S TALKING
ABOUT A FIRE SALE.
NOT UNLESS YOU'RE TELLING ME
YOU HELPED PLAN ONE.
(SCOFFS)
WHAT? NO, MAN, I'M JUST
SAYING... TO EXPLAIN...
APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN.
WE KNOW WHAT WE'RE DOING;
WE'RE ON IT. THANK YOU.
(MUMBLING): YOU'VE DONE
A BANG-UP JOB SO FAR.
WHAT?
BANG...
NOTHING. I GET...
I SAID I UNDERSTAND.
HEY.
THEY DIDN'T SEND THE GIRL SCOUTS
OUT TO GET THIS KID.
THEY SENT PROFESSIONAL GUYS,
FULL TACTICAL GEAR.
THEY BLEW THE
WHOLE JOINT UP.
NOW, LOOK,
I DON'T KNOW THIS KID.
AND FRANKLY, I DON'T
GIVE A SHIT. NO OFFENSE.
BUT SOMEBODY WANTS
THIS KID DEAD.
AND OBVIOUSLY,
IT'S GOT SOMETHING TO DO
WITH WHATEVER IS GOING ON HERE.
OKAY.
HOMELAND'S TAKING OVER
THE INTERROGATION OF THE HACKERS
WE'RE BRINGING IN.
I'LL GET YOU AN
ESCORT OVER THERE.
ALL RIGHT? MOLINA,
GET THIS KID
TO THE FRONT OF THE LINE.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HE KNOWS.
MOLINA:
RIGHT.
IF THAT GUY KNEW
HALF THE SHIT
THAT I KNOW, HIS FUZZY
LITTLE HEAD WOULD EXPLODE.
SPECIAL AGENT JOHNSON.
WE'LL TAKE THE SEDAN.
AGENT JOHNSON?
THAT'S RIGHT.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
GREAT.
SO, IS ANY OF THAT
ACTUALLY POSSIBLE,
WHAT YOU WERE SAYING BACK THERE?
IS IT POSSIBLE? HERE, LOOK,
I'M GONNA TELL YOU AGAIN.
YOU TAKE OUT ANY ONE THING,
THE SYSTEM CAN
RECOVER, RIGHT?
IF YOU TAKE IT ALL DOWN AT ONCE,
THE SYSTEM CRASHES AND...
LOOK AROUND, MAN!
COME ON.
GOVERNMENT'S GOT TO HAVE
DOZENS OF DEPARTMENTS
DEDICATED TO THAT SHIT.
IT TOOK FEMA FIVE DAYS
TO GET WATER TO THE SUPERDOME.
(CAR ENGINES STARTING)
(CLAMORING)
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
HOW LONG
TILL WE GET TO D.H.S.?
LAUGHLIN.
GET ON THE D.C. POLICE BAND,
AND GET 'EM TO CLEAR
A ROUTE TO D.H.S. FOR US.
D.C. METRO, THIS IS THE F.B.I.,
REQUESTING YOU
TO CLEAR A ROUTE...
(GARBLED VOICES)
FARRELL JUST RESURFACED
ON THE GRID.
FEDS ARE TAKING HIM TO HOMELAND.
GOOD. CLOSE THAT LOOP NOW.
ISOLATE THE FREQUENCY.
GET US A LOCATION
ON THE VEHICLES
AND PULL ME UP A FILE
ON THIS JOHN McCLANE.
WOMAN (OVER RADIO):
RAND, WE JUST FOUND FARRELL.
STAND BY FOR A LOCATION.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
LOOK, I DON'T MEAN
TO HARP, GUYS,
BUT WE JUST PASSED ANOTHER
ARBY'S AND I'M STARVING.
I-I COULD EAT
A WRAPPER.
LATER. SHUT UP.
YOU DON'T EVEN
HAVE TO ORDER ANYTHING.
SHUT UP.
JUST GET SOME
KETCHUP PACKETS.
SHUT UP.
YOU GOT ABOUT 14 MINUTES
TO TELL ME WHY YOU LIED
TO ME BACK THERE.
LIED TO YOU?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THE PICTURES ON THE WALL,
YOU KNEW THOSE GUYS, RIGHT?
I DON'T... I...
KID, DON'T LIE TO ME.
I'M A COP;
I CAN TELL YOU'RE LYING.
WHO WERE THEY?
OKAY.
OKAY, OKAY.
THEY WERE MY COMPETITION.
MAKE THE NEXT RIGHT
ONTO CONCORD.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
THEY SAID THEY WERE
A SOFTWARE FIRM
THAT HAD DEVELOPED
A MUTATING ENCRYPTION
ALGORITHM, AND THEY
JUST WANTED
TO SEE IF IT
COULD BE CRACKED.
THAT'S WHAT I DO. I DO...
I-I DO MATH-BASED SECURITY.
FARRELL:
HERE'S THE THING:
THE THING THAT I'VE BEEN
THINKING ABOUT IS,
IF YOU'RE GONNA PULL
SOMETHING AS-AS MASSIVE
AND CRAZY AS A FIRE SALE,
YOU'D NEED TONS OF START-UP GUYS
TO WRITE THE PROGRAMS,
BUT ONLY A FEW BLACK HATS
TO ACTUALLY IMPLEMENT IT,
SO THEN AT
THAT POINT,
THE START-UP GUYS,
THE GUYS WHO HAVEN'T REALLY
DONE ANYTHING WRONG, LIKE ME...
WOULD END UP AS PICTURES
ON SOME GUY'S WALL.
I SWEAR TO GOD, McCLANE...
I SWEAR TO YOU,
I HAD NO IDEA I
WAS GONNA BE...
AN ACCESSORY
TO-TO-TO ARMAGEDDON.
TAKE THE NEXT LEFT
AT LEXINGTON.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
MAN, THAT'S
A SEXY VOICE.
WHAT'S SHE TAKING US
THIS WAY FOR?
UNIT 510, THIS IS DISPATCH.
OH, MY GOD.
CLEAR A ROUTE FOR TWO F.B.I.
VEHICLES APPROACHING ON CONCORD.
COPY, DISPATCH.
F.B.I., WE'VE CLEARED A PATH.
THAT'S HER.
HER WHO?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
(SIREN BEEPING)
FARRELL:
IT'S THEM.
McCLANE:
YOU'RE SAYING IT'S THEM THEM?
FARRELL:
I SWEAR TO YOU, I KNOW HER.
I WOULD KNOW HER
VOICE ANYWHERE.
DON'T SAY
ANYTHING, DON'T...
JUST KEEP YOUR MOUTH
SHUT FOR A MINUTE.
HEY, METRO,
HOW'S YOUR DAY
GOING OVER THERE?
McCLANE:
YEAH, GOT TO BE PRETTY, UH,
CRAZY OVER THERE, WHAT,
WITH ALL THOSE 587s, HUH?
YES, SIR.
WE'VE HAD TO DISPATCH ALL UNITS.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
YEAH, YOU HAD
TO DISPATCH ALL UNITS
FOR ALL THE NAKED PEOPLE
WALKING AROUND?
(STATIC CRACKLES)
CUT THE BULLSHIT, HONEY,
AND JUST PUT YOUR BOSS ON.
LAUGHLIN,
WE'RE GETTING OFF THIS ROUTE.
MAKE A LEFT HERE ON 14th STREET.
(STEADY BEEPING)
OFFICER McCLANE.
IT'S DETECTIVE McCLANE, ASSHOLE.
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
PLENTY OF TIME
TO GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER
WHEN I COME
VISIT YOU IN PRISON.
BUT, JOHN, I ALREADY KNOW
SO MUCH ABOUT YOU.
YOUR ADDRESS IN BROOKLYN,
THE PAYMENTS ON YOUR MORTGAGE,
HOW LONG YOU'VE BEEN
A MEMBER OF THE N.Y.P.D.
AND HOW'S HOLLY?
OH, THAT'S SAD.
YOU'RE DIVORCED.
WAS THAT TOUGH
ON LITTLE JACK AND LUCY?
NOW, THIS IS SAD--
AFTER 30 YEARS, I THOUGHT
YOU'D HAVE A BETTER PENSION PLAN
ANNUITY THAN WHAT I SEE HERE.
OH.
AND IT GETS WORSE.
YOUR 401k
NO LONGER EXISTS.
TELL YOU WHAT.
LET ME MAKE IT UP TO YOU.
BOX THEM IN
AT THAT INTERSECTION.
SHOOT MR. FARRELL
IN THE HEAD AND DRIVE AWAY,
AND BY THE TIME YOU REACH
THE END OF THE NEXT BLOCK,
ALL YOUR DEBTS
WILL BE WIPED CLEAN,
AND YOUR CHILDREN
WILL BE SET FOR LIFE.
McCLANE:
NOW, THAT
REALLY IS TEMPTING,
ESPECIALLY THAT LAST PART.
BUT I THINK I'M GONNA HAVE
TO PASS, JERKOFF.
JOHN...
YOU'RE A TIMEX WATCH
IN A DIGITAL AGE.
YOU'RE GONNA LOSE.
McCLANE (SIGHS):
YEAH, WELL... THE OTHER THING
THAT COULD HAPPEN IS,
I COULD COME AND FIND YOU,
KICK YOUR ASS AND THROW YOU
OUT OF YOUR OWN PARTY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THAT, DICKHEAD?
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
HE'S NOT RESPONDING.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING OVERHEAD)
(GUNFIRE)
GET DOWN! GET DOWN! GET DOWN!
JUST STAY DOWN!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
OFFICERS DOWN,
THE CORNER OF MAIN
AND CONSTITUTION!
I REPEAT: OFFICERS DOWN!
(YELLS)
COME ON! COME ON! GET OUT!
LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
GODDAMN IT!
JUST STAY DOWN!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(GUNFIRE)
GET DOWN!
JUST HANG ON!
(BULLETS POPPING,
RICOCHETING)
WE'VE GOT A SQUAD CAR
UNDER FIRE!
WE NEED BACKUP!
I REPEAT: WE NEED BACKUP!
THIS IS BASE.
WE'RE SENDING BACKUP.
BRACE YOURSELF.
(TIRES SQUEAL)
HANG ON. HANG ON.
(BEEPING)
HANG ON.
(YELLS)
YEAH!
(TIRES SQUEAL)
WE LOST DEL.
STAY WITH THEM.
THEY'RE BACK.
I KNOW.
TAKE THE TUNNEL,
LEFT, LEFT, LEFT.
(BULLETS STRIKING)
(MUTTERING FEARFULLY)
BRING UP THE SCHEMATICS
ON THAT TUNNEL.
THE TUNNEL!
OPEN THE GATES
ON THE NORTH SIDE ENTRANCE.
(HORNS BEEPING, HONKING)
REDIRECT TRAFFIC.
OCCUPY ALL LANES.
(HORNS BEEPING, HONKING)
OPEN THE OTHER SIDE.
WHAT?
MOVE!
(HORN HONKING)
JUST HANG ON
TO SOMETHING!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(ENGINE REVS, TIRES SQUEAL)
(HORN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORNS HONKING,
TIRES SCREECHING)
HEY! HEY!
DON'T GET OUT OF THE CAR! HEY!
(YELLS)
McCLANE:
JUST STAY THERE! STAND STILL!
(FARRELL YELLS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
RUN!
(PANTING):
OH, GOD.
DON'T EVER HESITATE
LIKE THAT AGAIN.
(COUGHS)
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
(PANTING):
YEAH. YEAH.
(GROANS)
MAN: ARE YOU OKAY?
MAN 2: I CAN'T MOVE MY ARM!
(HELICOPTER HOVERS NEARBY)
JUST STAY HERE.
STAY RIGHT HERE
FOR A MINUTE,
ALL RIGHT?
WHAT?
"CAN'T BE A UNIFORM,
JOHN. NO."
GET OVER TO THE WALL, SIR!
"FEDS CALLED IN A FAVOR!"
YEAH. "ALL YOU GOT TO DO
IS GO PICK UP A KID
(GROANS): IN JERSEY
AND DRIVE HIM DOWN TO D.C."
HOW HARD CAN THAT BE, HUH?
CAN'T BE THAT HARD, NO,
CAN IT?
NO, GOTTA BE
A SENIOR DETECTIVE.
(TIRES SQUEAL)
A THING LIKE A TRAFFIC JAM,
THROWING A CAR AT ME'S
GONNA STOP ME, HUH?
RAND, GET IN THERE,
GET IT DONE.
(GUNFIRE)
THIS IS NOT A GOOD IDEA.
(GRUNTS)
HA-HA.
(GROANS):
OH...
(PANTS)
(RASPY LAUGH)
OH...
DON'T TOUCH!
DON'T TOUCH ME.
OH, OKAY. SORRY, SORRY.
ARE YOU OKAY?
OH, MY GOD.
(CRASH IN DISTANCE)
PRETTY LUCKY SHOT, HUH?
YEAH, LUCKY.
THAT WAS-- YOU JUST KILLED
A HELICOPTER WITH A CAR.
I WAS OUT OF BULLETS.
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHS WEAKLY)
HOW YOU DOING?
I-I SKINNED MY KNEE,
AND MY ASTHMA'S ACTING UP
A LITTLE BIT, BUT...
(LAUGHS)
WHATEVER. YEAH, I'M FINE.
I'M GETTING TOO OLD
TO JUMP OUT OF CARS.
(OVER RADIO):
RAND, CHECK IN.
WHAT ABOUT FARRELL AND McCLANE?
(COUGHS)
COME BACK IN.
OKAY, WE'RE MOVING ON.
BEGIN STAGE THREE.
I JUST SPOKE
TO EMERSON.
THE TEAM'S ARRIVING
AT WOODLAWN NOW.
VERY GOOD.
MAI, GET READY
FOR THE DOWNLOADS.
I.D., SIR.
PARK BEHIND THE TRANSPO.
WE'LL LEAD YOU IN.
MAN THE GATE.
YOU'RE WITH ME.
(ALARM BLARING)
ANTHRAX ALARMS ONLY WENT OFF
ON FIVE FLOORS.
BELOW THAT, YOU'LL
NEED D.O.D. CLEARANCE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU'D
NEED TO GO ANY FURTHER.
THERE'S NOTHING DOWN THERE
BUT SERVERS.
(GUNSHOT, GRUNTS)
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
GO AGAIN. RODRIGUEZ?
PLEASE COPY.
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
GATE SECURED.
COPY.
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
OKAY, WE ARE IN.
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING,
BLIPPING)
(QUIET PNEUMATIC HISS)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(DEEP WHOOSHING)
THIS IS INSANE. HEY.
HEY, THIS IS ABSURD.
MAN, THERE'S TOUGH
AND THERE'S STUPID.
YOU GOT TO GO TO A
HOSPITAL. LOOK AT YOU.
I'M NOT A DOCTOR, BUT YOU
LOOK LIKE YOU'RE HURT.
YEAH. SEXY, RIGHT?
NO.
COME ON.
WE DON'T NEED A DOCTOR.
WE NEED THE COPS.
(WHIRRING)
HE'S IN.
GET OUT OF THE WAY!
LOOK OUT!
MAKE A HOLE, PLEASE! COME ON.
(EXCITED CHATTER)
McCLANE:
WATCH OUT! EXCUSE ME! EXCUSE ME!
COME ON. N.Y.P.D.
ALL RIGHT?
I GOT THIS KID.
COME ON, LET'S GO, KID.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE)
(CLAMORING)
HOLD ON.
IT'S OKAY.
YEAH. OKAY. THANKS.
N.Y.P.D.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
(MUMBLES)
SERGEANT.
SERGEANT!
I NEED TO SPEAK TO YOU.
THE MEDIC'S IN THE BACK.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
N.Y.P.D.
I GOT TO TALK TO YOU.
JUST GIVE ME
A MINUTE.
SERGEANT.
(CLAMORING FADES)
OH, MY GOD.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
(TYPING)
(MUTTERING IN ITALIAN)
PRONTO. OPEN, OPEN.
(PHONE RINGS)
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
WE'RE A GO.
LAUNCH THE DOWNLOADS.
NOTHING'S HAPPENING.
BE PATIENT.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S NOT RESPONDING.
WAIT FOR IT.
SEE?
THERE YOU GO.
LET ME KNOW WHEN THE DOWNLOAD
REACHES 20%.
OKAY.
PLEASE REMAIN CALM.
(CLAMORING)
EXCUSE ME.
(GRUNTS QUIETLY IN PAIN)
EXCUSE ME! THANK YOU!
HOLY SHIT.
KID? KID. HEY.
YEAH. YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
YOU GOT A PHONE
IN THAT BAG?
YEAH.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
AND HERE YOU GO,
AGENT... TOVAREK.
GUESS THAT'S YOU.
DOWNLOAD'S AT 20%.
TIME TO MOVE.
LET'S KEEP THEM
CHASING THEIR TAILS.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
TV REPORTER:
DUE TO RECENT ACTIVITY,
LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES
ARE BEING EXTREMELY CAUTIOUS.
THEY ARE TELLING DRIVERS
TO ABANDON THEIR VEHICLES
UNTIL THEY ARE SEARCHED.
AND AS YOU CAN SEE, CANINE
UNITS ARE CHECKING
EACH VEHICLE.
NOW, WHETHER THIS IS
CONNECTED TO
THE ANTHRAX REPORTS
WE HEARD EARLIER OR FOR
SOME NEW TERRORIST THREAT...
F.A.A. JUST GROUNDED
ALL FLIGHTS.
GOOD.
SIR, WE HAVE
COMPLETE ACCESS
OVER SYSTEM NETWORKS:
THE PHONES, POWER GRIDS,
WATER, NUCLEAR.
HEY, EXCUSE ME...
JACK PARRY, N.S.A.
CHUCK SUMMER, D.H.S. LIAISON.
WHITE HOUSE MADE THE CALL.
ANYTHING YOU NEED,
WE'RE HERE TO HELP.
HELP.
WOW, THAT'S... THAT'S GREAT.
WE'RE GONNA NEED SOME
WORK SPACE FOR OUR PEOPLE.
WHAT CAN YOU
DO FOR US?
WELL, AS YOU CAN SEE,
WE'RE USING THE SPACE.
SO YOU GUYS CAN STAND
IN THE CORNER,
AND, UH, LIAISE.
IF I NEED SOMETHING,
I'LL JUST WAVE TO YOU.
(TRUCK ENGINE RUMBLING)
FARRELL:
WAIT.
NO, NO.
DON'T-DON'T-DON'T CALL.
WHY?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THEY PROBABLY
CRACKED THAT HOURS AGO.
YOU USE IT, THEY MIGHT
BE ABLE TO TRACE US.
JUST PUT IT IN YOUR POCKET.
YOU SURE?
YES.
OR... SMASH IT.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO SMASH IT.
EXCUSE ME. EXCUSE ME.
IT'S A POLICE EMERGENCY.
HEY!
HE'LL CALL YOU RIGHT BACK.
HERE. RIGHT IN HERE.
COME HERE.
YOU GOT A SIGNAL?
YEAH.
(PHONE RINGS)
YEAH?
THIS IS JOHN McCLANE
FOR AGENT BOWMAN.
SIR, JOHN McCLANE
IS ON THE LINE.
McCLANE, GO.
WE NEVER MADE IT TO D.H.S.
THEY CAME AFTER THE KID AGAIN.
ALL YOUR MEN ARE DOWN.
WHAT ABOUT FARRELL?
YEAH, I GOT HIM WITH ME
RIGHT NOW.
SIR?
HANG ON, JOHN.
YEAH, I'LL HOLD ON.
(SIGHS)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
ANOTHER DAY IN PARADISE.
THEY JUST SWARMED
INTO EVERYTHING.
THE WHOLE TELECOM
SYSTEM: PHONES,
CELLS, BROADCAST SATELLITES.
(ORCHESTRAL FANFARE PLAYING)
(FANFARE PLAYING
ON ALL CHANNELS)
O BEAUTIFUL...
THEY'RE BLANKETING
EVERY STATION.
...SPACIOUS SKIES
FOR AMBER WAVES OF GRAIN
FOR PURPLE
MOUNTAIN MAJESTIES
ABOVE
THE FRUITED PLAIN
AMERICA, AMERICA
GOD SHED...
CAN YOU PUT THE
NEWS BACK ON?
THIS IS THE NEWS.
IT'S ON EVERY CHANNEL.
BEEN THIS WAY FOR
A FEW MINUTES NOW.
("AMERICA THE BEAUTIFUL"
CONTINUES)
(EXPLOSIONS THUNDERING)
(EXCITED SHOUTS)
OH, MY GOD. OH, MY GOD.
McCLANE.
LOOK OUT! LOOK OUT!
LOOK OUT!
BOWMAN.
BOWMAN, DO YOU SEE THAT?
McCLANE.
BOWMAN, IT'S A FAKE.
(PANTING)
I SEE IT.
THANK GOD.
(SIGHS)
OH, SHIT.
(RADIO STATIC)
McCLANE?
BOWMAN?
(BEEPING)
(ALTERNATING TONES BEEPING)
SATELLITE'S DOWN.
GET ME A LANDLINE.
SHIT.
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(SIREN BLARING)
(STEADY BEEPING)
WROTE ONE LITTLE PIECE OF CODE
AND THE WORLD
FALLS APART.
THIS IS VIRTUAL TERRORISM.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW, IT'S CRAZY,
FIRST I TIME I HEARD
OF THE CONCEPT OF A FIRE SALE,
I ACTUALLY THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE COOL
IF ANYONE EVER
REALLY DID IT.
JUST... HIT THE RESET BUTTON.
MELT THE SYSTEM JUST FOR FUN.
HEY, IT'S NOT
A SYSTEM.
IT'S A COUNTRY.
YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT PEOPLE.
ALL RIGHT? A WHOLE
COUNTRY FULL OF PEOPLE.
SITTING AT HOME,
ALONE, SCARED TO DEATH
IN THEIR HOUSES, ALL RIGHT?
SO IF YOU'RE DONE WITH
YOUR LITTLE NOSTALGIC MOMENT,
MAYBE YOU CAN THINK A LITTLE BIT
AND HELP ME
CATCH THESE GUYS.
JUST HELP ME.
JUST PUT YOURSELF
IN THEIR SHOES.
COME ON. IF THIS
WERE YOUR FIRE SALE,
OKAY, OKAY.
YOU WERE RUNNING THIS THING,
WHAT WOULD BE YOUR NEXT MOVE?
OKAY, UH...
WELL, THE WHOLE POINT
OF A FIRE SALE
IS THAT IT-IT'S MOSTLY
DONE BY REMOTE, RIGHT?
BUT... BUT NOT EVERYTHING
IS RUN COMPLETELY ONLINE.
UH, UH, MAJOR UTILITIES AREN'T.
THEY'RE RUN BY CLOSED-CIRCUIT,
SO YOU COULD BREACH THE SECURITY
UP TO A CERTAIN POINT, BUT, UM,
TO SHUT IT DOWN,
YOU WOULD HAVE
TO PHYSICALLY GO THERE.
YOU'D HAVE TO SHOW UP,
RIGHT, AND-AND, UH...
YOU KNOW WHAT?
GIVE ME THAT GUY'S P.D.A.
THE PHONES DON'T WORK.
THEY'RE ALL DEAD.
NO, THE PHONES ARE FINE;
IT'S THE NETWORK THAT'S DEAD.
I'VE JUST GOT TO REPROGRAM IT
AND LINK IT
INTO THE OLD SATCOMs.
HACKERS SURF 'EM
ALL THE TIME--
THAT'S PROBABLY
WHAT THESE GUYS ARE USING
TO TALK TO EACH OTHER.
HOW DO YOU KNOW ALL THIS STUFF?
DUDE, I DON'T KNOW.
THERE'S A LOT RATTLING AROUND
UP THERE.
I COULDN'T TELL YOU.
OKAY. NATIONAL POWER GRID-- UH,
GAS AND ELECTRIC IS DIVIDED
INTO THREE ZONES, RIGHT?
EASTERN, CENTRAL AND WESTERN,
EACH WITH A PRIMARY HUB.
HERE IT IS.
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT ARE WE LOOKING AT?
THAT IS THE EASTERN HUB.
NOW, THEY TAKE
THIS OUT...
WIPES OUT ALL THE POWER FOR
THE ENTIRE EASTERN CORRIDOR.
BUT AGAIN, YOU'D HAVE
TO DO IT MANUALLY.
OKAY...
COME ON. LET'S GO.
WHAT, TO WEST VIRGINIA?
HEY, I-I HONESTLY DON'T THINK
I CAN HANDLE ANY MORE PEOPLE
TRYING TO KILL ME.
McCLANE? McCLANE?
WELL, YOU GET USED TO IT.
McCLANE... OH, SHIT.
SIR, WIRELESS
NETWORKS ARE DOWN,
AND I THINK THEY'RE HITTING
THE LANDLINES, TOO.
I DON'T CARE HOW.
YOU FIND ME A LINE.
COME ON. WHATCHA GOT?
WE SWEPT THE WHOLE BUILDING.
SEEMS CLEAN.
WE CAN SWEEP IT AGAIN.
I DON'T THINK WE'RE GONNA
FIND ANYTHING.
DON'T BOTHER. DON'T BOTHER.
IT'S A FAKE.
THIS GUY'S PLAYING US.
OKAY, GET EVERYONE BACK INSIDE
THE CRISIS CENTER NOW.
OKAY. LET'S OPEN IT UP!
COME ON. GET IN.
DOOR'S LOCKED,
UNLESS YOU HAVE
AN EXTRA GUN
I CAN USE TO UNLOCK IT.
(GRUNTS)
HEY, HEY, DON'T DO THAT.
HEY! YOU'RE GONNA DISABLE IT.
(GRUNTS)
JESUS CHRIST!
OH! THAT WAS CRAZY.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
SORRY ABOUT THAT, MAN.
I DIDN'T KNOW
IT WOULD COME OUT SO FAST.
(GRUNTS)
UH... MAN... (MUTTERS)
HOW'D YOU DO YOURS?
(SIGHS)
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT'D YOU...? WHAT, IT HIT YOU
A LITTLE BIT? SORRY.
OH, NO, LISTEN, DO-DO NOT...
PLEASE DON'T TOUCH THOSE, OKAY?
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
I'VE DONE THIS BEFORE.
I MEAN, I-I'VE READ ABOUT IT.
OPERATOR:
ROAD ASSIST, WE'VE DETECTED
AN AIR BAG DEPLOYMENT.
YES, UM...
PLEASE, WE JUST HIT A TREE,
AND MY-MY MY DAD IS HAVING
A HEART ATTACK.
AND I THINK HE'S GONNA DIE!
YOU NEED TO HELP US.
OPERATOR:
HOLD WHILE WE CONTACT
EMERGENCY SERVICES.
(SIGHS)
NO, NO, NO, HE'S... HE'S DYING.
PLEASE, LISTEN TO ME.
I-I CAN GET HIM TO A HOSPITAL.
I CAN DRIVE. I'M FINE.
BUT I CAN'T REALLY
TURN THE KEY.
THE KEY WON'T START,
SO YOU GOTTA START
(SOBS)
THE CAR FOR US, OKAY?
PLEASE, DAD...
OPERATOR:
YOUR NAME, PLEASE?
UH...
MY NAME IS-IS...
FRANK...
AND MY DAD'S
NAME IS,
UM...
IS...
"DVORAK TSARJENSKI."
PLEASE...
PLEASE JUST HELP US, OKAY?
WE NEED YOUR HELP, PLEASE!
OPERATOR:
EMERGENCY SERVICES
ARE ON THEIR WAY.
NO, NO, H-HOLD ON.
LISTEN TO ME.
LISTEN TO ME, MA'AM.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
DOLORES.
DOLORES?
OKAY, DOLORES, UH, I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU HAVE A DAD, BUT I DO,
AND I WANT TO BE ABLE TO SAY
THAT A YEAR FROM NOW, OKAY?
BECAUSE MY DAD
IS MY HERO,
AND RIGHT NOW
HE IS IN MY ARMS DYING.
A-AND HIS ONLY HOPE I-IS TO GET
TO A HOSPITAL RIGHT NOW.
AND WE CAN'T WAIT, SO PLEASE
START THE GODDAMN CAR!
(ENGINE TURNS)
(SEAT-BELT PROMPT CHIMES)
THANK YOU, DOLORES.
PASS ME THE P.D.A.
I GOTTA CALL THE WARLOCK.
THE WHAT?
THE WARLOCK.
HE'S A DIGITAL JEDI.
HE'S AMAZING.
MA'AM, YOU'RE NOT
AUTHORIZED TO BE HERE.
F.B.I. WE SUSPECT THERE'S
BEEN A SECURITY BREACH.
NO, YOU CAN'T LAND HERE
WITHOUT AUTHORIZA...
(GROANS)
(SILENCED SHOTS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
THAT WAS PRETTY GOOD
BACK THERE, KID.
THANKS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
NOTHING ELSE TO COMPLAIN ABOUT?
NO. JUST...
WHAT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
IT'S NOT FUNNY.
I'M NOT LIKE YOU.
I CAN'T... I CAN'T DO THIS SHIT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
LIKE WHAT?
I'M NOT, LIKE... LIKE HEROIC
AND EVERYTHING, I'M...
(CHUCKLES)
NOT BRAVE LIKE YOU ARE.
I'M NOT THAT GUY.
I'M NOBODY'S HERO, KID.
YOU SAVED MY LIFE, LIKE, TEN
TIMES IN THE LAST SIX HOURS.
JUST DOING MY JOB, THAT'S ALL.
AH...
KNOW WHAT YOU GET
FOR BEING A HERO? NOTHING.
YOU GET SHOT AT.
YOU GET A LITTLE PAT
ON THE BACK, BLAH-BLAH-BLAH.
THAT-A-BOY!
GET DIVORCED.
A WIFE THAT CAN'T REMEMBER
YOUR LAST NAME.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
THIS WHOLE FLOOR'S
KIDSRESTRICTED ACCESS.
(BODY THUDS)
(RUMBLING WHOOSH)
STAY HERE.
(WHISPERS):
ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
OKAY.
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
WE'RE IN.
GOOD. SHUT IT DOWN.
(BEEPING)
GUESS YOU WERE RIGHT, KID.
OKAY, THAT'S... AWFUL.
WE GOT COMPANY.
SO, HOW WOULD THEY SHUT DOWN
THE POWER GRID?
WHAT?
COME ON!
UH... CENTRAL CONTROL ROOM.
OKAY.
(BEEPS)
UH... FOURTH FLOOR.
FOURTH FLOOR!
COME ON!
TAKE THE RIGHT.
RIGHT.
(DOOR SQUEAKS, CLANGS)
OH...
SHH!
I'M GONNA STOP HERE FOR...
JUST TRY TO KEEP UP.
I AM KEEPING UP. I JUST
WANT TO STOP FOR TWO SECONDS
TO CATCH A BREATH.
THEY HAVE THESE THINGS
CALLED GYMNASIUMS.
IT'S NOT LIKE THEY'RE...
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
(GUNSHOT, YELLS)
COME ON. LET'S GO.
LET'S GO!
RIGHT.
INTEL'S FAIRLY CERTAIN THAT
THE TERRORISTS ARE MOBILE.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO CONSISTENTLY AVOID
SIGNAL TRIANGULATION,
AND JUDGING
BY THE AMOUNT OF HARDWARE
THEY'RE RUNNING,
WE'RE PROBABLY LOOKING
FOR A LARGE VEHICLE,
MOST LIKELY A SEMITRAILER RIG.
ALL RIGHT, TELL THE GUYS AT
HOMELAND SECURITY WE NEED EVERY
AGENT, SATELLITE AND FUNCTIONING
NETWORK THEY GOT-- NOW.
(BEEPS)
McCLANE:
PLAYTIME'S OVER, SWEETHEART.
DON'T.
TAKE YOUR HAND OFF THE GUN.
HANDS UP.
STAND UP.
GO ON, NOW!
LET'S GO, KID.
YOU'RE UP.
(WHISPERS):
OKAY.
AS FAST AS YOU CAN. HEY!
JESUS!
(GUNSHOT)
OH!
(GROANING)
THAT'S ENOUGH
OF THIS KUNG FU SHIT.
I'VE KNOWN
SOME BITCHES IN MY DAY,
BUT YOU ARE THE BIGGEST...
(GROANING)
OKAY, UH...
(GRUNTS)
UH...
STILL AWAKE, HUH?
JUST KEEP DOING
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
OKAY.
HOW MUCH TIME DO YOU NEED?
UM, UM... NOT MUCH.
(GROANS)
WHOO!
ARE YOU DONE?
(PANTING)
I...
ARE YOU DONE?
NO, NO, NOT QUITE.
WHAT?
I'M NOT EXACTLY CHECKING
MY E-MAIL HERE, YOU KNOW?
THEY RAN THIS HACK IN V.M.O.,
SO I'M ISOLATING THEIR A.P.I.,
AND JUST BOOTING
THE HOST.
WHAT?!
IT MEANS ABOUT 30 SECONDS, OKAY?
NOT THE EASIEST THING
TO DO WHEN...
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
OKAY!
UNDO EVERYTHING
YOU JUST DID... NOW!
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
I'M A RIGHTY. I'M A RIGHTY.
I'M A RIGHTY. I NEED MY
OTHER HAND. I REALLY DO.
I'M A RIGHTY.
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS WITH EFFORT)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
(CLIP CLICKING)
(HAMMER SNAPS)
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
ONE LAST DOOR TO OPEN.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
I MEAN, DO YOU REALIZE WHAT
THIS'LL DO TO THE COUNTRY?
YES, I DO.
NOW OPEN THE DOOR.
OKAY, GOOD.
GLAD WE'RE ON THE SAME PAGE.
(ENGINE ROARING)
YOU DO? I'M GLAD YOU KNOW.
OOH!
HOW YOU DOING?
(SCREAMS)
HANG ON!
(GROANING)
(METAL CREAKING AND GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(CLANGING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(CLATTERING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
LISTEN... LET'S JUST TALK
ABOUT THIS FOR ONE...
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
HOW YOU DOING?
THAT'S NOT TOO TIGHT,
IS IT? HUH? HUH?
DAMN IT!
SMILE PRETTY!
(GROANS)
(METAL CREAKING)
(GRUNTS)
McCLANE!
(WHISPERS):
OH, SHIT.
McCLANE, GET OUTTA THERE!
COME ON, MAN. COME ON!
COME ON, MAN!
(GASPS)
OH, GOD.
(GRUNTING)
DID YOU SEE THAT?
(WHOOPING LAUGH)
(TRIUMPHANT YELL)
McCLANE:
SO, YOU
STOPPED IT, RIGHT?
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH. YOU KNOW,
ACTUALLY, HAVING A GUN
TO YOUR HEAD MAKES IT HARDER
TO DO THIS KIND OF WORK.
WHAT?!
I KNOW THAT COMES AS A SURPRISE.
SHIT.
YOU CAN'T JUST
TURN IT OFF?
JUST LOCK 'EM OUT?
I'M NOT SURE.
I... MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SLOW THEM DOWN, THOUGH.
WESTERN AND CENTRAL HUBS
ARE OURS.
WE'RE JUST WAITING ON MAI'S END.
HANG ON.
SOMETHING'S UP.
ALL THE SECURITY'S REACTIVATING.
(CHUCKLES)
I THINK SOMEONE MIGHT BE
IN THE MARKET
FOR SOME CHEAP VIAGRA.
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE SOME OF THAT?
NOW THAT YOUR GIRLFRIEND'S DEAD,
WHY DON'T YOU CHECK OUT OUR SEXY
SINGLES THAT YOU CAN CHAT WITH?
IT'S AN E-BOMB.
(PHONE RINGING)
HEY, H-HEY...
(BLOWS ON PHONE)
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT.
(RINGING CONTINUES)
MAI, TALK TO ME.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
MAI?
OH, YEAH.
LITTLE ASIAN CHICK,
LIKES TO KICK PEOPLE?
I DON'T THINK SHE'S GONNA
BE TALKING TO ANYBODY
FOR A REALLY LONG TIME.
LAST TIME I SAW HER, SHE WAS AT
THE BOTTOM OF AN ELEVATOR SHAFT
WITH AN S.U.V.
RAMMED UP HER ASS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
CAT GOT YOUR TONGUE?
LISTEN, JACKASS,
YOUR FIRE SALE'S OVER.
SO PACK UP YOUR LITTLE CIRCUS,
OR I'M GONNA COME
AND I'M GONNA KICK YOUR ASS.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHO I AM
OR WHAT I AM CAPABLE OF.
WHEN I'M FINISHED HERE--
AND I PROMISE IT'LL BE SOON--
I WILL FOCUS
ALL MY ATTENTION ON YOU.
YOU WANT TO MAKE THINGS
PERSONAL, FINE.
REROUTE EVERY CUBIC FOOT
OF NATURAL GAS IN THE PIPELINES
TO THAT STATION.
CAN YOU GET BOWMAN
ON THIS THING?
SURE.
I CAN GET ANYONE.
DO IT.
NOW?
YEAH. NOW.
PLEASE, NO...
IT'S THOMAS GABRIEL.
SHIT.
McCLANE:
YOU KNOW THIS GUY?!
I WORKED WITH HIM.
HE WAS D.O.D.'s CHIEF PROGRAMMER
FOR INFRASTRUCTURE SECURITY.
AFTER 9/11, HE'S THE GUY
THAT TOLD JOINT CHIEFS
THE SYSTEM WAS VULNERABLE.
HE WAS PUSHING
FOR TOTAL OVERHAUL,
BUT THEY WOULDN'T LISTEN.
GABRIEL'S NOT EXACTLY
PEOPLE-FRIENDLY.
YOU THINK SO?
WHEN HE TRIED TO GO PUBLIC,
THEY CRUCIFIED HIM...
DESTROYED HIS REPUTATION.
FROZE ASSETS. AFTER THAT,
UH...
HE DISAPPEARED.
WE GOT A PRETTY
SERIOUS PROBLEM.
(BEEPING)
WH... HOLD ON ONE MINUTE. WHAT?
I THINK WE NEED TO GET
OUT OF HERE RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE SENDING
THE GAS LINES HERE.
GAS LINES? WHAT GAS LINES?
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
CHRIST.
OH...
ALL OF THEM. SEE THAT?
THOSE FLASHING ARROWS?
THAT'S NOT GOOD.
ALL THAT'S COMING HERE?
YEAH, I THINK
WE GOTTA GO.
HE-HEY, LISTEN,
I GOTTA GO, I GOTTA GO.
JUST FIND THOMAS GABRIEL.
McCLANE? McCLANE?
LET'S GO.
LET'S GO. FINISH THIS UP!
(RUMBLING WHOOSH)
RIGHT NOW. FINISH IT UP.
COME ON. LET'S GO!
GET IN THERE!
(BLIPPING)
(CREAKING)
(PANTING)
YOU OKAY?
(COUGHING)
LET'S GO, COME ON.
GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
WHAT'S THE POINT?
KNOCK THAT OFF.
COME ON.
THIS HAS SOMETHING TO DO WITH
THAT CODE YOU WROTE FOR THEM.
ALL RIGHT? NOW THINK.
COME ON.
HELP US WIN.
(COUGHING)
WIN?
WHEN DO WE START
WINNING? HUH?
TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
DOES IT LOOK LIKE
WE'RE EVEN CLOSE TO WINNING?
WE JUST GOT THE SHIT
KICKED OUT OF US.
WHAT, DO YOU THINK
I'M HOLDING OUT ON YOU,
THERE'S SOMETHING I'M
JUST NOT TELLING YOU?
IF I KNEW WHAT THEY
WANTED, I WOULD TELL YOU.
I WOULD HAPPILY TELL YOU.
JESUS.
(BREAKERS CLANKING,
GENERATORS POWERING DOWN)
THE WARLOCK.
OH, GREAT. AH!
THERE GOES THE CELL PHONE.
THEY KNOCK THE SATELLITES
OUT OF THE SKIES NOW?
NO, YOUR BATTERY RAN OUT.
LISTEN, WE SHOULD
GO SEE HIM.
WHO?
THE WARLOCK, WE SHOULD DRIVE
TO HIS HOUSE.
HE'S NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
HE'S IN BALTIMORE.
CAN'T GO TO WARLOCK'S HOUSE.
HEY, HEY, HEY,
YOU WANT ME TO HELP YOU.
THIS IS ME HELPING YOU.
OKAY? TRUST ME.
WE GOT TO GO SEE THE WARLOCK.
IT'S OUR ONLY HOPE.
HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT FLYING?
UH, ABOUT WHAT?
YOU MEAN LIKE WITH A PILOT?
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
JUST STICK IT
IN THE ROUND THING.
WHAT BROWN THING?
HERE, PUT THESE ON.
(CLEARS THROAT)
JUST STICK IT IN THERE.
THAT'LL WORK.
(GROANS)
YOU OKAY?
UH, YEAH, I'M JUST
KIND OF AFRAID OF FLYING...
YEAH, I USED TO BE TERRIFIED
OF FLYING.
REALLY?
YEAH. TOOK SOME LESSONS.
YOU KNOW, FACE YOUR FEARS,
THAT KIND OF THING.
YEAH? DID IT HELP?
NOT REALLY.
IS IT...
(ENGINE WHIRS,
ALARM BEEPS)
IS IT SUPPOSED
TO MAKE THAT SOUND?
YEAH.
(ENGINE PURRING)
MAYBE WE SHOULD JUST DRIVE.
IT'LL BE FUN, IT'LL
BE LIKE A ROAD TRIP.
JUST TAKE IT EASY. THEY SAY
TAKING OFF IS THE HARDEST PART.
REALLY? I... I HEARD...
TO BE HONEST,
I MISSED A COUPLE OF CLASSES.
HA-HA-HA.
YOU DID, REALLY?
BUT YOU HAVE YOUR LICENSE,
RIGHT? I MEAN, YOU CAN FLY
ONE OF THESE, RIGHT?
OH...
HEY! HERE WE GO.
HEY.
WE'RE UP.
(SIGHING):
OH, GOD.
OKAY. THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
JESUS, LOOK AT THAT.
THIS WHOLE AREA IS BLACKED OUT.
HOW WE GOING
TO FIND WARLOCK'S HOUSE?
UM, IT'S PROBABLY GONNA BE THE
ONE WITH THE LIGHTS STILL ON.
POWER OUTAGE KEEPS SPREADING.
ABOUT HALF THE EAST COAST
HAS ALREADY GONE DOWN.
BOWMAN:
ALL RIGHT.
PUT EVERYTHING
ON EMERGENCY GENERATORS.
HOW THE HELL
ARE THEY GETTING PAST US?
(HELICOPTER ENGINE HUMMING)
FARRELL:
UH, OKAY.
UH, DOWN THERE, DOWN THERE,
I SEE IT.
DOWN THERE?
LEFT, LEFT, DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA LAND THERE?
WE'RE GONNA LAND DOWN THERE?
ALL RIGHT, HANG ON.
OKAY, OKAY.
OH...
FENCE.
FENCE, FENCE.
FENCE, FENCE!
I SEE...
WATCH...!
(SCREAMING)
(ALARM BLARING)
WHOO!
(WHIMPERING)
OH...
OH. JESUS.
COME ON.
OH, YEAH, OH, YEAH, TAKING
OFF IS THE HARDEST PART.
LET'S GO.
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
FARRELL:
NOW, THERE'S SOMETHING YOU NEED
TO KNOW ABOUT WARLOCK.
HE, HE HATES COPS.
I MEAN, HE HATES THEM, OKAY?
SO JUST LET ME DO
ALL THE TALKING.
(CLEARS THROAT)
SHIT.
HEY, MRS. KALUDIS.
UM, IS FREDDY HOME?
I'M MATT FARRELL
AND THIS IS, UH... BILLY.
WE'RE FRIENDS FROM SPACE CAMP.
WE WENT TO SPACE
CAMP WITH FREDDY.
FREDDY!
(SOFTLY):
FREDDY?
YOU GOT COMPANY.
FREDERICK, DIDN'T
YOU HEAR ME?
ALL BALTIMORE HEARD YOU, MA.
YOUR FRIENDS
ARE HERE.
WARLOCK:
FRIENDS? WHAT... WHAT THE...?
COME ON, MA!
HOW MANY TIMES I GOT TO TELL YOU
DON'T BRING PEOPLE
DOWN HERE, MAN?
I CAN'T SEE TOO GOOD. IS THAT
A YOUNG BEARDED HAN SOLO?
WHAT HAPPENED, MAN?
YOU LOST SO MUCH WEIGHT.
NO, DUDE, I GAINED 30 POUNDS.
WHO IS THAT?
OH, THAT'S...
YOU KNOW WHAT? DOESN'T MATTER.
DUDE, WHAT ARE YOU EVEN
DOING HERE? 'CAUSE OF YOU,
I AM ROCKIN'
FIVE GENERATORS JUST
SO I CAN STAY ONLINE.
AND SINCE YOU'RE BEING
HUNTED BY ASSASSINS,
IT DOESN'T REALLY MAKE ME
THINK, LIKE, THIS VISIT
IS A VERY PRODUCTIVE OR
HEALTHY USE OF MY TIME, AND...
HEY, HEY, DON'T
TOUCH THAT, ALL RIGHT?
C.B. RADIO?
A LITTLE LOW-TECH FOR YOU GUYS,
ISN'T IT?
LOW-TECH-- DUDE, THAT, MY
FRIEND, IS AN END-OF-THE-WORLD
INSURANCE SYSTEM, OKAY?
SO WHEN THE LAST
MICROCHIP GOES DOWN,
I'M GONNA BE ABLE
TO STAY IN TOUCH WITH
WHOEVER'S OUT THERE,
WHETHER THEY BE ZOMBIES OR NOT,
I'LL TELL YOU THAT RIGHT NOW.
WHAT'D YOU BRING
YOUR DAD HERE FOR?!
HE'S COOL; HE'S INTO THE WHOLE
GAMING CULTURE...
NICE POSTER.
WHAT, LIKE,
YOU A BIG FAN OF THE FETT?
(WHISPERS):
OH, GOD.
NO.
I WAS ALWAYS MORE
OF A STAR WARS GUY.
STAR WARS GUY.
OH, HE'S KIDDING.
WHO IS THIS MAN?!
HE'S MY...
HEY, DUMP TRUCK,
I'M NOT HIS DAD.
I'M A COP.
HOW ABOUT THAT?
OH, A COP, I'M SORRY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHY'D YOU BRING A COP
INTO MY COMMAND CENTER?!
(LAUGHING):
IT'S A BASEMENT.
IT'S A COMMAND CENTER.
DON'T HELP, McCLANE.
I CAN EXPLAIN.
JUST TELL US WHAT YOU KNOW
ABOUT THOMAS GABRIEL, ALL RIGHT?
THAT'S WHY WE CAME HERE.
THOMAS GABRIEL. THAT'S COOL.
I DIDN'T KNOW. I'M SORRY.
GET OUT-- I WANT YOU
OUT RIGHT NOW!
WHY?
HEY, HEY.
'CAUSE!
JUST CALM DOWN, BIG BOY.
YOU CALM DOWN!
THIS IS MY HOUSE.
YOU'RE GOING TO TELL ME
WHAT I WANT TO KNOW,
OR I'M GOING TO BEAT YOU
TO DEATH IN YOUR OWN HOUSE.
(GATE CLANKS)
WARLOCK:
FOUR YEARS AGO, THE D.O.D.
RECRUITS THOMAS GABRIEL TO BE
A CYBER-SPOOK FOR THEM, OKAY?
FIRST DAY ON THE JOB,
GOES IN TO HIS BOSSES
AND TELLS THEM THIS NATION'S
SECURITY INFRASTRUCTURE
IS WIDE OPEN TO COMPROMISE,
AND WHAT DO THEY SAY?
"WE'LL TAKE IT
UNDER ADVISEMENT."
BUT THIS DUDE DON'T EASE UP,
'CAUSE HE'S COMMITTED,
LIKE YOU READ ABOUT,
SO HE BREAKS INTO
A MEETING OF THE JOINT CHIEFS
OF STAFF, OKAY?
AND USING JUST A LAPTOP,
HACKS INTO NORAD
AND SHUTS DOWN OUR
ENTIRE DEFENSE NETWORK,
TILL THEY PUT A GUN
TO THE MAN'S HEAD
AND FORCED HIM TO
STOP THE HACK.
THOMAS GABRIEL'S THE GUY WHO
SHUT DOWN NORAD WITH A LAPTOP
JUST TO PROVE A POINT.
YOU THINK I'M SCARED OF YOU?
JUST TELL US HOW TO FIND
THE GUY, THAT'S ALL.
HOW DO I KNOW HOW TO FIND
THE GUY? HE'S A GHOST, MAN;
HE JUST FELL OFF THE GRID.
ANOTHER DEAD-END.
COME ON.
HOLD ON, WAIT, McCLANE.
LISTEN, WARLOCK, A COUPLE
OF WEEKS AGO, I WROTE...
I KNOW, DUDE, YOU
WROTE A MUTATING
ALGORITHMIC SECURITY CODE
THAT'S PROBABLY BEING USED
BY THOMAS GABRIEL RIGHT NOW.
NO, WE KNOW THAT, YES.
CAN YOU TELL US
WHAT HE'S USING IT FOR?
I DON'T KNOW. I'VE BEEN
TRYING TO FIGURE THAT OUT.
HERE, LOOK.
THE ONLY SECURITY SYSTEM
IN THE COUNTRY THAT I CAN FIND
CURRENTLY EMPLOYING
THAT PARTICULAR TEMPLATE
IS THE SOCIAL SECURITY
ADMINISTRATION, OKAY?
BUT THEY DON'T EVEN USE IT
IN THE MAIN FACILITY. LOOK.
THEY USE IT IN THIS BUILDING.
OVER HERE IN WOODLAWN.
OOH. WHAT THE HELL? GOD.
I KNOW, RIGHT?
"RIGHT," WHAT?
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
GUYS TALKING ABOUT?
THE POWER CONSUMPTION
IS OFF THE CHARTS.
IT'S HOT.
WHY WOULD THERE BE
CHILLING TOWERS THERE?
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
HO.
WHAT'S A CHILLING TOWER?
SEE WHAT I'VE BEEN DEALING WITH?
LARGE SERVER FARMS
GENERATE A LOT OF HEAT
AND NEED TO BE COOLED.
BUT WHY THERE?
TELL YOU WHAT, GUYS.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S IN THAT BUILDING,
BUT I ASSURE YOU IT'S NOT
SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBERS.
(BEEPING)
I GOT A RED FLAG
OVER HERE.
SOMEONE'S HACKING
INTO WOODLAWN.
HONING IN ON THE HOST
SERVER RIGHT NOW.
FREDERICK KALUDIS.
LET'S HAVE A
LOOK AT HIM.
FAT BASTARD.
McCLANE.
WHERE IS HIS DAUGHTER?
WE JUST GOT A TRACE ON HER CELL.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE THIS.
(PHONE BEEPS)
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET
A BETTER LOOK AT YOU.
(ELEVATOR WHIRRING)
GABRIEL:
FREDDY.
WHAT?
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING
DICKING AROUND
INSIDE MY NETWORK?
GABRIEL:
McCLANE?
I THOUGHT I KILLED YOU ALREADY.
I GET THAT SOMETIMES.
YOU THINK YOU CAN, UH,
FIND A TRACK WHERE HE IS?
TWO MINUTES.
GABRIEL:
DETECTIVE,
COVERING THE CAMERA
WITH YOUR HAND
DOES NOT TURN OFF
THE MICROPHONE.
YEAH...
I KNOW I'M NOT
AS SMART AS YOU GUYS
AT ALL THIS COMPUTER SHIT.
BUT, HEY...
I'M STILL ALIVE, AIN'T I?
I MEAN, YOU'VE GOT TO BE RUNNING
OUT OF BAD GUYS BY NOW, RIGHT?
HUH?
GABRIEL?
HONESTLY,
YOU CAN TELL ME.
I MEAN,
HOW DOES THAT WORK?
GOT SOME KIND
OF SERVICE OR SOMETHING?
SOME KIND OF 800 NUMBER?
1-800-HENCHMEN?
OH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I BET YOU'RE STILL ON HOLD
WITH "CAN I GET ANOTHER DEAD
ASIAN HOOKER BITCH
OVER HERE RIGHT AWAY?"
HUH? BUT SERIOUSLY,
ALL THAT KICKING ASIDE,
THAT SKINNY LITTLE NINJA CHICK,
SHE WAS SMOKIN' HOT.
A NEW ONE OF THOSE GONNA BE
REAL HARD TO COME BY, RIGHT?
YOU'RE VERY IMPRESSED
WITH YOURSELF, AREN'T YOU?
I HAVE MY MOMENTS.
YEAH?
IS THIS ONE OF THEM?
(LINE RINGING)
LUCY:
HELLO?
YES, THIS IS
EMERGENCY SERVICES CALLING.
(SIGHING): OH, THANK GOD.
CAN SHE HEAR ME?
MY NAME IS LUCY GENNERO.
I'VE BEEN STUCK FOR HOURS.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO CALL...
HEY.
CAN SHE HEAR THIS?
LUCY, HANG UP THAT PHONE.
YES. CALM DOWN, MISS.
WE KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE YOU ARE.
EVERYTHING IS GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
(LUCY SIGHS)
LUCY, HANG UP THE PHONE!
PLEASE, JOHN, I'M TRYING
TO HAVE A CONVERSATION.
WE'RE A BIT OVERLOADED TONIGHT,
AS YOU MAY IMAGINE,
BUT I ASSURE YOU, WE'RE GOING
TO GET YOU OUT OF THERE,
EVEN IF I HAVE TO COME DOWN
THERE AND GET YOU MYSELF.
THANK YOU.
IN THE MEANTIME, MISS GENNERO,
IS THERE ANYONE
YOU WOULD LIKE US
TO CONTACT FOR YOU?
LUCY:
YEAH.
MY DAD.
HIS NAME IS JOHN McCLANE.
HE'S A NEW YORK CITY COP.
WE'LL FIND HIM.
JUST HANG IN THERE, MISS.
WE'LL GET TO YOU... VERY SOON.
(SIGHING):
THANK YOU.
WOW. THAT'S A GREAT GIRL
YOU GOT THERE.
CAN'T WAIT TO MEET HER.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
CAT GOT YOUR TONGUE?
COME ON, JOHN.
MAKE A JOKE.
SAY SOMETHING FUNNY.
(WARLOCK WHISTLES SOFTLY)
WHERE ARE YOU GO...
WH-WH...
(WHISPERING):
WHERE ARE YOU GOING? HEY.
FARRELL:
McCLANE! HEY!
HOLD UP. HOLD ON.
WHERE YOU GOING?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
I'M GOING TO DO?
I'M GOING TO GO KILL THIS GUY
AND GET MY DAUGHTER.
BUT SHE COULD BE ANYWHERE.
LISTEN TO ME.
IT'S GOING TO GET MESSY.
YOU SHOULD
JUST STAY HERE.
I THINK I...
HEY, I'M DOING
YOU A FAVOR.
I WOULDN'T BET ON ME, ALL RIGHT?
I'LL TAKE IT FROM HERE.
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
(ENGINE STARTS)
I WOULDN'T BET ON YOU, EITHER,
SO I FIGURED I'D LEND A HAND.
BUCKLE UP.
(CLANKING)
(BUZZING)
F.B.I., MA'AM,
JERSEY FIELD OFFICE.
MIND IF I SEE YOUR I.D.?
NOT AT ALL.
(WRY LAUGH)
MY DAD'S A COP.
FORCE OF HABIT.
YOUR FATHER SOUNDS LIKE
A VERY SMART MAN.
KID, CAN YOU GET BOWMAN?
UH, YEAH.
(BEEPING)
IT'S COMPLETELY DEAD.
GABRIEL MUST HAVE SHUT DOWN
ALL THE SATELLITE LINKS.
SHIT.
I'M SORRY
ABOUT LUCY, MAN.
ABOUT ALL OF IT.
IT'S MY FAULT
YOU GOT INTO THIS.
THIS WASN'T YOUR FIGHT.
YOU GOT NOTHING
TO BE SORRY ABOUT.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
LET GO OF ME,
YOU BASTARD.
THIS BITCH IS A HANDFUL.
(GROANS)
ARE YOU GONNA BE ALL RIGHT?
HEY... BEHAVE...
OR I WILL HURT YOU.
OH, YEAH?
LET'S STEP OUTSIDE,
JUST YOU AND ME.
WE'LL SEE WHO HURTS WHO.
YOU REALLY ARE HIS DAUGHTER.
TIE HER WRISTS.
TREY.
GABRIEL WANTS
TO SEE YOU.
IS IT THAT TIME ALREADY?
YEAH.
OKAY.
I'LL BE BACK IN A SECOND.
NO, NO, NO, PLEASE,
PLEASE!
(ALARM BEEPING)
WE'RE SHOWING A BREACH
ON AN EXTERIOR VENT.
GO TAKE A LOOK.
DON'T BE LONG.
WE'RE PACKING UP SOON.
HEY, McCLANE.
DO WE HAVE ANYTHING RESEMBLING
A PLAN OR ANYTHING?
FIND LUCY
AND KILL EVERYBODY ELSE.
I MEAN MORE LIKE A PLAN,
LIKE A WAY TO DO THAT.
COME ON.
OKAY, ACCORDING TO THE LAYOUT,
UH, THE CHILLING TOWERS
ARE KEPT ON THE BOTTOM LEVEL.
(GRUNTS)
I THINK MINE'S LOCKED.
OKAY, NOW IT LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE GETTING SOMEWHERE.
UH...
OKAY, THIS LOOKS LIKE
IT CONTROLS THE COOLING SYSTEM
FOR THE MAINFRAME,
WHICH SHOULD BE...
IF I CAN JUST HACK IN...
...TRIP THE ALARM,
IT MIGHT ALERT BOWMAN.
(POWERING DOWN)
(ALARM BLARING)
SOMEONE SET OFF
THE ALARMS.
YES. THANK YOU, DETECTIVE.
I CAN HEAR THAT.
FIND A WAY
TO TURN IT OFF.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
(SIGHS)
WE GOT A PROBLEM.
THE ALARMS WENT OFF
AT WOODLAWN.
IT'S GOT TO BE HIM.
AND WHAT'S WOODLAWN?
IT'S N.S.A.,
A SECURE FACILITY
OUTSIDE OF BALTIMORE.
IT'S A FAIL-SAFE
WE BUILT AFTER 9/11
TO BACK UP
ALL FINANCIAL INFORMATION.
THE MOMENT THE NETWORKS
WERE HIT,
ALL THE FINANCIAL DATA
AUTOMATICALLY
BEGAN DOWNLOADING
TO THOSE SERVERS.
BANKS, WALL STREET,
CORPORATE RECORDS,
GOVERNMENT FUNDS,
ALL OF IT, BASICALLY,
A BACKUP
FOR THE ACCUMULATED WEALTH
OF AMERICA.
ALL IN ONE LOCATION?
WHAT COULD GABRIEL DO WITH IT?
WELL, IF HE COULD GET IN, HE
MIGHT TRY TO TRANSFER THE DATA
TO A PORTABLE HARD DRIVE;
THEN HE COULD HAVE ACCESS TO
THOSE ACCOUNTS FROM ANYWHERE,
SIPHON OFF BILLIONS FOR HIMSELF.
WE'D HAVE NO WAY TO TRACE IT.
OR KNOWING HIM,
HE COULD ERASE IT ALL
AND SEND US ALL
BACK TO THE STONE AGE.
WHY THE HELL
WASN'T I TOLD ABOUT THIS?
FRANKLY, UH,
IT'S ABOVE YOUR PAY GRADE.
MY PAY GRADE?
HOW THE HELL
DID GABRIEL
FIND OUT ABOUT THIS, WHEN
EVEN I DIDN'T KNOW ABOUT IT?
(SIGHS)
HE DESIGNED IT.
IT WAS HIS PROGRAM.
HE KNEW THAT HACKING
YOUR SYSTEM LAST NIGHT
WOULD TRIGGER THE DOWNLOAD.
THAT'S BRILLIANT.
YOU TWO GENIUSES
STAY OUT OF MY WAY.
(ALARM BLARING)
FARRELL:
LET ME SEE IF I CAN GET
A FLOOR PLAN OF THIS PLACE.
OKAY...
DON'T MOVE!
YOU-- GET AWAY FROM THE BAG.
NOW!
OKAY. OKAY.
WE'VE BEEN WAITING FOR YOU.
YEAH?
I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU, TOO.
(GUNFIRE)
(YELPS)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
McCLANE!
KID!
MATT!
KID?!
(RATTLING)
EMERSON.
(BEEPING)
WE SEEM TO HAVE A PROBLEM
IN ONE OF THE COOLING TOWERS.
TOWER SEVEN.
FIND OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
(SPEAKS ITALIAN) OKAY.
SIR?
GET THE H.R. TEAM
TO STAND BY.
WE NEED TO GET
TO WOODLAWN NOW.
THE ROADS OUT
ARE COMPLETELY BLOCKED.
D.C. IS IN TOTAL GRIDLOCK.
WELL, GET US SOME HELICOPTERS.
SIR, THEY'VE ALL BEEN
PULLED BY THE PENTAGON
FOR SEARCH AND RESCUE.
MOLINA, FIND ME SOME GODDAMN
HELICOPTERS IMMEDIATELY.
LOOK, THE PENTAGON HAS JETS
FLYING CAP OVER D.C. HAVE
THEM SEND ONE OVER TO WOODLAWN
AND KEEP AN EYE ON THINGS
TILL WE GET THERE.
LET'S GO.
(GRUNTING)
WHERE'S MY DAUGHTER?
(BEEPING)
RUSSO, CHECK IN.
YEAH, I THINK, UH...
RUSSO'S ON HIS WAY DOWN
TO MEET YOUR GIRLFRIEND,
DICKHEAD.
HOLD ON A MINUTE.
LOOKS LIKE HE'S COMING AROUND.
IT'S McCLANE. HE'S ON THE
THIRD FLOOR AND THE KID IS...
(GUNSHOT, LUCY GASPS)
McCLANE:
GET ALL THAT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'M ON THE THIRD FLOOR,
BUT I'M COMING TO GET YOU.
DON'T MOVE NOW.
I'LL SEND A DOCTOR.
KILL THIS GUY AND I'LL
GIVE YOU MAI'S CUT.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(QUIETLY):
SHIT.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(QUIET PNEUMATIC HISS)
MY ALGORITHM.
(FOOTSTEPS)
OKAY, PLEASE GET IN.
(KISS)
OH, PLEASE. GOD.
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
(QUIET HUM)
OH, JESUS, THEY'RE GOING
AFTER THE MONEY.
GABRIEL:
YOU COMING TO GET ME, JOHN?
IS THAT THE PLAN?
YEP. THAT'S MY PLAN.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK I WON'T PUT
A BULLET IN YOUR DAUGHTER'S HEAD
RIGHT NOW?
'CAUSE YOU'RE SCARED OF ME.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YOU THINK I'M AFRAID OF YOU?
'CAUSE OTHERWISE
SHE'D BE DEAD ALREADY.
YOU NEED A BARGAINING CHIP.
STOP THERE.
HANDS UP.
IF YOU KILL ME, YOU'LL
NEVER GET IT OPEN.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
MOVE AWAY.
MOVE!
(BEEPING)
YOU KNOW, JOHN,
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE GOTTEN OFF
ON THE WRONG FOOT.
AND BECAUSE OF THAT,
YOU THINK I'M THE BAD GUY,
AND NOTHING COULD BE
FURTHER FROM THE TRUTH:
I'M THE GOOD GUY HERE.
I TOLD THEM THIS COULD HAPPEN
IF THEY DIDN'T PREPARE.
DID I GET A THANK-YOU?
NO, I GOT CRUCIFIED.
BUT THEY WOULDN'T LISTEN.
YOU GOT THEIR ATTENTION NOW,
DON'T YOU?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I AM DOING THE COUNTRY A FAVOR.
(CHUCKLING):
BY TEARING IT APART.
BETTER ME THAN SOME OUTSIDER,
SOME RELIGIOUS NUT JOB
BENT ON ARMAGEDDON.
NOBODY WANTS TO SEE THAT HAPPEN.
EVERYTHING I'VE BROKEN
CAN BE FIXED...
IF THE COUNTRY IS WILLING
TO PAY FOR IT.
AH, BULLSHIT.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
ABOUT THE MONEY.
WHAT, I SHOULDN'T GET PAID
FOR MY WORK?
I'M WORKING
MY ASS OFF HERE, JOHN.
WELL, JUST SIT TIGHT, ASSHOLE.
I GOT A CHECK FOR YOU.
(SIGHS)
I CAN'T TALK TO THIS GUY.
YOU TALK TO HIM, SEE IF
YOU CAN GET HIM TO FOCUS.
DAD?
HI, BABY.
NOW THERE ARE ONLY FIVE OF THEM.
HANG ON, LUCY. I'M COMING.
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
WOULD SOMEBODY PLEASE
KILL THIS SON OF A BITCH?
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
NO, THERE'S...
THERE'S ACTUALLY
NO PROBLEM.
I THINK I JUST GOT OFF
ON THE WRONG FLOOR.
TREY:
THIS IS A MESS.
WOW, I'M... I'M TRULY
IMPRESSED, MAN.
HACKING EVERY BYTE
OF FINANCIAL DATA FOR THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY WOULD TAKE WEEKS
UNLESS YOU ELIMINATED
THE CONGESTION.
THAT'S WHAT THIS
FIRE SALE'S ABOUT, ISN'T IT?
(CHUCKLING):
THAT'S BRILLIANT.
YES, IT IS.
PLEASE BE QUIET.
ASSHOLE.
WHO ARE YOU?
MATT FARRELL.
LUCY McCLANE.
I THOUGHT YOUR NAME
WAS GENNERO.
LUCY GENNERO.
NOT TODAY.
CAN YOU CRACK THE CODE?
MAYBE, I MEAN,
IF I HAD ENOUGH TIME.
THAT'S ENCOURAGING.
TAKE THEM WITH US.
LET'S GO.
GABRIEL, PENTAGON JUST
SENT AN F-35 TOWARDS US.
KEEP AN EYE ON IT.
PULLING DOWN THE GO CODES NOW.
(DOOR CREAKING)
YOU MIGHT WANT TO START
THINKING ABOUT WHAT YOU WANT
ON YOUR HEADSTONE, ASSHOLE.
(GUNFIRE)
CHRIST.
GODDAMN HAMSTER.
HERE YOU GO.
STAY STILL, SPIDER BOY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
GODDAMN IT!
(HISSING)
(LAUGHING):
OH-HO-HO, NO.
SERIOUSLY, YOU PROBABLY
SHOULDN'T ANTAGONIZE THEM
SINCE THEY HAVE ALL
THE LOADED GUNS AND WHATNOT.
LISTEN, WILL YOU
JUST TAKE A MINUTE
AND DIG DEEP FOR
A BIGGER SET OF BALLS,
'CAUSE YOU'RE GONNA NEED
THEM BEFORE WE'RE THROUGH.
WOW, I KNOW THAT TONE.
IT'S JUST WEIRD HEARING IT
COME FROM SOMEONE... WITH HAIR.
(ENGINES REVVING)
SIR.
E.T.A.: 15 MINUTES.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
FIX IT.
OH, WHY? YOU'RE JUST GOING
TO KILL ME IF I FIX IT.
I KNOW THAT.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING):
SHIT.
I'M NOT GONNA DO IT.
OH, NO, NO, NO. SHIT.
ROBINSON IS COMING PRETTY FAST.
I'M SORRY. WHAT?
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
ROBINSON IS COMING TOO FAST.
TREY:
IT'S NOT ROBINSON.
THAT WOULD BE MY DAD.
(RADIO STATIC)
McCLANE (OVER RADIO):
FREDDY.
FREDDY!
IT'S JOHN McCLANE.
LOOK, I KNOW YOU CAN HEAR ME.
THIS IS YOUR FREQUENCY, RIGHT?
666.
COME ON.
PICK UP THE MIKE, FREDDY.
UH, NOBODY HERE
BY THAT NAME, SORRY.
HACKER JERKOFF!
(ANGRY SIGH)
WARLOCK...
I NEED YOU TO DO
WHATEVER IT IS YOU DO TO
PATCH ME THROUGH TO THE F.B.I.,
TO DEPUTY DIRECTOR BOWMAN.
YOU HEAR ME?
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
YOU WANT ME TO INTENTIONALLY
OPEN UP A COMM LINE
TO THE HEAD OF THE F.B.I. CYBER
DIVISION? I DON'T THINK SO.
FREDDY, GODDAMN IT.
THEY HAVE MY DAUGHTER.
(STATIC HISSING)
I CAN DO THAT. HOLD ON.
THANK YOU.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
THIS IS CENTRAL. WE HAVE
A PATCH FOR DIRECTOR BOWMAN.
SIR, CENTRAL'S
TRYING TO REACH YOU.
GO.
BOWMAN, IT'S McCLANE.
McCLANE.
LISTEN TO ME.
GABRIEL IS ON THE 695 HEADED
NORTH IN A HAZMAT TRUCK.
BOWMAN:
WAIT, GABRIEL HAS LEFT WOODLAWN?
WE'RE HEADED THERE RIGHT NOW.
AND, BOWMAN,
HE'S GOT MY DAUGHTER.
LISTEN, THIS HAZMAT TRUCK
IS A GOVERNMENT VEHICLE,
SO IT SHOULD BE LOJACKED, RIGHT?
TRACK THAT DOWN, IT SHOULD
TAKE YOU RIGHT TO THEM.
GIVE ME THE TAG NUMBER.
ALL RIGHT, HANG ON.
HERE IT COMES.
GOLF-TANGO...
FIVE-NINER-TWO-NOVEMBER.
YEAH, GOT IT.
McCLANE, WHERE IS FARRELL?
HE'S WITH THEM.
LISTEN TO ME.
I'M GOING TO GO IN THERE
AND GET LUCY OUT,
BUT IF SOMETHING HAPPENS TO ME,
YOU GOT TO SEND THE CAVALRY IN,
YOU HEAR ME?
I MEAN EVERYBODY.
DON'T LET THAT MANIAC GET
MY DAUGHTER, YOU HEAR ME?
JOHN, DON'T WORRY.
I WANT YOUR WORD, BOWMAN.
YEAH, YOU HAVE IT.
McCLANE OUT.
(ENGINE ROARING)
THERE'S THE F-35.
DID YOU GET THE GO CODES?
TREY! DID YOU GET THE GO CODES?
YES, YEAH, I GOT THE GO CODES.
CAN YOU CONNECT ME TO THE PILOT?
UH...
UH... UH...
(TIRES SCREECHING)
ISOLATING HIS RADIO.
SENDING HIM THE GO CODES.
AV-81.
AV-81, THIS IS MARINE
AIR WING A.T.C.
PILOT (OVER RADIO):
GO FOR AV-81.
CONFIRMED TERRORIST VEHICLE
HAS BEEN LOCATED
IN YOUR SECTOR: BIG RIG TRUCK.
GABRIEL:
CURRENTLY IN PURSUIT
OF A HAZMAT VEHICLE.
PILOT:
I SEE THEM, A.T.C.
YOU ARE AUTHORIZED
TO ENGAGE AND DESTROY.
COPY THAT. AV-81 ENGAGING.
(F-35 ROARING OVERHEAD)
WHAT?
(BEEPING)
JESUS CHRIST!
GODDAMN IT!
YOU'RE SHOOTING
AT THE WRONG GUY!
I DON'T THINK
DADDY'S COMING, HONEY.
(F-35 ROARING OVERHEAD)
(RUMBLING)
HEY! JACKASS!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
IS THAT IT?! HUH?!
IS THAT YOUR BEST SHOT?!
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(TIRES SPINNING RAPIDLY)
(SQUEALING)
COME ON!
(BLIPPING)
(YELLS)
(ALARM BEEPING)
COME ON!
(GRUNTS)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(YELLING)
(YELLS)
(DEBRIS CLATTERING)
(COUGHING, GROANING)
WHEW.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(PANTING)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
LET'S GO! COME ON!
GOT TWO MORE TO GO.
THAT WAY. THAT WAY. GO.
LET'S GO. MOVE IT.
WE ARE LEAVING IN THREE MINUTES.
YOU HAVE ONE.
THE RULES HAVEN'T CHANGED, MAN.
YOU'RE GONNA KILL ME
THE MINUTE I UNLOCK IT.
(GUNSHOT, SCREAMS)
(FARRELL YELLING, LUCY CRYING)
OH, SHIT! OH, SHIT...
MATTHEW? MATTHEW!
I REALLY NEED YOU
TO PAY ATTENTION.
(EXHALES)
THE RULES CAN ALWAYS CHANGE.
OKAY, WAIT.
I'M GONNA SHOOT HER
IN TEN SECONDS.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
NINE...
I CAN'T.
EIGHT...
OH, GOD...
(GUNSHOT)
YAAH! OKAY!
(GUNSHOT, SOBBING)
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
SIX...
OKAY, JUST STOP. STOP, STOP.
I'M DOING IT. I'M DOING IT.
FARRELL:
OH, GOD.
(TYPING)
OH, MY GOD.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
FEDS ARE HEADED
THIS WAY.
GET EVERYTHING ON THE PLANE.
(GUNSHOT)
(GUNSHOTS)
DAD!
GABRIEL:
CAREFUL.
DON'T WORRY, BABY.
EVERYTHING'S
GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
(GUNSHOT)
LUCY (SOBBING):
DADDY!
(GROANS IN PAIN)
(LUCY GASPS, SOBS)
HOLD THIS.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOT, YELLS, GROANS)
(GASPS):
NO!
JESUS CHRIST.
YOU GOT HER?
YOU'RE SURE?
(GASPS)
IT'S A NICE EFFORT, THOUGH.
MATTHEW!
OH, SHIT!
ALL RIGHT, OKAY!
FARRELL:
OKAY, I'M DOING IT. I KNOW.
(GRUNTS)
(McCLANE GRUNTING, LUCY CRYING)
McCLANE.
(GRUNTS)
WOULD YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
I KNOW THE LIGHTS
ARE BEGINNING TO DIM,
BUT IF YOU COULD JUST HANG ON
FOR A SECOND, AS SOON
AS MATT'S FINISHED,
I'M GONNA KILL HIM
AND YOUR DAUGHTER,
AND I WOULD LOVE
FOR YOU TO SEE THAT.
GODDAMN IT. MATTHEW?
TEN SECONDS, OKAY, TEN SECONDS
YOU'LL HAVE ALL YOUR MONEY.
YOU JUST LEAVE.
NO ONE HAS TO GET HURT, OKAY?
A FEW SECONDS.
STAY WITH ME.
McCLANE!
(GRUNTS IN PAIN)
STAY WITH ME.
DAD?
ON YOUR TOMBSTONE,
IT SHOULD READ:
"ALWAYS IN THE WRONG PLACE
AT THE WRONG TIME."
HOW ABOUT... "YIPPEE-KI-YAY,
MOTHERFU..."
(GUNSHOT)
(GUNSHOTS)
(WINDSHIELD SQUEAKING)
LUCY (CRYING):
DADDY...
ARE YOU OKAY?
McCLANE (WHISPERS):
YES, BABY, I'M FINE.
(SOBBING):
I KNEW YOU WOULD COME FOR ME.
McCLANE:
OF COURSE I'D COME FOR YOU.
SORRY IT TOOK ME
SO LONG. IT'S OKAY.
(GRUNTING)
MOVE, MOVE!
AGENT:
FREEZE!
HOLD, HOLD!
HE'S OKAY.
MOVE AROUND. COME AROUND!
(GROANS):
HERE, HELP DADDY UP.
OKAY.
WAIT, WAIT. OH, WAIT.
I THINK I'LL
JUST STAY HERE
FOR A MINUTE.
OKAY. DADDY, YOU'RE
OUT OF YOUR MIND.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
(LAUGHS):
YOU SHOT YOURSELF!
IT SEEMED LIKE A GOOD
IDEA AT THE TIME.
DON'T TELL THESE GUYS
THAT I DID THAT.
(LUCY LAUGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER, HORN BLOWS)
THANKS FOR ALL
YOUR HELP, JOHN.
THANK YOU.
IS HE OKAY?
SHOULD I PUT MY HANDS UP?
NO, DON'T PUT YOUR HANDS UP.
PUT 'EM DOWN FARTHER?
YEAH.
HE MIGHT DIE OF SHOCK ON
THE WAY TO THE HOSPITAL.
ALL RIGHT.
(GROANING)
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
McCLANE:
HEY.
OH, HEY.
HOW'S IT FEEL TO BE SHOT?
IT ACTUALLY FEELS GREAT.
UH, HE GAVE ME SOME...
WHAT IS IT CALLED? MOR...
MORPHINE.
WOW, YOU GOT YOUR
MERIT BADGE NOW.
YEAH... HEY, I DON'T
KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
(CHUCKLES)
PLUS, YOU KNOW,
CHICKS DIG SCARS.
REALLY? HM.
NOT THAT ONE.
WHAT?
DON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT IT.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
WHAT I WAS THINKING?
WHY? DID SHE SAY
SOMETHING TO YOU?
I FELT LIKE WE HAD A, UM...
KIND OF A VIBE.
TAKE IT EASY.
THAT'S JUST THE
MORPHINE KICKING IN.
YEAH.
BESIDES,
AFTER ALL WE'VE
BEEN THROUGH,
I'D HATE TO HAVE TO
BEAT YOU TO DEATH.
(CHUCKLES)
THAT WOULD SUCK.
GOOD TO GO?
YEAH, WE'RE ALL SET.
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF.
I'LL SEE YOU AT THE HOSPITAL.
HEY.
THANKS FOR SAVING
MY DAUGHTER'S LIFE.
HEY...
WHAT WAS I GONNA DO?
THAT'S WHAT MAKES YOU THAT GUY.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
YEAH.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
SO, UH, DID HE SAY
ANYTHING ABOUT ME?
JESUS, LUCY!
WHAT? I-I'M SORRY.
I'M JUST ASKING.
I'M IN ENOUGH
PAIN ALREADY.
HOSPITAL.
(INTRO TO "FORTUNATE SON"
PLAYING)
SOME FOLKS ARE BORN
MADE TO WAVE THE FLAG
OOH, THEY'RE
RED, WHITE AND BLUE
AND WHEN THE BAND PLAYS
"HAIL TO THE CHIEF"
OOH, THEY POINT
THE CANNON AT YOU, LORD
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T
NO SENATOR'S SON, SON
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T NO FORTUNATE ONE, NO
SOME FOLKS ARE BORN
SILVER SPOON IN HAND
LORD, DON'T THEY
HELP THEMSELVES, OH
BUT WHEN THE TAX MAN
COMES TO THE DOOR
LORD, THE HOUSE LOOKS
LIKE A RUMMAGE SALE, YES
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T NO MILLIONAIRE'S SON,
NO, NO
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T NO FORTUNATE ONE, NO
YEAH
SOME FOLKS INHERIT
STAR-SPANGLED EYES
OOH, THEY SEND YOU
DOWN TO WAR
AND WHEN YOU ASK 'EM
HOW MUCH SHOULD WE GIVE?
OOH, THEY ONLY ANSWER
MORE, MORE, MORE, MORE
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T NO
MILITARY SON, SON
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T
NO FORTUNATE ONE, ONE
IT AIN'T ME
I AIN'T NO
FORTUNATE ONE, NO, NO, NO
(SONG FADES AWAY)
IT AIN'T ME...
(ORCHESTRAL SCORE FADES IN)
(OMINOUS THEME PLAYING)
CC/Subtitles by 3rd eye