A SHOCHIKU PRODUCTION
GOOD MORNING
Screenplay by KOGO NODA
YASUJIRO OZU
Photography by
YUSHUN ATSUTA
Music by
TOSHIRO MAYUZUMI
Film Editor
YOSHIYASU HAMAMURA
Cast
KEIJI SADA
YOSHIKO KUGA
CHISHU RYU KUNIKO MIYAKE
HARUKO SUGIMURA
KOJI SHIDARA
MASAHIKO SHIMAZU
KYOKO IZUMI TOYO TAKAHASHI
SADAKO SAWAMURA
EIJIRO TONO
TERUKO NAGAOKA
EIKO MIYOSHI HARUO TANAKA
AKIRA OIZUMI
Directed by
YASUJIRO OZU
Push again
See?
-Me too
You're no good
What's the matter?
Come on
Mrs. Okubo
Thankyou
Nice spinach
It's so expensive.
20 yen
Can't even eat spinach now
No. Listen
I heard a funny thing.
Our dues weren't paid
But we paid
Yes. Our women's
Assn Chairman said
we haven't paid our dues
But I paid
So did l.
-Then it's strange
It's strange
It couldn't be...?
-What?
She bought a washing machine
Yes, but on installments
But isn't it strange
about our dues?
Mrs. Okubo
She's here.
-Yes
Women's bulletin board!
Back?
You're early?
What is it?
I'm home
Where are you going?
Not next door!
No, I'm going to study
He's crazy about television
-Sumo wrestling season?
-Yes
Listen
What happened the other day?
It's very strange
Why?
I'll go over first
Please, Mother,
get me another pair of pants!
What's the matter? Loose tummy?
Why do you soil your pants?
It's every day
I didn't buy a washer
foryour pants!
Mother, please give me
a clean pair of pants
Watching wrestling's all right
But they never learn
anything good over there
Figures.
We don't associate with them,
but that couple is in pyjamas
all day long
She used to work in a cabaret, so...
Well...she's that kind?
Excuse me.
-How much is the sauce?
Never mind.
I owe you money too. Later
Then...
Hello
Come in. Come on
Minoru isn't here?
No
Wakanohana's good today
Any idea who'll win?
That's easy. Isn't it?
Sure. He's got a great overthrow.
Eat some
Time to go
Isn't your next door friend coming?
Shall we call him?
-Minoru!
Come on
What's the matter? Hurry!
-I'm going!
Where are you going?
To study English
Isamu too?
-Yes
Not TV again?
Don't go next door
Silly
Mrs. Hayashi
Excuse me
It's a funny question, but...
Did you hand over our dues
to our group head?
Yes, about 1 0 days ago
I see. I thought so!
But the Chairman said
she didn't receive them
Why?
Mrs. Haraguchi bought
a washing machine
But she wouldn't...
No, but...
Mrs. Okubo says
she handed them to you
Yes, she did.
Shall I ask our group head?
But ifshe's...
I handed them to her
Ofcourse.
You never make mistakes
What happened then?
It's distressing
Excuse me
Kozo, you're here again?
Why don't you listen?
How do you do
I'm sorry my son's always bothering you
What about your English lesson?
Minoru too?
Your mother will scold you, Zen
It must be such a nuisance foryou
We don't mind a bit
Hurry! Come home!
All ofyou!
I'm not going. I'm done studying
What? I'll tell your mother!
Come!
Excuse me
Good-bye
Tell your teacher "Hello"
from Big Sister
You're Big Sister?
What was the hold up?
What about your English lesson?
Excuse me
Yes? Who is it?
I heard from Mrs. Tomizawa
But I handed over the dues
to our group head long ago
But the fuss makes me
feel responsible
I really...
Don't worry about it, Mrs. Hayashi
We know it's not you
You didn't have to comejust for that
But l...
It's because Mrs. Tomizawa mentioned
the washing machine, so l...
That doesn't concern me
Ofcourse not.
Not at all
But why hasn't the Chairman
received the dues yet?
It's so unpleasant foryou, isn't it?
I'll ask Mrs. Haraguchi
I feel responsible
Oh, I wouldn't do that.
It would be hard on her
But l...
Don't worry.
We all trust you
Time will tell who's to blame.
Don't you worry
It's a whodunit...
Iike that movie, remember?
But l...
Don't you worry
What are you doing?
Did you do the translation?
I'm doing it right now
Are you done?
Read it
Translate it
My sister is three years old
and younger than me
No, that's a bit different.
Ko?
Translate it
Go ahead, translate it
-Sorry, it's become a habit
-What?
We all do it now.
Push here again
Fool
-Are you all right?
-Sure
What is it?
I practice every day
eating pumice powder
Stupid. Who said so?
-Zen's father
It's not true.
He was teasing you
No, it's true. Isn't it?
He's good at it
You called me?
No.
-I see
I'm back!
Why don't you listen to me?
You were next door again.
-So what? We went to see TV.
-I said no!
-Buy us a TV then!
-Nonsense!
Buy one.
-No! Eat your supper!
Dried fish and miso soup again?
Don't complain!
You, too, lsamu?
Not me
You're back?
I'm home
-You were together?
-From the station
-You're back
-We're having dried fish again
You said you wouldn't complain!
The pork soup's good.
-Is it? Good
No! Not every night!
Aunt!
My teacher said to wait for the
translation until tomorrow
I see
How was the sumo?
I don't know.
We don't have a television set
Mom, buy us a TV set!
No!
What about the radio?
It has to be a TV.
You can't see on the radio
Buy us a TV set!
-Buy us a TV set!
No, no! I said, "No!"
Would you like a bath?
You filled the tub?
Who spilled the toothpaste?
-Not me
-Me neither
Who then?
I don't know
Neither do I
Good morning, sir
Good morning
Don't dawdle on the way
Ready?
No good
Good. Push me
Let me
How about it?
You've gotten good.
Do you eat sweet potatoes?
No
Did you call me?
What is it?
I'm going to Kameido.
Do you want some sweets?
Yes, buy some
It's a fine day
Yes?
Good morning
You're early
Are you done with the translations?
I have to look up
every technical term
My office wants it today
-How is the rest?
-Let me see
Will you take this much then?
-I'll finish the rest today
-Ifyou will, please
Sis
Welcome, I thought it was you
-Good morning
-Good morning. To work already?
I'm sorry to botheryour brother
No, it's good sidework
My company folded so
I'll do anything
I'll take this.
Thanks
Setsuko. There's talk about doing
The class reunion at Chinzanso
Tell your sister.
-Yes, I will. Then...
Good-bye.
-Excuse me
Good-bye
Setsuko's nice
Wouldn't it be nice
ifshe married you?
Are you joking?
I'm out ofa job now
That's no problem.
You'll find a job
What about you?
How's yourjob?
I may sell another Austin today
I see. That's great
It's an insult
Excuse me!
Anyone here?
-Yes
Mrs. Haraguchi.
Come in from the front
Never mind. A word
What is it? Please come in
It's a mess but please
Excuse me then
You know we bought
a washing machine
Yes, I heard
I want one too,
but I can't afford it yet
Buy one ifyou want
It's your own money.
Why worry?
We're not rich like you
But we bought one
without bothering anyone else!
Mother's making money too!
We needn't steal the dues
It's an insult!
Who said such a thing?
Don't pretend you don't know.
Askyourself
What?
-I'm fastidious by nature!
I'd never steal anything!
This hateful gossip! I'm going to quit!
I'll quit being group head!
It's making a fool of me!
I'm afraid I don't understand
The dues. You're the treasurer
What about it?
You said you gave me the dues?
That sounds like I cheated!
I haven't received the dues!
I took them over.
I'm sure
When?
-Last month... the 28th
No!
-I did!
But I gave it to your mother...!
Then she'd hand it over to me
I wouldn't know. Ask her
Excuse me
How do you do
Want some rubber strings
tooth-brushes, pencils, brushes?
We have everything
I see. Everything?
Everybody says so
A pencil then?
Very quiet here, isn't it?
We don't need anything
No? Don't say that.
How about it? Buy a pencil
It cuts good
How about you? Want a pencil?
Pencils, rubber strings,
tooth-brushes, brushes?
Hey, Missus
Whatever...
-Grandmother!
-What's the fuss?
Did the vendor come?
Will you go out when he comes?
He's awful
What? What happened?
Excuse me.
-See? He came!
Yes, who is it?
How do you do
Rubber strings,
tooth-brushes, pencils
Scrubbing brushes
No, thanks
It cuts good. Buy this pencil?
No.
-Don't say that. Buy a pencil
Can I sharpen it to see?
Sure, sharpen it. You can
Never mind.
I'll sharpen it with ours
I've got cotton too. Want some?
-No
Lend me the pencil
It's sharp
How much is this?
50 yen
It's expensive. Too expensive
What's the matter? Leaving?
Come again
Shut the door
-He left?
-Yes, he even left a pencil. See?
-No one can beat you.
-Can't be a coward and be a midwife
Listen, you didn't by any chance
receive the dues?
I would have given it to you
-You would?
-Yes
Mrs. Hayashi swears she paid you
She didn't!
What is it?
Wait a minute
This?
Yes, this
Why didn't you give it to me?
But l...
But what?
Thanks to you,
I was ashamed everywhere!
I'm the group head!
I'm blamed for everything!
So senile
Go to Mt. Narayama
where the old go to die!
It makes me sick!
Humiliated when I didn't need to be
Senile!
It's the limit!
Always fussing
Thinks she grew up
all by herself!
After driving me crazy
Marrying a no-good husband
Thinks she's hot stuff
Bearing a son like that.
She's got some nerve
Excuse me again
Sorry about earlier
I'm so sorry
My mother is terrible
Shejust told me
she'd received the dues
I don't know how to apologize
I'm very sorry
It's all right ifyou know
I'm really sorry
I'd like to crawl into a hole
Please forget what I said
I don't mind
Really?
-It's over
I'm so glad! Thanks
Don't tell anybody, will you?
People gossip
No, I won't
Please. Excuse me
Listen, Mrs. Haraguchi
How about this?
A bell to prevent crimes.
Patent's pending
Push this for burglars and fires
and it can be heard for 200 meters
A burglar alarm?
For men who force sales too
You should've come sooner
Did he come here?
I had to buy pencils.
Rubber bands, too
That's why the police
recommend this
How about one?
Well... Shall I buy one?
Your place?
-I have a better one
-You do?
Grandmother.
She can handle most men
What a nice day
Yes, it is
UKIYO RESTAURANT
It's empty
One more!
-Yes
It's cold!
-You're late
-I bought this when I went out
Tomorrow's races?
You really like that?
How about the third race
It's no good. No chance
No?
-No
The opposite?
No good
-Here you are
-You think?
Me too
One more
Welcome
Did I leave my glove here?
No. Did you see it?
No, I didn't
Mr. Hayashi
Sit down
Thanks
Here you are
Where to, today?
No prospects but I have to eat
Thanks
When is it foryou?
Retirement
It's terrible.
Like being killed slowly
Companies think we don't eat
after we retire
But I eat and drink
My wife fusses
but I can't find a job
I'm bogged down
No place under the sky to hide
It's very sad
But your retirement allowance...
No, no, the company's smart
and won't pay much
For 30 years, rain or shine
riding a crowded train
It's all empty...futile
Mr. Tomizawa
Leave me alone
Some well-cooked root cake
What are you doing?
You're not eating?
No!
No? Don't then
It's no fun!
Behave or I'll...
Stingy!
Go hungry for all I care!
Isamu?
I won't eat
Do as you wish
Fools! How long are you going
to keep it up?
Come here, lsamu!
Isamu!
I won't go
Why are you so unreasonable?
I'll tell Father!
I don't care! I'm not afraid!
Here's Father!
It's Father!
You're home
It's cold, no?
Met Mr. Tomizawa at a pub.
He was pretty drunk
-What's up?
-They're impossible
-What's wrong?
-They won't listen to me at all
-What?
-I tell them not to
but they go next door
to watch TV anyway
So buy us one!
They went next door instead
of English class again today
They're a big headache
Then buy us a TV set!
Buy one!
-No, no
-Then I'll go next door to watch TV!
Me too!
Stubborn children!
-I don't care!
You're the stubborn one!
We go 'cuz there's no TV at home!
Wouldn't go ifwe had one!
Be quiet!
-Stop it! Father will scold you!
I'm not afraid!
-Shut up! Quiet!
-I won't! I don't have to!
Look here! What did you say?
No, let me go! Let go!
You talk too much!
Stop when I say so!
I didn't say anything
Fussing about a small thing
like a woman!
You talk too much for a kid!
Keep quiet!
See? You got scolded!
No! I want a TV set!
That's too much talking!
So do grownups!
Hello. Good morning.
Good evening
A fine day.
-Fool!
Where to?Just a ways.
Is that so?
Just a lot oftalk
I see, I see. Screw that!
Shut up! Be quiet!
Boys shouldn't chatter!
Be quiet for a while!
Okay, I will for days!
Yes, I'd appreciate that
1 00 days.
-Yes, be quiet! Don't talk!
Come on, lsamu!
Such a nuisance
Don't answer, lsamu,
no matter what they say
Get me? I mean it!
Don't talk!
-Outside too?
-Yes. A test!
Me too!
Okay?
-Okay
This means I can talk?
-Yes
Farting is okay
-I'm home
-You're back
You're late
Miss Fukui said
your class reunion may be
at Chinzanso
I see. You went over?
-Yes
Where are the boys?
In their room.
-I see
Good. Good. Studying?
Do you want some cake?
It's good
See?
What is it? Don't want any?
All right then
We'll eat it. It's awfully good
I'm hungry. Aren't you?
Time to eat, Grandmother!
Buy some pants for him
on your way home
Again?
Yes. Cheap ones will do
More?
No, don't.
Your loose tummy won't get well
More?
Good. Good. It's so quiet.
Don't talk
How long will it last?
Say, "Good-bye."
Good morning. You're early.
Kozo's coming
Kozo. Kozo
Good morning. That's a nice scarf
Did you have a fight with Minoru?
No, I didn't
I'm going
What happened? It's funny
Such strange children
What's the matter?
What's up?
The children from across
don't even say hi
What about it?
But they both looked at me
and didn't say a word
Is Mrs. Hayashi still mad at me
about yesterday?
Yesterday?
About the dues
No. Those things happen
It's Grandmother's fault
She didn't tell me
If I hadn't asked her,
she might have taken it
I wouldn't!
Everyone forgets
I don't. Not important things
You do forget! I know
What? What did I forget?
The gas bill I paid
That's all! You do too!
lgnoring your faults!
Stop it, stop it!
Stop it now!
I'm going
Saying you don't forget!
Forgetting to pay me back!
Always yakking
Why did I have a daughter like her?
Good morning
Good morning.
Your husband's left?
Listen
She's funny
Lingerie woman?
She's impossible too.
Mrs. Hayashi
-What?
-I was late with the dues
So she tells everyone I bought
a washer with it
She did? That's awful
Yes. I went over to complain
And she apologized
It was settled
But she's still mad.
She told her kids too
This morning I spoke to them
but they ignored me
I couldn't do it
I see! ls she like that?
Yes. I'm surprised at her
I wouldn't have thought it of her
Be careful. She holds grudges
I see. Maybe she does
Should I return the beer
I owe her?
You borrowed some?
You were out of it
That night? You better hurry
and return it
Yes. I'm glad you told me
Good morning
Excuse me.
-Oh, hello
I forgot all about the beer
I borrowed the other day
There's no hurry to return it
And the bus ticket
you paid for me
It's all right.
-No, I must return it
Excuse me
Mrs. Tomizawa. Are you in?
Mrs. Okubo's here
Welcome
Ifyou've borrowed something
from Mrs. Hayashi
return it.
-Why?
She holds grudges
about small things
No. I've borrowed a lot in the past
But she does I was told
I'm surprised too
She seems educated
but one can never tell
Maybe so
Our cat stole her dried fish.
Should I return it?
Yes, you should!
-I see
I did too. A load off my mind!
You understand the game?
Begin with the last letter
Crow-worm-moon
Next?
Akita
Moonlight Mask Man
No, it has to begin with an "N"
Shimizu
Suzunosuke
No, no. The letter "N"
Hayashi
What begins with "N"?
There are lots ofthem,
aren't there?
What's the matter?
Is anything wrong? The lavatory?
What's that?
What is it?
What?
Read it. Read it for me
Speak up. You can read it
You know the words
Stand there
That's all
Don't forget to bring
your lunch money tomorrow
Don't forget
Bring your lunch money tomorrow
Understand?
Raise your hand ifyou do
What about our lunch money?
Can I tell Mother?
No! Don't talk!
What will we do?
How long can they keep it up?
Ignoring them is best.
It's the rebellious period
So much like their father in funny ways
What?
So very stubborn
They took afteryou
That's not true
I wonder
What is it?
-What is it?
What do you think?
I wonder. Any idea?
No
What is it?
A building? A big house?
The Federal building?
A temple? A hospital?
No?
Oh, school?
School? What about school?
It's on fire?
Not a fire? It's not a fire?
Drink tea? Then what?
Drink tea, then eat?
Money? It's money?
The firemen put out the fire,
you gave them tea and you paid them
What?
-What is it?
Do you know?
No, I don't. What is it about?
What is it?
I wonder
He's good
Sure. He works
for the gas company
Minoru's good too
but now he won't talk
Not even at school
Why won't you talk?
It's pretty inconvenient, right?
What's the matter?
Did you make a vow?
What is it?
Fools
Still eating pumice powder?
Keep it up.
You'll die ofa stomach full ofstones
Really?
-Yes
That seal that died at the zoo?
It was full ofstones
It thought the stones
the visitors threw were food
Who is it?
Hello.
-It's you? What is it?
You're here, boys?
Why don't you come and watch TV?
Any vacant rooms here?
I don't think so.
Ask downstairs
Do you know ofany somewhere else?
I don't know. For who?
Me. I want to move.
The neighbors are such a nuisance
Don't you know any place?
You're not kind, are you?
Good-bye
Yes?
It's you?
Hello
You're here?
I have another translation
That other work was okay?
I'll come for it in 4 or 5 days
I see. The work's a great help
Thanks
What happened? They won't talk
They were scolded
for talking too much
so they won't talk
That's interesting
What did you say?
Say, lsamu
What happened?
They said grownups
talk too much too
Good morning. Good evening.
Good day. A fine day
I see. It's true
We all say that
Yes, we do.
But maybe it's necessary
It'd be a boring world
ifwe didn't
Yes, but the children
don't understand yet
No, they wouldn't know that yet
But isn't it necessary
in our world?
I think so
Say, lsamu.
What are you mad about?
Is that so? I see
Is it?
Have a drink
-Is it too much?
-No, no. Not at all
Never mind
Drinking, smoking
are a waste oftime too
but why worry?
That's all right
I know how the kids feel
when they askyou to buy it
I'd like one too,
but can't afford it
That's not the problem.
I'm against buying one
Someone said TV would produce
1 00 million idiots
Is that so? What does that mean?
It means all Japanese will become idiots
That would be pretty terrible
But what does it really mean?
What do you think about it?
What?
-About television?
Television?
The 1 00 million idiots?
You knew?
-Yes. TV sets are a nuisance
Think so too?
You don't say
Too many conveniences
are no good?
You're right.
-It's a problem
I'm back
Come to visit us, son?
I'm glad you came. Good boy
You're back?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Hayashi
My wife's out?
Thanks for housesitting
Your home's next door
Sorry, sorry
Shall I help you?
No, I'm all right
I'm back
I feel good
You drank again?
Right this time! My own home!
I feel good
Feeling good! The idea!
I feel good. Shut up
It feels good
Listen, are you through?
Not yet
The truck?
It'll come around 3.
Hurry
Are you hurrying? What are
you doing?
Next door is moving, I think
I see. Neighbors here are a pain
I feel like moving out too
Neighbors everywhere
-Unless you live in the mountains
-True
Do mice gnaw on pumice stone?
I don't think they do
No. But it's going fast
Shall I rub rat poison on it?
I'm hungry.
No snacks for a long time now
We won't die? Let's not eat
pumice stones any more
We're not so full ofstones yet?
Excuse me
-It's our teacher!
-What'll we do?
Come!
Is that so?
I scolded them
for talking too much
I see. It's all right
since I know now
Isamu won't talk either
I'm sorry we troubled you
Raising children is very hard
Please use Spartan methods
We don't mind.
-No, I'm afraid not
A guest?
-Please come in. I'm leaving
Excuse me
Thankyou. They'll bring
the money tomorrow
Yes. Excuse me
Come in, Mr. Tomizawa.
-Thanks. Excuse me
Nice weather, isn't it?
Yes. A spell of nice weather
Welcome.
-I'm sorry about last night
My wife gave it to me
You seemed very happy
Please be glad for me.
I found a job
That's great
It's not a big company
Kowa Electric Co. Know it?
Across from an eatery.
I'm in Sales
That's excellent
Hard work though.
I must go from door to door
I see. Toasters, mixers...
Washing machines too
How about buying one?
We can't
How about buying something?
We have installments too
We must buy something to celebrate
your newjob
Please do that.
I have other catalogues
I'll get them. Won't be a minute
It's time for us to think about it too
What?
Retirement
Want some tea?
Yes, I do
A mess, isn't it?
Yes. Fun, isn't it?
I want rice
It tastes good
I'd like some side dish too
Shall I get it?
-Yes, get some
Minoru!
Hurry up!
Who is it?
Hello.
-Good evening
Our boys aren't here?
No. Anything wrong?
Did they come at all?
No, not today
What is it?
-They went out in the afternoon
You must be worried
Yes. But they may be home now.
Excuse me
Take care
What happened?
Funny kids.
They're not talking yet?
It's rather interesting
For children
our greetings may seem
like a waste oftime
I do it all the time to sell cars.
I have to
Yes, it acts as a lubricant
in this world
But important things are difficult to say
Whereas meaningless things are
easy to say
You too
-Can't admit you're in love.
-What?
About Setsuko. You only talk
ofthe weather and work
You're wrong.
-I'm not wrong. I know
Get around to important things
Go out and look?
-What?
The kids. They're out since afternoon?
It's too long
Yes. Shall I look for them?
Yes, you do that
It's cold.
Wear something warm
Check in front ofthe movie houses
I'm back. Are they home?
Not yet.
-I see
I went to his apartment
What's that?
I got it at the police station
They left them and ran away
-Where did they go?
-The nuisances
Where'd they go?
I'll go and look.
-No, I'll go
Where'd they go?
-The nuisances
It's cold. Wear something warm
Good evening
Good evening.
Come in
Where were you?
They're back
Please don't scold them
They were watching TV in front
ofthe station
Thankyou very much.
-Idiots. You made us worry
Excuse me
Thankyou very much.
-Thanks a lot
Good-bye
Come in
Don't worry. Come in
Come on up
Come on
Great
TV!
-It's awesome!
You bought it?
-You really bought it?
Yes, Father did
It's awesome!
-Mr. Tomizawa brought it over
How much?
-It's expensive!
-Never mind
You two study hard now.
-Yes, I will!
Thanks!
Are we lucky! Nice?
We can watch baseball too
Are we lucky!
Aren't you hungry?
No. Teacher treated us
to noodles
Dumplings too
I see. Not hungry, then?
I'm so happy!
Look here!
Ifyou're so noisy,
I'll return it!
He's lying. His face says so
He's smiling
I'm going!
-I'm going!
Have the TV ready
when we come home!
We're off!
Good morning!
Did Kozo go?
Kozo. Kozo
Good morning!
Did Zen go?
Yes, hejust left
Hurry up, Ko!
I'm going!
What's going on?
They talked, didn't they?
What happened?
Listen, Mrs. Tomizawa!
What is it?
Hello. What is it?
The Hayashi boys were
very cheerful this morning
Yes. They said, "Good morning"
You've got them all wrong
That family is nice and Mrs. Hayashi's
very understanding
Think so?
-Yes, you're wrong
I'm going shopping. Need anything?
No? Then...
What's happened to her?
The Hayashis bought
a hot plate or something
Yes. A calculating woman
You still eat pumice stone?
It's bad foryou.
You'll die
I quit.
Changed to burdock
Push me
Me too
You now
No good. You're no good now
What's the matter?
I'm going home
I'll come later
Good morning
Good morning.
Thanks for last night
Where to?
To West Ginza
Then we can go together
A fine day, isn't it?
Yes, really. A fine day
It'll be nice weather for a while?
Yes, it looks like
nice weather for a while
That cloud's an interesting shape
Yes, it's an interesting shape
Looks like something
Yes, like something
A nice day
Yes, a really fine day
You're a fool! A big boy too!
Such a bother!
I won't die, will l?
I swallowed pumice stone
by mistake
You're better offdead!
Absent from school!
I won't feed you till you're well
Give me clean underwear, Mother?
Don't wear any until you're well!
THE END