Ja Hyeon.
Episode 17
Mother.
Who is it?
Look over here.
Are you the people who have aided Ja Hyeon?
I'm her older brother, Seong Deuk Shik.
How should I repay this debt?
G-g-g-grand prince!
It might be better for the two of you
to move far away and live together.
It's dangerous in Do Seong, head east.
Mother. I want to make your
daughter an unquestionable bride.
I can't make her live her
whole life being pursued.
But you can't continue to live
your life this way at the temple.
If we have love in our hearts, even if
we're apart, we are not truly apart.
I found out through your daughter, that
not even death could pull us apart.
Because I've made her go through so many difficulties,
I thought that maybe we shouldn't have met.
I thought that I should let her
go, and regretted this all once.
But, bidding her farewell
was even more difficult.
Born into privilege. The kind of hardship
you've been in is unseen and unheard of.
Because I've gone through hardship, I've
come to realize what's really precious.
Anger has helped me to think in more depth.
One difficult situation can
cut right to the bone.
If I had lived an uneventful life, I
wouldn't have known these things.
How life is so precious.
How much I love this person.
In my eyes, it's okay not
to realize these things.
I want you to live with
my daughter happily.
I wanted you to live a
life full of laughter.
Mother. I'm happy even now.
This makes no sense.
If he's going to die, why doesn't he die alone?
Why does he keep bringing Ja Hyeon into this?!
Then. If she keeps living
here and dies old and alone.
Is that good fate?
That Ja Hyeon is nothing but trouble!
It would've been great if she had just peacefully become
a concubine last time when she went to the palace!
Ah, just be quiet!
If they hear you it'll be bad news!
Ah really. How can you not know
your sister? You live with her!
Without the grand prince,
Ja Hyeon will die!
She can't live with anyone else!
Ah, really.
People give up on aspirations
as they live on.
Are there people who don't have a heart?
Are there people who don't like others?
Because of this and that reason, they just
give up knowing nothing will come of it.
A fiery love that transcends death,
How would you understand it?
Hey, I've been hurt more than you know.
Yeah, you're hurt.
Because you're hurt, you
can't summon up the courage.
If I summon the courage,
would you even accept me?
Does our blood lines disappear?
I could be like Mother and Father. I could be a
great lover like Ja Hyeon and the Grand Prince too.
Ah, it's scorched rice! It looks
so delicious. So delicious!
Because we're at the temple, there's
nothing else I can give you.
Open up.
It's really delicious.
Delicious.
Our Roo Si Gae has really
improved her speaking skills.
But still has zero sense.
Right? Roo Si Gae.
- Didn't the envoys from your country come here and go through some things?
- My homeland?
Envoys were sent here from Jurchen,
but our king cut off their heads.
Even if they're from Jurchen,
is it okay to just kill
envoys from other countries?
It shouldn't. That's why it's a big mess.
Oh my.
Northern Pyunggwan (Jurchen Envoys' Stay)
We're here from Byeongbu.
Open the door!
Was it not enough to
kill the senior envoy?!
How dare you enter the envoys' stay
and go through our possessions?!
Would you like to lay
down your life as well?
Make sure to collect everything
that appears to be a document!
Yes!
Are you in your right mind?
Even if they're foreigners.
They're envoys we have officially
recognized. This shouldn't be happening!
There as an instance when Goryeo's Ming
Nation's envoy Chae Bin was assassinated.
But that was ordered by those beneath
the king, not by the king himself!
I granted your wish Mother.
When you thought the missing Eun
Sung was thought to be dead.
Didn't you say you would
most definitely get revenge?
Since I have killed the envoy, they will
now be aware of Joseon's fiery anger.
If necessary, punishment
will also be given.
Why are you doing this now? What is the reason for
your revenge after Eun Sung has been declared dead?
They think that superior Joseon is
merely the land of the brothers.
Because they dare to think my position
on Joseon's throne is laughable.
Is that also the reason why
you overthrew your uncle?
My uncle... Wasn't he also impatient and
tried to separate me from the others?
I asked him to be the Prime Minister because we were in a state of
emergency but royal relatives shouldn't hold official positions.
I told him to lay low for now.
Think before you act, and think once
more before you establish your commands.
State affairs must be taken care of
by cooperating with the royal court.
With the subjects interfering, this nation's
affairs have never been able to run smoothly.
I don't desire to make this the
subjects' nation, but a king's nation.
With strong authoritarian responsibility placed on the king in its
background, I want to strengthen the monarchy of this nation.
Do you understand how one person's
tyranny can ruin the people
and turn history around??
Please open your ears
and control your heart!
The Huli people don't seem to
have brought the document.
We searched everywhere, but
couldn't find anything.
We never made a deal.
Rumors can't be spread to the public.
If the Jurchens reveal that
an envoy was killed...
That's what I want.
Because if they provoke me, I can
crush them all the more clearly.
Send an order to the north. Start
moving the soldiers to Pajeo River
and have them be completely prepared just
in case there is a provocation attack.
As you wish, Your Highness.
We found the lady.
She was on the mountain
that she used to visit.
She was meeting her family, so
I could only confirm it today.
Should we move her to a secret house? The conditions
aren't right for her to be moved to the palace...
Who took her?
We left spies around, but we
don't know who the enemy is yet.
I withdrew quietly lest she
should run away again.
Since we can't bring her here...
I will go.
Let us investigate the envoys.
The Ministry of War has already
obtained information and left.
We have few more things to
interrogate, so please open the gate.
Open the gate.
We won't be fooled by
people of Josen anymore.
War is the only way. Go back!
He says "get lost."
What do you gain by waging war?
If you run out of rations,
you will exchange the lives of
the soldiers for grain, right?
Are you mocking us?
I am giving you a chance.
You sided with Price Jin Yang
and created a war on purpose,
and tried to kill me, the
prince of this country.
I nearly escaped death, yet I
am willing to forgive you.
And I'm offering a chance
for us to become allies.
I won't make false promises like Grand Prince Jin Yang when
he didn't stick what he said when he promised you territory.
Instead, I will send Jeoson's technicians.
And have them teach you agricultural
techniques to cultivate your barren land.
We will resume your previously
blocked trade and through marriage,
I will find a way for both nations to live.
Make a choice. Will you return and
be investigated by your chief?
Or will you choose these new negotiations and
have the opportunity to revive your hometown?
You can trust Prince Eun Seong.
He's someone who guarded me with his life
even though I am from an enemy clan.
If you allow me to follow the envoy, I
will meet my father and get the documents.
A present for you.
He says it's a present for you.
I wish to give you a
present before I leave.
When we fight, we play the flute.
Father has told him to play the flute,
if Prince Jin Yang doesn't
keep his promise.
Letter of response from Grand Prince Jin Yang to Jurchen's Huligai Tribe,
Chieftain Li Man Zhu: Immediately, from the battlefield we will retreat to Joseon
and Gen. Choe Yun Deok will return the four sovereign counties to you
in return for your support pertaining to my ascension to the throne.
With this, we can uncover Grand
Prince Jin Yang's crime.
Your Highness, you have to eat a lot
and grow up quickly.
Did we get caught?
Your Highness. Your Highness!
What's the matter?
My brother is coming. We must leave!
Gi Teuk! Jin Yang is coming!
Jin Yang's coming!
- Who is it?
- Hurry, get up! Hurry!
- We must run!
- There must be a fire!
- How did he...?
- Hurry, hurry!
Your Highness, how did Grand
Prince Jin Yang find out?
Take His Highness and the lady and leave.
We will try to make time.
We need to all leave. Since His
Highness is here, we can't fight here!
The king probably is on his way because
he knows. We'll be pursued soon!
I will meet Grand Prince Jin Yang.
Escape this place.
I will not leave you to be in
front of my brother again.
If there is a fight here, His
Highness will be in danger.
Does that mean it's okay
if you're in danger?
The person who tortured me is Na
Gyeom, not Grand Prince Jin Yang.
I'm sure that we were caught because of
my family coming in and out of here.
If I take the lead, he won't be suspicious.
He doesn't know you're
alive, Your Highness.
I can't leave you here.
- Think about His Highness.
- I'll stay behind.
Grand Prince Jin Yang
won't do anything to me.
The queen sent me to the Jeongubwon.
The monks are here.
Hurry and go! We have no time.
After I take the prince
somewhere safe, I'll come back.
Did you know I would be coming?
The monks told me that they
thought a guest had arrived.
Your Majesty, that woman is the barbarian minion
that used to follow Grand Prince Eun Seong around.
She had nowhere to go, so
I am taking care of her.
Leave her be.
Isn't she a woman?
How are you feeling?
Scars on the body get better with time.
Will you give me some tea?
Come this way.
Search around to see if any others left.
Yes, sir!
Why didn't you kill me?
From your point of view, I
committed high treason.
You are being punished enough, aren't you?
Living in a world without Hwi is
like living in hell, isn't it?
Killing you is the same
as granting your wish.
If you die,
the two of you will unite
again, and I'll be alone.
I wish to keep you in this
world, even if you hate me.
How did you escape the Jeongubwon?
He may be gone. But his
people still remain.
They brought me here and left.
They are the real traitors.
To me, they are the saviors of my life.
We are not safe yet. We have to go farther.
Your Highness!
- Don't look back. Go to the brothel right away. Let's meet there.
- Your Highness.
Take care of His Highness.
I'm trusting you.
Uncle!
Let's go.
Living in hiding like this,
I realized that whether it's the Jeongubwon
or here, both are like a prison.
Let me go back home.
I want to be with my family.
Sending you to the Jeongubwon
was the queen's order.
Aren't you strong enough now?
You don't need to worry about the
people above or inside of the court.
Have you forgotten Eun Seong now?
It'll be a lie if I say I have.
But what is definite is that I am alive
while he... is dead.
What do you want?
I don't want to be your concubine.
Then?
- I want to become your queen.
If my father returns safely from
Ming, dethrone the current queen,
and give me that position.
So that is what all women want ultimately.
You are starting to resemble my queen.
I don't want to be trampled on again.
If you can't do that for me,
then you better forget me.
She may be a King's woman. But a royal
concubine is still a concubine.
Na Gyeom won't leave me alive.
I won't enter the palace just to
be whipped and tortured again.
If it's not everything, I'd
rather not have anything.
I am the King of Joseon now.
You should be grovelling at my feet.
What makes you so confident?
Prince Eun Seong staked
his everything for me.
You too stake your everything.
Otherwise, you'll never move my heart.
Didn't you hate me to death?
Did your vengeance towards the queen...
outstrip that hatred?
Didn't you come here in the
dead of the night to see me?
To subdue the remnants of the rebellion that you are
suspicious of, you could have just sent soldiers.
But you came here personally. Isn't it
because you wanted to see me even like this?
That heart of yours might move me.
Whether it's love or
obsession, you said that
it hurts your heart just the same.
Show that heart to me.
Then, even my frozen heart
may meltdown, who knows?
If that day comes, I will call you
"My King" instead of "Grand Prince".
You committed a deadly crime just by
calling me Grand Prince right now.
Did you ever see me frightened of death?
Mind your step.
Stay here for the time being.
Won't anyone see us?
I stopped accepting other
customers after I lost my eye.
I also sent out all the servants, so
you'll be safe as long as you stay inside.
Since it turned out like this, let's
pretend to be servants of this place.
That's a good idea.
- They'll have meat here, right?
Your life is hanging by a thread,
and you can still think of meat?
If you die with a full stomach, even
your ghost will look good, they say.
Please wait for a while. I will bring food.
Thank you!
I'm so grateful that I
don't know what to say.
You're amazing.
For now, let's say that you are not well.
Since that was your only excuse
for leaving the Jeongubwon.
Thank you.
However, I will leave a guard behind.
I can't have you run away from me
a second time.
Since I have determined on something,
I won't live as an outlaw.
I don't need a guard. But if
that's what you want, go ahead.
Go inside.
I'll be waiting to hear from you.
[Dragon Tiger Gate]
Are you okay?
Do you think he is safe?
Do you think she was being sincere?
How could I possibly know a lady's heart?
But what is certain is that
Prince Eun Seong is dead,
and you have become the king.
Whether it's because the shock has
died down after time has passed...
Now, you seem to have a
sharp mind once again.
I thought she resembled Hwi. But
she has started resembling me.
Do you not like that?
I like it... and I don't like it.
For now, sleep.
Get some good sleep now and
think about it tomorrow.
Since you're here at home, that's enough.
Since I'll be able to feed you and clothe you
with my own hands... That's something big.
Mother...
It's good that you came.
I would hope that you don't
have hardships anymore,
but living doesn't go as we want it to.
So, I got stronger too.
There is no more of the Ja
Hyeon who grew within a flower
in the shadows of you and Father.
I'm not afraid now.
As long as we live, there is hope...
His Highness said this.
Your Majesty.
Where did you go?
Being only in the palace got
stuffy, so I went to get some air.
The palace is so large,
but it feels stuffy?
There are so many places within the
palace that I still have not visited.
- What is the matter?
- I must tell you something.
You're pregnant?
Yes, Your Majesty. The
doctor felt my pulse.
Having no sign of pregnancy
after three years of marriage
caused me to be greatly worried.
But, the baby must have waited
to be born in the palace.
I will give birth to a grand prince who
will be a wonja (to-be crown prince).
A son who will be like you, for sure.
Your Majesty. How could you lie about that?
How will you deal with it in the future?
I will just make it become true.
For now, I must have the king
not think about anything else.
I need to solidify my spot as the queen.
- I'm sorry.
- Wait a moment.
You can open your eyes now.
Please sit over h-here.
What about the prince? Is he okay?
- He should be.
- He should be?
Didn't you bring the
prince all the way back?
I couldn't just go because
I was worried about you.
I was following you, and when the person
keeping an eye on you fell asleep,
I crossed over.
The safety of the prince is more important!
To me, you are as precious as the prince.
Next time, you can trust me.
If I wasn't confident,
I wouldn't have been stubborn
about staying behind by myself.
What were you so confident about?
Did you believe that since my brother
wants you, he wouldn't be dangerous?
Did you think that you could
handle his intentions?
As I was secretly following you and
my brother walking along a path...
Were you miserable?
Were you jealous?
I realized
that I am just one man amongst many others.
I realized that I am not as good
of a person as I thought I was.
I, too, was jealous of Roo Si Gae.
No, Roo Si Gae is not a woman,
but someone like a younger sister.
I was envious of Eunuch Park who's
been with you since you were children.
I was also envious of the prisoners who had
gone through such difficult times with you.
I was also envious of your first love,
the palace maid who had a deep
and genuine affection for you.
Yeon Hee? Who did you hear that from?
She wasn't my first love. She wasn't.
After meeting you, I realized this.
To carry someone within your
heart can be like Hell all day,
but it can also feel like
Heaven in just a moment.
That temporary happiness
helps to get through the
remaining Hell-like times.
Now, I lie, too.
I say things that are ingenuine and act.
I don't think I'm the Ja
Hyeon I was in the past.
Everything has changed
and become different.
But, my feelings for you are
the same, Your Highness.
Me, too.
Those exhausting days where I
couldn't even know the future...
You were the only thing clear to me.
♫ If I just keep walking ♫
♫ like this endlessly ♫
Is it okay for you to return to home?
I agreed to become a sick person.
I told them that I left the
Jeongubwon as a result of an illness.
What a relief that you can be at home now.
I liked being with you more, Your Highness.
Me, too. I was happy.
If I had known that the happiness
would end this quickly,
I would have stuck with you more.
We could've played with flowers
and drawn the scenery.
Next time, when we are together,
We will be husband and wife,
don't you think so?
♫ The places I want to go to, ♫
♫ The places I need to go to ♫
♫ Perhaps I don't want to know forever ♫
I will bring you my brother's clothes.
Rather than going out in
these everyday clothes,
leaving here as if you're a person from
this household would probably be best.
♫ When I get there, will
I call out only then? ♫
♫ That it's you ♫
In the future, if you need to send a message, I
ask you to tell my brother and not Kkeut Dan.
To make going in and out of
the streets not look strange,
I think having a man do
that would be better.
Since Roo Si Gae is also there,
messages could be exchanged.
Please be careful.
You, too.
Is it true that you are pregnant?
Yes, Your Highness. I planned on
informing you later on, but...
Let's call for the pharmacy
to start making a tonic.
Royalty is precious, so you
should be especially careful.
I am so happy that I will have a son,
especially right after coming into the palace.
I feel like I have given great news to
a royal family that has mourned a lot,
so that makes me very happy.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
It is a happy event for the royal
family in such a long time.
You have worked hard, Your Majesty.
But, Your Highness, how much longer
do I have to show my manners
to this deposed woman?
Your Majesty!
It is fine, Your Highness.
I didn't think it through.
Even after being deposed, I am grateful
that I can still remain in the palace.
The queen has shown her manners enough.
Whatever the cause may be,
The Queen was the wife of former
King and your older sister in law.
No matter what the situation may be, she is
not someone to be thoughtlessly talked to.
I didn't have any other meaning
behind it, Your Highness.
I just was curious about the customs of the
royal family, since I must protect them.
Letter of response from Grand Prince Jin Yang to Jurchen's Huligai Tribe,
Chieftain Li Man Zhu: Immediately, from the battlefield we will retreat to Joseon
and Gen. Choe Yun Deok will return the four sovereign counties to you
in return for your support pertaining to my ascension to the throne.
Is this saying that Grand Prince Jin Yang
is handing over Yongto land to the Juchens?
What will you do about this now?
Let's post it. Somewhere where
many people can see it.
Are you stupid? It'd be immediately
taken down by the government.
Roo Shi Gae has a good point.
We can let the people know and move their
opinions. And that of the ministers as well.
Even if Uncle lost his official position,
many of the ministers are his followers.
When hyungnim's anger subsides,
they must believe that Uncle will
return to the court ministers.
Chief Scholar is not in the country to help us
convince the ministers, so it's not in our favor.
Then... Do we have to wait
until Chief Scholar returns?
We do not wait for time. We make it.
The reason why my brother was
able to cast the prince aside
was because he cut off the
guardians of the prince.
Left Minister and Me.
We will use this as a weapon and,
we must cut off the rotting
foot of my brother first.
Why would His Highness talk all
about the important stuff?
They should secretly talk
about it amongst themselves.
It's because we're important people, too.
This is the first time I've been
treated like this in all of my life.
I couldn't understand a
word of what was said.
It's just best for me to
do what is ordered of me.
Oh, look at this!
Is Eunuch Park inside?
Why would a gisaeng ask such a thing?
He's handsome.
Will you live like that
based off of his looks?
Also, Gi Teuk...
Eunuchs get married, too.
They do everything.
How do you know such a thing?
There are many gisaengs (female entertainers)
who have gotten married to eunuchs.
Those who have nothing are
better off than I am.
Your Highness, I've brought some snacks.
So.
Being an eunuch or whatever... Do
you need to be handsome first?
These dim-wits.
I am not hanging around with you.
Me too.
Isn't that the case?
We are trying to track Prince Seungpyung
after receiving the king's order.
But, maybe Grand Prince Yang
Ahn is keeping hold of him.
I am suspicious.
If he has Prince Seungpyung, then he has a cause to
lead a restoration of the king whenever he wants.
Right now, he doesn't have a good
relationship with the king, either.
Be careful with your words.
You seem to be slandering me in
order to escape my suspicions.
Doesn't everyone know Grand Prince
Yang Ahn's true intentions?
Right now, he is restricted
to his own home.
The king considers him to
be a father-like figure.
Grand Prince Yang Ahn truly is doing things
for His Majesty, and not for his own greed?
Is that what you're trying to say?
An ally within the lieges who
truly is loyal to His Majesty...
There is no one else besides
you, Captain of Royal Guards.
If you just look at the movements
of Grand Prince Yang Ahn,
doesn't he have more of a
traitorous mind than a loyal one?
So, have you thought about it?
What is there to think about?
A powerless, lowly person like
me does what is ordered of me.
Good thinking.
If you wait, then there will be a time
when you are called again in the future.
I have given up the brothel and I'm
also settling things right now.
But, I thought I'd need to give you
a farewell drink, Your Excellency.
You must. Here, have a drink.
By the way, did Grand Prince Yang
Ahn have a child late in his life?
What are you saying?
Even though he is in a position where he cannot do
anything as a grand prince... Thanks to his young son,
they say that the crying never
stops within those walls.
Based on the words of the soldiers who
keep an eye on the grand prince's palace,
they say there is a young boy who is
around the age of Prince Seungpyung.
I've tried to talk to the Minister of Palace Guards but
he was so defensive we couldn't pass it on to the King.
That is the problem with the
Captain of the Royal Guards!
He is unaware of the importance of this
matter. I'll report this to His Majesty.
How about if you do the honor.
The position of the prime
minister is still empty.
When the Chief Scholar returns from
China, wouldn't he be demoted?
What did Chief Scholar do?
To be frank who contributed the most
in getting the King to the throne?
That was you, Your Excellency.
Rather than the household that almost
became the in-laws of a criminal,
We have to have a powerful
minister from the Queen's family.
If you find Prince Seungpyoung
in the atmosphere we are in,
you will have done a huge deed that
will relieve the King's worry.
I do not know what Prince
Seungpyung looks like.
For now, you should go and see if the child
in that house is really Prince Seungpyung.
Find that out first.
That order of things probably works best.
When that is confirmed, you
should inform the king.
Queen's older brother has
fallen into our trap.
He seems to have jumped forward due to
his greed to become a prime minister.
Did you get the children?
Yes, I found a few children
who are around the same age.
The children cannot be hurt.
Things will be managed as if they are
one of our own. They will be safe.
We will take out Hyungnim's
dogs, one by one.
Check things thoroughly. If
there's a young boy, capture him.
Yes, sir!
Your Excellency.
What's the matter?
We will search your house.
Even though I was discharged,
put under a house arrest,
I'm still the elder as the King's uncle.
What do you think you are doing?
We have information that you have a
suspicious young boy staying at your house.
A young boy?
Catch him! Catch him! Catch him!
Where is it?
Over there, sir.
- Where?
- Over there!
- Over here.
- Get out of my way.
Move out of the way!
There is nothing over there.
Go.
Over there, there.
You go that way and you go this way!
Why is he so fast?
One moment.
Why are you doing this?
Minister, Minister, I got him.
I got him here.
How dare you put a wedge
between me and the King.
What are you conspiring?
Conspire? Isn't this something
you started yourself?
In whose name are you doing this?
For what reason?
Minister, I'm simply doing the
work of the Investigation Bureau.
As the servant of this country, Joseon.
This bastard.
Minister!
How can you do this?
To Prince Seungpyung?
Your Excellency!
We found a strange document in your room.
Do you know what this is?
Letter of response from Grand Prince Jin Yang to Jurchen's Huligai Tribe,
Chieftain Li Man Zhu: Immediately, from the battlefield we will retreat to Joseon
and Gen. Choe Yun Deok will return the four sovereign counties to you
in return for your support pertaining to my ascension to the throne.
Letter stamped with royal seal
of Grand Prince Jin Yang.
How dare you!
You bastards.
You... You...
You...
The one who kidnapped Prince Seungpyung was
Grand Prince Yang An.
He worked with the Jurchens and
obtained the secret document
you told us to guard,
and made it into a weapon
that is not a threat.
Then took Prince Seungpyung
to raise him separately,
with a goal to make him the next heir.
So, did you find the young boy?
We searched the premise but
we were one step too late.
But it is certain that he has
been taken care of there.
I saw it myself.
Go find him in haste.
Right now!
What do you want to do
with Grand Prince Yang An?
I will have to give him
the last greeting.
Your Majesty, all of this is,
a entrapment by the enemies
to cause a misunderstanding.
I will for sure reveal their plans.
What were you going to do that young boy?
This is unfair, Your Majesty.
I have never even seen Prince Seungpyung.
When and how did you get hold of
the document from the Jurchens?
That also, I have never seen, Your Majesty.
This is all a trap set by them.
Who are they exactly?
Is dead Eun Seong sharpening
the knife from heaven?
Did my late brother become a ghost,
and is he looking after his little boy?
At least give me some excuses.
The monster nephew you raised
is not following your orders,
so you needed a new puppet!
Get yourself together
(speaking informally).
I gave my whole life to you
and tortured the former king.
I killed Eun Seong and
got rid of a competitor.
And at last, I wanted to
get rid of the young one,
so that your path will
be solid going forward.
How can you attack your
own relative this way?
If it wasn't me, you would never
have made it to where you are.
You are a King I made.
You're right.
I am King.
Do you know what that means?
I no longer,
need you, Uncle.
Your Majesty.
Are you out there, Eo Eul Woon?
Escort the uncle.
Given all that he has done,
I can't let him die in prison.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, please don't do this.
You can't do this to me.
Your Majesty. Your Majesty. Your Majesty!
Take it away.
You bastards. Do you not know who I am?
I am the uncle of the King.
One who made the King into King.
That's why a day like this has come.
To the Grand Prince who shouldn't be king,
you planted misdirected ambition into him.
You misguided loyal servants,
killed a brother and a nephew,
and made him be known as
an evil king in history.
The time has come for you
to pay the price, Uncle.
Eun Seong.
Are you my grim reaper?
Hyungnim ordered poison.
Remember this clearly
until your last breath.
You are,
dying at the hands of a nephew you raised.
Eun Seong. You were alive.
I had to die twice.
All of it because of you.
But, I did not die.
I am alive like this and
return to punish a criminal.
I had to die without a reason,
but I am letting you know of your crimes.
Eun Seong.
Eun Seong!
Will you take the poison Grand
Prince bestowed upon you?
Or a sword given to you
by Do Yeon Soo's son?
You bastards!
Grand Prince
The remaining rebels are using
the name of Prince Seungpyung
and stirring up the people's feelings.
Find that little boy!
We cannot succeed in our rebellion
without the help of the elders.
It's time to let them know that
the former King and I are alive.
Looks like we will have at
least another bloody battle.
If Hyungnim's kite arrives
and the door opens,
before they come out, we
cover them with the arrows.
If this work fails,
I'm not afraid.
Today, I am going to be your bride.
Grand Prince.