Previously on Royal Pains...
What have you decided about my proposal?
I'm in.
Hank, my translator, Christina Dumond.
Dr. Lawson,
- meet Dmitry Vasilyev.
- Pleasure.
Is Dmitry unwell, do you think?
Well, if I had to guess, I'd say diabetes.
This was definitely a first.
Firsts are good.
I like firsts.
Sorry to reinforce a stereotype...
I had a packing meltdown.
You're coming to Shadow Pond?
Of course. There's still work to be done.
So for those of you who lean green
and prefer to receive only
a digital copy of the schedule,
let me know.
Uh, where's Van Dyke?
According to this schedule,
he should have picked up
a schedule by now.
- I'm sure he'll be here.
- Okay.
What about Dr. Sacani?
Oh, he is giving a paper at a conference
on waterborne infectious diseases.
Now, there's a party where you don't want
to get thrown in the pool.
Could I add a clinic patient?
Uh, he's a family friend... Dr. Tom Fancy.
He's a large-animal vet.
When I was at the equestrian center,
I noticed that he dropped some pounds
and could possibly be
arthritic and depressed.
Hmm. Uh, yeah, we can look in on him
right now, if you like.
Great. I'll call him.
He's... he's a really good guy.
He helped me find
my very first horse, Elmer.
Aw, Elmer. Like the glue.
Oh, that's terrible.
Oh! Whoa.
Good morning, everybody.
Boop! Boop!
Oh... ls he drunk?
He smells like a jolly rancher
fell in a can of paint thinner.
Apple Martinis... that's his drink.
You all right in there, doctor?
I'm good. I just need coffee.
Yeah, we keep that in the kitchen.
Nope, need aspirin too.
[Shelves clanging]
All right, Divs, after the vet,
- can you cover his patient?
- Sure, no problem.
Great. Hopefully I can get him on his feet
for the afternoon.
Okay, and I will call his other patients,
apologize, and reschedule.
Perfect.
And you probably want
to talk about this, don't you?
[Sighs] I don't like it.
It concerns me, but I'm gonna trust
in your ability to handle it.
Good talk.
Good luck.
Oh-ho! Victory! Oh!
Whoa, whoa!
I'm okay. Good.
Okay.
Hey, Tom.
Hey, Divya.
Good to see you. Mmm.
- Tom, this is Dr. Hank Lawson.
- Hank.
- Tom Fancy. Nice to meet you.
- Yeah, you too.
Divya, I told you
you don't need to do this.
And I told you that I want to.
I thought you were a large-animal vet.
[Chuckles]
Well, sometimes the animal's large,
sometimes there's just
a large number of them.
Right. Do people ride these?
Not big people.
No, they're mostly pets,
but these are being trained
as guides for the blind.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, they're gentle,
they have excellent vision,
and they can live to be over 50.
Guide dogs only have a useful lifespan
of 8 to 12 years.
- I had no idea.
- Yeah.
So, Tom, what's going on with you?
Well, it's nothing.
I mean, yes, I've lost some weight,
my joints are creaky,
and I've got some G.I. stuff,
but you know, I'm getting older,
and I'm dealing with a busted marriage.
Sorry to hear that, Tom.
Tom's wedding was at the Central Park Zoo.
Oh.
Yeah, in front of the penguin habitat.
It was a very formal affair.
Right. You really love animals.
Some say too much.
One even cited it as grounds for divorce.
But... Sorry, I didn't mean...
No, no, no, no, it's fine, it's fine.
Don't worry. So, Tom,
when you say "G. I." stuff,
are we talking blood, diarrhea?
Uh, no to the first, yes to the second.
- Okay, how long?
- About three weeks.
Since the breakup, I guess.
I'm telling you,
there's no mystery here, I'm fine.
What about your diet?
It's good, I guess.
What'd you have for breakfast?
I'm gonna say granola?
[Chuckles] To be honest,
I've been working so hard
to keep up with the legal bills,
it all kind of blends together.
Okay, well, let's get blood,
stool, and urine.
Hopefully you're right,
and your symptoms are just
attributable to age and stress.
But let's find out.
100 million barrels
move through Novosibirsk
to the strategic reserves.
[Christina translating Boris to Russian]
You profit, I profit...
[Translation simultaneous]
And our Syrian friends get
some much-needed
humanitarian aid.
And what does it have to do
with your Cuban interests?
Nothing... Yet.
Hmm. Mm.
Hank... Would you care to join us?
Uh, sorry to interrupt.
- Dmitry?
- Yes?
If you'd like to speak privately...
No, you can say it.
Boris and I have no secrets, right?
Okay. I'd like to do another
therapeutic phlebotomy.
We're in the middle of business.
- Well, how's your insulin?
- Relax, doctor.
If I don't feel well, I will take later.
Dmitry, you can't just manage your sugars
when it's convenient.
You're eating all this rich food,
and you didn't pre-bolus?
[Speaks russian]
Pre-bolus?
Take insulin first.
May I?
[Instrument beeps] Yep, it's high.
Okay, lift your shirt, please.
[Muttering quietly]
[Speaks russian]
Okay.
Now the phlebotomy?
- Later.
One hour? Two hours?
Just looking for a number here.
You're a businessman.
You must understand that.
[Speaks Russian]
He says... One hour.
Perfect.
[The Blue Van's Independence]
♪
♪ My independence went away
♪ I didn't listen when it said ♪
♪ rely on yourself
♪ trusting someone else
♪ is a path for the silent ghost ♪
Royal Pains 4x08 - Manimal
Original air date August 1, 2012
Sync and corrections by atrn97g
for www.addic7ed.com
First, breakfast and business,
now a barber and a bloodletting?
Does this guy ever do
just one thing at a time?
A man who has too many hours in his day
is a man who a man who has
too little money in his pocket.
This is a Russian saying?
Rockefeller.
Hmm.
So you suggest insulinovaya pompa.
I do.
This pod provides a continuous
low dose of insulin.
- Mm.
- When you eat,
it can give an additional dose,
which is calculated by this remote.
[Speaking Russian]
Okay, but it only knows
how much to give you
if you tell it by inserting your
test strips here.
So if I try it, will you stop stalking me?
If you try it, if it's effective,
and if you commit to being vigilant
about your monitoring,
then, yeah, I'll stop stalking you.
Okay.
Is it... is it... it's hard to put...
Uh, no. I just have to prep it.
Draw up 200 units of insulin
and fill it right in this hole back here.
Okay... Good.
And now it adheres to the abdomen.
Goes on just like so.
And now you'll feel a little pinch
as the needle goes into your skin.
Mm.
So... What do you think?
Sexy.
Paging Dr. Van Dyke. Hello.
He's not waking up.
Well, take off his sunglasses.
Oh, that's a good idea.
These don't look like his, either.
- Oh! What is...
- Eww!
- That's disgusting.
- It works fine!
Oh... Hi.
Hey, welcome back.
How did you get here?
Dude, uh, your eye.
- What?
- It's...
No, not... not your eye.
Like, above your eye.
Your eyebrow. Don't touch it!
- Okay.
- Hold on a sec.
You know what?
Here, take a look.
Oh, yeah. That's gonna need a doctor.
Fortunately... I am one.
Uh, ha ha.
[Groans]
So, um...
- Whoa.
- Oh... ooh!
- Wow, uh...
- Sorry.
Yeah.
Here. Coffee.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Sorry again.
- It's all good.
She's pretty anal about her files, so...
But that's okay. They'll dry.
So, Paul, um, about last night, are you...
Whoa, whoa!
God.
So where were you last night?
Were you... hol... hold...
Ah!
- Were you...
- Can you hold that?
[Sighs]
Sure.
Why?
[Sighs]
Okay.
Are you sure you're okay to do that?
Yeah, stellar.
Uh... I'm gonna call Divya.
I mean, I just want to know
what happened, that's all.
Okay, okay, I'm in the parking lot
with my buddy Tyler,
and out of nowhere he goes,
"hit me as hard as you can." And I'm like,
"I don't know about this, Tyler."
Isn't that from Fight Club?
I can't talk about that.
So you're really not gonna
tell us what happened?
There is really nothing to tell.
I need to check your pupils.
[Sighs]
You could have a concussion.
I don't have a concussion.
What I do have is a pain in my ass.
Well, then, bend over
and let's take a look.
Hmm?
Are you really gonna let him do this?
What... no. [Scoffs]
Do what?
No excuse, no apology.
I feel like he's taking advantage of you.
What's going on?
He suddenly started
having pain... I'm not sure.
What did you do to me, huh?
When did you last check your glucose?
A few hours ago.
[Instrument beeps]
He's slipping into diabetic ketoacidosis.
[Retching]
Do we need an ambulance, Hank?
No. Insulin and fluids.
You said this was insulin.
Yeah. I also said it wasn't a substitute
for your own management.
[Christina translating]
If you can't be bothered
to check your sugars
before eating and drinking,
then maybe we need to talk about
an implantable glucose monitor too.
[Speaks Russian]
By the time you are done,
I will be like six-million-ruble man.
No, no pump, no monitor, no nothing.
I'm doing this my way.
Your way isn't working.
If you don't change what you're do...
Don't tell me what to do.
Mister, I am diabetic for years.
I know the consequences.
Right, but do you really want
to suffer them?
Look, if you can't stay on top of this...
[Translating]
And you don't want an
implanted pump or monitor,
then get someone to stay
on top of this for you.
Someone to be with you 24/7
who can think about your diabetes
so you don't have to.
[Christina finishes translating]
[Speaks Russian]
- Congratulations.
- What? Why?
You're hired.
Uh, just... just so you know,
I'm not considering
going to work for Dmitry.
Just so you know, I wasn't concerned.
What does concern me, Hank, is his health.
It is imperative that he be well
for this summit tomorrow.
I understand, but aside
from sitting next to him
and pricking his finger every 30 minutes,
I don't know what else to suggest.
I have invested significant
assets in this, Hank.
Everything from you yourself
to a repository of rare vodkas
with which to toast our success.
Well, then, until I can offer you more,
I suggest you delay the meeting.
No. Not an option.
A trigger cannot be un-pulled.
Well, then, I'll keep thinking.
Well, think fast.
And I'll trust in your ability
to handle it.
Hey.
You're feeling better, huh?
Mm. Ahh. Mostly.
You want half?
No. No, I'm good. Thank you, though.
So... You want to tell me
what happened last night?
No.
Come on, dude.
Just... As friends?
We're friends?
Yeah.
You just offered me
half your sandwich, come on.
Because I have good manners.
Oh.
Look, there's nothing to tell.
I went to that dive bar over on 4th,
and I had too much.
You do that a lot?
How is that your business?
It's my business because
you made it my business.
These are business hours,
and you are a doctor
who came to work intoxicated.
So I need a better explanation than,
"ooh, I drank too much."
Well, I'm sorry, but...
I drank too much.
Then I'm sorry... But you're fired.
[Clears throat]
[Snaps fingers]
[Sighs]
Just a little longer, squeaky.
Okay. Okay.
Let me guess, high cholesterol?
[Chuckles] Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
She's gonna need beta-blockers
and a calcium channel blocker.
So you literally saved her bacon.
Oh, we don't use the "b" word.
- Sorry.
- Tom, you look flushed.
Well, you should see me
after I give a camel
a pelvic exam.
Let me take your temperature anyway.
So, Tom, according to the tests we ran,
we know you aren't
absorbing nutrients properly.
We just don't know why yet.
[Instrument beeps]
Hopefully your cultures will tell us more.
101.5.
Tom, I want to do
a G.I. series with contrast.
Well, then, I hope you brought an X-ray.
I can't believe you brought an X-ray.
[Chuckles]
I feel like a thoroughbred.
You have one of these for horses?
Of course I do.
We're not that different, you and me.
Driving around the Hamptons,
treating patients.
It's just yours can
tell you their symptoms.
- We do have it easier that way.
- Yeah.
Okay, so, Tom, Crohn's, pancreatitis,
and ulcerative colitis
are all malabsorption disorders
that can present with fever,
but I don't see any evidence of them here.
- Intestinal biopsy?
- Yeah.
Oh, please don't tell me
you're gonna do that here.
No. For that you need an endoscopy,
which requires fasting for a full day.
Hank, as a medical professional,
I appreciate how thorough you're being,
but as a guy whose lawyers
don't work pro bono,
I don't have time for that.
I... I've gotta be here all day today
and probably tomorrow too.
I've got a pregnant cow
with a very specific birth plan.
I know the toll that the stress
of a failing marriage can take.
I'm seeing it with my own father.
But I have to say, if working 24/7
just to fight your ex is making you ill,
is it worth it?
Wolves, beavers, pigeons...
Hell, even termites mate for life.
A black vulture will even try to kill
an unfaithful member of its own species.
But my wife is a different kind of animal.
The kind that cheats on you,
and then goes after everything you've got.
Which means I have to keep fighting,
even if it kills me.
Privet.
[Chuckles]
Someone's been paying attention.
Sorry you had to be in the middle
of that awkward job offer before.
That wasn't even about you.
It wasn't?
No, that was a power play.
Dmitry showing he's
so unintimidated by Boris
he'd steal from him
without even doing him
the courtesy of hiding it.
Oh.
Yeah. I've worked with him enough to know
that nothing they do has a single motive.
Their relationship moves
on so many levels,
it's like a three-dimensional
game of chess.
Hmm. So here I thought
I was a good doctor.
Turns out I'm just a pawn.
If you weren't a great doctor,
you wouldn't even be that.
[Clears throat]
Boris awaits you.
Thank you.Do svidaniya.
Coffee?
I'm good.
Danke.
Please sit, Hank.
So... How are you getting on
with Christina?
Very well. Yeah, she's great.
Yes, she is. Good.
You two have been doing excellent work.
Thank you.
After the conclusion
of our meeting tomorrow,
I'd like to offer my car
and driver for you
to have an evening and a meal out.
Together?
Together, sequentially...
I'll leave the details to you.
Well, that's very generous.
Unless there's a secondary motive.
So tell me,
have you come up with a solution
for the Dmitry health situation?
Not really. I mean, worst case,
I can check him hourly during the meeting.
And long-term?
Dmitry can be a... difficult friend,
but he's an important ally.
Uh, long-term, I guess I could always
go work for Dmitry, if you want.
I do not think
you'd enjoy his guest house.
Ah.
[Cell phone vibrates]
Oh, uh, sorry. I'm on call.
I'm gonna take this.
Hey, what's going on?
I just got the results
from Tom's cultures.
Everything came back negative.
Okay. What about the endoscopy?
I've scheduled it,
but he is not answering his phone.
So what, you think he's avoiding you?
I was wondering that,
so I also tried from a hospital phone.
Look, Hank, given his symptoms,
I'm just worried that
he could be severely dehydrated
and passed out.
If he's still on that farm,
out in the field somewhere...
- I'm on my way.
- I'll meet you there.
Tom... we've been trying to reach you.
I've had my hands in a pregnant heifer,
and now Beulah here has got mastitis.
[Exhales uneasily]
Tom, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm... I'm fine.
[Cow moos]
Ooh! Oh!
Tom!
[Groans]
Is it bad?
It's not life-threatening.
Here, this should help with the pain.
Uhh. Thank you.
So it looked like you lost your balance.
I was just tired.
You're not just tired, Tom. You're sick.
Now, were you dizzy, lightheaded,
or was it something else?
It was my vision. I had floaters.
Huh.
It sounds like possible retinopathy
associated with the malabsorption.
- Yep.
- Addison's disease.
I don't think so.
He's got none of the skin darkening
that goes with Addison's.
Let's find his tooth
and get him to the hospital.
All right.
- No, no, no.
- Tom. No. You sit.
You're forgetting something.
- What's that?
- Beulah's mastitis.
I don't just walk out
on my patients, guys.
You guys are both very similar.
All right, here's what's gonna happen.
Divya, you find his tooth,
but don't touch the root.
That can disturb cells
that attach it to the bone.
The sooner we get it back
in the socket, the better.
Got it.
Tom, I'll treat Beulah.
You're a people doctor,
Hank. It's different.
All right, so talk me through it.
Well, you need to give her
an antibiotic injection.
That's not so different.
Into her teat canal.
- That's different.
- Yeah.
Okay... Found it.
Great.
[Chuckles]
But it is... it's filthy.
So we need to rinse it off
with milk, not water, right?
Right. Milk has a more neutral PH.
That works out perfectly.
Beulah needs a milking
before the injection anyway.
Uh... [Cow moos]
We're eating lunch here?
[Sighs] Yeah.
People say they have a great burger.
So anywhere? Okay.
Oh...
This is where Van Dyke
was drinking last night.
All right...
I'm convinced there's more to his story,
and I don't know why,
but I need to know what it is.
I know why.
Because you want to see
the best in people.
And because at a time
when we need doctors,
he is a known commodity.
The devil you know.
But don't forget, devils are evil,
and evil should be punished.
Whoa.
Is this how you're gonna be with our kids?
No excuses, take your medicine...
Kill 'em all, let God sort 'em out.
Rah, rah, rah!
Well, that's how I was raised.
By a four-star general.
And look how I turned out.
You are pretty awesome.
Thank you.
So is this how you're
gonna be with our kids...
a big softie?
I am not a softie. I'm compassionate.
Well, compassion is for charity,
not for child-rearing.
So you better be prepared
to step up, mister,
because I am not gonna
always be the bad cop.
Yes, ma'am.
You joke, but maybe there are some things
we need to talk about
before we get married.
I'm sure there are,
but how to discipline
our imaginary children
is probably one
we can back-burner for now.
You are so avoiding the issue.
I'm not avoi... they're imaginary.
I'm talking about Van Dyke.
Hank said handle it.
I am. I'm...
God, I know we're from Passaic.
I don't think he meant,
like, handle it handle it.
No, he meant make a decision,
which you did,
only now you're second-guessing it.
Don't.
[Cow moos]
Uh-huh.
Like that.
Ah.
Ehh...
[Chuckles] Ow.
Grab the teat...
Good.
Oh, I see. Okay.
Okay. Cheapest retainer ever made.
That should hold the tooth in place
till we get you examined at the hospital.
Plus, Tom, you might want
to up your brushing time.
You've got a little gingivitis in there.
Jeez, Hank. [Chuckles]
What kind of medicine doesn't he practice?
Can I help you?
Yeah. Yeah, actually.
We would like two IPAs,
uh, two Dive burgers, one with cheese.
And was this guy in here last night?
[Scoffs] I'll say.
And there we were, the two of us,
out in the field.
The hot summer rain soaked us to the skin.
Oh, my God, it hurts
just to think about it.
Why, Ronnie, why?
[Clears throat]
Look, I'm out of that apple crap.
So you want another round,
you're gonna have to switch
to a big-boy drink.
Okay, thanks.
[Sighs]
Oh!
Well, I guess this would be yours now.
Uhn! Oh!
Would you mind taking that, sir?
Unh! Oh!
[Grunts, groans]
Go home, appleseed.
And pick up that blood.
[Stifled groans]
And after that, he left.
Thank you.
That was very... Descriptive.
Poor guy.
She broke his heart.
Why wouldn't he tell us?
[Sighs] 'Cause we're not friends.
Evan, don't be like that.
Of course we are.
No, no, I'm not. It's him. He...
he's a hopeless romantic is what he is.
You have to hire him back.
[Horns honking]
If this is what a bitter divorce gets me,
maybe I shouldn't be so bitter.
Exactly. This fight is
letting your ex-wife
take your health too.
Well, she should get something.
I wasn't the perfect husband.
Always running out to see patients,
bringing them home without asking...
Adopting them.
What she did was unforgivable.
Of course I fought like an alley cat.
If only we could all be
as selfless as guide horses.
Or dogs.
Hey, Tom, did that farm
just train horses for the blind?
What do you mean?
I mean, are you asking
if they work with other animals,
[begins slurring]
or other medical conditions or...
Tom, you're slurring your words.
Maybe the cow hit a facial nerve.
It looks like Bell's palsy.
Can you wrinkle your forehead?
Okay, that's not Bell's palsy.
Tom, you're having a stroke.
Come on, people! Move!
All right, we can't sit in this.
Beulah did this?
Maybe the malabsorption disorder.
Maybe neither.
Arthropathy, weight loss,
fever, gingivitis,
and now a stroke.
Tom, I think you have Whipple's disease.
Isn't that a bacterial infection?
Yeah. And a serious one.
Hank? Hank, what are you doing?
We have to get to the hospital right now.
Lowering a stroke victim's
core temperature
can reduce the metabolic
activity of the brain.
- Hank, where are you...
- I'm gonna buy you some time.
Medical emergency! Excuse me, please!
Sir?
Hey, guys, come on in.
Come on in. Let's go.
- You grab his feet.
- All right.
Hey, doc, you got my thrombolytics?
Standing by.
We also need to get him on bactrim.
- For a CVA?
- For Whipple's disease.
I thought that was
just something they used
to trip kids up with at med school.
Yeah, first case I've seen too.
Hey... That'll be $727.50.
And it would help if you got exact change.
This is gonna help with diabetes?
This is Stanley.
[Translates in Russian]
You said you don't want an implant?
Well, you can't implant the dog.
[Translates in Russian]
A dog's nose has around
200 million scent receptors.
They can detect even
the most subtle odors.
[Translates in russian]
Bombs, drugs, cadavers.
Well, Stanley here
has been trained to detect
what a diabetic smells like
when his glucose gets too high
or too low.
It's a joke, right?
Not possible.
He doesn't think you can do it.
[Dog whimpers, barks]
Stanley says he can prove it.
[Laughs]
Good luck.
The bartender told us everything.
We know about Ronnie.
[Sighs]
Thanks.
Why didn't you tell us?
Because you would have made fun of me.
No, we wouldn't.
Dude, we've all been there.
No, not like this. This is different.
You guys, what am I gonna do?
I love her so much.
Of course you do.
I don't want to let her go.
Of course you don't.
But I also know that's crazy.
She is 15.
Of course... what?
Fired! Fired, fired, fired!
Hold on. So she's 15?
Yeah.
And most rabbits only live,
like, 8 to 12 years.
- Rabbits?
- Hold on, I'm sorry.
Ronnie is not a girl
who broke up with you?
A girl? No. What?
You said the bartender
told you everything.
Uh, apparently he left some stuff out.
Like the fact that you own a bunny...
[Chuckles]
And that's the love of your li... life.
[Giggles] Sorry.
Okay, see, this is why I didn't tell you.
- No, no, no. No.
- We're sorry.
- Yeah.
- Really, we're... we are.
We're being insensitive.
It's just, you know, when you think about
what drives a man to drink,
it's usually not a bun...
a bunny. [Laughter]
I told you, she's 15. That's old!
She can't see, she can't hear.
She's always hopping into stuff.
And she's not just a bunny, okay?
She was a present from a girl
I was in love with
a long time ago.
Pam.
That's really sweet.
Yeah, until she ended it.
And even though I know
the right thing to do
is to put her down, I just...
I keep losing my nerve.
The bunny, right? Not the...
The bunny. The bunny.
And that is why I went to the bar...
for... liquid courage.
So where is she now?
[Straining] Hey. Hey, Ronnie, come here.
Come here, girl. [Smooches]
Hi. Good bunny.
It's okay, no one's gonna hurt you.
She knows that's not true.
That's why she's hiding.
Hey.
Okay.
All right...
[Dry spits]
So... Here's the good news.
You don't need to put her down anymore.
[Quiet gasp]
Oh...
[Instrument beeps]
Yep, your glucose is slightly high.
Mm-hmm.
Now let's take it higher.
Are you sure that's wise, Hank?
We can't risk any further delay.
It's okay.
If you approach ketoacidosis,
you're hooked up to insulin,
but I don't think Stanley
will let it get that far.
Or you could just trust me on that
and get to your meeting on time.
[Clears throat]
Hey, sobaka...
Na zdorovie.
Ahh.
How are you feeling?
Uh, not fantastic, thank you.
Maybe your dog is broken.
[Dog barks, whimpers, barks]
He says your blood sugar is too high.
[Laughs] Fantastic!
[Speaking Russian]
Well, uh... "Son of a bitch."
Technically true, but
I think he prefers "Stanley."
Stanley.
So once you get a dog, you start training.
So if you're interested, you should apply
as soon as possible. But I like this one.
And he seems to like you,
but that's not how it works.
I was only able to borrow him
because of this vet I treated.
I take this one.
He's kinda like the floor model.
Can you translate "floor model"?
[Speaks Russian]
[Repeats in Russian]
I take this one.
Well done, Dr. Lawson.
And thank you.
You're welcome. And good luck in there.
Yeah.
[Doors shut]
The weird thing about Whipple's is
it's a bacterial infection
you can't culture.
Which is why it didn't
show up in any of the tests.
But we know for sure now?
Yeah. Your biopsy confirmed it.
At first, the infection was
just causing the malabsorption,
but eventually, bacteria
accumulated in a heart valve,
broke off, and traveled to your brain,
which caused the stroke.
So how'd I get it?
It's found in soil.
[Chuckles]
Well, I work with farm animals,
so that should be easy to avoid.
Look, Tom, it's rare.
And you're gonna be on
antibiotics for at least a year,
so hopefully it won't recur.
Thanks... Both of you.
You are seriously good human beings.
And coming from a guy who prefers animals,
that's saying a lot.
[Chuckles]
You're a good person too.
And I am glad that you changed your mind
about fighting your ex-wife.
What do you mean?
Well, you said that
you were going to stop,
that it wasn't worth it.
Yeah, that's when we thought
it was stress-induced.
You just said it's bacterial.
It is, but the lesson here...
the lesson here is that you can't avoid
random crappy soil bacteria.
Once I'm back up on my feet,
I'm going with both barrels at that harpy.
- Tom?
- One barrel?
All right, no barrels.
Thank you guys for coming.
[Sighs]
Thanks for handling the Van Dyke thing.
You done good.
You're welcome.
I... honestly, I was a little nervous
when you said, "handle it."
I thought you just wanted me to fire him.
I wanted you to handle it, which you did.
One of these days, I really need
to stop worrying so much
about what you think.
No, you don't.
[Chuckles]
- You doing a reading?
- Yeah.
What the hell is Thessalonians, anyway?
I have no idea.
[Clears throat] Um... Oh...
When Pam broke up with me,
I was left with two things:
Her memory...
and... her rabbit.
In fact, at first,
Ronnie was just a memory of Pam.
But eventually, Pam faded.
And today...
Oh...
It's cool, man.
Today... [Clears throat]
Ronnie has become her own memory.
And so I return you now, Ronnie,
from whence you came.
Bunnies don't come from the ocean.
Just roll with it.
Is... is this even legal?
Evan has a permit.
No, I don't.
- You said you applied for one.
- I did.
In six to eight weeks,
we'll see if it was approved.
Hey, Evan, I want to thank you
for being a good boss.
But more importantly,
for being a friend.
Absolutely, man.
All right.
So, uh... Even though I didn't...
I didn't really know Ronnie very well,
I thought I'd just, uh...
"we do not want you to be unaware,"
"brothers and sisters..."
Uh, I'm sorry to interrupt,
but there's a lifeguard
staring at us.
Is there a problem?
Only if we get caught.
This is technically illegal.
It's a lifeguard. What's he gonna do,
make us take swim lessons?
Or point us out to a cop,
like he's doing now.
My father's running for senate.
I can't get arrested for this.
All right, scatter. Everyone scatter.
But casually... casually scatter.
[Siren wails]
Come on!
Forget casually, just run!
Okay.
Good-bye, Ronnie!
[Shredder whirring]
Yep.
I thought we were going out.
We are. I thought
we could get a drink first.
- With Boris?
- Uh, no.
Boris and Dmitry are
celebrating on Boris' yacht.
Apparently, international deals call for
international waters.
So where are we going?
You'll see.
[Laughs]
- Narnia?
- No, not Narnia.
I feel like I might be hot.
Trust me. You're gonna be fine.
But it's summer.
Not in there.
[Chuckles, shivers]
- It's chilly in here.
- I know.
All right, here we go.
[Light switch clicks]
[Laughs, gasps]
- Holy...
- I know.
This used to be a meat locker
till Boris had it converted for Dmitry.
So then why are we in here,
and they're out on a boat?
Because given his liver and his diabetes,
Dmitry wisely chose the fish
over the vodka.
But that's no reason we can't enjoy it.
Please, step up to my bar.
[Chuckles]
You, uh... you have a favorite?
Um... Oh.
You can't buy this.
This is what Khrushchev used to serve
to visiting dignitaries.
Yeah?
So let's dignify it.
[Cork pops]
[Chuckles]
- Na zdorovie.
- Za lyubov.
Sync and corrections by atrn97g
for www.addic7ed.com