I have given my life for 18 years.
They will catch me if I go on.
You have kept me this crap in the gap 14 months!
I can not handle it.
Set me as though retirement,
, but that stuff I can not take care of.
I'm afraid too.
Lonny, the task is finished.
Lonny, it's over.
Lonny,
Am I going crazy?
I do not think so.
I want a sea view and it is not unreasonable.
Check this out.
It's like a castle.
-Waiting for you to retire.
I am ready to retire.
-No way.
I am ready. I seem to like it.
I was a wonder boy and the hero
litkimme and beer together.
Now I want a sea view!
-Sorry!
I have been a good subject for 18 years.
Do not you think?
This was prepared 14 months.
Now the train starts, and you say, you can not.
I'm scared.
I'm not ashamed to admit.
Yes you were.
How does it feel to be in a tray?
How are you, friend?
This evening, just enjoyed.
Sit. I'll give you something to drink.
No!
Get me out of this task, Lonny.
Final boarding call
flight to New York in 2057.
Wait a minute! It is my my flight!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Can not be true.
Let me out!
It is enough. Thank you.
-Please.
What do you want?
Do you have a fear of flying?
No, I love flying.
You seem a little...
-That is correct.
Is everything all right?
It is, plain abdominal pain.
Must be the stress.
The work is very stressful.
-What do you do?
I work...
What are you doing?
-I'm a psychiatrist.
Really?
's A simple touch: Mafia to use
Colombian money.
That 90-day waiting period?
Await Colombians for so long?
They are not known for their patience.
Depending on the credit.
Fulvio Nesstraat draftsman? He is the only
muskelimies.
Sala murderers Jeffrey Dahmer.
Diagram illustrates Minettin daughter,
may therefore play a role.
Where the money is going on?
Vaillarin family
cartel is one of the richest.
I would say that this is
more than half a billion.
Difficult choice. Is the aim
arrest or Vaillarin the money?
Both. Collect the current
commitments and evidence.
You should already begin.
Lucy goes on watch.
-I.
You do not budge a long time.
Take the C-10's son.
Jesus Christ with you.
Chris, you apply for Juniper's Dave?
-I'm sorry!
Perhaps you want to hear the single,
who is familiar with the entire operation.
Vaillarin 'money can not be accessed.
Money exchange current commitments
15-90 day intervals.
With such large sums moving,
people start dying like flies.
And if you have missed:
bad guys know.
Someone revealed to us.
We were in a tray,
Uzis stuffed up the ass!
I was like a game bird
Martha Stewart's kitchen!
The bad guys were shot.
-Warren Ganza is still at large.
Warren lacks credibility and contacts
All the players are now up to you, Charlie.
Okay, I'm involved in,
, but without a team.
No kyttäystä, no sirens
and no one will see it yourself!
I do not want to get this
other than a sea view.
He will not survive piece of the action.
-You do not know him.
Worst-case, he shines.
And we have no other options.
I know that he is a legend
drugs agency.
He ruined  Miami-operation.
One of the men was killed.
Let him go on, but the
we must have an emergency plan.
Yes he will take until we can strike.
He does it by instinct.
Charles Mayo?
-Mayo.
Mayo. I'm Dave Juniper.
I was assigned to taustatueksesi -
and I just want to say,
that you are one of my heroes.
Who are the other heroes?
-Keith Richards.
Remember,
I do not want to see you ever again.
Warren Ganza is still at large.
Not again!
I want to talk about my work.
Now this is confidential?
This is new to me -
but I want to say,
I did not find any inner child -
I do not want to hear,
I am disappointed with my mother.
I do not give a shit,
if the mother was not perfect.
I do not know the reason, but I said to just
: "Mother, Mother."
Over and over again.
I do not know...
Wipe your eyes.
Charles, time is running out,
but come back tomorrow.
We have just started.
Two hours ago. I can not go.
-I pay anything.
I stay, yes, but the
group therapy starting point.
I can not send more patients home.
Thank you.
Charles, you could stay in
group therapy.
No, no, no.
I'm not really able to share.
You need to share
more than anyone to feel.
City is a new,
situation untenable.
You suffer from a sense of alienation and a post-traumatic disorder.
You need support.
It is known
that is contrary to my nature -
have to face that.
Feigned innocence marginalized by necessity.
I asked him simple stuff thing:
"I would leave without buying the Mövenpick."
It tastes like chemicals. But he
offered as a dessert at the Mövenpick.
As a rule, when it's quiet,
meeting or dinner.
All of a sudden I feel the pressure to rise.
I can get punishment for good deeds,
rewarded me evil.
I was chairman for four years, and all of a sudden
Kramer got it Pallin.
I am indifferent.
-... the need to shout.
The bad guys always win.
It is humiliating!
-Am I not a man?
I got a huge need
to do something completely inappropriate.
Then I say to myself:
"If you extract your needs,
it will destroy your life."
But it will only increase the pressure.
-What do you do then?
First, put my tongue between your teeth.
This.
Then stick my hand up to the chin.
But it hurts,
so then bite my hand.
Does it work?
-So far has worked.
Each knows how wants to live
-
and it is said that people get the
what you deserve. I do not think so.
Is that a fact or your own perception?
I hate it when you talk to me
patronizing tone.
If we were living in hell -
and I would say that it is hot,
I would be negative?
Not a negative
-You said it.
I do, I asked, only
whether it is your own perception.
All is based on the observation. Life,
ego. It's how I express myself.
Wherever I look,
the bad guys win.
Next week it is the theme of the session.
So am I now a burden?
You are not a burden,
but we have only 20 minutes -
and I would like to tell
Charles's recent problems.
I really hate watermelons.
The biggest problem due to my work.
Exactly where else.
The work has always been tough.
Still, I thought that everything was under control.
But the latest job ...
What does it do?
Cheemo Partell sang to me -
ass shot my partner and threw the window.
I was thrown into a serving table,
of watermelon. Etova odor.
Cheemo then began to hum
ysimillisen and put in front of my face.
Just as he was ampumaisillaan,
guard and the team will be firing on all.
After that, I have been a little nervous.
But the worst of nightmares, that I see.
Fulvio Nesstraat whom
should be slots, it is psychoactive.
When I close my eyes, I see him,
even though I do not know what he looks like.
His gaze bores through me.
He knows what I think.
He ​​knows that I'm lying.
You're lying.
Did you think you could steal from me?
-I have not stolen, Fulvio.
Admit it, Larry.
Then you feel better.
I swear on my children's life...
-Shut up!
Let me ask you something.
What do you think of Arabs?
L...
I do not really understand them.
The entire Middle should be from the bomb.
Typical bigoted reaction to the culture, you do not know anything.
Saudi Arabia can be left on the table
million, even though the two days.
Believe that they're honest people.
Not any more than the Americans,
but they will respect the law.
Muslim countries
thief cut off the hand.
I did not take it.
-Hand on the table!
No matter what it was.
If we do not respect the property of
and the law, we are just animals.
Place the hand on the table.
This is fucking your newspaper!
Leave a neighbor alone.
Is the sports section?
-It is, it is.
Did tiling the kitchen?
-It looks good.
Good.
Ask Barbara to play.
Change your clothes.
Did you go shopping for a new magazine?
No, it was behind a dumpster.
're Lying.
I can see it in your eyes.
Am I a liar, Fulvio?
Crawled behind a dumpster looking for
your paper and you say liar.
I do not.
I'm not saying you are a liar.
You have a big heart.
Saved a hell of a thief
Journal of the loss of a hand.
Larry, will you in town?
I get a ride? The car is a workshop.
Charles, what do you say?
I'm getting dizzy
thick carpet.
I was buying.
-It's not imagoosi.
Estuvio hates this.
Come on, talk.
Cheemon death was a shock.
-The situation was bad.
Are we doing more and more business?
-Sure.
I heard that the FBI was involved.
No, it was Warren Ganza.
He wanted to division,
came in and shot all of them.
No negotiations.
Just mercilessly.
Is he the problem?
I told you that my family is no longer
not ready to Colombia kind of rodeo.
My father  trust me,
, therefore, I need to look good.
We're here to invest and the idea that you look great.
Warren Ganza is my problem and
Let's get him.
He drinks in 1 982 Margeaux'ta
tuna with. What show-off.
Taste finger potatoes,
salmon and sour cream.
It is not the language to stand on!
-I want a simple coffee.
Taste finger potatoes.
-No potatoes.
Coffee, milk and two sugars
.
If you are importing potatoes, I'll kill them both.
Coffee hot.
Shut up.
Jason, this is a business meeting.
It's not about the strange friendship between
and vegetables.
We meet a few hard type.
-Yeah. The same as I do.
Have not  Scarsdale pojuja,
has also the city is ours.
They are two of the toughest mobster.
Do not like the yuppie,
a stondis.
Stay tonight for business
do not tilaile all the food.
Right.
I'm just trying to be a good host.
I like fun. What's wrong with that?
-Overrated.
Calm down.
You do not understand.
I do not think I can do it.
He sees it in my eyes.
-Cancel an appointment.
Do you think that
I can just reschedule?
Take a deep breath and try to calm down.
You have a anxiety attack.
I'll give stronger pills,
it takes nervousness.
Take a pill an hour before the meeting.
Only one, you do not simahda.
And call this  gastroenterologist.
There is no harm
therapy for more than a continuous flatulence.
Can not be true.
Where is it?
Where is it a good, happy feeling?
One pill is enough, Doctor.
Nerves are still tight as a violin string.
There is one thing,
I would like to do.
I would like to enter into relations with Poland.
I like their cuisine, and if they dress nicely...
Their faces are soft.
Interesting people.
Charlie, I suppose.
Hello. I'm Jason Cane.
Did you find it difficult to find here?
-No.
They are crazy about me.
This is gonna be great.
You are already familiar with Fidel and Estuvion.
Charlie, this is Fulvio.
's Great.
Place the party started.
Bring bubbly.
I'd take with mineral water.
The same for me.
Yoo-hoo.
Do you have a beef stock?
-I'll see what I can do.
The first major event.
Let's make it important.
Start with.
Babes!
What the hell is this?
All out now.
This is too much.
What do you think about?
Shut up and listen!
I do not know, why do you think
that you can behave like a nerd -
but your behavior makes me nervous.
We came here just to go through the
agreement, then we go home.
Are these your kids?
Yes, my child.
-Beautiful are.
Why have not you shown me
on their photos?
It's just retarded.
-Enchanting children.
Such a face can change a man's life.
Who's that girl?
He is Esmeralda.
Just looking mother.
Ryhmäkuvakin is found.
Fidel, I understand why you wanted to
women. You have a wonderful family.
I was just trying to organize a joy.
I'm quite the nerd.
I apologize.
's All right, Jason.
I was too tight.
I am very sensitive to
kokadiilerin stereotypes.
It prevents me from relaamasta.
My wife tells me to loosen up.
Fuck. Let's party started.
No, let's first
is business, and then celebrated. Is that okay?
I'll go through the plan.
Is the stock market prediction familiar?
It is the case here as well.
I'll wash your money in such a way that...
How do I break down?
Minettit be
15% of investments and 50% of the profits.
What Minettit do it justice?
-Arrange the framework.
Charlie, what do you think?
I want a sea view.
What are you agonize over?
Let's do it.
Celebrations start.
I have not danced in years.
Babes, please come back!
Now is celebrated.
Do you think
that the eyes are the window to the soul?
I have a good read of people's eyes.
It's nice.
Right now, I read your eyes.
-What's the show?
They show
that you are sleepy.
But I can not make out,
you have taken too much medication -
been working too hard or are you sick and tired.
Maybe you have a weird sleeping sickness.
Narkolepsu It's a miracle or something.
I'll kill, if you see strange sight.
I just wanted you to know.
I wish I could sleep like that.
Oh fucking hell...
You might have a bit of slow play.
Must be the prostate.
You need more sex.
Kysyinkö you something?
Do not be jealous just because
käärmeesi no longer slither.
Damn how incredible.
Can not even go to the bathroom without having to pee
contest.
You won the competition wee...
I won the shooting competition.
This guy is an animal, Charlie!
-But it is billions.
He shot Estuviolta Pallin off!
Thank God you did not hit the egg!
This is not good imagolleni. -
I am afraid that the shit out of me.
Afraid he to you, Charlie?
I thought you were not afraid of anybody.
Fulvio, piittaan fuck that,
how big you are a crook -
but if you start with a Colombian cost -
staple dick onto your forehead.
Juniper, what did I say?
Do you want to get me killed?
I do not want to see you.
Do you know why?
If I see you, they, too, will see you
and then I'm gone.
You can not follow me anymore.
-I have to.
No, you just need to report.
When you do, do not worry.
You will spend the day at this park and
flirttaat with the girls.
Lllalla you take the pounding in the bar opposite the hotel.
I'll bring you a daily report.
They did not notice anything.
I do not tell you that you have a bad
tail.
I'm not bad.
-You. I did not want to offend.
But I do not want to see you, see
turns.
Charlie Mayo?
-I mean Mayo.
Judy Tipp,
enema queen.
Substance
bowels need to get hold of even if you feel the pressure.
What's that scar?
-Previous enemas.
How many you do a day?
Depends on the season.
Same shit, different assholes.
Now, I can no longer be contained.
-I have not counted the still water.
Think about the fun stuff.
Where are you from?
Ireland.
Mornings morning.
Lucky amulets, magical.
Drink a really lrish coffeeta?
-I can not talk now.
Relax. I'll tell you one thing.
One patient was afraid of this, so that
began to engage in meditation...
Tell us how you went to the meeting.
-Well.
Is not enough. Tell your details.
You got the job,
because we can not lose money.
Look, Daddy...
-Stop.
Do not call me  isukiksi.
Do not the father,  padre  hy,  pater  y the.
Do not talk as if you were upper-law in accordance.
My only son killed himself.
-I'm sorry...
Do you know my son?
He was  Finocchi.
Do you know what it is? Faggot!
One night he told me that
is gay. Knight of the brown hole.
Do you know how I felt?
I threw him out of the house.
I rejected him.
I loved her more than life.
Funeral, I cried like a child
Only one dared to come near me.
He laid his head on my shoulder and
together, we did mourn.
I felt a deep sense of connection  Leon,
kampaajapoikaystävään my son!
A beautiful son was dead -
and I sit here with psycho killer,
who took my daughter to marry mad.
I love Gloria, and I will not
Annakin you take care of it the money thing?
I was mistaken for a soft as a rotten peach.
What do you know about the financial doctrine?
You are a goon.
But you get the chance.
-I appreciate it, don Carmine.
I want to change my life and get your finances in shape -
to make you child's children.
Can you imagine your children?
They pelästyttäisivät Adolf Hitler!
Be merciful to Earth.
Forget the kids. Get a bit of money.
And keep  maintaining peace with my girl.
-Thank you, Don Carmine.
Are you okay?
You are the last days of the patient.
I offer you a ride.
No, thank you. We'll get there.
-Look, I'll take you home.
Put ​​some pants on.
How are you?
-Well.
And you're talkative.
What she ordered for you?
I do not know.
What the hell did you do?
-These destroy the gut once and for all.
You are insane woman.
Let me out?
Just because I support the alternative treatments?
I support the option for run.
-Good reflexes.
You do not clearly known drugs.
Help  I take pains in 2 weeks.
Month after they are gone.
Am I crazy  do you think?
-Yeah.
But attractive?
-Very.
2 weeks. You will not lose anything.
I can not.
-Come on.
I make my boss a better diagnosis.
Interested to hear about your problems?
Fear.
I see in your eyes,
that fear will eat you alive.
If you can not get it under control,
paskot yourself to death.
Let's go eat food strengthens the libido.
It sounds tempting.
Good. You are the road to recovery.
The worst part is that my life guided by
idiots that are looked down upon.
I would give anything to ohjatakseni it yourself.
Why do you feel you do not have
Lord of your life?
How many people is their boss?
We are a shit law.
-Then quit.
And I get even less for the second
egomaanikon under.
What the bosses' grip on?
Fear. They may fear that we will lose our position in
.
Why does the drive is obsessed with?
-Protective shield.
Other comment
amount of survival.
Strange to hear from the mouth of the police.
You have a real shield.
I'm undercover.
If it turns out my life is in danger.
What is the way to overcome fear?
-Luck... And retirement.
Holy Grail.
-Let me show you something.
Sea View. Servants.
Gas, electricity, water. 600 a month.
Jesus Christ! What language do they speak?
-What does it matter. It is a paradise.
Where you go at night?
Tofuburgerille and meditate?
Is that what you want?
Do not know what you want?
-I still do not know.
Fortunately, I know:
a good piece of ass, and eternal happiness.
How did you know?
-I'm good at it.
What the hell is this?
Chill out. This is an adventure.
-I do not like adventure.
Champagne?
-It Pierette.
Let's drink outdoors.
Is this all yours?
No, but there should be.
Lemuaa What's that?
Lanta. We will do the garden.
Thank you.
Look, what if I take you out to eat
?
We made it yes eat.
First you have to be foreplay.
I like foreplay.
-Here is our sex toys.
Is this foreplay?
-Definitely.
First, mix the cow shit in the mud.
Then you take this and the phallic apparatus costed
tökit holes on wet ground -
and I tossed the seeds.
Are you kidding me?
-I. Up the sleeves and a shovel in your hand.
I just drew this
and turned the knob.
Something has probably failed.
No!
Lso wop.
You can not even grow tomatoes.
Leave me in peace, Gloria.
This is important to me.
You do not have to play anything.
Tomatoes on the transaction.
Beefsteak Tomatoes pay 88 Centia.
-I would like to grow your own tomatoes.
Godfather garden.
Please.
Blush, you little shit.
I want this going.
My father loves money laundering -
but if it does something psychosis,
go to the ground, the bullets are flying.
Keep your mouth shut and pray for the best.
Charlie Mayo, see Cane.
-In. You expected.
Good morning.
-Welcome. Great to see.
Are we ready for the Grand Final?
That's a lot of cute banknotes.
Is it 10 million? -2.
Agreement was 10 million.
-I changed it.
I want to see what you can do.
We can also take them away.
From now it is right speech?
Two million is a big money game.
Let's play and see what happens.
Two million is .
We spells.
You should see the market price.
Jason? FSA
Cohler and Harris are here.
Stop! It is routine.
FSA reviews the new company headquarters within 90 days.
They are accountants.
I'll take care of this.
I got this.
I'm going to talk to them.
-No. They want in..
Ask them inside.
Ladies and gentlemen, put your guns away.
They are nothing more than accountants.
Can you get weapons from?
Ask them inside.
Take control of them here, Myrna.
Good morning, gentlemen.
FSA.
a routine check.
-Great. Jason, that was the book.
Bank guarantees and forms.
You want some cola?
No, thank you.
Papers that you do not have enough cash.
But here it seems to be.
Can you explain?
We just international shops.
Is a document?
This. Sorry.
I have a lot to tell you.
The first store was creepy.
FSA showed up to the door.
I thought was a thing of the past, but...
Strange that I would really like to talk about
wonderful woman, whom I met.
I met an amazing woman.
-Who is he?
Did you get hives?
I met Judy's doctor.
He ​​gave me an enema.
That, too, is access to the estate.
-I'm serious. She is gorgeous.
He took out on a date, and
for the first time in months I had a lot of fun.
How does it feel?
-The great thing, Charlie.
Does he know what you do?
No, but I will tell you yes.
Hey, Charlie.
Now, explaining accounts.
No speech, no promises.
I do not care, I love the mother of the boy.
I want money right now!
-I do not have any.
Shut up!
I know how much money is...
Warren Ganza.
The rat showed up.
Like I said, he wanted
division.
It would now go to Warren from over.
Who's that?
I'll explain later. Come on.
Charlie . He is an FBI agent.
Did you kill her?
Yes, he was in Warren.
The car is here.
Probably wondering why
I happened to spot when you came Ganza.
I thought that you were going to shoot me
Warren and do not want to get in time.
You are funny guy.
I was becoming a Police
hotel to provide you with a pounding -
and say, well you handled them
inspectors.
Really. I can well understand why
Cheemo appreciated you.
Thank you.
Have you ever been to New York?
-A couple of times in transit.
Meininki has changed the former.
Have you been in ltaly?
It is the most beautiful place in the world.
I, I have not been there.
But I have a lot of pictures.
I changed the time machine in Rome.
Really?
It must have been great.
-Airport was good.
I went shopping for snacks.
It was all in Italian.
Waited for a man behind.
He ​​said, " Cris cris. "
He's got a bag of potato chips,
so I said, " Cris cris. "
I, too, got some chips.
Cris cris.  Potato Chips.
It will keep in mind.
It is written cris cris,
but pronounced air aces.
As with all the roman languages.
I pronounced i, respectively,
final consonant is dropped off.
Did you buy souvenirs?
-I bought, fine leather goods.
You change the disc already. You can continue your job.
Warren Ganza is dead, the danger over.
He killed  Juniper!
It's tough to lose a colleague.
It belongs to the work.
We have to catch the killers.
-What about those who kill me?
Juniper's fate touched everyone.
I want you to know,
that the entire department is here for you.
How are you doing?
-I do very well, Dexter.
I'm going to throw myself off the roof.
What is the view from there?
It's tough to lose comrade.
Good, the humor is still there.
Hey, you.
What's up?
-Good.
Look, Judy,
I need to talk to you about an important matter.
's Take a walk at the same time.
A beautiful day.
And that's why I do not sleep, I eat
medications and bowel tricks.
For the first time, you do not say anything.
What do you think?
-I could tell you a parable.
Buddhist monk passes through the mountains and all of a sudden
tiger starts to chase.
Cliff's edge a monk sees,
the bottom there are five tigers.
Hanging on a bush in which he relies,
when you realize strawberries. He smiles.
He says:
"It's a perfect strawberry."
He picks it up and eats it.
So what?
-That's all.
That's all? The monk is getting into the
tigers jaw and eat strawberries?
What the hell does that mean?
It means that the
must live every second of life.
All living when are alive.
-Not if you fear gnawing.
You are close to the tiger's jaw,
twice the gods have saved -
but you are the luckiest man in the world
?
You will not, enter the calming and
paskot your pants.
Ahoy!
Are you gentlemen ready to celebrate the
stock prices a little cruise?
It is a little chilly.
-Jason gets really warm you feel.
Come aboard, gentlemen.
Come on now.
Champagne, ladies and gentlemen?
Okay. Proudly declare
-
the Transcontinental acquired lnvestments
800 000 soijapapuosaketta.
I would like to propose a toast to us,
soijapapupohatoille.
Beans?
You bought the beans  two million?
After all, you're joking.
I do not. We currently have a
2% soijapapumarkkinoista.
Are you crazy?
I tell my father that I bought the whole
amount of beans?
I would immediately run out of the hair and become a monk!
They are soy beans.
They are made of tofu.
Let soybean, green, brown,
kindergarten or even Heinz beans!
Do not even hint at all,
that my father is pavunpoimija!
I want the money back tomorrow!
Then we suffer a loss.
We will lose at least half.
Fidel, he is right.
-Charlie, not on my side.
Put ​​that jerk thing to handle.
-We do not wash your money for free.
Do you want macaroni war
300 000 Dollars?
Kolumbialaispaskat  What about you?
You will begin to immediately brandish Uzeja.
Let's get this right now.
-Come on.
Stop that machismo!
I do not care who has the biggest!
I came here to make money!
Fidel, do not make fun of your family.
It was a misunderstanding.
Do not you think?
-I swear it.
I did not realize that the Colombian
beans are a sensitive issue.
Enough of this, Jason.
Fidel, it was a misunderstanding.
Look what that shit does!
Pallin You shot him!
-Stop.
Yes, we came up with something.
-I did not take my dad beans!
We'll figure something out.
Are we doing more and more business?
First thing you should we get rid of the beans.
Father, it is a sensitive issue.
We do not eat beans.
Do you even  bean salad?
-Jason, shut up.
No one is infringing your family.
Heivataan beans.
He has to leave my husband alone.
They lost balls, broken ends.
Fulvio, you need to curb your anger.
We have to earn money.
We have a big problem.
No, no different from us.
Yuppie bought the beans and Fidel injured it.
Why?
As Mexicans eating beans.
Same as the negro should be
watermelon shares.
I was able to buy a
oliiviöljyosakkeita.
You the choice you did it yourself.
Peruuko Vaillar due to some error?
We'll take care of this.
-Let's end this thing.
We have 2 million.
-They are rich.
2 million is peanuts.
-By Colombian and keep the money.
Let's arrest now.
Charlie must finish the job together,
export our money.
Fulvio is a maniac.
I can not keep job together.
What do you think?
-Go on.
What do you think, Joey?
There is only one little problem.
You cover your losses if
Jason lost market?
Not really.
-No way.
Course.
-It's what I thought.
I come, I come!
Luxury News. Can I come in?
-Sure.
A nice roommate, Charlie.
You will travel in style.
Thank you. What news did you have?
-Jason heivasi beans.
How much was a loss?
-Just 20 per cent.
The flamboyant gambling
know how to move your money.
Losses he moved to the other customers. -Unbelievable.
When the options become due,
those guys jumping from the windows.
Now this is like a palace, Charlie.
I'm just saying that it is a little Fidel...
He is the best thank us.
I had to suffer because of it papufriikin.
I hope he knows it.
Fidelia is not easy to please.
Say more. When the wind turns,
he will get a scene.
He can not control himself.
-That's right. Jealous man off.
We have to be really quiet,
in order to Fidel's self-control does not disappoint.
I think we have succeeded in
very well.
Mostly  -
But he still remembers,
that ravaged his bodyguard.
A little bit.
Did I
I could not let her make fun of the prostate.
Like the temple. -When you get back to life,
is a well-deserved retirement.
Is this what you want?
Let's go upstairs.
What do you do?
There is
who wants to kill me.
His or her partner is here.
How do you ..?
-A little concerned.
What is it?
-They need more than that.
You think I'm paranoid?
The Colombians are there.
Charlie, this is crazy.
Yes, it would, if I were to
the common man -
but it is quite different.
If something goes wrong, I'm dead.
All the time something goes wrong,
but always gonna be.
But it is not always constant, and
kill me.
Your fear is like a magnet:
positions all with you.
Right. They then later point.
Guard while one bullet.
-As always.
Guess what.
You...
Let's go eat.
I'm starved.
Is that Charlie?
-Amazing!
Were you show?
And we chose the same restaurant.
Destiny interwoven.
Jason. -Judy.
Lady Judy. Sit down. -No.
I insist.
Everyone, this is Judy.
There is no room.
-You're kidding me. Ken, two more!
What's the matter?
-Guy group therapy is here.
Remember: the gods love to you.
Here is a walnut-kurpitsaraviolia,
which is bound to taste.
There are two further doses of ravioli.
-And a bowl of strawberries to my friend.
What was the Best in Show?
-Moorish villa.
A very romantic.
Full Marrakesh above, hashish-smoking
and seven veil dance.
Something like that.
I like the modern.
Other like classical music.
There is no reason to believe that any new
is the shit.
Everything new is shit. -He hates everything
less than 2000 years old.
Sicilian house of your own.
-Masterpiece.
Is the ruins of Agrigento photography.
They are lempiraunioni .
Charlie. The girl is a treasure.
I have a weakness to Rococo.
-The whole show is great.
The best of all.
Housing market to Disney World.
Let him go! Please help!
Get off me!
Please help!
Do you completely barmy?
I have to Elliot's friend.
He ​​explains it all.
I will pay the bill.
You'd better leave now.
Sorry for the interruption. He is my friend.
Liver to his bill and other expenses.
What was that?
He called down daamilleni
obscenities in front of his wife. I had no choice.
Let's go have a drink.
The girls are doing fine.
Tobacco?
Fidel . Jason and Fulvio
have a new plan.
The above was a bit too much.
-They nest in 2 million as liked.
And we nielimme victory.
What had in mind?
-Buy market.
If we have a majority, we can control the prices of
.
What would it cost?
-About 40 million.
Should I invest 40 million?
What kind of business issues do they have?
They wash money.
-What do you mean?
Kolumbialaishomot represent drug cartel.
Invest in the billions,
boyfriend arranged.
True thrill.
Fulvio really screw up the whole thing.
-Why?
He is in control of it. There is no intelligence to
and self-control that.
He pretends .
-Should trust him.
Fulvio would trust?
He ​​is a loser.
Want a gardener as the grandfather Heendâ
and can not even grow tomatoes.
Who is the Italian he could such a thing?
That says it all.
Where is the toilet?
I think they have a crisis.
-It would appear so.
Invest 20,
if panette the rest.
Fidel, they take care of their money in a deal
not need to be washed.
All money needs to be washed.
And if this is a lucrative trade,
I made a reasonable offer to pay half.
Do I look like Santa Claus?
Where can I get the rest of the 20 million?
Let's talk about the issue.
-Ahead. Let's talk.
Am I more and more popular among the gods?
-You're still alive.
So, since knocked Elliott.
This.
What is this?
-Do not ask.
It will probably good for me.
Kuolonenkeleistä What do you think?
-Normal guys.
Fulvio Are you normal?
He ​​shot Estuviolta Pallin out of it.
Fulvio seemed unhappy.
-I will. Did you talk to my wife?
He, too, seemed unhappy.
-Did he say Fulvio sensitive topic?
Tomatoes. -What's in
fruits and vegetables have?
What do you need me for?
-You explain the deal.
I do not explain it to your donillesi.
Yes, explain.
Why did he invest 20 million
relying on an unknown word?
People like you.
Fulvio says
that you're a smart guy.
I do not know whether
clever to ask me to invest 20 million.
You tell me.
-It's not smart, sir.
He's only joking.
-Low, Fulvio. Go on, Charlie.
When you invest a sum of
always take a big risk.
If one-third ownership provides the ability to control prices
-
why not do it?
On Wall Street on a daily basis.
-Shut up!
Tell risks, Charlie.
-The first acquisition of 40 million -
and to ensure that the
little things let you down -
livistä and no one with the money.
Manipulating the market for the audit secret -
which is impossible,
when you buy a third.
Inspectors noses sniffing,
also feature perästämme shit smell.
I like you, Charlie.
You do not try to fool me.
I think about it.
I'll call you then.
Keep your phone switched on.
That's how you help me?
You ruined the whole deal!
Wait until he plays.
Told me everything,
what's going wrong!
I wanted to win the trust.
-You would have to curry!
Nearly simply referred to go away!
Käänteispsykologiaa,
I do not seem eager.
I would be eager to withdraw from it!
I can no longer be a cliché!
I want money-
so that I can stop this mafia flick of life!
Do not you like to be a villain?
-I hate it!
Jesus, Fulvio.
I never would have...
You are so good
to beat up people.
You do not know me.
No one knows me.
I'm sorry.
I know how you feel.
How could you know?
You'll all be successful.
Dexter, I do not know.
I would like to own my money on the line.
20 million would be quite a high price.
We just need to show the money.
They look like theirs, I'll shoot them.
Leave it to a few millimeters in there and exported to the rest of the
.
One-day work
$ 18 million.
Sure that my son-in-law
shot in the side.
Why are agreeing to another diiliin?
Do you give them 20 million?
I give them 20 million,
, but I'll show them the money.
Then I'll kill Fulvio
Nesstraat and the money from him.
What about Charlie?
Our approach him too.
Remember who brought him on board.
Do not see it.
-They pay for your sufferings.
My life is shit, Charlie.
Maybe that's why I always
ready to beat up someone.
All the time I look only
that I get an excuse to kill.
Why?
-I do not know.
Maybe I have low self-esteem.
Even my grandmother
treated me like a dog shit.
Consider: Italian grandma treats
cute bambino  like a plague.
Fulvio, all of which are
unsure of themselves.
Not you.
You do not even blink an eye.
I threatened
gun at you and you took a nap.
You're trying to just get a feel
improving.
If only one change.
Life could be wonderful.
I, too, could be.
I want to be wonderful.
So, don Carmine?
He is involved.
Where did you guessed it?
-I trust your intuition.
They bring 40 million in cash.
Is not it time to arrest?
Vaillareilla is in the billions.
40 million of them pocket money.
We can also grab Fidel Vaillarin.
Pedro Vaillarilla of 1 2 sons.
He ​​is not taking care hinttaripojastaan.
Is Fidel gay?
I did not know.
-Charlie, you're doing a great job.
All amazing deals have been documented.
Vaillarin We close the taps and activities.
That's never been done
none of the cartel.
He just knocked you up?
Sheer carnage.
I never thought that I would experience such a thing.
Elliott, I'm really sorry.
I thought that result in death.
What I did I do?
Charlie. Elliott does not talk about it,
what happened in the restaurant.
What is this?
I no longer restrained myself at work.
-What happened?
I was at the meeting, and intimated,
that the marketing of the boss is the stiff.
And?
Questioned his expertise.
Then I jumped on the table and yelled,
that he was a crazy nigger fuck -
valid for work only
little bureaucrat. I got fired.
I do not care,
that I lost my job and wife.
Did your wife  you?
-Yesterday evening.
The worst part is when you have one of the assistant,
which makes the minutes of the meeting...
She is wonderful.
Has a face like an angel.
Good-natured man.
But when he heard that word,
he is African American, -
saw the pain on his face.
I did not want to offend him.
I lost everything because
I could not control myself.
Jesus,
this worthless piece of shit I have not.
Elliott, you is not shit.
Allow Elliott, a moment to calm down.
Charlie, you is a big deal.
It's tomorrow.
-Tomorrow?
What are you going to do?
-I'm trying to survive.
's It?
Let me ask: if you know that
turning out to be a fateful meeting -
what do you do?
-I am quiet and I'm trying to survive.
One way it should be.
-Defeat can not be avoided.
I'm sorry, but I have a
expenditure, which I can not cancel.
It's okay.
Since this is my last night alive
, you going to have a drink?
Blank yes would be nice.
Good evening, doctor.
Is Jerry Feinstein meeting?
-Who is Jerry Feinstein?
He was the model.
Wall Street bailuhirmu.
All know him.
Lonny, Jason Cane,
the Wall Street type...
Guess what.
The right name is Jerry Feinstein.
I consider whether there is anything about him.
DRUG POSSESSION
arrested Dexter Helvenshaw
Plaza Hotel. Good evening.
-Charles Mayo, thank you.
This is a message box
number 1601.
me.
Now is the devil to pay.
Meet
63 and 5 on the street corner.
I would like to propose a toast, ladies and gentlemen
-
those men,
that we had before.
I'm pretty much the same.
15 years ago, I went to work
dressed like Don Johnson.
I survived it all,
I was king, I was not afraid.
You kokkelipäissäsi.
Maybe a little bit. I was 25 years old.
I was like James Bond in Monte Carlo
playing baccarat with its...
Ernst Blofeld with.
-The one with the cat.
I've only played in Vegas
Hong Kong triad types.
It was incredible.
Huumeporhot knew how to celebrate.
Do not do?
-Not the ones that I know.
They are just as bad as we do.
-Are the bad guys unhappy?
Depressing.
Lonnya did you see?
He ​​räpläsi computer and just rushed out.
You are constantly in danger.
The pay is lousy.
You have no privacy.
Why do you do it?
Something to inspire you.
-You said your job miserable.
It has not always been terrible.
Sometimes it was just insane.
As drugs.
-Almost as if it would have been stoned.
The joint work was at the time of companionship.
But the best part was the risk ropes.
If mokaisi, would die for sure.
Me.
Now is the devil to pay.
See you
63.ja 5 on the street corner.
I love this.
When I grow up I want to be like Charles.
Describe a little bit crazy.
This is a risk.
There you are your own boss.
You are alone with a thug.
Every time you meet, you do not know,
what he knows, and you do not.
Lonny, Charlie asked me to get.
He ​​could not make it.
How do you know what to do?
-Hop.
This is followed by instinct.
It's a strange, magical sixth sense.
If it is wrong, is a thing of the past.
What happened, when the
Cheemo killed by your colleagues?
I still have not figured out how to
Cheemo got to know about me.
I could not live like that. -
It can not be understood unless experienced it.
You do not have to live like that.
Tell me more.
When you're a thug with a double,
talking about just ordinary stuff.
"Did you look at the yesterday's game?"
"Did you see what tits?"
What is Charlie doing?
-He's gonna be fine.
But it is not harmless.
Konnillakin is a good instinct.
It's not even about lying.
Pressure is enormous. You can say:
"The sky is blue," and as you know they are lying
, blow your cover.
I do not understand him.
-You're not the only one.
The hardest part is when you have to ask.
Question about a quick death.
Did  Charlie, from the phone?
-No.
Talking to?
-He wanted to meet with us immediately.
If they are friendly, speak up.
Be familiar, but do not be too.
Do not talk about your gold cellulite
nor the neighbor's house fronts.
I've been here for four weeks without seeing a single match in
.
Do you have connections to lipunmyyjiin?
It's like a constant job interview.
It is well-behaved,
pretending. All goes smoothly.
Then considers the wrong direction
and cease to exist.
Howard, Charlie here.
I call service.
Charlie, what is man?
Lose its first, and then I think of courage?
I do not know. But it is difficult to
get them back.
Trick stash is empty.
-You have to believe in change.
I'll see you soon.
As soon as you see the money,
take the gun out, but do not shoot.
I split from him prick, and then I'll blow your head off.
It is difficult to restrain myself.
I know.
His pain is my gift to you.
FBI agent Clemmensen.
-The Helvenshaw drug agency.
The mission is ruined
villain like the police.
I'm in danger, and I ask for help.
-Yes, sir.
Incredibly good timing
to make a deal just today.
Player to Tokyo in the morning and I heard something top secret.
What is it?
The Japanese have a new program,
that outperforms Microsoft.
They have been working on it for years.
-And now it's ready.
Katsumi announce soon.
-The Father loves it.
And also the fact that I placed the
40 million.
You do not even beer money.
-Life is a game. Here is the money.
I checked prices on the way.
A week later, the money has doubled.
Fantastic!
I can not wait to tell the father.
Good. Here is my money.
Show yours.
Forget about the plan. Let's make a deal.
-What do you do?
What the hell?
Shit!
Easy Buddy.
Agent Mayo, are you okay?
Charlie, Do you need help?
Are you a cop?
I liked you as a friend.
I'm your friend.
We met in poor conditions.
Agent Mayo, do you need help?
-I do not expose me before.
What is this?
He is the agent of Dexter Helvenshaw.
He ​​has arranged all this.
True.
-What the hell is he doing?
He wants you to shoot me -
then he shoots you, take your money and end up in
hero. Or what, Dex?
Exactly.
Asshole...
Are you alive, my precious?
Ribs would crack.
-I'll take you to safety.
Hands up, Charlie.
Put ​​your hands up!
Jason, take a bag and go over there.
I'll see you, you bastard.
He cheated  you, Fulvio,
, and now you're gonna die.
Do not be sweet revenge
before the end of the year?
Jesus, Fulvio,
I think I'd shoot me.
FBI! Guns and off the ground!
-I called and asked for help.
I'm an agent Mayo!
-He killed his boss.
Hands on the head. Who is she?
Fulvio Nesstraat Minettin family.
The Colombians are there.
Who is she?
Data sources. 'll Question him.
I raise my gun.
Do you need help?
No, I was just a scratch. Let's go.
A little bit more, my dear.
I can not, Fidel.
Save yourself.
I do not ever!
Estuvio, honey. Look at me.
When we get out of here,
I promise that I will leave my family.
We need to design clothes.
-So.
Fidel, do we have to?
-It's the only way out.
What do we do now?
Use the money in shares and sold when the price is doubled.
What about Carmine Minetti?
-Viiyytän him a couple of days.
FBI! Put your hands up!
Helvenshaw drug agency!
I heard even on the first time
-I'll take the badge.
What do you say, dear?
Somebody up there likes me.
Shit!
They must have gone through the back.
-Really? You could open a suitcase.
Did you see him?
Give me something Fulvio leg.
How did you do it?
Do you think that only you
gain access to the drugs?
Do not they have the FBI agents?
-Friends in a group.
Do not arrest us all?
-No.
What about the money?
We like them, Fulvio.
We can make your life wonderful.
Bowl area with sea views!
It was incredible!
We did it!
What does your father do,
when you hear what happened?
subtitled by  SELVAHEMA