(Episode 15)
Professor, I heard you
were going on a vacation.
It was a sudden change of mind.
I'm sorry for what happened.
You really need to get a rest.
By the way, where are you going?
I don't know yet.
That makes me...
a serial killer.
I visited the tunnel...
after a long time.
I found peace after 30 long years.
I thought no one knew who I was.
Keeping a secret...
was so exciting that it made me laugh.
I never thought he would
follow me all the way there.
- Thank you.
- Bye, Corporal Park.
Ma'am.
What is it?
Did you know that there was a
tunnel in this neighborhood?
- A tunnel?
- Yes.
I've been working here for three
years and yet I didn't know.
It looks really old.
I know that tunnel. It is old.
A woman was murdered there.
- What?
- It's been over 30 years.
I went to school with her.
I feel so sorry for her.
Why do you ask?
It's always people talking
about and remembering...
others' deaths that cause problems for me.
This is why...
I told you to leave me be.
Until then,
I just thought my peace was broken.
However, I realized today...
that everything that happened...
was destined for me.
I see a new face. Why don't we
at least exchange greetings?
I'm Detective Park Kwang... No.
- I'm Corporal Park Kwang Ho.
- I'm Mok Jin Woo.
My mother is also a victim of the
serial killing of 30 years ago.
How can that be?
I thought it was a relief
that I came to know...
Corporal Park is my father even
though it's a little late.
Destiny brought the three of them to me.
Yeon Ho, Yeon Ho?
Yeon Ho, Yeon Ho!
Yeon Ho!
What do you mean by that?
Professor Shin has gone missing?
She told me she'd come
to the police station.
She...
She told me...
Her cellphone was on the floor.
We don't really know what happened.
She said she'd arrive soon.
Sun Jae,
she'd never drop and leave
her things on the floor.
All right, I get what you are saying.
Let's check the CCTV first.
Wait. Go back to this part.
That scum.
I'll kill him.
What about the other CCTV? Can't
we check where his car went?
Wait a moment.
Let's go.
But Kwang Ho,
Professor Shin isn't there.
- No way.
- It can't be.
That scum.
She hasn't gone missing.
She has been kidnapped.
Put out an all-points
bulletin for the car...
and trace his phone's location.
What happened to the search warrant?
What? You need to get it no matter what!
Goodness.
- Did you get anything?
- He must have drugged her.
What is going on?
What would happen to Kwang Ho if
something has happened to her?
- Chief.
- Yes?
According to the assistant, she
left the office at 7:27pm.
The last phone call she made
to Kwang Ho was at 7:35pm.
The CCTV recording of his car
at the main gate was at 7:42pm.
That scum.
It's been over an hour.
- Any witnesses?
- None. And that's the only CCTV.
What about Kwang Ho and Sun Jae?
They went to the control center to
track the movements of his car.
It's a race against time. We need to hurry.
- Yes, sir.
Next.
No, the next one.
Stop there.
(8:40pm)
He left through the Hwayang
Tollgate 40 minutes ago.
The car stopped here.
- The car stopped?
- Yes.
But after kidnapping her,
he went straight to the Hwayang
Tollgate from the parking lot.
According to the recorded time,
it took 20 minutes, meaning he didn't stop.
That means he has a destination.
He's right. He won't be carrying
her in his car everywhere.
He'd be exposed easily.
The fact that the tracks
stopped at the tollgate...
He might have used a national
highway to hide his destination.
Then our first priority is to
figure out his destination.
We should watch all the CCTVs of
every national highway as well.
We also need to step up the inspection.
All right.
(Hwayang University parking lot,
Hwayang University main gate)
Chief, why don't we start
an open investigation?
No. If it's exposed in the media,
everything we do will be exposed.
Nobody knows what he will
do to Professor Shin.
Where on earth is the fountain pen?
It's only Professor Shin who knows it.
We should find her first.
Mok Jin Woo was born in Seoul.
It's been long since his
grandmother's house was gone.
Is there any real estate under his name?
There is one he's living in.
I couldn't find any clue there.
Let's go to his previous houses.
He must have gone to a
place he's familiar with.
We should investigate areas he
provided volunteer medical services.
Most of them are islands,
and there are many empty houses,
which are good to hide.
Chief, Kwang Ho and I are going
to find his destination first.
Okay. Go ahead.
Tae Hee and Min Ha,
investigate his call history,
bank statement, credit card details,
and the internet search history.
I'll check the CCTVs of the national roads.
The top priority is to catch up with him.
Come on. Let's go.
It's done.
Thank you.
Okay.
Sir, is there any other
problem in the trunk?
No, What's wrong?
I heard some sound from it.
Hello.
Yes, sir.
I'll be there shortly, sir.
Could you tell me again
where you are exactly?
Okay, I see.
I'm sorry. Drive safely, sir.
Thank you.
(Mok Jin Woo Personnel File)
(33 Shinhyun-dong, Hwayang,
Gyeonggi-do, no clue, no chance)
(Hwayang University Hospital
volunteer medical service daily log)
(Volunteer medical service)
(Volunteer medical service 2)
(Bank statements)
(Call history)
His call history of a month shows...
that he called only his
family and his office.
There's not a single unusual record.
He hardly used his credit cards.
He's beyond Jung Ho Young.
- If he'd used them, we could...
- Seriously?
A witness showed up.
You mean that customer?
There was a nail stuck in the wheel.
I patched it up.
Where was it?
It was 43 national highway in Yeonkyung.
Is it 43 national highway in Yeonkyung?
He's never lived in Yeonkyung.
Here it is.
He provided volunteer medical
service in Yeonkyung.
What?
Is there any other things to say about him?
Didn't you see a woman?
No, there wasn't a woman. He was alone.
Oh, right. There was some sound
coming out of the trunk.
What?
What is this? Gosh.
- Is this it?
- There doesn't seem to be a CCTV.
Come here.
It can't be a place we can easily find.
Mok Jin Woo took her to
a place only he knows.
Where on earth is that?
I'll ask where the fountain pen is...
three times only.
If you don't answer the question,
you will be dead.
You'll be given only three
chances to answer it.
Remember that.
Here goes the first one.
Where is the fountain pen?
You still have two chances left.
I'll ask the same question
for the second time...
and third time.
Where is the fountain pen?
Where on earth is it?
Are you going to answer it?
England.
It's in England.
What?
Do you expect me to believe that?
You know I was adopted.
Everything from my childhood is in England.
I just need to call.
You will have to pay for it...
if you're trying to fool me.
Answer me carefully.
Is it really in England?
(International call)
Hello?
It's me.
You mind checking the time
difference before calling?
Listen. I need you to do me a favor.
Remember the fountain pen I've always kept?
Do you think you can send it over here?
A fountain pen?
Yes, it should be in the bible
inside the third drawer of my desk.
The address is...
Send it to the university.
You can send it to my
office at the university.
And please hurry.
How long will it take?
It could arrive within...
as early as three days.
Three days.
What should we do in the meantime?
What is it?
Did something happen to Professor Shin?
How did you know that?
Did something really happen?
She called her friend in England.
What?
She made a call?
What is this about?
Her friend called me saying
something was wrong...
and that her phone was turned off.
She wanted her to send a fountain pen.
A fountain pen?
What?
I thought something was weird.
The desk that Jae Yi used
doesn't have any drawers.
And none of her things are here either.
You don't think something
bad happened to her?
Don't worry. I'll make sure
that nothing ever goes wrong.
First, I need you to put any
of your pen inside the bible.
And send it over as soon as possible.
All right. I'll do that.
It'll probably arrive in three days.
Please contact me once again
when you're done sending.
- All right.
- Thank you. Bye.
- What did she say?
- It'll arrive in three days.
I think Professor Shin was
trying to buy time for us.
She must have thought that if she
called her friend in England,
I would be able to hear about it.
We should hide in Hwayang
University and catch Mok Jin Woo.
What if he finds out about her lying?
We need to get him before that.
She lied while risking her life.
She knows better than anyone...
that it's the only evidence.
Don't worry. We'll get him this time.
He won't do anything before
he checks the pen...
with his own eyes. As
Professor Shin told us,
it's the one thing Mok Jin Woo
wants to retrieve the most.
We need to prepare for stakeout
during these three days.
That's right, kiddo. It'll
all be over in three days.
These three days...
seem like 30 years to me.
I have a question.
That picture...
was drawn by you, right?
You lived here with your mother.
Do you want an interview or something?
Or is this profiling?
We have three days until the pen arrives.
It doesn't seem like a bad idea...
to chat in the meantime.
I asked Jung Ho Young once...
why he was obsessed with skirts...
and if his mother liked to wear them.
But that...
was your obsession.
It was not his mom, but yours.
Actually,
Jung Ho Young didn't have a type.
But...
you did...
because you saw your mother in them.
What was your mother like?
Don't lie! You didn't catch
the man behind the mask!
(Bridal Mask)
You are invaders! You are
bullies who tried to fight me.
Take that!
Mom, I finished reading the comic book.
- Right. I swear if you don't...
- Come back. Come inside.
- Mom, Mom!
- Please, wait!
What? What is wrong with you?
I just...
You told me to call you when
I finish the comic book.
I'm sorry, Mom.
Come down. Let's eat.
Okay.
(Bridal Mask)
Did she wear a skirt and stockings...
and go out to see a man?
What?
You must've seen it every day until...
you were sent to your grandmother's.
You must've known that if your
mother wears a skirt and stockings,
it means she's going to work.
You probably waited alone in
this house until she came home.
There must have been many days
you fell asleep while waiting.
Then you suddenly...
started to resent your mother
for leaving you alone.
Hatred for someone deepens
as much as you love them.
You must've hated to see your mom go out.
Am I wrong?
Mom. Look at this.
Read the comic books and play alone, okay?
Gosh, darling.
Darling. Gosh, stop it.
What on earth is this?
This is the dress I got you yesterday.
Did you do this, Tiffany?
What on earth?
That's why you killed women
in stockings, right?
They reminded you of your mom.
It was you who was repeatedly
killing your mother,
not Jung Ho Young. It was you.
You don't know anything.
Those women had to die for a reason.
You killed them for a reason?
Don't be absurd.
You think you're different from Jung
Ho Young who killed women for sport.
You're wrong.
You're just like him.
I'm different!
I'm different.
All of those women were guilty.
What was Yoon Da Young guilty of?
What about Nam Ju Hee?
They shouldn't have
wandered around at night.
They shouldn't have done that.
What about Lieutenant Kim's mother...
who went out to buy her husband's tie?
I saw her on the bus.
She smiled at another man.
How can a mother like that
raise a child properly?
He's better off without a mother like that.
You're wrong.
You killed those women just
because you wanted to.
You killed them instead of your mom...
whether they're ordinary or not.
I don't even know how you can tell
if a person is ordinary or not.
You just...
enjoyed murdering them.
Just like Jung Ho Young.
What?
Are you going to strangle me again?
See? You just want to kill someone.
Strangle me.
Kill me.
Kill me, you murderer!
- It will only take a second.
- Gosh.
Can I take you tonight?
- All right. Let's go somewhere.
- Do you want to have some fun?
- You're so sexy.
- Honey.
- Come on.
- I'd love that.
Can you handle three guys?
- Baby, that's right.
- I won't charge you much.
- You can get the prettiest one.
- Me too.
- Don't worry about it.
- I got plenty.
It's a gift for entering middle school.
- How are you doing?
- Come here.
You're looking good tonight.
It's my baptismal name.
I'd love that.
Can you handle three guys?
Be good to your grandmother.
I got plenty.
- Do this thing.
- Look at these ladies.
Taxi.
Let's go.
Kid. You shouldn't come
to a place like this.
Hello.
- Hello, honey.
- Hi.
Those filthy women.
Hey!
My mom isn't that kind of a person.
She's not that kind of a person!
- She's not that kind of a person!
- Hey!
My mom...
isn't that kind of a person.
She's not that kind of a woman.
(Satellite map of Hwayang University)
Yes, this is Kim Sun Jae.
Hey, it's Kate.
I'm calling because I think the package...
will arrive some time tomorrow morning.
Professor Shin's office is here.
These two are the only
entrances to the building.
Unit Two will stake out
near these entrances.
- Yes, sir.
Where is the front gate of the school?
These are the front and back gates.
Her laboratory is nearer to the front gate.
Mok Jin Woo will probably use the
front gate to shorten the distance.
Tae Hee and Min Ha, you will wait
for him at the gate with me.
We have to catch him inside the building.
Otherwise, we might lose him.
You and I will wait for him near
Professor Shin's office and attack.
Do you think he will show up by himself?
I think he will.
It's too risky for him to take
Professor Shin here as the hostage.
Let's catch him first.
Sun Jae. When will the package arrive?
It'll arrive some time
between 10am and 11am.
Let's move now.
Be at the entrances of the
building where her office is.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
(Hwayang Police Station promises our
citizens safety and happiness.)
Be on standby at your positions for now,
and we'll take our places at dawn.
Stay quiet.
Stay alert.
An express delivery truck just went in.
It just went in.
(Operating Systems Laboratory)
Who's that?
What?
Excuse me. One moment.
By any chance, was there a package
delivered to Ms. Shin Jae Yi?
Ms. Shin Jae Yi?
That's right. I remember. Someone
else received it for her.
What?
Thank you.
Chief. Mok Jin Woo's not here.
These are the front and back gates.
Her laboratory is nearer to the front gate.
Mok Jin Woo will probably use the
front gate to shorten the distance.
We have to catch him inside the building.
You and I will wait for him near
Professor Shin's office and attack.
This is driving me crazy.
He must've sensed something.
We were hiding out since last night.
There's no way he could've known.
How could he have found out?
Also, how could he have known
Yeon Ho had the fountain pen?
That conversation was just
between Sun Jae and I.
Wait a minute.
Even if you've made a stupid move,
you shouldn't give up.
Why? What is it?
What is that? It can't be.
Gosh. Darn it.
That scumbag.
He was listening to everything.
If he dares to lay a finger on Yeon Ho,
I'll kill him.
Kwang Ho. Kwang Ho.
Did you fool me?
Why?
Did you think you'd be
able to earn some time?
It's not in England, is it?
Where is it?
Where's the fountain pen?
Tell me where it is!
Yeon Sook.
Forgive me.
I promise I'll...
I'll...
protect our daughter.
No matter what it takes,
I'll make sure to save her.
Then I'll look into Mok Jin Woo.
I'll try to see where the
mode of operation leads to...
and whether there are any clues.
The daughter left Jin
Woo with her mother...
when he was around 11 or 12 years old...
saying she was going to go earn money.
Whenever she visited, she showed
up with a handful of gifts.
From time to time, I received
a pair of stockings myself.
Back then, stockings were
considered as luxury goods.
- Stockings?
- That's right.
She worked at a place
called "Town" or somewhere.
Then how did his mother pass away?
She died in a hospital. Apparently,
she suffered from alcoholism.
It could be somewhere
connected to his mother.
You're looking for Kim
Ji Hye from 1985, right?
It says here she died of alcoholism.
What is it you'd like to know?
Her address. Do you have the
address of her house at the time?
I'm not sure if this place still exists.
House number 58 of "New
York Town" in Mijucheon.
The old lady in Yeon Ho's tape
recording also mentioned "Town".
Thank you for your help.
Chief. We found out where
Mok Jin Woo's hiding out.
I see. You're refusing
to answer, aren't you?
Does that mean it's my turn then?
The person you've been looking for...
is Park Kwang Ho, isn't it?
How does it feel to meet your
father who's younger than you?
Since you've revealed a secret that
I've had for the past 30 years,
it's only fair that I get
something from this, isn't it?
He killed the real Park Kwang Ho...
and he's using his identity
and acting as a policeman.
Who should I share this with?
The chief of the crime department?
The chief of police?
Or the press?
Please don't.
Tell me.
Where's the fountain pen?
Yeon Ho.
Shall we hide it here?
Okay.
The teddy bear's stomach must hurt a lot.
Dad will come back and take it out.
Really?
Of course.
You should never tell
anyone until he returns...
because this is a treasure hunt.
Okay.
My gosh.
I should've killed you from the start.
Guard every exit.
Sun Jae.
You jerk!
Hey!
Yeon Ho.
Yeon Ho. Yeon Ho.
Are you okay?
Yeon Ho.
Professor Shin, are you okay?
Are you really okay?
Yes.
(Hwayang University Hospital)
What? Why are you out already?
You should be getting examined.
What did the doctor say?
He said I'm fine. I just sprained my leg.
What happened to Mok Jin Woo?
What?
Are you serious?
Did you lose him?
I have the evidence. We just
have to find him again.
Let's go.
My gosh.
What? That teddy bear...
You hid it here?
Yes.
Thank you, Yeon Ho.
Thank you, Yeon Sook.
But...
why do you think Mok Jin Woo was so
obsessed with this fountain pen?
And why do you think he
didn't kill me right away?
If he killed me,
no one would've ever found this pen.
Do you think this fountain pen...
meant something special to him?
(National Institute of
Scientific Investigation)
Is that the result?
Yes, the results are here.
The bloodstains match with...
Yoon Da Young and Nam Ju Hee's DNA.
We also have Mok Jin Woo's
DNA and fingerprints.
That jerk.
What else?
What about the victims from 30 years ago?
It's been too long.
You know we can't charge
him with anything...
because the statute of limitations
have already expired.
We had no evidence when we had a suspect.
Now, we have the evidence but no suspect.
Where is this jerk hiding?
(Do not enter, Under investigation)
(Bridal Mask)
These are the numbers of people I killed.
I may be limping right now,
but not a single person could
fight me during the Vietnam War.
I should've killed more of
those dirty Vietnamese jerks.
Jin Woo.
We have to get rid of...
all dirty people.
Dirty things.
Mom.
Did you die...
because you were dirty too?
You guys...
failed to catch the Bridal Mask.
You invaders,
the gangsters who trampled
over this territory.
(Murders by Mok Jin Woo
in the Hwayang District)
Mok Jin Woo mentioned this
during the Jung Ho Young Case.
You should focus on what happened
before rather than afterwards.
Focus on his identity.
Then I'm sure it'll lead you
to where the suspects headed.
If he meant what he said,
Mok Jin Woo is sure to
go after females again.
He won't stop committing murders.
The reason he killed elders while
volunteering medical service...
was a passive way to reduce
any potential risk factors.
Hold on. Then do you mean to
say he'll commit more murders?
When he was released from
the station last time,
he was bold enough to kill
another female right after.
According to Yeon Ho, Mok Jin Woo...
is bound to go after a female
that reminds him of his mother.
Like he did in the past,
he'll move by foot.
Only this time, the location will
be somewhere easier to find.
The victims that Mok Jin
Woo normally goes after...
are usually found in the downtown area.
Then is it possible he could commit
a murder in a different town?
No. He'll still be in Hwayang.
It's hard to break a habit.
Just like how he returned
to the crime scene,
he won't be able to leave this town
where he committed the crimes.
He has to be somewhere near by.
We need to know where his
next destination will be.
That way, we'll be able
to wait for him there.
(Haein River, Playground)
Yoon Da Young was killed by Haein River,
Nam Ju Hee was killed at a playground...
and Son Bo Mi at a park near her apartment.
(Hwayang Police Station Jurisdiction Map)
Where could Mok Jin Woo have
initially met all his victims?
The place where he first met them?
In the past, he killed his victims
at the same place he abducted them.
But he couldn't have done that in Hwayang.
It's more developed and
there are more CCTVs.
If we know the victims' last whereabouts,
I'm sure we can find where
they crossed paths.
The bar that Yoon Da
Young worked at is here.
This is the clothing store that
Nam Ju Hee went to with friends.
The restaurant Son Bo Mi dined in is here.
This is it. This is his hunting ground.
The crime scenes were all
near Hwayang University.
The suspect has shown up.
What? Where?
He's near the park.
What is this?
But...
why do you think...
Mok Jin Woo was so persistent
in finding that fountain pen?
And why do you think he
didn't kill me right away?
If he killed me,
no one would've ever found this pen.
Do you think this fountain pen
meant something special to him?
Just like Corporal Park did to me,
I'll have to take away from him
what he cherishes the most.
Professor Shin.
Park Kwang Ho's daughter.
(Tunnel)
Yeon Ho. Where are you? Are you all right?
There are still so many that
must be punished in this world.
It's all because you
went after Mok Jin Woo.
Thanks to you, we were
able to catch the culprit.
Thank you and forgive me.
You deserve to die, you scum!
We would like to express
our sincere apologies.
You're going back?
I think I've done my job here.
I'm really going this time.