Griffin?
You believe she plans to sell the serum.
- Absolutely.
- Vanessa, we cannot let her do that.
Promise me you will get my
journal off this island.
You're the one who gives it to Brooke.
I am begging you, please, don't do this.
- I helped you.
- Yes, you did.
But he left me to die.
H.G.! H.G.!
- Is that true?
- He lied to your face.
- How can you ever trust him again?
- All this craziness,
it's too much. It's time
for me to go home.
Goodbye, H.G.
Adam? Who's at the door?
Griffin?
What did you do to me?
You're going through withdrawal.
Make it stop.
Take him down to the lab.
Achilles' heel returns.
- He's my brother.
- He tried to kill you...
And vice versa. I can't keep score.
Can you make it stop?
I can give you a maintenance dose
that'll help reduce the symptoms.
The question is, why should I?
Because we're family.
Damn it, Griffin.
You need to rest. We'll see
how you feel in a few hours.
Okay.
Are you going to help him?
Maybe. I want to monitor
his symptoms first.
It's Griffin.
I'm in.
Did she suspect anything?
She doesn't trust me,
but she didn't turn me away.
How are you feeling?
Mmph. I've been better.
Didn't have to exaggerate much.
- Hang in there.
- You have to
find the serum...
All of it... and destroy it.
It's too dangerous.
I understand.
I have to go now.
I'll call when I can.
If you help him, he'll
only betray you again.
What do you suggest I do?
He is my brother, and he's in pain.
Kill him.
That'll stop the pain.
I'll even do it for you.
Watch him. If he gets any
worse, you let me know.
And if he tries anything,
then kill him.
- Synced and corrected by medvidecek007 -
- www.addic7ed.com -
So, we're moving the
moon rocks to Gallery 3
- to make room for the space shuttle.
- Okay.
It's good to see you. It's been forever.
It's been two weeks.
A phone call would've
been nice... A text...
Anything. You practically disappeared.
I'm sorry, Leon. I must've
gotten carried away.
Into the glamorous world
of Vanessa Anders,
- or with your actor boyfriend?
- A little of both.
I knew it was that guy.
- It's always a guy.
- Well, that's over now.
Things got a little too intense,
but let's not talk about that.
I've been a really bad friend,
and I'm really sorry.
- Will you forgive me?
- We've all been there.
I'm just glad you're back.
Me too.
I forgot how exciting moon rocks can be.
Right?
I'll be right back.
Okay, Carl, what are you doing here?
I was instructed to keep an eye on you.
How are you feeling?
Like my skin is on fire.
This injection should
help stabilize you.
- What is it?
- The serum...
Just a small dose.
Just enough to help you
with withdrawal symptoms.
Mmph.
Has that Richard Knox fellow arrived?
Richard Knox?
Richard Knox, the venture capitalist?
- What are you doing with him?
- Don't worry about it.
Oh, didn't she tell you?
Your sister has big
plans for my magic DNA.
She's going to sell me
to the highest bidder.
Is that true? You're selling the serum?
We don't have Vanessa Anders' money.
Don't we deserve to salvage
something from all this?
Yes, Griffin, if I'm going
to be stuck in this time,
I'm going to do it as a rich man.
- What do you care about money?
- Enough. You need to rest.
You should feel better in a few hours.
I'll tell you all about it then.
May I help you?
H.G., what are you doing here?
I know that you called
Vanessa about Carl.
Don't blame her. It was my idea.
I needed to know that you were safe.
- John is still out there.
- I can handle myself just fine.
Selfishly, it was for
my own peace of mind.
And you had to come here
and tell me this in person?
Another selfish move on my behalf.
How are you?
Jane, I hate how we left things.
It's time for my break.
Why don't we go outside?
As you can see, the patient
has become septic.
He has a high fever, some swelling,
and even some mental deterioration.
He volunteered for this?
He let himself contract a fatal disease?
- Who does this?
- A brave individual
helping push the boundaries
of science, Mr. Knox.
And well-paid, I trust.
And just like that,
I've eradicated a disease
once considered deadly.
For the fourth time, I might add.
Remarkable.
How are you manipulating the DNA?
It's an offshoot of my father's work
combined with my own research.
This is my father's journal.
He left me his findings.
Your father's work with
the DOD back in the '80s.
It was
shut down before it was realized.
Now Brooke and I have
been continuing it.
No side effects of note?
Perhaps two worth mentioning.
Number one, the serum enhances
the subject's strength
approximately 600%. And two,
it's highly addictive.
You've created a Superman.
We prefer to call them "super soldiers."
You think there's a military
application for the drug?
During wartime, you're
gonna want these guys
on the front lines. Each has
the strength of six men,
significantly reducing the number
of soldiers needed on the ground.
They're resistant to disease
and chemical weapons, and...
They're easy to control.
All we need is the
funding to perfect it.
Who else knows about this?
Just you,
as of right now.
And you didn't want to take this
to the Department of Defense?
I've learned from my father's mistakes.
Mm.
I take it your test trials
wouldn't survive an ethics board.
Richard, that's why we called on you.
I know that discretion
is where you thrive.
I want to move on this right
away, before word gets out.
I can set up a meeting
tonight of investors.
- Are you prepared for that?
- Sure.
Just tell us where and when.
And you name again?
Stevenson...
Dr. Stevenson.
Well, doctors,
let me make a few phone calls.
I know I shouldn't
have come, but I just...
Wanted to know how you're doing.
I'm good.
I've really missed you.
I missed you, too, but...
What more can we do?
I mean, think about it.
What's gonna happen to us?
No matter how you write this story,
it always ends with you
returning to 1893,
where you belong. You
have to write your books.
You have to live your life,
and I should just get on with mine.
It's the only ending for us.
It's for the best.
I suppose so.
I should get back to work.
Goodbye, H.G.
- Ooh. God.
- Oh, I am so sorry.
Thank you.
I should've been looking. I'm so...
Get him in.
No!
They took him!
Hurry!
Who are you?
- What is the meaning of this?
- I'm sure you're
really confused right now,
but I'm gonna ask the questions,
- if you don't mind.
- Well, I do mind, actually.
- Where am I?
- Someplace private,
so we can talk without interruptions.
- Let's start with your name.
- I have nothing to tell you.
Well, my name is Agent Danielle Forbes,
and I work for the United
States Department of Defense.
Now, let's start with, how'd
you get to New York City,
how long have you been here,
and what are you doing here?
- None of which is your business.
- Wrong. My job is
to protect this country
from dangerous people.
Why do you believe that I'm dangerous?
Guys, thanks for helping out with this,
but I think I need to
question him alone.
I'll meet you back at the field office.
They're from the New York division.
They're not aware of
why I'm really here.
Which is...?
I'm from DC, and while
I do work for the DOD,
I'm an astrophysicist.
- While I wish I knew what that was...
- How disappointing.
I was hoping I wouldn't have
to explain that to H.G. Wells.
Well, that was easy.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't insult me, Mr. Wells.
I've put a lot on the line coming here.
Let's stop playing games.
What do you say?
- Try to sit up.
- Yeah.
I feel a little better. Thank you.
It's only temporary.
The serum has proved
extremely addictive.
- I'll try to wean you off of it slowly.
- Let's go!
Be back in a few hours.
So, how much money do you
think this serum will fetch?
Enough for all of us.
Knox is known for his overseas tales.
You don't care if the serum
goes to Russia or North Korea?
They have deeper pockets.
True. This could be huge.
John, congratulations,
you really are adapting
well to modern times.
We need to get going. Please
see my brother back to his room.
You mean my cell?
- You don't have to lock me up, Brooke.
- Yes, she does.
So, you refuse to admit it.
Why would I admit to
something so preposterous?
As an astrophysicist with the DOD,
it is my job to track
unexplained anomalies.
Recently, my department picked up
on a large energy source in New York.
It had a geographical signature
we've never seen before
with a structure that seemed
to pierce both space and time.
It sort of reminded me of a black hole.
- Does any of this sound familiar?
- It sounds ridiculous.
Perhaps you should
recalibrate your instruments.
That's what my colleagues said.
Well, perhaps you should listen to them.
I did, and I got the same results.
So I developed software that
mapped the fluctuations.
Multiple signatures across Manhattan,
another on an island
on the coast of Maine,
and one more in London.
I started to figure out the pattern...
The strength of the energy signature
tells me how long ago it was formed.
Based on the active rate of
energy decay, I dated them.
Manhattan is 2017,
Maine is 1980,
and London is 1893.
Do you know who lived in London in 1893?
Many people.
Including H.G. Wells,
but I'm sure that's just a coincidence.
I believe that these anomalies
pose a danger to space and time.
I need to understand what's going on.
- They're all gone.
- Okay.
I've deactivated her security system.
Great. Watch the door. Let us
know if anyone shows up.
Griffin, this is Cameron.
He's a cyber specialist.
- How you doing?
- He's on my payroll.
- Where's H.G.?
- He ran into some trouble.
Carl's on his way to get him right now.
Okay. The lab is downstairs.
We should hurry.
The only thing that's gonna get
you out of this is the truth.
I demand that you untie me.
I have to be somewhere.
Where? What's going on?
- Tell me and I might let you go.
- There's no time.
This would've been a lot easier
if you had just trusted me.
Draw your gun slowly...
And put it on the ground.
Jane?
Jane, you shouldn't be here.
I'm a Federal Agent.
You're making a big mistake.
Since when do Federal
Agents kidnap citizens?
This is official government business.
Really? Because this all
looks really shady to me.
Untie him.
Let's get out of here.
- How long is this gonna take you?
- Depends on
how sophisticated her security is.
I'll know in a bit.
- Is that the serum?
- Yes.
Are you okay?
I will be. Let's just get rid of it.
Are there any other computer
terminals in the house?
Brooke's research is on her laptop.
You'll need to wipe that, too.
I don't see it.
She must've taken it with her.
Damn it.
We need that laptop.
How did you know I was here?
Carl and I followed you.
Who was that woman?
She was a DOD Agent. She knows who I am.
The government knows?
It's Vanessa.
- Vanessa?
- Brooke is on her way to a meeting
with a venture capitalist
named Richard Knox.
He's the investor we've
been looking for.
- All right, what do I do now?
- Brooke took her laptop
with her to the meeting with Knox.
We're destroying everything at
the lab, but we need her laptop
because it contains all her research.
Where is this meeting taking place?
I'll text you the address.
Now, I have a way we
can remotely destroy
- everything on her computer.
- And how do I do that?
- I'll put Cameron on now.
- I've created an app
that can remotely
delete Brooke's laptop,
but I need you to download
it to your phone.
I'll send it to your phone, Jane.
What do we do after it's downloaded?
If you can get close
enough to Brooke's laptop,
I can do the rest on my end.
I'm texting you the address now.
Be careful.
Why does John care about Project Utopia?
- He was against it.
- Or he needed to control it.
John has always been
about power and prestige.
He wasn't just a doctor in 1893.
He was the chief surgeon.
You don't have to do this.
I know.
It's not far.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
William, I want you to stay in
the lobby and make sure we don't
- have any interruptions.
- Yes, Ma'am.
- Dr. Monroe.
- Mr. Knox.
Dr. Stevenson.
I have assembled some
very excited investors.
And we are very excited to meet them.
And I hope you're ready.
There's only one shot with these people.
We're more than ready.
Your confidence is inspiring.
Follow me.
- How do we know this is everything?
- I know my sister.
She keeps everything
contained in one place.
I have to find my father's journal.
I saw it earlier.
It has to be down here somewhere.
What?
Thank you.
I've ruined my life, Vanessa.
It's over for me, but it doesn't
have to be over for you.
- It's not over for you, Griffin.
- Everything I wanted...
My career, a life with you...
... there's no coming back from this.
How do we get inside?
There must be another entrance.
Carl, if you go that way,
I'll go around back.
I'm coming with you.
This way.
The staircase.
Knox's office is on the fourth floor.
Don't move.
Stop!
- Jane, you all right?
- Yeah.
Did you follow us?
Yes.
Now, care to explain what's going on?
It took five shots to stop that man.
Somebody better start
explaining this real quick.
You were right about me.
I am H.G. Wells, and I
traveled here from 1893.
And my time machine and I have
made an absolute mess of things,
and we're trying to fix it.
1980... The island in Maine...
Do you know what
happened on that island?
Yes, I do. It was a DOD research program
- Genetic engineering.
- Yes, but it went horribly wrong.
And a deadly drug was
brought back to this time,
and we have to stop it.
- How do we do that?
- By stopping the people who have it.
They're on the fourth
floor of this building.
Well, then, let's do it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we live in uncertain times...
ISIS, global terrorism,
even our own country is
divided against itself.
The world has become a powder keg,
and some days it seems like the match
could come from anywhere at nay second.
It's no longer a question of if there's
going to be another world war,
but when, and how bad it will be.
It's in our nature to
tear each other apart.
So now, more than ever,
safety is important,
strength is important.
We have better guns, bigger
bombs, chemical weapons,
but they're not making us any safer.
In fact, they're making our soldiers
more vulnerable than ever.
Warfare has evolved.
Our world has evolved...
but...
Human beings have not...
Until now.
Humanity is about to take
its next step forward.
This is Project Utopia.
Human enhancement...
It's no longer just a theory.
See for yourselves.
Increased strength...
The strength of six men.
Enhanced endurance and stamina.
Immunity to most known
bacteria and viral infections.
Rapid healing.
This way.
Tonight I am offering
you the opportunity...
And now it just needs to
log on to Brooke's computer.
The strength of six men? Please.
I've been involved with
Enhancement therapy for years.
This defies all current findings.
You're correct. It does.
What I'm saying, Dr. Monroe, is,
this sounds a lot like
your father talking.
And we know how his work went nowhere.
Perhaps a demonstration is in order.
Adam,
a simple handshake for Mr. Stillman.
Go ahead, shake his hand.
- Stop! Stop!
- Okay.
- You're breaking it.
- Adam, relax. Let him go.
- Aah.
- I think the point has been made.
This is not a trick.
Project Utopia is real.
Now, the serum does
have its side effects.
But with the right program
of maintenance doses,
we can use those effects
to make the subjects subservient.
Take Adam, for instance.
Would anyone care to
see what else he can do?
Any requests?
Is it working?
I installed the virus on her laptop,
but it's still too far
away to initiate the wipe.
- Well, how close does it need to be?
- I don't know.
Jane.
Imagine soldiers who
can withstand firearms
and biochemical weapons,
who don't need to rest or recover,
who don't experience
concussion or death.
Now, the serum...
... will experience fear or doubt.
This is all part of the
package that I can offer you.
Now, shall we talk
about your investment?
Brooke.
Is there something wrong?
I'm not sure.
What the devil is going on?
No.
No, they're wiping it.
_
- What the hell is this?
- It must be Wells.
- He must be in the building.
- What are you talking about?
You have a security breach.
They're trying to steal
my research right now.
We got to go.
No. They're in the...
They're in the lab, as well.
They'll destroy everything.
Look, I'll have to get back
to you when I figure out
what's going on. We have to
get to the lab. Where
are you going, John?
John?
Come on, hurry.
- Where's Jane?
- I don't know.
Hurry up! Hey, over there!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where's your friend?
I don't know.
Oh, God.
You all right?
I'm fine.
Go find her.
Are you sure?
I'll be back.
What are you doing here?
You seem frightened.
You've cornered me.
What do you expect?
Oh. Well, an explanation would be nice.
After everything he did to you,
after he lied to you...
... how can you still trust him?
- Don't do this.
- Where is he?
This is not about H.G. or me.
This is about the serum.
You need to stop.
- I know you're mad at me.
- "Mad"?
No, I'm... I'm not mad.
I'm gonna tear you apart.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine, I'm fine. Are you all right?
- Did he hurt you?
- I'm fine. He didn't get to me.
- We have to warn Vanessa.
- Right.
Were you able to wipe Brooke's laptop?
Yes, but you have to get
out of the townhouse.
- Brooke is on her way over.
- We're leaving now.
- Are we good here?
- All finished.
Good. Let's go.
We have to leave. They're
on their way back.
- I can't find the journal.
- Where else could it be?
I'll keep looking. You go.
Get out of here.
I'll be right behind you.
No. I'll help.
You should go.
Griffin.
Go.
Go. Get out of here.
Oh, God, she's really bleeding.
Take her somewhere safe.
- I'm going after Brooke.
- I'll make sure she gets help.
Come on.
Brooke.
I should've just let you
die the first time.
Where's the journal?
I don't know.
Liar.
It's the only thing you have left.
It's the only reason you came back.
What are you gonna do,
burn the place down?
Fitting, isn't it?
Wait.
Okay, you win.
Goodbye, Griffin.
Get out of my way.
No.
Utopia doesn't exist, Wells.
It never did, and it never will.
Wells, get the journal!
No!
Don't!
No, no, no, no!
No!
No. No.
No, no, no.
Wells, go!
Now!
I'm so sorry, Vanessa.
Griffin died to destroy the serum.
Yes. Project Utopia is no more.
And Brooke and John?
They're still out there.
But we will find them.
I want this to be over.
It's time for this to be over.
Yes.
The three-alarm fire
ripped through this townhouse
behind me earlier tonight,
spreading rapidly and
threatening nearby residences.
So far, we can confirm that
Griffin Monroe died in the fire.
Mr. Monroe was running for the
28th District's Senate spot
and was widely considered a shoo-in,
but saw a steady drop in
polls in recent months.
His campaign office de...
Let me help you with that.
You know this isn't over.
We can recreate the serum.
You can't be serious?
All we need is your blood and your DNA.
Everything else can be replicated.
Don't sell me a dog.
John, this is...
This is just a setback.
No, no, no, no, no.
This is over.
- I'm not a rich woman.
- I don't care.
There are plenty of
other ways to make money.
And I'm not playing your
little games anymore.
Your way failed,
so now we do things my way...
And we start by destroying Wells.
Do you understand?
- Do you understand?!
- Yes. Yes, of course.
Then we're clear.
Project Utopia is over.
Yeah. It's over.
Good.
It's unbelievable.
I'm putting my trust in you,
showing you this,
telling you the truth.
Who would I tell?
Who would believe me?
The DOD cut my budget
because they thought my
theories were a waste of time.
You're not tempted to run back,
try and prove your theories?
The DOD would not know what
to do with this information.
How's your wound?
I'll live.
So, aren't you worried?
About what?
You destroyed Project Utopia
and restored the time line,
but what about next time?
As long as the time machine exists,
don't you risk doing
this again, or worse?
Yes. There's a matter
of unfinished business.
I have to stop John.
I'll help you stop him.
Forgive my suspicions, but...
Why would you help me?
There are some of us out there
who believe in your Utopia.
Good does exist in this world.
Mm. One doubts.
One shouldn't.
So predictable.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
- Save your breath.
- Please.
You tried to sedate me
and take my blood without my permission.
I thought you were smarter than that.
What will you do?
Oh, don't you worry about that.
Just go to sleep.
When I wake...
Darling, you won't be waking up.
Vanessa's upstairs.
Oh, yes.
Thank you for helping me today.
I know how difficult it was for you.
Jane, I never meant for you
to be surrounded by so much danger.
I know.
And I know I said I didn't want to be
a part of all of this, but...
I can't help but think
that maybe I was wrong for walking away.
Maybe I'm supposed to be here.
Surrounded by death and destruction?
To help you stop all this
death and destruction.
It's a question of destiny.
There's only one real way we'll know
my purpose in all of this...
And that's to stay.
And when it's all over?
You'll leave,
and it'll break my heart...
... but I'll pick up the
pieces and move on...
And so will you.
Whether we want to or not?
Yes,
whether we want to or not.
Hello?
Good evening.
- John?
- Oh, if it isn't
Romeo himself,
back together again with
his Juliet... How romantic.
- Is Brooke with you?
- In a sense.
I don't think you have to worry
about Project Utopia anymore.
You killed her?
And you're next, H.G.
One last chat, you and me, old friend.
I'm coming for you,
and soon, this will all be over.
- Synced and corrected by medvidecek007 -
- www.addic7ed.com -