Alfredo Bini presents
absurd TOTO,
human TOTO
crazy TOTO
sweet TOTO
In a story
THE LARGE AND SMALL BIRDS
Narrated by PIER PAOLO PASOLINI
with the innocent, the sagacious one
DAVOLI NINETTO
Found in the streets of the entire
world, the other actors
In the sad running
In the happy running...
LUIGI SCACCIANOCE architect
DANILO DONATI prepared
NINO BARAGLI mounted and overcame
ENNIO MORRICONE musicó
BERNARDINE MARIO and TONINO DELLI COLLI,
photographers
FERNANDO FRANCHI organized
SERGIO CITTI, the philosopher, helper
A small groupe wandered
by the fields, the towns and the ways
Producer risking his position:
Director risking the reputation:
Where goes the humanity? Bof!
Extracted from an interview of MAO with
Mr. Edgard Snow.
With the moon nothing is caught.
Who said it to you? Why?
the fish is gotten sleepy. It is
necessary to wait for the high tide.
Does that depend on what, this high tide?
Have you seen the sweepings
that leaves the sea on the sand?
On what depends that?
the moon exerts a gravity force...
... with which the water raises
Dad, mom has nice new teeth
My, I know what it cost me
But these are not authentic teeth, like
those before.
They are teeth of teeth! And she is
crazy about them
She hides them in the drawer
so that grandpa does not rob them.
To intention...Have you thrown
the DDT in the stable?
- No, I forgot.
- Shit. What a idiot!
It's not my fault .
This morning, crazy Josefina
showed her chest on the balcony...
Pity you have not seen it...
I do't care about that! I
think about the stable.
The flies eat them poor cows
alive.
Hell, a little conscience needed.
didn't stopped to complain
all the night, poor cows.
Cinzano and a limonade.
How much?
270.
Dad, there'll be nothing with her
Go, drink your lemonade.
Do you want to learn?
Please
Count the steps, if not,
you will never learn.
Go... one, two, three...
... and four.
Boys, the bus!
Listen a little...
Tell me a thing...in the morning you comb
yourself with the vacuum cleaner?
Street BENITO TEAR. Unemployed
I have something to do...Do you remember?
I have already said it.
It's good...It's good...
- What happened?
- A marriage?
Who it was?
Martucci, that had a tic in the
mouth, and his woman.
I will see my friend.
I return in 5 minutes.
Hurry up
Street ANTONIO MANGIAPASTA. Street
cleaner
Street LILLO STRAPPALENZOLA.
left the house in 12 years
You seem an airplane!
What you want to do here?
we were proving the 600
with a friend mine...
To see what speed it's able to do
My friend was scared to death.
Sure, you are half crazy
For what these dresses?
Today is celebration of Maria's daughters
we give a celebration to the asylum.
That suits you well.
You come to dance with me, Sunday?
- No!
- Take your course.
If you come with the 600...
I cannot, my friend has taken
it to the mechanic...
for a revision. Later I will appear
this way...
You won't see me coming!
Do you know they have seen you with
my school friend ?
I met her by chance. We chattered...
Yes, chattered...In the meadow.
She said it to me.
What meadow? We were there
just because...
... it was late, her father would
have beat her.
Do you understand?
Good bye, Nino.
What happened?
Get out of here, I don't want
to see you anymore!
Do you give me a little kiss?
The police officer said that
they were covered with vomit.
He was on the bed...
... She, fallen down in the entrance,
with the hand stretched towards the door.
Dad, seems to me that the life is
worth of nothing.
Sure it is
Death is so strong.
When one dies,
all what he had to do...
...was already done.
Dad, always I think about the death
Because I say myself: What makes one to
die?
Little by little, breathing,
making "Ah"
... and why later already stops?
Suddenly, doesn't make ...
... "ah" any more...
He does't notice
that he can't make "Ah"?
How to find out when one is alive
or dead?
Ask that another one!
Am I already dead?
I would like to be a parrot
I would live 200 or 300 years.
A rich man died....
... left a lot of money here
the richest one of the cementery
Think a little, how angry he must be.
Happy poor man, cause only few know
that he has died.
They write: "So-and-so died.
and another one"
When a rich one dies, he pays his
debt to the life.
He pays for what the life gave him.
poor man, also pay, but the life has
not given him anything.
What makes the poor man?
Passes from death to another death.
Where you go, friends?
What you have said?
I have not said anything
Then I have hallucinations
May I accompany you?
But who is that?
Dad, watch who was it: A crow!
THE WAY BEGIN And The TRIP THIS ALREADY
FINISHED
Doesn't that annoy you,
if I come with you?
No, it will be a pleasure,
am I right, Dad?
Then we are going to be
part of the way together...
Can you tell me where you go?
We go there
But where?... It is a little misty.
Where is "there"?
Then... there.
- I believe that I will guess it.
- Guess.
You will make photographs of the
boy, which will work at FIAT.
- No. - No.
We already  made them last week.
Then, you go to your godfather,
to the baptism of his son
Shit. Is that
fortune tellers affluent... Eh?
already we were yesterday in the
baptism
Are you a prophet, or who?
Yes, a prophet...If you want...
a prophet or a cop, one of this.
Let me think... I will see...
You go to the chiromancer..
... to ask medicine for Ninetto...
...who has the tapeworm.
I burns, i burns...
Forgive me, if I insist,
you do not want to tell me where you go?
I already said to you, there.
But where? On right side, left, straight?
There, further.
Never had seen you here
From where you come? Who you are?
I come from a distant spot...
My country is called Ideology,
I live in the capital...
City of the Future, street Karl Marx,
the number 70 times 7.
And we, in the quarter
of the Trash.
- Street Died of Hunger.
- number 23.
Under the Mount of the Sewer...
Famous anywhere in the world by the
martyrdom of San Analfabeto
... That is...that is,hell...
sun begins to tighten.
cooks my brain.
Why we do not stop in this
meadow to make the siesta?
Go, bastard
I go with you
I have two corns,
the small one on the finger,
and the big one on the toe,
which makes me suffer the hell.
You lucky one
Lucky with a horn! With this
migraine?
Yes, lucky
Why "lucky"?
For you can freely walk by the
highways...
...the suburbs of the city,
...Morning you can enter
the taverns with the young workers...
... to kiss girls in costume of angel,
speaking about life and death, with
the first words that leave your lips
While me...
But you do not have parents,
family... nothing?
My parents are Mister Doubt and
Mistress Conscience
Me, however, I am Ninetto...
... Son of the Toto Innocent and the
Grace Simple.
Your innocence, simplicity and grace
...they are religious
The religion is the force
that moves you ahead
throughout a way that nobody knows
No matter who you are, farmers
or workers.
A way that leads you far
To where all the ways of the world meet
As for religion, I would like
to tell you a history
Go ahead, please.
That will relieve us of this long
walk under the sun.
I can?
The history that I am going to
tell...
...is the strange history
of large and small birds.
We are in the year 1200.
All coincidence with people of
our days...
... is not casual.
You who do not want to know,
...who live like assassins
among the clouds,
... that you live like bandits in the
wind and crazy people in the sky.
You, who have your laws outside the
laws
Who spend your days in a world
that stand on the foot of the world
Who you don't know the work and celebrate
the slaughters of the powerful ones
We simply can see you through God
Because our eyes already are accustomed
our lives
... and are not able to recognize that...
... that you live in the desert or the
forest
We must understand you
For you are the ones who give faith of
Christ to the faithfuls
with your joy, your pure force
which is faith.
For that reason, I order you, Fray
Cicillo and to you Fray Ninetto
... to continue the preaching to the
birds
and I say to you in addition, that it is
right that you begin...
... with the two very different species:
the hawks, which are powerful
and the sparrows, which are humble
- For the glory of the Lord
- Amen
What are you doin' with this sling?
Throw it and recites "Ave Maria"
These saints, they have their claims...
Does it seem easy to you to speak
with the birds?
I am speaking too
Keep your mouth shut.
You think that I also go for a saint?
Yes, saint... With that face you have.
What? What's wrong with my face?
Brother Cicillo , we can not
make a thing:
we will say to San Francisco...
... that the deal is not made,
so better look for others.
I am going to slap you.
Or even better ...
... we go away to house of those
farmers where one eats so well.
We will eat a lot, sleep a lot and
after a month we return and say to him:
"Brother Francisco, the birds need
you"
No, we are not saint
We are human men
But, thanks to the Lord, we have
a brain.
So, fray Cicillo and
fray Ninetto...
... start up...
... to spread gospel among
birds.
Now, what is their language?
Everything depends on you, fray
Ciccillo. And God helps you.
You know all and I cannot
help you. I am good for nothing.
I am going to pray
Lord, give me the power to remain in
this place...
... where I have put my knees...
... until it has sanctified all
the hawks on this rock...
... and on the world, according to the
will of San Francisco.
Look, what is that?
Maybe he is a mowering monk!
You come to spy for Christ?
Eh! Let's strip him off.
Think that they let me be a monk?
I eat very little.
Eh! Leave him in peace!
Let him go away.
Have you finished?
Here is fray Margarita
Let him go! Leave him in peace!
Shame on you, you do not know that he
is annoying santo.
A saint! A saint!
Yes... Saint Chicorey.
Help, fray Cicillo!
Damn it, how the grass grows
They are right when they call us
mowering monks.
Only the chicory.
And also a little ivy... you see?
...and the nettles...
Come... I am going to take nettles.
Tsss... be quiet... go away...
Summer comes.
The season of the cicadas, the nettles...
The lunches on the grass,
the tomatos.
Autumn comes.
Winter comes.
It never snowed as much as this year
And the beautiful season comes again.
That is enough, I am sick of it.
I want to leave.
What am I doing here? I serve for
nothing.
I want to speak with people, not
with the birds...
I pass the day watching the flies
I am sick of it.
I return at home.
I return to my mother.
But Fray Cicillo could not answer him.
... Because after on year of
silence...
...his throat got rusted.
Tell me brother, I am not right?
For what reason I must be here?
Night and day, day and night
Summer and winter, with sun and rain...
To waste my existence? Why?
To deserve the Paradise, my son!
Would it bother you if I rest
a little at your feet?
The Paradise...
I have found!
Lord...
...thank you, I have found it
Hawks, come, listen...
Come, listen...
Who are you?
What do you want?
Two creatures of God...
... that they want to speak with you...
... Creatures of God
God?
Who is God?
creator of all the creatures
For what reason God created us
Why you have created
your children?
Then, each one of us is God.
do not exaggerate, one gives you
an idea
and at once you become arrogant.
And the God: what he wants of
us?
Love...
Love!
good, good
Hell, what a hard work. But we succeeded.
I am really pleased, by you not by me.
But how have you done it?
Help yourself and God will help you.
the saints, with their faith could do
everything
But I am a man, Nino, a human man...
Do you know what I did?
I said myself: "Fray Cicillo...
... Think, use your brain."
With the help of faith one believes,
with the help of science one sure knows.
Luckily you have your head.
San Francisco was right to choose you.
He will be happy when
we tell him all that.
But now we would amuse a little...
... we deserve it.
Let us play the organ in the church
to thank the Lord.
and then to house of the farmer to eat
cheese and cream cheese
Their cellars are full of wine.
and we will request a new habit. These
are used and stink out.
It doesn't seem to you, fray Cicillo?
Who serves the Lord is always
in a hurry.
you are only a parasite
With the hawks, it is done.
and now it's turn of the sparrows.
Let us go
In agreement, fray Cicci, I have
not said anything,
Where we are going to turn the sparrows?
There
Hope it is not as hard as with
the hawks, my Lord.
But I swear again...
... I will not move an inch of
my poor knees...
... Until the sparrows have been
sanctified
Let's hope that they are not...
... hard-headed
What he's doing here,
sister Gramigna?
I don't know, sister Misery,
and you, sister Avarizia?
Perhaps to satisfy his corporal needs,
sister Gramigna.
Eh, little monk comes here.
- What do you want?
- But what is he doing?
He must stay at least a year here
in one year the figs will grow
on a fig tree,
But to a friar...What grows on him?
The beard?
would not speak thus, madam.
That man is a saint.
Do you believe it,
sister Gramigna?
Who knows it, sister Misery?
What do you say, sister Avarizia(Grifagna)?
we will see, sister Misery,
if he gets wet when it rains.
Now he is turning the sparrows...
... But in the other towns
he made many miracles.
In Frattochie he turned the water
into wine because they were drunk.
In Zagarolo, turned the water into
wine because they desired to drink
In Sgurgola, he did not change a thing,
because all was well.
Watermelon... sweet watermelon!
Cream cheese! Cream cheese!
God, give me a patience.
Grace is returned to you.
blessed you are, fray Cicillo.
I would be glad
If he save me from the wasps!
Lady Fortune,
touch me with your magical stick.
You really want it?
a minute of patience, Mister...
... forgive me what I am going to do
Like you in the Temple of Jerusalem:
When it is necessary to go. Go ahead!
Let's go Ninetto, it's time to end
this!
It is, I am ready
Let's thank to the Lord
- How, none comes?
- Keep silent yourself.
They don't answer. They don't answer.
They don't answer.
These dirty beasts!
science, yes, science.
It is the faith which you need,
not science.
It seems that I have not had
sufficient faith
Lord, I have not had enough faith
Can I play a little hopscotch?
Why you look at me?
just a little bit...
It's two years I did not play.
Go ahead, my son, go.
... play, play.
What can I say?
A little disaster. We must begin again
I have found!
I found it. At Easter,
everything will be done.
The sparrows do not speak
while chirping.
How stupid I have been!
How stupid!
Lord, I hope that it works
this time.
How, therefore, the sparrows
spoke between them?
What have learned fray
Ciccillo...
... after his long
meditations?
It is simple: the sparrows
communicated while hopping.
Sparrows, come, listen...
Come, listen...
Who  are you? What do you want?
We are servants of the Lord, we
bring good news to you.
We awaited it since so long time!
Really? Did you await it?
Yes, specially in winter...
when not one grain was in the field
to eat.
A moment! What good news are
you waiting?
news of a lot of wheat and millit.
How exhausting is to bring
good news!
well? What news you
brought to us?
The Lent
What? What do you say?
The Lent... But not until
the death of hunger!
The sacrifice... the love...
Oh Lord, the love!
Love...
Love!
LOVE!
My Lord Almighty...
... what joy of seeing the sun.
And what joy of seeing water....
... Thus, the dirty man can wash himself.
Are you pleasured fray Cicillo...
Eh?
Blessed be the Lord, for this
donkey...
... for all these sheep...
-... and this shepherd.
- Amen
Blessed be the Lord...
... for this blessed world
... where all can live
-... even those that cannot.
- Amen
Blessed is the fresh grass,
the nettle, the chicory
... And God glorifie those who eat it.
And curs those who die in the sin....
... that displeases me to see these
horrible funerals
Blessed the Lord, for the
kindness that lives in the hearts
and because everything what He gives us
is rose and flowers
Why? Why?... that?
Brother Francisco,
we converted the hawks
and the hawks, in their way
praise to the Lord
and soon, brother Francisco,
We also converted the sparrows.
and the sparrows, in their way
although with pain, praise to the Lord.
But between those two species ...
...they are massacred.
What to do so that the sparrows
and hawks will...
...  be put in agreement among
them?
"What to do?" Everything can be
done with the help of the Lord.
- What it means?
you must go to
teach them...
... everything what they have not
understood you must explain them
- What?
It is necessary to change this world,
fray Ciccillo
This is what you don't understand
One day a man with blue eyes come
and say:
"We know that justice is progressive...
...according to slow progress of society,...
"... we know conscience in its
imperfection wakes up...
"... and infiltrate in the world,
shouting and yeling..
"... about his inequality
that afflicts the humanity."
This inequality between classes, nations...
... isn't the most serious threats
against peace?
Go and start again for
the glory of the Lord.
Come, Nine, we start again
Come, my son, don't
discouraged yourself.
Courage, let us go... With joy...
If you are in doubts or distracted,
Let's recal that the Crow
is an intellectual of lefts...
... before the
death of Palmiro Togliatti.
With permission.
DISCHARGE PROHIBITED
Dad, what will I do now?
attack(load)!
PRIVATE PROPERTY
"You're with me in the car
that arrives to town with the sun"
How is called the man who went
on the moon?...Gagarin?
Dad, I don't know
Look... the moon seems so far...
... goes to sleep and ...
and they try to conquer him...
You see?... It seems to me that
I am only one to see.
I also see it
I know, I know.
Bastards, hooligans!
You all come here!
One day I will shoot you!
It is not a public toilet here.
I cannot see here all the day ...
...as they make dirt on my field,
I have young daughters.
Bring them here!
these things are against law,
disgusting!
I will denunciate you.
What?... we fertilized the soil,
you would have to pay to us.
Take that fertilizer and take it
to your house with you
You are joking or serious?
I don't joke, take that
nastiness because if not...
If not... What?!
Because if not, I will shoot you.
Severa, my riffle!
... I am going to kill you
The joke isn't bad... Eh?
but now, I have enough of it.
Severina, the riffle!
Shoot, shoot!
For a handspan of soil
the war burst...
Now you escape, you are scared...
Eh?
Help, mamma!
Papa... Run!
<And our cartridges were full of butts
full of butts...>
It was necessary to act like Gandhi!
To shake your handkerchief...
... put your excrement at it,
and take it away
Thus you would leave him there like
a clown, the owner on his property.
It's time to end the wars
We must fight united for peace
Is anobody in this house?
You are all dead? Revive!
By the body of Baco...
Where you hide yourselves, died of
hunger?
What devils put you up there?
You do not answer?
Ssssh... Silence!
Speak quietly, good morning
Speak quietly not to wake up the
children.
- At this hour?
- Come in.
Sleep!, it still is the night, sleep!
Quickly, the fact...either the money
or I put the subject
into the hands of lawyers and
morning happens what must happen.
Bravo, Dad!
Look, Mr Marcello. As they are
the things in here
we do not have anything
You must be a little patient
We already gave you the pig,
and before that the
wool mattresses and carpets.
But this time? We do not
have anything to give you.
But who eats nests of swallows?
The Chinese! The Chinese!
Sleep, it is still the night. Sleep.
It is a shack. But with the land
around...
... we will recover our money.
No, not the house!
Have a mercy! Not the house, not the
house!
I say the house! Exactly the house!
Bravo, Dad!
Sleep, it is still the night. Sleep!
4 days I keep the children
in the bed without eating...
... 4 days I say to them that
it is a night.
Because if they rise they will
want to eat.
What will I give them?
Madam, don't say that to me
I can do nothing
Ask Blessed Virgin, instead of me
"Bussines is bussines". Is it clear?
Ninetto, we go
Do you want to say anything?
If you must say me something
speak face to face.
Anyway I am right
I do not say: "You have done badly"
I simply say...
..."Attention, a larger fish
could eat you one day"
The nest is on the table.
Dear Sirs, excuse us...
would you to help us to push
this Cadillac that refuses to go?
Now you will say to me:
"You are 4, all powerful."
Well... No! Well... No.
This one here... Said with pardon...
... Have hemorroides.
The other, you see by yourself...
Madam, it is not necessary
to explains anything
As for the third one...
... Mister was in the manicurist
this morning,...
... and do not want to soil the hands
accordingly, but quickly.
- one, two ,three... - Go ahead, Nino.
- but you too, dad.
The hand of the Lord is
necessary to make it run.
Anyway, thanks for your cooperation
I present myself:
Pasquale Beautiful Ear.
Ciro "Koko"
non convinced
Urganda the Stranger
Hannibal the Vegetarian.
and these, my little children...
Kienpaga-Pagapoco
... Called "Ki"
and Colgadodelcuello, called "Col".
Have you calluses?
Don't speak to me about it, my good negro!
You know who walks
with the naked feet...
... on ardent coals to burn the Spirit of
the Death?
They do that in your village, I believe...
As for me, it is worse!
I have miraculous remedy
do not listen to him, this remedy-there,
... he use it only for himself.
He keeps the cream jealously .
and leave it only to the one who
can afford it.
Well, I can in some way...
... If it is not much sacrifice
How much...?
5 thousands
People!... People!
How much people!
HOW ROME HAS RUINED THE WORLD
We are in 2000 and continue
making these things
Poor ones!
What happened?
I know it.
Dad, run, run!
Quickly, child is on the way
To your age... you would not have to see
these things.
Hot water!... Hot water!
For what?
I know for what. I have 18
children
Hot water!
Hot water boys!
Another mouth but... Live Maria!
It is a girl! Live Jesus!
A big applause to mama!
Now you do not go to the first Church
that you find...
... and you leave her there... Eh?
How will you call her?
Nobody wanted her...
... nobody waited for her
and she wanted to come.
Yes!... You are Welcome(Benvenuta) !
Yes, yes, Welcome, Welcome!
Why do you laugh?
Do you know what there is in this box?
Read!
to read? It's 40 years that I
do not read
Look here, stupid
What is written on that small box?
- imposible to solve it.
- Read!
I do not understand anything
Aaantic Contraceptive ....
They sold to you...
the out-of-date contraceptive
pomade...
... poor men
What poor men? And you laugh
at misfortunes of the others?
What it means this pomada...
anti... anti-no-se-que-tiva?
you don't know it? How many
children do you have?
18... why?
If you had taken this medicine...
... you would have had less
children.
And why less children?
More than half of the beings...
... who forms this evolved
humanity...
... is in state of a
wretched and intolerable suffering.
They suffer literally from hunger...
it will be worse, they will have more
children...
....and the hunger grows.
You do not believe?
Use your wives with more understanding.
Carmen,Carmen...
... You single one, you are not
enough to me, I need other three...
I will make a good pasta
and satisfy all three...
I am not satisfied
and you must understand it.
I hold my head high, like all
The twilight of the great hopes...
These poor trickers are the first
ones who stay in the shadow...
...in company of Rossellini and
Brecht,...
While the workers, in this twilight...
...they go every day ahead
... ahead
The ideologies passed from mode,
But here is one who continues
speaking...
... no one knows of what.
... to the men who go, not
knowing where.
CONGRESS OF DENTISTS BY DANTE
the women finds professor Otto
Volanten extraordinary.
But in fact he have removed all his
material...
... from whole studies on
Dante by english professor F.Efamen
... published in Oxford at the end of
1933.
Fred Efame is, among others, the
author of the novel...
"Under pants covered with blood in
Scotland Yard"
... That is the source of all James
Bond
Please... What do you wish?
we have come to speak with Mr. engineer
Please, this way.
Be good....
and learn, Nino.
But Dad, one bite and he will
swallow me.
You never understand anything
This is a custom of affluent people
What do you find strange there?
But what I have with these peoples?
Your father have something, therefore
you have something too.
Good morning, Mister
Excuse me if I can not rise, but...
You have come to make your duty, I
suppose.
Today it is the 25th,...
end of the contract, if I am not
mistaken.
It was my intention.
I will explain you.
With all the snow that has fallen...
... two hectares of cabbages has frozen
I did not gain a lira there.
And this imbecile here...
... all Sundays...
... took the tractor to go to celebration.
But as he is not good driver...
...On sunday crashed the 600.
and I had to pay it... And money...
and in addition I have another 18
children, you know
and only one could help me...
... This idiot... have chosen
the occupation
... He became a monk.
Engineer...
... this beast...
I am a businessman...
... I make only businesses and I
take care of my businesses.
Give me my money...
... or you will go in prison.
It is simple!
Have you seen?
Your mama and you don't believe
... that I am always in troubles.
Excuse me, engineer
I had prepared a bunch
of roses for Madam,
... but I forgot it in the house
I will bring it another time.
Ignoramus!
Every day the same
Nothing will be able to change them.
Where you go?
Does a race starts now?
Where you go? Where you go?
Run!
Go!
Run, run, Dad, go!
Wait!
I go!
Hurry up Dad, run, it will leave!
Patience...
We will take the next one.
It's a great type that crow
I did not believe it, but you
have seen
He was right, speaking badly
of those comedians
I like only that bearded one
that made "Ta, ta, ta"
It seemed to me that it
is only a part of bird.
Dad... When I go to the factory...
... with the first strike I return
to the villa of the Engineer...
... and I kill all the dogs.
This will teach him,
you will come too... Eh?
Sure! I will come, and...
"Ta,ta,ta there..."
Let's go, Nine.
I do not ask you to where you go.
the end will come,
and I, who so many things know...
... this will never know.
The way begins...
... and the trip is already
finished.
What are you doing?
I watch the swallows.
What is your name?
Luna
100 meters beyond...
Help!
Ay,ay... my belly! What could it be?
My God
It is not possible
It starts again.
I have belly-ache
It makes glu, glu, glu...
I do not hold it! I return immediately.
Eh, brunette!
Ah, Luna, Luna, what effect you
have on me!
Let's go there. It is a
good place.
They cut the grass.
That smells so good.
What you have eaten at noon?
To tell the truth, I have still
not had breakfast.
I have eaten in house of my sister
Roasted with spinach
As I had said to you,
do you feel this perfume?
Ah, It is better now! Come,
Let's go.
What a pain!
I have a scouring.
It's truth Dad...
What we  have eaten today?
I can't hold it!
Wait here, I return
immediately.
Where you go, cretino, come here!
Luna,
Are you deaf?
Luna, I am his son!
I suspected it.
You have face of altar boy
Hell, what a beautiful tits!
More beautiful than those of
"Maria of the balcony"
What that?
countrywoman that we visited my
friends and I
But she is not young
Have a fat belly like that...
...a thin leg and the other enormous one.
In addition do not have nose
Have two eyes, mouth, but the nose...
Did I make you laugh?
I like people like you
With your father also I
laughed much.
Everything all right, doctor?
Eeeeeh.....You!
Professors eat the piquant sauce...
... said  Giorgio
Pasquali.
But who that eats and
digests...
,.. also become a little
professor.
Already I feel better
Let's go.
And don't eat any more these filths,...
... it makes you sick again.
Eh, whatever problems could be
spoken with regard to the whores
And the crow continued speaking,
speaking,speaking,...
God, Family, Fatherland...
How much I could dispute them.
Today, it's not worth it...
perhaps already I am finished.
My hour have come
My words fall in the emptiness
Mr. Toto, I'm not complaining...
...to see disappearing
all that I defended.
Another will come to take my torch
...and will hold it up high.
Then I will cry over my fate.
It is human, when one feels that
no longer will count
Master...do you allow me?
to say something to this
idiot?
- I will eat it
- What?
- We will eat it
If we won't eat it,
another one will.
In addition I believe that
already it's getting mad
You are right... I think so...
It'll teach him not to put feet
into another ones. How we will eat him?
Like the old ones...
... we clear the skin and ate
the fruit
It is so good, the small fish.
< It is completed thus.
It continues thus >