Let's see what you have there...
This picture looks scary...
Everyone ready?
Let's see it.
Do you believe in karma?
Does a snake's mother
drink from a well?
Go drink that well water.
I'm sorry you can't go in.
I'm a relative.
You'll have to help us then.
Grannie doesn't trust me.
Grannie, what are you doing here?
I've been looking everywhere for you.
I've got to go now
or I won't be on time.
Grannie, where are you going?
Grannie!
Wait!
So you're back!
Yes.
Hello Pong.
Let me help you.
Thanks.
Hey Pong what's that
powder outside? It stinks.
It's some herbal powder.
With all the rain lots
of poisonous snakes came out.
Safety first!
Has anyone moved out lately?
We've got a few free rooms.
Oh, I forgot to give you this.
I got you some chocolate.
- For me?
- Yes
I'm very grateful.
Make sure you eat all of them.
I will.
Just wait for the lift, please.
Thank you.
Shit, this is just no good.
I think that song
we played yesterday was OK.
Like the rehearsal.
Guys
Someone's complained
about loud music in your room.
So can't you make
it a little quieter?
Come on let's go.
Fuck him!
When we rehearse it has to be noisy!
Yeah, how can we make it quieter?
I'm not deaf and dumb.
The phone's broken again.
We can't get online either.
There's the security guard.
Hey guard what's wrong with the phone?
Did you call the repairman yet?
I've called already and
he's coming this evening.
What floor, please?
7 please.
Hold on.
Thanks.
What kind of costume is that?
An angel.
Wait please!
Hi, Nho?
I'm on the way.
I forgot something.
Yes ma'am.
Hey guys, didn't it say in the
news there were more than this?
That's right but
they've all gone away.
These are all I could catch.
These snakes look dangerous.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
They've come out because of the rain.
Hey Wit, be careful.
Well, will you go with me?
You've been here already.
Where to?
What are you doing here?
Someone told me that loads
of people got snakebites here.
Not one.
The only thing is someone
complained their phone is broken.
Could you please check?
You can go I don't
need you for anything.
What's going on Nin.
Somebody's said there were
a lot of snakebites here.
And they need help quickly.
In our building?
I put herbs all around the building already.
There shouldn't be any problems.
Believe me for you own good.
Because if what was in the news is true
it could be really dangerous here.
You better just leave.
Dead.
Dead already.
Grannie Pai.
Pai, who's dead?
Hey Pong, you and Chit stay here.
Never mind Grannie.
Pong, take care of everything here.
Yes I'll click the lift button for you.
Is it true, sir?
Yes it's true, cobras.
Go on, check.
Cobras?
He went out already.
He said that
he went to see his friend.
I'll have to put up with it.
Three to nothing.
You've lost again.
Today did you beat me or not?
So are you cheating?
Cheat what?
You lose all the time and say
that I've cheated...
I don't need to play you anymore.
Hey Thang come play with me.
Hey you can take my turn.
Can you go look at him?
You go, you lost!
You go look at him!
You order me around all the time.
Hey Thang what are you doing?
This is in real time. Why didn't you tell me?
Just let me see a little bit.
Get away! Get away! Get away!
I made that hole so let me look!
Move it!
What the fuck!
Aren't you gonna play?
Both of you,
you're only interested in sex!
Nobody answered.
That's the last room.
So it must be the right one.
You'd better take me up there.
Of course, follow me.
Where are you going?
I know the room.
Let me go too.
That's not necessary.
There's someone here to see you anyway.
I want to go too.
Go on, go talk to him.
How are you?
Why do you care?
Can't we speak in a civilized manner?
So when I was in a good
mood where were you?
- I don't understand.
- It's not that you don't understand!
It's because you never have the feeling.
Hey, you said it wouldn't be long.
Where's Chai?
Hold on a minute, he went upstairs.
Wait again?
Run! Run! Run!
Run! Run!
Officer Pong!
What's the matter, what happened?
Where's Chai.
On the third floor.
What's going on up there?
I'm not sure. I heard some
noise so I went to look.
Nin, Wit, you two stay down here!
Don't go anywhere!
I'm going too.
No you're not!
This is my apartment you know?
What are we waiting for? Let's go!
Wit stay here! Don't move!
Hurry up!
Chai!
Stop!
Don't come in here.
What's going on Chai?
Hurry up Nin!
Fast!
Hey Chai! Chai!
Chai!
Help me!
Be calm! Be calm!
Please help me!
Help me!
- Be calm!
- Help me please!
Hold on I'll be back!
Help me!
Please help me!
Chai!
- Be strong
- Open your eyes, Chai!
Be strong! Hold on!
Chai how do you feel?
Chai!
Wake up!
Hurry!
Is there anyone else there?
Come on hurry up!
How come you look so shocked?
Run! Run!
Wit!
Please!
Look at Chai first!
Chai!
Hey! Chai! Chai!
Mom!
- Get out of the way!
- I haven't seen anything yet!
Come on let me look!
What are you doing?
Shit!
I'm sick of this.
You want it again,
Hia?
I itch, Hia.
Hia.
What's that noise?
What the fuck is going on?
What is it?
What's wrong?
- Joop!
- Aek!
Joop!
Hey Tang!
It's a snake!
Aek!
Tang, Tang, where are you?
Snake!
It won't close!
Mae!
What the fuck is that?
Help me! Help me!
Mae! Help me! Help me!
Help me!
Choop go!
I'm your friend!
Can't you let me
get in there too?
Oh, was that the house in
the news for the snakes?
Oh yeah, it's just near here!
Sure thing. I'll get over there,
get the story and send it to you fast!
Choop! Choop!
Help me!
Help me! Help me!
You've gotta help me and my friend!
Hey you!
Choop.
Help me!
Run! Fast!
Chai!
Choop! Choop!
Don't pass out, wake up!
Why did you press up?
Don't you want to go down?
We can't go down!
Why not?
There's nothing but snakes down there.
Do you want to die?
Nong, don't sleep!
Go take care of your friend!
Wake up!
Wit?
Don't sleep, Choop!
Wake up! Wake up!
Nho... The whole building is full of snakes!
Is there anyone wounded?
Yes, someone's been bitten behind me.
Take a picture?
Don't pass out! Wake up!
- You want me to take a picture?
- I told you to wake up!
Did you get a chance to get any news?
Don't you want to be a reporter?
I just escaped with my life.
Hurry up! Send us a report!
Choop, wake up!
Wake up!
Choop!
Wit!
Brother!
- Brother
- Is that you Wit?
Hurry up!
Help me! Help me!
Hold my hand!
Brother, I'll help!
Hey help my friend!
My friend's been bitten by the snake!
Move!
Where?
On his leg.
Open your eyes!
Choop be strong, hold on!
Take your shirt off fast!
If we don't get him to
a hospital soon he won't make it!
Anybody got a phone?
I've got one!
I hope you're OK!
No signal!
Anyone got another one?
Shit!
Help me!
Snakes! Snakes!
The whole room is full of them!
It's not one room,
it's every room on every floor!
They're coming up from downstairs!
Where did they come from?
How come you let them get up here!
You know one of my
friends is dead already!
So what do you want to do now?
Don't move!
We'd better find a
way to get upstairs.
Mae!
I don't think I can make it.
Be strong. Come on.
Pai, we discussed this before didn't we?
Don't bother, let me do it my way!
No way!
If it's like this then who
would want to rent a room?
How does he feel now?
It looks pretty bad.
Grannie.
It's just karma.
You have to beg God for forgiveness.
We can't keep making
mistakes again and again.
Pornapha.
Don't you understand?
Your daughter has bad karma.
I've made enough merit already.
I can take care of my kid.
You'd better look after yourself first.
Grannie, enough of this crap.
I can manage it myself.
Nin, are you keeping some secret from me?
It's not important.
Sorry, Chook.
Where are you going?
Chai, the serum's in my bag.
I'll go get it.
I'll go with you.
Then what about here?
Let's look for something
to block the way in.
Come on!
That should do the trick.
I'll get Chai's bag.
Then I'm coming, maybe I can help.
Hey Wit, no need to come.
Stay here.
No need to go.
The you're leaving me here?
No matter what when we leave
here we're all going together.
OK, brother.
Come on.
Just hang in there.
It hurts, it hurts so much.
Mae, I can't make it, I can't make it.
Just hang in there.
Just cut my leg off, Mae.
Are you nuts?
There's only way I can survive
You've gotta cut it off.
No way! I won't do it!
Please!
No!
- Like this I'm gonna die.
- No
You have to help me.
I won't do it!
- You've gotta cut it off, cut it off!
- I'm not gonna do it!
- I won't do it!
- You have to help me!
You have to help me.
Help me, Mae!
So tell me, where will you move to?
I'm not sure yet.
I'm worried about you.
You should spend more
time worrying about your job.
I can take care of myself.
So I'm wrong?
The way I work, eh Nin?
No you're not wrong.
Your job just takes up all our time!
Never mind,
because the only thing
I need you can't give me!
Nin, you've changed too much!
I haven't changed at all!
Yes ma'am.
Where are you?
I'm in the building.
So how come you haven't
sent the pictures yet?
There's snakes.
Are you scared of snakes or getting fired?
No matter what you have to send them!
Hey, it looks worse than we thought!
Look at this!
Call the cops!
Not yet.
Wait until she sends some more.
What are you staring at?
Work!
The gods!
They have to be pissed off!
We have to pray for mercy.
Please have mercy.
This is bullshit, begging to snake gods!
They have them for sure.
I already made a spirit house.
If you have no respect for them,
you'll die a horrible death.
Do you mean the spirit house
outside the building?
You've all lost your minds!
This is 2010!
Dad's here!
Dad!
Where have you been?
Run! Fast!
Snakes!
The snakes are marching in!
Come on! Move it!
Fast!
What's going on?
Nothing.
Come on move! Fast!
Hurry up!
Come on!
Blood!
Mae!
The lift's here!
Come on let's get out of here!
Get in! Get the baby in there!
Come on Grannie!
The door won't close!
Come on close!
Lift, damn you close!
Close!
Oh man, close!
Why won't it close!
Can't you do something?
Open it!
Don't leave me!
Don't leave me! Open it!
Open it! Open it!
Don't leave me!
Hello? Hello, is that the Police?
Are you there?
Hello, hello!
Oh shit!
Where the hell are they?
Wit!
What are you doing?
We'd better get out of here!
What's going on?
It looks like there's
someone in that room.
Who's that?
Wit, don't!
Wit!
Grannie!
I'm glad everyone's still here.
Where's my brother?
Where are you going?
I'm gonna find my brother?
Wait a minute!
Help my baby a snake's bitten her!
Gif, my baby!
Gif!
Gif, my child!
How is she Doctor?
Her leg's bitten!
Gif!
Gif! Gif!
How many bottles of
serum have you got?
Two.
Then give my kid one, please.
Please!
Hold it! If you give that kid one then
what about the rest?
How can you talk like that?
Can't you see my kid's dying!
Relax, everybody!
I'll be right be back!
Doctor, Doctor, where are you going?
You didn't give my kid a shot yet!
Right now your kid's still OK.
I'll be right be back!
Doctor please give her
the shot first and then go!
Please give the shot first!
Just relax, I'll be right back!
Give the shot first!
Can't you give my kid the shot first?
Can't you help us first?
Take it easy! Take it easy!
Where are you going give her the shot first!
Can't you just relax?
You're all selfish!
You know you're all making bad karma!
Don't you know it will all
come back on you.
Stop!
Give my daughter the shot
or else I'll shoot you!
Drop the gun!
Don't do anything rash!
Stop!
I beg you!
Mon, don't!
Mon, don't do it, drop the gun!
Mon, drop the gun!
Good, kill yourself then!
Then we won't waste the serum!
I'm sorry!
I had to do it for my baby!
I told you give my kid the shot now!
I'll kill you all one by one!
Help!
Pai!
It may hurt a bit
but after she'll be OK.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Help!
Help! Wit! Help!
Don't open it, Doctor!
Get out of the way!
Help!
I'll shoot you for sure!
You're gonna shoot me?
Help!
Help! Wit! Help!
Where's Wit?
Are you OK? Mon?
What's with you?
Hey, you've been bitten.
What's wrong? Let me see it!
Doctor, have you got any more serum?
There's only one more.
Do you need another?
Hey, how can you say that?
You see, my wife looks terrible!
Mon!
Doctor, give her a shot! Please!
Just a second.
Hurry up, Doctor!
Just a second. Take it easy!
Hey! Where are you going?
Come back!
Hey you! Stop!
Don't follow me!
Give me that serum!
Don't touch me!
- Let go of me!
- Give it to me!
Let go!
What the fuck have you done?
It's not my fault!
All of you stop staring at me!
You all look just like me anyway!
You don't realize what you're doing!
I'm not wrong!
Don't come near me!
Hold it!
Don't touch me!
Move it!
Fast... fast!
Mon!
Mon, hang in there!
Mom, don't die!
What's with you?
Can't you do anything?
Are you a Doctor or not? Do something.
Get out of my way!
You!
It's not true!
It's not true, Mon!
Hang in there!
Don't worry, dear.
Mom!
Mon! Mon!
I'm not staying here!
I'm going downstairs!
Are you crazy!
Haven't you seen it?
There's only snakes down there.
Don't you care about your kid?
We've got to get away
from here or we'll die!
So you want down there then?
Don't cry!
This is my kid and I'll protect her myself!
Don't worry darling!
There got to be a way for
us to get out of here.
There must be a way.
You!
Don't worry darling.
Where did you see Wit?
In there.
Wit!
Don't go up there!
Stop!
Wit!
Don't go up there!
- Wit
- Don't go up there!
I'm telling you don't go up there!
Wit!
I told you don't go!
- Don't go!
- Wit!
Don't go!
What the hell is going on here!
Is this what you're hiding from me?
What's the meaning of this, Grannie?
Wit!
Get it off!
Don't! Wit!
Wit!
Wit! Don't!
Are you just going to leave me here?
No matter what we have
to leave here together.
Yes sir.
What the fuck happened?
I don't know! It's not my fault!
I didn't do it!
You didn't do it, eh?
Let go! Let go!
It's not Grannie's fault!
You've gotta believe us!
Believe you?
My brother's dead!
How can I believe you?
I didn't do it!
Stop!
Don't go!
Grannie!
Nin!
Let go of me!
Come on!
No! No!
No!
Please forgive all of us!
Grannie!
Nin!
What's...
Hey, what's that over there?
What's over there?
What's that?
You! You!
Where are you?
Mom!
Mom, relax!
Grannie!
I can't.
It's payback time for the snakes!
They're not going to forgive us.
A tattoo is the
only protection from fate!
It's karma!
No!
No matter what,
you can never escape your karma!
Mom!
Nin!
Tell me, how do you
think you survived?
From a miracle or from luck?
Do you believe in the law of Karma?
I believe that if I had used my life
to help anyone else stay alive
then I'd still be alive now.
So in the future, what will you do?
I'll develop the serum professionally
so that it helps those
who may need it.
Thank you very much.
You've made the correct decision.
No problem.
I only want to do what's best.
Just one life can save many lives,
that's invaluable.
You can never decide
who should survive or
who's good or who's bad.
But you have to decide
what you think is right.
Only that will help you find
the correct path to follow.
Darling.
Nin.
How many bottles of serum have you got left?
Two.
How could the Doctor survive?
This is unbelievable.
So how do all of you know
this is a true story?
It's true.
It's not important.
We can sell this news anyway.
Right?