These are gonna be great
Can you imagine if your wife
ever found these?
Crys, come on
Put down the camera
This is such good shit
Come on, Crys
Crys, come on...
What do I look like to you,
a '"Playboy'" bunny?
You're not gonna come and
take pictures...
and let me take the picture
I'm gonna fill up the whole scrapbook
Peisha, this is the most fun
Peisha!
Oh, shit
Fuck
Crys
Ow! Fuck!
Crys, Crys
What's wrong with him?
Shit
What's wrong, Crys? What happened?
Jesus Christ
Don't look at us, it was his shit
Are you sure he's dead?
Take the girls to the club
I got to call his people
I can't believe I voted for this asshole
It's not about winning ball games
It's about emotion
You know what that is?
Emotion?
The Lakers are not the Lakers
without Rambis
He was the spark, the inspiration
He was white
I didn't say that
But did it ever occur to you that's why
they let him go?
Rambis left on his own
Is that a brew in that bag?
On his own?
Yeah, on his own, read the paper
Oh, come on!
Christ, Moony, we're on duty...
and that shit you're eating is
sixty percent grease
He's got one
Dillnick? I don't believe it
Miss? Excuse me, miss
You talking to me, Elvis?
Oh, shit
What kind of action you looking for?
I was kind of hoping you could tell me
Translation, he doesn't know
Now she's gonna stick her balloons
through the window
Magic fingers are twenty
Fifty puts the pig in the blanket
You want something oral,
see you dentist
Did you see what he was
wearing tonight?
He wasn't wearing that striped thing,
was he?
So, what?
Looking for something kinky?
Want to hear the chef's special?
No, I'm sure whatever you do will be fine
Hope you have lots of raincoats...
because I don't ride bareback anymore
We're meeting him at the Bowl?
Yeah, sounds like we better hurry
Nice jacket
Seersucker makes me hot
Just relax
Just let me take control
You'll love it, believe me
Stone
Come on, Moon, forget him
We got to meet Dill, Moon,
leave him alone
Ah, Jesus
Promotions are next week
He's speeding
Being a cop's like being a pitcher, Harry
To hit the strikes, you've got to...
Risk your balls, for what, Moon?
What is this?
This is initiative, I'm showing initiative
No, this is harassment
There is something very perverse
about you and this Stone
Perverse? Yeah, perverse
It wasn't his fault she left you
Yeah? Yeah
Bullshit!
Hollywood, this is seven-one
Dillnick is making a Redi-Whip delivery
to the parking lot at the Bowl
Can somebody take her off his hands?
Thanks
Tell them to take their time
Phil, can you get the champagne?
Have a staff member find his body
in the morning
Police can notify his wife
Washington wants full damage control
Understand?
Sure you can handle these girls?
It's my business
It's your business if you don't
Graham
This is out of our league, Jack
It's also out of our jurisdiction
Come on, we're in Beverly Hills
Nice suit
It's OK, it's OK
He's just picking up her and
her girlfriend
He's their lawyer
They don't look safe to drive
Get lost, pal
Getting strange
Be cool, now
What? I didn't say anything
Stone! Somebody's calling you
Stone!
What?! What, what, what?
Zara, come on!
What the hell are you doing?
You out of your mind?
Move over! I'm gonna drive
You said you were gonna...
You said you were gonna quit
I want a promotion, Moon,
not a goddamn suspension
He's running, Harry
Well, you shot at him!
He's dirty I know he's dirty!
I'm finally gonna nail his black ass
to the wall
If you have any drugs in your purse...
would you please just throw them
out the window?
I don't believe...
You know, I could be disbarred
for this shit
Leon!
Give me the purse...
Hold the girls and get some backup
Oh, Moon
Ah, Jesus
Stay put
Stone!
Move
Fuck
Well, it's about time
Now, look, I'm a lawyer, all right?
And this is a clear-cut case
of harassment
Now, for the past six months
this poor excuse for a police off...
Are you gentlemen gonna keep this
mad dog off me, or what?
Thank you
All right, look...
I don't know what the problem
you have with...
Jesus, what the hell have you
been eating?
Your ass, nigger
You called him the '"n'" word?
You left Dillnick with a car date
at the Hollywood Bowl...
fired your weapon without cause
at a private club...
participated in a high-speed car chase...
then you decked a black lawyer in front
of a hundred people...
and called him the '"n'" word?
I made the arrest
You made squat, Moony...
and I am sick and tired of your
street cowboy attitude...
and your racist bullshit
But let me try and get through to you,
Moony
There are those of us who can say
the '"n'" word...
and there are those of us who cannot
Now, I can say the '"n'" word
Nigger, nigger, nigger, nigger, nigger
See, I can say the damn word all I want...
but your can't
In fact, Moony, if I catch your
little perverse, bigoted...
bullshit mouth saying it again...
I'm going to personally tear you out
a new asshole
Is this going to affect my...
promotion evaluation?
Promotion?
You are suspended, Sergeant
Leave your piece and your shield
with Rinselle on the way out of here
Called him the '"n'" word and
want a promotion
Sorry, Moon
Did you do it?
Moon?
You doing OK?
You don't look so good
Thank you
What was this all about tonight?
Is he pimping for you now?
I don't deserve that, Moon
Neither does he
What were you doing?
I didn't tell you I finished night school
finally...
and I got my application into
Valley Arts College...
and I saved up all the tuition...
What?
I don't know why I keep forgetting
to drop this off
Every time I'm near your house,
it's not the right time
Jesus Christ!
Why do you have to keep doing that?
I need it For what?
Self-defense
From what?
Why do you carry a gun?
I'm a cop!
Yeah, well, I'm not
Do you still have the fishbowl?
Yeah
Can you just put this in there
with the others?
And, like, if something happens to me...
have them print it up
You know, like, sprinkle them
over Hollywood Boulevard like ashes
Coming? Yeah
Crys
Bye, Moon
Because I love you so
Come here, here you go
Come on now
That's yours, yeah, that's yours
OK, you can have some of that, too,
all right?
Hey, come here
Look at that
Come out of here
There you go
You want some of this?
Just a bit
There you go
Yeah, I know, glad to see you, too
Get out of here, will you?
I'm trying to give you stuff you like
Get out, what's the matter with you?
That's it, Chuck, you don't get any more
Well, maybe just a...
just a little more
Chuck!
What are you saying?
That's it? He's dead?
He will be without a new heart...
and the odds of finding a
B-positive donor...
Dr. Posner
Excuse me
He was a cop?
Yeah, vice
How the hell did he get in that kind
of condition?
Vice
Sad news for the State of California
and the nation
Senator James Marquand...
one of the most respected leaders
on Capitol Hill...
is dead at fifty four
Found by a staff member in his
Bel Air home this morning...
the author of the new anti-drug
legislation...
is believed to have died from
heart failure
The President described Marquand
as a true gentleman...
a brilliant statesman...
OK, which one of you guys said
the Hail Mary?
The donor's condition?
It was a car accident...
severe trauma to the head and
lower back...
severed brainstem
Otherwise, the guy's a cream puff
His form's in order?
We got him on file
He had it marked on his license
Anything medical?
This guy's squeaky clean about
everything but his occupation
Pusher? Close
Proctologist? Getting warmer
Don't tell me he's a lawyer
But don't sweat malpractice
He's too dead to sue
Shit, turn that down
I got it
OK, he's asleep, come on, come on
You sure he knows?
It's only been a few weeks
Yeah, the doctor told him yesterday
Everything, right?
Yeah, everything, now will you come on?
You got it on him?
It won't stand up
Well, them, prop it up
You sure he knows, Harry?
He knows, he knows
Harry?
One, two, three, four...
Can't get enough of you, babe...
Can't get enough of you...
Ooh, darling...
Can't get enough of you, babe...
Can't get enough of you...
All I want is you, babe...
Don't you know it's true?
What the fuck is this?
Oh, shit
He doesn't know
Moony, stop! Come back here! Mo...
Posner said he was gonna tell you,
Moon
We didn't know
Jack, what do you think you're doing
out of bed?
You put it in
Now you take it out!
Want to tell me where he had it?
I want you to exercise, Jack...
or you can throw these ten months
of rehab...
out the window, understand?
No drinking, no smoking, no fatty foods
No more roundups, no more drug busts...
no more asinine car chases
You're a desk sergeant now,
a career paper jock
You got it?
Yeah, I got it
I didn't want to take you back, Moony
Central made me
Just because we got the same
color heart...
don't go thinking we're blood
Hey, Moony, starting to walk with
a little rhythm
Funny
Hey, Moondog...
Nice tan, Moony
They say the heart's not the only new
equipment you got
You wish
Terri...
did you ever locate Crystal Gerrity?
She's the carrot top Detective Zara
was checking out
Detective Zara?
Yeah, Harry, she's a hooker, right?
Yeah
He said she'd picked up a couple of
speeding tickets out near Malibu
Right, about six months ago
The addresses she gave on both
citations were phony
Zip on the Peisha chick, too
They're out there, but nobody
knows where
Could you run it through the machine
for me again?
Well, anything's possible for a little
of your honey
You got a dirty mind
See you
Now, that was all Harry's idea, Jack
If he's gonna ride with you, you got to
get him to get rid of those stripes
Ever since that night at the Bowl
he thinks that that's his lucky jacket
Shit
Well, we got to go
Yeah, go
Later
Yeah, Harry
Let me see your shield
Come on
Looks nice
Looks real good on you
Thanks
Keep the change
Don't eat that
Clogs the arteries
It makes your breath stink
Listen, ass...
Trust me
Now, look, look
I wasn't even gonna say anything,
you know
I tried to give you a chance to get into
the groove...
and as bad as those Camels are...
I was more than willing to let a few of
those go by...
but when you start shoving this dog
meat into your face...
I'm sorry, I just have to step in
I have to do something, now put it down
Put it down
Moony, put it down
Didn't you listen to the doctor?
Don't you know what this shit does
to your heart?
Moony, look, you're looking very
stupid now
You are dancing with a cheeseburger
We can do this all day, OK?
But you look real silly...
dancing around with a cheeseburger
The only person that can see me is you
What's up with that guy?
You know, you can't get away from me
This is a very good-looking car
I mean, this is absolutely fabulous
Has it ever been washed?
It's weird, I know, it's very weird
I'm not even used to it myself
It's kind of like that out-of-body...
you know, astral-projection,
Shirley Maclaine thing
I mean, one minute...
I'm sitting in the front seat of my car,
and I'm dying
Next time I know... boom!
I'm standing in the operating room
looking at myself...
while they're pulling my heart out of me
I mean, it was like that...
What's the name of that movie?
Oh, this is very good, this is good
Going back and forth is good because
it stimulates the heart
It makes you a lot strong...
Are you listening to me?
You are listening to me?
Hey, wait a minute
You're ignoring me, aren't you?
Now, listen, I didn't want my heart in you...
any more than you wanted my heart
in you...
and if I knew that my heart was
gonna be...
inside a piece of racist scum like you...
I never would've donated it in the
first place
But that's OK, you know,
because life's a bitch...
and then you die, you know?
It's true, isn't it?
Hey...
but I didn't die! I was murdered!
I didn't get a real good look...
if it was a Cutlass Sierra or a...
but I did get a real good look
at the driver...
right before he ran me off the road
Hey, Moony, you OK?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine
Aren't you gonna... Wait a minute!
Aren't you gonna talk to me?
I thought you said you wanted to
be a detective, huh?
I thought you said you wanted
that gold shield?
Well, this is your opportunity, this is it
Now are you gonna talk to me,
or aren't you?
No!
I'm gonna prescribe a little medication,
Jack
Nothing serious
Just something to calm your nerves...
help the hallucinations
I take these every once in a while...
hoping my wife will disappear
But you mean that this is a normal thing?
Oh, sure it is
This could be perfectly normal
A psycho-chemical aberration
of some kind
We're just beginning to learn...
how transplants affect the human body
and mind
Take a couple of days off
You'll feel much better
Is that tranquilizer working yet?
Say yes, you want to wind up in
a mental institution?
Jack? Yes!
Yeah, it's working fine
It's OK
Jesus! Chuck!
Personally, I think that this racism
this refusal to acknowledge me...
stems from feelings of inadequacy
I mean, you look at me
What do you see?
Someone college-educated,
damn good-looking...
hung like a Shetland pony,
and you feel threatened
Am I hitting a nerve?
Come on, Chuck
Oh, I see, you can talk to the cat,
but you can't talk to me
Get out of the way, Shithead
Ohh! You can talk to me, thank you
Racial prejudice I can understand...
but ghost prejudice?
An entirely new concept
As a matter of fact...
I think you're breaking new ground
in this area
Hey! Close the door
I can't, the only thing I can move is you
Shit
It's hard to believe Crys could live
in a pigpen like this
How long was it for, huh?
A month or two?
Four
Four?
And she wasn't hooking when she was
living with me
Yeah, probably too busy cleaning, huh?
You won't go away, will you?
Well, best as I can figure,
I go where you go
As long as that heart's beating
we're attached
Which is why you won't be eating that
bacon, that chili, that...
Polish sausage?
Look, go to hell!
That's what I'm trying to avoid
Now, look, Moony, you don't have
to like me...
but you are gonna have to live with me
now, whatever problem you had with me
because of Crys...
leave it behind you because
you're gonna need me...
if you want to help me find...
Find her?
Yeah
What do you know?
Only what happened the night
I was killed
She have something to do with that?
Yeah, now, she and the other girl
Peisha...
they both work for this big-time gangster...
called himself John Graham
He dealt strictly to the upper classes
You know, drugs, girls...
Yeah, yeah, I know, Pimp to the stars
Sounds like your kind of client
Say, say, don't go there, all right?
I represent the girls, not their employers
Anyway, Crys called me from
the country club...
said she was having a little legal trouble...
and asked me to pick her up
You give all your clients that kind
of service?
Well, she was upset
Is that why you hit her?
I was upset
Oh, you were both upset
Yeah, we were both upset!
All right, Moony?
Why don't you wash your dishes here...
for crying out loud?
Why did you run from me?
What?
Come on, you're dead now
Well, Peisha was holding some crack
that she got...
I knew it! You knew what?
You lucky son of bitch!
If I'd have caught you...
You couldn't have caught my mother,
Moony
I probably got my heart attack from you.
Well, had I known, I would've surren...
Can ghosts get colds?
I'm allergic to cats
But you're dead
It's psychological
What's so funny?
A hypochondriac spook
What the fuck was all that about?
Now we're even
This guy who allegedly ran you
off the road...
Are you here or not here?
Yeah, I'm here
What was his name?
Teller, he was the muscle
you saw with the girls at the club
If he ran you off the road, they think
you know something
The legal problem Crys called you
about...
maybe it was drugs
I don't think so
It was something more,
something bigger
I tried to find out from the girls
but they wouldn't talk
At least not that night
I didn't make it to the next morning, so...
Yeah, it's just on the left here
Turn at the next corner
This is Century Luxury Villas
These things start at almost a mil, huh?
Yeah, so?
Fix your collar and try not to
act like a cop
Shit
How much were you pulling down
a year?
The mortgage on a place like this
has gotta be, what, six grand a month?
That's my lizard pot
He's got my lizard pot
Twelve times six, seventy-two?
Hey, you got my lizard pot!
With tax, you're looking at eighty-five
grand a year!
Hey, you got a pool!
He's got my lizard pot
He's got my cactus
Hey, that's my... where you going with...
This is a lot of money
Where are you going with my cactus?
An awful lot of money
What's going on here?
Well, it's open house
'"All furniture, household effects...
'"and objet d'art may be purchased'"
Oh, mama, no
No, I left you the house
I didn't tell you you could sell it
Well, what else is the old lady gonna do
with it?
Fuck you, too
It's sterling
Actually, I was more interested
in the picture
You can take all the pictures if you like
In fact, I'll pay you to get rid of this harem
My mother's a church-going woman,
so watch what you say
Hello, Mommy
When I think of all the in-and-out
that went on in here
Not one grandchild to show for it
Well, I was planning on settling down
He always said he was planning
on settling down
Does this hump pen look like he was
settling down to you?
Hump pen? This place has style
His idea of style was my idea
of obscenity
I want to unload everything to do with it
Yeah, but not at K-Mart prices
Do you know this woman?
Do I know you?
I'm a cop You look it
I told you to fix your collar
I'm trying to locate this girl...
Crys Gerrity
I was wondering, can I look through
your son's Rolodex?
You can have my son's Rolodex
What?
But don't ask me about his women
Have you seen her since
your son's accident?
A cop got his heart, you know?
He knows I know
His name is Moony
I know, yeah, so's mine
She cried almost as much as I did
at the funeral
Such a pretty girl
Held my hand most of the day
The last time I saw her was when
she came by here...
to pick up a few things
It was near Thanksgiving time, I think
Do you know where she was going?
She didn't say, she just drove off...
with that slick man in his red Ferrari
Yes, this is John Graham
Any messages?
Jackson who?
Moony
What's that? Is that a scratch there?
Can you buff that out, please?
And use the toothbrush on the wheels
If you want to get to Graham,
you gotta trust me
Listen, asshole, already I've been
insulted...
by the car park guy, the guy at the door
We're not leaving, Moony
Now, this may be fun to you,
but I'm damned if I'm gonna...
pop for another three-dollar tea bag
Will you keep it down, please?
No, if I don't hit the can soon...
Moony, the man is smart
That's why he has an answering service
stead of a direct line
Now, would you rather him
call you back at the police station...
or a place that makes him feel
more comfortable...
like the Beverly Palm Hotel?
Call for you, Mr. Moony
All right, remember
Howard Steadman is your best friend
Tip him a deuce
Two dollars
Tip him a deuce for the phone
Thank God nobody can see me
Jackson Moony
Jackson Moony, John Graham
Sorry to pull you away from the pool
on such a delicious day...
but I got your message on my service...
and I don't believe we've ever met
I'm from New York, actually
I'm here on business
Howard Steadman said that you had
a redhead named Crystal...
that you might be able to put me
in touch with
It's a impossibility
Can you fix me up tomorrow night?
Well, as you probably know,
Howard's in Yugoslavia...
working on his picture,
so it's impossible for me...
to cross-check your reference
Would it help if I mentioned...
his night of leather in Palm Springs?
Crys said they were into gymnastics
You must be very good friends
You're working tomorrow night
That's all we could find on him
No address, no priors
Name's probably phony
OK, thanks
This Graham's gonna be hard to find
Which is why you gotta keep your date
with her
You're dreaming!
The guy deals with high rollers
I can't afford lunch
Where am I gonna get that kind
of money?
Or class?
What the fuck's that supposed to mean?
You think I got no class, huh?
You think wearing an Italian suit
gives you class?
It gives you nothing, nothing
He see his doctor?
Yesterday
He said Posner gave him some
new medication
Doesn't seem to be working
Why don't you get off my back?
Just get off my back!
Go on, get the fuck off!
Better keep an eye on him
Christ! What is it with you? Jesus!
Let me know what he's up to
Shit
A bowling alley?
I didn't know you people did this
Yeah, and we swim, too
Now, look, just relax, all right?
We're just here to pick up a little
pocket change
You're with the owner
The what?
The owner, you think I got rich
defending hookers?
You know what the cash return is
on a pair of bowling shoes?
We're on our way back to the pin setters
Just... loosen up
Two drink minimum if you don't bowl
Yeah, that's right
There's a two drink minimum
There's nothing wrong with making
a little profit
Now say hello to Bubba
Ask him how his mother is
Order a couple of beers
Hello, Bubba, how's your mother?
She died last summer
Well, I'm a little behind
I'll take a couple of beers
Which way to the pin setters?
Stone!
Every one of these mothers is
a Black Panther hungry for white meat
I'm gonna wind up dish of the day
What are we doing here?
See that hole over there?
The one that looks like a duck?
Yeah
You feel a pipe in there? Yeah
All right, pull it out
Yeah, that's it
Jesus!
My emergency cash reserve
How much is in here?
Two hundred thousand dollars
And I'm the only guy who was ever able
to take it with him
Don't want your beers?
Have a beer
Yeah, maybe just one Yeah, one beer
Can I help you?
Hey, it's my brother Archimedes
You find what you were looking for
back there?
Nice guy, I left him the bar
A few balls, a couple of pins
Here it is
How do they know about my stash?
And maybe a hundred and fifty grand?
How did you know... 150?
I left $200,000...
It's supposed to be
two hundred thousand
Oh, I see, you steal from your
own brother
You own... you flesh...
You know, Ma said you was...
You know, if I wasn't dead, I'll...
Hit him one time for me, Moony,
would you, please?
Did you know that this is
extortion money?
That your brother was about to
be brought up...
on Federal charges when he died?
Yeah, slap him one time for me
Now, I can walk out of here
with this evidence...
Or I can walk out of here with
this evidence and you
It's your choice, Archimedes
Right
Hold it, hold it, hold it, wait
What?
Oh, shit!
Jesus!
Get him out of there!
That was the most stupid...
I'm sorry, just start... let's go!
Go, go, go!
You want to tell me what the hell
that was all about?
So I was talking to a friend of mine
the other day...
and I hate to drop names...
you know that, but I said, '"Bobby... '"
Well, that's Bobby DeNiro,
but that's beside the point
'"Bobby, the thing is this... '"
Listen, what time is it?
It's time for you to get your big, fat,
extra-crispy-bucket-o'-chicken...
two-liter-pepsi-cola-drinking ass
out of bed
That's what time it I, allez, allez!
We must exercise!
Come on, Jack, let's go!
And one, two, three, four!
Come on, Jack,
Your public is waiting
Public, my ass
Well, it'll be your ass if you don't
hurry up and get up
We have to go downtown,
we have to exercise...
we have to get into some suits
Get your black ass out of here, will you?
Black man!
'"Get your black ass out of here'"
I like that, get down, brother!
Give me five! All right!
There's five
Fuck off!
Shit! I never knew...
there were so many hills in Hollywood
Fuck off!
Come on, come on, look at me!
I'm running circles around you
And you're supposed to be a cop, huh?
Is this L.A.'s finest, huh?
I'm a cop! Yeah, yeah!
Oh, well!
Get the fuck out of here! Shit!
He bought an $80,000 Mercedes-Benz
with cash?
It's not the Jack Moony I know
I don't know what the hell he's doing
Whatever he's doing,
it's got to be illegal
Well, we better get ready
They're dropping Crys off at eight
Did she really like this stuff?
She never seemed to mind 'em on me
Oh, come on, Moony, look
We fooled around, all right?
She took some pictures
That was the end of it
It wasn't serious
I was a single guy, you heard my mother
Last thing I needed or wanted was
to be tied down
Hey, look, what you gotta face is
the fact that she left the old Jack Moony
See, this is not the same girl who was
on the street corner...
dating cops and eating cheeseburgers
She's a different woman now
Same job
Yeah, but didn't she ever tell you about
going to art school?
It was a pipe dream, you saw her stuff
Oh, and we're art critics now, huh?
You know, you see a kid fishing
in a mud puddle
Is that any reason to take away his pole?
People have dreams, Moony
They have ambitions
And when she tells you about
her dreams...
you gotta respect them, you gotta listen
I always listened
Yeah?
I listened
All right, all right
What's the name of her dog back home?
Henry
How many sisters does she have?
Two... Lisa and Joanie
What's her favorite movie?
'"Rambo'"
'"Rambo'"?
'"Pinocchio'"
And I knew all of that in the first half-hour
You see? That's why she left Ohio,
Moony
Nobody listened
Nobody took her seriously...
and you're wondering why she left you
I kept her off the streets
Yes, by wrapping her up so tight,
she couldn't move
You see, you want to keep everybody
in little boxes
You want to keep me in the ghetto
You want to keep Crys back at home
Even that knucklehead Wendt
And you tell me that you don't resent him
being your superior officer
Yeah, you can't, can you?
You see, we're all like the film
in the goldfish bowl at your home
You want to keep us all right there...
where you can see us, don't you?
You don't want to let it out to
be developed
You know how much that stuff costs
to process?
Hey, it costs to go to art school
It costs to be a lawyer
It costs to be a fucking detective
Some of us are willing
to pay the price, Moony
Hey, there's nothing
to be scared of, Moony
Nobody's out to get you
You don't have to be scared
that we're all gonna leave you behind
Would you like something from the bar?
Yeah, ask her first
What do you think?
A glass of wine
Wine list, a couple of Evians
The wine list and two Evians
The wine list
I didn't know you knew what Evian was
Bottled water
I'm learning
What are you doing?
Is this some kind of a setup?
What do you mean?
Are you gonna bust me?
For what?
Bein' beautiful?
Touche
Did you process any of my film?
Why?
I wondered
It's still in the goldfish bowl
Good
Nice suit
Yeah
Did you polish your fingernails?
Did I tell you I knew what a woman likes?
You can't afford that on a cop's salary
Oh, I, uh...
I came into some money
How?
Oh, shit, how?
Don't tell me it's an inheritance
No, she's too smart for that
Malpractice
Your heart surgery
Yeah, they stitched me up
with a sponge inside
Good
Judges like that one
So then you quit the force and started
buying Italian suits?
Right, yeah
I don't believe that
Yeah, neither do I
OK, maybe you better go and call Teller
That's dangerous
I don't want to
Lucky
How's Chuck?
He's fat
I would like to tempt you...
with the chef's specials
before you decide
For appetizer, we have a shitake
and mushroom...
on the salmon dim sum dumpling
in a red currant sauce
Salmon dumplings in currant sauce
Are you still puttin' bourbon in his milk?
No
We're both reformed men
That's too bad
There is also a special poached scallop
with taro...
over a bed of squid ink fettuccine
with a ginger root sauce
Do you remember your tablecloth?
Yeah
Well, I... I had it... I had it cleaned
and mended
You didn't have to do that
No, you... you remember
the armenian lady next door?
Mrs. Arkmanian
Yeah! Yeah
Well, she saw the, um, you know...
Embroidery?
Yeah, well, she said
that was really good.
Then a duck feet, dim-sum style this,
over a bed of arugula with
a spicy rice vinegar...
Is he serious? He's serious
And finally we have the...
egg roll with a...
s-s-shredd-ed-ed squid...
'"Squeed'"
Shred-ed-ed squid!
Eggplant...
fresh stalk fennel, salmon,
ground oysters...
Excuse me
What the hell do you think you're doing?
Back off! Back off?
Look, I did not make this kind
of investment...
to see you blowing it with that girl!
I am not blowin' it!
Listen, I thank you for helpin' me
find Crys...
I thank you for the car, for the hotel...
for the clothes!
I even thank you for the goddamn
nail polish!
This is my date...
and my night...
and I want you to back the hell off!
Oh, I see, I see
So, I can set up the date, I can buy you
the clothes...
but she starts making eyes at you...
and you don't need me anymore,
is that it?
No! I don't need you anymore
Well, did it occur to you that she's a pro?
Has it occurred to you that you're...
that I'm paying for this?
Yes!
Yes, it did
But maybe I wanna pretend, huh?
Maybe it's easier for me to pretend...
if her ex... whatever you were...
is not hangin' over her shoulder...
tellin' me to order squid dum-dum!
Dim sum
Dim sum Dim sum
And you're gonna ask her about
what happened that night
Yeah! Yeah, OK, I'm gonna ask her!
Where's the waiter?
I think he has a few other tables
Yeah
Hey, why don't...
What?
What were you gonna say?
Where...
of all the places in this city...
Where do you want to eat?
I don't get it
I always had to drag you down here
Hey, allow for a little growth
A little growth
I mean, you can only eat so much...
S-s-shredd-ed-ed squid!
Before eight-ball and tube steak looks
pretty good.
So... how we doing?
We're down six points
Moon! What?
Hey! What?
Oh, you wanna play, huh?
Come on
You wanna play
So what do you wanna do?
I'll show you what I can do!
Stop it!
I didn't!
Yes, you did
Is it OK if I take this stuff off?
Sure
Whatever you want
Sometimes...
I just get so tired...
of doing everything the hard way
Yeah
Oh, God, I missed you
Oh, yeah
Does it hurt?
Not much anymore
They say that the blood an tissue types...
have to be an exact match
You and Leon
Blood brothers
Get out of here
Oh, Moon
He was a good guy
You would've liked him
You reminded me of him tonight
Maybe it's his heart
Oh, fuck
What's up?
I gotta go
You know...
I like... I liked your pictures
And all those things you were tellin' me?
I was listening
Like, I... I know you had a dog
named Henry...
and a couple of sisters
Lisa and, uh...
Joanie
Yeah
And your favorite movie is Pinocchio
Pinocchio?
Oh, please! Pinocchio?!
What am I always talkin' about?
The Parent Trap!
Moon!
So, you're using my material, too, huh?
Yeah, Pinocchio
So I lied, sue me
Put out that cigarette
It's her You smoked it
What else did you see?
Enough to know that you didn't ask her
about what happened that night
I'm workin' up to it
That's bullshit, Moony
Look, she needs time
This is delicate!
I kept my part of the bargain
You asked me to back off, I backed off
Now you keep yours
You're pissed because we're hittin' it off
Yes
No
Yes... no, I'm pissed because
the guy who killed me isn't behind bars
You wouldn't even be here if
it wasn't for me, Moony
you wouldn't even be here, not with Crys...
not at the Beverly Palm Hotel,
not on this earth
So when she comes back in this room
I want you to ask her what happened!
Were you talkin' to someone?
Room service
Oh, room service
Don't order for me, I have to go
Ask her
Can't you stay for breakfast?
It's not me, it's Graham
Ask her
Call you at home
Yeah
Uh, Crys...
What? That...
the night, uh...
Stone died...
the night I chased you, remember?
Hard to forget
Mmm, yeah
Did anything happen
before he picked you up that...
might have caused his murder?
Oh, shit!
No, Crys... I knew it!
Crys, please...
Crys, listen to me! Crys!
Crys, please!
Crys, it's not like that! Listen! Crys!
Come on, Moony!
Hurry up! She's getting away
So are my pants!
Harry
Harry, I think something's going on
down here!
Crys! Come on!
I shouldn't have asked her!
We should've waited!
For what? So you two could have
another go in bed?
You stayed in the living room
Of course, you think I can learn anything...
watching a white boy? Huh?
Well, according to Crys you can!
Oh, all right, Superman
Well, give it your best shot, then
That's it, you got it, you got it
Mercedes keys
They're all Mercedes keys!
Yeah, that one
Hey, Moon?
Harry?
What are you...
I found it
Bullshit
I inherited it
A bunch of crap
I was given it by a dead ni...
lawyer... to find out who killed him
Very good
I didn't know you had it in you
Now, you see how easy that was?
Today is my golf day...
and my foursome teed off about
twenty minutes ago
Maybe if I hurry, I can catch them
on the back nine
Hold him
He can't hold you
You can't hold me
Hmm, the hell I can't
Not without bail Not without bail
I got you, Moony
Maybe not this minute...
but I got you
Who got you that hat?
I want you in here at eight tomorrow
for a full psychiatric examination...
and until that time, you are suspended!
Yeah, that's what you need, suspenders
And you leave your badge...
Leave my badge and my piece
with Rinselle on the way out
Fore!
Fuck it!
Why the hell did I listen to you?
We gotta find Crys
We found her! You made me blow it!
Hey, I'm doin' this for you
For me? For you
You've just got me thrown off the force!
I'm on my way to a mental institution!
Well, nobody's perfect
Shit! Jack?
You... you OK?
Look, I just wanted you to know...
that I was following you 'cause
I was concerned...
not because of Wendt
Sure, Harry
I mean, you need help, partner
You really do
Yeah
Go home and get some sleep, OK?
Get the fuck away from me!
Get away!
What?
Chuck, get out of there
Come on, Moony, you can't order
an autopsy report...
when you're on suspension
Well, do it in Harry's name
I'll clear it with him
The man was a U.S. Senator
What do I say we're looking for?
Cocaine
You know what kind of scandal
this could be?
It's a cover-up thing,
like the Redford movie
We're not gonna find anything
in that autopsy report
Right, right, what's that got to do
with finding Crys out here?
She had black spots on the bottom
of her feet
Black spot... yeah?
It was beach tar
You know? Beach tar
There's not a lot of beaches up here
that have enough to stick
Yeah? Right
Now, in police work, that...
coupled with a Malibu speeding ticket...
and you've got...
You got what?
Oh, get the fuck out of here
This is too easy
Now, wait a minute, Jack, remember...
I know what to say
Crys!
Shit!
Get out of my life, Moony
I'm not gonna do that
No, you don't understand
You have to leave, OK?
I'm not gonna do that, either
Moony, turn around and walk away
Crys, I developed the film
Why? Why did you do that?
You gave them to me
No, I gave it to you...
because I knew you wouldn't develop it
You'd just throw it in the fishbowl
Until something happened to you!
Nothing's happened to me
Yes, it did! You met me!
Listen, Marquand died of
a drug overdose, right?
Yes
Graham killed Stone on the chance...
that you might have told him about it
Yes
Do they know about the pictures?
That's the only reason we're still alive
Has anyone seen them?
No, not yet, but I'm gonna take 'em down
Moon!
I know what you wanna do
You can't do it
What the fuck are you talkin' about?
Leave
And don't do anything...
please
Hey, listen to me!
Please, Moon!
Crys!
Go away!
They'll see you!
Listen!
I can help you get out of this!
No! We have a deal
You got a trap!
He can see us
There's nothing you can do about it
Moon... nothing's the same
You see that?
Everything's gone
No! It's not gone
They'll kill me
No! I'm an accessory
I'll go to jail
Well, testify for immunity!
They'll find me
Look, I can protect you!
I don't care what happens to me
Well, who the fuck do you care for?!
This is my baby
He already lost his father
You want him to lose me, too?
Stone?
My God
I was pregnant
couple of months before he died
I never told him
Baby...
I didn't want it to look like I was trying...
to force him into something
I want this baby
Hey, baby
Jesus
You wanted to marry him
Does that make a difference?
Oh, Jesus, he's so beautiful!
Thank you, baby
Hey... come...
Hey, hey, Moon, come on, hol...
Come on and hold him for me
Tell... you know, tell me how he feels
Come on, Moon
Tell me how he feels, huh?
Moon?
Hey, Moon, come on, tell me...
Hey, Moon, don't do this to me.
Come on, tell me how he's...
Moony, come on! Tell me how he feels!
Hey!
Moony!
Peisha
Ready to go get some Pampers?
Yeah, oK
Crys?
Sorry
That's OK, that's OK
Here, let me hold him
No... Come on
Oh, yeah
You're a big boy
I just got off the phone...
with Senator Marquand's people
They're very upset with me
Seems that someone from the
police department...
has pulled out the Senator's autopsy file
And that wouldn't happen
to be a Mr. Moony?
The jerk from last night?
Did you know he was a cop? Huh?
Did you? Did you know he was a cop?
Did you know your mommy was one
of his old roomies?
Did you? Did you know that?
At least that's what Peisha tells me
I just got some very good Mexican brown
I hope she didn't O.D.
You lied to me
What?
Hey, look, look, you never should've left
That's the bottom line, all right?
She wanted me to leave...
or weren't you listening?
The girl needs our help
Well, she don't need mine
The girl's in love with you, asshole!
Fuck off!
Yeah, well, fuck you!
She's in love with you!
What the hell has that got to do
with anything?
I'm dead now!
Like hell you are!
Shit!
What is this shit?!
Fucking gotta be some kind of curse!
Me and Rambis, man, fuck!
Ha! You work your ass off, for what?
Fuckin' what?!
I'm not good enough for Crys!
Even my own heart ain't good enough!
Shit!
Fuckin' white curse!
No, it's not! It's a black
fuckin' conspiracy!
A what?
You! You heard me!
You fuckin' people, you...
you creep up around and just
suck up to us!
You make us trust you...
and then you... all the time,
you're robbin' us blind!
Oh, we do that, huh?
You! You, you fuckin'...
Say it, Moony, say it!
Say it! Niggers, right? Coon, chinks!
Spics! Kike!
Mook!
Niggers! Niggers!
Niggers!
Moon?
All right, just take... take it easy,
take it easy
Moony, that you?
I know we've had problems, but...
I don't think rejecting my heart
is the answer
You agree?
Yeah, I mean, there's other ways...
we can vent our frustration
We could... we could go to
the amusement park, uh...
ride the bumper cars
Play Mike Tyson's video Nintendo
You could be Mike Tyson
I'll... l'll be the white guy
No, I wanna be Mike Tyson
Anyway, we can... ice hockey...
uh, full-contact karate
I mean, we're mature men, aren't we?
I think we should just...
just chalk this rejection episode...
up to a learning experience...
as something that will never
happen again
You do agree?
Oh, good
That makes me breathe a lot easier
Now we gotta do something about Crys
If Graham's suspicious, no telling
what could happen
Yeah, we better...
We gotta...
We gotta get her
Any ideas? Yeah
Wait a minute, let's not jump
to conclusions
That thing could be keeping us alive
My ass
Where's the fuckin' phone?
Who you gonna call?
Arnold Palmer
What?
Are you trying to screw up
my entire day?
I am rid of you, Moony
The shrink is gonna pull you...
and you are going to be out of my life
for good!
Not crazy?
Anyone who would think that
a U.S. Senator would o.d. On crack...
has got to be out of his damn mind
No, I don't believe it, either...
and besides, if you just had an attack...
you shouldn't even be on the telephone
Moon...
Moon, would you calm...
just calm down, all ri...
Iook, I will be there
I'm not supposed to take this out
of the building
Yeah, I... I remember the night
at the Bowl
Moon, don't...
don't tell my mother
Listen, hold on
OK, I'll do it, yeah
OK
Oh, and... and, Moon, um...
Someone the name of Crystal called...
and Terri said that she should call you
at home, OK?
Moon?
It's Crys
Peisha and I are in serious trouble...
you understand?
And I need to see you, please
Oh, Jesus
What is it? What did she say?
They know, they're gonna kill her
We're gonna take little Leo to...
you know the World House?
It's up past the old swim club...
That used to be Needle Park
for the surf set
We'll wait for you there until eight
And after that, I... I don't know
what's gonna happen
Tell him about the pictures
You have to bring the pictures...
and come alone, Moon
Please, come
I love you
We got forty minutes
Jesus, they got my kid
Call the police
I'd waste forty minutes trying to
make 'em believe me
I'll leave Harry a note
Two three nine, code blue, code blue
Two three nine
Grab ten ccs ccs!
I think they responded very well to that
Here
Hemorrhoids
Crude, but funny
Over there
A police car's a little obvious, isn't it?
We got thirty minutes
You wanna take a bus?
You sure you're gonna be OK?
If I'm not, you're gonna be
the first to know
The note says he's on his way to Malibu
Excuse me, I'm looking for Jack Moony
Who the hell isn't?
Yes, it's written to a guy named Harry
I'm Harry
You friend's lucky to be walking
How the deuce do you think he's gonna
get to the beach?
This is a little bit more excitement
than is called for in this situation...
don't you think?
He took the car because he needed it
You think he's gonna ask for it?
Look, I don't think you realize
just how serious his condition is
I realize it, I realize it
Harry! Harry...
Dillnick, what are you doing here?
Uh, Moon told me to bring
Marquand's autopsy file
Now, I know it's not supposed
to leave the precinct...
Son of a bitch!
What's going on here?
Holy shit
What?
They never even checked for drugs
Yeah
No, I'm certain I can arrange something
for you on Friday
Time check
Quarter to eight
You OK?
Yeah
Uh, I'm a little fuzzy
Did she ever read to you?
Yeah
Every Sunday morning
The funnies, you know?
Yeah? Yeah
Yeah, me, too
She'd start me out with Doonesbury
Peanuts
Yeah, figures
You should have married her, Moony
Yeah
We both should have
I don't give a damn what Wendt says
Meet me there with a chopper
You think he might suspend us, Harry?
Being a cop is like being a pitcher,
Dillnick
You want your strikes,
you gotta risk your balls
It really irritates me when people don't
check their answering machines
Well, shoot 'em up
Hold on
Take it easy, take it easy
This'll make you feel a lot better
Come on, we're out of here
Just give her half
Oh, God
You realize this is a setup, don't you?
Yeah
I realize this is a setup
Well, a good lawyer always makes sure
his clients are prepared
Yeah
I'm prepared
You OK?
You be the scout I'll be the scout
Hey, Stone
Thanks
Ah, there's nobody here
Shit
Moon?
Sunglasses and an uzi
Watch my back
You OK?
Yeah
Aw, Jesus
This is it
Teller's got Crys and... my son
The right side
Graham's on the left
I'll check the side rooms
Moon, I'm sorry
Hi
The side rooms are empty
I'll watch the door
Ain't love grand?
Cut the shit, I'm here
Now let the girls go
I'll forget about Marquand
and deliver the pictures
Moon, there's one coming up
behind you
He's got a big gun
That's the plan I had with the girls
Moon?
I don't like to make the same
mistake twice
Moon!
You're dead, I guarantee it
You're dead, you're dead!
Moon... Moon...
Crys... come on
Crys, come on
You gotta stand up
Come on, pick up the baby!
You gotta stand, pick up the baby
Come on, honey
Moon, Peisha...
Don't worry about Peisha
She's dead
Let me worry about Peisha, come on
You just worry about little Lee
Come on, honey, come on
Fight it, don't give in to it
Come on!
Honey...
Let's get out of here!
OK Lean on me
It's OK
It's OK, Lee
Yeah, it's OK, we're going
Yeah, you... you just keep going, honey
Get back! Back!
Now!
Come on, come on, come on
Keep with him, get behind me
Don't look, honey, don't look, come on
Come on, let's get out of here
Get back, get back, another guy
Come on
Let's get out of here, come on
Go this way! This way, Moon!
OK... honey, you gotta get up
You gotta get up!
No, I...
Moon!
Get up!
Come on, get up
Come on, it's only a ten-foot drop
No You gotta jump
Come on, you gotta jump
No Give me the baby
Jump
Come on, over you go
That's it
OK, honey, it's OK, it's OK, come on
Just let yourself down
That's it, that's it!
Don't drop the baby, Moon
I'm not gonna drop the baby
Don't drop the baby
Here's little Lee, here you go, fella
Down you go
All right, he can get down
Take him, take him
Honey, honey!
Tell her to go now
Tell her to go down to the beach
Go down to the beach, honey
Get out of here, go on
Where'd you go?
Hey, Harry,
detective Moony's holding his arm
A little funny, isn't he?
Yeah, it must have something to do
with his heart condition
Ripped by smokey888
http://tehPARADOX.COM