1
00:01:19,081 --> 00:01:20,912
(Man whispering) I'm sorry, Micky.

2
00:01:20,961 --> 00:01:23,156
Micky, I'm really sorry.

3
00:01:23,201 --> 00:01:25,590
I'm sorry.

4
00:01:25,641 --> 00:01:27,518
I really am sorry.

5
00:01:28,561 --> 00:01:31,553
It just came on me like that.
(Clicks fingers)

6
00:01:31,601 --> 00:01:33,193
Just like that.

7
00:01:34,241 --> 00:01:36,516
Like that.

8
00:01:36,561 --> 00:01:39,712
You know, I've never let you down
in the past, Micky.

9
00:01:39,761 --> 00:01:42,992
Shut up, Ronnie. Shut up.

10
00:01:43,041 --> 00:01:44,440
Sorry, Micky.

11
00:01:44,481 --> 00:01:49,953
You know, the doctor said,
"Don't whisper, don't speak."

12
00:01:50,001 --> 00:01:51,593
Never mind sing.

13
00:01:52,601 --> 00:01:54,478
We're gutted, Micky.

14
00:01:54,521 --> 00:01:55,874
We're gutted.

15
00:01:55,921 --> 00:01:57,240
Shut up.

16
00:01:58,841 --> 00:02:01,196
If this happens again, Micky...

17
00:02:01,241 --> 00:02:04,358
we're going to have
to go back to the docks.

18
00:02:41,441 --> 00:02:43,955
- Nancy!
- Nancy.

19
00:02:44,841 --> 00:02:46,320
(Both laugh)

20
00:02:55,081 --> 00:02:56,400
(♪ Jazz)

21
00:02:56,441 --> 00:02:59,114
(Music drowns out speech)

22
00:03:01,281 --> 00:03:02,600
(Nancy) Hi.

23
00:03:02,641 --> 00:03:04,791
Hello. Hi. How are you doing?

24
00:03:06,001 --> 00:03:07,400
See you later.

25
00:03:11,121 --> 00:03:13,999
Girls. Mwah! How are you?

26
00:03:14,041 --> 00:03:16,919
Yeah. No, I can't.
Speak to you later.

27
00:03:16,961 --> 00:03:18,360
Bye.

28
00:03:26,961 --> 00:03:28,519
Some of that, sir. Thank you.

29
00:03:28,561 --> 00:03:32,554
- Oh, boys! What's all this about?
- Can we have two more glasses?

30
00:03:32,601 --> 00:03:35,911
(Nancy) What's the occasion, then?
(Man 1) Who needs an occasion?

31
00:03:56,321 --> 00:03:58,039
- Nancy here?
- (Both) Yeah.

32
00:03:58,081 --> 00:04:00,197
- Champagne?
- (Both) Yeah.

33
00:04:05,521 --> 00:04:07,512
Give that to her halfway through
the second verse.

34
00:04:07,561 --> 00:04:09,199
What?

35
00:04:10,241 --> 00:04:11,674
I'm going on.

36
00:04:23,161 --> 00:04:25,595
Ladies and gentlemen,
can I have your attention, please?

37
00:04:25,641 --> 00:04:28,030
Please, please,
may I have your attention?

38
00:04:28,081 --> 00:04:30,390
Please, thank you.
Can I have some quiet, please?

39
00:04:30,441 --> 00:04:32,671
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.

40
00:04:32,721 --> 00:04:33,710
Ladies and gentlemen.

41
00:04:33,761 --> 00:04:35,797
The fire brigade have just phoned
to tell us

42
00:04:35,841 --> 00:04:39,151
that Ronnie Lavelle
is being cut out of his Ford Capri

43
00:04:39,201 --> 00:04:41,999
in the worst car crash
in the history of the M6 motorway.

44
00:04:42,041 --> 00:04:44,874
- (Dramatic piano chords)
- (Man) You're joking.

45
00:04:44,921 --> 00:04:46,400
(Piano stops, chatter)

46
00:04:46,441 --> 00:04:48,193
Thank you.

47
00:04:48,241 --> 00:04:51,074
But, at very short notice,

48
00:04:51,121 --> 00:04:53,510
we are proud to present

49
00:04:53,561 --> 00:04:56,121
the man who put the heart
back into Heartlys.

50
00:04:56,161 --> 00:04:58,629
Mr Micky O'Neill.

51
00:04:58,681 --> 00:05:00,797
(Drum roll)

52
00:05:04,121 --> 00:05:06,237
(Piano playing)

53
00:05:09,961 --> 00:05:12,350
(Man) We didn't pay to see you, O'Neill.

54
00:05:17,121 --> 00:05:19,191
♪ If I don't see her

55
00:05:19,241 --> 00:05:20,833
♪ Each day

56
00:05:20,881 --> 00:05:22,075
♪ I miss her

57
00:05:24,281 --> 00:05:27,034
♪ And, gee, what a thrill

58
00:05:27,081 --> 00:05:28,992
♪ Each time I kiss her

59
00:05:31,001 --> 00:05:32,639
♪ Believe me, I've got a case...

60
00:05:32,681 --> 00:05:34,956
(Woman) You're rubbish, O'Neill, get off.

61
00:05:35,001 --> 00:05:36,753
♪ Of Nancy

62
00:05:36,801 --> 00:05:38,917
♪ With the laughing face

63
00:05:39,961 --> 00:05:44,079
♪ She takes the winter
and makes it summer

64
00:05:44,121 --> 00:05:45,554
♪ I'll tell you

65
00:05:46,281 --> 00:05:51,071
♪ Summer could take
some lessons from her

66
00:05:51,121 --> 00:05:54,477
♪ Picture a tomboy in lace

67
00:05:54,521 --> 00:05:56,637
♪ That's Nancy

68
00:05:56,681 --> 00:06:00,879
♪ With the laughing face

69
00:06:00,921 --> 00:06:05,836
♪ Have you ever heard
mission bells ringing?

70
00:06:08,041 --> 00:06:13,115
♪ Well, she gives you
that very same glow

71
00:06:13,161 --> 00:06:14,674
♪ Just to speak

72
00:06:14,721 --> 00:06:18,316
♪ You would swear it was singing

73
00:06:20,081 --> 00:06:23,357
♪ Just to hear her say hello

74
00:06:24,361 --> 00:06:26,750
- What you got there?
- ♪ Keep Audrey Hepburn

75
00:06:26,801 --> 00:06:30,714
♪ Lamour and Taylor

76
00:06:32,521 --> 00:06:35,115
♪ Nancy's the feature

77
00:06:35,161 --> 00:06:38,471
♪ And they're just the trailer

78
00:06:38,521 --> 00:06:42,594
♪ No one could ever replace

79
00:06:42,641 --> 00:06:46,316
♪ My Nancy

80
00:06:46,361 --> 00:06:51,196
♪ With the laughing face ♪

81
00:06:53,921 --> 00:06:55,400
Very good.

82
00:07:00,121 --> 00:07:03,830
Make love to me, Micky,
make love to me.

83
00:07:03,881 --> 00:07:06,554
Micky, I love you!

84
00:07:06,601 --> 00:07:08,432
Micky!

85
00:07:08,481 --> 00:07:10,312
I love you!

86
00:07:10,361 --> 00:07:12,750
Vice versa, love. Vice versa.

87
00:07:12,801 --> 00:07:14,917
- I don't believe it!
- What?

88
00:07:14,961 --> 00:07:19,034
Vice versa?
Vice versa, what is vice versa?

89
00:07:19,081 --> 00:07:20,878
- Vice versa.
- What's wrong?

90
00:07:20,921 --> 00:07:22,593
You haven't really
made love to me yet.

91
00:07:22,641 --> 00:07:23,869
Damn it, we were there.

92
00:07:23,921 --> 00:07:25,274
- Micky!
- What?

93
00:07:25,321 --> 00:07:26,879
- No, I mean ever.
- What?

94
00:07:26,921 --> 00:07:29,116
Jesus, you just can't say it,
can you?

95
00:07:29,161 --> 00:07:32,836
Nancy! Nancy, no.
Munchkin. Plum-plum.

96
00:07:32,881 --> 00:07:34,030
Bollocks!

97
00:07:35,081 --> 00:07:37,037
Vice versa.

98
00:07:38,081 --> 00:07:41,676
(Micky) They've got to be universal, they've
got to be popular and they've got to be live.

99
00:07:41,721 --> 00:07:43,234
Mr Everybody?

100
00:07:43,281 --> 00:07:45,158
Not universal.

101
00:07:45,201 --> 00:07:46,873
Coffee and Cream?

102
00:07:46,921 --> 00:07:49,799
Not popular. God!

103
00:07:50,841 --> 00:07:52,274
Frank Sinatra?

104
00:07:53,961 --> 00:07:54,950
What?

105
00:07:59,641 --> 00:08:00,790
Frank Sinatra.

106
00:08:02,241 --> 00:08:05,233
No. F-R-A-N-C.

107
00:08:05,281 --> 00:08:07,636
C-l-N-A-T-R-A.

108
00:08:08,921 --> 00:08:09,910
Show me.

109
00:08:15,241 --> 00:08:17,277
Does it work?

110
00:08:17,321 --> 00:08:19,630
Fools them down south, Micky.

111
00:08:24,041 --> 00:08:25,440
Yeah!

112
00:08:27,161 --> 00:08:28,594
Bollocks.

113
00:08:28,641 --> 00:08:30,359
Book him.

114
00:08:31,561 --> 00:08:32,914
Where's the book?

115
00:09:05,401 --> 00:09:06,993
- (Song ends)
- Yeah.

116
00:09:08,041 --> 00:09:11,238
(Few people clapping)

117
00:09:11,281 --> 00:09:14,478
♪ Eat me up and then you'll

118
00:09:14,521 --> 00:09:16,910
♪ Taste what's on the menu

119
00:09:18,001 --> 00:09:20,674
♪ Lick your lips

120
00:09:20,721 --> 00:09:24,475
♪ Some sweet delights

121
00:09:24,521 --> 00:09:26,716
♪ We have here

122
00:09:26,761 --> 00:09:31,551
- ♪ For you tonight...
- (Man laughing)

123
00:09:31,601 --> 00:09:33,876
Where does it hurt you, baby?

124
00:09:33,921 --> 00:09:37,436
- (Woman) In my ears.
- OK, Oscar, hit it.

125
00:09:37,481 --> 00:09:40,314
♪ You're a delightful dish

126
00:09:40,361 --> 00:09:42,511
♪ I'm hooked

127
00:09:42,561 --> 00:09:44,199
♪ Just like a fish

128
00:09:44,241 --> 00:09:48,519
♪ I'll jump from Brooklyn Bridge
to Queens

129
00:09:48,561 --> 00:09:50,711
♪ Fly it with me

130
00:09:50,761 --> 00:09:53,434
♪ Take a ride with me

131
00:09:53,481 --> 00:09:56,234
♪ Mmm, sky high with me

132
00:09:56,281 --> 00:10:00,638
♪ Into my world of dreams

133
00:10:00,681 --> 00:10:02,956
♪ Zan-zan-zanidoo ♪

134
00:10:04,481 --> 00:10:05,630
The Ryans are here, Micky.

135
00:10:05,681 --> 00:10:07,876
Tell them I'm on the golf course
with Tony Bennett.

136
00:10:07,921 --> 00:10:10,071
- They're in the office.
- Bollocks.

137
00:10:10,121 --> 00:10:13,272
- Have you found anybody?
- Josef Locke.

138
00:10:13,321 --> 00:10:15,277
He's big. He's Irish.

139
00:10:15,321 --> 00:10:17,357
- He's a bigger draw than the Pope.
- Boys.

140
00:10:17,401 --> 00:10:19,392
I didn't go and see the Pope.
What is he?

141
00:10:19,441 --> 00:10:21,238
- He sings.
- Women weep.

142
00:10:22,521 --> 00:10:24,034
The Ryans weeping?

143
00:10:25,081 --> 00:10:26,355
This I've got to see.

144
00:10:31,441 --> 00:10:33,750
Cup of tea? Sherry?

145
00:10:33,801 --> 00:10:35,678
Take a seat.

146
00:10:37,161 --> 00:10:38,674
This is nice.

147
00:10:44,801 --> 00:10:48,510
The Ryan family has owned
this building for 50 years.

148
00:10:48,561 --> 00:10:51,758
We needed a two-thirds majority
to get you dismissed.

149
00:10:52,761 --> 00:10:57,152
- We got three thirds. You're out.
- Three thirds. It's a lot, isn't it?

150
00:10:57,201 --> 00:10:58,953
It wasn't difficult.

151
00:10:59,001 --> 00:11:03,279
Misuse of funds. Not paying our
seven-and-a-half per cent commission.

152
00:11:03,321 --> 00:11:06,711
- No management responsibilities.
- No competency.

153
00:11:06,761 --> 00:11:08,114
I'm 30.

154
00:11:10,041 --> 00:11:12,953
I was born in peacetime.

155
00:11:13,001 --> 00:11:16,880
I haven't been where you've been.
I haven't seen what you've seen.

156
00:11:16,921 --> 00:11:19,151
I didn't have much of a family.

157
00:11:19,201 --> 00:11:22,432
And, when I came here to Britain,
I thought, well, you know,

158
00:11:22,481 --> 00:11:24,915
maybe I could make this
Irish community my family.

159
00:11:26,481 --> 00:11:30,315
And, you know, to a certain extent,
I think I have.

160
00:11:36,001 --> 00:11:38,276
There are givers...

161
00:11:38,321 --> 00:11:40,118
and there are takers.

162
00:11:40,161 --> 00:11:43,471
There are those who find
a kind of giving in their taking.

163
00:11:43,521 --> 00:11:45,113
That's me.

164
00:11:45,161 --> 00:11:48,597
If ever I've taken, and I can't
consciously say that I ever have,

165
00:11:48,641 --> 00:11:51,997
I've found a kind of giving
in my taking.

166
00:11:52,041 --> 00:11:53,474
Bollocks.

167
00:11:53,521 --> 00:11:55,796
- (AIl) Bollocks.
- (Woman) Yeah.

168
00:11:55,841 --> 00:11:57,115
You're a bollocks!

169
00:12:01,761 --> 00:12:03,433
Who have you booked for next week?

170
00:12:03,481 --> 00:12:05,597
Bing Crosby with a K?

171
00:12:05,641 --> 00:12:08,474
No, Josef Locke.

172
00:12:08,521 --> 00:12:09,510
Get away.

173
00:12:09,561 --> 00:12:11,233
We've got him for one week.

174
00:12:11,281 --> 00:12:12,350
I don't believe you.

175
00:12:12,401 --> 00:12:14,232
Jo Locke's a wanted man.

176
00:12:14,281 --> 00:12:16,920
Tax or fraud or something.

177
00:12:16,961 --> 00:12:20,158
He'd be arrested if ever
he returned to England.

178
00:12:20,201 --> 00:12:22,635
- We know.
- You know?

179
00:12:23,761 --> 00:12:27,117
We know it's Jo.

180
00:12:27,161 --> 00:12:29,834
Youse all know it's Jo.

181
00:12:29,881 --> 00:12:32,076
But we don't bill him as Jo.

182
00:12:33,721 --> 00:12:36,110
Then what do we bill him as,
Ricky-fucking-Robert?

183
00:12:36,161 --> 00:12:39,790
No. Mr X.

184
00:12:39,841 --> 00:12:42,275
"Is it or isn't it?"

185
00:12:42,321 --> 00:12:46,678
We're not allowed
even to mention Jo Locke.

186
00:12:46,721 --> 00:12:48,279
How it is these days.

187
00:12:48,321 --> 00:12:51,518
Well, you can't get more popular
than Jo-bleeding-Locke.

188
00:12:51,561 --> 00:12:55,110
So, do I stay open
or do you lose Josef Locke?

189
00:12:55,161 --> 00:12:57,197
Seven-and-a-half per cent of that
would do nicely.

190
00:12:57,241 --> 00:12:59,232
(♪ Whistling Dance playing)

191
00:13:04,801 --> 00:13:07,395
(Whistles to tune of music)

192
00:13:39,961 --> 00:13:41,519
(Thunder)

193
00:13:47,081 --> 00:13:48,480
Wait here.

194
00:13:59,641 --> 00:14:01,359
You see these two goldfish?

195
00:14:01,401 --> 00:14:04,040
Apparently, they have an attention span
of only three seconds

196
00:14:04,081 --> 00:14:06,641
so that means every time
they go around and meet again,

197
00:14:06,681 --> 00:14:09,753
it's as if they've never met,
and they can start again.

198
00:14:09,801 --> 00:14:11,154
Is this you saying you're sorry?

199
00:14:11,201 --> 00:14:14,318
What I'm saying is you could say
that goldfish don't know what missing is.

200
00:14:14,361 --> 00:14:15,953
But Nancy...

201
00:14:19,721 --> 00:14:22,189
I don't think that's true.

202
00:14:31,321 --> 00:14:33,232
I hear you can sing.

203
00:14:34,561 --> 00:14:37,837
- Who are you?
- I'm Cathleen Doyle, Nancy's mother.

204
00:14:39,361 --> 00:14:41,921
Are these because she's a Pisces?

205
00:14:42,601 --> 00:14:44,990
- What?
- The two fish.

206
00:14:48,401 --> 00:14:49,834
Absolutely.

207
00:15:04,121 --> 00:15:07,796
What country, friend, is this?

208
00:15:08,561 --> 00:15:10,950
Caught between great icebergs of doubt

209
00:15:11,001 --> 00:15:14,152
Nipped upon the frozen floods
of philosophic despair

210
00:15:14,201 --> 00:15:18,353
Let nodding tempests of verbosity
whistle round your bottles

211
00:15:18,401 --> 00:15:23,111
Michael, row the boat ashore
for this peripatetic fugitive.

212
00:15:23,161 --> 00:15:25,038
Will a grand a week do?

213
00:15:25,081 --> 00:15:28,630
To know yourself
you've got to keep up with yourself.

214
00:15:28,681 --> 00:15:29,750
But your self moves on,

215
00:15:29,801 --> 00:15:32,759
and is not today
what it was yesterday,

216
00:15:32,801 --> 00:15:35,031
and you've got to run
to keep up with it.

217
00:15:35,081 --> 00:15:36,116
Twelve-fifty.

218
00:15:36,161 --> 00:15:38,800
Running after a figment of ourselves...

219
00:15:38,841 --> 00:15:39,990
Thirteen hundred.

220
00:15:40,041 --> 00:15:43,875
Ah, clever Odysseus,

221
00:15:43,921 --> 00:15:46,116
who outwitted the cyclop...

222
00:15:46,161 --> 00:15:47,150
Cash?

223
00:15:47,201 --> 00:15:48,680
Upfront.

224
00:15:49,721 --> 00:15:52,110
We go up at eight.

225
00:15:52,161 --> 00:15:54,595
And for fuck's sake, Jo...

226
00:15:56,561 --> 00:15:58,870
don't talk to nobody.

227
00:16:16,521 --> 00:16:18,910
Serendipity.

228
00:16:18,961 --> 00:16:21,600
(Laughs)

229
00:16:21,641 --> 00:16:25,190
Micky, City Scene want an interview.
They're outside.

230
00:16:25,241 --> 00:16:26,674
He's not the full shilling, is he?

231
00:16:26,721 --> 00:16:30,031
Norman Vaughan's outside with about
40 other people. Norman Vaughan!

232
00:16:30,081 --> 00:16:31,673
The lift doesn't reach the top floor.

233
00:16:31,721 --> 00:16:34,110
I said I was your personal assistant,
they said, "Come on with him."

234
00:16:34,161 --> 00:16:36,311
Yes, sure, love. No sweat.

235
00:16:36,361 --> 00:16:40,240
- Is he going to stay the distance?
- He's a pro, Micky. He's a pro.

236
00:16:42,001 --> 00:16:43,992
Does he run this operation,
this Micky O'Neill?

237
00:16:44,041 --> 00:16:45,713
I remember this
when it was a music hall.

238
00:16:45,761 --> 00:16:47,991
Micky baby, you're looking great.

239
00:16:48,041 --> 00:16:49,759
Listen, this is what
we're going to do.

240
00:16:49,801 --> 00:16:53,157
I'm going to talk to you about booking
someone as controversial as Jo.

241
00:16:53,201 --> 00:16:55,669
So, we're going to have to do
this straight away, OK?

242
00:16:55,721 --> 00:16:58,997
This is television, Micky.
This is television, Micky baby.

243
00:16:59,041 --> 00:17:00,793
OK, wet your lips, Nancy.

244
00:17:00,841 --> 00:17:05,073
Now, how many of you out there remember
the famous Irish tenor, Josef Locke?

245
00:17:05,121 --> 00:17:08,113
This was the question
put to 100 Merseysiders

246
00:17:08,161 --> 00:17:11,915
on hearing the news that Jo Locke
was topping the bill at Heartlys tonight.

247
00:17:11,961 --> 00:17:13,758
Twenty said they thought he was dead,

248
00:17:13,801 --> 00:17:16,599
thirty said they were sure
he was serving a life sentence,

249
00:17:16,641 --> 00:17:19,155
thirteen thought he was
a tax exile in Ireland,

250
00:17:19,201 --> 00:17:21,556
and 35 said, "Jo who?"

251
00:17:21,601 --> 00:17:26,311
All this, however, is overshadowed
by one exceptional statistic.

252
00:17:26,361 --> 00:17:30,240
So, let's ask local impresario,
boss of Heartlys, Micky O'Neill,

253
00:17:30,281 --> 00:17:31,509
why it's a sell-out. Micky.

254
00:17:31,561 --> 00:17:33,836
Well, I suppose it's because
he's the epitome

255
00:17:33,881 --> 00:17:36,679
of live popular universal entertainment
and he's a great guy.

256
00:17:36,721 --> 00:17:39,440
Yeah, but what's he like?
You've met him. What's he really like?

257
00:17:39,481 --> 00:17:42,757
He's, ha-ha... He's, he's very poetic,
very unto himself.

258
00:17:42,801 --> 00:17:45,076
But isn't there a risk involved?
Booking a wanted man?

259
00:17:45,121 --> 00:17:47,635
It's a risk I'm prepared to take.
These people deserve it.

260
00:17:47,681 --> 00:17:49,080
Nancy, what a pretty girl.

261
00:17:49,121 --> 00:17:51,681
You come here. I believe you have
a story of your own, is that right?

262
00:17:51,721 --> 00:17:53,712
Me mum will kill me for this.

263
00:17:53,761 --> 00:17:55,752
- Anyway, in 1958...
- Fifty-eight.

264
00:17:55,801 --> 00:17:59,111
...me mum won Miss Dairy Goodness
and Jo Locke was the judge.

265
00:17:59,161 --> 00:18:01,880
And she's coming to see him tonight
for the first time in 25 years.

266
00:18:01,921 --> 00:18:03,798
- First time in 25 years.
- That's the story.

267
00:18:03,841 --> 00:18:05,877
- What's your mother's name?
- Cathleen Doyle.

268
00:18:05,921 --> 00:18:10,597
Cathleen Doyle! So, Cathleen Doyle
was Miss Dairy Goodness in 1958...

269
00:18:20,201 --> 00:18:23,830
And to conclude this most
memorable event...

270
00:18:25,001 --> 00:18:28,357
one last look
at these ravishing beauties.

271
00:18:38,321 --> 00:18:39,959
One last look...

272
00:18:40,001 --> 00:18:42,913
while our judge reaches
his decision.

273
00:18:42,961 --> 00:18:46,715
And what more fitting way
than to ask Jo?

274
00:18:47,801 --> 00:18:49,393
We will never forget this.

275
00:18:49,441 --> 00:18:52,399
None of us. Ever.

276
00:19:06,201 --> 00:19:07,998
Jo's taking his time.

277
00:19:08,041 --> 00:19:09,554
Hard decision.

278
00:19:10,641 --> 00:19:12,711
Jo's gone for Cathleen.

279
00:19:13,881 --> 00:19:14,916
He likes her.

280
00:19:14,961 --> 00:19:18,078
He likes her! Well done, Cathleen.

281
00:19:18,121 --> 00:19:22,239
One thousand pounds
to Miss Dairy Goodness.

282
00:19:22,281 --> 00:19:23,760
(Laughs)

283
00:19:24,881 --> 00:19:26,473
That's enough, Jo.

284
00:19:26,521 --> 00:19:29,115
We... We won't tell a soul.

285
00:19:29,161 --> 00:19:31,755
We won't tell a soul.

286
00:19:31,801 --> 00:19:34,269
(Chuckles)

287
00:21:24,041 --> 00:21:25,156
<i>Last word for the viewers.</i>

288
00:21:25,201 --> 00:21:27,635
<i>There's going to be fireworks tonight,</i>
<i>believe you me.</i>

289
00:21:27,681 --> 00:21:29,751
<i>Believe you him,</i>
<i>and always remember, folks,</i>

290
00:21:29,801 --> 00:21:31,996
<i>do unto others but do it quick.</i>

291
00:21:32,041 --> 00:21:36,000
<i>This has been Norman Vaughan</i>
<i>for City Scene, outside Heartlys.</i>

292
00:21:36,041 --> 00:21:38,271
You can't keep it shut, can you?

293
00:21:38,321 --> 00:21:39,834
But everybody knows.

294
00:21:39,881 --> 00:21:40,916
Turn, please.

295
00:21:46,081 --> 00:21:47,434
Once again, please.

296
00:21:50,521 --> 00:21:52,591
How do I look?

297
00:21:52,641 --> 00:21:55,314
You look fatal. How do you feel?

298
00:21:55,361 --> 00:21:57,113
(Seamstress) Turn, please.

299
00:21:59,801 --> 00:22:01,792
I feel sick.

300
00:22:01,841 --> 00:22:05,390
(Man) Once-in-a-lifetime chance
to hear the great Josef Locke.

301
00:22:05,441 --> 00:22:08,160
Come along, ladies.
They're only five pounds each.

302
00:22:08,201 --> 00:22:09,429
(Man 2) You're welcome.

303
00:22:09,481 --> 00:22:12,996
(Man 1) Don't Locke Jo up,
ladies and gentlemen. Two for a tenner.

304
00:22:13,041 --> 00:22:15,475
Thank you, sir. Don't Locke Jo up.

305
00:22:18,841 --> 00:22:20,035
Erm, medium.

306
00:22:20,081 --> 00:22:23,312
Could I see Mr O'Neill, please?

307
00:22:23,361 --> 00:22:24,589
And your name, sir?

308
00:22:24,641 --> 00:22:26,040
Jim Abbott.

309
00:22:28,441 --> 00:22:29,840
Chief Constable.

310
00:22:35,681 --> 00:22:38,479
The chief constable to see you, Micky.

311
00:22:48,601 --> 00:22:49,716
You can't do it, Chief.

312
00:22:49,761 --> 00:22:52,036
The big guy's so popular here,
I've extended the run.

313
00:22:52,081 --> 00:22:55,118
You can't do it to these people.
We put everything into this.

314
00:22:55,161 --> 00:22:56,560
Yeah, I can see that.

315
00:22:57,561 --> 00:22:59,597
Look...

316
00:22:59,641 --> 00:23:02,235
just give me to the end of the run
and then...

317
00:23:04,561 --> 00:23:06,950
you can stick the bastard away
for as long as you like.

318
00:23:08,121 --> 00:23:10,191
I'd like a house seat, Mr O'Neill.

319
00:23:18,161 --> 00:23:21,119
And now you can take me
to his dressing room.

320
00:23:36,201 --> 00:23:37,634
(Buzzing)

321
00:23:43,521 --> 00:23:45,079
(Buzzing continues)

322
00:23:46,481 --> 00:23:47,960
(Buzzing stops)

323
00:23:55,321 --> 00:23:57,073
Thank you, Mr O'Neill.

324
00:23:57,121 --> 00:23:58,520
Everything OK?

325
00:23:58,561 --> 00:24:02,110
- The man is a fake.
- What?

326
00:24:02,161 --> 00:24:05,915
You mean I'm paying
three grand a week for a fake?

327
00:24:07,481 --> 00:24:09,756
I don't think you need to worry,
Mr O'Neill.

328
00:24:11,321 --> 00:24:13,960
I'm the only person here tonight
who'd know the difference.

329
00:24:19,161 --> 00:24:21,152
But, Chief... Chief!

330
00:24:22,561 --> 00:24:27,430
If it's not Jo Locke,
and you know that,

331
00:24:27,481 --> 00:24:29,915
why are you staying to see the show?

332
00:24:35,081 --> 00:24:36,673
Curiosity.

333
00:24:45,761 --> 00:24:47,319
You go up in 15.

334
00:24:50,561 --> 00:24:51,550
Good luck.

335
00:24:54,881 --> 00:24:56,360
(Whispers) Jo.

336
00:24:59,561 --> 00:25:01,279
Compliments from Micky, ladies.

337
00:25:01,321 --> 00:25:03,676
Enjoy yourselves.

338
00:25:07,961 --> 00:25:10,316
Everyone all right?

339
00:25:10,361 --> 00:25:12,921
- Thanks for the champagne.
- No problem.

340
00:25:12,961 --> 00:25:15,395
- How are the Ryans, then?
- You did well to get him, Micky.

341
00:25:15,441 --> 00:25:19,229
Gordon, bring the ladies
another bottle of champagne.

342
00:25:19,281 --> 00:25:20,555
Get away.

343
00:25:23,681 --> 00:25:25,399
Nice crowd tonight, Micky.

344
00:25:25,441 --> 00:25:28,513
Yeah, well, he's the real thing, isn't he?

345
00:25:28,561 --> 00:25:31,200
I'll be the judge of that.

346
00:25:32,481 --> 00:25:34,597
- Is it me?
- What?

347
00:25:35,601 --> 00:25:37,717
Your nose is bleeding.

348
00:25:42,561 --> 00:25:44,233
See you later.

349
00:25:50,401 --> 00:25:52,869
Barry, have you
met the chief of police?

350
00:25:52,921 --> 00:25:54,718
Jim Abbott, Barry Hayden.

351
00:26:05,561 --> 00:26:07,552
How's it going, mate,
everything all right?

352
00:26:07,601 --> 00:26:10,195
A touch comes when the white mind sleeps
and only then.

353
00:26:10,241 --> 00:26:12,550
Yeah, right. Listen.

354
00:26:13,281 --> 00:26:16,353
See that very tasty lady out there?

355
00:26:20,761 --> 00:26:23,036
You had an affair with her
25 years ago.

356
00:26:26,001 --> 00:26:30,199
I think I would have remembered that,
Michael. She's a fine-Iooking filly.

357
00:26:31,361 --> 00:26:35,639
Her name's Cathleen.
Sing to her, you could be on a winner.

358
00:26:37,521 --> 00:26:40,638
Come to think of it, I do...

359
00:26:46,801 --> 00:26:49,440
(♪ Band playing
I'll Take You Home Again, Cathleen)

360
00:26:50,481 --> 00:26:51,470
(Applause)

361
00:26:59,281 --> 00:27:04,833
♪ I'll take you home again, Cathleen

362
00:27:04,881 --> 00:27:07,634
♪ Across the ocean

363
00:27:07,681 --> 00:27:11,037
♪ Wild and wide

364
00:27:11,081 --> 00:27:16,792
♪ To where your heart has ever been

365
00:27:16,841 --> 00:27:22,473
♪ Since first
you were my bonnie bride

366
00:27:22,521 --> 00:27:25,319
♪ The roses all

367
00:27:25,361 --> 00:27:28,910
♪ Have left your cheeks

368
00:27:28,961 --> 00:27:34,593
♪ I've watched them fade away and die

369
00:27:34,641 --> 00:27:37,235
♪ Your voice is sad

370
00:27:37,281 --> 00:27:40,637
♪ When e'er you speak

371
00:27:40,681 --> 00:27:42,273
♪ And tears

372
00:27:42,321 --> 00:27:47,315
♪ Bedim your loving eyes

373
00:27:47,361 --> 00:27:49,033
♪ Oh

374
00:27:49,081 --> 00:27:54,394
♪ I will take you back, Cathleen

375
00:27:54,441 --> 00:27:59,993
♪ To where your heart
will feel no pain

376
00:28:01,001 --> 00:28:06,234
♪ And when the fields
are fresh and green

377
00:28:06,281 --> 00:28:08,636
♪ I'll take you... ♪

378
00:28:08,681 --> 00:28:10,558
Happy hour?

379
00:28:10,601 --> 00:28:12,432
We're still counting the advance, Micky.

380
00:28:13,721 --> 00:28:15,677
This is the night's takings here.

381
00:28:15,721 --> 00:28:19,157
It's only the beginning, fellas.
Only the beginning.

382
00:28:35,001 --> 00:28:37,640
Look at me. You'd think I was 18.

383
00:28:37,681 --> 00:28:38,875
Thanks.

384
00:28:40,041 --> 00:28:41,315
Has someone upset you, love?

385
00:28:41,361 --> 00:28:44,159
No. Are you enjoying it?

386
00:28:45,161 --> 00:28:48,756
Oh... (Chuckles)
Oh, I'm enjoying the whole thing.

387
00:28:50,321 --> 00:28:52,437
He's, erm...

388
00:28:52,481 --> 00:28:56,997
He's not quite what he was, though.

389
00:28:57,041 --> 00:28:58,759
How many of us are?

390
00:28:58,801 --> 00:28:59,870
Well, you.

391
00:28:59,921 --> 00:29:01,479
(Laughs)

392
00:29:01,521 --> 00:29:02,636
What's funny?

393
00:29:03,761 --> 00:29:08,596
How is it you can lock
something away for 25 years,

394
00:29:08,641 --> 00:29:11,394
almost make yourself believe
it doesn't exist...

395
00:29:13,161 --> 00:29:16,836
...then some heel sings a song
and you love him.

396
00:29:16,881 --> 00:29:19,793
And you can't imagine
a world without men.

397
00:29:22,601 --> 00:29:24,353
That's funny.

398
00:29:24,401 --> 00:29:26,995
(♪ Blaze Away - We'll Make A Bonfire
Of Our Troubles)

399
00:29:27,041 --> 00:29:28,520
♪ Ha-ha ha-ha-ha-ha

400
00:29:28,561 --> 00:29:32,440
♪ We'll make a bonfire
of our troubles

401
00:29:32,481 --> 00:29:36,315
♪ And we'll watch them blaze away

402
00:29:36,361 --> 00:29:39,876
♪ And when they've all gone up
in smoke clouds

403
00:29:39,921 --> 00:29:44,073
♪ We'll never worry
should there come another day

404
00:29:44,121 --> 00:29:45,110
♪ And as the bonfire...

405
00:29:45,161 --> 00:29:48,551
Carlo, it's Micky. Table for two,
my account, in the name of Mr X.

406
00:29:48,601 --> 00:29:51,354
Yep, Mr X.
Yeah, it went great. Great.

407
00:29:51,401 --> 00:29:53,790
I'll get you two for Thursday.
Buy you one later.

408
00:29:53,841 --> 00:29:56,514
Oh, and Carlo, put them
by the aquarium. Ciao.

409
00:29:56,561 --> 00:29:59,473
♪... troubles blaze away! ♪

410
00:30:00,881 --> 00:30:02,872
(Cheering and applause)

411
00:30:04,681 --> 00:30:06,717
Over here! Help yourselves,
help yourselves.

412
00:30:06,761 --> 00:30:10,549
- Must be the luck of the Irishmen.
- Bollocks.

413
00:30:10,601 --> 00:30:13,911
I think you'll find this

414
00:30:13,961 --> 00:30:16,680
a very square-shouldered little wine, Cathy.

415
00:30:19,721 --> 00:30:21,712
I married him on the rebound.

416
00:30:21,761 --> 00:30:24,514
It was just after you left
and I was...

417
00:30:24,561 --> 00:30:26,358
I was in pieces.

418
00:30:27,881 --> 00:30:32,955
For a while I thought he was...
tearing up your letters.

419
00:30:33,001 --> 00:30:35,196
But there weren't any, were there?

420
00:30:35,241 --> 00:30:39,837
I had to be persona non grata, Cathy.

421
00:30:39,881 --> 00:30:41,758
Did I leave anything behind?

422
00:30:43,081 --> 00:30:44,230
Nancy?

423
00:30:44,281 --> 00:30:47,159
Oh, no. No.

424
00:30:47,201 --> 00:30:48,634
Nancy's not yours.

425
00:30:48,681 --> 00:30:51,036
And your husband?

426
00:30:52,361 --> 00:30:54,079
He died seven years ago.

427
00:30:55,481 --> 00:31:01,351
Cast a cold eye on life, on death.
Horseman, pass by.

428
00:31:01,401 --> 00:31:04,359
Horseman, pass by.

429
00:31:06,361 --> 00:31:08,431
He was a sweet man.

430
00:31:10,201 --> 00:31:12,510
Till the day he died he called me...

431
00:31:13,521 --> 00:31:15,796
Miss Dairy Goodness.

432
00:31:17,321 --> 00:31:20,393
- Why was that, then?
- (♪ Mariachi music)

433
00:31:50,361 --> 00:31:53,398
(♪ Irish folk music)

434
00:32:04,201 --> 00:32:06,192
(Cheering)

435
00:32:08,321 --> 00:32:10,551
I don't know.

436
00:32:10,601 --> 00:32:13,354
Maybe it's just us.
Was it him or wasn't it?

437
00:32:13,401 --> 00:32:16,598
You just take it
from one who knows, love.

438
00:32:16,641 --> 00:32:21,271
You close your eyes
and you cast your mind back 30 years,

439
00:32:21,321 --> 00:32:26,190
and you see and hear
what you want to see and hear.

440
00:32:30,281 --> 00:32:32,272
(Folk music continues, muffled)

441
00:32:45,401 --> 00:32:47,437
Are this lot having a good time
or aren't they?

442
00:32:47,481 --> 00:32:49,915
Will they have sore heads
in the morning or won't they?

443
00:32:49,961 --> 00:32:53,351
- Do I love you or don't I?
- You better, you better.

444
00:32:53,401 --> 00:32:55,357
- What about your ma and Mr X?
- What?

445
00:32:55,401 --> 00:32:56,834
Well, is it or isn't it?

446
00:32:56,881 --> 00:32:59,634
Are they or aren't they?
Will they or won't they?

447
00:32:59,681 --> 00:33:02,832
Look, love, is she going to worry tomorrow,
was it or wasn't it?

448
00:33:02,881 --> 00:33:05,349
The thing is, she's having a good time
and it's all down to us.

449
00:33:05,401 --> 00:33:08,074
I mean, stick with me
and you'll be farting through silk.

450
00:33:24,001 --> 00:33:27,277
I don't know who the fuck
that man is up there,

451
00:33:27,321 --> 00:33:31,633
but I know who you are, O'Neill,
and I know what you are.

452
00:33:34,041 --> 00:33:37,113
(People whispering)

453
00:33:42,121 --> 00:33:44,589
I should never have done this.

454
00:33:45,361 --> 00:33:47,352
Nancy.

455
00:33:47,401 --> 00:33:50,359
Get your coat. We're going home.

456
00:34:11,761 --> 00:34:13,558
(People gasping)

457
00:34:14,241 --> 00:34:16,152
(People muttering)

458
00:34:17,161 --> 00:34:19,994
- (AII shouting)
- (Man) I want my money back!

459
00:34:20,041 --> 00:34:23,590
Come on! I paid for tickets.
I want my money back.

460
00:34:26,801 --> 00:34:32,273
To ask you again, you have
no other sets of keys to the premises?

461
00:34:35,481 --> 00:34:38,598
And you have no other
personal assets or monies

462
00:34:38,641 --> 00:34:42,111
that you've not already declared
within this document?

463
00:34:45,281 --> 00:34:47,749
I'm sorry, I need a yes or a no.

464
00:34:49,201 --> 00:34:50,759
No.

465
00:34:50,801 --> 00:34:51,836
Thank you.

466
00:34:54,361 --> 00:34:55,999
Here's your copy.

467
00:35:22,521 --> 00:35:26,400
♪ When your heart is... ♪

468
00:35:27,441 --> 00:35:29,159
Thanks for showing up, fellas.

469
00:35:29,201 --> 00:35:31,192
What are we going to do, Micky?

470
00:35:32,241 --> 00:35:34,960
You're going to house-sit this place
for a couple of weeks.

471
00:35:35,001 --> 00:35:36,480
Why? What are you going to do?

472
00:35:38,961 --> 00:35:40,872
I'm going home.

473
00:35:44,561 --> 00:35:45,994
(Horn blares)

474
00:35:46,041 --> 00:35:47,235
Shut up, ya...

475
00:35:47,281 --> 00:35:49,317
(Siren wails)

476
00:35:52,761 --> 00:35:54,592
(Horn blares)

477
00:35:56,801 --> 00:35:59,110
Get out of here!

478
00:36:06,361 --> 00:36:07,760
(Horn)

479
00:36:54,601 --> 00:36:56,592
(Bell clanging)

480
00:37:06,441 --> 00:37:07,556
(Man) Morning.

481
00:37:16,041 --> 00:37:17,440
Hello.

482
00:37:20,481 --> 00:37:22,073
Give us one of those sandwiches.

483
00:37:22,121 --> 00:37:24,191
Hey? Yeah, thanks. Great.

484
00:37:27,241 --> 00:37:29,357
The strip.

485
00:37:29,401 --> 00:37:31,119
You want to sit in while you wait?

486
00:37:42,001 --> 00:37:43,992
(Typewriter clacking)

487
00:37:56,401 --> 00:38:01,839
You know, when I first met him
he hadn't two pins to rub together.

488
00:38:01,881 --> 00:38:04,634
Molly, this specimen
used to be Micky O'Neill.

489
00:38:05,721 --> 00:38:09,270
- We very rarely see him out in daylight.
- I need five pounds for the carriage, Fintan.

490
00:38:09,321 --> 00:38:11,437
Molly, petty cash, please.

491
00:38:14,761 --> 00:38:16,558
What's with the map?

492
00:38:16,601 --> 00:38:18,080
What the map shows, Mr O'Neill,

493
00:38:18,121 --> 00:38:20,919
is that each artist
is represented by a pinhead.

494
00:38:25,721 --> 00:38:27,120
How you doing?

495
00:38:27,161 --> 00:38:29,834
That's my mate there.
I haven't got any...

496
00:38:29,881 --> 00:38:31,553
Thanks very much. Thank you.

497
00:38:33,401 --> 00:38:34,436
Where do I come in?

498
00:38:34,481 --> 00:38:36,472
Look, have I asked you
for anything yet?

499
00:38:36,521 --> 00:38:37,920
No, but it's coming.

500
00:38:40,121 --> 00:38:41,713
I'm here to find Jo Locke.

501
00:38:43,881 --> 00:38:46,156
- Jesus Christ, you're a madman.
- Father.

502
00:38:46,201 --> 00:38:49,318
The man went AWOL 25 years ago,
no one's heard tell of him since.

503
00:38:49,361 --> 00:38:50,919
What if he's dead? God spare him.

504
00:38:50,961 --> 00:38:52,758
I know he's here, Fintan.

505
00:38:53,881 --> 00:38:58,193
He's more than just a booking to me.
Make some calls, will you?

506
00:39:01,321 --> 00:39:02,356
(Fintan) Yeah.

507
00:39:02,401 --> 00:39:04,961
Right. I have another one
for Killarney.

508
00:39:05,001 --> 00:39:07,310
Thanks, Noel. Yeah, they're fine.

509
00:39:07,361 --> 00:39:09,272
Yeah, Sheila's fine too. Thanks.

510
00:39:10,441 --> 00:39:13,001
Well, Noel says he thinks
he saw Jo Locke

511
00:39:13,041 --> 00:39:15,999
at a cattle auction in Tullamore
about 18 months ago.

512
00:39:16,041 --> 00:39:19,317
So, that's six for Arklow,
five for Killarney, four for Tralee,

513
00:39:19,361 --> 00:39:20,919
and one for Tullamore.

514
00:39:20,961 --> 00:39:22,314
Right.

515
00:39:22,361 --> 00:39:24,238
We go to Tullamore.

516
00:39:24,281 --> 00:39:27,398
Not me, Micky. Ha. No way.

517
00:39:27,441 --> 00:39:29,432
(♪ Movin')

518
00:39:48,081 --> 00:39:49,639
♪ Moving

519
00:39:49,681 --> 00:39:50,909
♪ My buddy and me

520
00:39:50,961 --> 00:39:52,189
♪ We're moving

521
00:39:52,241 --> 00:39:53,594
♪ The freeway before us

522
00:39:53,641 --> 00:39:54,630
♪ Eating it up

523
00:39:54,681 --> 00:39:56,239
♪ The sun in our eyes

524
00:39:56,281 --> 00:39:57,760
♪ We're moving
♪ Yeah

525
00:39:57,801 --> 00:39:58,995
♪ From Mobile to Maine, yeah

526
00:39:59,041 --> 00:40:00,269
♪ We're grooving

527
00:40:00,321 --> 00:40:01,640
♪ All glisten and chrome

528
00:40:01,681 --> 00:40:03,399
♪ Hi fiddle-dee-dee

529
00:40:03,441 --> 00:40:04,794
♪ If you mess with me

530
00:40:04,841 --> 00:40:06,320
♪ You mess with my buddy

531
00:40:06,361 --> 00:40:07,555
♪ And if you knew my buddy

532
00:40:07,601 --> 00:40:09,319
♪ I'm telling you, buddy

533
00:40:09,361 --> 00:40:13,912
♪ You'd never mess with me

534
00:40:13,961 --> 00:40:16,031
♪ Bud-doo-da, yeah ♪

535
00:40:16,081 --> 00:40:19,312
(Micky) That is good. That is good.

536
00:40:19,361 --> 00:40:21,352
(Thunder)

537
00:40:22,921 --> 00:40:24,559
You told me left!

538
00:40:24,601 --> 00:40:27,559
You said it was supposed to be left.
I don't know which way to go.

539
00:40:28,921 --> 00:40:31,355
How could we miss
the tower at Doonagore?

540
00:40:31,401 --> 00:40:34,154
There's only one explanation.
Take your jacket off.

541
00:40:34,201 --> 00:40:35,839
- What?
- Just do as I tell you.

542
00:40:35,881 --> 00:40:39,237
Take your jacket off,
turn it inside out, put it back on again.

543
00:40:39,281 --> 00:40:42,398
You're wired to the moon, O'Donnell.
What's that in aid of?

544
00:40:42,441 --> 00:40:44,079
The fairies.

545
00:40:45,321 --> 00:40:46,913
They get you lost on purpose.

546
00:40:46,961 --> 00:40:49,316
- The fairies?
- They are bastards.

547
00:41:12,961 --> 00:41:14,474
(Croaking)

548
00:41:17,121 --> 00:41:18,600
Where are you sleeping?

549
00:41:18,641 --> 00:41:21,439
Just fix the groundsheet, will you?
Do you take sugar?

550
00:41:21,481 --> 00:41:23,312
(Micky) Aye. Three.

551
00:41:23,361 --> 00:41:26,080
Three? You're as thin as a stick,
how come?

552
00:41:26,121 --> 00:41:27,315
(Micky) Worry.

553
00:41:33,961 --> 00:41:36,759
- Do you ever see any of the rest of them?
- Now and again.

554
00:41:36,801 --> 00:41:39,713
I see Keiran a wee bit. He's married.

555
00:41:39,761 --> 00:41:41,877
He's got seven children.

556
00:41:41,921 --> 00:41:44,037
We all heard you were
doing really well.

557
00:41:44,081 --> 00:41:46,959
There was even some rumour
about you going steady.

558
00:41:47,001 --> 00:41:48,593
Course, I didn't believe any of that.

559
00:41:49,881 --> 00:41:52,270
Aye, I blew it.

560
00:41:52,321 --> 00:41:54,198
Mrs Keegan was right.

561
00:41:54,241 --> 00:41:56,232
There's a bit of a want in me.

562
00:41:57,001 --> 00:41:58,673
I don't know what it is, though.

563
00:41:58,721 --> 00:42:01,519
Ah, well, she was right
about all of us.

564
00:42:02,561 --> 00:42:04,836
Switch that torch off.

565
00:42:04,881 --> 00:42:06,678
(Owl hoots)

566
00:42:49,921 --> 00:42:51,991
- This is the place.
- Aye, it's great, isn't it?

567
00:42:52,041 --> 00:42:53,838
No, this is the place we're looking for.

568
00:42:53,881 --> 00:42:57,760
- All right. God bless the little people.
- God bless them.

569
00:42:58,881 --> 00:43:01,475
Right, away down and get us
some water for a drop of tea?

570
00:43:01,521 --> 00:43:04,911
The well's empty,
there's a stream in the woods. Here.

571
00:43:07,961 --> 00:43:09,758
(Laughs)

572
00:43:27,801 --> 00:43:29,757
(Man) Here, girl!

573
00:43:29,801 --> 00:43:31,837
Here, girl!

574
00:43:31,881 --> 00:43:34,076
(Claps) Come on!

575
00:43:35,161 --> 00:43:36,389
That's it!

576
00:43:36,441 --> 00:43:38,318
(Dog whimpers)

577
00:43:38,361 --> 00:43:39,919
What do you see?

578
00:43:39,961 --> 00:43:42,714
(Sighs)

579
00:43:42,761 --> 00:43:45,480
Is it or isn't it?

580
00:43:49,081 --> 00:43:50,070
Yeah.

581
00:44:01,961 --> 00:44:04,521
Fintan! Fintan!

582
00:44:04,561 --> 00:44:07,280
- Start the car. Get her going.
- What?

583
00:44:07,321 --> 00:44:09,232
He's in that car.

584
00:44:09,281 --> 00:44:11,192
He's in that car, let's go.

585
00:44:11,241 --> 00:44:12,674
Where's my container?

586
00:44:12,721 --> 00:44:14,837
What about the trout? Jesus!

587
00:44:14,881 --> 00:44:16,394
(Micky) Come on.

588
00:44:20,801 --> 00:44:23,235
(Micky) Hurry up!
(Fintan) I love trout.

589
00:44:23,281 --> 00:44:26,034
- Come on, let's go, let's go!
- I'm coming, I'm coming!

590
00:44:26,081 --> 00:44:28,356
- Come on!
- It won't start!

591
00:44:32,681 --> 00:44:35,639
(Yelling)

592
00:44:35,681 --> 00:44:37,797
Yes, yes, yes, yes!

593
00:44:45,041 --> 00:44:47,396
- (Micky) Have you got the photograph?
- Under the seat.

594
00:44:49,121 --> 00:44:50,110
Is this it?

595
00:44:50,161 --> 00:44:52,595
That's the best I could do.

596
00:45:01,001 --> 00:45:02,559
(Tyres squeal)

597
00:45:06,721 --> 00:45:08,598
Jesus, you're a terrible driver.

598
00:45:08,641 --> 00:45:10,836
You should see me when I'm on my own.

599
00:45:10,881 --> 00:45:13,270
I'd hate to be with you
when you're on your own.

600
00:45:29,761 --> 00:45:32,036
- Do you have a lounge?
- Nope.

601
00:45:32,081 --> 00:45:34,834
- This is all there is to the pub, then?
- Yep.

602
00:45:34,881 --> 00:45:37,190
- Where are all the customers?
- What customers?

603
00:45:37,241 --> 00:45:39,471
The man in the black car,
where did he go?

604
00:45:39,521 --> 00:45:41,557
Sure, I'm not legally open yet, lads.

605
00:45:44,881 --> 00:45:46,280
All right, we'll wait.

606
00:45:54,921 --> 00:45:56,240
(Clicks tongue)

607
00:46:11,441 --> 00:46:14,990
Oh, will someone
for the love and honour o' God

608
00:46:15,041 --> 00:46:20,673
get me to a dentist quick,
for this tooth has me driven to distraction.

609
00:46:20,721 --> 00:46:22,837
Will you haud your wheesht,
John James?

610
00:46:22,881 --> 00:46:25,349
- I have the wife asleep above.
- Ah, to hell with your wife!

611
00:46:25,401 --> 00:46:29,030
I'd give two of your lambs
and a hunk of bacon

612
00:46:29,081 --> 00:46:33,040
to the man who can rid me
of this... this torture.

613
00:46:33,081 --> 00:46:36,676
What in the name of God
and His Holy Mother is going on here?

614
00:46:36,721 --> 00:46:39,474
Can a man not have
a quiet game of poker?

615
00:46:39,521 --> 00:46:42,513
John James needs a lift
to the dentist.

616
00:46:42,561 --> 00:46:44,392
Does he now?

617
00:46:44,441 --> 00:46:45,794
Come here, John.

618
00:46:45,841 --> 00:46:47,479
Let's have a look.

619
00:46:47,521 --> 00:46:50,194
- That's a big job, John James.
- (Man) Looks bad.

620
00:46:50,241 --> 00:46:54,996
I'll tell you what I'll do.
Brendan here used to be a vet.

621
00:46:56,441 --> 00:47:00,150
Now, if a man can take the tooth
out of a fiery stallion,

622
00:47:00,201 --> 00:47:02,669
he could do the same for yourself.

623
00:47:02,721 --> 00:47:04,279
Sure, we're all God's creatures.

624
00:47:04,321 --> 00:47:06,710
- Are you sure he's a vet?
- He's a great vet.

625
00:47:06,761 --> 00:47:08,319
But a terrible poker player.

626
00:47:10,681 --> 00:47:14,230
I'll go to the car
and get the tools of the trade.

627
00:47:14,281 --> 00:47:16,670
We'll need ten cloves
and a bottle of whiskey.

628
00:47:16,721 --> 00:47:18,757
- Coming right up.
- There we go. All right.

629
00:47:18,801 --> 00:47:20,519
Up here on the bar counter.

630
00:47:20,561 --> 00:47:23,871
(AII shouting)

631
00:47:23,921 --> 00:47:27,231
Put him right there.
This will be the work table.

632
00:47:27,281 --> 00:47:30,034
Get him up. Come on, come on.
Come on, hold it, hold it, hold it.

633
00:47:30,081 --> 00:47:31,434
Both of you.

634
00:47:31,481 --> 00:47:33,597
All right, John James, all right.
Hold on.

635
00:47:33,641 --> 00:47:35,791
We're just going to carry you here.

636
00:47:38,001 --> 00:47:40,356
Put your head back.
Put your head back.

637
00:47:40,401 --> 00:47:44,030
That's a boy. All right. Come on,
swallow it down. Swallow it down.

638
00:47:44,081 --> 00:47:45,400
One more, one more.

639
00:47:45,441 --> 00:47:47,591
One more, here you go. Up, up, up.

640
00:47:47,641 --> 00:47:51,350
God, I'm not going one step further
with this until I...

641
00:47:51,401 --> 00:47:52,550
Open up.

642
00:47:52,601 --> 00:47:54,592
(Gurgling)

643
00:47:55,961 --> 00:47:57,917
(Gurgling)

644
00:48:00,601 --> 00:48:02,159
- Is it that one?
- No.

645
00:48:04,881 --> 00:48:06,234
- Is it that one?
- No.

646
00:48:09,681 --> 00:48:10,955
Is it...

647
00:48:11,001 --> 00:48:12,719
Argh!

648
00:48:12,761 --> 00:48:14,114
Come on, John James. Come on.

649
00:48:14,161 --> 00:48:16,231
- Argh! Oh, God.
- Get it round him.

650
00:48:16,281 --> 00:48:19,114
Oh, God. Oh, God. Argh. Argh.

651
00:48:20,921 --> 00:48:22,320
(John James) I can't.

652
00:48:22,361 --> 00:48:24,955
I can't, boys.
I can't go through with it.

653
00:48:25,001 --> 00:48:27,231
Give him another drink
of that whiskey there.

654
00:48:27,281 --> 00:48:28,600
(John James) Ah!

655
00:48:28,641 --> 00:48:30,154
Whoop!

656
00:48:32,081 --> 00:48:34,151
(Laughing)

657
00:48:38,401 --> 00:48:40,551
That was great, fellas.
That was great!

658
00:48:40,601 --> 00:48:44,310
I'd like to buy us all a drink.
What are you having, Jo?

659
00:48:47,961 --> 00:48:52,751
I don't know about you boys
but I think I'll go back to the game.

660
00:48:52,801 --> 00:48:57,272
Uh-huh. Huh. Hey, there.

661
00:49:10,801 --> 00:49:13,190
(Dogs barking)

662
00:49:25,121 --> 00:49:27,954
(Micky) We have to go.
Leave it. Just let's go.

663
00:49:28,001 --> 00:49:30,310
(Fintan) It's Sheila's birthday.

664
00:49:35,641 --> 00:49:36,869
<i>(Girl) Daddy?</i>

665
00:49:36,921 --> 00:49:38,559
<i>Daddy, daddy?</i>

666
00:49:38,601 --> 00:49:41,240
(Auctioneer) 420, I'm bid 430.

667
00:49:41,281 --> 00:49:43,317
440, I'm bid. 440, I'm bid 50.

668
00:49:43,361 --> 00:49:46,239
450, I'm bid 50. 450, I'm bid 60.

669
00:49:46,281 --> 00:49:48,158
460. 460.

670
00:49:48,201 --> 00:49:49,998
Gonna be sold. 70, I'm bid 70.

671
00:49:50,041 --> 00:49:52,077
470, I'm bid 70. 470, 80.

672
00:49:52,121 --> 00:49:54,999
480, 480. 490, 490, 490. 500?

673
00:49:55,041 --> 00:49:57,919
490, gonna be sold. 500.
10. 510, I'm bid 10.

674
00:49:57,961 --> 00:49:59,872
510, I'm bid 20. 20.

675
00:49:59,921 --> 00:50:01,991
20, I'm bid 30. 30, I'm bid 30.

676
00:50:02,041 --> 00:50:05,954
- (Cattle mooing)
- (Men laughing)

677
00:50:06,001 --> 00:50:07,753
(Auctioneer) Selling at 40, 40.

678
00:50:07,801 --> 00:50:09,678
550, 550.

679
00:50:09,721 --> 00:50:12,838
550, and I'll sell it to you,
I'll sell at 550.

680
00:50:12,881 --> 00:50:15,031
I sell at 550. (Bangs gavel)

681
00:50:16,841 --> 00:50:19,833
And the next cow will be
a Simmental cow. Good one there.

682
00:50:19,881 --> 00:50:22,839
20, I'm bid 30. 30, I'm bid 430, 30.

683
00:50:22,881 --> 00:50:24,633
30, I'm bid 430, 40.

684
00:50:24,681 --> 00:50:26,273
440, I'm bid. 40, 40.

685
00:50:26,321 --> 00:50:28,357
40, I'm bid 50. 50, I'm bid.

686
00:50:28,401 --> 00:50:29,436
I'm bid 60.

687
00:50:29,481 --> 00:50:32,075
470. 70, I'm bid 70. 470, 80.

688
00:50:32,121 --> 00:50:33,918
480, 490. 490, 500.

689
00:50:33,961 --> 00:50:35,872
- 510, I'm bid 20. 20.
- (Mooing)

690
00:50:35,921 --> 00:50:37,115
20, I'm bid 30.

691
00:50:37,161 --> 00:50:39,117
30, I'm bid 530. 30, I'm bid 30.

692
00:50:39,161 --> 00:50:41,072
Selling at 40. 40, I'm bid 50.

693
00:50:41,121 --> 00:50:44,079
50, I'm bid 550. 550,
and I sell at 550.

694
00:50:44,121 --> 00:50:45,520
60. 70.

695
00:50:45,561 --> 00:50:48,029
70, I'm bid 80. 80, I'm bid 90.

696
00:50:48,081 --> 00:50:50,197
600, I'm bid 600. 610.

697
00:50:50,241 --> 00:50:52,277
610, 20. 620, 30.

698
00:50:52,321 --> 00:50:54,232
30, I'm bid 40. 40, I bid 50.

699
00:50:54,281 --> 00:50:55,919
- 50, I'm bid 60.
- (Men laughing)

700
00:50:55,961 --> 00:50:57,599
70. 70, I'm bid 80.

701
00:50:57,641 --> 00:51:00,075
80, 90. 90, I'm bid 7.
700, I'm bid 10.

702
00:51:00,121 --> 00:51:01,839
20. 20, I'm bid 30.

703
00:51:01,881 --> 00:51:03,917
Selling at 30. 40. 40, I'm bid 50.

704
00:51:03,961 --> 00:51:05,872
And I sell at 750.

705
00:51:05,921 --> 00:51:08,276
(Cheering, laughter)

706
00:51:08,321 --> 00:51:10,710
Good on yourself. Good lad.
See you next week.

707
00:51:17,841 --> 00:51:20,560
(Fintan) Thank Christ
we're not vegetarians.

708
00:51:20,601 --> 00:51:22,193
We're in a shaggy dog story.

709
00:51:22,241 --> 00:51:23,993
This is my ticket.

710
00:51:24,041 --> 00:51:25,838
I'm giving her to Jo.

711
00:51:25,881 --> 00:51:27,075
It's not yours to give.

712
00:51:27,121 --> 00:51:29,999
I told you I'd pay you back
the 700 quid.

713
00:51:30,041 --> 00:51:31,554
750.

714
00:51:34,681 --> 00:51:36,672
I need this guy.

715
00:51:38,121 --> 00:51:39,918
Let me call the shots.

716
00:51:42,361 --> 00:51:44,431
(Peacock calling)

717
00:51:47,361 --> 00:51:49,317
(Fintan) Come on, easy.

718
00:51:56,161 --> 00:51:58,391
Come on. Come along.

719
00:52:02,721 --> 00:52:05,076
Right, you're coming with me.
Come on.

720
00:52:06,521 --> 00:52:08,159
(Micky) Come on.

721
00:52:22,161 --> 00:52:24,675
I don't know what youse
have done to him now,

722
00:52:24,721 --> 00:52:28,077
but he was that angry, he took
himself upstairs for a lie-down.

723
00:52:28,121 --> 00:52:32,160
- Well, you see, this gentleman...
- I don't want to hear about it.

724
00:52:32,201 --> 00:52:33,998
Give me the cow.

725
00:52:34,041 --> 00:52:36,032
I'll put it in the field.

726
00:52:36,081 --> 00:52:38,470
And take yourselves
down to the washhouse.

727
00:52:38,521 --> 00:52:41,399
There's a smell off the two of you
as would gag a tramp.

728
00:52:42,881 --> 00:52:44,872
(Clucking, mooing, crowing)

729
00:52:50,361 --> 00:52:52,829
(Honking)

730
00:52:57,161 --> 00:52:58,753
May I just take this opportunity, sir,

731
00:52:58,801 --> 00:53:01,235
to thank you for receiving us
in your splendid home.

732
00:53:01,281 --> 00:53:02,839
And for clothing us.

733
00:53:02,881 --> 00:53:04,997
You're probably wondering
what all this is about.

734
00:53:05,041 --> 00:53:08,431
I'm not going to beat about the bush,
that's not me. That's right, isn't it, Fintan?

735
00:53:08,481 --> 00:53:09,800
Fintan.

736
00:53:09,841 --> 00:53:11,069
May the road rise before you.

737
00:53:11,121 --> 00:53:13,635
And may the wind
be always at your back.

738
00:53:13,681 --> 00:53:15,080
Good luck.

739
00:53:16,361 --> 00:53:19,034
Now... Mr Locke.

740
00:53:19,081 --> 00:53:20,992
I'm 30.

741
00:53:22,321 --> 00:53:23,515
I was born in peacetime.

742
00:53:24,801 --> 00:53:28,510
I haven't been where you've been.
I haven't seen what you've seen.

743
00:53:31,681 --> 00:53:34,070
You know, Mr Locke...

744
00:53:34,121 --> 00:53:37,352
when I first heard you sing...

745
00:53:38,361 --> 00:53:39,794
What song was that?

746
00:53:41,921 --> 00:53:43,400
Cathleen.

747
00:53:43,441 --> 00:53:45,591
We'll Make A Bonfire, it's got to be.

748
00:53:45,641 --> 00:53:47,552
Was it live or recorded, Micky?

749
00:53:49,201 --> 00:53:51,032
Was it live or recorded?

750
00:53:51,081 --> 00:53:53,879
Was it live or recorded?
Was it live or recorded?

751
00:53:53,921 --> 00:53:59,871
The French four-glass clock.
How long has it been stopped?

752
00:53:59,921 --> 00:54:03,118
It's an old thing of me father's.
Hasn't moved in years.

753
00:54:03,161 --> 00:54:05,356
Have you any methylated spirits
in the house?

754
00:54:05,401 --> 00:54:10,873
I, er, can't promise you anything
but I've got these ones moving in the past.

755
00:54:12,441 --> 00:54:14,079
(Jo) Meths, huh?

756
00:54:14,121 --> 00:54:16,112
(Peacock calling)

757
00:54:18,801 --> 00:54:20,792
Christ. Give us a drink.

758
00:54:24,921 --> 00:54:27,355
You haven't a fucking clue
what you're doing, have you?

759
00:54:27,401 --> 00:54:32,191
Neither have you, you bollocks.
"I was born in peacetime." Jeez.

760
00:54:32,241 --> 00:54:34,550
At least I bought you some time.
How's it going anyway?

761
00:54:34,601 --> 00:54:37,559
He doesn't need the money, Fintan.
That's it. That is it.

762
00:54:37,601 --> 00:54:40,513
- How much did you offer him?
- I offered him a lot of money.

763
00:54:40,561 --> 00:54:42,916
Still, he's taking me out
for a drink, so you never know.

764
00:54:42,961 --> 00:54:44,110
Do you like the coat?

765
00:54:44,161 --> 00:54:46,721
Watch yourself. We're on his turf,
keep your eyes peeled.

766
00:54:46,761 --> 00:54:48,638
- I have to hang in there.
- Micky.

767
00:54:50,041 --> 00:54:52,111
You could do worse
than tell him the truth.

768
00:54:52,161 --> 00:54:55,790
Ha! That'd be something,
wouldn't it?

769
00:55:02,641 --> 00:55:04,120
(Bell chimes)

770
00:55:07,641 --> 00:55:09,233
(Thunder)

771
00:55:14,081 --> 00:55:15,400
(Micky) Look, Jo,

772
00:55:15,441 --> 00:55:18,001
it's not hard to imagine
the kind of publicity

773
00:55:18,041 --> 00:55:19,474
a comeback like yours would get.

774
00:55:19,521 --> 00:55:22,115
I mean, you haven't sung in 25 years.

775
00:55:22,161 --> 00:55:24,311
The women, Jo. The women.

776
00:55:24,361 --> 00:55:26,829
There wouldn't be a dry seat
in the house.

777
00:55:26,881 --> 00:55:28,872
It would be a celebration
of your career.

778
00:55:28,921 --> 00:55:31,958
No, Micky, it would be
a celebration of yours.

779
00:55:33,081 --> 00:55:35,914
Look, Jo, there's a big audience,

780
00:55:35,961 --> 00:55:38,521
a big audience out there
waiting to see you.

781
00:55:38,561 --> 00:55:40,552
I know, I've seen them.

782
00:55:43,681 --> 00:55:45,239
(Jo) What are you talking about?

783
00:55:45,281 --> 00:55:48,114
(Micky) Well, I mean, I can see them.
Don't you want to see them?

784
00:56:03,841 --> 00:56:05,832
Do you see those girls, Micky?

785
00:56:08,001 --> 00:56:10,390
Would you like to be responsible
for their dreams?

786
00:56:51,361 --> 00:56:54,194
(Micky) I thought you were
taking me for a drink.

787
00:56:54,241 --> 00:56:55,913
Fuck me! What's this place?

788
00:56:55,961 --> 00:56:58,919
(Jo) Aye. Would you look at it!

789
00:57:06,721 --> 00:57:08,120
What is this place?

790
00:57:09,881 --> 00:57:12,076
This used to be the edge
of the known world, Micky.

791
00:57:13,081 --> 00:57:15,834
Now, the next parish is New York.

792
00:57:18,641 --> 00:57:20,711
(Bats chirping)

793
00:57:21,801 --> 00:57:23,393
Try a drop of that.

794
00:57:28,841 --> 00:57:30,240
Come on.

795
00:57:31,521 --> 00:57:33,637
(Gasps)

796
00:57:54,721 --> 00:57:57,997
Jo, you can be straight with me.

797
00:57:58,041 --> 00:58:00,475
I mean, I'm sure the thought
of being arrested at your age

798
00:58:00,521 --> 00:58:01,556
must be frightening.

799
00:58:01,601 --> 00:58:04,354
But surely you haven't lost
your edge for a fight.

800
00:58:04,401 --> 00:58:06,676
I mean, we've all got
to face our demons, Jo.

801
00:58:07,561 --> 00:58:09,597
Shit. Jesus Christ!

802
00:58:09,641 --> 00:58:11,233
Oh, God!

803
00:58:11,281 --> 00:58:15,274
In the old days here, Micky,
the sailors never learned to swim.

804
00:58:16,641 --> 00:58:19,713
Gave them more respect for the sea.

805
00:58:20,161 --> 00:58:21,833
(Micky) Whoa! Jesus!

806
00:58:21,881 --> 00:58:24,190
Over here, come on.

807
00:58:24,241 --> 00:58:25,959
No. No!

808
00:58:26,001 --> 00:58:27,434
Right here. Yeah.

809
00:58:27,481 --> 00:58:29,915
- Grab hold of him. That's it.
- (Yelling)

810
00:58:29,961 --> 00:58:31,599
Take hold here.

811
00:58:31,641 --> 00:58:37,034
Right. Now, who are you,
what do you want? I want the truth.

812
00:58:37,081 --> 00:58:39,641
My name's Micky O'Neill!

813
00:58:39,681 --> 00:58:42,957
I'm a concert promoter!

814
00:58:43,001 --> 00:58:44,434
(Laughter)

815
00:58:46,361 --> 00:58:49,034
Honest to God, boys.

816
00:58:49,081 --> 00:58:52,118
I'm not wearing me own clothes.

817
00:58:52,161 --> 00:58:53,753
(Laughter)

818
00:58:55,281 --> 00:58:57,112
Well, lads, all I can say is,

819
00:58:57,161 --> 00:59:00,233
you know you're getting older
when the taxmen start getting younger.

820
00:59:00,281 --> 00:59:03,273
Thank God they don't get
any wiser, Jo, eh?

821
00:59:03,321 --> 00:59:07,439
Taxman? I'm not the taxman,
for Christ's sake, I'm not!

822
00:59:07,481 --> 00:59:09,836
- Then what are you after me for?
- I want you to come back.

823
00:59:09,881 --> 00:59:12,714
- I want you to do a gig.
- Why are you doing it?

824
00:59:12,761 --> 00:59:14,399
I'm doing it for the people.

825
00:59:14,441 --> 00:59:15,669
Bullshit.

826
00:59:15,721 --> 00:59:18,440
He hasn't uttered a word of truth
in the day and hour he arrived.

827
00:59:18,481 --> 00:59:20,153
Well, what do you want me to say?

828
00:59:20,201 --> 00:59:22,556
I want you to tell me,
what's in it for you?

829
00:59:22,601 --> 00:59:24,080
What do you want?

830
00:59:25,361 --> 00:59:28,080
- Come on, come on.
- Oh, shit!

831
00:59:28,121 --> 00:59:30,954
The simple truth, Micky.

832
00:59:37,761 --> 00:59:39,353
Nancy.

833
00:59:40,481 --> 00:59:41,630
Nancy.

834
00:59:42,681 --> 00:59:43,830
Nancy!

835
00:59:43,881 --> 00:59:46,395
I'm doing this for Nancy.

836
00:59:50,361 --> 00:59:51,430
Who's Nancy?

837
00:59:52,881 --> 00:59:55,315
My girlfriend.

838
00:59:55,361 --> 00:59:56,953
The girl I...

839
00:59:58,281 --> 00:59:59,316
...Iove.

840
00:59:59,361 --> 01:00:01,238
I'm doing this for her!

841
01:00:03,561 --> 01:00:05,199
OK. Come on.

842
01:00:47,161 --> 01:00:49,117
(Fintan snoring)

843
01:00:49,161 --> 01:00:51,152
(Dog whimpers)

844
01:01:04,561 --> 01:01:07,075
(Laughter)

845
01:01:07,121 --> 01:01:08,839
Micky!

846
01:01:08,881 --> 01:01:10,712
At least you tried.

847
01:01:10,761 --> 01:01:14,674
Go back for Nancy.
Sure it can't be all that serious.

848
01:01:14,721 --> 01:01:16,712
I booked you.

849
01:01:16,761 --> 01:01:18,080
What do you mean you booked me?

850
01:01:18,121 --> 01:01:20,157
I thought I was booking you
but I booked a fake.

851
01:01:20,201 --> 01:01:22,920
- I didn't get away with it.
- Bad, was he?

852
01:01:25,921 --> 01:01:27,639
No, he was all right.

853
01:01:27,681 --> 01:01:28,909
In fact, he was so all right,

854
01:01:28,961 --> 01:01:32,078
he managed, with my help I might add,
to seduce an old flame of yours.

855
01:01:32,121 --> 01:01:35,796
(Jo) There's a few of those around.
(Man) You're right there, Jo!

856
01:01:35,841 --> 01:01:37,240
(Laughter)

857
01:01:38,441 --> 01:01:40,875
Yeah, well, Cathleen just happens
to be Nancy's mother.

858
01:01:40,921 --> 01:01:43,196
She didn't like me in the first place,
now she hates me,

859
01:01:43,241 --> 01:01:46,039
and I was just trying to cheer her up,
so don't talk to me about serious!

860
01:01:47,721 --> 01:01:49,916
I've lost me money, me business...

861
01:01:49,961 --> 01:01:51,872
my friends.

862
01:01:51,921 --> 01:01:53,354
The girl I love.

863
01:01:55,041 --> 01:01:58,272
It's all because
of some fucking tenor...

864
01:01:58,321 --> 01:02:00,471
who hasn't sung in 25 years

865
01:02:00,521 --> 01:02:03,991
and has the audacity
to turn down six grand a week!

866
01:02:06,601 --> 01:02:08,273
Cathleen.

867
01:02:08,321 --> 01:02:12,394
Cathleen Doyle, she was
Miss Dairy Goodness in the '50s.

868
01:02:21,241 --> 01:02:23,471
1958.

869
01:02:27,081 --> 01:02:30,153
Out of the mouths of babes.

870
01:02:40,721 --> 01:02:43,519
How are you going to feel
if you don't go back for her, Micky?

871
01:02:45,361 --> 01:02:47,158
I don't know.

872
01:02:47,201 --> 01:02:48,600
Well, I know.

873
01:02:51,241 --> 01:02:55,120
And I wouldn't wish it on anyone.

874
01:02:59,801 --> 01:03:03,555
Not even a contemptible skitter
like yourself.

875
01:03:08,361 --> 01:03:11,239
How do we want to be remembered, Micky?

876
01:03:26,481 --> 01:03:28,472
What shape's the Sea Spray in?

877
01:03:29,881 --> 01:03:32,554
She'll take you anywhere, Jo.

878
01:03:32,601 --> 01:03:34,478
Is she still at Ballycotton?

879
01:03:34,521 --> 01:03:36,159
She's never left.

880
01:03:38,681 --> 01:03:40,911
We sail at first light.

881
01:03:47,201 --> 01:03:48,793
(Chatter)

882
01:04:06,401 --> 01:04:09,677
I don't know what his real name is, Jo,
but he calls himself Mr X.

883
01:04:09,721 --> 01:04:11,598
But don't worry, I'll deal with him.

884
01:04:11,641 --> 01:04:15,759
You know what, I will deal with him.
I'll have his bollocks in a jam jar.

885
01:04:15,801 --> 01:04:18,190
All right, Jo, but trust me,
I'll find him for you.

886
01:04:19,121 --> 01:04:21,954
You think I trust you, Micky?

887
01:04:22,001 --> 01:04:25,596
There's a well in the field out there.
Nobody knows how deep it is.

888
01:04:25,641 --> 01:04:28,553
If you're trying to pull a flanker on me
like others have in the past,

889
01:04:28,601 --> 01:04:30,557
you'll end up at the bottom of it.

890
01:04:30,601 --> 01:04:34,435
And one other thing,
I think you'll be leaving me the cow.

891
01:04:34,481 --> 01:04:38,440
No sweat, Jo,
that was always the idea.

892
01:04:44,361 --> 01:04:45,476
(Thud)

893
01:04:47,361 --> 01:04:49,192
What time do we leave?

894
01:04:49,241 --> 01:04:50,879
What time is it now?

895
01:05:04,401 --> 01:05:06,278
(Fintan) You see? You see?

896
01:05:06,321 --> 01:05:09,711
This is what happens
when you tell the truth, Micky.

897
01:05:09,761 --> 01:05:11,797
- What time do you leave?
- (Micky) Six.

898
01:05:11,841 --> 01:05:13,832
How did you manage to fix that clock?

899
01:05:13,881 --> 01:05:15,951
(Fintan) I don't know.
How did you persuade him?

900
01:05:16,001 --> 01:05:17,195
(Micky) I don't know.

901
01:05:17,241 --> 01:05:21,439
Cathleen, Nancy's ma. Her and Jo
were more of an item than I thought.

902
01:05:21,481 --> 01:05:23,949
- No wonder she was pissed off.
- (Laughs)

903
01:05:24,001 --> 01:05:25,354
This is it.

904
01:05:25,401 --> 01:05:26,834
- This is it.
- (Fintan) What?

905
01:05:26,881 --> 01:05:27,950
(Micky) Jo's well.

906
01:05:28,001 --> 01:05:29,992
He says nobody knows how deep it is.

907
01:05:36,441 --> 01:05:38,636
(Micky) Give us a coin.
(Fintan) Piss off.

908
01:05:38,681 --> 01:05:40,478
Fine, then I'll use me own.

909
01:05:43,041 --> 01:05:45,555
- (Flick)
- Sh. Sh.

910
01:05:47,321 --> 01:05:50,119
- Aye, so it's deep. Come on.
- Bollocks. Let's get something else.

911
01:05:50,161 --> 01:05:51,150
Why?

912
01:05:51,201 --> 01:05:53,237
Because I want to see how deep it is.

913
01:05:53,281 --> 01:05:55,158
This is pointless.
I'll see you at the tent.

914
01:05:55,201 --> 01:05:56,190
Here goes.

915
01:05:58,801 --> 01:06:03,591
Three, four, five, six,

916
01:06:03,641 --> 01:06:08,237
seven, eight, nine, ten,

917
01:06:08,281 --> 01:06:10,272
11, 12...

918
01:06:10,321 --> 01:06:11,390
I hate things like this.

919
01:06:11,441 --> 01:06:17,311
...13, 14, 15, 16.
- Jesus Christ, I can't stand it!

920
01:06:17,361 --> 01:06:19,477
Yeah, you're right.
Let's go back to the tent.

921
01:06:19,521 --> 01:06:21,512
No, no, no. Here, here, look.
Look, here.

922
01:06:21,561 --> 01:06:24,519
Give me a hand with this. Come on.
Up, right.

923
01:06:24,561 --> 01:06:26,040
(Both) Ah! Argh!

924
01:06:26,081 --> 01:06:27,196
Argh!

925
01:06:27,241 --> 01:06:28,469
(Fintan) Get it up, get it up.

926
01:06:28,521 --> 01:06:29,510
(BIows raspberry)

927
01:06:29,561 --> 01:06:30,550
Oh.

928
01:06:30,601 --> 01:06:34,480
Take that, you great big gaping hole.

929
01:06:35,721 --> 01:06:37,200
(Bellows)

930
01:06:38,041 --> 01:06:41,078
Jesus Christ, it's the cow!
Chop the chain!

931
01:06:43,001 --> 01:06:44,639
(Fintan) Come on. Go back.

932
01:06:44,681 --> 01:06:47,991
(Micky) I'll grab the chain.
You go back!

933
01:06:48,041 --> 01:06:50,032
(Fintan) I've got it, I've got it!

934
01:06:50,081 --> 01:06:52,436
- What do you want me to do?
- Go back to the bloody cow!

935
01:06:52,481 --> 01:06:53,630
Are you all right?

936
01:06:53,681 --> 01:06:55,399
Cut it off the blasted chain!

937
01:06:55,441 --> 01:06:58,319
- (Micky) It's not working.
- I know that. I know.

938
01:06:58,361 --> 01:07:00,921
Just stop. Just stop.

939
01:07:00,961 --> 01:07:04,033
(Fintan) Slow the damn thing down,
for Christ's sake!

940
01:07:05,241 --> 01:07:08,472
It won't stop.
It's picked up the pace.

941
01:07:08,521 --> 01:07:10,193
(Fintan) Stop!

942
01:07:10,241 --> 01:07:11,230
Argh.

943
01:07:12,481 --> 01:07:14,119
(Moos)

944
01:07:21,721 --> 01:07:24,189
(Splashing)

945
01:07:24,241 --> 01:07:26,311
(Moos)

946
01:07:26,361 --> 01:07:28,352
(CIock ticking)

947
01:07:33,761 --> 01:07:36,480
- Got it?
- Yep.

948
01:07:37,761 --> 01:07:39,558
Can you get that?

949
01:08:06,081 --> 01:08:08,072
(Seagulls cry)

950
01:08:31,161 --> 01:08:32,560
Hi, Jo.

951
01:08:32,601 --> 01:08:35,354
The engine's humming like a bird, Jo.

952
01:08:35,401 --> 01:08:37,073
Hi, Jo.

953
01:08:38,481 --> 01:08:39,800
Hi, Jo.

954
01:08:39,841 --> 01:08:41,593
(Laughter)

955
01:08:43,441 --> 01:08:45,636
So, clocks are your trade, are they?

956
01:08:45,681 --> 01:08:48,400
No, I'm actually a theatrical agent.

957
01:09:12,721 --> 01:09:15,110
When are you gonna let me
meet the wife and kids?

958
01:09:15,161 --> 01:09:18,437
- You know you can meet them any time.
- Yeah, I know. I know.

959
01:09:20,481 --> 01:09:24,679
- Fintan, what have I ever done for you?
- Nothing. But it doesn't matter.

960
01:09:29,401 --> 01:09:31,710
See you later, alligator!

961
01:09:32,841 --> 01:09:34,877
In a while, crocodile.

962
01:10:00,441 --> 01:10:02,477
(Jo) ♪ Laaaa

963
01:10:02,521 --> 01:10:06,400
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la

964
01:10:06,441 --> 01:10:08,432
(Hums)

965
01:10:12,081 --> 01:10:15,551
♪ Hear my

966
01:10:17,241 --> 01:10:20,870
♪ Hear my

967
01:10:20,921 --> 01:10:23,230
♪ Song

968
01:10:23,281 --> 01:10:26,557
♪ Vi-Vi

969
01:10:26,601 --> 01:10:30,719
♪ Violetta

970
01:10:32,361 --> 01:10:36,195
♪ Hear my song

971
01:10:36,241 --> 01:10:38,755
♪ Beneath

972
01:10:38,801 --> 01:10:44,797
♪ 'Neath the moon

973
01:10:44,841 --> 01:10:49,437
♪ Come to me

974
01:10:49,481 --> 01:10:53,793
♪ In my gondola

975
01:10:53,841 --> 01:10:57,038
♪ Waiting on

976
01:10:57,081 --> 01:11:01,871
♪ The old lagoon

977
01:11:04,641 --> 01:11:07,474
♪ Serenade

978
01:11:07,521 --> 01:11:10,672
♪ Across the water

979
01:11:14,201 --> 01:11:19,878
♪ Can you hear it soft and low?

980
01:11:22,201 --> 01:11:27,229
♪ A tale of love and lovers

981
01:11:27,281 --> 01:11:28,873
♪ Singing

982
01:11:28,921 --> 01:11:33,472
♪ Long ago

983
01:11:35,441 --> 01:11:40,310
♪ Hear my song

984
01:11:40,361 --> 01:11:46,231
♪ <i>In my gondola</i>

985
01:11:46,281 --> 01:11:49,671
♪ <i>Waiting on</i>

986
01:11:49,721 --> 01:11:55,034
♪ <i>The old lagoon</i> ♪

987
01:12:09,481 --> 01:12:11,039
It's up to you, Jo.

988
01:12:11,881 --> 01:12:14,315
What do you think?

989
01:12:18,161 --> 01:12:20,595
Ah, sure! This is grand.

990
01:13:10,041 --> 01:13:13,238
(Faint laughter)

991
01:13:13,281 --> 01:13:16,273
(Chatter)

992
01:13:33,481 --> 01:13:35,358
Do you have any fags, boys?

993
01:13:42,881 --> 01:13:44,234
You the stage manager, love?

994
01:13:45,641 --> 01:13:48,758
Pop over the road
and get me 20 cigarettes.

995
01:13:51,201 --> 01:13:53,271
Keep the change.

996
01:13:53,321 --> 01:13:54,674
Ta, love.

997
01:13:58,561 --> 01:14:00,517
Yeah, sure.

998
01:14:33,841 --> 01:14:35,957
(Dog barks)

999
01:14:48,041 --> 01:14:49,394
(Coughs)

1000
01:14:58,081 --> 01:15:01,960
Boys, you've got to start somewhere.

1001
01:15:02,001 --> 01:15:03,229
- Ha!
- Ben. Benny.

1002
01:15:03,281 --> 01:15:04,270
Benny.

1003
01:15:05,961 --> 01:15:08,714
- Good to see you.
- How are you doing?

1004
01:15:08,761 --> 01:15:10,717
You all right?

1005
01:15:10,761 --> 01:15:12,558
(Chatter)

1006
01:15:14,001 --> 01:15:15,354
Thank you.

1007
01:15:19,081 --> 01:15:22,312
- Hey, who are you?
- I'm in charge. Who are you?

1008
01:15:22,361 --> 01:15:23,714
(Laughter)

1009
01:15:25,121 --> 01:15:27,237
Benny Rose.

1010
01:15:27,281 --> 01:15:29,795
- Where's the dots?
- What dots?

1011
01:15:29,841 --> 01:15:31,240
The music.

1012
01:15:31,281 --> 01:15:33,272
Ah. Haven't you got it?

1013
01:15:33,321 --> 01:15:34,720
Aye.

1014
01:15:40,001 --> 01:15:41,400
Fucking watch.

1015
01:15:41,441 --> 01:15:43,557
You've got one hour.

1016
01:15:43,601 --> 01:15:45,080
Right.

1017
01:15:45,121 --> 01:15:46,998
Blimey, what a geezer. Come on.

1018
01:15:47,041 --> 01:15:48,030
(Laughter)

1019
01:15:48,081 --> 01:15:51,994
Ouch! Easy! It's all unnecessary,
I'm telling you.

1020
01:15:52,041 --> 01:15:55,192
Look, look, look, you see,
I've reached a stage in my life now

1021
01:15:55,241 --> 01:15:58,039
where, basically,
I don't argue with people.

1022
01:16:10,281 --> 01:16:11,475
(Tyres screech)

1023
01:16:15,481 --> 01:16:18,917
- Do you have any sheet music?
- (Man) I don't sell sheet music.

1024
01:16:32,081 --> 01:16:34,641
(Fake Jo laughs)

1025
01:16:34,681 --> 01:16:37,479
So, a Jewish landlady came up to me
in Blackpool

1026
01:16:37,521 --> 01:16:38,874
and she hit me with her handbag.

1027
01:16:38,921 --> 01:16:40,673
I said, "What's that for?"
And she said,

1028
01:16:40,721 --> 01:16:43,315
"You know very well.
What are you doing back in the country?"

1029
01:16:43,361 --> 01:16:45,795
So, you see, Jo, wherever I went
I wasn't allowed to be me.

1030
01:16:45,841 --> 01:16:48,719
And sure, isn't that all any of us
want to be, Jo, individuals.

1031
01:16:48,761 --> 01:16:50,956
Well, I've kept you boys long enough.

1032
01:16:51,001 --> 01:16:52,070
Why did you do it?

1033
01:16:52,121 --> 01:16:55,397
It's the other side of the coin, Jo.
I did it to keep your name alive.

1034
01:16:55,441 --> 01:16:57,477
You're an entertainer, aren't you?

1035
01:16:57,521 --> 01:16:58,590
I am.

1036
01:16:58,641 --> 01:17:00,597
You'd like to make people happy,
wouldn't you?

1037
01:17:00,641 --> 01:17:01,756
I would.

1038
01:17:02,801 --> 01:17:05,520
Do you think you made
Cathleen Doyle happy?

1039
01:17:15,081 --> 01:17:16,912
(Dentist's drill)

1040
01:17:16,961 --> 01:17:19,429
You can't take that animal
into a dentist's surgery.

1041
01:17:19,481 --> 01:17:21,995
It's not an animal, it's a whippet.

1042
01:17:23,041 --> 01:17:24,554
Look, I'm in deep shit.

1043
01:17:24,601 --> 01:17:27,718
I have to find the music for Jo Locke.
I've been all over town.

1044
01:17:27,761 --> 01:17:30,559
I can't find nothing. I want you to come
with me. What do you say?

1045
01:17:35,801 --> 01:17:38,156
- How much?
- What?

1046
01:17:39,961 --> 01:17:42,998
- How much will you pay me?
- Christ, this isn't about money.

1047
01:17:43,041 --> 01:17:45,919
Then what is it about, Micky?

1048
01:17:48,361 --> 01:17:50,352
It's about Micky O'Neill
going to Ireland,

1049
01:17:50,401 --> 01:17:53,154
nearly getting killed and bringing back
a singer to sing for nothing

1050
01:17:53,201 --> 01:17:56,318
to a crowd of bastards
who probably won't even appreciate it.

1051
01:17:56,361 --> 01:17:59,273
I've got 35 minutes
before the orchestra walks off.

1052
01:17:59,321 --> 01:18:02,438
For the first time in my life
I haven't one single idea in my head,

1053
01:18:02,481 --> 01:18:04,358
and all I can think about is you.

1054
01:18:08,361 --> 01:18:10,431
Now, you tell me what that means.

1055
01:18:17,921 --> 01:18:20,481
Just say it, Micky.

1056
01:18:23,561 --> 01:18:24,789
I love you.

1057
01:18:31,161 --> 01:18:33,470
And I want you to love me.

1058
01:18:48,881 --> 01:18:51,634
I'm sorry about Cathleen, Jo,
I really am.

1059
01:18:53,161 --> 01:18:57,677
All this bullshit aside,
she told me her side of the story.

1060
01:18:57,721 --> 01:19:02,875
She wanted me to be you so much.

1061
01:19:02,921 --> 01:19:03,990
That...

1062
01:19:04,041 --> 01:19:06,236
Look, any of you guys got a light?

1063
01:19:18,161 --> 01:19:20,880
In truth, Jo...

1064
01:19:20,921 --> 01:19:23,389
I'm only to blame...

1065
01:19:23,441 --> 01:19:26,194
because you're to blame.

1066
01:19:29,121 --> 01:19:31,715
No offence, Jo...

1067
01:19:31,761 --> 01:19:35,117
but do you think you made
Cathleen Doyle happy?

1068
01:19:44,401 --> 01:19:45,959
I didn't, did I?

1069
01:19:50,081 --> 01:19:52,151
Do you know why I'm here?

1070
01:19:52,201 --> 01:19:54,476
I'm hoping it's to sing.

1071
01:19:54,521 --> 01:19:56,512
Might put you out of a job.

1072
01:20:04,761 --> 01:20:06,911
When the surgeon went in here...

1073
01:20:09,521 --> 01:20:10,954
...he said I had a large heart.

1074
01:20:15,321 --> 01:20:17,960
Maybe there's room in this world
for two Jo Lockes.

1075
01:20:36,201 --> 01:20:37,634
- There she is.
- OK.

1076
01:20:37,681 --> 01:20:38,670
OK.

1077
01:20:38,721 --> 01:20:41,952
You're in luck.
His arrangements are registered.

1078
01:20:42,001 --> 01:20:44,640
Have you completed the buff form?

1079
01:20:44,681 --> 01:20:46,956
Yes. Here you go.

1080
01:20:47,001 --> 01:20:48,559
Yes, good.

1081
01:20:48,601 --> 01:20:50,557
You can collect these in...

1082
01:20:50,601 --> 01:20:52,239
oh, ten days.

1083
01:21:00,081 --> 01:21:03,437
We were born in peacetime.

1084
01:21:08,801 --> 01:21:10,917
We haven't been where you've been.

1085
01:21:12,481 --> 01:21:15,120
We haven't seen what you've seen.

1086
01:21:20,681 --> 01:21:21,875
- Thank you.
- Bye.

1087
01:21:21,921 --> 01:21:24,481
Yeah, yeah. See you again.

1088
01:21:31,521 --> 01:21:33,113
What did he say to you?

1089
01:21:33,161 --> 01:21:36,198
Did he tell you you were
the most beautiful woman he'd ever met?

1090
01:21:36,241 --> 01:21:38,880
Yes. Is that what you're going to say?

1091
01:21:48,121 --> 01:21:49,520
No.

1092
01:21:50,681 --> 01:21:52,273
I'm just here...

1093
01:21:56,441 --> 01:21:58,796
I'm just here...

1094
01:21:58,841 --> 01:22:00,672
to remind you that you are.

1095
01:22:00,721 --> 01:22:02,712
(♪ Band playing Hear My Song)

1096
01:22:31,681 --> 01:22:35,037
Sure, I'd rather be in jail
than in love again.

1097
01:22:36,641 --> 01:22:38,677
(Band warming up instruments)

1098
01:22:42,521 --> 01:22:44,591
- It's too late.
- Yeah.

1099
01:22:58,321 --> 01:23:00,881
(Sighs) Did I say get the originals?

1100
01:23:00,921 --> 01:23:02,354
No.

1101
01:23:03,321 --> 01:23:04,993
Then I'm a lucky man.

1102
01:23:05,041 --> 01:23:08,238
Boys, you know the score.

1103
01:23:08,281 --> 01:23:10,749
Let's keep it mono.

1104
01:23:10,801 --> 01:23:11,995
Who are you?

1105
01:23:13,361 --> 01:23:16,956
If the phone doesn't ring, it's me.

1106
01:23:17,001 --> 01:23:18,116
Ha-ha!

1107
01:23:23,441 --> 01:23:26,717
<i>(Micky) Ladies and gentlemen,</i>
<i>please take your seats.</i>

1108
01:23:26,761 --> 01:23:28,274
<i>Admission is free.</i>

1109
01:23:29,121 --> 01:23:30,236
<i>The theatre is filling up.</i>

1110
01:23:30,281 --> 01:23:33,717
<i>I urge you to take your seats</i>
<i>as we're about to close the doors.</i>

1111
01:23:33,761 --> 01:23:36,400
<i>We're about to bolt the doors.</i>
<i>Thank you.</i>

1112
01:23:36,441 --> 01:23:39,353
(Woman) Crystal's going to be happy,
anyway. Very happy!

1113
01:23:39,401 --> 01:23:42,791
- Oh! How are you?
- Very good.

1114
01:23:42,841 --> 01:23:44,832
(Crowd chattering noisily)

1115
01:23:46,761 --> 01:23:48,319
(Whispering)

1116
01:23:53,481 --> 01:23:56,120
(Crowd drowns out speech)

1117
01:24:02,801 --> 01:24:04,519
(Man) Shush. Shush.

1118
01:24:04,561 --> 01:24:06,517
(Hush descends)

1119
01:24:09,081 --> 01:24:10,639
Ladies and gentlemen.

1120
01:24:13,561 --> 01:24:15,517
At absolutely no expense...

1121
01:24:17,081 --> 01:24:19,072
Heartlys presents...

1122
01:24:19,121 --> 01:24:21,476
Josef Locke.

1123
01:24:21,521 --> 01:24:23,512
(Cheering)

1124
01:24:23,561 --> 01:24:26,075
(♪ Orchestra playing
Come Back to Sorrento)

1125
01:24:28,961 --> 01:24:31,077
(Cheering)

1126
01:24:44,521 --> 01:24:48,878
♪ Hear the music of the waters

1127
01:24:48,921 --> 01:24:53,517
♪ Fount of tender passion sighing

1128
01:24:53,561 --> 01:24:56,200
♪ Like thy heart

1129
01:24:56,241 --> 01:25:00,029
♪ To which go flying

1130
01:25:00,081 --> 01:25:02,311
♪ All my thoughts

1131
01:25:02,361 --> 01:25:06,559
♪ In wakeful dream

1132
01:25:06,601 --> 01:25:11,391
♪ See the lovely dewy garden

1133
01:25:11,441 --> 01:25:16,390
♪ Breathing orange perfumed greeting

1134
01:25:16,441 --> 01:25:21,276
♪ Nought can set my heart a-beating

1135
01:25:21,321 --> 01:25:27,271
♪ Like the fragrance of its bloom

1136
01:25:27,321 --> 01:25:32,315
♪ Now I hear that thou must leave me

1137
01:25:32,361 --> 01:25:38,675
♪ Thou and I will soon be parted

1138
01:25:38,721 --> 01:25:46,958
♪ Can'st thou leave me brokenhearted?

1139
01:25:47,001 --> 01:25:53,440
♪ Will thou never more return?

1140
01:25:54,921 --> 01:25:58,630
(Cheering and applause)

1141
01:26:15,801 --> 01:26:20,955
♪ Now I hear that thou must leave me

1142
01:26:21,001 --> 01:26:27,395
♪ Thou and I will soon be parted

1143
01:26:27,441 --> 01:26:35,871
♪ Can'st thou leave me brokenhearted?

1144
01:26:35,921 --> 01:26:43,396
♪ Will thou never more return?

1145
01:26:43,441 --> 01:26:50,916
♪ Then say not goodbye

1146
01:26:50,961 --> 01:26:56,479
♪ Come back again, beloved

1147
01:26:56,521 --> 01:27:03,950
♪ Back to Sorrento

1148
01:27:04,001 --> 01:27:09,712
♪ Or I

1149
01:27:09,761 --> 01:27:14,437
♪ Must die ♪

1150
01:27:16,641 --> 01:27:19,235
(Cheering)

1151
01:27:37,641 --> 01:27:39,632
(♪ Count Your Blessings)

1152
01:27:45,001 --> 01:27:48,357
♪ Count your blessings

1153
01:27:48,401 --> 01:27:51,393
♪ One by one

1154
01:27:51,441 --> 01:27:54,592
♪ When dawn appears

1155
01:27:54,641 --> 01:27:56,199
♪ And the day

1156
01:27:56,241 --> 01:28:02,032
♪ Has just begun

1157
01:28:02,081 --> 01:28:05,756
♪ They will light your heart

1158
01:28:05,801 --> 01:28:09,350
♪ With happiness

1159
01:28:09,401 --> 01:28:12,871
♪ Make each hour bright

1160
01:28:12,921 --> 01:28:18,917
♪ And bring you gladness

1161
01:28:18,961 --> 01:28:21,953
♪ Count your blessings

1162
01:28:22,001 --> 01:28:25,471
♪ While you may

1163
01:28:25,521 --> 01:28:28,433
♪ For we are here

1164
01:28:28,481 --> 01:28:31,996
- ♪ But little time to stay...
- (AII shouting)

1165
01:28:32,041 --> 01:28:33,030
(Jim) Move it!

1166
01:28:35,361 --> 01:28:39,195
♪ All around are hearts

1167
01:28:39,241 --> 01:28:42,597
♪ Sincere and true

1168
01:28:42,641 --> 01:28:46,953
- (People shouting)
- ♪ Lovely things abound

1169
01:28:47,001 --> 01:28:49,356
♪ Just waiting

1170
01:28:49,401 --> 01:28:52,757
♪ For you

1171
01:28:52,801 --> 01:28:55,793
♪ Count your blessings

1172
01:28:55,841 --> 01:28:59,117
♪ While you may

1173
01:28:59,161 --> 01:29:03,313
♪ The big or small

1174
01:29:03,361 --> 01:29:07,434
♪ Whichever comes your way...

1175
01:29:07,481 --> 01:29:10,473
I have a warrant for the arrest
of one Josef Locke.

1176
01:29:10,521 --> 01:29:12,796
- Chief, you can't do this.
- I can do anything I want.

1177
01:29:12,841 --> 01:29:15,719
As you see, this is signed
by Her Majesty's Inspector of Taxes.

1178
01:29:15,761 --> 01:29:19,117
♪... of love

1179
01:29:19,161 --> 01:29:21,516
♪ If you will

1180
01:29:21,561 --> 01:29:26,589
♪ Count your blessings

1181
01:29:26,641 --> 01:29:33,831
♪ From above ♪

1182
01:29:40,681 --> 01:29:41,909
(Cheering and applause)

1183
01:29:41,961 --> 01:29:43,952
- Can you hear them?
- I can, Mr O'Neill.

1184
01:29:44,001 --> 01:29:46,834
If you go in now,
you could have a riot on your hands.

1185
01:29:46,881 --> 01:29:48,951
No question about it, Chief.

1186
01:29:49,001 --> 01:29:50,992
(Cheering and applause)

1187
01:29:58,361 --> 01:29:59,555
Not yet, Frank.

1188
01:30:04,641 --> 01:30:09,999
I think we'd all like to hear
Mr Locke do his last encore.

1189
01:30:10,041 --> 01:30:12,475
(Cheering and applause)

1190
01:30:14,961 --> 01:30:16,394
Thanks.

1191
01:30:16,441 --> 01:30:18,432
(Cheering)

1192
01:30:37,001 --> 01:30:40,277
I bet you never thought
I was this big, eh, Micky.

1193
01:30:40,321 --> 01:30:43,870
Can you do a three-week booking
in August?

1194
01:30:45,401 --> 01:30:47,232
(Cheering and applause)

1195
01:30:49,721 --> 01:30:51,677
(♪ Goodbye)

1196
01:30:53,761 --> 01:30:54,955
Go on, Jo.

1197
01:30:56,641 --> 01:31:00,350
♪ My heart is broken, but what care I?

1198
01:31:00,401 --> 01:31:03,916
♪ Such pride inside me has woken

1199
01:31:03,961 --> 01:31:08,113
♪ I'll try my best not to cry by and by

1200
01:31:08,161 --> 01:31:11,551
♪ When the final farewells must be spoken

1201
01:31:11,601 --> 01:31:15,560
♪ I'll join the Legion, that's what I'll do

1202
01:31:15,601 --> 01:31:19,196
♪ And in some far distant region

1203
01:31:19,241 --> 01:31:23,154
♪ Where human hearts are staunch and true

1204
01:31:23,201 --> 01:31:28,878
♪ I shall start my life anew

1205
01:31:28,921 --> 01:31:33,472
♪ Goodbye!
It's time I sought a foreign clime

1206
01:31:33,521 --> 01:31:37,912
♪ Where I may find
there are hearts more kind

1207
01:31:37,961 --> 01:31:40,634
♪ Than I leave behind

1208
01:31:40,681 --> 01:31:44,469
♪ And so I go
to fight a savage foe

1209
01:31:44,521 --> 01:31:46,352
♪ Although

1210
01:31:46,401 --> 01:31:49,393
♪ I know that I'll be
sometimes missed

1211
01:31:49,441 --> 01:31:51,955
♪ By the girls I've kissed

1212
01:31:52,001 --> 01:31:55,880
♪ In some Abyssinian French Dominion
I shall do my bit

1213
01:31:55,921 --> 01:31:59,470
♪ And fall for the flag if I must

1214
01:31:59,521 --> 01:32:03,355
♪ Where the desert sand
is nice and handy, I'll be full of grit

1215
01:32:03,401 --> 01:32:07,440
♪ You won't see my heels
for the dust

1216
01:32:07,481 --> 01:32:11,679
♪ I'll do or die, you'll know the reason why

1217
01:32:11,721 --> 01:32:16,590
♪ When told of bold Leopold's
last stand

1218
01:32:16,641 --> 01:32:19,109
♪ For the Fatherland

1219
01:32:19,161 --> 01:32:23,712
♪ Goodbye!
It's time I sought a foreign clime

1220
01:32:23,761 --> 01:32:26,400
♪ Where I may find

1221
01:32:26,441 --> 01:32:30,798
♪ There are hearts more kind
than I leave behind

1222
01:32:30,841 --> 01:32:35,551
♪ And so I go to fight a savage foe

1223
01:32:35,601 --> 01:32:40,038
♪ Although, I know
that I'll be sometimes missed

1224
01:32:40,081 --> 01:32:42,800
♪ By the girls I've kissed

1225
01:32:42,841 --> 01:32:46,800
♪ In some Abyssinian French Dominion
I shall do my bit

1226
01:32:46,841 --> 01:32:50,436
♪ And fall for the flag if I must

1227
01:32:50,481 --> 01:32:54,713
♪ Where the desert sand
is nice and handy, I'll be full of grit

1228
01:32:54,761 --> 01:32:58,549
♪ You won't

1229
01:32:58,601 --> 01:33:02,594
♪ I'll do or die,
you'll know the reason why

1230
01:33:02,641 --> 01:33:07,351
♪ When told of bold Leopold's
last stand

1231
01:33:07,401 --> 01:33:10,234
♪ For the Fatherland

1232
01:33:10,281 --> 01:33:14,559
♪ Goodbye, goodbye

1233
01:33:14,601 --> 01:33:18,037
♪ I wish you all a last goodbye

1234
01:33:18,081 --> 01:33:25,510
♪ Goodbye, goodbye

1235
01:33:25,561 --> 01:33:27,711
♪ I wish you all

1236
01:33:27,761 --> 01:33:34,678
♪ A last goodbye ♪

1237
01:33:34,721 --> 01:33:37,554
(Cheering)

1238
01:34:27,001 --> 01:34:30,311
All right, Frank, you,
round the front

1239
01:34:30,361 --> 01:34:32,317
and the rest of you round the back.

1240
01:34:36,561 --> 01:34:40,031
Now, look, I must warn all of you...

1241
01:34:40,081 --> 01:34:41,639
- (Crashing)
...that you...

1242
01:34:42,641 --> 01:34:43,756
(Screaming)

1243
01:34:52,001 --> 01:34:53,480
(Cheering)

1244
01:35:05,321 --> 01:35:07,915
(♪ Come Back to Sorrento)

1245
01:35:07,961 --> 01:35:09,952
(Cheering)

1246
01:35:34,401 --> 01:35:36,312
Get out of my way!

1247
01:35:52,121 --> 01:35:53,998
Come on.

1248
01:35:54,041 --> 01:35:56,032
(Laughs)

1249
01:36:02,801 --> 01:36:04,553
(Men shouting)

1250
01:36:07,361 --> 01:36:08,760
Get out.

1251
01:36:13,921 --> 01:36:15,195
Where's the key?

1252
01:36:15,241 --> 01:36:17,755
(People chattering)

1253
01:36:17,801 --> 01:36:19,234
Wait! I've got it! I've got it!

1254
01:36:30,641 --> 01:36:32,871
- Name.
- Franc Cinatra.

1255
01:36:51,121 --> 01:36:52,236
Jo!

1256
01:36:55,481 --> 01:36:57,995
Yeeees!

1257
01:37:02,121 --> 01:37:05,238
Aaaargh!

1258
01:37:05,281 --> 01:37:08,637
Good luck, Jo.

1259
01:37:09,761 --> 01:37:11,513
(Laughs)

1260
01:37:11,561 --> 01:37:13,153
Ha! Whoo!

1261
01:37:13,201 --> 01:37:17,479
(Laughs) Yee-ha! Yee-ha!

1262
01:37:17,521 --> 01:37:21,309
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo! Yee-ha.

1263
01:37:21,361 --> 01:37:23,352
(Laughs)

1264
01:37:25,041 --> 01:37:27,760
Whee! Yee-ha!

