We listen to your concerns.
National counseling session!
We have four very charming singers today.
The gentle guy of SHINHWA is back solo.
Shin Hyesung!
K.Will!
Heo Youngji!
Ryeowook!
What a great combination today.
We met today. Our hair is the same color.
It makes you look like brothers.
You look like brothers from here.
I'd be a failure if we were brothers.
Your parents must be different.
What are you talking about?
How long has it been since SHINHWA debuted?
This is our 18th anniversary.
I was asked this question when I was twenty-one.
Where will SHINHWA be in 10 years?
I said everyone would be over thirty,
so we wouldn't be dancing singers.
I seriously said we would probably all be dads.
Nobody is a dad.
Right. Nobody is married yet.
Yes, officially there aren't any dads.
(Why are you doing this to me?)
Your album is a dance song.
It's the 10th anniversary album for my solo debut.
I wanted to try something special.
What is the key choreography?
A flower dance.
Show us.
Without looking at the camera, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
When your hands go down…
Look at the camera.
That's how it goes.
Sing for us. We'll dance along.
(Cute in a way / Somewhat sexy flower)
(Cute and pretty flower / Uncomfortable flower)
Isn't it easy?
What's with this response?
K.Will, try it.
(Brother, save the flower dance)
(Don't worry)
Magician.
(I'm your brother)
(Good job)
His eyes look charming in the end.
- Thank you. / - It's like a flower blossomed.
K.Will just did it,
but she's talking about Hyesung.
(K.Will didn't exist to Youngji!)
Super Junior was formed over 10 years ago, too.
It's been 11 years.
This is your 11th year.
Your new song is "The Little Prince".
Show us a bit.
(Attracting interest with the flower dance)
(How cute)
(A sweet voice that isn't mischievous)
(It makes your heart melt)
Nice.
Youngji, you imitated Hwang Jungeum before.
Yes.
It was really good.
There's a scene from "She Was Pretty"
where Jungeum really panics.
Oh! Oh! That's nonsense.
Oh! Oh! Gee! That's absurd!
It's really absurd!
You're good.
Do you have any concerns?
I'm thirty.
I'm into eel juice.
- Eel juice? / - Yes.
Why?
I used to jump right up in the morning before.
- What? / - You're tired?
I'm on my second pack now. I jump right up.
What?
(My energy shoots up)
My married daughter keeps calling me.
She said she couldn't sleep because
the baby cried all night.
She had to sleep because she was tired.
He doesn't help. He doesn't even do the dishes.
They take me with them when
they go to the dry sauna.
You watch the baby at the dry sauna?
Didn't you think about being independent?
I don't intend to.
Until the children go to middle school.
Did your daughter change after the show?
My husband scolded her a lot.
- He did? / - Yes.
She didn't call for a whole week.
Really? A whole week?
She said she was having a hard time
in the family chat room.
"I'm tired. I took the young one to daycare"
"and went to the hospital with the other."
"She's lying around sick."
She keeps complaining.
I took the child to the hospital by myself.
Mom always makes an appointment.
It was tough because she didn't.
Everyone lives like that.
Who is watching the kids today?
My husband.
He changed a lot, too, huh?
He really changed a lot.
He put both of them to bed after work.
Wow.
Let's see if she wins a second time.
What about the winner?
The winner receives a prize worth $1,000.
Show us what today's concerns are.
'I'm Going to Burst'.
That sounds a bit embarrassing.
It must be Dongyeop's.
Yes.
This woman gets really mad
all day because of a man.
Hello,
I'm a housewife of 6 years with two children.
I first met my husband at work 10 years ago.
I thought he was always calm and full of leisure.
I well for that and chased him around for 3 years.
We ended up getting married.
She courted him?
Yes.
I must have been crazy.
I dug my own grave.
Honey, where are you?
I made your favorite. Bean paste stew.
"I'm almost there. I'm right outside."
I thought you were right outside.
It's been 20 minutes.
"I'm outside the door."
Did he run into someone?
Are you kidding? You said you were
outside the door!
"I'm coming in."
He's so slow. It takes him 30 minutes
to park the car right in front and come in.
(Why?)
(No way)
When there's an important family gathering…
Honey, dad is asking for you. Where are you?
"I'll be right there."
"The party is almost over. Where are you?"
"Father, I'm right outside."
He said he was right outside,
but he was 2 hours late.
When I gave birth…
Honey, the baby is coming.
I have to get to the hospital!
"What? Okay!"
"Let me get my socks on first."
He should just run out.
What are you doing? The baby is coming!
"Okay, don't worry. Where's my watch?"
He is full of leisure in any urgent situation.
That's frustrating.
Is he crazy?
I'm going to burst from anger.
What will I do with this slow man?
I thought I'd have enough time to wash up
and get ready in an hour.
I was lying in bed and thought
40 minutes should do it.
(He put off getting up and was late!)
I always have to take a crap when
I'm about to go out.
Right.
(Everyone understands)
This is serious though.
How can it take him 30 minutes to go inside?
I really don't know why.
Why does it take him 30 minutes in the parking lot?
I wonder if he was late today.
Come on out!
(Who is frustrated because her husband is
always full of leisure and slow?)
(Lee Hyemin)
(Welcome)
Didn't you know he was like that when you dated?
You chased him around for 3 years.
I must have been blinded by love.
He looked leisurely and calm.
That's how you saw him.
Yes, he seemed mature.
You wanted to void the marriage?
The wedding day…
Was he late?
He took his time. The wedding was at 12:30.
We arrived 10 minutes before the wedding.
- What? / - The groom?
Yes.
The guests greeted us.
Sure. The guests arrive early.
That was bad.
We don't have any pictures with the guests.
In the waiting room.
(It's only once in a lifetime)
Is he the procrastinating type or is he just slow?
Both.
He's lazy and slow?
Yes.
When he has to go to the bathroom,
he sits and glances around.
He gets up and turns on the light,
then wonders why he did that.
He forgot he had to go to the bathroom?
Yes, it's like a slow motion video.
He does that when he has to take a crap?
Yes.
He's like that in any urgent situation.
His laziness overcomes natural instincts?
We live on the 1st floor.
The 1st floor?
It takes him 30 minutes?
It takes him 30 minutes to get home
from the parking lot.
What does he do?
He just parks and walks in.
How frustrating.
Does he walk like this?
(That must be it)
How else can it take 30 minutes?
Stepping on the pavement lines.
It doesn't make sense.
The husband. Hello.
Hello.
He doesn't look slow.
He paused a moment while saying hello.
There was a bit of a buffering.
Hello.
I'm really curious. Why does it take 30 minutes?
Honestly, I walk just like everyone else.
I don't know why she thinks I'm slow.
How far is it from the parking lot?
It feels like it's about 1km.
1km?
Hey! No parking lot is 1km away!
It is 1km away?
No, it's right in front.
I never thought I was late.
I don't see how this is a concern.
I think she's exaggerating a bit.
(How does he get home from work?)
(This is the apartment CCTV)
(Their house)
(He takes his time and slowly goes home)
(It looks like there's something stuck on his shoe)
(Get off!)
(He turns around)
(He looks in the mirror)
(He checks his phone)
(He finally presses the keypad for the door lock)
(It sure is hard to get home)
The production staff said he was slow at
folding the laundry, too.
Let's see how slow he is.
Come on out.
Give us laundry.
He doesn't get up right away.
Come on out!
He has a nice build.
He walks slowly.
(It's already frustrating)
Fold it.
Like you always do.
(Here!)
(Like he folds laundry at home)
(It's natural)
Does he help out a lot at home?
No, he's slow. I just do everything.
Because it's frustrating?
You must have asked for help in the beginning.
I can't watch. I just do it.
That could be intentional.
(He just folds it once?)
(That's it?)
That's how he folds socks?
He just folded it in half.
We have to compare.
Hyesung, sit next to him and fold.
We have to see how others do it.
He's really slow.
Take socks and…
- Fold them like this. / - Right.
Like this.
You're pretty fast, right?
I'm normal.
(He folds socks and moves on)
Hyesung started later.
Keep folding as you always do.
You don't have to fold slowly on purpose.
- Is that how he always folds? / - Yes.
He folded a shirt like that.
(Folding in the smallest size?)
(Did I do something wrong?)
(He looks this way and that)
What are you doing?
(Is it that hard?)
Is he meticulous?
He's folding it right though.
He looks at it and folds it strange.
Why are you folding it again?
Nobody folds it like that.
(Meanwhile Hyesung…)
(He's fast, but…)
(It seems a bit halfhearted)
He's folding it a bit strange, too.
This is how I fold it at home.
Hyesung's is a mess, too.
He didn't fold laundry much.
Hyesung is fast, but not good.
(Still folding)
(Neatly in half)
It's lined up.
(Unfolding it again?)
He folded it, then unfolded it and
lifted it several times.
Okay, stop.
He's slow.
(It's frustrating)
Try to fold it quickly on purpose.
Fold it really quickly.
Do it quickly.
There's no time. Hurry.
Your life is in danger.
You'd better fold quickly or else!
The baby's coming!
Hurry, hurry!
Hurry up!
His hands are slow.
(His hands are too slow!)
(Ordinary vs. In a rush)
(2X speed)
(There's no difference)
(He returns to his seat)
Hurry back!
We have to continue with the recording.
(Full of leisure)
Put them back on in your seat!
(He doesn't rush at all)
He's not fast, but he seems meticulous.
Maybe with folding laundry.
I asked him to replace a socket.
He said it would be slippery, so he got gloves.
It takes him long to prepare.
He decided to go with other gloves.
After he replaced one, he said he was hungry.
It became night. A day passed like that.
It took him all day?
Yes.
I think he's making excuses because
he doesn't want to do it.
Isn't that it? You do that on purpose.
It seems like a strike.
I'm just meticulous and neat. That's how I am.
You arrived for your wedding 10 minutes
before it started. Wasn't that too much?
I didn't want to look pathetic.
I tidied up. I was half hour late to the shop.
From the start?
A groom should look good in a tuxedo.
I was about 30 minutes late getting dressed.
I wasn't able to greet the guests.
We arrived at 12:20.
That was wrong, wasn't it?
Still…
We had the wedding.
What?
We had the wedding. Isn't that alright?
Don't you feel sorry to the guests?
I feel sorry to them.
(We almost couldn't have the wedding)
He was late when our parents met.
(Huh?)
(When the parents met?)
(He was late from the start!)
He probably tried to look nice.
All the parents waited for about 30 minutes.
I rushed him. It was because of his underwear.
Underwear?
Yes, his underwear.
Why is that important?
Everyone has a jinx.
Is it about color?
I have a good day when I wear red underwear.
I was wearing red underwear when
I first met my father-in-law.
It was really nice. That's why our parents
decided to meet each other.
Were things nice the day your parents met?
Yes, they were.
Even when you were 30 minutes late?
I think it was the red underwear.
Are you wearing red underwear today?
Yes, it's a special day.
The husband's family is here.
- Hello. / - Hello.
That must be his brother.
That looks like his brother.
How was he when he lived at home?
I didn't think he was slow.
(Huh?)
(What is he talking about?)
I didn't think he was slow.
He's the fastest in our family.
Are you slower?
He's slower.
He's slower?
- The brother is slower? / - Yes.
He's the fastest in the family.
Yes, he is.
(He's Usain Bolt at home)
This is like a comedy program.
The most common thing our family says is
"I'm on the way", "I'm almost there".
If we have to shower to go out,
he tells me to go first since I'm slow.
I always took a shower first.
(They're the same)
Who is the slowest in the family?
Our mother.
It runs in the family.
Is that your mother?
No, she couldn't come.
She's too slow. Is she on her way?
Is she on her way here now?
I spoke to her yesterday. She said she'd come.
She did?
(Is she really on her way?)
I don't know what happened.
He doesn't know.
(Mother, where are you?)
It must be frustrating when you go to their place
during the holidays.
We make all the food the day before the rite.
It takes mother an hour to set the table.
When she remembers to put something on
the table, it takes her an hour.
It takes her 2 hours to do the dishes.
After that, it's lunch time.
The table has to be set again?
(She's busy all day preparing meals)
There's only one grave to visit,
but it takes 2 hours to walk up.
Do you know what's frustrating?
My husband is slow, but he tells mother to hurry.
He says that?
It's really frustrating.
He's the fastest in the family.
Do you think your mom is slow?
My wife tells me I'm slow,
but I tell my mother she's slow.
She says "Wait, I'll get it done quickly."
She says that.
She was supposed to come today.
She could be on her way.
(Where is she?)
There are several people here
to tell us how slow the husband is.
Hello.
What is your relationship?
I'm her cousin.
- The wife's cousin? / - Yes.
Is he pretty slow?
I visit them.
We order fried chicken.
I call and ask where he is.
He says he's on his way home.
I tell him to pick up the fried chicken.
It takes him over an hour.
His workplace isn't that far.
It's about 10 minutes from their place.
So is the fried chicken place.
But it takes him an hour?
Yes.
Why? Why does it take an hour?
He probably doesn't know.
(Stepping on lines holding the chicken?)
I don't know. When I go out,
everyone seems to time me with a stopwatch.
I'm not obsessed with time. I never thought about
how long it takes me.
It takes him an hour, but he doesn't realize it.
Right.
The next person.
I'm his friend of 20 years.
You must know him well.
Tell us about him.
I was the MC at their wedding.
He asked me to arrive an hour ahead of time.
When he arrived 10 minutes early?
The bride and groom weren't there.
That must have been surprising.
I asked his mother if she knew what was going on.
She said he would show up
since it was his wedding.
She said that?
Yes. He would show up to his wedding.
They didn't come until 10 minutes were left.
I wondered if they were going to call off
the wedding like in a movie or a drama.
That's understandable.
He called me recently to go to eat jjamppong.
He said he was parking.
Then you should order the noodles.
I ordered two bowls.
But he didn't come.
I sat there with two bowls in front of me.
Like I was stood up.
(He couldn't eat and he couldn't just leave)
I can imagine.
Who is the next person?
I was his roommate
for 7 years until he got married.
Oh, his roommate?
You must really know him well.
He's way too slow.
If he goes to the bathroom,
he's in there for 30 minutes.
I had a really serious stomachache.
I told him to come out.
He said okay.
I said hurry!
"Okay."
I was about to go in my pants.
Is he like that at home, too?
Of course.
Our child knocked.
He said he had to pee.
My husband said he'd be out soon.
And stayed in there for half an hour?
The 5-year-old peed in his pants.
He apologized for peeing in his pants.
I cried with him.
That's sad.
Is your child slow?
The older one is really slow.
Does he take after his dad?
I think he does.
It took 18 hours to deliver him.
What does that have to do with your husband?
You're the one who had the baby.
When were you the most frustrated?
I panic when the child is sick.
Once, the older one had a fever of 40 degrees.
I told him we should hurry to the hospital.
He said he'd be home soon.
From work?
Yes.
How far away is it?
About 5 minutes.
But he didn't come for over an hour.
When your child was sick?
Yes.
What did you do?
I couldn't leave work just like that.
You told her you'd be home soon.
You should have told your boss.
I did, but it took that long.
(Weren't you worried about our child?)
You were slow when she had to go to
the hospital to give birth.
Were you acting leisurely?
He put his socks on and looked for his watch.
It was our second child.
I had a bit of leisure.
(Shock)
Why did you act leisurely?
It didn't feel right not to wear my watch.
Like red underwear?
I don't go out in my pajamas.
(Can't you see the baby is coming?)
It must not have been easy at work.
He was always late about 2-3 times a week.
(What a mess)
Being late to work isn't good.
I do what everyone else does.
I wash my face, brush my teeth, shave,
trim my nose hair and wash my hair.
How frustrating.
I dry my hair.
I eat.
I'll get yelled at whether I'm 5 minutes late
or 10 minutes late.
(Oh!)
You should get to work on time.
Your boss will see this.
It's alright. I quit that job.
I started a baseball goods store 2 years ago.
Does he go early since it's his store?
It's his store. He opens and closes when he wants.
Doesn't he think about the customers waiting?
They call.
They ask when the store will open.
He says he's 5 minutes away.
The customer waits for 30 minutes
and leaves angry.
What time was it?
Two in the afternoon.
Why does he open so late?
He opens when he wants to.
Were you ever in a rush?
I think I'm fast when I run.
What's your time for the 100m sprint?
About 12 seconds in high school.
That's really fast.
That's practically a professional athlete.
(No way)
Shall we see if you're really fast?
Yes.
Start here, run around the set and
finish over there.
One lap is quite a distance.
Get ready.
Run.
(I'll show you what speed is)
(They can't imagine him running)
(How fast does he run?)
Get ready!
Go!
Oh, he's fast.
(What?)
(How can this be?)
(He's fast)
(Running at full speed)
(In a daze)
(Is this a dream?)
He's fast!
I can't believe it.
He fell!
(He fell because he was too fast)
(It's like a scene from "The Chaser")
He's really fast.
(He's amazingly fast!)
He's fast.
(A kangaroo jump)
(He finished just like that)
(I saw a miracle)
He's really fast.
(You're really fast)
(This is basic)
(Is this the same person?)
You would have arrived in 5 minutes
if you ran like that with the fried chicken.
Or when your baby was sick.
It took him 22 seconds.
He was really fast when he got up from falling.
You never saw him like this?
Yes. I never saw him run.
Do you think it was sexy?
Isn't it charming?
(That's the man I am)
He'd be faster if he always ran.
Right.
He's really fast.
If someone has to use the bathroom,
you should say you'll be 5 minutes.
You should be more precise.
I said that to my wife.
I said I'd be there in 10 minutes or 5 minutes.
I was late and got into more trouble.
I'm slower if I set a time.
No way.
Then be honest.
Why do you bother wearing a watch?
You can't go out without your watch!
Why don't you keep time?
Okay. Say what you want to your husband.
You're always full of leisure,
but it always makes me anxious and nervous.
I wish you'd act faster.
Move faster in urgent situations.
Hyesung, is it a concern or not?
I think it's a concern.
If the situation calls for it, you have to rush.
That's what a cool person does.
I think it's definitely a concern.
I think it's a concern, too.
I don't think it's a concern.
I get stressed when I think about being on time.
But he doesn't think.
He's full of leisure.
He doesn't care about time.
He wears a watch, but he doesn't care.
Right.
He's not stressed at all.
I think he'll live a long life.
- He'll live long? / - Yes.
If you understand her concern,
press the button!
(What does the audience think?)
Okay.
Show us the result!
The last digit.
(A new winner with 177 votes?)
Is it 177?
(Nervous)
About 147?
157!
(Eliminated)
(Survives)
The title is 'Smooch, Smooch, Smooch!'
Hello, I'll be in the 4th grade. I'm Shin Sarang.
I'm always kissed every day.
The person who kisses me is my dad.
Dad, good morning.
"Oh, Sarang, you're up."
"Okay, 30 kisses."
30 kisses?
Smooch, smooch, smooch.
When he gets home…
"Sarang, daddy's home!"
"50 kisses!"
Smooch, smooch, smooch.
When I eat…
"Sarang eats so well."
"30 kisses."
"Sarang, you brushed your teeth."
He kisses me over 200 times a day.
That's a lot.
She counted.
When we wait for the pedestrian light to change…
"Sarang walks so pretty." Smooch, smooch, smooch.
On the street?
"She's not a baby. What a strange dad."
People point and talk, but he keeps kissing me.
Do you know what my friends say?
"Sarang, you still kiss your dad?"
"Sarang's dad kisses her."
It's so embarrassing.
Counselor MCs, please stop my dad
from kissing me.
(Poor thing)
Did your parents kiss you a lot?
I have a younger brother. I'm the oldest son.
My father was really scary.
If I have a daughter, I'll kiss her.
I think you'll be good at it.
Sure.
I can't?
No.
(Surprised)
Why can't I kiss my daughter?
It's his daughter.
You can't say no even if you're his fan.
That's wrong of you.
(Discipline seems nature for the idol of 18 years)
She's the same age as my son.
I kiss my son a lot, too.
He promised to until the 9th grade.
He'll allow it until the 9th grade?
Yes. He told me not to be so anxious or upset.
Why not after the 9th grade?
I don't know. That's what he said.
(Because…)
He'll smell like cigarettes in high school.
(Oh, my son…)
Let's meet her and talk more.
Come on out!
(Who is tired of her dad kissing her?)
How cute.
(Shin Sarang)
(Two guys get up)
(My hand…)
What is this?
K.Will, what will you do?
You're really honest.
She's honest.
I saw her.
She looked at K.Will and Ryeowook,
then held Ryeowook's hand.
She's really honest.
K.Will was closer.
How do you feel right now?
Me?
Can I swear?
Gee…
Was it in the confusion of the moment
or do you like Ryeowook?
It was the moment.
Please introduce yourself.
Hello, I'm from Cheongju.
I'm in the pre-4th grade. I'm Shin Sarang.
The pre-4th grade.
How cute.
Is it such a concern that your dad kisses you?
Yes.
I'm not a baby. I'm all grown up.
I'm 155cm tall. I'm taller than other kids my age.
I read a lot these days, so I'm smarter.
But my dad thinks I'm little.
How much does he kiss you?
He kisses me everywhere.
My cheeks, forehead, eyes, ears…
he bites my ears a lot.
My hands, mouth, everywhere.
A hundred times is basic.
We're together on holidays.
Sometimes, it's over a thousand times.
Really.
Did you count?
Yes, I did.
There's proof. Let's take a look.
Show us.
Agh!
He kisses you like that?
No wonder you don't like it.
Her expression…
She doesn't look that happy.
She didn't get to eat yet.
He won't let her get away.
It's a head lock.
(It's more of a head lock than a kiss)
Don't your friends kiss their dads?
I'm sure some do,
but not like this.
You're really bright.
I'd kiss you a lot if I was your dad.
You're such a bright girl. Why did you do that?
(Why didn't you hold my hand?)
Forget about that.
(It's not easy)
Dad must have a reason.
Let's meet him. Hello.
Hello.
What do you think? It's a concern for her.
Why is a dad kissing his daughter a concern?
If she hates it so much,
she shouldn't be my daughter.
Leave if you're not going to kiss me?
Right.
Is that what you're saying?
She exaggerated when she said
you kissed her a thousand times, right?
A thousand times on holidays.
Sometimes, it's over a thousand times.
Look at her.
She's so pretty and cute.
I think that's why I keep kissing her.
How are you cute?
When I want to buy something…
Oh, there's a purpose.
If I ask him to buy something for me,
he buys everything.
(He loves his daughter)
It's alright for him to kiss you then, right?
Yes.
I kiss him then.
(Can you see why?)
It's embarrassing for her on the street.
She's so pretty. I can't hold back.
It might look like a head lock,
but it's my expression of affection.
Show us. How do you do it?
(A reenactment)
We'll see if Sarang was exaggerating.
You met. She's cute.
(Smooch, smooch!)
(This is how they go to the grocery store)
(The audience stirs)
(He doesn't care)
(Poof)
(A cool exit)
That's an abduction.
It's like a bird pecking on feed.
Her friend saw this.
Is that the friend?
Yes.
Hi.
Hello.
Introduce yourself. You're her friend?
A close friend.
(I see)
I didn't imagine.
Did you see her dad kiss her?
Yes.
(Ha ha ha)
Tell us.
I went over to her place.
Her dad kissed her on the cheek and hugged her.
What did you think?
I envied her.
She envied her.
You envied her?
Your dad doesn't kiss you?
No.
Your dad doesn't kiss you much?
- Is that why you envied her? / - Yes.
What if your dad kissed you a thousand times?
I'd still like it.
Your friend envies you.
He kisses me too much.
He touches my butt on the street, too.
Your butt?
Yes, when we stop at a light.
Do you really touch her butt?
She's cute.
She yells and runs.
That's so cute.
That's why I do that.
What do you think of that?
I'd like that a lot.
Oh, boy.
You'd like that a lot?
She'd like it.
Why did you bring her?
She's not on your side.
Try it for a month. It's really tough!
When was the last time your dad kissed you?
I don't know.
She doesn't know. She doesn't remember.
Tell your dad to kiss you.
Dad, I want to be loved like Sarang, too.
Come here. You're the one with a concern.
(I need an average dad)
Is he only like that to you or your sister, too?
Everyone.
Your whole family?
Yes.
What grade is your sister in?
She's in the 9th grade.
She's going through puberty.
About a hundred times for my sister.
What about your mom?
About 150 times.
It's a concern for all three of us.
(Let's hear from the sister)
Does he kiss you a lot, too?
Yes, a lot.
Since I was little. If our eyes meet…
If your eyes meet?
What do you do?
I'm in the 9th grade.
I run. He comes after me and forces it.
It's irritating.
If Sarang passes, he kisses her?
Right.
He walks around like a dog that has to poop.
A kiss here, a kiss there.
What can you say to your sister?
Until you're independent…
(There's no solution)
That's a long time away.
You have to live with it.
She has no choice?
Right.
Father, you weren't kissed much as a child?
Or were you kissed too much?
My parents never expressed their affection.
- Both parents? / - Yes.
I told myself I'd express my affection a lot
to my children.
I think that's why I kiss them a lot.
Let's hear from mom. Hello.
She could think differently.
I have a hard time because he calls so much.
He calls?
My co-worker said he called 4 times in 30 minutes.
It makes me a bit uncomfortable.
I know you love your family,
but can't you see it's hard for them?
I don't call that much.
You called four times in 30 minutes.
To Sarang…
You call her, too?
About seven times? Twenty at most.
In one day?
In one day.
What about your older daughter?
She doesn't answer her phone that well.
She doesn't answer my calls.
She said you call your wife 50 times a day.
Yes, about fifty times.
(That's unimaginable)
My dad called me in school.
He acts really cute.
He said "Sarang, what are you doing?"
A 1st grader heard that.
He said "Are you a little baby?" and teased me.
I cried at home. My dad asked what was wrong
and kissed me again.
To make things worse.
How do you act cute? I can't imagine.
You don't look like you could be cute.
How do you act cute?
Let's say you called her.
Hello?
Sarang, it's me, dad.
Give me a kiss.
Sarang, you're pretty. Kiss. Smooch.
It's driving me crazy.
It gave me goose bumps.
Many daughters marry someone like their dad.
Do you think you should marry someone like him?
When you get married?
I don't think I will.
Why not?
It's a bit disgusting.
Oh.
What's disgusting?
That was a bit disgusting.
It's not that.
I like to dance. I like teaching.
I taught him how to do a dance by Girl's Day.
It was really disgusting.
I can imagine.
It looks disgusting the way he moves, right?
Yes, it's detestable.
It's that bad?
You did a girl group dance?
Sarang's dream is to be a dance singer.
I try to dance with her.
The friend.
Hold the mic.
What do you think of that?
I think it's fun. I like it.
You like it?
You like everything.
Let's talk after we see him dance.
Okay?
(A bad feeling)
(Dad heads to the stage)
It will be embarrassing by himself.
Dance with him.
"Expectation".
Give us music.
(Here goes)
Oh, oh, oh!
(Flexible)
You're more disgusting!
(I can't lose)
(Fluttering)
(Limp)
Father, are you drunk?
(I'm intoxicated by the music)
(A drunk move)
(Let's be independent)
(You're driving me crazy)
(Into it 200%)
(Poke, poke)
(Another cool exit)
He dances well.
How would you feel if your dad danced like that?
She covered her eyes.
She looked down.
I wouldn't teach him.
She wouldn't teach him.
He's pretty good for his age.
He's good.
He turns his waist well.
I take after my dad when it comes to dancing.
You have a nice personality after your dad.
So why did you do that?
Stop it! She's just a kid!
Forget about it.
(He has a grudge against a pre-4th grader)
I'm curious.
What do you do?
I'm a policeman.
A policeman?
He's a policeman.
Then start answering honestly.
Understood?
Yes.
It sounds like an interrogation.
What time did you start kissing her today?
I got up at 7:30, so…
I started at seven.
Answer honestly!
How many times did you kiss her today?
I can't be precise, but 100-150 times.
How many times did he kiss you today?
Over 150 times.
We have proof.
Really?
Yes.
We have a video.
Let's take a look.
You don't know about this.
Let's take a look at the proof.
We had a hidden camera in the van.
The van?
Yes.
(I let my guard down)
(9:00 a.m., the day of the recording)
(Hidden camera of the family coming from Cheongju)
(The seat is…)
(It's too far to kiss)
(Hm…)
He's smacking his lips.
He's getting warmed up.
(Her friend gets in the car)
(Sarang moves over)
(Should I start now?)
(Embarrassed)
This is my concern.
(Neat)
Your chin hurts!
(Why is dad's beard prickly?)
(Stuck like gum)
(Sniffing)
Stop it!
(Stop what?)
(This isn't a replay)
(He kissed her in the same spot a dozen times)
It's too much.
Her friend is there.
(I feel stiff)
(Tired from kissing too much)
(He takes a break)
(10 minutes later)
(He's recharged)
(Smile)
(Agh!)
(My baby)
(He starts kissing her again)
It hurts!
Why is it a concern?
My ear hurts!
No, it won’t hurt.
(Goose bumps)
(100% sincere)
(The same expression)
(We counted the kisses in 3 hours)
(About 180 times)
180 times.
It's so funny. It's making me cry.
What do you think?
He kissed a lot.
Right?
Father, what do you think?
How does it feel to see it for yourself?
When did you film that…
What do you think?
It must be a pain.
Right?
The friend. What do you think?
It must be a real pain.
(Now do you understand how I feel?)
We had a guest who cried because
she wanted to be loved by her dad.
It's a bit too much, but he expresses it a lot.
Which do you think is better?
Sometimes, I want him to be indifferent.
I liked a guy in the 2nd grade.
And?
I didn't do anything, but he got irritated
and mad at me for no reason.
He did?
I didn't do anything.
I wondered what was wrong with guys.
I was going to ask my dad.
I was going to talk to him, but he said okay
and kissed me again.
Before he listened to you?
Instead of talking?
I said he didn't understand and left.
He kept calling me.
Asking you where you went?
He told me to hurry back and kiss him.
He didn't know how you felt.
He's obsessed with kissing.
You should listen to her in such a situation,
not kiss her.
I should comfort her with kissing.
She went in her room and cried.
That was pretty and cute, too.
So I went and kissed her.
I think it would be a serious concern for her.
You only like kissing her.
You don't listen to her concerns.
Why are you crying?
It's a serious concern at her age.
She had a boyfriend in the 2nd grade.
It's a sensitive matter.
You're guilty.
Father is about to cry.
(Emotional)
Why are you both crying over this!
You're putting us in a bind.
If Sarang was mean, she'd get really mad,
but she lets him do it.
You should know that and refrain a bit.
It's so funny. Mother is crying, too.
The family is a mess because of kissing.
When she gets a boyfriend,
the boyfriend will be kissing her.
That will be very upsetting.
How would you feel if you saw them kiss?
Uh…
I never thought about it.
Think about it now.
I think I'll have to stick to her side
around the clock.
You can't do that.
Aren't you going to let her get married?
I should, but…
Your older daughter wants to move out
because you kiss her so much.
She's enduring it until then.
I think everyone will move out.
(No…)
Is there anything you want to say to your dad?
We're close now, but if you kiss me when
I'm going through puberty, we could be distanced.
Until I go to middle school… Refrain.
I love you.
Dad is crying, too.
What's going on?
(Everyone is in tears because of kissing)
Sarang.
You're tired of kissing.
I guess you won't kiss your boyfriend later.
I probably will once in a while.
(Disturbed)
Tell your dad you're going to kiss when
you meet a man you love.
When I find someone I like,
we'll kiss and hug, so don't be surprised.
I'll start preparing myself from now on.
Let's hear from the guests. Hyesung.
I'll say it's a concern.
From Sarang's point of view.
K.Will.
Gee…
What is this?
It's a concern. Father should change.
There's no answer if you say
it's because you love her.
Think of it from her position.
Youngji.
I think it's a concern.
Ryeowook.
It's not a concern.
You're the only one with a different opinion.
Would you like it if I kissed you all the time?
It's a concern!
Excessive kissing made a family cry.
If you think it's a concern, press the button!
(What does the audience think?)
Stop!
Father!
Say something to your daughter.
To Sarang.
Sarang.
I didn't know it was such a concern for you.
I'll cut down just a bit, so you're not stressed.
You won't kiss her just a bit?
You'll only cut down just a bit?
I'll control it, so you're not stressed.
Accept it until then. I love you.
Sarang, why are you crying more?
You can tell he loves you, right?
He didn't understand?
What's wrong?
Do you regret coming on the show?
It's not that. He does it because he loves me.
I feel sorry.
Then you regret coming on the show.
What does that make us?
We recorded for 2 hours.
I said it was a concern.
I wonder how many votes she got.
It's a cute concern.
Show us the result!
(Here is the result)
It's over 100.
(It's three digits!)
(Well?)
124.
That's a lot.
(Eliminated)
(Survives)
'Woman Who Attracts Attention'.
It's from a woman in the 20's.
Hello, I'm reporting my older sister.
I'm too embarrassed to go out.
Every morning…
Hey!
I have to go now.
This family, too?
Come out!
"Mm, all, all…"
Is she singing?
I have to go!
"All, all, all."
"All I have to give you is this song."
That was the song?
What was that?
She sings for an hour or two in the bathroom
every morning.
I have to grab my stomach and wait.
It's worse at night.
"Every lonely night."
"I don't want to think about you."
Come on!
Let me sleep!
"No!"
She sings until 3 or 4.
She sings all day.
Even when she sees a stranger…
"You were born to be loved."
Isn't she crazy?
Someone stop her from singing so much.
Singing like that to a stranger…
Really.
Let's meet the sister.
Come on out!
Don't go!
(Kim Seon)
(He wants to forget the humiliation)
(Why is this making me nervous?)
They're reaching out at the same time.
Well?
(Whose hand will she hold?)
(Crash)
(Her hand grazed K.Will's hand?)
Excuse me.
Ryeowook, good!
What does that make me?
(She tried to grab his hand to survive)
He pulled her hand.
Does your sister want to be a singer?
No, she's in college. She's just like that.
Everyone sits quietly on a bus.
She has earphones and sings loud enough
for everyone on the bus to hear.
Everyone stares.
When crossing the street, she stopped
in front of a car's headlights.
She started to dance.
Thinking it was lighting?
Headlights!
It will be recorded on the black box.
The driver must have been surprised.
I know, but she didn't care.
She walks up to strangers and sings.
Why? All of a sudden?
We were waiting to cross the street.
She acted bored. She spread her arms out
and started singing you were born to be loved.
What was the person's expression?
Dumbfounded.
What were you doing when she sang to strangers
and danced in front of a car?
I was embarrassed. I stood far away.
You can just ignore it and go your way.
She yells my name out loud and comes after me.
Where are you going?
What is your age difference?
8 years.
That's a lot.
Does she pester you?
Yes.
Let's meet the sister full of excitement.
Call her.
Sis.
- Hello. / - Hello.
She doesn't look it.
She looks like the quiet type.
She looks shy.
It seems like the sister is lying.
Did you really sing and dance on the street?
Yes.
Why did you do that?
You only live once. I want to enjoy life.
I envy you.
That's why you danced in front of headlights?
It was like lighting.
I thought the men who were driving
would be exhausted.
I did it to make them laugh.
It was dark in the car, so I couldn't see them.
You thought they laughed and liked it?
I think they would have liked it.
If we're waiting at a red light
and someone dances, it would be funny.
I'd crack the horn.
Why did you sing to strangers?
People passed and they weren't smiling.
It was sad to see.
You have the right to be loved.
I wanted to tell them.
How was their response?
They looked at me like I was crazy.
My sister drags me away.
I can't see their faces well.
I want to see their responses, but…
(It would be better not to)
It must be bad for her to drag you away.
Can you show us up to the moment
she drags you away?
Yes.
Come on out.
(That's strange)
Let's be sweethearts.
Who?
On the street.
- Me? / - Yes.
Okay.
Wow, she must be really rich.
Honey.
We're a couple. We look happy.
Point out someone who is frowning too much.
Who do you want to sing that song to?
(The sister's song of love)
(Who is the lucky person to be comforted?)
'You were born to be loved.'
Why does everyone choose me?
I was picked last week, too.
(Chanu is really lucky this year)
'In your life.'
'You're loved.'
I am.
'You were born…'
(Don't stop me)
Is she crazy?
Is that how she sings?
Yes.
- If she does that… / - It must be scary.
The production staff works hard.
Who do you want to sing that song to?
(Found one)
(You)
(Smile, love)
(Relaying love)
(It's embarrassing, stop it)
From the expression.
Huh?
(There's another one)
She saw someone.
There's someone else to be loved.
(The love messenger approaches)
(A touch of love)
(Hang in there)
Please give a round of applause.
(The work environment is tough today)
She's really strange.
That's amazing.
Her intention is good.
It would be scary if she suddenly did that.
If you're on the street and…
Did anyone ever sing with you?
Yes.
I was on the subway when I was in high school.
It was so boring.
A few elderly women were sitting.
I walked over and said I'd sing a song.
They said go ahead.
A few elderly women came from the next car.
Go ahead and sing.
Okay, I'll sing a song.
Okay.
(Clap, clap, clap)
(Here goes)
'It's raining.'
'The Honam Rail is headed south.'
'Beyond the shaking window…'
You're good.
'My memory is vague.'
(She did that on the subway?)
(That's really amazing)
(I want to hide)
She's embarrassed.
(Energy up!)
Hey!
I have to get off here.
Thank you.
You're good.
- The subway? / - Yes.
Everyone stared, right?
Yes.
Weren't you embarrassed?
Not at all.
You have a lot of courage.
That's amazing.
I felt proud.
They asked how I could enjoy life so much.
But my sister says I'm too loud.
I say people like it.
(That's what you think)
She's very positive.
Really.
Can't you let it go?
It's alright if she's like that herself,
but she makes me sing with her. A cappella.
She says she'll add harmony.
On the street.
Show us.
Yes. Together.
(Not again)
It looks like they did that a lot.
The number 7 bus in Gwangju.
'All I can give you is this voice.'
On the bus?
(They're in harmony even if she's forced)
She's into it.
(It's funny because she's so sincere)
(She has no soul, but she does as she's told)
Don't the passengers get surprised?
It's really embarrassing.
Isn't it?
I'm happy to sing with my sister.
You like to add harmony. There are five of them.
Choose a song and assign the parts.
Can I come out?
Do you want to?
Isn't it embarrassing?
Why would it be embarrassing?
Okay, come on out.
She doesn't get embarrassed.
She has a pitch pipe.
Sit here.
She brought a pitch pipe to do it right.
I always carry it around.
All year.
You're not a singer. Why?
Don't sigh.
Are you embarrassed?
From "The Lion King" OST.
(They challenge "The Lion Sleeps Tonight")
(I'll assign the parts)
Wimoweh.
- Wimoweh. / - Wimoweh.
You have to sing it together.
Altogether.
(A really low tone)
Oh!
(He was complimented)
In three parts.
Wimoweh, wimoweh.
What about the middle?
(The harmony becomes abundant)
Why are we going along?
(What's wrong with everyone?)
This side.
(The left side)
(It's too high)
Let's try it now. Keep going.
One, two, three, four.
(Happy)
(Everyone becomes one with music)
(This is why she does it)
One more time.
(She's really excited)
(Do it all today and stop)
Okay, that's it.
(The improv a cappella was successful)
She's good.
She's not a recreation instructor, is she?
No, she's not.
Will you take this?
I wonder what her job is.
(She's still excited)
(One more time?)
(I'm happy to)
(What will I do with her?)
I'm really excited right now.
Because we all sang with you?
Yes.
Did your wish come true?
No, I want to do more.
(She's greedy)
Not all sisters do what they're told.
Some don’t know matter what.
You must listen to her a lot.
I give her allowance when she's in need.
(Unbelievable)
I guess you could do it if she pays you.
She gave you allowance.
She makes me do voice imitations.
There's a price.
Who do you have to imitate?
There's something.
Kim Yeonghui in 'Last Love'.
(To get allowance)
(How is she at voice imitations?)
Oh!
(It's hard to make money)
(She's cute)
She's not like this.
How much does she give you if you do that?
$5 at most.
(It's not even a lot of money!)
That's not true.
You take more.
Sure, I take a bit more.
She tempts me with money.
If I say no, she gets mad until I do it.
What's really hard for you?
She imitates instruments with her voice.
She's practicing the haegeum,
trumpet and harmonica.
I made a deal with her.
She's Chanu's fan.
That's why she sang to him earlier.
(Fatal)
If Chanu says she's not good,
she promised to stop imitating instruments.
- If I say she's not good? / - Yes.
Are you really going to stop if I say so?
Yes.
I swear.
What will you do first?
The haegeum.
(I'll listen)
(The haegeum is a bit…)
Don't do it.
(How can this be?)
(That's it for the haegeum)
Anyone can do that!
(That's what I'm saying)
And?
The haegeum isn't that good.
The trumpet.
(With her life on the line)
(I have to make this good)
(It's much better than the haegeum)
(Aren't I good?)
(We can do that, too)
(Please don't imitate the trumpet)
Chanu, what do you think?
Don't do it.
Last.
What you're practicing these days. The harmonica.
Anyone can do that much.
The harmonica.
Hold this, mom.
Mom does what she's told.
I blushed following along.
(Will she be able to continue doing the harmonica?)
(Did it go in water?)
Don't do it.
Don't do any of them.
It's not even 1% similar at all?
It's not similar.
Okay.
It could be fun if you do it once in a while,
but it's torture if you keep doing it.
She was told.
She won't imitate instruments anymore.
You'll keep your promise, right?
Ah…
You said you'd stop if Chanu said it wasn't good.
It's alright if she doesn't hear it, right?
I'll do it to the dog.
What did the dog do to deserve that?
Your problem is solved if she doesn't
imitate instruments, right?
There's one more concern.
We were walking in an alley.
There were some scary men.
I said we should hurry past them.
But she sang again.
I'm worried she'll get into trouble
if she does that when she's by herself.
Even the scary men would be scared if
someone sang like that.
(It would be better to avoid her)
I think it would be really scary.
It's scarier if you let it show.
They’ll know you're afraid of them.
It's less scary if I sing.
That's why I sing more.
She's really worried.
Shouldn't you refrain a bit?
When I have a baby, I want to sing in harmony
with my husband and my children.
It would be nice to meet someone who likes that.
You can be happy by yourself.
Can't you leave your family alone?
We just grew close recently.
We grew closer singing and dancing.
I wanted to do it with her.
That's true, but there are places to sing.
I'd like her to distinguish that, but she doesn't.
I want to walk along silently on the street
like other sisters.
When I say I don't want to, don't make me.
Let's start with Hyesung. Is it a concern?
I don't think it's a concern.
I don't think it's a concern either.
I think it's a concern.
He keeps saying the opposite.
He gives an opposite opinion.
It's not a serious concern,
but it's a concern for the sister.
If you think it's a concern, press the button!
(What does the audience think?)
Stop!
Is there anything you want to say to your sister?
I didn't know you were that stressed. I'm sorry.
I love you a lot. I think I was selfish.
I'm going to cry.
Again?
Why is everyone crying today?
She feels sorry it's a concern for her sister.
Sing with me at home.
I'll try to refrain outside.
Show us the result!
7!
It's not over 100 from the sound of the beeps.
67!
(Eliminated)
'Lifetime Enemy' wins a second time!
She wins a prize worth $1,000.
(Congratulations)
Until the day Korea has no more concerns,
"Hello Counselor" is here to help.
Thank you!
("Rough" / GFRIEND)