(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
We will counsel you on your unspeakable concerns.
- National Competition on Worries! - National Competition on Worries!
Let me introduce our guests for today.
K.will!
(K.will, autumn ballad singer)
Actor Kang Tae Oh!
(Actor Kang Tae Oh, King Kang Tae Oh)
Kang Nam!
(Kang Nam, the handsome and sweet man)
- Hur Young Ji! - Hur Young Ji!
(Hur Young Ji, an idol singer and an entertainer)
When we see him on TV, we know that autumn has come.
- He's in season now. - He's in season.
Why do you think you're popular?
Is that something you should think about that seriously?
I don't know why. I guess I'm just lucky.
- I've been a singer for a while. - He sings so well.
- He sings really well. - That must be why.
Honestly, your looks aren't your selling point, right?
Why would you be so sure about that?
Everyone has his own preference.
People who like this kind of looks go crazy about me.
He's right.
Tae Oh is quite peculiar.
- The last time he was here, - Yes.
he looked so sad while saying he missed his hometown,
- but his hometown is Incheon. - Incheon.
Incheon is not far from Seoul.
- His eyes welled up with tears. - That's right.
- I thought he was from Haenam. - Exactly.
If Kang Nam says he misses his hometown, I would understand.
- That would be understandable. - That's right.
My mom lives in Yongsan.
(Laughing)
What about your father?
My father visits me often.
He comes to Seoul between 2 and 3 times in 1 month.
- I see. - Yes.
He visits me quite often.
Since you're here, tell us about your worries.
I have thin wrists.
- Thin wrists? - Yes.
- So? - Why is that a worry?
- Let me see. - Do you wish they were thick?
I wish my hands were bigger.
- Is this thick enough for you? - Yes.
I have hang ups about my thick bones.
- You have thick bones. - I wish I had thick bones.
What kind of worry is that?
"I wish I had thick bones."
- I wish I had a smaller head. - This is ridiculous.
I have so many worries about my bones.
- I wish I had a smaller head. - I wish I could be reborn.
Your face is ridiculously small.
Is everything small?
(Laughing)
I didn't mean it like that.
Those people with small hands usually have small feet.
Why did you make that hand gesture?
I meant his head, hands,
- and feet. - He asked if your are feet small too.
- Tae Oh, what did you think about? - Exactly.
Tae Oh is weird.
- Your ears are red. - He just asked you a question.
- His ears are red. - Look at his ears.
Kang Nam, do you have any worries?
There aren't many things I want to do.
What was that word? Hobby.
- I understand... - Hobby?
I don't have any hobby.
- That's not how you pronounce it. - Hobby?
- Hobby. - Hobby.
- Hobby. - Is that right?
- Yes. - I have nothing to do in my free time.
You can work without a break.
- A brick? - Without a break.
- If you work restlessly... - Hobby. Without a break.
When someone is overly enthusiastic about his hobby,
his family member sends us his story.
(They send us their stories.)
- It's good that you're not. - You should be moderate.
- I see. - Too much enthusiasm isn't good.
Let's see what kind of worries we have today.
Show us the keywords please.
(The keywords are revealed.)
- "A Midlife Crisis Is the Worst". - That's true.
"Do I Look Like an ATM?"
"Oh, Save Me".
The title is "A Midlife Crisis Is the Worst".
Hello. I'm a housewife in my 40s. I've been married for 22 years.
I'm going to report my husband who is having a midlife crisis.
- He's in a midlife crisis? - Yes.
It began five years ago.
My husband happened to join a contest.
- A singing contest. - "Did you see my dance?"
"I think I've finally discovered my cheery energy hidden inside of me."
"You saw me, right?"
Since then, my husband got hooked on dancing.
- He got hooked on dancing. - I see.
(I see.)
"Honey, look at me. Look at my dazzling steps."
"Look. This is called shuffle dance."
"I came up with a new dance move."
"What do you think?"
To me, it seems just horrible,
and funny.
However, he didn't stop there.
"I heard 'National Singing Contest' will be held in our town."
"Honey, wish me luck."
"Honey, 'National Singing Contest' will be held in our neighboring town."
"See you later."
It's unbelievable that he got hooked on dancing when he's almost 50.
Please help me stop his midlife crisis.
(Please help me stop his midlife crisis!)
She said her husband is almost 50.
You know how hard shuttle dance is, right?
- It's shuffle dance. - Shuffle dance.
- Not shuttle bus. - Shuttle dance should be like this.
- Shuttle dance? - Shuttle dance?
- What kind of dance is it? - Get in the bus now.
Shuttle dance?
Anyway, let's meet with our guest.
Please come out.
(Who is the wife of a man who is hooked on dancing?)
(Hesitating)
She's wearing a skirt.
(Come on.)
- Aren't they pants? - Look at her glasses.
(Kim Myung Shim)
(It's nice to meet you.)
She chose K.will.
(She chose K.will.)
She greeted Kang Nam.
Why did you hold K.will's hand after greeting Kang Nam?
I felt apologetic to him.
- I'm a big fan of K.will's. - I see.
- She's a fan of K.will's. - I see.
She really is a fan of his.
(I have a lot of fans too.)
Please introduce yourself.
Hello. I'm a housewife from Geumsan, South Chungcheong Province.
(Hello.)
Tell us how your husband got hooked on dancing.
Five years ago, he appeared on "Morning Forum"...
as his sister suggested. In the segment...
"Sing with Your Family", he danced on stage.
- "Morning Forum"? - I remember that segment.
Ever since he appeared on that show,
the cheerful energy inside of him burst out.
He became so confident in dancing, so he dances all the time.
He became confident.
An episode of "National Singing Contest" was recorded in Geumsan.
- Did he pass the preliminary round? - Yes, he did.
He won the Popularity Award.
He must be good at singing.
I wish he had been satisfied with that, but he didn't stop.
He applied for the contest held in Muju too.
Muju isn't a neighboring town. It's in Jeolla Province.
He went for the audition.
The staff must've recognized my husband.
Of course. He won an award.
How long had it been since the contest in Geumsan?
- It had been one year. - I see.
So they said he could apply for it at least three years after that.
- At least three years after that. - I didn't know that.
- I see. - I didn't know that either.
They sent him home, but he's still waiting for a chance.
- Even now? - Yes.
- What's his profession? - He's a used car salesman,
but I don't even know if he's a salesman or a dancer anymore.
He goes wherever he can let his cheerful energy out.
He performs at regional events and birthday parties.
He goes wherever he can perform.
He's even deluded that he's a celebrity.
Does he not greet other people?
Since his appearance on TV,
whenever people compliment about his performance,
- he becomes more confident. - Of course.
Doesn't he get paid?
If he's invited to events like that,
- he must be paid. - I think so too.
No, he performs without getting paid.
- He doesn't get paid? - That's right.
He doesn't get paid.
Dancing isn't a bad thing. It can enrich his life.
It's not necessarily a bad thing, is it?
I don't mind him enjoying himself, but he forces me to join him.
- He wants you to dance with him. - Yes.
He doesn't even care if I'm doing house chores.
"What do you think? I learned this move today. Is it good?"
That's not all. He dances on the streets or public places.
- He practically dances everywhere. - When we're having a barbecue...
with our relatives chatting with each other,
- He dances in front of them? - he stands up all of a sudden,
and starts dancing after saying "Do you want to see my dance?"
- What do your elders say? - In front of his elders?
They just laugh.
- Right. - "He's good."
Her husband is here. Let's meet him.
Where are you?
- Oh, my. - Look at him.
- He has showmanship. - Goodness.
Sir, you shouldn't do that here. Myung Shim's husband.
Do you understand why your wife is worried?
- No, I can't understand her at all. - Right? I knew you'd say that.
Why can't you understand her?
I just enjoy my hobby. I didn't know she would react like that.
Everyone else likes my performances.
I understand that you want to enjoy yourself,
but I don't think you really have to show your wife your dance,
or nag her to dance with you.
I want her to see my dance. I need to dance often...
so I can improve my dance skills.
You want her feedback.
- I want her to review my dance. - In fact,
- Other people give me feedback. - there's something you don't know.
Showing reactions all the time is a very hard thing to do.
- It's not easy at all. - Right.
- She has to show reactions always, - It's hard to do it all the time.
and he may get upset if you sound half-hearted, right?
He gets so angry.
He says that I make him feel like his life is meaningless.
His life is meaningless?
- Did he really say that? - He said he didn't want to be home.
You must've complimented his dance at first, right?
At first, I complimented his dance,
but he repeats the same dance move.
So I don't want to see it anymore.
(I'm tired of it.)
Your wife said your dance is just funny, not great.
What genre is your dance?
I learned shuffle dance from videos on the internet.
I mixed different kinds of dance.
- Did you create your own dance? - Yes, I did.
What kind of music do you usually dance to?
I dance to dance, trot, and ballad songs.
- Oh, my. - Ballad songs?
So, you can dance to any kind of music.
- That's amazing. - He must be very talented.
- He sounds like a dancing machine. - Right.
- He's a dancing machine. - He's a dancing machine.
Can you dance to K.will's sad ballad songs too?
Yes, I can.
- I want to see that. - It's because...
- shuffle dance is very... - It's difficult.
- It's difficult. - The steps are difficult.
You all know T-ara's dance...
for their song "Lovey-Dovey", right?
- I know that. - I'll show you.
- Show us. - Come on out.
You mentioned that because you wanted to dance, right?
It looks a bit weird.
- That's good. - This is how they dance.
- This is shuffle dance. - How close will you get to me?
You stood in the center like a lead dancer of a group.
We'd like to see his dance. Can you allow him just for today?
- Look how she's sighing. - Right.
She's worried that he may be even more enthusiastic about dance.
- Exactly. - She must be worried.
- If we see his dance... - We'll know how good he is.
Let's find out if his dance is as horrible as his wife said,
or if he's an excellent dancer who has the talent.
- Right. - Please come out.
How should I react to that?
Please stand up, guys.
Let's stand around him while he's dancing.
(If you have lips, pout them.)
- Look at him. - Oh, my.
(He moves his body awkwardly.)
Goodness.
- He knows how to do this dance. - That's impressive.
(Dancing awkwardly)
That's new.
That's amazing.
(She's the only one who isn't laughing.)
Okay. It's time.
- How about K.will's song? - That would be great.
"Missing You".
He'll dance to this song?
Look at him.
- That's impressive. - Take a full body shot.
My goodness.
(Oh, my eyes.)
Oh, boy.
Look at K.will's face.
- Look at his face. - Dance without music.
- How do you feel? - Sorry?
- How do you feel? - I wished my song would stop.
- Please dance without music now. - Dance without music.
Ready. Go.
- I was immature - Without music.
- He's singing... - He's tired.
(The dancing machine is already tired.)
Gosh. That must've been tiring.
- He's exhausted. - I'm okay.
- Sir. - He looks like he's going to faint.
I was too immature
When I was in love with you
(He looks so serious.)
May our love
Be fragrant forever
Please give him a round of applause.
- He's amazing. - He is, indeed.
(His wife feels like she's an island.)
How did you feel watching him dancing in front of many people?
I'm embarrassed. I'm so ashamed.
Imagine that he dances like that on the street.
- She must be embarrassed. - How embarrassed she must be.
Do you dance like that in public places?
As long as I get invited to events, I don't care where I perform.
What is the reason?
My father...
has always dreamed of appearing on "National Singing Contest".
- Your father? - I see.
- Your father has. - Yes.
I wanted to make his dream come true,
and I tried to achieve even more than that.
As I won an award, I came to want more.
- When you turn 60... - Your wife said...
that you're deluded that you're a celebrity.
- Is that true? - I think it's true.
- He thinks it's true. - He admitted it.
- I think it's true too. - People usually deny the problem.
Could you elaborate further?
Ever since my appearance on the show, people...
Do you mean "Morning Forum" or "National Singing Contest"?
- I meant both. - I see.
(He's immersed in the moment.)
(He's in the trance.)
People recognized me from the show for a while.
As I heard them compliment...
my performance, I became more confident.
So I learned and practiced more.
Then, you must be very excited to be here.
I'm so happy to be here.
- I can see that. - Are you happy?
Yes.
Does dancing affect your work negatively, by any chance?
I'm sure that it has a negative effect.
Has anyone bought a car because he recognized you?
- Yes. - Is that so?
- Then it had a positive effect. - It was helpful.
When it's time for his gig,
- Yes. - he doesn't answer his phone.
- It has a negative effect. - He doesn't answer his phone,
and cancels his meetings with his clients.
So it's been affecting his business negatively.
- It caused him a loss too. - I see.
- He doesn't get paid for his gigs. - That's right.
He even buys everyone a drink at the after party.
(He pays the bills at the after party.)
- He attends the after party too? - Yes.
He pays for his gigs.
- Exactly. - Exactly. Also,
because he attends many events, he drinks six times a week.
- My goodness. - He doesn't come home early.
- Why do you drink so much? - What does drinking have to do...
- with dancing? - It's because I can't refuse.
Myung Shim, please tell us.
- He organizes meetings like that. - He asks others to drink with him.
- To show them his dance? - Yes.
He gets excited while dancing, so he drinks.
The drink makes him excited, so he dances again.
I understand.
(That's how the infinite loop of drinking and dancing is formed.)
Do you really perform at events without getting paid?
Yes, I do.
They can buy a car from me instead.
I think it's part of my business.
That's not what your wife said.
She said you went to practice dancing even when you have...
a meeting with a client.
That was when I was learning to dance.
I learned to dance from a dance tutor.
- My lesson time... - You learned...
- My goodness. - You learned to dance?
- Yes. - How long did you learn from him?
For about six months.
- You learned for six months? - Yes.
- We thought... - He can't be here.
- Your tutor is not here, right? - That's right.
There's a reason he couldn't come on the show.
(I see.)
- So... - He must be embarrassed.
Could you tell us how it happened?
How did you lose a client because of your dance lesson?
When I was scheduled to meet a client at my dance lesson time,
I chose to delay the meeting with my client.
(You delayed a meeting with your client to practice dancing?)
When you call a car dealer to buy a car,
- and the dealer says he's busy, - Right.
- who would buy a car from him? - Exactly.
- You wouldn't buy a car from him. - That's right.
- That's right. - How much longer will you dance?
What's your plan?
Until I release my song album.
- A song album? - Yes.
- Until he releases an album? - A song album?
Do you sing well too?
- You'll release an album? - I've been learning to sing.
- He's learning to sing. - You just started to learn to sing?
If I get lucky and get a good song, I could earn a lot of money too.
You can get paid for your gigs.
Yes, I'll perform at events.
Then, will it be your day job?
It can be my backup plan for my later years.
- For your later years? - Your backup plan?
You're going to dance to prepare for your retirement?
He's quite determined.
We just heard his future plan. Did you know about this?
I do know that, but we have three kids.
Our youngest child is only seven.
- He's very young. - He's only seven years old.
My daughters are 21...
- and 18 years old. - Her kids have a big age gap.
They have a lot of problems with their dad.
- Which one of them is here? - Is he her youngest child?
My eldest daughter came here with me.
- Oh, she's Myung Shim's daughter. - She looks upset.
Let's meet with Myung Shim's eldest daughter. Hello.
Hello.
(Hello)
Do you understand your mom or your dad more?
I understand my mom's worries.
Why? Why do you understand her?
At first, I thought it'd be okay if Dad enjoys his hobby,
but things got worse and worse.
To me,
it just seems like his steps are a bit flashy.
Flashy steps?
But he thinks his dance skills are good.
Also,
I work as a nurse's aide in three shifts.
- That sounds tough. - My dad keeps...
asking me to edit or download dance videos.
It's just too much.
What do you think is troubling your mom the most?
Before, they used to divide house chores.
Since my dad took up dancing,
he's been staying out too much.
All the chores are done by my mom now.
Dad relieves his stress by dancing,
but Mom has to stay home all the time.
I think that troubles her the most.
Have you ever tried to persuade your dad to stop?
Yes, but it didn't work.
He must have helped you out a lot before.
Yes, he did.
We used to go on many trips as well.
There are house chores that can only be done by men.
He says I should hire someone...
and leaves home.
- To go dancing? - Yes.
As we live in the countryside,
there's no big hospital nearby.
- It's okay. - Was there a problem?
(She suddenly sighs.)
- She must be very worried. - She's upset.
When kids get sick, their dad should drive them to the hospital.
He probably couldn't.
My in-laws were visiting.
- You mean his parents. - Yes.
My father-in-law...
dislocated our kid's arm by mistake.
It got dislocated?
(Their kid's arm got dislocated.)
It was night.
All clinics were closed. So I called my husband.
(She called her husband.)
- You called him. - Yes.
He said he'd come soon, but he never seemed to come.
(Her husband didn't come.)
So I had to drive the crying kid...
- to the hospital. - That must have hurt.
When did your husband come?
Very late.
Were you drinking...
and dancing with people?
- I was drinking. - Tell us the truth.
I was with someone.
I drank too much.
(He's been neglecting his family.)
Your role is important.
Your son is seven years old now.
At home, I try to spend a lot of time with him.
I dance with him.
Dance?
Does he like it?
I like it.
- What about the kid? - What about the kid?
Does your son like it?
He does.
He likes it too.
- I mean... - Do you think...
your son likes to dance with his dad?
- As long as there's music, - He's too young.
- he enjoys himself. - He just mimics his dad.
But my husband dances with him too often.
When I see them dance together,
I see my husband in my son.
I hate it.
Your son goes to daycare center. His dad must be invited to the class.
Yes. He was invited the other day.
Instead of introducing himself normally,
- No way. - he...
- In the class? - No way.
- No way. - He danced...
when it was his turn to introduce himself. I was so embarrassed.
I'd love to see it.
What did you do?
It's your turn.
Hello, I'm Geumsan's Psy.
Oh, like that.
His steps are flashy.
Did the teacher say anything?
I didn't hear anything directly,
but my husband bragged about it.
I see.
Let's hear from their son.
- I'd love to hear from him. - What's his name?
- Tae Gyun. - He's so cute.
Tae Gyun. Say something.
- Tae Gyun. - Is your name Tae Gyun?
- Is his name Tae Gyun? - Kim Tae Gyun.
- Kim Tae Gyun? - Even his last name is Kim.
Hi, Tae Gyun.
- Hello. - He's so cute.
Say hi to Tae Gyun.
I'm Kim Tae Gyun. What's your name?
I'm Kim Tae Gyun.
- He's so cute. - Make a conversation.
What do you think when your dad dances?
I like it.
- Is he a good dancer? - Yes.
- Are you a good dancer too? - Yes.
- Can you show us? - Yes.
- Well... - Tae Gyun, let's have some fun.
Is it okay without any music?
- Do you want some music? - Come here.
He's putting on sunglasses.
Look at him.
- Come here. - He's coming here.
- Do you want to come here? - Come here.
- Come closer. - Come closer.
- Come a bit closer. - There you go.
(The kid looks comfortable.)
Play some music.
(She's not smiling.)
(Thank you.)
- He's so cute. - Good job.
Moms usually smile when their son dances.
- Why didn't you smile? - She didn't smile once.
You look so stiff.
She hates to see it.
- Do you hate it? - Yes.
It seems like his dad made him practice.
When the kid was dancing,
he wasn't looking at the audience.
- He was looking at his dad. - He was looking at his dad.
They must have practiced together.
- It breaks my heart. - She hates to see it.
Your husband looks so happy when he dances.
He usually looks stiff,
but he smiles when we talk about dancing.
Dance.
He looks so happy.
Can't you be more patient?
I wouldn't care if he dances as a hobby.
- But there's a problem. - What is it?
Because he dances too hard,
it's been affecting his body.
At first, he pulled a ligament in his knees.
- In his knees? - Yes.
After that,
- he cracked his bone. - He cracked his bone?
- How? - While dancing?
- He must have danced so hard. - He was hospitalized.
In the end,
his ligament got ruptured.
His bones got damaged.
He even went through serious surgery.
He was hospitalized for three months.
He went through three months of rehabilitation.
After that...
It's not like he's a professional dancer.
- After that, - He must have needed rest.
he started dancing again as soon as he was feeling better.
I can imagine how hard he must have tried to recover.
He must have wanted to recover so badly.
(It was a hard time.)
- How did you live? - At that time,
- How old was Tae Gyun? - our son was two years old.
I had to carry him on my back,
going back and forth between the hospital and home.
- That must have been tough. - You had to look after him.
- Yes. - How did you cope financially?
Living expenses and stuff.
We were in debt.
(They were in debt.)
Have you paid off your debt?
Pretty much.
- My in-laws helped us out. - She's been...
crying the whole time.
She must have been holding it back.
You're so irresponsible.
You don't seem to understand the situation.
I'm having a hard time trying to understand you.
You're not doing your job well because you dance too much,
and you're hanging out with people too much.
Isn't it problematic?
You even hurt yourself.
I do feel bad for my wife.
We have two daughters and a son together.
I want to show them that they should never give up...
- pursuing their dreams. - Hold on.
- There are things to look after. - What is your goal?
It seems like you have a bigger goal.
You can release an album any time you want.
Cultwo can help you.
If all you want is to release an album.
What are you talking about?
Dong Yeob will help you.
Seriously,
dancing shouldn't damage the rest of your life.
- You have your job. - In my opinion,
he's not being honest.
He must be a bit embarrassed.
I think what he really wants is to become famous.
He wants people to recognize him.
He's so happy when people recognize him.
He wants to become famous. Am I right?
- Yes, you're right. - He wants to become a celebrity.
Who would pay to see you dance? That's absurd.
Will your dream come true if you work hard?
Will you become famous? Will you get paid to perform?
The chance is lower than 0.01 percent.
- It's zero percent. - It won't happen.
I think I should be blunt for you to understand.
That's why I'm being blunt.
There's a zero-percent chance.
They don't normally get this worked up.
I've never seen them so upset.
- It's because... - I don't understand.
They must have had a bad day.
They're so upset.
Let me guess why.
They thought you were doing it as a hobby,
but then you were dreaming of becoming a professional dancer.
- That's what... - You're right.
- shocked... - That's accurate.
these guys.
As your wife is aware of it, she's so shocked.
Of course.
She's been crying the whole time.
Do you know what your wife's dream is?
I'm not sure.
Let me ask her. You'll hear it for the first time.
Did you have a dream?
- Of course. - What was it?
I got married kind of early.
I used to have many dreams.
Right now, I'd love to become a barista or a cook.
That's not impossible.
- If you start now... - It'll bring them money too.
Let's say she gets a barista certificate.
Would you be happy if she opens a cafe?
- Let me ask you. - Would you support her?
- I'd be happy. - You would?
Her cafe is doing great. But then she takes up dancing.
(I'll become a dancer instead.)
She's neglecting her business.
She says it's her goal to become a member of a girl group.
- What do you think about that? - That's perfect.
- That's a perfect analogy. - What do you think about that?
What do you think about that? Tell us.
If you put it that way, I understand how she feels.
- That's exactly what you are doing. - That's right.
You saw her legs, right? When you came down the slide,
I saw that you have the legs of an idol singer.
She will achieve her dream sooner than her husband's.
- That's entirely possible. - I know.
How does it feel to learn about her dream?
(How does it feel?)
I am embarrassed that I didn't know she had a dream.
I feel bad.
You're using a dream as an excuse to enjoy having a good time.
Lastly, say what you want to say to your husband.
Stop crying and be confident. Look at him.
He is your husband.
- From now on... - It's their first eye contact.
From now on,
I hope you would do your best in the work you do...
so that we can raise our children without a problem.
Is there anything else you want to say?
If people in the music industry are watching this program,
I hope they wouldn't contact him with an offer to release an album.
- I don't want that. - You don't have to worry.
- You don't have to worry. - It won't happen.
- You don't have to worry. - No one will contact him.
(It's a needless worry.)
Let's start with K.will.
Put yourself in her shoes. Do you think it's a worry?
When you want to do something, you look for excuses.
At first, he said it was his father's dream...
to perform in "National Singing Contest".
Then he said he wants to achieve his dream for his children.
- I don't usually say this, but... - Is it a worry or not?
It's a big worry.
Gosh, a man shouldn't be so chatty.
- I am sorry. - Tae Oh, please keep it short.
I thought that it wasn't a worry.
Hearing the full story let me know that it's a serious worry.
- Kang Nam. - In short, it's a worry.
- Young Ji. - I also think it's a worry.
I think Myung Shim has been raising four children.
- That's right. - You know how children are.
Even when they are sick, they lie in order to play more.
He is being that kind of a nuisance.
- He is an uncontrollable child. - Yes.
If you think it's a worry, please press the button.
(What does the audience think?)
5, 4, 3,
- 2, 1. - I don't think they will stop.
- I don't think they will stop. - Time's up.
Please say a few words to your wife.
Now that we talked about what's on our minds here,
I realized that I should change.
I will try my best.
I am always sorry and thankful. I love you.
Please make this clear.
If an agency contacts you after this episode airs...
(It's 1 in 10,000 chance.)
No one will contact him.
If that happens, would you accept the offer?
I am not ready yet.
You should say that you won't accept the offer.
- Don't say you aren't ready. - He says he isn't ready yet.
I will turn down the offer.
Don't dance in public when you are with your wife.
Your son will enter an elementary school soon.
When there are other parents, don't go, "Let me introduce myself."
It will be hard on your wife.
Let's see how many votes the worry got. Show us the result.
"A Midlife Crisis Is the Worst".
- I am curious. - All right.
- The number is over 100. - Of course it did.
(What will be the result?)
- 155. - 155.
The worry got a lot of votes.
I have a headache.
"Do I Look Like an ATM?"
Hello, I am a woman who turned 30 this year.
My worry involves someone who is incredibly immature.
She leaves the house in a mess and does what she wants to do.
When I scold her, she cries. She is practically a child...
- who lives as she pleases. - Is she going through puberty?
- Is she in 8th grade? - It's my 51-year-old mom.
- Mom? - My goodness.
"Golf is good for the health."
"Ta-da! I bought golf clubs."
"They are 3,500 dollars."
How expensive. She must have bought good ones.
"I need to buy clothes. Please give me 500 dollars."
"Mom, when will you grow up? Please stop causing trouble."
"Gosh, you should be used to my immaturity by now."
"I heard that water skiing is in vogue these days."
"From tomorrow on, I will learn how to water ski."
I don't know who is raising who.
"Mom, what is wrong with your face?"
"Your forehead, chin, and nose are chafed. How did it happen?"
"I think I fell down after I drank yesterday."
"What is wrong with me?"
She is very easily influenced, too. This happened once.
"Ma'am, you have a talent in singing."
- "You could be a singer." - No, no!
- No! - Stop it. Please.
No!
Perhaps there will be a duo after this shoot.
- No. - This is bad.
"I made up my mind. I am going to be a trot singer."
(Their worry came true.)
"Help me release an album."
"I really don't have money. Stop it already."
- Everyone wants an album. - "You have installment savings."
- "Use that money." - My goodness.
I am 30 years old. I need to get married at some point,
but everything I make goes to my mom.
How long do I need to live like this?
(Please help my immature mother come to her senses.)
Are we having an album special?
Seriously.
What is your opinion? I don't know what's going on today.
During the first worry, I told Myung Shim's husband that...
there is the right time for everything.
I said he can pursue his dream after his children grow up.
I see now it would be hard.
No one should use his or her child's money for it.
This woman is tired of looking after her immature mom.
Let's talk to her. Please come on out.
(Who is tired of looking after her immature mother?)
(He disappears.)
(He sacrificed himself to make people laugh.)
It's slippery.
(Yoo Min Hee)
She is the daughter.
- Tae Oh, are you okay? - Yes.
Tae Oh, since you collapsed,
we were more worried about you.
I didn't know the pool would be deep.
- Why did you do that? - I don't think that was the case.
I think he just collapsed.
He didn't watch where he was going.
Please introduce yourself.
I am from Icheon, Gyeonggi Province.
I am a 30-year-old, Yoo Min Hee.
- Min Hee, welcome. - Welcome.
How immature is your mom?
When I was young, my parents got a divorce.
Did it happen long time ago?
Yes. I was in elementary school. Because of that,
I began to live with my mom.
Everyone says that I raise my mom,
not the other way around.
I am responsible for all household chores.
When she goes outside for a short moment,
she tries on dozens of outfits.
- She does that. - She throws them on the floor.
- She doesn't clean after herself. - No, she doesn't.
When she eats at home, she leaves the dishes on the table.
In summer, the food rots.
(It makes the house smell bad.)
It would be moldy. There are times I can't go home...
- because of work. - The food rots.
Yes. It would be moldy.
Does food become moldy?
What?
It happens with leftovers.
- It happens with leftovers. - She never gets leftovers.
It sounds like your mom has to do...
- whatever she wants. - She gets sick otherwise.
- Give us some examples. - She gets depressed.
A few years ago, she was determined to learn how to water ski.
She ended up tearing her knee ligament.
Why do we keep hearing about a torn ligament today?
- We keep hearing about it. - Seriously.
- She got a cast on her leg. - I see.
She was so badly injured that she couldn't go to the toilet.
The next morning, she went to water ski again.
It sounds like she is full of good cheer.
How much is the equipment?
Didn't she rent the equipment?
- No, she didn't. - Did she buy the equipment?
- Yes, she did. - Doesn't it cost 10,000 dollars?
- She bought the equipment? - Yes.
It costs 2,000 dollars a month to water ski.
Did you pay for everything?
Yes, I did. My mom paid a small portion of it.
You must have made a lot of money.
My mom used up everything I earned.
- What about installment savings? - What about golf?
Even before she learned how to golf,
she bought 3,500 dollars' worth of golf clubs.
- Some people buy equipment first. - That's right.
- That's right. - She got an annual membership.
- An annual membership? - Yes.
- Isn't it really expensive? - Yes, it is.
- My goodness. - She golfed once or twice...
and said that it doesn't suit her.
- That's such a waste. - She stopped going.
What is the story about the album?
- She sighed. - My mom...
- often sings for volunteer work. - She doesn't get paid for that.
Whenever she does that, the others tell her...
It's an event that doesn't earn you any money.
The others tell her, "You can sing very well."
"You should be a singer." Upon hearing those compliments,
she closed the restaurant and became absorbed in trot music.
Is she currently working as a trot singer?
She is a regional singer who isn't well-known.
- A regional singer. - A regional singer.
- Is she a singer? - What's the region?
- Icheon. - Icheon, Gyeonggi Province.
- She doesn't get paid. - No.
What?
That's ridiculous.
The first worry was similar.
At Korean Melon Festival, she receives Korean melons.
- At least she gets something. - At Ceramic Festival,
- she receives ceramics. - At least she gets something.
How many albums has she released?
She has released two albums so far.
- She did release albums. - She is a regional singer.
It costs a lot of money to release an album.
It costs about 40,000 to 50,000 dollars.
(She spends about 40,000 to 50,000 dollars.)
- That's how much it costs. - It's usually cheaper than that.
- It's a single, right? - I don't know.
- Did she film a music video? - No, she didn't.
I am sure...
she got swindled by an agency.
It could be that Min Hee got swindled by her mom.
That's right.
40,000 dollars is a ridiculous amount.
It's one of the two.
My mom also likes to buy clothes.
She doesn't wear the clothes often after she buys them.
Her stage outfit costs about 500 to 600 dollars.
- You must have a negative balance. - She buys designer clothes.
Events are held at different places with different audiences.
She could wear the same outfit.
Even singers wear the outfit they wore on a show...
when they perform at events around the country.
- That's right. - Even the famous ones do that.
They wear the same outfit for a season.
You must have a lot of money.
No, I don't.
It sounds like you are a millionaire.
Seriously.
A conglomerate family.
I have credit card debts piled up.
She used up the money she got from selling the restaurant.
We now live in a house with a monthly rent.
- You are becoming poorer. - Yes.
Let's talk to the immature mom. Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
(Who is the immature mom who uses her daughter's money?)
- Ma'am. - Yes.
Do you think that you are immature?
(Does she think that she is immature?)
Yes, I do.
Really? Did you know...
about your daughter's worry?
Because I only think about myself,
I didn't think it would be a serious worry for her.
When did you take up trot music?
I sang for volunteer work for about 15 years...
at senior care centers and such.
They said, "You can sing very well."
"Why don't you release an album?"
- People asked you that. - Yes.
That's how I released an album.
Your daughter says it doesn't bring in much money.
I mostly donate my talent.
- It's a talent donation. - That's right.
I donate my talent...
for organizations for disabled or neglected people.
- It's good to volunteer. - Yes.
Singing gives me happiness.
Even if I don't have anything to eat tomorrow,
I am happy when I sing.
That's right. It's good...
that you sing for volunteer work.
It would have been great had you not released an album.
That's right. You could have sung hit songs by other singers.
When I performed at events,
people called me a fake singer.
They called you a fake singer.
- She used to cover hit songs. - When I performed,
people said, "Isn't she a fake singer?"
Now that you released albums, do you sing your own songs?
There are times I sing my own songs.
- People don't know your songs. - Of course they don't.
- "What kind of a singer is she?" - I am not surprised.
That's why I don't sing my songs often.
Releasing two albums didn't help much in the end.
- That's why... - They are useless.
Why do you keep asking for your daughter's help?
I depend on my daughter a lot.
That's why I keep asking for her help.
When it's her payday, I can't help but think,
"Won't she give me money?"
When I walk around complaining about money,
she puts allowance on my vanity.
Did you really ask her to close her installment savings account?
Since I wanted to release another album,
I asked her if she has installment savings.
Through which company did you release an album...
- that it cost thousands of dollars? - Seriously.
When I released my first album,
it cost that much.
Were you swindled?
I received songs from a composer.
It wasn't the composer who swindled me.
- The ones around him did. - A broker.
That's right.
She gave that much money because she was told to.
She doesn't even know in which process she got swindled.
- No, she doesn't. - That's right.
She just gave them the money.
How much did it cost to release your second album?
It didn't cost as much.
- How much did it cost? - 30,000 dollars?
- 20,000 dollars. 25,000 dollars. - 40,000 dollars.
We came close, right?
It didn't cost as much as the first album.
Since her 1st album cost 50,000 dollars,
she must have signed a contract readily...
when someone said he can do it for 40,000 dollars.
"I was swindled 10,000 dollars."
Even 40,000 dollars is a ridiculous amount.
Does she get conned often?
About six months ago,
she brought a strange contract.
I could tell that it was suspicious, so I told her clearly...
not to sign it.
However, she went ahead with it without my knowledge.
I ended up paying 7,000 dollars...
for the contract.
She signed a contract with an agency as a singer...
- and gave them money. - Did she really do that?
She should be the one receiving money in that situation.
Everyone should know this.
There is no proper agency in the world that asks for money.
It's a con by 100 percent.
When I perform at events,
there are people who give me their business cards...
and introduce themselves as composers.
"You need vocal training."
"It will cost money, but you will be able to perform at bigger stages."
I was scammed.
- It was a textbook scam. - I guess people still do that.
When I called them later, it was a non-existent number.
How much money in installment savings did you lose?
- Give us an estimate. - I think...
it's about 40,000 dollars.
(My goodness.)
That's a lot of money.
Has your mom ever paid you back?
- No, she hasn't. - She hasn't done it once.
No, not once.
- She was scammed by her mom. - I will pay her back.
You will pay her back. How will you do that?
I don't know how I will do that.
- What are you talking about? - However, I will pay her back.
- I will do it by any means. - How will you pay her back?
(Frustrated)
How did you save that money?
(How did she save that money?)
After I graduated from high school,
I worked as a salesperson for many years.
- I sold clothes. - You sold clothes.
I didn't even eat what I wanted to eat.
If I wanted to buy clothes,
I bought things that cost 9 dollars and 99 cents and such.
I worked hard to save 800 dollars.
- You saved that much every month. - Yes.
You saved up diligently.
- That was the installment savings. - Everything is gone now.
I don't have anything now.
- What about for your wedding? - I don't have anything.
- What should she do? - I don't have money for a wedding.
Have you tried talking to your mom?
"I can't give you more money. You really need to stop."
Have you done that?
- I have. - What did she say?
When I tell her that, she cries.
"Because of me, you can't do what you want to do."
- My goodness. - "I know that. I am sorry."
After that,
she reverts to her usual self.
- She does that again. - It's a scam.
- She can't turn down a request. - What has happened because of it?
- When her friends ask for money... - She lends it to them.
Even when she doesn't have money, she uses her credit card.
- Does she use her credit card? - She gets a cash advance...
and lends it to her friends. The problem is,
she doesn't know how to ask them to pay it back.
There is a lot of money she never got back.
What should we do when the problem is this serious?
- This is frustrating. - What should we do?
You know how she earned that money, right?
I know that she worked hard for that money.
Then how can you lend that kind of money so easily?
While I am not good to my daughter,
I am very good to those around me.
(What kind of nonsense is that?)
- My goodness. - How can you be...
so confident about it?
I was so surprised to hear her say it so confidently.
Why do you say that?
When the others tell me about their situation,
- I can't turn down their request. - Look.
Your daughter is telling you about her situation,
but you aren't listening.
Why do you listen to everyone...
- but your daughter? - Seriously.
When I began to make money,
my mom kept asking me to do things for my brother.
I decided to show her how hard I work...
so that she wouldn't ask me for money so easily.
I was very busy back then.
I would attend two shoots in a day...
and go to eight different events at night.
I dragged my mom everywhere. I said, "You saw that, right?"
Then I realized it might have been a mistake.
"I see that you make a lot of money."
- "You make a lot of money." - She said that.
It had an adverse effect.
She didn't know...
I was making that much money.
There is a debt...
you haven't told your daughter about, right?
Yes, there is.
- What is it? - Why are you so confident?
- My goodness. - What is it? Tell us.
I have a personal loan...
as well as money I borrowed from a friend.
It adds up to about 20,000 dollars.
Why did you borrow money?
I had to go to different places to perform.
- You used it for your performances. - Yes.
- You need money for costumes, - Yes. That's why I took out a loan.
transportation, and food.
A friend of hers is here. Let's talk to her.
- Hello. - Hello.
What are you most upset about?
What I am most upset about is...
I didn't know about these problems.
I am very frustrated right now.
- You didn't know the full story. - No, I didn't.
- You didn't know. - No.
- How does it feel to hear about it? - I am almost in tears.
When I was struggling with my business,
I had borrowed 10,000 dollars from her.
- You had borrowed it from her. - I thought she was doing well.
Hearing the full story choked me up.
It's difficult to get the words out.
You paid back 10,000 dollars, right?
- Of course I did. - She wouldn't be here otherwise.
You know,
- she was scammed many times. - I know about that.
She used a lot of money to release her albums...
and have vocal training.
She was scammed many times.
She lost about 100,000 or 200,000 dollars...
as far as I know.
- 100,000 or 200,000 dollars? - Yes.
- 100,000 or 200,000 dollars? - In total.
If Min Hee's mom takes up a different profession,
the situation wouldn't be this bad.
It would be the right thing to give up.
However, thinking about my friend gives me a change of heart.
- Thinking about her daughter... - Is she a talented singer?
- What? - Is she a talented singer?
I think she can sing very well.
I am curious about her singing skills.
- I know. - We saw a dance earlier.
It's time to listen to a song.
Would you like to dance behind her?
- He doesn't want to. - He is sick and tired of it now.
- Thank goodness. - He doesn't want to.
We are seeing some positive changes.
I would have said something had he gone, "I will do that."
- She is very tall. - I know.
She is cool.
("Brother" by Kum Jan Di)
(Since you say you love me)
(My goodness.)
(Since you say you really do)
She's pretty good.
(I ride the clouds)
(And soar into the bright sky)
(She isn't half bad.)
(She sings with a steady and relaxed voice.)
(This is wrong.)
(Even if I die right now, I have no regrets)
(I am happy that I am a woman)
Wasn't it surprising that she's actually good?
It felt like she was good...
because we saw someone dancing first.
- It's because of that. - His dancing was too weak.
What did you think of her singing, K.will?
Watching her, I... My gosh.
- What is it? - What's wrong?
She can't give up.
She can't get rid of the desire.
I understand that she's very desperate to do it.
But she can sing anywhere.
She could sing on the streets. All she needs is a mic.
She can have just one outfit for her performance.
- I want to ask her that. - You could have one outfit.
Ma'am, why do you buy new clothes...
when you go to different events and meet new people?
I don't want to go on stage wearing old clothes.
(She wants to wear new clothes every time she performs.)
- She is... - She's irresponsible and greedy.
Look.
I am starting to doubt...
if you actually love singing.
Perhaps you just want to become famous.
You already act as if you are a big celebrity.
It's not like your performances are aired on TV,
and yet you refuse to wear the clothes youve worn once.
It doesn't seem like you love singing so much.
- It doesn't seem like it. - Yes.
I don't do that only when I sing.
- I think that's how she lives. - I love buying new clothes,
- and I like changing clothes. - But...
- When I go somewhere... - You need to see the reality.
Once I wear the clothes once, I rarely wear them again.
Are you saying you have to live like that because it's how you are?
Yes.
You should change the way you think.
You should change.
- She should change. - She should change.
By any chance, do you drink a lot?
- It's... - I love to drink.
- What did she say? - I love to drink.
- Why would you brag it? - She loves to drink too.
There was a time when she drank every day of the week.
When I came home from work, all the lights were on.
All the clothes were scattered in the living room.
I thought someone broke in, and I got really surprised.
When I went in, I found my mother...
passed out on the bed with her shoes on.
When I saw her face, her entire face was scratched.
- You must've been so surprised. - Why did she do that?
- Really? - She fell after drinking.
Why do you drink so much?
- I love drinking. - You binge-drink.
Yes. I binge-drink, and I get drunk.
- Some people are like that. - My goodness.
But the problem is that she can't remember things.
But I don't behave badly even when I am drunk.
- That's behaving badly. - That's behaving badly.
Their positions are switched.
- I know. - I know.
She's not a typical mother figure.
My gosh. Why do you do it?
I married young and had children young.
I had a dream, but... I was often upset about it.
Before I got divorced, whenever my children were sleeping,
I thought about how unhappy I was.
I always questioned why I was living the way I was living.
- That's understandable. - Yes.
Do you think you traded your life with your daughter?
And is that why you want her to compensate you for it?
When I come home after drinking,
I resent my children.
- I tell them... - You had to give up your dream.
I tell them I had to give up my life to raise them.
But she didn't ask to be born.
- She didn't have a choice. - I know.
My daughter sometimes argues that.
And she says she doesn't know why I live like this.
Has your mother resented you a lot?
Whenever she drinks,
she says her life is ruined because of me.
- She says you ruined her life. - That's very hurtful.
She says things like that without filtering them.
(How does she feel when she hears it?)
How do you feel when you hear that?
It makes me wonder if I am actually standing in her way.
I even thought about that.
She's crying right now.
This is how crazy it is. It's beyond common sense.
- Why are you crying? - I know.
Does your mother treat you the same, Young Ji?
She's gotten emotional.
- Tell us about it. - I am sorry.
- It's just... - Is your mom...
- releasing a trot album? - She talks so calmly.
It must've broken her heart.
She seems very calm, but she must be...
- a mess inside. - She got...
- used to it. - Yes.
- She did. - She's worn off.
- She has to be worn off. - Yes.
She's not used to expressing her feelings.
I feel sorry for her.
Growing up, when was the toughest time for you?
It was when I was about 25 or 26.
- Why was it tough for you? - Why?
It was really tough. It was mostly because of Mom.
At the time,
I had no desire to live,
and I didn't go out of the house.
I didn't want to answer any calls, so I kept my phone turned off.
I didn't eat either. I lost 12kg in a week.
- That happens if you don't eat. - I couldn't eat.
It's not that I didn't want to eat. I couldn't eat.
How did you get over that?
Whenever I think about doing something bad,
I get worried about Mom.
I think she can't live without me.
- You're always worried about her. - Your mom is the cause,
- Yes, I am worried. - and she's also the drive.
- Yes. - Have you not known about this?
I thought she was on a diet.
(She thought her daughter was simply being on a diet.)
She didn't want to tell you. That's how uninterested you are in her.
You are so self-centered.
Right.
Since she was young,
we never really talked.
Something really upsets me, you see.
You don't seem sorry at all.
- Why is that? - Why is that?
I try to understand you, but I keep nearly losing my temper.
- You don't seem sorry at all. - I think I am an egoistic person.
- You think you're egoistic. - I am egoistic.
I had never been this frustrated while being on a TV show.
- It's because... - Do you have a sibling?
There are 13 of us.
- 13 children? - And I am the youngest.
- You're the youngest of 13. - You're the youngest of 13.
- Yes. - There are 13 of us.
- She must've been so loved. - Growing up as the youngest,
I was always told that I was the best and that I sing well.
I was always praised highly. Even after giving birth,
I continued to be constantly complimented.
And that made me selfish. I became egoistic.
Right. You are very self-centered.
How people look at you is very important to you,
and you want people to pay attention to you.
And you enjoy it immensely.
Meanwhile, your family is suffering a lot and going crazy.
Her daughter's mind is rotting away.
Our presenters rarely get this upset.
But they got upset twice today.
This is really tough.
- It's really tough. - Please pass the mic to the back.
This is the toughest shoot I've experienced in 27 years.
- Sir. - Dong Yeob is famous...
- Do you understand the lady? - for not showing his feelings.
I think she deserves to be here.
(He thinks it's a big worry.)
You are just like her.
You are just the same.
- I... - Look at your wife.
(I give up.)
There must've been a reason why you decided to take it here.
What are you mostly worried about?
Mom...
- wants to go to Japan. - Why?
- Japan? - She wants to go to Japan...
and become a singer there.
Who did she meet this time?
Did Kang Nam convince you?
- Did someone tell you to... - I feel so uncomfortable.
Does she speak any Japanese?
Not at all. She has never been to Japan,
- and she doesn't speak Japanese. - How did you think of this idea?
- She's unbelievable. - Why do you want to go to Japan?
I want to go to Japan...
and sing.
Wait. Who told you to go there?
Tell us about it. I want to tell you...
- if your plan is feasible. - I know someone...
who's lived in Japan for a long time.
He asked me to go with him to Japan...
- and audition at clubs. - But...
you need a place to stay,
and you need money to spend. Will that person pay for it?
- I didn't ask about that. - Who would pay for that?
It's understandable that you want to go to Japan to chase your dream.
What will happen to your daughter?
I didn't think about that.
(She's really unbelievable.)
- Since she was young... - Why didn't you think of that?
- She should've... - Do you think...
your daughter will pay for your trip?
- I dropped a hint. - What?
- What did she say? - She dropped a hint.
- She dropped a hint. - I asked her...
if she's got any more money to lend me.
Don't you think you are being very irresponsible?
I think it will work out somehow. So I just want to do it.
I want to start it and see what happens.
- You're upset, aren't you, Tae Oh? - This is crazy.
I think she's very immature.
Right.
I admit that. I admit that I am immature.
(Her shamelessness is beyond our imagination.)
It must be so tough for her daughter.
- I've been told that I'm immature. - Some of the audience...
are crying.
What did you say?
I've been told that I am too immature for my age.
Don't you think about how to become more mature?
That's life.
By any chance, did you drink before coming here?
It has never been this tough.
We can't communicate. I feel like I'm talking to a wall.
"You are selfish". "Yes. I am selfish."
- Right. - It just bounces back.
I want to ask you this question to make myself feel better.
Do you feel sorry to your daughter?
- Honestly. - I feel sorry.
- Do you feel very sorry to her? - Yes.
But do you have a hard time saying sorry? And do you...
unintentionally say mean things?
- Yes. - Thank goodness.
- I am bad at expressing myself. - I asked her that question...
with a thread of hope. It's because...
I think everyone who watches this will get disappointed and struggle.
You only say the most selfish things.
I asked you that question to try to understand your behavior.
Ma'am, trot music is different from regular pop music.
What do you need the most to sing trot?
- It's the emotions. - Yes.
You need the feeling of desperate love or sorrow.
When you sing,
it's not bad. It's technically good.
But it doesn't touch our heart.
In order to sing well, as you dearly hope to,
you should build a strong bond with your daughter before going to Japan.
I think your daughter needs your love.
- Yes. - That's what I think.
And you need to learn that emotion of love.
If you contain that emotion in your singing,
you will be able to touch more people's hearts.
I...
- Don't answer right away. - Right.
You should think before you give an answer.
I eat a lot, but I wait until everything is digested.
- Really? - Of course.
What would you want to tell her before we end?
This is your chance.
I want us to be like a typical mother and daughter.
I want us to talk a lot.
You should tell her yourself.
- I'm not used to talking to her. - It's awkward for them.
I will introduce her to you. She's your mother.
(She should muster up her courage.)
"Mom."
Mom. From now on...
I won't always say no.
I want you to discuss things with me...
no matter how menial things are.
Don't go somewhere and give an autograph.
I really don't want you...
to go to Japan.
Do you love your mom?
I do, but I've never said it.
- Let's do it today. - You've never said it?
Mom, I love you.
Let's be happy.
(Let's be happy.)
All right. Let's start the voting.
K. will.
It must've been really tough for her.
I suddenly feel so thankful to my parents.
It's a worry.
I hope you will talk to each other a lot.
I also think it's a worry.
It's a very big worry.
I kept looking at her...
when she was talking.
I am so thankful...
because she grew as such a lovely lady.
Her mother should be really thankful to her...
for growing as a lovely lady.
She should give her a hug for enduring the tough times.
I feel so thankful to her.
If you sympathize with her,
please press the buttons.
(What does the audience think?)
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
- Stop. - Stop.
Ma'am, this is your time to tell her how you really feel.
I think I depended on you a lot.
Now whenever something happens, I will discuss it with you.
I am sorry.
And I love you, Min Hee.
How about Japan?
I won't go.
You won't go.
Ma'am, you can go to Japan,
but you have to do more research and go when you can afford it.
I won't go.
Don't say it like a baby.
- I really won't go. - Don't go. All right.
If you go, I will go chase after you.
Don't you dare go to Japan.
All right. Let's find out how many votes she got.
"Do I Look Like an ATM?" Please show us the result.
(The result)
Wouldn't it be 156?
- It could be more than that. 166? - Will she get one more vote?
It might be 166.
- 166. - Is it 176?
(She's nervous.)
- 176? - 166.
(She got 166 votes.)
Before I introduce the next story, I want to say this.
I was feeling really frustrated a while ago...
- because I know my story. - Right.
Thinking about it,
I think I am in a similar situation.
No way.
- Please. - What's wrong with today?
Why is everything so serious today?
It's the director's fault.
(It worries me.)
Hello. I am a housewife in her 30s...
who has a romantic husband.
When I wake up in the morning...
"Good morning." "O Sole Mio".
It's just like a while ago.
It's a little different. Even in the afternoon...
"O Sole Mio".
Even at night...
He sings Italian songs day and night.
It's driving me mad.
"This is an announcement from the management."
"A lot of residents are complaining about the noise."
"Please keep the noise down..."
"so that your neighbors won't suffer from the noise."
"My goodness. Isn't that about us?"
"No, it's not." "O Sole Mio".
He sings even on streets. What's up with people?
"Do you want me to sing for you?"
"O Sole Mio".
You should at least change the song.
He even sings to strangers.
What's wrong with my husband?
Someone please seal my husband's mouth.
She must've been so fed up with him.
- She asked us to seal his mouth. - To seal his mouth.
- She wants to seal his mouth. - I...
Let's bring her in. Please come on out.
(Who's worried about her husband who keeps singing Italian songs?)
(Sung Si Eun)
She sat down.
I will throw a straight question.
- Is your husband a vocalist? - Please, say yes.
No, he is not a vocalist.
- Then... - He did study vocal music.
- He studied it. - He studied it.
- Thank goodness. - I'm glad he studied it.
- I know. - Still...
He teaches children singing.
(He's a teacher.)
At least it's related to what he does for a living.
Is he going to release an album?
- Please. - Please.
Let me ask you that. Is he going to release an album?
- No. - Thank goodness.
Thank you.
Has his ligament ever been ruptured?
(Please forget it now.)
Is it a little exaggerated? Or is he really like that?
- Does he always sing? - Does he constantly sing?
From the moment he wakes up to just before going to bed,
he sings for more than six hours.
Does he sing at home?
- That would drive you mad. - Yes.
When he comes home from work,
I hear my husband singing in the elevator.
- Does he sing in the elevator? - Yes.
(K.will is aging quickly.)
I understand what it's like.
My father was like this.
My father has passed away,
- but he wanted to be a vocalist. - That's amazing.
So he sang "O Sole Mio" all the time at home.
- Is that why... - When he drinks,
- he sings it on the way home. - He sings on the way.
That's how we knew that he was coming home.
He used to sing "O Sole Mio" like that 3 or 4 times a week.
- It's really embarrassing. - By the way,
does he sing like that even when he's sober?
He can't drink well.
- And he sings like that. - He's sober.
- Is he always sober? - Yes.
By the way,
since he studied vocal music, he must sing quite well.
And since he is a vocal trainer,
- It must be nice to hear. - it...
shouldn't stress you out so much.
Italian songs are not very quiet.
When you are right next to the person singing,
especially when he hits high notes, my ears feel as if they're bursting.
It's like playing drums next to your ears.
Because he's always so loud,
our child shouts whenever he comes home.
(The child copies her husband.)
And my husband scolds my child for shouting.
When I ask him if he can keep it down a little,
he says he's an understanding and considerate person.
He says I am being inconsiderate.
He's thick-faced.
Have you never tried telling him not to sing?
I tell him not to sing in a serious manner.
Whenever I do that, he says "Okay."
But when he gets inspired, he sings again.
I told him I couldn't...
live with him like this.
When I said that, he begged and said he wouldn't do it again.
- But he sings again? - Yes, he sang again after a while.
(Just imagining it is tough enough.)
There's a channel for vocal music. It's always on.
- He always watches that channel. - It's crazy.
He keeps explaining about the songs and the conductors.
He constantly talks about it.
Do you have to react when he says those?
Or does he not care and just goes on talking?
He goes on even if I don't react.
He must be someone who only cares about what he thinks.
He looks like it.
- Yes. - Even now,
he can't wait to talk.
He keeps nodding.
- He's waiting for his turn. - Yes.
Let's not ask him anything.
Let's end the shoot here.
Please press...
I almost pressed the button.
Let's meet her husband. Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
His voice is good.
- "Hello." - "Hello."
This is the question we always give.
Do you understand your wife's concern?
It's true that I sing.
I love singing,
so I don't think it's a worry.
It's a worry for your wife, not for you.
Are you saying it's not a worry for your wife?
I don't think it's a worry.
You've seen the man from the first story...
who dances all the time...
and the lady who sings trot.
What do you think about those people?
I don't think there's something wrong with them.
They are doing what they love.
This is going to be tough.
They should be praised.
What's wrong with today?
- They're not problematic. - Is this a special?
Please don't say that with such a peaceful face.
I think K.will doesn't suit this show well.
Whenever he comes out,
- the stories are very serious. - K.will...
looks about three years older than when he started.
(This is Hello effect.)
You're right.
She said he sings on streets.
I heard him singing in the waiting room.
Was he singing in the waiting room?
- Didn't you hear that? - He was humming.
That's why it was so loud.
Streets, grocery store, cinema, cafe, and hospital.
- Cinema? - Park.
He sang a while ago.
He always sings loud.
When he walks on a street, there are people in front of him.
When he sings loudly, people turn back.
- Right. - He enjoys it.
Then he pauses.
When people start walking again, he sings again.
When they turn back, he pretends it's not him.
- I'm ashamed. - I can understand.
Why do you sing all the time?
I had a desire to be successful by singing,
but I couldn't accomplish my dream as my parents were against it,
so I have deep resentment.
I'm singing all the time to fulfill my desire.
Then you should sing on the stage,
not next to people who don't like it.
You can sing on the stage.
I do that sometimes,
but music is my life,
- so... - Music is your life?
- I sing all day. - Music is his life.
(I'll sing for you 24 hours.)
(It's already ringing in her ears.)
There are many genres in music.
I know you like classic, but hip hop's been popular lately.
How do you feel when you listen to that?
I'm not interested in hip hop.
What if your wife raps all day long...
when you're not interested?
- Connection - She keeps rapping.
- Then... - Yangwha bridge
Yangwha bridge Yangwha bridge
You wouldn't even want to go near.
If she does, it's what she likes.
- Will you accept it? - I don't think it's a worry.
Your wife likes it?
I heard you sing in an elevator.
Yes. I keep singing in the elevator.
When people get on the elevator, I stop for a second,
then go down to the first floor.
- You go down? - I go down and if there's no one,
I sing again as I go up to my house.
It rings.
- It feels great. - Do you sing looking in the mirror?
Yes, I do.
Even if you sing in the elevator,
aren't you aware that the other houses can hear you?
It's a common sense. I'm aware of it,
- but I don't care since I like it. - My gosh.
Before my debut,
when I wanted to be a singer, I didn't have a place to practice.
I wanted to practice so badly,
so I used to sing under the bridge in Jungnangcheon.
Then there was a big road, I sang in the middle of it.
- Right. - That's what I did.
You shouldn't sing in the apartment.
- That's noise pollution. - There was even an announcement.
Even if there was an announcement, people can't say it's me.
(They don't know what to say.)
You said you're rational and considerate,
but think about it. It's okay when you don't mind it,
- but your wife doesn't like it. - Yes.
You should stop since your wife's getting stressed.
- Right. - If you're considerate.
- I feel sorry for her. - It's not like you live alone.
I reflect on myself too,
but what is learned in the cradle is carried to the tomb.
Are you saying you'll do it until you die?
Why did you describe yourself rational and considerate?
This isn't rational or considerate.
You're inconsistent.
- You're not considerate at all. - I agree.
- Selfish. - It's not right.
- What? - The lady next to him...
just said, "He's selfish."
I got goosebumps.
Selfish people recognize each other.
- Did she say he's selfish? - Yes. Just now.
Is there anyone who likes it?
When there are many people, he needs to sing together,
- but his voice stands out. - In the choir?
It'd make sense if he's in a choir.
Oh, when he just sings.
- Yes. When he just sings. - Alone?
Some people do that.
So people come to me, and say quietly,
"Your husband's too loud."
He's showing off...
- in public. - Right.
When I invite someone to my house, or when I'm invited,
he suddenly gets ready.
When we're having a conversation,
he asks the guests, "Would you mind if I sing for you?"
The guests can't possibly say no.
- Right. - Right.
They can't say, "I'm sorry, but no."
"No."
If I was there, I probably said no.
Then he sings 3 or 4 songs.
I'm worried about the complaints from the neighbors,
and what the guests would think.
Is it because of your resentment?
Other people's goal is to release an album.
I want to perform in front of Europeans as an Asian.
I also want to perform in Seoul Arts Center.
Are you going to release an album if you get to perform?
If I get a chance, I'll start working on it.
If you still want to be an opera singer,
you can stop bothering other people and get a practice room.
Right. Why would you do that at home?
I want to show people,
and let them hear me.
It'd make sense if he's practicing...
to perform in a bigger stage,
but that's not what he wants to do.
He wants to sing in front of people.
- He wants to show them. - He wants to show off.
He wants to enjoy people's reaction.
The two things...
- Coexist? - coexist.
We saw his dance.
Please come to the stage.
(Let's listen to your singing.)
(We don't want to hear it, but we will.)
("O sole mio")
Look at his pose.
(She looks like she heard it million times already.)
He's actually good.
(My ears.)
(Oh, my ears.)
(The evaluation is up to them.)
Do you have any other worries?
He often watches concerts.
- To watch? - Yes.
He's there for the rehearsal instead of the actual concert.
He wants me to go with him for the rehearsal.
- He wants to go with you. - Yes.
Everyone's busy in the waiting room.
Right. Because they have to get ready.
But he goes off and introduces me...
- and my daughter to them. - My goodness.
Do you really think that's necessary?
Since I love singing, I get vicarious satisfaction.
I want to be a great professor like them at music college.
Why would you bring your wife?
I want to take my wife with me...
and introduce her to the masters.
- But why? - She doesn't like it.
Even though she doesn't like it...
Your wife doesn't like it, and those people aren't interested.
- But I do that because I like it. - Gosh.
He's selfish.
Don't you think you're beyond selfish?
I do,
but rather than doing it alone,
food tastes better when we share it.
But it's bad food.
- What about your wife? - Your wife thinks it's bad food.
- She has no choice since I like it. - My goodness.
(She has no choice since I like it.)
What do you hate the most among what your husband forces you?
When we go on a trip,
he sings songs about the place we go,
and he wants me to film it.
- Pardon me? - Film it.
He wants to record himself singing?
- He wants to remember it. - Do you do it for him?
Let's watch the video.
Did you really film that?
He asked his wife to film it.
(Next to water)
(Ship on the way to Gangneung to greet the moon)
He sings this song when he goes there.
In Gangneung?
(Thousand years of Silla)
- Gyeongju. - Gyeongju.
(In front of ancient tombs in Gyeongju)
I've only heard a few songs, but I'm getting sick of it already.
I'm sure she's pretty stressed to listen to it all day.
Even when we were on honeymoon, every time he saw a European,
he'd sing a song from their country.
Then I'd stand alone and record it.
You recorded it? You're like a camerawoman.
I've always wanted to...
perform in Europe,
so when I see Europeans, I sing Italian songs,
and I feel satisfied from it.
What kind of songs do you like, ma'am?
I don't like any songs.
She doesn't like any songs. This is what happens.
- You make her hate it. - This is what happened to them.
They are unable to communicate.
"I like it, so she has no choice."
They're unable to communicate. It's one way.
Your wife's stressed because you force her.
It's not communication. She's in pain.
My husband made breakfast for me on the weekend,
but I was tired, and I wanted to sleep in more.
Bu he forces me to wake up,
- You have to eat. - and make me eat.
- With him? - Yes.
So I tell him I want to sleep for more,
but he says I must eat before it gets cold.
Also, if he peels some fruit for me,
but if I tell him I don't want to eat it,
he'd ask me why I don't want to eat it.
- He peeled it. - He forces me to eat it.
Why do you force her to eat it?
I have a desire to share everything with my wife.
That's why.
That's not love. You're forcing her.
He'd smile like that and force you to eat it, right?
That'd be so scary in the morning.
Why did you marry your husband?
That's one of the types you find very stressful.
- He's very unique. - What did you like about him?
Say something appropriate for the show.
(Something appropriate for the show)
Tell me one thing please.
He's very loving...
Right. That makes sense.
But after you married him, what did you think of his love?
- It's selfish love. - It's one way.
Yes.
We know that he has a warm heart,
but his way of expressing his feelings is wrong.
- He's the same person you fell for. - I know.
What about him worries you the most?
As you can see now, my husband...
thinks about singing all day long every day.
If he's that passionate about it,
I think he should give it a go,
and study overseas to learn more about it.
Where will he go? Japan?
- He should go to Italy. - Yes. To Europe.
If he fails to build a singing career,
we can come back to Korea and start from scratch again.
- She's willing to support him. - Yes, I am.
- You're so cool. - Well,
- that's what I think. - I see.
So I suggested that he should give it a try,
- but he's worried about his age, - Why?
and about leaving his parents alone in Korea.
He wants to be a filial son at the same time?
Why did you refuse to do that?
- Your wife is so supportive. - I know. I have...
many different reasons.
As I'm not so young,
I'm not very confident.
Also, it's not an easy decision to move to Europe...
- with my wife and child. - Then, you should change your mind.
- You should give up on your dream. - I don't...
I don't want to do that.
(He's stubborn, but not driven.)
You insist on singing your favorite song in front of her.
Even when she's not in the mood, you force her to hear you sing.
However, you never accepted her offer.
I do feel sorry.
So I pray every single night,
and reflect on myself, but in the morning, I do the same thing.
(I do the same thing next morning.)
I keep telling me to put myself in her shoes and fix my problems.
You think of it, but you never put that thought into action.
Wouldn't it be nice if you two could exchange your thoughts?
When your wife suggests something, you say, "Oh, right. I get it."
"I'll try harder. Did I do that again? I'm sorry."
"I can't seem to fix this problem."
Instead of praying at night and forgetting that in the morning,
pray every morning to help you not repeat the same mistakes.
It'd be better to pray in the morning.
Actually, he's so sly in a sense.
He doesn't block his ears. He pretends to listen to what she says.
- Whenever she talks to him, - That's right.
he pretends to hear her out, but he never changes his mind.
That's a really bad thing.
(It's hard if you keep insisting even with a smile.)
Tell him what you want from him.
Tell him everything.
Honey, I think you have a talent,
and it's rare to have it.
I also believe you're talented enough...
to perform on stage in Europe.
I hope you will relieve your desire in the right direction...
so you can develop your talent and build your own career.
Be brave.
- She's such a cool wife. - That was a great comment.
- She must love him deeply. - My goodness.
- Young Ji, let's start with you. - Okay.
I don't think it's a worry...
because he has such a great wife.
I think he can resolve this through communicating with her.
I don't think it's a worry.
- Kang Nam. - Oh, no. I didn't...
- I'm sorry. - You thought it was a worry inside.
She thought to herself that it's a worry.
Young Ji may have said cheerful comments,
- but she actually hated him. - She thinks it's a worry.
She pressed the button unconsciously.
She tried to maintain her public image.
We heard three different stories. All of them made me realize...
that I shouldn't let my hobby cause any trouble...
for my family.
- You pronounced "hobby" wrong. - Hobby.
I think this is a worry too.
I still don't think it's a worry.
If you really love your wife, you should start refraining yourself...
as your wife wants.
I...
won't press the button to keep myself in a good mood.
(K.will doesn't think it's a worry.)
If you have just a little self control,
- That's right. - I think it can be resolved.
If you think it's a worry, please press the button.
(What does the audience think?)
- 5, 4, 3, 2, 1. - 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
- Stop. - Time's up.
Say a word to your wife for the last time.
I would like to apologize to her once again.
Also, I promise that I will try to refrain myself...
so her worries can be resolved.
Thank you.
What should you do when she says she wants to sleep instead of eating?
- I should let her sleep. - That's right.
Is there anything you want him to stop doing?
I want him to stop singing in front of our baby...
because our baby is stressed out because of that.
- It's because he's loud. - No wonder she's a mother.
Do you think you can stop singing in front of your baby?
Yes, I'll keep my promise.
Let's see how many votes she got.
Please show us the result.
(The result)
The current winner got 166 votes.
(What could be the result?)
- Okay. - She got 92 votes.
(She got 92 votes.)
This week's winner is "Do I Look Like an ATM?"
We will give you a prize. Congratulations!
Until the day we are all worry-free...
Hello will continue to counsel you.
- Thank you! - Thank you!