*[Divine Thing
by Soup Dragons playing]
* YOU ARE
THE ONE SUPREME BEING *
* JUST DRESSED TO KILL
* AND FULFILL
JUST ANY DREAM *
* YOU ARE
THE ONE HEART'S DESIRE *
* ALL HIPS AND LIPS
* MADE TO TRICK
JUST ANY FOOL *
* I COULD HAVE SWORN
THAT YOU WERE AN ANGEL *
* 'CAUSE YOU'RE
A SWEET, SWEET, SWEET *
* DIVINE THING
* BUT I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
* THAT YOU WERE THE DEVIL
* DRESSED LIKE A SWEET,
SWEET, SWEET *
* DIVINE THING
* YOU LACK THE ONE THING
THAT IS DEVOTION *
* NOT ALWAYS THERE,
IN YOUR HAIR *
* IN A DAZE
* JUST TOO MIXED UP
IN YOUR OWN EMOTION *
* YOUR VANITY
* WILL ALWAYS BE
YOUR GREATEST THING *
* I COULD HAVE SWORN
THAT YOU WERE AN ANGEL *
* 'CAUSE YOU'RE
A SWEET, SWEET, SWEET *
* DIVINE THING
* BUT I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
* THAT YOU WERE THE DEVIL
* DRESSED LIKE A SWEET,
SWEET, SWEET *
* DIVINE THING *
[people chattering
in Japanese]
*[music playing]
(man)
MMM. MMM.
MMM.
GIN AND TONIC, PLEASE.
ANOTHER GINGER ALE.
AND HURRY,
BEFORE THEY REALIZE
MONKEYS COULD DO THIS JOB.
GET PAID WITH SCRAPS.
PARDON ME, FRIEND.
DO WE KNOW EACH OTHER?
I SINCERELY HOPE NOT.
I'M--I'M VICTOR THUMMELL,
V.P. OF MORTGAGES.
OH. THANK YOU.
[imitating monkey]
OH, THAT'S CUTE.
YOU'RE CUTE. HAVE A TREAT.
[grunting]
MMM.
*[music continues playing]
[sniffling]
MIGHT I INQUIRE
WHY YOU'RE CRYING?
THIS IS THE FIRST
NEW YEAR'S EVE
I'VE SPENT ON MY OWN,
SINCE MY DIVORCE.
OH.
I WAS MARRIED TO A MAN
WHO USED TO MAKE ME FEEL
LIKE DIRT.
LORD, I MISS HIM SO.
CEASE THOSE TEARS.
AND COME JOIN THE PARTY.
LEST PEOPLE THINK
I COULDN'T FIND A DATE
FOR NEW YEAR'S EVE.
*[Moon River
by Andy Williams playing]
* MOON RIVER
* WIDER THAN A MILE
* I'M CROSSING YOU
IN STYLE SOME DAY *
* OH, DREAM MAKER
[grunting]
* YOU HEART BREAKER *
[Rebecca laughing]
A THOROUGHBRED OWNER
FROM ENGLAND!
I THOUGHT ONLY DRUNKEN LOSERS
WOULD BE AT TONIGHT'S PARTY.
IF YOU THOUGHT THAT,
WHY DID YOU COME?
TO MEET SOMEBODY.
HERE'S TO RUNNING
WITH THE IN-CROWD
IN THE NEW YEAR.
[glass shattering]
OH! OH, MY GOD. OH.
I'M SORRY. OH.
OH.
YES, IT'S...
IT'S--IT'S ALL RIGHT.
OH.
(Gloria)
EXCUSE ME.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
THERE'S A PHONE CALL FOR YOU
AT THE FRONT DESK.
GLORIA, WHAT GIVES YOU
THE RIGHT TO INTERFERE?
YOU'RE LATE,
AND THERE'S AN EMERGENCY.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
THIS GUY'S CREDIT CARD
WON'T CLEAR
AND HE IS REALLY PISSED.
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
MATTHEW, I WANT THAT LINCOLN
RETURNED TO ME RIGHT NOW.
IT WAS A MISTAKE,
LETTING YOU BORROW IT.
WELL, IT'S ABOUT
GODDAMNED TIME.
YOU'RE USING
THE ACCESS CODE FOR VISA
INSTEAD OF AMERICAN EXPRESS.
[bell dinging]
WHAT KIND OF ASS-BACKWARD
HOTEL ARE YOU RUNNIN' HERE?
WELL, MY APOLOGIES, SIR,
BUT THIS LITTLE LADY HERE,
SHE'S JUST--
SHE'S JUST
LEARNING THE ROPES.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE
FROM LEXINGTON, SON.
BORN AND RAISED.
WELL, HAPPY NEW YEAR, BOY.
AND RIGHT BACK AT YA.
HI.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
WHERE AM I GOING, GLORIA?
I AM NOT SPENDING
ANOTHER NEW YEAR'S EVE
BEHIND THIS DESK.
[phone rings]
I AM GOING TO BE
DANCING THE NIGHT AWAY
WITH THE REST
OF NORTH AMERICA.
[telephone ringing]
HOLIDAY PALACE.
MATTHEW!
ASSISTANT MANAGER FOR YOU.
SIMON.
YOU HAVE THE NIGHT OFF.
WHY ARE YOU CALLING HERE?
(Simon)
JUST CHECKING IN.
WHY ARE YOU WEARING
A WHITE DINNER JACKET?
I HAVE GOT YOU
BY THE BALLS THIS TIME,
YOU ENTRY-LEVEL
PIECE OF SHIT. YEAH.
I'VE HEARD ALL ABOUT THE, UH,
LITTLE GAMES YOU PLAY
WHILE I'M NOT AROUND.
SIMON--
NO.
NO. YOU WILL GO
SEE MR. LEVINE.
[Mr. Levine clears throat]
MATTHEW.
YOU KNOW,
YOU REMIND ME OF MY OWN SON.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S NOT A COMPLIMENT.
MY OWN SON IS A PUTZ.
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
MIDNIGHT.
JESUS.
THE FIREWORKS JUST GAVE ME
A FLASHBACK TO VIETNAM.
YOU WERE IN VIETNAM?
NO.
BUT THERE ARE
A LOT OF MOVIES.
LISTEN.
WE'VE NEVER HAD
A PROBLEM BEFORE.
SO WHY DON'T YOU
JUST GO BACK TO WORK?
FAREWELL, LOSER.
I WASN'T LET GO, SIMON.
LEVINE DIDN'T FIRE YOU?
SHIT!
WHY ARE THE JEWISH PEOPLE
ALWAYS SO FORGIVING?
YOU'RE A PITIFUL FUCK, WELSH.
I'VE HATED GUYS LIKE YOU
ALL MY LIFE.
HETEROSEXUALS?
WHAT A DICK.
SIR, YOU WILL NEVER GUESS
WHO IS ON THE PHONE
RIGHT NOW.
SIMON, I AM NOT
IN THE MOOD TO GUESS.
JUST TELL ME.
I'LL GIVE YOU A HINT. FRANCE.
GO ON, TAKE A SHOT.
IT WON'T KILL YOU.
[glass shattering]
SHE'S ON LINE 2.
I'M CALLING IT A NIGHT.
ANY MESSAGES FOR ME?
I'M IN 796.
NO, SIR.
NO MESSAGES FOR YOU.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING
BACK THERE?
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU CHECKED ME IN
THIS MORNING.
YOU WORK HERE.
[laughing]
YOU WORK...
[continues laughing]
HEY. HEY, HE WORKS HERE.
OH, MY GOD, MATTHEW.
DON'T SAY IT, PLEASE.
OK, I'M SORRY. OK.
JUST DON'T SAY IT.
(Gloria)
LOOK, SHE'S EVERYWHERE.
I LIKE MEN
WHO DARE TO BE DIFFERENT.
[buffer whirring]
[vacuum cleaner humming]
I LIKE MEN
WHO KNOW HOW TO PLAY.
I LIKE MEN WHO AREN'T AFRAID
TO TAKE RISKS.
I LIKE MEN TO BE INDIFFERENT.
(man)
INDIFFERENCE.
FOR THOSE
WHO COULD CARE LESS.
FROM PIERRE KATZ.
[T.V. clicking off]
GOD, I WISH I SAW
A FACE LIKE THAT
IN THE MIRROR.
TRUST ME. I'VE SEEN
WHAT HEXINA LOOKS LIKE
IN THE MORNING.
IT'S GROTESQUE.
YOU'VE SLEPT
WITH HEXINA?
WHY DO YOU
ALWAYS LIE TO ME?
IT JUST SO HAPPENS
THAT I HAPPEN TO KNOW...
EVERY TIME YOU SEE
A CELEBRITY ON T.V...
...A LOT OF VERY,
VERY FAMOUS PEOPLE.
...YOU SAY YOU KNOW THEM.
YES, BUT THEY
DON'T KNOW YOU, RIGHT?
YEAH. LISTEN.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
IT--IT JUST SO HAPPENS
THAT HEXINA'S BODY
USED TO BE
MY OLD MAILING ADDRESS.
BOOM. SHH.
HEY, LEVINE NEEDS US.
YOU, TOO,
NEEDLE-DICK.
INCREDIBLE
AS IT MAY SEEM,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
AN IMPORTANT GUEST
HERE TOMORROW.
THE FASHION MODEL
FROM EUROPE.
VELVEETA.
HEXINA.
HEXINA. ALL RIGHT, HEXINA.
NOW, YOU PEOPLE
ARE THE ONLY ONES
I'M TELLING.
[chuckles]
THE WOMAN WISHES TO KEEP
HER VISIT TO THIS COUNTRY
A SECRET.
...HERE!
THAT'S WHY
SHE PICKED THIS HOTEL.
NOBODY GIVES A SHIT
WHO STAYS HERE.
WHAT THE HELL IS GOIN' ON?
WHAT--WHAT ARE YOU,
THE KATZENJAMMER KIDS
OR SOMETHING? WHAT IS IT?
WELL, SIR, UM,
MATTHEW WAS JUST
TELLING ME THAT--
[laughing]
THAT HE USED TO
DATE HEXINA.
[snickering]
OH, REALLY?
AND HITLER OWNED A DELI.
MATTHEW, COME ON.
COME ON.
IT WAS SUCH A COINCIDENCE.
I MEAN, WHY--WHY ARE YOU
FAILING TO SEE THE HUMOR
IN THIS?
WHY?
BECAUSE I HAVE BEEN
AT THIS HOTEL
FOR 12 YEARS, GLORIA.
SINCE I WAS 18.
[elevator bell dings]
AND--AND I'VE JUST
ALLOWED MYSELF TO BECOME
LIKE A PERMANENT FIXTURE HERE.
[people chattering]
BESIDES, IT'S NOT
A VERY GOOD FEELING
BEING TAKEN FOR GRANTED.
I KNOW.
[sighs]
[people chattering]
(woman)
YOU'RE IT.
[women laughing]
(man)
HEY, COME ON.
LET'S HAVE SOME ICE HERE.
[whooping]
COMING IN, I REALIZED
THE LEFT ENGINE WAS OUT.
I TURNED TO MY--MY COPILOT
AND I SAID, "HANK..."
(Matthew)
BUT I JUST SAID AGAIN,
AND AGAIN, AND AGAIN:
"IT IS NOT MY CLIENT
WHO IS ON TRIAL HERE.
IT IS THE LAW
THAT IS ON TRIAL
IN THIS CASE."
WELL, THE--THE COURTROOM
WENT WILD.
[door closing]
[men speaking Spanish
on T.V.]
[continue speaking Spanish]
(man)
900-FEEL.
YOU MUST AT LEAST SOUND 18
TO CALL.
(Tattoo)
THE PLANE! THE PLANE!
SOME THINGS
ARE HARD TO SWALLOW
WHILE OTHERS ARE EASY.
(female announcer)
YOGAIRE.
[laughs]
THE YOGURT OF FRANCE
IS NOW THE YOGURT OF SUBURBIA.
MMM.
*[Far Gone and Out
by Jesus and Mary Chain
playing]
* I CAN'T EXPLAIN
* EXACTLY WHAT I'M DOING
STANDING IN THE RAIN *
OH, THIS IS SO GOOD.
* DON'T DO IT FOR FUN
* DO IT IF YOU FEEL IT
KISS IT ON THE TONGUE *
* I'M TAKING MY THOUGHTS *
(Gloria)
OH, NO. OH, PLEASE.
AM I SUPPOSED TO BELIEVE
THAT THAT'S REAL?
AM I SUPPOSED TO ADMIRE
THE CRAFTSMANSHIP
THAT THAT TOOK?
WELL, YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU JUST PLAY
YOUR CARDS RIGHT
AND I MAY INTRODUCE YOU.
SHE'S VERY--
(Simon)
TO WHO?
HEY, HEY.
HEY, SIMON.
OR IS IT "WHOM"?
OH, WELSH. UH-HUH.
SIMON--
OH, LOOK AT THIS.
BEAUTIFUL. I THINK
THE KEY WORD HERE
IS "REALISTIC."
WHAT DO YOU THINK, HUH?
AND THE WINNER IS...
NOT YOU, WELSH.
NO COMMENT.
I'M OFF TO THE AIRPORT TO, UH,
PICK UP THE REAL THING.
HEY, MAYBE I'LL INVITE HEXINA
TO DINNER TONIGHT, HUH?
LET HER SAMPLE
THIS RARE DELICACY.
[snickering]
JESUS CHRIST.
HERE'S A MESSAGE
I DON'T WANT TO DELIVER.
THIS MAN IS A PIG.
HE TELLS ME THAT I REMIND HIM
OF THE WAITRESS
AT THE HOUSE OF PANCAKES
THAT HE ONCE BOFFED.
HERE. ALLOW ME
TO SPARE YOU
THE INDIGNITY.
DO, UH, ALL YOUR ROOMS
HAVE ONE OF THOSE
ADULT MOVIE CHANNELS?
OH, YES, THEY DO.
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
NO, NOT IN THE LEAST.
[people chattering]
HEY, HOTSHOT. WHAT'S UP?
MESSAGE FOR YOU.
IT'S MY WIFE.
SHE CAN CALL BACK LATER.
I'M GONNA BE IN ALL NIGHT.
OH, BY THE WAY, MATTHEW,
WHEN I GET BACK
UP TO MY ROOM,
I'M GONNA CALL THE MANAGER
AND HAVE YOU FIRED.
JUST WANTED YOU TO KNOW.
[exhales]
[woman screaming]
(man)
MY NECK! MY NECK!
YOU KNOW,
I CAN CLEARLY SEE MYSELF
50 YEARS FROM NOW.
OLD AND GRAY,
STILL WEARING THIS UNIFORM,
BARELY ABLE TO WALK.
MATTHEW, WHERE DO YOU COME UP
WITH THESE IMAGES?
[moaning]
PRETTY SOON WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE THE HEXINA
UNDER OUR ROOF.
WONDER WHAT SHE'S
DOING IN TOWN?
YOU KNOW, SHE'S IN
FOR A BIG SURPRISE.
SHE HAS NO IDEA
THAT I'M WORKING HERE.
MATTHEW, DO YOU REALIZE
HOW UNHEALTHY IT IS
THAT YOU CANNOT
ADMIT THE TRUTH?
HAS THE LINE
BETWEEN FANTASY
AND REALITY
BECOME SO COMPLETELY
BLURRED TO YOU?
BELIEVE ME,
I KNOW THE DIFFERENCE.
*[Rien Que Pour Toi
by Francois Feldman playing]
(worker)
HE AIN'T PAYIN' ME SHIT,
AND I GOTTA WORK
FOR LITTLE OR NOTHING.
GOD DAMN IT, I'M SICK
OF THIS FUCKING PLACE.
SO, BABE.
CAN I CALL YOU BABE?
YOU KNOW, I'D BE
PERSONALLY HONORED
TO SHOW YOU AROUND TOWN
DURING YOUR VISIT.
I HAPPEN TO BE FAMILIAR
WITH ALL THE FINEST
RESTAURANTS IN TOWN,
ESPECIALLY THIS LITTLE THAI--
LESBIAN.
CLEARLY, THIS GUY DOESN'T KNOW
HIS END OF THE TOTEM POLE.
I MEAN, HE WAS RUNNIN' AROUND
PRETENDING TO BE A GUEST,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
(Matthew)
SIR, I APOLOGIZE.
I'LL BE LETTING MATTHEW GO
AT THE END OF THE DAY.
DO I HAVE YOUR WORD ON THAT?
ABSOLUTELY.
AS MANAGER OF THE HOTEL,
YOU HAVE
MY PERSONAL GUARANTEE.
[laughing]
SCHMUCK.
[sighs]
MATTHEW.
THE GUY--
OUR SPECIAL BITCH GUEST
IS PEEVED ABOUT A BAG
THAT'S STUCK IN CUSTOMS.
THE SECOND IT ARRIVES,
YOU WILL SEND IT UP
TO HER ROOM.
SIMON,
I HAVE A CONFESSION TO MAKE.
I DON'T KNOW HEXINA.
IF YOU DID, DICKHEAD,
I'D JUMP OFF A ROOF.
[phone buzzing]
LOOK, SHE'S ALREADY
GETTING A CALL.
YOU GET THAT.
GLORIA?
WHAT?
MAYBE YOU'D LIKE
TO CATCH A MOVIE LATER?
I WOULD LOVE TO.
GREAT.
UH, HELLO?
THE GUEST IN 1204
IS ASLEEP.
WOULD YOU CARE
TO LEAVE A MESSAGE?
(Pratt)
ASLEEP?
SHE JUST CALLED A MINUTE AGO
WHILE I WAS IN THE SHOWER.
WELL, IF YOU'D LIKE
TO LEAVE A MESSAGE, SIR,
YOU'LL HAVE TO DO IT
THROUGH ME.
TELL HER PRATT CALLED BACK.
IT'S BEST TO MEET
AT MY HOUSE
FOR PRIVACY REASONS.
BESIDES, I DON'T WANT
TO HAVE TO DESCRIBE
WHAT I LOOK LIKE.
I'LL GIVE HER DIRECTIONS
WHEN SHE CALLS BACK.
THANK YOU.
[dial tone]
SO, MATTHEW,
WHAT TIME YOU WANNA GO SEE
THE MOVIE TONIGHT?
OH, I THINK
I ALREADY HAVE PLANS.
[grunts]
GOD.
[phone ringing]
(Hexina)
YES?
HELLO. IT'S MR. PRATT.
HOW PROMPT.
I JUST LEFT A MESSAGE
ON YOUR ANSWERING MACHINE.
SO, WHAT TIME ARE WE
MEETING TONIGHT?
HOW'S 7:00-ISH?
BE AT THE ENTRANCE
TO THE SIDE.
I'M REALLY
LOOKING FORWARD TO THIS.
NOT AS MUCH AS I AM,
MON AMI.
JENNIFER. EMERGENCY.
I NEED A CAR.
NO.
I'M WILLING TO PAY.
FORGET IT.
YOU'RE UNTRUSTWORTHY.
NO, I DIDN'T MEAN YOU, SIR.
I WASN'T REFERRING TO YOU.
[people laughing on T.V.]
PREPARED TO JUMP OFF A ROOF?
WHY DON'T YOU COME OUTSIDE
TONIGHT AT AROUND 7:00?
HEXINA AND I
ARE GOING ON A DATE
AND I'D LIKE YOU TO WITNESS
A DRIVE-BY.
HEY! HEY!
YOU STAY AWAY
FROM THAT WOMAN, ASSHOLE.
I'M WARNING YOU.
MATTHEW, WHAT ON EARTH
IS GOING ON?
FANTASY AND REALITY
HAVE JUST MET.
[coughing]
796.
A RED CORVETTE?
UNBE-FUCKING-LIEVABLE!
[engine roaring]
[tires screeching]
I GOTTA FIGURE OUT
WHO YOU ARE, MR. PRATT.
[muttering]
[garbage bin closing]
[sighs]
[car door closing]
WELL,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
JUST DRIVE.
I WOULD LIKE
TO GET THIS
OVER WITH.
*[music playing
on car stereo]
[shrieks]
[tires screeching]
YOU PROMISED THIS RENDEZVOUS
WOULD BE SECRET,
MONSIEUR PRATT.
WHAT'S WITH THIS
MONSIEUR PRATT?
WHY DON'T YOU JUST CALL ME
BY MY FIRST NAME?
WHY ARE YOU
TOYING WITH ME,
HENRY?
LET US JUST DO
WHAT WE NEED TO DO,
SO I MAY RETURN HOME.
BUT I WAS HOPING
WE COULD SPEND A NICE,
QUIET EVENING TOGETHER.
UM, TAKE ME
OVER THERE, PLEASE.
[Hexina exclaiming]
(Hexina)
PANTOMIME.
DO YOU HAVE ANY MONEY?
COME HERE, LITTLE MIME.
I HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU.
[laughing]
[tires screeching]
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
THIS IS AMERICA.
PEOPLE JUST DON'T GO AROUND
HITTING EACH OTHER,
EXCEPT MAYBE THE TEAMSTERS.
[chuckles]
YOU KNOW, I'M IN A MIND
JUST TO TAKE YOU BACK
TO THE HOTEL AND...
HENRY.
WHO?
I MEAN, YES?
LET'S GO BACK
TO YOUR PLACE.
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
CAN I OFFER YOU ANYTHING?
HMM, DO YOU HAVE, UM,
BLEU DE BRESSE,
ASSIETTE ANGLAISE,
PERHAPS A NICE BEAUJOLAIS?
WEDNESDAYS I'M USUALLY
JUST OUT.
[phone ringing]
(answering machine)
HELLO. THIS IS MATTHEW WELSH.
MY WORK FOR THE DAY--
BEAUJOLAIS!
...ASSIGNMENT. I'D LIKE TO--
[machine clicking off]
[muttering]
HENRY, WHAT IS THIS?
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
YOU'VE CAUGHT ME.
LET ME EXPLAIN.
THERE'S NO NEED.
IT'S PERFECTLY OBVIOUS
WHY YOU DOCTORED THESE PHOTOS.
YOU'VE BEEN FANTASIZING
ABOUT THIS MOMENT
FOR SOME TIME.
BEING SO CLOSE TO ME.
TRUE.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
YOU TELL ME.
[grunting]
[groaning]
[continues grunting]
[clattering]
[both groaning]
[groaning]
[cutlery clattering]
[both moaning]
NO. NO. NO.
[grunting]
[exclaiming]
[groaning]
GET OFF.
AH, BE PATIENT.
IT TAKES A WHILE.
OH, NO!
GET OFF OF ME!
[gasping]
[Matthew groaning]
MMM.
[panting]
WOULD YOU MIND
IF WE DID THIS
IN THE BEDROOM?
NO SKIN OFF MY BREAST.
[grunting]
GOD.
[speaking French]
ABSOLUTELY.
[shoe clattering]
[Matthew laughing]
[Hexina sighing]
OH, HENRY.
[breathing heavily]
[moaning]
[gasping]
[grunts]
[exclaiming in French]
OH, PAPA! PAPA!
WORK! WORK! WORK!
[whooping]
[Hexina groaning]
[grunts]
[moaning]
[growling]
[screaming]
[moaning]
[panting]
[exhaling]
[sighing]
YOU WERE MAGNIFICENT.
CAN I HAVE THAT
IN WRITING?
I AM DYING OF THIRST.
DO NOT MOVE FROM THE BED.
HENRY PRATT.
I LIKE WHO YOU ARE.
(Matthew)
I, UM,
I REALIZE THIS IS
A LITTLE LATE
TO BE ASKING,
BUT SHOULD I BE USING
SOME SORT OF PROTECTION?
UH-HUH.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
[laughing]
[screaming]
WHY DO YOU RUN, HENRY?
COME HERE AND LET ME CUT YOU,
YOU FUCKING SWINE!
OW!
[camera clicking]
OH, YOU COCKSUCKER, PRATT!
I'M NOT PRATT.
THE FUCK YOU AREN'T.
LET ME JUST...
[grunts]
MY NAME IS MATTHEW WELSH.
I WORK AT THE HOLIDAY PALACE.
[knocking at door]
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT
IN THERE, MR. WELSH?
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
WELL, KEEP IT DOWN
IN THERE.
YOU'RE DISTURBING
THE OTHER TENANTS.
WHITE TRASH.
(Matthew)
I'M SORRY.
I INTERCEPTED A MESSAGE
FROM PRATT TONIGHT, AND I--
I TOOK HIS PLACE.
WHY THE FUCK
DID YOU DO SUCH A THING?
WELL, SEE, I TOLD PEOPLE
THAT WE'VE HAD
A RELATIONSHIP IN THE PAST,
THAT WE WERE INVOLVED.
I'M--I'M A LITTLE BIT
OF A LIAR.
[squealing]
YOU JUST ATTEMPTED MURDER.
NO, I WAS JUST TRYING
TO SCARE YOU. HIM.
OH, GOD.
TAKE ME BACK
TO THE HOLIDAY PALACE.
FUCKING GEEK.
FIGURES. I'M WALKIN' AROUND
WITH HER AND NOBODY SEES ME.
AW, LIFE.
I DON'T WISH
TO BE DISTURBED.
TOO LATE.
YOU ALREADY ARE.
ALL RIGHT, LADY.
YOU GOT ABOUT 5 SECONDS
TO TELL ME
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE,
OR I'M GONNA HAVE
A LITTLE CHAT
WITH THE POLICE.
3 MONTHS AGO,
I RECEIVED THESE
IN THE MAIL.
OH, BOY.
(Hexina)
THAT'S ME.
7 YEARS AGO.
BEFORE NUTRISYSTEM.
WHERE WERE THESE TAKEN?
AT A HOSPITAL AROUND HERE
WHERE I WAS A PATIENT.
(Matthew)
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
IN THE STATES?
I'M AN AMERICAN CITIZEN.
BORN AND RAISED.
MY REAL NAME IS HELEN SPEARS.
HELEN SPEARS?
[chuckles]
AND I THOUGHT
I WAS THE ONLY ONE
PLAYING MASQUERADE GAMES.
SO, HOW'S HENRY PRATT
ENTER INTO THIS?
HE SAYS HE'S A CLERK
AT THE PATIENT RECORDS.
HE RECENTLY CAME ACROSS
THOSE OLD PHOTOS.
WHAT'S HE
ASKING FOR?
$400,000.
[whistles]
HMM.
HE ALSO EXPECTS ME
TO FUCK HIM.
THAT'S THE PART YOU GOT. HA!
I KNOW. I WAS THERE.
NONE OF WHAT YOU SAID
JUSTIFIES MURDER.
LOOK, I-- HOW MANY TIMES
DO I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
I JUST--
I--I JUST WANTED
TO SCARE THE GUY. OK?
SO HE WOULDN'T--WOULDN'T
RUIN MY IMAGE.
[Hexina sobbing]
ALL I'VE ACHIEVED
IS AT STAKE.
EVERYTHING.
I MEAN, LOOK AT ALL
THE GOOD STUFF I DO.
THE CHARITIES, THE TELETHONS,
JERRY'S KIDS, I MEAN--
[telephone ringing]
[gasps]
OH, GOD, THAT'S HIM.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
ANSWER IT.
I'LL GUIDE YOU THROUGH.
[exhales deeply]
HELLO?
(Pratt)
YOU LOUSY WHORE.
YOU KEPT ME
WAITING ALL NIGHT.
APOLOGIZE AND ASK
TO MEET NOW.
I'M SORRY.
UM, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO MEET NOW?
BE AT MY HOUSE
IN 20 MINUTES.
1163 CARLOTTA DRIVE.
DON'T BE LATE.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
I DIDN'T EXPECT TO PAY.
WELL, LOOK. WE'LL DRIVE
OVER THERE TOGETHER,
AND WE'LL JUST
SIT DOWN AND WE'LL
DISCUSS THIS LIKE ADULTS.
OH, LIKE ADULTS?
THE GUY'S A BLACKMAILER.
LISTEN, FOR BETTER
OR FOR WORSE,
I'M EXTREMELY GOOD
AT MANIPULATING PEOPLE.
[sniffling]
[knocking on door]
OH, WHAT NOW? YES?
(bellman)
A PIECE OF YOUR LUGGAGE
JUST ARRIVED, MA'AM.
HI.
[thudding]
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO HURRY.
LET ME JUST TAKE SOMETHING
TO CALM MY NERVES.
OK, BUT, YOU KNOW,
WE GOTTA-- WE GOTTA HURRY
UP WITH THIS THING.
(Matthew)
YOU OK IN THERE?
YOU KNOW, UM,
IF IT'S ONE OF THOSE
TWIST-OFF THINGS,
I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO GIVE YOU A HAND.
I'M VERY GOOD WITH THOSE.
MY, UH, MY--MY DAD I-INVENTED
THEM, ACTUALLY.
COME ON.
WE'VE REALLY GOTTA GO.
CARLOTTA. 1163 CARLOTTA.
FUCK!
WHAT--WHAT--WHAT?
I LEFT MY EARRINGS
IN YOUR APARTMENT.
THEY'RE FINE. DON'T WORRY--
THEY WERE DESIGNED
FOR ME BY LENEAU.
THAT'S OK.
BUT THEY'RE WORTH
A FORTUNE.
OK, WE'LL GET 'EM LATER.
(Matthew)
JUST LET ME
DO ALL THE TALKING.
I HAPPEN TO BE VERY GOOD
IN SITUATIONS LIKE THESE.
[crickets chirping]
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
TO BE NON-CONFRONTATIONAL.
*[music playing on radio]
(Matthew)
THIS MUST BE THE PLACE.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL EXPLAIN
MY PRESENCE HERE.
I'LL DO
ALL THE TALKING, OK?
AND REMEMBER,
NON-CONFRONTATIONAL.
WHA...?
DON'T JUST STAND THERE.
CLOSE THE DOOR.
HURRY UP.
[door thuds]
[breathing heavily]
HEY, HEY.
I GOT THE KEYS.
SO YOU CAN JUST FORGET
ABOUT TAKING A HIKE.
[keys jingling]
[Hexina grunting]
YOU SAID YOU WERE
JUST GONNA SCARE HIM.
I LIED. BUT YOU GOTTA ADMIT,
I WAS NON-CONFRONTATIONAL.
NOW HELP ME LOOK
FOR THE NEGATIVES.
YOU CAN START
BY SEARCHING
THAT TRASH HEAP.
[shudders]
[panting]
[whispering]
JESUS CHRIST.
WHERE WAS THE BASTARD
KEEPIN' IT?
YOU'VE JUST KILLED SOMEBODY.
MATTHEW, DO NOT
RAISE YOUR VOICE.
I'M FEELING VERY FRAGILE
AT THE MOMENT, OK?
BESIDES, THEY DIDN'T
INSTITUTIONALIZE ME
JUST FOR HAVING A YEN
FOR CHEESECAKE, YOU KNOW.
TELL ME
WHY THEY DID.
WHEN I WAS 16,
I WAS SEDUCED
BY AN OLDER MAN.
HE WAS CRUEL
AND SADISTIC.
WHAT DID HE DO?
HE SOLD INSURANCE.
NO. NO. NO.
TELL ME WHAT HE DID TO YOU.
I WAS EMOTIONALLY
AND SEXUALLY ABUSED.
AND THEN, ONE DAY,
HE JUST WENT TOO FAR.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE REFUSED TO MARRY ME.
SO I SET SOME SHRUBBERY
ON FIRE OUTSIDE HIS HOUSE
AS A PRANK.
INSTEAD, HE PERISHED
ALONG WITH
32 OTHER PEOPLE.
32 OTHER PEOPLE?
YEAH.
A SUPER BOWL WEEKEND.
[chuckles]
(Hexina)
I SPENT 6 FUCKING YEARS
IN THAT INSTITUTION!
6 FUCKING YEARS!
UPON RELEASE,
I JUMPED PAROLE,
FLED TO EUROPE,
CHANGED MY ENTIRE APPEARANCE,
STARTED MODELING.
HENCE HEXINA.
I PICKED THE NAME MYSELF.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
YOU'RE A FUGITIVE.
YES. AND THE SOLE REASON
FOR ALL THIS UNPLEASANTNESS
HAS BEEN THIS UGLY, STUPID,
SCUMBAG PIECE OF SHIT.
[sirens wailing]
STUPID-- AHHH!
[doorbell rings]
[whispering]
I WANNA SEE.
(Hexina)
EW!
WOULD YOU GET... SHH. SHH.
[police radio chattering]
WE'LL GO BACK,
RUN A CHECK ON THE VEHICLE,
SEE IF WE CAN MAKE IT.
[Hexina moaning]
MMM, MATTHEW.
CHH-CHH-CHH-CHH.
[Hexina laughing]
[Hexina sighing]
[Hexina gagging]
(Matthew)
WHAT'S WRONG NOW?
NOTHING. JUST TRYING
TO KEEP MY WEIGHT DOWN.
HEY.
HEY, YOU FOUND IT!
HMM, I LOVE YOU.
LET'S GO.
WAIT A MINUTE.
FINGERPRINTS.
I'M WEARING GLOVES.
MY FINGERPRINTS.
COME ON.
[glass shattering]
SHIT.
[breathing heavily]
[door hinges creaking]
WELL, TALKING TO THE POLICE
IS NOW OUT OF THE QUESTION,
MATTHEW.
YOU'VE JUST BECOME
AN ACCESSORY.
AND I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR YOUR FINE EFFORT TONIGHT.
AND THAT INCLUDES
MAKING ME COME
15 TIMES IN BED.
[exhaling heavily]
[policemen chattering]
(Novak)
THE VICTIM'S NAME
IS HENRY PRATT.
MAILMAN FOUND THE BODY.
LOOK WHAT
HE WAS DELIVERING.
HUH, SOME GUYS HAVE
ALL THE LUCK, DON'T THEY?
WOMAN ACROSS THE STREET
HEARD SOMETHIN'
AROUND 2:00 A.M.
A BLACK-AND-WHITE
RESPONDED.
IDENTIFIED
A RENTAL CAR
OUT FRONT.
REGISTRATION'S
TO THE LOCAL
HOLIDAY PALACE,
TO ONE
VICTOR THUMMELL.
(Larry)
ALL, RIGHT. ALL RIGHT,
GET OUT!
GET OUT, MATT! GET OUT, MAN,
WHERE YOU BEEN?
WHO SAID YOU COULD
BORROW THIS CAR, HUH?
I'VE BEEN LOOKIN'
FOR THIS CAR, MAN!
I COULD'VE BEEN FIRED, MATT!
MAN, WHAT DO YOU
GOTTA SAY?
SAY SOMETHING!
ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S WRONG, MAN!
I'M CHECKIN' OUT
IN 10 MINUTES.
WHERE THE HELL
IS MY WHITE SUIT?
I'M SORRY, SIR,
THEY JUST CAN'T SEEM
TO LOCATE IT. I--
HERE'S YOUR SUIT, SIR.
THANK YOU.
THE LAUNDRY MUST HAVE
LOST THE TICKET.
GOD! IF I WASN'T
IN SUCH A HURRY,
I WOULD CASTRATE YOU AGAIN!
SO, MATTHEW,
WHAT--WHAT DID
YOU DO LAST NIGHT?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE QUESTION.
[bell dings]
YES?
OH, SORRY. MY MISTAKE.
OK.
WELSH? WHO WAS
IN YOUR CAR LAST NIGHT?
[tittering]
CAR? I--I--I DON'T
REMEMBER ANY CAR.
IDIOT!
I DIDN'T HAVE A CAR
OR ANYTHING.
[bell ringing]
YES?
REMEMBER THE STORY
ABOUT THE BOY
WHO CRIED WOLF, HUH?
OK. ABSOLUTELY.
[bell rings]
OH, GOD.
[police radio chattering]
[pages being flipped]
I NEED YOU TO CALL
ONE OF YOUR GUESTS,
VICTOR THUMMELL, DOWN HERE.
[lifting phone]
[dialing]
[continues flipping pages]
[coughs]
UM, YES, HI.
SIR, YOUR--YOUR PRESENCE
IS REQUESTED IN THE LOBBY.
UH, YES, RIGHT NOW. THANKS.
SOME SORT OF TROUBLE?
WELL, WE DON'T
NORMALLY SHOW UP
TO MAKE A FASHION
STATEMENT, SON.
[flipping pages rapidly]
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT THE HELL IS GOIN' ON?
I'M TRYING TO PACK.
ARE YOU VICTOR THUMMELL?
YEAH, THAT'S ME.
WHY DON'T WE TALK
OVER THERE?
YOU RENTED
A RED '88 CORVETTE
FROM THIS HOTEL?
(Thummell)
YEAH, I DID.
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
[flipping pages]
WHERE'D YOU GO
LAST NIGHT?
I DIDN'T GO ANYWHERE.
I WENT TO BED EARLY.
(Ferguson)
SURE YOU DID.
[sighs]
MY WIFE AND I
WOULD LIKE A ROOM,
PLEASE.
FILL THIS OUT.
(Thummell)
I HAVE GOT
AN 8-HOUR DRIVE
BACK TO WEST COVINA,
AND I'M LEAVING.
OH, NO.
YOU'RE NOT
GOIN' ANYWHERE.
THIS IS
A MURDER
INVESTIGATION.
A MURDER?
(Thummell)
LOOK, I AM LEAVING.
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO
TO STOP ME.
(Ferguson)
I'M NOT VERY HAPPY
WITH YOUR ATTITUDE HERE.
OH, YEAH?
HA.
(Thummell)
OH, COME ON.
COME ON.
NOW, LOOK,
I WANT TO GO
TO MY ROOM.
I'M GONNA PACK UP.
YOU HAVE NO...
OK, OK, IT'S COOL.
IT'S COOL. I'LL GO.
HAH! OH, SHIT.
COME ON, LOOK.
GOD DAMN IT!
LOOK, I AM LEAVING,
AND YOU CAN'T STOP ME,
YOU PUSSIES!
[grunts]
WAIT, I'M A REPUBLICAN! OW!
[Thummell grunting]
(Thummell)
OW!
[groans]
(Matthew)
$150 FOR A DOUBLE.
[Thummell screaming]
BELLMAN WILL SHOW YOU
TO YOUR ROOM.
[bell ringing]
[bell continues ringing]
[Thummell groaning]
PLEASE, FOLKS.
THERE'S--THERE'S NOTHING
TO SEE HERE.
OFFICIAL POLICE BUSINESS.
[Thummell groaning]
(Ferguson)
I CERTAINLY HOPE
YOU'VE LEARNED
A LITTLE SOMETHING
HERE TODAY, MR. THUMMELL.
YOU NEVER MESS AROUND
WITH A FELLOW'S HAT
LIKE THAT.
[Matthew continues banging]
THE POLICE JUST TOOK
AN INNOCENT MAN INTO CUSTODY.
NO ONE IS TRULY INNOCENT.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
IT'S ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THE TRAIL
LEADS TO US.
THERE IS NO "US."
IT'S LIKE I WAS NEVER HERE.
YOU COLD-BLOODED MURDERESS!
[shouting]
WHAT DID YOU JUST CALL ME?
MURDERESS.
OH, I THOUGHT
YOU SAID METHODIST.
FOR A MOMENT,
I WAS INSULTED.
I'M GOING TO THE POLICE
RIGHT NOW.
YOUR WORD AGAINST MINE?
NO ONE WILL BELIEVE
WE'VE EVEN MET.
OH, THEY WON'T, HUH?
WELL, YOU LEFT PROOF BEHIND
IN MY APARTMENT. REMEMBER?
OH, FUCK!
MY FUCKING EARRINGS!
FUCK!
[knocking on door]
[Hexina speaking French]
I'VE COME TO DRIVE YOU
TO THE AIRPORT.
WHAT THE FUCK
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I FOUND THIS MAN RUMMAGING
THROUGH MY BELONGINGS.
SIMON, DON'T LISTEN TO HER,
SHE'S LYING.
MINE IS
AN EXPERT OPINION.
MY EARRINGS ARE MISSING,
AND NOW I KNOW
WHO THE CULPRIT IS.
WHAT, ARE YOU CRAZY?
DON'T TOUCH ME! NO!
(Simon)
THAT'S IT, THAT'S IT,
YOU'RE MINE!
SIMON!
YOU'RE FUCKING MINE, WELSH!
(Simon)
YOUR ASS IS MINE!
OH, GOD, SIMON!
I'VE BEEN WAITING
A LONG TIME FOR THIS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
SIMON, HEXINA WAS
IN MY APARTMENT
LAST NIGHT,
AND SHE TRIED
TO KILL ME!
I'VE SEEN HER NAKED!
SHUT UP, SHUT UP!
SHUT UP.
YOU'RE NOTHING
BUT A COMMON CRIMINAL
NOW, WELSH.
YOU'VE FUCKED YOURSELF
FOREVER, BUDDY.
SIMON, I'VE GOTTA
STOP HER.
YOU JUST DON'T--DON'T
GET IT, DO YOU?
[yelling]
[tray rattling]
OH, NO!
[muffled screaming]
[snickering]
[panting]
[flushing]
(Matthew)
IT'S FREE NOW.
*[music playing
on car stereo]
AS SOON AS WE
RECOVER YOUR EARRINGS,
THEY'LL BE SHIPPED TO YOU.
NO. I MISTRUST
PARCEL SERVICES.
LOOK, DO YOU KNOW
WHERE WELSH LIVES?
MAYBE HE IS KEEPING
MY JEWELRY THERE.
I'LL GIVE YOU A RIDE HOME
AFTER THE SHIFT,
NOT BEFORE. OK?
GLORIA, I--I HAVE
TO GO NOW.
I'M SORRY.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
CAN I BORROW
YOUR CAR?
LET ME JUST
HAVE THE KEYS. I'LL--
RIGHT.
[rings]
[bell crashes]
I NEED TO EXTEND MY STAY HERE.
INDEFINITELY.
WHERE'S YOUR BAR?
I THINK I'LL GO TRASH
6 YEARS OF FUCKING SOBRIETY.
THANK YOU.
LOOK OUT!
SORRY TO BOTHER YOU.
I WORK WITH MATTHEW WELSH
AT THE HOLIDAY PALACE.
HOLIDAY PALACE?
I THOUGHT HE WORKED
FOR N.A.S.A.
WE WERE WONDERING
IF YOU COULD LET US
INTO MR. WELSH'S APARTMENT?
WE'RE TRYING
TO RETRIEVE SOMETHING
OF A PERSONAL NATURE.
WELL, NORMALLY I WOULDN'T.
BUT SINCE I SAW YOU
HERE LAST NIGHT...
LOCK UP WHEN YOU FINISH.
STRANGE,
THAT LANDLADY THINKING
SHE'D SEEN YOU HERE
LAST NIGHT.
I'LL CHECK THIS ROOM.
YEAH, RIGHT.
BOOKS.
(Simon)
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR A THOROUGH SEARCH.
YOUR PLANE LEAVES
IN HALF AN HOUR.
[mumbling]
WAX.
THIS GUY.
GOOD NEWS.
I FOUND MY EARRINGS.
WHAT IS THAT?
I WAS JUST ABOUT
TO ASK YOU
THE SAME QUESTION.
I MEAN,
COULD WELSH,
FOR ONCE IN HIS LIFE,
BEEN TELLING THE TRUTH?
[sighing]
WE'LL GET TO THAT
LATER, KITTEN.
RIGHT NOW, SIMON WANTS
AN EXPLANATION.
SIMON.
IT'S ACTUALLY VERY,
VERY SIMPLE.
I MEAN, THE WHOLE THING
IS JUST SO SILLY.
I'M WAITING.
THE ANSWER IS...
[grunting]
I'M FUCKING BONKERS!
(Levine)
WHERE'S THAT VIKING, SIMON?
SIMON'S NOT BACK
FROM THE AIRPORT?
NO, HE'S NOT BACK
FROM THE AIRPORT.
YEAH, AND I GOT SOME PRIEST
IN MY OFFICE SCREAMIN'
ABOUT--ABOUT LAWSUITS.
YOU KNOW, THESE THINGS
HAPPEN TO EVERYONE.
YEAH, SURE. THANKS.
[whispering]
COULD YOU TAKE ME HOME
RIGHT NOW?
GONZALES, THAT THING GROWING
DOWN THE BACK OF YOUR NECK?
CUT IT OFF.
YOU LOOK LIKE FUCKING TONTO.
(Matthew)
I'M SORRY.
I HAVE SOME MORE WORK.
I JUST-- I GOTTA GO.
OK? ALL RIGHT.
THANKS A LOT, BYE.
GO ON. GO ON.
TALK TO YOU LATER.
YOU CAN JUST GO OUT
THIS WAY.
OK. ALL RIGHT.
BYE. BYE--BYE.
[spitting]
[sighs]
[both screaming]
WHAT A NIGHTMARE.
I DREAMED I WAS GIVING BIRTH
TO AN AUTOWORKER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I MISSED MY FLIGHT.
I'LL HAVE TO STAY HERE
UNTIL I CAN RESCHEDULE.
WHERE'S SIMON?
OH, HE'S LONG GONE.
WE ARE GONNA HAVE
SO MUCH FUN.
THERE'S SO MANY SEX GAMES
WE CAN PLAY.
DO YOU HAVE MAYONNAISE
AND A RAKE?
11738 BELLAGIO.
PLEASE, AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE. YEAH.
LOOK, A CAB
IS GONNA BE HERE
IN ABOUT 2 MINUTES.
BUT I DON'T CARE WHERE YOU GO,
JUST--JUST GET AWAY FROM ME.
I WAS SO LOOKING FORWARD
TO MAKING LOVE.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
WHY DO YOU STILL WANT
TO HAVE SEX WITH ME?
BECAUSE YOU'RE THE BEST
MALE LOVER I'VE EVER HAD.
THANK YOU. I--
YOU'VE BEEN DOING
SOME REARRANGING, I SEE.
WELL, I WAS HUNGRY.
YOUR CUPBOARDS WERE BARE.
COME ON.
YOU KNOW, NO ONE
WOULD BELIEVE THIS.
I DON'T-- I DON'T--
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
[gasping]
(Hexina)
WHAT?
(Matthew)
OH, MY GOD.
OH, THAT.
OH, JESUS!
I DON'T REMEMBER
THE NUMBER FOR 911.
UH-UH. I NEED YOUR HELP
DISPOSING OF THE BODY.
ABSOLUTELY NOT!
OH, FINE!
JUST LIKE A MAN.
YOU TAKE A GIRL TO BED,
BUT WHEN IT COMES TIME
FOR THE COMMITMENT, NO!
[phone rings]
(man)
WHAT'S GOING ON IN THERE?
OW! WOULD YOU STOP THAT?
OW! STOP THAT!
(man)
HEY, I PAY RENT HERE, BUDDY!
LEAVE ME ALONE, YOU BITCH,
OR I SWEAR I'M GONNA KILL YOU!
(Matthew)
YOU HEAR ME? I'LL KILL YOU!
I'LL KILL YOU!
[grunting]
[baby crying]
THAT'S IT!
[Hexina screams]
[grunting]
[crashing]
[Hexina screaming]
RIDE 'EM, COWBOY!
(Ms. Strickland)
I'VE CALLED THE POLICE ON YOU.
THEY'RE ON THEIR WAY.
GOOD! I WANT THEM
TO SEE THIS!
[telephone crashing]
I WANT EVERYBODY
TO SEE THIS.
THE MODEL, HEXINA,
IS IN MY APARTMENT!
SHE'S COMMITTED MURDER,
AND THERE IS A DEAD BODY
IN MY REFRIGERATOR!
SHIT! NO!
(Hexina)
TA-TA!
(Matthew)
WAIT, DRIVER! STOP!
OH, GOD DAMN IT!
GET OUT! GET OUT!
GET OUT! OUT! OUT!
RUN, RUN, RUN, RUN!
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
NO!
[screams]
[Ms. Strickland groaning]
THIS FEELS LIKE A RAPE!
NO.
WAIT UNTIL
THE POLICE GET HERE!
THEY'LL BEAT YOU
WHILE I WATCH.
[Matthew grunting]
JESUS!
[grunting]
[panting]
[joggers grunt]
OH, SORRY, UH,
I'M THE DESIGNATED DRIVER
TONIGHT.
LOVELY EVENING.
[trunk closing]
[crickets chirping]
[cork popping]
(cop)
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
[police radio chattering]
MY STEERING COLUMN
GAVE OUT.
I'M STILL PRETTY SHOOK UP
ABOUT IT. I WAS JUST--
DRIVER'S LICENSE,
PLEASE?
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S RIGHT HERE,
IN THE PLASTIC.
YOU'RE WEARING
YOUR HAIR DIFFERENTLY
THAN IN THIS PICTURE.
IT LOOKS BETTER NOW.
[sighs]
WHY ARE YOU
TELLING ME THIS?
I'M SECURE ENOUGH
IN MY MASCULINITY
THAT I CAN GIVE COMPLIMENTS.
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S VERY, VERY GOOD.
IT'S MY COMPANY CAR.
VEHICLE CAN'T REMAIN
ON THE ROAD.
I'LL HAVE TO CALL A TOW.
YOU--YOU CAN'T
IMPOUND THIS CAR.
IT--IT BELONGS
TO THE HOLIDAY PALACE.
THEY...
DON'T WORRY,
IT WON'T BE IMPOUNDED.
BASE, COPY?
(cop on radio)
ROGER.
WHERE DO YOU SUPPOSE
YOU'LL TAKE IT?
(Simon)
IF YOU DID,
I'D JUMP OFF A ROOF.
[grunts]
GOD DAMN IT!
MY PARENTS WOULD BE
SO PROUD.
BYE-BYE.
SHIT!
[groaning]
[breathing heavily]
PLEASE.
[grunting]
*[Thummell humming]
[water running]
*[Thummell continues humming]
(Thummell)
OH.
LARRY.
YES, SIR?
HAS SIMON RETURNED YET?
WELL, YOU KNOW, I THOUGHT
I SAW THE HOTEL SEDAN
BEING TOWED BACK.
HE'S AVOIDING ME.
YOU KNOW WHY?
NO.
BECAUSE HE KNOWS THAT
WHENEVER I RUN INTO HIM,
I'M GONNA KILL HIM.
NO.
[groaning]
[both grunting]
YOU!
[grunting]
STOP THAT BASTARD!
HE WAS ROBBING MY ROOM!
I'M GONNA TEAR YOU APART,
YOU LITTLE GREEN-COATED FUCK!
STOP THAT BASTARD!
HE WAS ROBBING MY ROOM!
[grunting]
HOLY SHIT!
[screaming]
[thudding]
THE GREEN BOY! AH! AH!
(female reporter)
PATRIOTISM TOOK
A BIZARRE TURN TONIGHT
WHEN A LOCAL HOTEL EMPLOYEE
WRAPPED HIMSELF
IN AN AMERICAN FLAG
AND APPARENTLY LEAPT
TO HIS DEATH.
IN 2 RELATED INCIDENTS...
NOBODY IS TO LEAVE
THIS HOTEL.
I'M QUESTIONING
EVERY LAST PERSON.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT YOU SAW, SIR?
[sobbing]
WELL, I, UH...
W-W-WELL, UH...
[woman coughing]
*[soft music playing]
YES, I NEED THE DESTINATION
OF ONE OF YOUR CABS
LAST NIGHT.
UM, SIMON SAID SOMETHING
ONCE ABOUT, UH,
THROWING HIMSELF
OFF A ROOF,
BUT IT JUST SOUNDED
LIKE SARCASM.
[coughing]
[people chattering]
A REPORTED 4-15.
HIS LANDLADY
PHONED IT IN LAST NIGHT.
UH-HUH, THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I THOUGHT.
THANK YOU.
[coughs]
THAT'LL BE ALL,
LITTLE LADY.
YEAH. PALM COURT HOTEL.
OK. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MATTHEW, I'M WORRIED.
THEY KEEP ASKING
ABOUT THE BAD BLOOD
BETWEEN YOU
AND SIMON.
MY GOD! WHY?
BECAUSE IT'S NO SECRET
THAT YOU TWO
DIDN'T GET ALONG.
[sighs]
LARRY, I'M NOT
ASKING YOU TO LIE,
JUST DON'T TELL THE COPS
THAT I TOOK THAT CAR.
LARRY, PLEASE.
YOU KNOW, IN PRISON
I'M GOING TO BE CONSIDERED
RELATIONSHIP MATERIAL.
WELL, ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I--I CAN DODGE
THE TRUTH, UH,
GIVE EVASIVE ANSWERS,
BUT, UH,
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE GONNA
OWE ME FOR THIS.
ABSOLUTELY.
ANYTHING.
(Ferguson)
DON'T LOOK AT THIS
AS AN INTERROGATION,
MORE OF A FATHER-SON CHAT.
YOU KNOW, MOST OF THE GUYS
DOWN AT THE STATION
JUST FONDLY REFER TO ME
AS "PAPPY" FERGUSON.
OH, WHAT THE HELL.
YOU CAN CALL ME PAPPY.
WOULD YOU LIKE THAT, SON?
PLAY MUCH BASKETBALL?
(Ferguson)
I JUST WANT TO KNOW
WHO TOOK THE CAR, SON.
NO!
(Larry)
I'M SORRY, MATTHEW, ALL RIGHT?
GLORIA, IT WAS HEXINA!
(Gloria)
MATTHEW! WHAT?
GLORIA, GLORIA,
IT WAS HEXINA!
MATTHEW!
IT WAS ALWAYS HEXINA!
SHE DID IT!
SHE DID IT ALL!
IT WAS ALWAYS HEXINA!
SHE'S STAYING
AT THE HOTEL
NEXT DOOR!
[people celebrating]
[people chattering]
I'M INNOCENT!
[screaming]
NO! NO, I'M INNOCENT!
I'M INNOCENT!
IT WASN'T ME!
(cop #1)
THERE HE GOES!
(cop #2)
I CAN'T SEE.
(cop #1)
HE'S GOT A KNIFE!
EXCUSE ME, PARDON ME,
PARDON ME.
[groaning]
(woman)
OH! THEY KILLED MY SON!
IT WASN'T ME!
YOU GOTTA BELIEVE ME!
IT WAS HEXINA!
I'M TELLING YOU!
[people screaming]
[Matthew screaming]
I'M NOT KIDDING!
YOU GOT THE WRONG GUY!
OH, SHIT!
[Ferguson groans]
SON OF A BITCH HIT ME
WITH A LEAD PIPE. HUH.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR? GO AFTER HIM.
THE NIGHT'S TOP STORY
IS THE MANHUNT
FOR SUSPECTED KILLER
MATTHEW WELSH.
IT'S SPECULATED NOW
THAT MATTHEW WELSH
MAY HAVE A FIXATION
FOR THE WORLD-RENOWNED
FASHION MODEL HEXINA.
[speaking Spanish]
(woman)
YOU'RE GETTING WARMER.
COME ON.
NO, YOU'RE COLD.
HEY! EXCUSE ME!
EXCUSE ME, WOULD YOU ANSWER
A FEW QUESTIONS FOR ME?
I MEAN, WHAT IS
YOUR RELATIONSHIP...
PLEASE.
...WITH MATTHEW WELSH?
SHUT UP.
DID YOU KNOW THAT HE WAS
A PSYCHOTIC KILLER?
(woman)
COME ON.
TO THE LEFT. LEFT.
COME ON. THAT'S IT.
[muffled screaming]
SHH. SHH. SHH.
LISTEN.
I'LL TAKE MY HAND AWAY
IF YOU PROMISE
NOT TO SCREAM, OK? OK?
I PROMISE!
SHH.
[shouting]
GLORIA! GLORIA,
YOU HAVE KNOWN ME
A LONG TIME.
HAVE I EVER SEEMED
LIKE A HOMICIDAL MANIAC?
YOU'RE ASKING
THE WRONG PERSON.
I--I HAD A CRUSH
ON NORMAN BATES
TILL THE END OF THE MOVIE.
OK.
I--I MIGHT AS WELL
JUST GIVE MYSELF UP, HUH?
WOULD YOU-- WOULD YOU PLEASE
CALL THE POLICE NOW?
OH, GOD!
[screams]
[panting]
GLORIA, HEY,
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAID OF.
PROVE IT.
EMPTY YOUR POCKETS!
COME ON.
OH.
MATTHEW, WHAT DID YOU
GET YOURSELF INTO?
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S GONNA TAKE A WHILE.
HEXINA? SHE'S BEHIND
ALL OF THIS.
SEE, SHE CAME TO TOWN
SO SHE COULD KILL
THIS BLACKMAILER...
SHE'S PROBABLY STILL
AT THE PALM COURT
EVEN AS WE SPEAK.
I SWEAR TO YOU ON MY LIFE
THAT EVERYTHING
I HAVE SAID JUST NOW
IS ABSOLUTELY TRUE.
THERE WERE JUST
SO MANY TIMES
THAT I COULD FEEL HIM
MENTALLY UNDRESSING ME.
(Ms. Strickland)
YOU THINK, I'M MAKING THIS UP,
I'M NOT.
HE'S COME ONTO EVERY WOMAN
IN THIS BUILDING.
HE'D MADE AT LEAST
20 OF THESE.
ANOTHER
PEYOTE-CHEWIN'
SICKO
SCREAMIN'
FOR RECOGNITION.
SIR, LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
UH-HUH, I KNEW
THAT HAD TO BE HERE.
THAT'S A GUN.
DO YOU HAVE ANY, UH,
ANY PHOTOS OR ANY--
OR ANY--ANY COPIES OR...
NO.
GLORIA, DO YOU HAVE
A TAPE RECORDER?
YEAH.
HERE. BE CAREFUL.
IT'S A SONY, AND I'M STILL
MAKING PAYMENTS ON IT.
GREAT.
OK, HOW ABOUT
A BIG ENVELOPE?
I WAS GONNA SEND THIS
TO MY PARENTS.
FANTASTIC.
ANYTHING ELSE, MASTER?
HOW ABOUT A SH-SHOWER?
(boy)
GRANDPA, COME ON.
[duck squeaking]
[knocking]
PARDON ME, MA'AM, UH,
DETECTIVE FERGUSON
ORDERED
ALL HOLIDAY PALACE
EMPLOYEES
BE GIVEN
POLICE PROTECTION.
THEY'VE APPARENTLY FOUND
WHAT THEY BELIEVE
IS THE MURDER WEAPON DURING
A SWEEP OF WELSH'S APARTMENT.
OH.
[water flowing]
UM, EXCUSE ME, UH,
WATER CONSERVATION
IS SO IMPORTANT.
GOD! GLORIA.
SHH, MATTHEW.
THE POLICE ARE HERE.
THE POLICE?
OH, JESUS! WHAT THE...
YOU MIND IF I USE THIS?
OH, WELL, ACTUALLY--
I'VE BEEN DRINKING
HERBAL TEA ALL MORNING--
OH, IT DOESN'T FLUSH.
IT'S--IT'S OVERFLOWING.
IT DOESN'T FLUSH.
(cop #1)
COME ON.
COME ON, MAN,
I GOTTA GO.
[speaking Spanish]
COME ON,
WE'VE OVERSTAYED
OUR WELCOME.
[door closing]
[coughing]
[sighs]
MATTHEW.
MATTHEW, YOU GOTTA
GET OUT OF HERE.
THEY SAY THAT THEY FOUND A GUN
IN YOUR APARTMENT.
A GUN?
YEAH.
WE USE THIS TRICK
ON CRACK DEALERS.
YOU SHOULDN'T LEAVE
YOUR WALLET OUT, MISTER.
I'LL REMEMBER
NEXT TIME.
WHOA!
(Gloria)
OH, NO, MATTHEW, RUN.
*[music playing on stereo]
OH, MY GOD!
OH, MY GOD, IT'S HIM!
DON'T KILL ME!
OH, FUCK!
ALL RIGHT, WHERE IS IT?
(man)
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHERE IS IT?
OH, I FOUND IT.
I FOUND IT.
[shouting]
(woman)
PROSTITUTION'S ILLEGAL HERE,
TOO?
YOU WERE HARBORING
A KNOWN CRIMINAL.
AND I'M TELLING YOU
THAT MATTHEW
IS NOT A MURDERER.
OSCAR WILDE SAID IT BEST:
"SOCIETY OFTEN
FORGIVES THE CRIMINAL.
IT NEVER FORGIVES
THE DREAMER."
I BURNED BETTER BOOKS
THAN THAT ON SUNDAYS,
YOU FILTHY HIPPIE.
SCRATCH THAT
"HIPPIE" THING.
[door opening]
DETECTIVE, THE D.A.'S OFFICE
IS RETURNING YOUR PHONE CALL.
I AM NOT
TO BE INTERRUPTED.
IS THAT CLEAR?
GOD DAMN IT!
[door closing]
NOW, YOU CAN COUNT
ON BEIN' IN THIS ROOM
ALL NIGHT, LITTLE LADY.
I'M DIVORCED,
WITH NO CHARISMA.
I'VE GOT NOWHERE TO GO.
[telephone ringing]
YES?
(desk clerk)
FRONT DESK, MA'AM.
YOU'RE CONFIRMED FOR TONIGHT'S
10:30 FLIGHT TO PARIS.
EXCELLENT.
BY THE WAY, I RESENT
THE CHEAP ARTWORK IN MY ROOM.
HEY, LOOK, I KNOW FOR A FACT
HEXINA'S STAYIN' THERE.
JUST PUT ME THROUGH TO HER.
[groans]
AH, YES. HELLO, UH,
THIS IS AN EMERGENCY.
I NEED TO PAGE SOMEONE
IN THE HOTEL.
(woman on P.A. system)
WILL HELEN SPEARS
PLEASE CONTACT THE FRONT DESK?
HELEN SPEARS,
THERE'S A MESSAGE FOR YOU.
[screams]
[telephone rings]
HELLO?
WHO IS THIS?
(Matthew)
THIS IS A FRIEND
OF HENRY PRATT
WHO'S BEEN FOLLOWING YOU.
I AM ACROSS THE STREET.
BE ON THE ROOF OF MY HOTEL
IN 5 MINUTES.
[shouting]
HOW MANY FUCKING MEN
DO I HAVE TO KILL
IN THIS FUCKING TOWN?
OPERATOR, CONNECT ME
TO THE NEAREST
POLICE PRECINCT.
[telephone rings]
YEAH, METRO DIVISION.
(Matthew)
THIS IS MATTHEW WELSH.
MY HOROSCOPE SAYS
THAT TONIGHT
IS A GOOD NIGHT
TO MAKE NEW FRIENDS
AND THEN DISMEMBER THEM.
I'LL BE ON THE ROOF
OF THE PALM COURT
IF YOU WISH TO TRY
AND STOP ME.
[snickering]
HEY, NOVAK.
RUN IN AND GIVE THIS
TO FERGUSON.
IT SOUNDS LIKE A CRANK.
NO WAY. HE JUST CHEWED
MY ASS OUT ROYAL.
I'LL WAIT
UNTIL HE TAKES A BREAK.
I WANT A ROOM.
HELEN SPEARS!
IS THAT YOU?
HAVEN'T YOU LEARNED?
PLAYING GAMES WITH ME
CAN BE FATAL.
WELL, FOR THIS REMATCH,
I HAVE A DISTINCT ADVANTAGE.
EVIDENCE
THAT YOU'VE LIVED
A PAST LIFE
AS A CRAZED ZEPPELIN.
BY THE WAY, YOU NEVER DID
TELL ME EXACTLY WHY
YOU KILLED SIMON.
WHEN YOU'VE KILLED
AS MANY PEOPLE AS I HAVE,
IT'S EASY TO LOSE TRACK.
NOW, WHICH ONE WAS SIMON?
TALL GUY? BAD SKIN?
MATTHEW TOLD ME
THAT THE MODEL
DID THE KILLING.
AND I BELIEVE HIM.
HE THINKS SHE'S STAYING
AT THE PALM COURT HOTEL.
I BELIEVE YOU'VE MADE
A TWISTED LOVE PACT
WITH THAT CLOWN
BASED ON YOUR MUTUAL
ADMIRATION OF SATAN.
[sighs]
YOU ALWAYS HEAR
ABOUT CELEBRITIES
GETTING AWAY
WITH MURDER.
BUT WHO WOULD THINK,
LITERALLY?
WHY DOES IT SEEM LIKE YOU'RE
STALLING FOR TIME?
[siren wailing]
HERE YOU GO.
YOU KNOW, WHEN IT COMES
TO DUPLICITY,
YOU ARE A RANK AMATEUR.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I CALLED THE COPS.
THEY'LL TAKE US BOTH
INTO CUSTODY
AND HEAR A FULL CONFESSION.
[siren continues wailing]
YOURS.
(Hexina)
WHEN YOU'VE KILLED
AS MANY PEOPLE AS I HAVE,
IT'S EASY TO LOSE TRACK.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS TO ME.
NO. BECAUSE YOU'RE NOTHIN'
BUT A FRONT-DESK CLERK!
SIR, THE WATCH COMMANDER
THOUGHT YOU SHOULD SEE THIS.
THE PALM COURT.
HAS A UNIT
BEEN DISPATCHED?
YOU SAID
NOT TO MAKE A MOVE
UNTIL YOU--
THIS IS NOT
THE PEACE CORPS HERE,
YOU IDIOTS!
MOBILIZE SOME BACKUP! NOW!
[sirens continue wailing]
GUESS WHAT?
[chuckling]
THAT WASN'T
A POLICE CAR.
LOOKS MORE
LIKE A SMALL AMBULANCE,
YOU DORK.
[laughing]
HUH.
WHO THE FUCK
IS THIS NOBODY?
SOME MIDDLE-CLASS
DOUCHE BAG YOU DATE?
SHE LOOKS LIKE A PYGMY.
YOU DON'T THREATEN ME.
I HAPPEN TO KNOW
FOR A FACT
THAT YOU LEFT YOUR GUN
IN MY APARTMENT.
TRUE.
BUT I KEPT
YOUR KNIFE.
[grunting]
FAGGOT HOLIDAY FUCKIN' PALACE!
LET ME SEE YOUR EYES
WHILE I KILL YOU!
[laughing]
(Matthew)
FORGET IT.
[screaming]
OH, SHIT.
[grunts]
[hissing]
[police siren wailing]
[growling]
[Hexina screams]
[chattering]
[rumbling]
*[I Touch Myself
by Divinyls playing]
* I DON'T WANT
ANYBODY ELSE *
* WHEN I THINK ABOUT YOU
I TOUCH MYSELF *
* OH, I DON'T *
[electricity surges]
(man)
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
[gasps]
[sobbing]
I HAVE SINNED AGAINST YOU,
OH, GOD,
AND I AM SORRY.
[grunting]
SORRY.
IT'S TOO LATE
TO MAKE NICE.
[grunting]
[sighs]
YOU FOUND MY G-SPOT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OH, SHIT!
[grunting]
(Turner)
GUESS IT WAS A CRANK
AFTER ALL.
(cop on radio)
ATTENTION ALL UNITS, CODE 3.
MURDER SUSPECT SPOTTED
AT HOLIDAY PALACE ON BAY ST.
(Ferguson)
THE SON OF A BITCH
HAS RETURNED
TO THE SCENE
OF THE CRIME.
(female reporter)
WE'VE RECEIVED WORD
[snoring]
THAT SUSPECTED MURDERER
MATTHEW WELSH
HAS JUST BEEN SIGHTED
AT THE HOLIDAY PALACE HOTEL
WHERE HE WAS
RECENTLY EMPLOYED.
MATTHEW'S BACK.
[people chattering]
MATTHEW'S BACK!
[grunts]
OH, I ALMOST FORGOT
TO TELL YOU, MATTHEW,
I'M PREGNANT.
WHAT?
JUST KIDDING.
[Matthew screaming]
[screaming]
[grunting]
REPEAT. SUSPECTED MURDERER
MATTHEW WELSH
IS SOMEWHERE
IN THE HOLIDAY PALACE HOTEL.
[people screaming]
OH, HOW APPROPRIATE.
"L" IS FOR "LIAR."
[signboard creaking]
(Matthew)
STOP THAT!
FOR GOD'S SAKE, STOP THAT!
[police siren wailing]
GET THAT HARSH LIGHT
OUT OF MY FACE.
[people clamoring]
[police siren wailing]
(Ferguson)
THAT LOOKS LIKE
WELSH UP THERE.
WHO THE HELL'S THAT
WITH HIM?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
(woman)
S.W.A.T. TEAM.
[tires screech]
HUT! HUT! HUT!
WHY WON'T YOU FALL?
PLEASE STOP IT!
I CAN'T GET A CLEAR SHOT
BECAUSE OF THE WOMAN.
SHOULD I TRY ANYWAY?
THERE'S NO MEDIA.
NO, GOD DAMN IT!
[screaming]
WHY WON'T YOU FALL?
[metal creaking]
[Matthew screaming]
[creaking]
[people clamoring]
[screaming]
(Hexina)
MY FACE!
[passengers exclaiming]
[Hexina grunts]
(driver)
HEY, ISN'T THAT HEXINA?
[whooshing]
(cop)
INCOMING!
[cop shouting]
WHY?
[siren blaring]
OH, GOD!
LET'S GO! WHAT HAVE
WE GOT HERE, SIR?
GUY ON THE ROOF, SIR!
OK, LET'S GO! AIRBAG!
OH, MY GOD!
I'M JUST A DESK CLERK.
[people shouting]
[screaming]
(fireman #1)
COME ON! LET'S FILL IT UP!
LET'S GO!
OH, MY GOD!
(fireman #2)
RIGHT THERE!
THANK YOU!
[people screaming]
OH, PAPA! PAPA!
HE'S AWAKE.
I'LL TELL THE DOCTOR.
I'M LOOKING
AT THE MOST WANTED MAN
IN AMERICA.
YOU'VE GOT THE STORY
OF THE YEAR, MY FRIEND.
HEY, THAT HEXINA,
ALIAS HELEN SPEARS
SOUNDED LIKE
A REAL NIGHTMARE ON LEGS.
SHE EVEN ATTACKED A MIME.
JUST FOUND OUT ABOUT IT.
SEEMS THE MIME HAD BEEN
RELUCTANT TO TALK.
OH, BY THE WAY,
YOU'VE GOT A REAL FRIEND
IN THAT GIRL GLORIA.
I MEAN, SHE BELIEVED IN YOU
WHEN NOBODY,
AND I DO MEAN NOBODY,
ELSE DID.
HAVE A GOOD READ.
[people chattering]
(female reporter)
AFTER RECUPERATING
FOR NEARLY 6 MONTHS,
MATTHEW WELSH
IS BEING RELEASED TODAY.
[people chattering]
[cameras clicking]
[reporters clamoring]
(Gloria)
MATTHEW!
GLORIA!
GLORIA.
GLORIA, HOW COME
YOU NEVER CAME
TO VISIT ME?
I TRIED, BUT I--I COULDN'T
GET THROUGH SECURITY.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD SEX
WITH THIS WOMAN?
YEAH. AND HAS SHE
EVER TRIED TO KILL YOU
IN BED?
MATTHEW, DO YOU THINK
OSWALD ACTED ALONE?
MATTHEW.
I NEED A BREAK.
[reporters continue clamoring]
YOU KNOW, I HONESTLY
DON'T RECOGNIZE YOU.
YOU--YOU LOOK DIFFERENT.
YOU'RE HAPPY.
WELL, I INTEND
TO STAY THAT WAY.
[yells]
[tires screeching]
[window shattering]
WHAT HAPPENED?
UM, HAD A LITTLE ACCIDENT.
[Thummell groaning]
SIR, ARE YOU--
ARE YOU OK?
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
OH, HI.
[screaming]
[continues screaming]
YOU MADE MY LIFE
A NIGHTMARE!
(Gloria)
NO!
[continues screaming]
(Gloria)
YOU'RE A MANIAC!
GET OFF OF HIM!
YOU! YOU!
[Thummell continues screaming]
* NA, NA, NA, NA,
NA NA, NA, NA, NA *
* NA, NA, NA, NA, NA
* WELL I'M NO ANGEL, NOW,
I'LL ADMIT *
* I MADE A FEW BAD MOVES
I SHOULD REGRET *
* I HURT YOU ONCE
OR SO YOU SAID *
* JUST ONE MORE CHANCE
IS ALL YOU GET *
* DIDN'T MEAN
TO DO YOU WRONG AGAIN *
* WORSE THINGS HAVE BEEN DONE
BY BETTER MEN *
* BABY, BABY, DON'T,
DON'T TREAT ME THIS WAY *
* I KNOW, YES,
I'VE GOT TO PAY NOW *
* I'M STILL PAYING
* WELL IF I COULD WALK
ON WATER *
* AND IF I COULD FIND
SOME WAY TO PROVE *
* IF I COULD WALK ON WATER
* WOULD YOU BELIEVE IN ME
* MY LOVE IS TRUE
* NA, NA, NA, NA,
NA, NA, NA, NA *
* OH
* ALL ALONG, I TOLD YOU LIES
* TO ERR IS HUMAN
FORGIVE IS DIVINE *
* DON'T BE A FOOL
DON'T SETTLE THE SCORE *
* CAUSE I CAN'T
TAKE IT NO MORE *
* I CAN'T TAKE IT
* WELL, IF I COULD
WALK ON WATER *
* AND IF I COULD FIND
SOME WAY TO PROVE *
* IF I COULD WALK ON WATER
WOULD YOU BELIEVE IN ME *
* MY LOVE IS TRUE
* WELL, IF I COULD
WALK ON WATER, IF I COULD *
* IS THAT WHAT I'M
GONNA HAVE TO DO *
* IF I COULD WALK ON WATER
* WOULD BE YOU BELIEVE IN ME
* MY LOVE IS SO TRUE
* NA, NA, NA, NA,
NA, NA, NA, NA, NA *
* DO I HAVE TO WALK
* WALK, WALK ON WATER
FOR YOU *
* YOU, YOU, YOU
* HEY, BABY, BABY
THERE'S A LITTLE TIME *
* LET'S SPEND IT TOGETHER
* WE'LL GET OVER
WHAT WE LEFT BEHIND *
* THERE'S OUR
FUTURE TOGETHER *
* YEAH, WELL,
LET'S STAY TOGETHER *
* OH, YEAH
* I KEEP WALKING
WALKING, WALKING *
* WITH YOU, WITH YOU
* WELL IF I COULD
WALK ON WATER *
* AND IF I COULD FIND
SOME WAY TO PROVE *