This is
Ninja extent by blood line ends here
! Why
! Sai
! Down, Naruto! We must continue the task
! Will not give up Sai
! Naruto
! Sai
! Sai, Wake up
! Shadow Copy Technology
! Edge bolt
Is Sai okay?
... What is your problem, Sacco
! See it?! Such a terrible injury
! If you will rescue operation, at least do the first strategy
! You're careless, you reckless idiot
They are just like you
Do not you think so, Oopitho?
Naruto Shippuuden
Awful 4
** The heirs of the will of fire **
We look at the effects of Ninja limit blood line of the four missing
Who have lost their villages for
All ended here
, Disappeared between the village of stone and the hidden village of grass hidden
In a series of mountains at Mount Konrin Homsn
Done well
What is the next step?
I'll think about something, do not worry
... If targeted Ninja limit blood line last, it is likely it will be
What's up?
None
Are they okay?
Yes, forced them to conduct tests at the hospital
It's not the kind that obeys orders and stays in bed
! It's wonderful
Do not eat greedily, Shoji
Teacher Assouma spared no expense, as you know
You're not the star here today
... And if you continue eating so, you will truly become cm
! Shikamaru
I am paying the account for you this time
! Thank you for the feast
Why are you all here?
Why? We heard that you live concert
To celebrate the better of Naruto and Sai
We also
Hinata said to me
! I am also
Naruto asked me to tell everyone
I thought that he wanted a smaller audience
We only will we share the account
I was reminded, that the guests of honor were late
! Sorry for waiting Ibakaikm
! Everyone who attended already
.. This is not true Naruto, we did not get permission to leave
There is nothing wrong, nothing wrong
! You can not add a million people to the guest list
Whenever they increased the more the merrier, right, Sai?
! Nutritious
! This is to celebrate the Pthassanna
! Eat as much as Machawon
! Shikamaru account will pay for all
.. Wait, I did not
! Thank you very much, Shikamaru
.. Great! Now let's start
! You two
Kma
It's all over
... Sakura, we have serious injuries
Really?
How many seriously injured who
You see them sneak into the barbecue?
Consider that this is your punishment
! If painful, he went to bed and slept
I know that Naruto, always recovers quickly
Why are angry anyway?
Bonkma seems in good condition
Teacher Kakashi, do you come to visit us?
Almost, I thought Bonkma Sthara bored?
Take
Thank you very much
Heart of a woman
Quick Guide
Girls try to hide his interest in your "
"To become angry and act harshly
This will be useful to me
And I?
We both know that you do not read
But I would like you to take care of this
What is it?
Mahzh?
I Jursan
Your mission is to steal one of them before lunch
! method of fire, fire ball technique
Sakura and Sasuke rebellious teacher Kakashi
And shared lunches with me
Have revealed totally ordered
I was sure that we all fail
! succeeded ...
But the teacher Kakashi in fact, a Binjahna
in the world of ninjas, people who break the rules are considered scum
but the people who do not care about their friends are worse than scum
I will never forget what Kakashi Dear teacher taught me at that time
Did you learn that, too?
Alonbo taught us to abandon our comrades
For the task if we had that
What is this bleak childhood
But why give me this?
As you can see, I mowed them down somewhat
So I would like you to fix it
I count on you
Now I hurry, so I'll let you deal with the bells
! Wait a minute, teacher Kakashi
Not really
How can I fix bells?
! Why not fix it yourself, the teacher of Kakashi?
Nectanebo Konoha
Do not worry, does not have any Ninja can reach me
Is that all?
I see that they have the element of earth
The time has come
! Lady Tsunade
What's up, Chezoni?
Have you heard anything from Alonbo who Orslanahm to Homsn?
! No, but look to the sky
I am ninja of the village of Konoha, Hiroko
! Why?
! This strange, impossible to be still a child Hiroko
What's up with this?
Chimera have used techniques to take the ninja techniques limit blood line
Of the four countries of the Great Ninja and made me
I will be invincible when I get a blood line limit V
I will be immortal ninja final
I will use this power to start the fourth ninja war world
And will be in control of everything
! Be carried out immediately, the village will be placed under military law
As you know, a ninja Hiroko had declared war
And this has put our village, in the case of the most serious ever
! Other village may attack us at any time, be careful
... Naruto, things seem hectic abroad
Alcazikaji Is ...?
Neighbor, not up yet?
Envoy left the Hidden Sand Village
And had already come to a series of surrounding hills
Should arrive within half an hour
... Lady Tsunade
This is too large for konoha to deal with him alone
We need help
Each of the five great ninja villages have their own hidden
They are ready to foreign invasions
We, the state fire, we pride ourselves stronger
We have to protect Konoha for many years
In any case, there is concern that you are planning to coup
Other States was prepared to "war
Ninja and these countries are turning towards us
Some reports claim that they started with the invasion
This put considerable pressure on our confidence in Konoha
! A moment, please
I admit that, before more than ten years there was a ninja named Hiroko
"It was illegal conduct research on technical" Chimera
But he left the village long ago
! And FreeBSD Oamark
Indicate the identity of real culprit and Take care of the situation immediately
If you fail to do so, I will destroy the village of Konoha
Hurry to prove innocence
Aattabreha and the only way to maintain the status of Konoha
! Neighbor
Lady Tsunade
Seems that the envoys of the Hidden Sand Village
May have suffered a rocky and the collapse of a large--scale
! What would you say?
We found these at the scene
... Lady Tsunade
Storm coming
... It's the worst nightmare for us
Ninja fourth world war is about to start
Chimera Technology does not have enough to eat up the blood line limit
Must be realized that certain conditions are first
I have met the conditions for absorption of the four baseline blood
... But in order to absorb the user V
Heaven, earth and man these conditions they must meet ...
The sky is the Eclipse in the form of ring
Earth is Homsn
... And the man
If you are able to absorb the blood line limit, all the five elements
Will be balanced in my body
I will be immortal, ultimate ninja will be completed
You Ninja limit blood line should be to become the fifth
For this let you to become the last
... After all, you are my dear friend, the old
It has been a long time, Hatake Kakashi
... You Hiroko
What's up?
Featured brand
Why?
Hiroko decided since ten years ago
Alharianjan that his blood line is the limit V
And that it must develop technical type "Marionette" somewhere
! Why?
Are they trying to take revenge on Konoha?
If so, if it is my fault, too
! Will not let you get Hiroko
No, let me go, please
This would not work
According to reports Anbu, he mastered the technique that allows him
Transfer techniques Ninja grateful to the net and eat it
In other words, even the best ninjas can not approach him
! Is primarily a ninja invincible
Why if he should summon Ninja limit blood line?
I think that must be met certain conditions
To be able to absorb the blood line limit
Why choose unbalanced now?
I heard that there is a requirement to deal with a special type of light
There is an annular eclipse in two days
Likely to be, we have no time to
Lady Tsunade, there is a technique I would like you used Ali
This is the only way to defeat Hiroko
Kakashi, I will have sacrificed one of my officers to protect konoha
Do you want to be seen to date Khokaji cold heart?
Yes, that's what I want
Lady Tsunade, this will fire your
Sarutobi Assouma
Assouma, the village is in danger of an unprecedented
... did you overcome even once in Alcoji
remember our words about the king?
... I'll tell you who is
... approached more
... Assouma! But you ...
... Please ... Shikamaru
Now it was my turn
I swear I will protect the king, who was for it
... Oopitho
Rennes ...
I was not able to protect any of you
But I Oadkma I will protect konoha
Teacher Kakashi, do you visit the grave of someone?
Almost, do you visit Assouma?
For
I will give my life to Konoha, if
This is what is needed to protect the left Assouma
That's all
... If this is the fire will have
Become a good Ninja
What is it?
I was hoping to find a message from me to Naruto
Why do not you tell him yourself?
Well, I can not really
Not only annoying thing to Tgerni
Always very serious
Are you sure that be worth it Tzllk from the hospital?
I spent one night in the hospital and the world is in chaos
! I can not only stretch in bed and sleep
! Dear old man, thank you for a meal
... Teacher Kakashi
We are under military law
Kakashi, I'm afraid we can not allow you to pass
! Teacher Kakashi
! Teacher Kakashi, what happens?
! Can not you hear me ...?
Wait, Naruto
! Away, Shikamaru
There's nothing wrong with the teacher Kakashi
! Simulation technology shadow
! What's going on?
Kakashi teacher wanted me to tell you something
He does not want you to go behind him after leaving the village
! Why?
! What do you know?
I can not say
But the law stipulates that the village Konoha ninja must obey orders
! ... Why are you
! I will not let him go
He was ready to risk his life to save the village
That will fire the teacher Kakashi
Teachers ...
! Teacher Kakashi
Hatake Kakashi fled from the village
From now on, all the links between him and cut off our village
No matter what happens, stay away from him
Of course, this means that you can not catch up with him
Make sure that all the teams you hear about this
... But Lady Tsunade
! Parting
Shikamaru, You Stay
We need to talk
Present
It is expected as the teacher Kakashi
Naruto tried to catch up with him
Imprisoned him in his cell until now
... So stupid
... On the teacher Kakashi
This related to this presentation of the animated image of the giant, is not it?
It was clear that someone had control of him when he left the village
But he knew what would happen and accepted by
He did it because he thought he was the only way to defeat the enemy
Am I wrong?
Flour ... as always
! And you let him do so?
Yes, ordered him to die for the village
! Let me out
! Ended with a joke, took me out of here
I have to catch up with the teacher Kakashi
! I should Oaidh
! Damn
! Any person, let him come here! Is not there one here?
Why? Why do not you leave me?
Why does not understand the one here?
... Teacher Kakashi
! Sakura
Naruto, why they did this to you?
I do not know
I was a teacher Kakashi acting strangely, so I tried to Oaidh
Lady Tsunade said that he abandoned the village
, Has said that the move away with him
And it is no longer part of the village anymore
! Impossible! That chaos
Kakashi was a teacher seems to be controlled by people
If you think we were Sntkhaly
Grandma Tsunade may fail to do so
Do you think that that is the Phantom?
True ... he said not to catch whatever it was
And that risking his life to protect the village is the will of the friendly fire
This is what the teacher Kakashi
! To be that the teacher would risk his life to clean up this mess
! If it is impossible to let him go alone
... But the Lady Tsunade
Sakura
Look at those bells?
Teacher Kakashi gave me them
Remember? What we have learned in the past
In the world of ninjas, people who break the rules are considered scum
But people who do not care about their friends are worse than scum
! I just want to protect my friends
! What I'm doing with Sasuke ... well also
Now, I want to re--teacher Kakashi hands of those
! That's all I want
Naruto ... This is a request age
prepared Sasuke here
! I promise you, yes I
This is a promise  Age
! Naruto, thank you
Naruto, can you protect the teacher Kakashi?
Can your hands to go?
! Order! I swear that I Soovi my promise this time
Naruto ...
! Why go it alone?
I am a key member of Team Kakashi also
You should say what a bad
Sakura ...
! This is an exaggeration in the Force
... If so it
! Lady Tsunade
! Naruto Uzumaki had fled
! Why?
Sakura seems to be assisted by the
! Damn them
Dear Ms. Hokage, why do not claim to command me?
Problems like it, is my job
I understand
Naruto and Sakura, Shikamaru you Sotrkhm
Everyone here, right?
Orders require the arrest of Ms. Tsunade
Naruto and Sakura, and returned
Wait a minute! What's going on here?
You heard the message Ms. Tsunade, is not it?
Naruto and Sakura Asyaha and went behind Kakashi
But why Ms. Tsunade did not tell us catch up with the teacher Kakashi?
I think it is natural to go
! They are part of Team Kakashi
Not too uptight
! This will not change my opinion
Me, stop this
As the Hokage ordered that the commander is the Shikamaru Sotia orders
But ...
And I also
This is the way the laws of Konoha
Seems, that we do not have a lot of time
We'd be the difference during our move
! To go
Hidden Sand Village they get to the front
! Go
Finally, we will meet again, Kakashi
Just go to welcome the guest of honor
If somebody is trying to hinder you, Kill him!
Present
! Teacher Kakashi
! Wait
! You Iarvaq
Naruto, Sakura, under the command
I am here to Iaidkm of the village
! Teacher Kakashi left the village because someone was Istir it
! Please, let go naruto
I will not do, Ms. Tsunade orders clear on Hatake Kakashi
Hokage ordered us not to approach him anymore
People who violate the laws of the village are considered scum
But you know ...
Our training during the first teacher taught me something, Kakashi
! People who do not care about their friends are worse than scum
! And I do not want to become a riff at the end of Almtafp
Is the teacher Kakashi was controlled by someone?
Yes, the teacher Kakashi left intentionally controlled
To be able to break into the hideout
! Well, if you know this, I'll do the same way Naruto
And I also
I would like that, too, if possible
But that is the only way to save the future of our village
! Diffusion
! Now, Naruto
! Yes
! Damn them
Negi, I want the first team to deal with this
Yes, we will do this
You are there, we have our reasons to do so
I can not Turkkm crossing of the gate
! Recall, snakes bilateral head
! Network Snakes
! What is this?
! Only Keep moving
! Alkonay explosive
Be careful! Has an enormous amount of chakra
You are not bad
Gate?
Teacher Kakashi seems that through this already
You are finally here
Dear children suffered bored to death
They want repayment for the last time you
! Excellent, and I owe them one, too
! You should keep your pets restricted
That's not normal dogs
What do you think, Hinata?
Has the same flow of chakra the ninja--trained dogs
It is clear that it is not normal dogs
They do not even look natural
Does not interfere in Hzati, Chino
Naruto, Sakura! I do not know if what you are doing is correct or not
But I understand exactly what tags are both
! Naruto, Sakura, I do not think are wrong Bonkma
... Kiba, Hinata
! I said that they Mtmellon! So Omtaohm
To put aside personal views
We will deal with these things here for you
After all, we have specialized in the beasts of our team
! To go, "Surprise
! Turning the beast to human
! Rapid turnover
! Very easy
! Set off, now
Keba ...
! Wait, Naruto
! Thank you, Kepa
Called her to us
! What Tflanh? Behind them, Go
Can not
Because they are going to master
! Service projects ... How dare?
! Recall
! Chimera Technology
! Here is arriving
It's time to fight real
! Naruto, listen to
Way the continuation of the emergence of new enemies and attack us
Proves the importance of their teacher Kakashi
This means Matoukah teacher Kakashi was true
Therefore, we must not let him follow his plan?
! This does not mean anything
! Dear Idiot, Duffer
, I want to save the teacher Kakashi, also
! But we can not sacrifice the whole village, for which
That was enough to welcome them
Now, Sosob them very carefully
Who should I start with the blood bath?
! Naruto, Sakura, Come
! Sai
They left us behind
Sai dreaded
! Explosives optical this is not just
... It seems that the number is now less
What should we do, Shikamaru?
I suspect he Sisedkna that told him that we are not enemies
To try this again
We must defeat
! But we can not waste more time
Airstream is stable, we need to go now
I understand
Sai, I'm glad you came
Gave us a big help
Well, I'm a member of Team Kakashi
If you do Tmaanaan Bokadkma?
Absolutely! True, Naruto?
Anyone who follows the teachings of the teacher Kakashi
Is a member of Team Kakashi
I have learned so
! The heart of a woman?
The book said that people would be grateful
When they appear in such times like these
I feel stupid because they fell for the
I dropped the book
Your defense is impressive, but you can not
If you continue to lose to defending
! If I Soqatlk
! Accelerate the launch of the Snake
! Session heavenly
We can not approach him
If we keep on the attack with defense
Session and to renew his heavenly Ovaih
Have the same level
I will not attack unless you do more of my speed
! Me, use primary lotus
! Tantn, national covered us
You this
! Primary lotus? Concept
No benefit
I will not let a stop
! Hey, we are! Primary lotus
! Marks the eight session of the heavenly Walid
! No benefit
! Why?
! Take this
You can not keep up with pace so the body mass, is not it?
Villains Konoha
! You to death
What a dirty trap
It seems you're busy with Kepa and forgotten me
And that gave me plenty of time to work on this
... It's just a hole! What Stvlh
Are you serious in the belief that I have this weakness?
! Insects?
! The field of insect
! Has been a long time, but we use the formation Ino -- check -- Shaw
Well --
! Technology increase the size
! Control technology on the mind
Well, I did it
Eno, tell him that we are here to re--Naruto and others only
We do not want to fight them
Osilih also the point of Kakashi
I understand, but I can not give you this information
! Why?
! Shikamaru
! Retreat, Shoji
! Technique invoking
... Of all times
! What is it?
! Chimera Technology
What is he doing?
I think that we have not overcome it
... I've told you already! We are not here to Mqat
I'm surprised that I managed to get out on your own, a neighbor
Not only Kakashi, any Ninja
Has a will of fire sacrifice his life to save Konoha
But is this enough to defeat Hiroko?
Yes, Kakashi, Naruto, or perhaps, will overcome it
Naruto, too?
In front of him is still a long ways Knynja
But the only man who inherited my way of Ninja is not never giving up
It is up to you, whether you believe or not Bimkanith
! Tsunad Lady, Please Come to the inside
Everyone Sesthdvunk
! I know that
! You have stopped
O members of the Hidden Sand Village, said Alcazikaji perfectly fine
And he gave me this as evidence that
This ...
Stop! This was the signal Alcazikaji to stop the fire temporarily
! Present
! Jiraiya, where a neighbor now?
So I do not know what his next move
! What is this sandstorm?
! My eyes hurt
! Neighbor
I came to help, too?
Naruto, I will not allow you to pass from here
Kakashi did not want this
Gaara ...
! What would you say? I will not let the teacher go Kakashi
! Not understand how it feels Kakashi?
! .. I do not stand in the way
! Naruto
! We will help, too
! You applied Iarvaq
But ...
... We can not at all
! Teacher Kakashi to leave alone ...
! What are you trying to stop me?
I said this to me once before
"I will not leave the people dearest to be harmed"
! And you will sacrifice your life for the protection of your friends
! Kakashi tries to sacrifice his life, in order to protect everyone
! No, no! Will not let this happen
! Will not leave the teacher Kakashi does this
! I do not want any one to sacrifice his life
You are very perfect
We are still very weak because the transform those ideals into reality
I Kazikaji Hidden Sand Village
Now, the lives of the villagers depend on
! Not have time for Mtalitk
Why do not you want to understand?
! I can not barter the lives of the villagers against Kakashi
... I
... I want to protect ...
! Teacher Kakashi ...
! Why do not you understand this?
I have no opportunity to launch the entomological Alkkaicho Thus
Tantn, you can output some strings?
For
What would you do?
! First, we'll charge wings that thing, the spread of
! Good, Withdraw chains at the same time
Feathers like leaves explosive, it is a dangerous thing
! Shikamaru! Go behind Naruto
, Even if we are all here
It will take time to defeat this thing
All understand what you think about it
, I know how it feels Naruto
But Omer Hokage is the basic
! Let us this
! Go, Shikamaru
! We will leave to you is Naruto
! Scurry, while we Mhasrene
Shikamaru ...
! Protect Village
You guys ...
... Man, what a nuisance
I am counting on you all
Damn ...
! Neighbor
Naruto went
... Do not tell me that you allowed him to go
Jiraiya told me a lot of things
The thought on the subject logically, the strategy
Kakashi is the only way to defeat
My thinking exactly the same
But when Naruto fought for the first time
Years ago, the feelings I received
Why?
, Because it does not have no hesitation in his own way Knynja
It never gives up
I also understand how it feels Jiraiya, he is betting on the possibilities of Naruto
There are times when I feel jealous of Naruto how to leave his heart that led
But no time for this now
... King, "which it Iitmanni Assouma"
! Children who are the future of the village ... must Ohmiam
I'm going to stop Naruto, even if must be to kill him
... This place
... The battle of the former
Teacher Kakashi, where are you?
Sakura, what's up?
! Look at that
! Teacher Kakashi
Why did not Toukvoh?
Whatever we called it, it does not listen
Kakashi seems to be under the control of the enemy in full
! Teacher Kakashi
Teacher Kakashi, RSVP! You know who I am, right?
! Wait
What's this?
"Tag to technology" release time
, Even if he had been tortured
The technology also will be activated and timed
He lives like a ticking time bomb
It's not much use in Alonbo, we consider the last resort
... If you, the teacher chose to Kakashi
This is true
! Shikamaru! You learn all this from the beginning, is not it
! Yes, Hokage and is placed upon the technology
When caught the enemy to Kakashi
In the Final Assessment Dvaathm that are isolated, will activate his Almaenjikio Harianjan
For the destruction of the enemy that
Absorbed ninja techniques are endless
This is the only way
Grandma Tsunade know?
That the teacher Kakashi going to die ...?
Impossible ...
Do you understand now?
This will fire the teacher Kakashi
This ... this ... this is not true
! Naruto! Teacher Kakashi can not hear your voice anymore
! Make him hear
! Wait
! Teacher Kakashi
It was a long, Hatake Kakashi
, I've been waiting your arrival
, It is almost time for the eclipse of the sun
! It was you
! You who did this teacher Kakashi! Why?
Why made you have created with the enemy?
In the past, there was a man in Konoha named Hiroko
Long ago, this man's dream of what will happen this day
And put a curse on the doll Kakashi
Hiroko was a friend of Jiraiya, Tsunade, and Orochimaru
Alsanin legendary for konoha
However, Hiroko not Ninja Maher as they were
, In order to overcome the weakness of physical
, He immersed himself in research
And try to complete the technical body Artificial, Chimera
This was during the Third Ninja World War
And it is said that the battle bridge Canapé was one of the most battles
! Eyes
Kakashi, are you okay?
... How ...? Should not be able to see me
! Hey guys, Orkadwa director
... Blind spot in my right eye
Are you both okay?
Rennes ... ... Kakashi
... Oopitho
Hatake Kakashi returned from that battle
I was shocked
! And had acquired a blood line limit Kakashi
Of Uchiha Oopitho, Alharianjan, and made her queen
"Then I thought," This is the
Using the Chimera technique, if you can put the power of the blood line limit myself to
! Then I would be as powerful as Jiraiya, Tsunade, and Orochimaru
But
! When he learned of Hokage ordered my research, tried to kill me
I Konoha Ninja?
Hiroko here
! Faster and showed yourself
Kakashi, come to
Thy blood line limit is the fifth and final
! Finally, I would be perfect, immortal ninja
! Do not go, teacher Kakashi
It seems that the only way to stop the teacher is to defeat Kakashi Hiroko
! Wait
! You can not use ninja techniques against
! Shadow Copy technology multi--
! First ... the wind, wave cloud lightning
! Rasinjan
! II ... a dark, absorbing the abyss
! Dark absorbs chakra
... III
Swords do not affect me, now I use a steel
! IV ... The speed
! Force violent fools just can not Costive
! Has evolved for more than absorption techniques
Can use the border line of the four blood absorbed by the
And used by indigenous Kmstkhaddmehm
! A dark, Judgement
Hakerakm you have prepared, they sat down quietly now
Well, Kakashi, it's time to become a part of me to become a full object
... Teacher Kakashi
... No ... that closed the gate
... This is the case, there is no other way
You've given me the reference for how to become a full object
When the moon casts a shadow on the sun and make a gold ring
The light of the sun that holds special powers
Cover me when that light, you will become a part of me
And I will be full, immortal ninja, Kakashi
... Teacher Kakashi
Damn ...
! Will not let you go
! That's enough, he moved away
! King "... You need to protect children who are yet unborn, the future of the village"
Do not worry, Sohmiam, also
... Teacher Kakashi taught me everything, my friends
... Sohmiam, our village, our comrades
Children ...
So why are you?
Must protect him
Will not be our future unless we protect the most important thing
The most important thing?
... Even think about, but the next generations with pride
! You need to protect the village
Compliance with laws so is the life of a ninja
Konoha ninja and protect their comrades, even if their lives were in danger
! But
Planning to sacrifice someone from the beginning?
Is this how we do things now?! Are you really OK on this?
And Do you think that everyone would be happy if they knew how they were rescued by?
! Is only bring more grief
! This is not built up that I love so much
I am ... I want to protect
, The village that I love, and the future of next generations of the village
! I want to protect both
Shikamaru ...
King "is children who will be the future of the village"
, Please Protect the village that I loved a lot
For these children
Do you agree to this, Shikamaru?
... He tries to protect
The same thing, Assouma
For
He's trying to protect the future of children who Osmithm "King" and leave nothing behind them
That is also the will of fire
... Assouma
! Naruto
! Sewing shadow
Naruto, now you have inherited the will of fire
Move on to follow through the ninja who believe
Shikamaru ...
! I understand
! Sohoudrh for you, too
Naruto ...
... You need to rely
! Will not let this happen
If this is what he meant Jiraiya?
Do you really built up betting on the fate of this man?
When the sun is hidden moon
And eclipse of the sun cast on the surface of the earth Duh
Then the conditions will be achieved heaven, earth and human
! Hatake Kakashi, Alharianjan Thy will be a part of me
! Stop
! Do not touch any of them
Using the power of light from the eclipse of the sun, the object will become a full
! Dear bastard
! Long overdue, Kakashi became a part of me
! Go to hell
! Why?! Kakashi, what are you doing?
! Can not be controlled! You are inside my body now
Is the teacher plans to use Kakashi Almaenjikio Harianjan
To blow up himself and this man in another dimension?
! But the teacher also said die to do this
! Shadow Copy technology multi--
! Rasinjan
! To go
! Why?
! Rasinjan
! Will not let you get away from me
... Teachers ... teachers
! Cohesion, teachers
! Please Open your eyes
! Please Wake up, teacher Kakashi
! I promised Sakura
... Teacher Kakashi, I promised that I Sohamik
! Why it always the case?
! Damn
Damn ...
Morning ...
! Teachers
Why do you think yourself active here, Naruto?
! Man, You have made me worry
! To see this
I Osalehthm
Teacher Kakashi, because you asked me this
Followed by a lesson that I learned of these bells and I came to save you
Teacher, Kakashi will never forget what has taught me
In the world of ninjas, people who break the rules are considered scum
! But the people who do not care about their friends are worse than scum
Naruto ...
... Oh my God
If you are alive, if The plan has failed
Must thank you, naruto
If not come to you in the wind with Kakashi
Instead, the student Kakashi saved me
Eclipse of the sun is not over yet
I still have conditions of the earth and the sky
! Kakashi, I'll kill you and take the human condition
Why?
! Start jogging, Naruto
Naruto, you did it?
Wait, my friend, Kakashi
! You will become a part of me
! What are you talking about?
! I protected the teacher Kakashi
! Not the only one who inherited the will of fire
! But everyone in Konoha
We must defeat all, right?
To do it
... I think he does not have a choice
! Dear silence those vulnerable irksome
I do not even need to face you
! Invoking
What's up?
It was a recall
... I really did not want to see this thing again
! Let me
, I remembered that
In the book that gave me Kakashi, he says that women
... Become a powerful infinite for the man you love
! Shut
! This will let you Iarvaq
It was supposed that everything has a solution in exchange for my life
Do not complain
All what I did is what is taught by a teacher Kakashi
Let's go, Naruto
Olaizal I use it in this light?
! Sewing shadow
! Now
! The art of the ninja, scroll Monster Ripper
! Strike cherry blossoms
! Weak! Very weak
! Surrendered, Kakashi! I Somtsk
! Final technical element of the wind disturbance
This is not an ordinary thunderstorm cloud
It takes chakra and continue to grow
And I will all this energy to the Earth
It is the beast that is made of technology in addition to the Chimera of the four blood line limit
But as long as it did not absorb the teacher Kakashi, The Fifth Element
He did not become fully
! Naruto
! Spot where teacher Kakashi wants to absorb the still empty
The only weakness is a wound on his chest
Well ...
Woe ...
! Comrades
... You came all of you
! Well, you guys do it
! Technology increase the size
! Tank edged meat
! Rapid turnover
! Signs of Eight, Sixty--four strike
! Konoha whirlwind
! Tantn
! A taste of this! Double Dragon Rising
! Naruto
! Well
! Shadow Copy technology multi--
Ninja techniques are useless against me
! Alrsenjan overwhelming
! Soaidha all of you
! Edge bolt
This is what I was waiting for him
Why?
! I will stun you Edge
!'s Not finished yet
! Dear Asshole
... It does not work
! Omasalt your technique? But as I said earlier
! Ninja techniques are useless against me
! Why? I can not absorbed?
! Like this technique ... I can not believe it
! This is impossible
! Take this! Component of the wind, screw Aelchoriken
! Did it! We did
... Bimtsask, you will become a full object
Where was my fault?
, In order to overcome the weaknesses
Ignored others, and tried to become a full on your own
And it was your fault
This is the logic of those who were born with the strength
At that time, I did not have any guys
This was the only way to live
You're wrong, Hiroko
I was here
I also
! Hiroko, back to your patience
I had to choose closer relationships with your friends ... and not live an isolated
If only you try, the comrades they will help you
... Comrades ... I understand
... But this is what you Kakashi tried to do this time
Yes, I'm just like you, Hiroko
Maybe you are not the only one who had wandered
I may also
, By thinking that if I sacrificed myself, I have rescued the village
I have isolated myself from my friends
Tried to sacrifice what is more important for the village
In fact, I am defeated
... I
Do you finally made the Commonwealth?
... With my friends ...
Beat me too much
Naruto ...
! Neighbor
Withdrew, I have been solve everything
! Present
! Withdrawal! Withdrawal
Sorry for the problem, Jiraiya
Because of you we were saved
... I do not
We both were saved
Acting as we did when we were young
... Yes, I think that we are old,
! Teacher Kakashi
Prefer, I stand by what taught me
It is true that in the world of ninja, those
Who violate the rules are considered scum
But ...
! Those who do not care about the comrades are worse than scum
If you would claim to scum in both cases, I prefer to break the rules
... Oopitho
, If that means I'm not real Benninja
! If I smash that idea
You just like him
What do you say?
! That smile is not alien to the great
... What is this filth
Why ... why?
... I had no idea that the teacher Kakashi prefers things like that ...
This book says more than once, when the parties feel
.... Ikhvqan that their hearts, this can lead to love
... But I do not know about men
Are you serious?
... Wait! It is not
! Teacher Gai said that this is also part of the Spring of Youth
I know that
! And you must be kidding me
! Naruto, it's not so
! Hurry
Stay away
! Naruto
! Not
My greetings to all members and visitors forum Forums "
"And I hope that translation has won the admiration
Awful 4
**... I hope that the story of this film with you forever **
** ** Masashi Kishimoto