(Episode 99)
How do others...
go to their mums when they're in trouble?
I can't even go in there because I don't want to worry Mum.
What are you doing here?
Mother.
What are you doing here at this hour?
Well...
Did you have a fight with Jae Min?
Yes.
What about the kids?
Jae Min is with them.
What are you thinking?
Mother, please.
No matter how upset you are,
you can't leave kids behind at this hour.
I'll explain at home.
- Mum will hear us. - What?
She should know you're doing this.
Mother, please.
Oh, my.
It's you, Mi So.
Why are you here at this hour?
Mum.
- Yes? - Ms Ok.
She came here after a fight with Jae Min.
What?
I couldn't go in because I didn't want to worry you.
Come on in.
What are you doing? Sit down.
Okay.
Well, tell us.
What happened?
We just argued about something trivial.
Then why did you have to come here leaving your kids behind?
She didn't bring anything. She doesn't mean to stay out long.
I was so upset, so I came to see Mum.
You should have come in right away.
What were you doing outside?
I didn't want to worry you.
When your husband makes you upset, you should go to your mum.
That's what everyone does.
Are you telling her to talk behind my son's back?
She should when he makes her upset, no matter how nice he usually is.
Hey.
You can't do this.
Your daughter left home in the middle of the night.
You should scold her and send her back home.
She must have been really upset...
if she left her kids behind at this hour.
Are you saying it's okay to do this?
That's not what I mean.
Mi So just needs someone to talk to.
Sleep here tonight and go home tomorrow morning.
Ms Ok.
Please let it pass this time.
This is what mums are for.
Fine. I get it.
Have a great time, you two.
A stranger should go home.
I'll send her home tomorrow.
Wait. Mother.
I'll be right back.
Mother.
Mum.
You can't leave like this.
Why not? You two can have fun.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
No matter how good Jae Min is at babysitting,
you still shouldn't sleep out.
I thought we'd have a huge fight if I was with him tonight.
That's why I left.
What is it?
Did he do something at work?
No.
If not, what could possibly make you leave your kids and sleep out?
I'll go home after tonight.
He did do something, didn't he?
You need to tell me.
Let's go. I'll see you off.
You can't leave your mum alone.
Go on.
Is Mi So over there?
Yes.
I'll take care of her tonight.
Make sure you take care of your children.
Okay. I'm sorry, Mother.
Mi So's here. Goodbye.
I completely forgot that Mi So found her mum.
Dad.
Did Mum go to Grandma's house?
Yes.
She's sleeping over tonight.
That's a relief.
Yes.
Dad, whatever you did, you were very wrong.
Why?
You told Mum, "You have nowhere to go."
Did you hear that?
She probably wanted to leave more because she heard that.
Oh, my. Leave it. I can do it myself.
Just lie down. You must be tired.
This is very comfortable, Mum.
It's just an old shirt.
I should get some casual clothes for you to wear.
I can bring some from home next time.
You know what?
This smells like you. I love it.
Were you surprised to see me?
Why did you fight with Jae Min?
Jae Min is...
too righteous.
Sometimes, that's too hard for me.
No one would be happy...
if he keeps picking on things he can overlook.
He's just like your father.
Was Dad like that?
When he'd see a fight,
he'd walk in to break it off.
He'd also scold at impolite kids.
I told him to not step in, but he'd never listen.
I'm so glad you know how I feel. How should I put this?
I feel very relieved.
I am...
always on your side.
Even if you did wrong, I'll be on your side.
So...
if something bothers you, don't worry about it...
and just come to me.
So this is what it's like to have a mum.
But you still shouldn't sleep out.
You should stay home even if you two fight.
You shouldn't walk out like this.
This is just for tonight, okay?
Okay.
Let's go to sleep.
What brings you here this late?
Mi So is at her mum's house.
How did you know?
So you already knew?
Mother called.
Why did you two fight?
What did you do wrong to make her leave her kids and walk out?
It's nothing.
Did you...
do something at work?
I didn't.
I shouldn't have asked. I knew you wouldn't tell.
You never start talking once you make up your mind.
Yes. You shouldn't have come.
Don't worry and go home and get some rest.
I'm going to sleep over.
Why?
I will fix whatever you did wrong.
There is nothing to fix here.
Let's wait and see.
I will find out what this is about.
What's she doing? Is she a detective?
This is driving me crazy.
Ga Ram, you're sound asleep.
Mum.
Bang Geul. You're up so early.
I was going to wake Dad up because you weren't home.
Come here.
I'm sorry, Bang Geul.
I was feeling awful yesterday.
So I slept over at Grandma's.
What about us?
My other grandma came over last night.
She's sleeping in my room.
Really?
Mum, are you staying out tonight, too?
No. I'm coming back tonight.
Bang Geul, I'm going to work now.
Okay.
Smile today!
Yes. Smile.
Goodbye.
- Honey. - Yes?
Do you really not know why Jae Min and Mi So got into a fight?
How would I know?
Do you have something to do with Mr Oh, too?
- Why do you ask? - Just because.
You made a deal with Mr Oh...
about my front money.
I'm not at a place to have something with him.
In my opinion,
Mr Oh is at a completely different level than Dung Kim.
You should be careful.
Dad. I'm hungry.
Are you? Wash up first. I'll bring your breakfast.
Okay.
Did Min Ho start studying Korean?
Don't worry. I'm teaching him.
I should've been more concerned about the basics.
What good is prior learning if he doesn't know Korean well?
How can he solve the difficult analytical problems?
Many people do not realise that. They only want to push forward.
No one looks back.
Eun Sol, eat up.
Is Mum angry, Dad?
No. Let's eat, Eun Sol.
Seung Ju's mum.
Yes. Do you know where Da Woon's house is?
Do you know anyone who knows?
That's good news. Please find out where it is for me.
Yes.
Why do you ask?
What will you do? Will you kneel down and apologise?
That's how things were back then.
There wasn't a hospital that gave maternity leave to nurses.
What about now?
Can people use maternity and a childcare leave?
Can our nurses do that?
Don't blame the society.
This was your decision.
When...
Bang Geul's mum went through a similar incident,
I couldn't imagine...
that people could be that awful.
I didn't realise my own husband was doing exactly the same thing.
You only pretend to be a gentleman to people of power.
You're...
a terrible person.
- You're here. - Yes.
Where's Ga Ram?
- My mum is with him. - Is she here?
How's Mi So?
She slept at her mother's place last night.
I see.
Well...
I ran into Mi So yesterday.
She asked me to tell her...
if you ever tell me anything about Mr Oh.
Do you mind if I ask what's going on?
I'll tell you when I need your help.
Bang Geul, your uncle is here. It's time for school.
Oh, you're here.
- Hello. - Let's go.
- Where? - What do you think?
I'm going to shared babysitting.
Why?
You babysit my grandkids. I should help out.
Are you sure you have no other intentions?
You guessed it right.
Let's go, Bang Geul.
Where's Min Ho?
He's waiting in the lobby.
Let's go.
Where's Ms Lee?
She's at her mother's place.
Why?
She wanted to sleep at her mother's place.
Get in.
They had a fight because of me.
I'm really okay. My goodness.
Have some. It'll be tasty.
You really didn't have to.
Try it. It'll taste amazing.
Gosh. I'm not hungry at all.
Do you have any soup?
I'm afraid I don't.
It's boring to have only rice.
Can't you whip up some egg soup?
Egg soup? Sure.
Let's see.
Ms Lee.
We don't have any kids here in the morning.
You can go home and...
Why did...
- they fight? - Sorry?
You don't know?
I have no idea.
Then can you try and ask Mi So about it?
She won't tell me anything.
Jae Min must have gotten in serious trouble at work.
I see. I'll ask Mi So when I meet her.
Have you had lunch yet?
I've been at our stores until now. Can we eat together?
I'm sorry.
You must have been hurt when I said...
you had nowhere to go.
I was just joking.
I got in trouble with Bang Geul for that, too.
Mr Oh...
How did your business trip go, Mr Oh?
What should I do?
I couldn't attend the disciplinary committee...
because I suddenly had to go on a business trip.
I heard the penalty turned out to be quite harsh.
Yes.
He regrets it very much.
Even though you supported his idea,
he should have informed you before carrying it out.
You did the interview...
to support him, right?
I appreciate it.
I'm glad you understand me.
I was worried that Mr Kim would get me wrong.
No way.
We decided to go along with everything you say from now on.
Don't worry.
I hope...
this will do for now.
I'm sorry, Mi So.
You had to apologise to Mr Oh for me.
Please stop being mad at me.
Then tell me the truth.
What's Mr Oh's secret that I don't know about?
You don't have to tell me.
Mum said...
I shouldn't keep it to myself and should always turn to her.
I'm not going home tonight, either.
Mi So.
How can he just leave like that?
I have to go home today.
How did it go?
The executives of Youngjin Industry...
complained a lot about their president.
They blamed him...
for the company's bankruptcy.
Is he really...
registered at SS Global?
I'm sure of it.
Once we get our hands on the employee list, we'll find out.
Even if we find his name on the list,
how are you going to prove his relation to Mr Oh?
I think I should meet Mr Park...
who's in charge of SS Global.
I should ask him about the president of Youngjin Industry.
Jae Min. Why do you care so much about this matter?
That's what I'm talking about.
Hey. Haven't you guys talked it out yet?
Talk it out?
In Mr Kim's eyes, I'm just a fly.
Would you have a conversation with a fly?
I'm not going home for the time being.
Please tell Mr Kim to take good care of the kids.
Hey. Why is she so upset?
She usually supports whatever you do.
The thing is...
It's driving me crazy.
My goodness. You sort it out.
Hi, Il Mok.
(We're looking for missing kids.)
We finally received some information about the missing kids.
- Really? - Yes.
Someone left a comment on my blog.
She says the kid looks a lot like a kid at an orphanage in Gumi.
That's great.
I called the kid's parents. They're on their way to Gumi.
My gosh.
I hope it's the right kid.
I really hope so.
So do I. I'll keep you updated.
Okay.
What are you doing now?
I'm telling my neighbours about the new information of the kid.
When are you going to call Mi So?
A bit later.
Do it right now.
Otherwise, I'll eat three meals here every day.
I'll text her right now.
Let's see.
I have something to tell you.
Meet me at the fried chicken place after work.
Why does he want to meet me alone?
(Meeting Room)
Have you lost your mind?
You want what?
I'd like to take paternity leave.
Do you have to copy everything others do?
Do you want to take paternity leave because Jae Min did?
I have no one to babysit my kids.
Isn't it that you want to get paid while slacking at home?
I barely managed to find a neighbour who can babysit today.
If you persuade Mr Oh...
This is why I was against Jae Min taking paternity leave.
I knew there would be copycats.
Copycats?
Taking paternity leave is not a crime.
You sound just like Jae Min.
After criticising him so much,
why do you try to copy him?
We haven't found any kids yet,
but please keep supporting us.
I'll call you back.
- Mi So. - Mr Kim.
Mr Choi is in the meeting room right now.
- Why? - His wife got in a car accident.
He told Dung Kim that he wanted paternity leave.
He got turned down right away.
- What? - Shouldn't you...
try to help him?
I should.
Stop being so angry, Mi So.
Don't worry about me.
Good luck with finding Mr Oh's fault.
What should we do? She still seems very angry.
What can I do? I need to make it right.
You should just tell her that it's because of me.
Never.
If she finds out that you used Mother's name,
she'll never see you again.
Everyone is in a mess because of me.
How long will I hide behind Mr Kim?
I need to step up.
I heard the story.
You want to take paternity leave.
Who says so?
Your wife is ill.
Of course you should take care of your children.
Mind your own business.
Like I said,
I am going to help anyone who wants to take paternity leave.
Think of your children. You need to make an effort.
Paternity leave is...
a right which every single employee has.
You should apply for it at the human resources team.
No, thanks. I do not want to be put to shame again.
I'd rather quit.
Mum.
Are you going back home tonight?
You can use me as an excuse.
I'll be at home with the kids.
Okay.
Thank goodness.
I didn't have a good excuse.
What is it?
I have something to discuss.
To discuss? About what?
I want to...
tell everyone about this situation.
Tell everyone? How will you do that?
I will become a whistle-blower.
I want to tell them what I have done wrong...
and get Dung Kim and Mr Oh while I'm at it.
What about you?
Giving over Mother's name to an affiliated company is a felony.
If they ask me to quit, I will.
That was wrong of me.
Fine. Let's say that you quit.
What if you can't disclose Mr Oh's corruption?
Please, wait a little more.
We'll make a move once we have something.
We can't move in vain.
We may lose everything.
I'm just so frustrated.
I can't even face Mum,
and I hate that you two are fighting because of me.
What if something bad happens to Mum?
What will I do then?
Mr Oh won't make a rash move.
He probably embezzled much money by an illegal use of her name.
He won't give that up.
We have to get as much information as we can...
until Mr Oh makes a move first.
I'm going to meet with Mr Park, the communicator with SS Global.
Ye Eun, please.
You really shouldn't make a rash move. Okay?
Please.
Okay.
Honey.
Mi So.
Why are you two together?
What's so weird about that?
I'm glad you're here. I had something to tell you.
What? What are you doing, Ye Eun?
What is it?
I'm sorry.
- I have... - Ye Eun.
- I... - Ye Eun.
What's with you? What is it?
I handed over Mum's name for SS Global to use.
- What? - Mr Kim found that out.
That's why he is after Mr Oh's corruption.
Why did you do that?
Why?
I'm sorry.
I doubt he'll tell me why they fought.
Do you mind if I ask what's going on?
I'll tell you when I need your help.
What if they were going after Ye Eun...
and not you?
Did something happen between you and Dung Kim?
Does it have something to do with her?
Wait. Get up.
Let's go outside and talk.
- Get up. - Why?
Why?
It's Il Mok. We were going to meet here.
- Get up. - Let's go.
What?
Hurry. Let's go.
Welcome, Il Mok.
Oh, hey.
Why are you all here?
Oh, it's because...
Jae Min, why are you here?
I come here often.
What's going on?