Mr. Thumbs Up, I'm home.
What brings you here?
My dad said you can use
this for a reference.
What is this?
I think he found out
you've been writing songs.
These are materials he's been
collecting regarding songwriting.
He said there are music notes of
famous songwriters in there too.
Has CEO Lee always been so considerate?
It runs in our family. We may not
look considerate, but we are.
I know CEO Lee is like that,
but I don't know about you.
Right, I had my TV debut today.
I know. That's why I've been
so busy all day long...
writing news releases for
you two in the office.
The audience seemed to like us,
and the director complimented us too.
Great job, Ji Hoon.
Were you eating?
Yes, do you want to join?
It's enough for two.
No, I just ate. I have to go.
To practice?
This is a hard-won chance,
and I want to do my best
regardless of the result.
Gosh, you're all grown up.
- You should eat. Bye.
- Okay.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
You did well, Ji Hoon.
You did well. That was good enough.
Mr. Thumbs Up.
Are you eating all right?
I'm sure it's night there too.
Welcome...
What brings you here?
Why would I come to a bakery?
I came to get something.
Can you make a recommendation for
a cake that's not too sweet?
You can take this one.
- Is this good?
- This is the most expensive.
- You're rich.
- Gosh.
You're the one who stole
our most popular singer.
Because of that, we took a huge hit.
You should've treated him better
while you had the chance.
Hey, Young Jae.
Hey, Bo Hee. It's been a while.
You should stop by more often.
Our bread is really good.
Oh, right. I should.
Can you give me an
assortment of your bread?
Hey, you are supposed to
pick out what you want.
Oh, really?
Is Gwang Jae good to you? If he
does anything wrong, call me.
I'll do away with him.
- Who are you to say that?
- What?
I'm her neighbor.
You're barely a neighbor.
Here you are.
- What's this?
- It's on the house.
By the way, let me use
your recording studio.
I have no time to reserve
a studio near here.
So I'll use yours just for a while.
You make such a brazen...
demand.
We'll see.
You didn't even give me a bag.
- Just leave.
- Bye.
Be nice to Young Jae.
He acts a bit sassy,
but he's not a bad guy.
What? Be nice?
Young Jae and I are doing great right now.
(5-year-old Ji Hoon. What a pretty boy.)
Gosh, I'm tired.
Man.
Could you...
put this...
in the ice cream?
I'm going to propose.
Please and thank you.
I'm really good at this.
This is delicious.
- Why are you staring?
- What?
It's nothing. Go ahead and eat.
- Eat up. It's good.
- Okay.
Excuse...
- I...
- What?
What is it?
I...
need to go to the hospital.
What? Hospital?
Why did you swallow this?
That was a close call.
It'll come out after a day or two.
Do you see it here?
Goodness. Isn't that...
a ring?
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
I've swallowed and kept these
words in for 20 years.
Maybe that's why...
I swallowed the ring too.
I don't have much,
but I can make you happy.
Will you...
marry me?
Thanks.
My answer...
is yes.
Thank you.
Congratulations.
I hope it'll come out tonight.
Hey.
Should we have had a wedding?
Later. We'll take it slow.
Mal Sook is in our family registry.
We're officially a family.
Goodness. You're so impatient.
- Should I look into it?
- I want to...
have a proper wedding.
I'll have it in the biggest hall...
in the biggest hotel.
Is that right?
Then we'll do it slowly.
Take your time.
Your new business is the
most important right now.
And stop coming down to the bakery.
Well...
A CEO should be in his office.
Don't you think so?
Is that right?
By the way, about your album,
I'm looking into it.
Now that I have my own company,
I can support you.
No.
Let's do that slowly too.
What?
I want to be a good mom and a good wife...
first.
After doing that,
if I still want to be a singer,
I'll let you know.
You have to back me up then.
Okay?
Okay.
Just tell me when you're ready.
Mr. Thumbs Up!
Mr. Thumbs Up.
Why aren't you back?
Did you forget me already?
Friday at 11am will work.
The location is...
It's in Sangam? Yes, I know where that is.
How will you conduct the interview?
Your Americano is ready.
Please wait a minute.
Okay.
Thank you.
(Tuna Mayo Gimbap)
(Triangular Gimbap)
I'm sorry.
When I woke up, I was on the street...
in front of the World Entertainment.
I guess I was laying there for a while.
Then...
what about Hyun Jae in 1994?
You make him sound like a different person.
He's also me.
Well...
You two don't seem like the same person.
You're right.
He's me, but he didn't seem like me.
It's because we lived different times...
and experienced different things.
Then...
what happened to him?
I'm not sure.
I guess he didn't want things
to change because of him.
How do you know?
Because I'm him.
I just have a feeling.
In any case, you're a really...
weird person.
What about you? What did
you do while I was gone?
A lot of things happened.
Did it?
I have plenty of time on my hands.
Tell me everything.
I'm a great speaker,
but I'm such a great listener too.
Mr. Thumbs Up.
You didn't get lost and
found your way back well.
I'm not sure, but I guess
this is where I belong.
I like it here more too.
Oh, right.
I think it's thanks to
the compass you gave me.
Look.
(Roar, Moo)
It's delicious, isn't it?
I'm getting more addicted to it.
It wasn't this good in the beginning.
- Do you have a place to stay?
- I should look for it.
Then stay here until you find a place.
I can't do that again
after how much I owe you.
You didn't owe me much.
Of course not. I'm the Yoo Hyun Jae.
I never cross the line.
Exactly. I trust you too.
Do you want more rice?
What? Yes, a little more, please.
Sure.
- Mr. Thumbs Up.
- What?
- I'll go wash up.
- Okay.
Is she taking a shower?
Then again, she said she
was going to wash up.
I don't know. Stop thinking about it.
Why am I hearing the sound so clearly?
Hyun Jae, you're better than this.
Stop thinking about it.
Gosh, Hyun Jae.
You're much better than this.
Stop it and be yourself.
You should wash up too. Go in and wash up.
What?
Oh, well...
I think I need to find a
place to stay quickly.
I wasn't like this, but I don't
know what's wrong with me.
Is that so?
Hey, by the way,
why do you look so tired all of a sudden?
Isn't it some kind of side
effect of time traveling?
Whatever. I barely won against myself.
Right, I need to see Gwang Jae.
You do?
You'll be back soon, right?
Yes.
Will he be all right?
Why did he drink so much water?
Can you go back and forth...
as you please?
It's not as I please. I almost died.
I'm never doing it again!
Anyway, I wonder where
someone like you came from.
It surprises me too.
Oh, right. What about your treatment?
Will it be cured with regular treatments?
Oh, that?
One of my fans became a professor.
She's going to help me.
But then again, those little kids...
must be grownups by now.
I guess.
Anyway, I'm glad you're back.
Help me in our company.
Train the kids and write songs.
Wait a minute. You're young
enough to be an idol singer.
Can't you debut again?
Just once is enough to be on stage.
I plan to work comfortably backstage.
Sure, that's fine.
By the way, I don't see Mr. Lee.
He went on a kindergarten
picnic with Mal Sook today.
What? Is he all right?
He said he'd be the first
patient to defeat dementia.
He exercises like crazy these days.
He was determined to win
all the prizes today.
He talked so big as he left.
Then again,
he's naturally great in being so stubborn.
Dementia might give up and run away first.
I know.
But why did you help me out like so?
- I was your manager.
- You were more than a manager.
I don't know.
You seemed lonely.
- What?
- That's how I felt.
I thought that you were like that
because you were lonely like me.
That thought helped me
bear with your temper.
Let's keep getting along.
You should address me CEO Lee now.
I didn't say I'd work for your company.
I'll be a freelancer. Do you get it?
Look at you trying to
use your petty tricks.
Hyun Jae.
What?
Don't go anywhere far away now.
Let's grow old together
at least from now on.
Okay?
All right, let's do that.
One and...
- Hold on. I think someone's here.
- What?
Who? No one's here.
Is that so? Oh, right.
You said so much about your stage fright,
but you were meant for the stage.
I had no idea either,
but I guess I was.
How did you hold it in all these years?
Look who's talking.
Should we make Korea go crazy for us?
Let's take this opportunity
and do just that.
- We're JB!
- JB!
- Hello!
Hello, guys.
I'll meet up with my old
friends and go back.
They're all excited after
seeing me on television.
- Don't drink alcohol.
- All right.
What? You...
I'm back again.
I knew you'd be back.
Why do you always say you knew it?
I heard you debuted. Congratulations.
Thanks. Are you going
to stay here for good?
- Yes.
- By Woo Seung's side?
Well, yes.
- Where's Drill?
- He went out to meet his friends.
I met your dad.
I wanted to tell you about your dad.
About why he made that choice.
At that critical moment, he
kept on asking about you.
I told him how nice of a kid you are.
I showed him your picture too.
I told him you were debuting as a singer.
- What did he say?
- He was proud of it.
Was he?
Here.
Your dad wanted me to give this to you.
Isn't it superb?
Yes, it's superb.
Hey.
Let's make this great.
Yes, let's make this great.
No matter how much I think about this,
don't you think this...
is really strange?
Yes, it's really strange.
Hey, cheers.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I...
was waiting for you.
Why were you standing out here?
I got nervous.
I thought you would disappear again.
What?
Give me your arm.
My arm?
This is too much.
You can't go anywhere...
without me anymore.
(Woo Seung's slave, Hyun Jae)
I'll pay you back someday.
Part-timer.
You scared me.
Hey.
Why are you in there?
I live here now.
- What?
- I was looking for a room,
and I thought I'd check this place out.
And it turns out this house was empty.
Anyway, let's have a great
time as neighbors, okay?
Are you seriously...
- How did you...
- Come on.
I won't bother you, don't worry.
Bye. See you later, neighbor.
When will you eat? What
are you going to eat?
I'm not curious at all. Bye.
Do you want to eat out tonight?
You can always eat alone,
but it's a crime, a serious
crime to eat alone...
with a superb next door neighbor like me.
You're really...
You're really weird.
Come on, you mean that I'm really superb.
It looks like you two
are pretty popular now.
We're a duo born to live off of popularity.
Of course, man.
JB.
Right, I heard you two moved.
Oh, MC Drill and I moved into a studio.
Then what about this place? Is it empty?
For the time being.
Really?
Woo Seung, how is your
songwriting coming along?
I've been doing it,
but it's not going as well as I thought.
I thought so. You look more like...
a civil servant.
If you write a great song,
you have to give it to us first.
Okay.
Don't you have anything that's colder?
Of course, I do.
Here.
- My gosh, it's so cold.
- Nice.
Awesome.
- Awesome.
- Thumbs up.
- Thumbs, up, up, up, up.
- What was that?
We talked and laughed for
a long time that night.
Our time now may not seem like much.
Everything we have may seem...
like it's nothing and trivial.
However, like a poet once said,
the greatest poem...
has not been written yet,
and the greatest song...
has not been sung yet.
Our best days are the days
we haven't lived yet.
That's why the present...
and everything we do now
are precious to us.
We still have our best hit coming.
We did this the last time.
- Let's go.
- Let's go!
(The Great Yoo Hyun Jae)
(Roar, Moo)
This is pretty superb.
Hey, neighbor.
What? How did you know I moved in here?
Have you forgotten that I
work for World Entertainment?
How dare you run away without telling me?
I didn't run away.
Do you know how expensive that place was?
Are you sure you aren't
trying to run away again?
I can't go anywhere without you.
Why do you have things on your face?
Do I have something on my face?
Right here.
(The Best Hit)
I didn't mean to do that.
Woo Seung doesn't have beer.
Can you please say "Cut"?
Are you the one who has been scaring me...
every single night?
Wait, that's not right.
How should I do this?
Can you help me out?
Cut.
Look into my eyes.
Nonsense.
He can use the storage by himself.
Hey, what...
Hey, what about me?
Hey!
I'm sorry.
Are you serious?
250 joules. Charge 250 joules.
Was I looking too into the camera?
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
I'm Choi Woo Seung. In the
end, Woo Seung will win.
I'm sorry.
You jerk. This is so embarrassing.
I raised her so preciously.
Who did that?
Being fixed is... My gosh, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
(Thank you for watching The Best Hit.)
- I have a line.
- I'm sorry.
(Thank you for watching The Best Hit.)
("Our best days have yet to
be lived." Nazim Hikmet)
Stop it.
My gosh, Tae Hyun.
I heard you walking out.
- Did you?
- Yes, we can hear you.
Cut.