Shall I tell you a secret, Séverine?
I love you more every day.
And I you, Pierre.
You're all I have, but -
But what?
I'd like everything to be perfect too.
If only you weren't so cold.
Please don't mention that again.
I didn't mean to upset you.
I feel a great tenderness for you.
What good is your tenderness to me?
You can be very cruel
when you wish.
Forgive me, Pierre.
Stop.
Get out.
- What's going on?
- I said get out.
But why?
Come on.
- Let me go!
- Come on!
Do what I told you.
How dare you!
Let me go!
You brutes!
Let go of me!
It's not my fault.
I can explain everything.
Go on.
Don't worry about roughing up
the little slut! Hurry!
Pierre, it's your fault too.
I can explain everything!
Shut your mouth, madame,
or I'll shut it for you!
Stop!
Please tell them to let me go!
Help!
Shut up, you little bitch!
Come on.
Pull.
Don't scream or I'll kill you,
you hear?
Pierre, I beg you.
I beg your forgiveness
with all my heart.
Pierre, please don't let the cats out!
That's enough.
She's yours now.
- Pierre, I love you!
- Go ahead.
What are you
thinking about, Séverine?
I was thinking about you... and us.
We were out for a ride in a carriage.
The carriage again?
I want to kiss you.
- You have an early day tomorrow.
- Why?
- To pack our bags.
- We're going somewhere?
- Yes.
- Where?
It's a surprise
for our wedding anniversary.
Our happiness has lasted a year already,
“and the suns of yesteryear...”
What about the hospital?
I want to forget about work
for a few days
and think only of you.
Happy?
Especially when you're here.
I wish you could be
near me every second.
No, please.
Sleep well.
Good night.
Forgive me.
You're so good,
so understanding, but I -
It's all right. Go to sleep.
You coming
to the party at the hotel?
I don't know.
Husson goes to bed at sundown.
Then come alone.
They say it's going to snow tonight.
I'd love to see the mesmerist.
I hear he's wonderful.
I won't let him put me to sleep.
A mesmerist isn't a hypnotist.
He makes the sun rise.
A hypnotist plunges you
down into the depths.
Well, see you later.
What time is it?
Five o'clock. You look bored.
Don't let me keep you.
One's never bored in a bar,
unlike in a church,
alone with one's own soul.
I have something nice to tell you.
I love you.
Your scars heal so nicely.
Oh, stop it.
Let's not go in.
She's with Husson.
Too late. He saw us.
What have you got against him?
He's an interesting fellow.
I don't like how he looks at me.
Come on.
I saw you two
pass by earlier arm in arm.
It was a pleasure to see.
Like newly-weds.
- We must have looked ridiculous.
- No, it was very reassuring,
like an everyday occurrence.
But you, Pierre - you sometimes
make me feel guilty and uneasy.
You and I are so different.
One really doesn't meet
many men like you.
I mean it sincerely.
Another missed opportunity
for punishment.
Why? Do you know them?
Is that all you're interested in?
Everything else is useless.
A lot of wasted time.
You should see a specialist
about your obsessions.
He's rich and idle.
Those are his two main illnesses.
Don't forget the hunt.
I also have
a special weakness for the poor.
I think of them when it snows,
with no fur coats, no hope. Nothing.
You're very attractive, Séverine.
Your compliments are too subtle,
so just be quiet.
You're asking the impossible.
I've been here three hours.
I feel a headache coming on.
It's not too cold outside?
- No, it's nice.
I'll get some fresh air before dark.
See you later, Renée.
- See you later.
- Have a nice walk.
I like him. He's amusing.
He's strange.
Worse than that.
- Forgot to ask how Husson is.
- He's fine.
- Still together?
- Afraid so. Let's not talk about it.
You remember Henriette?
- Yes, very well.
It seems...
she's turning tricks.
- What?
- In one of those houses.
They say she's there
several days a week.
Can you believe it? Henriette!
Of course,
that's all so far from your world.
But can you imagine?
A woman like you or me.
Can you see her
going with just anybody?
In those places
you don't get to choose.
Old or not, lousy-looking or not.
Even with a man you love
it can be unpleasant.
It must be horrible with a stranger.
Those places still exist?
Excuse me, ladies,
but I can assure you:
Those places do still exist.
Oh, maybe not like
the joints before the war.
The red lights are gone, of course.
But trust me:
There's no lack of business.
I could show you a good half dozen.
Part of my job, you see.
In 20 years of driving a cab
I've seen everything.
I've been mugged twice,
and I'm none the worse for it.
Hey, what's the matter?
We're here.
These flowers came for you, madame.
Very well. Who sent them?
Mr. Husson.
Why did you put them here?
I'll get a cloth.
It's nothing.
The water was clean.
What's the matter with me today?
Séverine, come quickly!
Are you coming or not?
- Will you be much longer?
- I'm almost done.
Can I ask you a silly question?
Go ahead.
Before you met me,
did you use to go
to those... houses a lot?
Those houses?
Not very often. Why?
Does that interest you?
Everything about you interests me.
But I thought
they'd been closed down.
They've gone underground.
I can't imagine how it works.
- Listen, I have to work.
Well, you go in.
The women are there.
You pick one.
You spend half an hour
alone with her,
and after you leave,
you're depressed all day.
But what can you do?
Semen retentum venenum est.
Be quiet.
I don't want to hear
any more, please.
What's the matter?
I've never seen you like this.
What's going on?
Nothing.
I'm just tired and on edge.
Go get some rest.
You're right.
- Shall I come with you?
Yes, stay with me
until I fall asleep.
Will you never grow up?
I can't hit anything today.
Take my place.
- You leaving?
- No, I'll wait for you inside.
- How are you?
- Not bad.
- We don't see much of you these days.
- That's true.
The mysterious Henriette!
The woman with two faces.
A double life. How intriguing!
Did Renée tell you?
- Yes. But why?
Simple: for the money.
Most women who sell themselves
do so, alas, for the money.
It's nice to see you, Séverine.
- I can't understand women like that.
It's the oldest profession
in the world.
It's mostly arranged by phone now,
but the women in those houses
are a special breed.
I'm sure you know them well.
Yes, I used to go a lot.
I enjoyed it.
There's a very special atmosphere.
The women are complete slaves.
I remember a few around the Opera.
Especially one run by Anais.
11 , cite' Jean de Saumur.
I have marvellous memories.
- Are you mad?
- It's nothing.
A cute compulsion, as the English say.
An insignificant little impulse.
I must see you sometime -
without your husband, of course.
I admire Pierre very much,
but I'd prefer he not be there.
Madame Anafg
11, cite Jean de Saamuz:
What's the matter with you?
- I wanted to speak to you.
- Come in.
Are you in charge of...?
I'm Madame Anais.
I came to see if -
Let's go inside.
We'll be more comfortable there.
Have a seat.
Can I offer you something?
- Cigarette?
- Thank you, I don't smoke.
Don't be frightened.
Make yourself at home.
I'll do whatever I can.
Sit down.
You're nice, and fresh.
Just what they like here.
I know it's hard at first,
but who doesn't need money
now and then?
We'll split fifty-fifty.
I have my expenses.
Thank you very much,
but I must be going.
Come now.
You're just a bit nervous.
I bet it's the first time
you've worked.
It's not really so awful.
It's still early.
The other girls aren't here yet.
You're about to lose a button.
When would you like to start?
I don't know.
Today?
Yes, perhaps.
But afternoons only.
I have to leave at five, without fail.
All right,
but you must be punctual
or I'll be very annoyed.
I promise
you'll be free to go at five.
Good-bye, and excuse me.
I'll expect you this afternoon at two.
What's the matter?
Anything serious?
No, I was out shopping
and just suddenly wanted
to see you.
- I thought you didn't like hospitals.
- No, I don't.
I don't feel like being alone.
Let me take you out to lunch.
I'm having lunch with the manager.
I told you this morning.
- That's true, but -
- I'm sorry.
Don't forget we're going out
with the Févrets tonight.
- Sorry to bother you.
- Bother me?
See you tonight.
I'll try to be home early.
I didn't think you'd be back.
You left so abruptly this morning.
I thought I'd scared you off.
Come in.
Put your things in here.
You'll meet the other two girls soon.
Mathilde and Charlotte.
Both very nice.
I only tolerate
well-bred people here,
and they must be cheerful.
I want people to enjoy their work.
Just last week I had to let a girl go.
Very beautiful, too.
But she was too vulgar.
It's a shame.
Come sit down.
What's your name?
- I don't want -
I'm not asking your real name.
You think mine is really Anais?
We'll have a little something
to celebrate your arrival.
- No, thank you.
- I insist.
Cherries in brandy.
We need to find you a name -
something simple and smart,
and easy to remember.
We can think of one together,
if you like.
We call him Mr. Adolphe.
One of our best clients.
You'll see. He's very funny.
I have an idea.
What if we called you
“Belle de jour”?
Since you're only here afternoons.
- If you like.
You look a bit nervous.
Relax.
You'll be out by five.
Don't worry.
You have someone waiting for you?
A boyfriend?
A husband?
Oh, don't think I'm prying.
Kiss me.
The girls are thirsty.
Wait here. I'll be back.
A new girl,
and you're hiding her from me?
Bring her in this minute
or H! go get her myself.
He's a funny chap. You'll see.
A sweet manufacturer.
He has factories in Bordeaux.
Makes a lot of money.
Come on.
Some night if I have to go without,
I can run to make myself sleep.
The other day in Brussels
I had a black girl.
What a time we had!
This is Belle de jour.
I told you to close those drapes.
Belle de jour,
my respects as of 2.45.
Have some champagne with us.
Anais, a bottle of bubbly,
and quick!
You're lucky. They always open
a bottle for a new girl.
It sounds like you already had some.
Get acquainted.
I'll be right back.
A hell of a woman, from head to toe.
Forget it. She's too high-class.
That's exactly why, sweetie!
Listen to him.
He never gets enough.
What a specimen.
This is pretty.
But you need something
that comes off in a jiffy. Right?
No, I think she's a knockout
in that little dress.
Very refined.
Just how I like them.
You promised me a present.
I'd love a dress like that.
I'm not Rothschild, baby!
Too bad.
What a great cut!
The detail work is incredible.
It's easy to dress well
when you've got money.
But you can't buy class.
Here's the champagne.
My throat was feeling dry.
No, let me do that.
That's a man's job.
I'm a world champion cork-popper.
A real virtuoso
from so much practice.
I like ham and sausage
I like ham when it's good
But I like even more
a nice pair of thighs
It wasn't cold enough.
Champagne over 46 degrees
tastes like tea.
Sorry. If I'd known,
I'd have put it in the fridge.
- You knew I was coming.
- But not that Belle de jour was.
To the person
I care most about - me!
And to Belle de jour.
Good, but a little warm.
Mathilde, I forgot.
I do have a present for you.
Here.
- What is it?
Open it and see.
He's funny.
He always has some surprise.
Here's to fun!
I love life.
I like people to have fun.
Well, Belle de jour?
You in a bad mood?
What's the matter?
You'll see.
I'll show you a good time, I promise.
What's with her?
Give me a minute with her.
We mustn't rush her.
It's her first time.
- I've heard that before.
- It's true, I swear.
- Who does she think she is?
- She's just new.
You're doing fine.
You're a big hit already.
Mr. Adolphe is a simple man,
so don't get upset.
Do what he wants.
That's all he asks.
- No, I want to go.
- What?
You about done putting on airs?
Where do you think you are?
Go on.
Yes, Madam. I'm going.
Leave me alone, you two.
Seems you need a firm hand, eh?
Go on.
Close the door.
Come here.
I sent the others away.
More intimate that way.
Now, then...
it seems it's your first time?
Careful!
I have a nose for these things.
Don't try to fool me.
But if it's true,
there's no need to be ashamed.
You're not telling me
you're still a virgin at your age?
But we'll soon find out.
What? Do I scare you?
Don't like my face?
Better get used to it,
my little friend.
No, you're not running off now.
Who do you think you are,
you little slut?
You get me excited
and then pull me up short?
You can put on airs for a while,
but I've had enough.
There.
See?
That's more like it.
you need the rough stuff, do you?
Jack of clubs, my gin card.
Mr. Adolphe
is taking a long time.
He always does.
Séverine, where are you?
Are you ready?
You're in here?
What's the matter?
ls something wrong?
Are you ill?
You don't have a temperature.
Shall I send for someone?
- No, it's nothing.
I was sleeping.
I had a headache.
I don't know why.
I took an aspirin and a hot bath.
I'll feel better tomorrow.
What time is it?
It's late.
I'll call the Févrets to cancel.
- You go by yourself.
- Absolutely not.
I'll be much better here.
Anyway, I have work to do.
Get some rest. Good night.
Is the soup ready?
It's cold,
and I can't warm it up.
Are bulls given names like cats?
- of course.
Most of those are called Remorse.
Except the last one.
His name is Expiation.
What time is it?
Between two and five,
but not later than five.
- How's your wife?
- Where is she?
- Right over there.
Want to say hello?
- I'd love to.
How are you, little slut?
Everything alright, you tramp?
Old whore!
Maggot!
Sodomite!
Scum!
Fellatomane!
Trollop! Harlot!
Pierre, please stop!
I love you!
Just what do you want?
I wanted -
Your job back?
So you can disappear again
for a week without a word?
I won't have amateurs here.
That's what the streets are for.
You're lucky you're dealing with me.
Some others would shut
the door in your face.
I'm too soft.
But if you come back,
you have to be serious about it.
Can I count on you every day?
Yes, but only until five o'clock.
Go on in.
Nice to see you again.
It's Belle de jour.
How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
- You ran out on us.
- Why didn't you come back sooner?
- I couldn't.
- Give me your coat.
It's so nice.
Say, may I ask a favour?
Could I borrow it this Sunday?
I'll bring it back Monday.
Listen, I hate to say no,
but Sunday wouldn't work so well,
because -
Don't worry.
I'm seen it in ready-to-wear.
Carducci! Only the best.
Who are you?
Was it tough coming back?
I do this because of my fiancé.
He was hurt in a cycling accident
and can't work.
He knows I come here.
But I really love him.
Of course,
I could make a living elsewhere.
- And how much would you make?
- That's true.
The Professor
will be here any minute.
I'll introduce you.
You're just his type.
Who is he?
A gynaecologist.
Apparently a big name.
With an international clientèle.
Did an operation in Copenhagen
just two months ago.
There he is.
Fill her in.
Time to turn the lights on already.
You'll see, it's easy.
If they were all like him...
I have a new girl.
I think you'll like her very much.
A little shy, perhaps,
but a real aristocrat.
- Really?
- Would I lie to you?
Very well. Send her in.
Go on in, please.
- What are you doing?
- I was -
Didn't they tell you?
Get dressed!
Come in.
The marquise called?
Isn't her Ladyship satisfied
with my services?
no, not really.
- Madame Anais?
You belong in the kitchen,
young lady.
She's no good.
Get me Charlotte, quickly!
Right away.
Come along.
Charlotte,
go in to the Professor right away.
Just a second
I'm getting undressed.
Go inside.
It's not brain surgery.
Come here.
Watch carefully what Charlotte does,
and don't make a sound.
Come in.
- The marquise called?
Isn't her Ladyship satisfied
with my services?
You're always making mistakes.
It's true, I admit it.
But the marquise is so good,
so kind,
and especially so beautiful.
Insolent man!
Look here.
Are you blind? Can't you see?
There's dust everywhere.
There, there, and there!
I broke a vase.
A vase? Now I've had enough!
This time you're fired!
No, I beg you, Marquise,
keep me on.
Give me another chance.
I'll be very careful, I swear.
- Not yet! Give me that.
Her Ladyship can punish me
if she wishes.
Let her beat me,
but she mustn't fire me.
What are you doing?
You dirty old man!
Nothing.
I'm not doing anything.
I keep my distance, alas.
I shouldn't tell you this.
It's a secret, Marquise.
I love you.
I love you, I tell you.
Now walk on me.
Spit on me. Stomp on my face.
Dirty old man! Pig!
I'll teach you!
But I love you.
Hit me harder!
Come along.
Someone's waiting.
Well, did you watch?
What do you think?
How can anyone sink so low?
You might be used to it,
but it disgusts me.
No, sir, not me!
What about her?
Will she do?
What's that?
This is no good here.
Cash only.
All right. Go on.
- Did you behave and study hard?
Say hello to your godmother
and show her your grades.
Hello, Cathy. How are you?
Show me your report card.
No hello for me?
Shall we go to the fair on Sunday?
Happy now?
A seven in history,
and a nine in speech. Good.
Madame Anais!
What?
The Professor wants an inkwell.
- What's going on?
- He wants an inkwell.
An inkwell?
As if I'd have one!
- Go upstairs and do your homework.
That man would scare me too.
It must be hard sometimes.
What would you know, Pallas?
May I, miss?
- Miss or Mrs.?
- Miss.
Perfect.
What's your name?
Belle de jour.
Charming.
I once had a cat
named Dark Beauty.
Do you come here often?
Every day in my thoughts.
Lovely morning, isn't it?
It really is.
Nothing I like more
than the autumn sun.
The black sun.
Black sun?
I think you're very elegant.
Thank you.
Do you like money?
I'd give you a lot
to come to my house.
- Your house?
- For a sort of religious ceremony.
A very moving one
that means a lot to me.
What can I say?
I'm from another era,
when people still had
a feeling for death.
If you'd accept,
I'd be a very happy man.
You're just the girl I'm looking for.
I live an hour from Paris.
Here's my card.
I'll meet you at the station.
Put this on, please.
What's this all about?
You needn't be afraid.
All the girls before you
would love to come back,
but the duke is very strict
on that point.
If you'd kindly follow me.
This way.
I brought you some lilies.
You loved them so.
How beautiful you are.
Your skin is even fairer.
Your hair is even softer.
My beloved daughter.
Your face is cold.
Remember how we played
together only yesterday?
We laughed and sang.
Now you lie there,
mute and motionless.
I hope you've forgiven me.
It wasn't my fault.
I loved you too much.
Duke, shall I let the cats in?
To hell with you and your cats!
We're alone.
The doors are closed.
Now...
your eyes will never open again.
Your limbs are stiff...
worms are eating your heart...
and this heady fragrance
of dead flowers...
this heady fragrance
You're still here?
What are you waiting for?
It's raining!
Get the hell out of here!
Out!
Are you almost done?
Coming.
Shall I get in with you?
I only wish you'd do this more often,
of your own free will.
I will, Pierre.
Just give me time.
I always feel like I'm forcing you.
You mustn't think that.
I want to be alone with you
more every day.
You don't frighten me anymore.
I feel like I understand you better,
like I'm getting closer to you.
I love you more every day,
you know.
ls the lady of the house in?
- Who should I say is calling?
Mr. Husson is here to see you.
Tell him I'm not in.
You're very attractive, Séverine.
Frankly, I'd like to write you a letter.
- I'd like that.
Would you let me?
There are so many people around.
- All the better.
I'll have to give you a receipt.
I'm counting on it.
- With this?
What are they doing?
Nothing. Just having fun.
Take a look.
No, just tell me.
- He's taking out an envelope.
- And?
It's a packet of lily seeds!
I see.
- What floor?
- Fourth, please.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Don't do anything stupid.
You're mad.
Hurry up. Quick!
Well, well... Hippolyte.
Hello, Anai's. Can we come in?
Of course.
That way.
- It's Hippolyte.
- The Spaniard?
I hoped we'd gotten rid of him.
He's with a fellow
I don't recognise.
Who's Hippolyte?
Wait and see.
An odd sort of chap.
When he has money,
he throws it around.
And when he's broke,
he wants it for free.
Come on, girls.
All three of you.
- How's the little girl?
Big enough to be tickled yet?
I don't know.
She has to finish school.
- Only the best.
Buen ganao.
- What's that mean?
How are things?
- Fine, and you?
- Getting by.
We haven't seen you in months.
- We've missed you a lot.
- Really?
Where have you been?
Travelling, in New York...
business.
Put three bottles on ice.
The good stuff.
My best.
From Paris straight to heaven...
What I miss most abroad
is French champagne...
and sexy girls like you.
I brought a friend along.
Be sure you treat him well.
Of course, Mr. Hippolyte.
When we're alone,
I have a new joke for you.
You'll love it.
- Keep it to yourself, honey.
- Your loss.
- Cow.
Get off. You're too heavy.
And you're scratching me.
Beat it.
Come here, new girl.
Now...
Let me have her.
Take her if you want
and have fun, kid.
You should at your age.
I'd slit my father's throat for less,
but friendship comes first.
We're not going fight
over some slut.
Your friend seems shy.
Shy isn't the word.
The champagne's cold.
Anyone thirsty?
What's your name?
Belle de jour.
What else?
That's it.
Don't trust me?
I want to know your name.
- Belle de jour.
- Why? Aren't you here at night?
What do you do then?
Nice boots.
Your teeth...
What happened?
Knocked out in one blow.
You mind?
Then get to it. I'm in a hurry.
How old are you?
- Twenty-three.
- Got anyone protecting you?
- What's that mean?
Are you free or what?
You making money?
ls business good?
- Yes, but -
- Don't lie. It's not nice.
No, leave your stockings on.
A girl tried to strangle me once.
Poor thing.
If you like, I won't charge you.
Naturally.
Plenty of girls
would love to be in your place.
Still won't tell me your name?
You're not much of a talker.
Fine with me.
Girls that talk are a pain.
Not bad.
Too bad you've only got two.
Let's have a look.
Turn over.
What's that little brown spot?
A birthmark.
I can't stand those!
Get dressed.
Not cold enough, as usual.
- You read English now?
- Me? Not at all.
Then what's this?
What's it to you?
Enough!
Take this to the room.
I'll be right there.
The other one's for Marcel.
Who is your friend?
He saved my life last year.
I love him like a son.
Think I'd let him have
the blond otherwise?
What's her story?
- Belle de jour?
Yes. ls she in demand?
She's the one they come for.
She's got class, and -
And what?
- She's a pearl.
- A pearl?
I thought you were going to leave.
I'm glad I stayed.
I don? mind telling you: I like you.
Look at my hand.
I'm still trembling.
What's this?
- A scar.
- From a knife?
Maybe.
What are you doing here?
Don't ask questions.
I'd like to keep you till tonight,
but I can't.
I like you too, Marcel.
Will you come back?
- Maybe.
If you don't have money -
Money isn't a problem.
You frighten me.
See? You're bored.
I'm not.
I'd just like to get back to Paris.
You can tell me absolutely anything,
but you're hiding something.
If you tell me what's bothering you,
Perhaps I can help.
Tell you what?
That you love someone.
- Someone besides you?
You know that's impossible.
I suggested this little vacation to see
if anything was tying you to Paris.
I was right.
You want to go back.
You're always so distant.
I've never felt you
really close to me.
I'm sorry.
I suppose it's my fault.
Does that prove I don't love you?
I think so.
I don 't know how to explain.
There's so much I wish
I understood myself, darling.
Things about myself.
What I feel for you
isn't about pleasure.
It? so much more than that'.
I don? expect you to believe me,
but I've never felt so close to you.
You want to go home?
I'm telling you, I'm not bored.
We can stay another week
if you'd like.
No, we'll leave tomorrow.
I have to get back anyway.
Something wrong, Mr. Marcel?
I've seen men bitten by the bug,
but never like you.
Ah, shut up, will you?
You behaved like an idiot,
not like a man.
We waited for you on Thursday.
- So?
- So next time we won't wait.
- We almost didn't come today either.
Your cut keeps going up.
We're getting sick of you
and your little thug.
Don't fight with these hoodlums.
Settle down.
Gentlemen, if you have
something to settle, go outside.
Shut your trap, you.
The snow.
We know you've got it.
Now don't let us keep you.
We'll discuss that “thug” remark
some other time.
As you like.
Pierrot, another bottle.
- Where you going?
- To make a call.
Again?
Birds... what a curse!
You can say that again.
He's got it bad.
It's cost him dearly before.
But it's always been his weakness.
Nothing I can do.
Anais? It's Marcel.
Any news?
When?
Really?
I'll be right there.
“Carried his father on his back.”
Six letters.
The third letter's an N.
“Aeneas,” with A-E at the start.
Ah, right.
That comes up a lot in crosswords.
Belle, it's him again.
He's waiting.
How are you?
Where were you?
Why did you go away?
I had to leave Paris for a few days.
I can explain.
I'll explain a few things too,
and I'll leave my signature as well.
Don't touch my face.
Don't touch me!
Do that once more
and you'll never see me again.
Very well... this time.
I missed you, you know.
I shouldn't tell you this,
but I waited for you.
I want to see you more often now.
At night too.
I'm here every day.
Isn't that enough?
You know I'm not free.
- I don't give a damn.
I don't get it.
You seem to like being with me.
Very much...
but it's not enough.
You love the other fellow?
Then why are you here?
I don't know.
They're two different things.
I'm starving.
Where should we eat?
No idea.
We'll decide on the way.
I'll be back at three.
You've changed so much.
I hardly recognise you.
It's so nice to see you smile.
- I do feel much better.
I've never seen you like this.
If only -
What?
If only one day you had
some great news for me.
- What do you mean?
- You know very well.
What I want
more than anything: a child.
- What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
This old thing caught my eye.
I don't know why. It's strange.
- Nothing strange about it.
- No, you're right.
You're back!
I didn't recognise you.
Did you forget about us,
you ungrateful devil? It's been ages.
But you haven't changed.
First door on the right.
Come on, girls.
An old friend is back.
Well? Let's go.
Yes, yes, you look lovely.
- You 're flattering me.
- No, sir, I remember you well.
I even dream about you sometimes.
I don't like the sound of that.
- No, I couldn't.
- I insist. Do me the pleasure.
Hello, ladies. Sit down.
Belle de jour? That's original.
Perhaps you'd like some refreshment.
Later.
Nothing's changed here.
Still the same homely welcome...
the same drapes.
Whatever happened to that girl,
the lion tamer?
I haven't heard from her.
- And the heat's up all the way?
- You haven't changed either.
Look, that armchair.
It was snowing...
The same special fragrance
in the air.
Still jasmine.
I hope you have some time for us.
All my life.
I'm a man of leisure.
Now, then...
I'd like to be alone with Belle de jour.
No, I won't!
Is this any way to behave?
You'll stay.
She's very sweet.
Just a little on edge sometimes.
Happy now?
Don't tell me it's coincidence.
You knew I was here.
You're wrong.
It's your fault.
You gave me this address.
- You're wrong.
- Come closer and I'll scream.
I'll jump out the window!
Is this your bed?
You disgust me.
I already told you that.
Yes, it's my bed.
What else do you want to know?
You like being humiliated.
I don't.
Don't tell Pierre.
I admire him more and more.
Please don't tell him.
At least try to understand.
I'm lost.
I can't help it. I can't fight it.
I know I'll have to atone
for everything one day.
But I couldn't live without it.
Fine. Do as you like with me.
No. Not now, anyway.
I guess what attracted me
about you was your virtue.
You were the wife of a boy scout.
That's all changed now.
I have principles, unlike you.
I won't tell Pierre, of course.
But I have friends I could tell.
I could send you some business.
Sorry I don't feel like it.
It really doesn't appeal at all.
Another time, perhaps.
Who knows?
I won't take up your time.
This isn't for you.
Get Pierre some chocolates for me.
Ready? Go!
Prepare!
Fire!
- He left already?
May I speak with you?
Run along.
- I have to leave.
- When?
Now.
- But you'll be back?
- Definitely not.
Why?
You could have told me sooner.
Aren't you happy here?
- Yes, fine. It's just -
Now I get it.
It's Marcel.
He was just here.
He was furious.
Almost barged into your room.
There's something odd there.
Has he demanding?
Wants you to be his alone,
day and night?
It's always the same story with men.
You're right. You'd better go.
There could be trouble one day.
But I'll miss you.
Women like you...
You and I got along well.
It's true.
Let me know how you're doing.
Call once in a while.
I'd like that-.
Is there some address -
Too bad.
What else can I say?
Madame,
there's a gentleman to see you.
Who is it?
Do you know him?
No, but he says it's urgent.
- Did you bring the catalogue?
Sit down.
Not bad, the catalogue thing.
I like your little pad.
What are you doing here?
You're mad! Go away!
Since you weren't at Anais' anymore,
I thought I'd pay you a visit,
see how you're doing.
- How did you find me?
- Child's play.
Is this your husband?
Good-looking.
A nice fellow.
A lot better than me.
- Please leave.
- Don't worry.
I won't make a scene.
I just want to know why you left.
You hear me?
- Be quiet. The maid will hear.
Go away. He'll be home soon.
I just got here
and you want me to leave?
- What do you want?
- To see you again.
Impossible.
I'm never going back there.
I'll give you three days.
Find some excuse.
I'll be waiting at the Hétel Du Bois
on rue Fromentin.
You'll spend the night with me.
- Impossible.
Very well. I'll wait for him.
I have a lot to tell him.
- You wouldn't dare.
Yes, I would.
I didn't want it to come to this,
but since you're forcing me -
I guess it's just as well.
I'd decided to tell him anyway.
- Really?
He'd have found out
sooner or later.
One of our friends
discovered I was there.
I want to get it all off my chest.
Fine. We'll both wait for him
and tell him together.
I don't mind.
I'm begging you: Leave!
He'll be home soon.
Don't worry.
I'll leave.
I didn't believe you,
but I'm starting to understand.
Here's the obstacle.
See you soon...
- Did you see her?
- Let me have the car.
- Where are you going?
- I need it.
Let me have the car, and beat it.
What are you up to now?
I said beat it.
This time you've seen
the last of me, kid.
Oh no, you don't.
You're not running off.
Any news?
The killer's dead,
and the police are baffled.
Either he shot the wrong man
or he was insane.
- Has he been identified?
- Yes, a common crook.
It wasn't his first murder.
- Strange.
- How is Sérizy?
- Too early to say.
His wife's in the waiting room.
How is he?
It's too early to say,
but he'll live, so try to relax.
- Can I see him?
- No, he's still in a coma.
Perhaps tomorrow.
You should go home and try to rest.
We'll give you an hourly report,
I promise.
Don't worry.
Come on. I'll see you home.
I sent Maria for the newspapers.
I know the articles you like.
I'll read them to you.
Maria's very nice,
and she's so fond of you.
Everyone's asking about you.
You're getting better, you know.
The doctor's very optimistic.
You don't realise it,
but you've made great progress.
Your eyes especially.
It's funny.
Ever since you were -
Ever since your accident,
my dreams have stopped.
I think it's time for your drops.
Mr. Husson, madame.
He'd like to see your husband.
I'm coming.
I'm sorry to bother you.
You want to see Pierre?
Just for a moment.
You know, he still can't speak.
I know.
I'm sorry I couldn't come sooner.
You know how I admire Pierre,
but I was out of town.
Pretty dress.
You look like
a precocious schoolgirl.
- What do you want to tell Pierre?
- Everything I know about you.
What?
Calm down.
He's paralysed now,
completely dependent on you.
He's ashamed of being a burden
on such a virtuous wife,
so I've decided
to tell him everything.
He'll be hurt, but I think
I'll be doing him a favour.
Who could call me cruel after that?
Take me to him, please.
He's in there.
Would you like to be present
for our conversation?
What are you
thinking about, Séverine?
I was thinking about you.
I'm thirsty.
- Shall I ask for some ice?
- No, don't bother.
I can get two weeks off
this February.
- Shall we go to the mountains?
- If you'd like.
Do you hear that?