- Hey, I just got the...
- Hey.
Why are you drinking beer
at 10:00 in the morning?
Uh, we are out of orange juice.
No, we're not.
It's right behind the...
Beer.
I like beer.
Anyway, I just got
the estimate from our painter.
Oh, wow.
How much would it cost
if we used paint
instead of liquid gold?
He said it'll be done
by Saturday.
But to avoid inhaling
all the paint fumes,
he suggested
we stay in a hotel.
Hotel?
[Scoffs]
How bad can the fumes be?
Bad enough
to cause brain damage.
[Scoffs]
How much brain damage?
Here I thought we could have
a nice, romantic night away.
Really?
"Birthday" stuff?
Mm, maybe.
If it's a nice hotel.
- Oh, you mean...
- Yes, Jeff.
I want a bathroom
right in the room.
[Knock at door]
Howdy, neighbors.
Hey, Liz.
What's up?
I have a bit
of an announcement.
I've come to the conclusion
that I don't need men
to have a good time.
Men agree.
Now, I'll admit,
I did enjoy
that little rabbit Russell
thumping away on top of me.
[Scoffs]
But we all know he's a cad.
So I've decided
to become an empowered woman.
Oh. What does
today's empowered woman do?
Oh, all sorts of things.
Have you ever examined yourself
with a hand mirror?
[Spits up noisily]
Oh, say,
can you guys watch my cats
this weekend?
Especially Marty.
He'll need his eye sopped.
It's gotten all milky again.
And, oh, how he fights
those suppositories.
Just...
Well, look, we can't.
We're going away
to a nice hotel.
- Yeah.
- Private bath...
[Mutters]
Oh, sexy.
[Laughter]
I look forward to the stories.
Err on the side
of way too graphic.
Okay, here's
the key to our place.
The painter will be
finished on Saturday,
so we need you to
go in on Sunday
and close all the windows.
No problemo.
[Chuckles]
Don't touch any of my stuff.
- Ah, hey, losers.
- Hey.
Whoa.
Time has not been kind
to Dennis the menace.
[Laughter]
Dennis the menace--
precocious rascal,
adored the world over.
I'll take it.
The big news is,
I booked myself
on a cruise this weekend,
and I'm told the passengers
are almost all ladies.
Anyway, I'd say
the chances of me dropping
ye old anchor this weekend
are pretty high.
And by "anchor," I do mean...
Yeah, we know what you mean.
Uh, penis?
Yeah, we just gave this guy
a key to our apartment.
Wait, you're gonna be
on that cruise all weekend?
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, this is perfect.
Not for the women on the ship
who aren't strong swimmers.
No, he's not gonna be
in his new apartment,
so we could stay there?
That's fine by me.
Just don't get any
of your marriage cobwebs
on my furniture.
Well, what do you say, Aud?
It'd save us a chunk of change.
Yeah. Sleeping
at Russell's?
Sure. Yeah.
We were just talking about
how it doesn't burn enough
when we pee.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
[phone rings]
Russell Dunbar's office.
Ahoy there, Timmy!
This is your
cruise director Russell
aboard the s. S. Intercourse.
Ah, the rare single entendre.
Yeah, this is
actually the perfect spot.
I'll be the first man
the chicks see
when they come onboard.
Oh, I just hope
there won't be a stampede
at the refund desk.
I already checked.
There's no refunds.
Ooh, here they come.
Hey.
Hi.
[Chattering]
Timmy, what's going on?
These chicks,
they're not young.
Actually, none of them.
Timmy, why is this happening?
Oh, I don't know, sir.
Sometimes bad things happen
to horrible people.
Can you get online
and look up this cruise?
It's supposed to be filled
with red-hot ladies.
Oh, this is brilliant!
What you thought
were red-hot ladies
are in fact a group of women
known as the "red hat ladies."
- What's that?
- Well...
It says here that
the red hat society gals--
and I'm quoting
when I say "gals"--
are a group
of fun, frisky women over 50.
I'm sorry? Over 50?
Oh, my God. I'm knee-deep
in granny cranny?
Oh, sir, I had no plans
for the weekend,
but now with
the amount of laughing
I'll be doing at your expense,
I find myself overbooked.
It's best I get started.
[Laughs]
Fix this. Get me out of here,
all right? Asap.
[Ship's horn blares]
Oh. Oh, no.
Oh, no.
[Cheering]
[Calypso music]
Timmy, get me out of--
Timmy!
Timmy, call the coast guard!
Timmy, save me!
Wow, look at this place.
Wow!
Oh!
Have you ever seen
a more spectacular view?
I haven't.
[Laughs]
I know we make fun of Russell,
but I gotta say,
this place is pretty classy.
[Music plays suddenly]
Oh, I may have spoken too soon.
Well, we can judge him,
or...
We can share love,
and we can make love.
[Chuckles]
Say, how about champagne?
Ooh, did you bring any?
No, but there's
a bottle coming up
and out of that table
right now.
Oh. Yeah.
Thank you, ladies!
That's great.
[Phone rings]
- Hello?
- Hey.
These red hat loonies
are coming for me, Tim.
Well, put on your arm floaties
and swim for it.
I guess I'll just
hunker down in my cabin
and try to ignore
the sounds of breasts
dragging down the corridor.
Sir, how old are these women?
I don't know--
40? 90?
Let's be honest.
After 28, it's all the same.
I only asked
because it seems as though
they're only just a few years
older than you are, sir.
Oh, ba-ba-ba--
Timmy, Timmy.
You're breaking up.
Ship's going through a tunnel.
Ugh.
Oh, please allow me.
Nicely blown.
[Chuckles]
I get that a lot.
I'm Sylvia.
Uh, Russell.
[Chuckles]
Hmm. Care to dance,
Russell?
Oh, no, thank you.
I'm not much
of a dancer, per se.
Ohh...
[Music playing]
Although this is my jam.
Ooh-wah! Ooh-wah!
Come on, get you some!
Yeah! Don't be shy.
Get some of this.
Mm! Mm!
- Whoo!
- Okay, gals!
Do the dolphin!
Whoo! Whoo!
Ah, the Binghams.
Join me for breakfast?
Why don't I sit here
so you can sit
across from your lovely--
gee, I'm just wondering why...
- Don't want to look at him.
- Fine by me.
Hmm.
Well, then...
Elbows in
when the eggs arrive, yes?
We had a fight
at Russell's last night,
and, of course,
Jeff refused to apologize.
- I did apologize.
- You did not.
I did too.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to be rude,
but I couldn't help
but overhear.
But we could always
look at the videotape.
What videotape?
As one might expect
from a perv
like Mr. dunbar...
His apartment is rigged
with the latest
in video surveillance
equipment.
Oh, that's disgusting!
And doesn't he have to tell us
if we're being taped?
Only if he
releases it publicly.
In his employ, I've become
somewhat of a scholar
on this dark,
dank corner of the law.
[Sighs]
I'm glad that it's recorded.
Now we can settle this thing.
Yes, we can.
Let's go to Russell's.
- Let's.
- Fine.
I don't know why
Audrey asked you to go with me.
I know how to open the windows.
You're supposed to close them.
- I'm so glad you came.
- Mm.
Oh, we've never been in here
without them.
It's kind of weird.
I know.
Hey.
You know what we should do?
I think I'm thinking
what you're thinking.
Yeah.
Let's go eat
some of their cereal.
Uh, I, uh...
I had a slightly
different thought.
But after this,
I'm gonna crush some cereal.
[Exhales]
[Laughs]
Very funny, Sylvia.
Two husbands in the ground,
and you still know
how to laugh.
[Laughs]
Okay, I've pulled up
the footage from yesterday.
There we are.
Ew! That's what
we look like kissing?
I like my moves.
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
Did you remember
to turn off the coffee maker?
And there it is.
Audrey derails the sex train.
I don't know.
[Sighs]
Now I'm gonna be distracted.
You know what?
I just remembered.
I did.
I did turn it off.
He so didn't turn it off.
You just said whatever it took
to get me on my back.
So the coffee pot is on.
What's the worst that happens?
We get home,
and there's coffee?
That's not the point.
The point is you lied
just to get what you want.
You're the one that always
has to make a big deal
out of nothing.
You can't just let go
and have a good time.
Am I right, Timmy?
I'm really just here
to work the remote.
Well, you wanna know
what his problem is?
It's not difficult.
Play, pause, so forth.
He never cares at all
about things that matter to me.
Everything he says
is just designed to...
Get you on your back.
So you said, and I remember.
Um...
Let's try to focus
on the apology.
That's what gets us all home.
Little later.
Fast forward.
[Sped-up dialogue]
You look like angry puppets.
"I'm mad at you."
Just let it play then, shall I?
You know I need my mind at ease
in order to get in the mood,
especially for birthday stuff.
Birthday--
- let's just say
I give him a cake.
Go ahead.
[Sighs]
Sorry.
[Laughs]
I did apologize.
Thank you, video.
That is not a real apology.
You did not mean that at all.
I did too.
What do you think, Timmy?
Yeah, what do you think?
Oh, good.
There's no way
this ends poorly for me.
Sorry.
Certainly the monotone
suggests a lack of conviction
or even mild interest.
Thank you.
That being said,
given what we know
of Mr. Bingham's limitations
in voice modulation,
I found the apology
to be quite earnest.
See?
I'm a great guy.
[Sighs]
Uh, that's not what I said.
I...
Nothing.
Hey, wait, roll that back.
[Sped-up dialogue]
You know, we wouldn't have
to keep going through this
if just for once you would...
The video giveth...
The video taketh away.
Okay, look, pearl...
You've been divorced two years.
We all know
that Bernie's gonna do
what Bernie's gonna do.
I'm more concerned with pearl.
Okay, everyone!
Let's see those
statement necklaces!
[Laughs]
Ohh...
Mm-hmm, that's right.
Nailed it.
Huh? Huh?
How do you think
it feels to know
every time I turn my back
my husband is mocking me?
A little better than
if I were to do it to your face.
Maybe that wasn't
the best apology.
But look...
At least I don't do that.
Every time
we get in an argument,
she walks out the room.
I was hurt, Jeff.
Excuse me for not wanting you
to see me vulnerable.
Actually, Mrs. Bingham.
It may help him understand
if he sees you like that.
I'll switch to the kitchen cam.
There's a kit--
kitchen cam?
Mm-hmm.
Whoa.
Angry birds, indeed.
What the...
Adam, I think
we have a problem!
I know.
This cereal is expired.
Is it from this morning,
or do I have until midnight?
No. I have paint
all over my back.
Oh, my God.
It must be from the door.
Well...
It's not too bad.
No.
No. I can just get a brush
and smooth it over.
I think we're okay.
Is that the only spot?
Where else did we do it?
Let me see.
Okay, we started here, right,
and then we took it over here.
We brought it to...
Uh-oh.
- Is that...
- Yup.
That's your butt.
So then the first cowboy says,
"no, no, no,
I said 'posse.'"
[laughter]
What's the matter, Russell?
Don't you get it?
You see, "posse" sounds like...
No, no, no.
I know, I know, I know.
It's very clever.
That's a good one.
Are you having any fun?
Well, not the kind of fun
I was hoping to have.
Mm-hmm.
And don't get me wrong.
You guys are great.
I mean, pearl,
if you were 100 years younger,
I mean, who knows.
But aren't there any
young chicks on this raft?
Oh, yes. Younger.
- Younger?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah! We got
a couple gals in our group.
See, if they're under 50,
they wear pink hats.
Pink hats.
Well, okay.
Pink hats...
Gonna use this, pearl,
real quick.
A-ha!
Okay! Excuse me
one second.
Well, hello there,
youngish lady.
Well, hello, Russell.
Oh, for...
[Ship's horn blares]
Sake!
Well, maybe
I'll just leave then.
Oh, yeah, thanks a lot.
What?
Your little video idea
just made things worse.
Look, let's not shift
the blame to me.
Clearly you both have
some deep-seated resentments
toward each other.
- Yeah, we're married.
- And I could've done better.
Go on.
Anyway,
there's work to be done.
If you truly want
your relationship to grow,
then you're going to need
to communicate better.
So I suggest getting out
those emotional shovels
and digging until
you uncover everything
that needs to be said.
I'll leave you to it.
Wow.
He really laid it out there,
didn't he?
Yeah, I guess so.
Quite a bit to think about.
[Sighs]
Sounds like
a lot of work, doesn't it?
A lot. Plus it's Timmy,
for crying out loud!
What does he know?
We've been married
for 16 years.
I think we kind of know
what we're doing.
"I suggest you get out
your emotional shovels."
Shovel this, pal.
Idiot.
[Laughs]
I really must stop
trying to help people.
Okay, thank you.
Thanks.
So the upholstery place
said they can fix it by tonight,
but we have to
get it there right now.
But the cushions are sewn in.
We'd have to bring
the whole chair, and it's big.
Hey, they got it in,
we can get it out.
How'd they get it in?
I don't know,
but we've gotta do something.
Okay, okay, let me
just think for a second.
[Sighs]
"Sweep your chimney for you,
governor?"
Okay, how about this?
We put the chair back
and then cover the paint
with a sharpie.
I mean, the way Jeff drinks,
he'll never know
the difference.
Oh, hey, guys.
Oh, I closed your windows,
just like you asked.
Oh, it's
so beautifully designed.
And the way
the light flickers off it...
I just hope
I can do it justice.
Yeah, try to do a good job
on the necklace too.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com